Shaun...
You need to give me
your driver's license.
No, I don't.
Do you remember the
memory test I gave you?
Vividly.
Yes. It demonstrated
you have a deficit.
A deficit. You shouldn't be
driving. Dr. Blaize agreed.
Shaun, that test was
supposed to be between us.
That's why I didn't want
to do it at the hospital.
Yes. Your doctor
needs to be informed
of the results of all
your medical tests.
Even tests that
are done at home.
Shaun, I've been driving
for like half a century.
I'm an excellent driver, okay?
I don't need to give
you my driver's license.
Okay. Then I'll have
to notify the DMV.
Dr. Glassman?
You're not gonna
notify the DMV, Shaun.
Yes, I will notify the DMV.
Shaun, you will
not notify the DMV.
Dr. Glassman, if you don't
give me your driver's license,
I will notify the DMV.
Dr. Glassman?
George Reynolds, 28, sudden
onset of arm and leg weakness,
right facial droop
and trouble speaking.
CT confirmed a middle
cerebral artery embolism.
I booked us into
interventional radiology.
When did you first notice
your symptoms, George?
About four and a half hours
ago. Wait, what's wrong with me?
You may be having a stroke.
You're on monthly
injections of Lupron?
- For three months.
- That may have caused this.
Do you have prostate cancer?
No. I was diagnosed with,
uh, atypical hyperplasia.
That shouldn't have any effect
on what we're gonna do now.
We're gonna take care of
you, George. Don't worry.
This is local anesthetic.
You'll feel a pinch.
Are you a real doctor?
I'm Dr. Shaun Murphy.
People ever call you "Murph"?
No. I'm going to
make a small incision,
so, we can insert the
tube and reinflate your lung.
What do they call you, Billy?
Crater-head, Volcano, Three-Eyes...
Those are just the creative ones.
Hold tight. Here comes the tube.
You guys really know
what you're doing.
Yes, we do.
We'll order an
MRI for your lungs.
Then we will fix your
fractured eye orbit.
That will require surgery.
What do you say we
fix your forehead, too?
- You could do that?
- I think so.
I don't think so.
It's a preexisting condition
and it's not medically necessary.
It shouldn't be approved.
The MCA clot is
obstructing all distal flow.
Anti-androgens aren't
indicated for hyperplasia.
He said atypical.
You think he's lying?
Maybe, he's
gender transitioning.
Aside from cancer, there
aren't many other indications.
Let's focus on what we do know.
Feeding the catheter.
Suctioning the thrombus.
And he's recanalizing.
Slowly retract.
Whatever his reasons are
for taking anti-androgens,
hopefully there are options.
He either drops them, or he's
gonna keep having strokes.
The forehead repair would
be expensive and cosmetic.
It's not about prettying him up.
It could give him a new life,
friends, maybe a few less beatings.
Stopping the beatings
is the guard's job.
You really don't have
any empathy for Billy?
Empathy is a bad reason
to fight for someone.
If empathy makes me only want
to help patients who are
from Wyoming or have ASD,
then that's very unfair to all my
neurotypical patients from Idaho.
I need to take those drugs.
They caused your stroke.
We don't think you
have hyperplasia.
If you tell us the real reason,
I'm sure there are
other safer treatments...
No, there aren't!
If you're transitioning,
there are alternatives...
I told you why I
was taking the meds.
George, we are your doctors.
We need to know the truth.
We're not gonna tell anyone.
I'm not transitioning.
And I don't have hyperplasia.
I have problems
with my sex drive.
I know it sounds stupid. Like,
why can't I just control myself, but...
It's all I think about.
It's all I can think about.
I can't work, I can't
socialize, I can't have a life.
And those meds
are the only thing
that makes it even
remotely tolerable.
They'll kill you.
The residents have a betting
pool on who you're going to appoint
as your replacement
as Chief of Surgery.
The decision needs to be made
with decorum and expediency.
I haven't quite gotten
around to analyzing...
You've had little face
time with your attendings
since you became president.
You need to correct that.
I've scheduled your
announcement. You've got two days.
Where is he?
He's gone, signed
out AMA. I tried...
- How long ago?
- Five minutes.
Why are we in a hurry?
I was researching
alternative meds for him.
Realized Lupron
didn't make any sense.
Prescribing anti-androgens
for sexual urges
is like hitting a
mosquito with a mallet.
Unless they're deviant urges.
We might have just
released a child molester.
Should we call the police?
We can't. We have
no evidence of a crime.
Lim's at three-to-two.
Melendez is just
behind at two-to-one.
Cooperberg's seven-to-one,
and if Dartling or anybody
else comes in, you can retire.
Andrews might bail on
Melendez when he finds out
our patient bolted.
Which is why Melendez
is now four-to-one.
Pari-mutuel betting
is very exciting.
Do you need empathy
to be a good doctor?
No. I think it can interfere
with effective decision-making.
She's just saying that to
avoid hurting your feelings,
thus making her fake point for real.
Her empathy made her lie to you.
I think you just agreed with me
and insulted me at the same time.
I think empathy's
very important.
Telling the cold hard
truth even when it hurts,
sometimes is the most
empathetic thing we can do.
Which is what I'm doing
for Shaun right now.
You're welcome.
I have autism, which means I
have a deficiency of mirror neurons,
which inhibits me from emotionally
trading places with people,
which makes
empathy very difficult.
Does that mean I
can't be a good doctor?
No, it doesn't.
We all have our strengths
and weaknesses, Shaun.
One of Claire's is making
sure everyone feels validated.
The creep is back.
Is George having another stroke?
No. Severe lacerations
to the scrotum.
- Did you give him anything for pain?
- Morphine, four milligrams.
And I notified the cops. I
think it was a hate crime.
Yeah, I don't think so.
All right, on my
count. One, two, three.
- We'll take it from here.
- I'll pack him and prep him.
You did this to
yourself, didn't you?
I think I know what kind of
urges you've been having.
I'm not a monster. I
never touched anyone...
Any child.
My sister and I were
always best friends,
but then she had children.
If I can't keep taking the
drugs... I had to do this.
Home surgery tends to not
have the results you're hoping for.
You did a lot of damage, but
your testicles are unscathed.
Please, finish the job.
- I say we do it. He's a pedophile.
- No, he's not.
He just told us he was.
He has never acted on his urges,
and he's asking us to do
something to ensure he never does.
He is a decent person trying...
I'm confused. What do
you wanna do with him?
Treat him like a
patient with a diagnosis.
Put him on antidepressants,
refer him to a urologist,
give him a psych eval.
Let the experts determine if
he should have a castration.
Psych eval? Antidepressants?
When we refer people for counseling,
how often do they get cured?
I am looking to help
him manage this...
And if they don't get
cured, what happens?
They get more depressed,
can't cope, quit jobs,
maybe kill themselves.
All bad, but not
rape-a-child bad.
So, what are you going to do?
We can't ethically remove
healthy organs for crime prevention.
We don't amputate a kleptomaniac's
hands to prevent them from stealing.
Hands have many purposes. The
balls of a pedophile have but one.
Set up his referrals
and patch him up.
How long you been at Foothills?
Nine months.
Time flies in juvie.
Any visitors?
I don't have a granny
bringing me cookies,
if that's what you mean.
This is why empathy is bad.
You're talking to our
patient because you like him,
which is causing him to move,
which is affecting our imagery.
He's scared.
I'm talking to him to calm him
down, which is improving our imagery.
The fact that I like
him is beside the point.
You grow up in San Jose?
East Paly, but I got out
of there as soon as I could.
I was 15.
Your parents still there?
Mom's gone... Dear
old Dad is terrible.
- Siblings?
- A little brother. He's gone, too.
Crappy dad. Lost his brother...
I mean, you really don't have...
He's not scared.
He's short of breath because
his diaphragm is lacerated.
His stomach has
passed through that tear,
and is now in his chest.
Billy needs emergency
surgery on his diaphragm.
The defect reaches all
the way from the center,
to the anterior costal margin.
So, what do we need to do?
Divide the inferior pulmonary
ligament to bring the lung upwards.
Uh-huh. Mesh.
Whoever kicked him was
wearing some serious footwear.
And they'll be waiting for
him when he goes back,
unless we help him.
Dr. Park wants
to fix his forehead.
The Constitution guarantees prisoners
get the same care as everyone else.
Most non-prisoners can't
afford cosmetic surgery.
He would be getting better
care than everyone else.
The kid is smart and personable
and puts up a great front,
but he's scared to death.
And he got 36 months for selling weed,
a crime that doesn't even exist anymore.
You think his life would
be anything like this
if he didn't grow up with a
massive dent in his head?
Sorry. I'm not convinced.
Is that because you don't
have any empathy for Billy?
No. It's because I agree with you.
It's expensive, risky, and unnecessary.
But empathy can be an
invaluable motivator, Dr. Murphy,
that truly connects the
physician with their patient.
Is he still up there?
Yes, he is.
We can't do the
castration, George.
Not without the proper
psychiatric clearance.
- That will take forever.
- Just a few months.
A few months is forever.
Binge-watch your favorite
shows, catch up on your reading.
You attracted to
men, Dr. Reznick?
Yes. Adult men.
And if that were reprehensible,
do you think you could stop?
You have no idea what it's
like to live with these thoughts.
I hate them, and I hate
myself for having them,
but I can't stop them, and
I'm afraid of what I could do.
We will start the
process immediately.
In the meantime, we'll transfuse
you, get you on antibiotics.
No. I'm refusing treatment.
No transfusion, no antibiotics,
no repair. Let them rot.
We have something in common.
Neither of us has
a driver's license.
How do you feel about not
having a driver's license?
I'm pissed, Shaun.
- You feel pissed.
- Yes, I feel pissed.
I feel very pissed because
something important
was taken away from
me, and by a friend.
You feel very pissed
because something important
was taken away from
you, and by a friend.
And parroting everything
I say isn't helping.
I'm finding commonality,
Dr. Glassman.
I'm inquiring about
your emotional state,
and actively listening by
restating your responses.
External corroboration
enhances our sense of self-worth.
Okay. The day after I
got my driver's license,
you want to know what I did?
I went out and bought a
1963 Galaxie, midnight blue.
1,255 bucks. Every penny I
earned for the past three years
working in a gas station.
How do you think
that made me feel?
You liked it?
No, Shaun, I loved it.
You want to know why?
Because a car to a 16-year-old
kid means independence,
which means he can go wherever
he wants, whenever he wants.
And that doesn't
change with age, Shaun.
In fact, it means even more.
When you took my license,
that's what you took from me.
I don't expect you to understand,
so, you don't have to pretend.
Hey, is Andrews stalking you?
Yeah.
It's annoying. We need to stand
together and tell him to back off.
I'm not telling the
president he's annoying.
He's infringing on our autonomy
and inhibiting the free flow of ideas,
both of which affect our ability
to deliver the best patient care.
That sounds slightly
better. Okay, I'm in.
- Are you?
- No, of course not.
The last thing I'm gonna
do right now is confront him.
I'm the front-runner.
Not according to
Vegas. I'm three-to-two.
Guess they don't know that you
have double my mortality rate.
I'm a trauma surgeon. You're
comparing apples to asshats.
I resent being called an apple.
The diaphragm
repair went very well,
and we've scheduled
your orbital fracture repair.
And we'll get you some stronger
pain meds for the recovery.
When are you gonna fix my
forehead, make me all John Legend?
I tried, Billy. I'm sorry.
Wasn't really getting
my hopes up, anyway.
My dad taught me that. He'd say,
"You know what, Billy?" and
he'd just punch me in the face.
At least, I think that was the
lesson he was trying to impart.
That's what happened
to your forehead?
He was a big A's fan.
Watched every game
with a bat in his hand.
August 14th, 2008, they
lost in the twelfth inning...
Infection's setting in,
but his testicles still show
good flow on the Doppler.
Pain meds?
He won't take them. He
thinks they'll knock him out,
and we'll step in
and repair them.
I hate this.
Me, too.
I'm going to be a good driver.
I got every answer correct
on the written test, except one,
but that was because it
was improperly worded.
I told the DMV they
need to rewrite it,
and they said they'd
take it under advisement.
Great. Let's go.
Okay, let's close our eyes, and
take some nice deep breaths.
And how about a
little guided imagery
to evoke positive
visualizations?
Okay.
Let's picture the parking
lot, the cars around us,
the yellow steel thingy at
the entrance of the parking lot
that could really
do a lot of damage...
A bollard.
The speed bump that is
15 feet from the corner,
with the stop sign
that someone put
a "Hate" sticker on,
so, it says "Stop Hate,"
which is right in front of the
Jiff-E Mart, which says it's open
"8:00 till late, 24/7,"
which can't be true...
That's great, Shaun. Super
amount of visualization.
And now, that we're feeling
comfortable about our surroundings,
we can put the car into drive,
ease our foot off the brake.
Very nice. We can open
our eyes now, Shaun.
What we're doing is cruel.
I am open to all
options, Dr. Browne.
I'm gonna have to ask
you to give us some privacy.
Really? You want to throw
the president of the hospital
out of a medical discussion?
You're infringing on my autonomy
and inhibiting the free flow of ideas,
both of which affect my ability
to deliver the best patient care.
Dr. Melendez.
There are many drivers not
following the rules of the road.
They fail to signal,
check their blind spots...
Display a red flag when the load extends
more than four feet past the tail lamp.
You're right, Shaun.
It's a mad world,
but there's nothing
you can do about them.
You just gotta focus on you.
- Yes, let's focus on me.
- Yes.
Let's take the next right.
You can drive in the bike lane when
you're this close to the turn, Shaun.
No, I can't.
It's a broken line.
That was the improperly
worded question.
Whether it's broken or solid,
you can't enter the bike lane
this distance from the
intersection. I told them that...
Okay, Shaun, you
don't have to go so slow.
She's in the lane. She's not
supposed to be in the lane.
It's a violation
carrying a fine.
Okay, Shaun, don't worry
about what she's doing.
No.
Shaun, you have to
pull into the bike lane.
Don't worry about
what she's doing.
You can't just stop.
Shaun, you can't just stop.
Shaun.
George is screaming in agony,
and we are doing nothing except
hiding behind ethical red tape.
Ethical red tape is there
to protect people like him
from making permanent,
regrettable mistakes.
I'm glad we're not using
it to cover our asses
the day before the new
Chief of Surgery is announced.
Let me sign off on
the documentation.
I'll note his scrotum is
already beyond repair,
and surgical castration
is our only option.
I vote yes.
No. I'm not gonna let
anyone falsify medical records.
Not for pain, not
for a pedophile.
Once his testes are
actually beyond repair,
we will castrate him.
So, we're just gonna
leave him there screaming,
keeping his entire unit awake?
Move him.
I'd like a clean dissection
through the periosteal plane,
so, I can slip the MEDPOR
mesh over the fracture.
And why do I prefer MEDPOR mesh?
It allows fibrovascular ingrowth
and integration of the patient's tissue.
Prisoner surgeries are approved
for psychological reasons all the time.
Tattoo removal, gender
reassignments, including breast implants.
Hell, if he had a crappy smile,
we could justify dental work
as needed for
proper mastication.
You send a few kids to juvie?
More than a few.
You feel guilty. Think that's
maybe clouding your judgment?
Maybe.
You're afraid of ruffling Andrews'
feathers this close to decision day.
Think that's maybe
clouding yours?
We could give Billy
a breast implant.
We could insert it over his split
thickness frontal bone defect.
It would only require a
tiny incision at his eyebrow.
Now, you're in favor of this?
I was against it because it was too
expensive, and unnecessary and risky,
but if we do it now, it won't
require any additional surgery,
and it'd be very economical.
He did give us verbal consent
when he was first admitted.
Keep him under.
Get what we need, Dr. Murphy.
Ready or not...
Tell Melendez to
meet us in the OR.
Showing signs of ischemia.
We have a strong
medical case for removing.
Dr. Lim, you a castration fan?
Right now I am. Andrews
told me he's backing off.
Great.
Because you presented him
with a very good argument,
my argument, which
you regurgitated to him
right after you said you
wouldn't back me up.
- Call that leadership?
- Yes, I do.
You presented me with
a very good argument,
but you didn't have the guts to
take it to Andrews on your own.
One more reason I don't
want to work under you.
You don't want this promotion, so
that you can improve the hospital.
You want it for
the pretty title.
You're an adrenaline junkie.
You won't last two weeks
liaising with board members.
There's a long and dusty trail
littered with people who
have underestimated me.
We're ready to go.
Curved tissue scissors, please.
His systolic is 68,
and look at this.
He's septic.
He's going into DIC.
Rerun his labs. Have
platelets, plasma and cryo ready.
If he starts
bleeding, he'll die.
I reduced the volume
from 80 cc to 35.
Have the odds changed
in the last 24 hours?
- A little.
- Where am I at?
Six-to-one.
Put 100 on me.
He's becoming
severely bradycardic.
The pressure on his orbit
caused a retrobulbar hematoma.
We don't relieve it now, he'll
arrest. Forceps and scissors.
I just lost his pulse.
Pushing atropine.
Set up a temporary
transcutaneous pacemaker.
If we inject the orbital
muscle with local anesthetic,
we might be able
to fatigue the reflex.
Do it.
Starting CPR.
I hope that's a look of resolve.
Melendez stood up to
me in front of his residents.
I did the same thing to
O'Connell when I was his age.
What about Lim?
She has the kind of focus
it took me years to develop.
And Cooperberg, he reminds
me of me when I was...
Marcus, you were good,
but no one's gonna be as
good as you think you were.
One of your weaknesses
was decision-making.
I trust you've gotten past that
since I made you president.
Continuing compressions
until I have capture
on the pacemaker.
Pacing pads are in position.
Stopping CPR.
Injecting lidocaine.
I have set the rate to 80.
Increase the ventricular
by two milliamps.
Increase by two more.
Blood pressure is
responding. 102 over 68.
Keep those pacer settings, and
let's get back to the main event.
Both his PT and PTT
are coming back down.
His systolic is stable at 110,
and no ectopy on the monitor.
His DIC score is back
under four. He's stabilized.
Ball's in your court.
Dr. Melendez?
Effects of low testosterone on
cardiovascular function and sepsis?
Possible acute vascular
response, circulatory collapse.
And what about on DIC?
Increased risk of
clots and stroke.
George's body can't tolerate
any loss of testosterone right now.
If we want to save his life,
we have to save his testicles.
Sutures.
I know how to get you to drive.
I can't drive.
Driving is just like surgery.
Say you're driving
down the street,
and suddenly, somebody steps
off the sidewalk right in front of you.
Things like that must happen when
you're deep inside someone's belly.
- That doesn't make any sense.
- It's an analogy, Shaun.
I need you to work with
me just a little bit. Gimme.
Okay.
It would be something
unexpected, out of our control,
from an aberrant
source, and very bad.
It would be analogous
to an arterial bleed.
How about if a truck
stalls out, crippling traffic?
A thrombus impeding
blood flow, so we divert.
A thrombus, exactly.
What if you're
just cruising along,
and a car comes out of
nowhere and goes racing by?
A tachyarrhythmia.
Yes, Shaun, you got this!
- Yes.
- So, let's get you driving that hooptie.
I've got this, Albert.
We did the surgery.
Your circulatory and clotting
systems were shutting down.
But removing your testicles
would have put you at
greater risk by reducing your...
You would have died.
I've set you up with a
psychiatrist and a urologist.
They'll screen you, get you cleared,
and then we can do this the right way.
George, we can get this done.
You just cannot try this again.
I get it. I do it your way,
or it just doesn't happen.
It's just another
intersection, Shaun,
just like the last one,
and just like the next one.
The last intersection
isn't where everyone
honked at me and made me freeze.
That was a different
day, with different drivers,
and a different Shaun behind
the wheel, because today,
this Shaun has a plan for
this intersection, which is...
I am going to dissect it.
Damn right you are.
And today, you're gonna turn
right, which you will do by...
Determining laterality,
and waiting until I can
legally enter the bike lane.
Somebody just made a turn.
Shaun!
Everybody okay?
You were wrong.
You were wrong,
Lea. I can't drive.
- Shaun, I thought I had it figured out.
- I can't drive.
Surgery is mechanical.
Mechanics are predictable.
Driving is subject
to human foibles,
which means there
are limitless possibilities.
- You're right. My metaphor sucked.
- It sucked very much.
Because becoming a surgeon is
about way more than operating.
You had to learn about
interacting with teachers,
co-workers, patients, bosses.
Cooperating with them,
communicating with them...
I am very bad at communicating.
Shaun, you became a surgeon,
one of the hardest
things that anyone can do.
And you proved that just
because something is hard,
doesn't mean you can't do it.
And look what you just did.
I just hit a trash can.
Exactly. A trash can instead of
an oncoming car or a pedestrian.
You did great, Shaun.
That soccer ball was a
dropped Metzenbaum.
I know, right?
When I accidentally drop
an instrument in the OR,
I react quickly to
minimize damage.
- Yes. I dropped a Metzenbaum.
- Yes.
I can drive this hooptie.
Window's about to close.
Ten will get you 20 on Melendez.
Ten will get you 1,000
if you want to bet on me.
Hey, everybody.
I can't be prouder
of all of you.
We have grown into a
preeminent surgical department,
which has been recognized
with the official designation of
Surgical Center of Excellence.
It's now more important than ever
that we maintain our high standards,
and so, while there are
many worthy candidates,
I have decided
to retain the title
myself. Thank you.
Thank you.
- Hey.
- Yes!
You did it. You really did it.
It was his idea.
Murph, you...
We inserted a small breast
implant to fill in the depression
and create a more
aesthetically pleasing contour.
- Breast implant?
- Yes.
You saved my life.
It was a mistake.
It caused an oculocardiac
reflex, and you almost died.
It was a mistake.
George?
Why didn't his
monitor alarm go off?
He was stable. I disconnected
it, so he could use the restroom.
- I didn't...
- Morgan, he's gone!
George!
I was never gonna
confront Andrews.
I was playing you.
But damn if you didn't
actually make it work.
It didn't work for anybody.
He played us both. He
set us against each other.
I think you were right,
even if you were just bluffing.
We need to stand together.
Where was that
wisdom two days ago?
Still in the bottle.
Hey, how'd you come
up with that idea?
You mentioned breast
implants and I thought...
Of his forehead.
We were operating on his
eye. His forehead was covered.
Why were you thinking of it?
You care about him.
You were worried about his
problem. You empathized with him.
- My idea almost killed him.
- No, it didn't.
I found these in Billy's drawer.
Three days of pain meds.
He was cheeking
them to build up a stash.
He wasn't exaggerating.
You saved his life, Shaun.
This isn't the way this
should have ended.
But I'm not so sure the
world is a worse place
than it was a
couple of hours ago.
You almost look
comfortable behind the wheel.
This seat has excellent lumbar
support, but I am still very nervous.
- I can drive a car.
- I can see that.
Lea taught me using
a very bad analogy.
Nothing works
like a bad analogy.
He's getting pretty good.
Won't be long before
he gets his operator's.
Your next radiation
appointment is in 45 minutes.
Ow.
Thank you.
I'd go the whole wide world
I'd go the whole wide world...
Whoo!
Just to find her
I'd go the whole wide world
To find out where
they hide her...