- Uh...
- Ha.
- That wasn't the warm reception
I was expecting.
- Sorry. Just thinking
about the day ahead.
- Speaking of...
dinner before the recruiting
event tonight?
- Oh, yeah.
of the next generation
of Navy sailors.
- [laughs]
Don't sound so excited.
- Wish I could stay,
but duty calls.
- Hey, you okay?
You were tossing and turning
like crazy last night.
- Yeah, all good,
and yes to dinner.
- You're not hearing me,
Dr. Halstead.
With the hospital
being sued--
- I'm under a microscope.
I get it.
Doesn't make it fair.
- You ignored
your patient's wishes
and put the hospital
in jeopardy.
It's absolutely fair,
and now you have to deal
with the consequences.
You're in for interrogatories,
depositions, mediation,
and then possibly
a civil trial,
and that doesn't even include
what you may have to
go through with
the state medical board.
- Yeah. Okay.
- Every move you make
will be scrutinized
by Jennifer Baker's
attorneys.
Stick to the script.
Don't give them
any more ammo.
Until the lawsuit is settled,
you are the perfect doctor.
Are we clear?
Because your future
at this hospital...
depends on it.
- Five, six,
seven, eight...
Uh-uh, girlfriend.
Go to Treatment 4, please.
- You got it.
- Thank you.
- Right this way.
- All right.
Reese, why so glum?
- Residency Match picks.
- Ah.
- They have to be in
by end of day
and I have no clue
what to do.
I'm literally choosing
where I'll spend
the next four years of my life.
- And probably the rest
of your life after that.
- Be nice.
[phone beeps]
Dr. Choi, incoming!
- Where are we going, Maggie?
- Trauma 2.
- Dad?
- Bret Cooper, 17-year-old male,
down on the ice after a hip
check--GCS 10, improved to a 12.
- I'm his father.
I was there.
He didn't get his bell rung.
He barely got hit.
- Bret, I'm Dr. Choi.
Can you hear me?
Can you breathe?
- Get me off of here!
- All right, let's transfer him.
Reese, on your count.
- Okay, nice and easy.
One, two, three.
- [groans]
Uhh!
and let's get him up
on the monitors.
- On it.
- Check his sat levels.
- [whimpering]
- Okay. Pupils equal
bilaterally and reactive.
- He stayed on his skates
the whole time.
- Bret, I need you to focus
on me--is there any pain?
- Ah--there!
Right where you're touching.
- Your show, Reese.
- He needs a CT head
and spine,
and I would get him
a chest X-ray.
- Come on, really?
- We got this.
- Oh, my God--is it a
concussion--What happened, Jack?
- He was battling for a puck
along the boards--it's nothing.
- Mr. and Mrs. Cooper, I'm
gonna need you to step outside.
- Bret had a bad concussion
last month.
- Honey, it's not a concussion.
Look, Doc,
he's got a scholarship
on the table
for Boston College, okay?
Another concussion,
they might rescind the offer.
- My eyes--everything's blurry!
- Bret, you have to stay still.
Please, Bret, you have to hold
still--hold still, buddy.
- Dad!
- Son, you okay?
Dad, I can't see!
- Stay still, Bret.
- I can't see!
Stay still.
- Wake up, Sleeping Beauty.
The cat nap's over.
- Oh, yeah.
- They're on their way in.
- How long was I down?
- About 20 minutes.
- Oh, it felt like 20 seconds.
- You know you're only supposed
to work 12-hour shifts, right?
It's the law.
- I know.
But Dr. Downey
makes his own rules.
- All right--
- Half a minute more.
[whimpering]
Come on.
- Down.
Ticktock.
- Doc, hey.
How is he?
- What happened to his eyesight?
- His vision's fine.
It was a transient impairment,
probably caused by anxiety.
- What about his head?
Is it another concussion?
- Can't say for sure yet.
We're doing a CT of his head
and cervical spine
to make sure
there's no bleeding.
That might require
surgery.
- Surgery?
Oh, God.
- I'm not saying
he needs surgery.
We just need
to rule everything out.
Let's not get worked up
before the tests come back.
It's--it--it's...
it's like...
it's like I...
It's like I said before.
It--it l-looks worse than it is.
Look, Doc, I played 18 seasons.
I took a hit or two.
I sat out a shift,
got right back in.
- Trust me, I get it.
Listen, as soon
as we get the tests back,
we'll figure out our next step.
- Okay.
- Thanks.
- Sure.
Ma'am.
- It's gonna be fine.
- Whoa.
- Tired, Dr. Rhodes?
- No, I feel great.
- Sign for the lungs,
and let's move.
- All right.
How long was he waiting?
- Half a minute.
- Watch out, please.
- Yes. Spoke with Dr. Bucchheit
about Loratazone--
think it's gonna work out.
Hey, Greg,
let me call you back.
Dr. Halstead--Will.
- Zoe, how are you?
Your hair's different.
I like it.
- Yeah?
- Yeah. Thank you.
- Had a great time
the other night.
You've officially converted me
to a rye whiskey girl.
- It cleanses the soul,
or at least the memory.
- Things any better?
- Well, they
haven't gotten worse.
Guess that's something.
- Good.
Cup half full--my kind of guy.
- Round two soon?
- I'll call you
when my shift's over.
- Yeah.
Okay.
- Mr. Anderson,
I'm Dr. Halstead.
- Oh, please, call me Tim.
- You got it, Tim.
So you're a diabetic?
- Yeah, since after college.
Lucky bastard, I know.
- I see you're
on the blood-thinner Warfarin.
How's your INR?
- Don't know.
I haven't had it checked
in a few weeks.
- Mm-hmm.
Let's have a listen.
Uh-huh.
Yeah, you've also had
a mitral valve replaced.
I can hear the clicking.
- Yeah, two stent operations,
an atherectomy,
and a laser angioplasty.
- And somehow
still putting us all to shame.
- Well, look good,
feel good, Dr. Manning.
I was wondering
if I would see you.
- Dr. Halstead,
you mind if I sit in?
- You don't have to ask.
- So what's going on
today?
Last time you were in
for a foot infection.
Any reoccurrence?
- No,
just a little shortness
of breath.
I was cleaning out my attic,
started feeling
a little light-headed.
Nothing, really,
to worry about,
but, still,
better safe than sorry.
- Anything else?
- My left leg's
been aching a bit.
- Mr. Anderson
is in congestive heart failure.
- Oh?
- It's mild.
At least, that's what
my last doctor told me.
- But you could still stand
to lose some of that fluid.
All right, what we're gonna
do--chest X-ray, EKG, labs.
Have IR do an angiogram,
check the flow of the leg.
for the Bulls game.
- Don't worry, Tim, we'll
get you the wi-fi password.
You can watch the game
on your phone.
- Hey.
- [murmuring]
- A little overboard.
His leg wasn't cold.
A vascular ultrasound,
maybe,
but an angiogram's
a bit much to start.
- He's a decade-long
vasculopath.
His blood vessels are shot.
- He's not indicating.
I hardly think he needs another
uncomfortable procedure.
- There's no telling
what he needs.
Look, I am not
dismissing you, Nat,
but I did the intake.
It's my call.
[tense music]
♪
- Thanks.
- Hey.
- Hoo, you look like crap.
- [laughs]
Thanks.
Downey boot camp.
- Presume
you're on the transplant?
- Ex-vivo--have you
ever seen one?
The lungs are
perfused out--
- Outside the body, yeah.
I know the procedure.
- Yeah, the patient was
an NYFD first responder on 9/11.
He developed pulmonary fibrosis
from debris exposure.
So no good deed, right?
[pager beeping]
- I got to jet.
Your trauma pages
are coming to me now.
- Lunch later?
- Page me.
- So then I just break up
the center
and carry the puck
into the zone myself?
- Exactly. You catch the D-man
in the neutral zone.
- And I'll be left
with a two-on-one.
- Good read.
- Hey,
put that away now.
- Good news.
CT head and spine were clear.
- No concussion?
- No concussion.
- So I'm out of here?
- And off to Chestnut Hill.
Go, Eagles.
- Sweet! Thanks, Doc.
- Sure.
- Sports aren't really my thing.
- What'd I tell you, hon?
Nothing.
The kid's a rock.
Like father, like son.
Doc, thanks so much.
- You got it.
- Okay, so let's go tell
those bad-news scouts
that the nation's number-one
recruit is good to go.
- Dr. Choi, is it possible
you missed something?
Bret complains of headaches.
- Mom.
- He's had this one
for two weeks.
- Joan, enough!
Look, the scan
came back clean, honey.
Stop looking for something
that isn't there.
- LP?
- Headaches could be
a symptom of meningitis.
An infection like that wouldn't
show up on the CT.
Could explain why a minor hit
caused such a big
reaction earlier.
I think it's best
we do a spinal tap.
- Okay, but meningitis,
that is treatable, right?
- Hockey can wait
for an hour, Jack.
- Okay, Joan.
- So, Bret,
if you could lie
on your side
and pull your knees
up to your chest,
I'm gonna numb you
with a local anesthetic.
Are you okay?
- Feeling a little dizzy.
- Okay.
- Bret? Bret!
- Bret!
- Reese!
Little help!
- Anything hurt?
- Not really.
Gonna be stiff tomorrow,
though, aren't I?
- Yeah,
but pain builds character.
- According to who,
exactly?
[both chuckle]
- Bret still needs an LP.
You good?
- Uh...fourth period,
bottom of the 9th--
put me back in, Coach.
- Butchered hockey,
football,
and baseball
in one sentence--impressive.
- Dr. Charles,
thanks for coming down.
Quick favor?
- Shoot.
- Uh, got a patient,
17-year-old hockey player.
- I heard.
Bret "Bear" Cooper.
Dad was a heavy.
Hear the kid's
even better.
- Wouldn't have taken you
for a jock.
- Oh, come on--sport's the
oldest form of group therapy.
We yell.
We scream.
Testosterone spikes.
Every now and then, we even
get to believe in a miracle.
Your patient...
- It's actually his father Jack
that I needed the consult on.
He's exhibiting memory loss,
hand tremors, agitation--
could be Chronic
Traumatic Encephalopathy,
but I'd like to rule out
anxiety and depression first.
- CTE sounds right.
Get hit in the head
that many times,
it's bound to catch up
with you.
- Yeah.
- Past always does.
- Listen,
sorry about the other day.
We got slammed.
- I get it.
E.D. never sleeps.
But if you keep skipping
our sessions, buddy,
I'm afraid
you won't either.
- So finally, as we reintroduce
blood into your lungs,
we will manually compress
the pulmonary artery
to avoid
initial volume overload.
- Hey, can I see those lungs
again, please, Doc?
- Yeah, of course.
- Science fiction
meets reality.
[both chuckle]
I just hope they work as well
once they're in me.
- Believe me,
you couldn't be in better hands
than Dr. Downey's.
- We'll see you in the O.R.,
Mr. Mosconi.
- Your lungs
got a Chicago Fire escort
like I have never seen.
- Brothers in arms.
This is really happening.
- It is.
We'll see you on the other side.
- Yeah.
- Quite the presentation,
Dr. Rhodes.
- I wanted to be thorough.
- Great.
Next time, in English.
Patient's
already overwhelmed.
- Okay.
- Start of the second,
Bulls are looking strong...
- What's the score?
- Bulls are up by 4.
- Nice.
- Dr. Manning,
Tim's blood work came back.
INR's high.
- Same thing happened
the last time he came in.
All right, let's ease him off
the blood thinners
and give him 10mg
of Vitamin K
to level off
his clotting factors.
- Put in the order.
- Thanks.
Oh, those tests
that Dr. Halstead ordered?
- All negative.
- Put Tim through
all that stress for nothing.
- They won't listen.
They're doing a lumbar puncture.
That is exactly what I was
trying to tell them.
Okay, yeah.
I'll keep you posted, Doc.
Thanks.
- Mr. Cooper?
Dan Charles.
Boy, what a pleasure.
- That's quite a grip.
Good for stick handling.
You ever played hockey?
- Oh, a million years ago.
Only Junior League goalie,
but had one shut-out.
Best day of my life.
- Ha. I loved
the Junior Leagues.
played the game for no other
reason than it was fun.
Don't read too much into that.
You are a shrink, right?
- Oh, boy,
what gave me away?
- Well, the team always
had a couple on the payroll.
Soft spoken, loved eye contact,
and not to mention
the sweater vest
and the Rockports didn't help.
- [laughs] Oh, geez.
Well, then you know
exactly what
my next question's gonna be.
- How am I feeling?
Conflicted.
I mean,
my son is in the E.D.,
so as a dad, I'm concerned.
But as a former player,
knowing that leaving it out
on the ice is what got us here,
couldn't be more proud.
- Sacrifice in the name
of sport--
wouldn't know
anything about that.
I never played hockey.
- You know, that's a shame.
I mean, you got
great width, you know?
You never thought
about playing goalie?
- Mm--more of a bookworm
than a bruiser.
- [chuckles]
Yeah, I got you.
- The spinal tap's done.
We'll get it off to the lab
and go from there.
- Great.
Well, nice to meet you,
Doc.
- Real pleasure.
- Short-term memory loss--
- As of now,
CTE's only diagnosable
postmortem,
but I'm afraid
your instincts are correct.
- You still at it?
- Mm-hmm.
- Didn't your mom
ever tell you you'd go blind
staring at a screen
that long?
- My mother
was a litigation attorney
and worked 90-hour weeks.
She didn't tell me much.
- Well, guess
it's on the nurses then.
All right, this hospital's
too far from the city.
You wouldn't last a week
in the boonies.
- [laughs] Oh,
and this one's way too vanilla.
You've been rolling with us.
You got a little flavor now.
- This one's Boston?
Winters are terrible.
All right,
you got me on that one.
Maybe...we're angling
for you to stay.
- Chicago Med's definitely
in the running.
- Ah?
- It's my specialty
I'm torn over.
I always thought
I'd choose pathology,
but the E.D.'s really...
grown on me.
I can't believe
I just said that.
- Oh, that's okay,
sweetie.
You're not the first lab geek
that we've turned.
- You shouldn't be
the last one in.
- Patient's ready, Dr. Downey.
- Let's get this show
on the road.
- Propofol's going in.
[rapid beeping]
Pressure's tanking.
- No pulse.
- Rhodes, on his chest.
Allen, how much epi
has he gotten?
- 20 mics.
[flatline tone]
[flatline stops]
[steady beeping
- Got a pulse back.
- Good waveform on the A Line.
He's in sinus rhythm.
- Let's TEE.
- All right.
- Here you go, Doctor.
- Thank you, Nurse.
- Get in there.
- Show me what I need to see.
- Look at the aortic
valve.
- Valve area's .6.
- Cardiologist said it was only
mild to moderately stenotic.
- I know,
but this is critical.
He needs a new valve.
- How long have the lungs
been perfusing?
- Including transport,
at least six hours.
They're good for another
five to six,
but we can't transplant
until we fix that valve.
- Keep him deep--between
his lungs and the blockage,
he won't tolerate
going under again.
You and I need to figure out
a plan quickly.
[alarm]
- Code blue, treatment 1.
Code blue, treatment 1.
- What happened?
- A second ago,
he was perfectly stable.
We were talking.
- Hold compressions.
[flatline tone]
No pulse.
- What's going on?
- I don't know.
No breath sounds.
- V-Fib!
- Crash cart!
- Charge to 200 joules.
- Charging.
Charged.
- Everyone clear.
[beep beep]
Nat, back away.
- No, just give me
one more second.
I see the cords.
I'm almost in.
All right, tube's in.
Let's go.
- Everyone clear!
- Nothing.
Copy. O.R. on standby.
- Round of epi.
- Got it.
- Charging.
- Charged.
- Clear!
- Clear.
[beep beep]
[thump]
- Still in fib.
- Nat, you take over
compressions.
Don't stop for anything.
April, where's that epi?
- Epi's in.
- Clear.
Clear!
[beep beep]
[thump]
- [murmurs in background]
- CPR. Epi again.
Follow it
with an amp of bicarb.
- Yes, Doctor.
- Asystole--he's got no pulse.
- I got it.
- Will.
Will, he's gone.
[dramatic music]
♪
Time of death--14:21.
- Balloon valvuloplasty
will stabilize the valve
and allow us to do
the transplant.
- It's only a stopgap.
In a month
we're back at square one
needing to replace the valve,
only now the patient's
fresh off a transplant.
- Then we open him up,
replace the aortic valve,
and do the transplant
afterwards.
- I don't want him
open that long.
Invites a whole host
of complications.
- Okay.
How about this?
We do the valve replacement
and the lung transplant
at the same time.
- We'll do a trans-aortic
valve replacement first--
Cardiologist can go in
through the groin via catheter
to fix the valve.
Once they're done, we'll move
on with the transplant.
- A brain infection--
like meningitis?
- You can treat this
with antibiotics, can't you?
- Possibly.
We did catch this one early.
This is cerebritis,
not meningitis,
which is not only serious
but stems from
some underlying condition,
one we have yet to find.
- So...more tests?
- Afraid so.
- Hey.
Third period, son.
We got this.
- Mr. Cooper...
mind if I talk to you
for a second?
- Yeah, sure.
- Hang tight.
We're gonna get
to the bottom of this.
Hey.
- Hey.
- Look, I couldn't help
but notice earlier--
- The CTE.
- Yeah.
- Yeah, I know.
I know.
I got it under control.
- Mr. Cooper,
the disease is progressive.
- You think I don't know that?
I have a private physician,
a team doctor
from when I played,
and he says
it's not too bad.
- And Bret?
- Bret is fine.
All right?
The game's changed, huh?
Safer.
Better equipment,
better penalty regulations--
- Does he know?
- Well, I don't really see
how that's any
of your damn business.
- Bret deserves the truth.
What kind of father
keeps his kid in the dark?
- Hey, you watch
what you say to me!
- Dr. Choi!
I apologize
for my colleague, sincerely.
Why don't you, um,
why don't you go
check on your wife and son?
I'm very sorry about that.
- Okay.
Thanks.
- He's keeping it from Bret.
- And so you thought
threatening him
would make him more
forthcoming?
That's my conversation anyway.
Why didn't you page me?
- Wouldn't have helped--
guy's in total denial.
- Oh, he is?
Huh.
[scoffs]
This is why you go
to therapy
and why you stick
with it.
- [whispers]
Come on.
What the hell?
Can I talk to you
for a minute?
Why did you administer
vitamin K to my patient
without consulting me?
- His clotting was slow.
It's standard protocol,
and I think
you mean our patient.
- Your protocol may have caused
a pulmonary embolism.
- You have no grounds
to say that.
Any number of things
could've happened.
He has been battling
his vasculopathy for years.
- Oh, so now he was
a ticking time bomb?
- That's not
what I said,
and if you had listened,
you'd know that.
- I heard you loud and clear.
You thought nothing was wrong,
and where is Tim now?
He was stable when I left him.
- You better think about
what you're saying right now.
- Nat, that vitamin K
made him throw a clot.
- You don't know that.
- If you hadn't interfered,
he'd still be here.
- No, this is not about me.
This is about you and the mess
that you made
when you resuscitated
Jennifer Baker against her DNR.
Well, blaming me for this
is not gonna make that right.
[tense music]
♪
- Hey, I paged you twice.
- Shouldn't you be
operating?
- No, the patient arrested.
Cardiologist is doing a TAVR,
and I had a minute and figured
we might grab a bite to eat.
- Sit.
- I--you know,
maybe I'm missing something.
I-I just--I pitched Downey
at least four solutions,
right?
Not one bullet hit its mark.
You know, half the time,
I feel like I'm the chosen one.
The other half,
I feel like I'm failing him.
I just can't get a read
on the guy.
- Mind if we talk
about something else?
- Is there something
we should be talking about,
'cause I get the feeling--
[beeping]
Damn, uh...I gotta go.
Look, we'll pick this up
later, okay?
- Yeah.
- Often,
brain infections are caused
by inflammation in the sinuses
and in the ears.
Your ears look okay.
- Always know you wanted
to be a doctor?
- Yes.
- Huh.
- And no.
As a kid, I was intrigued
by anatomy,
dissecting frogs
and looking at their organs
under the microscope.
I never thought I'd be
dealing with people
in their most difficult
times.
And you?
Hockey...
[both chuckle]
Hockey is...
Well, it's so...
- Vicious?
- Well, yeah.
- [laughs]
Yeah.
- I don't understand
how someone could risk all of
their teeth for a game.
- [chuckles]
My dad played pro,
and I was skating
before I could walk.
Even if I wanted
a different career,
nothing else would feel
right on me.
Guess you can't
escape who you are.
- You've got a little
dried blood in your nose,
but it's probably
just because of the fall.
- Oh, no, I had a nosebleed
this morning.
I get 'em all the time.
- All the time?
- Yeah, it's no big deal.
- Can I take a look
in your mouth, please?
- Okay.
[tense music]
♪
- I'll be right back.
- Ms. Goodwin?
- Yeah?
- My schedule--I would like
to be on different shifts
than Dr. Halstead.
- Oh?
- I think it's in the best
interest of our patients.
It's nothing personal.
- It sounds personal.
You two at odds?
- That's putting it mildly.
- Listen,
I couldn't honor your request
even if I wanted to.
With the hospital
under scrutiny,
any changes
with Dr. Halstead
could be interpreted
as culpability.
It's status quo
until the dust clears.
You know, when I'm faced
with a snarling dog,
I try to remind myself
it's self-preservation
that's making him
show his teeth.
- Sinuses and ears
were clear of infection,
but Bret gets frequent
nosebleeds,
has since he was a kid,
and he's got dilated vessels
on the inside of his mouth.
- You're thinking HHT?
- It's rare,
but it fits the symptoms.
- Okay, let's get
a CT chest and belly
and see what comes back.
- Okay.
- Reese, good call.
- No sign of foreign bodies.
No abnormalities
in my external exam.
What's your theory?
- Pulmonary embolism.
He came into the E.D.
with mild CHF
and was dead in a couple hours.
- I'm gonna start
with the chest then.
[saw buzzing]
[bones cracking]
A pulmonary embolism wouldn't
manifest this much blood.
Give me some suction.
Definitely not a PE.
Give me your hand.
You feel that?
- Mm-hmm.
- You feel the hole?
Ruptured aortic aneurysm.
He didn't stand a chance.
- So I was wrong.
- Nothing you
or anyone else could've done.
- Yeah.
- [murmuring]
Just go at him right there...
[whistle blows]
[crowd noise]
[Bret continues murmuring]
- Hey, Bret.
- Mr. and Mrs. Cooper, Bret,
we got our chest CT back.
Why don't we have a seat?
- Okay.
- Bret has a condition
called hereditary hemorrhagic
telangiectasia or HHT.
- HHT?
What's that?
- Hey, hey,
it's okay, son.
- It causes the blood vessels
in different parts of the body
to form fragile bundles called
arterial venous malformations.
These AVMs can sometimes allow
bacteria to seep into the blood
- Is it curable?
- It's manageable.
The AVMs can be repaired,
but they have
a tendency to recur.
- Okay, so what does it mean?
- I can still play, right?
- We'll try to monitor any AVMs
that might develop,
but if there's an AVM
we don't know about,
one wrong hit, and you could
suffer a catastrophic bleed.
Look, I'm sorry, Bret,
but it's my recommendation
that you quit hockey.
- Okay, listen,
if he's had this his whole life,
why is it only a problem now?
- Yeah...
You know what?
I am getting a second opinion.
- Hey, it's gonna be okay,
sweetie.
- Mind if we have
a minute?
- I'll be right outside.
- You said
if I take the wrong hit,
you're saying I could die?
- That's what I'm saying.
Listen to me.
I know what you're thinking.
"One in a million hit
can't happen to me,"
but it can.
It can.
I know.
Think about it.
[pat pat]
- You'll find
another path...
And it'll feel right.
I'm sure of it.
- I was so certain
I was right.
I did everything I could,
covered every single base--
- I'm sure you did.
- The worst part--
I attacked a colleague.
A friend.
- You're under
a lot of pressure.
Everyone knows that.
If you apologize,
I'm Dr. Manning
will understand.
It's her, right?
Why don't we rain-check
dinner tonight?
It's okay.
- Thanks, Zoe.
- We are ready to transplant.
- Not yet.
You cut too shallow.
If the vessels are too long.
They could thrombose.
Here, trim the atrial cuff.
Not too deep.
Not too quickly.
Don't want
to damage the vessel.
Good.
All right,
let's get the lungs in.
- Maybe you should
take over.
- The aortic cannula's loose.
[rapid beeping]
- BP and sats falling.
- Get him clamped now
or he's gonna bleed out.
[beeping continues]
[tense music]
♪
- Got it.
He's clamped.
- And the pressure
is improving.
- Let's get the lungs in
and get him off the pump.
- Are you all right?
- You're gonna have
to take lead from here.
- Okay, I'll cover you.
I'm ready for the lung.
- Here, Doctor.
- Bronchus first,
followed by
the left atrial cuff
and the pulmonary artery.
Good.
Let's start sewing.
- 4-0 prolene.
- And that's
the cerebellum.
[continues murmuring]
- You see what Bret
tweeted?
- "Off my skates
for a couple of days,
but I'll be
back at All Star Clinics,
stronger than ever.
#downbutnotout."
Seriously?
He's still gonna play?
I told him he could die.
- Boys will always want to be
better than their fathers,
which is precisely
what their fathers want.
- Ready to go?
"What price glory," right?
- Headed out?
Made your decision?
- Let me guess--
E.D. strikes again.
- No--pathology.
- What?
- It's the patients.
They come in,
and you want to help them.
You care about them,
so you try to connect,
and, just when you think
you're getting through,
they go back to
what they were doing before.
And it's like you were
never even there--
like everything you did
was for nothing.
I can't take a life of that.
I'll see you tomorrow.
- I am in no mood, Will.
- I get it.
Natalie, I'm sorry.
It wasn't the vitamin K.
I was wrong.
- You, wrong?
Amazing.
- Yeah.
I've been an ass,
not just today--
since last week--
Before that.
I should not have
yelled at you.
- Why do you always
take things out on me?
You invite me in,
and then you push me back.
You ask for my opinion, and then
you completely ignore me.
It hurts, Will.
You wouldn't treat anyone else
like this, so why me?
- Don't you know?
- No.
- Mr. Mosconi's
gas exchange is good.
We'll rest him overnight,
hopefully extubate him
in the morning.
- I thought
maybe you'd be at home resting
after that episode in the O.R.
- Episode?
- You didn't need me
to take over.
- I've usually found,
Dr. Rhodes,
that when given responsibility,
people rise to the occasion.
I know the last few weeks
have been...challenging,
and I'd be lying
if I said the months to come
will be any easier.
I have an impossible amount
to teach you
in a diminishing amount of time.
You don't have to show me
how smart you are,
and you don't have to please me.
Just learn.
- He's breathing on his own.
- Indeed he is.
- Sorry about dinner.
- Wasn't sure
you were gonna show.
- I--
- What is it?
- I've been talking
to Dr. Charles,
the hospital psychiatrist.
Shared some things
about my service--tough things.
- You don't have to explain.
I know.
- I thought if I didn't think
about it or talk about it...
- I'm here.
- My dad was Navy.
- That why you enlisted?
- It just always
seemed like
that was what
I was gonna do.
- There's a room
full of kids in there
who are gonna ask you
about your service.
What are you gonna tell 'em?
- That I'd do it again.
[pop music plays]
- Scotch--rocks.
Thanks.
Who's winning?
- The Blackhawks by one.
- Nice.
- Thanks.
We haven't exactly been the same
since I started with Downey.
- No, we haven't.
- Sam, I know
this can't be easy for you...
But if you're gonna make me
choose between you and Downey...
- It's gonna be Downey.
- Yeah.
- I'm not gonna make you choose.
[somber music]
♪