I'll get a caregiver,
someone who could be
with him when I'm not.
What about you?
What about your job?
What about your life?
This is not a
long-term solution.
He's trying to sue me
to make a quick buck
off of the hospital.
It'd be my word against Pawel's.
A respected physician's
word against a con man's?
The guy's a freaking menace.
Am I gonna die?
I must've done something wrong.
Sometimes, patients
don't survive.
But it's the burden we bear.
You promised me. You
said you could save him.
I thought I could.
So what's this one?
Ginger chamomile.
I like it.
- Really?
- Mm.
How much?
I mean, words just
can't begin to...
It's Med.
Why? You're not on call.
No idea.
Ripley.
Uh-huh.
Yeah, now's... now's
not a great time for me.
Isn't there anyone
else you can call?
I'm on my way.
- Aw.
Norovirus hit the night shift.
They're short.
That's not fair.
We finally get a night together.
Yeah.
But... to be continued.
Definitely.
- Loren, talk to me.
42-year-old male.
Impalement injury
to the abdomen.
Vitals are stable. GCS 14.
He's conscious and
able to communicate.
I gave him 100 mics
of fentanyl en route.
What did he get impaled on?
You ready for this?
Voilà.
- Is that...
- Yeah, antlers.
He shot the animal and
tripped trying to move it.
Payback. It's payback.
Give him another 50 of fentanyl.
X-ray. Lateral torso, please.
It's... it's... what
do they call it?
Karma?
Just take it easy.
We're gonna take
good care of you.
Bilateral breath sounds.
Give him a gram of ceftriaxone.
150 milligrams of metronidazole.
- X-ray.
Am I gonna die?
No.
But you are gonna need surgery.
Looks like the antlers go
all the way into the back.
All right, we're gonna
take you up to the OR
where we can put you to sleep,
have this thing removed,
and see what we
need to fix, okay?
Will you let them know
that we're coming up?
Loren, you're with me.
Bambi's revenge.
Yep. Yep. Yep, I'm awake.
Good morning.
Now it is.
Here.
Thank you.
You're a lifesaver.
I know.
How was your night?
Ah, above average.
Hmm. I'd love to
hear about that.
But Maggie is asking for you.
Of course she is.
Yeah. Come on.
Ripley? You're on deck.
What's going on, Maggie?
High-risk prisoner coming
in from Statesville.
High-risk?
Yeah, violent
offender. Anthony?
Doug Green, injured
in an altercation
with another inmate.
Contusions, facial
fractures, broken ribs.
You're going to treatment four.
You get all the fun.
You give him anything
for the pain?
There was concern he
was drug-seeking, so no.
Joe?
Keep getting those
good grades, yeah?
Make something of your life.
Mr. Green, I'm Dr. Ripley.
I'm gonna take care of you.
Wha...
Do you know where you are?
The dentist?
No, you're in the
hospital. Do you know why?
I got that damn COVID again.
All right. Cut it out, Green.
Be straight with him.
I don't like you.
Officer, can I have a word?
Keep an eye on him.
How about you remove
those shackles?
Can you work around them?
- It's a hassle.
- But you can.
Shackles stay on.
Why? That guy's
not going anywhere.
Don't let the act fool you.
Green is a
cold-blooded murderer,
and he's a lying son of a bitch.
Mr. Goodwin, you need
to take smaller bites.
And maybe if you sit up
a little straighter...
Leave me alone!
I'm just trying to help you.
You treat me like a baby.
- Thanks, Mike.
- Mm-hmm.
Hey, when's chow time?
Pretty soon.
Well, this confirms
his prison X-ray.
Ribs are fractured.
He's legitimately in pain.
25 of fentanyl.
Let's get some ice on the
face, draw routine labs,
and see when we can get
him up for a pan CT.
Got it.
When's chow time?
Just ignore him.
We'll get you something to eat.
How'd you get hurt?
He provoked a fight.
Who keeps talking? Yakety-yak!
You're not fooling anyone.
His hands aren't bruised.
Doesn't look like he
threw any punches.
Well, maybe he
wanted a beatdown.
Get a hospital vacation.
Happens all the time.
- I'll be back.
- Hmm.
Morning.
Hey. Good morning.
How, uh... how's it all going?
Well, I'm not getting
very much sleep.
You know, I hear Bert get up,
start wandering
around the house.
I have to go put him back to bed
two to three times a night.
Oh, man.
He's starting to
have trouble eating,
yelling at the caregiver,
and he can't take a
shower by himself anymore.
I'm sorry.
You know, I think about
a facility, Daniel,
but I don't know.
It's so hard.
You remember the
kind of man he was...
a great father,
teacher, beloved coach.
I sure do.
And, you know, after
all he put me through,
it still feels like I'd
be throwing him away.
I don't know. Let
me go to work.
- You hang in there.
- Okay.
Here you go. Here's two.
Crockett.
- Hey, Mags.
You heard anything from
Bill Storch, Colin's dad?
All right. Well, let
me know if you do?
Hey, I know it was tough,
sending that little boy home.
Yeah.
All right.
Dr. Charles, we got
a patient from DOC.
Ooh, man. I can see that.
Yeah.
The guy got life 50 years ago
for some pretty horrific crimes.
He was brought in today with
injuries from a beating.
They don't look severe,
but there's another issue.
He strikes me as demented.
Well, a long stretch
in the prison system?
Not the best way to, you know,
maintain one's mental faculties.
The guard says he's faking it,
and that's certainly possible.
I mean, convicts have
been known to lie.
You ever hear of Vinny
"The Chin" Gigante?
Mafioso, used to wander
around Greenwich Village
in his robe and slippers,
trying to convince the Feds
that he was non compos mentis.
It was hilarious.
Anyway, you get a CT yet?
Scans are ordered.
He's in the queue.
CT is gonna give
us the best idea,
but I'm happy to have
a chat in the meantime.
Give me a couple of minutes?
- I'll shoot you his chart.
- Thank you.
How's our antler guy?
Mighty Nimrod?
He'll be okay, but
that's one rack
he won't be hanging
up on the wall.
Hey.
So I gotta get the bird
back in the hangar,
but we still good for
snow crab tomorrow?
Uh, can't wait.
Loren gets that
trauma fellowship,
I know who will
be a happy woman.
Should be hearing soon.
Uh-huh.
Mr. Green?
Morning, Officer.
Mr. Green, I'm Dr. Charles.
I was hoping we could
have a little chat.
Yakety-yak. Don't talk back.
Psychiatry.
Here we go.
Do you mind if I just get a
few minutes with the patient?
I call the shots when it comes
to this jackass, Doc, not you.
Whatever you wanna chat about,
you do it in front of me.
Okay.
So, Mr. Green, I understand
that you were
injured in a fight.
A fight? If you say so.
You don't... you
don't remember?
Yeah, I remember.
Okay, well, can you
tell me what happened?
A fight, like...
like... like you said.
Yeah.
- Okay.
So how long have
you been in prison?
I'm not in prison.
Go ahead and tell them
what you're in for.
Don't you wanna know
who you're dealing with?
Tell them what you did,
you remorseless prick.
Go ahead.
- Okay, give me a break.
Why is he talking
to me like that?
Mr. Green, don't
worry about him.
Don't worry about him.
You're talking to me.
Who are you?
Katherine Walker,
20 weeks pregnant,
lost her balance on the stairs.
GCS 15. Good vitals.
Possible fracture,
lower right leg.
Okay, on my count.
One, two, three.
She's been dizzy,
short of breath,
throwing up a lot.
Oh, God, her leg.
My boyfriend, Derek.
We splinted in the field.
She says she still
has fetal movement.
No abdominal trauma.
Make sure my baby's okay.
I'm going to, Katherine.
I'm Dr. Asher. Let's
get her some fluids.
Right.
Needles.
- Honey?
- Why don't you sit down?
Okay, I'd like to
get a chest X-ray
and an AP on the leg.
Check the baby.
I'm about to.
X-ray.
The chest looks good.
Okay.
Well, your leg isn't broken.
This is a pretty, pretty
nasty contusion, though.
Okay, I'm gonna
check the fetus now.
Doctor told me years ago
I couldn't get pregnant,
so we weren't using
birth control.
This baby's a miracle.
Yeah.
Kind of a surprise.
Okay, I am seeing abnormally
high levels of amniotic fluid
called polyhydramnios.
Likely why you're short
of breath and nauseated.
The position of the
head and the heart is...
is a little off.
Because she fell?
No, this is something
that was happening before.
- What was happening before?
- I can't tell yet.
We'll need you to get a formal
ultrasound and a fetal MRI.
Do whatever you
have to, but please,
you've gotta save this baby.
Excuse me.
Okay, so he is either
the greatest actor
since Marlon Brando
or he's, you know,
not only got dementia,
he's pretty deep into it.
If so, why hasn't
he been diagnosed?
Mitch, prison health care?
I mean, not exactly
concierge medicine, right?
So this patient
from corrections,
what's happening?
Waiting to get him up to CT.
Well, I can't have
these officers
impeding flow in the ED.
- Or that.
I'll call radiology and
see if he can cut the line.
You expedite his treatment.
If you can't admit him,
then send him back.
I don't have enough
to worry about.
Hey, get me CT.
Hi, Katherine, Derek.
This is Dr. Marcel.
- Hi.
He's a trauma surgeon.
I'd love for him to
take a look at your leg.
May I?
It looks even worse.
Yeah, compartments are tight.
Pulse is still
palpable, but barely.
Okay.
So, Katherine, the MRI showed
that the fetus has a
diaphragmatic hernia.
That's an abnormal
opening in the muscle
between the chest
and the abdomen.
It's a congenital malformation.
Congenital?
You know, I think my sister's
baby had something like that.
Really? You never told me.
It's not like it would come up.
We never even talked about kids.
Well, we've only known
each other for five months.
It's kind of like we just
met and then this happened.
Well, the good news is,
a surgical procedure
will allow for you to
deliver a healthy baby.
I don't understand.
You mean a surgical procedure
before I give birth?
- Mm-hmm.
- On the baby?
Yes, a fetal surgery.
We have a surgeon who
specializes in this procedure.
He'll make a small puncture
into the abdomen and uterus
and treat the fetus inside.
Oh, God.
I've already spoken with
him, and he suggests
that we proceed with the
procedure immediately,
given the size of the hernia.
Unfortunately, as a
result of the bleeding
to the muscle of
your leg, you have
what's called a
compartment syndrome.
It also needs to be
addressed immediately.
So we have to go in and
open the sides of your calf
to release the pressure,
and we'll do that
while Dr. Asher assists
in fetal surgery.
Two surgeries at the same time?
Is that absolutely necessary?
Obviously it is.
I have a bit of a problem with
hospitals and stuff, okay?
How did you think we
were gonna have a baby
without going to the hospital?
Yes. I'll do it.
- Great.
- Okay. All right.
All right. We'll
be back shortly.
Sharon.
Hey, Dennis.
How are you doing?
I'm okay.
You know, Bert's been a handful.
I guessed that.
I've been missing you.
Well, that goes both ways.
Look, I...
I'm sorry.
I realize having my
ex living with me
is not exactly what
you signed up for.
That's not what's bothering me.
It's you not letting me
into this to help you,
you wanting to do
it all by yourself.
But it's... it's not like
I wanna do it by myself, Dennis.
I just feel like it's not
fair to burden you with it.
Burden me?
You must not think much of me
to think that I'd be
burdened by your problems.
You know I think
the world of you.
Sharon, our relationship is
not just about the good times.
It's a partnership.
I know that.
Then invite me into your life.
Dr. Archer, got one
for you. Baghdad.
Howard, with me.
Dustin Norris, 20s,
fell off his scooter.
Possible fractured wrist.
Arousable but sedate.
The paramedic thought
he was on something.
- Dude!
- Vitals?
BP is a little low. 104/80.
Heart rate's high. 114.
Dustin, I'm Dr. Archer.
Oh, the man!
And I'm third-year medical
student Naomi Howard.
Oh, cute.
All right, can you turn
your head from side to side?
Uh, no problemo.
- Up and down.
- Yeah. Yeah.
C-spine's clear.
Collar can stay off.
Breath sounds bilaterally.
Did you hurt your wrist?
I guess.
Ow! What'd you do that for?
Dr. Archer needed to see if
you can discriminate pain.
Well, duh.
Dustin, you on any drugs?
You're not allowed
to ask me that.
Well, actually, I am.
So are you?
You tell me.
- Give us a urine sample?
- Mm-mm.
And I don't gotta pee either.
- Howard.
Just give him a liter of
some fluids and he'll...
he'll pee soon enough.
Yeah.
Ugh. Got all the
winners today.
Got a contact for this clown?
- Yeah.
It's your friend
Dr. Collins, Sean's boss.
The guy's a resident
in her facility.
Let's give Margo a call.
This isn't one of
her success stories.
Yeah.
Whatever you gave me for
throwing up last time,
how about making it a double?
I'll check with
Dr. Washington.
I'm gonna beat this.
Yeah. I know you are.
All I can think
about is that kid.
Funny.
I never thought I had
it in me to be a dad.
Yeah, me neither.
That's fair enough.
Hey.
How's that prick who sued you?
Pawel?
I don't know.
Why do you care?
He went after you.
That's why.
Sully, just let it go.
You're letting him
get away with it?
What happened to you, man?
You used to be the
king of payback.
Mr. Sullivan.
Hey, Doc.
I understand you had
some side effects
after your first infusion.
Yeah. Out of both ends.
I'm sorry.
But I can help with that.
Well, I better, or
your friend here
is gonna give me a hard time.
Nah.
My boy's gone soft.
Mike, getting a picture
of that wrist for me?
Yep.
Well, Dustin, I guess you
did have to pee after all,
and lo and behold,
your urine tested
positive for heroin.
No, you must have mixed
it up with somebody else.
Yeah, I've heard
that one before.
X-ray.
Yeah, you got a broken
wrist. Colles fracture.
We'll get ortho down
here to check up on you,
and they'll probably
wanna put a cast on you.
Dean. Dr. Collins
and Sean are here.
Don't go anywhere.
- Hi.
- Hey.
So is he badly hurt?
He took a spill off an
e-scooter, broke his wrist.
Gonna give him a CT,
head and abdomen,
just to check all the boxes.
Was he high?
Sean, I cannot...
- He was.
- Hey, Sean. Sean.
Dustin. You swore to me.
Oh, Sean. Sean.
This is the third time.
Hey, hey, hey.
It's not the time.
You don't get it, Dad.
I believed you. I believed you.
All right, let's go. Let's go.
Come on. I need you
to leave right now.
He's using again.
I mean, it's part
of the process.
It was with you, Sean.
- Hey, Sean.
- Sean, hey.
What's going on?
- Ugh.
Sean felt he had a bond with
this guy he's been sponsoring,
and he fell off the wagon.
Again.
Look, I need to
get into surgery,
but let me know if I
can help with anything.
- Thank you.
- Mm-hmm.
Margo.
Dustin's X-ray.
There's something
in his stomach?
Yeah, looks that way.
Wanna tell us what it is?
Um, breakfast.
Okay, tell us what
it is, Dustin.
Let me guess. Bag of smack?
Didn't wanna get caught with it?
- Do we need to scope him?
I hate to do it
unless we have to.
Let's see if he
passes it on his own.
Keep him on the monitors
and track it with
the serial X-ray.
Little future advice... only
food belongs in your stomach.
Crockett?
- Yeah.
Yeah.
- You said you wanted to know.
Oh, no.
Oh, dear God.
- Kai?
- Hey.
Where's Crockett?
He asked me to cover for him.
Why?
He just said he didn't
think he'd be at his best.
What?
I don't know.
Man of mystery.
Don't worry. He
thoroughly briefed me.
Much more than I
needed. Way more.
Position of the fetus is good.
Injecting roc.
Dr. Cho and I can't
proceed until the fetus is
thoroughly sedated
and not moving,
so you can start.
All right.
Making the medial incision.
Going to release the superficial
and deep compartments.
Then I can get
some hematoma out.
Fetus is fully anesthetized.
Continuing hernia repair.
Evacuating the hematoma.
Ah, I love this part.
Good position beneath
the vocal cords.
And deploying.
The deployment looks good.
And I've got hemostasis.
Ready to close.
Mr. Green's head CT.
- Global atrophy.
- Yeah.
He's not faking his dementia.
No, sir.
With this degree of dementia,
Mr. Green doesn't
belong in prison.
Well, he doesn't belong
in my ED, either.
Where he belongs, and
many others like him,
is in a memory care unit.
I mean, I'm telling you,
aging prisoners with dementia,
it's really becoming a crisis.
Daniel, you know
that's not up to us.
You've treated his injuries.
Now he's the responsibility of
the Department of Corrections.
What will late-stage
dementia look like
for Mr. Green in prison?
As his illness progresses...
Dr. Charles, maybe you
wanna take it from here.
As he becomes more
and more disoriented,
he might forget
where his cell is
and the bathroom.
You know, he'll likely
become incontinent.
I mean, I've literally
seen patients
in Mr. Green's predicament
urinating on prison walls.
He won't be able to
feed himself anymore.
He will forget to wash.
And all in an environment
that punishes for noncompliance,
an environment
that will hurt him.
Can't we recommend he
be kept out of gen pop
and put in the infirmary?
But all they'd
really do is just,
you know, strap him to a bed.
At least he won't get beat up.
Yeah, my point is, it's just not
a long-term solution, Mitch.
It sucks, right?
But the system
simply is not set up
to deal with prisoners
like Mr. Green.
Okay, so what would
you like me to do?
I suppose I could petition
for compassionate release.
Actually, that would be great.
Unfortunately, as a prisoner
who is not terminally ill,
he simply won't get it.
Okay.
I do know the attorney general.
It's a long shot, but
I could give her a call
and see if she can
get him remanded
to a state mental institution.
Wow.
That absolutely is worth a shot.
Thank you, Ms. Goodwin.
- Yes. Thank you, Ms. Goodwin,
I really appreciate
you making the effort.
I'm sorry.
I know you didn't
need this today.
Dr. Archer?
Please.
- All right.
Margo?
When did this start?
- A couple minutes ago.
What's happening?
I'm sorry, man. I'm sorry.
I swallowed the dope.
What were you thinking?
Sean, give us some air, okay?
- Is that the pylorus?
- Yeah.
It's obstructing the
stomach from emptying.
Bag won't make it out.
All right, we'll
have to go get it.
Can you order up an
endoscopy, please?
How could you, man?
All those nights we
stayed up talking.
I know. I know.
All right, Sean. Let's go.
Let's go.
What if I don't
want it pulled out?
Well, you don't have a choice.
I don't wanna get in trouble.
Dustin, you can't
leave it there.
Could burst in your
stomach and kill you.
Oh. Daniel.
The AG was apologetic but
said this isn't something
she could deal with quickly.
Frankly, I think she's just
afraid of looking soft on crime
in an election year.
Discharge him.
Sorry, pal.
That's it?
We're just...
we're just gonna throw
this guy to the wolves?
Unfortunately, there
are no good moves.
- That sounds like a cop-out.
- Really?
I guess I'm just confused
why Ms. Goodwin
seemed more willing
to try to help this
guy than you were.
I think it's probably because
she was indulging you a bit,
because she saw
how much you cared.
Mitch, I've been advocating for
prisoners with mental health...
Like you advocated for me?
Seriously?
We're going back there again?
I did the best I could. I
don't know what else to say,
except for maybe I'm
tired of apologizing.
And frankly, I've been
advocating for you
ever since you got here...
protecting you too.
And you know what?
I'm sick of it.
I'm done.
All right. Swallow.
Swallow. Okay. Come on.
Easy, deep breaths.
You got it.
In through the nose,
out through the mouth.
Good. Breathe.
And we're in the stomach,
and there's the bag.
Okay. Sarah, grab
this, will you?
All right.
Okay, I'm gonna snag
it with the snare.
Good.
All right, got it.
All right. Endoscope's
coming out.
Keep breathing. Sarah,
take that, will you?
There we go.
Yeah.
All right. Breathe. Breathe.
Good work.
All right. Good. Almost.
Okay.
All done.
Should I call security?
No.
Ah.
The bag is removed.
He's gonna be fine, at
least in that regard.
Where is it?
The baggie?
I disposed of it.
Well, you need to get it back.
Get it back?
We need to give it to the cops.
What?
- He needs to be arrested.
- Why?
'Cause that's the only way
he's gonna stop doing this.
Hey, this is not the place.
All right, let me
finish up with Dustin,
and I'll see you guys outside.
Hey, Maggie.
I forgot I have an
appointment at the DMV.
Shouldn't take too long.
Zach's covering for me.
Sure.
- Come in.
Ms. Goodwin?
Oh.
Ah, Dr. Marcel.
I was told you took
yourself out of a surgery?
Now, that's not like you.
I learned that Colin Stewart,
you know, the young boy who
needed that liver transplant,
he died.
And then his...
his father, Bill...
Killed himself.
Oh, no.
Oh, Dr. Marcel,
I am so sorry.
I know this is a terrible blow.
Take all the time
you need. Please.
Thank you.
The procedure went well.
We successfully deployed a
tiny balloon as a temporary fix
until the baby is
delivered and we can do
a permanent hernia repair.
Thank you. Thank you so much.
Mm-hmm.
Guess I'd better get
used to hospitals.
What's with you and hospitals?
I, uh, kind of had
a bad experience
when I was living in India
and my appendix burst.
India?
Her dressings look good.
Only a little strike-through.
Okay.
Katherine, can you
wiggle your toes?
Nice. All right.
Pulse is strong.
Color of the foot looks good.
Any tingling or numbness?
No.
Why were you living in India?
I was working for
a tech startup.
Okay. Everything
here looks good.
Thank you again.
Why didn't you tell
me about any of this?
We're gonna give you
guys some time to rest.
Any other countries?
Those two don't seem to
know much about each other.
Yeah, that's for sure.
Oh, man. What are we doing?
What... where are
we going? What?
Come on, man. What's
happening? What... what...
that's my lawyer!
That's my lawyer!
I have a right to
talk to my lawyer.
Let me talk to my lawyer!
I think it's time, Daniel.
This man can't get the
help that he needs.
But Bert can.
I agree.
I'm gonna go call the kids.
Sean, listen.
Uh, drugs are gone.
I disposed of them properly.
And in any event,
the cops won't bother
with such a small amount.
Well, that's beside the point.
I mean, Dustin doesn't
need incarceration.
That wouldn't help him.
Helped me.
Never would have gotten
straight otherwise, right, Dad?
You? Okay.
But everyone is different.
And for some, it would only
make the problem worse.
Dad, why aren't you
saying anything?
What do you want me to say?
Zero tolerance is what
you always told me.
Well, maybe I look at
things differently now.
Because of her?
So Dustin gets a
pass, and I didn't?
- It's not like that.
- No?
You kicked me out of the
house, told me you never wanted
to see me again
unless I cleaned up.
I told you, I'm
not proud of that.
People can change, Sean.
Junkies cheat.
They lie.
And the only way they'll
change is if you lock them up.
Okay, I understand that you
feel betrayed by Dustin.
Yeah.
And by you.
Sean.
- Hey, Mags?
- Yeah.
Do you know what's
going on with Crockett?
Oh.
Leave it alone. Trust me.
Doris?
- Hmm?
- Cover for me?
- Sure.
- Thank you so much.
- Mm-hmm.
Did you hear how Bill did it?
Paramedics said
it was a handgun.
I know how he felt.
I didn't have a gun.
What?
I, uh...
I lost a child too.
Oh, my. I had no idea.
Yeah.
Harper.
Leukemia.
She died just after
her first birthday.
I'm so sorry.
What saved me was my work.
Work kept me going.
Has all along.
So when I sent Colin home
knowing he was gonna die,
it just put me right
back there again.
I felt that same
sense of helplessness.
Nothing I could do.
Death was coming,
and there was...
nothing I could do.
I guess it made me realize
the way I've been living,
working full-on for years now...
I never really took
the time to grieve.
Grieve for my baby girl.
I don't know what
to say, Crockett.
I appreciate you, Maggie.
And I appreciate you.
See you tomorrow?
Yeah.
Lots of old folks.
Well, we're not so
young ourselves, Bert.
- Yeah.
What are we doing here?
This is gonna be
your new home, Dad.
Home?
I have a home.
No.
There was a fire, remember?
And then you moved in
with me for a while.
Mr. Goodwin, we're
so glad to see you.
Can we show you your room?
I wan... I wanna go home.
They'll take really good
care of you here, Bert,
in ways that we just can't.
They'll cook for you.
They'll clean for
you. Everything.
Ms. Goodwin says
you like to swim.
We have an indoor pool.
You can... you could
use it all year long.
We also hear you love chili.
That's what we're
having for dinner.
Chili...
I think you'll
like it here, Bert.
Give it a try, Dad.
I... I... I don't think so.
Don't worry.
He's gonna be fine.
Uh, let us show you your room.
I'm sure you're
gonna like the view.
Are you coming?
We'll see you soon.
Michael's picking up
David at the airport,
and then they're on their way.
Your sons are coming.
I know.
I'll drop by the house later.
Please.
Love you.
I love you.
Thank you for coming.
Thank you for asking.
- Dr. Ripley, we have incoming.
Naomi, with me.
Juliette, talk to me.
You're going to Baghdad.
55-year-old male,
Pawel Wapniarski,
facial contusion, significant
trauma to the left knee.
Gave him 4 milligrams
of morphine in the ambo.
Emergency contact's on her way.
Said he'd been assaulted
by a masked assailant
with a baseball bat.
- I was attacked.
Dran!
- X-ray.
Mitch, you can't treat
him, not with your history.
- I can do the intake.
- Thank you.
Uh...
yeah, give me an AP on his knee.
Clear.
X-ray.
Yeah, it looks like the
patella is comminuted.
We're gonna take you to CT,
then the orthopedic
surgeons will most likely
take you to surgery.
You'll be okay.
Yeah, I'll never be okay.
Maggie, let CT
know we're coming.
You got it. Let's
go. Let's go.
Boze. What happened?
He did this.
What?
'Cause I win the case.
- Did you?
- No.
You did. Didn't you?
- Lili.
- Look, he's not a good person.
Let's take a beat, okay?
You always take
his side, not mine.
Dr. Ripley.
You got anything to say?
Why didn't he say anything?