I didn't want to give
up fighting for her.
I would've gone on forever.
I mean, little Susie's
almost a year old.
She's been with me forever.
Her birthday's next
week. Did I mention that?
She fell in love
with our neighbor's
little puppy, JoBo,
so I got her this
stuffed little animal...
Black and white, floppy ears.
Did I tell you the
daycare center called?
It seems I still have
an outstanding bill.
Gotta love that whole...
insult to injury thing.
I kind of hate
going up there, but...
it's Susie's birthday next
week. Did I mention that?
I've got to remember
to send her a present.
Anyway, I suppose
things are okay.
I don't have to get
up twice a night,
so at least I'm getting
some more sleep.
Just going to work,
coming home,
sticking to a routine.
I guess life's getting
back to normal...
before the baby, that is.
Ma'am?
Hello. Hi.
I'm Father Ruiz-Anchia.
Can I help you?
Uh, yeah.
That lady who
just sat down there,
She dropped this outside.
Last week, it was her keys.
Once, she even
stepped out of a shoe.
Didn't even realize it.
Thank you.
I'll give it to her. Okay.
It's beautiful, isn't it?
They're rehearsing for
a christening tomorrow.
"Salve Mater Misericordia."
based on the sequence
"Salve Mater Salvatoris"
by Adam of Saint Victor.
No one knows who
did the translation.
Is there anything
else I can do for you?
Hello?
Can I help you?
I don't know.
Turfed the chest
pain to Cardiology,
the chronic puker to Medicine.
I love these things.
My daughter, she left
them after her last visit.
Bipolar to Psych, and
say goodbye to Mr. Barry.
The one who called you
an incompetent poser?
That was only before
his horrifying rectal
revealed an even more horrifying
case of hemorrhoids.
Sent him to the Surgery clinic.
Carter's with that otitis media,
Ross isn't on yet,
and Lewis is late.
No. She worked an
extra four hours last night.
She's not due for another hour.
You just want her to be late.
Don't be ridiculous.
"A propensity for tardiness
"makes her a
problematic candidate
for Chief Resident"?
Mark, I can't
believe that you think
I'd keep tabs on anyone.
You're late, Jerry.
Time out. What do you see?
Well, come on. Al
and I are engaged.
Oh, yeah. It's gorgeous.
Congratulations.
And the rest of the good news
is paramedics are on their way in.
Some failure-to-fly
suicide attempt. GCS-3.
If he's gorked, why are
they bringing him here?
Landed in the lake,
which is still a little chilly.
Got to warm him up before
they can pronounce him.
Can't be cold and dead.
I thought we were going
to do something fun today.
I'm having fun.
Yeah. Is this what you and
Dad used to do every morning?
If it makes you feel any better,
Dad couldn't keep
up if he were driving.
You know that you're the first
woman I've ever jogged for?
Doug, I'm so flattered.
Yeah, it's a fact.
Remind me to reward
you when we go back.
Let's go back.
Ow!
Wait, wait, wait.
Hang on. I got you.
My knee, my knee.
Hang on. Let me see this.
Damn. It goes out
on me all the time.
I'm a doctor, you know.
Yeah, a pediatrician.
Are you complaining?
Uh... not necessarily.
Here you go. Like this.
Is this helping at all?
Uh... uh-huh.
Yeah?
I really am sorry.
I'm not saying that she,
the individual in question,
isn't a possible candidate
for Chief Resident.
Just not a probable candidate.
I'm not saying that either.
30 years old,
traumatic full arrest,
been down 45 minutes.
Did a half-gainer
off of a 75-foot crane
right into the lake.
On my count. One, two, three.
Last epi? Four minutes.
I'm only saying that this
candidate for Chief Resident
has had some serious
personal difficulties of late.
Which have been
handled quite well,
considering all things.
Gave two of
atropine in the field.
Pupils fixed and dilated.
I could consider
supporting this individual
if there were more
supervision involved.
No BP, no pulse.
By the new ER Attending
Morgenstern wants to bring in?
It's a possibility.
Flatline.
And the candidates
for that job are..?
Gosh, I think it's
still pretty wide open.
Temp's normal.
He's warmed up. He's dead.
So whoever I support
for that position
will support my choice
for Chief Resident.
It's a possibility.
Mark, excuse me,
but whenever you two
are done talking in code
about Dr. Lewis
being Chief Resident
and Dr. Weaver
becoming an Attending,
can we call the time of
death? This guy is toast.
Yeah, yeah. Sure.
Uh, time of death, 8:53.
Let me know when
the family get here.
And call the eye bank.
Ooh-eee, girl, that's pretty!
Finally popped
the question, huh?
Yep. He really wanted me
to have his mother's ring,
but she's still alive.
Oh, Susan. Hi.
Hi. Where is everyone?
Field trip to the park.
Spring at last, thank God.
Oh. Well, I have a bill to pay.
Well, listen, would you
mind stopping back?
They're holding the bus for me.
And of course, we get up there,
and no one's there
but an OB nurse,
and Chloe is screaming
for the Beatles.
"The White Album"!
Carter's fumbling,
can't find it anywhere.
Chloe doesn't want
to breathe, right,
but she thinks this
singing will help.
So there we are, like
a bunch of crazies...
♪ Blackbird singing
In the dead of night ♪
♪ Take these broken
wings And learn to fly ♪
♪ All your life... ♪
And there I am,
in between verses,
telling her, "Push,
Chloe. Push. Come on.
You can do it,
girl. You can do it."
And I cut the cord
and wrapped the little
warm baby all up and...
put it on her chest.
Oh, this brand-new life.
Chloe was crying.
I was crying.
She was so beautiful...
our baby girl.
I told her,
"You did it, Chloe.
You really did it."
You know what she said?
She said, "No, we did it.
We did it."
Our baby girl.
I did send the check in.
I wouldn't say it were
in the mail if it weren't.
Jerry, get off the phone
and clear Curtain Area 3.
Clear Curtain Area 3.
You got it.
Okay, come on.
Don't play with that.
That's really
expensive, okay, Jimmy?
Here, give me back your
gun. Give me back this.
Come on. Annie, Jimmy, come on.
I'll take you inside.
You have to give that back.
No, I want to stay with my mom.
Annie, take your
brother and go with Lydia.
Gently. Here we go.
Dr. Greene, I don't feel
good. I just don't feel good.
We've got you,
Loretta. We've got you.
Gently, gently, gently.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to scare you.
No, no, you didn't, not really.
We couldn't be out
of penicillin, could we?
Oh, they moved the
antibiotics down there.
Oh, this is adorable.
Yeah, I had to clear
out some of Susie's stuff
from upstairs at Daycare.
Susan, if there's
anything I can do
I mean, if you want
to talk about anything...
You were right.
Here it is. Thanks.
I'm with Pickman.
I know. Shep's off today.
Yeah, well, I'd be with
Pickman even if he wasn't.
You shouldn't have filed
that complaint with the IAD.
Hey, he shouldn't
have slammed that kid.
That's not what happened.
Yeah, sure, whatever.
You were there, right?
You think he was
just doing his job?
Yes, I do.
Well, I'll tell you
what I believe.
I believe the job doesn't
have to be done that way.
And who died and made
you the voice of experience?
Raul, that's who.
Look, I'm sorry. I
didn't mean that.
You know, Shep's
been working at this job
for almost eight years,
so if you ever want to step off
that high moral
ground you're sitting on,
you just might learn something.
Yeah, I already have.
Then that's what you should
be telling the IAD investigator.
I already have.
Abdominal pain for how long?
Couple of days.
I feel so bloated.
It doesn't go away.
Any vomiting?
Yeah.
Could I be dehydrated again?
We'll get some fluids
in you, just in case.
D-5. Half at 150 an hour.
CBC, lytes, chest
and abdominal series.
Coming up.
I couldn't even get
the kids to school.
They shouldn't be in here.
Don't worry. Jerry's
probably showing them
some horribly
educational pictures
of open heart surgery
or something worse.
I'll check back when
the tests are back.
Okay.
Hey, there you are.
Oh, hi. How'd it go?
Oh, man, that guy was
a real son of a bitch.
Shep, it's just an interview.
It's not a military inquest.
Yeah, but he asked
a thousand questions.
You know, he
already talked to Reilly.
I know. Little peckerhead.
Guy hasn't seen half
the stuff I've seen.
Calm down. It's
going to be fine.
So you're going to tell him
that you were there
the whole time, right?
I mean, that you saw everything.
Yes. I was there. The
guy stumbled into the table.
That simple.
Anyone could see it was
kind of a tough situation.
Shep, you're driving me crazy.
I'm going to speak to
this investigator guy,
then this whole thing's
going to go away.
Will you please go away?
It's my day off.
I don't really have
anything else to do.
Well, it's spring, you know?
Plant some flowers,
drive some golf balls.
I don't play golf.
Start.
Annie, will you stop...
Just...
Want me to call the cops?
Don't laugh. Al's on the way.
By the way, congratulations.
We just got into town
practicing for a basketball
tournament on Saturday.
I talked to her mom.
She said she was operated on
when she was eight weeks old.
It was something
called a Kasai procedure.
Carter? Hepatoportoenterostomy.
Done for liver failure
from bile duct obstruction.
Okay, up and in.
I can do it myself, thank you.
T.C.'s what you'd
call dedicated.
I finally knew
something was wrong
when she didn't want to play.
I need to be fixed now, okay?
Because I have a
tournament on Saturday,
and it's very important.
My son's in a peewee
tournament next week.
Peewee stops at eight. I'm ten.
Sit up.
Fever's 101.
Mm-hm. Uh, how long
has she been jaundiced?
We've got a lot of kids.
I didn't really notice.
Dr. Ross, can I speak
to you for a minute?
Yeah.
Her folks live in Penrose.
Penrose? That's, like,
150 miles from here.
Yeah. Soybean country.
They're on their way,
but I got all these
other kids at the motel,
and God knows what
damage they're doing.
Okay. Well, I
would imagine T.C.'s
going to have to be admitted.
In the meantime, we'll
keep a good eye on her here.
All right, thanks.
Come with me. You're
going to be okay.
Cats!
Burmese, Cornish
Rex, Japanese Bobtail...
My hatred for them
knows no bounds.
Short hair, long hair.
I hate them. I just...
I think you're
allergic to them, Iris.
I never used to be.
My brother had a cat growing up,
and I hated that thing.
Sometimes your allergies
get worse when you get older.
Or maybe that's
completely false.
I'm shooting the
Chicago cat show,
and suddenly,
I'm Tippi Hedren in The Birds.
They're everywhere!
Iris, Iris, Iris, stop.
Okay. We're just
going to get you
your own room here, okay?
Russian blue, Himalayan,
Egyptian Mau, Bengal, Balinese,
Burmese, Cornish
Rex, Japanese Bobtail...
Please, somebody help me.
It's my baby.
Clear Trauma 1.
What happened?
She was in her
crib. She doesn't cry.
I can't wake her up.
How old is she?
Just turned six months.
Her name's Grace.
She's not breathing,
and she's cyanotic.
What is wrong with her?
What is it?
Pediatric intubation tray.
4.0 ET tube.
Heart rate's only 40.
O.14 of atropine. Has
she been sick, Mrs..?
Ramsey. Judith Ramsey.
Um, a little. She was vomiting,
just getting over the flu.
Fever or seizures?
Damn it. Temp's normal.
She was jerking.
I couldn't get her to stop.
I need a 3.5, not a four.
Use a four.
Susan? I'll do it.
Please, just tell me
what is wrong with her.
Mrs. Ramsey, you're
gonna have to wait outside
so that we can
take care of Grace.
I don't want to leave her.
Susan, take Mrs. Ramsey
to the Waiting Room.
Kerry... No, please.
Susan, now.
20 cc's per kilogram
bolus normal saline.
CBC, Chem-7,
heel stick glucose,
get a head CT,
and we may need an LP.
Come on.
Oh, God.
Oh. Oh.
Let me see, let me see.
Think she'll be able to
play in that tournament?
I doubt it.
Let me know when the LFT's, BUN,
and creatinine are back.
Okay.
And Carter? She's in here alone,
so stay close.
Okay.
Eww.
What are you kids
doing in the hall?
Why is it that Chloe
always called Mom "Cookie"
and I always called Mom "Mom"?
She was such a
great kid that way...
Funny and fearless.
Just one big party
all wrapped up in...
We'd dress up and
put on these plays
at the top of the stairs.
Chloe, of course, went
straight for mom's best dresses,
best jewelry, best shoes,
I was always afraid
they'd get mad,
so I was the one in the
bathrobe and the sneakers...
but they never did.
Never. Not once.
Chloe went for the good stuff,
and I went for
being the good girl.
She was such an
accomplished adult
by the time she was nine,
and so lousy at it by
the time she was 19.
I mean, if she could just
go back to some of that...
then if she wanted
to be a mother...
What am I saying?
She is a mother.
Boy, when you buy
somebody lunch,
you go all out.
How's your knee?
You know, if it's
still bothering you,
I can get you
something for that.
I heard from Ray.
Oh yeah?
Well, not from him,
actually. About him.
How's the good
life in the Caymans?
Never went there.
He's in Mexico.
Kind of sends a
message, doesn't it?
Like what? Like he's
not coming back?
Well, what's it
look like to you?
Well, I'm used to
him disappearing.
He doesn't tend to
mention it in advance.
Yeah. I guess not, considering
he took my money with him.
Well...
thanks for all the sympathy.
No, uh, no.
I'm sorry. I'm just,
I'm disappointed.
Well, don't be. It
wasn't your money.
Well, he bolted on
me year after year,
but I just would think
with you in the picture...
With me in the picture.
What's that got to do with it?
I would think that he
would want to see you.
Come back and see me?
Come back and see us?
Is that what you mean?
He doesn't even
know about us, Karen.
Maybe it's your idea of
fun to watch him find out.
Is that what this is about,
Doug? What we're about?
You finally getting back at
Daddy, stealing his girlfriend?
You know what?
That's ridiculous.
Is it? For three weeks,
you've been telling me
how you can't stand the guy
could care less if you
ever see him again,
and now you're disappointed
he's not coming back?
That is ridiculous.
My motto is: "Think Jordan."
Okay, I'm just saying
that you can't rule out Orlando.
What do they know
about basketball in Florida?
Does this hurt?
Yeah. A little.
All right.
T.C.'s right. Orlando's
got a good record,
but when push comes
to shove, they'll choke.
Only one NBA leader in scoring,
and zip in rebounds.
Okay. I give up.
Carter.
Liver is enlarged and
firm upon examination.
Lab tests show elevated
LFT's, leukocytosis,
and a prolonged PT,
consistent with
ascending cholangitis.
Start her on one gram
cefotaxime IV Q-6.
Is she on a list for
a liver transplant?
Yeah. Status 3.
All right. Move
her up to Status 2.
She's going to have
to stay hospitalized
until we find her a liver.
Guess I better brush up
on my basketball trivia.
Well, you should do that anyway.
Hey, Dr. Benton. Al Boulet.
Hey. How you doing?
I got some kind
of flu or something.
Yeah, um... well, take care.
Right.
I'm sorry about those
kids and the camera.
Oh, I'm just glad I got it back.
I'm sorry about snorting
all over your hand.
It's just another adventure.
Uh, speaking of
which, I was thinking...
Bless you.
Thank you.
Who are you?
Lily.
Where'd you come from?
The bus stop.
What's wrong?
I can't get him off.
Is that a hermit crab?
Herman. My dad named him.
I'm afraid we're gonna
have to cut him off, Lily.
But he'd die, right?
I can't kill Herman.
No. Of course you can't.
Cats you can kill,
but not Herman.
It's just water, honey.
There you go.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
I produced this cheesy
Jacques Cousteau rip-off thing
a couple of months ago.
Anything on that little
baby, Grace Ramsey?
She's breathing spontaneously.
We're waiting on the CT.
Okay. Let me know.
They're seriously
backed up up there.
Just let me know.
Hi. I'm Dr. Weaver.
Hi.
Your name's Al Boulet?
Yeah.
We got a Jeanie Boulet
here. Any relation?
She's my wife.
Actually, we're separated.
You've been losing weight,
having fevers, sweating?
Yeah. I think I've
got the 24-day flu
instead of the 24-hour.
A lot of stuff's been
going around at work.
Deep breath.
The shortness of breath,
how long's that been going on?
Uh, a month or so.
Mr. Boulet, I'm going
to get a chest x-ray,
and I'll talk to you
about some blood
tests I'd like to order.
Okay.
Seen Dr. Greene?
Yeah. He snuck
out for some lunch.
Radiology screwed up
the films on Loretta Sweet.
We have to redo them.
What happened? Are you okay?
I'm fine, I'm fine.
Teach this SOB to grapple
with a soon-to-be-married man.
Come on. Let's go
pour a little cold peroxide
on those cuts.
You don't look so good.
Well, don't you worry.
Nothing's going to ruin
our celebration night
at the Ritz Carlton.
Okay, let's get you cleaned up.
Hey, Jeanie.
I didn't know you were here.
Yeah. I'm just getting
a little checkup.
What's wrong?
Nothing, really.
Just, uh...
a little tired lately.
Breath feels kind of
short or something.
Working too much, that's all.
Did they say anything?
No. They just took
a bunch of blood.
Did some x-rays.
Look, I've got
some other patients.
Hey, don't worry about it.
Go do your thing. They
got me in good hands.
I'll try and stop by later.
Hi. This is Jeanie
down in the ER.
We've been waiting on
some lab tests forever.
Boulet. Al Boulet.
Yeah.
If you could put a rush
on them, I'd appreciate it.
Thanks.
Carol Hathaway?
Yes.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
I'm David Haskell from IAD.
That's Investigations and...
Audit Division. Yes, I know.
Sorry to have kept you waiting.
You said that.
Must've really meant it then.
So, you saw Anh stumble.
Who?
Anh Nguyen. Vietnamese
boy. You saw him stumble
and hit his head
on a coffee table?
That's right.
Just lost his balance?
Must have.
Which would make sense
after Mr. Shepherd gave
him a... What did he call it?
"a light shove."
Is that how you'd
describe it? A light shove?
Well, the kid wasn't
falling very fast,
so, yeah, it was
probably pretty light.
Now, Mr. Brown says you
helped him unstrap a board.
Yes. He was nervous
and frustrated,
so I helped him do it.
Then you both took the
board back into the kitchen.
No. Reilly took it.
That's right.
He says he was headed to
the kitchen with the board,
and that's when he
saw Mr. Shepherd...
"slam" is the word he used...
Slam Anh Nguyen across the room.
So you must've gone
back into the kitchen
at pretty much the same time.
No. Reilly moved in first.
He carried the
board ahead of me.
Yeah, but if you
both saw the incident,
which obviously you did,
since you think it
was a light shove
and Mr. Brown
thinks it was a slam...
Then both of you had to
be there the whole time.
Yes. That's right.
I was there the whole time.
No, we had a fight
and I feel like a jerk.
My dad did take her money,
and I wasn't all that
sympathetic, but...
she was accusing me of
wanting him to come back.
Doug, what is this all about?
I don't know. What kind
of a question is that?
Your dad stealing her
money is not your fault.
Except that he gave
the money to me.
So give it back.
I can't. I only have $10,000.
I gave $15,000 for
that kid's chemotherapy.
This is way too
complicated for me.
Kerry, the CT's are back.
Subdural hematoma,
loud and clear.
There are retinal
hemorrhages in each eye.
You found this upon examination
and didn't even
bother to tell me.
You were already upset
about the intubation.
This mother's abusing
her child, and you know it.
Where is she? I
want to talk to her.
Not yet. Not yet?
A subdural hematoma
and retinal hemorrhages
are the hallmarks of
Shaken Baby Syndrome.
I know that, Susan. But...
This child could
have brain damage.
I've ordered a
Neurosurgical consult.
Yeah. Great. I want
to talk to the mother.
She is the problem.
I've called Children
and Family Services.
They have a thousand cases.
Who's going to keep
tabs on this one?
I've also notified the police.
You think they have
time to deal with this?
It's the best we can do.
You know that if this
mother doesn't get it,
and that baby starts crying,
and she picks her up,
and the baby doesn't stop,
she's just going
to start shaking her
and shaking her.
We can't solve this, Susan.
I wish we could, but
we both know we can't,
so we're going to take
care of the child, okay?
We're going to do
everything we can
for the child.
They took the baby
up to Pediatrics ICU.
Children and Family Services
came down to talk to the mother.
The police are looking into
it, and that's the last I know.
It's the last I'm gonna know.
Sometimes that's the good
thing about being an ER doc.
Treat 'em and street
'em. Turf 'em upstairs.
Got to hand it to that
Kerry Weaver, though.
She surprises you.
Just when you think
she's completely clueless,
she hangs in there,
stalling, arguing with me,
agreeing with me.
"We can't solve the problem.
We can take care of the child."
Until I finally let go.
Getting bored
sitting in your room?
Hey, your fever's down.
Come on. Bounce me one.
The good news is that
once you get a new liver,
the disease won't come back.
And you're official now.
You're all signed up
on the transplant list.
It's not like we need this
thing to happen right away.
If it takes a few months,
you're still gonna be fine.
Unfortunately, you're
going to have to stay here.
Well, not here. You're
going to be upstairs,
but I'll come visit
you whenever I can,
and you can educate me
on the finer points
of the point guard.
Maybe we can watch
the playoffs together.
That sounds pretty
cool, doesn't it?
But I can't play in
my tournament, can I?
No. No, I'm sorry, T.C.
You can't play in
your tournament.
Thought I'd never
get out of there.
I'm glad you didn't wait.
Tuna on whole wheat
with lettuce and tomato.
You want it? I'm
not really hungry.
Right after I finish
my cheese steak.
I know I've said
this before, but...
you have to get Kerry
Weaver off my back.
What now?
Six-month-old baby
girl came in cyanotic.
Kerry thinks I can't
handle the intubation.
But you did, right?
No! She took over.
Yes, it was a baby,
yes, it was hard,
but I've done this
a hundred times.
How's everything else?
You mean therapy?
That is what you mean, right?
Well, do I feel
terrific? Not really.
Um, am I marginally
better? Not really.
Am I happy I'm spending
my money on therapy
and not, say,
Gymboree or a stroller?
Not really.
So everything's going okay?
You want to walk back?
They didn't page me.
I wish there was
something I could do,
something I could say.
So do I.
It would be so much easier
if this bad news were
happening to some patient.
Mm, I shouldn't
be drinking this.
I'll never get to sleep.
I never sleep anyway.
Yeah, you know, we actually
had a class in medical school,
uh, sort of how to
deliver the bad news.
We even had to make
videotapes and perform it.
"I'm very sorry, sir, but your
wife was hit by a Mack truck,
and we did everything
possible, but she died."
Then some actor
playing the husband
would go into
convulsions on the floor
and start crying out in agony.
That's not usually
how they react.
They shake, then
they start to cry.
Yeah, I remember the
first time I had to do it.
It was this elderly man,
and his wife had just died.
No big accident, just old age.
And he looked at me for about...
a minute,
and then walked away.
Yeah, I was the
one left shaking.
Practice makes perfect, though.
Now I can deliver that
speech in a heartbeat,
and it's not that
I don't feel badly,
because I do,
but I get the words
out, and I move on.
The healers are always
taught to move on...
and for the life of me, I
can't seem to do that now.
This hurt is so
strong and so present,
it makes me feel her...
and to still be
able to feel her...
I don't want to
move on from that.
You need something?
Your interview
must have gone well.
I got a lot of work, Reilly.
Haskell just called. They
dropped the investigation.
Seems your answers confirmed
Shep's side of the story.
Well, now we can
all get back to work.
Look, I like you, Hathaway,
but whatever you said in there,
I don't think you're
doing Shep any favors.
Look, maybe it's the Raul thing,
and maybe he's going
to come through this,
but right now, he
doesn't belong out there.
He's dangerous.
I can't keep doing this.
Yes, you can.
You made it through
the last surgery.
You can make it
through this one.
It's the kids.
They never know what's going on
from one day to the next...
Where I'm gonna be,
where they're gonna be.
They're going to be at
my house tonight, okay?
My parental skills can
use a little brushing up.
I don't know what to tell them.
I don't know what to say.
I've hardly even
seen them all day.
Well, I can tell you one thing.
They've been pretty
busy. Take a look.
Look, Mom.
They turned us into doctors.
Officer, I'm so sorry.
Are you kidding?
He was the center of attention.
He loved it.
Are you sure you
can't stay for dinner?
Mom, look, thank you,
but I can't eat dinner
at 5:30 in the afternoon.
Oh. Pathetic, isn't it?
Howard comes
back from the office,
grabs dinner, rushes
back to the office.
I thought tax season was over.
What happened to April 15?
Does the word "extension"
mean anything to you?
As a matter of fact,
I think I have one of those.
All right. Listen, Mom...
So, how much do you need?
No. You can't
possibly know that.
I haven't said
anything about money.
Well, you're not here
for dinner, are you?
No.
And you don't drop
by a lot to play Bridge.
I don't play Bridge.
My point exactly.
Doug, there are three reasons
kids come back home.
One, to announce
they're getting married...
Two, they're depressed
and they need a place
to sleep for three years,
and three, they need money.
My money's on the money.
So, were you always so smart?
Right up until the day
I married your father.
Doug...
all those years you
were growing up
not knowing about your dad...
I couldn't help you then.
Nothing would make me happier
than to help you now.
Don't you even want to know
what I'm gonna
use the money for?
You really want to tell me?
Bring the carrots over here.
Okay.
Broken tib-fib.
Jeanie, do you have a minute?
If I call Ortho now,
they ought to make
it down by summer.
Jeanie...
It's about Al, isn't it?
Yeah.
And is it AIDS?
Yeah. Pneumocystis pneumonia.
I saw his chart, and when
he told me how he was feeling,
his symptoms...
I need to give him the news,
but I thought it might
be easier for him if...
No, I'll do it. I'll do it.
I know you're separated...
but he may have
been HIV-positive
for a few years.
Have you ever been tested?
How many married
people get tested?
I checked for you
at the hotel suite.
Doesn't seem to be mine anymore.
Something about when
you lose company money.
You're going to have to let me
write you something for that.
Whatever.
I got to say, I much
prefer your place.
Whatever.
Some of what you said,
I don't know if
it's true or not,
but you made me think about it,
and I...
I realized that...
I want to be with you, Karen.
You don't see me
kicking you out the door.
You're going to
have to let me do this,
because I have a very
low threshold for your pain.
Up and there you go.
Karen?
Doug?
I have a confession to make.
You're not married, are you?
No. It's worse than that.
Okay.
You know the money that
my father took from you?
He, uh... he gave it to me.
What?
Yeah. I... I mean, he
never gave me a dime
when I was in medical school.
I mean, he just...
he just handed
me a bunch of cash
before he took off.
$25,000.
Yeah. I want you to have it.
$25,000?
Ray stole over 250 grand.
250 grand?
You got it.
This is nothing.
This is, uh...
this is a drop in the bucket.
No, it's everything.
That's the sweetest thing
anybody's ever done for me.
I mean, I could
get fired tomorrow,
but I got to love
you for this one.
Mmm...
Great news, huh, baby?
They dropped the whole thing!
Whatever you said in
there, it made the difference.
We are home free.
Let's celebrate.
Let's go do something.
Shep, I got a lot of paperwork.
Ah, you can do this
later. This can wait.
No! I really need
to do this now.
Okay, we go to dinner, then.
Dinner, maybe a club.
You know, um...
they're playing
basketball outside.
Um, I'll join you
when I'm finished.
Okay.
Don't be too long.
Al, I need to talk to you.
It's cold in here tonight.
Maybe Chloe is
getting it together,
or maybe Joe can
keep it together.
Sometimes I dream
that they call and say
"Hey, Suz, why don't you
take her again for a while?"
and in my dream, I say,
"Yes, Chloe, I will
take her forever."
Then I wake up, and
I know it's not true,
because my arms hurt
from feeling so empty.
I always knew you
loved your children.
I just never realized how
much you fell in love with them.
Little Susie was
like a storybook...
One that you never
wanted to put down.
Every smile was some new page
to be pored over,
studied, touched...
remembered.
I loved my storybook.
For the first time
in a long time...
I didn't feel alone.