Susie...
Susie!
Mmm...
Chloe, I worked till
1:00 in the morning.
I-I think it's time
for, you know, the baby.
Are you sure?
Uh-huh.
Are you having contractions?
Every couple of minutes.
Why did you wait so long?!
I had some stuff to do.
I had to take a shower,
pack the baby clothes.
Chloe, your contractions
are two minutes apart.
We should be at the hospital.
I thought you needed the sleep.
Oh, you picked a hell of a
time to start being considerate.
Ow!!
Chloe, Chloe...
Chloe, breathe. Breathe, Chloe.
Hee, hee, hee. Hee, hee...
Oh, my Go... I need my music.
Get me my tape player, please.
Lug that thing?
Susie-cake, please.
Okay, okay, okay.
Uh, wh-wh-which tapes?
The White Album.
Okay.
Ow!
Oh, damn it! My keys!
Chloe, stop it.
I got to clap for my keys.
Got it.
Okay, Chloe.
Wow, this is scary.
Hee, hee, hee...
Carter, get over here.
I need your help.
Hee, hee, hee.
Keep panting.
We're almost there, Chloe.
Hee, hee, hee... Is
that coffee? Thanks.
Get me drugs!
Contractions are 90 seconds
apart. Why'd you wait so long?
Get her up to OB now.
Breathe, Chloe, hee, hee, hee.
Hee, hee, hee,
hee... What is "hee"?
What is with you people
and this "hee, hee" thing?
Have you ever had a baby?
Do you think that really helps?
Just give me some drugs!
Janet, Susan Lewis.
It's... oh, ah...
it's 4:30.
My sister's here,
membrane's ruptured,
contractions are
90 seconds apart.
Right, get her up to OB.
Okay, I have.
Okay, okay, I'll see you in 20.
Coburn's on her way.
Susan Lewis. I'm her sister.
Marquez.
Shoot me, just please shoot me.
Chloe, hang in there just
a little bit longer, okay?
No kidding. This
baby's crowning.
Oh, my God. Coburn's
never going to make it.
Who else is on?
O'Melveny, but she's doing
a crash C-section in four.
Okay, let's shift her up.
All right, you've got to remember
your breathing. Come on.
Susie, Susie, Susie.
I-I can't do this.
Yes, you can. Yes,
you can, Chloe.
Breathe through the pain.
No, no, no, it's a bad idea.
I can't do this, really.
Chloe, on the next one, you're
going to push, you hear me?
I need my music!
Carter, the cassette player.
The tapes are in my bag.
You're doing great,
honey. Just hang on, okay?
Okay, Chloe, you're
going to push now.
One, two, three...
Come on, honey, push.
Four. Oh, good push.
Good push, Chloe. Good, good.
No, not that one!
Is that French?
Seven, eight...
nine, ten.
Push, honey. Good.
Come on, Chloe. Come on.
Where's my tape?
Where's the "Blackbird."
I need "Blackbird."
Carter, The White Album.
White Album...
Okay, Chloe, you're doing
a great job.
You really are.
Good job. Okay,
another contraction.
Push!
One, two, three...
four.
Is this it?
Carter, forget it!
♪ Blackbird singing ♪
♪ In the dead of night... ♪
♪ Take these broken
wings and learn ♪
♪ To fly... ♪
♪ All your life ♪
Seven
eight, nine, ten.
♪ Waiting for... ♪
Will you sing with me
please?
Please?
Okay...
♪ Blackbird singing
in the dead of night ♪
♪ Take these broken
wings and learn to fly ♪
♪ All your life ♪
♪ You were always waiting ♪
♪ For this moment ♪
♪ To arrive! ♪
The head's coming. Stop pushing.
Almost...
Oh, oh.
Suction.
Almost. That's
it, Chloe, that's it.
Okay, Chloe.
It's a girl, Chloe.
Good job, Chloe.
She's beautiful, Chloe.
Oh, my God.
You did it.
Chloe, she's beautiful.
She's a beautiful baby girl.
Oh, my God.
Oh.
Hey.
You did it, Chloe, you did it.
We did it, Susie.
We did it.
Captioning sponsored
by WARNER BROS.
Chloe says she looks like me.
What do you think?
Uh...
yeah, well, I suppose.
Maybe.
Never thought I'd
deliver my own niece.
On Mother's Day, no less.
Hey, can I hold her?
Sure.
Hey, little one.
Oh...
So, are you and Tag
going to try for kids soon?
If we're still speaking
after the wedding.
15 of his relatives
arrived yesterday,
a week early,
to help us do some
things around the house.
Sounds scary.
Mm-hmm.
Yep, when I left this morning
they were planning
on painting a bathroom.
Oh, okay. Ooh.
All right.
Good-bye, little one.
Got to get back to work.
Congratulations, Carter.
You got the E.R. Sub-I.
Really?
Swift and I agree
you're the guy.
Thank you.
I didn't think you were
going to decide so soon.
I don't know what to say.
Well, say yes.
You want it, don't you?
I haven't heard about
the surgery Sub-I yet.
I got to know by
the end of the day.
Carter, come on. Get in here
and get the bullet. Let's go.
James Schaeffer, 15 years old,
horsing around a
construction site,
fell off the second floor,
got impaled on a strip of rebar.
We cut it at the site.
He's in shock, pulse
140 and thready.
B.P.'s 50/30.
Let's go! Go!
Rolando, there's a horse
in my parking space.
Why are you riding a horse?
It's not mine, Rolando.
Oh. Would I call
security about that?
I don't know.
That's why they pay
you the big bucks.
Wait, Dr. Ross?
Eight little Ranger
scouts, diarrhea.
Mucho.
Which is why they
pay you the big bucks.
Josh got off early.
He let me sleep in.
Our mothers were
coming for lunch.
He was going to clean the
kitchen and the bathrooms.
Was he unconscious
when you found him?
Yes! He mixed
ammonia with bleach.
I thought he'd
know not to do that.
Okay, we'll take care of
him. Let's get him in here.
You're going to have
to stay out here, uh...
Michelle.
We'll take care of him, okay?
On three. One, two, three.
He's wheezing.
O2, ten liters.
Albuterol nebulizer?
Yeah, and give him
125 milligrams
solumedrol, I.V. push.
Malik, call radiology.
Let's get a portable chest film.
You've got it.
B.P.'s going
nowhere. Still 50/30.
C.B.C. temp request eight units?
Carter, should we yank it?
No. Not here, never.
Then I need a Foley.
Right.
Go to O.R. for
exploratory laparotomy?
Right again.
That's my son, James.
Is he going to be okay?
I'm Dr. Hicks, Mrs. Schaeffer.
I don't know yet, but
we'll do everything we can.
Please wait out here.
What have we got, Peter?
15-year-old male,
impaled on a rebar.
We need to get him up
to the O.R. for an ex lap.
Netzley's up there.
He'll take him.
Anesthesia's on its way.
Carter, come on.
You're going with me.
I can't leave.
Hold it.
All right, clear the hallway.
Let's get the elevator.
Let's move! Go! Clear, clear!
Get out the way!
Let's move!
Heads up! Look out!
Nice corsage.
My kids. Mother's day. Yeah?
Shooting!
You guys need any help?
Nope. Got it under control.
Chlorine gas poisoning.
He's on humidified oxygen,
15 liters per minute.
Gave him solumedrol,
125 milligrams I.V.
Respiratory's coming down.
Call me if you need anything.
I'll draw a blood gas.
They've had diarrhea all morning
in addition to abdominal cramps
and excessive flatus.
We farted the
whole way over here.
Pipe down, Palmer!
And you are...?
Dolores Minky, Little
Ranger Scout Mother.
Hi, Dolores. Hey, um, uh, Mark?
I've got a seven-year-old
in curtain two
uh, high temperature
and excessive vomiting.
Could you take a look?
Happy to.
I suspect it's a
case of Giardia.
We had a camping trip
about three weeks ago.
Contaminated stream
water, beaver feces,
that sort of thing.
Gross. Jeffrey just cut one.
I'm going to puke.
I didn't do it.
It was Andrew.
Boys, now, that's enough!
Hey, now, guys, come on.
Come on, guys. Hey,
hey. You don't need that.
Come on, come on.
Oh, oh, there
you go. There it is.
Told you.
Temperature's 102.
Does that hurt?
Yeah.
Yeah. Has anyone
else in your family
been sick recently?
No, we've all been fine.
Your daughter has a very
faint heart murmur, is that right?
Yeah, since birth.
But they call it an
innocent murmur,
not supposed to be dangerous.
No, it's fine, Mrs. Lafferty.
Joanie's probably got the flu.
I think she's dehydrated,
so I'd like to get her
started on some fluids.
And I think it's best
if we get a spinal tap
and rule out meningitis.
Spinal tap? That's very serious.
We hope it will rule
out anything serious.
What are they going to do, Mom?
We are going to help you
get better, that's what, okay?
Be right back.
Let's start an I.V.,
saline, 100cc's per hour.
Get a C.B.C., chem
seven and prep for an LP.
You got it.
Thanks.
All right.
Retract the liver.
Suction.
I had a case like this just
a couple of weeks ago.
Rebar went straight through
the inferior vena cava.
Extend the incision
up through the chest
and divide the sternum.
Scalpel?
Yeah, this guy's
putting a TV
antenna on his roof.
It fell, and he
fell, right on it.
Ouch.
All right.
Bone saw.
Carter, can you see
anything back there?
Uh, not really.
All right, well, step up.
Hold the retractor.
Aluminum spike right
through his gallbladder.
Lungs down.
Sternal retractor.
What happened?
Well, ruined his
reception, for one thing.
I'm a cable man myself.
Okay, um, open the
pericardium and put a 2-O
proline purse string
around the auricle
of the right atrium.
I.V.C.'s dissected free.
Carter, get ready to pull.
We're close.
Now.
Okay, ease it out.
Easy. Get ready
to advance the cath.
Say when.
Okay. Now!
Okay, tighten the
purse string around it.
Pretty cool, huh, Carter?
Very cool.
Okay, let's do some
repair work here, huh?
V-fib!
Internal paddles!
Carter, get over
here, stick your hands
in there and massage the heart!
Charge to ten.
Clear.
Hey.
Hey. Nice shirt.
Ha-ha! Occupational hazard.
Listen, is there any chance
you can get off early today?
Jake and I are
going house hunting.
What's that about?
Well, the landlord gave
us two months' notice.
He wants his
daughter to move in.
That's a drag.
Dr. Ross,
you are coming back in, right?
Yes, Wendy, I'm coming back in.
No, it's okay.
I'd like a bigger place
and, um, Jake needs a backyard.
Mm-hmm.
You know, depending
on how we feel
there could be room for you.
Uh... um...
are you, uh, talking about us
moving in together?
Maybe, you know, at some point.
Well... you...
you know...
Oh, you can stop
stuttering, Doug.
It's just an idea.
I mean, I just...
do you think that we're ready?
Well, I think I'm
probably more ready
than you are, but
I'm in no hurry.
Well, you let me know
if you find anything today
and I'll take a look.
Call me later.
Okay.
I've got an appendectomy
late this afternoon.
Make sure you do
charts and labs first.
Are you saying I can scrub in?
After charts and labs.
Of course. Right.
Hi, Mrs. Schaeffer.
I'm Dr. Benton.
As you know
your son James was brought in
with severe head trauma
and internal bleeding.
His heart stopped during
emergency surgery.
We tried for 33 minutes
to resuscitate him.
We used all of our capabilities
but his injuries were
too severe, and he died.
Tag... Tag, please.
I do like your mom.
I just don't want to have dinner
with her three nights in a row.
Tag? Tag?
Don't say anything.
It's only a wedding.
So what if the
caterers just canceled
and the bridesmaids'
dresses are late
the relatives are early?
I'm sure this is going to
make me a much better person.
So, are you going up to
Milwaukee for Mother's Day?
Rachel's got a sleep-over.
Jen's coming down
for dinner tonight.
Sounds like a date.
Yeah. That's the idea.
Oh, Carter!
Carter?
How's Chloe?
She's fine.
The baby's great.
They're staying one more night,
then home to mom and pop Lewis.
Oh, so your folks
finally gave in?
Yeah. Guilt's a wonderful thing.
See you later.
Carter, sit down.
So, did you make a decision?
Uh... well, I'm grateful
for the year I've survived
but I guess I'm going
to have to decline.
Benton came through
with the surgical?
No, not exactly, not yet,
but I think surgery
is what I want.
More like being a real doctor?
No. No, of course not.
Surgeons, they
get all the glory.
You know, we're
just the middlemen.
Don't worry, Carter.
You're going to do great,
whatever you choose.
Oh, excuse me.
Where can I find Chloe Lewis?
You're family?
Yes.
I'm Cookie Lewis.
Room 304 on the right.
Thanks.
Mom?
Susie-cake!
Mom!
What's that ridiculous
shirt you're wearing?
Do they allow you
to wear that to work?
Good to see you, too.
Come on, Chloe's in here.
Hi, Cookie. Get in here.
Oh, what a cute little thing.
Oh!
Yeah.
It's pretty neat, huh?
Oh, my, yes.
Mm-hmm.
Almost makes me glad
you got yourself knocked up.
Mom!
What's the matter, Susie cakes?
Am I embarrassing you?
Ow! God, she's got a
mouth like a staple gun.
Yeah. So did you.
Both of you.
Will you take her, Susie?
Yeah.
Yeah, I got her.
Mom, they do feed
people here, you know.
A little extra won't hurt.
She's going to be here a week.
No. She's not.
I told you, she's
leaving tomorrow.
Here.
No. I told your father
it would be a week.
He's putting up
the crib, isn't he?
You know how he is
with that sort of thing.
Mom, please.
Well, I was always the one
putting things together
on Christmas eve.
Yeah. Right.
Like what?
Chloe, please.
Don't start.
Don't start what, Susie?
I mean, how many little
red wagons did you see
around the house?
Oh, I think she's going to
have your father's curly hair.
Mom, Ronnie has curly hair too.
How would I know that?
Have I ever met him?
Well, you will.
Next week.
Well, I had to call him
and tell him he was a father.
He's going to come up and visit.
Don't worry. He's
not going to stay.
Why would he stay?
He's only got a
brand-new baby to support.
Why stay?
I got to get back to work.
Mom, please get
Dad started on the crib.
We're going to be there
tomorrow afternoon.
Don't forget to call
before you come.
What?
Well, you know. In
case we're not home.
Aw, please.
Henry hasn't left the
barcalounger in 15 years.
Don't talk about
your father like that.
The guy doesn't even
come down to visit
his firstborn grandchild?
He's a lazy, fat pig freak.
If you'd played catcher,
this wouldn't have happened.
Mom...
We play in the
mother-daughter
tournament every year.
This morning, bees.
Everywhere, bees.
I don't think there's a
problem, Mrs. Sandburgh.
Well, think again, doctor.
Kaitlin is allergic to bees.
Well, there's no sign
of reaction.
There will be.
I know.
I'm allergic to bees.
It's not necessarily genetic.
Oh, right.
Like you know that, huh?
I'm going to get some forceps.
I'll be right back.
I don't like him.
Trade you.
Mm-mm.
What happened in here?
Mother's Day.
I had no idea it could
be so dangerous.
Why is she sleeping?
Passed out. Brunch
at the pump room.
Drank too many mimosas,
stumbled in the parking lot
and her kids brought her in.
I've got another mother for you.
A little old lady in
exam room four.
Arm laceration.
Check on her when you're done.
The results of the spinal tap
are negative,
so we can rule out meningitis.
Murmur's a little
louder... three/six.
B.P.'s 80/50m
but her pulse is 120, resp 36.
Can I see your hands?
They are very pretty.
You know, I have a
daughter about your age
and her favorite color is pink.
Unfortunately, we're
going to have to take it off
so I can look at
your nails, okay?
Okay.
Let's find some acetone
and take off the nail polish.
Mrs. Lafferty, can I please
speak to you for a minute?
Is it her heart?
They said the murmur
wasn't dangerous.
We need to do more blood work
and get a chest X ray.
It could be pneumonia
or possibly early heart failure.
Oh, my God.
Has your daughter had
any other injuries recently?
Any medical or dental work?
She went to the dentist
two weeks ago, had
her teeth cleaned.
She could have what's
called endocarditis.
Bacteria spreads
into the bloodstream
and causes an infection
around the heart valves.
It can be treated
with antibiotics.
Excuse me. I
ordered a burger, fries
and a vanilla shake,
very, very thick.
Look at you,
working on a Sunday.
No rest for the ambitious.
Do you have Mother's Day plans?
No, thankfully, I do not.
Hmm. Well, you're
welcome to join me and mine.
We're drinking
Manhattans at Shaw's.
And boyfriend Brian?
Couldn't, uh...
couldn't keep up.
Had to cut him loose.
Well, thank you,
but I can't make it.
How about afterwards?
No. I can't do that, either.
God, you're being good.
But I knew you
when you were bad.
See ya.
He was eating the Sunday
special at Chulac's on 23rd,
turned blue and collapsed.
We tried the
Heimlich. Got nothing.
Heart attack?
Yeah. Sounds like it.
He's cyanotic, pulse
58, B.P.'s 50 palp.
Stopped breathing
at your back door.
We got two I.V.s of
normal saline going,
500cc's bolus in the field.
All right, people,
on my count...
One, two, three.
Grab the I.V.s.
Cap refill's no good.
Give him a mig of atropine
and start a dopamine drip.
Pulse is still 58,
B.P.'s 40 palp.
Mr. Carter, this gentleman
has stopped breathing
and he would appreciate
being able to do so.
Would you intubate him, please?
Sure. Of course.
Laryngoscope.
Carter, hurry up.
I can't.
I think there's an obstruction.
Joe said he
was eating, right?
Again.
Yeah, there's an obstruction.
Get the Magill forceps.
Here, Carter. You
need to learn this.
Pulse ox is falling.
Susie-cakes!
Can I talk to you for a minute?
Mom, not in here.
I'll be out there in a minute.
I got something.
Suction.
Damn. That's nasty.
All right, let's
hyperventilate him
and get a blood gas. Let's move.
Mom?
Mom, I'm sorry about that,
but we don't want anyone
in the trauma room while
we're working on a patient.
Hello.
I'm John Carter.
Dr. Benton told me
that you cut your arm.
Oh, no. No. It's not me.
I'm Ethyl.
It's my mother, Ada.
Oh, hello, Ada.
Can I look at your arm?
Ada?
So, what did you need?
I can't do it, Susie.
I can't take the baby,
and I can't take Chloe.
Somebody help! Code blue!
What? Mom... I know I
said I would, but I just can't.
And quite honestly,
I don't think it was
fair of you to ask me.
I mean, it's not fair to me, and you
should have known better. Mom...
I mean, you know, the crib's
not going to be up in time.
The wallpaper isn't
right in that room.
Your father and I still
might take that cruise
in Alaska this summer,
and so I just think you'd
better make other plans.
Mom, what happened?
Did Chloe say
something, do something?
No.
So you're just
changing your mind
after agreeing to
do this, is that it?
Yes.
Well, what the hell am I
supposed to do with her?
She doesn't have any money.
She doesn't have
a place to live.
This is your granddaughter
we're talking about!
Susan, don't you throw that
in my face.
Now, I did my
best with you girls,
but I just... I
can't do it again.
I don't want to do it again.
I had my kids, Susie.
I'm done.
Now... I have to stop by
the market on the way home
'cause we're out of beer.
You know how your father
hates it when we're out of beer.
Where are you going
on your honeymoon?
Tag's going to Paris.
I'm going to Hawaii.
Can I go with you?
Sure. You can leave
Chloe and the baby
with his 15 cousins.
Good. Thanks.
I might stay.
In Hawaii?
Yeah.
Okay.
I can do that.
You think Tag'll mind?
He'll get over it.
Think Chloe'll mind?
I don't think
she'll even notice.
Think they've noticed
that we've been gone?
Probably.
Think we should head back?
See, that was your
first elevator ride.
Yeah.
Oh, here, this is a window, see?
That's gum stuck to the window.
Yuck.
And this is...
Send him to O.R. three.
Metcalf's on his way.
And that?
Hold the elevator.
That's whatever that is.
I'll get his parents to
talk to him in a second.
Chloe? Hey, is this
little Miss Lewis?
Yeah. Isn't she perfect?
Oh, yeah. She sure is.
What's her name?
Susan, Susie,
maybe little Susie.
Oh, hey.
You know where big Susie is?
Uh, big Susie?
No. Chloe, you really
shouldn't have the baby
out here so soon.
Oh, no, no, no, it's
okay. She likes it.
Well, I'm sure she
does, but you might want
to wait a month or so.
Please, help me!
Somebody help me!
Nina's in trouble here.
Lydia, I need some help.
Jerry, get a gurney.
Clear trauma one.
What's her name?
Nina.
Nina, can you hear me?
What'd she take?
I don't know for sure.
She did a speedball
and maybe some downs.
What kind of downs?
I don't know, I don't remember.
Please help her.
Mouth shield?
She's crashing.
Let's get her out of here.
Let's go. Trauma one.
What's your name?
Everett.
Call respiratory stat Everett, you're
going to have to try and remember
to trauma one. if she
took red or she took blue.
We had everything.
I don't know for sure.
Watch your head.
Lydia, get me an invasion tray.
Right. The paddles
over here, too.
You got to stay
out here, please.
Look at the little baby.
What a doll.
Can you please take
her back to the nursery?
She's not supposed
to be down here.
Sure, I'll take her up.
You said the pediatric
surgeon would be coming in?
Yes, Dr. Netzley.
We'll schedule surgery with
him as soon as he gets here.
And he's done this before?
Mitral valve replacement?
Yes, many times.
I know it's a lot to
take in, Mrs. Lafferty,
but it's a routine procedure.
Is your husband able to come?
We're divorced.
He lives in Tucson.
Hey, Chloe.
What are you doing here?
What happened?
What's wrong?
A baby is so small, Susie,
and I just started thinking
about all the bad stuff
that can happen, you know?
And how do I keep
it from happening?
What are you talking about?
Mom and dad couldn't
keep it from happening.
Nothing's going to happen.
The baby's fine.
She is now, but...
Oh...
All right, I'm just scared.
I guess I'll feel better
when we get home
even if it is with
Cookie and Henry.
So...
Yeah, you'll feel better
when you get some sleep.
Yeah.
Get up to your room
and I'll come see
you later, okay?
Okay.
Thanks, Susie.
The decision's made, Peter.
That's all there is to it.
Look, I've trained
this guy all year.
Peter, Susan? We
need you down here.
Dueling gang chicks.
This one's Rosario Guitterez,
also known as La Puppet.
Stab wounds to the chest.
Pulse 140, thready, B.P.. 60/30.
Decreased breath
sounds on the left.
That one's Angelina
Figueroa, La Blue Eyes.
GSW to the head.
Pulse 60, B.P.. 90/60, GCS 5.
All right, people, let's
lift her on my count.
One, two, three.
Have a nice day.
O2, 15 liters.
Tracheal shift.
She's really cyanotic.
Capillary blanch is positive.
Tension pneumo. Hey,
Dr. Ross, use a 16-gauge needle.
You got it.
Give me a 6.5 tube.
No respiratory effort.
What have we got?
Gray matter all over her hair.
All right, let's
hyperventilate her.
Sinus brady 52.
Mannitol, 75 grams,
and a gram of Ancef, I.V.
O2, 15 liters.
That's right.
Second intercostal
space, midclavicular line.
O-neg's here.
Want to do a chest tube?
Yeah, let's get one prepped.
La Puppet's breathing easier.
Rosario, can you hear me?
Hey, Rosario, can you hear me?
Get off of me!
Get off me!
Whoa, baby, I guess you can.
Hold her down.
I'm fine!
Let me go.
Let me go, I said.
Let her die!
You stabbed me with
my own knife, you bitch.
I hope you die, you whore.
Connie, get her restrained
and 2.5 of Droperidol I.V. now!
How about a tox screen?
Yeah. Guess that one woke up.
Let's get a CBC.
Chem seven, type and
cross-match two units.
Get a chest film and do a C.T.
on the way to I.C.U.
Pupils are blown.
No reflexes, flaccid paralysis.
Want me to track
down her family?
Yeah. Haleh, why don't
you check her wallet,
see if there's a donor
card on her driver's license.
Yeah, that's likely.
She stole my boyfriend.
I want her to die.
Lydia, call the I.C.U.
and tell them we'll be
up in a few minutes. Now!
You damn bitch!
Look what you did to me.
Get her out of here!
You cut my ear off!
Where the hell is security?
Get her off!
Malik!
Focus, Carter.
Do the chest tube.
I'll get you!
No!!
Dr. Benton, your mother's
nursing home is on the phone.
Tell them I'll have
to call them back.
They say it's urgent.
Go, go. Go, go.
All right. Get her up to I.C.U.
Everything all right in here?
Hunky-dory.
More Droperidol?
Yeah, 2.5.
Trauma team's on its way down.
Let's clamp the suction tube.
Okay, let's move her.
Carter!
Grab the monitor.
Come on. Come on.
Where's Dr. Benton?
Uh, had to go.
Uh, Mr. Carter
I know Dr. Benton wanted
to talk to you about this
but I need to
notify some people.
We had a number of
excellent candidates this year
for the surgical sub-internship.
The selection process
was very difficult
and while you've done
some excellent work,
another applicant
was more qualified.
I'm sure you'll do well in
whatever else you choose.
Hey, having fun
in here, big Susie?
What did you call me?
Big Susie?
I like that.
Hey, starting nose tackle
for the Chicago Bears
Malik Williams,
ladies and gentlemen.
All right!
Security's got her
restrained in the suture room
if anyone wants to
check out that ear.
She brought the ear?
Carol... hey.
Ow!
Thanks, Malik.
We'll be right there.
Carter, you seen Benton?
Carter, you all right?
What?
Yeah, fine.
Dr. Benton...
What is it? What's happened?
I'm sorry I couldn't
get to you sooner.
What's going on?
They wouldn't tell me
anything on the phone.
Dr. Benton, your mother
arrested at 5:15 this afternoon
while I was in attendance.
We tried to resuscitate
her for 25 minutes.
We used all our capabilities,
but her heart was too
weak, and she died.
I'm sorry.
Are you all right?
Yeah, we're okay, uncle Peter.
Mama's still in with her.
Yeah.
Hey.
I'm going to go check
on the kids, okay?
I thought you were off at 8:00.
I'm on my way home.
I thought you and Jen
were having dinner.
She's running late.
You in the mood
to give a little
personal advice?
Not really.
Diane's thinking about
us moving in together.
Sorry, Doug, I'm not
going to touch that one.
Did you and Jen live together
before you got married?
She says we barely
live together now.
The answer is no.
Her dad would have killed us.
So you bowed to the
reverend's wishes?
I try not to look at
it that way, exactly.
So, what are you going to do?
I don't know.
Did you know when
you were ready?
Yeah.
So, you mean, if I don't
know, then I'm not ready?
That's what I thought.
Does your lack of
readiness have anything to do
with Carol getting
married next week?
What's that supposed to mean?
It might be liberating.
Does your lack of
readiness have anything to do
with me making this next shot?
Yes, completely.
Okay. If I make it,
you're ready,
and if I don't, you're not.
Look, those are the stars.
That's... the little dipper...
and... that's the big dipper
and...
I don't know the names
of any of the others,
but we'll find out, okay?
Dr. Lewis?
Carter.
Do you know the names
of the constellations?
Um...
Well, there's, uh...
Moe...
and over there is Larry...
and that's got to be Curly.
You're worse than I am.
She's adorable.
I've delivered so many babies
and I've never realized
how little they are.
Look at her hands.
I'm sorry you're not doing
the E.R. Sub-I.
Mark told me.
Actually, I wanted to
talk to you about that.
Uh... maybe I made
the wrong decision.
Not if surgery's what you want.
Yeah, yeah... I
was just thinking
maybe the E.R. is
really what I want.
What do you think
Dr. Greene would say
if I told him I changed my mind?
Well, I think he'd
say it's too late.
He offered it to Garreau.
I suppose she said yes?
I think so.
What was that?
A baby burp?
Oh, yeah, little one.
You look sleepy.
Yeah, we should put you down.
Carol, page Netzley
to trauma one now.
When Jen arrives, can
you tell her I'll be out
as soon as I can.
Lydia, we got pulmonary edema.
Draw up five of morphine,
start a nitroglycerine drip
and get a blood gas.
Mark?
Jen, I got
a seven-year-old crashing.
Can you please wait, okay?
It's not what you think.
Diane... Diane, listen to me!
Now, wait!
I want you to listen to me.
I've done that already.
Don't do this.
No, don't you do this!
Don't tell me it's
not what I think
when you're
standing there lying.
You are lying, aren't you?
Oh, yes, I am lying.
Maybe that's because
the idea of you and
I moving in together
was something that
I wasn't ready for.
You could have just said that.
It's because I'm scared
and I was stupid, and I'm sorry.
Give me another chance.
No.
It won't happen again.
Yes, it will.
Come on, Diane!
How long will the surgery take?
Uh, a little over... a
little over three hours.
And you're sure it's all right
to do it now,
even after all this?
Oh, yes.
She's quite stable,
Mrs. Lafferty.
And believe me, this
procedure is really routine.
Joanie's going to be fine.
There's a waiting room just
down the hall from surgery.
Thanks, Mark.
Thank you.
Uh-uh. It is a total
myth that it's the bride
that wants the splashy wedding.
I know. How big is your church?
Well, it's too small for the
3,000 people on the groom's side,
and too big for the
12 people on mine.
He invited everyone he ever met.
So did Mark. What a nightmare.
His relatives had
every motel for 20 miles.
How'd you get through it?
Drugs.
Hi.
What's going on?
Pre-marital advice.
Oh, is she telling you
about how I wanted to elope
but she insisted on Notre Dame?
Yeah, right.
Sorry... uh, sorry about dinner.
You had a patient, Mark.
She was supposed
to go up hours ago.
There were complications
and then, the usual...
These things happen.
What are you going to do?
It's getting late.
We should get going.
Come on.
Peter?
"All of our capabilities."
Whoo.
I've said those words I
don't know how many times.
I've never actually
heard them until today.
I'm sorry, Peter.
Jackie, uh...
Jackie brought the kids home
way past dinner time.
I told her I'd stay here
and, you know, finish up.
You know something?
I, uh... hmm.
I thought I'd be more
prepared for this.
No one's prepared.
They said we could
come back tomorrow
and pick up her
things, and... you know.
I sat beside her...
and I held her hand...
and I touched her face.
Her skin was so soft.
And just for a moment, you know,
just a second, I guess...
I thought I could stay there...
forever.
But I can't do that, can I?
I mean...
I can't hold her.
I can't... I can't touch her.
I can't... I can't do anything.
Shh. Shh.
To keep her.
Hey, little girl.
♪ Blackbird singing
in the dead of night ♪
♪ Take these broken
wings and learn to fly ♪
♪ All your life ♪
♪ You were only waiting
for this moment to arrive ♪
♪ You were only waiting ♪
♪ For this moment to arrive. ♪