Carol?
Yes, Mama?
Are you all right?
Just woke up early, that's all.
Go back to bed.
I'll wake you when I leave.
You don't have to work today.
I want to.
If you're not ready,
no one would mind.
I know, but I am ready, Mama.
It's all right.
Don't worry.
Go on. Go back to bed.
Who is it?
♪ The problem
now, of course, is ♪
♪ To simply hold your horses ♪
♪ To rush would be a crime ♪
♪ 'Cause nice and easy does it ♪
♪ Nice and easy does it ♪
♪ Nice and easy
does it every time. ♪
Got to teach it who's boss.
Thanks.
Sure.
Have we...? Excuse me.
Carol Hathaway.
Right. I met you my first day.
Oh, my last, or so I thought.
Hey, Wendy.
Carol, welcome
back. How are you?
Great. Thanks. You got
a slow Monday for me?
Like always.
♪ It's going to be so easy... ♪
You know whose patient this is?
No, but I can name that tune.
Well, can you find
out whose patient it is?
Sure, but I'm on my
way to Radiology.
Be back in ten.
That's fine.
That's fine. Good.
Dr. Greene, is
this your patient?
No, this is my
patient... Mr. Resnick.
How you doing, Mr. Resnick?
I'm having an enema.
How do you think I'm doing?
♪ The problem now ♪
♪ Of course is ♪
♪ To simply hold
your horses... ♪
Room 4 is Mrs. Yakimoto's
four-year-old daughter, Grace.
C.C... lingering cough
and a runny nose.
No doubt because
the kid has a cold.
All right, I'll take
Baby Huey first.
Mark, have you seen Carol?
You're almost done, Mr. Resnick.
Doug, this is the third time
you've asked me this morning.
The answer is still no.
We need to be a
little sensitive here.
It's her...
first day back?
Yeah. Yeah.
Excuse me.
I'm here to unload that
new shipment of barbiturates.
Hi. Hey.
At least you didn't kill off
your sense of humor.
No. Just a few brain cells.
Hi.
Hi, Jerry.
Jerry...
Jerry, you're killing me.
Nothing you
haven't tried already.
Don't start.
Oh, please.
Don't start what?
Dr. Ross asked us all to
be a little sensitive today.
Ah, there she is.
Whose patient is this?
Hey, Carol, welcome back.
Thanks.
Where did you find her?
Who is she?
I don't know.
Cops brought her in.
They found her riding
the el about 4:00 a.m.
She had no I.D., wouldn't talk.
Oh, yeah?
Well, she sings...
loudly.
Really?
Sorry, Dr. Benton.
All right, so who's going
to take Madame X here?
I've got a laceration
in the suture room.
Abdominal pain, room 1.
I will, in just a minute,
but Dr. Jones wants
these X rays right away.
Oh, I'll get it.
E.R.
♪ We're on the road to romance ♪
♪ That's safe to say ♪
♪ So let's make all the
stops along the way... ♪
All right.
Any congestion,
vomiting, diarrhea?
No. He just doesn't seem right.
Have you or your wife
been sick recently? No.
Do you have other
kids, or a baby-sitter?
No. We never even left
him with a baby-sitter.
Okay. We're going to
get some blood tests,
and we're going to do
some fever control measures
to get his temperature down,
and we'll see how he
does, okay? All right.
He looks a little lethargic.
Let's get a CBC,
blood culture, chest,
urine, throat swabs.
And hope against hope
we don't have to
do a lumbar puncture
or we're looking at
a Valium drip for dad.
By the way, have you seen...?
No, but I certainly
will remember
to be sensitive when I do.
If you ever want to take a
few minutes, talk about it...
Thanks.
See you around.
Lab results on Mr. Newton?
Not back yet.
Okay. Thanks.
Hey, Carol, I hope
you don't mind
that we were joking
with you earlier.
You don't think
attempted suicide
is something to joke about?
Jerry, don't worry. It was fine.
Okay. If you ever want
to talk or anything...
Boy, am I happy to see you.
'Cause I don't have to
be charge nurse anymore.
Welcome back.
Carol, I have the perfect
first-day-back patient for you.
Jerry, where did
they drop Arthur?
Other side of curtain area 3.
Our Arthur?
Yeah.
So, how's it going?
Couldn't wait for
this day to get here.
Now I think I'll be
glad when it's over.
I feel like everyone's
watching me.
Everyone is, but no one
is looking for you to fail,
if that's what you're
worried about.
My shrink wanted me to consider
working in a doctor's
office instead of the E.R.
Uh-huh. Dermatology's good.
I don't think so.
Maybe this was too
soon to dive back in.
Come on. It's
Monday. It'll be easy.
Kids who faked being
sick to stay out of school,
a few people who partied
too hard this weekend...
and Arthur.
Gosh, it is good to be back.
All the familiar faces.
Arthur?
Arthur, get up!
Come on, let's go.
Ma'am?
Ma'am, are, uh...?
Are you okay?
I mean, I can see that...
that you're not okay.
Uh... if I could
just get your...
your name for the... the, uh...
If I could just get your...
your first name?
Or your...?
It's okay, actually.
I don't need your name.
Um...
Hey, now, uh...
would you, uh...?
Would you... like a drink?
I know I would like a drink.
Gunshot wound's on its way.
When?
Now.
Malik, find Benton,
clear trauma 1
and notify the O.R.
Lydia, draw a CBC.
Get the lab to cross and
type six units whole blood.
Find out how much
"0" negative's around.
This guy's a major bleeder.
We've got another
one... 79-year-old male,
probable heart attack.
E.M.T.s are here in two minutes.
Call Susan Lewis, and
get the cardiologist on call.
A couple of sick kids?
Weekend partiers?
Welcome home.
He's in shock.
Keep those I.V.s wide open.
All right, people.
Show time. Let's move.
He's not breathing.
Get the intubation tray.
All right, no breath sounds.
Hyperresonant on the left side.
He's got a touch of pneumo.
Let's et a chest tube,
and let's get it now. Move.
Seven and a half?
Where the hell is X ray?
I'll find them.
Check with Susan.
See if she needs help
with that heart guy.
We need X ray, trauma 1.
He's on his way.
Hey, welcome back to Beirut.
I could use some company.
Timmy, find Pam.
What have you got?
Classic heart attack symptoms...
Sudden onset, crushing
substernal chest pains
radiating down left
arm with diaphoresis.
Had nitro spray times
two without relief,
and five milligrams morphine.
Hey, Carol, hi. Hey.
Vitals?
BP's down 90/50, respiration 24.
He was in sinus rhythm.
Went into this as we pulled up.
Okay, one, two, three.
Mr. Flanagan, I'm Dr. Lewis.
How's your pain now?
Oh, much better.
Dr. Kayson's my cardiologist.
Someone was going to call him.
Okay, let's check on Dr. Kayson.
Get an EKG,
chest, CBC,
Chem seven, enzymes
and coag panel.
BP's 90/55.
Pulse is racing at 180.
What's his rhythm
look like to you?
It's hard to say. V-tach,
we need to shock him.
You want to do it?
No. He seems relatively stable.
Let's try adenosine...
Six milligrams
I.V. push.
Heart rate's dropping.
BP's down. Down to 50 palp.
Damn. Get the
external pacemaker.
Where's the pacer?
In the drawer.
Carol, stay put. We
need you in here.
Take this to Susan in 4.
How's the belly?
Abdomen is rigid.
You got it. Lavage time.
Anesthesia?
Well, I'd say his buddies
already took care of it for us.
Heart rate's still low.
Give him another
milligram of atropine.
Pacemaker's capturing.
Is the dopamine running?
Yes. You sure you don't
want to intubate him?
He's biting down. I'd
have to paralyze him,
which I'd rather not do
considering his low BP.
Dr. Lewis? Keep bagging.
Nothing's going right.
This guy's blood gas stinks.
Did you reach Kayson?
He's being paged.
I can't wait.
Get the Pavulon, Versed and SUX.
Prep a dose of
TPA, just in case.
Vitals?
BP's 50/30, respiration's
36, pulse 140.
All right, let's take a look.
Catheter.
His S.T. wave is way up.
Acute M.I.
We're in trouble.
You want to inject TPA?
Hand me his old chart.
He has no contraindications
to giving TPA,
but I don't want to
start him bleeding.
90/60. How's his pressure?
Oh. man. Okay,
we got to go with it.
5,000 units Heparin and TPA ten
milligrams push, 60 over one hour.
Let's get another EKG.
Keep him on the monitor.
BP?
Still 90/60.
He's in V-fib.
Crash cart.
Yes. 200?
And clear.
Clear again.
I'm Dr. Kayson.
What have we got?
He's having an
acute inferior wall M.I.
I just started TPA.
Without consulting me?
He should go to cath
lab for angioplasty.
I felt drug therapy
was indicated.
Did you think
angioplasty wasn't?
No. Of course not. But, since...
Well, I favor a more
aggressive approach.
That's one opinion. I chose
drugs. They're less invasive.
Dr. Lewis, Mr. Flanagan
is my patient.
You're a resident.
All decisions concerning
his care will be made by me.
Call the cath lab. Tell
them we're on the way up.
Vitals?
Blood pressure is 110/70.
Pulse is 90.
Okay. Pacemaker
captured... That's a start.
Prep another milligram atropine.
Keep bagging.
All right, come on.
Let's go. Let's go. Move!
I'll get up to the blood bank.
How's that M.I.?
Kayson seems to
have it under control.
Want to grab some coffee?
That was good
work in there, Carol.
You may have doubts
about being back,
but none of us do.
Thanks.
Have you seen Morgenstern?
No.
Doug, have you seen Susan?
Am I the hall monitor? No!
Mark, need you in exam 4.
Mrs. Cheung, early 30s.
Eye and cheek badly swollen,
facial lacerations,
bruised ribs.
Don't know how it happened.
She doesn't speak English,
but her son does.
♪ Travel my way ♪
♪ Take the highway ♪
♪ That's the best... ♪
Madame X?
She doesn't answer
to that, but yes.
♪ Get your kicks
on Route 66... ♪
At least she's good.
♪ It was from
Chicago to L.A... ♪
You are absolutely wrong.
I'm not wrong.
It was a bad
call. Admit it, Div.
Anybody could have made it.
Are you kidding?
You don't pick a guy off first
with the winning run on third.
There were two outs.
McDowell had it
sewed up right there.
Yeah. Until he
threw it in the dugout.
Right. What do you need?
This is Madame X.
I've completed a physical,
but I'm having a little trouble
with the psych exam.
Did you run the mental
status questions?
Tried. Half the
time, she screamed.
The other half the
time, she was in tears.
Okay, let's see what we can do.
Nei wa bei yisun tang
wa mamee di chor lor lao tai.
Ng ho wa baba da
ngoh, nei zi dou ma?
She fell down the stairs.
At your house?
Yeah.
Did you see her fall, Frank?
And you live at 311
West MacArthur.
Apartment "A"?
Apartment "A."
That would be
on the third floor.
Right, Frank?
No. We live on the first floor.
So where were the stairs?
Lao tai hai bin dou?
Kinman...
nei ng sai ken.
Kiu koi bong mamee ler.
Will you help her?
Yes, we will.
Malik, why don't you
take Frank back out front?
Come on, Frank.
I'll show you how
to get free stuff
out of the candy machine, huh?
X rays?
Yes.
Left orbit, chest and ribs.
What do you bet we find
a few healed fractures?
My dad once saw Benny Goodman
play at the old Monroe Theater.
On 33rd street?
Yep.
I used to sing
there during the war.
All those boys in uniform.
Well, he was one of them.
Who knows?
Maybe you even danced with him.
I never thought to
talk to her about music.
I don't even know
anything about music.
Neither does he.
So you ready to try
some of those questions?
Like on Jeopardy?
Yeah. Yeah.
Can you tell me where you are?
What is a jail?
No. No, you're not in jail.
The cops brought me in here.
Okay, okay, I'll
give you that one.
Um... Do you know
what year it is?
Um... What is 1948?
And who's the president?
Harry Truman.
Who is...
Harry Truman?
Okay, now, this is a
different kind of question.
If you found a sealed letter
with a stamp on it, okay,
lying in the street,
what would you do?
Uh...
I... I would, uh...
I... would...
It's okay.
Forget it. We'll
try another one.
We'll try another one.
Can you tell me
what the difference is
between a child and a dwarf?
I am a child,
but I'm not a dwarf.
Excellent.
Very good. Good.
Carol.
Dr. Morgenstern.
Walk with me.
You glad to be back?
Glad to be anywhere.
How's your family handling this?
Pretty good. I
think, for a while,
they were afraid
it was their fault.
And how are you holding up?
Okay. Just hoping
to slip back into work,
and not have everyone
make such a big deal about it.
It is a big deal.
People should be concerned:
your family, the staff.
But everyone felt you were ready
to come back.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Now go work too hard.
Hypothyroidism?
Cushing's syndrome?
Hepatolenticular degeneration?
Vascular disease?
When you hear hooves,
think horses, not zebras.
You mean, think
obvious: think Alzheimer's.
That would account for the
mood swings, loss of memory,
confused judgment, yeah.
What should I do with her?
Find her family.
She probably just wandered off.
Mr. Carter, I asked
you to check her over,
not to become her
personal physician.
I see Malik taught
you his trick.
Frank... I know
sometimes it's scary
to tell the truth...
especially about stuff
that happens at home.
Like when your
mom and dad argue,
you don't want to
take sides, right?
Telling the truth
isn't taking sides.
It's just saying what happened.
And, if we knew what really
happened to your mom...
we might be able
to help her more.
She didn't really fall
down the stairs, did she?
Here you go.
Don't worry, Frank.
Your mom's going
to be fine, all right?
Just fine.
Hey!
Going to lunch?
Uh...
You know, the cafeteria
has taken a real
dive since you left.
It's got all this low-fat
health food junk.
It's a major drag.
Doug, I can't really do this.
Do what?
Go to lunch?
Look, I'm not asking you out.
I'm not suggesting
that we should see
each other... again.
Hey, Carol, I'm sorry I'm late.
Had a knee
arthroscopy on this kid...
Captain of the high
school football team.
His folks are a little worried
about his college
scholarship, but...
Doug, you know John Taglieri.
Hi, John.
Hi, Doug.
How's pediatrics?
You must have a
lot of worried parents.
All of them.
So maybe we should go, huh?
Yeah.
But not the cafeteria.
No burgers, no fries.
Place is worthless.
Hey, really good
seeing you again.
That's a really funny story.
I'm going to have to
remember that one, Mr. Karnow.
Dr. Carter? Yes?
Can I see you for a minute?
Excuse me.
You were supposed to be
in Radiology 20 minutes ago.
Yes.
Look, he can talk about
his mother, his father,
his brother, his
sister, his dog.
Your job is to remained focused
on his medical problem, okay?
Bird touching down
in two minutes.
Teenagers. Some
kind of boating accident.
All right, now, these
chopper jockeys move fast,
so stay close, pay
attention, listen up,
don't go near the rear blade,
and try not to
fall off the roof.
You're really not being
much help with this, Mark.
Well, I've surrendered. You haven't
been able to decide for six months.
But I've really narrowed it
down to either the Cherokee,
Explorer, Montero,
Trooper or Pathfinder.
What? No 4Runner?
Susan, Mark, I'm going to switch
this week's M&M
to this afternoon.
I want Dr. Kayson to come,
and he can't be there on Friday.
Dr. Kayson?
Present your heart
case from this morning.
Mr. Flanagan.
Excellent teaching case.
All part of the process.
I'll see you at 5:00.
Oh, God.
He didn't crump, did he?
No. I gave him TPA.
Kayson wanted angioplasty.
Just hate to get into it again.
Well, I'm sure It will be an
excellent teaching case, Susan.
Follow me.
Stay close, all right?
Don't get in the way,
whatever you do.
Stay on me.
I'll call you.
Go!
What have you got?
16-Year-old girl...
Jet Ski accident by Navy Pier.
Boyfriend tried to
outrun a 20-foot whaler.
Altered L.O.C. from head trauma.
Okay, go. What are her vitals?
Four-inch scalp laceration.
Bleeding controlled
with pressure.
Carter, go! Move!
Left arm and right leg with
obvious support fractures.
Vitals are 60/40,
pulse 140 and thready.
GCS 3-4-3. Skin
is pale and cool.
How long was she
down in the water?
Three minutes max.
Boyfriend started
CPR, got her sputtering.
Was there any...?
Carter, move!
Get the door! Go ahead. Go!
Bring her down.
Mr. Layton, Huey's test results
failed to show a
source of infection.
What does that mean?
It doesn't necessarily
mean anything
but, with his lethargy, we
need to rule out meningitis,
so I would like to do
a lumbar puncture.
Lumbar puncture?
A spinal tap.
Spinal tap?
You'll have to fill me in.
Dr. Carter?
Uh... she's 16.
There was an accident on
the lake. She's hypotensive.
I think she was
underwater five minutes.
Three minutes.
Multiple trauma, hypotension,
tachycardia, GCS 3-4-3,
multiple extremity fractures,
neuro and vascular intact.
Thank you, Dr. Carter.
We'll take it from here.
Let's move, people.
Tell X ray we need a
cross table, C-spine...
Chem seven, CBC-type,
and crossmatch eight
units packed cells.
Call the O.R. Tell them
we'll be down. Let's move.
The bathroom is right over here,
you want to splash
some water on your face.
Malik will show you
where you can wait, okay?
Thank you.
There you go.
Hey.
I heard you had a crasher.
The trials of fatherhood.
Talk to Carol yet?
I tried to.
Taglieri showed up.
You're not surprised, are you?
They've been
going out for a while.
You didn't expect her to
pine away for you forever.
No, I didn't.
Just hoped she would?
Yeah. Nobody
likes being replaced.
All right, I did it first.
Although, for the life of me,
I can't remember why.
Maybe it was just
because you're stupid,
childish, immature...
I get the point.
We'll have someone in here
to do your stitches in
a few minutes, okay?
Thank you.
Sure. Your blood test came back.
You didn't tell me
you have leukemia.
You asked what I came
in for... this darn cut.
I feel so stupid,
slipping in the kitchen.
You're supposed to
slip in the bathtub, right?
I don't think you slipped,
Mrs. Packer. I think you fainted.
Your white blood cell and
platelet counts are very low.
You have severe aplastic anemia.
If someone could
just sew me up...
You need to be
admitted to the hospital
for a blood transfusion.
That's just not
possible... not today.
Mrs. Packer, without
transfusion of blood components,
you're susceptible to
infection, bleeding...
Possibly even a heart attack.
I know all about it, Doctor.
I've been dealing with
this for quite some time.
And time is something
that I don't have
a great deal of anymore.
I'd rather not spend
it in the hospital.
Now, if I could just
get a few stitches.
Okay. We'll have someone
in here in a minute, all right?
Thank you.
I know. I know.
Okay.
All right, you're
a very brave boy.
All finished.
Dr. Carter, next time
you can do the lumbar.
Come here, buddy.
Here we go.
I know.
It's all over.
Come on.
Susan needs you
to do some stitches
by the nurse's desk.
Okay.
Hey.
Hey, have you seen Mark?
No. Sorry.
Hanging in?
We still having coffee later?
Yeah, sure.
That ought to do
it, Mrs. Packer.
Thank you.
Are you okay?
No.
Shh! You're going to be okay.
You're going to be okay.
Shh...
You know, when I think
of all the great ones,
Ella Fitzgerald is
probably my favorite.
Yeah, yeah.
I mean, she's amazing.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
And the music...
There's nothing
like that music today.
No, there isn't.
No.
Do you want to sing?
♪ Life begins ♪
♪ And spirits rise ♪
♪ And they become memories ♪
♪ That vaporize ♪
♪ And the vapor becomes ♪
♪ The dreams we devise ♪
♪ And while we are dreaming ♪
♪ Time flies ♪
♪ Time... ♪
flies.
Excuse me.
My breasts hurt.
Okay.
Dr. Carter, please.
And your name again?
Proserpina, daughter of Ceres,
who was whisked away
into the dark, dank bowels
of the underworld by Pluto,
who not only had
his way with her,
but also forced her to eat
three red, ripe, dripping
pomegranate seeds.
And to think you could
have missed all this.
All right, Miss
Pina, let's start
with a Social Security number.
Jennifer make it by for lunch?
No. She had a job interview
with Pitten, Pitten
and Stefronofsky.
What a mouthful. I'd
hate to be the receptionist.
I'm going to take off early
and meet her for dinner.
Don't leave before
today's teaching session.
I need all the friends
I can get with Kayson.
Miss your interrogation?
I don't think so.
Mark? I need you for a minute.
Don't be late.
That little boy, Frank,
wants to talk to you.
About his mother?
Didn't say, but I think
that's a pretty good guess.
He's scared to death.
Shot again, huh?
Never have I seen such a thing.
I've turned into a magnet.
What's your name, sir?
Ivan Gregor. He
owns a liquor store.
They're damn bad shots.
Maybe I should buy a gun.
Never wanted one around,
but what I am supposed to do?
Calm down, Mr. Gregor.
Let's get him in here.
Call Radiology.
Let's get a left tib-fib
X ray right away.
Carter!
Malik, can you go find Carter?
He's been disappearing.
All right, people, we're
going to do this on my count,
and we're going to do it right.
Lisa, I don't think
that we should...
Okay.
Remember that thing
that you did the other night?
Mm-hmm. The thing in
the car or in the kitchen?
The thing on the stairs.
Mm-hmm.
Well, there's nothing
compared to...
I don't think we have
any uneven parallel bars.
You know what they
say in med school?
S-1, S-2, S-3, S-4,
keep the pelvis off the floor.
Patient: Gregor, Ivan.
Medical record 6955.
A.P. and lateral views,
left tibia and fibula.
♪ La-da-di-da-dum-da-dum ♪
♪ Da-di-da-ba-la da-di-da-dum ♪
♪ Life begins... ♪
Mrs. Packer, please reconsider.
We can start a
transfusion immediately.
You'd only have to
be here one night.
I know that doesn't seem
like very long to either of you.
To me, it is an eternity.
We want to give you
more time, not less.
You've already given
me a wonderful afternoon.
It's not every day
that I get to hear
Mary Cavanaugh sing in person.
Mary Cavanaugh?
♪ Time flies... ♪
My husband and I
saw her perform in San Francisco
on our honeymoon in 1948.
I appreciate your concern,
but I have to go.
♪ Da-di-da-ba-ba-la ♪
♪ Da-di-da-dum ♪
♪ Da-da-dum-da-dum-da-dum ♪
♪ Mm-mmm-mm-mmm-mm... ♪
Mrs. Packer!
We need a wheelchair!
And has your
father hit her before?
Has your father
ever hit you, Frank?
Does your father know that
you and your mom are here?
He's coming to pick us up.
I guess I shouldn't have told.
No, no, no, no. You
did the right thing.
We're going to try and get
some people to help you, okay?
Why don't you go back
in and see your mom?
Call Social Services
and Children and
Family Services.
See if anyone can come
up with a shelter for them.
Let me know when they're here.
Don't think I've seen
such an old little boy.
So you elected
not to cardiovert?
He seemed stable.
Hypotensive with chest pain?
The pain was controlled.
Somewhat.
Let's continue, please.
Could be a wide
complex tachycardia.
Was that a consideration?
I felt it was rate-related.
Which it wasn't.
No. Heart rate fell.
EKG shows an
acute inferior wall M.I.
Why the delay on the intubation?
You had the bad gasses.
I was hoping he'd come
around with bagging.
When I got the gasses
back, I tubed him.
So you recommended
drug therapy... TPA?
I do angioplasty with my M.I.s.
Jumping in with TPA
messed everything up.
He had no contraindications,
you weren't available,
and time is heart muscle.
I was on my way!
I didn't know that.
People, please. It's
just a teaching session.
What was the outcome?
Did the angio cath,
and it was a mess.
Bled like a stuck pig.
Before I got
to the angioplasty,
his heart rhythm
went haywire.
Shocked him once,
then he came around.
EKG came back to
normal... The artery opened.
So you never did angioplasty?
Well, I could hardly...
and the TPA worked.
Yes.
Dr. Benton, what
would you have done?
Angioplasty.
Dr. Langworthy?
Dr. Greene?
Angioplasty.
Just because we're friends
doesn't mean we're
always going to agree.
That's not the
point. The point is,
I'm getting dragged
over the coals,
you stroll in late,
don't say a word.
Well, I missed the first half.
How was I supposed to comment?
Didn't stop you from
commenting in the end.
Why do I feel like a traitor?
It wasn't personal.
I'm dying out there,
and you're siding with
the slicers and dicers.
Benton, Langworthy...
They're all surgeons.
All they ever want to
do is cut people open.
That may be a little
bit of an exaggeration.
The patient was fine
with a dose of TPA
versus a $10,000
surgical procedure.
My decision was valid.
You should have backed me up.
Have you seen the chart on the
sliced finger in the stitch room?
Yep. Hey, did
Proserpina find you?
Who?
Oh, Liz. Yeah.
She seems like
an interesting girl.
Yep. Yeah, she is.
I knew a girl like that once.
Freshman year of college.
"Penicillin" was
her middle name.
No meningitis.
He's got no infection.
You got to continue to
monitor his temperature,
and you have his doctor check
the blood cultures tomorrow.
All righty. Thank you.
Okay?
Hey.
Want to get some coffee?
Uh... you know, I'm not sure
right now is really a good time.
We'll go outside,
we'll watch them polish
up the ambulances.
Well, uh... yeah. Okay.
I'll just be a few minutes.
Okay.
Dr. Lewis was so persistent,
I had to agree to a transfusion
just to get rid of her.
We're just worried
about you, Mrs. Packer.
I'm worried about missing
my granddaughter's
christening tonight.
8:00 service.
Well, your family could
always reschedule.
Why should they?
I'm not going to die on them.
Not today.
You know, in all this mess,
I've had a lot of time
to think about dying.
Can't say I recommend it.
A nice fat stroke would
have suited me better.
But each morning I wake
up I think of as a gift and...
there's this feeling I have...
I don't know when
it's going to happen,
but I know when it's not.
I'm not going to die today.
I am going to a christening.
Father showed
up ten minutes ago,
very determined to leave.
Mr. Cheung...
I'm Dr. Greene.
You like to go somewhere
to talk this through?
There is no need,
but thank you.
I want to get my family home.
This mother and son
need to get to a shelter.
They've got to want to go.
Frank told me that
his father hit her.
Look at her face.
She denies it.
My son was very upset
when his mother fell.
Confused.
You understand.
Frank...
please ask your
mother again for me.
Will you?
Can we get Children
and Family Services here?
Not unless the
child's been beaten.
How can you say such a thing?
Has your father
ever hit you, Frank?
Frank, did your
father hit your mom?
No...
No.
Hao, zen mo?
Fai dee, fai dee.
Thank you for your concern.
Mmm! I don't think so.
I'll get it.
Uh...
Who was... Who was Jimmy Dorsey?
Glenn Miller.
Well, I got Duke
Ellington, didn't I?
Big deal.
What are we doing here?
We're waiting.
Your granddaughter's
here. Remember?
You're going home.
That's right.
My granddaughter's here.
Did you meet her?
Yes.
I'm going home.
Can you come?
Well, I'm very busy today,
but some other time.
You all set?
Thanks again.
And I'm sorry about this.
She usually doesn't
wander so far.
It's okay, really. Don't worry.
She's really great.
Love you, love you, love you.
I love you, too.
♪ Let's take it nice and easy ♪
♪ It's going to be so easy ♪
Come on, Ellen. Come
on, come on, come on.
♪ Hey, baby,
what's your hurry? ♪
♪ Relax and don't you worry ♪
♪ We're going to fall in love ♪
♪ We're on the road to romance ♪
♪ That's safe to say... ♪
Hey.
Thanks.
Good first day?
Yeah, so far.
That's good. I'm glad.
Listen, I was hoping that...
Um... that... I mean, I know
that you're seeing Taglieri,
but I was thinking that
maybe you and I could
see each other again.
If I'd known you'd find
suicide such a turn-on,
I would have tried it
when we were together.
I'm serious.
No, you're not.
You're standing
there like a puppy
with its tail between its
legs 'cause you feel guilty.
No, I don't.
I do, but that's not
what this is about.
Yes, it is. You think
you had something to do
with my swallowing
a whole bunch of pills.
Well, you didn't.
There were actually
more depressing
events in my life than you.
Tell me about them.
I want to know.
Aw, it's a combination
of things, you know?
Too much stuff starts piling up.
You feel trapped.
I spend a lot of time
talking about all this stuff
with my shrink, so, um...
I have a lot of work to do.
Carol, do you really
want to be with Taglieri?
He was there for me
before this happened...
When it happened.
What we had...
Is it worth another chance?
You thought what we had
didn't work. Remember?
I don't suppose we could
talk you out of
this one more time?
I told you Dr. Lewis let me in
first thing in the morning
for the rest of my transfusion.
I can't miss one
minute of one thing.
Not one minute,
one hour, one day.
Of course, when I was your age,
I never thought of such a thing.
I do.
Life might be giving up on me,
but I'm not giving up on it.
Then we'll see you
tomorrow morning?
Yes, you will.
She leaving again?
She's going to a christening.
Carol!
Carol, come quick.
Mark's hurt.
Surprise!
Speech!
Okay.
Uh... we wanted to
give you something
to let you know how glad we are
that you're back.
Eight weeks ago,
you managed to
grab our attention.
So, if you feel like you
need to do that again,
we'd like you to put this on.
Oh, God.
Speech!
Uh... okay.
Well, to say I feel lucky
would be kind of
an understatement.
What you all did to, uh...
to save me was like a gift.
And, uh...
I've promised myself to
remember that every day, so...
Thank you.
Captioning sponsored
by WARNER BROS.