Doc! Help! Doc!
It stopped bleeding.
That's because your blood is
freezing as it's hitting the air.
Here. Apply pressure on it.
I think my leg is frozen.
That's the least of your problems.
The blade severed your femoral artery.
Am I going to lose my leg?
Frostbite's not too bad.
But I've got to fix your artery
now. This is going to hurt.
Are you going to put that in me?
Glue's the best way to repair
your artery at this temperature.
It looks okay.
Here. Tear off some pieces.
I have to check your foot.
Blood flow looks good.
Your leg should be okay.
I thought I was done.
Yeah, like I'd let
anything happen to you.
You're the only one who
could fix the generators.
Okay. One, two...
Cate. Cate, are you
okay? Are you okay?
Hey.
I need help.
Who am I supposed to get?
Why do I even
give you an office?
New case. Psych department
asked for you personally.
The patient's a crazy person?
You're a crazy person.
The patient's a psychiatrist.
There's something wrong
with coma guy's cable.
He seems fine with it.
Your patient is an adjunct faculty
member here, but currently...
The budget committee voted to
charge for cable in the patient rooms.
Slippery slope.
Today, we withhold porn.
Tomorrow, it's clean bandages.
Talk to Carlson in Derm, he
runs the budget committee,
after you look at this.
After you talk to
Carlson, maybe I'll...
The patient is trapped
at the South Pole.
Any possibility of
evacuating her?
Well, that wouldn't be any fun.
And for the next two months, winds make
it impossible to fly anything in or out.
Could be appendicitis
or a gallstone.
Or a kidney stone.
That wouldn't be any fun.
If it's appendicitis down there,
her appendix ruptures, she dies.
There's nothing we can do. If
it's a stone, she takes pain meds,
stone passes. There's
nothing we need to do.
Could be a struvite
kidney stone.
Most kidney stones are calcium and benign.
Why would you suspect a struvite stone?
Because he said kidney
stones were boring.
It's possible. She's
on birth control.
Lots of sex could lead
to urinary tract infection,
which could lead to an
infection-laced struvite kidney stone.
Excessive Antarctic drilling,
bad for the environment
and the ladies.
If it's a struvite stone, she
needs to break it up quickly
before the infection
shuts down her kidneys.
This is where it gets fun.
These are the supplies and
medications she has available.
Nothing here that could
break up a kidney stone.
What else do they
have down there?
I just said... I don't mean
medical stuff. Other stuff.
Some geological equipment
breaks ice and rock
the same way we
break kidney stones.
Discovery Channel. I like
watching them blow stuff up.
Who doesn't?
That reminds me.
Coma guy needs cable.
Women's billiards is the only
thing that's keeping him alive.
I'm sure Carlson will
be moved by his plight.
Carlson won't listen.
He says I hit on his wife.
You knew? God, no.
I thought I was
hitting on his daughter.
Look, you're on the
committee. He'll listen to you.
I'm an avid reader of Committees
with Hotties message boards.
Amoxicillin, 500 milligrams, IV.
Studies conducted
at major hospitals
indicate that happy
patients recover faster.
Studies conducted in my apartment
show that TV makes people happy.
Premium channels have
a particularly striking effect.
Charging patients for cable is
bringing in 13 grand a month.
Until this injustice is righted, I
am going to waste 13 grand a day.
That's $2.49 down.
Get an EKG and a cardiac enzyme.
If those check out, discharge him,
and tell him to get a snow-blower.
How much is 13 grand
divided by 4 cents?
I am not giving you cable.
You're gonna have to somehow
survive with the broadcast networks alone.
I'll be fine on Tuesdays.
If sound waves from the
flaw detector break the egg,
it should safely dissolve
your kidney stone.
This isn't going to work.
Well, there's no
reason it shouldn't.
Sound waves are sound
waves. Stones are stones.
Some are bigger than
others. Some are inside me.
How's it going, Team MacGyver?
Oh, great.
I can't get cable, but I can
get the South Pole on high-def.
We're almost ready
to start the test.
Test? Did Ford test the Edsel?
Did Coke test New Coke? Did
Shakespeare test his final play, Snow Dogs?
I'm guessing you're Dr. House?
I was wondering when
you might drop by.
Could she see me?
Oh, yeah.
You think Jagger shows
up for the sound check?
Okay, roadies, off the stage.
Go help Cameron in the ER.
Why? No way you're
just doing her a favor.
ER is standing room only.
Which means Cameron's
bound to make a mistake.
Find it so I can blackmail her.
As far as you know,
this is way more than just
some silly battle over cable.
Ready.
You might wanna
dial it down a smidge.
I am not doing this.
Your kidney stone theory
hinges on me having sex, but I...
Let me guess. You're as
pure as the driven snow.
Only if the snow
likes to be on top.
But I am here doing
psychological research.
Generally not a good idea to
swap fluids with your subjects.
Struvite stones are possible
in people who don't have sex.
They're certainly possible
in people who claim not to...
I've had no UTI's,
no pain on urination.
You do realize that only
one of us is a real doctor.
You do realize only one of us
has any control over my actions.
Dr. Milton, are you
able to run a CHEM-7?
Yes.
Well, that'd tell us if her
kidney function is declining.
If it is, he's right.
Struvite stone's the
most likely explanation.
If not, she's right.
Sorry. I know how you like to
avoid avoiding confrontation.
While we're waiting for that test to
prove me right, start IV cefuroxime.
Keep the infection in the stone
from wiping out your kidneys.
I'll send the CHEM-7
results when I'm done.
She's a great psychiatrist.
One session, I've got shrinkage.
House wants us to
spy on you, report back.
And you're telling
me this because...
We don't want to do it.
I don't see a problem so far.
If our choice is between pissing
House off or pissing you off,
that's not much of a choice.
So unless I give House cable,
you're gonna make
my life miserable.
Yes.
And you're telling me this so you
won't feel as guilty when you do it.
Yes.
Accommodating House's every
whim is not my job anymore.
But it is ours.
House will get what he wants.
Maybe we should just pay for it
ourselves and tell him she folded.
No.
Your CHEM-7 results showed
your kidney function is declining.
Sounds like a
kidney stone to me.
The decreased function
could be from dehydration caused
by vomiting due to a gallstone.
You agreed that the CHEM-7
would decide if it was a struvite stone.
I agreed to do the test. The
results are up for interpretation.
I'll re-do the test in an
hour when I'm re-hydrated.
Have you noticed any improvement
since starting the cefuroxime?
Not really. Pain's
about the same.
While you're waiting,
we should run another test
with the geology equipment.
You're not taking
the cefuroxime.
She's right-handed.
Means she would put
the IV in her left arm.
Catheter in the arm makes
it hard to bend the elbow,
the way people
do when they drink.
We have a limited supply of
medication, and I am not about to waste it.
Last I checked you had a
limited supply of doctors.
Right before I got sick, one of my crew
members severed his femoral artery.
He needs the cefuroxime.
Right. He called dibs.
His need is definitive.
Mine is speculative.
You're breathing fast.
It's because I'm pissed off!
Lift up your chin.
Show me your windpipe.
My chest hurts.
It's deviating to the left.
Because her right
lung is collapsing.
Cate, is anyone there with you?
Sean went to the mess.
You need to call someone.
There's no time. Get
a syringe and a needle.
Why am I doing
that? Shut up and look.
She could pass
out. She needs to...
She needs to
re-inflate that lung.
Okay. Now, pull out the plunger.
I want you to stab
yourself in your right side
between the second and third
rib, in the midclavicular line.
By the time we get someone
else there, you'll have suffocated.
Just do it.
See all the good stuff that
happens when you listen to me?
Means it's not a kidney stone.
Right side pain, vomiting,
and now a lung that gets
traumatized without any trauma.
Sounds odd. Probably is odd.
We should discuss
this, then call her back.
No, it's fine. I made sure we got
the South Pole long distance plan.
Her latest kidney
function test shows...
I know what it shows. I ran it.
The more you interrupt, the longer
my grandstanding is going to take.
Since when do you let patients
participate in differentials?
Since the patient and her doctor
happen to be the same person.
Your kidney function is still declining.
Means you have a kidney problem.
But not one that needed
antibiotics. Makes us equally wrong.
No. Makes us both
wrong. Not equally.
You were at least six wronger.
They run a PPD
before you shipped out?
On me and everybody
else here. It's not TB.
Excuse us a second.
Cancer explains her symptoms.
A tumor in her lung or kidney
that threw a clot to the other organ.
And you're worried the tumor
might overhear, realize we're on to it.
Cancer's a hard diagnosis for patients,
even when they're not in the South Pole.
We should figure this
out, maybe bring Wilson in.
Obviously, you two
think I'm in bad shape.
Only if you count
the tumor. House.
Probably in your abdomen.
But you don't have any
advanced imaging equipment.
You also don't have
a surgeon to biopsy it,
any stains to use on the slide,
or an oncologist to analyze it.
I'm too far away
to hold her hand.
I have cancer?
Possibly.
Since the only imaging equipment
you have is x-ray, let's start there.
X-ray your entire body.
I'll upload the images
when I'm done.
Good for you.
She's annoying.
Refused to take the antibiotics
because other people might need them.
She said she cares
about other people?
What a poser.
KUB is clean.
You don't like her
because she's a psychiatrist.
Mmm, I'm a complicated man.
I loathe her for many reasons.
Never before has a
profession been so decried
by someone who
needed it so badly.
You talk a lot of smack
about tranny hookers.
Enlarged mediastinal node.
Lymphoma? Probably,
but we can't confirm
it without a biopsy.
We can't analyze a
biopsy without a stain.
We can't biopsy.
Since they don't have stains
down there, we need a substitute.
She can't biopsy that node
without a surgical team and an OR.
Anything with a strong
color could work as a stain.
Printer ink, food
coloring, coffee.
No, thanks.
I'll find a node closer to the
surface. One she can biopsy.
That makes sense.
That makes sense?
I said it first.
In a shockingly calm manner.
After I've just been jerking
you around for 30 seconds
without you complaining
or analyzing said jerking.
I was being mature.
In a lavender shirt.
You, for some reason, are happy.
How dare you.
The x-rays don't show
any other abnormal nodes.
Abnormal nodes can be felt
before they can be seen on an x-ray.
You're wearing that
shirt for someone.
The Health Department.
They frown on topless oncology.
You're gonna do a physical?
Have to. You and Foreman are
going to be here looking for a stain.
I can do the physical. There's
no reason you need to watch.
I can think of at
least three reasons.
One of them is medical.
Where are you?
Not in your office.
You're not in the hospital.
No reason for me to be.
I'm not undressing for
you in your apartment.
You're not in my apartment.
You're three quarters
of a world away.
I promise not to get fresh.
I'm not taking off my clothes.
One of us has to.
Show me your place.
It's got walls, a floor,
and in some places, a roof.
I am not exposing myself
without some reciprocity.
It's my apartment.
It's not my soul.
Living room.
Slow down.
Huh!
Lots of books. I'm
betting all medical.
Only if you count Jenna Jameson's
autobiography as a gynecological text.
Fiction is a waste of time.
Unless you can laugh at it?
I love to laugh. Moving on.
Back up.
How bad is the insomnia?
Let me quantify that.
Do you drink two or three scotches
before passing out in front of the TV?
You are so far off.
It's bourbon.
No photos anywhere.
Family and friends
aren't important?
Well, you're sick.
You have 20 people down the hall,
and you've had exactly one visitor.
I don't want to panic anyone.
You don't like people. You
hide on that ice cube, so...
Stop projecting. You're antisocial,
so you assume I'm antisocial?
How about if I just get
naked, and you shut up?
If I thought I could get you
naked, I would have led with that.
You'd rather show me
your soul than your leg.
Great. You got
me all figured out.
You going to try and fix me now?
I never said you needed fixing.
He's letting her take
part in the differentials.
Of course he is. He likes her.
Big shock. Spaghetti sauce
doesn't work as a lymph tissue stain.
I'll try the coffee.
He's annoyed by her,
doesn't respect her as a doctor,
constantly insults her.
That's House's
version of courtship.
Oh, God. He's been
wooing me for years.
She's the perfect woman for him.
Willing to literally go to the
end of the earth for her career,
making her unavailable
for a real relationship.
And she's afflicted
with a mysterious illness.
Soy sauce is a no-go.
We're gonna be here all night.
How long does it
take you to get naked?
It's the South Pole.
I wear a lot of layers.
Okay. Ready.
I saw socks.
That's not naked.
Have I mentioned
it's freezing here?
When they discover lymph nodes
in feet, I will take off my socks.
Use your right hand
to palpate the nodes.
Any node you can feel
is the one we can biopsy.
Let's start with your breasts,
move down to the ass, then...
I was thinking go from the
neck and work my way down.
We could,
but I'd never forgive myself if we found
something before we got to your breasts.
I'm starting with the
anterior cervical nodes.
Turn your head.
Locate the SCM muscle.
I know how to find
my lymph nodes.
Did they teach you that before or after
the class on fondling your inner child?
No swelling. No
tenderness. And...
I can hear that, House.
Just thought it
might help you relax.
Anything in the axillary nodes?
All clear.
Both sides.
Now slide your
hand to your sternum.
Probe for nodes
moving slowly downward.
Down to what, House?
Sorry. Can't hear you on
account of your heavy breathing.
I'm supposed to be
on oxygen, you tool.
Hold it.
Your fingers didn't go quite
as deep. Feel that node again.
It's swollen.
Looks like you're
doing a biopsy.
It's pretty numb.
Okay. Take a deep breath and
insert the needle into the node.
Come on, Cate.
Let's get this over with.
You used her name.
Just trying to move
things along, Bob.
Okay. I'm in.
You need to pull
back on the syringe.
You need to pull harder.
You okay?
Yeah.
"Are you okay?"
It's a valid medical question.
I have never heard you
ask a patient that question.
You've never asked
me that question,
and you've seen me fall
down a flight of stairs drunk.
You've slept with her.
She's 9,000 miles away.
And while a certain
part of me, unfurled...
No, I...
Somehow, you've
been intimate with her.
Why are you following me?
I thought you were following me.
No. You are
definitely following me.
Where are you
going? Out to lunch.
You never go out to lunch.
Which means there's a
reason you're going out to lunch.
I assume that reason
is a human being.
Or a sandwich.
Sandwiches can come here.
So can human beings.
And yet, she's not,
which I find interesting.
I'm leaving, now.
Small world.
Are you going to
follow me into my car?
It's got two doors.
Okay, look, the reason
I haven't told you is...
Call off your dogs, House.
Your little helpers are
interrogating my patients,
swiping my charts,
intercepting prescriptions.
Why would you think that I...
Because I'm not a moron.
You had to be pulling
the strings, here.
You think that because
they make me miserable,
I'm going to give you cable.
Let's assume that's true,
and it certainly
sounds like it might be.
What are you going
to do? Nothing.
I resigned from the
budget committee.
I only joined the committee to help
the hospital. You made me a liability.
I now have zero influence
over the hospital's cable policy.
Well done.
It didn't work. There's
nothing more that we can do...
Put these up.
"Free Rottweiler puppies.
"Please call after 11:00
p.m. and before 5:00 a.m."
Is this Cameron's home number?
I'd love a new puppy.
My last one was
delicious, very tender.
There's no point
in torturing her.
If she can resign, she can
un-resign. Go to DEFCON 1.
Forget waiting for a
mistake. Make her make one.
You want us to
sabotage another doctor,
possibly harm a patient,
all so you can have cable.
Harm suggests permanent damage.
Get her to screw up, then fix it.
Oh! And this time,
don't tell her what you're
gonna do before you do it.
So, how long do I let the lymph
node marinate in the red wine?
It should be ready, now.
Try increasing the
magnification on the camera.
You know, I emailed a couple of
colleagues at the hospital about you.
You're checking up
on me? Not House?
Yeah, well House is
straightforward, brilliant and an ass.
Two out of three good
qualities. Clear majority.
Whereas you, on the other
hand, have a perfect score.
You are responsible,
nice, human.
And yet, you're
House's best friend.
Hold there.
Makes you think he's
secretly nicer than he seems?
Makes me think that you're
secretly a lot less nice than you seem.
Do you always
insult your doctors?
It's not an insult. Indiscriminate
niceness is overrated.
No wonder he likes you.
Based on this slide
you do not have cancer.
Oh!
Thank God.
I do see some inflammation,
which could mean...
Cate?
You all right?
My left side. It hurts.
It's the same pain
that I had on the right.
Your other kidney.
No. I hope it's, it's
something, it's maybe...
I'm screwed.
The bad news is you're O for
two in the kidney department.
Is there good news?
You're back at home.
Of course. There's cable.
And freedom to work pant-free.
That is good news.
Wilson found signs of
inflammation in your biopsy.
That, plus the two failing kidneys,
points to autoimmune disease.
Probably SLE or vasculitis.
Treatment for both is prednisone.
Start with a hundred milligrams.
Autoimmune is just
your latest theory.
Like cancer before that,
and a kidney stone before.
Take the prednisone. You'll get
better. That will be your confirmation.
You practice medicine
like it's a fire sale.
You've wasted
antibiotics, x-rays...
That was not a waste.
We've ruled out...
We have a crew member
here who has asthma.
If he has an episode after I've
used up the prednisone, he'll die.
There's a good chance
he's going to die anyway.
Since there won't be a
doctor there to help him.
Show me proof
that it's autoimmune,
and then I'll take
the prednisone.
We should send her outside.
Right. Let's just tell her to head
north until she runs into a hospital.
Autoimmune diseases are
basically inflammation running wild.
Extreme cold has been used as treatment,
like putting ice on a sprained ankle.
She starts to feel better
outside, we know it's autoimmune.
Is that my wallet?
You can have it back.
I've already been through it.
I like your ice on
the sprain metaphor.
Makes it seem like
we're not killing her.
She'd only need to
be outside five minutes.
Without her mittens. Mom
told me that was a bad idea.
Especially that winter. It was 70
below, and I had dual kidney failure.
This is a good idea. It's perfect
for you. Experimental, risky.
Wilson's right.
You care about...
You didn't touch the cash,
but you took the receipts?
A hundred and ninety dollar restaurant
tab. That's dessert, probably booze.
It means you lingered.
Means it's at least
a third date. Means...
Where are you going?
To talk to the people I pay
to come up with medical ideas.
There are no ideas.
The test for autoimmune is ANA.
Unless penguins poop
immunoanalyzers...
Before ANA testing,
people had autoimmune diseases.
How did they know?
C3. Before that.
LE Prep. But she doesn't have
any controlled pore glass beads.
You don't need them.
When you shake the test tube,
the paperclip will damage
some of your blood cells.
If you have an
autoimmune disease,
your immune system will
gorge itself on the damaged cells.
They'll get big and fat so that you
can see them under a microscope.
How you doing?
No change.
So, how long should I give the
cells to fatten up before I check them?
A couple hours.
Or you could stop being a hypocrite
and take the prednisone now.
Not bending to your will
makes me a hypocrite?
If your psych patients demanded lab
results you'd never make a diagnosis.
So, I'm wrong.
You sleep like a baby. Your
life is unfolding as you dreamed.
Everyone is miserable.
You don't change that
because people don't change.
You want to believe that
because then you're freed from
any responsibility for your misery.
Oh, shut up.
I get enough of
this from Wilson.
And yet, you keep
hanging out with him.
And, from what I hear, you have spent more
time with me than with any other patient.
Sorry about that.
Call me when
you get the results.
How's your patient?
She has an autoimmune disease.
Tell the psych
department she's in denial.
I had to fire Cameron.
What? What happened?
A sixty-five-year-old man came
into the ER with a hip fracture.
Cameron gave him Demerol.
The guy was on an MAOI.
Put him into a
hypertensive crisis.
Is he going to live?
Taub caught the error in time.
If she'd just
admitted the mistake,
maybe I could have
just suspended her, but...
She's packing up. If
you want to say goodbye.
We should be hearing from
the South Pole in a few minutes.
That's it?
There's nothing to be done.
She screwed up. She's got
no one to blame but herself.
I've got to go talk to Cameron.
Cuddy wouldn't can
her for one screw-up.
And if she did, she
wouldn't come to me.
And if she did, she wouldn't
open with, "How's your patient?"
And if she did...
Why would she lie?
Timeless question.
In this case, she conspired
with your co-workers to teach me
that some things are
more important than cable.
I'm going to have to teach
them that they're wrong.
Come on. South Pole
really should be calling.
LE Prep test was negative.
It's not autoimmune.
You're basing that on a test done with
a paper clip. Just take the prednisone.
Either find another
diagnosis, or find another test.
There is one way.
You can take this experimental
drug called prednisone.
If your kidneys start working...
There is another test.
I think Foreman may
have just broken up, there.
What he actually said
was, "There is no other test."
If you have an
autoimmune disease,
exposure to the cold should
decrease your kidney pain.
If I go outside, we'll
have our answer?
And you knew about this?
I rejected it because
if you're frozen solid,
it's hard to get the
needles into your arms.
How long do I need to stay out?
At least five minutes.
Eight minutes outside
would kill a healthy person.
And healthy people don't
suck on oxygen masks.
Healthy people can pee.
I'll go get Sean, have
him come with me.
Just take the prednisone.
Once I come inside,
if it's autoimmune.
Are you all right?
Oh, I'm sure she's just fine.
Cate?
Do you know if there's anyone
down there who has a cell phone?
It took the station mechanic
20 minutes to respond.
She'd already
slipped into a coma.
Started her on prednisone,
but no improvement.
Means it's not autoimmune.
Good thing she's in a coma.
Or we'd have to
listen to her gloat.
And where are we going?
To find the useful
members of my team.
You're letting
them off the hook?
You happy? Because of you, I'm not gonna
be able to watch Law & Order in Korean.
Why am I here?
Because I want to ask
you about your girlfriend.
I must know who she is, or
you'd have told me her name.
She doesn't have a name.
It's some sort of birth defect.
There's only about 12
people we both know.
And I can't remember
five of their names,
so we're down to
Cuddy, your ex-wives.
Your mama.
You need to run a
kidney function test.
Yes. If only she wasn't in a
coma, we could get her to run a test
to find out why she's in a coma.
The results would
likely be paradoxical.
It can't be Cuddy, because
you're straight. It can't be...
We could talk the
mechanic through the test.
Too complicated.
Unless he's thirsty.
Drink her urine?
If it has a strong,
concentrated taste,
it means the problems
are in her kidneys.
Watery taste
means it's her brain.
And then you can fix it?
Let's say, yeah.
How do I get the
urine out of her?
Take a straight
catheter and insert it...
Those are your only questions?
Not, "Is it safe?"
Or, "Is there another way?"
Or, "Are you out of your minds?"
You wouldn't ask me if...
Wait a second.
You're in love with her.
That explains why you're so eager
to get her naked, then have a drink.
Because most guys like
to go the other way around.
Why do you care
how I feel about her?
Because now I know that I can
get you to do anything to save her.
Tell him how to tap the keg.
You got Cameron fired.
Cuddy wasn't
supposed to find out.
No kidding!
Get me cable. How tough can
that be? You cost a woman her job.
There's only one thing you can
say to keep me from firing you.
Cameron wasn't fired. We...
Wrong.
You know? We're still fired?
That should be a hint as to
what you're supposed to say.
We're sorry. Wrong.
I love you.
Wrong.
This is a game? First, we have
to screw with our co-worker,
now we have to try to figure
out what you want us to say?
This is insane. I'm not playing.
Right.
You should have
said this two days ago.
Do not play games with me.
Number one, you are going
to lose. You're just not ready.
Number two, the game was to
force you to stop playing games.
I need you to stand up
to me. Challenge me.
I need you to stop
worrying about getting fired.
And go pay for my cable.
No!
I didn't mean on this.
Seriously. I need cable.
Milk, milk, lemonade.
It tastes kind of watery.
That's bad news.
Either increased
intracranial pressure
or something's wrong
with her hypothalamus.
How do you figure
out which one it is?
We don't do anything.
You're gonna drill
a hole in her skull.
If she regains consciousness,
it's increased intracranial pressure.
And if it's the other thing?
She'll die.
But if it's the hypothalamus,
she's dead, anyway.
If the problem is the pressure
in her brain, and I fix it,
is she going to be all better?
No, but it'll give us more
time to figure out what's wrong.
I have to get someone
else. I can't do this.
You love her.
You'd do anything to save her.
Not this.
I can't do this.
If she dies because of
something that I did, then I...
Listen. Listen.
I am not going to let
you hurt her. Okay?
Now, please. This
is her only chance.
Okay.
That was easy.
Okay. Her head is stabilized,
and the drill bit is sterile.
Place the drill bit against the
upper left part of her forehead,
about an inch above the temple.
It's not going anywhere.
Bone's harder than
wood. Lean into it.
The skull is only a
quarter inch thick.
Once you're midway
through, drill in shorter bursts.
If you come out the other
side, you've gone too far.
Okay. Now, what? Now, what?
Let the fluid drain.
She's waking up.
Sean?
What's going on?
South Pole doc
is out of her coma,
and now we have a new symptom.
Increased intracranial pressure.
Why are we out here?
That's the patient room.
ICP plus kidney problems
plus lung collapse equals...
The most likely suspect is
a tumor throwing off clots.
We ruled out cancer.
But not clots.
What causes blood clots?
Bacterial endocarditis.
Not without a fever.
Deep vein thrombosis
plus an existing PFO.
PFO would have been discovered
on her pre-South Pole physical exam.
What if the clots aren't clots?
Atherosclerosis. Fatty plaque
builds up on the arterial walls.
Pieces break off, block blood
flow. Explains everything.
She has zero risk factors.
Forget fat. Think clots.
No.
You're standing up to me?
Maybe.
Just to clarify, you should
do that when you're right.
Sorry for the confusion.
How could a clot... Could
be a different kind of fat.
Fat emboli.
It's a perfect fit. Except
it's completely impossible.
Fat emboli requires an
un-repaired bone breakage.
Between the x-ray and the
exam, I've seen her entire...
See, that's what
I'm talking about.
Take off her socks.
I can... I can do it.
No. I got it.
Your toe is broken.
Oh, my God.
Bits of bone marrow have been
leaking into your bloodstream.
Those fat emboli have caused
blockages in your kidney, lungs, and brain.
It doesn't even hurt.
Cold numbs everything.
Does a particularly great
job on the extremities.
You'll need to close the break
to stop the marrow from leaking.
This one you will feel.
Will you do it?
He drilled a hole
in your skull after
drinking your pee. I
think he's up for this.
Grab the tip of her toe
with your right hand.
Hold the break with the other.
On the count of
three, pull hard.
One, two,
three.
Splint your toe. You'll be fine.
Thank you, House.
Don't thank me. He's the
one who saved your life.
He likes her.
A bottle of the Bordeaux
and some sparkling water.
Well, you didn't pick her up, which
means she's coming from work, too,
which means you're
comfortable enough to meet her.
Damn. I thought I lost you
when I walked backwards
through my own
footprints in the snow.
I think I've got it narrowed
down to three possibilities.
Better leave. If you
see her, it'll be cheating.
It's not one of your ex-wives.
Because they hate me.
They don't. They should,
but they don't. I called them.
It's someone new,
but someone I know.
Did you ever consider
being happy for me?
Briefly.
You ordering the wine
before she got here...
Girls are good,
House, and you know it.
You solved your case because
you cared about that girl.
You're demonstrating the
illusion of manly confidence,
which means you haven't
closed the deal, yet.
I closed the deal.
I just like her.
Still?
You knew your patient
hated having cold feet,
because you did a physical
exam, because you liked her.
Your theory is I cared, therefore
I let her keep her socks on.
If that's what love is, then I don't
wanna have anything to do with it.
It starts with warm feet,
but leads to other things.
Your mom and I will
explain when you're older.
If I'd made her take them off like I
should have, I'd have seen the toe
and solved the case days ago.
But you don't care about her.
Of course not. House
doesn't care about anyone.
Hi.
Sorry I'm late.
Cutthroat Bitch?
I call her Amber.
Was she on your list?