The body is an infinitely complex
mass of interacting systems.
People like to think
doctors see it all clearly.
But it's not always obvious
what's a hiccup in the system,
and what's a full-on
medical disaster.
We figure that out in
our first year of residency.
Hey, you sleep okay?
Great.
We spend the rest of
our careers lying about it.
I probably can't write
about this in the article,
but something about how
my toothpaste hit the sink
made me realize
that the array could be
designed asymmetrically.
Makes it more
versatile. Exactly.
So what you're saying is
that you can't spit
without having a
genius idea. Oh.
Well, it may not work.
Zola, are your socks on?
It was a revolutionary
glob of spit.
So if you need anything,
just call me and...
No, I don't need anything.
I just need to read everything
that was ever written
on the mediastinal teratomas
and crank out a grant proposal.
All I need is quiet.
Well, I can't promise
you too much quiet
because you did say
that I could come visit.
I did say that. Yeah.
Oh, that's the
best part of my day.
Mmm-hmm.
Hey, welcome back.
Hey, thanks. Beats the
hell out of a courtroom.
She brought muffins.
It's her day off. She's
doing homework.
In a hospital?
Yeah. God.
Get some air. See
the world, right?
I think it's sweet.
It's adorable.
Dr. Webber's bugging
me for another stress test.
Oh, he failed the last
one two minutes in.
I know, but he's
been practicing.
As soon as I get a minute
I'll go check on him again.
Hi.
You're on my service again?
I'm sorry.
As soon as I change, I wanna go
through the computer model again
before we start
printing the vein.
I'm sorry. Before you do that,
you're gonna have to go
check on your pancreas lady,
Donna Kaufman.
Not good.
We were hoping we
could remove the tumor,
but it's advanced further
than we initially thought.
The best course of action would
be to relieve your obstruction
and block the
nerves in the area.
That should help with the pain.
You're not even gonna try?
Victor.
I'm sorry.
I wish there was
more that we could do.
Dealing with the pain is
a lot better than nothing.
Let's do that.
Okay. Okay.
Sooner is better.
We've been treating him with
diuretics and beta blockers,
but he's still got
a lot of edema.
He'll rally once
we put in the graft.
Then we can get him out of here.
Poor kid's been here
for almost three weeks.
You done with
all the test prints?
Yeah, we finished
them last night.
Shane's printing
out the real one now.
Emma's here. With muffins. Mmm.
Owen's chick?
You wanna get rid of her?
No.
I'm glad he's getting laid.
Everyone should be getting laid.
I should be getting laid.
Oh, here we go again.
My work suffers when I'm
not. It's bad for humanity.
All right, can you
make up with Mer
so I don't have to
talk to you about sex?
Why are you being such a priss?
Don't you talk to your
guy friends about sex?
Who? Avery? No.
You don't talk about who's
got the best rack in the shack?
Maybe.
So you can do it
with me. Okay, fine.
Your work's suffering so bad,
then find something to play with.
Get your yayas out
and leave me alone.
What, like, battery-operated?
No. Human.
A human sex toy?
You asked.
How long you been there?
Somewhere around "yayas."
That's great.
We have a problem.
Our conduit's contaminated.
How the hell did that happen?
I don't know.
I can print another one
and try vacuum seeding,
but it'll take longer.
We won't be able to
do the procedure today.
I don't know if this kid can
hang on for one more day.
We gotta try, right?
It's still his best shot.
I'll talk to Karev.
Dr. Grey's supposed to have
the printer by 10:00 am today.
We made the schedule
and made a big stink
about how she
had to stick to it.
Edwards! Hey!
Uh, can you write down
your mailing address for me?
Sure.
I'm sending you an
invitation to my wedding.
Thought about doing them online.
It's better for the environment,
I know, but I just couldn't deal
with an e-vite to my wedding.
Great. I really
hope you'll come.
And, um, obviously, you
can also, like, bring a guest.
His BP's in the toilet.
If this procedure's not ready, you
gotta come up with something else.
It's one day. Can you relax?
God, maybe you're
the one who needs
a little recreational
energy release.
I'm getting laid. Regularly.
So all my anxiety
is based on the fact
that you brought me on this case
and asked me to keep a kid
alive long enough for you to do
a fancy procedure
that's not gonna work.
All right, maybe it's nothing.
But maybe it's worth
having a conversation
with somebody in psych.
Oh, you're making
a mountain out of...
Look, it can't hurt.
Look, hell, I'd like to have
a sit-down with somebody
and talk a couple things
out every now and then.
Well, then you go. I
have a busy schedule.
Navel gazing is not on it.
That's my point.
Overloading your
schedule can exacerbate
the kind of behaviors
you've been...
I'm not having behaviors.
I'm having a life.
Like you used to have
when you were pursuing
something that challenged you.
Bailey, you have
time for an ex-lap?
I got a burn patient
with a surgical abdomen.
Absolutely. JACKSON: Trauma two.
What do we got?
Ella Holmes, six, hit by a car.
Tachycardic and hypotensive.
She was on a scooter.
She knows she's not
supposed to ride it down the hill.
I don't know what happened.
Show me the ultrasound.
Is she gonna be okay?
Are you her mom?
They're out of town.
Intraperitoneal free fluid.
Call CT and book
an OR just in case.
Dr. Robbins?
She's got a supracondylar
femur fracture.
Okay, call Torres.
Is that gonna be okay?
Yeah, we're on the mend.
I'm glad to hear it.
Murphy, Go with
Torres and Robbins.
It's not a good idea.
It'll be fine. I don't think...
Murphy!
- Pressure's dropping!
- What is that?
I can't wait for a CT.
Prep her for the OR.
I have to call her parents.
What am I supposed to tell them?
I'll update you as
soon as we know.
All right, let's move,
people. Let's go.
But is everything
going to be okay?
It's all going to be fine.
Okay, can you
pull that lap pad out
and see if there's any bleeding?
Slowly.
I don't see anything. Good.
Dr. Torres is gonna
fix the femur? Yeah.
But she'll need some help
so you should stick around.
Well, you'll help her, right?
I mean, you don't think
she needs two people.
You're a resident.
You're supposed to
beg to be in that room.
I'm sorry if it's awkward. I
hope that it doesn't have to be.
You two are definitely
getting back together?
We are.
Like you're trying
it out or like...
Leah.
You don't wanna be
the person who says,
"I'll wait for you in case it
doesn't work out with your wife."
So you're trying to
find a woman for him
to be with once you've passed.
I know it sounds strange.
But I don't want
him to be alone.
And if he's on his own,
I don't think he'll do it.
It's certainly unusual.
But I understand.
You love your husband.
It's not my husband.
I mean, I love my husband.
But this is for
someone else. Stan.
He's a very special friend.
Donna, I'm gonna need
to get at that left arm.
Yeah, it's a lot more versatile.
Well, it's an
improvement, no question.
Maybe if you have
time over lunch,
you can look over the proposal.
I wish I could. I've got
back-to-back surgeries.
How's it feel to be back
in the anesthesia game?
It's fine.
Not ideal, but, you
know, got a family.
You make compromises.
Yeah, Meredith is gonna kill me.
What, she doesn't like
an symmetrical array?
I'm supposed to be downshifting,
and she's supposed
to be upshifting.
Ah. And yet you find
inspiration in toothpaste.
Maybe next time,
you keep it to yourself.
That works for you?
In a marriage? Yes.
You keep your mouth shut.
Although, uh, Miranda's
been kind of struggling lately.
She has what, uh, if
you squint real hard
looks a lot like OCD.
Bailey? Yeah.
She had that incident
with the hole in the gloves.
I knew it freaked her
out, but I was away.
I didn't know how
much it freaked her out.
You really think it's OCD?
I don't know.
I wanted to let her
deal with it her way,
but I'm not sure
she's dealing with it.
We were in the OR the other day,
and she kept the patient
under easily an extra hour.
Ben...
She went past
that. I'm not sure...
No, I know, I know. I
should stay out of it.
But when I'm watching
a surgeon perform
what looks like
unnecessary procedures...
I am on the board
of this hospital.
I can't hear about
a physician's misconduct
and not report it.
I think you telling Dr. Grey
is gonna go over better than...
No, I don't have time to
manage her feelings right now.
Just apologize, we feel
terrible, it won't happen again.
She'll be pissy,
but she'll get over it.
I could have Edwards tell
her. She's on her service.
Even better.
If you ever need
any yaya extraction...
Getting the yayas out...
I'm available.
Are you offering to service me?
Sorry. It was inappropriate.
It's just, you know, for
the sake of the work.
That's even worse.
You're supposed to claim
that you're in love
with me or something.
Well, I certainly find you
attractive. There's no question.
I mean, I wouldn't be so
presumptuous as to assume it's...
Stop talking.
Good.
Hey, are those left over
from the morning meeting?
Uh-huh. She baked them.
You're kidding.
I kind of hate you. Mmm.
Yeah, I kinda hate me, too. Mmm.
Hmm. If she's cooking
your Thanksgiving dinner,
I want the leftovers.
Oh, I'm not... Oh, we're not...
Well, I mean, we could.
No, you don't have to say that.
I hadn't given it
much thought so...
Sorry, I didn't mean to
open a can of worms. I just...
I mean, you could do
what we do at my house,
which is act like it's
not even happening.
So, you're not going
home to your family, or...
I'm on call the next day.
Oh. Well, we could do something.
Oh, they're painting
my apartment next week.
And we can't really
cook in the trailer.
Why not? We could
just eat outdoors, and...
In November? Yeah.
You could cook at my house.
You'd have to feed us, too, but...
That could be fun.
I don't wanna
commandeer your kitchen.
Oh, please. Someone should.
They made those construction
paper turkeys at Zola's school,
and she had no idea what
they were talking about.
You'd make me look
like a better mother.
Think about it.
Pancreatic tumor. Gotta go.
Mmm-hmm.
Thanks. Welcome.
Do you have Donna's pre-op labs?
In process.
I'm gonna go examine Dr. Webber.
And when I get back, we're
gonna get started on the printer.
Is that okay with you?
Yeah.
Pfft, what was that about?
I got her kicked off her
own surgery a few days ago.
Alex told me. Ballsy.
Stupid.
Did Kepner invite
you to her wedding?
No.
So she didn't ask
you for your address?
No, but I'm sure Alex is
invited. I'm probably the plus one.
Hey, Dr. Yang needs
the printer again today.
Uh, no.
One day. Tell Grey we're sorry.
No, you tell her. Can't.
Gotta get the printer going
so we only take one day
away from you, not two.
Shane... Dying baby
waiting on a part.
No...
Get back here!
I'm a waste of a bed.
Your stress test was a disaster.
You want me to dwell
on all your past failures?
I'm a different man
than I was last week.
I exercise.
I don't know why you don't think
about going into a rehab facility.
We can get you in there
even if you don't pass.
Look, I don't want
to go to a facility.
It's bad enough I'm here.
Where everyone knows
me. And has to be nice.
Well, you can't go home alone.
I'll get a home health aide.
I'll have Wilson run
another stress test.
You watch. Flying colors.
If you get out of here in time,
you can have Thanksgiving
dinner at our house
if you and Catherine
don't have plans.
You cookin'?
Is that so preposterous?
You want a straight answer?
No, Owen's
girlfriend is cooking.
Does she put
mushrooms in her stuffing?
I find it makes it soggy.
Hey.
Hey. You done already?
No, she was too edematous.
We packed her and put
in a temporary closure.
You can do her femur
tomorrow after we close.
Okay.
I wanna talk to you
about something. Hmm?
I was with someone
when we were apart.
I don't think that it was
completely out-of-bounds.
We were separated, and you'd
kicked me out of the house.
Oh, so it's my fault?
There are no faults. I just
feel like you should know.
We're starting fresh,
and I wanna be honest with you.
I shouldn't have said anything.
No, no.
I'm sorry. You're right.
Thank you
for being so very honest.
I'm trying.
Is there anything that
you wanna ask me?
Oh, wow. Um...
No.
I don't know.
Was it once?
It was more than once.
More than twice?
More than 10?
You know what? I don't
wanna know anything about it.
I'm sorry.
Is it over?
Yes. Completely.
Okay. That's all I need to know.
You didn't? What?
Cheat on you?
Get involved with anyone?
I got involved with myself.
I danced in my underwear,
and I tried to remember that I
used to be a person who had fun.
I'm really trying.
Callie, please.
Tell me that you're trying, too.
I am.
Can I hug you?
Yeah.
I really missed you.
Me, too.
Sorry.
Uh... Ella's thigh is really
swollen. She's hypotensive.
All right, we gotta
get her back in the OR
and do the femur right now.
Um... Are you gonna help me?
Sure.
Will you give the
family an update?
They're on a plane.
It's just the babysitter.
Dr. Grey.
I have to stop in post-ops.
Tell Wilson to run a
stress test on Dr. Webber...
They need the
printer today. Dr. Yang.
What? No. Sorry.
They said it's not up for
discussion. They're already running it.
I mean, I tried to talk to Ross,
but he said Dr. Yang isn't
even interested in having...
Nurses' station.
We need to talk.
We really don't. No, we do.
I have to wrap up a patient
in the ER. Back here in 15?
Yes. Great. Okay.
Dr. Hunt? Mmm-hmm?
Hey, so I invited
Dr. Webber to Thanksgiving,
so now it really has to happen.
His lady is cooking
Thanksgiving dinner at our house.
Oh, that's nice.
Should we invite more people?
Well, uh, if we're making a whole
turkey, we can invite a few more.
Okay, let's get
Dr. Yang here, please.
You and Bailey can come.
We're going to my family.
Assuming she's still
speaking to me by then.
Hmm. We should
probably invite Callie.
I'm sure with the trial, I'm
sure she didn't have time...
So we're not inviting
Arizona. We can't have both.
They're back together,
so... They are?
Hey, can you go do your thing
so we can get to our thing? Yes.
So we're not inviting Yang,
right? Because that wouldn't be...
Uh, she probably has plans.
No, she probably doesn't. - Oh.
Do you have Thanksgiving plans?
What do you think?
My house. 3:00.
All right, I'm
bringing Jo. I figured.
Don't sound so excited.
You were an intern
balling an attending once.
Mmm-hmm.
You kiss my kids
with that mouth?
I got a pre-op. It'll be fast.
But do not start with
Hunt until I get back.
I won't. WOMAN: Thank you.
You don't wanna know.
I called Dr. Yang. She's
not available right now.
Does she know it's me
who's asking for her?
Yes.
You okay?
Sure.
I'm going to update
a patient's babysitter
instead of doing surgery.
Because Torres and
Robbins don't need me.
They have each other.
Are the two of you...
They're getting back together.
Were you really
into her or was it...
I was really into her.
Why do I do this?
I can't keep falling apart at
work every time I get dumped.
It's starting to
be all the time.
So get off the floor.
Go talk to your
babysitter and get back
in the OR, like a
surgeon would do.
Hey.
Oh, my vascular graft...
Yeah, the one you printed? I
was gonna come and see it.
It had a glitch, so it'll
be tomorrow, hopefully.
Not today. Okay.
Hey, you have
Thanksgiving plans?
Well, I'll probably pick up
an extra shift. You know?
I don't get all that worked
up about cranberries.
You?
Um...
Well, uh, it's evolving.
You can tell me you're
spending it with Emma.
I won't melt if I hear her name.
Yes. I'll be with Emma.
She gonna cook? Mmm-hmm.
Hmm. Well, watch out.
You let her make a turkey
for just the two of you,
you're gonna be eating
leftovers for the rest of your life.
Her femur was bleeding
very heavily into her thigh,
and she was in danger
of losing too much blood.
Oh, my God.
They've taken her
back into the OR,
and they're working
on her right now.
You told me it was
just a broken leg.
A femur break
can be complicated,
but we're gonna take care of it.
Oh, my God, they
are gonna kill me.
I'm sure that they won't.
I really liked them,
too. They work together.
They're in Alaska, studying
the nesting habits of eagles.
I cannot believe I'm
gonna lose this job.
They're not gonna fire you. They'll
understand it wasn't your fault.
Something terrible happened.
You have to blame somebody.
What, are they gonna
blame their child?
They're probably never
gonna let me see her again.
I guess it's my fault
for getting so attached.
Hey.
Can I boot you out
of your OR at 4:00?
Uh, the mastoidectomy
after this? Yeah.
I need to put a gastro-j
on the schedule,
and if I tell Grey she can't
get into the OR until 7:00,
she's gonna shove
her hand into my chest
and rip out my
heart with her claws.
That means I have to work late.
You'll be working late anyhow,
because you're so committed
to the welfare of this hospital.
And to the people who
count on you for support.
All right. All
right, I will take it.
Thank you. Mmm-hmm.
And Kepner invited
me to her wedding.
Did she? Plus one.
And you're gonna
be invited, plus one.
Is she expecting us
to bring other people?
No, brides are weird. Go think
about something else. Please?
Okay.
Is he gonna make it?
Well, if Yang can
get her act together.
I keep diuresing him,
but that's not gonna work
for much longer. Mmm.
Hey, you're invited to
Mer's for Thanksgiving.
Really?
I'm invited and,
uh, I'm bringing you.
The attendings are
gonna be weird if I'm there.
No, they're not.
Just go without me.
We'll meet up after.
You think I wanna
be there if you're not?
You're sweet.
Okay, screw it.
How about we get takeout
chicken and eat it in the car
like we were raised to do?
I think I love you.
Yeah, yeah, settle down.
Two more women
responded to the ad.
One of them's gonna come
by in about half an hour.
Did she seem nice?
Yeah.
I told Stan.
What? Why?
I couldn't let it go, and he...
Oh! He'll hate this.
It was supposed to seem natural,
like someone you'd
met at the pool.
I can't lie to him.
We've always been honest.
That's how it's worked.
This isn't some big lie.
It's a kindness. You agreed.
Well, that was before...
Before I was dying?
It matters more now, not less.
So you're saying she performed
unnecessary procedures?
I'm not saying anything.
I was shooting the
breeze with a friend,
I wasn't making a
report to the board.
I'm sorry.
Whatever. Let's
just reel it back in.
You know he can't do
that, and I certainly can't.
But she's gonna handle it.
That is not what you said.
You said you saw the Virgin
Mary in your toothpaste.
We were talking.
I need to pull
her off the floor,
at least until this
is under control.
She was gonna go...
I'm sorry.
Can you let me talk to her?
Yeah.
She seems nice, right?
Oh, the woman? Yeah.
Oh, I don't know.
Okay, I tried to check
her out, but I just...
There wasn't a good enough
reason for me to stay in the room.
It is strange.
There's no question.
My wife and I looking
for a female companion
for her lover.
Yeah, it's a first for me.
Eh, you're young.
Donna and I had a wonderful
marriage for 30 years.
And then the fire went away.
And we both found other people.
But she was still
my best friend.
We somehow both hated the
idea of divorcing each other.
So now you're helping
her pick somebody for...
Stan. Stan.
He's never been in
love like this before.
She's afraid he's
gonna be alone forever.
He's a wonderful person.
We played golf
together for years.
I don't want to see
him alone, either.
You told the chief of surgery
that I have a psychiatric condition?
It was an accident.
Derek and I were talking...
Where the hell do you get...
All we're talking
about is a few days.
Take a break! Figure
out how to manage this.
Stay out of my...
Bench yourself.
Or the chief will.
Miranda...
You send your lackey
to tell my lackey?
You can't tell me to my face
you're destroying my study?
You know I'm not
destroying your study...
If I don't finish this phase
by the end of this week,
I lose my funding.
Come with me.
Please.
That's Nathan. He's a real baby.
We're not talking about
me. We're talking about him.
That's Ashley, his mom.
He has a very nice father.
This isn't a study,
Meredith. This is a baby.
Nathan is the first
one in his family
who's supposed to go to college.
I mean, he's a baby.
Have you lost your mind?
Do you think that
because I have kids,
every time I see a child,
I'm gonna start lactating
and lose my ability to reason?
No.
You wanted to do something
flashy with the equipment.
It didn't work.
Now you want me to
shut down my entire study,
so that you can run a Hail Mary
that very well might
kill this very cute child.
Baby Nathan and all
of his college potential,
can get an artificial graft...
No.
Like every other HLHS baby.
No, he can't.
Because you can't make it work.
How many people?
We might be up to 16.
But some of them are
kids, and they barely eat.
I thought this was
dinner for four.
I know. I'm sorry. It just
kinda got out of hand.
We can all just cook together.
I thought Meredith doesn't
know how to turn on an oven.
Well, the rest of us.
I'll do all the shopping.
I'll do all the planning.
I will do everything, and you
just get to shout out orders.
Okay, it's starting
to sound better.
Okay. Good.
So maybe I should quit
while I'm ahead but, um...
What?
Cristina isn't...
She doesn't have
Thanksgiving plans.
I mean, just as
a friend, I, uh...
I shouldn't have said
anything. Just forget it.
No, Owen. It's okay.
If you say you're
over her, I believe you.
And really, it's up to
Meredith and Derek
'cause it's their house.
Are you sure?
I want you to be comfortable.
Well, I'm gonna be
cooking for what could be,
at the end of the
day, 30 people,
so I won't have time
to be uncomfortable.
Okay.
I'm gonna speak to
her about the stuffing.
You think she could
handle a deep-fried turkey?
I mean, there's nothing like it.
Don't people kill themselves
trying to make those?
Everything has a price.
You guys, my patient
has a husband and a lover.
And she and the husband
are interviewing women
for the lover to date
when she's dead.
When the patient's dead?
It's weird.
Is that like a threesome thing?
Dr. Webber...
I'm just asking a question.
You hiding from Grey again?
On your way, Edwards.
I need you to take over
Bailey's surgical load today.
I can't. My study
is falling apart,
and I have a palliative
surgery later today.
Meredith.
You ever done an
ex-fix before, Murphy?
No.
Hmm. Try it.
Yeah. Right there.
Now, the first cortex is hard.
Then it'll feel
spongy in the middle,
and then hard again when
you hit the second cortex, okay?
That's it. Really push through.
Uh, okay. It feels spongy.
Okay, ease up a bit now.
Now the pitch'll change
when you hit the cortex, okay?
Can you hear it?
Oh, my God.
Okay, you drilled right
through her leg into the table.
Oh, my God! No,
it's... Back it up.
Just put the drill in reverse.
I can't... Put the
drill in reverse!
I can't find the...
Can you just take it?
My hand is shaking.
Okay, all right. Pull it
together... Can you please just...
Murphy, pull it together.
Oh! Please! Murphy!
Can you please do something?
Callie, can you
take it yourself?
Just give her a few
minutes to calm down.
Well...
It was her?
Ten-plus times! That was her?
That is just perfect.
Why would you tell her?
I didn't.
I told her it was
someone. I didn't say who.
I mean, listen,
she figured it out
because you fell apart in there.
You could've just
forgotten about it
and gone on with
your happy life.
This is my marriage
we're talking about.
Yeah, and it's my career!
She hates me now.
No, she doesn't.
Oh, please. Of course she does.
She can't blame
you. She loves you.
The only one she
can blame is me.
Hey.
So you realize that Stephanie
and I are serious, right?
You get that?
Yeah, yeah. Uh-huh. Great.
I think it's nice
that you guys are...
Whatever you are.
Right.
So why is it that you invited
her to your wedding, plus a guest,
and you're gonna
invite me, plus a guest?
What's going on?
Right, yeah. Um, I wanted
to talk to you about that.
You are actually not
getting an invitation,
but Stephanie is, so you
could just be her plus one.
Mmm-hmm.
Look, I put your
name on the invite list.
Your name is Avery. We
don't know any other A's.
You're literally
the top of the list,
first thing we see
when we look at it.
I didn't wanna rub
it in Matthew's face.
If he has a problem with
my name on a piece of paper,
why should I be at this wedding?
Because of me.
Because you're my friend
and I want you to be there.
Yeah.
Yeah, well, I wanna
be there, too, but...
Come on.
Jackson, I can't go through with
this if I don't have your blessing.
Well, you have it. All right?
But I don't think
I should be there.
Dr. Grey was pulled into
an emergency surgery.
So we are gonna have to push Mrs.
Kaufman's procedure to tomorrow.
I... What is she doing?
I apologize. I'll be over here.
You don't have to actually
date the woman she chooses.
I don't wanna date any woman.
That's why she's
doing this, Stan.
I thought you were
gonna talk her out of it.
You need to tell her yourself.
You're both putting me in the middle.
Because she listens to you.
She doesn't listen to anyone.
Besides, this is not
such a terrible idea.
I'm not a child she has
to arrange daycare for.
What, a bunch of women
she scared up on the internet?
It's awful.
It's taking her mind off
what's actually happening.
That can't be the
worst thing in the world.
She thinks she can find
someone to replace her?
You can't replace her.
Nobody can possibly replace her.
Why?
Why is this happening?
He's desatted to 60.
If we're gonna do this
thing, we gotta do it now.
I can't. I don't have a
conduit to put in him.
It won't be done for
another six hours.
I don't know if he's
gonna last that long.
Okay.
Okay, let's put
him on an oscillator.
It will stabilize his
sats for easily a day.
I don't wanna wait
a day, Cristina.
No, neither do I, Alex.
But in the long run,
it's still his best chance.
Good.
Well, thanks to you, my
resident offered to service me.
What?
To drive me around the
block before my battery dies.
Ah. You gonna do it?
Shane? No. It'll be like
having sex with a baby seal.
Sats are better.
Good.
Why don't you talk to Meredith?
Explain that everything
is gonna be fine.
Maybe she'll cut me some slack.
She's got a point.
Which is what?
You could put in
an artificial graft.
We tried. He rejected it.
So try again.
Pump him full of meds.
Hold him over for a couple years
until your brand-new
procedure's old news,
tested hundreds of times.
That's what I'd do.
You wanna fight a different
battle, that's your own problem.
You're right, Alex.
This is my problem.
Your heart rate's pretty high.
Keep going. I'm fine.
This is when we're
supposed to take it up a notch.
But I'm not sure...
Wilson, I'm gonna hurt you.
Dr. Webber, I
don't think that we...
No!
Take it up again!
Wilson!
Oh, my God!
I need some help
here! Dr. Shepherd!
What happened?
Dr. Bailey, could we
speak for a moment?
Uh, I'm about to
get started here.
Why don't I track you
down when I'm done?
This is a conversation
we should have now.
Dr. Grey can take over.
Dr. Bailey...
I will speak to you
when I am finished here.
Do you mind?
Dr. Grey,
please move Dr. Bailey's bovie
one inch to the left.
Oh, don't touch...
Grey.
And move the
suction one inch down.
Get away from my...
Maybe even four...
Get away from my table!
Bruising over the chest wall.
I need a portable ultrasound.
I don't need an
ultrasound. My rib's broken.
His pulse ox is low.
What the hell happened?
Please, don't.
He fell off the
treadmill. What...
You're jogging now? Oh!
Yeah. Rib's broken.
Stress test. He
wanted out of here.
All right, can we get a
portable X-ray in here?
I'm Dr. Robbins. I'm so sorry.
How you doing?
I should probably go.
I mean, I'm the last person
they wanna see right now.
I'm sure they're glad
to have you here.
It's stupid, right?
I mean, she's not even my kid.
Maybe I could, uh, hang
out a little, you know?
See if they need anything?
I can wait with you.
This is what the fracture
looked like initially.
And this is how...
What happened with Bailey? I
heard she got kicked out of her OR.
I can't get into that with you.
Come on.
Oh, we don't have to
go to Kepner's wedding.
I talked to her. We don't
have to worry about any of that.
Why?
It's just simpler.
You know, um...
My patient and her husband
are interviewing women
to date her lover when she dies.
They're all friends,
and they're supporting each
other through this horrible time.
And when Stan
cries, Victor hugs him.
That's what it looks like when
people are over each other.
You think I should
be hugging Matthew?
Why aren't we
going to the wedding?
Because my name starts with "A".
Because April is neurotic.
Because Matthew
and I do not hug,
and no, it's not
gonna be comfortable.
It's awkward, frankly. It's
probably gonna be awkward forever.
But that does not mean
that it is not over between us
because it is.
It's important to me
that you believe that.
'Cause if you don't, I
could really ruin our night.
I have some really nice
ideas about our night.
Okay, you've had a day. Day's
over. I need you to clear out.
We need some more time.
You have had more time!
I need to get started printing
my portal vein by tonight or...
We're having trouble
with the vacuum seeding.
And we need to print
out another conduit.
Again? Yes.
We started a new one, and
it should be done by 3:00 am.
I mean, Cristina,
no. It's not working.
You are not Christ
child reincarnate.
You don't walk on water.
You have failed to
revolutionize modern medicine
and save a baby
all in one fell swoop.
And you are endangering
a child's life while you...
Stop!
Excuse me...
That's enough.
Ross, take a walk.
She wasn't gonna do
this. Because of you.
I practically had
to force her into it.
Ross, just...
Because she cares about you.
Oh, somebody's got
the hero worship down!
No, you've made this emotional.
You made it about
your friendship.
If it was about the work,
you would've gone
to the chief of surgery,
but you know what
he would've said.
You'll get the printer
tomorrow, Dr. Grey.
I'm sorry if that
was out of line.
I just couldn't listen to
her go after you like that.
Hey, you just about ready?
I was gonna check on
our patient before I left,
but maybe you should make
sure Leah's not near the room.
I don't wanna make her
cry. She's not gonna...
Look, I think that the next time
you exercise your
right to play around
when we're taking a break,
I'm gonna ask you to
keep it out of the hospital.
Not that it isn't fun, all
the drama in the OR...
I realize that you're hurt,
but when we got back together,
we got back together
based on the assumption
that we both made mistakes
and we were ready to start fresh.
I can't keep apologizing. And
you can't keep playing a victim.
If you want me back, I'm back,
but I'm not here to
be your whipping boy.
I've been sleeping on
the couch for a week.
If I'm back, I sleep in the bed.
Uh, okay. I get a night
to just digest this all.
And then fine, you
can sleep in the bed.
That's enthusiastic.
Arizona...
Fine.
If you spent half
the time working
that you do having
girl talk with Shepherd,
we wouldn't be in this mess.
Yeah, 100% my fault.
Just stay out of my career!
I made one mistake. Oh,
one? Because I can think...
I waited for Derek
to push me into it.
I should've gone to
Owen Hunt myself,
and I should've
done it days ago.
I should've stopped the test.
He's a hard guy to say no to.
Yeah, but it's sort of my job.
He couldn't do the stress test.
He wasn't ready to go home.
You should go to
Dr. Grey's for Thanksgiving.
Me and these guys are gonna
hang out with Dr. Webber.
Is that okay?
Oh, you're blowing me off for
some old guy in a hospital bed?
I'm sitting at the kids
table. I like the kids table.
You meet me after?
Booty call.
Mmm.
Well, we can do a potluck.
What exactly are you gonna cook?
I could probably
handle a turkey.
You think they're gonna
give you six hours off
to baste a turkey?
It takes six hours?
You're not making a turkey.
What about fried chicken?
From the Colonel's?
You said that you
liked fried turkey.
The bucket lacks dignity.
It's family style.
They do make a
nice mashed potato.
All right, I'm
gonna make a list.
Uh, biscuits. Gravy.
Coleslaw. How many pieces?
Yes, and the gravy.
My best friend's a mean
girl. Why did I choose that?
I don't know.
It never bothered me when
she was mean to other people.
But it really sucks
when she's mean to me.
Well, is she mean or is she...
What?
Nothing.
Oh, Meredith. You can
invite Cristina if you want.
You know, Thanksgiving.
I checked with Emma.
She's fine with it.
Well, I'm glad
she's fine with it.
Hi.
Uh...
It's just a cold.
Muscle through it.
I'm gonna go pick up the kids.
It'll pass.
Nothing's really wrong.
We're doctors.
We'd know if
something was wrong.
We'll be fine.
Nothing's wrong.