Mm, I love this so much.
The lake, the fir
trees, the fresh air...
Good. You have 14
minutes to enjoy it.
We are 4 hours and 10
minutes away from the resort,
and your Prenatal Massage and
Aura Cleansing begins at 5:45,
given six rest stops at
eight minutes apiece.
Wait, you've timed
my pee breaks?
Generously.
Shaun, we're supposed
to be relaxing.
Schedules are not relaxing.
I find them... very soothing.
Okay.
- 14 minutes it is.
- 13.
14 is fine.
Oh, that poor dog.
47-year-old male,
multi-impalement, disoriented,
significant blood loss.
Ultrasound and surgical tape.
These spikes...
Wood and metal?
We... We were
trimming trees and...
And a shovel got sucked
into the wood chipper.
- You work with him?
- Sometimes. I'm... I'm his son.
I count 20 pieces. Airway's
patent, and he's got good pulses.
Lalo? He's one of my patients.
No significant free
fluid in the abdomen.
No bronchospasms or wheezing.
No. Fluid's accumulating
in the pericardium.
You jostle that spike,
he could bleed out.
We'll have to do
it in the O.R.
Dad? Dad, can you hear me?
- Aah!
- No.
- No, no, no, Dad!
- Oh!
- No!
- Aah!
Let's get him to the O.R.!
He couldn't have gotten far.
We don't know that,
and that ground is very uneven,
and we know from experience,
- the woods can be dangerous.
- Shh.
Hey, there, buddy.
We're here to help.
It is having trouble breathing.
Leg and multiple rib fractures.
Poor little guy.
I need to reduce
the rib fractures.
- Hold it steady.
- Uh, okay.
Hang on, buddy. It'll be okay.
We need to get it to
a veterinary hospital.
Vince?
Resync By M_I_S
www.opensubtitles.org
I gotta get you to St. Bon's.
I need you to do it here.
I'm a first-year resident.
That's unsupervised surgery.
I can't go to the hospital.
There was a gang
member at that party.
Me being there was a patrol violation.
Cops get that bullet,
I'm going back to prison.
Just go to your P.O.
Tell him the truth.
'Cause the criminal justice
system is always fair,
especially to guys
who look like me.
I finally got my
life back on track.
I have a good job.
I'm trying to work
things out with Viva.
I'm watching my
baby twice a week.
I go back inside, I
could lose everything.
Danni... please.
All right, the bullet's
close to the surface.
It's more of a procedure
than a surgery.
Thank you.
All right, I gotta
get some stuff first.
What's the strategy?
We should start
with the most
life-threatening spikes...
These two in the chest,
maybe the abdomen...
We can't risk a major
hemorrhage so soon.
Do the easier ones,
buy time for the
transfusions to work.
Oh.
Dr. Reznick's right.
We start with the distal
extremities. I'll take his leg.
You get the pieces in his
right arm. I'll take his left.
Now that there's an
adult in the room...
Always a pleasure.
You leaving, I mean.
Hey.
So, after basketball
on Wednesday,
I'm introducing Clay to
the wonders of Su Cai Bao.
You in?
Assuming that's food, sure.
Great. It's a date.
8:00 p.m. my place.
Didn't you just
finish a night shift?
Too much caffeine.
I'm building a trauma simulator
to practice removing
foreign bodies.
You're weird.
You'll probably be
my boss someday.
First grade, I begged
my parents for a puppy.
Tessa... chocolate Lab,
sweetest little face.
Next morning, Tessa peed
on my dad's briefcase.
He returned her that night.
That doesn't sound
like good parenting.
It wasn't.
The dog's got a damaged
spleen, broken ribs,
and a fractured radius,
and skin lacerations.
- He'll need...
- An ex-lap and thoracotomy.
I'm a surgeon at San Jose
St. Bonaventure Hospital.
We should go.
When are you planning to do it?
I'm not.
I don't work without
up-front payment,
and since we don't know
the dog's owners...
Well, we'll pay.
That... could be expensive.
Quite.
I could slot him in
tomorrow morning.
Well, I guess we
could stay in a motel?
I mean, we should really
be here for Buddy.
I've named him Buddy.
Whatever its real name is,
it is a dog and not our dog.
And we are going to miss
your Prenatal Massage.
Buddy needs us more than I
need my aura cleansed, Shaun.
Okay.
It is your babymoon.
Ready?
It's just a fragment.
The bullet must have shattered.
- It's still in me?
- Yeah.
There's damage
deeper in your leg.
I can't locate the
rest of the bullet
unless I cut further
in your muscle.
So cut.
I need a second opinion.
Hey.
Question... if a bullet's stuck
behind the vastus medialis...
This for your simulator?
Yeah, it's a scenario
I'm practicing.
Um, how do you decide
if you leave it in?
Well, it depends on the imaging.
What if you're going in blind?
Well, it depends on
the angle of entry,
caliber of the bullet,
exact location.
Okay. I'll figure it out.
Danni...
how about you tell me
what's actually going on?
Removing the
left lateral mid-thigh spike.
Irrigating the
spike near the sternum.
No signs of pneumothorax.
Starting
on the shoulder.
- Lost the pulse. He's in V-tach.
- Get the internal paddles.
Setting up the internal paddles.
He's coding. Where
are those paddles?
Almost ready.
There's no time.
Starting cardiac massage.
Push 1 milligram epi.
We've got sinus rhythm.
Blood pressure's normalizing.
Good job, Dr. Park.
I'll do more sharp dissection.
His body can't take any more.
We'll get a panscan
CT, CTA, transfuse him,
and resume in the morning.
Nine spikes down, 11 to go.
Definitely landed
in the medial compartment.
Blood flow?
Good pulses. Intact nerve
function in the leg.
If he was in the O.R.,
we'd leave the bullet in.
Got it. Thank you.
I'll pack the wound
and send him home.
Hold on. Can you
take me off video?
Yeah, I'm not a big
fan of being lied to.
It won't happen again.
Thanks, Asher.
There's... a stain
on the floor.
Mmm.
Now there's a
pillow on the floor.
Yeah, they should really
clean that carpet.
Let me call the front desk.
Ugh, it's sticky!
Okay, maybe...
Maybe I overreacted.
You did.
I... I thought
you loved animals.
I love rabbits and fish.
They don't slobber or jump
on you or make messes.
Well, you know, Shaun,
someone's about to
come into our life
who's going to slobber and
jump on us and make messes.
If you are talking
about our son...
Yes, of course, I'm
talking about our son.
Sorry.
Clearly, we are both stressed.
I don't think I'm stressed.
Fine.
Only I am.
And tired.
And... I'm gonna
get ready for bed.
Ew!
Something's wrong.
That's infected.
If I don't get the rest of the
bullet out, you're gonna go septic.
So you can do it here, right?
I shouldn't.
You got me this far.
Please.
Okay. I'm gonna
need some help.
During the surgery,
we discovered
sacral and lumbar fractures.
What does that mean?
The dog will have
trouble walking
and will be incontinent.
So...
a second surgery?
Unlikely to be effective.
The dog would still be at
risk for infections, UTIs,
and will require constant care.
Euthanasia would be more humane.
We brought this dog
here to save him,
not have him put down.
I'm gonna find his family.
And if I can't, I will
find him a new family.
And you're gonna find a surgery
to fix his incontinence.
Dr. Sinclair is the expert
in veterinary medicine.
If he cannot think of
an effective surgery
for incontinence, there
probably isn't one.
In which case,
it's very unlikely
the dog will be adopted.
Then we'll adopt him.
I will find a surgery.
Hey. Where are the supplies?
I didn't bring them.
Danni, you shouldn't
be doing this.
This is straight-up surgery.
Go home.
Let me help you take him
back to the hospital.
- That's not happening.
- Why not?
If you weren't gonna do
this, why'd you even come?
Because I... I didn't
want to desert you.
So don't.
I'll go get the supplies myself.
I just need you to
talk me through it.
You won't even
have to touch him.
If this ever gets out,
I'll take the fall.
This is why he went into V-tach.
The spike in his
shoulder damaged
every critical
structure in the area.
We need to do a carotid to subclavian
bypass before we pull it out.
Risks sending him
into V-tach again.
Well, we need to
remove the spike.
Unless we remove his arm.
In his current condition,
it's a less risky surgery.
Comes down to what
Lalo's willing to risk.
And we can't ask him
because he's too unstable
to take him off the ventilator.
We could ask his son.
He's 16.
He's not authorized to
make medical decisions.
Sure, but he'd have
a better idea than us
what his father would want.
Talk to him.
Oh, Buddy.
It's okay.
We're gonna find your humans.
Are you okay?
Yep. All good.
Were you trying to pet the dog?
No. Mmm-mmm.
You should never touch an
injured animal near its wound.
I know.
I'm gonna start putting
up lost dog fliers.
Making the incision.
Dissecting at the muscle
to free up the purulence.
What's her name?
Lila.
What's she like?
The first time she saw
snow, she ran outside...
No gloves, no hat.
I-I had to drag her
back in before she...
Before she turned blue.
She's like me... Never
listens to anyone.
Mmm.
Sounds like Powell, actually.
I know I can be... a bit much.
My parents were really tough.
I learned at a young age
that if I didn't push back,
hard, that I'd be pushed around.
So it helped me,
especially after I lost my leg.
My med school advisor told me
that I shouldn't be a surgeon
because I wouldn't be able to
stand for hours in the O.R.
But I can.
And I am.
Danni, are you okay?
It's Audrey.
I called out
of my shift this morning.
I just told her it was
a family emergency.
Oh, she's been
calling and texting.
This is not
good. This is not good.
I know.
Wait, wait, wait!
Where are you...
Just, shh. Just...
- Hey.
- Hey, is everything okay?
Yeah, yeah, a good friend's
having some issues.
We're still in the middle of it.
Oh.
After what happened with
Perez, I was worried.
Just wanted to check on you.
Thanks. I totally get it.
- You'll be in tomorrow?
- Yeah.
What was that?
Hey.
If we remove the spike
from your dad's shoulder,
it could cause complications
that would kill him.
How likely?
Maybe a 5% to 10% chance.
The safer option would
be to amputate the arm.
So you're asking me to decide
whether to cut off my dad's arm?
No, we're not.
We just want to figure out
what your dad would want
if he was awake.
Do you have any
other support system?
Family, friends who help out?
Not really.
Mom died, and the rest of
the family's in El Salvador.
Has he ever worked
with other gardeners?
I mean, me. I help out most
mornings before school.
Um, he fell off a
roof last winter.
Got a concussion.
I picked up some
slack, and it was fine.
I-I know this is different,
but he always says, "We stick
together, we'll find a way."
If cutting off his arm
means he'll live...
then do it.
That's what he'd want.
Why are you talking to me
about operating on a dog?
Lea asked me to.
She is very stressed,
and I don't know why.
Well, considering what she's
been through, you know?
But she knows her
pregnancy is safe now.
Well, you don't get over something
like that in... in a week.
Okay, s-so how much
time will she need?
I don't know, Shaun.
Maybe this isn't even
the main issue, you know?
Mmm.
Maybe Lea is worried
about being a mom?
Well, she wouldn't be the first.
Aren't you a little bit
worried about being a dad?
A little.
Crying babies can be very loud,
and their bowel
movements and spit-up
can be very
disgusting and smelly.
But I have
noise-reducing earplugs
and peppermint oil
for under my nose.
And I will keep a supply
of surgical smocks at home.
You've certainly
gamed that out, huh?
Yes. How do I help
Lea be less worried?
I don't know, Shaun.
You don't know what
the issue is, right?
So I would talk to her
and tell her that you've noticed
she's been a little
bit stressed lately,
and ask her what's going on.
And send me the doggy imaging.
He's
stable, for now.
- I'm so sorry.
- You should be.
If you're gonna blame
anybody, blame me.
Oh, I do. This was
unethical, stupid,
and if he dies,
possibly criminal.
Vince would've died of sepsis.
- So call an ambulance.
- Then what?
EMTs can't force him
to go to the hospital.
They can if he's unconscious.
But he could be dead by then.
The only way to make
sure that he lives
is to operate here.
You're a trauma surgeon. It
would be simple and ethical.
- Who is this guy?
- I told you.
He's a friend of
mine from the Navy.
Who's on parole... for what?
- That doesn't matter.
- Does to me.
Vince was the first
one to the accident.
He tourniqueted my leg.
He held my hand.
He comforted me.
He was the only person that day
that looked me
straight in the eyes.
Everybody else was
just too scared,
too freaked out...
too disgusted.
I'm sorry.
Will you give us a second?
If I hadn't warned you
off of that surgery
four months ago,
you could've ended up worse
off or dead on the table.
And whether you knew it or not,
you needed me.
Right now, Audrey, I need you.
I will help you
with your friend.
And then we'll deal
with what you did.
I put up tons of fliers,
called around to
all the shelters
and vet hospitals and...
- Did Glassman have ideas at least?
- Yes.
That I should talk to you.
I've noticed you are stressed,
and I don't know exactly why,
but maybe it is because you
are worried about motherhood.
I meant about the
surgery for the dog.
But... I am worried, yeah.
You shouldn't be.
You'll be great.
Thanks.
And I know you'll be a
great dad to our son,
but what if we're
incompatible as parents?
We can't even agree
how to wash dishes.
And look at us with this dog.
We're arguing. Buddy hates me.
I lied.
He snapped at me after I petted
too close to his stitches.
I thought so.
We will work as a team
and figure it out.
But... what if we
don't know how?
We've both had pretty
lousy parental role models.
I don't think I'm like
my parents at all.
And I don't plan to
treat our children
like they did me and Steve.
I can see my parents in me
in ways I really don't like.
I can be stubborn like my
dad and flaky like my mom.
I can't tell you how many times
I was the last kid
at after-school
because she forgot
to pick me up.
What if I mess up like they did?
You probably will
mess up sometimes,
in those ways...
other ways, too.
I probably will as well.
But we will support
each other and each...
I know how to help the dog.
I'm gonna
inject more lidocaine.
Turn on the ultrasound probe.
How'd you end up in prison?
When I got back from
Afghanistan, I couldn't sleep.
I would lie in bed just
staring at the door
waiting for someone
to come at me and...
I-I was in a bar,
and I thought some guy
looked at me wrong.
Are you getting help?
I'm on meds, in therapy.
I don't want to be what I was.
I want to be a good
man for my family.
I don't see the bullet.
It must have migrated.
Three centimeters deep
and medial to the femur
in the adductor magnus.
And what does that mean?
It's harder to get to now.
We can do it.
This'll hurt.
Aah!
Let's amputate. Book the O.R.
On it.
I think we should save the arm.
Did you not hear
what Dylan just said?
I heard a son who'll do anything
to make sure his dad lives.
But that's not necessarily
what the dad would want.
Lalo's a poor, undocumented
manual laborer.
No support system.
If he can't work as a
gardener, then what?
Dylan told us what.
They'll find a way.
And Dylan will drop out of
school to take care of him.
He just told us how he works
for his dad most mornings.
Already took care of him
when he had a concussion.
The future Lalo spent building
his son would disappear.
You know what else
would ruin his future?
Having a dead dad.
Lalo would take the risk.
Morgan heard everything you did
and came away with a
different impression.
She's not a parent.
That's very patronizing.
But that doesn't
mean he's wrong.
- You're confident you can save his arm?
- Very.
Then let's do it.
What a dick move.
I am so sick of being
told that childless people
can't understand what it
means to love someone.
There's love and then
there's being a parent.
In nine months or
so, you'll get it.
After drilling the
lamina from L4 to S1,
we will use a Kerrison punch
to remove fragments 2
millimeters at a time,
then support the spine
with screws and rods.
And that is how we will fix
the incontinence
and leg weakness.
And by we, I mean you.
A little outside my wheelhouse.
That's why they
called in the bullpen.
Ah, yes. You're an
expert... on humans.
I'm still very unsure.
Why can't you just
do the surgery?
Buddy is an innocent little
guy who really needs our help.
And I've put in a ton of work
with Shaun and Dr. Glassman
to find a way that
could save him.
And... And I recognize
you have valid questions.
And I know, my hormones are
probably playing a role right now,
and my attachment to
a dog I met yesterday
probably doesn't make sense
to you, but it is real.
And I really need
Buddy to be okay.
So I'm asking you to please
set aside your concerns
and please help us help Buddy.
Who's paying for this?
Um...
Seriously?
Gah!
I need longer forceps.
- God.
- We're almost there.
No.
Vince? Vince!
It's cold.
Poor pulses.
The fragment must have
caused a thrombosis.
I'm calling it.
Push more fluids.
I need an ambulance at 302 West
Holden Drive, Apartment 2A.
We're gonna try to
save your dad's arm.
- Did... Did something get better?
- No.
But we decided it's
worth the risk.
Why did you even ask me then?
So I could screw up and
make the wrong decision?
You didn't screw up.
He hasn't taken a
weekend off in six years.
He... He wears old clothes so
I can have new ones for school.
He's given up his whole
life t-to make sure I'm...
I'm happy and healthy and safe.
- I'm just trying to help him and...
- You did.
You gave us the
information we needed.
Right.
Ten-blade.
Twenty's better.
You worried about
a scar? It's a dog.
Dogs like scars, actually.
They think it makes
them look cool.
A Veterinary Medical
Review longitudinal study
showed that post-op
recovery outcomes...
Shaun, the man knows
how to cut into a dog.
But he may not have
read the study, which...
I've already made
the incision...
with a ten-blade.
Preparing to place the 3
millimeter pedicle screw.
A 5 millimeter screw's better.
Removing the bullet.
Slowly release
the proximal clamp
and let's look for flow.
It's good flow.
Vascular repair's hemostatic.
Let's finish this up and
get him off to recovery.
Bag the bullet for
forensic evidence.
Hey.
How'd it go?
We won't know until he wakes up.
It meant a lot that you came.
How can you say no to a dog?
Yeah.
You know, when Maddie
was a newborn...
we were worried
that she wasn't...
latching on, you know?
But she did.
And then we were worried
that she wasn't crawling,
and she did.
And then we were worried
she wasn't talking,
and...
You're gonna be a mom.
You're gonna worry,
that goes with the gig.
99% of the time, everything
works out just fine.
What was Maddie like?
Maddie...
She never walked
anywhere, she always ran.
She was angry... a lot.
That was her default.
But she loved so deeply.
It was like you were the
only one in the world.
I wish I'd known her.
Why'd you ask me about Maddie?
I just can't imagine
going through what
you went through.
And I am... so scared...
of that 1%.
After Maddie died, I didn't
think that I was gonna make it.
There were times that I
hoped that I wouldn't.
But I did.
And then I met Shaun.
And then I met you.
And I'm grateful
every single day
because I love you both so much.
You and Shaun have love,
and you have faith
in each other.
If I was a betting man...
I would bet the house
on the both of you.
We're on full flow.
Removing the spike.
Low blood flow to the brain.
How's the NIRS?
61%.
Graft must have
caused an obstruction.
I can fix it. Clamps.
11-blade and 6-0 prolene.
NIRS?
56%. Dropping fast.
Below 50, he risks brain damage.
We should call this off
and ligate the subclavian.
No. We're this close
to saving his arm.
- More sutures.
- 52%.
Dr. Park?
Dr. Park.
Get ready to flush and unclamp.
Go.
- Starting flush.
- Unclamping.
Arm's pink.
NIRS at 70% and climbing.
10 spikes to go.
If the surgery fails and
he is still incontinent...
I found a waterproof
dog bed he might like.
For our place?
Buddy is...
very calming to pet.
Oh.
I think he needs to pee.
We need to get him to the pad.
Hey, Buddy, you gotta hold it in
until we get you over there.
- Okay, not yet, Buddy.
- Almost there, Buddy.
-No pee pee.-Keep holding it in.
Not yet, no pee pee.
Almost there. Keep
holding it in.
There we go. All right.
Time for urination.
Go pee pee.
- Okay, oh.
- Oh, oh!
He did it.
Oh, we did it.
- We got him to pee.
- We did it.
Oh, oh.
Oh, good boy.
I'm thinking letters
in their records,
remediation plans,
and a two-month probationary
direct supervision.
One more misstep, they're out.
That's appropriate...
for Asher.
It's not easy to draw a
line between what they did.
Asher never picked
up an instrument
until you were supervising him.
And Powell has shown a
pattern of disobedience
even from her first surgery.
Wolke's made
mistakes of his own.
And he knows that.
Does Powell?
Listen, your
department, your call.
But you almost lost Shaun
as a friend this year.
And I'm worried you're acting
out of fear of losing another.
Color looks good.
Strong radial pulse.
Now I want you to try
to move your fingers,
very slow, just a little.
Okay.
Is that good?
It's great.
Muchas gracias, Doctor.
You saved my life.
What's wrong?
Um, they... they asked
me what you would...
You know, about your arm.
I told them to amputate.
I made the wrong choice.
Mijo, whatever you did,
you were there for me.
I've never been so proud of you.
I love you, too.
So, I started
looking for dog walkers.
They're not cheap,
but what is, so...
Cooper!
♪♪ I've been going
through the motions ♪♪
You're Lea? We
just saw the flier.
We have been searching for days.
We will, of course, pay
you back for any expenses.
Good. It's $22,563.
Yeah, we could
work something out.
♪♪ Maybe it's just a
phase, but regardless ♪♪
♪♪ I'm flipping
the pages, pages ♪♪
You saved the arm.
Guess you were right.
Or I was lucky.
I almost lost him.
Well, you didn't.
Yeah, I think I pushed
too hard on this surgery.
And I definitely said things
to you that weren't fair.
Last week Kellan told me
he wasn't coming home
for the holidays.
Going on a trip
with his roommates.
Feels like I'm losing him.
Like I've been a crappy father.
You're not.
Anyway... I'm sorry.
My implantation failed.
It's been, what, nine days?
Blood tests wouldn't
be fully accurate.
I could feel I was pregnant...
and...
then I wasn't.
I'll be here.
Anytime you need a friend.
I just might.
Probation.
I'm sorry.
We're letting you
go from the program.
What about Vince?
If you have any leeway
not to report him...
The bullet was misplaced.
Misplaced?
So I don't see the point
in alerting the police.
Thank you.
Danni, this wasn't an easy call.
You gotta learn to
compromise sometimes.
If you don't, it's
gonna hurt you,
not just as a
doctor, but in life.
I'm sorry it worked
out this way.
I'm not.
If I'd done anything else,
Vince would be dead or
headed back to prison.
And either way, his
family would be destroyed.
So I did the right thing.
I'll live with the consequences.
Good luck.
You, too.
I'm gonna miss you, Buddy.
Cooper.
But I'll write you every week.
- He won't get it.
- I was kidding.
You're a good boy.
Look, I know everyone
says this to you,
but I really mean
it.
♪♪ But I swear I'm the same ♪♪
♪♪ Could you show
me some patience ♪♪
♪♪ Along the way ♪♪
He will be okay.
Yeah, he will.
We still have time to make
the 11:00 a.m. nature walk.
Mmm. ♪♪ Start to stray ♪♪
♪♪ Trying to fight
the seasons ♪♪
♪♪ Trying to find my meaning ♪♪
♪♪ Maybe there's a reason ♪♪
♪♪ Why I'm going
through these changes ♪♪