Knock, knock.
Ahh. Who's there?
Me.
You want some company?
Sure.
Whoa!
Oh, whoa, Nick.
Nick, get out of here, Nick.
Nick, come on.
Sorry.
I'll be right back.
All right.
Nick, get out of here.
Please leave a
message at the tone.
Hey, sweet pea.
Out of bed, sleepyhead.
Hi.
Hi, Polly.
Yeah... no, I was
just about to call you.
Dinner tonight?
Yeah, that sounds great.
About 8:00?
Mark...
You ran out of shampoo.
Yeah, it's, uh... on the shelf.
Okay.
I got to go.
Yeah, bye-bye.
Who was that?
That was a doctor.
We've got a staff
meeting tonight.
Oh, but we have
basketball tickets.
I thought that was
tomorrow night.
No, it's tonight.
Remember?
But you know,
if you really can't make it...
No, I think I can postpone...
Morning, Dr. Carter.
What have you got?
City bus versus
drunk pedestrian.
Open-book fracture of the
pelvis, blunt abdominal trauma.
You want to take this?
Lavage was
positive, so I thought
we'd start with an ex-lap.
I haven't got your
paperwork... Go.
Benton told me he'd do it.
Hasn't arrived in my office yet.
It's on its way.
I told you yesterday,
you can't begin the new rotation
until he's signed
off on the last one.
What am I supposed to do?
Until I get your
evaluation, nothing.
Dr. Hicks, please...
Find Benton,
get your paperwork.
Until then, you're grounded.
Oh, come on, man.
Let it go.
You was out of control.
It was offensive?
You charged.
Malik, if I'm up in the air,
you got to give me
room to come down.
So what you trying to
say? You get up so high
that I slide right up under you?
That's right.
So white men can jump?
They just can't land.
That's why we don't do it.
Oh, man.
Hey, you want me to carry you?
Hey, Kerry.
Doug, that's not funny.
I sprained my
ankle playing hoops.
We've got a kid choking.
On what?
I don't know.
How long ago?
About ten minutes... I
drove as fast as I could.
He's not breathing.
Let's get him in. Go, go, go.
Connie.
All right, take care of the dad,
would you, please?
Magill forceps.
There you go.
Find him a sterile drape.
Let me borrow this.
He'll be all right.
Come on.
Move him over.
Get him on a monitor.
All right, what's in there?
Looks like a jacks ball.
Pulse ox is 80.
He's cyanotic.
Can you reach it?
No... the ball's
wedged in there.
He's in V-tach.
Give him 15 of lidocaine.
I'll shock him.
Go.
Get some lidocaine on board!
Clear. Everybody off.
Clear.
Still in V-tach.
Okay, here we go.
Clear.
Here we go.
Okay, prep for a trach.
Give me a 16-gauge
needle on a syringe.
Trach kit...
Hang on, hang on.
Just one second.
Let me try this.
Trach tray.
What the hell are you doing?
Trying to boost
the jack ball up.
Oh, man.
I can feel it.
This kid needs an airway.
Okay.
Get the forceps.
I can feel the ball.
It's moving.
I almost got it.
It's... it's moving.
Can you get it?
I got it.
All right, good.
All right.
Pedes resident's
on their way down.
Is he breathing?
Yep, he's breathing.
What on earth made
you think to do that?
Peter.
Yeah, yeah.
Hey.
Hey, yourself. I've
been calling for days.
Where you been?
I've been busy.
Oh, this place is a mess.
Yeah. I've been
working long hours.
You feeling all right?
Yeah, I'm just
a little tired is all.
You look terrible.
I saw Carla yesterday.
She's put on weight.
You noticed?
She's pregnant.
How could you be so stupid?
Are you going to marry her?
I don't know.
Be a father to your child?
What, she's not
good enough for you?
I didn't say that.
So what's the problem here?
Don't walk away from me.
Hey, look.
Hey.
Now, you don't
have to do this alone.
You've got family...
People who care for you, Peter.
Jackie, I know.
I'm... I'm going to
handle it, all right?
I'll take care of it.
How?
I don't know.
I, uh, I got to get
dressed for work.
Damn.
So when do you get off the cane?
About a week.
How'd you end up going out
with two women
on the same night?
Scheduling mix-up.
Any suggestions?
Dinner with one,
drinks with the other.
Yeah, I think they're
both expecting the works.
Who do you like more?
Well, Heather's a lot of fun.
Fun is good.
Polly, she's...
she's very spiritual.
Spiritual like what?
Like crystals or something?
Heather's got Bulls' tickets.
Bulls! Say no more.
Yeah, you're right.
I'll call Polly,
make up an excuse
and go out with
her tomorrow night.
You're playing with fire here.
I can juggle.
I think you'll get burnt.
Women can smell deceit.
Yeah, you ought to know.
Those days are
long gone, my friend.
So what do you do now?
Uh... give advice.
The form was very confusing.
Evidently.
What's going on?
Haleh's playing at nurse
manager while Carol's away.
I ordered 12 emesis basins.
She ordered 12 gross.
Hey, anybody seen our paychecks?
Ask your friendly nurse manager.
They always come in by noon.
Did you guys see this
memo from Dr. Fischer?
He wants to swab and culture
everyone for resistant staph.
What? What's this about?
Eight of our patients
came down with staph.
They think one of
us is spreading it.
Any idea who?
Could be anyone: you, me...
Jerry, get these
boxes out of here.
You still haven't
filled this out?
It's the evaluation I need
to transfer to Hicks's team.
Put it in my box.
I can't operate until
you sign off on it.
Leave it in my box.
No, do it now.
"Satisfactory work"?
Thanks for your time.
What have you got?
28-year-old female.
Multiple stab wounds
to the chest, arms.
This is my case.
Looks surgical to me.
Well, I'll page you
if I need a consult.
There's plenty
here for everyone.
Superficial lacerations,
deep penetrating wounds.
I'll get the bloods.
Spin a crit.
Sounds like a pneumo.
Haleh, chest tube tray.
Connie, I need a tray
over here too, please.
Why don't you two work together?
Doyle can suture.
You first. Connie, give
Carter some 4-O nylon.
Who's going to put the tube in?
I am. I am.
Trouble in the sandbox?
I'd like to put in a chest tube.
I don't know what you're doing.
Surgery's always
hogging our procedures.
I agree.
Dr. Doyle, you do it.
But, I've got more
experience, right?
Dr. Benton?
Ask Dr. Hicks.
Well, you're in luck.
The patient has
bilateral pneumothoraces.
You can each put
in your own tube.
I'll take this side.
Fine.
Peter, are you okay?
Yeah... yeah.
I like to make a
subcutaneous tunnel
above the rib to
avoid an air leak.
It's a nice technique...
Where'd you learn that?
I don't remember.
Kerry, you got this?
Yeah.
Are you sure you're okay?
Yeah, it's just a
little indigestion.
Try to avoid hitting
the intercostal bundle.
It's a common intern mistake.
For surgical interns.
Mine's in!
How you doing
over there, Maggie?
This pamphlet says
that 40% of all doctors
don't wash their
hands between patients.
Oh, no kidding.
Yeah, and medical
personnel pick their noses
an average of
three times an hour.
Many interns only
bathe twice a week.
Wendy, there's a limit to
how well informed I want to be.
Hey, Doug, we've
got a sick kid out front.
All right.
Nice technique.
Perhaps I could interest
you in a little detective work.
I doubt it.
I'm trying to track the culprit
that's been spreading
staph infection down here.
Good luck.
Jeanie,
please,
I could really use your help.
Well, it's not a very
attractive proposition.
We both know where
staph comes from.
Somebody's not
washing their hands
after going to the bathroom.
How do you propose
to flush them out?
Carefully.
Very carefully.
Can't catch his breath...
He's got cystic fibrosis.
What's his name?
Jad Heuston.
All right, Jad, hang
in there, buddy.
Fix you right up.
What's your name?
Katy Reed.
How old is he?
He's 19.
Has he been here before?
No, he hasn't...
We live in Racine.
Let's go.
What are you doing down here?
We were just visiting.
A kid this sick
shouldn't be traveling.
Wendy, get a CBC, portable chest
and O2 ten liters, please.
Pulse ox is bad: 82.
He's coughing up blood.
He's got rales, and
he's wheezing bilaterally.
Want a bronchodilator?
Yeah, give me five migs
of nebulized albuterol
and 200 of
aerosolized tobramycin.
Pulse ox is down to 78.
Heart rate's 130.
We're going to
have to intubate him.
No.
We can't wait.
He doesn't want to
be put on a machine.
Does he have a DNR order?
I think so... yes,
he does, he does.
If he's DNR, we can't tube him.
You understand he's going to die
if we don't tube him.
Jad, please.
No... no.
Please don't leave me.
What's his doctor's name?
Dobry, I think...
Something like that.
All right, Lydia, call
Dr. Dobry in Racine.
Call about the DNR order.
Find out now... now, please.
One, two, three.
Mr. Papillon?
One... yes, three.
One, two, three.
I'm Dr. Greene.
What seems to be the problem?
Busy.
Paged psych?
On the way.
One, two, three. One, two...
Mr. Papillon, would you like me
to give you something to relax?
No... two, three.
Got any other ideas?
I'm thinking.
Hey, Archie.
Hi.
Psych consult?
You stopped taking your
medication, didn't you?
Yeah... two, three.
Nina Pomerantz.
Mark Greene.
He's one of our regulars.
Archie! Snap it.
Thanks.
That's amazing.
Basic behavior therapy.
You think it'd work on my
seven-year-old daughter?
What's her problem?
She started sucking
her thumb again
when my wife and I got divorced.
My six-year-old started to wet
the bed when I got divorced.
Did you use behavioral therapy?
No... electroshock.
Works like a charm.
Kidding.
I'm just kidding.
I hate to interrupt...
Oh, yeah... gosh, Archie.
Come on, let's go
upstairs and talk.
Nice meeting you.
You, too. See you around.
We're losing him.
Any word on the DNR?
Not yet.
I found a pipe
and some weed in his socks.
He's smoking dope with CF?
Must be a death wish.
They're paging Dr. Dobry.
Guess what? He's a pediatrician.
How old is he?
I told you, he's 19.
19-year-olds don't
go to a pediatrician.
How old is he?
He's 17.
Eight ET Tube!
He's crashing!
Should we restrain him?
Yeah, give him sux and pav.
I'm tubing him.
Hold his head.
I'm sorry, Jad.
Yeah, it hit me suddenly,
so I have to cancel.
Bless you.
He's not sick.
He's blowing off a date.
Oh, yeah?
So yeah, I'm going
to get to bed early.
So I'll call you tomorrow.
Okay, bye, Pol.
What's wrong with Polly?
Don't start.
He had to make room for Heather.
So you got two on the line.
Hi, Mark.
I forgot Mr. Papillon's chart.
Oh, well, that's a coincidence,
because I have it right here.
A Freudian might say
I forgot it on purpose.
Oh?
Actually, you know,
I was supposed to
have dinner tonight with a
colleague, and they canceled.
I was wondering, are you free?
I'd love to, but
I'm all jammed up.
Oh.
But I'd really like to.
Well, it's just an impulse.
Probably another time.
No, no, no, no.
It's a great impulse.
I got to have
dinner with a friend...
My accountant, Roy...
But we could do drinks.
Are you sure?
Yeah... meet down here at 6:00?
Okay, I'll see you then.
All right, good.
Jerry, can we lose these boxes?
Busy boy.
Pulse ox is up to 94.
Prep for an extubation.
Okay... his mother's out front.
Said she would have
been here sooner,
but her car was stolen...
The one that's outside.
You want to fill me in?
We were going to Mexico.
We were going to get
a place on the beach
and be together till the end.
The doctors gave
him three months.
Why can't you be together here?
His mom wants to put him back
in the hospital.
Is he all right?
He's fine, his
airway was blocked,
but we got it cleared.
Oh, thank God.
Sweetheart, I was so worried.
Katy, I knew you'd be here.
What are you trying
to do... kill him?
He'd rather be dead
than be with you.
Katy, would you give
us a minute, please?
Sure.
He wants me to stay.
Can we, uh, talk over here?
Yes, absolutely.
I was in the process
of taking the tube out.
Already?
Well, his lungs
are fairly clear,
and, uh... he wanted it out.
When I first brought him in here
he didn't want to be intubated.
He said that he had
a "Do not resuscitate" order.
He lied.
Look, he has this...
romantic notion about dying.
Well, I just needed to know
that if he stops
breathing again...
Intubate him.
Okay.
All right, Jad.
We'll get this tube out for you.
Now, why don't
you do me a favor?
I want you to take
a real deep breath,
as deep as you
can... Now blow hard.
Blow, blow. Okay.
You okay?
Hmm?
Don't ever...
tube me again.
Why are you taking our picture?
It's the best way to keep
track of the suspects.
Two swabs?
Nasal and rectal.
We need them back by 3:00.
God, I feel like a convict.
The number
matches your lab slip.
I hope the doctors
get the same treatment.
Oh, yeah, they
have to swab, too.
Staphylococcus
does not discriminate.
Smile, Wendy.
Give me the bullet!
Give me the bullet.
23-year-old I.V. drug user,
multiple GSW's,
BP 80 palp, pulse 140.
Lost at least a
liter at the scene.
His buddy says he's got AIDS.
Okay, let's have him
cross-matched for six.
And get some O-neg down here.
All taken care of.
I can run this one.
So can I.
I'll run it.
We'll start with the ABCs.
He's bleeding from his mouth.
Pressure's falling, 60 palp.
I got the O-neg.
Run it through the transfuser.
Intubation tray.
He may have a
hemopneumo... Chest tube tray?
You need help, Dr. Doyle?
No, thank you.
I got the film.
Clamp.
Don't touch it, Carter!
The bullet. What?
Where you're about
to stick your finger.
This guy has AIDS.
So?
It's a black talon... the edges
are like razors.
Okay... I'm never
going to find this thing.
Oh, I don't believe
it, I don't believe it.
It's right there.
Yeah, I got it. I got it.
He's arrested.
Let's crack him.
Want to do the honors?
Second unit's in.
Has anyone seen the
damn nursing schedule?
I thought you
were in charge of it.
I better have this weekend off.
I've got National Guard duty.
Oh, God help us.
Anybody seen the ultrasound?
Everything's a little
disorganized here
without Carol.
I would try Exam 2.
When's she coming back?
We just hope she is coming back.
One unit plasma.
Suction!
She can't see a thing in here.
Bullet must have
nicked an artery.
All right, Statinski.
Intracardiac epi ready.
What the hell? This
thing is jammed.
I can't use this.
I'll find another one.
Doyle, put pressure on the lung.
Carter, do compressions.
I'm squeezing.
No, it's me.
Oh, I got it, I got it.
Good job, you two...
Now, can you hold on
while we take him upstairs?
Yeah.
Sure.
Can I assist?
Is your paperwork done?
Signed and in your box.
Okay, let's get him
to the OR, people.
Come on, let's go!
What's the ultrasound
doing in there?
I don't know,
but that CF kid wants
to talk to an attending.
All right, I'll be right there.
Peter?
What are you doing?
Nothing.
It must be something.
When did the pain start?
Last night.
Location?
Mid-epigastric.
Shifted to the right lower
quadrant this morning.
Fever?
100.2.
Lie down, Peter.
You know what, Kerry,
it's probably just a virus.
Lie down.
Lydia, can you assist?
Dr. Benton?
Just relax, Peter.
Sorry.
Alert the OR.
Dr. Benton has
a hot appendix.
So? ¿Oistes lo de Mark Greene
y las tres chavas?
¿ Tu crees?
Ya parece un doctor don juan.
¿Estas celosa?
No, nosotros tuvimos
algo, tu sabes,
un little fling, pero...
Is it true what they
say about los calvitos?
Girl, ese es bien apasionado.
Todo lo que quiere
hacer es sexo, sexo, sexo.
No!
Hey, uh, you guys seen Doug?
Uh... try the admit desk.
What?
N... nothing.
Hey, Doug, you busy?
What's the
recommended antibiotics
for end-stage cystic fibrosis?
Oh, I'm sorry.
So I took your advice,
and I canceled with Polly.
Good.
And then I met Nina.
So now it's drinks with Nina
and basketball with Heather.
Great.
Listen, do you think
I should call up Heather,
and have her meet
me at the stadium?
Then I could spend a
little more time with Nina.
Mark, I'm a little busy
here with a sick kid.
Can we just talk
about this later?
Oh, yeah, sure.
Catch you later.
Hi.
Hi, Mark.
That's a tough case.
You know, that kid
with end-stage CF.
Yeah, if he had a jacks
ball caught in his throat
maybe I could fix him.
You know, he wants
to be made DNR.
You talked to him?
Yes.
He's my patient.
Well, he spoke to me,
maybe because you
haven't been listening to him.
He's 17 years old... It's
his mother's decision.
He'll be 18 in three weeks.
So?
So maybe we should
consider his feelings.
He's a teenager.
He's mixed up... He
ran away from home.
He's also terminally ill
and doesn't want
to be on a respirator.
You know, I can't go along
with letting him
die... Can't do it.
Whose problem is
this, his or yours?
Oh, my God. It's true.
I thought the nurses
were just kidding.
Look, Dr. Hicks, I don't want
any residents
operating on me, okay?
Don't worry, Peter.
It's just your average
run-of-the-mill appendectomy.
All right, so
you'll do it, right?
I'll be there.
Okay.
I'd better go scrub.
I need you to sign
this consent form.
If you have any questions,
Dr. Hicks will answer them.
That won't be necessary.
All right.
Come on, let's, uh...
let's get this thing over with.
Okay, time to prep.
Raise your gown.
It's a mystery.
Doesn't add up.
Here are the patients
with resistant staph.
But none of them were treated
by the same doctor or nurse.
Where's the missing link?
Well, we could put
cameras in the bathrooms
to see who doesn't
wash their hands.
Wait a minute.
What?
All these charts
have the same
handwriting on top.
You recognize it?
Uh-huh.
Yeah, fine.
Hey, Jeanie, Dr. Fischer.
Can I offer you guys
a homemade brownie?
No, thanks.
What, something wrong?
Hey.
What are you doing?
Scrubbing in.
Dr. Hicks said I could help
out on that thoracotomy.
Oh, you're
interested in surgery?
Yeah, you know,
I'm thinking about
doing an elective.
Hey, I want to thank you again
for warning me
about that bullet.
My dad's a cop.
We talk ammo at
the dinner table.
Seriously?
Yeah, you should
see my gun collection.
I got a Beretta 687, a
Winchester Golden Quail,
and I got a Tommy gun
that belonged to Dillinger.
Wow.
Change in plans.
Simon's got the gunshot,
we're doing the Appy.
The Appy?
Disappointed?
Yeah... yeah,
they're kind of boring.
You haven't seen
the patient yet.
Ho...
Oh... there is a God.
What are my chances
of getting out of here?
I can't say.
Don't give me that crap.
You still have some time.
Three months, max.
You could spend
that time with Katy.
Great.
She can suction the
snot out of my lungs
while I stare at the ceiling.
I've been in hospitals
my whole life.
I watched two friends
die on a respirator slowly...
wasting away.
No, thanks.
It's not your decision.
Oh, please.
I'll be 18 in three weeks.
I can't do it.
Screw you!
What about me?
It's up to your mom.
She's been telling me
what to do my whole life.
For once, let me do what I want.
No.
She's afraid of losing you.
She's going to lose me anyway.
Talk to her.
Tell her to let me go.
Hey, look who it is.
Hi.
What are you doing here?
Came to pick up my paycheck.
Not here yet.
Thanks for taking our
side against management.
I guess you're paying for it.
Yeah.
What are all these
boxes doing here?
Procurement screwed up.
Oh, some fool ordered
by the gross, huh?
Here's my paycheck.
Any idea when
you're coming back?
No...
The hearing's in a couple
of weeks, though, so...
We've missed you.
Thanks.
Well, I'm off to Pottery Barn.
Going to go buy some candles.
See you.
Someone order some hypodermics?
Ah, this is ridiculous.
I do not need
hand-washing lessons.
Scrub hard, Jerry, to
scrape off the bacteria.
The most important
thing is to wash your hands
after you go to the bathroom.
What, every time?
You have the Roux retractor?
Yes, Peter, and the Army-navies
and the Kocher.
Okay, listen, listen.
Make sure you put
an "X" on my right side,
because I don't want you
taking out my left kidney, okay?
I'm putting you to sleep now.
Where's Dr. Hicks?
Oh, there's been a
last-minute substitution.
Carter?
Don't worry, Dr. Benton.
I'm going to take
very good care of you.
He hates me.
I know he loves me,
but he also hates me.
Is he an only child?
After he was diagnosed,
we decided not to
risk passing it on.
So I spoke to Jad,
and he wants you to
sign his DNR papers.
Of course he does.
And he's got a pretty
convincing argument.
Just wants to hurt me.
I don't... I don't
think that's true.
Shouldn't you give him a chance
to, you know,
make this decision?
He's almost 18 years old.
He was a beautiful
baby, Dr. Ross.
When the doctors told us
that he had cystic fibrosis,
it was like somebody
plunged a knife into my heart.
And now he's grown up
and he wants to
take control of his life
and he doesn't want to die
hooked up to a respirator.
And you agree with him?
It doesn't...
He doesn't have much time left.
It seems a shame
to-to spend it...
you know, fighting
with your son.
I don't know what to do.
Well, he does.
Jerry, how we
doing on the board?
Actually, there's a
psychotic wrestler in 2.
Would you like me to page
a certain psych consult?
That's an excellent idea.
Hey, sweet pea.
Oh, you poor thing,
having to work
while you're sick.
Polly, I-I-I can't talk.
I got laryngitis.
This is Elderberry
extract. It's homeopathic.
Cleared my flu right up.
Thank you, but excuse me.
Cancel that page.
Look, you should go.
I don't want you to catch this.
Mm-mm.
Not until I make
you an herbal steam
of lavender for your throat.
Yeah... uh, Jerry,
we'll be in the lounge.
Shirley?
Yes, sir.
Would you put on my
special music, please?
Certainly, Dr. Carter, sir.
Scalpel.
Hold it, Dr. Carter.
Shirley.
Come here... let's get this one.
Let's get one with
Dr. Hicks and Dr. Doyle.
What's your approach?
I'm going to make a
minimal Rocky-Davis incision
in the right lower quadrant
at McBurney's point.
Proceed.
Inhale.
The steam won't work
unless you breathe it in.
Uh, excuse me, Dr. Greene.
Um, your psychiatrist
is at the desk.
Oh, uh, I'll be right back.
Thought I told you to cancel.
The page went through.
Sorry.
Hi.
Did you page me, Mark?
Uh, yeah.
We have a patient in 2
who needs evaluating.
Okay, I'm looking
forward to this evening.
Me, too.
Uh, Dr. Greene to
the front desk, please.
Emergency at the
front desk, Dr. Greene.
I'll see you at 7:00.
6:00.
Right.
Mark, my brother got
us court-side seats.
I was so excited,
I had to come by.
That's terrific.
We could get a bite
before the game.
I've got that meeting at 6:00.
Safety committee?
Yeah, I was hoping I could
meet you at the stadium.
Okay, how about
dinner afterwards?
You know, we should
talk, but I'm really swamped.
Well, that's okay,
I'll just have a seat.
Uh, Dr. Greene.
You know what?
You don't really
want to sit in there.
There's this rampant
staph infection
that's going around the ER.
So why don't you
just sit over here?
Here?
Yeah, yeah, this is fine.
I'll be right back.
Mark, you really
shouldn't be on your feet.
You know, Polly,
why don't you go back
and keep that lavender
steaming? Okay?
Thanks.
That is a very
interesting case, Mark.
He says he's diagnosed
with multiple
personality disorder.
Really?
Are you okay? Yeah.
Nina?
Polly?
Oh! I haven't seen
you in a blue moon.
I thought you practiced
at Northwestern.
I used to.
Are you still at the gallery?
I sure am.
Mark, this is Polly McKenzie.
My old friend
Polly, Mark Greene.
I know.
Mark and I are
seeing each other.
We were supposed to have
dinner tonight,
but he came down with the flu,
poor baby.
That's funny... I thought
we were having drinks.
Gee...
was that drinks before or after
the basketball game?
You're not sick.
Uh, no, but I'm starting
to feel a little nauseous.
Did he spike a fever?
Five minutes ago.
Get blood cultures times three.
I'll get the intubation tray.
No, no...
His mother signed a DNR order.
How you doing, buddy?
Remember, Dr. Ross...
Put an O2 mask on him, please.
You're sure?
Yes.
Where's his mom?
She's in the cafeteria.
Get her now, will you? Go!
♪ Fancy gloves, though ♪
♪ Wears old Macheath, babe... ♪
Shirley, could you
turn that down?
Just a bit.
I am ready to close.
Nice work, Carter.
Thanks.
Maybe I'll staple my
name into his belly.
All right, let's irrigate
one more time.
We don't want to give
Dr. Benton an abscess.
Dr. Doyle, you want to
suction out Dr. Benton?
Can I have O-PDS on a CT-3?
I will close out with
a running stitch.
You ever done a one-handed tie?
No.
I often practice on pigs' feet,
but since Dr. Benton
is available...
Hold the suture
in your left hand,
and don't let go.
And you take it between your
thumb and your forefinger...
All right...
Around...
and through.
Pretty nifty.
Yeah... yeah.
Would it be all right
if Dr. Doyle tried one?
I don't think
Dr. Benton would mind.
After all, we are a
teaching hospital.
Thanks for all your help today.
Yeah, sure.
You know, we make a good team.
Maybe we should go
out again sometime.
No, I don't think so.
It could be fun.
I don't think it's a good idea.
Come on, Jeanie, dinner.
Let's just keep it
professional, okay?
His pulse ox is falling, 83.
What happened?
He's in respiratory failure.
I'm here, sweetheart.
Sweetie.
He stopped breathing.
Oh, my God.
Oh, God. I can't watch this.
Intubate him.
Yeah, please.
No, we promised.
No, no.
Mrs. Heuston. Do it!
Mrs. Heuston, no.
You signed the paper.
Well, then, rip up the paper!
Just do it!
I said do it!
I'm sorry.
Intubation tray.
Hold him down.
50 Of sux.
We'll have to paralyze him.
Hold him down.
Number eight ET Tube
Please.
I'm in.
There you go... bag him.
He's tubed.
I feel like such a klutz.
Lots of people fall
off step ladders.
I fell over one... I
was hanging a picture
took three steps back
and landed on my ass.
You're lucky.
I guess.
I bet you don't
remember me, do you?
Should I?
I was in here about a year ago.
I weighed 40 pounds less.
I had pneumonia and almost died.
You took care of me.
You have AIDS.
Yeah.
I was all set to die.
I said good-bye to everyone.
I got rid of my stuff,
even cashed in
my life insurance.
Then everything changed.
Really?
You've heard of the cocktail.
Mm-hmm.
My doctor put me on it.
I haven't felt this
good in a long time.
That's great.
It's weird.
It's like I was on death row
and the governor called.
Takes a little getting used to.
But it is a hell of a
lot better than dying.
Peter?
Peter, I'm pregnant.
What?
I'm pregnant.
No.
Dr. Benton.
I'm pregnant.
Dr. Benton?
There we go.
The surgery was a
complete success.
You had an acute
suppurative appendicitis
with no complications.
Here's your appendix.
What?
Shh, don't try and talk.
You're just coming
out of the anesthesia.
I really screwed up.
I really did.
You did?
I never gave the kid a chance.
And Carla...
I'm so sorry.
I don't... I don't
know what to do.
No, it's... it's me... Carter.
What's going on?
Uh, you're in the recovery room.
I just took out your appendix.
You want me to call Carla?
What?
You were asking about her.
What else did I say?
Uh, that you screwed up.
That... you regret
treating me so badly.
That... if you could
change things, if you
could do it over again...
Carter, Carter.
Just...
Oh, I was just
coming up to see you.
Really?
Did you settle
things with Polly,
and was it Heather?
I want to apologize.
I was a real jerk today.
Uh-huh.
I-I-I was hoping I could
make it up to you somehow.
Are you free Tuesday night?
Sure.
Great... that's the night
of my sex addicts and
compulsive liars therapy group.
Nina, I've never
acted like this before.
I'm really sorry
about what happened.
Maybe we could, uh...
maybe we could have lunch.
Maybe.
In the meantime,
whenever you have an urge
to date three women at once...
Snap it.
Hey... Hope I'm not
disturbing you.
No, no.
What's on your mind?
I thought I'd take
you up on your offer.
For dinner?
Yeah.
How about tonight?
That sounds good.
Do you, uh... like zabaglione?
Should I?
I know a great Italian place.
Okay.
Transfer papers
on the Heuston boy.
I see you got a bed.
Yeah, they're moving him now.
Thank you, Dr. Ross.
Thanks.
Okay.
I'm sorry.
Chuny, I need a
couple vials of lidocaine.
You still here?
I thought you had a date.
Canceled.
They busted you.
They busted me.
Men are so stupid.
How many women were you dating
when you were with me?
Just you.
Really?
Yeah, you know,
except for that night
that my neighbor the ballerina
broke up with her boyfriend.
You know, I had to comfort her.
So that was like
a public service?
Yeah, yeah... other than that,
I was totally faithful.
Oh, I feel blessed.
You know, I still have
dinner reservations.
Where?
La Soiree.
How come you never
took me to La Soiree?
Just an oversight
which I'd like to correct.
Well... I'll have to take
a look at my calendar.
Hey, what are you doing?
Practicing one-handed sutures.
What is that?
An eggplant.
What, did they run
out of pigs' feet?
No, I'm a vegetarian.
Ah...
So, uh...
You doing anything later?
Um, actually, I,
uh... I got plans.
Okay.
Well, maybe some other time.
If you want, you
can come with me.
I'd love... yeah, I'd love to.
Where?
How could you forget to
send in our time cards?
I didn't forget to
send in the time cards.
Then how come we
didn't get our paychecks?
I don't know.
Someone in administration
must have screwed up.
I distinctly remember
collecting all the time cards,
wrapping them in a rubber band,
and then stuffing
them in my purse...
Mm-hmm.
Pretty good, except you're
supposed to hit your own target.
You might want
to keep your eyes
open this time.
Let me show you.
Okay, now relax.
The trick is...
to caress the butt,
and squeeze the trigger slowly.
Oh, my God. What?
Uh... over there. Where?
Don't look... maybe
she won't see us. Who?
That woman in the red sweater.
The tall one?
Don't look.
Why?
That's-that's my ex-girlfriend
Amy Elliot.
Girlfriend.
Cop.
I broke up with her
two months ago.
She's jealous as hell.
Here.
Would you like some
more champagne?
Are you trying to get me drunk?
Yeah, I need the company.
So you lost all three, right?
Yes!
I told you.
How was your day?
I don't want to talk about it.
All right.
So what do you want
to do after dinner?
See a movie?
Mmm.
Go bowling?
I forgot.
Let's just, uh... get another
bottle of champagne.
I like that idea a lot.
I had a really nice time.
I hope it is the first of many.
So there's my car.
Want to get some coffee?
I know a great little place
a couple blocks from here.
You know what?
It's getting late,
and I got to work
early tomorrow.
Are you sure that's the reason?
Well, I'm afraid.
Of what?
Of liking you too much.
What's wrong?
Nobody's done that
in a really long time.
Aren't you afraid?