Deep-fried shrimp. And lobster.
I never had lobster. What,
do they boil them or grill them?
Which one's better?
Just get them both.
And I know I need
a strawberry malt.
And then there's those chocolate
donuts, they come in a box.
We'll do our best to accommodate.
Tomorrow you'll be moved to a holding cell.
That's where you'll
get your last meal.
You also have a constitutional right
to a spiritual advisor of your choice.
No, I don't need none of that.
One last thing to think about.
After I read the
execution warrant,
you'll be given an opportunity
to make a statement.
You might wanna take some time
and think about what you wanna say
as your final words.
Yo, Clarence! You hear that?
A spiritual advisor
of my choice.
Don't matter, you're
going to hell anyway.
You think I'll get
another stay? You should.
Supreme Court said it
ain't right to kill retards.
Cut the chatter!
Exercise time.
Be back in an hour. Enjoy.
Huh? What?
Why did you hit me so
many times, Clarence?
You know why!
You could have stopped. You
stabbed me in the back, man.
Look, I never... You
couldn't fight fair?
Like you did?
I had a wife and three kids.
You were a sick bastard!
Open the door! Open the door!
Clarence!
What'd I ever do to you, man?
You better stay in this place.
I was just minding
my own business.
You can't go in there.
Who are you? And why
are you wearing a tie?
I'm Dr. Cuddy's new assistant.
Can I tell her what it's regarding?
Yes. I would like to know why
she gets a secretary and I don't.
I'm her assistant, not her
secretary. I graduated from Rutgers.
I didn't know they had
a secretarial school.
Well, I hope you took some
classes in sexual harassment law.
Does the word "ka-ching" mean
anything to you? I'm going in now.
Dr. House, we are in
the middle of a meeting.
What's with hiring a male
secretary? J-Date not working out?
He is cute, be careful.
She's not like you, she
can't just walk into a bar
and pick up her soul
mate in 20 minutes.
I met Mark at a fundraiser
that happened to be held at a...
You met me at a strip club.
You were the worst $2 I've
ever spent. We'll catch up later.
Stacy, it's House. I
know you can handle it.
Nothing to handle. He obviously
wants to talk to you alone.
If you have a problem
working with Stacy,
you should have said so.
What was I supposed to do?
Ask her to leave? That's just rude.
Death row guy. I want the case.
How do you even know about him?
You don't have access to
the hospital's mainframe.
No, but Party-Pants does.
You stole my password?
Hardly counts as stealing,
it's a pretty obvious choice.
Well, I have already assigned
"death row guy" to Dr. Nolo.
Nolo? Well, I...
I don't wanna say anything
bad about another doctor,
especially a useless drunk.
You are addicted to pain pills.
Yeah, but I'm not useless.
Tell Nolo I'm taking over.
Dr. Nolo is a
board-certified cardiologist.
Well, good. I'm sure he'll
explore all the usual options
for why a guy's heart starts beating
so fast it pumps out air instead of blood.
Wait a second. There
are no usual options.
How badly do you want this?
I will give you two more
clinic hours this week.
Don't bend over for the soap.
Just the heart, or the patient
have any other complaints?
Patient's not
talking to anybody.
Where are we going?
You are going to the
clinic for two hours.
Me? Why?
Talk to Cuddy.
She's got me going to Mercer
State Prison, Capital Sentences Unit.
Aren't there better
ways to spend our time?
Good question. What
makes a person deserving?
Is a man who cheats on his wife
more deserving than a
man who kills his wife?
Yeah, actually, he is.
What about a child molester?
Certainly not a good guy,
but he didn't kill anybody.
Maybe he can get
antibiotics, but no MRIs.
What about you?
What medical care should you
be denied for being a car thief?
Tell you what. Three
of you work on a list
of what medical treatments a person
loses based on the crime they committed.
I'll review it when I get back.
Your patient shanked one
inmate his first month here.
Broke another one's neck. Nearly
decapitated one of my guards.
Relax. I got a great
bedside manner.
Too dangerous to
house him in the infirmary.
You don't have to worry,
we've taken every precaution.
I've had my men clear from the
cell all pens, paper clips, and staplers.
Any supplies that might
be used as a weapon.
Open her up!
For your visit, we've got
him cuffed and shackled.
And yet you're
staying out there.
You're gonna have to give me that.
Wouldn't want anybody to get hurt.
Hi. Hi.
I'm Dr. Cameron.
How you feeling?
Little cough, no big deal.
Okay, then what you doing here?
I just got a job at the university,
they need a health clearance.
Apparently, I'm a little anemic, so
they made me get some more tests.
Any family history of anemia?
Not that I know of. My mom
died of cancer when I was a kid.
My dad's heart gave
out a couple of years ago.
Brothers and sisters?
I'm afraid it's a short
family history. That's it.
I had a husband
once, but it didn't stick.
My tests should be
back, probably in that file.
Probably. Yeah.
Is everything okay?
Did you redo the x-ray? Twice.
Well, you don't need a consult.
You know the diagnosis.
All she has is a cough.
Bluish tinge to the
fingernails. Lips.
He's hypoxic. What's that mean?
It means he's not
getting enough oxygen.
You know how people say
you can't live without love?
Well, oxygen's
even more important.
He's got fluid in his
lungs. Breathing rate of 50.
He needs to be intubated,
put on a respirator.
Don't have a respirator.
Better get one in about an
hour, or you're gonna lose him.
I'll make out a requisition. State's
already sentenced this man to die.
I think the state was a tad
more specific about how.
This is Dr. Gregory House.
I need an ambulance
pick-up at Mercer State Prison.
Wasted call, my men
will stop them at the gate.
No way a death row
inmate leaves my prison.
At least, not through
the front doors.
You work fast. So do you.
Was that a shot? Yeah.
It was easy, once I convinced the
clerk to take it to Judge Markham.
She's a sucker for Eighth
Amendment arguments.
Stop, I'm getting turned on.
House!
It was just a consult!
You expect us to shut down
an entire floor for this guy?
Did you do something
to your hair?
Stacy!
You said you
cleared it with her!
Come on, you've
known me how long?
And you still can't tell
when I'm joshing you?
Take him back to
prison. Now. No, can't.
See, ironically, I'm bound by this
court order that your ace attorney got.
I have to make
him all better before
shipping him back
for the state to kill him.
Is it just me, or is that weird?
Anyway, we're walking.
Somebody left this on my chair.
It's clever, 'cause it
forces me to either
deal with the file or
never sit down again.
Cindy Kramer. I told
her you'd see her.
Well, you shouldn't
have told her that.
She's got metastatic squamous
cell lung cancer. Six months tops.
Have you even
looked at the x-ray?
No. Just guessing.
It's a new game. If I'm
wrong, she wins a stuffed bear.
A spot on an x-ray doesn't
necessarily mean that she's terminal.
I love children.
So filled with hope.
It could be pneumonia.
It could be sarcoidosis.
Could be. If she
didn't already have
swollen hilar lymph
nodes on the other lung.
Can we at least
brainstorm for other ideas?
Thank you.
I still think pneumonia
and sarcoidosis.
But, we should
check for tuberculosis
and definitely rule out
congestive heart failure.
Five stages of dying.
Exactly.
Personally, I think it's
all just New Age crap,
but from your tear-filled,
puppy dog eyes,
I think I've made my point.
Now go tell Cindy
whatever-her-name-is that she's dying.
Tachycardia. Pulmonary
edema. Likely suspects?
The death row guy?
That's who you're working
on instead of Cindy?
God, I've got to learn not
to beat around the bush.
By "dying," I meant
no matter what we do.
Very, very soon she is going to
be dead. Is that still too subtle?
I took an oath to "do no harm."
Yeah, but it's not like they
make you sign it or anything.
We cure your patient, he
goes back to death row.
He goes back to
death row, they kill him.
He stays here and we
don't treat him, he dies.
And I still don't treat
"Cindy Lou Who."
Can we get on with this?
Yeah, I knew I could count
on your help for your homie.
Exactly. I'm black. I sympathize
with guys who grew up in the inner city,
kept down by The Man.
- Makes sense to me.
- It's a bunch of crap!
You can't blame society for the
fact that you chose to become a killer.
The guy's probably
a heroin addict.
That explains the tachycardia,
which caused the pulmonary edema.
How does an inmate on death
row get his hands on heroin?
Are you serious? HOUSE:
Man knows prisons.
When we got a yachting
question, we'll come to you.
Okay, drugs it is. Test his
hair, blood, urine, works.
Thanks for getting my back.
I thought you seminary boys
were against the death penalty.
I've left the seminary.
Over their stance on
capital punishment?
I'm against the death
penalty in principle.
In practice, however, watching
a murderer die causes me
a lot less grief than
annoying my boss.
We gotta check you
out before you go in.
Department of
Justice statistics show
that it's a racially motivated
form of punishment.
Black defendants are 10 times more
likely to get a death sentence than whites.
Doesn't mean we need to
get rid of the death penalty.
Just means we need
to kill more white people.
It's okay. You're in a hospital,
we're taking care of you.
Stay calm, you hear me?
Push two milligrams Ativan!
Water. Water.
What's the differential
for being thirsty?
He was just a little
dehydrated. And out of his mind.
We upped his saline
drip. He's fine now.
Blood and urine tests came back
clean, no sign of opiates in his system.
Don't do that.
What? You have some House
theory explaining heroin use
despite a negative test? Nope.
Only I get to
write on the board.
So it's not drugs.
What else can cause a
heart to do wind sprints?
You got the blood work back,
anything out of the ordinary?
His bi-carb is low.
Yeah, but which column?
It could be the result of the
tachycardia, or it could be the cause.
It's the cause. Why,
because you want it to be?
Let's see how well that
works with your other patient.
We're just talking
semantics here.
We should put him on a
bi-carb drip and send him back.
Right. Buff his numbers, don't bother
trying to figure out the underlying cause.
I thought you cared
about patients.
Our job isn't to make sure he can
bounce his grandkids on his lap.
Our job is to get him healthy
enough to go back to death row.
Our job is to diagnose him.
What?
Mommy and Daddy are having a little fight,
doesn't mean we've stopped loving you.
Now, go outside and play.
Get Daddy some smokes,
and an arterial blood gas test.
That was impressive. Okay,
what number am I thinking of?
Are you trying to get me fired?
If you didn't want me working
here, why didn't you just say so?
I just don't want you working
right here, in my office.
But anywhere else in
the building is fine. Oh.
It's a really big hospital.
I'm a lawyer, you're a jerk.
There's gonna be some overlap.
God, I hope that
was a euphemism.
Cuddy just reamed me!
I hope that one means
what I think it means.
For trusting you.
She figured when she hired
me she'd at least have someone
you couldn't walk all over.
The number was six, by the way.
I need to know, can I trust you?
If I hadn't lied to you about Cuddy's
approval, my patient would be dead.
Great.
Now I know.
Now we can work together.
I'll be drawing some blood
from your femoral artery.
From my what? Runs
through your groin.
You think you're gonna stick
me in the jewels with that?
It's really closer to your thigh.
Technically at this point, it seems like
your jewels are more for
display purposes anyway.
Hold up, hold up. Gimme
some painkillers or something.
A tough guy like you don't need
them. Forget that, numb me up, man.
You got some gang
ink? Let me see that.
It's a Native American symbol.
It means "the force of life."
That's what you tell all these white
dudes so they let you play doctor.
Yup, got them all fooled.
For real, how a brother like you go from
gang banging to wearing that white coat?
How's a brother like you go from
loving a woman to punching her skull in?
Bitch stepped out.
Sorry about that. Guess I
didn't use enough lidocaine.
Blood gas came back with a pH
of 7.28, and decreased HCO-3.
Which means two things.
Most importantly, Cameron
was wrong about the bi-carb.
And less significantly,
we have a new symptom.
Anion gap acidosis.
Who's chubby? Come on,
pretend he loves puppies.
Pretend he's a human
being. What do you got?
I think we should
reconsider drugs.
He already tested negative.
That's why I said reconsider.
Back in juvie, I cut up
oregano and sold it as pot.
Is that how you put
yourself through med school?
What if Clarence thought he was
taking heroin, but it was something else?
What "something else" could
lead to anion gap acidosis?
Mudpiles.
Well, you don't have to ask, just
wash your hands before you come back.
Methanol, uremia, diabetes...
Oh, it's a mnemonic.
That makes sense, too.
Paraldehyde, INH,
Lactic acid... Rewind.
INH? Yahtzee.
Drugs for tuberculosis.
Nearly a quarter of the prison
population is infected with TB.
Clever entrepreneur like Foreman here
chops up his meds, passes it off as heroin.
INH poisoning would
explain all the symptoms.
Who wants to head over to the
prison and find Clarence's secret stash?
Fine, I'll do it.
Great! Chase it is.
I assume you have a reason beyond
wanting to make me completely miserable.
You got a prettier mouth.
Better chance the
inmates will open up to you.
Perhaps I'll come out
looking just as monstrous.
I mean, isn't that
what I deserve?
Dr. VIVIAN: John,
it wasn't your fault.
If your father hadn't slipped you those
drugs, you would have never done...
The man's in a coma!
He didn't mind. I asked.
You're getting
crumbs all over him.
Why do you think they put TVs
in coma patients' rooms, anyway?
Some people think
they can still hear.
Well, so leave them a radio.
His eyes are closed.
Who thinks they can see?
Do you know why people
are nice to other people?
Oh, I know this one!
Because people are
good, decent and caring.
Either that, or
people are cowards.
If I'm mean to you, you'll be mean
to me. Mutually-assured destruction.
Exactly. Are you
gonna eat these chips?
Are you gonna get to your point?
You need people to like you.
I don't care if people like me.
Yes, but you need people to
like you because you need people.
Unless you think you can get
the next court order yourself.
If Stacy can't trust
you, you can't use her.
And, that's not even dealing with
the greater agenda of getting her
to dump her husband and fall
in love with you all over again.
Dr. BRUCE: We were gonna
be with each other forever!
Look, I know you're friends
with her, but there is a code.
"Bros before hoes, man."
Crap. What is it?
Death row guy is dying.
Bradycardia. His heart
rate's dropped to 30.
It's not gonna hold
out much longer.
You just waiting to call time of death,
or are you gonna give him atropine?
Temporary fix. Right.
Don't know why those diabetics
are all hung up on insulin.
They're just gonna
have to take more.
Atropine's only gonna
buy you a few hours.
We don't even know
what's wrong with him.
Just get out of here.
This is Chase.
Did you beat any
confessions out of anybody?
I haven't spoken to any inmates.
Does anybody do
their jobs anymore?
I decided Clarence's life
isn't worth risking mine for.
Appreciate your candor.
Did you even go to the prison,
or are you just out playing polo?
I'm searching both
of Clarence's cells.
I figured if he's on something,
it's stashed somewhere.
Unless he finished it.
Yeah, that'd be a shame. He
could have shoved it anywhere.
There's envelopes stacked to
the ceiling, bottles of copier toner,
boxes of rubber bands,
paper, file folders.
Call it off.
Come on back.
What's going on?
You're dying.
A man deserves a last drink.
You're okay.
Thanks. That means a lot.
All the tests have
been inconclusive?
Diagnostics is more
of an art than a science.
Should I be worried right now?
I work for one of the top
diagnosticians in the country.
We're pouring all of our
energy into figuring this out.
I thought you convicts
knew how to drink.
You're at least
three shots behind.
Now you're four shots behind.
You better get me the next
one, or I'm gonna kill you.
House.
I was just waiting for
test results, I was...
Little busy right now.
Getting my drink on.
Unbelievable.
That's the finest piece
I've seen in 10 years.
I could've hit that.
And you didn't?
Man, you're the one
that should be locked up.
Tell me something. I've
been trying to figure this out.
Why does a guy
who's on death row
suddenly try to off himself?
I know you drank
that copier fluid.
It's not as visually dramatic as slitting
your wrists with a homemade shiv,
but it will do the trick.
It just hit me all of a sudden.
It was like, they tell me
when to eat, when to sleep,
when to walk, when
to talk, everything.
I had to take control
of something, right?
When to die.
I figured that was
as good as anything.
And that thought just
came to you, just like that?
Man, I told you, for 23 hours...
Look, here's the good news.
The copier fluid you drank
contains about 90% methanol,
which is very poisonous,
and you took more than
enough to kill yourself.
The bad news is, the
alcohol you just drank
contains so much ethanol
that it's going to bind with that
nasty formic acid
rampaging through your body,
hence you're just
gonna pee it out.
Harmlessly.
Man, you are drunk.
Yes, I am. I also
saved your life.
At least for now.
Morning! Your head hurts?
No, you just have
a very grating voice.
You always were a lightweight.
Why are you talking to me?
Can't it be enough that I
wanna cause you pain?
The patient's okay now,
you're gonna send him back?
Absolutely.
Can I trust you? You used to.
I still think the patient's
sick. I'm keeping him here.
Yeah. Either you can do your
job and keep the hospital informed,
or you can help me make
sure the hospital is not informed
and buy me some time.
Have you done a
CT? Yeah, I have.
With contrast?
She's done everything she needs to do
except tell her patient that she's dying.
I told you, only I get to
play with the markers.
Our prisoner has a new symptom.
I'm not telling Cindy she's dying
until the diagnosis is confirmed.
I'm not buying that Clarence
was trying to take control
of his life by suicide.
Healthy people
don't kill themselves.
don't kill other people.
Guy just filed an appeal in a state
that hasn't actually killed anybody
in about 30 years.
What if it wasn't suicide?
What if it was an escape plan?
Drink enough methanol to get transferred
to a hospital, try to escape from here.
Excellent.
Explains everything except
the symptom that got him here.
His heart went nuts before
he got stuck in that storage cell
and chugged a toner martini.
I think there's something
going on in his head.
Check for intracranial lesions, brain
infections, autoimmune diseases,
do a CT, LP, full workup.
State's paying, so go nuts.
Where'd you get these scars?
I got shivved my first month
in. After I healed up, I got mines.
You guys still think I'm sick?
Obviously.
Why do you care? Why
don't you just let me die?
Well, I'm different than you.
Right. You love me
like your own mama.
That's why the nurse says you kicked
her out when my heart nearly stopped.
Take a deep breath.
Any family history
of mental illness?
I always heard my pop was
crazy, I never met the man.
With my mom, it was the drugs.
Any siblings?
I got a brother, pretty
much raised him on my own.
Inspirational story. He
doing time, too? Hey...
He's a good kid. Don't go
judging what you don't know.
How's his health?
I haven't heard from
him since I went inside.
Spent 16 years with him,
changed his damn diapers.
Can you imagine your whole life
being all about the
worst thing you ever did?
You killed four people.
And somehow making mac
and cheese just the way he wants
kind of loses its significance.
Oh, no. Now you've left
your entire body in my chair.
What does that mean you want?
I need a segmental
bronchoalveolar lavage.
I take it the CT with
contrast came back?
They're not definitive.
Biopsy would be.
Biopsy would be
invasive and unnecessary.
And definitive.
But you don't want definitive, you
want to hang onto your delusions
as long as you can.
A lavage could
prove it's not cancer.
But you need me to approve
the procedure. Must be a bitch.
The answer is no. Why?
Because it's me?
I'm over you! I've jumped
on the bandwagon.
And I hate you, okay?
Great. Let's treat her.
What is it?
You won't help Cindy, but you're
obsessed with this piece of dirt!
Are you just trying to prove that
who someone is doesn't matter,
or that all that matters
is your stupid puzzle?
Fine.
Treat them the same,
that's all I'm asking.
One test.
Wow.
That is remarkable.
According to those patchouli
oil-selling New Agers,
it's supposed to be
the terminal patient,
but you're going
through the five stages.
You just made a completely
seamless transition from anger
to bargaining.
Cover two more
of my clinic hours,
and you can have
your one procedure.
No lesions, no aneurysms.
Ironically, the mind of a
killer looks completely normal.
If someone asked you
to describe me to them,
what's the first
thing you'd tell them?
Insecure.
What are you asking?
Like if you were setting
me up on a blind date.
Would you describe me to the
girl as the black guy? A neurologist?
Car thief?
This guy's really
getting to you, isn't he?
There's no sign of infection.
You're gonna have
to do the biopsy.
Your death row guy's still here.
Yeah, sorry. I've just
gotta get him stabilized.
Probably keep him on fluids for a
few more hours, then off he goes.
Oh, yeah? 'Cause I'm figuring
that you still think he's sick.
Figuring requires deductive reasoning.
I'm figuring that you did no figuring.
Stacy just ratted me out, right?
So much for attorney-client privilege.
I'm the client, you moron.
Stacy has a duty to this hospital.
Right. I'm sending
him back to prison.
Can't. Court order.
Court order says he has
to be declared healthy.
Doesn't specify which doctor
needs to make that declaration.
What is it, Clarence? My gut!
Would you describe
it as a shooting pain?
A throbbing pain?
Or maybe an imaginary pain because
you don't want to go back to prison?
Where does it hurt? My gut,
I feel like I'm getting stabbed!
Well, he'd know.
Let me take a look.
Oh, so everybody lies
except a convicted murderer?
I don't think he's
faking this stuff.
What do you think, Doctor?
I didn't have any choice.
No, you had to tell Cuddy.
She's your boss, I get it.
Hitler thought he was
doing the world a favor, too.
Yeah, pretty much
on that same level.
Gandhi didn't march to the sea
because his buddies asked him to.
Pol Pot didn't wipe out the teachers
because he wanted to make friends.
You're not making
friends right now.
I trusted you. I know.
Wilson's a fool. I'm an idiot.
I had to do what I
thought was right.
It's the only reason
anybody does anything.
Surgery went fine. They removed
almost a foot of necrotic bowel.
They're shackling him and
taking him into recovery.
I wonder.
I wonder why Clarence
killed that second inmate?
Fine, I'll bite. What the
hell are you talking about?
Everything we do
is dictated by motive.
Why did he kill his girlfriend?
Because he's a maniac!
Is that the reason he gave?
She was cheating on him.
Jealousy. That gets
him sent to prison.
Where he kills inmate
number one. Why?
Guy attacked him first.
Revenge.
Who'd he kill after
that? Prison guard.
Who had a file full
of abuse complaints.
Probably been kicking
Clarence's ass for months.
Clarence is just ridding
the world of bad seeds.
We'll call that one retribution.
Then he kills inmate number two.
Anybody know why?
Uh-uh.
It's not in there.
All of a sudden, I
gotta have a reason?
It's an anomaly.
Doctors love anomalies.
Dark spot on an x-ray,
bright spot on an MRI.
Killing that second inmate
was the homicidal equivalent
of blood in the urine. It doesn't fit.
I'm interested in
things that don't fit.
Tell me why you did it.
Your other victims you
were almost bragging about.
What was different
about this guy?
It happened when
I was in gen pop.
I was in the
library, just reading.
And I started feeling real
nervous. This guy was staring at me.
I could feel his eyes digging
holes in the back of my neck.
Made me feel crazy.
Sweat was pouring down my face.
I could hear my heartbeat
racing in my ears.
I just raged out on the dude.
So what's the
differential for raging out?
Excess testosterone,
steroids. Adrenalin?
Prep Clarence for surgery.
Care to share with the class?
Oh, come on, do I have to spell it
out for you? Pheochromocytoma.
Actually, I'm not
sure how you spell it.
But you said it
yourself, adrenalin.
Pheochromocytoma sits
on top of the adrenal gland,
randomly spits out oodles
of the stuff. It's perfect.
It explains everything, the tachycardia,
pulmonary edema, the vasoconstriction that
caused the necrotic bowel.
Even explains how he had the
strength to rip the rail off his bed.
But pheo's extremely
rare. I love rare.
Set up an MRI. Where's Cameron?
Like I don't know.
Dr. Cameron, could I
borrow you for a consult?
Bittersweet thing about being
head of the Oncology Department,
I get cc'd on all
the biopsy results.
Yeah, I know.
She's terminal. Yeah.
So I take it you were
in there informing her?
Well, I hadn't exactly gotten
around to that, but I was just...
Doing what? Making friends?
Cindy's divorced.
She doesn't have any kids, no
siblings, both her parents are gone...
It's not your job to be her
friend! Do you understand?
And it's not worth it.
She feels better her final few days,
and you're not the same, maybe for years.
You don't think it's worth
it? I know it's not worth it.
My husband...
I met him just after he was
diagnosed with terminal brain cancer.
If I hadn't married
him... He was alone.
When a good person dies, there
should be an impact on the world.
Somebody should notice.
Somebody should be upset.
"Pheo" what?
I don't even remember.
It's just a fancy way of saying
"small, adrenalin-secreting tumor."
Yeah, that clarified it for you.
All you need to know is,
if I'm right, we can fix it.
Just gotta find it first.
We need an MRI.
It's completely
painless for most people.
But not for me?
I assume you got
those tattoos in prison.
Prison tats often contain
inks with heavy metals.
The MRI is basically
a giant magnet,
suck those metallic
inks right out of your skin.
Stop squirming.
Don't make us do this again.
Big baby.
Still don't see anything.
Turn it off!
There's Waldo.
Found it, Clarence.
Turn it off!
Turn this damn thing off!
Keep him in there until
you guys see it, too.
Son of a bitch.
Looks like they got the
pheo out successfully.
So, what now?
Clarence goes back to death row.
Just like that?
He's cured.
That tumor caused
random shots of adrenalin,
which obviously led to the rage attacks
that made him become a murderer
in the first place.
My God, you're right!
Let's call the surgeons,
we gotta save that tumor.
Put it on the witness stand.
We could testify at
Clarence's appeal.
You smell that? I think
that is the stink of hypocrisy.
You wouldn't even consider the
notion that Clarence's social upbringing
was responsible for what he became, but
now you're sprinting to the witness stand
to blame everything
on a little tumor.
A person's upbringing and their
biology are completely different.
Yeah.
Because you only
overcame one of them.
Well, let's just give
Clarence a free pass.
Which is probably gonna piss
off all those other pheo sufferers
who managed to
control their rage attacks
and become lawyers, race
car drivers, or even doctors.
Removing that tumor puts a stop
to those random shots of adrenalin.
It doesn't absolve him.
You want him to be executed?
That's not what I'm saying.
Got an opinion?
Everyone's got an opinion.
I... I think I'm gonna
testify at Clarence's appeal.
You'll do what
you think is right.
On your own time.
But it's just a cough.