♪ Ohhh ohhh ohhh ♪
Nurse:
Welcome back, Dr. King.
Thank you.
You're staring at me again.
No, I'm not.
Okay, I am.
You ready to talk about it now?
I can't.
You can tell me.
Whatever it is.
I can keep a secret.
Stop staring at me.
You were staring at me first.
You wanna play doctor?
I can be the doctor
and you can be the patient.
Doctor-patient confidentiality.
Oh.
No. No.
No, I can't talk about it.
Has anyone talked to Charlotte?
I left her a couple messages,
but she-- she didn't call
me back.
What do we say?
Sam:
"Get well" or "sorry this
happened"
both seem pretty ridiculous.
Amelia:
Is there a card that says:
"I'm sorry you got viciously
beaten and robbed"?
You need to learn to filter
before you speak.
You must have talked to her.
I sent flowers.
Oh, flowers. Crap.
I should have sent her flowers.
Hey. Charlotte went
to the hospital first,
but now she's parking
downstairs,
so I need-- I need, uh...
You need to go to the gym.
Shut up.
She's gonna be here any second.
Just don't act weird.
You're setting a great example.
Just tell her she looks great.
Does she?
No. She looks like she got
the crap kicked out of her.
But-- shh. Ahem.
Good morning.
Sam &amp; Amelia: Morning.
Take a good look,
then get over it.
If you're gonna be all nervous
and annoying around me,
just stay the hell
out of my way.
What did I say?
I said don't act weird
and you all acted weird.
Like weird people.
Well, I thought it went about
as well as could be expected.
I think it's too soon
for her to be back.
Well, look, I mean,
she faced everybody.
Clearly stated her needs.
She told us off.
Therapeutically speaking,
that's a good day's work.
Violet's right.
Either you get swallowed up
by that kind of trauma
or you try to regain
control of your life.
Charlotte's regaining control.
I just got your page.
Elisa, it's gonna be okay.
All right, you're gonna feel
a little pinch.
I'm in.
Now we just have
to drain the fluid.
Thank you, Dr. Wilder.
Pete:
No problem.
You did great.
Papi, I'm okay. Really.
She isn't, is she?
Her cancer's back.
I'm sorry.
I think the lymphoma tissue
has seeded the pericardium.
We'll have to confirm
with the ct.
Please don't worry, papi.
Diego:
Her body can't take more chemo.
The last two times,
she lost all her hair.
Her mouth and tongue
were covered in ulcers.
I can try something different
to treat the side effects.
Diego, we've talked about this.
Even after a relapse,
Elisa's type of lymphoma
is curable.
I believe that.
But not with western medicine.
Chemotherapy is the way
to fight this.
There's another way.
I'm taking Elisa to a shaman.
Oh, hey.
I was thinking about getting
a latte and then, uh,
you know, I thought of you,
so I went to your office,
but you weren't there
and I thought I'd check
downstairs and--
you sound like a stalker.
I don't. But...
Okay, I kind of do.
But, uh, coffee?
No, thanks.
Tea, then?
Or we could get one of those
iced, fruity-ccino things.
We're not friends.
You need another pelvic exam
to make sure
you're healing properly.
Not to mention follow-up labs,
continued HIV drugs.
I'll take care of that myself.
Charlotte, you...
All right,
we're not friends.
But we could be.
I could be your friend.
I'm the only one
who knows what happened,
and I could,
I don't know,
be there
for you or whatever.
I only need one thing from you.
Anything. Name it.
Keep your damn trap shut
about what happened.
His daughter has been
through chemo twice
and her cancer is back.
You can't blame Diego
for wanting to try something.
Consulting a witch doctor
instead of an oncologist
borders on child abuse.
Shamans have been healing people
for thousands of years, Cooper.
So even if you
don't believe in it--
Elisa's mother didn't.
This would not be an issue
if Alice were alive.
She would never
let a medicine man
try to clear the trauma
in Elisa's soul
to restore the balance in her
body, because it's crap.
You know as well as I do
that a person's faith
plays a huge role
in their recovery.
So if Elisa and Diego believe
a shaman can help,
then she can.
She is sick, Pete.
She needs real help.
She does need help.
And if you wanna
be a part of it, open your mind.
With all my health problems,
I feel like I've robbed
you of your youth.
Heh. My youth was spent
just fine.
Every week, we come in here,
and all I can think about is,
it's not fair.
I mean, first
it was my diabetes.
You had that long
before I met you.
Doesn't count.
And then the breast cancer.
Which we beat together.
Taking care of me is exhausting.
I see it in you.
And sometimes I'm afraid
you'll start to resent me.
Oh, that's crazy.
No, wait, Nick.
Let's talk about that.
How do you relieve the stress
that her illness
puts on your marriage?
Do you exercise?
Do you drink?
Not for years. On either count.
You fight?
We fight, sure.
Every couple does.
That's true.
So why is it making you
so uncomfortable?
She doesn't mean to, but--
Nick!
I'm sorry.
My last patient was, uh...
I've got some more right here.
It's okay, honey.
I don't wanna talk about it.
Rachel.
Rachel: Unh.
Rachel!
She doesn't mean to.
Rachel?
"Rachel and Nick" Rachel?
She's been with him
for 20 years.
I mean, people get
upset in therapy.
No, this was not
an emotional outburst.
Okay, it was
an adrenaline surge.
It was the kind of rage
you see from an addict.
Is she taking drugs?
Yes, but not the kind you think.
We're managing her diabetes
and the kidney problems
that causes,
but she's not a junkie.
In fact, she's the most
resilient woman I know.
She never complains about
her health, never stops trying.
Well-- no, she's incredible.
She's abusive.
Sheldon, come on.
She was a ballerina
and Nick looks like
a lumberjack.
Really, I mean, how badly
can she really hurt him?
Abuse is abuse.
Would we be having
this conversation
if Rachel were the one being hit
instead of Nick?
Sheldon.
I'm serious.
Would you tell a woman to stay
with an abusive spouse?
No. But this is...
Okay, this feels different.
Rachel and Nick
are not a cautionary tale,
they're a love story.
You ever heard
of Judith and holofernes?
Famous love story.
Ends with Judith chopping
off the head of her beloved.
You know, Florence,
great paintings
by rubens and Rembrandt.
You should see them.
What?
Nothing. You're just
a little odd and pretentious.
But I'm not wrong.
Something's going
on with Rachel.
What's wrong, Coop?
Shamans.
And Charlotte.
Shamans and Charlotte?
No, no, no. Mostly Charlotte.
She's having nightmares,
she wakes up screaming.
I try to get her to eat,
she says she's not hungry.
I try to talk about
the police investigation,
she just shuts me down.
Well, she's trying
to put herself back together
in her own way, Coop.
There's no blueprint
for any of this.
Yeah, no, i-- I-I know that.
Everyone handles
trauma differently.
It takes time to heal.
You gotta put one foot
in front of blah, blah, blah.
Glad to see you hold the tools
of my profession in high regard.
Well, none of that helps me,
Violet.
Well, it's not about you,
Cooper.
It's about Charlotte.
So you're saying...
Back off.
You're a bad shrink.
Can I hide out here for a while?
Yeah. As long as you want.
I have to report
the abuse, Nick.
If you say anything,
I'll deny it.
She's hitting you.
Most of the time she's fine.
And when she's not,
I can handle her.
For now.
But what I saw, it...
She could hurt you.
Are you married, Dr. Wallace?
No.
Then with all due respect,
you can't understand.
I met her right out
of journalism school.
I was a reporter for the times,
got tagged to cover
a performance of swan lake.
What the hell did I know
about ballet, right?
But when I saw her dance,
I don't know,
she was just mesmerizing.
She has this quality like
when you're with her,
nothing else matters.
I won't give up on her.
Not ever.
Who sent you to spy on me?
Cooper? Addison?
I came looking
for you on my own.
I figured your day
was probably pretty weird
and you might need some
sugary, deep-fried batter.
So are you--?
If you ask me if I'm okay,
I swear to god
I'll take this cast
and knock you upside the head.
I wasn't gonna ask you that.
When I first kicked drugs,
I took up running.
I mean, an addict's gotta be
addicted to something, right?
So I would get up
when it was still dark
and I would go for miles.
Until the morning
I got clipped by a minivan.
I didn't get anything like
the injuries that you have,
but I started
craving pills again.
So I was thinking that maybe
you were craving pills again.
I took your advice
and I'm back at meetings.
And if you wanna go--
I grew up wrestling
two brothers.
I have an incredibly
high pain threshold.
Anything else?
Can--? Can you hold that?
Hey.
I got Nick to agree
to bring Rachel in.
Would you check her out?
Of course.
Okay.
Sheldon.
It's been a while since
we've discussed man troubles
and I was beginning to think
you'd found another therapist.
Oh. No, I wanna talk
about Charlotte.
Do you think she's okay?
Because I don't,
but she won't listen to me.
I didn't realize
you two were close.
Well, we're not, exactly,
but I was there that night
and it was horrific.
If it was Nai or Amelia,
I'd know what to do.
But because it's Charlotte--
she's just not interested.
It's because you were
there that night.
No, she wanted me there.
No, at the time, yes.
But you saw her when she was
in her most fragile state.
Which means you're the living,
breathing reminder
of what happened.
When she sees you,
she's that victim again.
I just wanna help.
Well, then, you'll need to find
a more indirect way to do it.
Um...
Hi.
Thank you for allowing
us to observe.
I brought something for Elisa.
The medicine men
I've worked with
say that quartz
is a very powerful healer.
So you understand my beliefs?
Pete:
I worked with a shaman
in the Congo
to treat an outbreak of measles.
And you think it was the shaman
that cured those people
and not the vaccinations?
Maybe it was one thing,
maybe it was both.
Either way, people got better.
Diego:
I know you think
I'm crazy, Dr. Freedman.
But my only concern
is that Elisa get well.
We tried western medicine.
It failed.
It kept her alive.
It killed my wife.
Alice died of an aneurysm
that ruptured.
Nobody could have saved her.
And Elisa,
she can still be saved.
Papi, is she okay?
Elisa?
Pete: Elisa?
Cooper: She needs help.
She's getting help.
It's just the bad energy
leaving her body.
I'm not getting a pulse.
Diego: Leave her alone.
Pete: I'm calling an ambulance.
Stop it. Let the shaman finish.
Cooper:
Elisa, stay with me now.
Come on.
Is Elisa okay?
Yes.
She was in hypotensive shock
by the time
the ambulance got here,
so she needed surgery
to make a small incision
in the sac around the heart
to drain the fluid.
She's in recovery now.
Can she come home?
She's gonna have to stay
here for a few more days.
Cooper:
I'd like to keep her under
observation
while we start chemo.
You brought Elisa here
against my wishes.
I want her discharged.
Pete:
No, she can't go anyplace
until the surgical
drain's removed.
Do you understand what's
happening?
She has a tube draining fluid
out of her heart
and she has a tumor
that's getting larger every day,
and no shaman can stop that.
Elisa is my daughter
and I will decide
what medical treatment she--
not if you're incapable of
making a responsible decision.
Alternative therapies work,
Cooper.
I've seen patients cured.
With the right combination
of homeopathic remedies,
Elisa can get the kind
of treatment Diego wants.
Cooper:
Enough. I'm sorry.
I don't care what Diego wants.
I'm getting a judge
to order Elisa's chemo.
No, you can't do that.
Yes, I can.
And I will.
Sam, I have to tell you
something.
Right now?
Do you wanna know my secret
or do you wanna have
sex with me?
Well, both would be good. Right?
I did something the other night.
A rape kit.
Okay, we really need to work
on your pillow talk.
Technically, it was just some
washings, but see the thing is
that the victim didn't want it.
Wait, what?
She was upset
and I thought she might
want the DNA later,
so I went ahead
and did it anyway,
but then I didn't tell her.
And then I labeled it Jane Doe
and I locked it in the hospital
refrigerator, but...
But I didn't report it.
Well, that's illegal.
Why wouldn't you--?
Because Charlotte
made you promise.
You're staring at me.
I'm sorry.
And yet you're still
staring at me.
Oh.
It's what we do. The addisam.
We, uh-- we do that.
Oh, god, I'm starting to sound
like her, aren't I?
Ahh. Oh, brother.
Okay.
Okay. Um, ahem.
I have a thing
that I can't tell you.
Or anyone.
So I'm not gonna tell you.
But I need for you to get
what I'm saying.
What, did I black out
for a minute?
Because you are not
making any sense.
Okay, uh... talk to Charlotte.
She wants to be left alone.
Well, since when has that
ever stopped you?
I mean, let's face it, Violet,
you're kind of nosy.
I am not.
I'm-- I'm interested.
Okay. Talk to Charlotte.
She needs help.
And you are a shrink.
So do what shrinks do.
I saw Elisa this morning.
She's hanging in there.
No thanks to her
crazy-ass father.
You think taking him to court
is the right thing to do?
I had to. He was threatening
to take her home.
If Diego tells the judge
he's refusing treatment on
religious grounds, you'll lose.
Not necessarily.
The California supreme court
prosecuted a mother
whose child died of meningitis.
She'd refused life-saving
medical treatment
in favor of divine healing.
Look, I get that you're worried
about Elisa.
I am too.
But you're not gonna help her
by tearing her family apart.
If Diego won't look out for his
daughter's best interests,
I will.
I don't know what I would do
if she was my kid.
But Elisa and Diego have a right
to follow their beliefs.
They're not crazy, Cooper.
They're just different.
And if you take them
to court to force chemo,
I'll testify on their behalf.
He never complains.
His only concern
is that I'll get hurt.
I don't mean to get so angry,
I just can't control myself.
Okay, enough whining.
What do you think is going on?
Well, there's nothing
on the head mri or chest ct.
But I did find a high level
of testosterone in your blood
which could be caused by a tumor
of the adrenal glands or lungs,
but I ruled that out.
That's good news.
Or by metastatic breast cancer.
But I had a mastectomy
ten years ago.
I know. But sometimes breast
cancer cells get left behind
and grow somewhere else.
That could be a tumor
on your ovary.
And if it's secreting
testosterone,
that buildup
could cause sudden rages.
Are you sure?
The only way to know for sure
would be to go in
and take a look.
But surgery is a big gamble
for someone in your health.
I don't care.
I wanna do it for Nick.
Please, Dr. Montgomery.
I-- I can't hurt
my husband anymore.
You got a minute?
What for?
It's been a few days.
I should take a look
at your injuries.
They're fine.
Then this will be fast.
We can do it here
or we can go to an exam room.
Let's just get this over with.
Everything is healing
up beautifully.
I told you.
Okay. Let's take
a look at your back.
Oh, here, I got it. I got it.
Hmm.
Cooper did a crap job
changing this bandage.
He didn't do it.
I did.
I got it.
When it needs to be changed
again, let me know.
Hey. Sorry I had to run out
so early this morning.
You wanna have lunch?
What is it with you people
and food?
I don't want coffee
or tea or donuts.
Can't you just leave me alone?
I was just trying
to be thoughtful.
No, you came in here
to check on me.
I want you to stop hovering.
I'm not hovering.
All I need is for you
and everybody else to back off.
Okay, I'm not everybody,
I'm your fiancé.
I'm in this with you.
You are not inside this, Cooper.
You have no idea.
And now the way
you're looking at me.
Just stop.
I can't take it.
I can't breathe.
Charlotte.
Dr. Montgomery will remove
Rachel's tumor,
then stage it to determine
the necessary postoperative
treatment.
And if all goes well,
Rachel's testosterone
levels will decrease
and she'll have more control
over her anger.
Good. That's good.
But if the surgery
isn't successful
and Rachel's rages continue--
we'll get through it.
The love you and Rachel have
for each other, it's a gift.
Under normal circumstances,
I would work
to keep this marriage healthy
another 50 years.
But sometimes--
sometimes I have to counsel
people to walk away.
No one stays together anymore.
They just have a fight,
get a divorce,
pretend like
it never happened.
When instead, they should
be fighting for each other
through whatever comes.
This is what love
is supposed to be.
I'm never walking away.
Hey, Elisa. How you feeling?
Much, much better.
I'm ready to go home now.
You need to heal
a bit more first.
Papi told me Dr. Freedman
is bringing in a judge.
Please. I don't want chemo.
Do you believe a shaman
can heal you?
Papi does.
Forget your father
and Dr. Freedman.
I wanna know what you believe.
If you have faith in the shaman,
I will back you with the judge.
It's okay. You can tell me.
Elisa, what is it?
I don't want chemo.
Addison?
How long you been out here?
I don't know.
I couldn't sleep.
Hey.
It's gonna be okay.
Not if Violet doesn't talk
to Charlotte.
She will.
What if somebody decides to look
in the lab fridge, you know?
And they wonder what
the Jane Doe bag is?
I don't know what
I was thinking.
You were thinking that
you wanted to help a friend.
I could lose my license, Sam.
What am I supposed to do?
We wait.
Violet will come through.
Charlotte:
Is that fresh?
I just made it.
Help yourself.
Thank you, Sheldon.
For what?
Leaving me alone.
I wish everybody
else would just, uh...
...do nothing.
I'd do nothing
for you anytime.
You know that, right?
I do.
How's it going?
Just dandy. Thanks.
You know, I, uh...
I know how hard it can be to
reintegrate after you've been...
...victimized.
So if you ever wanna talk...
You always been such a busybody
or is that just
a professional hazard?
Heh. No, actually,
Charlotte, i--
I truly believe
in the therapeutic process.
And after Katie attacked me--
you think because a crazy woman
cut out your baby
you've got
some kind of an insight
into what makes me tick?
You don't.
All you've got is a nasty scar
and a horror story.
You're damaged goods, Violet.
You, not me.
You got no business telling
anybody how to run their lives.
Pete:
You got any tips for getting
a 14-year-old to talk?
I really wanna
go to bat for Elisa,
but she's holding
something back.
Well, she's a kid.
Even as adults, we're reluctant
to say certain things out loud.
You know, it makes it real.
And then, you know,
you have to deal with it.
I wouldn't know
anything about that.
Pete Wilder, open book.
I know. It's not fair.
I push you to tell me things.
And then I have stuff myself.
There was...
Well, it happened
a long time ago.
In college.
And I never told you.
Violet, I know.
Or, at least, I suspected.
We have been through a lot.
And I've seen you react
in so many ways.
Why didn't you say anything?
I figured that when
you were ready
to talk about it, you would.
I'm probably wrong.
What?
Well, you were the first one
to see her that night.
Is it possible...?
Was Charlotte raped?
If she told me,
you know I couldn't--
no, I know. I know. Of course.
But what do you think?
I think you're right.
Don't.
What can I do?
What do you need?
Lie really close to me.
But don't touch me.
It's been a long time
since I wore a pair of these.
What are you doing here?
I came to wish you luck.
Thanks.
You know, Nick and Rachel,
they're special.
A lot of couples stay together
for the long haul,
but not many stay in love.
Your parents still married?
Ha, ha.
No, they split
when I was a teenager.
Waterboarding in Guantánamo
was less brutal
than that divorce.
Are you close to them?
I call my mother every week.
But my father and I...
Well, let's just say that when
you wash out of your er rotation
and you're a surgeon's son,
it doesn't help
the relationship.
I guess it can make you
a little odd and pretentious.
Who's to say
those are bad things?
Call you when it's over.
Alice believed in chemo
and I believed in Alice,
so that's what we did.
But she's gone now.
I've seen
the shaman heal people.
I think she can do the same
for my Elisa.
What do you want, Elisa?
What papi wants.
Cooper:
And what about your mother?
Alice would have pushed
for chemo.
She wouldn't want you to die.
Diego: Don't say that.
How dare you say that?
She's not gonna die.
Your honor,
what Diego is asking for
may seem unconventional,
but I have seen it work.
As an m.D.
And also a practitioner
of alternative therapies,
I urge you, please,
don't disregard
what Diego is asking for.
The only guaranteed cure
for lymphoma is chemotherapy.
I need to take the family's
religious beliefs into account--
okay, what kind of father
just stands by
and doesn't save their child?
Stop it. Please, Dr. Freedman.
If I have more chemo,
my family won't make it.
We're living in a trailer park
because of me.
My treatments bankrupted us
and papi had to sell the house.
I hear you on the phone begging
to keep the power on.
I see you skipping meals
so the rest of us can eat.
Carlos and Pilar,
they deserve a life
that doesn't revolve
around my hospital visits.
Diego:
And so do you.
The shaman will save you.
No, she won't.
I'm sorry, papi.
I don't believe
what you believe.
I'm not afraid.
Let the shaman take me to mama.
I think we all know
what needs to be done.
Do you think I don't know
what's true anymore
because I was attacked?
I think working
through that experience
has made you a better therapist.
Sam told me
I should talk to Charlotte.
Well, that's not surprising.
You both survived
a brutal trauma.
Yeah, yeah.
But the way he said it,
it was like there was
more to it than that.
And then I started projecting
my own stuff on her.
Well, what sort of stuff?
I wish you had been there.
That night. Then we could
compare notes.
Unfortunately, I spent the night
in an interrogation room
getting throttled
by a rapist, so...
Is that what--?
Do you think Charlotte
was raped?
Pete:
The judge ordered the chemo.
You didn't have to arrange this.
Cooper: I know.
Pete: I'm just saying...
Cooper:
I'm not completely unreasonable.
Thank you for letting
us bend the rules.
I made sure she wasn't gonna
sacrifice a chicken or anything.
I know I should leave you alone,
but here's the thing:
I can't.
You're not ready.
Cooper--
I know you.
Rachel:
It didn't go well, did it?
The tumor was worse than
the imaging originally showed.
I couldn't resect it all.
I removed what I could.
Nick:
No. I can't accept that.
You have to stop the cancer.
How long do I have?
Not as long as you'd want.
Oh.
There are
testosterone-blocking agents
we could try
to manage your anger,
but they're not
very effective.
So I'm just gonna
keep on hurting Nick?
There's nothing I can do?
Sheldon:
You can move into hospice
for round-the-clock
care with people
who know how
to manage your anger
and keep you safe.
What the hell
are you talking about?
Don't listen to him, Rachel.
We can manage at home.
You know that's not true, love.
I'm dying.
You don't know
how long you have.
I want that time with you.
I don't care what you do to me.
But I do.
Those people at hospice,
they won't know how
to take care of you.
I've learned that over the past
20 years. I'm good at it.
Well, then,
you'll tell them how.
Every day,
when you come to visit.
You'll find a place
where I can go?
Yes. I promise.
Rachel:
It's the right thing, Nick.
You know it is.
Please.
Let me take care
of you for once.
Rachel:
Shh, shh, shh.
Yeah?
You need something?
It was an Indian summer
my junior year in college,
and I'd left the window open
because it was the only way
to cool down enough
to get to sleep.
So when I first
felt his breath on me,
I thought,
"finally, a breeze."
And then I opened my eyes.
He wrapped one hand
around my throat
and with the other
ripped off my panties.
He whispered to me:
"Shh, shh, shh."
Like, um...
Like you do to a child
having a bad dream.
He told me
not to make a sound.
And when he finished,
he slammed my head
against the wall
till my hair
was sticky with blood.
I thought...
...that if I stayed quiet,
then I'd be okay.
Like it never happened.
Because things like that--
well, they don't happen
to people like me.
Or to people like you.
So...
I just
wanted you to know...
...that I get it.
I get it, Charlotte.
And I'm here for you.
Shelly. What are you doing here?
The guy I evaluated last week?
Lee McHenry?
Yeah.
I think I know who he raped.
Yes, this is
Dr. Addison Montgomery
at St. ambrose.
I have pelvic washings
from a rape
that need to be processed.
Charlotte? What happened?
Will you go
to a meeting with me?
I'm right behind you.