- Previously
on "New Amsterdam"...
- My refugee status
is being revoked,
and if I don't fight it,
I'll be sent back to Pakistan.
- How much do you need?
- Roofies didn't put you
in that situation.
You did that all on your own.
- How can you--
- And that's infidelity, Iggy.
Emotional infidelity.
- What is it?
- Speak...
c-c-c...
c-c-can't.
- You got this, babe.
You can do it.
Show those fine motor skills
who's boss.
♪
Wow, this looks incredible.
Look how far you've come.
- Thank y...
- Thank you,
are you kidding me?
I'm the lucky one.
This is...
And I'm hearing real
improvement in your speech.
- R-r-really?
- Yes, ma'am.
You know what?
Before you know it,
this is all gonna be behind us,
and we're gonna
be back in London.
No ifs, ands, or buts.
- No if...
And...buts.
- You're getting there,
you're doing it.
You're doing so great, babe.
♪
- Apple.
So now tell me,
"I have the apple."
- Apple.
- I have the apple.
- I, um...
Apple.
I...
That's two hours.
- Great work, Dr. Sharpe.
- Well, we try not to quantify
any stroke victim's recovery.
You're doing all your homework.
You're driven.
That's the focus.
♪
Well, in terms of raw numbers,
your scores are lower today.
♪
- Mm.
- It's just one day.
- Hey, morning.
- Morning.
- Oh, yeah, hey,
check it out.
I used our French press
for the first time ever,
and I made some coffee.
To the sophisticated palate,
one will note hints
of chocolate and chicory.
Pour toi.
- Oh, thank you.
- Yeah, you got it.
Hey, babe,
our marriage is the joy
of my life--
- Yeah, I gotta get to work.
- Okay, yeah.
Just please, hang on.
I...I have been looking
for a couples counselor.
- We know all the good ones
in the city.
It won't be a neutral space.
- Right.
That's why we could go
to this amazing guy
that I found up in Stamford.
- Stamford.
- Yeah.
- It's a 40-minute drive.
- I know.
So, you know, we...
we listen to podcasts
and we figure out the commute
and we figure out
the childcare,
and we figure out all of it,
Martin, because we're worth it,
aren't we?
I just--
I need to fix this, Martin.
I need you
to help me fix this.
- You know what,
put it on my iCal.
- Yeah, okay.
Have a good day.
♪
- ♪ Oh, hot sand on toes,
cold sand in sleeping bags ♪
♪ I've come to know
that memories ♪
♪ Were the best things
you ever had ♪
♪ The summer shone,
beat down on bony backs ♪
♪ So far from home,
where the ocean stood ♪
♪ Down dust
and pine cone tracks ♪
♪
♪ Oh, we slept like dogs
down by the fireside ♪
♪ Awoke to the fog
where all around us ♪
♪ The boom
of summertime, yeah ♪
♪
- Hey, I know I'm behind.
Just go ahead
and have them start the prep
for Mr. Azad and...
What do you mean he cancelled?
No, no, I'll...
I'll handle it.
Okay.
Mr. Azad,
this surgery isn't optional.
You have pancreatic cancer.
- Had.
You cut it out in the first
surgery, remember?
- Right, right, we resected the
tumor in the primary surgery,
but now we need to go back in
to clear the margins.
Otherwise, the cancer
will just come back.
- Always upselling, huh?
- Wait, excuse me?
- After my surgery,
New Amsterdam sent me a bill
for 28 grand
after my insurance paid up.
- What?
Wait, what was the bill for?
- You.
It said you were a consulting
surgeon in my case.
You told me
you were in network.
I-I am.
Look, Mr. Azad,
I'll figure out a way
to make this right, but we got
to get you in for surgery now.
- Well, I guess
I can't afford to live.
Consult on that.
- Thanks, but I brought
my own lunch to school.
- It's the first installment
of my loan repayment.
$1,000.
- Leyla, you didn't have to--
- I did.
I'll keep paying you back
whenever I have the money to.
My lawyer said a paper trail
would kill my chances
at a visa, so...
- Cash, right.
- Do you wanna count it?
- No, I don't.
I trust you.
- I'll try to have more
for you next week.
- It's Leyla.
Do you know what would
make the situation better?
- Hm?
- Ritalin, booze.
Sex with a stranger.
- Mm.
- Just so happens
that all the things
that actually work on stress
are sobriety-wreckers.
- What about meditation
and exercise?
- Yeah, I said something
that actually works.
- I mean,
there's got to be some crutch
to help me deal
before I completely lose it.
- Oh, wait, here it is.
Gum.
- I found Kyle
in the elevator struggling.
Diaphoretic, tachy,
tachypneic.
- And, madonne,
the diarrhea.
- All right,
let's get you to a room.
Famous Kyle's.
Best calzones in the city.
- Oh, that's me.
I'm famous Kyle.
- Oh, no way.
- Wait, no way.
That's my favorite spot
in Midtown.
- Famous Kyle's Calzones
is Lower East Side.
Kyle's Original Calzones
are in Midtown.
And the balls on those
rip-off artist bastards
for calling themselves
"original" when--
- You ever had this pain before?
- No.
- Okay, any medical history
I should know about?
- I've got MS.
I've had it for years.
It's been acting up,
so I did
an immune modulator trial
three days ago.
- Azathioprine?
Methotrexate?
- It's...fecal transplant.
- For MS?
Is that indicated?
- No. Someone
was way out of line.
I'm sorry,
where did you get this done?
- Downstairs.
New Amsterdam.
A Dr. Mia Castries.
- Huh.
- Dude!
- Hey, hey, hey!
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey!
- Ah!
- Hey, no, okay.
- Oh, my gosh!
- Close the door please.
- They started it!
- Hey, hey!
It doesn't matter
who started it.
You can't
physically hurt somebody
because you don't
like what they said.
- It's not what they said.
It's what they did.
Isaac--Isaac dumped me.
It's his fault.
- Oh.
- He started it!
- Okay, okay.
I didn't know that.
I'm sorry.
Heartbreak, that's rough,
but you can talk to me
about it, okay?
No matter how awful it gets.
- The only one who's gonna
feel awful is him.
I'm coming for you, you freak!
- Okay, time out, time out,
time out, come on.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Well, looky here.
What, is it Visitor's Day?
- Actually, I work here.
For Urgent Medicine.
Yeah, lovely little outfit
on the sixth floor.
Nice people, great benefits.
- And UMI is a subcontractor,
so I can't fire you.
Cute.
- Yeah, isn't it?
You know, the cutest thing
might actually be
UMI's seat
on New Amsterdam's board,
which I believe
meets this afternoon, right?
Which is great for me
because...
I got a lot to say.
Hey, I'll see you there.
- Can't wait.
- Hey, in my office.
- "Office"
is an ambitious word choice.
- Well, underestimate me
at your own risk.
I have a way to take out
our target once and for all.
In 2004, there was
a huge malpractice suit.
A patient died,
they settled out of court,
and that NDA just expired.
I can take that NDA
to the board
and blow the lid
off this thing.
- We can't.
- I mean, I don't want to
use it either,
but what choice do we have?
- I mean, we can't because
the board's already heard it.
Veronica told the story
at her job interview.
Took full responsibility.
That's what
great politicians do,
turn weakness into strength.
What they don't do
is show up at the OK Corral
at High Noon
with an empty gun.
We still have
the element of surprise.
At least she doesn't
know we're coming for her.
- Yeah, well, about that,
she kind of knows.
- Is this your office?
- Rude.
- Patient Oren Azad
got handed
an unjustified bill
from New Amsterdam.
Not only is it unjustified,
it is intentionally predatory.
- Well, did he talk to billing?
Sometimes they can
help negotiate that down.
- He did,
and that's where he found out
it was already
referred to collections.
- Yeah, where he can
fight it in court
with a bunch of money
he doesn't have.
- Exactly. But since
you are always the Mozart
of helping people not pay,
I thought maybe a little
"Goodwin special sauce" might--
- Floyd.
- Oh, I like that face.
That's a classic
"Max brings justice
to the people" face
right there.
- This is it.
This is what's gonna
finally bring Veronica down.
- You know, when somebody
breaks up with you,
it is perfectly natural to feel
a whole well of emotion--
sadness, loss...
- Revenge.
The desire to make his pathetic
life an ever-living hell.
- Sure, yeah, that's an emotion
one could feel, yeah.
Why do you think
you're feeling that?
- Because I-I liked him.
I spent my first kiss on him.
- Oh.
How was it?
- Good?
But then I got confused,
'cause I know
I don't feel things the way
other people feel things.
- Sure.
- So I decided
I should test it.
- You decided to test it?
How?
- I kissed every other boy
on the inpatient floor
to see how those kisses
made me feel.
- Ah.
- And none of them even came
close to kissing Isaac.
His kiss was...different.
I don't know.
He made me feel something.
- Hmm.
- But then he found out.
He should have been happy.
The test proved
his kiss was the best one,
but instead he dumped me
in front of everyone.
And now he's gonna pay.
- Did you ever consider
that Isaac might feel another
emotion other than happiness,
after he learned
about the kissing?
♪
- If you...hurt a person
that you really like,
even by accident,
can you ever get them back?
- Well, all you can do is try.
- Mmm, yeah.
And worth coming to
the sixth floor for, huh?
- I love this place.
Best calzones in Brooklyn.
- Oh, yeah.
- No, no, no,
Brooklyn is Classic Kyle's.
Midtown is Original Kyle's.
Famous Kyle's--
the only real Kyle's--
is Lower East Side.
- All right, thanks, Kyle.
- How hard is this?
- Hey, I just heard that
Kyle Vincenzi came back in.
How's he doing?
- Oh, yeah.
He's doing much better
since I pushed
broad-spectrum antibiotics...
to reverse your unindicated
and dangerous FMT.
- Oh, I think you'll see that
it was indicated,
just not by his MS.
His neuroimmune issues,
his weight issues,
his compulsive behaviors--
they all suggest
a maladaptive gut biome.
- Right, well,
Kyle is my patient now,
so I am gonna treat him
with traditional medicine.
- No, that's what
I've been doing.
- No, what you do
is alternative medicine.
What I do
is traditional medicine.
- No, what you do
is modern medicine.
- Okay, um, I wanna say
awful things to you right now--
I mean, like, way worse
than I've already said--
but I know
that it's not okay
to rip someone's head off
and jump down their throat
just because you disagree
on a diagnosis.
Unfortunately,
I haven't found a better way
to deal
with my negative emotion,
so I suggest you leave very,
very quickly.
- I like hot yoga
and a week of a honey elixir
and leafy greens.
- Thank you.
- Feel better.
- Mr. Azad.
- I got nothing to say to you.
- Well, I just came
for a detail.
- You came to me for a detail?
- Yeah.
The, uh, gold package
with the hand wax
should do her right.
- You left in the original V8,
or you chrome it out?
- You know,
I'm not much of a car nut.
- With a car like this?
- Oh, yeah,
this belonged to my dad.
You know, he, uh...
I don't have too
many memories of him,
but him showing me
how to clean a car right--
that was one.
- Look, doc, I appreciate
the business,
but I'm still not coming in
for the surgery.
- Look, Mr. Azad,
the surgery's on the house.
No, in fact,
if you get charged one dime,
you get the car.
- ♪ No ifs, ands, or buts
♪ No ifs, ands, or buts
With me.
♪ No ifs
- ♪ If
- You're doing great.
- N-n-not gr...
- Helen,
I have seen patients
with your aphasia recover.
I-it can happen any moment.
This beautiful
breakthrough where...
♪ No ifs, ands, or buts
slides right off the tongue,
and your language skills
come flooding back.
That moment could happen
for you right now,
or in a week, or in a year.
I hope it's soon, but, Helen,
you have a mountain to climb.
You're not climbing badly.
You're just climbing.
I've also seen a lot
of benefits
from bringing a partner
to the sessions.
This afternoon,
why don't you bring Max?
- So Reynolds came to me
with this egregious case
of overcharging,
and I looked into it.
It's everywhere.
Veronica
is overcharging patients
and then threatening them
with court
before their stitches
are even out.
Oren Azad wasn't an accident.
He's the plan.
- She'll claim she's doing
what every hospital does.
- Yeah, but how much?
Right now, Veronica's
an industry leader in greed.
- The board likes money.
They won't care if it's dirty.
- No, but the world will.
- You want to go public,
force the board's hand?
You tell the world
what you just told me,
and the hospital's reputation
will be in tatters.
We'll be synonymous with greed,
poor care,
and we may never recover.
So I need to be sure
you understand
you'd be taking down
New Amsterdam.
- It may be the only way
to save it.
- Hi.
Big, fat scam right there.
Enjoy.
New Amsterdam is robbing you,
putting profits over patients.
Boycott New Amsterdam today.
Here you go.
- New Amsterdam charges
60 bucks for a Band-Aid?
- Well, that's just
for the little ones.
Imagine what
the regular-sized ones cost.
Urgent Medicine,
however, is different.
Sixth floor.
Come by anytime.
♪
Hi there.
- Hello.
- Would you like a flyer?
- I'm good, actually.
You know,
you can't project graphics
onto the real estate
of the people
that you're slandering.
- Well, it's only slander
if it's not, uh, true.
- What do you think
I'm gonna do?
I'm just gonna go cower
in my office
or resign in shame?
This isn't going to
accomplish anything, Max.
- Have you checked your
surgical cancellations lately?
'Cause I think we just
picked up 11 of your patients,
and thanks to them,
the world is gonna hear
all about what you've
turned this place into,
and so will the board.
There you go. Enjoy.
- And that's...
that's why I'm so sorry, Isaac.
I'm the most sorry
I've ever been
in my entire life.
- I know what you're doing.
- Isaac--
- No, she does this, Dr. Frome.
- Juliet's disorder
does make it harder
for her to connect
with other people.
- She had no problem connecting
with everybody else
on the floor behind my back.
- You said
an apology would work.
- No, I didn't.
I said that it was worth a try,
and I never said
it was a guarantee.
- You really
want the truth, Isaac?
You really want honesty?
- I guess.
- When we kissed,
I felt like I was gonna...
throw up.
No, but like--
like good...throw up.
I-I don't...
I don't know how else
to describe it, but...
I really liked that feeling.
And I don't want to
lose it or you.
- Okay, good, thank you.
Um, Isaac, Juliet has shared
her truth with you,
and I wonder if you might
share yours with her,
even if it's hard.
- I don't wanna
lose you either.
Kissing you felt--well,
not like throwing up exactly,
but...
definitely a stomach thing.
Like...
like being
on a roller coaster.
I kinda feel it right now.
♪
- Aw.
- Oh, my God,
mind your business.
- You're right.
I'm sorry, my bad.
As you were.
- Hey.
Hello, gorgeous.
How's therapy going?
Come on.
I'm sure you're crushing it.
You're gonna be doing
Shakespeare in the Park
in no time.
You wanna say something.
- J-just...
H-hi.
- Hi.
Love you.
You got this.
He's tachy and hypotensive.
- It's anaphylactic shock.
Hit him with EPI sub Q.
- On it.
- He must be having
an allergic reaction
to the antibiotics we gave him.
Come on, Kyle.
Come on.
Okay, BP's rising.
- Heart rate's slowing.
- Okay, you had a bad reaction
Kyle, but you're gonna be okay.
Look at his legs.
That's not
an allergic reaction.
2 milligrams of Ativan IV.
- That's not gonna help his MS.
- I don't think
he's got MS at all.
Come on, Kyle, come on.
- Spleen fully retracted.
- And with that,
the midline margins
of the tumor are clear.
- Bravo.
- Let's investigate the
posterior margins on the tail.
Throw us
a little bit more light.
- Wait, let me see here...
Damn it!
More tumor remnants.
- Right up against
his superior mesenteric artery.
- If we resect
and the tumor's eroded in,
he'll bleed out in seconds.
We need to get a vascular
surgeon in here to attack that.
- Call in
one of New Amsterdam's.
- His insurance only covers
one consulting surgeon.
New Amsterdam
is out of his network.
- He's gonna get slapped
with a huge bill.
- Well, if we don't get
a specialist in here fast,
he won't be alive to see it.
- Hey, Dr. Christy.
How are my fricatives?
- Exquisite.
You ready to go?
- Ready for...
- For Helen's therapy.
I decided this morning
that you should be there.
- Oh, uh...I'd love that,
but she...
she didn't invite me.
- Well, I'm sure she will
when she sees you.
♪
- Hey.
I heard you
weren't in art class today.
- She dumped me.
- Oof, that's rough.
You know, God knows
that affairs of the heart
almost never go
the way we planned.
- This went exactly
how she planned.
She tricked me back and then
humiliated me on purpose.
I'm so stupid.
- Well, Isaac,
are we sure that--
- This was an attack.
She waited till
everybody on the floor
was gathered for group,
and then she
stood up on a chair
and yelled
that she was dumping me.
- Yeah.
Yeah, that's pretty terrible.
- And she said she was
dumping me because I was gross
and that I kiss like
I'm spitting into her mouth.
And that my breath
smells like armpits.
She said she wanted
to get back together.
Why would she do this?
- This is Dr. Reynolds
at New Amsterdam.
Yes, I'm in need
of a vascular surgeon.
I know it's last-minute,
but, uh...
Yeah, I see. Um...
Do you know
of anyone else I can call?
♪
You're the only one
in Lower Manhattan.
Right.
Okay, no Gold PPO,
but how about Silver?
Bronze? Any other metal?
No, yeah--he's open
on the table right now.
I'm looking at the man's liver.
Hi. You don't know me,
but I know your boyfriend's
sister's husband,
and they told me that--
Wait, I'm desperate here.
And I know it's bullcrap
that the only way
to save a man's life
without bankrupting him
is me cold-calling strangers,
but you're a doctor in America,
so I know you've been
standing where I am right now
and I'm asking you
doctor to doctor,
human to human,
to just drop everything
and save this guy's life.
Please.
Yeah, yeah, sure,
if something opens up.
Okay.
- Okay, Kyle, I just want you
to take some deep breaths
and try to relax as the toxins
are leaving your body.
- You can't steal from me.
- I took a calzone.
- My patient.
It is unacceptable.
I'm upstairs trying
to figure out a diagnosis,
and you're down here laying
a tea party out on his back.
- It's called cupping.
- Yeah.
Well, what it is not
called is medicine.
Give me one good reason
why I shouldn't
report you to the board.
- 'Cause I didn't
steal your patient.
He requested
to be transferred to me.
- Why would he do that?
- Because his doctors
keep trying to figure out
if he has this kind of MS
or that kind of infection,
and all he wants
is to feel better.
But I have some good news.
The tea party is working.
It's triggering
some muscle relaxation,
and he's actually feeling
really good right now.
- That is good news.
Sorry.
- It's okay.
It's not like you
ripped my head off
and spat down my throat
just because we disagreed.
- Wait.
Um...
I've had a really hard stretch.
And, uh...
the things that I used to
rely on to get me through...
Well, they're, um...
turns out
they're not so sustainable.
So I'm lashing out.
I guess I need a new crutch.
Not doing so hot
with the old ones.
- Do you know what a crutch is?
- I think so.
But you know what,
I've embarrassed myself enough.
So I'm gonna let you tell me.
- It's leaning on something
instead of fixing
what's really wrong.
And I only know that because
that was me for a long time.
But, the big irony is,
you think
you're skipping the feelings,
but you're
just prolonging them.
They're still in there
waiting to be let out.
I think the toxins
came out.
- What is that?
- That is the best calzone
on the Lower East Side.
I think I know
what's really wrong with him.
♪
- Ifs...
N...
no...
But...buts.
- Hey.
- Hi.
W-why...
- Oh, yeah, you weren't
answering my texts, and...
Oh, yeah, sorry.
You're in the zone.
I get it.
But your doctor, I bumped
into her in the hallway.
I think
she wanted me to be here.
- Mm.
You, um...
Bus...y.
- No, no, I'm not too busy
for you ever.
Come on,
let's get in there.
- Go.
- Go?
Why?
- Go.
- Helen,
I don't presume to understand
what you're going through,
but I am trying.
And your doctor wants me--
I wanna be here, okay?
I wanna be here
to support you.
- You...
no...
mm.
S...port.
- How can you say that?
- You no...
S-s-see m--
- I don't see you?
What are you talking about?
Of course I see you.
W-w-what...
you...
s-s-see?
- I see the most incredible
person I've ever seen.
I see someone who's strong
and amazing and brave.
Fail.
- No, no, don't say that.
- B-broken.
- You're not broken, Helen.
That's ridiculous.
You're not broken.
- You...
see...
mm...
Perfect.
- I love you.
I love you.
And I'm always
gonna love you, even if--
- N-not...
better...
E--hm.
Ev--ever?
- Mm-hmm.
- Say--
- I'm still gonna love you.
No matter what,
doesn't matter.
Even if--
Even if.
But...you will get better.
I'm not giving up on that.
Are you?
- You two ready?
- Lea...ving.
♪
- And Mr. Azad's margins
are clear.
- Dr. Loh,
you are a literal lifesaver.
Thank God Floyd got to you.
- It was a near miss.
I had a conflict,
but he's covering for me,
so it all worked out.
- What was the conflict?
- "Flowers for Algernon."
What a book.
Yes?
- What were the flowers
supposed to symbolize?
- Right, uh...
- Celiac disease?
- Yeah.
- Yes.
- Not MS?
- No.
- But my famous calzones...
- Are making you sick.
- But not because
they're not delicious.
It's the gluten.
Your immune system
is treating it as a threat.
- The inflammation it's
causing is what's triggering
your numbness,
weakness, the rashes--
symptoms almost always
associated with MS.
- I'm so sorry, Kyle.
- Why would you be sorry
that he doesn't have MS?
- 'Cause it's hard to accept
when something you love
is hurting you.
- Are you kidding?
It's great.
I finally have a way
to put daylight
between me
and those other Kyles.
Gluten-free calzones.
It sounds so classy I'll be
able to charge whatever I want.
♪
- Hey, great job
on that diagnosis.
- Something I love
is hurting me.
I'm just not really sure
how to let it out.
How can I help?
♪
- Juliet, come on.
I know you're in there.
We need to talk about
what you did to Isaac.
- Fine.
Just get it over with.
- Look,
I know that he hurt you,
and I know that that stings.
But that does not give you
the right to hurt him back,
no matter how bad you want to.
No, no,
that's not gonna work on me.
- I'm not trying to do it!
They just keep coming.
They won't stop.
It's so annoying!
What is happening?
- I think that
it's because deep down,
you still care a lot
for Isaac.
- Well, duh.
Of course I do.
- Why do you think
you hurt him then?
- I was really, really happy
when we got back together.
And I thought
everything was gonna be
the same as it was before.
But he was different with me.
He was distant,
and I knew it was only a matter
of time before I got dumped.
So I wanted to win
before I lost again.
- Hmm.
Wow, that must
have felt strange...
first time winning felt bad.
- It's my own fault.
- How so?
- I'm callous-unemotional.
I'm not supposed to be happy
with someone else.
I'm clinically predisposed
to be alone,
and these feelings prove it.
- Holy moly, did you ever
get this one wrong.
- You making fun of me?
- No.
Feeling like
you're doomed to be alone?
That you screwed things up
so badly
with the one person for you
that you're never
gonna be happy again?
These are big emotions
that everyone feels
when they get broken up with.
Juliet, these are
the most recognizable emotions
you've ever shared with me.
- Really?
- Yes, really.
But you know what I think
these tears mean?
I think they mean
you're getting better.
- I move to immediately
dismiss Veronica Fuentes
as Medical Director
of New Amsterdam.
Can I get a second?
- Hi--
You started without me?
Hi, everybody.
- Veronica, welcome.
You are just in time to take
a vote on your termination.
- Mm, shame.
Well, I guess I could just
make it easier on everybody
and hand in my resignation.
- Wow, that would be great.
- But before I do that,
I would like to make
one final proposal.
I would like to acquire
Urgent Medicine Inc.
You see, there's this little
buyout option in the contract,
and call me crazy,
but Max's very weird
and rather ugly
grandstanding today
actually created
a beautiful opportunity for us.
But I want to be very clear--
this is not just a PR win.
This is a huge
financial gain for us
because once we bring back
our former patients,
plus UMI's,
we will be netting
approximately--ooh, let's see,
hmm, maybe about
$3 million a month,
give or take.
I'm sorry, I--who
still wants me to resign?
♪
What happened?
- How do you beat
greed personified?
You give her something to buy.
- She took the bait?
She bought UMI?
- Veronica just bought herself
a Trojan horse.
We are in.
♪
- ♪ Trust me when I say
that I understand ♪
♪ That believin' in nothing
is a lead heavy hand ♪
♪
♪ That the fate of the water
resolves in the sand ♪
♪
- Ignatius Frome?
- Yes, hi.
Iggy, just call me Iggy.
- Is your husband joining us?
- No, no, I told him not to.
You know,
I was making this about us,
and I think it's really me
that has the work to do, so...
- This way.
- ♪ When you sit down
to play ♪
♪
♪ So you stand
in the doorway ♪
♪ And wait for a change
♪
♪ Wishin' that every piece
was for something ♪
♪ But if nothing is sacred,
then nothing is lost ♪
- You know,
I wouldn't have taken your car.
- Why not?
- It was your father's.
- ♪ Keeping you down
♪ Then we'll fight
a little harder ♪
♪ And find another way
around ♪
♪ 'Cause if nothing is sacred,
then nothing is lost ♪
♪ And I'm in your corner
whatever the cost ♪
♪ If the fists that are flying
are keeping you down ♪
♪ Then we'll fight
a little harder ♪
- Hi, I'm, uh,
trying to track down
an employee
who worked there some time ago.
- ♪ If the fists that are
flying are keeping you down ♪
♪ We'll fight
a little harder ♪
♪ And find another
way around ♪
- Hey.
"I should have let you
come to my session."
"I was ashamed and embarrassed
"and scared.
"But this is where I am.
This is my journey."
- W-w-will...
y-y-you...
cuh--
- Always.
-...come?
- No ifs, ands, or buts.
Say it with me.
Come on.
- Now?
- Yeah.
Now, come on.
We'll make it fun.
It'll be like
a strip poker version.
Ready? Here we go.
No ifs, ands, or buts.
Your turn.
- No...
ifs...
nan--
- And, no, sorry.
That's a mistake.
So that's gonna
cost you a shirt.
Let's go, shirt off.
I'm waiting.
I got all day.
Here we go.
No ifs, ands, or buts.
Easy, okay?
You got it.
- No ifs,
ands,
or...mm...buts.
So good.
- No...
ifs...
ands or...
- Yeah.
- Buts.
- Don't stop now.
- No...
ifs...
ands...
or buts.
How good is that?
That's amazing.
I knew you could do it.
But your shirt is still on,
and you made
a very big mistake,
so I'm gonna need
that shirt off.
♪