Carter. Carter!
Carter, wake up!
Yeah.
GSW. To the head coming in.
Benton's in surgery,
and Greene's got an MI.
Carter!
What?!
Let's go!
Oh, God.
Ouch!
Put a .357 in his mouth
and pulled the trigger.
It isn't pretty.
Two large bore
IVs, 15 liters O2.
BP's 80/50... Ready?
One, two, three!
Cynotic. Blood loss?
At least a liter.
Where's Benton?
He's still with
that knife wound.
Hey, we need a doctor in here!
There's no gray matter up here.
Pupils mid-range and sluggish.
Today's my last day.
Where's his face?
Left it on the dining room wall.
Oh, sweet Jesus!
Oh, God!
Ma'am? Ma'am, please.
I didn't think he knew
where I kept my gun.
Okay. Pulse ox 70.
He's going to need an airway.
You've done it.
I've only watched.
Get somebody down here now.
Who? If they've got on
a white coat, tackle them.
Oh, boy. I hope medical
malpractice covers this, huh?
Okay. 7.5 ET Tube.
Suction.
No, no... Damn it,
I can't see a thing.
Bag him.
PCO-2's 60.
PO-2's 55.
PH is 7.20.
Wet rales, diminished
breath sounds.
Where the hell is everybody?!
He's hypoxic as
hell. He needs a crike.
I can't do it. Really, I can't.
Well, somebody do something.
All right. Get the crike tray.
Versed, Norcuron?
No, no, no, no.
If I paralyze him,
I don't get the
crike, then he dies.
Okay, drape. Drape!
Could someone please
hand me a sterile drape!
Is that the membrane? Mm-hmm.
Horizontal or vertical?
Horizontal. No...
vertical skin incision first,
then cut horizontally
through the membrane.
I'm sure.
Thyroid's got to be
in there somewhere.
Okay, horizontal.
All right, Carter,
give me the bullet.
14-Year-old with a
self-inflicted GSW. To the mouth.
He's had four units.
BP's 70/50. Uh... pulse is 54.
Tried to intubate him,
but there was too much
blood and tissue
occluding his airway.
Just about to start a
crike thyroid on him.
All right, all right.
You paralyze him?
No. Good boy, good boy.
All right.
Skin hook.
Come on, come
on. 6.0 Trach tube.
Let's move.
Call radiology, let them know
he's on his way with a CT.
Bag him.
Come on. Let's move.
All right, let's pack it.
Stop all this bleeding.
So you were going
to do the crike?
Yeah.
Huh.
All right. Malik?
Yo.
Get head and neck out of bed.
This is their lucky day. Got it.
Wrong choice?
Nope. All right,
come on, people,
let's go, let's get him up,
let's get him up, move.
Last day, right?
All right, don't forget to turn
in your lab coat and your ID.
You'll get your deposit back.
Chloe, you need
to do the laundry.
The detergent's
in the closet, okay?
Oh, my God.
Chloe, can you hear me? Please?
She's finally asleep.
Were you up all
night again? Sorry.
Oh, gosh, I hope it stops
raining before the wedding.
I don't think I'm
going to make it.
Yes.
Chloe, yes, you are.
I'm not strong enough, Suz.
Chloe, you're doing great.
Listen. I'm already
running late.
Please do the laundry.
The machines are
in the basement.
The wedding starts at 5:00,
so I have to be
back here by 3:00.
Start getting ready, okay?
Bye, little one.
3:00.
3:00, Right?
Yeah.
Car TC, no seat belt.
Complain of chest pains
Somebody give
me a damn cigarette!
IV started.
Well, go see her.
Tell her how you feel.
Well, I'd have to
know how I feel.
Oh.
Yeah. Oh.
Maybe it's for the best.
Except for Jake.
Yeah, yeah.
Well, except for Rachel.
Yes.
Who are they?
Ah, new meat...
medical students.
This way, children. Follow me.
Mark, a drunk MVA in Trauma One.
Carter, the attempted suicide's
mother's still down here.
Get her up to the
OR waiting room.
How is he?
Tell her he's in surgery.
I'm sorry to hear
about your mother.
Yeah, thanks.
Carter, I need your
course evaluation by noon.
My what? Course evaluation.
Your assessment of
your E.R. trauma rotation.
I get to grade you?
Just get a form from Rolando
and put it in Dr. Hicks's box.
Is he joking? Nope.
Oh, there is a God.
Pulse is thready
at 120, resps 36.
She's shocky, 70/50.
Hit a parked
car... no seat belt.
Bent the steering
wheel of her Buick.
Name's Bonnie Curtis.
No sign of head trauma.
Pulse ox is 85.
Glucose is normal at 110.
Bonnie? Bonnie, do
you know where you are?
Whew, God!
Ooh, she's drunk.
Oh, yeah.
I need a cigarette.
Bonnie, do you
know where you are?
Somebody, get me
a damn cigarette!
CBC, chem 7,
cardiac enzymes, EKG.
Blood alcohol?
I need a cigarette.
Sure. Get a chest and a
cross table C-spine going now.
"The resident helped you
achieve competency
with procedures."
Yes, he did.
That's a four.
"The resident made himself
available to answer questions."
No. Two?
I'd go for a one.
Really? Seems kind of harsh.
We're talking about Benton here.
One.
"The resident provided you
with constructive comments
and criticism of
your performance."
Constructive.
Do they have negative numbers?
There's a zero.
Hey, hey, hey.
Zero it is.
That's it.
What's the total?
Sixteen.
Out of a possible...?
Forty.
Hmm. Maybe I ought to go
a little easier on him, huh?
He had to turn in his
evaluation of you last week.
16 it is.
Where's Dr. Hicks's box?
What have we got?
Single car accident.
No seat belt.
Hit the steering wheel. Drunk.
He's shocky, but
I'm not sure why.
Internal bleeding?
Abdomen's soft, nontender.
No rebound or guarding.
Normal bowel sounds.
Pulse ox is 85,
but she's a smoker.
PO2's 70 on room air.
Resps are high.
No widened
mediastinum or apical cap.
Ruptured aorta
is highly unlikely.
Could be a mild
myocardial contusion or MI.
I'm thinking pulmonary embolus.
Resps are high, tachy, low PO2.
This woman is drunk
at 7:00 in the morning.
It's probably just
alcoholic cardiomyopathy.
I'd like to get a VQ scan.
You're grasping at straws.
Give her thiamine,
folate, multi-vits.
Rehydrate her with D5 NS.
Support her pressure
with dopamine
and then admit her to telemetry
for serial EKGs and enzymes.
Get her to Radiology
and get a VQ scan.
Do Swift's orders
and scan her anyway.
Hi, Caleb.
I'm Dr. Ross.
This is Dr. Carter,
and you have a fever.
101. No cough,
no abdominal pain.
Mm-hmm. I feel okay.
He just finished
a round of chemo.
Look for a bacterial
focus of the infection.
You been around any sick people?
It's probably just the Hickman.
That's what happened last time.
Catheter? Is it sore?
Yeah. It's always sore.
It's no big deal.
Sarah just freaks out.
I was scared, Caleb.
Did you call your parents
and tell them you're here?
Now, Sarah did the right thing.
After chemo, your body
doesn't want to fight infection.
CBC plus differential,
blood cultures times three,
urine culture,
throat swab, a chest film.
What else, Dr. Carter?
I'd do an LP.
I don't want a spinal tap!
I just had one. I don't
need another one.
Why a tap, Carter?
Irritability, and/or lethargy
are early signs of meningitis.
Yes, see, the
deal is this, Caleb:
You're not lethargic,
but you are irritable.
Now, that could either
be a sign of meningitis
or just your personality.
So, I tell you what
we're gonna do:
We're gonna wait
a couple of minutes,
take a look at some tests
and if you're still
being a pain in the ass,
then we're going to
give you the tap, okay?
Broad-spectrum antibiotics?
Mm-hmm, yep.
Gentamicin, 80mgs
Oxacillin, one
gram, Piperacillin,
1.5 grams, IV,
and find out who's
on call for oncology.
Peter.
Hey.
Hi.
I called you.
You, uh, you get my messages?
Yeah, I'm sorry. I've
been working a lot.
Yeah. And you really
shouldn't call me at home.
Uh... we need to talk.
All right.
Lunch?
All right. We'll talk.
Yeah.
Okay. See you then.
You paged me, Doctor.
Saddle embolus.
You ordered
pulmonary angiography.
Yes.
Before or after you went
ahead and scanned her?
BP Was falling,
increased respiratory rate,
rising PCO-2,
falling PO-2 and pH.
S-one, Q-three on the EKG.
Did you book an O.R.?
Mm-hmm.
Well, what are you waiting for?
Go ahead, move her!
Go! Go!
Good work.
Thanks.
We got served today
on your pre-eclampsia.
Malpractice suit.
Jody O'Brien?
Yeah. Wrongful death, pain
and suffering... the usual.
What, you didn't
think they would?
Wasn't sure.
Oh. Come see me later.
We'll talk it out.
Get some blood culture, Bonnie.
What medications are
you taking, Mr. Allison?
DDC, Bactrim, AZT,
Fluconazole and Rifabutin.
Let's start hydration
with D5 NS, 300cc's.
Susan, what do you got?
End-stage AIDS patient.
Multiple meds, temp 101, tachy.
"History of GI lymphoma,
PCP pneumonia, Kaposi's
AIDS dementia, oral thrush,
cryptococcal meningitis."
He has high-pitched bowel sounds
tenderness, distention,
hepatosplenomegaly
positive guaiac, no
recent stool or gas.
He's vomiting blood and bile.
Started a 300cc fluid challenge.
Okay, let's get a
KUB, lateral decubitus,
chest films, blood
cultures times three
including microbacteria,
fungal and CMV,
CBC, chem 24, urine, and
let's get an NG tube down now.
He's all yours.
All right.
Morphine four IV.
We suspect he has
a bowel obstruction
from enlarged lymph nodes
due to recurrent lymphoma.
This is Dr. Benton.
He's the surgical resident.
Oh. Is-is he going
to need surgery?
Maybe.
We'll try drugs
and hydration first.
Thanks.
All right, let's get
some Neupogen.
300 mikes to stimulate
neutrophil growth.
See if we can't
get some of those
good white blood
cells going again, huh?
I know what neutrophils are.
Do I have to stay
in the hospital?
Well, it's too early to say.
We're going to have wait
and see if you respond
to the antibiotics.
Let me know how he's
doing in a couple of hours.
Okay. Dr. Carter is going
to keep an eye on you
and I'll be back, all right?
Last time I got a rash
from the antibiotics.
Do you need anything?
You don't have to leave, too?!
He's just trying
to be nice, Caleb.
Shut up, fat Sarah!
Hey.
No, actually, I don't
have to be anywhere.
Today is my last day.
I can be anywhere I want.
Okay. See you later.
I'm bored.
Well, I could get you
a VCR from Pediatrics.
You could watch a video.
I don't want to watch TV.
I'm sick of TV.
Last chance.
Suit yourself.
Temp's 102.
BP's still 70/50.
We're not seeing much
progress, Mr. Warren.
Do you have power of attorney
to make decisions for Mr. Thomas
in situations like this?
I don't know; his mother does.
We should call her.
I already have.
What do you want to do?
Well, if the bowel
obstruction doesn't clear,
we're going to
resolve with surgery.
A colostomy?
Yes.
Yeah. We've had a lot
of friends go though this.
How soon can his
mother get here?
What? Can it wait?
Not long, no.
I'll, uh, I'll go
call her again.
Hey! Thought you
were a bridesmaid.
On my way out.
So it's a late
afternoon wedding?
As if you didn't know.
Got an unconscious
geezer in Two.
Four martini lunch
I'm already off.
With a belly ache in Five.
Carter, I got a drunk in Five.
Whatever happened
to the practice
of Pediatrics around here?
Carter...
I turned in my course
evaluation this morning.
It is in Dr. Hicks's box.
Yeah, yeah, fine.
Look, Wilkins decided
to take the orthopedic sub-I,
so the surgical
sub-I is left open.
Left us hanging.
You want it or not?
In the E.R.?
Yeah. Look, I mean,
hurry. Yes or no?
I got it?! Carter...
Yeah, yeah, I
want it, I want it.
Definitely want it.
Okay, okay, okay.
September 5, 5:00 a.m.
Don't be late. Okay, thank you!
Oh, oh...
Excuse me.
Get drunk for me.
Free champagne?
You can count on it.
Rolando!
What?
What happened to all the
stuff that was in Dr. Hicks's box?
My course evaluation that I
turned in this morning is gone!
She cleaned out her
box a couple minutes ago.
It finally stopped
raining? Hours ago.
Have fun!
You know we will, girl.
Is there anybody who
isn't going to this wedding?
Just us... the sick,
the lame, the uninvited.
Oh, I'm a dead man.
Ah, here it is.
Do I need an attorney?
The hospital will handle it.
My wife's an attorney.
She may want someone
to take a look at
it independently.
It's your money.
Thanks.
Is that it?
No. I've decided
to take a chance.
Sign off on you as
attending for next year.
Show of appreciation
is customary.
I have to talk to my wife.
Fair enough.
I'll need to know by tomorrow.
Thank you.
I didn't get a chance
to say good-bye.
She knew, Peter.
Yeah, but look, we...
Sorry.
I can't do this.
Do what?
I like you, Peter,
but I-I... I don't know.
I think this is
about your mother.
Hmm.
We'd like to think that, huh?
Chloe, I am so late.
Could you grab a
half-slip and some-some...
hose out of, out of, uh...
Gosh, I, uh... I think
they're in the second drawer.
Oh, Chloe, I asked
you to do the laundry.
I don't even have a dry towel.
Chloe.
Chloe?
Of course. Perfect.
Oh, my...
Oh, yeah. It's okay.
It's all right, it's all right.
Shh...
Yes?
Dr. Hicks?
Hi. I'm John Carter.
I'm Dr. Benton's student.
Come on in, Carter.
I turned in my course evaluation
from my trauma
rotation this morning
and I was wondering
if I might get it back to
make some revisions.
Yes. I've read it.
A 16.
Sounds like you had a
disappointing experience.
Uh...
Would you like to hear
what he said about you?
Sure.
Ah. "Carter, John Truman.
"An exceptional student.
"Well-trained,
"superior diagnostic skills
"fast learner,
dedicated, selfless.
"Excellent bedside
manner with patients.
"Far more successful at dealing
"with the patients' emotional
needs than this instructor.
Highly intelligent."
Want to hear more?
It concludes, "one
of the finest students
"I've ever had the
opportunity to work with.
Recommend high honors."
He gave me high honors?
I was upset because he
didn't give me the surgery sub-I.
Did he tell you
Wilkins had dropped
out and you had
the surgical sub-I?
So you came up
here to get this back.
This is what you really
thought of Dr. Benton's
supervision?
No, no, no. I mean, He was
hard on me and demanding,
but I learned a lot.
Why don't you take another
crack at this evaluation.
Thank you.
And Carter, I don't want it back
at a 40.
Be honest, fair.
Right. Uh... 38 okay?
Yeah, something like that.
♪ I'll give you ever so many ♪
♪ But baby, do go to sleep ♪
♪ Bye-bye, my babykin, bye ♪
♪ Why won't you
shut your eyes? ♪
♪ Bye-bye, my babykin, bye ♪
♪ Why won't you
shut your eyes? ♪
Mrs. Allison?
Hi. I'm Dr. Benton.
We need your permission
to perform an
emergency colostomy.
The lymphoma?
This would be a very difficult
and painful way for him to die.
It can't be any worse
than what he's
already been through.
I won't put him through it.
Okay.
We'll, uh, we'll try to make
him as comfortable as possible
and maybe the current treatment
will resolve the obstruction.
Four more morphine IV.
Marjorie decided against
the surgery, didn't she?
Yeah.
Yeah, I knew she would.
It's what Thomas
would have wanted.
That's why he chose
her instead of me.
He knew I wouldn't
have the strength.
Um... can I take him home?
I... I wouldn't.
If he does regain
consciousness, it could be rough.
Here, we can manage his pain.
You know, we-we've
already said our good-byes.
But I-I guess you're
never really ready.
Well...
back to the deathwatch.
Yeah.
Mr. Hahn, I'm Dr. Ross.
Is Caleb going to be okay?
How's his temperature, Wendy?
Down to 99.
It's not the chemo, Mr. Hahn.
His white blood cells look fine.
Caleb has a temperature,
we think, from an infection.
The antibiotics
seem to be working,
but we'll keep him for a
few hours just to make sure.
Mr. Hahn, there's a call from
a Dr. Bernstein on line two.
You can take it out here.
Our oncologist.
Mm-hmm. Okay. I'm going
to check back in a little bit.
Why don't you and your daughter
get something to eat,
bring it back for Caleb.
Cheeseburger and
fries, am I right?
Right.
Be right back.
Still bored?
What do you think?
Mortal Kombat.
I stole it from a
hemophiliac in Pediatrics.
You stole it?
Rented it, really.
Cost me ten bucks.
But I'm pretty good,
and it's got to be more
fun than sitting here,
feeling sorry for yourself.
Come on. You can
be anybody you want.
Johnny cage.
What?
I get to be Johnny cage.
Okay, right.
I thought you said
you knew how to play.
I do, I do. I just, I just know
them more by their colors.
Dime a match.
How much is that
going to cost me?
Depends on if you
really know how to play.
All right, you're on.
Mark.
Hi, everybody.
Mark, Jennifer, could
you take the baby, please?
Don't ask.
The bottle's in the pouch
and I just changed her, okay?
Where's Chloe?
Who knows?
I got to go.
I'm sorry.
Chloe stuck me with the baby.
How do I look?
Like a big peach snow cone.
Oh, oh, oh, here she comes.
She looks beautiful.
Carol.
Come on, girlfriend.
I think this dress cost more
than both of my weddings.
Oh, carol.
So?
You look great.
Oh, God, I'm really nervous.
Time to seat the bride's mother.
I'm not going to cry.
Now, remember, not too
many petals at once, okay?
I know how to do it.
You all set, Carol?
Yep. Uncle Mikhel, you're on.
Oh.
Well, Father, we're all set.
Let's go.
Yep. All we need
now is the groom.
How's Thomas doing?
Temp's up to 103.
BP is 65/50.
Tag, what are you doing?
It's beautiful here, isn't it?
Yeah, it is.
Tag, we've got a whole church
full of our friends
and family waiting.
Are you scared?
A little.
Me, too.
I was thinking that maybe
you don't love me enough.
Tag, I love you.
Do you really?
I was waiting in the sacristy
and I was thinking that
you really don't love me,
that I've known it all along,
and I've just been
kidding myself.
I wouldn't be marrying
you if I didn't love you.
I wake up every
morning and I thank God
for bringing you into my life.
I wake up in the middle
of the night sometimes
just to watch you sleep.
When we're at the
movies and your hand
brushes against mine,
I can hardly breathe.
Do you love me like that, Carol?
If you care at all about
me, please tell me the truth.
No.
I don't.
But I do love you, Tag,
and I want to be with you.
Thank you.
After 6:00.
Should be Dr. And
Mrs. Taglieri by now.
Connie, did anyone ever tell you
you're a truly evil person?
Somebody's waiting for you.
I can't, I got to look in
on a patient in Three.
He's been waiting awhile.
Was it something I did?
No, you didn't do anything.
You were great.
This is all me.
Well, maybe we can fix it.
I don't think so.
We can try.
Jake, look, I did something bad.
I hurt your mother, okay?
What did you do?
Come here. Sit down.
Sit down.
I know that you think
that I'm a... a good guy,
but I'm not really.
I... don't know why I hurt
people sometimes, and...
I did something
with another woman
that I shouldn't have done
and your mother
found out about it
and now she doesn't want
me to come around anymore.
Oh.
You and I can't hang out.
I never meant to hurt... you.
I mean, I...
The one with the nice
clothes and all the hair?
Yeah, um... the
one with all the hair.
I'm sorry, buddy.
I got to go.
My mom would be mad
if she knew I was here.
Show me the thing...
how you do the thing
where they rip
the guy's head off
and they set him on fire.
Up, right, kick,
kick, down, block.
Wait, up, up...
Up, right, down, down, kick.
Die, you bastard!
Yes! Triple power move...
and a fatality!
You're pretty
rough on your sister.
You've got A-L-L, right?
My brother Bobby had leukemia.
Yeah?
Mm-hmm.
He used to pick
on me all the time.
Come up and hit me
when I wasn't expecting
it for no reason.
Come on!
Yeah, he... he hated
my mom for babying him.
He just wanted to
be a regular kid, so...
so he took it out on me.
He was just, um... pretending
he could still do
everything that he used to,
but...
he couldn't.
Your turn.
Did he make it?
Um... no.
No, he died.
But he had AML, which is a...
is a lot harder to beat.
It was a long time ago.
Medicines are
a lot better now...
and the kids are a lot tougher.
Where's Carol?
Talking to her mother.
How is she?
We confiscated her
shoelaces and belt.
Somebody ought to shoot him.
Amen.
What do you think they're
going to do with all that food?
Probably give it to a
shelter or something.
Yeah, but shelter?
Alkies can barely keep down
a peanut butter sandwich.
How the hell are they gonna
hold on to lobster Newburg?
They got lobster?
Big ones... size of your head.
You guys are going to eat?
They're not gonna miss
a couple plates' worth.
Mommy, I'm hungry.
Come on, Rach.
Mark...
She's hungry.
Anybody want a drink?
Uh-huh.
Gin and tonic.
Chivas straight up.
You in one piece?
Yeah, never been better.
So I thought I was
having a bad day.
What's that?
Oh, they went ahead
with the reception.
You know my family.
What's a little humiliation
when there's free
food and drink?
What's wrong with me?
Why can't I fall in
love with a nice guy?
Someone who loves me,
who wants to be with me,
who's honest and decent?
Hmm...
And boring.
God, he was dull.
All that talk about
fly-fishing and bowling
and his glory days
playing football in college.
Bowling?
Yeah.
I just want to be happy
and I'm so afraid
I never will be.
You will.
Dr. Benton?
I just want to say
thank you for everything.
I learned a lot.
Have a good summer.
You, too.
Carter...
You're going to
make a good doctor.
Thanks.
♪ So good ♪
♪ 'Cause I got you... ♪
Yeah! All right!
Carol!
Carol.
Speech!
Come on. Speech!
Oh, please.
Speech! Speech! Speech!
Speech! Speech! Speech! Okay.
Speech! Speech!
Oh, I'm sure all this is
going to hit me tomorrow.
Wait till you get the bar bill.
No, no. That's going to Tag.
I don't know what to say.
I don't know what
the future holds,
but I guess I'm
just lucky to be alive
and to have so many good
friends who care for me.
It's been a wonderful year
because of all of you.
May I have a dance?
You bet.
Music!
We need music!
♪ ♪
Oh.
Go.
Oh, okay.
Dance.
♪ Tequila! ♪
Yeah. Well, sure, you can wait,
but by then, he might be dead.
And I need your ID badge.
Dr. Carter?
Hey, Sarah.
I thought you guys left.
What you did for
my brother today...
I hope that just
once in my life,
I can make a
difference like that
in someone else's life.
Thanks.
No, Sarah, thank you.
What's this?
Your deposit... the lab coat.
Hey, don't be a stranger, okay?
Come by and see us sometime.
No, I'm, uh... coming
back in the fall.
All right. I'll see you then.
E.R.
Okay, what have we got?
15-year-old GSW. To the head.
Tried to hold up a 7-Eleven.
Ten liters 02, BP's 90/60,
pulse 120.
We started two large bore IVs...
Captioning sponsored
by WARNER BROS.