Morning, doc.
Good morning, Kenny.
Hey, hey, hey.
Brosef, your cable's out.
I don't have cable.
- I have a digital antenna.
- Why?
Digital antennae
receive superior picture
and sound quality, and
the channels are free.
Yeah, but you only get,
like, 10 channels that way.
I only watch three.
You mind if I run
a line to your tube?
Cable guy can't fit
me in till next week.
Mmm-hmm...
Come on, 10 channels
are better than none.
- Yes, they are.
- All right. Gracias, amigo.
What?
Mmm...
Dr. Reznick was orphaned
once Dr. Coyle was transferred,
so she'll be joining our team.
Hi. I'm Claire.
Nice to meet you.
- Are you the autistic one?
- No.
That's me.
- Dr. Shaun Murphy.
- Mmm, hi.
We've got two pretty
straightforward cases,
nice level playing
field for an eager group.
- Not interested.
- Competition can foster teamwork.
Which can lead to a greater
understanding and appreciation
of residents' strengths and
weaknesses and improve patient care.
You're playing the same
game Glassman had us do
when we were
interns. Not interested.
Winning team gets first dibs on
assisting on all surgeries next week.
- In.
- Out.
Mmm-hmm...
I pick the boy genius.
That's you.
Dr. Browne.
- Kalu.
- Dr. Reznick.
Thank you. I'm
looking forward to it.
Thank you.
Same stakes as last time?
Absolutely.
Hi, Quinn. We hear you've
had some stomach pain.
Do you mind if we take a look?
It doesn't hurt that bad.
Poor thing says
everything is okay,
but when Quinnie didn't
want to go swimming today,
I knew that something
must be wrong.
We'll be as gentle
with her as possible.
Quinn's parents are out of
town, so I, I flew in to babysit.
Mmm-hmm.
Okay. Let's see.
- That's a...
- Penis.
She's not a girl. He's a boy.
- It's just a phase.
- Stop saying that.
I'm not a boy. I'm a girl.
- You're transgender?
- Yes.
No. Quinn has XY
chromosomes like Jared and me,
not XX like you.
Science says he's male.
No, Quinn has gender dysphoria.
Her assigned gender is not
the one she identifies with.
She's mismatched, Dr. Murphy.
- But biologically...
- Other than biologically...
How do you know you're
supposed to be a boy?
Your question doesn't make sense.
I'm not supposed to be anything.
I am a boy.
Biologically, that's it.
Okay, deep tenderness
at McBurney's point.
Could be acute appendicitis.
Murphy, get imaging to confirm.
Mmm.
Mr. Shaw, your chart says
that you passed out in class.
- What do you teach?
- History.
I got a little dizzy because
I skipped breakfast.
Uh, it's nothing. The school
insisted on calling an ambulance.
Taken any medications
in the last few months?
Uh, I took some Vicodin after I
threw out my back six weeks ago,
and then I had a stomach
flu, so I took ofloxacin.
But the flu part didn't totally
go away, so I took azithromycin
and prednisone because
my glands were swollen.
Uh, but I still had a sore
throat, so I took some Cipro.
What doctor
prescribed you all that?
They were leftovers I had
in my medicine cabinet.
- Uh...
- All right, lay back for me.
Look, I'm a single
dad with twins
who bring home every disgusting
germ they touch at preschool.
Uh, I can't afford to miss work.
You've got a fever
and you've gone through two IVs,
which tells me that you're
severely dehydrated.
You can't stand me touching your
stomach without wincing in pain.
Dr. Reznick, let's get
Mr. Shaw here an ultrasound.
- We've been trying for a while.
- Five months.
I realize my prime egg
days were two decades ago,
but I've been vigilant.
Ovulation kits, LH and FSH
testing, basal body temp.
I've checked my
estradiol and AMH levels.
The old-fashioned
way wasn't working.
Okay, well, there are a lot
of possibilities to consider.
Many benign, many
easily corrected.
So I will take some
samples from you both,
run some tests,
we go from there.
There's a clock.
We need to know if
we start with IUI or IVF...
Both of you, you
need to stop worrying.
Isabel, you are not the
first 40-something woman
to come here and
ask these questions.
Myself included.
You came to me
because you trust me, yes?
Right. So let me do what I do,
and you two focus on each other.
Hey.
We're a team, babe.
In this together, all right?
Okay.
I'm afraid, Howard, your
appendix has already ruptured.
Book an OR stat
and page Melendez.
Wait. I need to figure out who's
gonna take care of my kids,
call the school, so they
can get subs for my classes.
Mr. Shaw, if we don't
get you into surgery now
your infection could spread
and you could become septic.
Dr. Browne will make all
the necessary phone calls
while I prep you for surgery.
Isn't that so, Dr. Browne?
You're in good hands,
Mr. Shaw. We've got you covered.
Let's go.
Hello.
- Do you wear dresses?
- Murphy, don't.
Quinn is a boy who
thinks he's a girl.
I want to know
why he thinks that.
Sometimes I wear dresses,
but sometimes I wear leggings.
Do you like the color pink?
I'm more of a purple girl.
Do you play with dolls?
Since I was five, but
I'm super into mermaids.
- Do you take dance?
- Murphy, 20 questions are up.
I only asked four.
- Do you wear perfume?
- It doesn't matter.
- The CT's ready. Let's go.
- Do you always paint your nails?
Let's go.
Perforated appendix is out.
Lavage or no lavage, Dr. Browne?
Lavage before closing the wound
decreases residual fluid accumulation
and minimizes
residual contamination.
Claire's right. Although, a recent
study documented a higher abscess rate
when irrigation was used
for perforated appendicitis.
Well, someone
did their homework.
I'm partial to AMSURG
since they published me.
As a medical student?
It was about the cost and
stabilization of disease in patients
undergoing transcatheter and
surgical aortic valve replacement.
Are you thinking of
specializing in cardio-thoracic?
A girl can dream.
Staple up and close up.
Well,
it's, uh, it's good to have
you on board, Morgan.
It's great to have
another female surgeon.
Oh, uh...
I'm sorry, you and I
are not gonna be friends,
and hanging out, having
sleepovers, braiding each other's hair.
That's not exactly
where I was going with it.
When residency's over,
the hospital's likely
only keeping two of us.
Shaun is Glassman's
pet project, so he's in.
Jared is persona
non grata, so he's out.
Which means every time
you win, I lose. And vice versa.
Thanks for the heads up.
Do you think he's
complicated or confused?
Dude, you've got to
quit calling her a "he."
We're never going
to win this competition
with you disrespecting
our patient.
Don't they have transgender
people in Wyoming?
Okay. Transgender patient care
was not part of my
medical school curriculum.
Was it part of yours?
No.
Quinn doesn't have appendicitis.
He has testicular cancer.
She.
We found a mass
on Quinn's left testicle.
- She has cancer, but...
- Am I gonna die?
No, no. Prognosis is very good.
We've caught it
before it spread,
and we'll do surgery
on the mass to remove it.
The CT also showed
he has osteopenia.
Murphy, stop with the "he."
Uh...
- Quinnie, it's your mom. I have to...
- Of course.
Osteopenia. That's
low bone density, right?
Yeah. How'd you know that?
Do you know how I got cancer?
There are several possible
causes, but I would...
Microlithiasis,
mumps, hypospadias...
- Murphy.
- Intraepithelial germ cell neoplasia...
- Inguinal hernia, HIV...
- Murphy? Enough.
Your parents are
on their way here.
Um, they just told me... Quinn,
are you on puberty blockers?
That's the likely cause
of the osteopenia.
Are you taking
leuprorelin or histrelin?
I... I've been on
leuprorelin for nine months.
Well, why didn't you
say anything earlier?
Because my parents didn't
want my grandma to know.
Looks like he has an abscess.
You have an infection.
We'll drain it, put
you on antibiotics.
It's nothing to worry about.
It just means you might be in the
hospital a couple of extra nights.
I can't spend a
couple of extra nights.
I need to get out of here.
Are you worried about your kids?
Well, they're with
my sister, they're safe,
but they've never spent a night
without me since they were born.
Well, then consider this a blessing.
A free vacation from your kids.
They're my life.
My wife died of
ovarian cancer last year.
I, uh...
I hate hospitals.
I'm so sorry.
Why don't I find a laptop
so you can Skype with them?
And I'll rustle up a couple of toy
bears from Peds for you to take home.
Thank you.
I want to reassure you
that the puberty blockers
are in no way responsible
for causing cancer.
The leuprorelin did
cause your osteopenia.
Does this mean I have to
stop taking puberty blockers?
Yes.
We'll get you on dietary supplements
to help regain your bone strength,
but the puberty
blockers are hurting you.
You'll be fine without them.
Fine?
I don't want an Adam's
apple or a deep voice
or hair all over my body. You
can't reverse that, can you?
No, I'm afraid not.
Girls have body hair, too.
Toy bears, Skype with
kids? You've got game.
"Game"?
I believe the name for what I
did is "basic human decency."
Everyone has an agenda.
Sometimes it's conscious,
sometimes it's not, but it's always there.
And you've got this whole
"queen of kindness" thing down pat.
Awfully cynical for
someone so young.
Mmm, not cynical. Just the
reality of how the world works.
It's Howard.
He spiked a fever, temp's
105. BP's tanking, 80 over 40.
He's soiled his sheets.
Site's clean. Infection
should be clearing by now.
- What's going on?
- I don't know. Page Melendez.
Give me 500 milligrams
acetaminophen,
two grams of meropenem
IV infusion empirically.
Run a full chem panel,
CBC, and get cultures ASAP.
Hang in there, Howard.
We're gonna figure this out.
Any word on Quinn Darby's labs?
Big backup today.
Nothing much I can do.
- Text you when they're ready?
- Yeah.
Hey, Gus.
I saw raspberry and rose petal
doughnuts in the cafeteria today.
Got you the last one.
You remembered. Thank you.
Howard Shaw's labs. I
put a rush on 'em for you.
You're the best.
Why did you give Gus a doughnut?
I was being nice.
I needed my patient's labs
expedited. Gus likes doughnuts.
- It's called bribery.
- I call it "basic human decency."
See you later.
Howard has a superbug.
A c. diff infection?
It's resistant to
all medication.
Quinn's pre-op labs are normal,
so we can do the surgery
first thing in the morning.
The procedure is called a
radical inguinal orchiectomy.
It's radical in that the entire
cancerous testicle is removed.
Uh, all functionality
will remain the same.
Quinn should be able to resume her
normal activities in one or two weeks.
- See? Baby, that's good news.
- No, not really.
Without the puberty blockers,
I'll be the freak in
ballet with a mustache.
Aren't there any other options?
- I wish there were.
- If we do a bilateral orchiectomy,
Quinn will have the
testosterone level of a girl.
We are not removing
both testicles.
You want to castrate
my grandson?
- No!
- Oh...
- I'm so sorry for Dr. Murphy's outburst.
I'm gonna have gender confirmation
surgery when I'm 18 anyway.
Why not just do it now?
Quinn is a child who still plays
dress-up and make-believe.
He may want to have
children of his own someday.
Ew.
- We'll give you some privacy.
- Thank you.
- I will not allow you...
- It's not up to you.
You are making me doubt the
wisdom of drafting you, Murphy.
If you go around saying
inflammatory things to people,
it will only upset them.
How will I know if I said
something inflammatory until I say it?
Test it on Kalu first.
Which you can do while the two
of you prep an SDA for this case.
An SDA?
A Shared Decision Aid
is a paper presenting the pros
and cons of making a difficult...
I know what it is, Murphy.
But why am I being punished?
It's not a punishment,
it's necessary.
It'll help Quinn's
family understand
all the options available
to them for her care.
Understood?
Understood.
The stool culture
and sensitivity tests
indicate that you're
resistant to every antibiotic.
Which only happens when you've
been exposed to every antibiotic.
I did this to myself?
But I've used those medications
before without a problem.
Why did this happen now?
You weren't under
a doctor's care,
so you were likely taking
the wrong medication
for the wrong symptoms.
But you can fix this, right?
We're gonna have to
perform a colostomy,
where we attach an ostomy
pouching system to your abdomen
to collect waste from your body.
For how long?
Well, with the level of
damage we're seeing
throughout the
colon, indefinitely.
I'm so sorry, Howard.
I don't understand why you'd
suggest the bilateral orchiectomy
when you don't even
believe Quinn's a girl.
I was answering
Dr. Lim's question.
She said there were no
other options, but I found one.
- And now we're here.
- Yes.
You're actually enjoying
this scut work, aren't you?
Yes. We are being helpful.
We're not doing this
to be helpful, Murphy.
We're doing this because
you pissed off Lim,
and I'm collateral damage.
Okay. We're still being helpful.
Doesn't matter.
Doesn't matter,
competition's over.
Is it?
We're in here and
not with the patient.
No face time, plus you calling her
a "he", equals crappy survey scores.
It's okay. It's a game.
It's not important.
It is to me.
I'm a pariah.
These scores are part
of our resident evaluation.
Our jobs depend on them.
Mine does, at least.
Then we should do
this scut work very well.
Finola called.
She found an irregularity
with one of the tests
but wants to
re-run it to be sure.
Okay, so...
We wait until she re-runs it.
Marcus, we're both doctors.
The results aren't gonna change.
I waited too long.
It's all my fault.
This is the part where
you say, "No, babe, it isn't."
You had goals, other priorities.
You said you supported
my career choices...
- Just like I supported yours.
- I do support you. Always.
And I am so proud of you.
But it came at a cost that
we both knew was possible.
We should have
started trying sooner.
When? When you were 3,000
miles away teaching at Dartmouth?
Or, what, when you were
chasing down head of surgery?
We would have figured it out.
"Figuring it out" would have meant
me and a nanny raising a baby.
I didn't want that.
I tried to bring it
up four years ago,
but you wanted to get your
practice up and running.
A baby didn't fit in
that picture, either.
It is not the same.
How many pregnant
women get hired for anything?
Or when they find out a
woman's got a child at home,
suddenly it's all, "Who's
gonna take care of the baby?"
No one asks men that question.
Well, none of it matters now.
Right? Because
it's probably too late.
And I knew it. I knew
this was gonna happen.
You've been stewing over this.
Resenting me. For how long?
I don't resent you, Is.
But, you know, if you want
me to sit here and tell you
that it's not your fault, I...
I can't do that, I'm sorry.
- Oh.
- I love you, my friend.
Hey. You like?
- That door was locked.
- I know.
The cable guy had a
cancellation, so he hooked me up,
got us a two-for-one.
Little thanks for
being so chill earlier.
Mmm, gracias, amigo.
So, what kind of doctor are you?
- I'm a surgeon.
- A surgeon?
Your stuff doesn't
say surgeon, does it?
It's like, uh,
Selena and Justin.
It doesn't really go together.
Furniture's from, like, a
dozen different places.
Fourteen.
The people in Casper knew
I didn't have any money,
so they gave me
things to make a home.
The bookshelf is from
Jennifer, the town librarian.
My table and chairs are
from Mr. Grady's diner.
The lamp is from Sheryl who teaches
Sunday school at Highland Church.
Dr. Glassman, he
got me my bed...
Well, you don't have to
tell me the whole list, but...
Okay. Yes.
Everything I have works.
There is no need to change it.
Respect.
Mmm... Hi.
- I'm Dr. Glassman.
- Hi.
- I'm the president of the hospital.
- Is everything okay?
Sit down.
There has been no
change in Quinn's condition.
However, her grandmother
has made a claim of child abuse
against you and your husband.
She's claiming that putting
Quinn on puberty blockers,
and, these are her words...
"Making her think that
being trans is okay"
is a form of emotional
and physical abuse.
Now, just to be clear,
we don't believe any
of these allegations
have any merit whatsoever.
I know my mom, okay?
She's not gonna drop this.
She'll go to court.
Could she get custody?
Well, she could try, but,
uh, Dr. Lim would testify.
- They could put her in a foster home.
- Hey.
Ty, she won't make it.
If we let Quinn do the surgery
she wants now, it'll all be over.
There will be no reason
for Ruth to fight us.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Do what Quinn wants.
Do the bilateral surgery.
There is an issue.
Your tests confirmed abnormalities
in the semen parameters.
- I beg your pardon?
- The semen analysis.
It showed that you have a low
sperm count and low motility.
- It's my fault?
- No.
We... We do not
speak in terms of fault.
15% of all couples
struggle with infertility,
and of those, 50% have
a male factor component.
It's not great news,
but it's not a dead end.
So what's the next step?
I'm gonna refer you
to Dr. Arjun Dhillon.
He's an excellent urologist, and
he'll give Marcus a full physical,
do some blood work,
and an ultrasound.
- That can't be right.
- Marcus.
- It can't be right.
- Marcus. We got this. Okay?
We're gonna get
through this together.
Hey. Hey!
Why didn't you tell me
Howard's labs came back?
I should have been there when
you broke the bad news to him.
So Melendez could see your
touching bedside manner?
- It doesn't matter anyway.
- Oh, it doesn't? How the hell not?
The poor guy's
getting a colostomy.
There's no way we're
winning this competition.
You really have no sympathy
for what Howard's going through.
It's a major bummer, no doubt.
But we don't have time
to get emotionally invested
in every patient that we treat.
Our job is to go in, do
the surgery, and get out.
Afterwards, his poop, someone
else's poop, it's not our problem.
Hey, well, wait.
What if we could get Howard
a fecal microbiota transplant?
FMT for a surgical case?
Theoretically, we transfer
healthy feces to him,
it restores good flora to
the body, kills off the CDI,
and he avoids
surgery altogether.
We could actually
win this thing.
I'm gonna pull all the research
before pitching it to Melendez.
So, this meeting is called
a Challenging Patient
Consultation Process.
The name sucks, but there
are things about it I do like.
All you got to do
is talk and listen
and try to understand
each other.
What's to understand? Ruth
accused us of being child abusers.
And what's to discuss?
We are Quinn's parents. We
get to make her medical decisions.
What if Quinnie's
better off as a boy?
You have no idea what
Quinn has been through.
Every kid goes
through rough patches.
Every kid is confused.
Quinn has always told us exactly
who she was, ever since she was three.
So you let Quinn play
with dolls. Big deal.
You don't make life-altering decisions
because a child wants to be a princess.
We used to let Quinn do
whatever she wanted at home.
But when she went out in public,
we made her present as a boy.
It felt false to her.
She hated it.
She hated herself.
She became reclusive, depressed.
And then a year ago,
Quinn tried to kill herself.
Sorry I'm late.
Howard might not
need the colostomy
if we give him a fecal
microbiota transplant.
Hasn't the FDA gone
back and forth on that?
We could be introducing new bacteria
into his system that could kill him.
The likelihood of that is low.
But not zero.
But if we do the colostomy, we
may not really be helping him.
15 to 30% of patients get
recurrent CDI after the initial bout.
That's a good point.
I believe 65% of that time,
recurrent CDI becomes chronic,
which can lead to repeated
hospitalizations and death.
Are my numbers right, Claire?
Yes.
But recent studies show better
than a 95% success rate with FMTs.
Howard is a good candidate.
We should try it before he
develops a toxic megacolon.
Don't we owe it
to him, to his twins,
to at least try an
experimental treatment
before doing an invasive surgery
which will alter his life forever?
You're right. Prep
him for the procedure.
I appreciate your passionate
advocacy for your patient.
Good work, both of you.
- Oh, now you're a team player.
- When it benefits me, yes.
Speaking of which, while
you were doing your research,
I found Howard a
match at the stool bank.
- Sample arrives in a couple of hours.
- Great.
I let them know you'd
be the designated doctor
to handle the medical chain of
custody when the sample arrives.
So?
So you're the only person
who can handle the sample.
You'll have to dilute it, blend
it, strain it all on your own.
To safeguard against
cross-contamination, of course.
Of course.
Your temperature
and BP are normal.
Normal, whatever that means.
Typical. Usual.
Expected.
Yeah, I don't feel like
any of those things.
What does it feel
like to be a girl?
Are you angry? Was that
an inflammatory question?
I'd rather people ask questions
instead of pointing and staring.
When I used to look like a boy,
I felt different.
The kids at school didn't
understand me, so they picked on me.
I spent a lot of time alone.
When my parents let me be me,
I felt like I didn't have
to pretend anymore.
I felt free, like when you're in a
pool and you just let go and float.
I'm not a very good swimmer.
I don't know what it feels
like to be anyone but me.
Me, too.
Is the bilateral more risky
than the unilateral surgery?
The big issue
with the bilateral is
Quinn will never be able
to have biological children.
If Quinn's parents think
that Quinn's mature enough
and strong enough in her beliefs,
then they should do it now.
It's an elective
surgery on a child.
There is no medical necessity.
Except with a previous
suicide attempt, she's still at risk.
Her situation is different now.
She's socially transitioned
and living as a girl.
But there just isn't enough good
data on trans kids and their outcomes.
On the other hand,
there's very good reason
to preserve future fertility.
Dr. Lim and Dr. Andrews are
both very excellent surgeons,
and they very clearly have
some passionate points of view,
but their views are their own.
You all need to decide
what's best for Quinn.
Whatever we decide,
Quinn is still gonna be a girl.
I don't know if I'll ever
be able to accept that.
I know that makes
me sound horrible.
I know what it's like to
not put your family first.
And it cost me.
It cost me a great deal.
And if I had to do it all
over again, I'd ask myself,
"Is it really worth
sacrificing a life
"with someone I love
"over an idea that
may never be?"
Why don't we give them the room?
Hey. I got the page.
What's going on?
She started screaming in
pain and vomiting. Temp's 104.
Increased groin pain
could be attributed to
epididymitis, kidney
stones, inguinal hernia.
The extra weight of the tumor could
be causing the testicle to twist on itself.
There'd be no blood flow.
Thank you.
She has a testicular torsion.
She needs surgery now.
Excuse me. Have
you made a decision?
Not yet. I mean, there's
a lot to work through...
We need one now.
Quinn has testicular torsion.
The spermatic cord is twisted
and cutting off blood supply.
We need to operate.
If you want Quinn to
live the way she wants,
don't limit her future now.
You heard her when my mom
said she might want kids someday.
She can't even fathom the
thought because she's just a child.
Just do what's
medically necessary.
Doesn't appear to be any
palpable lymphadenopathy.
It's likely a stromal tumor, but
get that to pathology right away.
Yes, sir.
Quinn has tachycardia
and hypotension.
- I'm not seeing any bleeding.
- EKG's normal. It's not coronary.
CO2 and O2 are
normal, so it's not a PE.
It must be a reaction
to the anesthesia.
I'm already pushing
fluids and vasoconstrictors.
Six syringes in, and
no sign of leakage.
Okay, we're wrapped up here.
Let's get Howard into recovery.
- Well done.
- Thanks.
I was thinking of
writing up the procedure,
possibly submit
it for publication?
I'd be happy to assist,
seeing as I've done it before.
Thanks, but I think I can...
I read your paper in AMSURG,
Dr. Reznick. You continue to impress.
Coming from you, I take
that as a huge compliment.
When you get a chance,
Dr. Browne, you should read it.
Will do.
I've given vasopressors and
reduced her meds as much as I can.
She's losing volume somewhere.
It was dry when we
ligated the spermatic cord.
I'm still not seeing the bleed.
Could be vagal stimulation
from the severed nerve.
But she's not
responding to epi. Sepsis?
It's too early for an infection.
Her MAP is 20.
She's barely profusing.
All right.
Okay, excuse me, guys.
- You're breaking scrub.
- I'm so sorry.
Grey-Turner sign.
Could be a
retroperitoneal hemorrhage.
Jared could be right.
It is possible that there
is internal bleeding.
The testicular artery can
retract up into the pelvis.
It's rare, but it can happen.
Rare is an understatement.
Dr. Andrews?
I don't think we have any other choice.
We need to do an ex-lap. 10 blade.
Murphy, retract.
Internal bleeding.
Jared was right.
- Nice call, Dr. Kalu.
- Thank you, sir.
Kalu, suction. We need
a clear view of the field.
Fever's down, and the flora in your
system seems to be returning to normal.
- We expect a full recovery.
- Thank you. For everything.
Do you know when
I can have visitors?
I thought you might
ask that question.
There are a couple of eager
preschoolers who'd like to say hi.
- Oh. Keira! Sammy!
- Daddy!
Oh, I think you guys have grown.
Hey. Hey, these are the
doctors that saved Daddy.
Dr. Reznick, and
this is, uh, uh, uh...
I'm sorry, I forgot your name.
Dr. Browne.
- Thank you!
You're welcome.
Okay.
Who's this guy?
- Bear Bear.
- Bear Bear?
Did you do it? Did
you remove both?
No. Just the cancerous one.
What? Why not?
That's on me.
I couldn't, in good conscience,
remove a healthy organ.
Quinnie, this was our decision.
- No! You said you were on my side.
- Hey, we are.
Always.
We haven't had
enough time to talk,
not with each other, with your
therapist, with your doctors.
So I'm gonna turn into a boy?
Not right away.
Your endocrinologist
will talk to you
about the right timeline for
starting feminizing hormones.
You know...
The thought of having your own
kids someday is a big decision,
but you never know what you will
or will not want once you get older.
Cis people are always so
worked up about having bio kids.
If I really want a kid
that bad, I can just adopt.
You know, I'll be back when I'm 18
for my gender confirmation surgery.
And when you do,
I'll be here to help you.
Patient satisfaction survey
scores are in, and it was very close.
Not really. She's being kind.
Congratulations go to
Dr. Reznick and Dr. Browne.
- Yes.
- Thank you.
- Congratulations.
- Thank you, Shaun.
Claire and I make a nice team.
- You should be psyched.
- Yeah. I should be.
To the victor belong
the spoils. Pay up.
Oh, humility was
never your strong suit.
Thank you, Mortimer.
Don't spend it all in one place.
Spend it? I'm gonna frame it.
What made you think of a
retroperitoneal hemorrhage?
Homework. You were right.
Prepping for an
SDA was important.
We make a good team.
Quinn doesn't like pink.
- Oh...
- Uh, I think she will like these.
I hope so.
She's more of a purple girl.
Did you read Morgan's
AMSURG article yet?
It is on the top
of my to-do list.
I didn't tell you to
read it to rub it in.
I told you to read it so you
knew what you'd be up against.
You think I need to
be more cutthroat?
No. That's Morgan's
MO. You're different.
You're smart, you're special.
Rise up, play the game
on your own terms.
Don't wait for it.
I heard you saved Quinn's life.
Jared and I did. I like her.
"Her."
So you get that she is a "she"?
I have lots of questions.
Yeah, well, questions are good.
Leads to awareness
and understanding.
And, who knows,
maybe even acceptance.
Being a kid is tough
enough, but being a trans kid?
Oh, man, that's off the chart.
I can't imagine how
it must feel to be so
different on the outside
than you are on the inside.
Hey, Shaun. I
can give you a lift.
Mmm...
We could grab a bite.
You said you can't be my friend.
So, no, thank you.
Okay.
- Hey, amigo. What's up?
- I need your help.
You're not gonna do
any laps or nothing?
No.
Then what are you doing?
Understanding.
Rivers and roads
Rivers 'til I reach you