Have you seen
this person?
Uh-uh.
His name is Danny.
Maybe he found
a shelter.
Yeah, maybe.
Or he could be riding
the train all night
to stay warm.
Ethan, if you're trying
to make me feel better,
it's not going to work.
I'm not, I'm just saying.
We can't look everywhere,
and it's time to go to work.
Well, you go ahead.
I'm going to keep looking.
Um, excuse me.
Excuse me?
Sarah. Sarah, Sarah.
Lower Wacker is much
more popular
this time of year.
We'll check it out
tonight after our shift.
Okay.
You ordered a pâté
platter and sweet breads?
Yeah, pathologists
love organ meats.
You recognize
that's weird, right?
I think
it's a vitamin D thing.
We don't get much sunshine.
Have a good day.
Morning.
Hey, what's up?
Big moving-in
party tonight, huh?
Evite wouldn't lie.
Yeah, well, we'll be there.
So, how's it been so far,
living together?
Only a couple days,
but so far so good.
I bet.
I heard there's
a giant Whole Foods
across the street.
That's awesome.
Yeah, it is.
Good. Well, I'm really
happy for you guys.
Mmm-hmm?
Dr. Manning.
Got it.
Treatment 6.
You and Dr. Shore
better be the real deal.
I am bringing
a Chateau Pichon 2005.
Great, wine spritzers.
Don't you dare. Treatment One.
Hey, uh, did you get
those lab results yet?
They just came in.
Want me to come with you?
Um, I think I better
do this myself.
Okay, just tell her
if she needs
anything I'm here.
Don't come too close.
My TB's become active.
The spot on your lung's
a half a centimeter larger.
I'm sorry.
I took my meds.
I didn't overexert.
I just don't get it.
Thing is, uh,
that's not all.
Here, just read it.
Come on, Noah.
Just...
Just read it.
Wait...
I'm pregnant?
I'm pregnant.
Is it just me,
or these Santas
seem to come out
earlier every year?
Right?
The psych nurse
station still has
their Halloween
decorations up.
Any Thanksgiving plans?
Taking Robin out
for some sushi.
Good, so the two of you
are spending
some time together?
Yeah.
Here and there. Yeah.
Doing great, you know?
I mean, such a great kid.
But you know how it is.
You don't really
worry about them.
You worry about the people
they surround themselves with.
Sounds like
someone in particular.
No, not really.
I guess there's this
one guy.
You know, a great fella.
I mean, we work together.
Terrific surgeon.
But he's got these
family issues, man.
Big family issues.
And obviously with
Robin's family history,
it just can all
turn into a bit
of a powder keg.
Have you spoken
to her about this?
No.
Oh.
So, you're just
keeping it all
to yourself?
Daniel.
Didn't I just
tell my shrink?
I don't know.
I might have said
something to the guy.
Nothing intrusive.
Just, I don't know,
some friendly advice.
"Advice"?
Yeah.
Daniel.
Don't make the holidays
any more hard
than they have to be.
Hey, I know
this isn't ideal,
but a couple of weeks,
we should have your
TB back under control.
Yeah, you'll be back
in the ED throwing me
shade again in no time.
But how did this happen?
I take birth control.
My opinion,
your TB meds made
your birth
control less effective,
and then becoming pregnant
weakened your immune system
to let the TB
become active.
Oh, God.
No one could have
predicted this, April.
In a few months,
I'll be walking
down the aisle
with a baby bump.
Yeah, but it's all good.
Right?
Yeah.
No, it is, but...
What about Tate?
You know Tate.
He'll love it.
He's head over heels for you.
Yeah, right now.
But what if I get sick?
What if I can't
take care of this baby?
April...
He didn't sign up
for this.
It's okay. Go.
I'll check on you soon, okay?
Jim Vance,
38, end-stage
kidney failure,
suffered a
syncopal episode
following dialysis.
Too far down the list.
Transplant candidate?
Hi, Mr. Vance.
This is Dr. Halstead.
Heard you had
some trouble today.
Today, Tuesday,
last Friday.
Almost every time
I get dialysis now.
What happens?
My chest, uh,
it starts to flutter.
Uh-huh.
I feel really weak.
Um... Ventricular...
Ectopy. Yeah.
Ectopy.
May be IDH.
Intradialytic hypotension.
In some people,
dialysis can cause
an extreme drop
in blood pressure,
which prevents enough oxygen
from reaching the heart,
and over time,
that can cause dysrhythmias
or even a heart attack.
So, tell the
transplant people.
Maybe they can
move me up the list.
Well, we can try,
but I'm sorry to say,
heart disease
usually moves people
down the list, not up.
But I'm not even 40 yet.
I hear you.
And I promise
we're going to do
everything we can to help.
Yeah.
Let's get him on
15 PO of kayexalate
and start him on esmolol
to stabilize his rhythm.
Or we could do
low-volume dialysis.
We could.
Otherwise we're just
treating the symptoms
and not the actual problem.
Yeah. Okay.
Great.
I'll be back in a few.
We'll see you.
Natalie.
We don't usually disagree
in front of a patient.
I had to say something.
You really think
low-volume dialysis
will make a difference?
I mean,
it seems like six of one,
half a dozen the other...
I don't know.
Maybe. Let's find out.
Hey, you bringing
Clarke tonight?
Mmm-hmm.
Good. Pathology party.
Not much to look at.
So, how's it going
with him?
Good. You know, we're just
trying to let it happen,
not trying to force anything.
"Force anything"?
Like moving in together
for financial reasons
or convenience.
No, I wish Will all the best.
I just think it's weird.
Thirty-six-year-old male,
penetrating stab
wound to the abdomen.
You're going to Trauma One.
Got it.
What happened?
I got jumped in the yard.
Three guys.
Why would they do that?
All I do is make friends.
We need to transfer him.
Yeah, hold up.
Okay, he's ready.
On my count.
One, two, three.
Guys, I got a hole in my gut.
I ain't going anywhere.
Left lower quadrant
looks clean
and no major vessels,
no bowel.
I can take it.
You need to put me under,
you do what you gotta do.
No, I think you got lucky
on this one, Mr. Wallace.
CT abdomen,
then bring him back.
We can take care
of this one here.
Okay.
Okay, Doc.
I trust you, but I gotta ask.
After you're done,
am I gonna be able
to play the piano?
Hey, come on.
Don't leave me hanging here.
Let me guess.
You never could
play it before.
I like you, Doc.
You can stick
your fingers in me
any time you want.
How's he doing?
He'll be fine,
though with
a nice-looking scar.
Pretty fortunate,
considering it was
three against one.
That's actually not the case,
Dr. Choi.
Seems he stabbed
himself hoping to score
a holiday from prison.
What?
I guess when you're
up against 30 to life
for a double homicide,
you look for
little diversions.
Her name
is Karrina Goff.
She's 16 years old,
with a history notable
for Williams Syndrome.
Her mom found her
passed out on the couch.
Williams Syndrome.
You ever seen it?
No, never.
It's a genetic
disorder, right?
Uh-huh. It's commonly
associated with
cardiovascular disease,
but even more striking
is their personalities.
They produce enormous
amounts of oxytocin,
which is the hormone
commonly associated
with feelings of trust
and the desire to be social.
They're very
interesting people.
Hi, Dr. Clarke!
Hi, Karrina.
Wendy, this is
Dr. Latham and Dr. Rhodes.
Hi, Karrina.
Oh, I like your earrings.
It's a moon
and the stars.
I see that.
So, how are we
feeling today?
Tired.
Still awake enough to donate
her entire allowance
to UNICEF this morning.
Which is what?
The third time this month?
Is this the first time
she's fainted?
Yes.
May I listen to your heart?
Mid-systolic ejection murmur
over the right
second intercostal space.
Aortic stenosis?
Probably.
Let's get an echo.
Okay.
Can you make me better?
I am going to try my best.
Okay, dear.
Let the doctor breathe.
Doctor?
Uh, let us run a few tests,
and we'll be back
with our recommendations.
I thought maybe Sunday
we can go to the Field Museum.
That sounds good.
The DNA Center
has an exhibit
on the reproductive
habits of sharks
that's supposed to be great.
I'm sorry.
What were you saying?
Danny still hasn't checked in
on Facebook, has he?
No.
He'll turn up.
You don't know that.
He's helpless and
alone out there.
And you've been
out there every day
looking for him.
There's nothing
else you can do.
I could have let him
stay with me
when he asked.
No, Reese, you couldn't have.
That's not your
responsibility.
Mmm-hmm.
He found you
when he needed
you in the past.
He'll turn up.
I said get out of here.
I just want to
talk to the doctor.
You better get
out of my face, man,
I'm not playing.
I just wanted to
know if you're okay.
Do I look like
I'm okay, man?
Excuse me, sir?
Is everything okay in here?
Uh, yeah.
I'm Ian. Jim's brother.
Some brother.
Go ahead. Tell them.
Jim...
Go ahead
and tell them, man!
Tell them.
I'm a perfect match
to donate my kidney.
Right.
And he'd rather watch me die
than give it to me.
I love my brother.
I'd love to
give him my kidney.
What's stopping you?
I'm HIV-positive.
But giving him a kidney
would be giving
him HIV as well.
I'm guessing by his reaction
that he doesn't know?
Not a clue.
May I ask,
why don't you tell him?
Because Jim is
incredibly homophobic.
He thinks homosexuality is
disgusting, deviant behavior.
Yeah, but right now,
he thinks you're
willing to let him die.
Well, right now...
Right now he hates me
for what I'm doing.
If I tell him this,
he'll hate me for who I am.
I understand.
But just so you know,
if you don't tell him soon,
it may be too late.
Hey, hello.
Hey. You better
put that mask on.
I brought you some
stuff from home, okay?
Thank you.
All right.
All right,
so, how you feeling?
Sit down.
Why?
What is it?
I'm pregnant.
Pregnant? Are you sure?
You're on the pill.
My TB meds screwed things up.
I'm sorry.
I know we didn't
plan for this.
I know this
changes everything.
Yeah.
We're going to have a baby.
Oh, you can't see.
Okay, now put that back on.
Babe, we slept in
the same bed last night.
Put it back on.
It's a beautiful thing, honey.
It really is.
Ms. Charles, what brings you
to the ED today?
Yellow fever? Plague?
Nah, just a
plain old cough.
Things have not been the same
since the swine flu died down.
Well, don't worry.
There'll be another
epidemic one day.
That's what I keep
telling myself. You know,
gotta stay positive.
I never figured
you for an optimist.
Are you kidding me?
I still root
for the White Sox.
Wow.
I do.
How do you do it?
I would love to tell you.
I don't know.
Maybe over drinks tonight?
That sounds great.
Really, uh...
Just not sure
your father would approve.
What?
Did he say something to you?
No, not really.
He just mentioned
something in passing.
Huh.
I see.
Ms. Goff, hi.
So, we got
Karrina's test results.
The large vessel leaving
her heart has become
severely congested.
It's making her heart
work harder and harder
and decreasing
the amount of oxygen
that it can deliver.
That's why she's become
so tired and listless.
Oh, God. What do we do?
We recommend an operation
to either fix the aortic
valve or replace it.
Yes.
Heart surgery?
Hi, Dr. Rhodes!
What are you guys
talking about?
Dr. Rhodes
was just explaining
your test results.
Hey, Karrina, why don't we
get you back to bed?
There you are.
So, based on what
I am seeing,
I believe you need surgery.
Will that make me better?
Well, there are
never any guarantees.
But, if things go well,
then, yes, it will.
Good! Then I want to do it.
It's not that simple,
sweetheart.
We need to think about this.
Give the doctor
and I a minute.
Okay.
We'll be right back.
I know you think
surgery has the best odds,
but I also know
that Williams patients
have a much higher chance
of not surviving
general anesthesia.
I completely understand,
but the fact is
her condition is
quite advanced,
and she did express
that she wants the surgery.
She doesn't understand.
She says that
just to please you.
She may not be able to
make a completely
informed decision,
but she does know
how she feels.
She's under 18.
It's my decision to make.
Shouldn't we at least
let her be a part of
the conversation...
Dr. Rhodes, Karrina is not like
your other patients.
I want options.
Okay.
Um, let me talk
to Dr. Latham.
See if he has any ideas.
What did you tell Connor?
Come again?
Did you tell him to
stay away from me?
No.
You said something.
I might have...
Who I date
is not your concern.
You are
absolutely right, 100%.
You are unbelievable.
I'm sorry. I was wrong.
I worry about you,
I can't help it.
Okay, well,
that's going to need to stop.
Can't do it. I'm your dad.
I know I haven't
won any awards
in that department...
This is not
a referendum on you.
I'm sorry I wasn't there.
I'm sorry I wasn't a...
Okay, see that?
That right there.
Why does it
always go back to that?
Does it ever occur to you
that I have moved on?
I didn't...
Not only am I past it,
but I really...
I do not care.
So you can feel as
guilty as you want,
but you being
overinvolved in my life now
is not going to cut it.
Hey, Doc.
We gotta stop
meeting like this, right?
Oh, you giving me
the silent treatment, huh?
Hey, you think
I could get
a TV in here?
You and I could
watch a little, uh,
Family Feud.
Not enough time.
I'm stitching you up
and then you're leaving,
which means you
won't be needing those.
Ah, come on.
Why you gotta be like that?
Because you're not
here on vacation.
Hey, give me a break here.
I'm injured.
By your own hand, I hear.
You want to play that game?
I am extremely depressed,
and you know what?
That makes me
want to hurt myself.
Excuse me?
You heard me.
You heard me, too.
I am gonna
hurt myself!
And we all know
what that means.
We have no choice.
I'll call Dr. Charles
for a psych consult.
That's right you will.
He's in v-tach.
Stop the dialysis.
Pulse is thready.
Shortness of breath.
Lost his pulse.
We gotta defibrillate now.
Bag him.
Get me the paddles.
What's going on?
Charge to 200.
He's in cardiac arrest.
Clear.
Still in v-tach.
Come on. Charge to 300.
Sinus rhythm.
Jim, can you hear me?
He's stable for now.
Jim?
I need to talk to you.
I gotta tell you something.
There she is. Yeah.
Thank you.
Hey, is there somewhere
we can go talk for a minute?
Did you find Danny?
He's...
He's dead, isn't he?
Yes.
I'm so sorry.
Hey.
Hey, you did everything
you could.
This is Sarah Reese.
Hi, are you family?
A friend?
No, I'm his doctor.
I was his doctor.
Was he beaten to death?
It looks that way.
We won't know for sure
until we have
the results of the autopsy.
Hey.
Your sputum cultures
just came back.
It turns out you
don't have regular TB.
It's multi-drug resistant.
Okay, so...
I'm gonna have to be on
three or four meds
instead of one?
It's not quite that simple.
It's only susceptible
to one drug,
but it's
completely susceptible,
so it'll
definitely work, but...
This medication
can cause neural tube defects
in a growing fetus.
But not always.
There's just a chance.
Well, there must be
something else.
They couldn't have
tested everything.
They have.
Well, tell them
to test it again.
I mean, try something.
There's nothing else to try.
I just placed the order.
The first dose should be
up in a little while.
I'm sorry, April.
Spoke to your patient,
Mr. Wallace.
Let me guess,
not a suicide risk.
Garden-variety sociopath.
He's an opportunist.
Knows all the buzz words.
Not a sincere bone
in his body.
Good enough for me.
Let's start
discharge paperwork
on Treatment Four.
Chalk one up
for the good guys.
Hi, Mr. Vance.
Your rhythm looks good.
How are you feeling?
Disgusted.
Given your latest reaction,
I'd like to try
something different.
A medication called midodrine
to raise your blood pressure,
followed by a special course
of low-calcium dialysate.
Will it work?
Well, to be honest,
it's a long shot,
but it's our best option.
Just tell me.
How long have I got?
You're experiencing
cardiac events
with every dialysis,
and you need dialysis
three days a week,
so realistically,
it can happen at any time.
We are trying
everything we have.
Okay.
Wait.
You wouldn't
give me your kidney
'cause of the virus, right?
But what if I don't care?
Would you give it to me then?
But you'll get infected.
HIV, it's better than dying.
Would you do it?
Yeah. Of course.
Then let's do that.
I want his kidney.
Mr. Vance, you are
severely immunocompromised.
If you received
an HIV-positive organ,
if you contracted
HIV in any way,
it could immediately
progress to AIDS,
and that would
most likely kill you.
Let's just do it.
As your doctor,
I strongly...
Stop.
Will you excuse us
for a moment?
Thank you.
We should look into this.
Look into what?
Purposely giving someone HIV?
He knows the risks.
What does he have?
Days? A couple of weeks?
That's the thing.
We don't know.
He could surprise us,
and make it long enough
to get a healthy kidney.
We could put him on carnitine,
try sodium modeling.
That's grasping at straws.
Yes, a transplant
is dangerous,
but if it works,
it could give him years.
It's unethical and illegal.
Even if you found
a surgeon willing to do it,
the minute anyone found out,
our licenses would be revoked.
So we get
a special dispensation.
Look, that man
is dying in there.
The least we could do
is give him a chance.
Natalie, I'm sorry.
As the attending physician,
I cannot sign off on this.
Fine.
Then I'll
figure it out myself.
I'm going to call
the OR, see if they can bump
anybody till tomorrow.
Dr. Rhodes, any news?
We were actually
just about to see you.
Uh, the final reading
of the echo showed
even more significant
disease than we thought.
You need to consider
scheduling
surgery immediately.
Where's Karrina?
That patient in there,
where did she go?
I told her to stay in
her room. Where is she?
We'll find out.
Check the ambulance bay.
You don't know where she is?
Ma'am...
Karrina?
She's in here.
Sweetie, I need you to
step away from that man.
Get away from him!
Mom, it's okay.
No, it's not okay.
That man is dangerous.
I was just saying hi.
Okay, I know,
I know, sweetie.
Can't take my eyes
off you for one minute.
It's my fault.
No, that's not true.
Of course it is.
I told him we could
remove the chip.
I encouraged him to run away.
You empowered him
to make decisions.
It's what good doctors do.
But they were
the wrong decisions.
It's the wrong outcome.
And now he's dead.
I mean, who knows.
If I'd have told him
to wait,
maybe the police
would have come
and broken up
the ring and he'd be free.
I was careless with his life.
Dr. Reese...
You're anything but careless.
Sometimes the best advice,
you know,
it's just not enough.
Dangerous thing
about psychiatry,
it can sometimes give
those of us who practice it
the illusion of control.
But the human brain,
it's...
It is the most complex,
mysterious object
in the universe.
That means that
what we do, it...
It just doesn't come
with any guarantees.
I don't think that
makes me feel any better.
I know. Never does.
It must be hard.
It is.
She is such a bright light.
A breath of fresh air.
You should see
how people spark up
when they see her,
and how happy it makes
Karrina.
It's like she feeds off of it.
If you don't operate,
I'll be taking that from her.
Do the surgery.
We'll get her
upstairs shortly.
Dr. Halstead?
Yeah?
Um...
April is refusing to
take her new medication.
She won't listen to me. I...
I just don't know what to do.
You know I'm
here to convince you
to change your mind.
I'm a nurse.
I stopped listening to doctors
a long time ago.
I know it doesn't make sense.
But there's another
life inside of me now.
How can I take a medicine
that could endanger it?
Hopefully it won't.
"Hopefully."
I see a lot of
hopeful people come in here,
and we tell them
we're doing everything we can.
If I take that medication
and something
happens to this baby,
then I didn't do
everything I could.
I can't live with that.
April, you've been put into
an impossible situation,
and I can't tell you
what to do,
but if you don't
take this medication,
there is a very high chance
both you and
your baby will die.
It's unbelievable.
Health and Human Services
won't okay that HIV
kidney transplant?
Won't even consider it.
Our local contact at the FDA.
Deals with compassionate use
and experimental drugs.
Might as well try everything.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Looks like our
time together is up.
Mmm, yeah,
you got me, Doc.
Can't put
anything over on you.
I sent his prescription
ahead to the
prison pharmacy.
Great.
Yeah, you're a real
tough guy, huh?
Took my best shots.
Bang, bang, bang.
You just deflected them
like Captain freaking America.
I'm sorry your stay
was not satisfactory.
"Satisfactory"?
What the hell?
Get me a portable
chest X-ray, stat.
On it.
Doctor's too smart
for a stupid con like me.
Lungs are clear.
Doctor.
Come on.
Did he swallow anything?
Not that I saw.
Wait, what are those?
They look like
little stars.
They must have
lacerated his esophagus.
Get him up to surgery now.
Wires are in.
Chest is dry.
Let's close the sternum.
Dr. Vorspan, was the patient
wearing any earrings?
No, why?
They think
she gave them to
that convict downstairs,
and he swallowed them.
You think you've
seen everything.
We'll need wire cutters soon.
Yes, Doctor.
You know,
they did a study
once on oxytocin.
College students
exposed to high levels of it
just started
giving their money away.
Did you see how freely
she interacted with that man?
Just a total stranger?
I've never been
good at that.
It's just a symptom of
her genetic condition.
True.
But maybe that's not
entirely a bad thing.
Any luck getting someone
to approve the transplant?
Nope. Got stonewalled
by everybody.
I'm sorry.
Yeah.
Time to go tell Jim
the bad news.
I'll come with.
No.
No, I'll do it.
I'm the one who got
his hopes up, so...
What are you
going to tell him?
The truth.
That the one thing
he needs most in the world
is right in front of him
and he can't have it,
and he doesn't
even have a choice.
Natalie.
There's still one thing
we can do to make this legal.
What are you
talking about?
He's already said he's willing
to deal with HIV infection.
Let's give him the option.
Wait, are you serious?
It's his decision.
We'd just be
giving him a choice.
You realize
the implications of this?
I do.
But if we want to
save his life,
is there any other way?
Mr. Vance,
I'm afraid that
as things stand,
there is no possible way
you can receive
your brother's kidney.
Wait, so there's
nothing at all
that we can do?
No, not as things
currently stand.
Even though
I know the risk?
Even though I want to do it?
That's correct.
It is illegal to
give an infected organ
to a noninfected recipient.
That's the terrible irony,
because if you
already had HIV,
the procedure
would be legal.
Now, obviously,
we can't give you HIV.
No, but...
But he can.
And you do have a choice.
How's he doing?
Gonna be off solid
food for a while,
could be a lot of scarring.
We should know
more in a few days.
I guess he got his
vacation after all.
Yeah.
I just can't believe
I let him win.
Really?
Does this look
like a win to you?
He got what he wanted.
So he's a patient
who came here to be treated.
That should have
been your focus.
Are you saying
I should have let him
have his way?
You know,
my grandfather used to say,
"Never wrestle with a pig.
"You both get dirty,
but the pig likes it."
She's going to be fine.
Back to herself.
Fortune favors the bold.
Congratulations, Dr. Rhodes.
Good night, Dr. Latham.
Hey, Sox fan.
Hey.
Is it too late
for those drinks?
What about not
upsetting my father?
Why stop now?
Okay.
You need anything?
Uh, no, I'm good.
Thank you.
Hey.
This is a really
great place.
I love the breakfast nook.
Yeah, thanks.
Mmm-hmm.
Are you feeling
good about today?
Yeah. Yeah, I am.
Good.
Hey, everybody.
Um, thank you
so much for coming.
Celebrating with the people
who know Will and me best,
it means a lot,
but there is something that
most of you may
not know about Will.
Uh, he's still got a lot
of med school debt...
But he paid part of his way
through it by singing
at Irish weddings.
What?
No, no.
Come on.
Yeah, you paying half
the rent now, buddy.
No, seriously.
These people are
trying to have a good time.
Come on.
Everybody wants you to.
Just one song.
Okay, Ms. Goodwin.
One song. She's the boss.
You guys think
you're funny, don't you?
I know
we're funny.
All right...
Baby
It's been a long day, baby
Things ain't
been goin' my way
You know I need you here
To ease my mind
All of the time
Baby
The way you
move me is crazy