Perfect.
What are you doing to me?
Not the results we'd hoped for.
Your labs confirm what
we saw on the ultrasound.
You're in end
stage liver disease.
But I always took my medicine.
I know. You're the most
compliant patient I have,
but autoimmune hepatitis can
progress even with treatment.
You need a liver transplant.
We talked about that
before, remember?
But you're gonna have a
fantastic team of surgeons
working their tails
off to get you fixed up.
We're gonna get you admitted.
Do you have any questions?
Someone has to
die so I can live?
I want to pray,
but I can't pray for
someone else to die.
Ooh! Hold the door!
Thank you. I'm
late enough already.
- What happened to you?
- Oh, not much.
Just slept through my
alarm, stubbed my toe,
then got a parking
ticket and a flat tire.
You drive a 50-year-old relic
and you don't use Triple A?
I drive a 44-year-old
car, and it takes longer
to wait for help than it does
to put the spare on myself.
I'm surprised you
know how to use it.
- Because I'm a woman?
- Because you're a millennial.
Also an engineer who used
to work for a car company.
A computer company.
You built software.
For self-driving cars.
So Sony is a car company
because they build stereos...
My point is that I know
how to change a tire
faster than any tow
truck driver. Or you.
Okay, no need to be hostile. I'm
just trying to make conversation.
Have a nice day.
- What do you got?
- He almost drowned in a triathlon.
We restarted his
heart, but he's obtunded
- and breathing's labored.
- He was in a triathlon?
Agonal respiration,
accessory muscle use...
- His sats are dropping.
- It's Cort Graham.
Eight liters oxygen. Are we
supposed to know who that is?
Cancer survivor and
endurance athlete.
Also heads a big cancer charity.
Left lung has focal
consolidation and fluid collection.
- I need a chest tube.
- On it.
If he's an experienced swimmer,
something must've made him pass out.
Could be a heart attack. Stroke.
- Head trauma?
- From swimming?
I did a sprint tri once.
The swim was like a
roller derby in water.
Oh, damn it. Pyxis won't open. I
put in my code but nothing happens.
Well, figure it out. We
need the chest tube.
I'm going to go in
with a ten blade.
That won't release enough fluid.
I know.
Come on!
Oh, he's cyanotic.
- Come on, open!
- Get out of the way.
Don't just stand
there. Get the tube.
Oh, sorry. Sorry.
What's going on?
Why didn't it open?
I don't know. The power's on,
but our computers are down.
- All of them? The whole hospital?
- Looks that way.
We'll need to temporarily
close the clinic, E.R.,
and divert new patients.
Good news is the O.R.s
are isolated from the network.
So we won't be able to share
imaging on external monitors,
but the MRI and radiology
machines are still functional.
Well, great. Let's postpone
all elective procedures,
keep the most urgent
cases on the board.
Got it. You call the cops?
San Jose Police and the FBI,
and the Cyber Attack
insurance carrier.
What's the ransom?
Two million. Well, we
have the data backed up.
We got it covered.
We got a problem.
If it's only one problem, it'll
make me extraordinarily happy.
No, it won't.
They actually hacked into the
network over three months ago.
Took their time to not
only encrypt our servers,
but our on-site and
cloud-based backups.
- Don't we have backups? Data?
- Actually, we have three,
which get rotated
out every 30 days,
which means the
oldest backup we have
was synced four days
after the bastards broke in.
And we have no data?
Technically, we still have data.
We just can't access it
without their encryption key.
Okay.
You can't pay the ransom. You
don't negotiate with terrorists.
No, what I can't do is pay an
exorbitant amount of money
to an insurance company
and then not use them.
They gave us 24
hours to get the Bitcoin.
If I can find a mistake in
their encryption software,
I might be able to
get our data back.
Of course, I'll also have
to retrace the attack chain
to find the exact
door they came in.
Otherwise we might as well toss every
computer we have in the recycle bin.
If you're trying to convince
me to not pay the ransom,
you maybe shouldn't
have said that last part.
I realized that
as I was saying it.
You've got 24 hours.
The surgery shouldn't be a
problem, but finding a liver will be.
- Her MELD score puts her first up.
- On our list,
which still leaves her competing
against every patient in the region.
No procurement coordinator
is gonna discriminate against
a patient with Down syndrome,
but they are gonna give a patient with
shorter life expectancy a low priority.
She also lives alone and doesn't
have any family to help with recovery.
She's worked so hard
to be independent,
- and now it's gonna be held against her?
- It sucks, but it's not unfair.
I'm not giving up.
You don't have to worry about
the list if you can find a living donor.
Look for one who's already
volunteered to give a kidney.
Get help. With the network down,
everything's gonna take longer
and she doesn't have much time.
I couldn't have gotten kicked,
wasn't even close to the pack.
I thought swim was
your strongest section?
Usually, but I let my
ego get the best of me.
I went out way too fast and
got dropped at the first turn.
Well, I'm impressed
you're even out there.
I can barely finish a 5K.
I used to be the same way too.
Cancer actually made
me a better runner.
That can't be true.
The chemo you had
reduces lung capacity.
And how could losing a leg
make you a faster runner?
Well, once you get past
a mile it's not about speed,
it's about pain, and how much
you're willing to push through.
And my threshold definitely
increased after chemo and rehab.
And seeing the
hope I give survivors
every single time that
I cross a finish line,
that doesn't hurt either.
His cancer could be back.
The odds of sarcoma
reoccurrence are very high.
Oh, it could be lots of things.
It could be a virus or bacteria.
More likely cancer.
Overtraining can weaken
the immune system.
I'm a motivational speaker, so
literally a professional optimist.
I can handle the truth.
Dr. Murphy is probably right,
but we'll do a full blood panel
and chest C.T. to be sure.
The good news is it's clearly
an underfunded startup.
Their website's garbage,
and the ransom's only
half your cyber policy limit.
Underfunded? Startup?
Website? Where do I start?
Despite what you see on TV,
these attacks don't
come from lone wolves.
It's a global business,
with websites and
customer service call centers.
Our I.T. director thinks that we
might be able to decrypt the data.
Even if he could do
that, which is impossible,
it wouldn't do any good
unless he could also
retrace the entire attack chain.
She explained that.
She also said that she
might be able to do both.
I'm sure your I.T.
director's excellent.
I'm also sure that this is
outside her area of expertise.
The only way to retrieve
your data is to pay the fee.
I'm sure I can negotiate it
down to a few hundred grand.
From two million?
Well, they're amateurs. I'm not.
Thought I had a perfect match,
but she's in Shanghai on business.
- How long's a flight from...
- Eleven hours.
But I couldn't talk her into it.
She's about to close the
most important deal of her life.
Who talked to John
Raponi? Retired firefighter,
peak physical condition.
I did. He was at
a bar. At 3 p.m.
Doesn't give me high hopes that
his liver will be in perfect condition.
- Not ideal, but not disqualifying.
- Rachel Trainor's the better option.
She's local, a preschool teacher,
and an extremely devout Christian.
What makes you
think her faith helps us?
I'm a devout Christian
and I'm not sure I'd be a live
liver donor for a family member,
much less a stranger.
You may be devout,
but you're also selfish.
I mean, we all are,
relatively speaking.
So, what makes you
think Rachel isn't?
Her Instagram.
I mean, you'd be surprised
by how much you can
learn from what people "like."
And Rachel likes
everything she sees.
Like, literally everything.
We rescheduled the chemo
appointments we could,
but there's still three that
need their infusions today.
We're doing our best
to modify the regimens.
Okay. Check and see if
they got second opinions
from other oncologists,
and if so, then maybe
we can use those records.
Okay.
- And keep me posted.
- Yes.
What the hell? You
said I had 24 hours.
God, you're gonna
give me a heart attack.
I authorized a negotiation.
I didn't authorize the payment.
- You don't trust me?
- It's not about trust. It's about...
weighing the costs of a delay.
Well, then you should
know your costs just went up.
They sent us a Signal text.
What's a bot worm?
It's what happens when
you listen to an insurance rep
instead of your own head of I.T.
They were insulted by the
offer, so they doubled the ransom
and activated malware.
If we don't pay, they're
gonna delete our data
and destroy all of our MRI,
CT, and x-ray machines.
They obviously just figured
out what the policy limit is,
which means they didn't do their
research and are now improvising.
They're playing catch-up.
Can you still get them
down to a few hundred K?
No. That was before they
had the policy information.
We'll end up between their
initial and current demands.
This is just a piece of paper
and a check to you, isn't it?
I'm sorry you're upset
because your insurance rep
- wants to promptly pay a claim?
- The frequency of these attacks
is skyrocketing because insurance
companies make it so easy to collect.
I quibble with the analysis,
accept the compliment.
It's a matter of time before
these bastards kill someone.
I agree, but do
you have a solution
- or just a lecture?
- Give me the time I asked for
to decrypt the data
and restore the network.
You're not gonna
be able to restore...
- How do you know?
- I've never seen it done.
I'm not running...
Stop, stop, stop, stop. Enough.
Your solutions aren't
mutually exclusive.
You, keep negotiating,
and you do whatever you do
to get the network back online.
We have some good news.
Your cancer hasn't returned.
You have a fungal infection that
is causing a bleed in your left lung.
- That's great.
- No, it's not.
The best treatment is surgical
excision of the infected lobe,
but we can't do that
because of scarring
from the Bleomycin you were
treated with during chemotherapy.
They always do this
good cop, bad cop thing?
Um, I'm sorry, Dr. Murphy just
has a more direct bedside manner.
That's good. I like direct.
You can't climb an obstacle
until you're facing it head-on.
We're going to start you
on an anti-fungal drug.
Well, if surgery is the
best, that is what I want.
The chemo was
over ten years ago.
Bleomycin weakens
the lungs permanently.
For most people.
I climbed five of the Seven
Summits with these lungs.
It's my decision. I
want the surgery.
I'm sorry,
but sometimes a positive
attitude just isn't enough.
We may have to try you
on several different drugs
before we see some improvement,
so you're gonna have to be patient.
It's not one of my strengths.
Me neither.
But we're gonna get
through this together.
Turkey, avocado and Swiss on
wheat bread with mayonnaise.
- It's your favorite.
- I don't have time.
Low blood sugar can decrease
your ability to concentrate.
I've had five energy drinks
and three granola bars.
Okay.
I have an interesting patient.
He said he thought
cancer made him stronger,
- but that is obviously not true...
- Shaun!
Would you walk in on Glassman
while he's doing brain
surgery, offer him a sandwich,
and start telling
him about your day?
That's different.
Of course.
Because his job's
important and mine's not.
You have any idea how insulting
it is to hear you demean what I do?
Just like every man I've worked
under and over my whole career?
You...
You don't respect me.
You can't bring
sandwiches into an O.R.
I have to go.
Ah. Heh.
King me.
Oh.
We have a problem.
Am I too sick for
the transplant?
No. But you are.
Your bloodwork indicates
non-alcoholic fatty liver disease.
It's a minor case which
should be manageable with diet,
but it means you
can't be a liver donor.
Wouldn't a fatty liver
be better than nothing?
It wouldn't be safe
for either of you.
There has to be another
way. We can't give up.
We're not giving up, but...
Thank you for trying to help me.
I'm sorry you're sick too.
Your kidney is fine. Would
you be willing to donate it?
Uh, of course, but how
does that help Jamie?
You might be able to save
two lives with one kidney.
What's going on?
Blood oxygen level
dropping. He's hypoxic.
Yeah, the anti-fungal
regimen isn't working,
but don't worry, there
are other drugs we can try.
I want the surgery. Please.
I'll take the risk, whatever it is.
It's not a risk, it's a guarantee.
Increase voriconazole by 320 milligrams
and add Amphotericin
at 24 milligrams.
- We may need to intubate you...
- Stop! Stop.
- I would survive the surgery.
- No, you...
Yes. I would.
Because I never had the drug...
Because I never had cancer.
So how'd he lose his leg?
Drunken motorcycle
accident when he was 22.
It's good news.
Now we can give him
the surgery he needs.
No way. He needs
to find new doctors,
and we need to figure out
a way to alert the charity.
He faked cancer so
he could steal money,
date models, and get his
face on a Wheaties box.
He didn't steal the money.
He gave it all to charity.
I don't care what he did with it
after he lied and cheated
thousands of people to get it.
He should be in
prison, not our O.R.
Can we even do that?
Refuse to treat him?
We refuse to treat
noncompliant patients all the time.
What's going on?
I mean, he's obviously not
the first patient who's lied to you.
He didn't just hide how
much he smokes or drinks.
He weaponized people's empathy,
and he kept pushing his lie until
he was some sort of national hero.
- How does that not piss you off?
- It does.
But I can be pissed
off and professional.
Get him prepped for surgery.
A multi-organ chain.
We need to find someone
who wants to give a kidney
to their loved one, but isn't a
match, but is a match to Jamie.
And the loved one has
to be a match to Rachel.
We have to match
blood and tissue types
as well as organ size.
And kidneys and livers have
different test requirements.
And we need another
donor willing to do a surgery
that's more painful and
dangerous than the one
- they already signed up for.
- Twice the challenge.
To save twice as many lives.
Park and I will start
calling hospitals.
Asher, back to social media stalking.
Jordan, check local news reports
and any other corner of
the Internet you can scour.
Stay back or you're gonna
contaminate my clean room.
I found an error.
Not theirs. Ours.
The serial numbers on
the servers didn't match up.
Turns out one of my techs
spilled coffee on a server,
didn't want to tell me,
so he switched it out
three days before the hack.
His screw-up might
just save our ass.
So it's not encrypted?
No. But it is corrupted from
the coffee and dust and dirt.
I found it under a pile of
junk in the recycling bin.
But if my patient pulls through,
I'll be able to
restore the network
without having to pay
the hackers a dime.
- Wow, that's great.
- Yeah.
The insurance guy came to an
agreement with the hackers, didn't he?
Actually, he negotiated them down
below the original ransom amount.
I didn't authorize it yet.
You have till 9 a.m.
to get us back online.
Okay.
We will get one more chest C.T.
and then we will insert
the central venous line
and the arterial line to
finalize your surgical prep.
You must think I'm a sociopath,
- but I'm...
- Don't even bother.
It's not like I planned this
all out. It just... happened.
You just forgot the drunk
driving on a motorcycle detail
while you raked in cash
and collected famous friends?
I went back to school.
I got my MBA in
Non-profit Finance.
My first interview
after graduation
was with this small
cancer charity and...
for some reason the woman
assumed I lost my leg to cancer.
And I didn't correct her.
It was a weak, stupid moment.
It wasn't just a moment.
It was years.
Where I was raising money,
helping thousands
of cancer survivors.
And I knew if the truth
came out, that would all end.
I have helped far more
people over the last ten years
than I have hurt.
You're scheduled for surgery
first thing in the morning.
Hey, what's going on?
Hey.
Don't you have a
thoracotomy to prep for?
Yeah, I just... needed a break.
I'm fine.
"I'm fine" is a pretty
reliable indicator
that someone is not fine.
I suck at this.
I completely froze,
could've killed the patient.
I always freeze. Lim knows it.
I feel like an impostor
because... I am.
It's a stressful job.
Patient's being a
jerk? Get used to it.
Chief of Surgery
doesn't appreciate you?
Earn her respect.
If you want to be a
successful surgeon,
you gotta develop thicker skin.
- My skin's not the...
- Suck it up and get back to work.
I did it! If I had a mic, I'd
drop it. I fixed the server.
It's still missing the
last 96 days of records,
but it's totally malware-free,
which means we can
restore the network with...
three hours to spare.
And the, uh... the bot worm,
the thing on the imaging?
- How did you get rid of that?
- I didn't. But I don't have to,
because I went through every line
of code and there's no sign of a worm.
They were obviously bluffing.
Obviously? It's
not obvious to me.
No, the cyber
insurance rep was right.
These guys are amateurs.
And the level of skill it would take
to cause an offline
machine to self-destruct?
They'd have to be, like, the
Sidney Crosby of hackers.
And they're beer league at best.
Are you sure?
Totally.
Ninety-five percent.
Okay. Well... Yeah.
You have three hours
to get to a hundred.
It's not going to
work. I already tried.
Why would the hack
affect the microwave?
- It's a smart microwave.
- Apparently not.
Why are you so
angry about Cort's lies?
You told me before: when
the truth can't help someone,
you should lie.
I was talking about small
white lies. Cort's lies are huge.
When does a lie stop being
white and start being huge?
The amount of good Cort did
was proportional
to the size of his lies.
Looks like you got
what you wanted.
I just got off the
phone with a reporter.
She wanted a comment on
her soon-to-be front-page exposé
on Cort Graham.
Because her source is an
employee in my department.
- I mean, I didn't...
- You're off the case.
And you're lucky I
can't prove it was you,
or you'd be out of a job.
- What? Crap.
- It's okay. I got someone.
I called an old buddy
who runs the infirmary at
the state pen in Arizona.
He put me in touch
with an ex-inmate,
just paroled on compassionate
release for kidney failure.
He's a match for Rachel, his
daughter's a match for Jamie.
They're on their way
here with a police escort.
ETA twenty minutes. The
chain is closed. We did it.
Not to be a buzzkill,
but an ex-inmate?
What'd he do?
He killed someone?
It was a complicated
case. Over 20 years ago.
- He's paid his debt...
- I can't do this.
You're not doing it for him,
you're doing it for Jamie,
who's an innocent and deserving
woman the system failed.
I understand.
But you want to put my
kidney in a murderer's body.
He's a person who did
something wrong a long time ago.
It's more than just wrong.
I'm not going to risk my life to
help someone who took another's.
Please take this I.V.
out of my arm. Now.
I get it. I wouldn't want to
save a murderer's life either.
But you should understand what
Dr. Park means by "complicated."
Chris was abused as a
child. Sexually, physically...
You don't want to
know the horrors.
Once he got strong enough,
he put a stop to it. With a bullet.
But the prosecutor and the
jury didn't see a brutalized kid,
they just saw a thug.
So they put him away
for life, for fighting back.
All finished. You're free to go.
That man shot
someone in a robbery.
If the lie saves a
life, it's fine by me.
It saves two lives,
so I definitely think
we can let it slide.
I think I've actually
solved a huge problem,
but Glassman wants me
to be 100 percent sure,
and I can't be.
I need your advice.
If I'm wrong,
all the imaging machines
in the entire hospital
will self-destruct,
tens of millions of
dollars' worth of damage.
But if I'm right, I'd
save the whole hospital
and prevent some
really bad people
from getting almost $2 million.
And I'm almost sure I'm right.
I'm never 100 percent sure
a surgery is going
to cure the patient.
There's always a chance
something could go wrong,
but I still do the surgery.
But you get the
patient's permission first.
And in my case, Glassman
is kind of the patient,
and he hasn't given me
permission. In fact, he told me not to.
- Then I wouldn't do the surgery.
- But this isn't actually surgery.
I don't know what
you want me to say.
It's all right. Sorry. I'll just
figure it out on my own.
Lea?
I wouldn't bring Dr. Glassman
a sandwich in the O.R.
because you can't
eat in the O.R.
I knew that because
I know about surgery.
I don't know about computers.
Neither does Dr. Glassman.
But you do.
You always know
how to fix things.
I respect you.
I would've thought you
would respect me enough
to at least ask me the question.
To hear me out before
kicking me off the case
- and threatening to fire me.
- I did hear you out.
You sat right there and said you
wanted to blow the whistle on a patient.
And then that's
exactly what happened.
- What am I supposed to think?
- You're supposed to trust me.
I thought we were friends.
Is that why you went over my head
to tell my boss about my diagnosis?
- Is that what this is about?
- No.
I'm capable of separating
my personal feelings
from my professional decisions.
Excuse me
Yeah, what is it?
Sorry. Cort just coded. We had to
do CPR and manual cardiac massage.
Dr. Murphy didn't wanna
start the lobectomy without...
I'll assist Dr. Murphy.
You coming or not?
♪ There's some things
You can't explain ♪
♪ Is it chance or is it fate? ♪
♪ You're past the point
Where this could break ♪
♪ Not much more
than you can take ♪
♪ Is there any medicine? ♪
♪ It hurts too much to mend ♪
♪ When you can't
hold on any longer ♪
♪ I will lift you up ♪
♪ And when you feel The
storm getting stronger ♪
♪ I won't let you give up ♪
♪ Where there's pain
There's healing too ♪
♪ Oh, I'll be there for you ♪
♪ I will lift you up ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh ♪
Spread the ribs more with
the Finochietto Retractor.
Would you really
fire Dr. Browne?
If I find evidence
she did it, I will.
Shingle the ribs.
But you and Claire are friends.
Professional responsibilities
come before friendships.
It wasn't Dr. Browne.
It was me. I
called the reporter.
Why?
People suffered real tragedies
and he used their
pain to enrich himself.
But why confess?
You're the kind of
person I aspire to be.
So is Dr. Browne.
And if you two lost
trust in each other,
it would do a lot of
damage to this department...
to what makes it so special.
I didn't want to be
responsible for that.
Scrub out.
Stapler.
Transecting the
bronchial branches.
Stop! Stop! Stop!
Please tell me you haven't
made the transfer yet.
No, but I'm authorizing it.
Turn your computer on.
Your employee ID is
your temp password.
Who knows their
employee ID number?
I remotely rebooted
every authorized user.
Totally. One hundred
percent. Successfully.
Imaging's unscathed. No
malware. No worm. No nothing.
Bastards were obviously
bluffing, just like I told you.
You gambled your entire
imaging department on a hunch?
You have any idea
how reckless that was?
Thank you. I appreciate
all you've done.
That decision was
not yours to make.
If you ever usurp my authority again,
I'm gonna fire you right on the spot.
- I'm sorry, but I just saved the whole...
- Will you just...? Shush! For a second!
Wait for the compliment.
Thank you. Well done.
You're welcome.
If I ever have another
poker night, you're invited.
You'll need to take
all three of these
every morning
and before bedtime.
Call me if you need anything.
Thank you for not
giving up on me.
You can't just leave.
I've never been fired before,
but I'm pretty sure
that's how it works.
I'll talk to Lim, convince her
to give you a second chance.
I do not think she'll do that.
She was willing to fire
you, and she likes you
- a lot more than her.
- Shaun...
It's okay.
I've enjoyed working
with you both.
Thank you.
If there's anything I can
do, don't hesitate to call.
I'll miss you. But I
don't want to hug you.
Surgery went well. You'll be back
to competition in a couple of months.
Was it you?
I... I can't claim credit
for that good deed.
Not a terribly
convincing denial.
If I cared about convincing
you, I'd try harder.
I knew this day would
eventually come.
I expected I'd feel
vulnerable. Exposed.
And I do.
But I also didn't expect
that, you know, I'd feel...
relieved.
It's a little like getting back
in the water the first time
without my prosthetic.
I had to awkwardly
hop to the water,
people staring at me.
But once I got in I...
I felt a little bit lighter.
♪ Ever feel like
you can't breathe? ♪
♪ Does the water
feel too deep? ♪
♪ Lie awake 'cause you
can't sleep Without it... ♪
Livvy.
♪ When you're lost But
you're already home... ♪
You weren't gonna say goodbye?
Uncle Marcus, I
can't. Not now. I just...
I'm sorry I let you down.
You didn't let me down.
You confused me.
I know you're not
the whistleblower.
- It wasn't Dr. Browne.
- I know. It was me.
You? Why?
Exposing that guy
was the right thing to do.
Patient privacy is an
important obligation,
but it's not our only one.
I knew there'd be no proof,
so no one was gonna get fired.
I never expected
Lim to blame Browne.
But I know that's not why you
destroyed your whole career here.
- How can I help you...
- I don't want your help.
- Livvy...
- I never wanted to be a doctor.
But every time I try to tell my
parents, my professors, you,
you just push me and
encourage me until I back down.
I knew if I got myself fired,
there was no way that
you could pep-talk me
back into a career
that I don't want.
I don't want to be
important or successful.
I just want to be myself.
But I don't even
know who that is.
The only way to find out is if
I burn the bridges behind me.
♪ Maybe you don't know
it But it gets better... ♪
I know exactly who you are.
You are a resilient,
amazing young woman.
And I can't wait to see
what else you become.
I'll be rooting for you.
♪ Everybody falls
down All the way down ♪
♪ You just gotta hold on tight ♪
♪ You gotta get
up, gotta get up ♪
♪ Gonna make it
through this time... ♪
I know, I'm the last person
you want to see right now.
So I brought a bribe.
I was wrong to accuse you.
And not only because you didn't do it,
but because I was holding against you
the very thing that makes
you such an awesome doctor...
You care.
When you meet a patient,
you don't just see
muscles, bones, and organs,
you see a human being with
all of their strengths and flaws.
And you should never lose that.
Even if it does make the job harder.
And most importantly,
you're a good friend.
You got salted
caramel in that bag?
And an insane
amount of hot fudge.
♪ Everybody falls
down All the way down ♪
♪ You just gotta hold on tight ♪
♪ You gotta get
up, gotta get up ♪
♪ Gonna make it
through this time ♪
♪ You gotta get
up, gotta get up ♪
♪ Gonna make it
through this time ♪