Previously on ER:
You look like an
old-fashioned doctor.
Well, I am an
Give yourself at least a
week to be better than us.
You're doing great. I
just wanted to tell you...
that there are still many, many,
many problems for you to work on.
And if there's one word I can't
emphasize enough, Susan, it's "leadership."
That's it. Carry on.
Right. Down from last
year, I can see that.
Patient satisfaction scores?
Yes. Rush had a higher average.
They also have a bigger budget.
How'd we do?
All right, fine. I'm on it.
- Weaver?
- Yup.
Otherwise known as the
four-letter word beginning with a "C."
Crab?
Seventy-three percent of respondents
would not recommend this ER to others.
Our patients hate us. More precisely,
they hate Residents for not listening...
not spending enough time. Ray,
Morris, Pratt, all scored 2.5 or lower.
- Ah, it could be worse.
- The best being a five.
- Oops.
- Last in the class, Neela, at 2.12.
- How about Abby?
- Not bad, 4.15, but she has other issues.
They don't make
interns like they used to.
They're focused on
the science at first.
Once convinced they've mastered it,
they're free to focus on humanistic skills.
They're works in progress.
They have to be taught.
But you can't teach empathy.
Or common sense.
- Ray?
- Yeah?
People want to see a
doctor, not a rock star.
Put on some scrubs. We do
have a dress code here, people.
No stains, no tattered clothes,
no leather, no piercings. Got it?
You mean visible
piercings, right?
And if your shift starts at
7:00 and you come in at 7:02...
that's two minutes off
another Resident's life...
which is wrong and
salary-reducible.
You say something?
You think it's the tone of a woman's
voice that makes it easier to ignore?
Sorry?
I got a call from a renal Attending about
a dialysis order you finagled last week.
- "Finagled"?
- And in order to appease them...
I agreed to review three
months' worth of your charts.
- Wait a minute...
- There were concerns.
You started a central line
with no procedure notes.
Well, wait. You
reviewed all of my cases?
You admitted unstable angina patient
into telemetry before troponin was back.
Yes. Well, the bed was
ready, the lab was slow.
And here we have:
"Patient presents with rash. Discussed
with Dr. Cohen, agrees with the plan."
The problem is no one in Derm, including
Dr. Cohen, ever heard of this patient.
Abby, these are legal
documents. In a court, these...
He had Lyme Disease. I didn't call Derm,
I called Cohen in ID. And who are you?
- What?
- MVA, ETA two minutes.
You get promoted, everyone's a
slouch and I'm falsifying legal documents?
- Look, I'm...
- Forget it. I'm on break.
- Residents don't get breaks.
- I'm waiting for the MVA, then.
Help, my brother's
bleeding. You a doctor?
- What happened?
- They shot him!
- Where'd he get hit?
- You gotta help. I think he's dying.
Hey!
Hey! What...?
- Go!
- What are you doing?
- Go, man, come on.
- Hey!
Get off me. What are...?
Stop this car. What
are you doing?
Help!
Loose. Loose!
Stop, hey. Help!
Shut up.
- He's in the back.
- What?
Get in the back of the car!
Got me from behind,
came out the front.
- Oh, my God.
- Fix him!
He needs to go to the hospital.
Fix my brother, bitch,
before I blow your head off!
Try to stay calm, all right?
- Trying.
- How long have you been short of breath?
Day or so. My regular
doctor's on vacation.
- I'm pretty particular about who I see.
- Smart lady.
Dr. Barnett will be
with you right away.
Señora, you need to settle down.
Ma'am, the splinter is out. It
can't possibly still hurt, okay?
Neosporin and
wound-care instructions?
- Yeah, you got it.
- So, uh, was she faking or what?
No. That's what's affectionately
known in the ER as "Hispanic panic."
Okay. Let's see, we've got
cough and dyspnea on exertion.
How are we feeling,
Miss, um... Mitchell?
Ms. So-so, I guess.
Okay. "Ms." it is.
We're gonna run a few tests, get back,
and examine you as soon as possible.
- ICON, CBC, and chest x-ray.
- EKG too?
You the man.
I thought "Ms."
went out in the '80s.
Here you go, for the urinalysis.
Um... Is there any chance
that I could see another doctor?
He's lost a lot of blood. I don't
think there's anything I can do.
All right, um, let me
try to stop the bleeding.
Do you have a napkin,
or a towel, or anything?
No. All he's got is CD's and crap.
CJ, you got any towels in your ride?
Use whatever you got
until we get some supplies.
Listen to me. You need more
than supplies, you need surgery.
No.
- Just patch me up, I'm good.
- You need to go to a hospital.
Make a list of everything
I'm gonna need.
Get her some paper.
- If she moves, shoot.
- Okay, wait, wait, wait.
I can't just patch you up. I can't.
Even if I could, it wouldn't help.
You have internal injuries,
okay? You could bleed to death.
Bullet went clean through. You
use a needle and thread if you got to.
And get us some antibiotics or
whatever. You got a medicine pad, right?
Start writing.
Cause of ulcerative
colitis is not known.
Probably some combination of
external agents and host factors.
- More common in women or men?
- Women.
Right. And peak incidence is
bi-modal. Who can tell me the age range?
- Excuse me. Miss?
- Yes?
I know you're not my doctor, but
melanoma, when spreading, how long?
It's impossible to say, sir. It depends
on the number of metastatic sites...
location of the
primary lesion...
a number of factors.
I'll make sure your
doctor comes to see you.
That was tough.
Yes. But there are some biological
explanations for excessive emotionality.
Who can tell me the
differential diagnosis of crying?
Starting with the obvious. Limbic-system
lesion, temporal lobe meds would do it.
It could also be a thyroid
dysfunction. Other ideas?
A sense of doom has been
associated with acute MI.
Right. Inappropriate weeping
can also be produced by...
Neela.
That man's just been
told his cancer has spread.
Don't you think he
has a reason to cry?
Well, yes, of course he does.
But there are also other organic causes
of crying which warrant consideration.
Excuse me.
This man's looking for
anyone who worked on Monday.
- I did. Can I help you?
- Um, my wife died here.
Uh, Jenna Putnam.
I was hoping to talk to anybody
that might remember her.
I don't believe she
was my patient.
Oh.
I'm sorry. Maybe you can
ask at the nurses' station.
Someone there should
be able to help you.
Dr. Carter? This gentleman's
wife died here last week.
Oh.
I'm very sorry for your loss.
Thank you. Um...
I was up in Maine, and then
by the time I got back, uh...
You know, she was by herself.
You know.
And, well, I was just wondering
if maybe she said anything...
or, uh, you know,
if she was scared?
- What was her name?
- Jenna Putnam.
I'll look into it, I'm a social
worker. It might take me a while.
Do you want me to
call you at home, or...?
Oh. Uh... Could I wait
here? Is that okay?
All right. Uh...
Is there any way to know
what room she was in?
Not really. No.
All right, thank you.
- Sad.
- Yeah.
- It's nice of you, by the way.
- It's my job.
- Um...
- Yes?
It's forward of me, but I
was wondering if you'd...
It's bad enough I got saddled
with the shifts Chen dumped on me.
Now I got Residents bailing
too. Have you seen Abby?
No. Why?
She went to wait on a
rig, she's been MIA since.
- We can talk later.
- Okay.
When was this?
Hey, I got a couple more
GSWs en route. ETAs five.
- Okay. Half an hour ago, 40 minutes.
- She went out to meet a rig?
I called her on some stuff, she got
bent out of shape and stormed off.
I guess I hurt her feelings and
she declared herself "on break."
You know what? Malik, text message
Abby and tell her to get back on the job.
You don't got a cell phone?
Not with me.
My brother's got one.
Plays this funny little
song when somebody calls.
He's like the captain
of the ship, you know?
- What's his name?
- CJ.
What's yours?
Mostly they call me Little C.
Why?
Because CJ's really, really sick.
And I know your friend thinks...
Loose? He's our cousin.
Well...
I know he thinks CJ can be
helped this way, but he can't.
Okay?
You need to listen to me.
Listen to me. I'm a doctor.
Your brother's gonna die
unless he gets an operation.
So we have to take
him to the hospital.
Here's your stuff.
Get busy!
Another? Some kind
of gang war going on?
This one's got multiple GSWs
to the abdomen and legs.
- I ain't in no gang...
- Spontaneous resps, tachy at 121.
BP's holding, 106/64.
- I'm Dr. Lewis. What's your name?
- I was just waiting on the bus.
Second GSW's coming in on
another rig. This one's the youngest.
She looks 13. Jerry, did
you get hold of Abby yet?
Paging her now.
I need some light back
here. I can't see anything.
- What you gotta do first?
- Put his intestines back in.
- Is that hurting him?
- Yeah.
I have to keep pressure on this
to stop him from losing more blood.
Just do what you gotta do.
I can't do anything
while we're moving.
I think I hit something.
Oh, man, it's
a little kitty cat.
Hey, I think it's still alive.
Give me the gun.
Here.
I need you to help
me lift his head up.
Come on.
All right, CJ.
I need you to
swallow this, okay?
Oop... Okay.
CJ.
Come on, dog.
Good, man. Drink it all down.
That's good.
Don't be stupid, all
right? Pay attention.
- Come on. Sew me up.
- Not yet.
Give the codeine
a little time to work.
- One exit wound, right flank.
- My dad usually drives me.
- The other bullets must be in the belly.
- Through left thigh.
- Distal pulse is good.
- It was for his birthday.
Hang in there, Tisha. Ray,
call the O.R., we're on our way.
- Me?
- There's blood in the Foley.
Page Urology, the
bladder's been hit.
- Want me to call in a dinner order too?
- Roll on my count. One, two, three...
I was just going to the mall.
- Sats only 84.
- She needs an airway.
- Neela, go.
- Pratt, go.
- Pratt.
- Twenty of etomidate and 100 of sux.
- Set me up with a 75.
- Tachy at 133. BP's 82/50.
Central line kit, sterile gloves
and a gram of cefotetan.
- Can I do the femoral?
- Last resort in abdominal trauma.
Could pour blood and
fluids into a severed vessel.
How about a subclavian, then?
No. Call the blood bank. Tell them
to send type-specific to the O.R.
- Systolic's dropping, 78.
- Okay, another liter, mix up dopamine.
- Bag her.
- Urology knows.
- Good. Now call for an X-ray and a vent.
- Are you serious?
Second GSW coming in.
Can you spare a Resident?
- Yes, she can.
- Take Pratt too. We can handle this.
BP's 82/59. How much dopamine?
None. Aim for a relative hypotension
in a young person with internal bleeding.
If you jack up the BP,
she'll just bleed more.
Like this, she can tolerate.
Fine. Pretty controversial
approach. But, hey, I just work here.
Saline flush and 0 silk.
Hey, Malik. Can you
waste this ketamine for me?
- Done deal.
- Thanks.
Excuse me, sir?
I can feel her presence.
It's very strong here.
- Uh, sorry?
- Um...
I'm pretty sure this
is where my wife died.
She was in a car
accident this week.
Do you remember her?
Uh, I'm not quite sure that
I was working on that day.
Well, she has red hair. Uh...
Well, she had.
Flaming.
What was her name?
Jenna.
Hazel eyes.
Ringing any bells?
- This is stupid.
This is stupid. CJ: No.
- No. I'm feeling better.
- No. It's a needle and thread.
- It's not gonna work.
- He said he was feeling better.
You're gonna bleed to death.
Sewing you up like this is pointless.
- You need surgery.
- Do it.
- I can barely see what I'm doing.
- You heard him.
This should
numb it a little bit.
All right, it's good.
It's good!
All right.
Okay.
Listen...
brace yourself.
Aah! What you
doing to me, woman?
- It's just an IV, dude.
- What you call me?
We'll give you something for
the pain when we get this in.
- Ray, secondary survey, let's go.
- Yeah. You're okay, homey.
- Bullet grazed the scalp.
- You buy a book to talk like that?
He's saying you're lucky the
bullet didn't cause more damage.
You the lucky one. You free!
Wound's superficial,
chest clear, pelvis stable.
- Distal pulse is good.
- I bet you like hip-hop too. Mr. Cool Guy.
Send for a CBC, trauma panel, PT,
PTT, type and screen, and five of morphine.
- That's what I'm talking about.
- Shut up.
- Bolus is in.
- TKO. What else?
That's it. Entrance and exit sites,
left arm. Small laceration, right arm.
- Dr. Barnett, that lady's asking for you.
- Thanks.
Whoa, you didn't roll him yet.
- Pratt's got him.
- Excuse me?
- He's got a better connection.
- What?
He's not comfortable with
me, what do you want?
Ray, we're in the middle of a
trauma. Nobody gets to be comfortable.
I got a patient who needs me.
- How's he doing?
- He's gonna die...
- if he doesn't get to a hospital.
- Pssh.
Listen.
Can I ask what's the plan here?
To stay out of sight
until the cops are gone.
Then we can get him home.
To get something to eat.
I need to talk about your
patient satisfaction scores.
- Problem?
- They sucked. Abby, you there?
Abby, you can't be serious.
Come on, walking off a shift?
If you're there, pick up.
Fine. All right, call me
if you get this message.
- Wow, was she really that pissed off?
- Abby left?
Yeah. Now I'm pissed. Here,
Neela. Go satisfy a patient.
Weeping pregnant
teenager in Curtain 3.
Make eye contact, introduce yourself,
stay in the room more than two minutes.
- I'm about to go and do a digital block.
- I'm not really asking.
Dr. Lewis?
Uh, that patient of Ray's
is still waiting to see you.
- Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah. What'd she say?
- Uh...
- Fatigue and shortness of breath.
- No, about Ray.
- Oh. I don't know. She didn't say.
- Hi. I'm Dr. Lewis. What's the problem?
- Just a little winded mostly.
- Any fever? Coughing up any junk?
No.
- A little effusion here.
- What's that mean?
Uh, just some fluid around your lungs.
But heart looks good. No pneumonia.
- Does that hurt?
- No. I just...
I didn't tell the
other doctor that...
Sam, could you go
check on her labs?
Sure.
- Why is Lewis seeing my patient?
- Uh, the patient...
The labs got back a second ago.
What the hell does she want from me?
Ms. Mitchell, I'm so
sorry to keep you waiting.
I think I can explain to you
why you've been so tired lately.
You're pregnant.
Congratulations.
I think I got this.
No, you don't.
Come again?
Excuse us.
I still need to work up the effusion.
But I don't need a chaperone for...
She requested another doctor.
Why would she do that?
Maybe because she's a he and
didn't feel comfortable telling you...
that she's a pre-op transsexual.
But it was a positive
pregnancy test.
Yeah. Which in a man,
means only one thing.
Eleven fifty-two, please.
- Busy night, huh?
- A little.
Three cheeseburgers,
three fries.
Three sodas.
One bottled water, one Frosty.
Anything else?
- Have a nice night.
- Thanks. You too.
So...
snowboarding, you and I,
overnight at Telluride next Friday?
Ah. Oh...
What? Don't tell
me you're a skier.
That, and, uh...
I have other plans.
Oh.
Dr. Carter, I think my
6-year-old knee pain has skiffy.
A little young for that.
Go ahead, order the films.
Look, I, uh...
I realize this might
sound a bit weird.
Me and Abby have been
roommates for a while.
But you've known her for a lot longer.
I was wondering if I should be worried.
- She's not back yet?
- No.
I can't imagine her just
walking off her shift, can you?
Uh, no. But that doesn't
mean that she wouldn't.
Hello?
Hey.
- What?
- I need to use the bathroom.
Please.
You just drove right
past the gas station.
You just drove
Where are you going?
Excuse me. Where are you going?
You know what? It's okay.
It's okay. Never mind.
- Look, I really don't... Okay.
- Get out. I said get out.
- Let's move.
- Okay.
You said you had to go.
Go.
But you ain't going alone.
- Right here?
- Drop them and go.
Come on.
Scared of big black men, huh?
No. I'm scared
of big black guns.
- Yeah. Soon, hopefully.
- CJ?
- I don't know exactly.
- CJ, how are you doing?
I'm not sure.
Whew. Yeah. Okay, I guess.
See that?
Now look here.
Just got mine a few weeks ago.
- Healed nice.
- What's it mean?
- It's getting cold though.
- I don't know exactly.
He don't wanna tell me.
Told me not to get one.
- Whatever. Find out soon enough.
- Yeah. All right, dog.
Yeah, peace.
Cops been all over the 'hood.
Boo said he'll call when they're
gone. We'll take him home then.
Yo, give me those, man.
What? My comics? For real?
- I need them for the fire.
- Dog, I'm right in the middle of a story.
I'll tell you a story.
So there's this punk
and his girl, right?
They was parked out
in the middle of nowhere.
Know what I'm saying? Kind
of like this. They was in the car.
Working it.
Getting things all hot and
sweaty. You know what I'm saying?
But on the radio...
Can I have one of those?
Gives you cancer.
She has been under
a lot of pressure.
It's still not like her.
- She can also be very emotional.
- Easily hurt, stubborn.
Then again, she might
just be going out for a walk.
Probably just blowing
off smoke someplace.
- Steam.
- Hmm?
Did you two finish
your QA reports?
- Uh, no. Not quite exactly, no.
- When were those due again?
This sucks.
- Susan.
- You know why?
- It sets a tone.
- What tone?
If my Attendings don't take me
seriously, why should the staff?
You're taken seriously.
All right, what do I
have to do, pull rank?
I'm the chief of this department. If I
set a deadline, it needs to be honored.
- Okay, I'm sorry.
- No, forget sorry.
Just do what I
ask when I ask it.
Dr. Carter, that
gang kid's crashing.
I guess the fire helped.
He ain't shivering no more.
CJ?
CJ? He's apneic.
Get him on his back.
- What's apneic?
- He's not breathing.
No, no. He's warm right now.
- He doesn't have a pulse.
- What are you doing?
- Trying to get his heart started.
- What happened?
He was just fine
five minutes ago.
- Sats down to 79.
- What did the CT show?
Keeps getting bumped
for more acute cases.
More acute than this?
- Seizure stopped.
- The wound was superficial.
- The guy had a GCS of 15.
- Tangential GSWs...
can cause intracranial bleeding.
- You saw him.
- He was lucid and talking.
- Bilateral papilledema.
- Fifty of mannitol.
- He's not moving air.
Intubate, and this time run
him through the scanner.
Eight-oh on a mac two.
- He needs a hospital.
- He ain't gonna let us do that.
He's unconscious. He can't
tell you what to do anymore.
CJ, can you hear me?
- Can you hear me, CJ?
- He can't hear you.
- Just do something.
- I am.
Watch your back.
- Sedation's wearing off.
- Dose him again when we get inside.
The movement
will jack up his ICP.
What did CT say?
Diffused hemorrhagic
contusions with edema.
- Ventricles are collapsed.
- He's bradying down.
Blown pupil. Neurosurg
ready for him?
They said the bleed
was inoperative.
If we don't decompress the
brain, he'll herniate and die.
Sam, page Neurosurg again.
They're stuck in the
O.R. with a shunt revision.
- We'll do a ventriculostomy here.
- Cool.
- Sam, let's get Neela up for this.
- What?
- I've only gotten to do it once before.
- Yeah. And she's never done it at all.
Somebody needs
to help me do this.
- Do what?
- The breathing part.
One breath after
I count to five.
I can't do it myself anymore.
You.
Okay, fine. You do the compressions,
I'll do the breathing. Get in here.
Here. Put your hands like this.
Here, you press
down hard five times.
One, two, three, four, five.
I'll give a breath.
Ready? One, two,
three, four, five.
- Go. Go.
- Come on. Do it.
- Go ahead.
- One, two, three...
- I need a flush.
- Sorry, it took a while to find her.
Checked Jumbo Mart.
Abby's not there. What's this?
A ventriculostomy.
- I've made the skin incision.
- What?
- Three-oh silk.
- Getting your flash, Pratt.
Separate the attachments of the
temporal muscle from the bone.
- Is it normal to have this much bleeding?
- Yes.
Sterile gauze and retractor.
- I can't see.
- More gauze, Sam.
Frontal bones exposed.
Nice. You'll use the twist drill
to penetrate the outer cranium.
Hold it perpendicular to the skull
toward the ipsilateral medial canthus.
Like this?
Perfect.
You can do this, okay?
- Hey. Oh, sorry.
- What is it?
I just need Neela
when she has a sec.
Is this about my
pregnant teenager?
No. A guy whose wife died last week.
He's been hanging around the hospital.
Wants to talk to the
doctor who handled her.
That'd be you.
One, two...
- three, four, five.
- Where are we?
- One, two, three...
- I don't know.
- Four, five.
- He really needs help.
Can't... Can't do it no more.
Can't do it no more.
I got it.
One, two, three...
four, five.
One, two, three, four, five.
Hey.
Hi.
Dr. Lewis was pulled onto a critical
case and won't be available for a while.
Now, I'm sure you'd
prefer her to do this.
But we don't have a lot of time.
And, unfortunately, I'm going
to have to be the one to tell you.
We think you have
testicular cancer.
What?
Yeah, your urine was positive...
for a hormone called Beta HCG.
Now, in women that
hormone means pregnancy.
In men it means
testicular cancer.
- Are you sure?
- Yeah. We ran a number of blood tests...
that support the diagnosis. We
will do a testicular ultrasound.
But, yeah, I'm sure.
But listen, it's treatable.
Even if it spreads...
- your chances are great, okay?
- That's funny.
- What?
- I was getting rid of the equipment.
Ms. Mitchell...
you mind if I ask you why
you wanted another doctor?
It's like you put
on a show here...
like you're not comfortable
in your own skin.
I don't trust that kind of
energy. I know it too well.
Three, four, five.
He dying?
Two, three...
four, five.
He ain't dying, bitch.
You hear me?
- Don't you let him die!
- Three, four, five.
Come on!
One, two, three.
- Come on.
- No, wait.
- Wait. Please.
- I said, let's go.
Got no shovel here.
We'll do it somewhere else.
You don't have to do this.
Lay down.
Let's go.
I said, lay down.
- Transducer's reading on the portable.
- Bring a dose of Ativan.
- Pratt, walk him up to ICU.
- Me?
Yeah, just to be safe.
Thank you. That was incredible.
You're gifted
technically, Neela.
That's what makes you feel
best. Now all you have to do:
Take the confidence you have
when you do a procedure like that...
and put it in the other
half of your game.
- Not sure I know what you mean.
- Here's her chart.
Jenna Putnam, multiple
injuries sustained in MVC.
- Your signature.
- I still can't believe it.
You handle what, 20, 30 cases a
day? Easy to see how you could forget.
But it was just Monday.
- I don't know what to tell him.
- Yes, you do.
Dr. Kovac, I have no
memory of that man's wife.
- Are you telling me to lie?
- No. I'm telling you...
to trust yourself
enough to comfort.
Mr. Putnam?
Yes?
I'm sorry I didn't recognize
your wife's name earlier.
Oh, no. That's okay.
But you do remember
her now, though?
She was lovely.
She talked about how
much you meant to her.
How much she loved you.
And I don't think
she was scared.
Hey.
Changed my plans.
- I'm sorry?
- Telluride. I'm in.
If the offer's still open.
Yeah. Yeah.
- What?
- Nothing.
Oh, it's something. I can tell.
I just...
Are you all right moving...
forward with...
- this?
- Yeah.
Are you?
Yeah. Yeah.
- Good.
- Okay.
She wasn't even in the room?
- Nope.
- He pulled her from somewhere else?
Hey, Carter, I
need your opinion.
- Talk to you later?
- Yeah.
- What's up?
- Neurosurg called...
to find out why Kovac did a
ventriculostomy in the ER...
which is difficult
enough to explain.
Factor in the idea that he
actually let Neela perform it.
- And so...?
- A, it's a very difficult procedure.
B, in a delicate
situation like that...
it's customary to let the senior
Resident have first crack at it...
- and Pratt was right there.
- Hey, I told her it was no big deal.
Well, I'm gonna talk
to Kovac about it.
- Are you kidding?
- No, I'm not kidding.
- You don't think that's an overreaction?
- Thanks for your support.
Susan, I understand you
want to define yourself as chief.
- I do, we all do.
- But?
Are you sure that this is
the way you want to do it?
Stop crying, man. It
won't bring him back.
It's almost 10:00. They'll be
getting up around the block.
Listen.
I'm not gonna tell anybody.
Okay, I really won't.
I just wanna go home.
Hiding out, are you?
Uh... Maybe.
Sometimes I'd use
the utility closet instead.
Worse lighting,
but more privacy.
- So how's it going?
- Good.
Actually, it blows. Every time I
turn around, I'm offending someone...
or hurting someone's
feelings or acting like a total...
- crab.
- Tell me about it.
It sucks to be in charge.
So, what do you do?
Get used to not being liked.
That's it? That's your advice?
Look, it's what we as women
have the hardest time with.
We want to be liked,
care what people think.
The fact is, when you're in a position
of authority, you'll piss people off...
and you're gonna lose friends.
Thanks.
Hope it helps.
Hi, this is Abby.
Leave a message.
Hey, it's Susan. You're
probably not there.
Don't know, maybe you're at the movies
or down by the river having a smoke.
If that's the case, I should be
pissed. If it's not, I'm worried.
Uh... Hopefully I'll see you
before you get this message.
Sorry about today.
This is it.
Let's go. We got
business to take care of.
Get out.
Thanks anyway.