Honey?
Are you all right? Yeah.
Yeah, I'm just fighting off
a stomach bug. I'll be fine.
Did he sleep okay? Great,
as long as I was holding him.
I can't wait for
colic to be over.
Hold on, Mikey.
Bath time's coming.
He lifted his head yesterday.
Take the day off.
I mean, you're sick anyway,
and you hardly ever see him
or me.
I can't.
I've got a meeting with Crandall's
Kitchens. I think that deal's gonna close.
They called about
the car payment again.
It's two months late.
We're gonna be fine, honey.
Enjoy your bath, little man.
You know, honey?
Honey, I'm not gonna go in.
I'm coming down with something.
Honey?
Kara?
Kara!
Mikey!
Four-week-old infant submerged
in a bathtub. Don't know how long.
Non-responsive at the scene.
Get a trauma team for six.
Obviously breathing now.
Continue the Bodybox. Stat portable chest.
- Caucasian female, 32.
Where am I? EMT: Tonic-clonic
seizure in the bathroom.
- Brent, where am I?
- On one, two, three.
- Where am I?
- One, two, three.
You're in the hospital,
honey. You're in the hospital.
Honey, Mikey's here, and the
doctors say he's gonna be okay.
Hopefully. He needs to be
checked out by the NICU.
What happened?
You passed out. KARA: What?
Mikey fell. Has your
wife had a seizure before?
No.
I can't move my
head! I want to see him!
He's right here, honey.
He's okay. He's right here.
Tonight. L Word marathon.
You watch The L Word? On mute.
I'll pass.
Dinner with Cuddy.
Still sucking up so she'll fund
your play space for the chemo kids?
They really ought to save their
energy for other things, like crying.
She's the suck-up.
She asked you?
She's smart. She knows if
she buys me enough alcohol
my defenses just
might be weakened.
It doesn't make sense.
Unless she ran out of batteries.
Hey. I'm recently
single, she's single.
You're too nice for her to like you.
She's not needy enough for you to like her.
She's got an agenda, just not one that
includes an appearance by little Jimmy.
I'll poll my peeps. How many
of you think that Cuddy asked...
Or, rather, peep.
Chase caught a case in the
ER. He wants us to take a look.
Unless Chase broke his
neck falling off his polo pony,
he had no reason
to be in the ER.
Cuddy put him on a two-week NICU rotation.
Patient had an unexplained seizure.
Seizures are cool to
watch, boring to diagnose.
What about Foreman? He needs
to get his malingering butt back here.
He almost died.
"Almost" being the
operative word. Hey.
How are you doing? You
look great. Thanks. I feel great.
Glad you're back. Cameron
makes lousy coffee.
I take mine black, the way I take
my brain-damaged neurologists.
Happy to help.
How are you coming along?
Tell her everything's great.
Neither of us wants to deal
with her guilt. I don't feel guilty.
Of course not. Hell,
if people felt guilt
every time they accidentally
lobotomized a guy...
I was trying to save his life.
Yeah. Your heart
was in the right place.
It's just his brain that's not
quite where it's supposed to be.
Tell her everything's
great. It's true.
No more left side/right side reversals.
Still some short-term memory loss
and spatial processing problems, but
I'm trying not to be too hard on myself.
Yeah, might pull a muscle.
We have a case? Seizure that
can't be explained by epilepsy
and accompanied by
elevated calcium levels.
Still bored. Tell her why.
Because seizure with mildly elevated
calcium is diagnostically simple.
It's either hyperparathyroid, cancer,
or calcium-mediated neurotoxicity.
Well done.
But until you can remember how to
make coffee, hands off the patients.
House.
All those reasons this case bores
you, the ER has already ruled them out.
Lungs are clear. Get an EEG.
Confirm the brain function is okay.
Can we focus on
the task at hand?
Why did Mommy twitch so hard that
she tossed the baby in with the bath water?
You don't need me for this. Of
course I need you. We're a team.
Polyarteritis nodosa. Inflamed
arteries in the brain cause seizures.
Inflamed arteries in the
kidneys cause calcium buildup.
You're a moron. Did you even look
at the file? Kidney function is fine.
Whipple's? What?
Whipple's. Test her.
Cameron thinks it starts
with a "W". I'm thinking "V".
The dad vomited this morning.
Maybe they've both got strep.
You think you can do
a strep-throat culture
without the swab ending
up in the guy's poop chute?
"V" for "vasoconstriction."
That'd be my guess.
Excess calcium makes blood
vessels in the brain clamp down.
Best case scenario,
seizure. Worst case, stroke.
Do a digital
subtraction angiogram.
Foreman can't tell up from down, Cameron's
a girl. All that mechanical stuff.
Sorry. Cuddy
says I'm stuck here.
You're late.
And you are in my locked office.
Again. What you got there?
Special panties for
your date with Wilson?
It's not a date. And it's
none of your business.
If it's not a date,
it is business.
And if it was business, you wouldn't
say it was none of my business.
What do you want? I want to
talk about your date with Wilson.
It's not a date. This is fun.
Spring Chase from NICU
and I'll shut up about your date.
NICU is short-staffed. Have
you suddenly lost the ability to lie?
Nobody's quit NICU in two years.
And if you're making up reasons,
that means there is no reason,
which means he asked for
the assignment, didn't he?
If Chase needs a break
from you, he should take it.
Absolutely.
Both Mom and Dad
are negative for strep.
You'll be back playing
with the big toys soon.
Or not. Either way, I'm fine.
You don't have to say that.
It's okay. I could always
work in a research lab or teach.
And you'd be okay with
that? Why wouldn't I be?
You were planning on pursuing grants
of your own, running a department.
I'm alive.
Changing jobs,
not making coffee,
if that stuff bothers me now, I
don't deserve this second chance.
They say that physical contact
helps the healing process.
What's happening?
Your son's not getting enough
oxygen. Take Mr. Mason outside.
Lung's collapsed. He's not getting
any air. I need an IV catheter.
Another seizure?
Her chest muscles aren't
contracting. It's something else.
Her whole back is spasming. I need
two milligrams of lorazepam, stat!
He's okay.
His lung wouldn't
collapse if he was okay.
What the hell's
happening? I have no idea.
So what causes seizures,
hypercalcemia, and the thing
where Mommy bends like Gumby.
Little busy here. Uh-oh.
Baby's lungs are gonna conk out any
minute. Probably want to deal with that.
I'll get right on it as soon
as I finish indulging my boss.
Multi-task. Chemical
pneumonitis.
Bubble bath got into the baby's
lungs when he was underwater.
Start him on prednisone.
Keep him on high Fl02.
Let the indulging commence.
Lithium could cause all three
of the mother's symptoms.
No record she's on lithium.
And the tox screen was negative.
Lithium doesn't show on a
basic tox screen, Scarecrow.
Myelomatous meningitis
could also cover everything.
Rare complications of a rare blood
cancer. You're not totally hopeless.
Get an S-PEP and an MRI
for myelomatous meningitis.
Search the patient's
place for lithium.
The baby's lung problem is bacterial
and not chemical. Start ECMO.
While you're searching for the lithium,
take a water sample and check the pipes.
You want me to write
this down for you?
I ask you, is almost dying
any excuse for not being fun?
I'm not putting that
baby on ECMO.
The chance of there being
bacteria in bathwater...
Why don't you
want to work for me?
I'm nice, I'm fun at parties.
I'm not working
NICU because of you.
The baby's x-ray suggested
chemical pneumonitis.
Not to me. The x-ray
was too consolidated.
So, why are you down here?
Hoping to expand your make-out pool
to include the preemie to
nine-year-old demographic?
I needed a break.
From the patients.
They lie to us all the time.
Foreman almost died trying
to save a drug-dealing cop.
I just wanted to get
away from that for a while.
What a complete load of crap.
What am I? A nurse you're trying
to prep with this vulnerability thing?
ECMO could kill him.
You don't start him on ECMO and that
infection could rampage through his body
like Pistons fans
after a championship.
But you do it your way. Nothing
more honest than a dead baby.
ECMO stands for extracorporeal
membrane oxygenation.
Basically, we remove your son'
s blood... Okay, all of his blood?
We run it through a machine which
takes out carbon dioxide and adds oxygen.
Then we re-warm the blood
and run it back into his body.
There is a significant risk of internal
hemorrhaging, and he may also suffer...
You put him on antibiotics. Won't
that take care of the infection?
Not fast enough.
Are you sure this
is Mikey's best shot?
Absolutely.
Cuddy's trash? Not anymore.
I paid good money for it.
Look at what she bought.
Red clover. What is red
clover used for, Dr. Wilson?
Also used to treat asthma,
psoriasis, joint pain... She
doesn't wheeze, flake, or ache.
And she didn't ask a pulmonologist
or a dermatologist for dinner.
She invited an oncologist.
It's not a date. It's a consult.
Mom's MRI was negative
for masses, abscesses.
There's no sign she has
myelomatous... Fascinating.
Call me when we have...
She has a subarachnoid bleed.
So, why is our patient
bleeding into her brain?
Her blood workup shows
her pro-time's elevated.
She's bleeding because she's not
clotting. So, why is she not clotting?
What did you bring us, Daddy?
The only mood-altering drug
was vodka at the back of a drawer.
Hiding booze is a classic alcoholic
behavior. That'd explain the bleeding.
What bleeding?
You don't remember? She bled
all over you this morning. Kidding.
Idiots are fun. No wonder
every village wants one.
If she's an alcoholic, she would
also be more prone to hypercalcemia.
But the tox screen was negative
for alcohol. Hey, it was your idea.
Now, it's even better. Mommy
quits. She gets the DTs.
Even explains the seizure. It
also fits conversion disorder.
They're deep in debt, he' s working
around the clock, they got a new baby.
I think the seizure was a physical
response to psychological stress.
Boozy Mommy
covers more symptoms.
Put her in a nice phenobarbital
coma before the DTs kill her.
Where are you going? To
put her in a pheno coma.
What if I'm wrong? What
if Daddy's the drunk?
Do you want us to give
her the pheno or not?
I want him to argue his point.
I assume you considered
the father and ruled him out.
What's that saying? When you assume,
you become a pain in the ass to me.
Why should I argue?
You'd just overrule me.
Enough! Get a pony
or a watermelon farm.
House? I need him to react.
I need him to act
like a human being.
I need him to get over this
boring near-death rebirth.
I have changed. That's
not something you get over.
Nearly dying changes everything
forever. For about two months.
Two months is too long. I
need the guy I hired back. Now.
No matter how much your misery
loves company, it's not getting mine.
I'll talk to the dad.
Cameron can take the mom.
We'll figure out if Mom was
the drinker. Waste of time.
Put her in a coma
before the DTs kill her.
So,
is this a separation, or...
Well, lawyers have been
hired, friends divvied up.
Oddly, she didn't
fight me for House.
At least there aren't kids involved.
You just have each other to deal with.
If there had been kids, maybe
we would have done more of that.
Do you want kids?
Listen, is there anything in
particular you wanted to...
Hospital business
or... Catching up.
I mean, you know, it's not like
either one of us has
anybody to run home to.
No.
How are you feeling?
Okay. A little groggy.
There's somebody
here to see you.
Hey, Mikey. Mommy's awake.
Oh, Mikey. Gosh,
I was so scared.
Oh, I love you.
I love you so much. Oh.
I'm sorry.
You don't have anything to
be sorry about. You were sick.
Turns out she and
her husband met in AA.
Obviously, she
slipped. Good call.
It wasn't hard, considering my other
choice was your stupid psych theory.
Which was not stupid.
I'm telling you, I'm gonna
drop the N-bomb if I have to.
You're addicted to conflict.
Did they change the name?
You could have handled this
patient without dragging Chase in.
But the fact that he
didn't want in killed you.
Just like the fact you
can't get a rise out of me.
Where's the baby?
Get off me! No!
I have to do this!
No breath sounds.
Crash cart and epi! Stat!
I told you your psych
theory wasn't stupid.
Your son is stable.
But the lack of oxygen
damaged his kidneys.
She must have rolled
over on him by mistake.
Mr. Mason, I was there.
Your wife tried to
smother your son.
That's impossible. Kara
would never hurt Mikey.
He knows. They said Mikey knows.
You hear voices?
They wouldn't quit saying that
Mikey would be better off if...
They were right.
We've been trying to diagnose
a seizure that didn't exist.
She faked it when her husband
caught her. I don't think she faked it.
She just happened to seize right
in the middle of drowning her child?
Lucky break for the kid.
Hey, take it easy on Foreman. He's
playing with one lobe tied behind his back.
Postpartum psychosis makes
her want to drown her kid.
The internal conflict
triggers a seizure.
You know what else might be a trigger? A
physical illness. It's a wild idea, I know.
Especially since she doesn't have
any obviously physical symptoms,
like internal bleeding or excess
calcium. I'll draw some blood, test for...
Oh! Jeez! You've done it
again! Will you argue with me?
Drinkers don't eat right. That
explains the bleeding and the calcium.
This might just be
some crazy drunk,
and I'm telling you that she's about
to die of myelomatous meningitis.
We already tested for...
Exactly. It's an insane idea.
Okay. What do you want me
to do? Have an original thought.
In the meantime, stress her
into having another seizure.
We can't. She's on haloperidol.
You also can't because it's
dangerous and highly unethical.
Therefore, if you get caught,
pretend you can't make coffee.
Mental defectives
get tons of slack.
Take her off the haloperidol,
hook her up to an EEG,
flash some lights, make her
pant, shoot her up with a placebo.
When she starts twitching, if the
machine twitches along, it's real. If not,
well, call the cops, 'cause
she's a psycho killer.
Stop pushing him.
Stop protecting him.
He needs it. Not if
he wants to get better.
He might not be able to get better.
Well, then, I need a new neurologist.
He got sick doing his job.
If he got killed doing his job, I
wouldn't keep him on the payroll.
I don't care how guilty you feel or
how touched you are by his reborn spirit.
I am not touched.
Then you're guilt-ridden.
I'm not guilt-ridden.
Then you're pathetic.
Right now, I'm annoyed.
Keeping him up all
night in the seizure lab
is not the way to advance
his recovery. It's too much.
You're right.
You should stick around.
Make sure he doesn't screw up.
Kara, look directly
into the light.
Keep looking.
Thought you'd be
gone for the day.
Thought I'd wait for the
bone marrow biopsy results.
House sent you to baby-sit me, didn't
he? He asked me to wait for the results.
Cameron, it's
fine. Of course it is.
Look, a few weeks ago, you were
upset that I didn't consider you a friend.
Now you're upset that I'm happy?
What can I say?
Apparently, I'm a bitch.
I didn't say that.
It's annoying.
Insisting every day of
your life is a blessing
is basically calling
everyone else shallow.
It gets old. Sorry.
Oh, give it a rest.
How was dinner?
Cuddy did not mention cancer.
She lost her
nerve. It was a date.
What are you doing? PCR test.
You're doing it yourself
in the middle of the night.
On a spoon.
Cuddy's spoon. I'm checking
her saliva for cancer markers.
Yeah. I do that after
all my dates, too.
People think you're the nice one.
Why are you so worried about Cuddy?
You go first. You desperately
want this to be a date.
Because the
alternative is cancer.
Just admit that you like her.
She's smart, funny,
got a zesty bod.
I think it's great you can look
beyond the fact she's the devil.
I stole a spoon. You
stole her garbage.
She's my boss.
If she gets sick, the hospital might
replace her, especially if she dies.
I'd have to learn how to
manipulate someone new.
Whoa.
I think I'm gonna cry.
Find me when
the results come in.
Mr. Mason,
because of the damage done to your
son's kidneys, his potassium is climbing.
That's causing
irregular heartbeats.
I'm doubling the meds
and starting him on dialysis.
But unless we get
his potassium down,
he's gonna have a heart attack.
Kara, just another few minutes.
Biopsy's back. She's negative
for myelomatous meningitis.
And she's not seizing.
So, we're wrong and House is
wrong. And you're okay with that?
She's seizing.
She's not doing anything.
Her brain activity isn't
accelerating, it's slowing down.
Muscle rigidity, involuntary
grasping and sucking motions.
She's in an
encephalopathic delirium.
Hmm.
A genuine physiological illness.
That rules out a few things.
Like what, I wonder?
Postpartum psychosis
and conversion disorder.
The thing about being a
good loser, you're still a loser.
Ouch.
The delirium means her
brain is shutting down,
reverting to its most
instinctual functions.
And since it's progressing, I think
we can assume it's progressive,
which means it won't be long before
the brain closes shop altogether. Ideas?
He's in V-fib. His
potassium's still too high.
No pulse. Get him
off the machine.
Charge to 10. Clear.
Still in V-fib.
Another amp of epi.
Chase shouldn't be
wasting his time in NICU.
Could be Wernicke's.
No. Treatment for Wernicke's is thiamine.
We gave her that together with the pheno.
Delirium points to lithium. I
know we didn't' t find any, but...
She'd have to be smuggling
it in to be getting sicker.
Whipple's causes encephalopathic
delirium. The test was negative.
The test could have been
wrong. Ideas are not soda cans.
Recycling sucks. Give me
something new and shiny.
Or go retro. Take an old idea,
shine it up, and add a new symptom.
Encephalopathic delirium.
Pellagra.
She drinks.
Alcoholics get pellagra.
They eat lousy
diets, so no niacin.
He agrees with me. What
a shock. Well, you're right.
Lack of niacin starves the
brain. Neurons shut down.
Causes seizures, encephalopathic
delirium and psychosis.
We give Kara niacin, she'll
come out of her delirium
and she'll be totally sane.
Don't think she's ever
gonna be sane again.
Her son just died.
How do you feel?
Uh...
My stomach kinda hurts.
I need to ask you some
questions, see how you're doing.
Mmm-hmm.
Tell me your name.
Kara Mason. Is my son here?
When were you born?
Please. Where's
Michael? Is he okay?
Do you hear any other
voices besides mine?
No. Answer me.
You've been suffering
from delusions.
They were caused by a
vitamin deficiency, pellagra.
It made you believe
things that were not real.
Like the voices.
I
Remember doing things to Mikey.
Were those real?
I'm afraid so.
So, I...
You tried to suffocate
your son. But...
You... You stopped me.
And
that other doctor, he
got Mikey breathing.
Your son's organs were
damaged too severely.
He passed away this morning.
Oh, no, no, no, no, no, no!
No!
Oh, my God! No! Oh, my God!
Pellagra doesn't
cause bloody vomit.
She's still sick
and getting worse.
So what causes pellagra
and crimson spew?
Dead baby, while sad, not our problem. I
should have given him more polystyrene.
You killed him. If you don't get
over it, you're gonna kill Mama, too.
Her alcoholism caused the pellagra.
Maybe it also explains the vomiting.
Gastritis. Gastritis
meds aren't helping,
which may confirm her
story. She only slipped once.
You remove drinking
from the equation,
internal bleeding, hypercalcemia,
seizure, and pellagra are all back in.
Chase, will you get your
head out of the dead baby's butt
and focus on the barely alive?
How much polystyrene
did you give the kid?
One gram.
His potassium just kept rising.
I need your son.
Who are you?
Your wife's doctor. Your son may
have had the same condition she does.
My son didn't have a
condition. She killed him.
If I biopsy her intestine,
she'll bleed out.
He obviously won't. You're not
using my son's body to help her.
Okay. How about
trading him for a beer?
Or maybe you're
more of a whiskey guy.
You didn't have strep or a stomach
bug the morning you came in.
You puked because
you were hung over.
Accuse a recovered drunk of slipping
and most of the time, you'll be right.
So I drink.
You're acting like this is my fault.
People are gonna feel sorry for you,
and they'll tell you that you
can't anticipate the unthinkable.
The fact is, you can.
It's just not all that pleasant.
Look, you don't
know anything about...
I know that people don't get
crazy enough to kill someone
without first being crazy
enough for someone to notice.
How many times did you go out
for a drink because she was crying?
How many times
did you stay at work
because you couldn't listen to her
telling you what a bad mother she is?
You were relieved
when she shut down
and just sat staring
for hours at a time.
She held the pillow over his
head. You slept while she went nuts.
Not exactly a draw, but...
What is wrong with you?
What kind of a person
says those things now?
Let me do the test.
It'll be one less thing for
you to feel crappy about.
I got a dead baby
for you to biopsy.
Let Cameron do it.
Love working NICU?
I could get you transferred. I told
you. I just wanted to trust patients.
You don't give a
crap about patients.
Your paycheck.
You've been double-dipping.
Taking your vacation time here,
while drawing a salary in NICU.
Strange. Rich boy doing
all that for some extra cash.
I'm not rich. But your
dad was. Now he's dead.
If you're not rich, that
means that Daddy cut you out.
I'm not rich.
Don't let it change you.
And do the test.
God of compassion, take
Michael into your arms
and welcome him into paradise.
Let there be no sorrow,
no weeping, and no pain.
Peace and joy forevermore.
I'm sorry.
It was a date. Cuddy's
negative for all cancer markers.
It was a date.
The baby's intestine
shows slight villous atrophy.
Why would a baby
have flattened villi?
He was being treated
with polystyrene.
Polystyrene
shouldn't... It didn't.
The question is, what do they
use in the NICU to bind it together?
Wheat gluten. It's great stuff.
Unless your body
can't tolerate it.
The baby didn't have
colic? He had celiac disease?
Just like Mom.
Celiac can be triggered
by all kinds of stress.
Bills, childbirth,
drunk husband...
Every time she had a bowl of pasta or
a slice of bread or a slosh of soy sauce,
her small intestine
became more damaged,
less able to absorb the vitamins
and minerals into her bloodstream.
Her body couldn't absorb
enough niacin, caused the pellagra.
Couldn't absorb vitamin
K, caused the bleeding.
And celiac is why the
baby's meds didn't work.
His body just
couldn't absorb them.
Switch Mom to IV
nutrition. It's gluten-free.
That'll spruce
her villi right up.
No. Celiac causes nutritional deprivation.
Our patient has excess calcium.
Tell them what causes excess
calcium with a chaser of bloody vomit.
Celiac patients are susceptible
to cancer of the stomach lining.
She has MALT lymphoma.
Well, she's your patient, now.
And it wasn't a date.
You don't have cancer.
You don't have dwarfism.
You have no proof of that. I,
on the other hand, have this.
You ran a PCR on me
without my consent?
Hey, it's good news. Really?
It's just hard to access because of this
overwhelming sense of personal violation.
Deal with it on your own time.
Bad news.
Estrogen is too high.
No matter how many
people you tell otherwise,
I am and always have been
a woman. Estrogen is normal.
Not this much. Not for,
at least, another week.
That's when you ovulate.
You monitor my periods
based on when I get bitchy or...
Once a month, when you leave the
kids' cancer ward, your eyes glisten.
And about three days later,
you break your ban on sugar
and chow down a bucket of frozen yogurt
in the cafeteria. Sprinkles included.
Based on the last yogurt sighting,
you've got another week before you ovulate.
You're on fertility meds.
With red clover as
an herbal booster.
And the dinner with
Wilson was an audition.
It's too bad he didn't land the
gig. He would have had fun.
I was considering a
donation. Not a party.
So when's our dinner?
Oh, he's gonna be
so disappointed. Right.
You two are gonna
have a lot of fun with this.
Your patient won't
let me touch her.
I killed my son.
Is it my turn to say
something obvious now?
Oh, I know. You were insane.
I did it. I chose to do it.
Yeah. Like diabetics
choose to not produce insulin.
Listen. Someone got
sick. Someone died.
It happens every day.
The only difference in this case
is, it wasn't the same someone.
I could have stopped.
I didn't have to
listen to those voices.
Spoken like a true sane person.
This is not your fault.
You're healthy now.
Except for the cancer.
Those voices felt as real to me
as Michael's hand
right here, when he nursed,
and the smell of his hair.
You do not deserve to die.
Maybe.
I don't want to live.
She said no.
So we get her declared
unstable, appoint a medical proxy...
She was unstable. Now, she's sane.
She's entitled to refuse the treatment.
You have to change her
mind. You can't just walk away.
Fine! Go on in there and tell
her that every day is a blessing.
"So you killed your baby? Shake it off.
Think positive. At least you're alive."
Hmm.
Kinda hard to sell when
you don't believe it, huh?
And you never believed it.
You just wanted all that crap you
went through to mean something.
Well, it didn't mean anything.
It never does. Welcome back.
Why are you doing
this to me? I was happy.
You were aspiring to be content.
Don't give me a semantic argument. I
was content with the way things were.
That's what happiness is. Yeah.
If we were all just satisfied with what
we had, what a beautiful world it would be.
We'd all slowly starve to death in our
own filth, but at least we'd be happy.
Listen. I need your
self-worth to hang on this job.
Kicking ass here to be all that
lets you rise above miserable.
If waking up in the morning
is enough, I don't need you.
I can live with that.
No, you can't. Not anymore.
If you got treatment,
then maybe we could...
When you see Mikey,
tell him his dad
says he's sorry.
Hi.
Night. Night.
Did you tell Cuddy we
tested her for cancer?
Yeah. And?
It wasn't a date.
Turned out she had some skin lesions.
Guess there was no genetic predisposition.
You TiVo The L Word?