Previously on "ER".
They got you on oxygen?
I need help
living my life, Mark
you'll be
the first person I call.
I mean, he did
every crappy assignment
that the navy wanted him to do.
It didn't matter.
He never got the nod.
You wanna talk
about this later?
No, I didn't mean to make you
feel uncomfortable. I was just‐‐
You didn't make me
feel uncomfortable.
Your father loves you
very much, Mark.
He may not show it in the way
that you want him to
'but he does.'
'Ladies and gentlemen,
welcome to San Diego.'
'Please remain seated
until the aircraft'
'has come to a full
and complete stop.'
'Flight 89
from Chicago has arrived.'
'We apologize for the delay
and we will begin boarding'
'for continuation
in just a few minutes.'
Mark?
Dad, I told you
I was gonna rent a car.
Your mother
appreciates you coming.
Wishes she could have
called you herself.
‐ They get her knee wired?
‐ And put in a cast.
I've been warning her
for years not to use
that footstool
like a stepladder.
Were you there?
I was out in the garage.
I don't have any bags.
We can go.
We've got to wait for the next
flight. Your friend's coming.
She tried to catch up with you
at O'Hare, but she missed you.
What friend?
Surprise!
Hi, Mark.
Hi.
Mm.
‐ Dad, this is Cynthia Hooper.
‐ Hi.
I hope you weren't
just being polite
on the phone, Captain Green.
I, I didn't want to barge in
but sounded like
you had your hands full
and I just really
wanted to help out.
That's nice of you.
‐ Here, let me take that.
‐ Oh, thanks.
I got it. I got it.
‐ How was your flight?
‐ It was great.
Especially the landing.
I've never seen
the Pacific before, so.
Do you have luggage?
Uh, I think
I packed too much.
You look like your dad.
'I can't believe
they lost my bags.'
'It's pretty late, but your mom
will be disappointed'
'if you don't stop by.'
'New hospital looks nice.'
'Best facility in the country.'
'I knew I couldn't
let you do this alone.'
That's sweet.
It's just, you know.
What about your shifts?
I left a message
for Kerry Weaver.
I mean, Mark, this is family.
I mean, I know
it's your family, but..
Mrs. Greene.
please, Mrs. Greene.
Be careful, please, Mrs. Greene.
No, don't make me stop.
No, no, no.
I thought sailors loved
the cancan.
‐ Hi, mom.
‐ Oh, there you are!
Oh, I'm so glad!
‐ You okay?
‐ Oh, look what I did.
‐ I'm so mad at myself.
‐ Yeah, well, accidents happen.
All I can do is cancan, and the
corpsman says I can't cancan.
Cancan. Cancan.
What meds is she on?
‐ Uh, morphine and benzo.
‐ Ativan?
Yeah, Dr. Sayers
has started tapering her off.
Dr. Sayers?
Is that her orthopod?
He's the neurology consult.
Why does she have a neurologist?
You don't mind me filling
in your son, do you?
A mother has to have
some secrets, right?
‐ Could you get him for me?
‐ I can see if he's on call.
‐ Hello.
‐ Hi.
Mom, this is Cynthia Hooper.
Nice to meet you, Mrs. Greene.
You're not getting
married again?
No, we're not, uh, thinking
about that now.
‐ At least she's not a sourpuss.
‐ I hope not.
His first wife
had a real sour streak.
Mark, you know,
as much as I hate to say it
I'm afraid Rachel's got it, too.
You can, uh,
visit more tomorrow.
Yeah, we‐we gotta
say goodnight, mom.
Okay, baby, night‐night.
Sweet dreams.
‐ I love you.
‐ Love you, too.
‐ Bye. Nice meeting you.
‐ We'll see you tomorrow.
'Goodnight. Buh‐bye.'
‐ Goodnight, Mrs. Greene.
‐ Bye‐bye, sweetheart.
Ahem, I wanna
speak with Dr. Sayers
whether he's on call or not.
Your mother's heavily medicated.
That's not my mother.
Could she have hit
her head when she fell?
Mark, for the fifth time,
I have no idea.
She didn't mention it.
Maybe something
slid off the shelf and hit her.
Dr. Sayers says that was normal.
I disagree.
Looks like
a little low density to me.
What would that mean?
She wasn't acting
like this before?
You mean
being emotional and all?
No, I mean being completely
loony and out of control.
Mark, she wasn't that bad.
It's the morphine.
That's what Dr. Sayers said.
It's just with her history of
high blood pressure
I don't wanna take any chances.
Excuse me, Dr. Greene.
I have Dr. Sayers for you.
Dr. Sayers
is a straight shooter.
I respect the man.
Your mother's getting
first‐rate care.
They owe her that.
Don't you worry about this.
'Mark is gonna get
to the bottom of it.'
No, it doesn't
look like artifact to me.
'That's not good enough.'
I want the MRI done
tomorrow morning first thing.
'What a nice quiet
neighborhood you live in.'
You got beer in the house?
Look, you may find
a couple in the garage.
Uh, may I please
use your bathroom?
My eyeballs are
about ready to float.
Yes, ma'am.
Right through there.
Why doesn't anybody
say that anymore?
Yes, ma'am. No, ma'am.
It makes you feel better
about people
just hearing it.
Yes, ma'am, it does.
'Oh, I feel so much better.
Thanks for the shampoo.'
Is this too weird?
No. Me in my old bed.
You in my mom's bathrobe.
'It's not weird at all.'
‐ I can take it off.
‐ No, that's alright.
Do you think your dad minds
that I'm here?
‐ I think he likes me.
‐ Of course, he likes you.
What's not to like?
He's really beating himself up
over your mom.
That would be a first.
I'm sorry, it's just
being here brings out
the adolescent in me.
Flip over.
I'll do your back.
'So this was your bed
growing up?'
From age eight.
We moved it from, uh,
Jacksonville to Norfolk
to Corpus Christi to DC.
So that's why you curl up
when you sleep.
Hmm?
Your feet are hanging
over the edge of the bed.
All through high school.
And during high school
you would lie in this very bed..
And think about Kate Jackson.
Kate Jackson?
‐ Not Farrah Fawcett?
‐ No, no.
Farrah Fawcett was too scary.
Oh, and Holly Fecteau
the girl next door.
Who would one night..
...sneak into this room..
...pick up the covers..
...and slide into the bed
next to you.
What?
Mm.
‐ 'We're late.'
‐ I told you to give me a shout.
I didn't know it would take you
so long to get cleaned up.
You don't just turn off
a router and walk away.
‐ There he is.
‐ Who?
Dr. Sayers.
Uh, Dr. Sayers.
You caught me, sir.
I guess it's addiction
when you're running late
and still have to stop
for your morning fix.
This is my son, Mark.
Oh, it's nice
to meet you in person.
Did you get
a few hours sleep?
A few.
Uh, I'd like
a triple grande, non‐fat cap.
Gentlemen?
‐ No, thanks.
‐ I'll take a tall latte.
We're navy,
but we're still California.
And one of those
almond buns, too, please.
I know you're concerned
about your mom.
With my mom's history
of high blood pressure‐‐
And she has
an upgoing right toe.
'It suggests stroke,
no two ways about it'
but the CT didn't confirm that
and I didn't detect any
hemiparesis or hyperreflexia.
That's why I wanted
to go ahead with the MRI.
I was only waiting
to complete a neuro exam
before I put her
through more tests.
‐ Mark, if that's better‐‐
‐ Dealer's choice.
My concern was giving
your mom some time to‐‐
Time could be
my mom's worst enemy.
That's why we moved it up.
Listen, I'd like to be present
for the neuro exam.
I mean, I know you're tapering
her off the narcotics
but frankly, I'm a little..
Present arms!
Mrs. Greene, we're going
to begin the first sequence.
Okay.
This will take about
a half an hour, mom.
It's important that
you don't move or speak.
Just take shallow, easy breaths.
This first sequence will take
two and a half minutes to shoot.
Beginning...now.
Where did my dad go?
He said he'd be back
after lunch.
Uh‐huh. Back to his garage.
He's building a wheelchair ramp
for my mom when she comes home.
That's all he's worried about.
‐ It'll come in handy.
‐ Okay.
Hang in there, Mrs. Greene.
You're doing well.
No...no.
Just relax.
‐ No.
‐ I'm here, mom. I'm here.
I...Mark..
I can't stand it, Mark.
Get me out!
Alright, stop it.
I'm getting her out.
Mark! Oh, please!
‐ Alright. It's okay.
‐ Oh, please! No!
I'm here, mom. I'm here.
Okay. Okay. Shh.
It's okay.
Don't move your leg.
‐ I can't stand it.
‐ I know. I know.
‐ What's the matter with me?
‐ No, no, no. It's normal.
It's a normal,
it's a normal reaction.
I was all alone.
‐ No, no, no.
‐ Yes, I was all alone.
No, no. You're not alone now.
I'm here.
I'm here for you, mom.
I'm here. Shh. Shh. Shh.
You're a good boy, Mark.
Stay with me, please.
I'll stay. I'll stay.
I'll stay.
Just like always.
How's that ramp coming?
Taking a break.
What did the doctor say?
Just presumptive diagnosis.
Doctor's best guess.
Her symptoms present
like a deep tissue disease
'in the frontal lobe
of the brain.'
MRI and second CT don't
indicate stroke or injury.
Sayers is thinking
uh, multi‐infarct dementia.
What's that?
Small infarcts..
...too small to detect..
...in the brain tissue.
'It could manifest
as disinhibition.'
It fits with her history
of hypertension.
Can you, uh,
explain that in English?
What's an infarct?
A series
of very small strokes.
‐ What can they do about it?
‐ Not much.
Take a wait and see approach.
‐ You still box?
‐ No.
You always had
the footwork for it.
‐ I hated the whole thing.
‐ You made that clear.
What do you think
about this wait and see
for your mother?
I think the whole thing stinks.
'Dad?'
Greene residence.
Uh, no, she's not.
Uh, hold on just a second.
Uh, what was that? Stanley..
Stanley what?
Uh‐huh.
What's this regarding?
Well, she may know,
but this is her son
and she's gonna be
tied up this week.
So I don't think
she's gonna keep
her appointment,
whatever it's for.
Right, okay.
I'll pass it along.
'It's like
a foreign language.'
You have to grow up
in it to get it right.
Hey, good morning.
My luggage didn't come, did it?
Nope.
Dad, do you know
a Stanley Black?
No.
Where does mom go
every Thursday?
What do you mean?
On her calendar,
2 o'clock is marked
every Thursday
for the last couple of months.
It could be her women's group
over at Family Services
Pavilion.
‐ 'Which group is that?'
‐ Spouses of retired officers.
The wives get together.
Uh‐huh. Is that for bridge
or service projects or what?
It's your mother's group, Mark.
I have no idea.
Who wants breakfast?
I can scramble up some eggs.
You already got one
burning there, dad.
You take that one,
instead of sneaking mine
when I'm not around.
You counting cigarettes now?
I'll pass on breakfast, thanks.
I didn't start that.
He was in a good mood before.
'What were those three items'
'that I asked you
to remember earlier?'
There were three?
'Yeah. One was a phone book.'
Mm.
Were they important?
‐ 'Not really.'
‐ Hmm.
'But do you remember?'
'Phone book.'
'An apple and..'
Banana?
No?
Do I lose points for guessing?
Not at all.
Let's move on.
I'm going to tell you a saying.
It'll be something
that you've heard before
and I want you
to tell me what it means.
Okay.
"People who live in glass houses
shouldn't throw bricks."
Have you heard that one?
‐ Yes, I have. I've heard.
‐ Hmm.
And what does it mean?
I should get this.
We've lived in lots
of different houses
haven't we, Mark?
Never a glass house.
"People in glass houses
shouldn't throw bricks."
Well, people shouldn't
throw bricks
even if it's close quarters,
and it usually is.
You've got to get along
with all the other families.
They're all in
the same boat you are.
The children are probably
the ones throwing the bricks.
And how are the mothers
supposed to stop them
if the fathers aren't around?
It's always the mother's fault
even if she doesn't
wanna have the children
in the first place.
That was a trick question.
I think I've got it, sneaky.
If you live in a glass house..
...there are no bricks to throw.
Right? Right?
'Dr. Greene?'
‐ Yes?
‐ 'Okay.'
I've got Corey‐Bloom
"Acta Neurologica Scandinavica"
McLauchlin, Sandison
and Flostein.
Thank you.
I'm off at midnight
but you're welcome
to stay if you need to.
I will.
'Hey.'
I thought you were asleep.
'I woke up.'
‐ Sorry I got ahead of you.
‐ Oh, don't you dare apologize.
I thought you were with me.
You are the most considerate man
that I have ever been with.
Every single time doesn't
have to be about me.
Still..
I don't know
where you get it.
You know, being so generous.
If I had..
...whatever it is
that your mom has..
...and if I just said..
...everything
that was on my mind
I would thank both
of your parents
for raising a son
who was such a good lover.
You bring it out in me.
You lie.
It has nothing to do with me.
You take care of people.
Yeah.
That's me, the caretaker.
It's not a bad thing.
I'm like a magnet
for needy people.
They find me wherever I go.
Like I did?
‐ No, I‐I‐‐
‐ Yeah, Mark, I lean on you.
I mean...it must be a drag.
No...it..
It's just all this..
...stuff with my mom.
Yeah.
You're just overwhelmed
right now.
'Very still, mom.
Very still.'
What's this one for?
We wanna rule out encephalitis.
It might be why you're not
feeling like yourself.
Isn't that why
they scanned my belly?
'That was to rule out
paraneoplastic syndrome.'
Hmm. Almost done.
'How many more
rule‐outs are left?'
Are you getting tired?
The other doctor said
I could go home.
He signed off on the knee.
We still have to do
an EEG tomorrow.
Actually it doesn't
have to be tomorrow.
If it's Jakob‐Creutzfeldt,
I don't wanna mess around.
How about a brain biopsy
while we are at it?
I know I'm pushing you
for a more aggressive approach
than you're used to.
I can be thorough
without being aggressive.
‐ All done, Mrs. Greene.
‐ Can I go now?
Probably in another day or two.
Oh.
Look, if my mother
were in the ER
I'd be terrible support for her.
I don't have the temperament
for emergent care.
for a passive course
of treatment.
Is your mother sick,
too, doctor?
No, Mrs. Greene.
My mother's fine.
Your indulging me
in a few tests is not enough.
I want a second opinion.
I'll arrange for the chairman
of neurology to come in.
No. I'm gonna find a civilian.
'She's been seeing
this shrink for a month.'
'What for?'
The guy wouldn't tell me
without a release.
I'm gonna meet with him
at the hospital tomorrow.
Uh, sorry, son,
you a retired naval officer?
Uh, no, my father is.
We're meeting him here.
I'm afraid I'll have
to ask you to leave.
‐ Give me a break.
‐ It's club night.
You need to be in the company
of a retired officer.
Well, he's on his way, he must
be running a little late.
Then, you'll have to wait
for him if you wanna be seated.
You're wrong, pal.
We're seated.
I'll have a draft
and a margarita.
‐ And what are you buying me?
‐ I beg your pardon?
You're as stubborn
as your old man.
Don't tell me you're as cheap
as he is, too.
Admiral J. Jackson, retired.
And you better be
Dave Greene's son
or I got myself
into a hornet's nest.
That's right...Mark Greene.
‐ This is Cynthia Hooper.
‐ How do you do?
Your dad just called
to say he'd be late.
‐ So what are you drinking?
‐ Not a drop more.
I'm late for dinner as it is.
Pleased to see
you again, though.
We met your senior year.
You were considering Annapolis.
My dad was considering
Annapolis.
Hey, you can't blame
your old man for trying.
Turn down
a flag billet for your family..
...you don't mind seeing
your son make the grade.
‐ What's a flag billet?
‐ Admiral.
His dad was in line.
Middle of his command tour.
Took himself out of the running.
Why, didn't he wanna be admiral?
Long story.
Put their drinks on my tab.
Are you sure you
don't want to stay?
Admiral Jay,
nice to see you, sir.
Sorry I have to run.
I could relive
the Korean conflict
for you young folks.
‐ How's Ruth?
‐ She'll be home tomorrow.
‐ She will?
‐ That's what I said.
Uh, Lucy and I will drop by
when she's feeling better.
‐ Nice seeing you, meeting you.
‐ Same here.
What can I get you, dad?
‐ Not a thing.
‐ Something wrong?
Why did you say
mom was coming home?
‐ She's had her last test.
‐ No, she hasn't.
Yes, she has, Mark.
‐ Syphilis?
‐ What?
You had your mother tested
for syphilis?
‐ Did the results come back?
‐ No.
I stopped the whole damn thing.
Whatever gave you the idea..
I'm looking
for an explanation.
What the hell do you think
of your mother?
The symptoms fit.
What the hell
do you think of me?
Settle down, dad.
Why don't you use your inhaler?
Is your oxygen in the car?
Some damn nerve.
If the test is so unthinkable,
what's your fear?
You're accusing me?
No, he didn't mean it like that.
I need a diagnosis.
You need someone
to blame, like always.
‐ Oh, take it easy, dad.
‐ Don't you patronize me!
There's no need
for you to meddle.
Should I get your oxygen?
Insult your mother.
Okay. Great.
Go back to Chicago
and leave us alone.
I mean, she's going home.
Good, then I'll just tell
that psychiatrist
'that she's been
secretly seeing'
to not bother coming
to the hospital.
What the hell
are you talking about?
She's going to a shrink
not a sewing circle
every Thursday.
Now why would she be doing that?
Mark, come on!
Or is that me meddling, huh?
Making too much trouble
when her life with you
is so picture perfect?
Alright, dad, take a breath,
take‐take a breath.
Where's your Albuterol?
‐ Shall I get the oxygen?
‐ Yes, go!
‐ He's not breathing.
‐ Let's get him on the ground.
‐ 'Call 911 for him.'
‐ Let him down easy.
'Your dad's peak flow's
improved to 250.'
'He's maintained a pH of 7.38
on ten liters.'
His PO2's 65,
his PCO2 is down to 48.
It's not gonna
get much better.
‐ He's a pretty heavy smoker.
‐ Yeah.
We've got him
on 125 Solu‐Medrol IV.
Captain Greene,
do you feel better?
I feel fine.
I understand you've been
under some stress lately
with your wife
admitted upstairs.
That's right.
That may have brought on
the attack.
We're gonna keep an eye
on you here in the ER
for a few more hours.
Why don't you come back later,
see if we can release him.
Thanks.
You kinda gave us a scare.
‐ Is Cynthia up with your mom?
‐ Drove her home.
She was asleep on her feet.
You're not going to bother
your mother with this.
No. She doesn't need to know.
I'm sorry if I upset you.
‐ About that test for your mom‐‐
‐ It's canceled.
No.
Draw the blood.
You need to know.
I was treating your mother's
depression with Paxil.
She failed to mention
her hypertension.
I should let you know that
I'm getting a second
neurological consult
from a colleague at UCSD.
Dr. Hemmings,
she was with your mother
when I arrived this morning
Good.
But I told her I agree
with Dr. Sayers' diagnosis.
Multi‐infarct dementia
and co‐morbidity
with her depression.
I know it's not
the kind of diagnosis
you were hoping for.
It's not about what
I hope for, Dr. Black.
It's about my mother's care.
I'm sure you've heard about
how stubborn the men
are in my family.
I'm not asking you
to break confidentiality.
Actually your mother
signed a full release.
You're welcome to know anything
about her psychiatric
treatment
that you'd care to.
If I wanna know about my mom's
depression
I'll ask her.
Be sure you want the answers.
In her current state of mind
she's liable to tell you.
Mark.
‐ What's wrong?
‐ Nothing.
Everything's fine.
You were gone for a long time.
I needed it.
Yeah, um, Dr. Hemmings called.
She wanted to push up
your meeting to 3 o'clock.
It's the neurologist
I called in.
She's an old friend?
Went to med school.
She wanted to know
if I'd be coming along
if we'd meet, but I figured
that you probably want
to talk
about your mom privately.
Yeah. It's about her condition.
'Hey, guys, take turns'
'or you're both gonna
get a time out.'
'Thank you, Josh.'
They say girls are more mellow.
Please confirm that.
‐ Don't ask me.
‐ You have Rachel.
Not full time.
I remember when Rachel was born.
You were third year.
I was so envious
of you and Jen.
You? You were the most
driven student in class.
Yeah, but you were
the most together.
You knew you wanted a family
and you went for it.
‐ Now you've lapped me.
‐ Twice.
If I'd known you were
on maternity leave
I wouldn't have called.
Oh, it was my pleasure.
I was a little taken aback
when I found out
that your mom's a patient
of Andrew Sayers.
He's hot stuff.
Gaining a national reputation.
I haven't been that wowed.
You know, I'm really
surprised at you.
I..
Josh, no.
Please. We don't throw sand.
I thought the ER
would be a brief detour.
I thought for sure
you'd end up in family practice.
Really? I was that boring, huh?
You know I didn't think that.
We were 25.
I was busy showing
how independent I was
and you were determined
to be the good family man.
Now, here I am,
and you're a cowboy.
Well, I still haven't given up
on the idea of having a family.
Yeah, Cynthia sounded sweet.
Still know how to cut
to the quick, don't you?
You wanna hear about your mom?
Do I?
Your mom may not fully return
to the way she was.
That's gonna take
some getting used to.
‐ How's she doing?
‐ She was asleep when I arrived.
I owe you an apology.
No, you don't. It's your mother.
Still, I..
Just know it wasn't personal.
You don't have to explain.
My dad was in the navy, too.
Chip on my shoulder's
that easy to read?
Plain as rank.
Strong, hard‐working father.
Never there.
But you followed
in your dad's footsteps.
I wish I could tell you
it got me closer.
'Okay, people,
give me a hand, here!'
What's going on?
We gotta move your dad
out of the way.
I got a mass cal coming in.
They had chopper crash, a CH‐46.
'The Sea Knight?
Holds a platoon?'
Lucky, she just
had her crew aboard
and one injured on the ground.
‐ 'How many critical?'
‐ Three.
Evac's landed!
Let's move, people!
Third‐degree burns,
20% to face and legs.
He's had ten of morphine.
Ready, one, two, three.
Alright, people, on my count.
Ready? One, two, three.
She's got an eviscerating
abdominal wound!
Get O‐neg on the rapid infuser.
BP's 40.
Pulse is weak and thready.
'Okay, people, on three.
Ready? One, two, three.'
‐ How bad are they?
‐ Pretty bad.
‐ Fib!
‐ They're gonna defibrillate.
They're gonna shock her.
I tried to pull up,
but the stick got heavy.
'The stick..'
'...it wouldn't budge.'
'We were only 30 feet
off the deck.'
'Don't worry, son.'
Hey, are the others
gonna be alright?
They're doing
everything they can.
We pitched forward.
I couldn't pull her back.
I couldn't budge the stick!
Just thank God you weren't full.
I gotta get up.
I gotta help my crew!
Settle down, son.
You did your best.
‐ I couldn't pull the stick!
‐ Now, that sounds mechanical.
'Now, you got
the best doctors and nurses'
'and corpsmen in the world
working on your crew.'
So stop blaming yourself
and let them do their work.
Can you hear me, son?
Mark?
Hey, buddy.
‐ This guy's not breathing.
‐ What happened?
‐ He was just talking.
‐ No carotid pulse. Bag him.
‐ Mark.
‐ He's crashing!
‐ Corpsman, take over here!
‐ It's a tension pneumo.
Yeah, you're right.
Fourteen gauge.
'Notify the surgical
and critical care unit.'
'Alright, but notify the OR.'
Is he okay?
'She's got eviscerating
abdominal wound.'
'Get O‐neg
on the rapid infuser.'
Good call.
Yeah, I'm prepping for an
escharotomy on the burn victim.
‐ You ever done a chest tube?
‐ I've seen two.
You don't have staff privileges,
do you, doctor?
I'm not even licensed
in this state.
You mind running
this intern through it?
No, not a problem.
Chest tube tray.
'Whatever Dr. Greene says,
consider it an order.'
Yes, sir.
Alright, get gloves on.
I'll assist.
You'll need a 36 French.
Is he okay now?
He should be.
How about you?
Fifth intercostal space
'mid‐axillary line.'
20 CCs of Xylocaine.
'That's right.'
‐ Home sweet home!
‐ Oh, you guys were so fast!
‐ Dinner isn't even ready!
‐ 'Oh, look at the azaleas.'
‐ 'They never looked so good!'
‐ I picked off all dead ones.
That's why you like 'em.
It's so good to be back,
I'm telling you.
‐ Welcome home!
‐ Oh, thank you.
No wonder you took a spill.
Well, I had to start
cleaning things up.
I don't even know
half the stuff that's in there.
‐ Oh, look, was this yours?
‐ Oh, my God. Mr. Funny Bear.
You sure loved the fur
off this thing.
‐ Oh, and what is this?
‐ 'Oh, no, not that fiasco.'
You remember?
You saw it in the PX.
And you begged
and begged me for it.
We hung it from the ceiling
in his bedroom.
It was Dave's first tour
of Vietnam..
It was his first tour,
wasn't it?
‐ I don't remember.
‐ Must've been.
Your father took you
to the airfield
and put you in the cockpit
before he left.
You looked at this thing
'hanging from the ceiling
every night.'
Until he got home
and laughed his head off.
We'd gotten
the wrong damn plane.
That's a Phantom.
Dad flew A‐6s.
"What the hell's that doing
in your bedroom?"
He wasn't angry with you.
‐ He tore it down.
‐ No, you tore it down.
'Don't you remember
you got a spanking'
'for standing on your dresser.'
That was the one
that he bought to replace it.
I tore that one down.
Well, somebody tore
something down.
Anyway, I'm hungry!
Oh, um, look,
I'm really sorry about dinner.
I'm just...I wasn't used
to your oven
so let me make you
something to eat.
You know, every woman's not
cut out for the kitchen.
'In my generation,
we all had to be'
natural‐born wives and mothers.
Doesn't sound so bad.
Ah, I think he's back.
You know, sex isn't enough
to hold a family together.
God knows Dave and I always
got the sex part right.
Can't count on that
if you are counting on it.
We're not counting
on anything, mom.
This is a little inappropriate.
‐ We're not?
‐ See, she's counting on it.
‐ I don't know what we're‐‐
‐ We're talking about sex.
And whether sex means
anything more than sex.
Okay, leave me out
of that conversation.
Why wouldn't you
want to talk about that?
I know why.
You don't have to say.
I hope pizza's okay.
The sandwich place was closed.
I'm not hungry.
I am so sorry.
You are a wonderful,
beautiful person.
But you don't love me.
I‐I don't know.
Then you don't.
I was such an idiot
to come out here
like I was part of your family.
No, no, no, that's my fault.
I..
I should have told you.
I was..
...just being selfish.
You mean a lot to me.
I never intended
to lead you on.
I‐I thought we were both
en‐enjoying ourselves‐‐
Stop.
Please.
This may be new for you,
but I've heard it before..
...too many times.
So I guess I asked for it.
No.
I never should have
let it go on so long.
You know, we should go.
I, uh, I don't wanna
miss my plane.
Cynthia, you really
don't need to leave.
Yeah, I really do.
I'll be back in Chicago
in a week at the latest.
‐ We'll talk more?
‐ We don't have to talk.
You know, there's a lot that's
good about us together.
I, I mean, I feel that way.
That...I hope you do, too.
At least I got to see
the Pacific.
‐ Ready, mom?
‐ 'Yeah. I'm ready.'
Put your arm around my neck.
Lean on me.
Good.
No weight on that leg.
I don't know
why I can't use the walker.
Wait until the therapist
gives you your lesson, okay?
Don't empty that.
I might need to use it again.
Your nurse isn't gonna
be here for an hour.
You know, you've got to let dad
and I help sometimes.
I do. I am.
It's time for your pills.
I'm tired of pills.
Just take the pills, mom.
I can't get dad
to pay attention.
He pays attention.
Yeah. From the garage.
Now, don't be like that.
Is it true that dad
had a shot at making admiral?
Yes, of course, he did.
You know that story.
Remind me.
Oh, it was that Leadbetter boy.
He was such a bully to you.
‐ Tommy Leadbetter?
‐ Uh‐huh.
He used to beat me up
every day in sixth grade?
You were scared
to go to school.
I don't remember that part.
Well..
...I made your father
come back..
...'cause..
I didn't tell him he had to
but I knew that if I wrote
enough, he'd‐he'd come.
That's when he took
that desk job in Hueneme?
Mm‐hmm.
And you know,
he never once complained.
Dr. Black says that
you and your father
are responsible
for your own feelings.
'But I know
I started it.'
I blamed him.
I blamed you.
I...I didn't want a baby.
'It was too soon.'
'We'd only dated
a couple of times.'
Of course, when I saw you
I loved you.
And I tried to make up for it.
But I'd already
spoiled everything
between you and your father.
And it just kept going wrong.
'No matter how much
I loved you both.'
'David!'
What's going on?
I don't know. She's not in bed.
'David!'
'Help me! Help me!'
David! Hurry! Oh!
'Hurry up!
Oh, God, hurry up!'
‐ Hurry up! Hurry up!
‐ Dad, get the wheelchair.
Mom, mom, what happened?
I just thought
a little broth would be nice.
Okay. Alright, we're gonna
get you up slowly.
Dad, give me a hand.
Okay, on a count.
One, two, three.
Okay? Alright, easy, easy.
Is your leg okay?
Oh, gosh!
What if I broke it?
Yeah.
Ha ha ha.
Slide back. There you go.
That's why you can't
use that walker, okay?
'Cause this can happen.
Oh, dear, I forgot
to go to the bathroom.
It's okay. I'll clean it up.
You just go ahead.
Oh! Okay.
'We have a non‐injury accident
in the right‐hand lane.'
'Traffic is extremely slow
on the Bay Bridge today'
'with the USS Long Beach
home ported at North Island.'
'Is that gonna hold us up?'
'We're not going
on the Bay Bridge.'
'I heard you tell the nurse
we wouldn't be back for lunch.'
'That's right.
No more clues.'
You used to bring me down here.
There used to be
something to see.
Every one of those docks
used to be full.
Here.
‐ No, thanks. I've stopped.
‐ You what?
Gave them up
for your mother.
‐ Since when?
‐ Since the hospital.
Have you seen me
take a cigarette?
You smoked two packs
a day for 50 years.
You must be going through
some heavy‐duty withdrawals.
Uh‐huh.
We saw the Kitty Hawk here,
remember?
Yeah. It scared me.
It's huge.
I remember that flight deck,
it was like, uh..
It was like standing
on the edge of the earth.
The most hazardous
work site there is.
What was it like
working on a carrier?
Hard.
How many aircraft
would you launch in a day?
Oh, up to 140
in a 12‐hour shift.
Launchings 20 seconds apart.
Landings every 40 seconds.
We worked all kind of weather.
Day and night.
Sounds intense.
The best time was first thing
in the morning
'before they started
the engines.'
I'd come up on the...the bridge
watch the sun rise
over the flight deck
and the canopies.
'Ocean rolling as far
as you could see.'
'Admiral wasn't up yet'
complaining of the jet fuel
in his water.
Deck crew would be out working
on the catapults
and the arresting gear.
Ordnance guys loading up.
'You knew in a minute
the engines would start'
'and lives would be at stake'
'for every minute of
the next 12 hours.'
Sound familiar?
Sort of.
I'm proud of what you do, son.
'I'm proud of you.'
Thanks for helping me get there.
Your mother's gonna be worried.
We should get back.