She almost took my head off.
Your fault. You didn't
guard your left side.
Point.
Stop, stop, stop!
Addie, you're bleeding.
I never even hit her.
Good morning.
This is funny. People don't...
Not done reading. Go away.
Most likely, she coughed it up.
Which would mean it's from her
lungs. Drugs, toxins, infection...
No fever and no elevated white
count. Which rules out infection.
And blood panels found
no drugs, no toxins.
The bronchoscopy was
pristine. So much for the lungs.
Good morning. Not yet.
So then, the blood
came from her stomach.
Which would mean it's
an ulcer or a GI bleed.
ER also did an upper and lower
GI. No occult blood in her stool.
Which means no
ulcer or GI bleed.
Which means it's not
from the stomach, either.
Which means it didn't
come from anywhere.
You guys get to the point where
the blood didn't come from anywhere?
Rupture in her sinus cavity?
Drip through the back?
Not that much blood.
Trauma from karate?
No trauma. She kicked
the other guy's ass.
Now a good time?
If you can tell me how blood
can mysteriously appear in a...
Now. This includes you.
What's going on?
Feel free to speculate
amongst yourselves.
Are you sure? Yeah.
Why?
He's afraid of turning into me.
Well, that's a good
enough reason.
Sign here.
Doesn't look promising.
Good luck.
Thank you. That's it?
You're not going to tell
him that we're a family
and families don't
abandon each other?
You want me to? No.
Would it make
any difference? No.
Good luck, Dr. Foreman.
So, where were we?
College sophomore
coughing up blood.
Not the case. The speculation. The
palace intrigue. The rising self-doubts.
Did Foreman get a promotion?
I resigned.
What?
Personally, I can't believe I've had the
same three employees for three years.
Patient could have
a heart problem.
Yes. Life goes on. Look at the
eager beaver combing his hair.
Hyper-dynamic heart could force
too much blood into her lungs.
She coughed up the overflow.
Wouldn't leave a trace in her lungs because
it's traveling through normal plumbing.
Foreman, go do a stress
echo test to see if he's right.
Cameron? Check out the
dorm, then re-do the ER labs.
I'll get going on
Foreman's farewell party.
Everybody good with a
"Mermaid Under the Stars" theme?
So, why are you leaving?
Or is it just some
sort of power play?
You can have my
parking space, my locker.
Is it about House?
Let me get all sensitive
and confide in you.
Addie? Pedal harder.
Need your heart rate at 170.
Why wouldn't you
want to tell me?
I don't like you.
Never have. Never will.
You want me to share some more?
Even if you do hate me, if you'd
found another job, you'd tell me.
If House did something to drive
you out of here, you'd tell me.
The fact that you won't tell me
means that whatever the real reason is
you're ashamed of it.
Guys? I'm at 170.
Pulmonary artery looks
good. It's not a heart problem.
Are you cold? No.
Scared? I'm okay. Why?
On your arm.
Addie has goose bumps.
No recovering from those babies.
You don't have goose
bumps for no reason.
They're a reaction to
the body thinking it's cold.
She wasn't cold. Her
temperature was normal.
But her body thought
it was. Which means...
What? A brain problem?
A messed up hypothalamus
could cause goose bumps
but they're not going to
cause her to cough up blood.
She has no neurological
issues. She had a shiver.
I think there's an infection.
We've ruled out infection
because no fever, no white count.
I think there's an infection.
Blood goes where it's needed. Infection
likes nice, wet places. Her lungs.
Start treatment. All that cool stuff for
bacterial, fungal, and atypical infections.
Get a lung biopsy. I want to
see the little bugger up close.
Why is Foreman quitting?
He wants to breed llamas.
Interesting.
You're ashamed
of the reason, too.
No one writes
tamoxifen like you.
Well, I use a "G."
Foreman resigned.
I'm sorry.
It's okay. No biggie.
Right. He give a reason?
He said he didn't want to end
up like me. I had a brilliant retort.
I can't remember what
it was at the moment.
You don't want
to end up like you.
Good point. Can I resign?
What's up with that?
With what? You yawned.
I just told you something
interesting, so you're not bored.
It's 11:00 in the morning, you're
drinking coffee, so you're not tired.
I didn't yawn, so it's not
a mirror-neuron reaction.
Which leaves symptom. Vasovagal
issue, maybe a heart problem.
My heart's fine. I was up late.
You're just deflecting having
a conversation about Foreman.
I'm okay with Foreman leaving.
Either you're lying, or you
don't really think he's leaving
or you just jumped
right to acceptance.
I'm sorry. I yawned because I
was trying to communicate boredom.
You could try bargaining
with him. Give him a raise.
How much do you think it would
cost to make him want to be like me?
Thanks for the coffee.
She seems fine.
She is fine. She
coughed up blood.
Past tense. She has diarrhea.
From the antibiotics
for the infection.
Lung biopsy says she
doesn't have an infection.
Well, then, you
screwed up the biopsy.
Or you're wrong about infection.
If I'm wrong, then
so is her body.
Because it obviously
thinks she's got an infection,
or it wouldn't have gotten
better from the antibiotics.
What is pandiculation
symptomatic of?
Yawning is a symptom of
fatigue or cholinergic excitation.
Does this have anything
to do with Addie?
Let's say yes.
Cerebral tumor, epilepsy...
Could also be a medication
reaction to antidepressants
or some meds for
end-stage liver failure.
Let's say no.
You don't want
to leave this job.
Three years you've been here.
You've never once
laughed at anything he said.
Because I wasn't
kissing his ass.
But now, you are? No.
Now, you're nervous.
Uncomfortable about your decision.
Wasn't even that good a joke.
Oh, crap.
Most of your jokes are excellent.
I just meant in comparison.
Shut up. I think she
may not have an infection.
Better deal with her
before she crashes.
She can't breathe.
Get off the bed.
Need a crash cart.
What's happening?
Let's get her down. Now.
Pressure's collapsing her
lungs. She's not getting any air.
Oh, my God.
She couldn't breathe because
she had a pleural effusion.
Thoracentesis revealed low protein
count, effusion was transudative,
which means she has cirrhosis
of the liver, or she's in heart failure.
Heart was fine, liver
enzymes were normal.
There's something called
"blude" in the pleural effusion.
Oh. It's not
"blude," it's blood.
Which is great. Not for her, but for me.
Because it means I think it's an infection.
Labs indicated
minute traces of blood.
You can't ignore the blood because
it's a minority. Can you, Foreman?
If we count the traces
of blood as significant,
the differential
isn't just infection.
Could be lung cancer,
breast cancer, lymphoma...
Great. Go tell her
she's got one of those.
Or you can tell her that we haven't given
her enough antibiotics for her infection.
Double the dose.
Then check her lungs.
We checked her
lungs. They're clean.
On the outside. She
needs an arteriogram.
It's about my bowel movements.
What isn't, these days?
You sure you want
to be here for this?
We do everything together.
Of course. A toilet
can be a lonely place.
Drop your pants. I'll suit up.
They float. Huh?
My bowel movements. Honey
says they're not supposed to?
I'm a nutritionist.
Yes, I could tell from
the cool toe-loop sandals.
Thank you. You're welcome.
And the natural fiber
clothing, I assume,
means some kind of
vegetarian denomination?
We're vegans. At first, I was a little
concerned about the lack of protein
but Honey showed me
you can get it from lots...
Well, whatever floats your poop.
And you've been together
how long? Six months?
How did you know?
Because after six
months, poop love fades
and if you'd been together
shorter than that, then...
I'll explain right
after this break.
Three 10-milligram pills of
your finest amphetamines.
Arteriogram was normal.
Which means her lungs are fine.
What if the clear
arteriogram is significant?
It is significant. It means
there's no infection.
I think there's an infection.
Infections don't come and go.
People don't get better then
worse on the same treatment.
Unless her body
can't finish off the fight.
Maybe goes a couple
of rounds, then gives up.
Why would it give up?
Maybe its name is Foreman.
Come on. Where's that smile?
That laugh that makes
the whole world sunny
without contributing
to global warming?
Maybe she's missing a protein.
Blood panel and enzymes
show her proteins are normal.
You can't have tested
for every protein.
I can think of at least
one you can't test for at all.
Complement factor-H deficiency.
If she has that, she's dead.
No way to fend off bacteria.
She'll get one infection after
another until her body shuts down.
Maybe we can get ahead of the game.
Manage each symptom as it comes up.
Give her five miserable years
instead of six miserable months.
There's no diagnostic test for
complement factor-H deficiency.
So we isolate the cells
that are yummiest for it.
Stick a needle in her eye.
You're cheating on Honey.
What? No. I'm not.
Oh, yes, you are.
It's okay. I get it.
Well, I was going to say relax.
But, oddly enough, you
seem pretty relaxed already.
You're accomplished.
You're funny.
You can have whatever you
want. Women are gonna...
He's not cheating
with another woman.
He's cheating with
another food group.
What?
His floaters float
because they're full of fat.
Probably had a big
cheeseburger for lunch.
You're eating flesh?
It's just a hamburger.
Not all the time...
You're disgusting.
Soy cakes taste like
cardboard. Unsalted cardboard.
I'm accomplished. I'm funny.
Can I have whatever I want?
Can we wait a second?
What's wrong? I feel good.
Do you really need
to put that needle in?
You felt good yesterday, and
then you almost suffocated.
And you know that,
that thing is in my eye?
We think it could be.
If we find it, the hope
is that we can treat it.
You hope? Mom. Don't
hang on every word.
He said he hopes. That
means he doesn't know.
I just want to understand
what's going on.
We won't know anything
until we do the test.
Addie, this all looks really scary,
but you'll feel nothing. Okay?
Okay.
You rang? You called me.
I bought you an espresso.
You've been buying me
coffee for a couple of weeks.
I thought I'd pay
you back with one.
How did you walk with the
cane and the two coffees?
Why are you suspicious?
Because it's either that, or accept the
fact that you've done something nice.
And then I have to deal with the horsemen
and the rain of fire and the end of days.
You think I spat in yours?
Or worse.
I stacked them.
What do you think of me hiring a
nutritionist instead of a neurologist?
I mean, they sound
almost the same.
I take it you've met
a hot nutritionist.
Don't cheapen this.
We had an in-depth conversation
about proteins and fats.
I was about to examine
her boyfriend's rectum.
You asked for a date while
your finger was in her boyfriend?
I got her number.
No. No. No way.
This is an employment
application.
She doesn't want to go out
with you. She's looking for a job.
Oh, God. She's 26.
But with the wisdom of
a much younger woman.
Have you spoken to Foreman?
Several times. We laughed...
You're going to lose him.
And that will be depressing.
But it will only make me appreciate
all the good things that I do have.
Macular biopsy was negative.
Which means you're wrong.
There's no complement
factor-H deficiency.
Most likely cause of altering blood
flow in the brain is a clot or a tumor.
We can rule out a clotting issue
because she has a bleeding issue.
Which means we should
be looking for a tumor.
I think there's an infection.
Just 'cause the cells in her eye aren't
dead yet doesn't mean they're working.
So, why did we do the test?
Because if it had been positive,
it would have proved I was right.
But negative doesn't
prove you wrong?
That's the beauty of the test.
She needs an MRI of her brain.
Absolutely.
As long as you're scanning, you
mind having a boo for an abscess
for something caused
by an infection?
I didn't expect House
to beg me to stay.
But it seems like he's in
a better mood since I quit.
Nothing in the axial view.
You haven't asked
me why I'm leaving.
I figured you'd tell me
when you wanted to.
I don't want to be like him.
You're not a jerk.
Thank you.
I mean, sometimes you are.
But I don't think we
can pin that on House.
And you're a better doctor than
when you came through the door.
I'm better at some
things. Worse at others.
Again, not House's
fault. It's a job.
We're supposed to take
the good and leave the bad.
It's easier for you.
Why? Because you think
I need to toughen up?
You think I'm weak?
Yeah.
See? I am a jerk. I've
got to get out of here.
What's wrong, Addie?
My head hurts!
Her brain's clean. No
tumor and no abscess.
We're all wrong. My head!
My head!
Grody.
Looks like massive tissue death.
Who cares? Her head blew up.
- How cool is that?
- It's not pussy.
Meaning you don't think it's an infection
and you'd be right, if you weren't wrong.
Here we go again.
She's got infections
that come and go.
Which means... It means
it has to be something else.
Good guess. But no.
It either she's got a
leprechaun in her colon,
which is playing
with the doggie door,
letting bacteria in and out, or she's
got complement factor-H deficiency.
You enjoying this?
I'm saving a woman's life.
I'm saving a woman's life!
Actually, I'm diagnosing her.
Technically, I'm diagnosing her
with something that's going to kill her.
But, other than that,
I'm saving her life.
An autoimmune problem
makes more sense.
You can't explain a
transudative pleural effusion
with giant cell arteritis.
You'd need three whiteboards
and 100 different colored markers.
No, it's much more likely
she has an invisible protein
that allowed bacteria to
arbitrarily invade her lungs
then arbitrarily invade her pleura,
then arbitrarily jump into her head.
If it's autoimmune,
she can live.
But we have to give her steroids,
now. Before her heart ruptures.
If you're wrong, and you give
her steroids she dies, now.
Foreman. Want to run down how it feels
to go with your gut and kill a person?
You can get into the whole
spiraling out of control,
and the self-doubt,
and the resigning thing.
Do it.
Worst that can
happen is you quit.
Cameron, want to
explain to the parents
why you'll be holding
paddles while he's doing it?
Because if her heart goes
"boom", it will "boom" right away.
She really has to
be awake for this?
If there's a problem, she
could tell us what she feels.
Relax.
We're scared.
I don't want you to be scared.
Then, get better. Okay, sweetie?
We love you.
I'm sorry.
Ready?
Ready.
My patient's about to have a
heart attack. It's going to be massive.
Oh, wow. That's too bad.
Because I just got tickets
to a stroke on the third floor.
Have you had a
conversation with Foreman?
Do me a favor?
You haven't.
Because then you would have
to confront your own emotions.
Is bile an emotion? Because I
definitely feel something here.
Get me some liquorice. This is going
to be the best heart attack of all time.
Oh! Wait, wait, wait, wait!
She's going to shock her.
There's always tomorrow.
You wanted to see me?
Pretty sure the
label is straight.
Are you really going to
leave? Where are you going?
You lined up interviews
yet? I'm not sure.
You're pissed at House. I get it.
You're symbolicating killing him.
Symbolicating.
What? Symbolicalating.
Gosh, that's a hard
word. Are you okay?
Hey, I'm not the
one... I'm not the one...
I'm not the one
pretending to kill someone.
What would it take for you to stay?
Is it money? He wants you to stay.
He said that? If I
said he said that,
would that make a difference?
Are you sure you're okay? Hello?
I'm leaving now.
I'm late for a breast thing.
You know he wants you.
You know he's good. You
know he can make you good.
I don't know what I'm saying. You know...
I don't... You know what I'm saying.
And you know I'm
right. I've got to go.
Sorry it took me so long to
get down here. I'm Dr. Wilson.
I guess Dr. Stein is
gone. Don't worry about it.
I'll talk to him
when we're done.
Dr. Stein said they're
probably calcium deposits.
But with your medical history,
you don't want to take chances.
I can't seem to put my
gloves on today. That's weird.
Okay. Well, that's fine. One's
enough. Well, let's have a look.
You sure talk fast.
This is nothing. You should
see me when we're busy.
I just winked at you. I just... I've
never winked at a patient in my life.
I have no... I am so sorry. I
have no idea what I was thinking.
It's okay. No, it's not.
I was hitting on you.
I mean, I wasn't... I wasn't
consciously hitting on you, but I...
What else could you think?
That you were being reassuring?
Yeah. That would make
sense. On the other hand, I...
I feel like my heart's
going to explode.
Are you okay?
I feel a little sweaty.
Am I sweating?
Yeah.
Is something wrong? I can't...
I put on gloves to do a
breast exam. Perfect. Sorry.
It's 185.
One eighty-five.
One eighty-five?
Excuse me. I have
to go kill someone.
You dosed me!
Yes, I did. But only
because you didn't trust me.
Your best friend!
You could have killed me!
Amphetamines
aren't going to kill you.
You don't know
my medical history!
I could have... I could have...
You could have given
me a heart attack!
A heart attack is not going to
kill you. You were in a hospital.
You yawned!
You tried to kill me!
I put you on uppers
and you still yawned.
Means it's a symptom
of being a big, fat liar.
Yawning is a side effect
of some anti-depressants.
Apparently, the ones you're on.
I'm not on anti-depressants,
I'm on speed.
That means it's a symptom
of a cerebral tumor.
You got six weeks to live.
Mr. Well-adjusted is as
messed up as the rest of us.
Why... Why would
you keep that a secret?
Are you ashamed of recognizing
how pathetic your life is?
It's not a secret.
House, it's... It's...
It's personal.
How long has it been
personal? It's personal.
Yawning is recent. So,
either you just started,
or you changed prescriptions.
This is why I take them.
They're anti-depressants,
not anti-annoyance-ants.
You'd think this would naturally
come up in conversation.
Oh, don't act hurt.
You don't care.
On one of the occasions when
you were pompously lecturing me
on what to do to fix my life.
You wouldn't take them.
You'd rather OD on Vicodin
or stick electrodes in your head, because
you could say you did it to get high.
The only reason to take anti-depressants
is because you're depressed.
You... You have to admit
that you're depressed.
Give me.
Are you going to admit that...
No, I'm gonna prove
that I'm not depressed.
Well, I can't give you my prescription.
You've got to meet with a psychiatrist.
You... You need a whole work-up.
Give me a Vicodin
so I don't stroke.
I wouldn't drink that.
My leg hurt, and I...
House, why didn't
you pick up the phone?
We've been calling.
I was sleeping.
What did you do?
Nothing.
This is how regular people
look when you wake them up.
Chase was wrong.
Addie's kidneys shut down.
Hemolytic uremic syndrome
shut down Addie's kidneys.
Peripheral smear of red
cells had schistocytes.
HUS is usually caused by an
infection or protein deficiency.
What a coincidence.
I know a patient with an
infection and a protein deficiency.
Do you think it's possible
there's a connection?
I want to hear you say it,
Chase. It will please me.
Doesn't mean you're right.
You predicted cardiac arrest,
instant cardiac arrest.
There were only two choices.
Since yours was wrong,
mine must have been right.
Either that, or we
missed the leprechaun.
If you're right, there's
nothing to be done.
The steroid treatment
we gave her means
when the next infection hits, it will
hit hard. Liver failure, cardiac arrest.
On the bright side it
confirms my diagnosis.
Don't you see how incredible
this call was? A protein deficiency.
It can't be tested.
Can't be seen.
I called it based
on coughing blood.
You're happy about this.
She's going to die.
That's not my fault.
She was going to die, anyway.
And now, thanks to me,
at least she'll know why.
I'm sure you'll see that gratitude
in her eyes when you tell her.
I'm not telling her.
No one's telling her. Not
until we're sure I'm right.
But we're waiting for
her to stroke or have
a heart attack to confirm
before we tell her?
Seems like the humane approach.
Her heart went into V-fib.
Brought her back, barely.
Congratulations, you
have your confirmation.
What's her name?
Who? The co-ed? Sure.
Dead sophomore girl?
You know her father's name?
Dad. Her mother's name is Mommy.
Ben and Jody are about to
lose their only daughter, Addie.
You think that they're gonna
give a crap if I know their names?
Five years from now, when the
father's looking at photographs
of his daughter graduating
from high school,
they're not going to
remember the nice black doctor
who called them
by their first name.
You don't wanna quit.
You saying you
don't want me to quit?
Didn't sound like I said that.
I'm saying that suddenly you're trying
to turn me into a kinder, gentler ass.
Because you know who you are.
And you figure if you can make me decent
and caring, then maybe there's hope for...
You're about to tell a girl she's
dying and you think it's about you.
God, I hope I'm not you.
I'm sorry.
Addie, you're dying.
Are you sure?
Yes.
Your infections will get worse.
The toxins will spill into your blood.
How long?
Two days, maybe less.
You have a condition called...
Does it matter?
It's a very rare protein
deficiency that only manifests...
I don't want to hear it.
Okay.
It's what's killing you.
This is what's killing you.
You're not interested
in what's killing you?
Will it make any difference?
Will I live any longer?
Please, could you just leave?
What's the point in living without
curiosity? Without craving the...
So, I'm screwing up my last few
hours because I won't listen to you?
Get out of here.
It's... It's like the dark
matter in the universe.
You're smiling.
No, I'm not.
You can only diagnose a
problem by looking at what's...
Missing.
Oh, God.
I have to go.
Nineteen-year-old didn't want
to hear the coolest explanation
of why she's going to
die, begged me to shut up.
If you can't shut up,
at least talk quietly.
Amphetamine withdrawal's a
bitch. She thought that I was happy.
You were happy? No, I was hazy.
And I don't get hazy on Vicodin,
or anything else I throw down.
Which means I was
throwing down something
I didn't know I was throwing
down. Which got me to wondering...
Why didn't you give
me those happy pills?
I told you. You've got
to be checked out by...
No, you just didn't
want me double-dosing.
You dosed me!
Those coffees... They worked!
You've been smiling,
relaxed, happy.
A dying girl
thought I was happy.
A moron thought I was happy.
Who the hell doesn't want
to know why she's dying?
House was happy. Hazy.
Happy. Hazy!
Oh, right. A dying girl
mistook hazy for happy.
Because dying people
see happiness everywhere.
She's miserable.
She wasn't miserable.
Of course she was
miserable. You just told her...
She was no different
than she'd ever been.
Oh, God.
I gotta go.
Need a minute
with your daughter.
Dr. House, get
out of here before...
She's gonna live.
Does that help? Now, get out.
Are you jerking us around...
Get out.
You have got leprechauns in you.
Depression manifests
in lots of different ways.
Some people can't
get out of bed all day,
others have serial relationships
and become oncologists.
I'm dying, I'm not depressed.
Wrong. And wrong.
You tried to kill yourself by
throwing down kitchen cleanser.
Now, most normal suicidal morons
would have just drank the stuff.
Burned the hell out of
their mouth and throat.
Painful, but not deadly.
But being a college-educated
suicidal moron,
you wrapped it in
gel caps or gum.
Which left no trace, but it
burned a hole in your intestine.
But the body can repair
almost anything, which is cool.
In your case, scar
tissue closed up the hole.
But it also formed a bridge
between a vein and an artery.
Now, veins are supposed to help
the intestine flush bacteria away.
But the bridge allowed the
bacteria entrance to the artery.
Where they got a
free ride everywhere.
Can you fix me?
Surgery to fix the bridge'll
take about two hours.
The psychotherapy's
going to take a little longer.
Why'd you do it?
I don't know.
I've just
never been happy.
Please don't tell my parents.
They'll blame themselves
and it's not their fault.
Please, you can't tell them.
Technically, all you have to do is
promise me that you won't do it again.
Then, legally, I
can't tell them.
I promise.
Yeah, sure.
We can't thank you...
Your daughter
tried to kill herself.
That's why she's here.
Legally, I'm supposed to
keep that between me and her.
Which makes sense,
she's obviously an adult,
capable of her own
well-reasoned decisions.
You're sure?
If she doesn't die in
the next couple of hours,
yeah, I'm right.
How could she hide this?
Everyone has secrets.
We'll take care of
her. Figure it out.
Make her happy?
We'll get her into therapy.
Might want to try
some meds, too.
Can we call you?
If we have any questions?
No.
What's up? Nothing.
You wanted to see me? Yeah.
House's patient? Yeah.
The one that would
have died, if not for him.
Subtle. Thanks.
You're really scared
you'll turn into him.
Don't tell me I'm
better than him.
Don't tell me, take the
good and leave the bad.
Cameron already tried.
I'm telling you there are
worse things to turn into.
It's not worth it.
I didn't think you
were going to show.
Sorry, surgery
went a little late.
So, you really think I have all
the necessary qualifications?
I can't discuss this with a dry
mouth. What do you got there?
Peppermint tea.
I'm going to have a mug
of peppermint tea, please.
This isn't a job
interview, is it?
It's some kind of interview.
You're judging
me. I'm judging you.
You have the upper hand.
I don't know anything about you.
I'm on antidepressants
because a doctor friend of
mine thinks I'm miserable.
I don't like them, they make
me hazy. I eat meat, I like drugs.
And I'm not always
faithful to the women I date.
You don't seem depressed.
You do realize you just skipped
over several deep character flaws
that most women would
run screaming from.
You told the truth.
Yeah, I don't always
do that, either.
Well, how miserable can you be,
saving lives, sleeping
around, and doing drugs?
Were you on the debating
team in high school?
Also, I hate
tea.