All right. Stand here.
You're just tall enough.
I don't...
I don't think I am.
It just goes around.
There's nothing to
be scared of, all right?
I didn't say I was scared.
It'll be fun.
Come on, when I was a kid,
this was my favorite thing ever.
I don't like rides.
All right. All right.
I just... I thought
it would be fun.
I shouldn't be
making you do this.
Uh...
Let's go home. We
can have fun at home.
No, Daddy. Wait.
The ride does look like fun.
Oh, this is awesome.
Alice? Are you all right?
Honey, you all right?
Alice? Alice? Are you okay?
Nothing happened.
Something happened.
It was a little kiddie ride.
She hates those rides.
I don't understand why
you insist on making her...
Okay, I appreciate the
fullness of your answers,
but I just wanted
to know if she'd had
any history of
abdominal problems.
No. No.
The admitting doctor
noted no family history of...
I have an aunt with
Crohn's disease.
You didn't mention that?
I forgot what it
was called, okay?
Your aunt's got a million
things wrong with her.
If you paid attention
for five minutes...
I doubt it's Crohn's. She has
none of the other symptoms.
You're alone with her for eight
hours, she ends up in the hospital.
I'm wondering if we can focus on
answering the
questions, Mrs. Hartmann.
I'm not Mrs. Hartmann.
We're divorced.
I suspected.
And your past generosity
made me think of you.
We're half a million
dollars from our goal.
Of course, this is a naming
opportunity for your foundation.
Is there a problem?
There's something on your face.
It's, uh...
Excuse me. Oh...
Oh, God.
I'm sitting in there
hoping it's a sniper,
because at least then the
sociopath isn't my employee.
This baby won me second
place in the clinic's weekly
"weirdest thing pulled
out of an orifice" contest.
I am this close to putting
a new lab in Oncology.
You do not want to
know what came in first.
House.
It rhymes with fucchini.
Give me his pills.
Where's my prescription?
No more free-floating
prescriptions.
Princeton P.D. has already
forced Wilson to shut down.
A cop says, "Boo,"
Wilson shuts down.
Every doctor in
this place is afraid
to make a move
without covering his ass.
You think maybe you're
shouting at the wrong person?
Tritter's obviously out
to get me. He doesn't...
You forged prescriptions!
Allegedly.
Your pain has become my pain.
From now on, you get reasonable
doses at reasonable times.
But I hurt in an
unreasonable way.
Then dip into your secret stash.
Tritter took it.
Then move on to your
secret, secret stash.
I ran out.
Then move on to your
secret, secret, secret stash.
Parents say she's
not on any meds.
If the pancreatitis wasn't set off
by drugs, and she hasn't been sick,
that leaves trauma or some
kind of structural defect.
Put up the CT.
What's that density there?
Shadow. Looks normal to me.
We got a referral from...
Excuse me.
You stash your drugs
in a lupus textbook?
It's never lupus.
Who's got gallstones,
and why do we care?
Gallstones?
Biliary duct is dilated, probably
from a stone lodged in it.
Must've caused a nasty
case of pancreatitis.
She's six. Six-year-olds
don't get gallstones.
So, she didn't
have pancreatitis?
Your theory is an
invisible gallstone?
His theory correctly
predicted pancreatitis.
You might want to wait until
he actually tells us his theory
before you start
kissing his theory's ass.
My theory is...
Vanishing gallstone.
She had it and it passed.
Those things travel in packs.
The rest of them are
probably hiding out
in her gallbladder.
Do an ultrasound.
If I'm right, take out the organ,
so we can analyze the stones.
I wasn't kissing his ass.
It must have just looked
that way from our angle,
you on your knees,
House bending over.
He predicted the pancreatitis.
It's his dad's fault.
My dad was an ass.
But you did everything
he wanted you to,
and in return, you got
everything you wanted.
Yeah, it's that simple.
The strategy worked.
Dad got him a cushy
job, paid for his cushy life.
Cut me out of his cushy will.
Told you. It's just his nature.
Poor guy's
hard-wired to kiss ass.
House was right. Gallstones.
I didn't know a kid
could get gallstones.
It's unusual.
That's why we need
to see what's causing it.
We'd like to remove Alice's
gallbladder and analyze the stones.
Sure. No.
Just 'cause I said sure?
I am capable of my own thoughts.
It's a simple procedure.
The gallbladder
isn't essential to...
The doctor thinks
we should do it.
We should do it, Edie.
You think maybe we
should get a second opinion
before we start removing
our child's organs?
It's an effective use
of taxpayer's money.
I'm actually off this week.
I'm guessing you
don't have a family.
Most people have enough
going on in their lives
that they don't have to
personalize every slight.
This isn't personal.
Not anymore.
My head of Oncology
had to shut down.
My entire staff are afraid to make
a move without covering their ass.
I think you're angry
at the wrong person.
You think Dr. Wilson deserved
to have his assets seized,
his entire practice ruined?
No.
So, you just don't care?
This is how I get what I want.
I put pressure on people,
and if it doesn't work on Wilson,
it'll work on you.
You punish the innocent.
None of you are innocent.
Not one of you.
Not one of you has told me
the truth about Dr. House.
The pills allow him
to cope with the pain.
No. The pills distort
reality. He is an addict.
He's not out robbing
a liquor store, or...
No, he's treating people.
He needs to find a different way
to cope before he kills somebody.
If he hasn't done that already.
If you're right, he has
a medical problem.
It should be dealt
with by doctors.
Not by...
It's not being dealt
with by doctors.
Doctors are covering it up.
The whole point of the
criminal justice system
is to make things right
when everything else fails.
With all due respect,
you have failed.
Sorry, didn't know you
wanted your kid dead.
Although, for a couple of
G's, I can still make it happen.
Who the hell are you?
I am a complete stranger,
who apparently cares more about
whether your kid dies than you do.
You're Dr. House.
You've seen my stage show.
She's not dying.
She has pancreatitis.
Once you've treated
that, I'm taking her home.
And do what, burn sage?
I want you to do the surgery.
My father had gallstones.
They were totally harmless.
Alice had one bad
one, but it passed.
For all we know, this is over.
And for all we know, she
could get sick again tomorrow.
Then I'll take her
to her pediatrician.
She's six, Rob.
She shouldn't have
unnecessary surgery.
Or a moron for a mom,
but what can you do?
You're the doctor.
I'm the mother.
I outrank you. Live with it.
I've read the file.
You've got 15 minutes.
It's people like this
who killed Copernicus.
Galileo.
Either way.
And they just locked Galileo up.
They killed his spirit, and
nobody likes a show-off.
Luckily, Alice Hartmann has a
dad who's willing to see reason.
Reason, as defined by
slavishly deferring to you.
Their doctor.
Your Honor, I've
had no opportunity
to consult my attorney.
There's no time.
All I want is a second
opinion before...
No time.
Your testimony is
their child will die
if I don't grant this
motion right now?
Am I under oath?
Let's say yes.
My testimony is that this child
might die if you don't
grant this motion right now.
Literally no time for
a second opinion?
Wouldn't be as good
as the first opinion.
Dr. Cuddy, what do you think?
She's not a
specialist in this area.
Her opinion is worthless.
Dr. Cuddy, what do
you think of Dr. House?
Is he as big a jerk
as I think he is?
Bigger.
But he knows what
he's talking about.
Got a page.
She's complaining
about her stitches.
The nurse just said
that's completely normal.
Did you get the test
results for the gallstones?
Any minute now.
No time for a second opinion,
but the test takes three...
My skin hurts.
I know I no longer
have the right
to demand it but could
you please take a look?
Sure.
She's pissed, so now she's just
looking for things to go wrong.
You're right, I'm so petty I hope
she dies so it vindicates my opinion.
I didn't mean that, sweetie.
Mommy was being sarcastic.
She's a few years away from
grasping sarcasm, don't you think?
Guys.
I already gave you that number.
Simple surgical procedure turns
a little girl into The English Patient.
What gives?
Must be allergic to something
we used in the surgery.
Cameron,
C-A-M-E-R-O-N.
This is my office. I'm talking.
There are people
here who work for me.
They're not listening.
Explain this to me.
Tritter froze my account.
They're checking theirs.
I'm on hold with a lawyer.
Call Wilson's lawyer.
He'll tell you exactly how
and why you're screwed.
This kid has no
history of allergies so...
You gotta talk to Tritter.
You gotta make this go away.
Yeah, great plan.
The man is obviously
open to reason.
Well, here's the
plan, we do nothing.
We while away the time
diagnosing the patient.
The stones were
calcium bilirubinate.
Pigment stones.
Which are non-conclusive.
Kid presented with
low-grade fever, mild anemia.
That, plus the stones,
indicates bacterial infection.
Bacterial infections don't
cause a vesicular rash,
and doing nothing is not a plan.
It's specifically
a lack of a plan.
We cut into her belly,
the bad boys escape.
They swarm over, colonize the
wounds, and kaplow, vesicular rash.
Allergic reaction is 100 times
more likely, with or without a history.
Fever and anemia could have
been symptoms of pancreatitis.
Hello?
Thank you for your help.
They froze my accounts.
"Thank you for your help"?
It's not her fault.
He hasn't gotten to mine, yet.
I'm gonna withdraw as
much as I can, as fast as I can.
Lunch is on me.
Do a scratch test.
Check for allergies.
When it comes back negative,
start broad-spectrum antibiotics.
Bullies bully.
They don't get a
reaction, they lose interest.
Now go do what I ask before
I stick your heads in toilets.
How'd Otter get here?
Daddy got him last night.
It was at the dry cleaner.
They close at 6:00.
How'd you get it?
I drove over there,
and I knocked for about 10
minutes, and then I begged.
How about some ice cream
for when this is through?
My tummy hurts.
Ginger ale?
Yeah?
I'll take over.
Be right back.
He's always been really good
at the big romantic gestures,
but ask him to do the dishes, or show
up for a meal on time, or drive her...
Almost done here.
What are you doing here?
I work here.
You passively-aggressively
gave up your practice.
I have clinic hours.
And now you're passively-aggressively
spreading peanut butter
with a big sign around
your neck saying,
"Wilson doesn't have
enough cash for the cafeteria."
You know, before Lenny
Bruce died of a drug overdose...
If you're going to confront me
with everyone who
ever abused narcotics,
I think I'm gonna have
to get something to read.
He was arrested on
obscenity charges.
He went through a
series of arrests and trials,
because he just couldn't
stop challenging the police.
He became obsessed
with his own legal problems,
and his act turned into
long, humorless rants
about fascist cops and
the violation of his rights.
I get it, I get it.
I need to change
my nightclub act.
You think more props?
House, scratch test is
getting results, a lot of results.
How can she be
allergic to everything?
She can't be.
It has to be an infection.
You see a positive allergy
test and decide it's infection?
The bacteria got into
the scratches in her back.
The infection's radial.
The shape of
this isn't. Eat this.
I don't feel like eating.
It'll make you better.
A sandwich?
Magic sandwich.
There's no such thing as...
Just take a damn
bite, okay, kid?
Amazing how she didn't
go into anaphylactic shock.
That's diagnostically
ridiculous.
Right, she's allergic to
everything except peanuts.
If she is allergic, antibiotics could
cause a massive systemic reaction.
If she's allergic,
but she's not.
Chase, you're right.
The shape indicates allergy.
The tests indicate allergy.
Just because she's
not allergic to peanuts,
doesn't mean she's not
allergic to lidocaine or...
Chase, hang the bag.
You can grow a
backbone tomorrow.
No, I'm not giving
my daughter drugs
that could shut her system down.
You know what else
shuts down systems?
Death.
Sorry. I can't let you do this.
Luckily, Alice Hartmann has a
mom, who is willing to see reason.
You were in here
yesterday, telling me
her father's guardianship
was best for her.
I honestly figured I'd get
a different judge today.
You agree with Dr. House now?
Now my kid actually is sick.
She was sick yesterday.
Her pediatrician doesn't
know what's wrong
with her, says
Dr. House is the best.
She loses guardianship, and
all of a sudden House is a hero.
It's got nothing to
do with me deciding...
Hey, zip it!
I've heard enough.
This lawyering thing is easy.
You shut up, too.
Arguing over every decision
is a waste of her time and mine.
Since her parents
can't, or won't, agree,
I'm awarding temporary
guardianship to a doctor,
who'll place the health of
the child above all else...
I don't think Dr. House
is capable of...
Dr. Cuddy.
Yes, Your Honor.
No, I was finishing my sentence.
The kid's all yours.
HOUSE: 3:00, give me the pills.
I don't even know this kid.
How am I supposed to
decide what's best for her?
Fine, I'll choose.
I'm going to side with
the angry doctor's opinion.
Give me my pills.
We're not gonna
go broad-spectrum.
If there's any chance
that she's allergic...
There is no chance.
Of course there's a
chance. I'm appealing.
No, you're not.
If you think it's bacterial,
pick one antibiotic.
It's not going to be enough.
We need to go broad-spectrum.
It kills bugs. That's
what you want.
We'll go with metronidazole.
You don't have to testify
he's broken any laws,
though I'm sure you could.
Just how many pills
he takes in a day.
'Cause I'm fairly confident
I can prove that he didn't
have that many
legitimate prescriptions.
I really hope no one dies while
I'm sitting here not talking to you.
I, uh, I had a, uh...
Had a buddy at Trenton P.D.
do some digging.
Your brother,
locked up for drugs.
Your own flesh and blood,
and you don't even visit.
But your boss practices
medicine on drugs,
time to start lying to the cops.
If I run out for coffee, will I get
back before you make your point?
You testify,
I can make sure that
Marcus goes free on parole
in less than two months.
My brother and I, uh...
We grew up in the same home.
But...
I made something of myself.
He didn't.
Dr. Foreman, the way you talk,
you'd think you never
committed any crimes yourself.
Now, you and Dr. House,
you are both cold bastards.
You don't give a damn about your
brother, and you can't stand House.
But I do expect
you to take this deal,
because you hate hypocrisy more.
House has had 1,000 chances.
You've got two chances.
Why is your
brother stuck at one?
Well, if she were allergic to this
antibiotic, we would have seen it by now.
I think we are out of the
woods as far as that goes.
Guess they
occasionally get one right.
You're going to
be glib about this?
You almost killed her.
I made a choice.
The same choice
you made yesterday,
only when I make
it I'm an imbecile.
Every decision you have
made has been wrong.
When this is over, I'm
suing for sole custody.
Because I trusted
doctors when you didn't?
Because it's not just
about the past two days.
Like you have the hotline on
what's best for Alice. She loves me.
She never does her
homework when she's with you.
She never brushes her hair.
Her heart's racing,
pressure's rising.
The two of you get out.
I'm her mother.
You can't just...
You fight, she has
an anxiety attack.
The two of you are
making her worse.
Get out, and don't come back.
How's the kid doing?
Much better as of
about two hours ago.
You got any money for lunch?
If you like parsley
and croutons.
Tritter finally
froze my accounts.
Really?
You surprised? Why wouldn't he?
I figured if he was
singling you out,
you must have done
something different.
What? Like talking? Yeah.
And now that he's frozen your
accounts, you probably will.
You need the cash, right?
He doesn't freeze my
accounts, I'm guilty.
He does freeze my
Is Alice having some
procedure done?
She's fine. She's resting.
Where? In her room.
Where you're not supposed...
I was just at the window.
There's no one in there.
Her backpack
wasn't there, either.
You don't think her
father could have...
Call Security.
Get a gurney.
She's stiff. She can't move.
I don't know what happened.
She seemed fine.
Help her. Please.
On the plus side, she
could medal in luge.
Muscle rigidity is almost
exclusively neurological.
Neuroaxonal dystrophy?
She's the right age.
Except that her liver's
starting to shut down.
No dystrophy would...
Metronidazole, great idea.
"Let's not go broad-spectrum.
"Let's not take any chances
on actually curing her."
House, can you
focus on the case?
No, because I'm in pain,
'cause you think that compromise
is the answer to everything.
I need more pills.
Muscle rigidity plus liver
involvement means Wilson's.
No. No corneal rings,
no mental changes.
Then what?
I need more pills!
No! You are on a reasonable...
What the hell does
"reasonable" mean?
Keep it quiet.
Her BP reacts to stress
and yelling is not...
If you think that I'm not in pain,
then don't give me anything.
Keep me away from the aspirin,
but if I'm in a butt-load of
pain, I need a butt-load of pills.
Fine. You need more pills.
You're not getting them.
You can have all
the aspirin you want.
I say we draw straws.
Loser drives down to Trenton
and scores him an eight ball.
Which one of you two
gave her an aspirin?
What? Her symptoms
fit Reye's Syndrome.
Which doesn't make any
sense, unless she took aspirin.
Rob? No way. She's a kid.
I've read the 800
warning labels.
I'm not even angry.
I just want her to be okay.
She's lying.
She's angry, 'cause
you kidnapped her kid.
She'll be angrier
if the kid dies.
I didn't. One aspirin
combined with a
pre-existing infection,
that's all it takes
to set off an attack.
I'm not lying.
Well, sure, you've
certainly earned our trust.
Where was Alice the
night before she came in?
With me. Well, at my house.
I went out. She stayed
with the babysitter.
Where were you?
None of your business.
You hired someone that might
have poisoned our daughter.
She's 15. She's
very responsible.
Is she a 15-year-old pharmacist?
Or just some kid
from down the street
who needed 20
bucks for lip gloss
and a couple of Tiger Beats?
Put your kid on
charcoal hemoperfusion.
Shouldn't we see what
the babysitter has to say?
I know what she's gonna say.
She's gonna lie to
save her business.
I need more pills.
We are going to use this
machine to clean your blood.
It goes out of you
and through a filter,
like the filter in a fish tank.
It's kind of cool, actually.
I'm scared.
It won't hurt.
It takes a while, so it'll
be boring, but it won't hurt.
It's going to make you better.
They hate each
other, don't they?
We're never going
to be together again.
Well, you never know.
You're going to break out the
rubber hoses, the bright lights?
I'm not going to testify just because
I have to borrow lunch money.
I know. Women don't give up
guys that they're in love with.
I'm not in love with House.
The guy is unhinged
and unethical,
does what he wants
with no concern for others,
but you stand by him.
It can't just be
loyalty and respect?
No.
I'm a girl, so I must
be in love with him.
Not because you're a girl.
Because 10 years ago
you got an A in calculus,
until you ratted yourself out.
Showed your professor
a mistake he missed.
Because you married a man...
Don't go there.
You used to be someone
who did the right thing.
House has changed you.
Do you think it's all
been for the better?
How's it going?
Boring.
Told you. FOREMAN:
So far so good.
Just like five minutes ago,
and 10 minutes before that.
What's the matter?
She's thrown a clot.
Let's get her out of
here. I'll call the OR.
You said it wouldn't hurt.
Found it. She's burning up.
Give me a sec.
Foreman, she is on fire.
Almost there.
Get me some
cooling blankets now.
Right away.
Every time we touch this
kid, something goes wrong.
Bad mojo is not a diagnosis.
You really have to flash your
private stash in front of me?
You find it easier to lie
for me if it's more subtle?
Fine.
You told your associates
that I had frozen your accounts.
Yes.
Smart lie.
You figured they'd think there was
a reason that you'd been singled out.
Like that you'd agreed
to testify against House.
Yeah, I assume
that's why you did it.
You have a reputation
as a bit of an opportunist.
You already gave your boss
up once from what I heard.
To save my job.
He goes down now, I lose my job.
You lose your job,
you find another one.
You get fired,
your chances don't look so hot.
Why would he fire me?
Because you rolled on him.
I haven't rolled on him.
I think you will.
And he's gonna
think you already did.
As far as he knows,
my accounts are frozen
just like everyone else's.
In 24 hours, all three of you will
have access to your accounts again.
Why would you do...
If I was looking at
this as an outsider,
I would say
it was because
Detective Tritter had
what appeared to be a very
pleasant lunch with Dr. Chase.
Yeah.
The two of them appear
to be working together.
How the hell are there
no ice packs in the OR?
Clot's out.
Ice packs aren't
gonna hold it for long.
Where are the blankets?
In the ER.
They're dealing with
a four-car collision.
We need to cool this kid
down before her brain melts.
What are you doing?
She got a major dose of heparin
to thin her blood
for the procedure.
Could have induced
thrombocytopenia.
That's unlikely.
The charcoal would have
absorbed a lot of the heparin.
She's been anemic.
Could be a primary
blood disorder.
Or we never cured the infection.
Are you saying she
never had Reye's?
We just put that little girl
through excruciating pain.
The pain wasn't House's fault.
Even if the clot was a reaction
to what we gave
her, we still had to...
I don't need you
to cover my ass!
What I need is my Vicodin!
Two pills every six hours,
like I'm on an allowance.
She's giving a cop leverage
over medical decisions.
What the hell? Why don't we get
a plumber in here,
ask his opinion?
Hey, Cuddy, you know any
rodeo clowns who can weigh in...
Where the hell is she?
Look at her arm.
I told you it was an infection.
We fixed the infection.
Well, apparently not.
I asked you for broad-spectrum.
You put her on the bare minimum.
It's a good thing you failed to
become a mom, because you suck at it.
What's so good about this rash?
Good guesses, but no.
It's on parts of her body
that we haven't touched.
She's got a fever of 103. She's
in and out of consciousness,
but it's not a reaction
to anything we did.
Our mojo is off the table.
Which means...
Oh, so close.
Means thanks to Cuddy's
candy-ass approach,
broad-spectrum antibiotics
are no longer an option.
This thing has grown
horns and fangs.
We've gotta figure
out what species it is,
go in with a spear to the heart.
Okay, you guys are sulking.
I don't really care
why, but apparently
I can't do my job
without finding out.
Tritter released
our bank accounts.
Horrible, horrible news.
Wow, I'm glad we
didn't let that fester.
If she did have
Reye's, then it could
be varicella.
They're associated.
He released our money.
You do know what that means?
The correct question is,
how could it be varicella
given that she's not itchy?
Rickettsial pox causes
rash, fever and muscle pain.
Pain, not paralysis.
Rocky Mountain spotted
fever, on the other hand,
rash, fever, anemia, paralysis.
And I didn't say
anything to Tritter.
Neither did I.
Maybe he wants us to
think that one of us talked.
It worked. You were with him.
We were all with him.
We weren't laughing with him.
Maybe he just gave up.
Start the kid on chloramphenicol
for Rocky Mountain
spotted fever.
Can we talk?
No. I really think we...
Either you screwed me
and you want absolution, or
you didn't and you want applause.
Either way, I'm not interested.
I'm busy.
You okay?
Yeah, sure.
What I meant by "Are you okay?"
is "What the hell did House do?"
Nothing. What did he say?
I've seen House be rude 1,000
times, usually to achieve something.
I have never seen him be
mean just because he can.
Seriously?
What did he say?
Nothing. It doesn't matter.
Well, I've seen House
be rude to you 1,000 times,
but I've never
seen it get to you.
People think House
has no inner censor,
but the fact is he
holds himself back.
Because when he wants to hurt,
he knows just where
to poke a sharp stick.
I have been trying to get
pregnant, and House knew.
He told me I would
fail as a mother.
And you're this upset
because you think he's right?
I've had three
separate implantations.
The first two never took.
The last one, I lost.
I'm sorry.
You didn't fail. Those
were physical events.
A little girl is
scared and in pain.
I was awkward, terrified
of doing the wrong thing.
That's normal. That's...
I didn't hug her.
I didn't even reach
out and hold her hand.
I told her it was gonna be okay.
She needed reassurance.
I told her, her folks
might get back together.
When I see people with
their kids, it's so natural.
It's like they have an instruction
book imprinted on their genes.
Maybe I just didn't get a copy.
Maybe my wanting
to be a mother is like
a tone-deaf person
wanting to sing opera,
or a paraplegic who wants to...
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Well, I see what you mean
about House poking the right spot.
Chloramphenicol isn't working.
What dose did you give her?
Yeah, maybe Chase screwed up.
You always end up there.
Just getting a jump on it.
I doubled her up.
The infection's morphed.
It's moved into
her muscle sheath.
Necrotizing fasciitis?
That's impervious to drugs.
The only treatment is to
cut away the infected area.
So, we amputate.
Arm and leg?
We can't cut a
six-year-old kid in half
without a confirmed diagnosis.
Moves too quickly,
and we waited too long.
We don't have
time for a culture.
We can at least observe
her for a few hours,
confirm the rash is spreading.
It spreads, she dies.
You're talking
about crippling her.
We're not even certain
this was an infection.
Right! She's six! She's cute!
She can't have
flesh-eating bacteria!
It's just wrong!
Let's cure her with
sunshine and puppies.
Cute kids die of terrible illnesses,
innocent doctors go to jail,
and it's because
cowards like you
won't stand up and
do what's required.
You can sit around and moan
about who's the bigger weakling.
I'm going to go do my job.
What kind of quality of
life will she have without...
Great thing about
life, it's got qualities.
And if we can't agree?
I don't know.
He's yelled at us before.
Because he thought
our theories were dumb.
Not because our theories
were sending him to jail.
He's going through withdrawal.
Could be causing mild paranoia.
It'll pass. We just
have to suffer through it.
We never ruled out allergy.
We gave her drugs. She
had no negative reaction.
We cut open her belly,
she got a rash on her belly.
We did a scratch test on her
back, she got a rash on her back.
I know House ruled out mojo,
but it can't be a coincidence...
A little late to play
differential games, isn't it?
Get that thing away from me.
I don't want to get burned.
Laser pointers don't
burn you, genius.
Skin, no. Retina, yes.
You don't trust my aim?
Maybe you should
cover any sensitive...
He was wrong about the puppies.
House! You got
to stop the surgery.
She doesn't have
necrotizing fasciitis.
Oh, good.
She's got erythropoietic
protoporphyria.
She's allergic to light.
It's genetic. Either parent
could have carried it.
I know what it is.
Infection fits better.
She gets worse every time
she goes under surgical lights,
dad takes her outside...
Her liver's shot, too.
Did she swallow a flashlight?
Stop the surgery.
Get the hell out of my way.
No, I'm...
Light damages the blood cells,
the damaged blood cells
contain protoporphyrin,
the protoporphyrin
builds up in the liver.
That's why the
liver's shutting down.
Stop.
How can she be
allergic to light?
She's never had
this problem before.
The negative
reaction starts at birth.
It reaches critical
mass around this age.
Her blood cells create
chemicals in reaction to light.
When they reach the liver, it
tries to filter out the bad cells.
The chemicals damage the liver,
and one byproduct is gallstones.
So, she'll just
keep getting worse?
EP can be managed.
We'll give her beta-carotene.
She's gonna need special light
bulbs and filters on the windows.
She's probably gonna
need to be home-schooled.
Her life will be
complicated, but she will live.
How do you get
something like this?
It's genetic.
So, one of us...
Both of you must be carriers.
She's gonna want to see
you when she wakes up.
So, don't screw it up.
So, what's new?
House missed one.
That's happened before.
He nearly maimed a little girl.
And I got it right.
And I told him,
and it didn't matter.
Chase, you solved one.
You helped a patient, that
better be enough for you.
Beckett was going
to call his play
Waiting for House's Approval,
but decided it was too grim.
Trust me,
I'm not waiting anymore.
I'm gonna need
30 pieces of silver.