Oh, happy birthday, sir.
Well, thank you.
Uh, Richard, happy birthday.
Now, you're only saying that
because you heard her say that.
Uh... Guilty.
Actually, can you come and
find me at the end of your day?
I need to talk to you about
your surgical schedule.
Oh, is that right?
Yeah. Yeah, it is.
Well, Catherine let it slip
that she was gonna
be here today,
so, I'm assuming there's
some sort of something.
Don't worry. Don't
worry. I... I like surprises.
I'm sorry, but it is actually
about your surgical schedule.
Bailey, you can't lie to me.
Wait... I don't know
anything about any party.
Happy birthday, though. Hmm.
Oh, oh, I do have
something for you, though.
Owen, you shouldn't have.
I didn't. It's from
the hospital.
Uh, make sure you come and
see me at the end of the day.
Dr. Hunt, do you have a second?
Yeah.
That would be great.
There's a stage you go
through during childbirth,
and it's the toughest part.
It's called the
transition stage.
Hey, happy birthday!
Happy birthday.
That's great. Thank you.
It was.
You've been pushing
so hard and so long,
you're exhausted, spent.
And there's nothing to
show for all of your effort.
Oh, my God! There she is!
Well, she's not
a she, she's an it,
and she's fragile,
so, don't touch it.
Sorry, I'm just, uh,
extremely excited.
Well, you're not gonna be
printing anything just yet.
Isn't that the job?
I... You hired me to help
re-engineer your... Your portal veins.
I beat out 100
bioengineers for the gig.
I've, uh, cooked up
a couple of designs.
Oh, that's awesome.
No, actually, it's presumptuous
until you've read
every scrap of data
on every test we've
run, you touch nothing.
There are the research binders,
so, you should probably
just go ahead and dig in.
Great. Can I, uh,
touch the chair?
Keep an eye on him.
He touches nothing.
Do you want me to
watch him read? Yes.
During this transition stage,
it feels like you can't go on.
But it's only because
you're very nearly there.
Your son is four years old?
Four, yes.
And he's had two
previous conduit failures.
But your conduit works, right?
From what we read,
Baby Nathan is doing great.
Yes. It was successful
in Nathan's case.
This clinical
trial is to identify
certain aspects
of the procedure.
But he'll get the conduit?
If you're chosen for the study.
Dr. Yang has the final say,
and I'm forwarding
your materials on to her.
Ooh.
Number 14 looks good.
Some EC TCPC narrowing
with early signs of obstruction.
There is evidence of... Hey.
You, uh, picking
research subjects today?
How's it going? Uh, good.
Shane's meeting
with the candidates.
I'm only looking at the hearts,
trying to keep my
judgment unsullied.
But it's hard finding candidates
that meet all the
criteria. Yeah.
You need this.
What? A hypoplastic
left ventricle?
No, like an algorithm.
Some scientific way of
choosing the perfect mate,
where you input only
the criteria you want,
and you're presented with
only suitable candidates.
So, Internet dating.
Oh, right. They have that.
Listen, I don't
need a date. Okay?
Oh, uh, keep me
posted on the hearts.
How long does it take to
wash one, like 10 seconds?
I don't like a filthy
kitchen, either.
Dirty cereal bowls in the sink
aren't gonna exactly tip the scales.
Oh, my Jesus.
Well, now that he's
in the conversation,
I'll make sure to
clean the bowls...
Your mother. Your mother.
Oh.
Um... She does not look happy.
Come on. It'll... It'll be fine.
Okay. All right.
But you told her, right?
Her? I did.
How did she take it? Hmm?
So,
I understand
congratulations are in order.
And how long have you been
experiencing this pain, Greg?
You know, comes and goes.
Ten years.
Ten years?
Mmm-hmm, since we've been
married. He won't go see anyone.
I just got ObamaCare.
I'm a junk collector.
I sell stuff at flea markets.
Doesn't really make
for regular coverage.
Oh, there's definitely
a mass here.
Oh, it's cancer.
Is it cancer? Jodi.
What?
Oh, nothing.
Nothing. Uh, could be minor.
We'll know more
when we get a CT.
See? I knew we should
have come in earlier.
What did you see? Was it bad?
If it was bad, why do
you look so happy?
Just get him to CT.
And speak to no
one of this, no one!
You paged me? Hey, Callie.
What happened to my surgery?
I was supposed to remove
the sensors on Will Mitchell,
and, uh, I found out my
surgery was canceled.
Yeah, that's why I paged you.
Uh, Dr. Torres came
to me with a concern
about an intellectual-property
conflict between you two.
What, is this about the sensors?
Yes, Derek. It's
about our sensors.
Look, let's just talk.
I'm sure we can find a solution.
Who's this?
Oh, that's Paula.
She's my lawyer.
Is it? Is it?
It is!
What?
Look at it, Murphy.
It's glorious.
It's a mass. It's a
massive mass, but...
Oh, my God.
Aah!
Okay, so, we're gonna need
a 3D reconstruction and, um...
Hey, Dr. Bailey. Hey, do
you have the labs on the, um...
I said, "Tell no one"! I didn't!
Tell no one what? Is that a...
Yeah! Okay, keep
your voice down.
I want in.
No! It's mine.
It's ours.
Page Dr. Webber. Why him?
It's his birthday.
I'll be forwarding your
materials on to Dr. Yang.
Thank you, Doctor.
We'll let you know.
Oh. Sorry. Hi. I'm
here for the HLHS trial.
Yes, and you are...
Sheryll Jeffries.
Oh, no, I'm not on the list.
That stupid nurse, or whatever
she was, said I didn't qualify.
I'm what you're looking for.
HLHS with at least one
failed conduit procedure.
That's me.
Ah. I'm sorry, Sheryll.
The study is for pediatric
patients over one.
I'm 17. I am a
pediatric patient.
We're looking for
pre-pubescent specifically,
kids that are still growing.
That's perfect.
I just had a huge growth spurt.
This is the first time
since I got knocked up
someone said I'm
too old for something.
Look, I'm due in six weeks.
I want a heart that's
gonna survive it, okay?
And why do you
need me to look at it?
It's for your birthday.
No more talk about my birthday.
I mean, there are fine surgeons
working well into their 70s,
and I am nowhere near 70.
Will you just look
at the monitor?
Monitor.
Let's see. Okay. Well...
Oh, my word.
Is that a little leg?
And a spinal column.
It is.
It's a fetus in fetu.
The man absorbed his own twin.
He did.
You know, in all my
years, I've never seen one.
Neither have I! Neither have I!
Well...
Hot diggity!
Happy birthday.
Ah, look at that. Oh, my.
A love contract?
Where did Grey get this,
Zola's Barbie Dreamhouse?
No. It's a real thing. I swear.
"We confirm that any sexual
and/or romantic relationship
"is completely voluntary."
This is so creepy.
Like, we have to vow
to the hospital gods?
Hey, Alex, we have a
transoral fundoplication.
I sent you the latest labs.
- What's that?
Oh, it's really, really cool.
First, we go in orally,
and then we go in
through the belly button
to fix a kid's reflux
without leaving a scar.
It puts the "fun"
in "fundoplication."
God, that does sound fun.
Yeah. See? You
could get on that.
Just sign that, and you
could be back on peds.
Yeah, I'm not signing that.
I have a twin?
You did in utero.
Oh, gross. He ate his twin?
Absorbed it.
Or rather enveloped it.
Greg, you developed around it.
Oh, wow. Oh, wow. Oh,
I'm gonna need a minute.
Is it dangerous? I mean,
can it kill him? Jodi.
No. In... In many
cases, it's harmless,
but Greg's is the
source of his pain,
so that likely
indicates that it will
cause problems
if it hasn't already.
Good news.
We were able to schedule
surgery today to remove it.
Stop calling him "it"!
Everyone needs to slow down.
I just found out
I have a brother.
I'm sorry, Sheryll.
I wish I could help
you, but rules are rules.
Just bend them, okay?
I can't.
Sheryll, please, if I could...
My water broke. I think.
Oh, boy.
I need a wheelchair here!
- I'll get one.
And page labor and delivery!
Right away.
Can I call the baby's
father, your parents?
My parents don't talk to me.
Not sure who the father is,
probably why my
parents don't talk to me.
The person you
can call is Dr. Yang.
And tell her to
make an exception.
She's too old.
You need a refresher on
when puberty begins, Ross?
I know. I just thought
we could bend the rules.
And skew the
results of the trial.
No, but this patient...
I told you.
I don't want to know
about the patient,
so I'm not influenced.
I only want to see the heart.
A heart that has had
a previous surgery
to correct the defect,
is currently in
poor cardiac health,
and is in the body of a kid
between the ages of one and 12.
A heart that is still growing.
Is this that heart?
Hey. So, I was thinking about
this whole Internet-dating thing.
It takes five minutes. Wait.
That's why you paged me?
You said this was urgent.
It is. I'm about to get
busy with this trial.
And you need someone to
snuggle with on rainy Seattle nights.
Ooh. Say that in your profile.
I Got to go. I got to go.
Callie, this is not
something I'm doing to you.
I have a signed
contract with them.
Yeah, that you
had no right to sign.
You signed away
something that's ours.
Come on. We spent half
the day together yesterday.
We were on a play
date. Why didn't you say...
We were with the kids.
Oh, we have Sofia's dressy doll.
I think Zola
thought it was hers.
Ha. What?
Oh, like father, like
daughter, I guess.
I think we're drifting here.
Yes, yes, you're right.
I'm sorry. That
was unprofessional.
What I should have said was,
the sensors are materials
that you co-developed with me
in service of research I started
and invited you
to participate in.
If you attempt to impair my
access to these materials,
I will have you prosecuted
to the fullest extent of the law.
Well said.
This is insane. You
don't have a case.
Listen, before anyone
resorts to litigation,
let me just take this before
the other board members.
Maybe we can find a solution
that is fair to both parties.
In the meantime, I want you
both to leave this matter alone
until you hear from me.
All right?
I'm sure it was a shock.
I mean, I was shocked.
I can't even imagine
what you must be feeling.
Actually, I can. I can
imagine it because I...
You know what? Babe,
don't. She doesn't care.
But I know why you're here, Mom,
and I could have
saved you a trip.
I already called Mike Farris.
The time to call
Mike would have been
before you stood
up at that barn.
Wait, who is Mike Harris?
"Farris". He's our
attorney. Avery Foundation.
Protects our
financial interests.
Um, are you suggesting
that I'm after your money?
I have no idea what
you're after, dear.
All right, that's enough.
You're not gonna march in here
and start questioning
my wife's character.
You want to talk
about her character?
She left a man at the altar.
She broke his heart
and humiliated him
in front of everyone
that he loves.
I have no idea what she's
capable of, never mind you.
I am not interested
in your money.
Wonderful.
That's what I said when I
married into the Avery family,
and you know what I did next?
I signed a prenuptial agreement.
I said I'd handle it.
This is totally inappropriate.
What's inappropriate
is the engagement
was 15 minutes at a
rest stop on the turnpike.
Fortunately,
postnuptial agreements
were created for
moments like this.
And this meeting is over.
Jackson. It's over!
Look at this. I...
I'll sign the stupid paper.
Really, I don't mind.
You're not signing
anything. Why not?
I don't want your
money. I want you.
A prenup or
whatever the hell it is
is only for if we get divorced,
which we're not gonna
do, so it doesn't matter.
April, that is not
the point, okay?
This is a conversation for
you and I when we are ready,
not for her to come
barging in dictating terms.
But it will calm her down.
I'm part of her family now.
I don't think an olive branch
is the worst thing
in the world to offer.
Yeah, well, you're a
better person than I am.
Well, yes.
And than she is.
I'm better than everyone.
Mmm-mmm. Not right now.
We can let her stew for a while.
Wait, wait, wait.
Come on.
I hate you.
I know, right? Do
you want to see?
No. I want to work
on that printer.
And it's my job to
make sure he doesn't.
Seriously? Yeah. Don't...
That's what you're
doing instead of this.
Oh, come on!
All right. What is that?
Okay.
Have you ever, ever
seen anything like this?
Oh, holy God! No, I never
wanted to! What is that?
It's a fetus in a fetus.
That I am down here not seeing.
I can totally read
without supervision.
Been doing it for years.
That's not reading.
That's doodling. Read.
Well...
This has been fun, but I have
to take a man out of a man.
Want another peak?
I'm good, actually.
That. How would it
work? Theoretically.
Let's go. Keep it
moving, people.
Everybody needs to take a look,
because this, my friends, is the
Halley's Comet of your careers,
as rare, wondrous
and fleeting...
Dr. Hunt. Can I help
you with something?
Yeah, I just came
to have a look.
You know there's a line.
You're... You're serious?
I'm deadly serious.
These kids want to
learn. Back of the line.
Thank you.
Now, you notice
that the absorbed twin
gets its blood supply
from the renal artery.
First glance, nothing special.
Take a second look,
and the Mona Lisa.
We will start by cutting
through the adhesions.
Once that occurs...
We're not taking him out.
What do you mean?
You heard the man.
My little twin is an
incredibly rare find.
Uh, yes.
Yes, it is, Greg, but it
still has to come out.
You want to destroy
the Mona Lisa?
No. I won't sign the consent.
I mean, you're
fixing baby hearts,
Derek's mapping
the brain, and I'm...
Have the most
amazing surgery ever.
I mean, please, tell
me this is pressing.
Nowhere near the heart.
Hey. Did you see this?
Oh, that the absorbed twin?
Technically, that's a peds case.
Back off. It's
the reason I live.
Aw, she's mopey 'cause she
let a lab rat loose in her lab.
Boo-hoo. You
gonna eat that bacon?
No, it's like leaving your
kids with a babysitter.
I mean, you say, "Put the kids
to bed at 7:00," but will they?
Or will they drink all
your tequila, pass out,
leave the gas on, the
whole house blows up
and everybody dies?
Okay. What do you think
of her? She's hot, right?
Have you given up on men?
No, for Owen.
There is this
Internet-dating site.
There are pages
of women like this.
Owen should be
doing this, right? Yes.
Why don't you just
keep banging him?
At least it's legal
for you guys.
You know, Jo's not gonna sign
that stupid love contract you gave me.
Why not?
Oh, I don't know.
Because it's stupid.
I knew I shouldn't
have given it to her.
Just tell her it's just a
stupid piece of paper.
Yeah, if she runs,
I'm blaming you.
She looks like she's 20.
She's cute.
I hate your husband.
Owen said not to talk about it.
I'm not. I'm talking to myself.
I hate Derek
Shepherd. Really? Why?
Oh, 'cause he's an
arrogant, stealing bastard.
I totally agree.
Do you ladies think she's hot?
Yeah, very.
And now, I hate you.
Nice. Oh.
Oh, no, no, no,
no, no. I got to go.
What did you do?
He talked the
man out of surgery.
Now, he loves
his little brother,
can't bear to part with him.
What?
I was explaining the
uniqueness of his condition.
Apparently, my
words cast a spell. Ah!
Okay, so, now, what do we tell
him? How do we get him back?
Tell him it could have adverse
effects on his blood pressure.
Tell him it could explode.
Tell him it's a demon.
Oh, that's good.
Okay, stop! I ruined it.
I'll fix it. I'll talk to him.
What are you gonna say?
I don't know!
I'm coming with you.
This is the worst birthday ever.
Oh, hey. Hey, did
you talk to Dr. Yang?
Ow! Sweet, geez.
What did she say? She...
She didn't say.
She was busy.
Oh, damn.
She said no. She said no.
Oh...
Look, they said
I'd be dead by 15.
I... I dropped out
of high school.
I hitchhiked. I had sex.
I'm having this baby because
I thought I was gonna die.
Now that it's coming,
I really want to live.
I want the chance to be her mom.
So, can you please
bring Dr. Yang in here,
so I can talk to her, please?
For my baby. Oh!
Okay, okay, breathe.
I am breathing!
Hey. What are you do... Shh.
What are you doing?
Webber's post-ops.
Since he got the
fetus in fetu, I get this.
Well, I'm heading in
to do the fundoplication,
and you'd be there,
too, if you were in peds.
No.
Okay, look, I thought it was
nuts when Mer gave it to me,
and I knew you'd hate it, too.
But, honest to God, it's just
a piece of paper that says...
It's a legal document,
Alex, so it's not just...
What is your problem?
In my experience, you sign
papers, and it's a kiss of death.
You sign a marriage license,
and the romance goes away.
She signed a DNR two days ago.
Guess what. She's using it.
Hey, Alex. Our guy's
being prepped. Ooh.
For what?
Our fundoplication.
Is that the cool transoral
thing? Cutting-edge?
Only being done in a few
top-level peds-surg programs?
Yeah, that's the one.
Okay. Let's do it.
I'm not talking to you.
Okay, then just listen.
If you understood what the
brain-mapping project can do,
you would share your technology.
Oh, share? I'm sharing
now? You're stealing it.
You're stealing it.
Callie, the brain
has more nerve cells
than humans on earth.
We want to understand
how all those neurons interact,
so we're gonna start
with a smaller group,
like everybody
here in the hospital.
And we're gonna determine how
they interact with each other and talk.
Please, stop. Stop patronizing
me... And then we move out.
You're just saying that your
thing is more important than mine.
I'm saying my thing
feeds your thing.
It will revolutionize our understanding
of what it means to be human.
And yet, you would have
never had the sensors
if it weren't for my
thing, you selfish...
Selfish?
Here! Let me show you a diagram.
This is you.
I'm an asterisk? No.
You think you are the
white-hot center of the universe.
Also, it looks like a
butthole. Either way, it works.
Sheryll, this is Dr. Yang.
Oh, hi. Dr. Yang.
I'd hug you, but... Ow!
Just breathe. I can
wait. No, I'm fine.
Uh, my doctor wanted to
put me on a transplant list,
but I heard about your
success with Baby Nathan.
Oh.
Dr. Ross, this is the patient
you already spoke to me about.
Listen, I know you're
only looking for little kids,
but can you please,
just... Please! Ah!
You know, just let
me take a listen here.
Oh, my goodness.
Thank you so much.
You have a slight murmur,
but besides that, you are well.
Your OB will monitor
your cardiac function,
and page me if there
are any complications.
Good luck.
Dr. Ross, a minute?
I'm sorry. She just really wanted
to have a chance to plead her case.
That was out of
line. I already said no.
I know it was wrong. I'm sorry.
She doesn't meet the
criteria. It's that simple.
I know it's hard because
they're kids and they're dying.
And they've got their
stories and lives and family...
Well, she doesn't!
Her parents don't talk to her.
Ross, stop it!
You're too emotionally involved,
and you've gotten her hopes up.
It's gonna be worse on
her when you tell her no.
Do your job.
Do you have my discharge papers?
Uh.
No. No, no, I don't. I think
you need to reconsider.
You need to have this
thing removed, Greg.
Dr. Webber, you said
it was incredibly rare.
And it's mine.
People chuck stuff all the time,
no clue of the value of the
thing that they're throwing away.
Finding treasure in
their trash is what I do.
And I didn't have to dig through
anyone's yard-sale crap to find this.
It was inside of me all along.
This is a wad of
bones and teeth.
It's not some crummy
box of VHS tapes.
We've talked about this.
Analog's coming
back in a big way.
Just because it's rare
doesn't mean it has value.
A heart has value.
A liver has value.
Actually, I'm on
Greg's side here.
No, you're not.
People do throw
things away too easily.
They throw out
people just like that.
They're done with you, and then
they throw you out with the trash.
Sir... I'm not gonna
do that, Greg.
Stop! Yeah, stop.
Okay, Greg, I have
a proposition for you.
You let me remove
this fetus in fetu,
and I promise you I
won't throw it in the trash.
I'll throw it in a jar, and
you can take it home.
You aren't serious.
It'll look a hell of a lot better
on a shelf than in your belly.
And you won't have
that pain anymore.
You can do that?
I do it all the time.
It comes down to this.
My research is just
as important as yours.
You're talking about
microscopic neurons.
I'm talking about giving a
person the ability to walk again.
It's just as important!
And you wouldn't
have come up with
the sensors if it
wasn't for my work.
The sensors were an answer
to a question that I asked you.
It was my answer! What...
Don't fight this, Callie.
You don't want to.
Oh, why, 'cause you have
government lawyers now?
I'm not gonna be bullied.
You don't have a case!
My name is on the material,
and my name is on the patents.
They're mine. You can
hear it from me now.
Or you can hear it
from a judge in court.
My suggestion is to save
your time and money.
Listen to me as your friend.
I'm sorry. I feel terrible.
There's a reason
you feel terrible.
It's 'cause it's the wrong
thing to do, and you know it.
You're not used to
answering to people,
and now, you have the President
himself calling
you on the phone.
And you're afraid to say no
even though you know
this is 100% wrong.
You're a good person.
That's why you feel bad.
'Cause you should.
Down to seven. That's fast.
I know what I want. Uh,
did you do the profile?
What? The dating thing? No, no.
Cristina, I've spent my
morning trying to figure out
a way to fix this thing
between Torres and Shepherd.
I haven't had time.
Sit. I'll do it for you.
Describe yourself.
No. Stubborn.
Listen, I'm not being
stubborn. I'm just...
Smart, athletic.
Listen, I'm too busy to...
"A busy professional
seeks..." What?
Nothing. I seek nothing.
Ah, "seeks same,
"someone who is
passionate about her work,
"someone who's..."
Come on. What?
Fine. Fine.
Um... Someone who
doesn't care to cook
or get out of bed when
it's not a work day.
Someone who sleeps
so soundly and peacefully,
that I have to check
her pulse sometimes.
Someone who's suffered
and understands suffering.
I'd keep it more upbeat.
To the point that I
don't have to say a word.
She just looks at me and
sees who I am and how I feel.
And accepts it.
You know, she doesn't try to
change it, doesn't want to change it.
That person.
There's a billion
people out there.
But I imagine,
there's only one her.
I am happy to sign the document.
That's wonderful.
I don't have a pen.
No, sweetheart, you
don't actually sign it here.
You review it with your lawyer,
and he will then confer
with our family lawyer.
I... I will consult a lawyer.
Good. Now, let's talk
about the children.
Oh, my God.
Will you have children? Yes.
Yes. Yes. I said, "Yes."
In what religious tradition
will they be raised?
We don't know.
We haven't talked about
what religious tradition
we will or won't raise our
theoretical children in yet.
That's a conversation
you might want to have.
Avery children become Avery
Foundation board members.
The foundation controls
$480 million in charitable funds
for the advancement of medicine.
What? Yeah.
Your children, when they are 15,
will start sitting in on
board meetings, you know,
begin to learn the
business, like Jackson did.
When they are 18, they
will gain a seat on the board.
They will be voting members.
You are a born-again Christian,
who I presume is pro-life.
That's right.
Will your children
be taught that
people who are
pro-choice go to hell
or their pro-choice father is
going to hell or their grandmother?
Wait. Whoa!
I don't think anyone
is going to hell.
It's so much more
complicated than that.
Will they stop supporting
medical institutions
that perform abortions
or provide information
about abortions like, for
example, this hospital?
Will they vote to stop
supporting stem-cell research?
We'd all like to think that
the problem at the table
is the meddling mother-in-law
who didn't get to walk
her son down the aisle,
but I have built a
massive institution
with my blood and my
sweat, and you will inherit it.
And, one day, your
children will control it.
And I don't get the
impression that either of you
has given a moment's
thought to what that means!
Hello, little brother.
I see a finger. No,
two... Three fingers.
Gross! Where?
He just wants
to try the printer.
Why does he need to?
Because it's why he's here.
And as long as you
won't let him do anything,
I can't be in here.
Tell him I said no.
Is... Is that an ear?
- No. That's a lung.
- That's a lung.
But that is a tooth.
It's a tooth.
And that is a spinal column.
Look! Every damn vertebrae.
I still want to know what
you said to get him to consent.
He promised him a doggy bag.
You didn't.
I did.
He's right. It's part of him.
He should be able
to have it and share it.
This is of great medical
interest. That's valuable.
You don't hide it inside
of some basement
or let it rot away.
You share it.
You let people benefit from it,
because, if you do, you can
change the face of medicine.
Oh, my God, I'm gonna say
this to you for the last time.
All right. This relationship is not
new. This decision was not rash.
You only feel that way because
you didn't get to weigh in on it.
Because you didn't
include me in it,
like everything
else in your life.
I don't need to include you!
You include yourself
in everything always!
Stop! Oh, stop it!
Stop it, both of you!
April, sweetheart, don't...
No, stop it!
You're right.
There are a lot of things
we still haven't figured out,
but we will figure them
out, Jackson and I.
But if you think
that I am judging you
or anyone because of my beliefs,
then I'm... I'm so
sorry because I'm not.
That is not me.
And I would love to talk to
you about that sometime,
but if it's our children that
you are so concerned about,
if they disagree with
you on some things,
if that's not okay with
you, then I don't know.
Restructure the board?
I'm making this up.
I have no idea how
it works. Clearly.
Look, the point is, there
will be a way to figure it out.
We did something
that wasn't responsible,
but we did it because
we love each other
and we want to spend every
day together until we die.
I am sorry.
No, you don't have
to apologize to her.
I do. I do. We got married.
We had a wedding,
and all she got
was a phone call
after it was over.
If our kids do that, I will kill
them with my bare hands.
We made a huge mess.
We hurt Matthew,
and we hurt Stephanie.
And we hurt you.
And I am so sorry.
And I'm gonna spend the next,
I don't know how many years,
trying to make it up to you.
Apologize to your mom.
Come on.
Can you stand up?
What the hell were you thinking?
I love her.
Mom.
And I am sorry.
But I love her.
She's the one.
You could have had
Grandma's cake topper.
It's Limoges.
I know. I know.
I'm sure it's lovely.
Ow.
Okay.
Can't do it! It hurts.
The epidural's
worn off, Sheryll.
You've really got
to start pushing.
I can't. I'm trying. I
swear I can't do it.
God, I just want my mama!
Somebody, please, call my mom!
Ah! Sheryll, your
baby's almost here.
Just hang in there. I can't!
I can't. Can you
please call her?
Tell her I'm really sorry,
and I need her
really, really badly.
I can't do it. I just
need my mama.
Her blood pressure's
skyrocketing.
Prep an OR for a C-section.
We'll call your mom, okay?
But you're gonna have
to do this on your own.
I know you can. Just push.
Come on, Sheryll. Push.
One more time. Push!
Sheryll, you did it.
I did it?
You did it, Sheryll. I...
Hey, Lloyd. How's
everything at the NIH?
Uh, hello, Derek. I...
We, uh, still can't see you.
Yeah, we're working on that.
Lloyd, I have
Dr. Callie Torres here.
She and I developed
the sensors together.
Hi, Lloyd.
He can't see you.
Oh.
Look, Lloyd, I'm
afraid this whole
proprietary thing
isn't going to work.
Dr. Torres' and my work has
to continue with our sensors.
Derek, uh, before
we, uh, continue,
I should tell you
that we are here
with some folks from the
NIH and, uh, the White House.
Here we are.
Gary Neal, Director of NIBS,
and Sid Garret, our presidential
liaison for the Bioethics Committee,
and this is Robin Marks of
the European Brain Initiative,
and, uh, you know, of
course, Linda McCrary,
and, uh, I'm sorry
I forgot your name.
Yeah, I'm glad you're all there.
Actually, um, this
affects all of you.
Lloyd, our work to map the
brain is like the brain itself.
It's dependent upon connections,
our innovation and
inspiration of scientists
like Dr. Torres and
millions of others.
If we have a policy
that thwarts innovation,
then we're stopping
before we even start.
It's, uh, a fundamentally
wrong approach,
and I can't support it.
Okay.
We are willing to share
our sensors with you,
but only if our work continues.
If everybody's
research continues.
Dr. Shepherd, your
contract is very clear.
We have sole right to
your sensors, or you are out.
Then I am out.
The President himself...
You can tell that
to the President.
Better yet, get him on the
phone. I will tell him myself.
Either the policy goes, or I go.
We will...
have to figure out...
a way to share.
In the meantime, you can send
us the plans for your sensors,
and, uh, Dr. Torres, of course,
uh, should continue her work.
Thank you, uh, Lloyd,
for your cooperation.
I'll talk to you soon.
Whoo-hoo-hoo-hoo-hoo!
Yes! Unh!
Greg. Jodi.
Okay, everything went very well.
We're going... You promised me.
Cough it up. Murphy.
Thank you.
Oh, my God! That's horrible!
Thank you for
taking that out of me.
Take that away. Take that away.
Thank you. Oh...
Oh. Oh...
Oh. You stupid idiot.
You want me to take
that back to Path?
Oh, are you kidding me?
This is my birthday present.
Oh...
Uh, speaking of which, I'll see
you, what, in about, uh, half an hour?
Sir?
Okay, now, you're
making me feel bad.
What... If I'd have
known you wanted a party,
I would have...
Look, come to dinner
with me and Ben.
Oh, oh, please.
Please, we'd love to...
We'd love to...
Bailey, stop. Bailey.
I was just joking.
Go and have fun.
Happy birthday.
It's not blurry?
No, it's good.
Edwards. You had one job.
Oh...
Dr. Grey, we were just,
uh, looking at Eric's designs,
which are actually
kind of amazing.
I'm fired. I'm totally fired.
Listen, Gary... Uh, Eric.
What... Whatever. This
was my mother's project.
I took it over. It's my project.
So, it's sort of like
my family heirloom.
I totally get it. I
have this teacup...
It's my baby, and I failed it.
No, you didn't. Stop talking.
I failed it, and that's
not okay because
other people's
babies are growing.
They're thriving.
They're saving lives.
They're getting pats on
the backs from presidents.
And mine is sitting
in a basement,
and we need to change that.
She said "We."
Yeah, it's a good sign.
Have a seat.
Before you start printing, I want
to go over a few things with you.
Well, I'm good right here.
I said sit.
So, the first time we printed,
I think where I went wrong is...
She's so beautiful.
You're telling me she's gonna
have to grow up without a mother?
There are other options.
You can get on
a transplant list,
and maybe the next phase
of trials will be more inclusive.
But I want this one.
I am so, so sorry.
You don't meet the criteria.
Call your mom.
I bet she's worried about you.
Honestly, I'm really
proud of my boy.
He had the stones to stand
up and ask for true love.
I... That's scary.
Of course, I would
never tell him that.
Mmm-hmm.
What's the matter with you?
You were quiet all the way here.
Are you sad because no
one celebrated your birthday?
Oh, come on. I'm not a child.
Hunt's trying to push
me into retirement.
What?
He started the day by handing
me directions to the pasture.
And you told him
where to stick it, right?
Oh, come on. Don't
slow down on me now.
I'm ready to start the
next part of my life.
And I thought I was
gonna do it with you.
If you're not up for it,
you'd better step aside.
And if you are, you... Mmm.
Mmm.
Let's go.
All right.
Now, smile.
And act surprised.
What? Mmm.
Surprise!
Happy birthday, Dr. Webber!
Surprise.
Happy birthday, sir.
You looked right in my eyes,
and you lied to me, Bailey.
Yeah, but it didn't count
because you were being stupid.
Hey. Happy birthday.
Well, thank you. Thank you.
Hey, Arizona told me that
Jackson put together a committee
to look into this thing
for you and Callie.
My God. Whoops.
You can tell him to stop.
You need a drink? Yeah.
You can have a drink.
Wait, well... Well,
what happened?
We overthrew the
government today. We're thirsty.
I don't... What?
How are you doing?
Okay.
Here's your drink.
I'll be better
once I've had this.
Here you go.
Women love you.
You've had over 20 responses.
I narrowed it down to 10.
You should look these over.
Pick three for coffee dates.
Hmm.
Hmm? Hmm. Hmm!
Okay, I got to go talk to
Webber, and, after that,
I think we should
get out of here.
Owen. You could just wait here.
Or we could meet
back at your place.
Owen. Mmm-hmm?
See?
I can get in trouble for
that, and I don't want to.
This isn't a
promise of anything.
You want a promise?
I can promise you this.
You can't count on me,
'cause stuff happens, you know?
Houses burn. Cars
crash. People get sick.
One of us could die tomorrow.
I promise you cannot count on
anything, but this makes it so...
I can kiss you
whenever I want to.
I don't want the stupid
running around and hiding.
I want to kiss you
when I want to kiss you.
What can I get for you?
Yes.
I know.
Know what?
What religious tradition I
want to bring my kids up in.
You said you
don't know, but I do.
It's important to me
that they're Christian.
I thought you knew that.
That my kids would have
different beliefs than I do?
That's a little weird, April.
Transition is movement from
one part of life to a whole new one.
And board meetings at 15?
I kind of pictured
my kids in 4-H.
Like raising pigs?
Or cows.
It's important that they're
comfortable around livestock.
Is it? Jackson.
They'll ride horses
at boarding school.
They're going to
boarding school?
And it can feel like one
long, scary, dark tunnel...
So, this morning, I mentioned
pulling back on your
surgical schedule.
You want to do this
now, on my birthday?
I'm sorry, Hunt,
I'm not retiring.
You can force me, but I'm not...
I'd like to appoint you director
of the residency program.
You'd be in charge
of all the decisions
regarding the educational
arm of this hospital.
But you have to come
out the other side...
I can teach. I'm good at it.
But you bring something
to it that I just can't.
Well, what's that?
You.
Take some time
to think about it.
I'd like to make a
toast to Dr. Webber.
Me, too. What?
Not before I finish mine.
While you guys fight
it out, I just want to say
I wouldn't be here if it
weren't for Dr. Webber.
Thank you, sir. Happy birthday.
Happy birthday.
Thank you.
Because what's
been waiting there...
Cheers.
Might be glorious.
Residency director,
hmm? Mmm-hmm.
Yeah. I'll think about it.