Blue Calamari
is still in the lead,
but Ample Parking
is making strides,
and is now in fourth, third,
and holding second place, while
Blue Calamari is at a steady speed.
And down the stretch they come!
Ample Parking comes from behind.
And it's Ample Parking by a nose.
This is the last call for the third
race. You may still wager if you hurry.
Here's your
information on the race...
Out of the way.
Cripple coming through.
Sixth race at Golden Downs.
I'll take the two and the
four. Hey, that's my birthday.
February 4, 1963. Do
you think that's a good bet?
What's your birthday?
Take your time.
Don't worry. There's
only 30 seconds to post.
Is there any way I can bet
on the six and the three also?
You know, for the year? All
four horses. Can I do that?
He wants a $2 exacta box,
two, four, six, three. Give him $24.
Your turn.
The ninth at Gulfstream
Park. $500 on the three horse,
Seminole Uprising to win.
Might as well burn your money.
I'll burn my winnings.
Bigger flame.
Same race, Termigator to win.
Sorry, race just closed.
Damn it.
She was 14-to-1, too.
Then fatass over there
just saved you money.
No way Seminole Uprising's...
I don't bet on the
horses. I bet on the jocks.
My rider's bulimic,
purges after his weigh-ins.
Leave a two-pound
pile at the starting gate,
shaves valuable time
off that final eighth.
Nice to have inside information.
By a length.
The Burning Bush and
on the level is Candy,
right up on the
inside is Bowfinger...
And Termigator pulling
up against the rail.
Is anybody here a doctor?
Trying to cop a feel?
I took a CPR class at the Y.
That would be useful if she was
having a heart attack instead of a seizure.
Seizure? Hold her tongue down?
If you wanna get
a finger bitten off.
Call an ambulance.
Methodist's three blocks down.
I could drive her.
Just make the call.
What the hell is that?
How should I know?
Tell the paramedics to take
her to Princeton-Plainsboro.
Her doctor's name is House.
And it's Termigator,
winning by two lengths.
Since when does
House hang out at OTB?
The man's an addict.
Right, addicted to
pills, not gambling.
It's the same thing.
Drug abuse, drinking, gambling.
They all fire up the same
pleasure centers in the brain.
An addict is an addict is an...
Gambling doesn't
take away his pain.
It does when I win.
Hot OTB babe has grand mal
and inexplicable bruising.
What up with that?
You were just standing
there, and she started to seize?
Spend as much time
around the real people as I do,
someone gets sick.
Her platelets are
89, she's anemic.
And she has a blood
alcohol level of 0.13.
Hot OTB babe?
Obviously a working girl.
Probably an STD infection.
No fever. No infection.
Alcohol abuse explains it all.
Causes seizures and affects
her blood's ability to clot,
which causes bruising.
Start her on heparin,
she'll be fine by morning.
Except for the fact that the
bruises are not petechial,
which means it's not DIC.
So the bruises were
caused by trauma.
She probably got beat up
by her boyfriend. Or her pimp.
What's that called when you judge
someone before ever meeting them?
She's a regular at OTB.
Somehow, I don't see her holding
down a 9-to-5 and going to PTA meetings.
I was there. I
have a 9-to-3 job.
It could be SLE, familial
telangiectasias, or even Cushing's.
Good. Start with those.
Which one?
Cushing's. It explains the
seizure and the bruising.
Not the anemia.
So she doesn't
eat a lot of meat.
DIC brought on by alcohol
abuse is far more likely.
Do a full workup, H and
P. And lab her up, LP, MRI.
Did you just ever so subtly order
me to get her medical history?
Cuddy put me in charge
last week, so, yeah.
It was a pretend in charge, a
formality to get past the suits in legal.
Right, those licensing-board folk
love to play dress up and pretend.
Hey, no worries. I'll let you
keep your parking space.
You can have it. You'll also
need my handicap placard.
Bend over.
You make a pretty
convincing argument.
Chase killed that woman.
Now Foreman's in charge?
Yeah, we have a
pecking order here.
If Cameron kills somebody,
Chase takes over.
There's a flow
chart in the lobby.
For the next three weeks, you
answer directly to Dr. Foreman.
And I expect you here
for grand rounds at 9:00.
By the way, I like
sugar in my coffee.
If there's a screw
up, it's your screw up.
You won't have
Dr. House to fall back on.
"Do you wear a seat belt?" Is
that really relevant to a seizure?
Skip it.
How about, "Were you
vaccinated for polio?"
I think you gave me the
form intended for FDR.
You really like Teeny
Tiny Mo in the fifth?
I went 4-for-6 yesterday.
You want winners? Cure me first.
"Are you generally
satisfied with your life?"
It does not ask that.
You know, I was gonna ask
what a respectable doctor
was doing at an OTB parlor.
Somehow that question
doesn't seem relevant anymore.
What's your excuse?
It turns me on.
Yeah? What else
turns you on? Drugs?
Casual sex? Rough sex?
Casual rough sex?
I'm a doctor. I need to know.
No sex.
Just moved here. Haven't
even found a job yet.
Don't know anybody.
Came here without a job.
That means you didn't move here,
you moved away from somewhere else.
Does that hurt? No.
Are you on any prescription
meds? Hormones? Prednisone?
I already answered that one. I think
it was question number 20-something.
Well, yeah. And I could
reach down and get it.
But that would kind of
spoil the whole cool move.
I'm not on any medications.
Are you a vegetarian?
No. Why?
Because you might have
something called Cushing's syndrome,
which basically means...
My pituitary is
overproducing ACTH,
which is causing my adrenal glands to
push too much cortisol into my bloodstream.
What a coincidence.
I'm a doctor, too.
Yeah, I had it last year.
They did brain surgery, removed
an adenoma from my pituitary.
What did you just say?
"You were right, House. Her
pituitary tumor regrew. It is Cushing's.
"Uncanny how you do that."
Actually, it was Cameron's idea.
No, Cameron had three ideas.
I chose one to
encourage, to nurture...
Yeah, you're all
about the nurturing.
Do you need a hug?
I don't see any regrowth.
You get her medical
records faxed over?
Work smart, not hard.
That's my philosophy, boss.
I'll take that as a no.
Anica, I need you to
stay completely still.
Sorry.
Still don't see anything.
Okay, so it's a microadenoma.
Too small to see.
So small, it's not even there.
Right. It's just a coincidence
that I predicted a rare condition
that she happened
to have a year ago.
Results from her LP back yet?
Didn't do an LP. I
knew what she had.
Go do the LP.
Okay, I need you to roll over
on your side, kiss your kneecaps.
Party time.
I thought it only took
one doctor to do this.
I'm observing.
She's here to make
sure I don't paralyze you.
You've done this before, right?
Successfully?
He's kidding. He's
an excellent doctor.
I'm going to numb the
area with some lidocaine,
and then we're off to the races.
See what I did there?
I used horse-racing jargon to make
the patient feel more comfortable.
Okay, here we go.
Felt like bone. Does that hurt?
A little bit. What
are you doing?
Try rounding your
back a bit more.
You're perfect just
the way you are.
Oops, that was all me.
Might want to move
down one vertebra.
This is actually much
harder than I remember.
My chest feels a little tight.
Try taking a deep breath.
Dr. House, maybe I
should take it from here.
Eighth time's the charm.
You trying to piss off Foreman?
Just let...
BP's 240 over 140.
Turn that thing off, will you?
Take the needle out.
Take the needle out! Okay.
It's a hypertensive crisis.
Start her on an IV lopressor drip.
Titrate to systolic less
than 140. She'll be fine.
Cameron. Meet me in my office.
At the risk of sounding
redundant and right, again,
she has Cushing's. Cushing's.
Right, the fact that you mangled
her LP has nothing to do with it.
Actually, it has
everything to do with it.
Cushing's plus stress
equals hypertensive crisis.
Smart move, sending the rookie.
Her initial symptoms could have
been caused by alcohol-induced DIC.
She had a hypertensive crisis
because it's been at least six
hours since she had her last drink.
She's detoxing.
The exact same moment that
I'm futilely trying to give her an LP?
Right. An invisible tumor on
her pituitary is much more likely.
What if the tumor
is somewhere else?
There could be an ACTH-secreting
tumor on her lung or pancreas.
It's awfully rare.
Not as rare as
an invisible tumor.
Why didn't they put you in
charge instead of Foreman?
Oh, yeah, you're the
guy that killed that woman.
Get a pan-man scan
before she dies a cortisol OD.
Fine. Do it.
But when you don't find
anything, put her on a Librium taper
for the withdrawal and get
her a bed in a rehab clinic.
Lungs look clean.
Her lymph nodes
are not enlarged.
Cuddy tapped Foreman
to run the department.
I didn't even get asked.
Neither did I.
You were suspended.
I was kidding.
It's the irony of women in charge.
They don't like other women in charge.
What? You think
it's something else?
You sabotaged yourself.
You went on a date with House.
You slept with me. Putting
you in charge of this department
is like a sexual harassment
suit waiting to happen.
Yeah, they're really worried
that I'm gonna create a
hostile work environment.
Maybe that's the problem.
Being in charge means
having to say no to House.
Would you hire you for that?
Anderson coming out
strong. What is he thinking?
He watched what
Tom Mants just did.
You ordered MRIs for
the entire maternity ward?
I was in a crazy mood.
Good thing I got a new
boss to back me up.
Although, I think one of
those is actually necessary.
Better comb through
before you cancel them all.
What do you expect me
to do, House? Quit? Cry?
Actually, I expect you
to act like what you are.
My employee. My subordinate.
My bitch.
Well, since you asked nicely...
My God.
I can't believe I got more than a year
behind on my discharge summaries.
Got to get caught
up. Oh, no, wait.
I'm not authorized to sign
these anymore. Only you are.
Keep it coming.
I'm not gonna break.
Scan showed a
mass on her pancreas.
Looks malignant.
Probably inoperable.
I'd give her two months.
On the bright side, it
still means I was right.
Where's Dr. House?
Dr. Foreman's
overseeing your case.
He thought it'd be best if I spoke with
you. We found a mass in your pancreas.
It looks like cancer.
So something in my pancreas
caused me to have a seizure?
Probably. But the
bigger point is...
A one-year survival rate for
pancreatic cancer is less than 20%.
So what's the treatment?
We need to biopsy the mass
to see what we're dealing with,
and then we can
recommend options from there.
Sounds good.
I need your consent
to do the biopsy.
Thanks.
Wish me luck.
Good luck.
It was weird. She
barely reacted at all.
I've had people hug me and
people take a swing at me.
This was more like
she didn't even hear me.
Magnify three times.
House assisting.
That is funny.
Too bad Foreman's gonna die.
Good afternoon, I'm Dr. House.
I'm gonna be looking at your...
Perfect.
Excuse me.
Need Dr. Foreman in
exam room one for a consult.
So, when did this start?
Couple weeks ago.
I didn't want to get pregnant. Jake's
not into rubbers, so I got on the jelly.
You think I'm
allergic or something?
You have an infection.
I'm gonna need a sample.
I brought the jar.
No, I meant a sample of your...
Okay. We have a
neurological problem here.
There's something
wrong with my brain?
Oh, yeah.
Cover yourself up.
Got what I need.
What's up?
Smell this.
Smells like vaginosis,
but it's not really my call.
Great. I'll be sure to put a gold
star by your name on the board.
Anica's biopsy for pancreatic
cancer was negative.
Okay, I'm gonna give
you some antibiotics
and you probably shouldn't
have sex for a while.
How long?
On an evolutionary basis,
I'd recommend forever.
The mass in the pancreas is
benign. It's probably just scar tissue.
Good news. She's not sick at
all. Other than being an alcoholic.
The labs you sent yesterday put her
ACTH at 64 picograms per milliliter.
She's got Cushing's.
Something set it off.
It's gotta be in her brain. Set
her up for a venous sampling.
There is another possibility.
Chase, hold on.
How'd you get him trained
so fast? Electronic collar?
Got treats in your pocket?
She didn't even read the consent
form for the pancreatic biopsy.
Who reads those things?
Maybe she didn't read it because she
knew that there was nothing wrong with her.
There is another
explanation for the Cushing's.
Maybe she injected herself with the
ACTH. Her behavior suggests Munchausen's.
She's had four hospitalizations
in the last four months.
Well, being hospitalized a lot certainly
points to nothing being wrong with you.
She's had zero symptoms
since she got here.
The scarring on her pancreas
could be caused from injecting
herself with the benzene
and setting off the seizures.
She's had brain surgery.
You can fake a stomachache.
You can't fake a brain tumor.
You can fake an invisible one.
We should check her apartment.
Look for medications, syringes...
Venous sampling's easier.
And more dangerous.
Not if you get
caught breaking in.
So don't get caught, House.
Why do you think Cuddy
picked Foreman over me?
Have I done something wrong?
Or if there's something I
needed to improve on...
Will it make you shut up
if I told you she
wanted someone black?
How would you describe
my leadership skills?
Nonexistent.
Otherwise excellent.
There's more to being a
leader than being a jerk.
The world will never know.
No. No way. It just snowed.
Yesterday. The
streets are clear.
My car is right there.
There's construction on
Elm. Bike will be faster.
There's even books
in the bathroom.
Well, either she's very smart or
she has a severe fiber deficiency.
She's got an appointment with
her ophthalmologist on Tuesday
and an appointment with
her gynecologist on Thursday.
Multiple appointments
with multiple doctors.
Symptom of Munchausen's.
Or, just thinking
outside the box here,
she has a vagina
and trouble reading.
There's three pairs of reading
glasses, each with different prescriptions.
Which would be explained by a
tumor pressing on the optic nerve.
Because you're looking
for her to have a tumor.
And you're looking for...
A person with Munchausen's
syndrome drinks battery acid.
But they don't go to an ophthalmologist
to get their pupils dilated.
An ophthalmologist is a
doctor. Attention is attention.
How many hospitals have you
contacted? Has one doctor said she's crazy?
It's not Munchausen's.
It's not your call.
If you think she's
got Munchausen's,
then obviously you got
something to show the man.
A syringe in her
apartment. A bottle of ACTH.
Munchausen's patients are
good at covering their tracks.
Right. So, the fact that we found
nothing proves there's something.
Look at the pathology reports
from the surgery she had in Chicago.
They removed 30% of her
pituitary. They found no tumor.
It's possible the
surgeons just missed it.
In that kind of surgery,
you're just cutting and hoping...
Of course, we're both right.
Excellent solution,
everybody's happy.
Come on, step up, Foreman.
If you think I'm right, order
me to stick a needle in her brain.
If you think Cameron's
right, send the patient home.
Either she'll be
fine, or she'll die.
Do the venous sampling.
Get her consent.
Nice move, boss.
Way to cover your ass.
I just agreed with you.
Not because you think I'm right,
you're just taking the
safe route. You're a wuss.
Don't worry, your
secret's safe with me.
Hey, Wilson, guess
what Foreman just did!
Hi.
This is a consent form to
stick a wire into your brain.
It's important for hospitals to
get these signed for procedures
that are completely unnecessary.
Then why are you doing it?
Because you're mentally ill.
You injected yourself with ACTH to induce
Cushing's to get attention from doctors.
And so far, it's worked.
I'd like to see another doctor.
I'm not giving you
what you want?
I don't want a bitch.
Just sign the forms, okay?
And I'll get out of here.
Hopefully for you, whatever you
injected yourself with won't wear off
before you get the fun of a caring and
concerned doctor cutting into your head.
You chose me to make
House miserable, didn't you?
Apparently, he's making you
miserable. That's impressive.
Find someone else.
No.
For the first time in six years,
I'm getting copied on all
experimental tests and procedures.
Clinic hours have been
logged and completed.
You've given me four
months of House's dictations
so I can finally bill
insurance companies.
I only did that stuff to prove
he couldn't make me miserable.
Well, way to go.
Now everybody's getting
what they need, even House.
He gets to play mad scientist,
and this department runs smoothly.
So I'm stuck with this
for the next three weeks.
Maybe longer.
Would you be interested
if this wasn't just pretend?
What did Mommy say? I don't
get any candy in my stocking?
Patient being prepped
for the venous sampling?
Yeah, a mentally ill patient is right
on track for a pointless procedure.
Yeah, we get your objection.
Foreman. Are you sure?
That doesn't make any
sense. Check it again.
We gotta delay the
venous sampling.
Why? Her urine turning orange?
How would you know that?
Because that's
what rifampin does.
She's not on antibiotics.
But if a Munchausen's patient
thinks she's about to get busted,
she sees pills labeled
"Dangerous, might cause seizures,"
she might grab a couple.
And if that label were accidentally
on a bottle of antibiotics,
and if that bottle were
accidentally left in her room...
You set her up?
Might have. It's Munchausen's.
All this, she did to herself.
I don't know what the
hell you're talking about.
I had a seizure. I'm
sick. I need your help.
Not from this department.
The half-life of
rifampin is three hours.
After that, you'll get your psych
referral and your discharge papers.
You know, just because you
stick your fingers down your throat
doesn't mean the rest
of us are screwed up.
I guess when cooperation
fails, you move on to hostility.
I didn't do this to myself.
100% commitment.
Sign of a good liar.
Also the sign of a sociopath.
What are you doing?
Correcting your last note.
We can't discharge
her if she's sick.
Anybody ever tell you,
you write like a girl?
What?
You got some other
explanation for orange urine?
It's Munchausen's.
Correct, but not complete.
You just don't want to
admit that she skunked you.
At the end of The Boy Who Cried
Wolf, the wolf really does come.
Then he eats the sheep,
and the boy, and his parents.
The wolf doesn't
eat the parents.
He does when I tell it.
You're not telling
the story now. I am.
Look, I checked her records.
All her hospitalizations
were for different things.
Brain tumor, fainting
spells, skin rashes, seizures.
She's had every blood
test known to man
and the results are
all over the map.
There's only one
constant, low HCT.
The anemia's real.
There's a million things
she could have taken
to have done that.
True, it could just be her MO.
She self-induces two illnesses.
One always changes, one never does.
Or maybe she has
Munchausen's and aplastic anemia,
which would mean,
without proper treatment,
she'll continue to
get sicker, weaker,
eventually she'll start
bleeding internally and die.
She's not getting
sicker. She will.
If her bone marrow was dying, the
entire blood panel would be affected.
Her white count's normal.
- So far.
We need to do a
bone marrow biopsy.
No. No more tests.
Look, you kick her to the curb
with a Munchausen's diagnosis
you're guaranteeing that no
doctor will ever listen to her again.
We do more tests, we'll
only be feeding her psychosis.
The more attention we give
her, the more she'll want.
What if she doesn't
know we're testing her?
House, you were
wrong. Live with it.
There's probably some blood
left over from previous tests.
Blood tests alone can't
confirm aplastic anemia.
Yes, I know. That's why I want
to do a bone marrow biopsy.
But blood tests could
show a systemic disease.
A virus or a toxin could
be the cause. Fine.
You want to test the extra
blood? Knock yourself out.
But the patient is off-limits.
And if the results are
positive, I get my biopsy?
It's the safe way to go.
I need all of these tests and
a PCR done on this sample.
You're gonna need more blood.
Patient's empty.
Then I can't do it.
You can try.
I can try to look like Salma Hayek,
that's not gonna make it happen.
You may not have Salma's ass,
but she doesn't have your eyes.
Yeah, right.
How soon you need it?
Dr. Wilson, can I talk to you
about something in confidence?
Of course. It's about House.
Oh, then no.
Fine. I won't say anything.
Do you think there's any way House
would take me seriously as his boss?
Where is this coming from?
Did Cuddy say something?
We talked. She intimated.
And you want my advice
on how to usurp him?
It's very ancient Rome, you'll
need a toga, of course, a sword.
It's not a coup. I just want to figure
out some way we can work together.
I mean, I keep the team running
from an administrative point of view,
House doesn't have to deal
with the red tape. It's a win-win.
I'm sure he'll see it that way.
Do you have any advice
on how to approach him?
How to deal the guy?
No.
But you won't
tell him we talked?
No.
There is no way this
is going to happen.
Epstein-Barr titers
are through the roof,
the most common viral
cause of aplastic anemia.
So what I'm saying is...
Fetal hemoglobin's also
elevated. Just a wee bit.
Could indicate...
You see that in sickle cell.
Not all sickle cell
patients are black.
None of her other blood panels showed
any sign of sickle cell, which means
either something's changed drastically
since yesterday, or this isn't her blood.
Of course it is.
Metaphorically.
Look, I couldn't do the tests.
I tried, but there wasn't
enough blood left over.
If you'd just let
me do the biopsy.
No way.
I just got back
from a suspension.
And if it wasn't for me,
you would've been fired.
Why don't you just get
the sample yourself?
Since when have you
cared what your boss said?
I don't care what anybody
says, I care what they do.
Right now Blackpoleon Blackaparte
has got the nurses on red alert.
I can't get into
the patient's room.
So, come on, I'll draw the
enemy fire, you outflank them
get in there, get the
bone marrow sample.
Can't.
Who you more afraid of?
I'm not afraid of Foreman, I agree
with him. All the tests back him up.
All the tests have
not been done.
You do realize that Blackaparte's
reign is only temporary.
I also realize that no matter what I
do, you're still gonna treat me like crap.
"Crap" is a relative term.
I never even
made it to the room.
Nurses called the attending
as soon as a trocar was ordered.
You used her real name?
I just processed your
patient's discharge papers.
She's on her way out right now.
Wait up.
It's all right,
she's gonna stay.
Wonderful. Oh, bite me.
I don't need to hear
the riot act again.
How'd you like
another medical test?
What? Sit.
Why?
So you don't crack your
skull when you pass out.
Just do it.
You know what colchicine is?
No.
Well, don't feel
bad. It's for gout.
It's got nothing to do with anything
you've ever pretended to have.
I'm not pretending to...
Shut up.
Colchicine decimates
your white blood cells.
Leaves almost no trace.
It's great for faking
your way into hospitals.
I didn't fake my way... Shut up.
You've been
doing this for years.
Don't worry, it's
probably not your fault.
When you were a kid,
you had a close relative
who had a chronic
disease, probably your sister.
And you saw all the attention she
got while you were left alone, ignored.
And it really, seriously
screwed you up.
I do not have a
relative... Shut up!
I'm trying to give
you what you want.
And save your life.
You have aplastic anemia.
What, are you trying
to scare me now?
It means you're not
just sick in the head.
Problem is, the rest
of you appears well.
So I gotta make you seem as
sick as you're supposed to be
by injecting you with a drug
that simulates the symptoms
that you actually have.
All you need to know is, you've
hit the Munchausen's jackpot.
I'm gonna give you a cocktail of
insulin for seizure and colchicine
to kill your white count.
This will absolutely confirm
my diagnosis of aplastic anemia.
There is one small catch.
If you've actually done something
to yourself to cause the anemia,
then I'm wrong.
And if I do what I plan to do,
then the treatment will kill
you instead of saving you.
So I need to know.
Have you been taking anything
besides the insulin, the ACTH,
and the pills Cameron
left in your room?
No.
Good. Give me your arm.
It was my mom.
She had MS.
She was in and out
of hospitals all the time.
People were always
trying to do things for her.
Bring her food, or brush
her hair, or make her happy.
People cared.
She died when I was 16.
Then there was no one.
Boo-hoo.
Where are you going?
I obviously can't be
around when it happens.
Well, what are you gonna
do, you're just gonna...
Relax, you know the drill.
People walk by here
all the time, you'll be fine.
So, barely out the door
and she has another seizure.
She must have somehow
grabbed insulin on the way out.
Once she's stable, we
need to get her out of here
before she does more
damage to herself.
We can't.
Her white count's down.
Sorry, I missed that.
Hearing's been off since
the Ricky Martin concert,
some cholo kicked
me in the head.
White count, hematocrit,
and platelets are all off.
Her bone marrow's shutting down.
She actually has aplastic anemia.
Say what?
All her other labs show
nothing that would...
Labs, shmabs. A good
diagnostician reads between the labs.
You were right.
Hey, we're not here to
play the blame game.
These things happen.
Sometimes doctors send
people out on the street to die
after other doctors
have warned them
that they're sending people
out on the street to die.
There's no way you could know.
I'll go give her the news.
Who are you?
I'm Dr. Foreman. I'm
in charge of your case.
You have aplastic anemia,
which means your bone
marrow has shut down.
Your body can't make
new blood anymore.
Are you sure?
I went back and checked your
old records. It makes sense.
The aplastic anemia's apparently
been developing for months.
I'm sorry, we should
have caught it earlier.
So
It's not just the latest white count
that's leading you to feel this...
I know this is scary.
But a bone marrow
transplant could cure you.
A marrow transplant
could kill me.
The other option is
weekly blood transfusions,
injections of GCSF.
It's a lifelong regimen.
Yeah, I don't want that.
You sure?
I don't want to be cruel here,
but you've jumped through a lot
of hoops to get this sort of attention.
I just want to be healthy.
It's not so much fun
when you're actually sick.
No.
We'll check the registry.
See if there's a donor match.
Thank you.
We have to kill all the old bone
marrow before we give you the new stuff.
You'll have no immune system.
We'll keep you in a
sterile room for two weeks
to make sure everything's dead,
then we'll give you the donor marrow.
It'll take another couple
weeks until it takes hold.
You won't feel a thing.
If you get uncomfortable for any
reason and need to talk, don't yell.
Walls are four
inches thick, lead.
Use the microphone.
Are you ready?
Okay.
Where's Dr. House?
Turn it off!
Now what?
How long has she been in there?
Three minutes. What's going on?
She doesn't have
aplastic anemia.
She has an infection. No.
Her white count would be
through the roof. Hers is on the floor.
Well, body does crazy things.
"Body does crazy things."
That explains everything!
She had no fever.
'Cause her self-inflicted Cushing's
suppressed her immune system.
Stopped her from having
a fever, hid the infection.
Clostridium perfringens
could cause the bruises,
the schistocytes, the anemia.
Explains everything
except the white count.
Augmentin is a lot safer than
destroying her immune system.
Why don't we try that?
You're taking the safe
course? What's going on?
There's lots of explanations
for a low white count.
Name one that fits her case.
Colchicine.
I figure that she'd gotten her
hands on it and self-medicated.
That's brilliant of her.
Take the exact medication that
would confirm your diagnosis.
People do crazy things.
You injected her against her
will just so you could be right?
She consented.
She's mentally ill!
But she smells oh-so-sweet.
She would've gotten sicker when
I said she was gonna get sicker
except Cameron dosed
her with antibiotics.
Just hold this. Is
everything okay?
Pull my finger.
Grapey.
You have a bacterium.
It's on all of us.
But the bruises you gave yourself
with the Cushing's made a lovely home.
Bacteria moved in, parked
their cars on the lawn.
There goes the neighborhood.
By neighborhood, I
mean, your internal organs.
So, should we put her
on the Augmentin, boss?
Or do you think she
injected herself with grapes?
I love the smell of
pus in the morning.
Smells like... victory.
If you were serious about the
offer, I'm serious about accepting.
I'd like to run the department. And
you said it yourself, things run smooth.
Except for the part where
House went behind your back
and KO'd the patient
with insulin and colchicine.
There was no reason
to suspect an infection.
Even House didn't
think it was an infection.
You would have done
the same thing I did.
And I'd be just as wrong.
What House did was
insane. But he saved her life.
He got lucky.
He got her to admit
she's got a problem.
She's agreed to outpatient
treatment. He gets lucky a lot.
Did you ever really
intend to give me this job,
or were you just trying to
stop me from stepping down?
Well, you've got two
more weeks in charge.
Hopefully the next
case will go better.
She should've died.
House is not a hero.
A person who has the
guts to break a bad rule,
they're a hero.
House doesn't break
rules, he ignores them.
He's not Rosa Parks,
he's an anarchist.
All he stands for is the right for
everyone to grab whatever they want
whenever they want.
You tell doctors that's okay,
your mortality rate is
gonna go through the roof.
Kind of digging this whole
Foreman-in-charge thing.
Give me those.
Frees me up to watch my soaps,
catch a movie in the
afternoon, have lunch with you.
Yeah, that's a big
change for you.
Now Cuddy's on
Foreman's ass, not mine.
You couldn't live with
Foreman as your boss.
Why not?
People can change, you know.
Your white count is way down.
We're going to need to admit
you, just to run a few more tests.
Whatever you think is best.
Last race at Belmont.
Put it all on the five
to win.