Well, I'm glad you're thinking about it.
- Oh, no, just, uh, breakfast.
- We won't discuss it now,
but I am looking forward
to hearing where you are on my offer.
We're still having dinner tonight?
- Oh, I'll be there.
- Great.
SHELDON:
How are you?
He's meeting with everyone.
Everyone except me.
You have a contract.
He can't push you out.
I'm trying to talk to you
about what's going on.
[PAGER BEEPING]
It's Violet again.
- Grasshopper.
- Cooper.
COOPER:
Grasshopper!
[SIGHS]
You "grasshoppered" me, right?
Yeah, okay, it's the baby.
It's the baby? It's the bug? Okay.
- Now we're gonna breathe?
- Mm-hm.
We're gonna breathe now.
Hey, I know, I know, this is your case.
I am not hovering.
I just wanted to see how she's doing.
DELL: That's what we're gonna find out.
- This is it, Pete.
- It's happening.
- Not happening today.
No cervical dilation.
You're not in labor, Violet.
What? I am a doctor.
I know labor when I feel labor.
You know psychosis.
But labor, not so much.
- Uh, Addison?
- He's right, yeah. I gotta go.
- I gotta go prep another patient.
VIOLET: What? No, no, no!
This chicken is cooked.
This bug is ready to be served.
This baby boy has gotta get out of me.
I am a week overdue.
Violet. Violet, shh. Hey.
You just have to give him
a little more time.
He'll be here.
[THUDS]
The baby.
- Is he here?
PETE: It's a false alarm. Just...
Oh, I brought this. Kids love pigs.
That's really sweet, Sheldon.
I'm sure he's gonna love it.
I know.
[ZOE & AMELIA LAUGHING]
NAOMl: Well, you two are having fun.
- Hey.
Oh, we're just comparing notes.
Same checkup, same implantation,
same symptoms.
Well, Amelia, come on back.
We'll go over your CVS results.
Zoe, you'll be next.
Take your time.
I'm waiting on my husband.
Bye.
KATIE:
God, that feels good, whatever that is.
Good.
Good. Do it more.
- So you're feeling better?
- What do you mean?
Since your loss.
My loss?
The baby, the miscarriage.
Oh, that.
No, I'm fine. I'm doing great.
So, uh...
Dr. Turner's been helping you
through your grief?
Grief? What grief? There's no grief.
I mean, there was,
but there isn't anymore.
I just changed my way of thinking.
It's a celebration, really.
I made life.
I mean, yes, the baby died,
but that doesn't change the fact
that life was made,
- which is the real miracle. Making life.
- Oh.
I mean, labor's hard.
It hurts. And... And... And at least
I don't have to go through that.
Katie,
I'm really glad you're feeling better,
but recovery is an ongoing process,
and it's important for you
to remember to follow the regimen
that Dr. Turner and I laid out for you.
That means taking your medications.
Because with your history
of mental-health issues,
you don't wanna backslide
into delusions.
Look at me.
Dr. Wilder, I am smiling again.
- So he's fine?
- Yeah.
Oh, I keep calling it a "he" because of Vic.
He really wanted a boy.
You know,
someone to carry on the family name.
Not that he wouldn't have loved
a girl too.
- I like to think he's watching from heaven.
- Oh, he is.
This was your dream, all right?
This is what you and Vic wanted.
He'd want you to have this baby.
I'll be right back in one second, okay?
Just give me a minute.
What's up?
ADDISON:
Okay, that's it. Cerclage is out.
The hard part's over.
You can deliver anytime now.
Oh, dizzy.
Oh, that's, uh, probably
a mild stress reaction.
Just stay here for a couple hours
and rest until it subsides.
I'm gonna go back to the hospital,
check on some patients,
and I'll pick you up in a few hours,
okay?
Thanks for, um, for everything.
I saw that.
The way you looked at him,
the way he looked at you.
- Morgan...
- Are you sleeping with Noah?
Morgan just asked me point-blank
if I was sleeping with Noah.
I mean, I told her no.
I'm not. Because we're not.
- I'm barely in the same room...
- Addison.
- What? What? What?
I was just in with Amelia Sawyer,
and I started going over the CVS results.
And the baby tested positive
for the beta-thalassemia trait.
- It's just a marker.
- I know, but Amelia isn't a carrier.
And neither was her husband.
We screened.
And so I checked the IVF records
to see who else I implanted that day.
I implanted Zoe Salter that morning.
Zoe is a carrier for beta-thalassemia.
Oh, my God.
- How? How?
- I don't know how. I don't know.
But Amelia's embryo is inside of Zoe,
and Zoe's embryo is inside of Amelia.
They're carrying each other's baby.
- You switched them?
- This is a disaster.
Wait. Why assume it was my fault?
You're the one who delivers the syringes
for implantations.
You've been walking around unfocused,
not giving a damn.
But there are steps to the process, okay?
Multiple steps.
And in the end, Naomi injects them.
Now, I'm not saying it was you. I'm not.
I'm just saying, we don't know.
Hey, he's right. I am the doctor.
Ultimately, this is my responsibility.
But listen, we should be focused on these
women and... And not pointing fingers.
I cannot imagine what it feels like.
Hard enough to carry your own.
Imagine carrying somebody else's.
I suppose they could decide to terminate,
start over.
No, this is Amelia's last embryo
with her dead husband's sperm.
This is it. There are no do-overs.
ADDISON: This is a nightmare.
Lawsuits, our reputation.
I'm gonna call our lawyers,
start trying to do damage control.
- All right, I'll call Duncan.
- Duncan?
NAOMl: Yeah, medical malpractice
is his specialty.
- And he's someone we can trust.
- He's someone you can trust.
- I'll go ahead and call him.
- L... I said I'd call him.
As head of the practice,
the call should come from me.
I'll call him on the way to the hospital.
AMELIA:
This isn't my baby?
How can this not be my baby?
I know this is difficult to digest,
and I wish I didn't have to tell you this.
Words cannot convey how sorry I am.
There's no explanation I can offer you
that can excuse what's happened.
ZOE:
I can't believe this.
This isn't happening.
We've spent two years
trying to get pregnant, and now...
This isn't my baby?
You're telling me that this isn't...
This isn't my pregnancy?
I saw the waddler
walking into her office.
I'm assuming the grasshopper
was a false alarm.
L... l... I should have called you. I got caught
up with some patients, and, uh,
we've got some stuff going on here.
You'll make it up to me.
I need you to be my beard.
Oh.
William left again without talking to me,
but I found out where he's gonna be later.
I'll bump into him, start a conversation,
impress him.
Stalk him.
What do I ever ask from you, Coop?
Little slap, little tickle,
repeat as necessary.
I even let you live with another woman.
So you wanna make an issue of this,
or you wanna help me?
What time should I be there?
AMELIA:
Zoe.
It's you, isn't it?
You're carrying my baby.
Amelia,
maybe let's give Zoe some time.
I know this is awful, but at least it's you.
We can do it, right? We can do this?
I'll respect your wishes about the baby,
about everything.
And I'll trust you with mine.
Amelia, I ca...
I can't. We have other embryos stored.
We're gonna start over.
But that's my baby. You ca...
I don't have any other eggs.
- I'm carrying your baby.
- I don't want that.
We want you to fix this mistake.
What? You want me to kill the baby?
I can't do that. You can't do that.
Wait. Why don't we all
go back into my office?
- No, I just wanna go home.
AMELIA: Well, I want a lot of things.
Please, please. I won't do this.
I will not end this pregnancy.
And if you do anything to that baby,
I'm gonna have this baby,
and I'm gonna keep it.
Oh, hey, I saw Katie this morning.
I'm worried she's off her meds.
Katie? Oh, no,
she's been really compliant.
She's cheerful,
which is always a worry.
Not cheerful. She's euphoric.
She's talking about her miscarriage
with excitement.
Well, we have a session this afternoon,
and I'll talk to her about it then. Thanks.
- Pete.
- Sheldon.
She still hasn't given me an answer
to my proposal.
[SIGHS]
See, this is awkward between us.
- I like you. I do, Pete.
- Are you gonna propose to me?
[CHUCKLES]
You're funny. I bet she likes that.
I guess whichever way this turns out,
I'll know.
I'll know I tried.
We have done nothing wrong.
I mean, nothing biblical, anyway.
Well, there's coveting.
Okay, coveting.
But that's not the bad sin.
- There are no good sins.
- Are you religious?
Why are we talking about sin?
- You brought up the Bible.
- I did not.
It doesn't matter
who brought it up, okay?
Because we're both going to hell.
What?
[BOTH LAUGHING]
I feel guilty. I feel awful.
Which is why I should tell her.
No, this...
This will destroy her life.
But at least it'll be honest,
and she deserves the truth.
We could be together.
Think about that.
Okay?
Okay.
I covet you.
[BOTH LAUGHING]
I'm not the kind of guy who fights.
I just don't see the point to it.
The times I've tried it,
you hurt your knuckles.
You don't feel better.
It doesn't solve anything.
I guess I'm, at heart, just a pacifist
because I think fighting is stupid.
And I think war is wrong.
And taking up arms for some cause
just lacks nobility in today's world, so...
- Pete.
- I'm not the kind of guy who fights,
but I should have fought for you.
I should have fought for you, Violet.
And I don't really know
how else to say it,
except I want your kid.
Whether it's mine or not.
And I want your body,
whether it's pregnant or not.
And I want your heart,
whether I have to fight for it or not.
And I should have fought for it.
But I was confused and angry
and scared.
So I am fighting now.
Because I love you.
And I think we can be something.
I think we can be a family.
Well, I'm, uh...
Look, I'm fat and overdue
and tired and cranky and...
- Violet, l...
- No. No.
No, Pete, I'm sorry.
This is not what I want.
A year ago I was stalking a man
who wanted nothing to do with me,
and now I'm turning
two good men down.
Do I hate myself? Is it me? Is it?
Am I the problem?
Do you think you're the problem?
Oh, that's very therapeutic.
Making the patient answer
her own question. And now I'm avoiding it.
Okay, do you think one of them, Pete
or Sheldon, do you think that could work?
You have to answer that one.
- I don't know, Cooper.
KATIE: Dr. Turner.
Hi. No one was up front.
It's time for my appointment, right?
I think your focus needs to be
on damage control.
First, you want to mitigate
pain and suffering.
So approach each woman separately
about a settlement.
Offer to cover all medical expenses
and make a large lump-sum payment
in exchange for releasing all claims
and signing a confidentiality agreement.
You need to show these women
that someone has paid for the mistake.
[DUNCAN SIGHS]
You need to fire Dell.
No. No, no, Dell... Dell is like family.
And we don't even know
that this is his fault.
You wanna defend him, fine.
But I do not believe that this was you.
Dell is family. But if saving the practice
means cutting him loose, then...
Are you firing me?
No. But for now, you're behind a desk.
- Phones and mail only.
- But I have patients.
- I'm delivering Violet's baby.
NAOMl: Dell.
It's... It's just for now.
So I spoke with Dr. Wilder,
and, um, we have some concerns.
Is it a boy or a girl, your baby?
Katie, your medication
is a very important part
of managing your delusional disorder.
- It's important that you keep taking it.
- Does she kick much?
Katie?
I'm sorry. You were voicing your concerns,
and I wasn't answering.
Yes, yes, I am taking my meds.
I don't want things to go back
to the way they were, Dr. Turner.
It was crazy. I was crazy.
I'm taking my meds,
and I'm feeling great.
- Can I touch it?
- No, I don't think that's a good idea.
Oh, the baby's moving.
Oh, it's a smart baby. You can just tell.
Is it a boy or a girl?
PETE: You agree she's off her meds?
- Yeah, I think she's off her meds.
I think she's lying about it.
I don't have any proof.
I'd like to 5150 her.
I just... l... l... I think she's on the edge.
- I got a bad feeling.
- You can't commit someone on a feeling.
It creeped me out
the way she was looking at me.
Pete's right.
You can't commit someone on a feeling.
VIOLET:
What if the delusions are amping up again?
What if she's just happy?
- She's done grieving.
- I know happiness when I see it.
What?
You know happiness?
When it's offered to you?
Katie. We are talking about Katie.
She may just be happy.
She wasn't happy.
I know happy.
MORGAN:
Hi.
- Hey.
- I wanted to apologize for this morning.
Don't. No, uh...
You didn't do anything.
I thought...
Well, I thought I saw something.
But now I realize
I was just jumping to conclusions.
And, um,
you reassured me, and I trust you.
NOAH:
I went back to the birthing suite and...
- Can we talk a minute?
- Noah.
No, it's okay, Addison, um...
I insulted her this morning after you left.
I was feeling insecure about you,
and I insulted her.
I just hope she'll still deliver our baby.
You didn't do anything. Of course
I'm still going to deliver your baby.
- Addison.
- Family is the most important thing,
and nothing
should get in the way of that.
William, I am...
I am so flattered by the offer.
But something happened today,
a very serious medical error,
and my practice is under fire.
So I'm... I'm no longer a good candidate.
The measure of a person
is not the mistakes they make,
it's how they respond to them.
I want you.
I guess I'm just gonna have to sell you
a little harder.
WAITRESS: May I get you another drink
while you wait?
[SIGHS]
Noah was gonna leave his wife.
For me.
And I stopped him.
And I hate that I stopped him.
And I hate
myself for feeling that way.
[CHUCKLES]
Who would have thought
that you'd turn out to be the nice guy?
Not Violet.
Congratulations, mama,
on popping out that baby.
You did pop out that baby, right?
That's the only possible reason
I can fathom for Coop to have left me
sitting alone like a fool at a restaurant.
- Oh, Charlotte, I'm...
- I'm sorry. It was my fault. I was a wreck.
Clearly.
You and I need to talk.
Uh, l...
I can't talk about this,
I have a patient in crisis right now.
I can't have this conversation.
I'm sorry.
What's going on? Is there a problem?
The problem, Sam, is that your ex-wife
is trying to steal my job.
Amelia can't do it. Not yet.
So I'm gonna have her
talk to Violet instead.
DUNCAN: Trust me. It would be
much better if you would just...
ADDISON:
Naomi, we went over this.
I am not gonna force her to talk
to an attorney if she's not ready to do it.
Well, I think you should bring in
another attorney.
L... I'm not trying to put you in the middle,
I'll call you later.
[NAOMI SIGHS]
I hate this.
I hate being on opposite sides.
Yeah, well, you may hate it,
but your side always wins.
This isn't about winning, Naomi.
I've been offered Charlotte King's job.
- At Pacific Wellcare Center.
- What?
That's crazy.
I mean, you know that, right?
- I thought so at first.
- Right?
I thought so at first too. I did.
But Addison,
I'm floundering.
This whole year, just...
Losing the practice and Sam,
renting out the fourth floor.
I mean,
I'm trying to move forward. I am.
But I, uh... I haven't, not really.
And this offer, it's exciting.
Nai, you are my best friend.
And with everything going on, Addison,
me leaving
would show that you did something.
This is your practice.
Not anymore.
HEATHER:
Dell.
Where's Betsey?
- Tell me she's okay.
- She's fine.
She's, um...
She's at a motel with a friend.
That's it? You took my daughter
in the middle of the night.
And I had no idea where you were,
if she was okay, and you just dr...
You're high, aren't you?
St. Louis was bad.
I need money.
You think I'm gonna give you money
for drugs?
I don't need a lecture, okay?
I need 10,000 dollars.
You're insane. I mean,
even if I had that kind of money,
after everything you've done,
you think I'd give it to you?
If you give me the money,
[SIGHS]
I'll give you Betsey.
Maybe I'm not meant to be a mother.
Maybe I'm not meant to be happy.
I don't believe that's true.
I think everybody's meant to be happy.
Well, it's easy for you to say.
You're about to have a baby.
This isn't what you want.
I know that, Amelia.
But you could carry this child
and give it up
and then become a mother
another way.
Naomi's right. There are other ways.
My happiness, it's right here.
It's right in front of me.
I can't fathom letting it go.
Maybe you and Sheldon are right.
Maybe I don't know how to be happy.
- Violet.
- For a long time, I've been at baseline.
Just alive, breathing, heart beating.
"Happy" just seemed really far away.
And that was the best I could do.
[SOBS]
But I'm having a baby, Pete.
I am making a person,
which is a really optimistic thing to do.
I mean, that is really happy.
Which scares me a lot.
But the point is, the point...
- Violet.
- Maybe I don't know how to be happy.
But I wanna learn.
I wanna be happy, Pete.
And you so often make me happy.
So I know that I said no,
but if you are still willing to fight for me,
then I am willing to be fought for.
Except it wouldn't be much of a fight.
You'd win.
Be quiet.
I have to give Sheldon an answer.
I don't wanna have any secrets
anymore.
I'm gonna go home and sleep
because I have not been sleeping...
What did I say about being quiet?
Oh, I forgot to tell you that I love you.
I think it was my fault. Zoe and Amelia.
I checked the calendar,
and, uh, my lawyer called that day
to tell me that he couldn't find
Heather and Betsey.
And it was killing me and, uh...
What?
Heather's back.
She showed up strung out.
She'll give me my daughter
if I give her 10,000 dollars.
You can't buy your daughter.
I can't let her run with my child.
So then you come running to Naomi
after you blamed her for your mistake.
Sam, he apologized.
Of course he apologized.
He wants your money.
It's not your problem.
- I'm sorry I asked.
- Dell.
No, it's... I'm sorry I asked.
- What is wrong with you?
- No, what is wrong with you?
You do not buy children.
You don't help drug addicts
kill themselves.
And you do not take the fall for Dell
and then flee
to work for the enemy.
How could you not tell me?
- We were supposed to be partners here.
- Wait.
- You're the one who wanted distance.
- I said we couldn't be best friends.
- I didn't tell you to leave.
- You were right.
I mean, look at how you reacted
to Duncan yesterday, Sam.
That's... That's not business. That's you
not liking the fact that I'm dating Duncan.
- I don't like you dating him.
- You know, you don't get a say.
Why do you get a say?
We're not married, Sam.
- Why should it matter?
- Because I'm still in love with you.
Why? What? What do you...? What...?
What, is that supposed
to make me wanna stay,
or is that supposed
to make me wanna go?
God.
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
Hi, Katie. You okay?
I will be.
How did you get my address?
Oh, I'm sorry to bother you at home.
I know it crosses a boundary.
It's just, uh...
Well, I don't wanna lie to you.
You've helped me so much.
I needed to talk to you.
I needed to let you know that I know.
What? What is it?
You have my baby. And I want it back.
[VIOLET GASPS]
VIOLET:
Katie? Katie?
Yes, Dr. Turner?
- What was in the syringe?
- Doesn't matter what was in the syringe.
What matters is you can't move
from the neck down.
Did you know you can order drugs
from other countries
and have them delivered
right to your door?
The Internet is amazing.
Katie, we need to talk about this.
You've done a very dangerous thing,
so we should discuss your options.
I'm not listening to you anymore.
I'm getting my baby out of your body
and bringing him home where he belongs.
I don't...
What are you gonna do?
Cut him out of my body?
Oh, you're scared, I can tell.
But don't worry.
I read all about it on the Internet.
The Internet. It's amazing.
You can even order surgical supplies.
AMELIA:
Thank you for coming.
ZOE:
Martin didn't want me to,
but he doesn't know you. I do.
And I wanted you to know
that I'm not a monster.
I just...
This is my life, and I have dreams.
And I have one chance
to make them happen,
and I can't.
I can't turn what I've always wanted
into a nightmare.
For me, that baby inside you,
I thought that was my last chance.
Only, maybe it's not.
I want that baby.
But I can't make you carry him,
so maybe, maybe the reason this all
happened is that this
is my new chance.
You wanna carry your own child,
I understand.
But this baby,
I can't get rid of it.
I love him.
NAOMl: We all have dreams,
and sometimes they get complicated.
And so sometimes we have to stop
and let go of one dream
so that we can move forward
with another one.
[SIGHS]
I can't.
I can't let you keep my child.
I'm sorry.
CHARLOTTE: I know you're meeting
with other doctors.
And while Naomi Bennett
is an amazing fertility specialist,
her track record at running a practice...
- This is not about Dr. Bennett.
- You're right.
This is about whether or not
I can give you what you want.
If you wanna make this the next Mayo,
Cleveland, Palo Alto Clinic,
- I can do that.
- Really?
These are letters of intent
from Wilson Stafford,
Sanjay Finamore and Joy Hopkins.
Each one, the best in their field.
All it takes is your signature,
and I can have them working
for us tomorrow.
Well, I'll give this some thought.
Impressive speech.
Don't try and get in my good graces.
I'm sorry about last night,
and I know
I haven't been giving you enough.
But listen to this,
things are gonna change.
Violet is moving in with Pete.
Every time you had a choice,
you chose her.
Now she doesn't need you anymore.
Well, you know what?
Neither do I.
I'm sorry. I couldn't.
I just...
- She loves you. I couldn't...
- I understand.
I can't be this person,
you know, a person who does
this horrible thing to another woman.
- I know, I know.
- I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
Oh, we can't. We can't.
I love you.
If you want me to walk away,
I'll walk away. If you want me to stay...
Noah.
[PHONE BEEPING]
It's Morgan.
She's in labor.
[BOTH SIGH]
Katie, I know you can remember
what happened to your baby.
Try. Try and think.
My baby died.
That's what you want me to say, right?
That's the correct answer?
What do you think
the correct answer is?
My baby didn't die. Yours died.
So you took mine. You stole my baby.
But your baby was a girl.
Mine is a boy.
There's a boy in here.
I know it sounds crazy. I do.
But I'm not crazy. I'm a normal person.
I believe it's true. This is my baby.
And if I don't follow my instincts
and I let you take my baby...
Katie, Katie. Look at me, look at me.
I believe you.
That you think this is your baby.
But I think this is my baby too.
It has grown in me for months,
and I love this baby.
And I know you love this baby too.
So if you cut,
then the baby might get hurt.
And we both love this baby
too much to hurt it, right?
Yes.
Okay.
So let's not do this. Not right now.
It kicked.
- It's calling me.
- Katie.
- My baby's calling me.
- No, no. No.
Katie, if you would just wait...
- Can you...?
- No, no. I told you, I'm not crazy.
I know I can't wait.
I've attacked you in your home,
drugged you.
Think they'll give me my baby
after that?
- Katie!
- Shut up!
- I'm sorry. I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
- Katie. Katie, please, please, please.
Oh, God,
you'll be better once the baby's out.
Once the baby's out, I'll be gone, and you
won't have to worry about me anymore.
- I'll work fast.
- Katie, please.
Please. Katie!
Please.
NAOMI [ON TV]: Your family,
whatever that means, if you're single,
if you're married, if you have kids,
or if you want kids,
your family
should be the most important thing.
Your family is the most important...
- Dr. Bennett?
- Zoe.
I've been walking around thinking
about Amelia and about the baby,
and I can't let her keep my child.
Just the thought of it.
But maybe you're right
about moving forward,
and so I'm thinking
maybe I can carry Amelia's baby
- and she can carry mine.
- Okay.
- Okay, come on.
[CLEARS THROAT]
I'm upset with you, Dell,
for what you did,
for the position you put the practice in,
how you've been acting...
- Sam, just...
- Let me finish.
But I know that you've been hurting.
And I know that when you've lost
somebody that you love,
I know that you need to do
whatever it takes to get them back.
Ten thousand dollars.
Get your daughter back.
- Our baby's coming. He's really coming.
- How are you feeling?
Good. Everything's good,
right, Dr. Montgomery?
Uh, everything looks fine, yeah.
Let's just see how dilated you are.
WILLIAM:
This list, impressive.
Almost perfect.
But if you brought all these doctors here,
how long do you suppose they'd last?
Your staff doesn't like you, Charlotte.
You use them like pawns.
The best work is done
by people who are inspired,
who push themselves because
they wanna be part of something larger.
And you think that Naomi Bennett,
or anyone else,
is gonna be able to do that for you?
Plans I have for this practice
require someone with a heart,
Charlotte.
- Daddy.
- Hey. Hey.
- Where's the money, Dell?
You said you'd give me the money.
I need the money.
- Or you're not gonna see her again.
DELL: Come here, sweetheart. It's okay.
It's okay.
I have the money,
but I'm not giving it to you.
- And she's not going anywhere.
- You don't have custody. I do.
You're strung out, Heather. I can
pick up the phone and I can call DCFS.
I can call the police, and we can
have them come down here, you tell me.
I am not giving you this money
to let you kill yourself,
because I may hate you right now,
but I love her, and you're her mother,
and I'm not letting go of my daughter.
So come say goodbye to your daughter.
Come say goodbye to Betsey.
Come say goodbye.
HEATHER:
Hi, baby.
Uh...
[CRYING]
You're gonna have to stay with Daddy
for a little while, okay?
I love you.
- I'm gonna get her back.
BETSEY: Mommy.
Come here. Come here. Come here.
It's okay, it's okay, it's okay.
Violet isn't answering the phone.
She came down, I was with a patient,
but she left me a note.
She said it was important, you know,
and I got the sense that, uh...
Have you heard anything from her?
No. Not in the last few hours.
Well, it sounded like
she had an answer to my proposal.
I'm sure she'll call you back.
You know.
You know the answer.
You should talk to Violet.
Take good care of her.
Of them.
Okay, uh,
maybe I shouldn't have said
what I said about how I feel.
That's my issue. It's not yours,
and I can deal with it.
But this...
This is our practice.
We built it.
I can be okay with you moving on.
But not...
Not with you leaving.
- You are the heart of this place, Naomi.
- I took the job, Sam.
That's a cop-out.
I do not accept it.
It's what I have to do.
MORGAN: Oh, that was a strong one.
NOAH: You're doing great.
- You okay?
- Please don't. Just don't.
MORGAN [GROANING]:
Oh, okay, I should have asked for drugs.
Is it too late for drugs?
I'm sorry, uh, Morgan, it is.
MORGAN: Oh, here comes another one.
NOAH: Okay, okay.
MORGAN: Noah.
- You're doing great. You're doing fine.
MORGAN:
I can't believe we're finally getting to...
After the babies that died,
we're actually gonna be a family.
[MORGAN GROANING]
Hey.
Um,
Morgan Gellman's in the birthing suite.
I need you to go deliver her baby.
Oh.
- What about no patient con...?
- Just deliver the baby. I, uh...
I can't.
And, uh, I'll be here if you need anything,
- but I need you to go do this.
- Okay, okay, okay.
Hey, Betsey, I've got some work to do,
okay? But Addison's right here.
[PHONE RINGING]
- Hello?
- I need you, Cooper.
- Yeah, I just got to Violet's.
- I really need you.
I got fired.
Okay, I'll be right there.
[VIOLET WHIMPERING FAINTLY]
[VIOLET MUMBLING]
Shh.
- Cooper.
- He's gone.
- I'm gonna get started.
VIOLET:
Cooper.
KATIE:
Transverse incision.
[VIOLET WHIMPERING]
- Katie, Katie, Katie.
- What?
Don't cut there. It's too high.
You know no matter where I cut,
you won't survive, right?
I know.
It's for the baby.
If you cut there, you'll cut the baby.
I know, I'm a doctor.
I'm your doctor, Katie.
Tell me what to do.
Measure two fingers
above my pelvic bone.
Now what?
After...
After you get the baby out,
you cut that cord right away.
You cut it right away,
and you keep him warm.
And you make sure
to clear his mouth and his nose.
- You promise me you'll do that?
- I promise.
Tell me.
Make a clean slice on the horizontal.
You're gonna have to cut
through the muscle to get to the baby.
I just wanna say,
I think under different circumstances
we could have been friends.
Don't you think?
Yeah.
Friends.