Good morning.
I wouldn't go that far.
You're not allowed to be crabby.
You were off yesterday.
I got a call from Morgenstern
about Vennerbeck.
That M.I. that crumped?
Kayson claims I presented
the case incompetently.
Morgenstern wants me
in his office in an hour.
I want to throw up.
Yeah, well, Kayson's
just trying to cover his ass.
Morgenstern knows that.
Hey, maybe I'll get lucky
and Kayson will
fall in front of a bus.
Ix-nay on the ayson-kay.
Morning, Dr. Greene.
Morning.
Carol, have you seen Carter?
Took a D.B. to four.
Pathology's backed up.
Yeah, well, what else is new?
Oh, sorry.
Oh, sorry. Excuse me.
Dr. Benton?
Carter.
Carter!
What are you doing?
I'm sleeping.
Okay, well, you sleep
when I tell you to sleep.
Now, come on, get up.
I got a new student I
need you to break in. Yo!
Yo!
Come here.
What's your name?
Deb.
Yeah, right, well,
this is Carter.
He's going to show you around.
All right, she's all yours.
Uh, Dr. Benton, you're
not going up to the...
Yes, I am, and no, you can't.
I've got wall-to-wall surgeries
with a prima donna from Boston.
And the last thing I
need to do is baby-sit you.
Is he really dead?
Five bucks gets you
Super Lotto and Insta-pic.
Timmy?
Pass.
Carol? Oh, why not?
Morning, gang.
Timmy, what do we got?
Our specials for today
are suicidal junkie in four.
Going once...
I'll take it.
I could use a
little cheering up.
Hamster versus finger
in the suture room.
Ross took it.
HIV-positive kid with
a busted tooth in one.
Lots of blood.
What's an "L.L. Owie"?
That's a scissors
in the left leg.
It's a medical term.
Ubaldo's back, stinky as ever.
Oh, man.
He's drunk, possible seizure.
I could use a hand.
Double-glove time.
So, is this the perp?
His name is Royden B.
I thought you might want
to check him for rabies.
Oh, well, the only way
that Royden B. Could have rabies
is if he's been bitten
by a wild animal.
And given his lifestyle,
that's pretty unlikely.
The finger's infected.
It's probably because
Lucy's been sucking on it.
But we'll clean it up.
We'll give her some antibiotics,
and then your
daughter is going to be
good as new.
Niece.
Niece. Sorry.
There was a family resemblance.
You go to the fifth
street gym, don't you?
No, I've never been.
Mmm...
My mistake, but
you work out, though.
I can tell.
Excuse me.
Uh, well, you know,
um, I play a little
basketball now and then.
Bulls fan?
Yeah, I'm a Bulls fan.
I have a friend
who can get tickets, courtside.
That is, if you're interested.
You know, I have tickets
so maybe I'll just
see you there.
Care for a drink?
After you.
So you get away for the weekend?
Yeah, Tag and I rented a cottage
in Door County,
right on the lake.
Went ice fishing.
That was a highlight?
The one I can tell you about.
Have you guys set a date yet?
Why does everyone
keep asking me that?
I mean, what's the big rush?
Sorry I asked.
No, it's just I feel like I've
finally gotten my life in order
and now it's all
shaken up again.
You having doubts?
Well, it's a big step.
I mean, it's natural to
have some doubts, right?
Maybe it's the forever part.
You know, it's like infinity.
It's hard getting a handle...
What?
Oh.
Bye-bye.
That was more than an invitation
to a basketball game.
I know, I've been invited
to basketball games.
Yeah, so what?
So I want an explanation.
Mark, grow up.
Does this mean that you
and Linda are that serious?
Serious? Our longest
phone conversation is
"get over here."
Yeah, so, then, what
happened in there?
Hey.
Hey, I've been summoned.
Don't worry, it'll be fine.
I'm just curious how
you can turn down
practically guaranteed sex
with an undeniably
attractive woman.
If that's all there is,
I'd rather play tennis.
This is disappointing
coming from you.
Nine times I've been stuck
and never caught
so much as the flu.
I've been lucky so far.
This makes five for me.
Isn't the chance of getting HIV
from a needle stick
like one in a hundred?
One out of every 250
if the patient's infected.
Well, when Ubaldo wakes up
I'll try and get a
consent from him
so we can test him.
And I'll get his t-cell
count regardless.
Thanks, Lydia.
Says here, to be safe,
you shouldn't have
unprotected sex
until after the
follow-up in six months.
Thanks, Wendy.
Hi. I'm Dr. Greene.
Serena. U.S. Customs Service.
Yeah, we're going this way.
What's the problem?
We picked him up at O'Hare
coming in from La Paz.
Source I.D.'d him
as a body packer.
He's got half a kilo of cocaine
in his belly wrapped in condoms.
Here. Sit right here.
Sientese.
What's your name?
Jorge. He doesn't speak English.
He's been retaining the
evidence, so to speak,
since we picked him
up eight days ago.
Eight days?
That sounds like one for the
Guinness Book of Records.
Well, you can't
blame him for trying
He's facing 20 years.
No obvious signs of toxicity.
The condom must still be intact.
If you can give him a laxative
it'd make my job easier.
Uh, I can't give
him any medication
without his consent.
Can I borrow a pen?
We'll work him up, x-ray him,
hope that nature
takes its course
before a condom breaks.
Jorge, si un condom
con coca romper
uh, sera muy mal.
Uh, tu voy, a morir muy rapido.
Entiendo?
Si.
Where'd you learn Spanish?
Here.
We work Benton's hours, sleep
when he sleeps, which
is practically never.
We've been on call
since yesterday morning
and he hasn't even sat down yet.
This is one of four I.V. carts.
Most patients get an I.V.
the second they
come through the door.
Angio cath, 16-needle
large bore, if they're bleeding.
You know how to
start an I.V., right?
Yeah. Oh, actually, no.
I thought you were third year?
Carter, we got a
body packer in four.
Work him up... K.U.B.,
drug screen, urinalysis.
Ever do a urinalysis?
Uh-uh.
Carter? Yeah?
Do a rectal.
This is your lucky day.
Can you ventilate him?
Yeah, as long as I get a seal.
I'm going to get...
What do we got?
Came in with
respiratory distress.
We were taking vitals
when he crashed.
Went from bradycardic
at 35 to flat line.
Temp's 104, blood culture sent.
Sounds like septic shock.
Let's give him an amp
of epi, a meg of atropine
and 1.5. of each
erythro and cefataxime.
What's going on?
Are you his father?
Yes.
We're giving him drugs
to stimulate his heart.
Epi and atopine on four.
Here's the epi.
Any heart sounds? Negative.
All right, let's piggyback
an isuprel drip.
This ever happened before?
Once, when he was
hospitalized for pneumonia.
Cerebral palsy?
No, he's brain damaged.
Got a pulse.
All right, heart is back.
He's in v-tach.
What the hell?
All right, hold the isuprel
now and give him Lidocaine.
50 Milligrams I.V. push.
What's happening?
His heart is racing.
Why?
I don't know.
Let's get the 12-lead in there.
I need to see what's going on.
Move that. Mm-hmm. Move it.
Stop the...
I tried to convince Kayson
that this kind of
finger-pointing
runs contrary to the spirit
of a teaching hospital.
Juice?
No, thank you.
He failed to see my point.
He's bringing disciplinary
charges against you.
What does that mean exactly?
You'll come before the
committee next week,
defend yourself, we'll
make a determination,
and steps will be
taken accordingly.
Dr. Morgenstern,
I want you to know
that I tried to present
Mr. Vennerbeck's history.
Dr. Kayson cut me off Susan...
and ordered him
released. Susan...
the specifics don't concern me
nearly as much as your
inability to assert yourself.
Excuse me?
You allowed Kayson
to intimidate you...
Not the first time.
I seem to recall a similar
incident with Benton
about a retrocecal appendix.
I was right about that.
But you deferred to
Benton's judgment.
That's my point.
You seem to lack the authority
to put forward
your own opinions,
to act as an aggressive
advocate for your patients.
I guess...
I have to work on that.
Yes, you do.
Confidence...
composure under pressure,
assertiveness.
These are the
requisite qualities
of a good E.R. Specialist.
I'm willing to give you the
chance to develop them.
If you don't, we're going
to have a future discussion
about which specialty might
best match your temperament.
Peaked t-waves, unstable rhythm.
Got to be his potassium, right?
Are his lytes back?
Not yet. Can't wait.
All right, let's give him
Calcium gluconate, 15 mils.
It could kill him.
Just do it.
Asystole.
All right, repeat
epi and atropine.
Doctor?
Sir, it looks like
your son's
potassium is too high,
probably from renal failure.
We're going to do everything
we can to bring it down.
I think I got a pulse...
Weak, but it's there.
B.P.'s 35 palp.
I'll take it.
His lytes are back.
Potassium's high... 7.5.
All right, we're
on the right track.
Stand by with
glucose and insulin.
Is he going to live?
It looks like he's
going to make it.
Carol, I heard you
got stuck again.
What is it, number four?
Count 'em.
Five. Wow, I've only got three.
Timmy, why don't you put me down
for emptying the
sharps containers.
I need to catch up.
Don't tempt the fates.
So you and Tag set a date yet?
Not yet.
Hey, how did it go?
How'd it go?
Well, it's... it's
hard to describe.
Timmy, where's
Petrofsky's chart?
Why, what happened?
You know, if I
told you right now,
I think I'd lose it.
Go down to exam two.
And you live at the
Marymount home?
For the emotionally disabled.
That's what society
has labeled me.
Timmy, what's open?
Trauma room.
Everything else is full.
Thanks.
When did this
shortness of breath start?
About a month ago, but
this week it got worse.
Are you on any medications?
Uh, yes. This is
my medical binder.
I've kept it since I was 14.
Medications are in orange...
Well, actually it'd be
more of a pumpkin.
And you take lithium,
depakote and synthroid.
Yes, I've taken these.
Um, my allergy section,
these pages are mauve,
vaccinations are gray,
doctors' names and
numbers are plum,
and past medical records
are in various shades of red
from vermillion to puce.
Very colorful.
Thank you.
And you're dressed all in blue.
Yes. It's Monday.
Ah.
Come on in, Alan.
I can't.
Why not?
It's green.
Is that bad?
Very.
He asleep?
Yeah.
I went and got a
few of his things.
Ben's pretty sick, Mr. Gaither.
He's got a bad case of pneumonia
which caused his heart
problems earlier today.
Hopefully, the antibiotics
will turn him around.
The last time, the doctors
put him on a ventilator.
Well, we may have to do that
if his blood gases
don't improve.
When will you know?
We'll check in an hour or so.
He likes rhythm.
You know, before the accident,
he was taking trumpet lessons.
Used the metronome to practice.
I don't think he remembers.
The kid had a hell of a bat.
Now if that picture isn't
there when he wakes up,
he gets his look.
What happened?
He's riding his bike to school
and this 85-year-old man
waves Ben across the street
then gets confused between
the brake and the accelerator.
Look, I got a job interview.
You got kids?
I have a son.
How old?
He's eight.
That's a nice age.
Okay, Deb, as we say
around here, quite often,
glove up and dig in.
Carter, isn't that your job?
Deb's got to learn.
Um, exactly what
am I looking for?
Ah, obstructions, masses,
anything out of the ordinary.
But I don't have
anything to compare it to.
Mm-hmm. You will soon.
Um, Mr. Jorge, could you
turn on your side, please?
A tu lado.
Thank you.
Ai!
I'm sorry.
Everything okay?
Well, he seems
a little... tense.
Show him who's boss.
Sorry.
Ai, Santa Maria!
Ayudame, por favor!
How's it going in there, Deb?
Um... I'm stuck.
Deb?
Yes?
Did you use any lubricant?
Was I supposed to?
Breathe.
Fever's 101.
Have any of your
doctors ever told you
you have a heart murmur?
Uh, I don't think so.
I could check my book though.
Have you had a cough lately?
Yes.
Loose cough? Bringing up sputum?
What color?
Well, sort of a sulphur
yellow with saffron mixed in.
Kind of like these tiles here,
but more of a yellow...
these are more of a
yellow-beige, I do suppose.
Alan's into colors.
I see.
Alan, I want to run some
tests, do a chest X ray.
All right.
Did you have red
hair as a child?
No.
I thought I saw a touch
of russet in your hair.
It was probably
ketchup from lunch.
Zeidenberg's going
to a lecture series
in Detroit all next week.
You want to cover for him?
Sure.
You have to take over
all the scheduling...
Risk management
B.S., shift reports.
No problem; it'll
be good training
for when I'm chief
surgical resident.
That's what I like
about you, Peter...
Naked ambition
tempered by arrogance.
Dr. Benton, you have
an emergency phone call.
Your brother-in-law.
Telling him I'm
scrubbing in for surgery.
He said your mother's missing.
Go. I'll get
Schneider to scrub in.
Peter, go. It's your mother.
Okay, I'll, uh... I'll be
back this afternoon
in time for the pheo.
Uh, hold on.
Dr. Lewis, you took care
of Miss Callahan who
went up to O.B., right?
Mm-hmm.
Dr. Bernardi, upstairs, for you.
Her chart still around?
Yeah, um...
Yeah, this is Dr. Lewis.
Uh, yeah, we gave her...
Thanks.
Magnesium sulfate,
a six gram bolus
right before we sent her to you.
Uh-huh.
Yeah, no problem.
Hey, Timmy, any idea
why Mark signed this chart?
Uh-uh.
Where's Greene?
Exam room four.
Ah, there must be at least
a hundred of them in there.
Are they moving along?
Not really.
Well, how long is
this going to take?
Well, you're going to
have to ask Jorge that.
Why are you
co-signing all my charts?
Excuse me.
Every chart I worked on today
has your signature on it. Why?
Morgenstern told me to.
You think I'm incompetent?
You think you need to
oversee every decision I make?
No, of course not.
Did you tell Morgenstern that?
Well, he didn't ask my opinion.
He just told me to do it.
Why didn't you stand up for me?
You seem to forget that
a patient died, Susan.
Your patient.
I know it could have
happened to any of us,
but it happened to you.
And now there's a lawsuit,
and an inquiry, and
because I'm chief resident
it becomes my problem, too.
So, if Morgenstern wants
me to co-sign your charts
I'm going to do it.
You knew what he was
going to say to me today,
didn't you?
Yes.
You talked about me.
I have conversations
with Morgenstern
about every resident down here.
What'd you say?
I told him Kayson gives
you a hard time. And...?
And the way he rides you,
it's no wonder this happened.
And...? And when you go
head-to-head with
strong-willed guys
like Benton and Kayson
you tend to back down.
Son of a bitch.
Hey, Ben. How are you?
I got it.
Dr. Ross?
Hey, Wendy, look who's up.
O-2 sats' falling.
To be safe, let's get
him on a ventilator.
You better look at this.
"Do not resuscitate"?
His father did this?
Mm-hmm.
Wendy, give Mr. Menkens
350 milligrams a minute
of dopamine.
Uh, I think you
mean "micrograms."
That's what I said, isn't it?
No.
Oh.
Have Ubaldo's
t-cells come back yet?
Not yet. Lab's backed up.
Get this little smidge
out of my face.
What's wrong with him?
Who cares?
Uh, Carol, can you
get a chart going?
Sure.
What did you do to her?
Questioned her
sexual orientation.
Oh, well, that's rude.
No malice intended.
Did she do this?
Uh-uh. Newsstand
guy on Rush street.
What did you say to him?
A few derogatory comments
about his Middle
Eastern heritage.
It didn't take much.
Do you have any other
injuries anywhere else?
I think I've got a cracked rib.
Yeah? Newsstand guy?
Florist in Wicker Park,
sensitive about his hair weave.
Malik, why don't you
give me a hand here.
We'll take him to
the suture room.
What do you do?
You go around the
city insulting people
until they hit you?
Uh-huh. I'm a sociologist
at the University of Chicago
specializing in violence.
I select a subject
ask two questions to
probe for insecurities,
then use the information
to antagonize them
until they assault me.
Sounds like dangerous work.
Tell me about it.
My insurance company
charges me the same premiums
as NASCAR drivers.
We'll be moving him
to intensive care soon.
I see that you've
made a decision.
Mr. Gaither,
Ben's blood gases are not good.
He's not getting enough oxygen.
If he's not put on a
ventilator, he could die.
When?
It's difficult to say.
It could be a matter of hours.
With the proper care,
he could live a long time.
Are...
Are you sure that
you want to give up?
I can't believe Mrs. Lookee.
That woman shouldn't
have taken my money
if she was too
senile to do the job.
Myatt kid saw someone, it
could have been your mom,
down here at the corner.
I can't believe she
waited two hours to call us.
She didn't call
us, she called me.
I mean, she made
me look like an idiot...
Look, look, Peter, I left a station
full of cars needing service.
All of this because you insisted
on hiring some old woman
to take care of your mom
instead of putting
her in a home.
She's not going in a home.
Oh, like hell she isn't.
Wh-whoa, don't go
telling me what to do.
Look, I'm telling you, man,
I'm not letting you
put me and your sister
through this anymore.
Now, I'm sorry if it
makes you feel sad
but there's no other choice.
She's my mother, so who are you
to tell me how to handle this?
I'm the man who's paid
for her food, her clothes
and her care, for
the last six years.
And-and she let you
live in her house...
Yeah, who pays
the damn mortgage?
Who pays the bills?
You don't get
anything out of it, huh?
How many high school
student dropouts do you know
have a $100,000 business
just dropped in their lap?
High school dropout.
I cared for your
family for six years.
I carried your
I'm responsible for
your mother, your sister
the house and the station.
The only one that Peter
is responsible for is Peter.
I'm going to look
by the firehouse.
Okay, Mr. Desmond,
I'm going to clean
your abrasions.
We will start with your wrist.
It may sting a little.
That's a big engagement ring.
Isn't it?
Kind of ostentatious,
don't you think?
No, I-I don't.
Can I ask two questions?
All right.
Excuse me.
What does your fiancé do?
He's a doctor.
So, you're going
to be a doctor's wife.
When's the date?
We haven't set one yet.
Why not?
Your two questions are up.
What's the matter?
Somebody can't commit?
Based on the ring,
I don't think it's
him, so... what is it?
Think you're too good for him.
Scared of spending
the rest of your life
with someone who doesn't
quite meet your standards.
Got a pretty high opinion of
yourself, don't you, princess?
"Sure, I'll marry you.
Just don't tie me down
to anything
definite like a date."
That stings. Really?
Yes, it does.
Oh, God!
21-second P.A.I.
Puts you in the top
percentile in the hostility index.
P.A.I. is...?
Provocation-to-assault interval.
You're good.
My God, you're good.
John, what's this?
It's a laryngoscope.
No, no, second
shelf from the top.
Hey, can you teach
me how these work?
Some other time.
Carter...
we need this crash cart in four.
Body packer popped a condom.
Got it? Let's go.
Out of the way.
Give me some room, huh?
Here you go.
Stay here and try
not to get in the way.
Can't you cut him open
and pull out the coke?
We got to stabilize him first.
We got a multi-focal P.V.C.'s.
Yeah, okay, Lidocaine,
150, I.V. push.
He's in fib. Paddles.
Oh, my God!
What was that set on?
Two hundred.
Oh, he should be okay.
Okay... thank you.
Why don't you
check on him, okay?
All right, clear. Clear.
Oh, that's not good.
Let's go again.
Three hundred.
No, no, por favor.
Clear.
Normal signs.
Let's take him upstairs.
Notify the O.R.
Let them know they
got a laparotomy.
We got to get these
condoms out of him.
Don't worry, honey,
he just bumped his head.
Alan, the guy with the colors?
His films came back. Radiology
had a bunch of them
from a few years ago, too.
Susan?
I could stay in
this room all day.
It's warm like flannel.
I wish I could wear it.
Alan, when you gave me your
medical history this morning
you didn't tell me
you had cancer.
What's nice about
this room is that...
it's not... it's not too bright.
When yellow's too
bright, it's not welcoming.
Alan,
you have a tumor in your chest
encasing your heart
and infiltrating your lungs.
On the other hand,
if yellow is too pale, it
feels cold and... and clammy.
There are treatments, Alan.
Chemotherapy, radiation...
Dr. Lewis and I think you
should see an oncologist.
I'll tell you one thing,
whoever made this room
sure knew his yellow.
Could I be alone, please?
Sure.
Oh, that's good.
Look out, look out!
Yeah, I'm all right.
Ma...
Ma, what are you doing up here?
Who is that?
Peter?
Yeah, Ma, it's me.
Aren't you supposed
to be in school?
Ma, I work at a
hospital, remember?
I'm a doctor.
I know that.
Why do I feel I don't
get a chance to see you?
Well, because they
keep us pretty busy.
But we see each other
sometimes, don't we?
So serious.
I remember you sitting
in that green chair
by the window
reading your books.
So serious.
You know, Ma, um...
with Jackie at work all day
and the kids at school,
we worry about you being alone.
Oh, I don't like it
that way, either.
I like a full house.
Well, that's why we...
we were thinking maybe...
well, maybe you'd be happier
in a place where there...
you know, there's...
with other people your age,
people that could
take care of you.
I used to bring Jackie
to take skating
lessons right here.
And your father and I
watched you in the...
in the Little League
right on this field.
Remember?
Yeah, I remember.
Your father's dead.
Yeah...
yeah, he's dead.
Uh... Peter...
I don't want to go
into a nursing home.
All right... all right.
Shh.
It's all right. It's all right.
Spin a crit,
type and cross-match four units
and get some O-negative
down here now!
Man, you got to do something.
Out of the way!
She didn't do nothing.
Out of the way.
Stay here.
We're going to take care of her.
Somebody call radiology.
Set up a two blood lyte.
B.P.'s 40 palp.
Someone call a surgeon.
I see the entrance.
Who sees the exit?
Here on her back.
Cop said
it was a drive-by;
she was a bystander.
Yeah, her brother's a banger.
Look at his clothes.
What have we got?
Gunshot to the chest.
Looks like it's
through and through.
She's hyper-resident.
Tracheal shift
to the left.
She needs a chest tube.
I'll do it.
Okay.
I.V. is flowing.
Yeah... heart sounds funky.
Let's get a
cardiologist down here.
Damn it, where's
all this coming from?
Pressure's crashing.
She's taching. Bullet must
have tumbled into the heart.
Okay, let's crack her.
Clamp the bleeder.
Thoracotomy tray!
I'll do it.
Okay.
What's the problem?
We have bleeder.
It sounded like a murmur.
Better open her quick.
Give her O-neg; wide open.
Damn it!
I need suction.
I can't visualize
the lungs.
Six and a half? Yeah.
Hurry up!
How about now?
I can't see the pleura.
Her cut's not deep enough.
Susan?
Yes, the cut is deep enough.
I... I just can't see anything.
Okay, calm down. You'll get it.
She's bleeding out.
She's going to make it...
How much longer are
you going let her do this?
Susan? More suction.
We're losing her.
She can't do it.
Damn it, I can't see
anything. You try.
Scalpel.
Okay, I'm in.
Yeah, I see the bleeder.
Pulmonary artery. Clamp.
Stabinsky.
Got it. Let's get her to O.R.
Good job, Dr. Greene.
Okay, let's go.
Peter, we've got
a possible appendectomy in six.
All right, call the floor...
See who else is on.
I'm late for a pheo.
You got his picture in there?
It's in there.
How about the
metronome? He likes that.
It's there. We can take
him from here, Dr. Ross.
It's okay. I'm going
to take him up.
I didn't know you had a son.
Well, we're not exactly close.
What's his name?
I don't know, Wendy.
I've never seen him. Here we go.
Watch yourself.
Mm-hmm.
The DNR sticker's on there.
Thanks.
Are we doing an anterior
abdominal approach
or are we excising
the adrenal laterally?
Whoa, Peter there's
no need to scrub in.
I couldn't wait, so
I asked Schneider
to assist Dr. Kenner and me.
Hey, Peter, how's it going?
Do you take the Eisenhower in?
Uh-huh.
Did you notice that piano
showroom near Halsted?
Yeah. I got my wife's
harpsichord there.
Wait. You've been inside?
Oh, Yeah.
They've got a Steinway
collection in there
that would knock your socks off.
How long ago did
you notice this place?
Two years ago. Two years ago?
Where is he?
We took Ben up
to intensive care.
Intensive care.
They're aware of your
decision. You okay?
Yeah.
I just got offered a job
managing a recycling
plant in Detroit.
I got to pick up and move.
Coming back, I just
couldn't help thinking
how much easier it
would be if Ben were dead.
What kind of a
man thinks like that?
What kind of a father
prays for his own boy to die?
And for two years, it's
been just me and Ben.
There's been no work...
no friends...
nobody.
He needs me 24 hours a
day to turn him and feed him...
and sing to him when he cries.
I love my boy.
I've given Ben two years...
two years.
I just can't give anymore.
I need for this to end.
To end... oh, God...
Mmm.
Well, well, look who's back.
Oh, my head.
You took quite a fall,
Carter, but don't worry,
Deb's been taking care of you.
She worked you up real good.
"Blood pressure 90/60.
"Respiration...
'guiac negative stool."
"'Guiac negative stool?"
You gave me a rectal?
Well, Haleh thought it
would be good practice.
Good practice? Good practice?
Oh, now, settle down, Carter.
She has to learn, doesn't she?
Oh, Deb, another thing: Mmm?
The proper term isn't
"average" male genitalia.
It's "normal" male genitalia.
What? Where does it say that?
Oh, you guys are just kidding?
So you didn't...?
Uh-uh.
You didn't...?
Told you we'd get him.
Um... uh...
Do you know where
you are, Mr. Parnell?
Yeah. In the chump cellar.
Three knockout
losses in a row. Damn!
And I had him
against the ropes too...
before I stepped
into that cross.
I thought you might like
some company, Mr. Desmond.
This is Mr. Parnell.
Hello.
What happened to you?
Don't want to talk about it.
Huh.
Can I ask you two questions?
I should have warned
you about Morgenstern,
and I should have
been more up front
about the co-signing business.
I didn't know how to tell you.
Susan, no one could
have done that thoracotomy
under the circumstances,
with Kayson breathing
down your neck
and the hearing next week...
Are you trying to
make me feel better?
I'm trying to apologize.
So you can feel better yourself?
Some of us are going to
Doc Magoo's after work.
If you want to come...
Alan?
You know, my buddy, Max,
moved out of the
home last summer,
got an apartment.
Been trying to get
me to split the rent.
Problem is, the bathroom.
Celadon green.
I asked him to retile.
Now I'm thinking...
what the hell?
Sometimes you got to
take the plunge, you know?
Well, you don't want
to forget your book.
There's a section missing.
Guess which color?
Green.
If you're trying to get
those wheels to go...
Lydia, you going to Magoo's?
I'll be over in a few minutes.
Anyone seen Carol?
Oh, just went upstairs.
I'll let her know.
Try and see if you
can get Susan to come.
What a day.
Yeah.
That answers your two questions.
And, Lydia, somebody should
probably check on Mr. Desmond.
I don't care.
I am not drinking
anything with a worm in it.
Who's got the tequila?
All right, give me
your glass, Dr. Ross.
Onion rings, extra
greasy? Right here.
Ooh, thanks, Timmy.
No, no, no, no.
You have to sit at the
counter with what's-her-name.
I'm not kidding.
They just announced
the $40 million jackpot
went to a dry
cleaner in Winnetka.
Aw, man. I was counting
on that money too.
You didn't even kick in.
You get a second
chance with the Insta-pic.
You just rub the spot.
Did you hear about Carter's
unscheduled electroshock?
I'm sorry I missed
it. Guess how many
condoms he had in his belly?
How many? 50?
A hundred and eighty-five.
And he lived?
Hey, B.
I got your double burger,
double cheese right here.
Keep your
lard-burgers to yourself.
All right, everybody, Listen up.
Carol has an
announcement to make.
Oh, it's no big deal.
Just keep May 18th open.
That's when Tag and I
are getting married.
All right.
Whoo!
Susan coming? Couldn't find her.
Lydia, it's for Carol.
What's this? Your lotto ticket.
Dr. Benton,
how's your mother? She's fine.
How was your rectal?
Hey, I won ten bucks.
Oh, great, you can
pick up the check.
What are the odds?
How can you tell?
Just flip it over.
Let me get a fruit plate.
Let's see.
$10 win... one in 250.
Sounds familiar.
Ah, don't even think about it.
What are the odds
you're going to win $10
set a wedding date
and get HIV on the same day?
You got yogurt?
A bran muffin?
Okay, hey, everybody, I
want to propose a toast.
To Carol.
Shh. What's he doing?
May your upcoming marriage
bring you laughter and happiness
and kids, and most of all, love.
God knows, you
deserve all of those things.
Hear, hear!
Cheers.
Congratulations, girl.
Thank you. To Carol.
Long time have to wait.
Where's the stripper?
I had a May wedding.
What month did you divorce?
Hey, B,
look like you put
on some weight.
I wouldn't say that
and smile, brother.
Lydia and I also have
an announcement.
We got married...
So...?
Captioning sponsored
by Warner Bros.