Carter.
Oh, man, somebody
get a drool bucket.
Carter... Where?
Up, up, up! Let's go.
Where's your pager?
I've been beeping
you for five minutes.
It's right... It's right here.
You take this, and you
keep it on your pillow.
That way, you don't
sleep though a page.
Now, come on. Let's go.
You've got patients to see.
Carter, let's go! Come on!
We've got an unwashed
and undomiciled male
with a laceration
to the forehead in 2.
Clean the wound, and
stitch him if need be.
Whatever you do, please,
don't take off his shoes or socks.
God knows what you'll find.
Heads up! Coming through.
This way, this way,
this way. Come on.
When you finish with him,
see the little old lady
with leg pain in 6. Got it?
Yeah. You ever get used to this?
Used to what?
Going on three hours' sleep.
Anything more than three
hours, and I'm sluggish all day.
Chart's right there.
Mark, how was the big day off?
First two hours was great.
Then Rachel and Jen
left for Detroit for five days.
What's that all about?
Job interview. Oh, really?
Don't even start.
Morning, guys.
Susan, can you
work Thursday night?
I am on Thursday night.
It's tough.
Wife so far away,
and other more immediate
temptations so close.
You haven't the faintest idea
what you're talking about.
I know exactly what
I'm talking about.
Doug, I need you in 3.
And good morning to
you, Nurse Hathaway.
Good morning.
No, the price breaks
on the photocopiers
start with five-unit orders.
Be off in a jiff.
Tell you what, Sam.
If you're free to sit down this
afternoon, say around 3:00,
I'd like to lay out a package
that covers your phone,
fax and e-mail needs as well.
All right, tomorrow then.
Sam, have I told you
about our all-inclusive
five-year service plan?
Okay, in broad strokes,
We guarantee every
pinion, spindle, sprocket,
for the life of the machine,
including unlimited service
for the first five years.
It started last week.
People would speak to Ozzie,
but he wouldn't respond.
I thought maybe
something was
wrong with his hearing.
Ozzie, can you hear me?
You wouldn't stick things
in your ears, would you?
That's good, because
my mom told me
that you never put
anything in your ears
smaller than your elbow.
Ozzie, can you
hear me whispering?
Okay. Yes.
Okay, I'll tell you,
Mrs. Schap, um...
there's no sign of
infection, and no injury,
and, right now, Ozzie's
hearing seems to be fine.
Yeah. That's
what's so frustrating.
He does hear some things,
but he doesn't hear others.
What are some of the
things that he doesn't hear?
Hmm... like my
mother's voice, for one.
She says really
terrible, terrible things.
She thinks that
I'm a bad mother.
And your mother lives with you?
No, no, no, no,
no, no. She's dead.
Uh... but you still hear her?
Mm-hmm.
What are some
of the other voices
that Ozzie can't hear?
My ex-husband's,
the ice cream man's,
Diana...
Diana?
The Princess of Wales!
Does that ring a bell?!
Can you excuse
us just for a second?
Call Psych Services.
Tell them we need a consult.
Get Social Services
down here for the boy.
Leave the door open
until he gets here.
Hey. Doctor...
Yeah. What's up, kiddo?
Me and my mom...
we can stay together, right?
You bet you can.
Did you leave the money there?
Oh, that was...
That's what you sound like!
Patient is experiencing
severe pain
in the right lower extremity.
Recent history
includes colon cancer,
as well as a
four-hour plane flight.
Upon examination, patient's
calf was found to be tender
as well as four centimeters
larger than the unaffected side.
Differential diagnoses
include cellulitis injury,
hematoma, Baker's cyst,
and deep vein thrombosis.
Okay, so what would you do?
I suggest a CBC, Chem seven,
coag study and a
duplex scan of the leg.
All right. Bye, now.
In addition, given
that two elements
of Virchow's Triad are present,
I feel that a
venogram is indicated
if the scan is inconclusive.
Proceed.
So you concur with
my recommendations?
I said, proceed.
Mr. Madsen gets a GI cocktail,
and check with Urology.
Can I get some help, please?
We need a doctor.
Malik, get a wheelchair.
She came in with chest pains.
Hi. I'm Dr. Greene. Can
you show me where it hurts?
My heart.
Have you had heart
problems before?
She had two heart attacks
before they put that
machine in her chest.
A pacemaker?
No. A defibrillator.
Okay, well, just relax.
I want a 12-lead,
CBC, Chem seven,
cardiac enzymes
and a coag profile.
What's your name, ma'am?
Vilma.
Okay, Vilma, you just relax,
and we're going
to take care of you.
Sir, sir... I need you
to go with the nurse
and go to the waiting room.
I'll come talk to you as
soon as I can, all right?
What the hell is
Virchow's Triad anyway?
That sounds like a
board exam question.
One that I'd skip.
Jerry, do me a favor.
Bring the fan over here.
I'm burning up.
Word on the vine is
that you and Langworthy
both put in for the
Starzl Fellowship.
Yeah? Well, that's
no big surprise.
She's a year ahead
of you. So what?
So, heads up. Here
comes the competition.
You get the results on bed four?
Not yet.
Sarah...
what's Virchow's Triad?
Stasis, trauma and
hypercoagulability.
And, Jerry, get
this fan out of here.
It's blowing right in my face.
Dr. B. Wanted it there.
Code 3 scoop and run...
Auto versus pedestrian...
Just pulled up.
I'll take it.
Come on, Peter. You can assist.
Come on! Step on it! Step on it!
Hit-and-run victim,
approximately 17.
Found him lying in a
crosswalk, in full arrest.
Vitals?
Negative.
Pupils are blown.
How long was he lying there?
Who knows? No one saw him.
Get five units of
O-neg to Trauma 1.
Come on, grab that I.V., Peter.
Step on it, people.
Let us through.
We need more blood,
and give an amp of EPI.
Any heart sounds? Negative.
18 minutes. Time?
X ray?
Wait! Aprons!
People, move it!
Protect your gonads, Peter.
I always do when
you're around, Sarah.
Let's move, people.
Come on, move it! Move it!
Fire in the hole.
Come on.
Move it, people.
What's going on?
Kid was D.O.A.
They're trying to
bring him back.
His tube is loose.
Carter, get over here
and hold his E.T. tube.
His left side is full of blood.
Autotransfuser.
Let me in.
Give me some help.
Come on, give me some help.
Come on, come on. You can do it.
Come on.
B.P.?
150/105.
How are you feeling, Vilma?
I can't breathe.
Respiration is 28, pulse 120.
Let's give her .4
nitro sublingually.
Please, Doc...
I feel like I'm dying.
Respiration's 32.
She's hyperventilating.
Try and control
your breath, Vilma.
Slowly.
It hurts.
Let's get her some morphine.
Vilma?
Oh, my God.
Blood pressure's coming down.
Feeling better?
Better.
Much better.
I think you guys
can take it from here.
She says she's been taking
both Prolixin and Ativan.
Schizophrenic?
Floridly, yes.
Went off her meds...
Now she's delusional.
Hearing voices.
I'm going to have to admit her.
What about the boy?
The social worker's calling
the Presbyterian Home.
Skull fracture,
C-5 neck fracture,
hemopneumothorax,
ruptured diaphragm.
Any heart activity?
Time?
31 Minutes.
Sarah...
Time of death...
10:06.
We lose them all
the time, Carter.
Does the pain move around?
It just sits there like
a bayonet to the gut.
Ah!
How long have you had this?
A year, off and on.
Never this bad.
Also, I get constipated,
and sometimes there's
blood in the bowl.
You haven't seen a doctor?
If he was open nights
and Sundays, I would have,
but who's got the time?
It's me.
Harry Stopak.
Bob Wellman!
How are you?
You got the
brochure I sent over?
Sorry. I got to take this.
So, you like the EM-250?
That's a good copier, Bob.
But, frankly, I saw you
more in an EM-250R.
Yeah.
You get any breakfast yet?
No.
Well, get some,
and be back in 15.
Carter, come here a minute.
He must have been on
his way to shoot buckets.
No I.D., no name on the ball.
His gym shorts say
Von Steuben High.
Call the high school.
It's summer vacation, but
maybe someone can I.D. him.
Wait a minute. Who
gave you permission
to assign duties to my students?
I didn't know you
owned Mr. Carter.
I thought he was assigned
to the Surgical Service.
Yeah? Well, he isn't.
Are you saying he's
unavailable to me?
I'm saying, next time, you ask.
Dr. Carter, identify the dead
boy for Dr. Langworthy here,
and then you report back to me.
Doug Ross.
We've got a little girl who
may have a broken hand.
Let go of me,
you son of a bitch!
Can you hold on a second?
You son of a bitch!
Get his hands off me!
No, no!
You're in a hospital.
Mrs. Schap...
Get his hands off me!
Nobody's going to hurt you.
Thank you.
No, no...
Ow!
Damn it!
No, no, no!
Where am I going?
Give her five Haldol
I.M., and get her upstairs.
Oh, look at you!
Why are you doing this?
Ozzie?
Stop this!
The kid's gone.
Ozzie! Ozzie!
I'll call Security.
Damn it!
You got to get somebody
to look at your hand.
Thank you, Doctor.
God!
Vilma, your lab tests look fine
and your heart rhythm's normal.
I'm going to give you the name
of an anti-gas tablet.
And I'd lay off the
kielbasas for breakfast.
Thank you, Doctor.
You saved her.
It's another attack!
Is she seizing?
Hold on, hold on,
hold on, hold on.
Just relax. Just relax.
No, her heart's fine.
Has this happened before?
Never.
What was it?
I definitely felt that.
What's happening, Doc?
The defibrillator in your
wife's chest is going off.
Why is it shocking me?
It's supposed to, but only
when you're having arrhythmia,
which you are not.
Must be malfunctioning.
Can't you shut it off?
That's what we're
going to try and do.
Call Cardiology.
She really sank
her teeth into you.
Any patient who's even
potentially psychotic
should be placed in
four-point restraints
and muzzled.
Spoken like a true healer.
After 15 years, not
one week has gone by...
Not one week... without being
bitten, spat, puked or peed on.
You're a misanthropic old fart.
I'm not old.
Is this necessary?
The human mouth
literally swims with bacteria.
Staph aureus, eikenella.
The woman deserves a lobotomy.
A hammer to the head.
Ow!
Sorry. Did that hurt?
Yeah.
Dr. Langworthy?
Yes?
The only one left
over at the high
school is the janitor
who left a message
for the principal
and he's going to give
me a copy of the yearbook
so maybe I can
find the boy's picture.
I just wish there was
something more I could do.
Such as?
I don't know.
So, for now, should I go
back to Dr. Benton or...?
Go.
Okay.
My passing hand.
If Billy Fleishell
hadn't piled on,
it never would have happened.
He left cleat marks
on your knuckles.
It's from his teeth.
He speared me, so I popped him.
The game's rougher
than when I played.
I don't think it's broken,
but Carol will take
Blair up to X ray,
and give her something
for the pain, okay?
I don't need anything.
Right this way.
John, thanks for coming down.
Hey, no problem.
Hey, listen, I understand
you've been quite
attentive to carol
since she got back.
Well, I didn't mean to be.
No, no, it's okay.
I'm glad you guys
are still friends, really.
Okay?
Call me anytime, okay?
Okay.
Hi.
Mr. Stopak, you need
to see a specialist
for further tests to rule out
ulcerative colitis,
which is very serious.
You think that's what I've got?
Based on your history,
and what I've seen, no.
I think you have
irritable bowel syndrome,
which can become
serious if untreated.
Assuming that's what I've
got, how do I get rid of it?
Increase the bran in your
diet and, more important,
decrease the
stress in your life.
I don't exactly control
the stress in my life.
Cut back your work hours.
Cut back? Doctor, in my office,
there are two kinds of guys:
those who sell
more than $10 million
and make the annual
trip to Palm Springs,
and those who don't.
You know how long it's been
since I missed the trip?
I have never missed the trip.
I'm back.
Good.
Fill out these slips,
and take those urine
samples up to the lab.
It's good to be back.
Hey, Walt, what's up, man?
Parked you in the first
row near the Dumpsters.
Oh, yeah? So, it was
the transmission, huh?
That sucker was shot.
Hey, how you getting
back to the station?
Peanut followed me in the truck.
Jackie's excited about tonight?
Oh, yeah. I'm taking
her to this fancy place
she's been dying to try
ever since she heard
that Oprah owned it.
It's steep, but I figure,
hey, it's our tenth anniversary.
What the hell?
Your sister's worth it.
And I appreciate
you coming to sit
with your mom.
Yeah.
How's she doing, man?
No incidents this week,
but you can't
leave her alone
for five minutes.
She'll be in the backyard
yelling at the neighbors.
But she's making Jackie
take her to the beauty parlor
so she can look pretty for you.
Look, man, I got to split.
8:30, right?
Yeah. I'll be there.
Hi.
My name is Carol.
I like your sneakers.
They're not the good kind.
My mom got them
from the cheapo store.
Where is she?
The doctors took her upstairs.
She's very sick.
They're going to try
and make her better.
That doctor said
we can stay together.
Well, it looks like
your mom may have
to stay her for a while.
Can I see her?
I don't know if she
can have visitors,
but I'll check.
You want to hang out with me?
I'm taking you up to Cardiology.
They're familiar
with this problem,
so you don't have to
worry about anything.
You'll be okay. Hold on.
Let me grab your records.
Dr. Lewis, listen, I
appreciate what you said.
My wife's been telling me
the same thing for 18 years.
You have the number
for the gastroenterologist?
Hey, you happen to
know who's in charge
of business machine
procurement around here?
Hello.
Louise!
Did you get the
rate card faxed over?
Sorry. I can't hear you!
It's quite noisy here.
Sir, hang up that phone.
What?
Hang up the phone now!
Are you okay?
What kind of phone is that?
The most powerful
handheld on the market.
It's got turbo-dial,
alphanumeric memory.
I'll get you half-price.
I don't want to buy one.
I want you to take that phone
out of this hospital. Now. Now!
You're supposed
to screw the caps on.
Here. Von Steuben High yearbook.
A guy dropped it off.
Sure, I'll take care of it.
Find him?
Yeah, uh...
Steven Tierney, a junior.
A member of the marching
band, and on the debate club.
He was kind of a nerd.
Kind of like me.
I, um... I got to get up to
the O.R. and do a hernia.
You call his folks?
Should I?
Just get them down here.
Let Langworthy break the news.
Change your clothes, huh?
You haven't even thought
about it with Susan?
So what? I'm a married man.
Doesn't mean I'm not allowed
to even speculate.
You're saying you would
never act on it, ever?
If your question is,
are there circumstances
in which I might
possibly, conceivably...
commit adultery, yes.
Let's say Jen takes
a job out of town
in, oh, I don't know, Detroit,
and she leaves you here.
No, no, there would
have to be more.
An affair, perhaps.
She goes out on you,
and you could, justifiably...
even the score?
Yes.
That's not going
to happen though.
You never know.
Maybe I could be of service.
Ow!
Mark, that chest pain
rule-out M.I. just got here.
Oh, okay.
55-Year-old with
substernal chest pains.
Thank you.
What about her?
They lost the key.
We're going to need
bolt cutters for these cuffs.
And cut off these chaps, okay?
This is so embarrassing.
Exam room 2, Jer?
Curtain 3; and what's
the patient's name?
It's Neil Shearer.
Thank you.
Hey, Jerry, this is Ozzie.
Hi.
How you doing?
He's going to hang
out with us for a while.
His mom's on the fifth floor.
Ah. Okay.
I have to check
on some patients.
Can you watch him for a while?
Sure. No problem.
I'll be right back.
So, you ever seen a picture
of a diseased gall bladder?
Check it out.
Excuse me.
My neighbor says that my
husband was brought here
in an ambulance.
What's his name?
Neil Shearer.
Uh...
Wait here one second.
His rhythm's off.
He's having multifocal VCs.
Uh-huh. Give him a hundred
of Lidocaine I.V.
push and start a drip.
There you go.
Here you go, ma'am.
Sit down right here.
Thank you. Thank you.
Excuse me. What is it?
Mr. Shearer's
wife is at the desk.
Oh, God!
Are you and Mrs.
Shearer acquainted?
I'm her secretary.
Jerry, why don't you
show Mrs. Shearer
to the waiting room?
Behind you. Look out.
Ah, Malik, you
look like a surgeon.
Yeah. Excuse me.
Oh, can you...?
Come on.
Okay, does it hurt
anywhere in here?
Not really.
All right. Just tell me
when it does, okay?
You did an abdominal
series, and ultrasound?
They were negative.
C.B.C., U.A. Chem
seven, amylase?
All negative, but
her sed rate's 50.
Oh! Right there.
Okay, okay. Just sit tight.
You pulled me out of
my first pantaloon hernia
for an old lady with
arthritis in her back?
But her sed rate...
Her sed rate is high due
to chronic inflammation.
She's got no G.I. symptoms,
no rectal mass,
Y.A. negative stool.
So just what surgical
problem do you think she has?
Gall bladder, appendix,
mysenteric infarction...
Based on what?
Based on what the
patient's telling me.
Okay. Well, I'll leave you two
to chat a little bit more.
I'll be in the O.R.
if you get a real
surgical candidate.
Mrs. Shearer?
Ozzie.
Ozzie?
I'll find him.
Hello, Mr. Tierney.
This is, um...
My name's John Carter,
over at the emergency room at
Cook County General Hospital.
Your... your son Steven has
been involved in an accident
and, uh...
well, his condition
is... serious,
and I think you should
come down here right away.
It's serious.
Very, very serious.
Thank you.
Carol, does the
name Joey Skarneckia
ring a bell?
It's a pedes case... car
accident... three months ago.
Not a clue.
Well, this insurance company
wants some information.
Will you call medical
records for me?
Are your hands painted on?
What?
Pick up the phone and dial.
Now, out of curiosity,
is this free-flowing
hostility aimed
at the world in
general, or just me?
You don't want to know.
What?
You told that little boy
he could stay with his mother
when you knew she'd be put away,
probably for a long time.
Just who did you
help by lying to him?
I didn't lie.
Sure, you did.
You told him what
he wanted to hear
because you didn't want
a big emotional scene,
which is something
you can't handle,
and avoid at all costs.
Oh, boy.
White count's 20,000.
Oh, God! Call the O.R.!
Get Morgenstern down here now!
Hang in there.
Come on! Come on!
I'm trying.
Faster! Please!
Relax.
We still got S.T. elevation
in the anterior leads.
Go to the left, please!
There's a Mrs. Shearer outside.
I've got to go!
Patient's conscious.
God. Neil, what happened?
Patient's unconscious.
He had a small heart attack,
but we were able to
give him medication,
and he's stabilized now.
However, I'm going to have
to ask you to wait outside.
Why do I have to
wait in the hallway
if you said he's stabilized?
It's hospital policy.
I'm sorry.
No, I'm sorry.
This is my husband,
and I want to be wherever he is.
What's this?
Do you have a pen?
Oh, yeah.
Where are my husband's clothes?
Excuse me?
The clothes that he was wearing
when he was brought in here.
Where are his clothes?
Uh... I'm not sure.
Well, they have to be here
somewhere, don't they?
Priscilla?
I suppose you all think
this is very, very funny.
Don't you?
Excuse me.
Call the O.R.!
Tell them we got
a retrocecal appendix,
and we need a room!
Did she perf?
Yes, she did,
thanks to Dr. Lewis.
Patient presents with
stabbing lower back pain,
and you didn't ask
for a surgical consult?
A medical student
would know better.
She consulted me.
I assessed that the patient
wasn't a surgical candidate.
Do you need an assist?
Yes, I do.
Come on, Sarah.
Watch it!
Have you seen Dr. Langworthy?
What do you want her for?
Well, the parents of
the high school kid...
They're here.
What's his name?
Steven Tierney.
All right, um... come on.
You got to learn this anyway.
Mr. and Mrs. Tierney?
Hi. I'm Dr. Benton.
At around 9:30 this morning
your son Steven was brought in
at full cardiac
and respiratory arrest.
We tried to revive him
but with no success.
I'm sorry.
Your son died.
No... No...
Can...
Can we see him?
Sure.
Oh, no.
Dear God.
Jack?
Doctor...
this isn't our son.
Dr. Greene!
Damn, it's good to see you, man.
Bob Brickley.
One year ago today,
you saved my life.
Of... course.
A small token of my gratitude.
Frozen T-bone
steaks... The real deal...
All the way from Texas.
From now on, August 25 will
be "Dr. Greene Day" in my book.
I'm going to honor it every year
for the rest of my life.
Well, uh...
I don't know what to say.
Thank you.
Hey, man, a
handshake won't do it.
Happy Dr. Greene Day!
I was embraced by two men today.
I find that highly unusual.
Some guys have all the luck.
One of them gave me
a dozen steaks as a gift.
How about a cookout
up on the roof?
That sounds nice,
but I've got a date.
Oh, yeah? Anyone I know?
Yeah, actually. Div Cvetic.
We've kind of been
together for a month or so.
Really?
Great. Div's a great guy.
What's with this patient?
Drug addict going
through withdrawal.
He sounds like a car
alarm that you can't shut off.
Mr. and Mrs. Fisher?
I'm John Carter.
Your son David was
hit by a car this morning,
and he was brought here
by ambulance in full arrest
and, uh...
we tried to resuscitate
him for 31 minutes.
We used all of our capabilities,
but his injuries were too severe
and, uh... he died.
And I'm sorry.
How is she?
Fine. Grabbed the appendix,
in and out, 20 minutes.
Peter, listen, that was
a difficult diagnosis.
A lot of surgeons
would have missed it
because a lot of surgeons
don't take the time
to listen to their patients.
The good ones do.
I'm doing a Whipple procedure.
Care to assist?
A Whipple?
Are you kidding?
Patient's a 62-year-old man
with a history of
pancreatic cancer.
First presented four
weeks ago with...
E.R.
Dr. Ross, Dr. Taglieri wants
to see you outside Supply.
It's about that missing kid.
And these squiggly tubes here...
These are the intestines. See?
And this blob...
That's the heart.
Where's the gallbladder?
What do you know?
Someone took it out.
Must have been diseased.
You still got yours,
though, don't you?
It's down there somewhere.
Hey, Ozzie.
Where are you
taking me this time?
A social worker is
going to take you
to the Presbyterian Home.
I can't stay with my mom?
The truth is that your
mother is very sick.
It's not her fault.
She hasn't done anything wrong.
But, to help her get better,
she's being sent to
the psychiatric hospital.
I hate her.
I don't think that's true.
Listen, your mama
loves you very much.
Then why is this happening?
I wish I could tell you.
Come here.
I wish I knew.
How was the Whipple?
No problem. In and out.
Who performed it?
I did.
Walt, I'm sorry...
Our tenth anniversary...
I know. I got held
up in the O.R.
Don't hand me that O.R. crap!
I already know how
important your work is
compared to the
small events of my life.
Walter, I'm sorry.
We don't ask much.
Practically nothing.
Just that, once in a while,
you come over and
sit with your mother
so your sister and I can
have a few hours together.
And you act like you're
doing us a damn favor!
Okay. All right, Walter,
my next three nights off,
I'll come, I'll sit
with her, I promise.
It's just... I forgot, man.
I swear. I'm sorry.
Yeah.
Funny how that happens
when it comes to your family.
Carter.
Ah...
You off?
Yeah.
Me, too.
12 whole hours.
When you back on?
Tomorrow...
if I come back.
You serious?
I can't remember
even why I'm doing this.
Well, you want to
be a doctor, right?
Benton told my adviser
that I was doing a
generally adequate job,
and that was before today.
I don't...
I don't belong here.
What kind of drugs
is that guy on?
Help! Help!
My wife is having a baby!
It's coming.
It's coming. I can feel it.
That's the head.
What do we do?
You take it. I'll get help.
Okay, ma'am,
you'll be just fine.
Your baby's coming.
All you have to do
is lie back and push.
Okay, whenever you're ready.
Here it comes.
That's it. Just push.
Push.
That's it. Push.
Okay, one final
push now. Come on.
That's it.
You're doing great.
You're doing great. Just push.
Move the cord
back over the head.
Yeah, you got it. That's it.
You're doing great.
Okay, one final push. Come on.
One final push.
Here it comes.
Move the cord over the head.
That's it. That's it.
Don't drop it.
Yes, yes.
It's a girl.
There you go.
Oh.
Everything all right?
Yeah.
You got her?
Yeah, I got her.
You got to undo the lock.
Yes!
Hey, Doug.
Hey, John.
Uh, you know...
it's a bad idea.
Who is it?
Doug Ross.
What are you doing?
Nothing. My, uh... you
know, car broke down,
and the tow truck
was taking so long.
I thought I'd come in
here and use your phone.
I'm late for my date.
You know, I see the
tow truck right there...
now...
I'm really sorry.
Hey!
Hey! Hey!
What were you thinking?
What could you possibly
have been thinking
would happen tonight?
That you would come to my
doorstep at midnight, drunk,
and I would find that some
sort of grand gesture of love?
Is that what you were thinking?
That you can just show up
and I'll invite you back
in my life? In my bed?
I don't know. Is that what you
imagined would happen tonight?
You have no right to
even think about doing this!
I'm sorry.
Do you think that
you love me? Huh?
For how long, Doug?
How long till you
start wondering
if there isn't someone better
in the next room
or the next bar?
How long till that
little voice in your head
starts reminding you of
all the infinite 22-year-olds
you could be screwing tomorrow
or the next day or the next?
I will not let you
do this to me again.
I'm sorry.
Captioning sponsored
by WARNER BROS.