So, Mom, how were you
able to save the day?
Actually,
I didn't, you did.
Mmm.
You took one look at the map,
and you could see connections
we couldn't.
I knew right then
you were gonna be
a scientist, I swear.
Did you...
Oh, I did.
Oh. Speaking of science,
this is the office calling.
Sorry, hold on two secs.
Hello?
You did good there.
We did good.
Danny, I have something
to tell you.
My lymphoma is back
and my old chemo regime
isn't working.
Okay.
I already got third
and fourth opinions
and the only thing left
is clinical trials.
Gaffney has a promising
new drug study I might
qualify for,
and they're screening
me for it today.
Does Robin know?
Mmm-hmm.
Well, why'd you wait
so long to tell me?
I was married
to you, remember?
I know that your
first instinct is to
think the worst,
and I'm not going there.
Okay, I just want you
to remember I work here.
All right?
Anything you need, anything...
I know.
Do you hear me?
I hear you. Thank you.
Apartment app again?
No go on that place
in River North?
Well, it turns out by "one
bedroom," they meant closet.
Pretty fussy for a guy
who's been on his brother's
couch for a few weeks.
I'm just saying.
Your patient came in
with shortness of breath,
pleural effusions
on the right side.
EKG unchanged from his
previous trip to the ED.
The cardiac labs
are mildly elevated.
Diuretics aren't doing enough.
No.
I got it from here, thanks.
Hey, Francis. Kathleen.
I'm worried, Dr. Rhodes.
I heard that.
Bump in the road,
Kathleen, that's all.
So, I am going to
admit you, Francis.
We're gonna do an echo, we'll
tap the fluid off your lungs,
so you can breathe easier.
And then we're gonna try
a new combination of meds
to help your heart
until a new one's available.
We've been on the waiting list
for over a year.
Any update on when
a transplant might happen?
I'm sorry, but no.
Is there someone we can call?
Let them know our situation?
I'm not checking
out yet, Kathleen.
I've still got
big plans for us.
Techs are gonna be by soon,
they'll take you upstairs.
Hang in there, Kathleen.
Thank you.
It's the middle of the winter
and there's a street fair.
South Side gets a bad rap.
Oh, look at that.
What do you think?
Well, I like that
it's strapless.
Yeah?
But it's a summer dress,
it's just gonna sit in
your closet, you know?
You're right.
I'll be back in the Spring.
Okay.
Thank you.
What's up?
It's Philip. Another long
night with baby Sophie.
Whoa.
You gave him your number?
He's living out
of a PICU recliner.
I wanted him to know
he's not alone.
You're his daughter's doctor.
You're crossing boundaries.
You know what?
I don't think you're qualified
to lecture about boundaries
after you gave your kidney
to someone who you
barely know.
Okay?
Oh, you're throwing
that back at me?
You're the one who
started pointing fingers.
What's happening?
Natalie, watch out!
It's gonna be okay.
Hang in there.
Oh, my God.
Get a half-inch line
on the crashed vehicle
in case it goes up, and have
PD set up a perimeter.
Boden.
Hey.
We've got red tags
all over the place
and more trampled victims
than we can count.
We triggered a plan three,
response teams are en route,
ten ambos.
You okay?
Coping.
Maggie, I need help.
Coming.
Open tib-fib fracture.
No pulse in the foot,
I need to reduce it.
All right. Sir,
look at me, look at me.
This is gonna hurt.
One, two...
Got it.
You got a pulse?
Yeah.
Okay, okay.
They're gonna
take care of you.
There are more ambos
on the way,
but it's not gonna be enough.
As long as we get
the red tags to the ED,
we should be able to manage
the yellow tags
until reinforcement gets here.
Natalie, not outside,
it's too cold.
What about that?
Get the victims ready to move.
Who's the manager?
That's me.
I'm a doctor, we need
your place to treat
the injured.
Yeah, I... Okay, okay.
Everybody, we need
to make some space.
Here, help me.
Come with me.
Move back, move back.
This way.
Monique. Trauma bays
turned over?
Yeah, one, two,
and Baghdad are ready to roll.
Okay, perfect. Go help Leah
triage the waiting room.
ED's staying open
for walk-ins.
What do we got?
Thirty-three year old female,
got pinned beneath the car.
Treatment Four.
Got it.
Twenty-eight year old male,
dragged by the vehicle.
Treatment Five.
Baghdad's all yours.
Yep.
Jada Harris, 18 years old,
GCS 3. Couldn't get an airway.
Witnesses said she took
a direct hit from the truck
and was thrown.
That's her mom,
Jalissa Harris,
got clipped by the truck's
side view mirror.
Ms. Harris, let me take you
to a treatment room.
I'm fine.
My daughter, Jada, she wasn't
breathing in the ambulance.
Our trauma team
is treating her.
Let me look at you and then...
No, I need to see her now.
Ms. Harris, Sharon Goodwin,
come with me.
I'll take you to see
your daughter.
Jada just got accepted
to Northwestern.
We were at the fair
celebrating and then this...
Come.
I'm in. There we go.
Hang two units of O-neg.
Yup.
Trigger the MTP.
Let's get a chest
and pelvis x-ray.
Hank, get the ultrasound
ready. What are vitals?
BP 75/40, heart rate 133.
All right, everybody clear.
Left side's whited out.
Give me a chest tube.
Scalpel.
Here's a ten.
Oh, my God, my baby.
Aw, man. Okay, okay.
Ultrasound.
Ultrasound's ready.
Her belly's full of blood.
I can't fix this here.
Let's page my team,
get her over to the Hybrid OR.
Let's go.
I love you, Jada.
Ms. Harris.
Let them take her to surgery.
I love you.
No.
They're gonna take
good care of her.
Kenneth Baker, 53, GCS 8.
BP's 144/86, pulse 88.
Superficial head laceration.
Hit by the car
or trample victim?
He's the driver,
plowed through half the fair
and wrapped his truck
around a pole.
Unconscious
the whole ride over?
Yeah, it might not have
been from the crash.
Pharmacy in his backpack.
On my count.
One, two, three...
Accident scene's a war zone,
gonna make a few round trips.
Thanks, Brett.
Breath sounds are good.
Monique, dig in his backpack.
See what he's on.
On it.
Pupils are equal
and reactive.
I want trauma labs,
a tox screen,
chest and pelvis x-rays,
and send him over to CT
for a pan scan.
A lot of pain meds,
oxycodone, naproxen...
Phenytoin, that's
an anti-epileptic.
If he had a seizure
while driving, he wouldn't
even know what happened.
Here you go.
Thank you.
Hey, down to our last ambo
for a bit. It's our call
who needs to go now.
Well, this is Grace.
She helped a woman
who had fallen,
but got trampled herself.
Clear head trauma.
Did you get knocked out?
I don't think so,
but everything
is a little blurry.
We got one more spot
in the ambulance,
it's yours.
We need to get you
to the ED for a head CT.
But I don't have insurance,
I can't afford it.
I understand, but since you
don't know if you blacked out,
it's best to be overcautious.
I think
I feel better already.
I swear,
I'm not just saying it.
Okay, hold on to this.
A trip to the ED
is gonna cost a fortune.
Look, her GCS is 15,
her pupils are clear,
and she has a good
recollection of the incident.
Let's hold her off
for the next set of ambos,
if she even needs one.
Keep an eye on her
and I'll take a second look
at our yellow tags.
Give the spot to one of them.
Okay.
A lot of whispers
the driver was high.
He wasn't.
Metastatic cancer.
Terminal.
What all those
meds were for.
Just extubated, but no one's
told him what happened,
that people have died.
Or that he's responsible.
Getting news like this
can really break someone.
Let me take the lead?
How did it go?
I had to remove her left
kidney, spleen, and a portion
of her small intestine.
She needed 15 units of blood,
another 15 of plasma.
What about head trauma?
She was too unstable
for CT before surgery.
She's going up for one now.
You're concerned.
Yeah.
I'm gonna change
and fill in the mom.
Well, I'd like to be
there when you do.
Jada's all she's got,
she shouldn't have to go
through this alone.
How many people died?
Seven.
But many more are injured.
So, they may die also?
There are likely to be
more fatalities.
I'm very sorry.
Don't be.
They had it coming. They're
trying to deny our heritage...
All this mixing,
they wanna eliminate us.
"Us"?
The white race.
But before cancer takes me,
I'm taking some of them.
Was hoping for 20,
but the day's not over yet.
Okay, everybody
clear the scene.
Get back now.
What the hell is going on?
The truck is loaded
with explosives.
We are pulling out
and locking down.
But you can't.
We have victims that need
to go to the hospital.
They have to wait.
Nobody in or out until
the bomb squad says it's okay.
How long is that gonna take?
I don't know, but you
have to get inside
and stay away
from the windows.
Go, right now. Go.
Two kits?
That's all you could get?
Ambos got pushed
off the scene.
I go to them,
I don't get back in.
All right.
Golden hour's almost up.
Our yellow tags
are at risk of becoming reds.
Divide and conquer?
Yeah.
Okay.
Did you get the results
of Jada's head CT?
Diffuse blood throughout
the brain, catastrophic.
She's brain-dead.
Oh...
Have you told her mother yet?
Not yet, but I think
she already feels it.
Let's tell her together.
You're being moved
to the jail ward.
I want the head nurse.
I am the head nurse.
One of those bossy blacks,
aren't you?
That's right.
Just finished the eval
on a walk-in patient.
I'm ready to present.
Okay, let's go take a look.
I know I said
I'd put on the gown,
but then I realized
just because I feel like crap,
doesn't mean I have
to look like it.
I'm more concerned
with your pain
than your outfit.
Dr. Choi, Sebastian Lopez.
Nice to meet you, Mr. Lopez.
Sebastian.
And I'm sorry for
taking you away
from all the people injured
in the street fair.
I didn't wanna come in, but...
I can't take the pain anymore.
It's like...
It's like I'm getting stabbed.
The pain's confined
to the right flank.
It's been steady
the last two days,
became severe overnight.
This morning he noticed
his urine was cloudy
and malodorous.
Well, just tell
the whole world.
Fever?
Low grade.
I'm thinking pyelonephritis.
It fits. Labs?
CBC, CMP, UA
and an ultrasound.
Agreed, run them.
I know it's painful,
but if left untreated,
a kidney infection can lead
to permanent damage.
It's good you came in.
I'm glad I did... Now.
Keep me posted, Terry.
Oh, my...
Tall, dark and intense.
Mmm. Gets me every time.
Amari Moore, 35,
severe blunt force trauma.
Pushed his son
out of the way of the truck,
took the hit for him.
He refused a board and collar,
wouldn't let us take him
with the first wave of ambos.
Barely got him out
before they locked
up the scene.
Off-duty cop,
could hardly breathe,
still wanted to stay and help.
My son, Andre...
Where's Andre?
He rode up front,
Stacy's with him.
I think he hurt his arm.
Take care of him first.
I'm staying with you,
but Andre will be safe.
I promise.
On my count.
One, two, three...
Get a second line
and a chest x-ray.
I want my dad.
Andre Moore, eight.
Fell on his arm,
no visible deformities,
doesn't complain of pain.
Where's my dad?
Your dad is with the doctor
right now, honey.
Let me take a look
at your arm.
No!
I need him.
Dad, where are you?
Hey, hey, hey. How you doing?
I'm Dr. Charles,
tell me your name.
Andre.
Andre, really nice
to meet you.
How about I take you
to where we can see
what's going on with your dad?
Okay?
Okay.
Okay. T-Two ready?
Yep.
Okay, come on.
Dad?
Okay, okay, you can
see him right here.
Okay?
What are they doing?
Well, they're helping him.
You see the plastic mask over
his nose? That's to help him
breathe easier.
And that machine can actually
look inside his chest.
It's got x-ray vision
just like Superman.
Now, that woman,
she's a very special
kind of doctor.
If they find
something in his chest,
she's trained to fix it.
What are they doing?
Where are they taking him?
Dad, Dad,
where are you going?
I have to go upstairs
with the doctor.
I wanna go.
No.
I need you to stay here
and be brave.
Come here.
Andre, I know you're scared...
But I believe in you.
Okay, I can do it.
I'll be brave.
Be brave.
We gotta go.
Not heading home
today, am I?
No.
Your echo showed an ejection
fraction rate of 12%.
Your heart is failing
and the meds aren't working.
Ticker's on its last legs.
That's gotta move me up
the transplant list, huh?
Straight to the top,
status 1A.
Well, next in line,
can't beat that.
It's gonna work out, Kathleen,
just like it always has.
'Cause what are we?
Blessed.
I will be back to check
on you guys in just
a little bit, okay?
Ms. Goodwin,
may I have a moment?
Excuse me, Ms. Harris.
I have a patient,
Francis Buckley,
with biventricular
heart failure.
Now, I know that Ms. Harris
has just lost her daughter,
and she hasn't had
any time to grieve...
But Jada's heart
could save his life.
They have
the same blood type,
it's the first step
towards her heart
being an HLA match.
If it is, with it being
right across the hall,
Francis will get it.
I'll ask her if she'll
speak to the Gift of Hope.
Thank you.
The man who did this,
he didn't even know Jada.
Just wanted to hurt her.
All of us.
Yes, I know.
But there's a way
she can live on...
Through organ donation.
You mean cut Jada up
even more? As if she hasn't
already given enough.
Well, nothing about today
is fair, Ms. Harris.
Not just today.
How does it work?
Donation?
Well, transplants
are overseen
and managed
by an organization
called Gift of Hope.
They'll take over
and guide you
through the process.
What will they use from her?
The doctors will make
that assessment.
Just make sure her organs
go to someone like us.
Ms. Harris, I don't
have any control
over the organ donor list.
So, Jada's organs
can go to anyone,
even some racist
like the man who did this?
Then, no. I can't
give permission.
Oh, God.
I am so sorry. Just hold
pressure right there, okay?
My kit is down to
a few pieces of gauze.
Yeah, well,
more than I've got.
I just flushed shrapnel
from a woman's eye with this.
Help. He can't breathe.
I'm holding pressure
just like you said,
but he keeps gasping.
Sucking chest wound.
He needs a chest tube.
But we don't have any,
but I saw something
that we can use.
Yeah?
Natalie.
Okay, got it.
Look at me, I know you're
uncomfortable right now,
but just try and relax,
keep looking at me
and breathe in nice and easy.
You're gonna be okay.
Plastic wrap and duct tape.
That should do it.
Do what?
Every time he breathes in,
air gets in through the wound,
and it gets caught
in his chest,
compressing on his lungs.
The plastic wrap reverses it.
It acts as a one-way valve.
It seals the wound
when he inhales
and lets out the air
from the open end
when he exhales.
There you go.
Okay, just breathe.
I can breathe better.
Good. Nice job.
You need a break?
Me?
I saw you working
out your shoulder.
Hey.
Dr. Choi, we have to stop
meeting like...
Well, there's the pain again.
So much for being smooth.
So, your labs don't support
a kidney infection.
Student Doctor McNeal
has a new theory
about what's going on.
Do you mind if I take a look?
Well, I thought
you'd never ask.
All right, have at it.
I agree,
most likely kidney stones.
How would you confirm?
CT with contrast
of the right ureter.
Perfect, get it going.
We'll figure this out,
get you fixed up.
Uh, Dr. Choi, before you go...
How about we grab
a drink sometime?
I'm your doctor.
Better if we kept it at that.
Well, that's not exactly a no.
You know this...
Hold on a second, Mom.
Hi.
Hey, Robin.
Thank you for the text.
I didn't know if...
No.
Connor, this is
my mom, Caroline.
Caroline, this is Connor.
Pleasure to meet
you, Caroline.
Connor. I have
wanted to meet you
for a very long time.
Thank you so much
for taking such good
care of my girl
when she needed you.
Uh, this is for you.
It's a list of mindless
but very entertaining apps.
I figured some games
might make the waiting
room purgatory
go by a little faster.
Now this gonna be fun.
See, this is what I need
to keep my mind off things.
Oh. What are we,
chopped liver?
Anyway, now that you're
occupied, I'm gonna
check in with the ED.
And Mom, we'll be
right over here.
Mmm-hmm.
Still saving the day, I see.
And now with a beard.
Change of pace.
Connor, I'm sorry.
I should've stayed in touch.
No, it's okay.
Out of sight,
not out of mind.
Eh.
It's the ICU.
I have a patient
with questions that I don't
have answers to.
Look, if there's anything
that Caroline needs,
you just let me know.
And the same goes
for you, too.
Thank you.
You know, I'll be in town
for a little while.
Let's catch up.
I'd love that.
Okay.
Sebastian's CT
results are back.
Mildly dilated ureter.
No evidence of acute
obstruction, but several
stones in the bladder
causing significant clot.
So you have
your diagnosis,
what's next?
IV Ketorolac for the pain,
3-way Foley catheter
to irrigate the clot.
Good.
Ethan, patient in Two
has questions about meds.
Let the pharmacy handle it?
Yeah, thanks.
Actually, the pharmacy
takes forever to respond.
I'll speak with the patient.
Okay.
What about Sebastian's Foley?
You're not gonna supervise me?
Grab Nurse Doris.
She's done a thousand more
than I have anyway.
Ms. Goodwin.
Yes?
You said that
you were gonna speak
to Jalissa Harris
about donating Jada's organs.
I haven't heard
from Gift of Hope.
I did speak with Ms. Harris.
She's not consenting
to organ donation,
because she can't have a say
in who the recipient is.
Well, no one has a say,
that's the whole entire point.
I know.
Francis Buckley
is running out of time.
If he doesn't get
Jada's heart, he might not
live long enough to get one.
I understand, Dr. Rhodes.
But for Ms. Harris,
this has become
a racial issue.
Ms. Goodwin, I know
that she is hurting,
but what happened today
was the act of one,
ignorant, violent man.
Yes, but for her,
this decision goes deeper
than one man, one action.
So then what do we do?
I don't know, Dr. Rhodes.
I don't know.
Andre's dad didn't
survive the surgery?
His aunt's on the way,
but she won't be here
for hours.
This kid is desperate
for information about his dad.
Did she give us permission
to tell him?
Yeah.
Let's go do it.
Where's my dad?
Sit down a second.
So I gotta tell you something
really sad, okay?
No. No, he didn't! No!
Dad!
He didn't die!
He didn't, no!
Thank God, Herrmann, supplies.
We literally have
nothing left.
This is it?
It's the best
I can do right now.
Any word from the bomb squad
about when the scene's
gonna be cleared?
Help me!
Maggie! Maggie,
I need help.
Soon as I know, you'll know.
All right.
She's seizing.
Damn it.
I should have put her
in that last ambo
when I had the chance.
Not on you. We made
a judgment call.
Come on, sweetie.
She stopped seizing.
She's got a pulse,
but she's not breathing.
All right,
there's an airway kit.
There.
Yeah.
Got it.
Hey. You okay?
Some days it seems
like we do nothing
but give bad news.
I was hoping to see
CeCe before her exam.
Where's Robin?
Getting a bite.
Have you eaten, Daniel?
You know, I keep thinking
about when CeCe and I told
our parents we were engaged.
They were not too happy,
to say the least.
You remember, they didn't even
come to the wedding.
I remember,
but it's their loss.
That reception was the bomb.
All of your friends
and CeCe's friends, it was
like the last days of disco.
More like Soul Train with
a few extra Caucasians,
as I recall.
Long time ago.
You're still not in touch
with your mother?
A cousin told me she is in
a nursing home around here
somewhere, that's all I know.
I tell you what,
CeCe was as whole lot better
when it came to
forgiving her parents.
I just... I couldn't...
I couldn't let it go.
We're all
gonna have to let it go
at some point, Daniel.
It'll just go on and on.
Tell CeCe that
I'll come back later.
You bet.
I said no. I'm not speaking
with Gift of Hope.
I thought you
would understand.
I do, Ms. Harris.
I understand
you're devastated,
you're angry.
I have every right to be.
Especially today.
Yes, you do.
But please don't let Jada's
legacy be one of hate.
His is.
But it doesn't
have to be yours.
Ms. Harris, you have the power
to gift life to someone else.
Please use it.
Oh, baby.
All went well
with Sebastian.
Foley's in and he said
he's feeling better already.
Good.
Dr. Lanik's doing
an intraosseous line insertion
in Trauma Three,
go check it out.
Okay.
Skipping out on the Foley,
were you confident
in my ability
or just uncomfortable
Sebastian was flirting
with you?
I would never ask you
to do anything
you're not ready for.
Same time, yeah,
I was kinda relieved when
something else came up.
You know the feeling.
Wouldn't you be
a little thrown by a guy
blatantly hitting on you?
No. I mean, it doesn't
bother me when women do it.
What do you mean?
I thought you knew. It's no
secret in the ED, I'm gay.
No, uh, I wasn't aware.
So, I'm gonna go check in
on Dr. Lanik's intraosseous
line insertion.
Gift of Hope.
Whatever you said, thank you.
My brother was a single dad,
yet never missed
a teacher's conference,
a flag football game,
trick or treating...
I don't know
how to replace that.
You know, I would really
like to help.
I hope that you'll
call me. Anytime.
Really.
Andre, let's go, honey.
What you got there, Andre?
I'm gonna grow up
and be brave,
just like my dad.
I think that's
wonderful idea.
Guys, guys, listen up!
Hey, we got the all clear,
all right?
Calvary's rolling in,
dozen ambos, more on the way.
Who's going to the hospital?
Everyone,
and I'll take a sling.
All right, you got it.
Thank you.
We did it.
Maggie, you okay?
What's wrong?
I don't know.
Oh, my God.
Natalie...
Maggie.
No... Oh, my God.
Help! I need help.
Maggie, open your eyes.
Oh, whoa. What happened?
She had surgery last week,
her incision opened up.
God, she must have been
in pain all day.
All right, let's get her
on a backboard and loaded.
I want IVs in and fluids
running now, let's go.
All right, ready?
On my count.
One, two, three...
All right.
Robin.
Oh, hey, Ava.
You back working
at the hospital?
No, no, my mom's
a patient here,
or might be a patient.
Oncology.
I'm sorry to hear that.
Yeah.
Have you seen Connor yet?
Briefly.
We've made loose plans
to get together soon.
It's uncertain times,
so I'm thankful to have
a friend close by.
Anyway, I gotta get
back upstairs.
Of course.
Hey, Terry.
Hey, man.
Look, I am sorry
for being such a dope earlier.
Hey, don't worry
about it, man.
You didn't know I was gay.
No, still I'm not that guy.
We're good.
Being an alpha male myself,
I know the difference
between bigotry
and being caught off guard.
Appreciate that.
Yeah.
But truth be told,
Sebastian was laying
it on pretty thick.
If I was in your shoes,
I might have been
flustered, too.
He's not my type, either.
Where's Mom?
She needed a moment.
Didn't get into the study.
I mean, not the one
she wanted, anyway.
Doctor said she was a good
candidate for this new
experimental trial, but...
It wasn't our first choice,
but it's something.
Yeah, but experimental
means Phase 1.
You know?
A lot of bugs, unknown
side effects, dosing
problems, safety issues...
Dad, it's okay.
We've beaten cancer before,
we can beat it again.
Mom needs us.
How'd you get so brave?
Come here.
I'm gonna.
Don't tell me.
I popped some stitches.
Yeah.
And you lost a lot of blood,
plus you were dehydrated.
All right.
Go ahead, give me the "I told
you to take it easy" look.
I'm not really one
to gloat today.
Philip?
Go up and see him.
You're not wrong
about crossing boundaries...
But I don't care.
And I love you for that.
Man. His owner?
Yeah.
So, what? You just take
him to a shelter?
Yeah, but he's
an older dog, so...
I'll take him.
You sure?
Yeah.
Hi.
Hey, come on.
Let's go, boy.
She's right there.
Hi, Mom.
Daniel.
Do you mind if I sit down?
It's been so long.
Yeah.
Um...
Thirty... Thirty-five years.
Why are you here?
I wanna show you something.
This is your granddaughter.
Her name is Robin.
She's beautiful.
Yeah.
I would, um...
I would very much
like you to meet her.