Good morning.
What time is it?
6:28.
You should be asleep,
but I'm glad you're not.
Your post-op pathology
and MRI results are finally in,
and...
They're good.
Very good.
Was the pause
for dramatic effect?
Yes.
The surgery was a success.
The only thing you
need now is rest.
And chemo and radiation.
Have you been here all night?
I slept in a chair in the lab.
Well, you should go
home and go to sleep.
I can't go home.
My next shift
starts in 31 minutes.
The surgery was a success.
I used to think maybe you
loved me Now baby I'm sure
And I just can't wait till the
day When you knock on my door
I'm walking on sunshine Wow!
And don't it feel good
Hey, all right now And
don't it feel good, hey
The surgery was a success.
All Dr. Glassman
needs now is rest.
- That's great news.
- And chemo and radiation.
How are you?
I don't need rest. I fell
asleep in a comfortable chair.
Good. Someone screwed
up the on-call schedule
and left the ER short-staffed.
I need two
volunteers to fill in.
Good news is, you won't have
me breathing down your neck.
Bad news is, it's
a 36-hour shift.
This new flex-time
policy is ridiculous.
Aren't our salaries
low enough already?
It's not about the money.
Andrews believes that
surgeons need to be at their best
even when they're exhausted.
The only way for residents
to learn it is to do it.
You gotta practice
like you play.
And you can't do
either without sleep.
You're free to take it up
with Andrews anytime.
Pick a number
between one and five.
Two-point-five.
- One.
- No, that's not between...
- Five.
- Three.
Oh, damn it.
Good news. Dr. Melendez won't
be breathing down our necks.
You're second-year residents.
This is a great opportunity
for you to prove that you don't
need a babysitter anymore.
And I have a ton of personal
crap I gotta take care of today,
so I'm on-call, but don't call me
unless you absolutely need to.
But you better not need to.
We've got an MI in One, and
a compound femur in Two...
I'm gonna kill that bastard!
He's dead! I'm gonna kill him!
And a bleeding, angry
drunk guy in Five.
Get your hands off of me!
What the hell are
you looking at?
Excising the endometrial lesions
should only take about an hour.
We'll be operating through a
single incision in your belly button.
You won't even be
able to see the scar.
How can you operate
through such a small opening?
It's a new technique
using a single port
divided into sections for
the camera and our tools.
New?
To them. Don't
worry. It isn't to me.
I'm confident that this will resolve
your pain and infertility issues.
Thank you, all of you.
Being a mother is
all I've ever wanted.
On our first date, she
told me the babies' names
she'd picked out.
We were 17.
So, let's hear 'em.
Jackson for a boy,
and Cameron for a girl.
Very nice. I like them.
So do I.
And you are going to
be an amazing mother.
Very soon.
Let's get her prepped.
I thought it was just
because she was so pretty,
and, uh, it had been a while.
But after she left,
it stayed.
You think she roofied
me with Viagra?
Sure, that could've happened.
Or maybe it was the alcohol,
marijuana and Molly
you pre-gamed with.
A lot of different drugs
can cause priapism.
Especially those
cooked up in a garage.
Is it okay if I touch it?
Uh, okay. Uh...
Rigid corpora cavernosa
and flaccid glans.
What's that mean?
What's she getting?
It's been over four hours. You
don't want necrosis to set in.
Necrosis? Are you saying
that my penis could die?
It could, but it won't because
we are gonna move fast.
What the hell are you
gonna do with that?
We need to remove the deoxygenated
blood to restore circulation.
You're gonna feel a small
pinch, and then pressure.
Is she lying?
I'm not sure.
Holy mother of God, that hurts!
Wow!
I go out for a short walk to
have one moment of peace,
and this is what I come home to.
What's the problem?
His mouth was obviously
big enough to get it in.
He must've strained
his masseter.
It's gone into spasm
and caused lockjaw.
So, give him a sedative
and pry it with a McIvor.
I tried. It won't budge.
- And he said it hurt like son-of-a...
- Inez.
That's what he said.
I put in a bite-block,
but I don't know...
Call Lim.
We're supposed to be
proving our independence.
I will try again
with the McIvor.
You don't wanna
tear the masseter.
If the bite-block
slips, and he gags,
he will have broken glass
and vomit in his lungs.
I could put him under,
then I can dislocate
his jaw if I have to.
We definitely can't do
that without calling Lim.
That's true.
I hope we don't interrupt
anything important.
Don't worry. She's either
sleeping or doing laundry.
There's nothing
interesting in her life.
Not guilty.
Do you have something
against traffic school?
Your Honor, the defendant's
not eligible for traffic school.
This is her third moving
violation in the last year.
Alleged violation,
thank you very much.
Traveling 100 miles per
hour on a motorcycle?
Do you have a death wish?
I wasn't going
anywhere near 100.
So, how fast were you going?
Excellent question.
And one I assure you the officer
who issued my ticket
will not be able to answer.
California State
Vehicle code mandates
that all LIDAR speed
measurement devices
be calibrated at least once
a... I'm sorry. I need to get this.
No, you need to turn it off.
Your Honor, I'm a trauma
surgeon at Saint Bonaventure,
and I'm on call, so...
Five minutes.
The court is adjourned
for a five-minute recess.
I thought I was clear.
I'm available to help with
stuff you can't do on your own.
Uncle Fester Junior
does not qualify.
I think the situation warrants
putting him under a general...
And dislocating his jaw?
He's not a damn snake.
So, what should we do?
Prove to me you're as
capable as I think you are.
It doesn't make any sense.
We are the only hospital
on the West Coast
that hasn't adopted
the ACGME mandate
on a 24-hour max shift length.
And numerous studies have shown
the negative effects
that sleep deprivation
has on critical thinking,
which can cause
residents to make mistakes
that not only harm patients,
but that waste money.
You've done your homework.
Um, it's something I've been
thinking about for a long time.
I actually did a paper
on it at med school.
Well, Dr. Browne, I've
also thought about it.
In fact, when the new ACGME
guidelines were released,
I joined a nationwide study
analyzing a flex-time schedule.
It found that as long as a weekly
max of 80 hours is adhered to,
patient outcomes and resident
satisfaction scores are better
than at hospitals
with a daily max.
So, we're just going to
have to agree to disagree
about whether my foolish
new policies make any sense.
No, I didn't say...
Now, I know I told you
to be more assertive,
but you also need to make
sure that you don't forsake
your normally excellent
judgment in that effort.
Excuse me, yeah.
Hi. I'm sorry. I'm back.
How wonderful. Take a
seat until your case is called.
My case was called.
You said I could have
a five-minute break.
The court took a
five-minute break.
Yours is going to be
considerably longer.
Continue.
Make a stab incision
with an 11 blade,
and I'll insert the Veress.
He'll get over it. Don't worry.
Andrews just likes to hammer
a nail every now and then.
I didn't call him a fool. I just
said his policy didn't make sense.
Insufflation's complete.
Ready for the multi-port.
You said it didn't make sense,
and he explained that in his
opinion it did. What's the problem?
The problem is men who
tell women to be assertive,
then as soon as we
are, they criticize us for it.
We're the bitch.
You didn't call him a fool.
He didn't call you a bitch.
Not to her face.
He just suggested she choose
her words more carefully.
So, women have to be
assertive, but careful?
When you're talking to your
boss, yes. Everyone does.
If you're all done debating,
this boss could use some help.
You see that?
There are lesions on her ovary.
That wasn't visible
on the imaging.
It's small.
We can excise it without
damaging the ovary, but...
There are others.
Bowel, bladder, uterus.
No wonder she's
been in so much pain.
We'll start with the
fallopian lesions,
and just go one by one.
Browne, I need you to scrub
out and brief the husband.
Explain the endometriosis is
way more severe than we thought.
Why me? Why not Park?
Because I think you're better
at talking to anxious relatives.
Is there a problem?
No.
Retract that tissue.
Why is she so on edge today?
No idea.
It's one of those days.
I didn't mean one
of "those" days.
I just meant people wake up
on the wrong side
of the bed sometimes.
Dr. Browne explained
exactly why she was on edge.
Did you forget already, or were
you just not listening to begin with?
Excuse me?
We should cut back
on the conversation
and focus on the procedure.
I agree.
I wanna see her.
I'm sorry. You
can't go into the OR.
I'll just... I'll just look
through the window. Please.
Daniel, trust me.
Seeing your beautiful
wife on the operating table
is not gonna make
you less anxious.
Hey, everything
is under control.
The only thing that's changed is
how long the surgery's gonna take.
Look, I'm... I'm sorry.
I... I don't mean to be a pain.
You're not a pain. You're
just scared. I would be too.
She's getting the best care
possible, and as soon as we're done,
we'll bring you to her.
Thank you.
Okay.
You're good at this.
Shouldn't you be in the ER?
Lea keeps calling me.
She wants to talk about why I
told her to go back to Hershey.
You told Lea to go
back to Hershey?
I thought it would
solve the problem,
but, no, no, it just
made it worse.
Now she wants to talk about it
more, but there's no more to be said.
That's not the way
it works, Shaun.
It can't just be one person
who does the talking.
You have to listen, too.
I don't want to listen to her.
It's too hard. It's too hard.
Well, relationships
aren't always easy.
They get complicated and messy.
Exactly. That's
why I don't want one.
Well, that's not true.
The reason that you left
the ER to come talk to me
is because we
have a relationship,
and we both benefit from it.
Lea's your friend. You can't
just wall yourself off from people
in the hope that
you'll never get hurt.
Oh, we need to wall it
off so he doesn't get hurt.
Stay calm, buddy.
Just relax your throat and
breathe through your nose.
Clamp.
- Got it.
- Cool!
Now bite down.
This is a surgical pouch. It
can't even be cut by a scalpel.
Come on, you can do it.
On the count of
three. One, two, three.
- Inez!
- What? He was being a total wuss.
That was amazing.
You wanna create a plane
between the outer serosa
and muscularis layer
to avoid disrupting the lumen.
Everything go okay
with the husband?
Yes. And, uh, I apologize.
I shouldn't have
questioned your decision.
It's all good.
Two fallopian lesions
down, and one more to go.
You wanna take the
wheel on the next one?
Sure.
Figures.
Nurse Flores, do you have a problem
with Dr. Browne taking the lead?
No. I just find it interesting
that you only gave her the
opportunity after she apologized.
You can scrub out.
No. I'll stay.
I'm not asking, I'm
ordering. Scrub out.
No, I've done nothing wrong.
You're undermining my
management of this procedure.
By answering a
question you asked me?
By making snide comments
questioning my judgment.
I'm not leaving my post,
so why don't we
just get back to work?
You, me and Andrews
will be discussing this later.
I look forward to it.
I'm gonna need more saline now!
Hi, Daddy.
Have you eaten?
Not yet.
I'll get lunch
after I finish this.
Lunch? It's almost 5:00.
Then dinner.
Look, I'll go now, I'm
starving. I'll be back in 30.
Hey, your erection's back.
She's not talking about me.
Thirty-day suspended
sentence and a $700 fine.
Take all these
documents to room 306.
Mr. Alex Leon.
No way, Your Honor.
I've been waiting patiently.
We'll get to you.
When? At 4:59, so you can
tell me you've run out of time
and make me come back
to do this all over again?
Well, I guess we'll just have
to see about that, won't we?
No, we won't. Take a seat, kid.
Your Honor, I am so sorry
that my two-minute phone call was
such an incredible inconvenience,
but I went out of my way to be
here today to have my case heard.
And that is exactly
what I'm gonna do. Now.
Can I have
Dr. Lim's file, please?
Thank you.
And I promise
this won't take long,
because as I
started to explain...
Guilty. $1,500 fine and
license suspension for one year.
The bailiff will have some paperwork
for you to sign on the way out.
You can't do that.
I have a thick book in
my office that says I can.
No. This is America.
I pay taxes, which pay
your salary by the way.
- I wouldn't go there.
- Oh, I'm definitely going there.
I strongly advise you
don't say another word.
You can appeal this
verdict to a different judge.
I don't want a different judge. I
want this one to do her damn job!
We keep the TP up front. Just
give a yell if you need some.
Is it gonna die?
Just relax. Everything's
under control.
That's not a no.
We're gonna review your lab
results, and we'll be right back.
Excuse me. We've
already reviewed his labs.
There's no sign of a malignancy,
sickle cell, lymphoma or leukemia.
I know. I just need
a minute to think.
I think we should...
No, we're not calling Lim.
We got our asses
chewed out last time,
and this is not life and death.
We can inject diluted phenylephrine
every five minutes for an hour.
That's a lot of
injections in his penis.
I'll give him a lidocaine local.
Fine. A dorsal nerve block.
- You guys are such wimps.
- That much phenylephrine
could also cause a
hypertensive crisis.
Okay, Dr. No, what's
your idea, then?
You already rejected it.
We are not calling Lim.
Are you awake?
Yes.
If a patient has reoccurring
low-flow priapism,
but there is no sign of sickle
cell, blood dyscrasia or Hodgkin's...
Why are you asking
me? I'm a neurosurgeon.
My work is up
here, not down there.
Because Morgan
won't let me ask...
Dr. Glassman,
why do you ignore
Dr. Ko's medical advice?
I'm not.
Really? She advised you do
consults from your ICU bed?
I didn't ask him
to come in here.
Go to sleep.
What do you think
I've been trying to do
for the last 14 hours
and... What time is it?
8:17.
Forty-seven minutes.
I would like some more
morphine, please, and an Ambien.
You know you can't have either.
Well, then, how the hell
am I supposed to fall asleep?
Every time I turn,
I strangle myself.
You nurses come
here every 30 minutes
to steal my bodily fluids.
Have you tried easing
yourself onto your side
and putting a pillow
between your legs?
Of course, that's the problem. I
don't know how to use a pillow.
Try it. And I will turn
the light all the way off,
and Dr. Murphy
will leave you alone.
Winter's procedure.
It's not the solution,
but it'll buy you enough time
to maybe find another one.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Goodnight, Dr. Glassman.
Seems like for every lesion
we excise, we find two more.
- What time is it?
- 1:12 in the morning.
My bladder is about to burst.
After I finish this one,
I'm gonna take a break.
While I'm out,
Park, you take over.
Start on the lesions I
showed you on the bladder,
but be careful...
Her pressure's dropping.
She's bleeding out.
I can't see anything.
We're taking out the scope.
We're gonna have to open her up.
I've got two units
on the rapid infuser.
MAP is still hovering at 60.
As fast as I can.
Paint her with chlorhexidine
and don't make a
Picasso. It's a crash lap.
- On it.
- Knife.
Yeah, the bleeding's
under control.
What about her bladder?
There's infiltrating
lesions all over it.
Even the walls are involved.
We're gonna have to remove it.
And give her a urostomy bag?
There has to be another option.
If I had another
option, Nurse Flores,
I would've suggested it.
What if we excise part of her
bowel, reconstruct a bladder?
That's a lot more
dangerous than...
Making a 28-year-old
woman urinate
through a hole in her
abdomen for the rest of her life?
I think the additional
risk is worth it.
See if the husband agrees.
- Okay, I'll go.
- No, Park will.
And while he does, I
want everyone but JL,
Dr. Browne and Nurse
Flores to clear the OR.
You, monitor the patient. You
two, we need to have a talk.
Do I have a choice?
Do you want to keep a
fully-functioning penis?
- Of course.
- Then no.
That's even bigger
than it was last time.
Winter's procedure requires
an extra-large-gauge needle
to poke a hole big enough
to restore blood flow.
We'll give you a
lidocaine nerve block.
You won't feel a thing.
Why wasn't I
given that last time?
The risk wasn't worth it before.
Trust me, it was
worth before too.
Good choice.
We'll be right back.
You said we needed
to do this now.
We do. I just need to confer
with my colleague for a moment.
You talking to Lim
behind my back?
No.
Don't lie. You're
not good at it.
I saw you delete her text.
I knew Glassman didn't
give you the Winter's idea.
The text wasn't from
Dr. Lim. It was from Lea.
If it was from Lea, then
why'd you delete it so fast?
Claire thinks I shouldn't
push a good friend away,
but thinking about her...
I don't want to talk to her.
You shouldn't listen
to them. Either of them.
Lea and Claire are
nice to you, but...
They're not your friends.
They wanna take care
of you, like a cute pet.
They take you seriously as
a doctor, but not as a man.
Lea kissed me,
after we sang karaoke.
Shaun, it was a pity kiss.
You've never even met Lea.
True. But I know that
she's not in middle school,
which means if she really
thought of you as a man,
she wouldn't have settled
for just one innocent peck.
I just...
What are you looking at?
Hey, Shaun.
What's going on?
I thought I couldn't be
released until I was arraigned.
Judge decided nine hours
was enough punishment.
She's the one who should
be punished. I should sue her.
What you should do is
learn to keep your mouth shut.
You're lucky I'm hungry.
This stops now. We
need to work together.
We are. That's how we came up
with the idea to rebuild her bladder.
There's a way to offer your input
without undermining my authority.
The only thing that
undermines your authority
is your comments about
Dr. Browne's supposed PMS.
- What?
- I never said you had PMS.
I just asked Park if he knew why
you were more irritable than usual.
I'm not irritable,
and I'm not a whiner!
- I never said you were...
- You told me to take it up with Andrews.
- This was your idea.
- If anyone's a whiner, it's you.
That's enough!
You're 12 hours into an operation
you thought would take one,
so I think it's safe to say you're
all more irritable than usual,
but you need to get a grip.
Dr. Melendez, maybe it's
time you took a little break.
Get an energy
bar and some juice.
- I don't need a...
- Do it anyway.
And when he gets back, I
expect everyone in this OR
to conduct themselves with
the utmost professionalism.
Can I get two
brisket tacos, please?
You know what?
Actually, make it three.
Thank you.
You're out of order!
Hmm.
She's out of order!
This whole traffic-court
hearing is out of order!
Okay, very funny, smart-ass.
Actually, I gotta
give you props.
You were right about
the LIDAR calibration.
- Hmm.
- If your phone hadn't rung,
you might've gotten off.
Next time, I will
turn my phone off.
Next time? You're
done. Case closed.
You're gonna start having to work
on upping your ride-share rating.
I'm obviously gonna appeal.
She was biased
against me from the start.
I see it all the time. Women
in power are worse than men.
No comment.
Order up. Brisket tacos.
Thanks.
- Oh, thank you.
- You want one?
I would love a beer, but I can't.
I'm on call for the next 17 hours.
You're still on call?
What would you have done if they
needed you while you were locked up?
I would've had them phone
my secondary coverage.
- Hmm. Hmm.
- I didn't see the point
in waking another doctor.
Or publicizing your predicament.
I'm competing for a promotion.
I didn't feel the need to
tell my boss I was locked up
unless I absolutely
had to. No harm, no foul.
Husband consented. We're
good to go whenever you are.
Scrub back in.
I'll be right there.
Oh, I'm gonna kill them.
- Okay.
- Oh, God.
- Sorry.
- It's okay.
What?
We had a patient come in this
morning with low-flow priapism.
We thought it was drug-induced,
but then I noticed a foot drop...
Cut to the chase.
We found an epidural abscess
with pelvic extension, and...
Get him prepped.
I'll be there in 15.
- What?
- I gotta go.
No. Is someone dying?
Not if I can get there in time.
Oh, um,
can you give me a ride?
Irrigate with
diluted bacitracin.
Morgan, irrigation.
Sorry, it's been a long day.
And you only have another
nine-and-a-half hours to go.
Only nine hours, 21 minutes.
Browne's right. This
flex-time schedule is absurd.
Yeah, it has its drawbacks.
But if this penis had been
passed on to the next shift,
they would've assumed
you missed something,
and they would've done
a whole new workup.
The delay could've
paralyzed him.
Or maybe they
wouldn't be so tired,
and would've noticed
the foot drop faster.
Guys, you're doing fine.
And you'll get
used to the fatigue.
After a while, it won't
even bother you.
It's easy for you to say.
You were on home call,
chilling on your couch all day.
Good point.
Orthotopic
neobladder's in place.
Let's make sure it drains
properly before we move on.
Flow looks good.
Hold on. Push it back again.
What's that, at the
base of the uterus?
It looks dusky.
Can I get some more dye?
That's a polyploid mass.
It extends from the
uterine to the ovarian artery.
All collateral blood
supplies have been invaded.
We're gonna have to
do a full hysterectomy.
What if we resect the mass and
graft the saphenous vein for bypass?
Risk of graft occlusion is
too high. She'd go septic.
The last thing she told us
was her lifelong dream
was to be a mother.
It's an innovative idea, but...
It's not our decision.
I'll scrub out and
talk to the husband.
No, I'll do it.
No, I can't make that
decision for my wife.
Yes, you can. You've
already done it once.
This is different.
But this is what Gina wants.
It's why she made you her proxy.
No, I'm her proxy
because she didn't think
she should ask her mother
and sisters to fly from Maine
for a minor surgery.
Look, you have to call them.
No, Gina chose you.
You are the one who knows
her, who truly understands her.
What would she want us to do?
I don't... I don't know.
I mean, how can any man...
Please, just tell me what to do.
I met her yesterday,
I barely know her.
So, you can be objective,
you can make the right call.
No, Gina didn't choose someone
to be objective, she chose you.
- Please, just tell me what to do.
- I can't.
You have to, because I won't!
I can't do that to her.
Please, just... Just help me.
Whatever you say, that's...
That's what I'll do.
Whatever you say.
Do you feel sorry for me?
Why would I?
Morgan says Lea is only nice to
me because she feels sorry for me.
Does Morgan have a theory
for why Morgan is so nice to you?
I'm being honest,
which is better than nice.
Cut this fibrinous tissue.
Bipolar.
Some women put a
guy in the friend zone,
and they end up treating him
more like a pet than a person.
Morgan has a point.
Some women do that.
But the only way to find out if
Lea does that is to talk to her.
The wound is clean.
No more macroscopic
signs of infection.
Any spinal nerve damage?
Won't be able to
tell until he wakes up.
So, what'd he decide?
He didn't.
He refused to make a decision.
He, uh, insisted
that I do it for him.
She really wants to be a mom,
so I think that we should try to...
No.
He chose me to
make the decision.
Her life matters
more than a dream.
Do a full hysterectomy.
You're right.
Let's go. She's already
been under for 22 hours,
and we got a lot more work
to do. Metz and a forcep.
Cut the uterosacral ligament.
Large pan.
Time?
4:10. She's been under
26 hours, 10 minutes.
All right, let's close her
up so we can wake her up.
I'll go tell the husband.
No, I'll do it.
Dr. Browne, you
take lead on the close.
Wiggle your toes.
All 10 are going to market.
You're gonna be fine.
And, uh, what about my...
He'll be fine, too.
- Thank you.
- Oh, don't thank me.
Those two are the
ones who saved you.
All on their own...
Almost.
What happened?
The endometrial lesions
were much more invasive
than we saw on the imaging.
In order to remove them all,
we needed to
reconstruct a new bladder
out of a section
of your intestine.
And we had to
remove your uterus.
Honey, I am so sorry.
It's gonna be okay.
I love you so much.
I love you, too.
Now that we've handled
the surgical crisis,
it's time we deal with the
unprofessional behavior.
The only question I have
is who exactly is to blame?
It was a 27-hour surgery.
There were some tense moments,
but I was very pleased
with how everyone
ultimately worked
together as a team.
I was especially impressed
with how Dr. Browne
aggressively stood her ground,
and insisted that I respect
the husband's final decisions
regarding his
wife's hysterectomy.
Is there anything the two
of you would like to share?
No, I'm good.
Well, I'd like to say,
I was very impressed with
Dr. Melendez's openness
to hearing input from
all of the surgical team.
It's definitely something all of
us on the nursing staff appreciate.
Very good.
Go home. Get some rest.
You're here.
Yeah, I am.
I shouldn't have
told you to go away.
It wasn't very nice, and
you've always been nice to me.
You've been a good friend.
If you want to
talk, I will listen.
You're right. I have
been a good friend.
Actually, I've been
an awesome friend,
but you have been a total jerk.
You were so worried
about me hurting you?
What about how you hurt me?
What, you think you're the
only one who has feelings?
You think you're the only
one who needs someone
who doesn't judge them, doesn't
make them feel totally alone,
like there's not one
person in the world
who actually gives
a damn about them?
Okay, I'm sorry.
No, you're not.
You're just... You're
just uncomfortable,
and you're trying
to get me to shut up,
which don't worry, I will, just
as soon as I finish telling you
that friendship is a
two-way street, Shaun.
A two-way street, you jackass!
Guess I was wrong. She does
think of you like a real man.
Are you awake?
Hi, Daddy.
Maddie?
How are you feeling?
It's so good to see you.
You're dead.
Don't you think I know that?
Am I dead?
No, dummy.
You're just tired.
Yeah.