We fight.
No, we don't.
You yell and then you go silent.
I yell because you...
We don't communicate.
There's no intimacy.
There's intimacy.
Okay. All right.
There's intimacy,
but we're not on the same page.
Because I don't do
what you want me to do.
Because you had an abortion.
We've done couples
therapy before.
He has PTSD.
From the war, and
she's had it, too.
From the shooting,
but not at the same time.
We didn't have it
at the same time.
And mine wasn't
as bad as his is.
You lay on the floor of an OR.
You choked me. You
quit being a doctor.
So...
For a little while.
But now we're fine.
Really?
Oh, sure. Okay. We're fine.
I meant the PTSD.
Okay. Yeah. We're fine.
We're fine.
Except for the part where you
aborted the child that I wanted.
Except for the part
where you held my hand
while I exercised
my right to choose,
and then four months later,
you screamed I killed your baby
in front of all our friends.
When you've tried everything
but that headache won't go away,
you can't stop coughing,
the swelling won't go down,
that's when you
turn to a professional.
So...
As surgeons, we spend years
developing skills of perception
that allow us to see
exactly what the problem is.
You haven't even looked.
Amy, I am telling you, it
is unresectable. Let it go.
I came all the way
from LA to show you this.
You could spend
more than 30 seconds.
I am looking right at it.
It's a gliosarcoma that has
invaded the carotid artery.
You try and remove
it, she will stroke out.
Stop being a jackass.
I'm... She called... She
called you a jackass.
Dr. Grey, excuse us.
Dr. Grey, stay
here. I need backup.
Fine.
You just got out of rehab.
I want you to get on your
feet. But you can't help her.
Look at his face.
His name is Mason.
This gliosarcoma belongs
to his mother Erica.
He's a great kid. I
don't know him that well,
but he seems great.
I do know his dad well.
His name is Cooper,
and he works with me
and he is a good guy.
He is a good dad, which
means he is the one
who is gonna have to tell
Mason that his mom is dead.
That he doesn't
have a mom anymore
because we didn't do anything.
You tell Cooper
you're sorry. You tried.
Let it go.
I have a surgery.
Trouble is,
sometimes all that time spent
developing those skills of perception
can leave a person with an
extremely narrow point of view.
And how are you supposed
to argue with someone
who has science on their side?
65-year-old woman
enters the ER. In shock.
Presents with a pulsatile,
expanding abdominal mass.
Go.
Ruptured triple-A.
I would take the patient
straight to the OR.
And access the peritoneal cavity
through a vertical
midline incision.
Nice.
You guys studying for the oral
boards in the middle of the day?
Just another benefit of
having a study buddy.
You should get one. I have one.
It's just that my stupid
study buddy's too busy
trying to save her stupid
marriage to actually help me study.
Well, you know what's
better than a study buddy?
A study lackey. Check it.
Hey, you.
Brown-haired girl, you're up.
Trauma incident or
a surgical situation?
You made your interns
come up with study questions?
Surprise me.
A 12-year-old
boy fell off his bike,
hitting his abdomen
against the handlebars.
Complains of progressive
abdominal pain and is short of breath.
What is it?
Sloan. 911.
Hey, if you want, we could...
I don't need help. I'm
an excellent surgeon.
You know it, and I know
it. Everybody knows it.
I don't have to prove
myself to anyone.
Yeah, except to the
American Board of Surgery.
Yeah, there's them.
Meredith Grey.
No.
Not Grey.
Yang, maybe.
Yang's a cowboy.
Kepner.
Kepner?
Not Kepner.
Definitely not Grey.
She spent all
that time in neuro,
and suddenly, she's
chasing general.
She's unfocused.
You're underestimating her.
I think she'd surprise you.
She'd have to.
She will.
She'll have to come to me.
I'd do an exploratory
laparotomy.
You said that already.
I know. Um...
The patient's still
crashing? Yep.
Oh! I gotta crack
open his chest.
You've gotta what?
Relax. Not you.
Good morning, Chuck.
Hey, Karev. And, Dr. Peterson,
it's always nice
to see you in peds.
Thank you, Dr. Robbins.
So, Chuck's looking pretty good.
His abdominal pain's decreased,
and I think it's a good time
to schedule a gastroscopy.
Great, great. Well, then,
you're in luck, Dr. Peterson,
because I think that Karev
would be an excellent supervisor
for your first gastroscopy.
Thank you.
Okay, Megan. Let's go
schedule that gastroscopy.
Uh, it's Morgan.
What is? My name.
It's Morgan.
Whatever. Same difference.
Carrie Rissler is my patient.
Has been for eight years.
I'm aware.
She was given
six months to live,
but after a mastectomy,
oophorectomy,
and risky experimental
biological therapy,
I managed to save her life.
Which is awesome.
No, it is not awesome.
It is a miracle.
And when I saw on the OR
board that my patient, my miracle,
is undergoing a lymph node
transfer without my knowledge...
She came to us, Dr. Bailey.
Said she brought it to
you a few months ago,
and you shot it down.
'Cause her extensive scarring
makes her a poor candidate.
That's what I thought.
But then Avery suggested
we do some angio
studies on her arm...
Avery suggested?
Dr. Bailey, this procedure
has had outstanding results
for patients with vessels
just like Mrs. Rissler's, okay?
This could make it worse.
It could even kill her.
That's not gonna happen.
Well, you're right, it's not,
because you're not operating,
not after I speak to my patient.
You paged me
911 to get yelled at?
No, I paged you 911 so
that you could help me
convince Bailey we're
doing the right thing here.
You failed.
Okay. So what do we do now?
Well, let's hope Carrie's a little
bit more persuasive than you are.
Dr. Torres,
Dr. Webber suggested...
Here's how this is gonna
work. I talk, and you listen.
You are here because
you and your little pals
are all freaked out
about the oral boards,
and Dr. Webber
suggested that Callie Torres
might have a special
secret study method, right?
Mmm-hmm. Yeah,
Dr. Webber's correct.
Callie Torres does
have a study method,
an excellent study method,
but she's not about
to just give it away.
Callie Torres' study
method has to be earned.
Frankly, she doesn't think that
Meredith Grey has what it takes.
I think she does. I think
His BP was low and his
vessels are collapsed.
We could only
get one good IV in.
We're gonna have
to get another one.
For her sake, Meredith
Grey better hope she's right,
'cause today,
today is gonna be a grind.
Excuse me. Coming through.
Excuse me.
A grind? Really?
It's a meat grinder.
Whatever. Like you
weren't thinking it, too.
Hang in there, Dom.
Yeah, you're looking
good, bro, real good.
You're lying, Tommy.
I look like sopressata.
Don't worry, Dominic. We just
gave you some drugs for the pain.
Okay.
You're gonna start to
feel better real quick.
What do you think, Dr. Torres?
Is this an amputation?
I don't know. Is it?
What?
No, you tell me, Dr. Grey.
Does this look like
an amputation to you?
I mean, yeah.
Amputate? No, you
can't. I need my hand.
Tommy, don't let them take my...
All right.
Whoa! Is he... No,
those are the drugs.
They work quickly,
just like we have to.
But you're just gonna
cut off his arm? I mean, I...
No, this is a teaching
hospital, Mike, okay?
I'm doing a thing.
Grey, here's how it's gonna work
if you want my
help on the boards.
You're gonna run this. You're
gonna decide our course of action.
You're gonna be the person
that stands between Dominic
and a hook for a
hand. You in or you out?
I already said amputation
is our best option.
Oh. Best? Yeah, best.
Okay, so book an OR.
And fire up the bone saw.
Let's move him out, people.
Grey wants to amputate.
Yeah.
Dr. Torres, wait.
I have a finger here.
I knew that already, Dr. Grey.
No, a viable finger.
Look at the cap refill.
Is that bad or good?
Dr. Grey, is that bad or good?
That's good.
All right. So what
do you want to do?
I think we should take this
thing off and see what's left.
All right. Time's a
factor here, Grey.
Why is time a factor?
Because the longer
his hand stays in there,
the more we
compromise his circulation.
Tick tock, Dr. Grey.
So let's call up to
maintenance and get a Sawzall.
Mmm. You really
want to wait that long?
Fire and rescue
has tools. Better.
Okay.
Hey, these tools,
what are they gonna do,
rip apart the grinder?
To save his hand.
Yeah, we dropped a
couple grand on that thing.
You can't trash it.
To save his hand?
Mike, how long is it gonna
take you to get that thing apart?
I take it apart and
clean it every night.
We can get him out. Yeah.
Dr. Torres?
Can you do it in
under 45 minutes?
Give or take.
Grey? MEREDITH: Dr. Grey what?
Do I think it's okay to
let a couple of civilians
take apart the machine that's
grinding their brother's hand?
Yeah.
Let's do it. Okay.
I'm gonna need a
set of Allen wrenches
and a Phillips head screwdriver.
Make that two.
Stat!
Hang in there, Dom.
Hey, you paged?
Look, I can remove the tumor
and the diseased carotid together.
All I have to do is
run balloon catheters
in through the femoral,
place them in precise position,
inflate them to stop the blood
flow, do two arteriotomies,
then feed a heparinized
shunt into place,
and reestablish blood flow.
That's all?
Oh. And I have to
do it in 90 seconds.
Any more than that,
and she strokes out.
Is that even possible?
Not sure. I would
love to test it out.
We should set up a simulator.
Don't we need to
get Derek's approval?
Yeah, but that shouldn't
be a big problem...
He loves to say no to me.
That is his
favorite thing to do.
Maybe you should refrain
from calling him a jackass.
I can't help it,
'cause he is one.
Maybe I should
ask him. Would you?
Yeah.
He's in surgery, OR two.
You just called me down here
so that I would go to Derek for you.
Made me feel
like it was my idea.
Aren't I good?
Amazing.
I have always been clear.
You have not always been clear.
She loves to say that.
Always been clear,
I do not want kids.
He knew that. I
did not know that.
You knew that.
I did not know that
in the beginning.
What, I have an icicle in me,
and I'm supposed to tell a stranger,
"Hey, I don't want
to have kids?"
I'm not talking about the
icicle. I am talking about after.
After.
No, I told you when it was
relevant to the relationship.
Most people would've considered
dropping a bomb like that
before the wedding. That is
when it would've been relevant.
Well, you proposed and we
were married, like, 12 hours later.
So sue me if, in the moment,
I was thinking of other things.
I know the lymphedema is bad.
Oh, it's miserable.
These are sausages, not arms.
I can't lift them. Oh!
I'm in pain all the time.
I think...
Look, we just need to be
happy the cancer is gone
and look at the lymphedema as
the price we're paying...
The price I'm paying.
Oh, look...
You don't think I felt awful,
sneaking in here like a
thief to get my surgery?
You saved my life.
You know how I feel about
you. You're a hero to me.
But I...
I want to be able
to brush my hair...
Hold my grandson.
Erin had a baby?
Having one, in the spring.
Oh, my... She was just starting
college when you were first diagnosed.
I know.
You promised me I'd
make it to her graduation.
If you really think
this is a mistake,
I won't do it.
Okay. You got it?
You got it? I got it.
So what's your plan, Grey?
Okay, my plan is, they get this
thing off, and then we assess.
Right, but what if they don't?
You need an alternate plan.
Well, I don't need
an alternate plan,
because they're
gonna get it off.
What'd you do? I
didn't do anything.
The more you guys loosen
that, the more he's gonna bleed.
Should we stop?
No, keep going, just go faster.
You sure you have time for that?
If you have something
to suggest, why don't you?
Now you're just
wasting everyone's time.
Well, we have to get him up to
the OR or he's gonna bleed out.
Yeah, well, his hand's
still trapped in that grinder.
Let's get a pneumatic tourniquet
on his arm above the grinder.
That'll buy us a few minutes.
Okay.
I can give you guys 15 minutes,
and after that, I
have to amputate.
Understood.
We've operated on worse.
Lexie, she showed us
a picture of a little boy.
I know. It's clear that
she is passionate...
My sister is too emotionally
wrapped up in this patient
to clearly see that she
can't help this woman.
You know, it tells me that
she's passionate
enough to try harder.
Yeah, well, all the
passion in the world
is not gonna make her
plan doable in 90 seconds.
You need to see that
for yourself, fine, set it up.
Only you're gonna be
the one who sees a thing.
I mean, thank you.
Dr. Robbins said I
would be doing this.
Yeah, how can you do a
gastroscopy and read the index cards?
Come on. Keep them coming.
Congenital aganglionic
megacolon, also known as...
Hirschsprung's disease.
Typical treatment?
A pull-through procedure.
Did you skip symptoms?
Uh, symptoms, right. Sorry.
Don't crap out on me now, Megan.
Morgan.
Symptoms are
severe and persistent
tightness in chest,
indigestion, blurred
vision, shortness of breath...
Yeah, that's not Hirschsprung's.
Severe headache, nausea.
Patient is 24 weeks pregnant.
Yeah? Well, that narrows
it down. It could be PIH.
Yeah, I'd order labs and a UA.
Then I'd take her down to the OB.
So she could be monitored.
Okay. Yeah. Yeah. You
should probably do that.
Hey. Hey. Hey!
Hey!
Are you gonna just stand
there or are you gonna help her?
Morgan?
When were you gonna
tell me you were pregnant?
Everybody in this hospital
knows that I'm pregnant.
But then they also know my name.
Well, there's a
good fetal heart rate.
The baby looks fine. These
are definitely not contractions.
List the symptoms.
I am not quizzing you right now.
No, your symptoms.
Chest tightness...
Nausea, shortness
of breath, indigestion.
You mean like heartburn?
Page cardio.
You're having a heart attack.
There is no deeper reason.
There has to be.
I wasn't abused. I
don't have a dark secret.
I wasn't mugged by a
baby. I just don't want kids.
Nobody doesn't want kids.
People can not
want kids. It's a thing.
That is not a thing.
Well, it's my thing.
You're gonna change your mind.
You're gonna change your
mind in three years or five.
mind about having a baby,
and then it's gonna be too
late. And you're gonna regret it.
And I will know and understand
that I made a choice.
I choose medicine. I choose me.
I choose that over
the remote possibility
that I might one day
regret not having a child.
And by the way, it's all
right to never want kids.
Some people don't
ever want kids.
Well, I want to know why.
Why?
In 2004, I was removing mets
from Carrie Rissler's
abdomen and pelvis,
and decided to go for one near her
liver when she started bleeding out.
As I was trying to stop the
bleeding, she went into heart failure.
I had to send her to the ICU,
tell her daughter Erin
that she was in a coma
and that there was a good
chance she wouldn't wake up.
But she did.
And she still had two
more surgeries ahead of her
and chemo and radiation.
Her body is a battlefield...
I get it. You
talked her out of it.
No.
You're doing the
lymph node transfer,
but not without reading
every page of this file twice.
But we're supposed to
operate in half an hour.
Then start reading.
Okay.
I'm watching you, Avery.
Yes, ma'am.
- Come on.
- I almost got it.
Come on. Come on.
BP's dropping, Grey.
You guys need to be done now.
Just one second, Dr. Grey.
Just one more...
And done.
We should be able to turn
back the auger and pull him out.
No, we'll pull him out.
It's time for you to go.
Grey, take this. You've
got the auger. Okay.
Look, can't we just
stick around and see...
There we go.
Holy God.
Okay, so... We've got a piece
of hand with sort of fingers on it.
What about these?
Can these be saved?
I don't know. Can they?
Boom!
97 seconds.
Bite me!
Sorry.
Just...
Sorry. I just...
I've been at 97 seconds
for eight freaking tries now.
Maybe not the ninth.
If I can find another stopwatch.
I mean, Derek's probably right.
I'm just... I'm
gonna let her down.
He should know. I've let
him down enough times.
Let's take a break.
Let's go... You want
to get something to eat?
I want something.
It's not food.
There's a guy who got his
hand stuck in a meat grinder.
I wouldn't mind seeing that.
Yes.
Okay, Morgan,
you had an acute MI
from a spontaneous
coronary artery dissection.
Are you kidding? I don't
have any of the risk factors.
Yeah, well, most likely,
related to your pregnancy.
We need to get you
upstairs right now.
Dr. Robbins, why are you here?
We need to repair the
dissection immediately.
My baby's fine, right? You
said that my baby was fine?
Morgan, listen to me...
If my baby's fine,
why are you here?
Lie back, lie
back, listen to me.
All right, we need
to go right now.
But it's too early to
take the baby out.
He, she could have
RDS or get septic?
The dissection's extensive.
We have to put you on
bypass in order to fix it,
so the baby needs
to be delivered now.
She barely has any lungs.
Twenty-four weeks is premature,
but there's a very good chance.
No, you can't say that, okay?
I know what you can and
can't say is very good...
And you can't say that.
My baby was born at 23 weeks,
and it's terrifying, I know,
but I'll be here for you.
We're all gonna be here.
Will someone call my boyfriend?
His name is the
first in my phone.
All right. Karev,
call her boyfriend
and let him know
what's happening.
I'm scrubbing in.
She's your intern, Karev.
Yeah, okay.
Uh, wait...
Her name's, Megan, right?
Her name is Morgan.
Ugh!
Grey, I'm surprised.
I wouldn't think you'd be thrown
by a little thing like
a severed finger.
Yeah, well, it's just,
it smells like pork.
Mmm-hmm.
There she goes again.
She's gonna yack.
Would you quit it
with that, all right?
I gotta finish this thing
before I go into surgery.
Hey, where is your study lackey?
Of course the one competent
intern in the whole program
just so happens to be pregnant
and needs surgery for a
coronary artery dissection.
Morgan needs surgery?
How do you know about Morgan?
Everybody knows about
the pregnant intern, Karev.
There's my ride.
Here we go.
If Morgan needs surgery,
then why are you here?
My attending gave me
a job, call the boyfriend.
I left, like, six messages.
Chris is a fourth year
at the Cleveland Clinic.
I mean, you know
how busy it gets.
How do you know his name?
They're not just amputating
and fitting him for a prosthetic?
No. She thinks
she's gonna be able
to salvage the finger
bits and reattach
because she's cracked.
That's gonna be so much harder.
You know what else
would be harder?
Going through the carotid.
For fingers?
It would be harder,
but there'd be better control
than going through the femoral.
All right. All right. Come
on. Here we go again.
Come on, Mer. Just a few chunks.
Come on. Just puke already.
Oh, that's a
good-looking lymph node.
You got it? Yeah.
- Oop!
- Did he say "oops"?
Dr. Bailey.
What a pleasant surprise.
The man said "oops."
JACKSON: I didn't.
Actually, Dr. Bailey,
I just said "oop."
He was picking up a lymph
node, almost dropped it, but didn't.
Let's make some
room so Dr. Bailey
can get a better view
of our every move.
As you were, Avery.
You don't want a little
more suction, Avery?
Dr. Bailey, while I'm always
glad to hear your perspective,
I'll instruct the resident.
But your instructions
result in oops.
We don't oops in my OR.
Let's try a little more suction.
With Mr. Hamilton's laminectomy,
I want an epidural drain
for the next few days.
Yes, Doctor.
You should at
least listen to her.
Look, I swear, you gotta
stop encouraging her.
Well, this is what
you taught me to do.
You taught me to not give
up until we've tried everything.
Because you can handle it.
When we lose a patient,
I know if you're
okay or you're not
because I'm right
there with you.
With her, I cannot do that,
because I don't think
she can handle it. Not now.
You are the one who is
too emotionally involved.
Okay, if this tumor had come
to you from any other doctor,
you would still
be looking at it.
You are so worried about
your sister's outcome,
you won't even think
about her patient's.
Am I wrong?
You have to try.
I am. I'm trying.
We're supposed to focus on each
other and breathe, and you're not.
I mean, your mind
is totally elsewhere.
So now you know my
every thought and intention?
We used to be able
to look at each other.
And I'd feel...
Like we were gonna be okay.
There is a reason
we're together, Owen.
There is a reason we're married.
Please.
Look at me.
All right. I'm looking at you.
Right now.
I'm looking right at you.
He has to stop holding a grudge.
He has to see me for who I am.
He has to take his
little list of all my crimes
and rip it up, otherwise...
Otherwise what?
You know, I don't know.
How about you stop
thinking that you're the sun,
and that I revolve around you,
and that being a cardio god,
maybe that isn't everything,
and maybe what I need is
worthy of some consideration?
And we're back to the abortion?
Yeah. Yeah, we are.
I'm ready for the
transfer, Avery.
Dr. Sloan. Yes.
You know that this
patient has a history
of multiple
surgeries in that area.
She sure does.
Okay, then I don't
understand why you think
it's a good idea to continue
to dissect right there.
Respectfully, Dr. Bailey,
it's not entirely important
that you understand everything
I do every step of the way.
No, respectfully,
Dr. Sloan, I disagree.
I think it's
extremely important.
Now if you had read the
file like you said you did,
you'd know that she'd
have massive scar tissue
exactly in the area
that you're dissecting,
so I think going forward
with that dissection
is a monumentally
stupid course...
Respectfully, Dr. Bailey,
the bulk of that scar tissue is
gonna be found near her axilla.
So if Dr. Sloan continues
dissecting right there,
I really don't think
there'll be a problem.
And I read that in the file,
the file that you... Carrie's file,
that you gave me to read, I...
I did... I did read it.
Damn it. We've got
a big bleeder here.
Is that subclavian?
Respectfully,
Doctors, I told you so.
Okay, so I think it'll work.
If we cut down the
macerated part of the finger,
it'll be short, but it'll
still be salvageable.
Okay, but this thumb, I'm
gonna go ahead and say
that's not salvageable.
Yeah, you're done here.
He'll be better off
with a prosthetic.
No.
The thumb is responsible
for 40% of hand function.
Without it, we're done.
But there's gotta
be something else.
I mean, I read
something about surgeons
using a man's big toe as
a replacement for a thumb.
Let's do that. Let's
use his big toe.
Listen, Dr. Frankenstein,
the big toe,
it's pretty important,
you know, for walking.
And he can learn to rebalance.
Or he can keep
his toe where it is.
This is a good
fix. I know it is.
No, it's not.
Dr. Torres, it has to be.
The big toe is not the fix.
That is why we're gonna
use the second toe.
It'll provide the same benefits,
but reduce potential disability.
Really?
Yeah, but we're not doing anything
without the patient's consent.
All right. Tell me what
you're trying to do.
Uh...
I'm going in through the carotid
with two catheters,
one in the proximal...
A carotid stick?
That'll kill her even
faster. Damn it, Derek...
Amy, I'm sorry,
but you can't stop
and reestablish blood
flow in 90 seconds.
I mean, I can't do
it in 90 seconds.
Well, the great god of
neurosurgery has spoken...
Look, now I'm
trying to help you.
But please don't put yourself
through this. You're too fragile.
I am not fragile.
I'm a drug addict.
I've fallen off the wagon
twice, and I've gotten back on.
That does not make
you fragile, Derek.
That makes you
very freaking strong.
I am standing in a building
full of pills right now,
a fact that I am painfully
aware of, but I am doing this.
That is not fragile.
Okay.
Show me what
you're trying to do.
So you think there's a way?
No, I don't.
But I can't stop you, so...
I'll be here with you.
Show me what
you're trying to do.
I was right.
Right?
Too soon to tell.
Cut the crap, Torres.
You two are gonna put
a toe on a man's hand.
That was her idea.
Maybe we are.
His toe? Are you serious?
Maybe we're not.
Tommy, calm down.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to yell.
It's just...
That's weird.
Yeah.
But if I say okay, I
get my hand back?
Otherwise, you
fit me for a hook?
A prosthetic, but if
you give the go-ahead...
He gets a hand.
Well, what are you looking at
me for? Take my toe already.
Take my left nut if it'll help.
I think the toe will be fine.
I was right.
So...
This is how you're gonna
spend your time now,
pulling strings
behind the scenes
like some kind of puppet master?
I am really good at it.
So I'm a 2-month-old baby.
Symptoms?
I'm underweight, fussy, I belch,
and when I vomit,
it hits the ceiling.
You have pyloric stenosis.
These cards are so
detailed. Whose are these?
Uh, well, those would
be the smart one's.
The only smart one.
What the hell? What
happened to Morgan's baby?
Wait. Morgan had her baby?
Oh, crap.
One more clamp, please.
Well, is it subclavian? Can
you get under the clavicle?
Vascular clamp.
It's still oozing, Dr. Avery.
How do you want to proceed?
Um, I don't... I don't know.
Oh, he did not just
say, "I don't know."
Man, tell me what you see.
We're staring
straight at the defect.
You think we should
call in vascular?
No, no, I think we can
repair this ourselves.
Maybe patch it? Stick tie.
Patch it?
Yeah. Isn't that...
No, no, it's a good thought.
Get on that. Bovie.
Sorry, Dr. Sloan. Just
a little distracted here.
Dr. Avery, let me give you
one small piece of advice.
If there is anything,
I mean anything, distracting
you from helping your patient,
you need to leave it outside.
Respectfully, I...
This is your patient now.
Yours.
Someone had better
tell me what is going on
and had better
tell me right now.
Dr. Bailey...
You need to leave this OR.
Excuse me?
This patient, my patient,
developed a subclavian bleed
because we misjudged
her adhesions.
But I am now doing
an arterioplasty,
which is not an
easy thing to do,
and you are making it more
difficult by distracting me.
You are compromising my ability
to care for my
patient, Dr. Bailey.
Well, if you're telling
me you can't focus in...
I'm telling you you
need to get out.
Now.
Dr. Sloan, if you
let your resident
speak to an
attending this way...
Dr. Bailey.
I believe Dr. Avery
made it very clear.
Leave the OR
or I'll have you removed.
Get out of the way! Move! Move!
Damn it!
Wait. Is that for
the Peterson baby?
For the mother. It's not good.
All right. Get outta the way!
Come on. Come on.
Crap.
What the hell happened?
We were barely in the NICU
before he suffered an intestinal perf.
Scrub in. I need
your extra hands.
Uh...
Give me a minute.
Hello?
Yeah, this is Dr. Alex Karev.
I work with Morgan in Seattle.
Listen up, you're
fourth year, right?
Good. Listen up,
she's still in surgery,
but she's critical,
so's the baby.
You need to get on
a plane right now.
Meredith and I do not
do everything together.
The twisted sisters.
Yeah, well, we're best
friends. What do you expect?
She has a baby.
Oh, my God. That
doesn't mean I have to.
I don't see why not. You
do everything else together.
It's like you're a team.
Because she's my person.
I should be your person!
Be my person!
Be my person, Owen!
Be my freaking person!
Be my person.
He's dorsal dominant,
so I'm not going to
use a plantar incision
to find the artery. Okay.
And I have isolated
a good draining vein.
Uh-huh.
Is that it? You're not
gonna ask me if I'm sure?
Are you sure?
Yes.
Okay, then.
You're impressive.
I am.
Look, there's always been a lot
of hype surrounding you, okay?
"Meredith Grey, ooh, child of
Ellis. Ooh! Isn't she so special?"
You don't have to help
me if you don't want to.
No, no, no, that's not what
I'm saying. I'm saying...
You're tougher than I thought.
I'm saying you're smart. I'm...
Saying... Okay, look...
We've never been friends, not
even when I was with George.
Mainly because you thought I was
a freak and you're
blonde and very...
And now you have a
baby, and I have a baby,
and we're both married, and...
I don't know. I'm
saying we're both alike.
I'm saying I'll help you.
You're not a freak.
And we can be friends.
Every morning, five days a week,
you are in my
office at 4:00 a.m.
And we work, Grey.
If you don't show up, if you
are late, I will kick your ass.
We work, Grey. We work.
And you're gonna pass this
test. You're gonna pass it hard.
Okay. We've got it threaded.
We need to position the
balloons and then inflate.
You need to get
yours in position faster.
I think you should
do it. You can do it.
You just gotta
get in there faster.
Okay, ready? Inflate.
Starting the clock. Let's move.
Mr. Price is awake
and responsive.
And the rest of the
post-ops are done.
What are you doing?
We needed two surgeons.
One on the internal carotid,
the other on the external,
controlling the balloons. We've
almost got it to 90 seconds.
You think it's gonna work?
Well, let's not get
ahead of ourselves.
It's one step, one step of
a very complicated tumor.
He doesn't think
it's gonna work.
Well, we're gonna
go down trying.
That's all. Thank
you. You can go.
I want to go down trying.
All right. Pick
up the stopwatch.
Ready?
Hey, little boy.
I'm Dr. Robbins,
and this is Dr. Karev.
You've got a long
road ahead of you,
but we're gonna do
everything we can to help you.
And your mom, too.
How's she doing?
Morgan?
Um...
I haven't checked.
I ran a pregnant chick
all over the hospital today.
Made her quiz me
on my stupid boards
till she damn near died,
and I haven't even checked
to see how she's doing.
Apparently, I'm the only
person in this hospital
who didn't know
she was pregnant.
Because I'm too busy worrying
about my own stupid damn self
to even make an effort to
learn my interns' freaking names.
It doesn't matter if I
pass those boards or not,
I don't deserve that fellowship.
You know why I like you so much?
I honestly have no idea.
You remind me of me.
Peds surgeons? We're vicious.
We're the most hardcore
surgeons in the hospital.
I mean, when I was
a resident, I was...
I was a full-on horror show.
But that's what
it takes to learn
how to save tiny
humans like this one.
Yeah.
But do me a favor.
Learn your interns'
freaking names.
We may not like it,
but it really is important to
stop every once in a while,
get out of your own head,
and see the bigger picture.
Dr. Sloan, I need a word
with you about Avery.
Dr. Bailey, I have a patient.
He was right.
Avery, he was... Was right.
She's gonna be
able to use her arms.
So...
Why did I say no?
You were being careful.
Yeah, but she was
my prize patient.
I've done groundbreaking
work on her behalf.
You were a resident like Avery.
You get more experience,
you get more conservative.
Conservative?
Oh! Is that what
success buys you?
What, you get happy
and then you get scared?
Don't want anything
in life to change?
You're a grown-up.
You're risk-averse,
'cause you know risk
has actual consequences.
That's why we keep residents
around. They keep us fresh.
Are you telling me that
I'm not young anymore?
I'm trying to tell
you you've arrived.
Huh.
Oh.
You pull that crap
in my OR again,
I'll report you to the board.
Actually,
finding out that you've been
looking at things all wrong,
can be sort of liberating.
What happened?
You're fine.
You know, Altman, she
did a kick-ass repair on you.
My baby?
Where is my baby?
He's stable.
Okay? I mean,
that's the first thing...
He?
Oh, yeah. That's...
I guess the first thing,
he's a boy, and he's stable.
But?
He's intubated.
We're giving him
indomethacin to treat his PDA.
And he had a spontaneous
intestinal perf that we fixed.
Robbins, she's
observing him right now.
Listen, Morgan, he's
doing great right now.
And Robbins is watching
him, and, you know,
when she leaves,
I'm gonna watch him,
and, you know, I talked to Chris,
and he's on his way right now.
Okay?
Okay.
So, you know, I thought
I'd just hang out here
for a while with you, and, you
know, wait till Chris gets here.
Leave it at that,
if that's okay.
You're hanging out here because
it's quiet and
you need to study.
What? No. No way.
You should.
I would.
And suddenly you
see new potential.
New possibilities.
Okay.
Where you'd never
seen them before.
Done. Done.
We have blood flow.
86 seconds.
Call your patient.
Get her up here.
And that's all fine when a hopeless
situation suddenly looks good.
Unfortunately...
I'm afraid our time is up.
Sometimes it goes the other way.