-Previously on The Resident...
-The child you gave up
when you were 13,
he's-he's out there,
he's looking for you.
Well, I wrote back and I told
him I wanted no contact.
Hey, how's it going so far?
-Just enjoy the spa retreat.
-Okay.
I got this. I'm Super Dad.
Hey, do you want to get a bite?
That's really sweet,
but I am just whipped.
You know, it's not
like I meant anything by it.
I'll wait for you,
and we can talk
about moving in together.
Excuse me, I've been waiting
to get a cast.
Our tech just went home sick.
I'll have someone with you
as soon as possible.
And I don't feel great myself.
Hey, I don't see that
Winston ever checked out.
I'm gonna go down and check
on my patient
Winston Robards, okay?
♪ We don't know your thoughts ♪
♪ You stay bein' locked up
in the house
♪
♪ Baby girl,
the West's so far away
♪
♪ Just getting started, girl,
the best days are far away
♪
♪ That's not enough,
just call me up
♪
♪ Just call me up,
I'm coming to fix you
♪
Hi, it's Devon. I can't get to
the phone right now. Leave a
message and I'll call you back.
It's Leela. This is the third
time I've called or texted.
Call me back when you can.
I'm starting to get worried.
♪ I'm coming to fix you. ♪
Kit, I just wanted to talk
to you about last night.
Me asking you to dinner.
Of course, but can it wait?
I've got eight full hours
of bureaucratic nonsense
in my future.
A board meeting,
two high-end donor phone calls,
and a mandated kitchen
hygiene inspection.
-The board.
-Oh, thank you.
Oh, and I've almost
landed Dr. Browner
from St. Paul's Hospital.
Browner? The neurosurgeon?
He's a specialist
in skull-based tumors.
He'd be
a Barrett Cain replacement.
Expensive, but I'd love
to have him at Chastain.
Browner is a star
with a national reputation.
He would burnish our image.
Oh, come on.
Another item
to add to the list:
call Custodial
about the elevator.
Yancy.
-Yeah?
Elevator two is stuck
at the roof. Go take a gander.
Have either of you
heard from Devon?
-I've been calling him
all morning.
-Probably overslept.
-Coffee?
-He doesn't oversleep.
And he said he'd quit
after he rounded
on his last few patients
last night,
and then he didn't
text me after that.
Might have turned off his phone
and fallen asleep
in a spare room. I've done that.
More than once.
I'll try the on-call room.
That's probably the answer.
That's odd.
Oh, my God.
This is Yancy. I need help.
By the helipad.
I need a doctor. Hurry!
♪
-Hey, watch out!
She's ODing. We need
to get her to a hospital.
No, no, no. We drop her
back at the dorms.
Campus security will find her.
Yeah. Yeah, yeah. Good idea.
They'll take care of her.
They'll take care of her?
With what--
Band-Aids and a flashlight?
Dude, if we take her to the ER,
they're gonna call the police.
Then they're gonna
drug test her and us.
Then they'll call the school
and we'll all get expelled.
So you'll let her die to protect
your B.A. in French Literature?
You know you'll lose
your scholarship, too.
He doesn't care, okay?
He can go
-anywhere he wants.
-Okay, you guys can bail.
I'll take her to the ER myself.
Hospital, now!
Okay! Okay, okay, okay, okay.
Hi.
-Hello.
-Ah.
Look at that-- no crying.
The perfect drop-off.
Oh, my gosh.
When your mom
comes over tonight, mm,
she's gonna be so impressed.
Ooh... I love you, GiGi!
Say, "Bye, Da Da." Yeah.
Bye-bye.
Hey, man, are you a doctor?
My friend OD'd. She's still
breathing but she needs help.
OD incoming!
Need some help in here.
What did she take
and when did she take it?
Uh, I d-I don't know.
I just found her like this.
-What's your name?
-Trevor.
Trevor, listen to me carefully.
I need to know exactly
what drug she took,
otherwise I can't help her.
Two milligrams of a generic 3,4
methylenedioxymethamphetamine.
A party drug, like ecstasy.
But it wouldn't cause
respiratory distress like this.
Okay. So, maybe opiates, too?
No, no, no. She told me
she wasn't using those.
Conrad. It's Devon, he's hurt.
He's in Bay Ten.
Give her O2 and Narcan. Let me
know if she doesn't wake up.
We'll take care of her.
What the hell happened?
They found him collapsed
in the elevator on the roof.
-Is her responsive?
-Unconscious,
localizing to pain.
Devon.
Devon?
You know where you are, buddy?
-He's seizing.
-Push two of Lorazepam.
Hold him steady.
This better work.
-Done.
He's settling.
We need a scan.
I'll take him.
I'm going with you.
Irving, can you take
the OD in Bay Two?
Sure.
Hundley, with me.
Oh, my God.
Why are you here?
-I'm not here to see you.
-Please just
-lower your voice.
-W-Wait, wait, you think
I'm stalking you
in an ER? Are you really
that self-absorbed?
I know this is hard,
but I can't have you
in my life right now.
I told you that.
-I thought we had an agreement.
-Get a grip.
I am not trying to reconnect
with my birth mother.
I gave up on that.
The sign out front
said this was a hospital.
My friend's ODing.
She's dying. So maybe
do your job and help her?
I am a neurosurgeon,
not an ER doctor.
But our team here is great.
They'll take good care
of your friend.
Oh, and nobody here
knows about you, so please,
if you would just
respect my privacy.
Give her another dose of Narcan
and double the dose.
If she doesn't respond,
we intubate.
Giving .08.
This is dose number three.
Sleeping Beauty awakens.
What the hell?
Who are you?
Oh, damn it!
Son of a bitch, my head.
Oh. I was fine.
-I was...
-You weren't fine,
you were dead.
I doubt that.
Doctors are always saying
how they saved your life,
but it's crap.
Actually, it was your friend
that saved your life.
You OD'd.
He carried you into the ER.
Trev?
Hey.
You feeling okay?
I'm good. Better.
You really
carried me in here?
You're the best.
Seriously.
My hero.
Knight in shining armor.
Okay, here's the deal.
Hospitals freak me out.
I feel fine. I'm leaving.
I've got a sick doctor
going to CT
and I see ten ODs a week.
I don't have time
for your nonsense.
You leave when I say you can.
101.4.
Could be the drugs you took,
but have you been having
any fevers at home?
Any cough or cold?
Mm-mmm.
Anyone ever tell you
you have a heart murmur?
No. Why are you asking?
Page Raptor.
We need an echo.
There's a lot
she's not telling us.
We just heard.
How is he?
Still profoundly altered.
Bradycardic, hypotensive.
Well, a nurse told us
he might have been assaulted.
Was there head trauma?
Bruising and lacerations,
but I'm reserving judgment
until that CT comes up.
If he was assaulted
in our hospital,
I have to call the police.
Scans are coming up now.
Well, that's a normal
head CT.
No evidence of stroke
or bleed.
Which rules out brain injury
as the primary issue.
I don't think he was assaulted.
Look at his lungs.
-Bilateral infiltrates.
You know, he could have
aspirated when he was down,
and that would explain
the hypoxemia.
He might have, but that wouldn't
explain the seizure.
I just don't know.
Let's review the differential.
We ruled out brain bleed.
And stroke.
-What about an arrhythmia?
Maybe it made him pass out
and hit his head.
It's possible,
but his EKG was normal.
Nothing strange on telemetry.
Are his labs back?
Uh, his potassium and magnesium
are okay.
His urine tox was negative,
but his lactate is sky-high.
He's got profound
metabolic acidosis.
No, he's septic?
That makes no sense.
White count's normal, his
abdominal scan was benign.
No, it doesn't read
like an infection.
Must be something else.
Look at his watch.
His dad gave it to him,
but it was silver
and now it's black.
-It's tarnished.
It's blood.
A tarnished watch.
Frothy, blood-tinged secretions.
It's a chemical reaction.
His airways are involved.
And whatever it is crossed
the blood-brain barrier.
That's why he seized.
And if it's in his airway,
chances are...
It's a gas.
But which one?
-Carbon monoxide doesn't fit.
-Yeah, but hydrogen sulfide
would.
Okay. Yes, that's a possibility.
We'll keep him on oxygen,
bolus fluids and give him the
antidotes to hydrogen sulfide.
Leela.
We're getting there.
Something poisoned him
at Chastain.
If it was hydrogen sulfide,
then there is an imminent threat
-to patients and staff.
-Yeah, I know, I agree.
You stay, and I'll cover for you
with Browner and the board.
Are you sure?
I know all about
wooing arrogant doctors.
I won't blow it.
Thanks.
So I see you've had an
aortic valve replacement.
Your scar here in the
ultrasound tells the tale.
-What does that mean?
-Well, it means
your friend needed surgery
to replace the valve
that allows the blood
to exit the heart.
Sophomore year.
I thought I had the flu.
I... I'd been partying.
A lot.
And I collapsed in my dorm.
When I woke up in the hospital,
they told me I had
an infection in my heart.
Well, now the new valve
is infected,
which is why you have a fever.
And I'm guessing the source is
recent IV drug use.
You told me no more dope.
Junkie broke a promise.
I'm shocked.
I'm gonna go check on Devon.
My head's pounding.
Can we move on?
Sure.
You see that bright spot
on your heart?
It's called vegetation.
It means there's a mess
of germs and clot on your valve.
And these infections travel fast
in the bloodstream.
And given that you have
a headache,
my guess is your heart
is not the only thing in danger.
So I'm going to page
a neuro consult.
How's he doing?
He's on oxygen and fluids.
We gave him
the potential antidotes.
Fingers crossed they work.
He's waking up.
Devon?
Can you hear me?
W-Where am I?
Oh, my God.
You're at Chastain.
You're okay.
You're gonna be fine.
Did I almost die?
Definitely almost died.
Welcome back, brother.
How do you feel?
Like I drank a bottle of gin.
Three bottles.
-It really, really hurts
to breathe.
I got to go.
You scared us.
Hang in there.
What happened?
Do you remember anything
from yesterday?
Nothing.
That's okay.
It'll come to you.
-Okay.
Just take it easy.
We'll figure it out.
Get some rest.
If your breathing gets worse,
you tell me right away.
He can tell me.
I'm not leaving his side
until he walks
out of this hospital.
Probably not after that, either.
You called a neuro consult?
Yeah.
Yeah, the patient
is Janey Moore.
Prosthetic aortic valve
endocarditis with headache.
Excuse me.
Any trouble with your eyesight?
Double vision?
If I study all night.
Follow my finger.
Tell me about the headache.
Just a migraine, I think.
-No big.
-You've had one every day
this past week.
Exam suggests
a possible sixth nerve palsy.
She'll need a CT angiogram
of her head and neck
to rule out stroke, aneurysm
or abscess
related to the infection.
Ms. Moore,
I'll see you in imaging.
Oh.
Hey, hey, hey, hey,
hey, hey, hey. Hey.
Is she gonna be okay?
-I'll need to see her scans.
-Okay.
But do you think
there's something wrong
-with her brain?
-I don't know.
I mean, she's a junkie,
so there's that.
-What, is she your girlfriend?
-Not really.
Well, if I were you,
I'd count my blessings
-and move on.
-Oh, well, you don't know her.
And I'm not taking
romantic advice from you.
For obvious reasons.
You don't know
what you're talking about.
Oh. Well, you got that right.
Because I don't know
where I come from.
I don't know
why I am the way that I am.
I thought
maybe you could explain
-given the fact that you're...
-Excuse me.
Bro, you want to...
you want to explain this?
Oh.
-Yeah, right.
-Wait a minute. Hold on.
Where you going, bro?
It's, uh, it's an entactogen.
A dopamine agonist that bonds
to the serotonin receptors
but with zero effect
on the GABA receptors.
So it's a schematic for a drug
that you created?
Yeah. It's recreational.
For parties.
You know, emotional connection.
Bring people
out of their shells.
And if I'd known she was using,
I would've synthesized
a Suboxone equivalent,
-given her that instead.
-Hang on, how do you know
how to do all this?
I'm a medicinal chemistry major.
I formulated the drug
so she wouldn't get too high.
It's totally safe.
You can clutch your pearls,
act all outraged.
Whatever. I don't care.
The only reason
I was cooking that stuff
was to keep her happy
and off dope.
You think it matters
if your motivation
is to keep your dream girl
off heroin?
You're a drug dealer.
That's just the truth.
I don't sell drugs.
-I'm a chemist.
I create them for fun.
What I made
didn't put Janey
in the hospital,
because my science works.
Now, I'm fully prepared
to accept the consequences
of my actions.
-Can you say that
about yourself?
Oh,
you are not as clever
as you think you are.
-Oh, did I ask for your opinion?
-And you sure as hell
haven't earned
-the moral high ground.
-What gives you the right
to talk
-about a moral high ground
while you...
Hey, hey.
This is not the place,
all right?
-Uh...
Trevor, why don't you go
in the waiting area
and just give us a few minutes,
all right?
I'm calling the police.
Do it.
You know, if I wasn't
a semi-observant Buddhist,
I'd punch him in the throat
myself.
But it occurs to me
that if someone
called the cops on me
every time I deserved it,
I wouldn't be standing here.
Triple Board-certified all-star.
Now, clearly,
you two know each other.
Want to tell me what the deal is
between you two?
No, I don't.
What I want is to run the scans
on Janey's head
and be done with both of them.
Does Devon's recovery
mean he was poisoned
by hydrogen sulfide?
Unclear.
But seems most likely.
Hydrogen sulfide
mostly comes out of septic tanks
and manure pits.
Devon didn't leave Chastain
yesterday.
That means whatever he got
in his lungs--
hydrogen sulfide
or something else--
he inhaled inside the hospital.
Well, if there's a poisonous
gas leak in the hospital,
it could be devastating.
People could die.
We may have to evacuate.
Agreed.
But no one else is sick yet.
If we retrace Devon's steps,
account for every second
of the day,
there's a decent chance
we'll run into the source.
I'll talk to security.
I'll check with the nurses.
We have to figure this out.
Fast.
Hey, Bailey, what time did
Dr. Pravesh badge in yesterday?
Start of his shift.
7:00 a.m.
And he never badged out?
Nope.
Here all day.
-Thank you.
How many patients
-did he see?
-Yesterday in the ER?
There were too many to count.
Well,
any out of the ordinary cases?
-Toxins? Poisonings?
-No.
-I'd remember that.
Does he show up
on any of the CCTVs
outside the ER?
-Getting onto the elevator?
-We don't have cameras
in the elevators, and all
of our other CCTVs went down
-because
of the ransomware attack.
So Devon was in the ER
-all night?
-Yep. Well, all of my time.
-What do you mean?
-I had a half shift.
Uh, Shelly, the night nurse--
she finished up.
Hi, Shelly.
It's Kit Voss from Chastain.
I'm so sorry to wake you,
but we're trying to track down
Dr. Pravesh's movements
in the hospital last night.
Did you ever see him
leave the ER?
Do you remember
the name of the patient
he went to check on?
Winston Robards.
Fractured wrist.
Devon sent him for X-rays.
And a cast?
-Casting room.
-Thanks, Shelly.
You're an angel.
♪
Andrew!
Grab the wheelchair.
One, two, three.
I'm gonna take him to the ER.
Call Kit Voss,
tell her
to seal off the basement.
I'll notify hazmat.
No, I know Dr. Voss was sorry
she couldn't be here.
-Something serious came up.
-Honestly,
it's a chance to meet
the famous Dr. Bell,
so, uh, no worries.
You know, I-I'm-I'm gonna
spare you the small talk.
Chastain is a fabulous hospital.
It's full of smart,
hardworking doctors,
and yeah,
we're a public hospital,
so no, you won't make
as much money as you're used to.
But, you know, I look at that
as a chance to give back.
To our community,
to our young residents. And,
you know, and at this point
in my career, it...
This feels
like the right thing to do.
So come to Chastain.
You'll never be sorry you did.
Done.
That was considerably easier
than I expected.
Dr. Voss will be overjoyed.
You mind
if I just make a few calls
-just to do my due diligence?
-Would expect nothing less.
Uh, I'll text you
some phone numbers.
Great.
Janey's scans are up.
What you got?
Mycotic aneurysm.
The bacteria
from her heart valve
-lodged
in her anterior cerebral artery.
Well,
-that explains the vision issues
and the migraines.
-Mm-hmm.
And she has a sentinel bleed.
The aneurysm
has started to leak.
So you'll repair it?
Sure.
But not until we make a decision
on replacing her heart valve.
Until you make a decision.
Look, I know some surgeons
who would refuse
a valve replacement
on a drug user.
Some of my mentors, even.
But I say, look, if she's
strong enough for surgery,
this might be
the second chance she needs.
Third chance, actually.
She was born healthy, used,
got repaired, then used again.
And we have proof.
Her urine tox screen
came back positive for opiates.
-She's a chronic user.
-Great.
I recommend
clipping the aneurysm,
continue antibiotics
and hold off on the
valve surgery until she's logged
-some sober hours.
-Which could kill her
-before she has a chance
to recover.
-Whoa, hold up.
You get to decide
whether she lives or dies?
-You cannot be a part
of this discussion.
-What?
Who made you God?
Because that's what you're doing
right now. You're playing God.
Am I missing something?
You're not the patient
and you're not family.
Go sit in the waiting room.
Oh, I am not leaving.
And you're missing
everything, dude.
All you see
are these lab results.
You don't even know her.
Janey,
who's literally
the best person I know.
I'll call security.
Hold up, Irving.
Listen to me, dude.
It's not as simple
as her being a good person.
All right?
If I replace Janey's valve,
her recovery's gonna be tough.
Not just physically
but mentally.
She's got to stay clean.
That valve gets infected,
she won't live long enough
to get another one.
Without rock-solid support,
even my masterful
surgical skills
are useless.
Then I'll make sure
she stays clean.
No, she already
had you fooled once.
What makes you think
she can't spin your head again?
This is not about her,
Dr. Sutton.
I never abandon
the people who need me.
Never.
Bay 2, Doctors.
Janey is hypotensive.
She's crashing.
Her pulse pressure
wasn't this wide before.
I'm hearing crackles
half the way up.
Fluid is backing up
into her lungs.
I see a new paravalvular leak.
-This valve is shot.
-I can still repair
the aneurysm,
but we all know
that won't save her life.
What's the call,
Dr. Austin?
You fixing her valve or not?
It's not up to me to decide
how many chances
a person gets.
Brain first,
then heart.
Let's book an OR.
I'll start prep.
I'll get transpo.
I-Is she gonna be okay?
No guarantees.
They need to get her to prep.
That's gonna take a minute.
Meanwhile,
let's you and I have a talk.
Follow. Now.
Get him on 100% O2.
Bolus a liter
and give him what we
gave Devon-- sodium nitrate
and hydroxocobalamin.
It might be too late to work,
but it's worth a try.
Confirmed it was
hydrogen sulfide.
Rotten egg smell
all over the casting room.
I called hazmat response.
The basement's being sealed off.
Do we know
how long he was exposed?
Since last night.
Best hope is the exposure
was low-level.
Someone vented
the room he was in,
so it's possible
he got a small dose.
Well, here's hoping.
Look, if this is gonna be
a lecture on addiction,
spare me, okay?
I know it's a disease...
A disease that you can't cure
no matter what drug you make.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Seriously, man, uh,
there's nothing you can tell me
I don't already know.
Are you gonna
fix her heart or not?
Of course.
Okay.
Great.
And you won't let Dr. Sutton
talk you out of it?
What's your beef
with Dr. Sutton, huh?
Home come
you keep coming at her?
She's my mother.
That's why.
She gave birth to me
and then wanted
nothing to do with me.
So, if it seems
like I'm coming at her,
there's your reason.
Okay. Um...
Look, there's a, uh,
a surgery waiting room
on the fifth floor.
All right?
You go there.
And I'll call you
when the surgery's over.
You must have been quite young
when you had him.
I should have
figured it out myself.
Watching you and Trevor go at it
is like watching someone fight
with themselves in the mirror.
I don't want to talk about it.
I told you that.
And I heard you.
But we're going to be operating
on your son's friend.
I know you've had
a complicated day today,
and I want to respect that,
but I must
point out the elephant
in the room and ask...
I'll be able to do my job?
Well?
If you want to know,
I was 13 years old.
-Hey.
Hey.
Winston's recovering.
He's awake.
Lucid.
He breathed in a small dose.
That's a huge relief.
It's good to hear your voice,
Dr. Pravesh.
Dr. Hawkins says
you don't remember yesterday.
I don't.
But I thought
if I saw your face, I would.
Maybe if you just listen
to my voice.
I've been blind my whole life,
so that's how I remember people.
Your voice.
Your father's remedy
for everything
is to rub dirt on it.
I thought that was hilarious.
I sent you to get a cast.
You didn't come back.
So I went down
to the casting room
because I thought you were lost.
Hello?
Then you were out on the floor.
I could smell the gas.
Hey, can I get
some help in here?!
-I vented the room.
I tried to drag you, but I got
very dizzy. I-I just, like...
I remember I couldn't breathe.
I thought if I could get
to the elevator, get to the ER,
I could call for help.
Then everything went black.
You turned on the vent.
That cleared out the worst
of the hydrogen sulfide.
Winston had limited exposure.
That saved his life.
You saved his life.
Thank you.
Okay. First brain,
then heart. That way,
we get in and out safely.
You okay with that, Sutton?
You don't need to worry
about my focus.
Regardless of what's going on
outside of this room.
Good to know.
Okay, removing the skull cup.
Opening the dura.
Working my way down
through the fissure.
Cannulating the femoral artery.
Okay, I see the aneurysm.
Just need to establish control
around the blood flow.
Clip applier to me.
-Damn it.
The aneurysm ruptured.
I need your hands. Get up here.
All right. What do you need?
Consider me
-your assistant.
I need you
to suction the field. Now.
Come on.
Sutton, I watched you operate
on my mother.
You got this.
All right. Bleeding stopped.
I think I've got control.
-Straight clip, please.
Great work.
What'd you do?
Not sure.
Sometimes you get lucky.
-Or else...
We didn't actually fix it.
Her heart is failing.
She doesn't have
enough blood pressure
to bleed from the aneurysm.
-Chu, how we doing?
Not good, team.
Maxing my pressors.
It's the valve. It's blown.
Wide-open regurge.
I'm gonna have to crack
her chest open,
put her on bypass
before we lose her.
And this time, Sutton,
I'm gonna need you to help me.
Browner raked in the money
for us at St. Paul's.
He was a publicity machine,
as well.
-And his outcomes?
-Strong.
-Plays well with others?
-I think you'll be happy.
Okay. Well,
that seems to be the consensus.
Thank you.
Randolph.
Long time. What's up?
Tina. Quick question.
I know you worked
with Jim Browner
over at St. Paul's,
and we're thinking
of hiring him.
Don't do it.
-Excuse me?
-He's got
millions in lawsuits
against him.
Bullying residents.
Sexual harassment of nurses.
He threw a cell phone at a PA.
Broke the guy's nose.
He's a walking court order.
Every doctor I spoke to
at St. Paul's
gave him glowing reviews.
They're trying
to unload him on you
to get him off their payroll.
Classic pump and dump.
He's costing them a fortune.
I have one word for you.
Run.
Thanks.
All right, I'm inside the aorta.
This valve is totally destroyed.
Leaflets this thick
and inflamed,
patient's been sitting
on this infection for a while.
And yet she was determined
to keep it
from those around her.
Even as her heart
started to fail.
Some secrets need to be kept.
But they can corrode
nonetheless.
Hold my valve for me.
What made you decide
to give her the valve?
I'd always intended to
if it became necessary.
People make mistakes, right?
And like Trevor said,
no one should get to play God.
Not even surgeons.
In my OR,
there is no room for judgment.
Not for Janey.
Not for anyone.
Well, you were right.
Fits perfectly.
Now, listen,
when we leave this OR,
you don't have to see Janey
or Trevor ever again.
I'll handle the post-ops.
And I won't say a word.
To anyone.
Dr. Voss.
It was hydrogen sulfide gas.
How the hell did that get
into Chastain?
The hazmat team says it's
happened in hospitals before.
Techs dump plaster of paris
from casts down the drain.
It clogs the pipes,
so janitors
use acid-based cleaner
to cut through the sludge,
-and the...
-And the acid, um...
Mixes with the sulfate
in the plaster,
and you get hydrogen sulfide.
Right.
And how about the patient
Conrad found?
-He's gonna make it.
-Oh, fantastic.
Yeah.
But for all the good we do here,
sometimes running this hospital
feels like
a Sisyphean task.
Ransomware attacks,
gas leaks. So come on,
give me some good news.
How did it go with Browner?
You can't hire him.
He's got a raft of problems.
HR issues, lawsuits.
St. Paul's was just trying
to dump him on us.
-How did you find out?
-Every doctor I talked to
at St. Paul's
did nothing
but sing his praises.
Not a single bad word,
and it just s-seemed off,
so I called a friend,
and friends tell you the truth.
Oh, bloody hell.
Well... it's disappointing,
but at least we know
the truth.
Thanks for having my back.
Yeah, l-listen, I've been...
I've been meaning to talk to you
about this all day.
Uh...
Just wanted to apologize
for yesterday, asking you out.
We have
such a good thing together,
and I... I don't want
to mess that up
by stepping over the line,
so I promise,
it won't happen again.
Oh.
Really?
Because I was...
I was wondering
if you would want
to have dinner with me tonight?
Yes. Absolutely.
-I know
this great Italian place.
Open late.
Hey, it's me.
Just trying you again.
Call me back.
-Nic?
Yeah.
She's driving back from the spa.
I got to pick up GiGi. She had
a long day at the nursery.
I love my girls.
Thought we were gonna
lose you there
for a second.
I didn't like that at all.
Thanks.
Me, neither.
I'm really happy you're okay.
See you.
-See you guys tomorrow.
Thanks, Conrad.
So...
I was thinking...
Maybe we
should move in together.
So you can look after me?
If you're gonna keep being
a hero, somebody has to.
I'd love that.
Surgery was a success.
She's looking good.
The recovery
is going to be a beast,
but I'll check again
in the morning.
I get it.
No, really.
I do.
The defining experience
of your life is abandonment.
I don't know
what you're talki...
Just shut up.
I was the same way, bro.
I was hurt.
I was alone.
I lashed out.
See, I used my words
and my intelligence
like a bully uses his fists.
-And it worked for a while.
I felt good.
But it never gave me
the one thing
that I really wanted,
which was to belong.
Look, you're loyal.
You care.
Everybody sees it.
But in the long run?
That's not going to end well,
and I know you know that.
But you don't know me,
so I'm not gonna be the one
to tell you
don't go down that path.
But I will tell you
that if you do,
brother, you aren't gonna
end well, either.
See you in the morning.
I have to go check on a patient.
How about I give GiGi
a big kiss?
Oh, my gosh.
You ate all your food.
Let's see.
Let's see where she is.
-Mommy's gonna be
so impressed with you.
Ate all your dinner.
-Where are you going?
-What? I just... Oh!
Who's that?
Who's there?
Is it Mommy?
Yes!
Mommy. Mommy.
Mommy's home.
Let's go.
Whee!
Let's go get Mommy.
Conrad Hawkins?
There's been an accident.
Captioning sponsored by
20th CENTURY FOX TELEVISION
and TOYOTA.
Captioned by
Media Access Group at WGBH
access.wgbh.org