Previously on ER:
Got it!
They warned me about this
place. They weren't kidding.
This is the second time you've
been wrong about my patients today.
And you know
what? It's the last.
I wanna know where
the damn social worker is.
Covering two hospitals
by herself till midnight.
That's my excuse for being late.
What's yours for being an ass?
Dr. Lewis?
When do you need me to start?
Shock, shock...
epi, shock, lido, shock,
consider mag two grams, shock...
procainamide, shock,
consider bicarb, shock...
shock, epi, shock,
lido, shock...
consider mag two grams, shock...
lido, shock, consider
mag two grams, shock...
procainamide, shock,
consider bicarb, shock.
Shit.
- You going?
- Yeah.
I'm sorry. Rounds start at 7.
It's barely even light out.
Yeah, well, welcome to my life.
Nice meeting you.
I'm killing my plants, ignoring
my bills. I have to get it together.
- What's a loading dose of amiodarone?
- Neela, stop.
And remind me to buy
toilet paper on the way home.
This is weird. Don't
you think this is weird?
Am I destined to spend my youth
in a fetid, windowless hospital?
You needed a job and now
you're here. Quit whining.
I'm not sure if this
is really what I want.
Well, fake it.
Does everyone know I
had a meltdown and quit?
Hey, Dr. Jumbo
Mart. How you feeling?
Need a doctor over here.
Fifteen-year-old,
multiple GSW to the chest.
Tachy with shallow resps,
18 gauge in the right antecube.
- Hey, man. What's your name?
- He's apneic. Throw me that bag.
Sam, we need a trauma room.
Nothing's open. We got
them lining the hallways.
- Get an Attending. SAM:
Lewis is doing a subclavian.
He's lost his pulse.
Starting compressions.
- Eight-0.
Mg of epi. Atropine ready to go.
- Got it.
- Tube.
- Neela, could you open his shirt, please?
I'm in. Neela,
listen to the chest.
Neela, come on!
- IV's infiltrated.
- I'll give it endotrachially.
No breath sounds on the right.
- Okay. He needs a chest tube.
- Open a chest-tube tray.
- You carry a scalpel? RAY:
Yeah. Bone saw's too bulky.
Could you take
over for me, please?
- No carotid.
- Atropine and another epi.
Forty French on
a Kelly, right here.
A huge hemothorax. ABBY: Oh.
How come nobody told
me you were such a badass?
Got a pulse.
That's what I like to
see, interns with initiative.
Come on. Trauma 2's open.
Someone call Housekeeping.
Next?
And finally, in Curtain 3, we
have 3-year-old GB here with RW.
- RW?
- She's going crazy...
- with this patient-privacy thing.
- What's RW stand for?
- Really whiny?
- Refusal to walk.
"Refusal to walk" has
its own abbreviation?
Neela, what's your differential?
- Septic hip.
- Intra-articular infection...
toxic synovitis, osteo, sickle
crisis and avascular necrosis.
- What about the workup?
- CBC, sed rate, cultures, x-ray...
and arthrocentesis
if there's an effusion.
Wow, first day back and
she's showing up you bums.
Dr. Pratt, what's the most common
pathogen found in septic arthritis?
Dr. Barnett, septic arthritis?
Um... Med students...
for a new dishwasher and
a lifetime supply of Ensure:
What is the most common
bug in septic arthritis?
- Staph aureus.
- Followed by strep and hemophilus.
I gotta go. Chuck's
waiting in the car.
- I guess the dream team is reunited.
- Ha, ha. Cool.
Yeah.
Good morning, Urbanus.
Guess I'm with you again?
Over 60 in Triage. Some of them
were here when I left last night.
Okay, Pratt, run the board.
Let's move some patients, huh?
Okay, people,
come on, listen up.
For the past month, we've
been cutting you a lot of slack.
- You have?
- Today the training wheels come off.
You're doctors. It's time to
stop thinking like students...
and take on a real patient load.
I want you to discharge
25 patients this shift each.
- Twenty-five?
- It's just two an hour.
Med students, present
your patients to interns.
Interns, run your cases by me or an
Attending before ordering labs or scans.
All right, here we go.
Ray, asthmatic in two.
Abby, PPD reading.
Neela, teenager with a cough.
Something nice and
easy to get you started.
Twenty-five each.
And I'm counting.
Only ones left. I guess
that makes us a team.
Oh. Jane Figler,
fourth-year medical student.
- It was quite a flash entrance you made.
- Thanks.
With rumors about how you
freaked out, it's great how you...
- came in and set everyone straight...
- Excuse me.
- Can you sign my procedure log?
- Mm.
Chest tube in your first five
minutes. Trying to impress me?
Just so you know, I don't
want you to go easy on me.
Believe me, I won't. If
you need help, just ask.
Dude, I forgot. Kuharczuk
in Curtain 4 needs a pelvic.
You're signing out a
pelvic? That's weak.
I gotta get out of here,
man. I'm back in 11 hours.
She's yours.
And by the way, nice move starting
late. Makes internship shorter.
Okay, so I gotta ask.
Why did they kick you out of Michigan?
- Chocolate?
Okay. History of two ICU admissions
and prior intubation a few months ago.
We gotta be aggressive with
this guy. Chuny, chocolate?
- Uh, no, thanks. I'm trying to watch it.
- You? You can eat whatever you want.
Okay. What do you need, Ray?
Could you please hit our
wheezer in 3 with 60 of pred?
- You got it.
- All right.
Lesson number one: Feed the nurses.
It'll make the jobs 50 percent easier.
Hi. Chocolate?
Too early. We like
bagels in the morning.
- No, no. Come on, take one for later.
- Ooh, hazelnut.
- Where do we keep peak-flow meters?
- Uh, in drug lockup...
- and, yes, I will get it for you, Ray.
- You're the best, Sam.
The result is borderline
but your steroid use...
and your incarceration
put you at risk.
- For what?
- TB.
- So I do have it?
- Not necessarily.
- Okay, can I see a doctor?
- Sir, I am the doctor.
We're gonna get you a chest
x-ray and a couple more tests.
Do we call it positive
and treat with INH?
See what the x-ray says.
Does a positive PPD involve type
three or type four hypersensitivity?
Sorry. Obscure question,
just trying to impress you.
Community-acquired
pneumonia, mycoplasma...
viral pneumonitis, reactive
airways, pulmonary edema...
- tracheal foreign body...
- Stop.
His chest is clear. It's a cold.
Fluids, ibuprofen and home.
I've got a guy with an equivocal
PPD and a load of risk factors.
- Does he have to take INH?
- Call ID, check it out.
- Okay. Let's look it up.
- No, no. Ha. He'll go look it up.
It doesn't take
two to open a book.
Delegate to your student
and find a new patient.
See, look at Ray. He's discharged
his second patient already.
Come on, pick it up, ladies.
He's making you look bad.
- Need a doc over here!
- Hey, go.
Dropped right in front of us.
Transient, LOC. Never even signed in.
Hello, my name is Dr. Rasgotra.
- Can you tell me your name?
- Juan Enriquez.
I forgot to eat
breakfast, that's all.
- Let's get him up.
- Oh, he's bleeding.
- Pulse is racing.
- I'm... I'm okay.
- Chuny, what's open?
- Exam 2.
- I just gotta go... Gotta go home.
- Just a second.
What are the bruises from?
I noticed them last night on my
legs, but I really didn't think much of it.
When I woke up this morning,
it was... It was much worse.
- Okay, let's go.
- Seven-year-old with a lead level of 59.
The city notified the family
three weeks ago to come in.
Three weeks ago? Okay,
what does that tell us?
- He's got bad parents?
- It tells us his lead exposure is chronic.
If he was poisoned, he'd have symptoms
and there's no way they would wait.
- Does this case belong in the ER?
- No.
They wouldn't wait here unless
they didn't have someplace else.
System's broken.
Can't blame the victims.
Good morning, Mr. Lucas.
I'm Dr. Barnett. Heard
you have a lead problem.
- Am I getting a shot?
- No, man. We wouldn't do that to you.
They, uh, tested him at school.
I don't know how he got it.
The city will send somebody to
your house to look for sources.
He's always been
sick. Born early.
But look at you now, tough guy.
- You a pro football player?
- No.
He had breathing problems
when he was a baby.
How about basketball?
- Aren't you the point guard for the Bulls?
- No, I'm in first grade.
Lucas, dude, you're playing it
cool but I know you're famous.
So I'm gonna have to ask
for your autograph. Okay?
Do a quick head-to-toe. Okay.
- Hey, lead clinic, please.
- Just a minute.
He had a seizure
once when he was 2...
- when he was sick.
- Febrile seizure. It's very common.
Hey, it's Dr. Barnett in the ER.
Yeah, I have a 7-year-old with an
elevated lead who needs chelation.
Okay. Thank you very much.
Okay, you're all set. A nurse
will walk you over to the lead clinic.
- Okay. Thanks, doc.
- Punch it.
I'm gonna sell your autograph
on eBay for a million dollars.
- A billion dollars.
- All right.
Let's go.
Five-minute discharge,
boys. Watch and learn.
Are troponins useful in ruling out
coronary aneurysms in Kawasaki's?
Aren't enough
good studies on kids.
Do ex-preemies have a
problem with lead metabolism?
No. Patients will tell you
all kinds of irrelevant crap.
- They don't know what's important.
- You're so patient.
The key is to look like you're listening
while you're doing your charting.
Multitask.
Guys, it is the key to survival
in the ER. There you go.
Is that really the best
advice you can come up with?
- Second best. First was feed the nurses.
- Well, they're students.
They should focus on taking a
history and learn efficiency later.
Med school teaches them to
practice medicine in fantasyland.
Never gonna clear that room if it
takes us two hours working up a case.
No such thing as a slam-dunk
case, not as an intern.
Suit up. We got a
trauma coming in.
Jet ski crash. Injuries
to head and neck.
Tachy and hypotensive, 78 palp.
GCS one, one, one in the field.
Check out the asthmatic.
This may take a while.
- On my count. One, two, three.
- Okay, on my count.
Got a 911 page. Looks
like I'm in the right place.
Yeah, jet ski accident.
Okay, Abby, your patient.
- Too much trauma...
- Poor aeration.
We're gonna need a crike.
Weak carotid. Crike tray to me.
- Can I hear vitals?
- Access?
- One peripheral.
- Start another one.
- Hang a liter of LR.
- Do we have a pressure yet?
- His wife is here.
- Get this?
Why don't we give the doctors room to
work and I'll explain everything to you.
Why don't you call
the blood bank?
- Full trauma panel, type and cross for 6.
- Sats only 84.
We need a portable chest
and respiratory down here.
Get him a blanket. He's cold.
- Blood bank.
- Hi, I need four units of O-neg in the ER.
- What happened? That was yours.
- No, it's a trauma.
- No medical-record number yet. Thanks.
- Don't say thank you...
- and don't let the boys bully you.
- I wasn't letting the boys...
You play with your hair
when you're nervous.
I can't get a vein.
Get back in there. Your
patient needs a central line.
Chest x-ray's clear.
CT's negative...
- BP's better after 2 liters.
- What does that mean? Huh? Is it bad?
- It's too soon to make any diagnosis.
- Just hang in there.
It sounds like the
fluids helped you.
You ordered a CT, films and
labs without talking to me first?
- You were busy.
- So where's your student?
- She's in Sutures taking out stitches.
- You know, I really don't get it.
I mean, you're proactive,
you're delegating...
and yet you're
still in last place.
Here. Med refill, five minutes. Go.
Ray and Abby are stuck in Trauma.
This is your chance to catch up.
- Femoral's in.
- Sats down to 78.
Neck's too mangled.
Anatomy's distorted.
Feel the landmarks.
Jet skis account for 20 percent of boats
but are involved in 44 percent of injuries.
- Know why that is, Dr. Lockhart?
- No. Three-0 nylon.
No is right. No throttle,
no steering, no way to stop.
- Still can't find...
- You're fine.
Make your cut.
Extend with the clamp.
Good. Perfect. Insert the tube.
So if this poor guy hit a pylon
driving his jet ski 30 miles an hour...
what was the equivalent G-force?
- Got it. Give me the bag.
- Seven G's.
This guy's head was subjected to 7
G's of force. That's equivalent to...?
- We're doctors, not physicists.
- Uh, pressure's dropping.
- V-tach. Lost the pulse. Take the airway.
- Starting compressions.
The impact of 999 pounds
dropped on his head.
- That's what you're up against.
- Not all I'm up against.
- You're gonna shock him?
- Charging to 200.
- Watch yourself.
- I'm not near the bed.
Exactly.
You want me to grab the
paddles out of his hand?
Mg of epi, have lido on deck.
- You did it again.
- Did what?
The hair.
I mean, eight years of school. Most
people would just suck it up, you know?
- Diarrhea times eleven months?
- What did your parents say?
- My dad would have ripped my head off.
- Why don't you start the history?
All right, guys, talk to me.
Homeless guy with gnarly feet.
Clotrimazole, new socks, home.
Seven-year-old with lice.
Permethrin shampoo, repeat in a week.
Good work, guys.
Keep them coming.
Still in the lead with 11,
Abby seven, Neela four.
Ray gets credit for those? He's in
Trauma, he didn't even see them.
- The students are part of his team.
- That's not fair. He's got two.
Can you handle two students?
You better go in with me. There's
a patient crouched in the corner.
Every time I go near her, she
starts, like, yelling in Chinese.
That galea. He's
basically scalped.
- Just tamponade the bleeding.
- He's maxed out on dopa.
- His pressure still sucks.
- Of course. Why?
- Spinal shock. DUBENKO:
Yep. No sympathetic tone.
- What do you want to do?
- Epi drip.
Get the BP up, increase
the cerebral oxygen delivery.
Right. Ready for
the cruel twist?
Systolic's 58. Come on, guys.
- Epi drip, one mic per kilo per minute.
- Didn't I just say that?
Ischemic brain needs
oxygen, but oxygen
also forms free
radicals after brain injury.
Mother Nature is such a bitch.
- V-tach.
- No pulse.
- Paddles to Lockhart.
Charge to 360. Clear.
Free radicals cause
secondary-cell death. You following?
Clear.
Can we take a break
from chemistry class?
Difference between a physician and a
witch doctor is appreciation of science.
These trauma algorithms should
be automatic for you by now.
- Oh, God.
- Barnett, take over compressions.
Look at his face.
His brain is gravely injured.
The brain is starting to
compromise his heart.
I didn't see it happen.
I told him not
to rent that thing.
I'm sorry, his body
is shutting down.
- Going again.
- You know, I was running this.
Really? I hadn't noticed. Clear.
Procainamide.
What?
Fine. It's all yours.
Clear.
So, wait, why did you
decide to come back, then?
- It's not like anything has changed.
- I don't know.
Neela, knee
sprain won't leave...
until she gets a prescription for
some memory pill she saw on TV.
- Positive tox on the kindergarten teacher.
- Thanks.
Get knee lady out of here
and meet me in Curtain 2.
- What do you want me to tell her?
- She can ask her primary doc.
Pratt, fix this order.
Teach your interns the difference
between micrograms and milligrams.
I can't be with them every minute.
- Excuse me.
If I've made a mistake on an order,
I'd appreciate it if you'd confront me.
I'd like to be
treated the same...
- and subjected to the same scrutiny.
- Neela, we weren't talking about you.
Oh.
Pupils fixed and dilated.
No gag, no corneals.
- Here. Sit down.
- Thank you.
So, what now?
- We wait.
- At least he's in sinus.
That means that the brain is no
longer capable of telling the body to die.
- Kovac needs some help.
- I got it.
Elena Flemming, 32,
poly-pharmacy overdose.
Paramedics
couldn't get the line.
Let me give it a try.
Elena, what did you take?
- The stuff that was in my cabinet.
- What was in your cabinet?
Usual stuff. I don't remember.
Urbanus, catch the paramedics, see
if they got any meds from the home.
- What's your plan?
- CBC, lytes, serum and urine tox...
Tylenol and salicylate
levels, activated charcoal...
- and KUB to check for iron fragments.
- Good.
And call, uh, Psych
and Social Services.
Elena, were you
trying to kill yourself?
I don't know.
- Looks pretty rough in there.
- Guy is brain-dead.
- They have kids?
- Three.
- Coming?
- No, they're too young.
- You okay?
- Yeah, it's part of the job.
Bruised guy's
CBC is finally back.
It's full of blasts.
You ever told anyone
they had leukemia before?
Part of the job.
ICU can't find a bed
for our jet ski trauma.
- They're not expecting to find one.
- He's gonna be with us for a while.
Why don't you call Social
Services for the wife.
What are you guys
still doing here?
Can't send them out until the
chart's signed by an Attending.
Okay, a 7-year-old was sent
by the city with a lead level of 59.
Asymptomatic, dispo'd
to lead clinic for chelation.
- Did you get a repeat level?
- Figured they'd get it there.
- Uh, come on.
- Tell me...
- Is that cool?
- No, Ray, that's not cool.
You've been a
doctor for a month.
You know you can't sign off
before you run it past an Attending.
So why don't you get a repeat
level and then I'll sign the chart.
- Where are you going?
- I... I need to go to church.
You're too sick to go
anywhere right now.
I need to talk to you about
the results of your blood test.
Juan?
I got one in my eye now. Look.
Your platelet count is very low.
That's why you're bleeding so easily.
Juan, your blood smear showed
some abnormal white cells.
The abnormal cells are crowding out
the healthy ones in your bone marrow.
Juan, please listen.
We can help you.
You can't... You can't
help me. Okay, nobody can.
Yesterday I hit a man with
my car. It was an accident.
But today I wake up like this.
Your blood pressure's still a
bit low. You need to be in bed.
I want to review your smear
and check on more labs.
And then I'll be back to go
over everything with you, okay?
Why didn't you tell
him he has leukemia?
Overdose only had antacids and a
bottle of Benadryl in the medicine cabinet.
She'll sleep off the
antihistamine and be good.
What the hell is going on here?
I've been here for four hours
and there's nothing wrong with me.
Sir, we honestly don't know.
You could have TB even
though you don't feel sick.
We are going to
recommend treatment.
You want me to take medicine for a
disease you don't even know I've got?
People tolerate the
medicine. There are risks.
You people are really something.
- Mr. Decoyte...
- I want a better doctor!
Whoa. I'm Dr. Pratt.
Can I help you?
I've been here all day
for a stupid skin test.
And no one here seems
to know if I've got TB or not.
The safest thing for us to do is
to treat it as if you do have TB.
If I were in your position,
I would do the same thing.
- Fine. Then get me out of here.
- Please, have a seat in the waiting area.
We'll get your discharge
paperwork and your prescription.
A good doctor knows how to make
"I don't know" sound reassuring.
Lymphoblastic leukemia has a
remission rate of over 80 percent.
- How did he take it?
- I should know the treatment...
before I tell him. Can
you page Oncology?
Okay, halftime score.
Ray fourteen, Neela seven.
The nurses were tied up in
traumas. It slowed things down.
So you're gonna blame the
nurses while you're on your ass?
Ray's using the same nurses and
discharged twice as many patients.
- My man.
- No more than 10 minutes in the room.
At seven, you start saying goodbye. You
better start wrapping things up in five.
There's a jammed
finger in Sutures.
- Go check it out.
- Ray, how is it that you get lice...
and I get new-onset leukemia
and a referral from Kazakhstan?
Wow. You got some cool cases.
Our boy in 4. I think it
could be intussusception.
You get jammed finger,
I get intussusception.
Are you accusing me of
cherry-picking charts, Neela? That hurts.
Evans Syndrome with varicella,
unexplained vision loss...
idiopathic proteinuria, LOC
NOS, cystic fibrosis with SBO.
Oh. And drug-seeking heroin
addict with a butt abscess...
who threw an emesis basin at
my head. Yeah, she was a winner.
Fine. I'm just slow then.
You're not slow. You're
just differently abled.
Ha. Don't let Pratt get
to you. Abby's slower.
Not that he'd ever
call her out on it.
But Attendings love
her, nurses protect her.
- Must be nice to be the teacher's pet.
- Screw you, Ray.
Oh, hi. Uh, good,
you're all here.
We didn't finish talking
about my research...
with free radicals and
superoxide dismutase.
It's good stuff. Hold up, hold up.
Come on, you might learn something.
Step into my office.
Right over here.
Free radicals are the link to so many
disease processes in the human body.
- Ischemia, cancer, aging.
- I think that's permanent marker.
They form after tissue
is deprived of oxygen.
Why are they bad?
Lockhart, we went
over this in the trauma.
We did?
Okay, what happens
when the radical...
encounters mitochondria
of a healthy cell? Lockhart?
Why don't you let me
do some research...
- and I'll present to you?
- I just told you the answer.
Okay, let's try this.
Draw an oxygen atom.
I'm not trying to trick you. This is
easy. Just draw an oxygen atom.
Look, you guys...
everything that
we do in the ER...
every intervention
ultimately operates...
at a molecular level.
I don't understand how any
of you expects to manipulate...
the complicated machinery of the
body if you don't understand the basics.
Okay.
There. I've done
the hard part for you.
That's an oxygen atom.
Now, all you have to
do is add the electrons.
I have patients to see.
You couldn't tell, really.
You didn't even seem upset.
I know how to draw
a damn oxygen atom.
That guy just gives
me the creeps.
Okay, that's truly disgusting.
Look, don't knock it. It's
fast, high in protein and free.
Sutures is à la casa,
Exam 4 splint and home...
and fever is just
waiting on a chest film.
Okay. That would be 17,
Neela 12. That brings you to 21.
- It's only 4:00.
- When I hit 25, can I go home early?
- Dr. Lockhart, what have you got?
- Diverticulitis versus biliary colic in 2.
In 4, MI versus reflux, and in
3, sepsis versus viral syndrome.
In Admit, Abby versus Ray.
Neela, you're getting your ass kicked.
Start making decisions
and move those patients.
Ray's logged 21 discharges
with three hours left.
- I guess 25 was too easy.
- Yeah, right.
- I better up the target to 30.
- Thirty?
Double your speed,
you might make it.
Pratt, your lacrosse player's
sedated. Come do his lid lac.
What? It wasn't
like it was my idea.
Dr. Barnett? Wendall
Meade, Social Services.
- Uh, yes. I paged you like four times.
- Yeah, in like 15 minutes.
If I don't answer you right
away, there's a reason.
Okay. I need you to talk to
Trauma 1's wife. He's brain-dead.
- Interesting name, "Trauma 1."
- Ben Coleman. Wife's name is Stacy.
- He's an intern.
- Ah. I see.
So referring to a patient by name
instead of room is a second-year skill.
- Did you go through the care pathway?
- The what?
The checklist that
systematically covers...
all postmortem issues
with the patient's family.
You need a list to check off
questions you'd ask anyway?
I'll see her when you're done.
- Contact dermatitis versus candida.
- Call it dermatitis.
Topical steroids and send her
home. It resolves, we were right.
- If it doesn't?
- She'll come back.
The overdose is waking up.
And here's the UA on
your tarantula dealer.
Ah, UTI versus kidney
failure. If I'm right,
she takes antibiotics
and gets better.
If I'm wrong, she becomes
hyperkalemic and dies.
I'm trying to
embrace uncertainty.
Oh.
- How am I doing?
- Not so good.
You know, you haven't had
anything to eat or drink all shift.
Go to Oncology and get a
copy of the chemo protocols.
- Isn't that Oncology's job?
- They said it might be a couple of hours.
I wanna be prepared to cover all the
bases for when we go back in there.
Uh, I'm on an ER rotation.
Shouldn't I be cracking chests
instead of making copies?
I got a 15-year-old
skateboarder versus firetruck.
The ladder clipped his leg.
Looks like an angulated tib-fib.
Leave him. We'll
find him a hallway.
- I've got it.
- I'll get it.
- My med student is driving me mad.
- Wanna trade?
- Were we that annoying?
- I wasn't.
Hi, I'm Dr. Lockhart.
Does your arm hurt?
You got hit by a firetruck
and just broke a leg?
Lucky guy.
Hey, hello in there. We're your
doctors. We'll try to keep this brief.
My sister is coming.
How am I gonna tell our kids?
Well, the social worker will be here to
see you. She can help you with all that.
Would you like to speak with
clergy? Any denomination?
Okay.
I'm sorry to bring this up so soon, but
we only have a limited amount of time...
- to make this decision.
- Is it okay if I don't tell them yet?
Have you thought about
donating your husband's organs?
- I think it's okay.
- Okay.
Let them have one last night
before their lives change forever.
- Well, you're looking better.
- Ha-ha-ha.
Just don't make me drink
any more of that mud.
Well, the good news is your
tox screen came back negative...
and your EKG was normal. So from
a medical standpoint, you're clear.
Good. Can I get out of here?
- I wasn't trying to commit suicide.
- What were you trying to do?
Abby? Is the baby
in 3 a real ALTE...
- or just a choking episode?
- I don't know. I haven't presented him.
The parents are refusing
blood draws and x-rays.
Okay, I'll go find
them when I'm done.
I need Psychiatry to see you
before I can send you home.
I'm not crazy, just stupid.
Abby, is IV contrast
contraindicated...
in someone with wheat
and peanut allergies?
- I don't think so.
- Can you find out?
- CT's calling for your MVA.
- Okay, um...
Hold them off
and I'll look into it.
Um, I'm gonna page Psych for
you and get you an ETA, okay?
The condom broke.
- Abby.
- What?
Your abdominal pain is gonna
leave AMA if he's not sent up soon.
I tried to admit as
acalculous cholecystitis...
but they think it's a
retrocecal appendix.
- What do you think?
- I don't know.
- I'm waiting for Surgery to see him.
- Keep it moving.
- Three an hour now.
- Thank you for your concern.
So the condom broke?
I'm a temp at a
commodities firm...
and I slept with one
of the traders last night.
He left a note on my bed:
- "I got HIV. See a doctor."
- Oh.
Five years of needles and
I managed to stay negative.
I cleaned myself up,
turned everything around...
and because of one stupid
night, now I'm gonna get AIDS?
I can't get sick. I have a kid.
Just because you've been exposed
doesn't mean you're infected.
The incidence of transmission from
one exposure is actually relatively low.
You know, it might be better if I
told him he has leukemia alone.
I wouldn't wanna
cramp your style.
- Seen Juan Enriquez anywhere?
- That leukemia guy?
- He was out here a while ago.
- He's gone.
- He'll be back.
- There's a patient in his bed.
Nobody would
have discharged him.
- Damn it. He's gone.
- Doughnut?
- Who?
- My leukemia patient. I'm such an idiot.
I hadn't even told him,
but I think he knew.
You're not making a
lot of sense right now.
He thinks he's being
punished by God.
I should have realized
he was a flight risk.
No, there's nothing
you could have done.
I could have told him it was
treatable. He has a shot at remission.
There isn't enough time to
help the people who want help.
Don't beat yourself up
over people who don't.
He was distraught, and I left him
alone so I could go and do research.
- Dude, where did you go?
- Jane's gonna hang with us, okay?
You seem stressed out.
It's about time for the nurses'
nighttime feeding. Better go.
Beastie Boys.
He's out.
Have you ever
heard of prescribing...
prophylactic triple cocktail
after a known HIV exposure?
Sure. The hospital gives it to health
workers all the time for needle sticks.
I'm not talking about
a health worker.
One of my patients had unprotected
sex with an HIV-positive guy last night.
Uh, it's really only available
for occupational exposures.
Too expensive.
Okay, on my count pull the
distal segment out and down...
while I give counter traction.
One, two, three.
Only health-care workers
are worthy of HIV prophylaxis?
We can't give preventive
meds to every one-night stand...
when we still can't afford to treat
people who are actually infected.
I'm talking about one patient who's
here now and she's asking for my help.
And what about the patient who
walks in tomorrow and the next day?
Put him in a long leg splint and
stay with him until he wakes up.
The guy's been here for eight
hours and hadn't been told?
What were you waiting for?
Oncology couldn't get here. I
was figuring out what to tell him.
- He wasn't gonna hear anything.
- It was important I get my facts straight.
- Why didn't you call a social worker?
- I thought it was better for him...
No, it's not about him, it's about
you and your need to be perfect.
Stop being a slow A-plus
and start becoming a fast B...
or you're not gonna make it.
Now, find him before he
bleeds out and he dies.
Yes. I'm looking for funding for HIV
medication for an uninsured ER patient.
If anyone ever actually
checks this machine...
please call
Dr. Lockhart in the ER.
What?
I look at you and Ray,
you're so confident in...
It's your first day. Give
yourself at least a week...
- to be better than the rest of us.
- I don't even know why I'm here.
Listen. Every shift
at about this time...
I start fantasizing about
working in a tollbooth.
Neela, what's going on
with that football player in 3?
Uh, knee pain times two days. No
drawer sign, no AP or lateral laxity.
- Point tenderness?
- When he's bearing down weight.
- Rest, ice and Ace wrap, right?
- Yeah. Excuse me.
No, you can't! No, no, no!
There's nothing wrong with him...
- Looking good today, Dori. Doughnut?
- I am not helping with the disimpaction.
Doughnut? SEVERA: Babinka?
Don't act immune to my charms just
because you brought your own sweets.
- He does that every day?
- Twice. Start of each nursing shift.
- It actually works?
- Apparently.
- Abby, you're lagging.
- Well, I have more patients on the board.
Which is meaningless
if you can't dispo them.
You're taking up
room, jamming the flow.
Yesterday, I got a hot MI
to the lab in 15 minutes...
reduced a perilunate
dislocation and a case of malaria.
Today, I'm in some
kind of bizarre vortex.
Okay, okay. Cough
times two days. In and out.
Doubt it. Probably turn into myocarditis
versus tracheoesophageal fistula.
All of my patients need three
consults and a huge workup...
and even then, there's
no definitive diagnosis.
I guess you're gonna have...
No, I'm not gonna pretend
things are cut and dry!
I just want one patient today that
has a clear problem that I can help.
- Okay.
Sam, how come Brandon
still hasn't gone to the scanner?
- Because CT's been backed up for hours.
- Charlie's the CT tech from 3 to 11.
He loves bear claws. The rest of the
doughnuts go to the nurses' station.
- Should I make sure someone sees me?
- Yeah.
You don't find all this wheeling
and dealing a bit slimy?
Yeah, but you gotta play
games to get stuff done.
Excuse me. Let's
review the standings.
Ray, still in the lead with 25.
- Got 26.
Ah. Abby at 19, Neela
brings up the rear with 16.
File this under Neela.
- And why would you do that?
- Because you'll owe me.
Hey, there's a patient with an ER
wristband who's upstairs in the chapel.
- Been up there a couple of hours.
- Where are you going? You're only at 16.
- Uh, Employee Health.
- Can I help you?
This is Abby Lockhart in the
ER. I've been stuck by a needle.
Let's roll. Curtain 2 needs a thumb spica
and we need to take off a toenail in 4.
- Dr. Barnett, did you fill this out?
- What?
This is the postmortem checklist
for the jet-ski guy in Trauma 1.
Oh. Yeah, yeah.
Did you actually talk to Stacy Coleman,
or did you just fill this out to save time?
What?
Well, you checked off that she wanted
to have her husband's organs donated.
She said she never
consented to that.
No, no, no. I asked
her all the questions.
While the transplant surgeon
was prepping to harvest...
she thought her husband
was getting better, so...
Okay. Can we talk about
this someplace else, please?
UNOS has been on the phone with a
kid who thought she was getting a heart.
Are you worried
about getting yelled at?
- The lady said she was fine with it.
- No, Ray, she did not!
- Did you make sure she was...?
- I asked her all the questions.
Did you take time
to explain it to her?
- How am I supposed to...?
- Nobody said this job was easy.
When you take shortcuts and
you drop details, people get hurt.
We'll send this in for
hep B, hep C and HIV.
You can call
tomorrow for results.
And never stick your hand
in a full sharps container.
Stupid.
AZT and 3TC in a combined pill.
The other is your protease
inhibitor, BID, on an empty stomach.
Two quarts of water a day.
And we'll see you in two
weeks to check your LFTs.
Juan.
We've been looking for you.
Have you been down
here the whole time?
Juan, you have leukemia.
Leukemia is very treatable and you
have an excellent chance of a cure.
I know...
it feels like something bigger
than you is making this happen...
but something also led you here.
We will help you
get through this.
There's a reason why you
came to this hospital today.
- Hey.
- Hi.
I heard you got a needle
stick. Are you okay?
Oh, yeah. Yeah, fine.
- You wanna go home early?
- No.
I'm fine, really. Excuse me.
- Hey, Wendall?
- Yeah?
- Did you get to see my overdose?
- Uh, yeah. I left a note in the chart.
I'm comfortable discharging
with outpatient follow-up.
- Great.
- Listen, I heard about your needle stick.
- Are you all right?
- I am.
- Page me if you wanna talk.
- I will.
You're back.
Can I do anything?
- Do you feel okay?
- Yes, I'm fine.
A little woozy from all the
blood they took, though.
- I'll get you water.
- Great.
How about an iced tea
from across the street?
- Yeah, you got it.
- Thanks.
Hey, Sam, did the radial
fracture get Ancef yet?
Uh... Yeah. Just a minute. I gotta
give this message to Mrs. Coleman.
I'll do it.
Mrs. Coleman.
They took him to the morgue.
Your sister called.
She took your kids to
your house for the night.
Hey, I guess we had some kind
of misunderstanding back there...
and I'm not even
sure what it was about.
If there's anything
I can do, uh...
Can I call you a
cab or something?
I'm sorry for your loss.
- Just the man I was looking for.
- Do you know how often I hear that?
- Are you okay in there?
- Yeah, it's...
It was just a little mix-up.
What do you got there?
Um...
I need a favor.
I'm into favors.
These are for my
patient in Exam 3...
but as you can see, they
have my name on them.
- HIV meds.
- Yeah.
Do you have any friends in the
pharmacy that could doctor those labels?
Yeah. I think
I'm falling in love.
- How was your first day?
- Hard.
- You gonna come back tomorrow?
- Yep.
Juan Enriquez's priest
called. Still no word from him?
He's on the Oncology Ward starting
chemo. I found him in the chapel.
Oh. Great.
- Hey, thanks for your help today.
- Sure.
- You off?
- Yeah.
Yeah, me too. If you
wait for a second...
- I'll walk out with you.
- Okay.
I, uh, think I hear
rounds starting.
Make sure you drink at least
two quarts of water a day...
and see your doctor in two weeks
and get your liver function tested.
I don't know what to say.
- Thank you.
- Sure.
- Take care of yourself, okay?
- Okay. Bye-bye.
Bye.
- You have dinner plans tonight?
- No.
Maybe that was too subtle.
Would you like to have
dinner with me tonight?
- It wasn't too subtle, Urbanus. I got it.
- Answer still no?
Yeah.
Okay.
Good morning.
You buy your t-shirt like
that or you rip it yourself?
- Hey, I met my discharge quota today.
- So did I.
Uh, not quite, Dr. Barnett.
Twenty-nine, you're one short, buddy.
- After work cocktail?
- That's totally gross.
- Good. Let's go get a real drink then.
- Mm, not a chance.
- I'm exhausted.
- Come on, guys.
Lewis is handing out
the paychecks today.
How can he still have
energy after a day like this?
Work is easy when you have the entire
staff literally eating out of your hand.
I don't know how he can finish
his work at the end of his shift.
- I still have an hour's worth of charting.
- Two hours.
Hello, Abby, Neela. Survive?
Okay, let's round so the
day crew can get out of here.
In 2, we have DZ with V and HA.
- Finishing a liter, PO challenge and home.
- All right.
Who can tell me what the
criteria is for scanning headaches?
- Worst case...
- Thunderclap onset.