Where are those projections?
Three, six and nine are in their folders.
Can I have some more—
Excellent. Tea's at your seat. Hello.
Oh, hold on.
Ben Federman
again, another pre-call.
We did the pre-call. Is
this the post pre-call call?
The board's gonna want specifics
with the push into the Asian markets.
Ben, there are no
specifics about Asia.
We came up with that as a
Hail Mary at 3:00 in the morning...
to placate the board
about international.
Carly, I'm just giving you
a heads-up about Asia.
There is no Asia.
Let's talk about Asia.
We're in the preliminary stages of forming
a strategic alliance with Credit Lyonnais.
Within three months, you won't be able to
walk four feet in Kangham, South Korea...
without seeing one of
our beautiful models...
smiling at you from billboards and
drugstore windows, inviting you in.
That's incredible news, Carly. We'd
hoped to hear something about Asia.
Had no idea plans
were so far along.
Well, you know Asia.
Nothing's done until it's done.
Carly, I was wondering,
could you walk us through what you
were thinking for other Asian territories?
Absolutely. India has
over half a billion women.
In terms of spending power, it's the single
largest potential market in the world.
Um, we have retained a local firm to ensure
that cultural differences are respected.
Um, however, I can't go into the specifics
of my plan with you until tomorrow.
Right now I have a
meeting and I need the room.
We were just getting started.
I know and I do
apologize. It's last minute,
but the meeting is with
three state department
officials to smooth
the way for China.
China? This is just incredible.
- We'll be in touch.
- Thank you.
What is it? I need a doctor.
I can't move my leg.
32-year-old female, paralysis and
severe pain in her right quad. Go.
- How'd she get to you?
- She's the C.E.O. of Sonyo Cosmetics.
Three assistants and 15 V.P.'s
checked out who should be treating her.
Who da man? I da
man. I always suspected.
Dr. House, I know the chances are
very slim, but I'm sure you recognize...
that she may have what
you had, a clot in her thigh.
A bit of a long shot.
- What about a disk herniation?
- I don't know, Eric.
If her disk were herniated, she'd
present with pain elsewhere, wouldn't she?
- Yeah, I suppose.
- You're right.
A clot's also the most
deadly, right, Robert?
True. The clot breaks off,
she could stroke and die.
Dr. House, I believe
that they're right—
- Stop talking.
- What?
You read one of those
negotiating books, didn't you?
Getting To Yes.
Fifty Ways to Win an
Argument. Hitchhiker's
Guide to Being a Pal.
In five seconds, you
just manipulated these
two into agreeing
with your point of view.
Fellas, this is known as
soft positional bargaining.
It's not gonna work.
Dr. House, are you saying
that she doesn't have a clot,
or are you saying that
if she does have a clot,
she doesn't need blood
thinners and an angiogram?
Chase, put her on blood
thinners. Do an angiogram.
When that comes back
negative, M.R.I. the spine.
If that's clean, cut her
open and biopsy the leg.
Excellent suggestion.
Read less, more TV.
It's rare for an individual
to make a donation...
significant enough to
impact an organization
as large and
unwieldy as a hospital.
This donation does
come with one string,
that he be made
chairman of the board.
I think that's a reasonable request. I
think he should have the right to know...
what it is we do
with his $ 100 million.
Please welcome our new chairman
of the board, Edward Vogler.
Thank you.
When I was 18,
my dad loaned me
$20,000 for a college tuition,
which he would have known was a mistake
had he known I wasn't actually in college.
I took his money and invested in
a friend who had a little business.
And when my dad found out
what I had done with his money,
he and I didn't
talk much after that.
But my friend's
business took off,
and I used the profits from that to
buy another company and another.
And I must have been pretty
good at it, had a good eye,
because before I knew it, people
were making offers for my company.
And about a year
ago, I went public,
and overnight I was
worth a billion dollars.
So, I went to see my dad.
I'll admit. I wanted a little payback. You
know, kind of shove the win in his face.
So, I drove upstate, and
sat in the kitchen I grew up in,
and, uh, he had no reaction.
It wasn't his fault. He
didn't even know who I was,
because his Alzheimer's
had taken a turn for the worse,
despite the best drugs
and care out there.
And that is why I'm here.
What if my contribution to this
hospital is the difference between...
no cure and a cure for cancer?
The difference between a man
not recognizing his wife of 35 years...
and being able to look at her and
say, "Good morning, honey. I love you."
If there's a disease
out there killing people,
I am writing you a
blank check to fight back.
So, things are
going to change a lot.
We're gonna have to
ask you for the cell phone.
Do what you need
to do. I'm okay.
I'm pretty sure my X-ray machine
can take your phone in a fight.
It'll fry it.
Fine.
- How old is she?
- Thirty-two.
Wow. And she's already the
C.E.O. of a public company.
She's a workaholic.
Okay, Carly, hold still.
The X-ray machine is
gonna pass over your leg.
Okay. What'd you
do with your time off?
Snowboarding in Gstaad.
Switzerland.
Do you ski or board? You
can come with if you like.
Maybe we should start with a
drink before we go around the world.
Oh, you wanna
have a drink with me?
Oh, very
aggressive. I like that.
I wanna run this
place like a business.
What, you want to put more
vending machines in the hallway?
Maybe a roulette wheel?
Nice one. But I'm serious.
The product that you're selling is
good health. It shouldn't be a tough sell.
If you don't wanna sell, it means you
don't care if people get your product.
You care if people are healthy,
or are you too proud for that?
Who's that?
Oh, that's just
one of our doctors.
Aren't, uh, doctors
supposed to wear lab coats?
- He's different.
- Everyone's buddy.
- No, not exactly.
- Then why does he get away with it?
It's just a coat.
He's very good.
Hmm.
- Say "Ah."
- Ah.
Now really belt it out, like
you're gonna throw up. Ahh!
Perfect.
Okay, that's it.
We should know in a couple of days
what's growing in your son's throat.
Hello?
- He can't talk.
- Excuse me?
- He had knee surgery.
- Right?
About a year ago, and
then he couldn't talk.
Right. Yeah, well, that happens.
You know, it's very dangerous
operating so close to the vocal cords.
Okay. Well, we'll send your kid's culture
to the lab and somebody will call you.
Boo!
Just wanted to see if your
dad, you know— Bizarre.
I need you to
wear your lab coat.
I need two days of
outrageous sex with someone
obscenely younger than
you, like half your age.
Wear the coat.
Man, oh, man, someone got
spanked real good this morning.
A guy gives $100
million to cure cancer.
A pretty small concession
to wear a lab coat.
Cure cancer?
Is the hospital getting out of the
dull business of treating patients?
You know that's not what he's
doing. I know exactly what he's doing.
He's using us to
run clinical trials.
Oh, shame on him,
saving lives like that.
It's unethical.
Oh, are you coming in too? I
thought I had you convinced.
Clinical trials save
thousands of lives.
He's using patients
as guinea pigs.
Pharmaceutical
companies do that every day.
Are we a pharmaceutical
company? We're gonna
wind up pressuring
desperate patients...
into choices that are
bad for them, good for us.
We're gonna compromise patient
care. Who the hell am I talking to?
Suddenly ethical lapses
are a major concern for you?
What's interesting is it
suddenly doesn't bother you.
So, if you ignore ethics to
save one person it's admirable,
but if you do it to save a
thousand, you're a bastard.
All he's done is taken
your game and gone pro.
He's not gonna kill a few patients.
He's gonna kill this hospital.
It took him three
seconds to size you up.
And surprise, he
doesn't like you.
Wear the damn coat.
Hello. I'm, uh, Dr. Foreman.
I work with Dr. House.
Our initial tests
say you're fine.
We think you had a clot,
but it resolved on its own.
So, we're gonna keep you overnight to be
safe, and you can go back home tomorrow...
or back to work.
Hey, are you okay?
Get in here! I need a line
in her. I.V. morphine, stat!
You get any read on the
new chairman of the board?
- Yeah, he took your parking space.
- It's not necessarily bad news.
Do you ever watch
Gilligan's Island reruns...
and really, really think they're
gonna get off the island this time?
We should introduce
ourselves. It couldn't hurt.
Make him a Bundt cake. A patient hit a 10
on the pain scale. What would explain that?
There was no clot in her leg.
The angio was totally clean.
What about the muscle biopsy?
No neurogenic or
myopathic abnormalities.
She was also negative for trichinosis.
No toxoplasmosis or polyarteritis nodosa.
Robert, what was her
sedimentation rate?
Normal, Allison.
Therefore, no inflammation,
no immunologic response.
Do you mind sharing
that number with me?
Fifteen, Allison.
- Are you mocking me?
- Duh, Allison.
I'm just suggesting we look outside
the box. What if her sed rate is elevated?
Well, let's go further outside the
box. Let's say the angio revealed a clot.
And then let's say
we treated that clot,
and now she's all better and
personally thanked me by performing...
My Aunt Elyssa
lives in Philadelphia.
Oh, it's story time.
Let me get my "baba."
Her normal temperature is
96.2, not 98.6 like you and me.
If her temperature were
98.6, she'd have a fever.
I'm just wondering if you think we could
apply the same logic to Carly's sed rate.
It's absurd.
I love it.
If 15 is high for Carly,
then she has inflammation.
Which could, in turn, mean
cancer. I'll talk to Wilson.
Next time, skip Aunt Elyssa.
You're probably talking
about a primary bone cancer.
It could be tricky to detect.
We'll need a bone scan.
That's why I'm talking
to an oncologist.
Sure. I've nothing better to do besides
departmental meetings and budget reports.
New chairman of the board,
you know. Oh, I hadn't heard.
Right. Clinical trials.
Completely unethical.
And a very bad omen
for you. There's not much
money in curing African
sleeping sickness.
No. I have seen every
scary movie ever made.
Six-year-old twins in front
of an elevator of blood.
Boys' choirs. Those
are bad omens.
This is much more mundane.
A billionaire wants to get laid.
Billionaires buy movie
studios to get laid.
They buy hospitals
to get respect.
And the reason you
want respect? To get laid.
Okay then. Just gotta
think like a billionaire.
Let's see. There'll be big,
scary changes and then,
"Oh, Dr. Cameron, we should have dinner to
discuss your future on my G5 private jet."
Come on. You know
how good you have it here.
Yes, I'm the big poobah,
the big cheese, the go-to guy.
You do the cases you wanna
do when you wanna do them.
You're not gonna have
that anywhere else. Relax.
I've been through three regime changes
in this hospital. Every time same story.
Just keep your head
down. That's all I'm saying.
And put on your coat. It itches.
So, you gonna do this
bone scan for me, or what?
Yes.
Dr. Simpson, did you
hear? New management.
I'm thinking of
switching to orthopedics.
How much do you guys get for a
massage now? Without the happy ending.
Dr. House, what do you want? Do you
remember a guy named Van Der Meer?
Not a big talker.
You fixed his A.C.L.
No, not according to my
medical malpractice premiums.
Didn't get hypotensive
during surgery?
No strokes? Maybe
some connectivity loss?
What, you're gonna get
involved now? I'm not involved.
A guy brought his son into
the clinic. I didn't touch the son.
I'm not taking any responsibility
there. The son's fine. Can't shut him up.
Dad show any symptoms of
cortical disease? Wernicke's?
No. Nothing.
That's why we settled because
we couldn't find anything.
The guy got over a million dollars.
Don't tell me he's complaining.
He's not saying boo.
Your father wants to know
when you'll be back from your trip.
E-mail back it's taking
longer than I thought.
He doesn't need to see me like
this. What about your brother?
- No.
- Hello. I'm Dr. Wilson. I was...
- Um, Robin, I'm gonna need a minute.
- Oh.
Thank you.
There are two
Dr. Wilsons in this hospital,
one in ophthalmology
and one in cancer.
My eyes are fine, so I'm guessing
you're here to tell me that I have cancer.
There is no cancer in your bone.
You're not smiling.
There's something
called referred pain. You
could have cancer in
one part of your body...
that presents in another.
Given your age and your family
history, I'm thinking your colon.
Great.
I was at Columbia when my
mom died. Now there's a blast.
Cleaning up her vomit, and
then running to my econ final.
Look.
If I'm a short-timer, give me drugs.
I'll go back to work. I'll die there.
Whoa. There's a very quick test to
see if you even have it— a colonoscopy.
I know how you do that test.
If you have colon cancer,
we can treat it. It's early.
That's what they told my mom.
She was dead six months later.
You're a smart person about
to make a very bad decision.
You know, cancer
treatment's come a long way
in 12 years, but if
you don't do this now...
I don't wanna be looked at.
There is another way.
We could do a
virtual colonoscopy.
Basically, we do a C. T. scan
of your colon. It's noninvasive.
But it's very expensive. I'm
assuming that's not a problem.
Say yes.
Dr. Becker—
Mr. Van Der Meer.
What?
Relax. Ricky's gonna be
just "finkf." Strep throat.
Here's a prescription for an antibiotic.
He should be all better in a few days.
Although, this
might sting a little.
I wanna see you again real soon.
Virtual colonoscopy was clean.
No colon cancer.
What happened to our regular,
old-fashioned colonoscopy?
She was uncomfortable doing any more tests.
I had to convince her to do that one.
Do you get that often? Women would
rather die than get naked with you?
She's scared.
But not of tests. Just
embarrassing ones.
Yeah.
It's not an inflammatory process. It's
not a clot, because Chase's angio says so.
And it's not cancer,
because her tush is perfect.
Anybody else got an Aunt
Elyssa with weird stuff?
Maybe it's worth looking into—
I thought you said
Carly's angio was clean.
It was clean.
You guys see the problem here?
There's no indication
of any abnormalities.
No lesions, no
spurs, no mastis...
Her toes are screwed
up. They're backwards.
You guys know how much surgery
it's gonna take to swap 'em back?
What are you talking about?
Well, either she literally has two
left feet, or you angioed the wrong leg.
That's impossible. It can't
be— Or maybe it was Jenny.
How come some
resident signed this
radiology report? Were
you even in the room?
- I'll redo her angio—
- You'll do nothing!
Foreman, you do the angiogram.
I can't believe I did that.
Why do we have to
redo the angiogram?
There was a shadow on
the first test result. Shadow?
A shadow means there
could be a blood clot, right?
I read Conn's Current Therapy.
A real page-turner. No, it
wasn't that kind of shadow.
My chest hurts. It's
from the tracer I injected.
You might also get a little nauseous
or have a metallic taste. All normal.
I'm a runner. I
shouldn't feel like this.
Carly, I'm looking at
your vitals right now and...
I can't breathe. Carly?
My chest.
Respiratory arrest. Call code.
- What do you got?
- She's drowning.
Foreman did a thoracentesis
to drain the fluid from her lungs.
She's stable. They sent the fluid to
the lab. It'll be back in a few hours.
You'll be happy to know Chase's mistake
didn't cost her. Angio revealed no clot.
I'm thrilled.
Okay, see, now you’re
just being stubborn.
It's cold. It's a perfectly good
excuse to wear your lab coat.
Carly needs a heart transplant.
Thoracentesis
revealed a transudate?
I haven't gotten it back yet.
Her MUGA scan, what
was the ejection fraction?
Maybe you could treat it
surgically. I haven't done the MUGA.
How do you know she
needs a heart transplant?
I got my aura read today.
It said someone close
to me had a broken heart.
Since when do I need the
secret pass code to talk to you?
I can't tell you anything.
Professional responsibility.
Like that matters to you.
Not my professional
responsibility, yours.
New regime. You gotta
keep your head down too.
Now that's good thinking, because
I was gonna go right to Cuddy...
and rat you out as soon
as you were done talking.
I'm not saying you want to.
I'm saying you'd be obligated to.
Because of my
position on the board?
Because of my position on
the transplant committee?
Hey, you brought this up for a
reason. You need to talk to me.
I can't.
You sure you're
doing the right thing?
I've come up with a few
really great rationalizations.
Sorry to interrupt.
We have a problem.
Thoracentesis
revealed a transudate.
We did an echo. She's in
severe congestive heart failure.
She needs a heart transplant.
- We'll get her on the list immediately.
- She's already on the list.
Come in.
Thanks.
What is a department
of Diagnostic Medicine?
That's Dr. House's department.
They deal with cases that
other doctors can't figure out.
It's a financial black hole.
The department costs
us three million a year...
to treat one patient a week.
He saves one patient per
week. What about everyone else?
His department's not going to
find the cure for breast cancer.
- Uh, maybe not, but— -
Are you sleeping with House?
What? No. But you did. Right?
A long time ago?
That's an incredibly
inappropriate question.
If your judgment is
compromised by a prior
or current relationship,
that is my business.
I respect him. That is
all you need to know.
He's still not wearing the coat.
Well, I told him—
I'm sure you did.
And yet he's not wearing it. I'm just
wondering if that's a reflection on him...
or on you.
You're Dr. House.
I found a picture online of you at a
conference. You need a heart transplant.
- I run. I work out—
- You cut yourself.
Probably highly ritualized.
You play the same Sarah McLachlan
song over and over while you do it.
Probably works better
than antidepressants.
- I don't understand
how that— - You're a
high-powered bulimic.
You make yourself throw up.
You had to find the
most efficient way to vomit
without revealing the
telltale signs of bulimia,
which is all, ooh, very
unseemly for a C.E.O.
So, you found a common antidote
to accidental poisoning to do the job...
Ipecac.
Which is great if your kid's
just swallowed a bottle of aspirin,
but really, really
bad if it's a habit.
It causes muscle damage.
It caused the pain in your leg.
And destroyed your heart.
How often do you do it?
Three times a week.
In about an hour, there's
gonna be an emergency
meeting of the
transplant committee...
to discuss where you fall on the list
should a new heart become available.
Problem is, I am required to tell
the committee about your bulimia.
It's a major psychiatric
condition. Ranks right
up there with suicidal.
Makes you a very bad risk.
So, you're here to tell me I
have just a few hours to live?
Unless I lie to the committee.
But if they find out, I
lose my medical license.
This would be a very good
time to offer me a bribe.
You know, how much is your life
worth? How much is my job worth?
Why are you here doing this
to me? What do you want?
I wanna know what's right.
Am I worth it?
You think I'm pathetic.
Has a good job.
Everything in the world.
But she just doesn't like
the way that she looks.
Oh, stop hiding!
I'm asking you if you wanna live
or die? You can't even say that.
What do you want
me to do? Cry? Yes.
I want you to tell me that your life is
important to you, because I don't know.
Because that's what's on
the table right now— your life.
I don't wanna die.
I don't.
This 32-year-old female
was admitted by my staff...
because of paralysis
and pain in her right thigh.
The patient rapidly deteriorated and
now has severe congestive heart failure.
Pressors and vasodilators have not
improved her condition whatsoever.
Pulmonary function tests show
an F. E. C. of over three liters,
with F. E. V.-1 of at
least 90% of predicted...
and preserved F.E.D./F.E.C. ratio
and preserved D.L.C.O. as well.
Her MUGA had an ejection fraction of 19%
with no focal wall motion abnormalities.
Heart catheterization revealed
clean left, right and circumflex arteries.
And a subsequent biopsy
revealed irreversible cardiomyopathy.
Which is why we're here.
Uh, Dr. House, I'm confused
by your time and date stamps.
It appears that you put Carly on the
transplant list before you did these tests.
I had a hunch.
You don't have
hunches. You know.
Look, if the tests had
come back differently,
obviously I would have
taken her off the list.
But on the long shot...
On the long shot that I was
right, I didn't want to waste time.
Is there any exclusion
criteria we should know about?
CAT scan revealed no tumors, and
Dr. Wilson found no trace of cancer.
What about any other criteria?
- No atherosclerotic vascular disease.
- Are there any...
No pneumonia, no bacteremia.
No hep "B" or "C" or any other letters.
Substance abuse. Any history...
No alcohol. No drugs.
Any psychiatric conditions? History
of depression? She's a little blue.
But turns out she needs
a heart transplant, so...
Dr. House, if you subvert
or mislead this committee,
you will be subject
to disciplinary action.
Dr. Cuddy, do you have
reason to think that I would lie?
I simply want you to
answer the question.
Is there anything on the
recipient exclusion criteria...
that would disqualify your
patient from getting a heart?
No.
Beautiful organ donor weather.
You lied, didn't you?
I never lie. Big mistake.
Then you should have voted
against putting her on the list.
- You're my friend.
- Oh, geez, have some backbone.
If you think I'm
wrong, do something.
Wait. You're getting mad
at me for sticking up for you?
You value our friendship more
than your ethical responsibilities.
Our friendship is an
ethical responsibility.
What is it?
My patient's getting a heart.
He's not gonna fire you.
I'd fire you. Bye-bye.
I screw up, the patient
dies, I'll never get another job.
So stick your head between your
legs and go lick your wounds in Gstaad.
Well, I like it here.
You guys don't think it's weird House knew
the patient needed a heart transplant...
before we did any heart tests?
That's House. He knows things.
But usually he's
putting it in our face.
Telling us how
cleverly he figured it out.
This time nothing.
Just had a hunch.
That is weird.
Cauterize that one bleeder.
Okay, ready for the donor heart.
They just stopped Carly's
heart, and your dumb patient...
They're all— Oh, the guy who
can't talk. Mr. Van Der Meer.
He's scheduled an appointment
to see you. Oh, goody.
I wanted you to know Chase is
worried you're going to fire him.
It's bad enough that
screw-ups cost lives.
Now we've got Vogler,
screw-ups cost jobs.
I want Chase scared.
I want him doing everything
he can to protect his job.
Dr. House, if you were in
his position, wouldn't you
be more likely to perform
well if you were reassured...
Oh, will you stop it with the
book? Why are you doing this?
I'm not doing anything.
You're manipulating everyone.
People... dismiss me.
Because I'm a woman.
Because I'm pretty.
Because... I'm not aggressive.
My opinions shouldn't be rejected
just because people don't like me.
They like you.
Everyone likes you.
Do you?
I have to know.
No.
Okay.
Five hours, 23
minutes. That's fast.
Is that good or bad? It depends.
Either surgery went really
well, or it ended really abruptly.
Textbook. She'll outlive us all.
Thank you.
Triage nurse,
pick up line 274 1.
So, sing for me.
Oh, no, no, no,
no. Come on, look.
When you had your
surgery, you were intubated.
The surgeon stuck a
tube down your throat.
Now, it never happens and it's
never caught, but it happened.
Your vocal cords were paralyzed. I
treated the spastic dysphonia with Botox.
Ironically, a substance that tightens
every other corner of your face.
It actually loosens the tongue. I
have healed you. You can talk.
Oh, well.
Boo!
Okay.
You don't have to say anything.
It can be our little secret.
If you can talk, blink twice.
But you're not going to,
because you think you
won't be entitled to the
money you won in the
settlement with Simpson.
Yesterday, I would have said
you had to give the money back.
Today, hospital's
come into a lot of money.
Mum's the word.
Hey.
I know the cardiologist has
given you some guidelines,
a schedule of medication
and a strict diet.
Just what somebody with
an eating disorder needs.
So I thought I'd
get you started.
Fried chicken from
the Carnegie Deli.
- You're kidding.
- Yeah.
Actually, I got it downstairs.
Why did you fight for me?
You risked so much,
and you hardly know me.
You're my patient.
Don't screw it up.
♪♪
Love this part!
Okay. He ruined it.
Just wanted to stop
by and introduce myself.
I'm Edward Vogler, new
chairman of the board.
In a way, I guess that
makes me your boss.
I am sorry about the lab coat thing.
My dry cleaners just destroyed it.
That was my very first heart transplant
committee meeting. Very exciting.
Trust me, Six Flags—
Way more exciting.
Your patient's very lucky
to have such a passionate
doctor. Stands up for
what he believes in.
Sweet of you to say.
Yeah. Afraid you've
been duped though.
The nurse found this
in the patient's purse.
Oh, my. If only I'd known.
Tough being a doctor,
having all that power.
The power to play God.
Yes. I don't envy the transplant
committee their responsibility.
They basically would have
been forced to kill that poor girl.
I'm not sure I could
have done that.
This is not a game
to me, Dr. House.
No. It's actually more like
we're dancing right now.
So let's get to the
point. You don't like me.
I'm pretty sure I'm not gonna
like you. It's nothing personal.
I don't like anybody.
But none of that
really matters, does it?
Because you've got
money, and I've got tenure.
You need full board approval
to get rid of me. I've got Cuddy.
Right. And Wilson.
So, as long as we're
stuck with each other,
we might as well
ignore each other.
♪♪
That wasn't nearly as
dramatic as I was hoping.
I looked into that tenure
thing, and you're right.
It's actually easier for me to get rid of
a board member like Cuddy or Wilson...
than to get rid of a doctor.
That's interesting, isn't it?
That's some bad hat, Harry.