Hello. I'm Freddie Highmore.
The following episode
portrays our hope for the future.
A future where no one
will have to wear masks
or take other steps to
stay safe from COVID.
Until then, please protect
yourself and others.
I'm Jordan Allen. My
first year in med school,
I designed an ankle brace
that monitors the extent of
immobilization via a phone app.
When I licensed it to Bioventus,
I was able to pay off
over half my student loans.
John Lundberg.
I've worked every summer since I
was 16 at Camp Hope Heartland,
a summer program
for kids with cancer
in Des Moines, where I grew up.
Asher Wolke.
Uh, when I was 18, I left
the Hasidic community
that I was raised in.
I realized if there
really was a God,
it had to be a cruel being
that I felt nothing
but contempt for.
That's also when I
decided to go to med school,
and start dating men.
I'm Olivia Jackson.
I'm 25. From Chicago.
I play ragtime piano
alone in my apartment.
Is that interesting?
Will Hooper.
Uh, technically, I'm
a professional athlete.
Although in a sport
nobody pays attention to,
and the stipend barely
covers our training expenses,
but I'm on the U.S.
National Rowing Team.
Men's Eight.
Hey, I'm Enrique.
I spent last summer
in Costa Rica,
where I learned to surf, which
I'm totally obsessed with now.
Uh, I had a pretty interesting
encounter with a saltwater crocodile.
I just thought it was a big...
Why are you wearing a swimsuit?
They're actually
hybrid board shorts.
I like to work hard, and it's easier
to do when you're comfortable.
Plus, I think the casual
dress puts patients at ease.
Uh, and Dr. Lim said
that the shorts were fine.
Hospital policy
requires all residents to...
He's not a resident.
He's a resident applicant.
One of six finalists
for four openings.
Now, they'll be
shadowing for two days.
Give them the grand
tour, show them the ropes.
Feel free to turn up the heat,
see how they react under pressure.
You will be responsible
for supervising them,
so I want your totally honest input
before I make any final decisions.
- Those shorts...
- Eh, let's call them strike one.
Oh. And in addition
to being an Olympian,
Will Hooper is a Rhodes
and graduated top of
his class at Stanford.
- He is very handsome.
- He's very full of himself.
He's ranked first by
every top program,
so whatever you can do
to recruit him to ours, do it.
- I can already give you my input on the...
- Don't judge a book by its board shorts.
- You wanted to see me?
- Good morning.
Sorry. Good morning.
What'd I do wrong?
I just wanted to check in, see
how the new role was coming along.
Honestly?
You could start a new supervisor-resident
relationship with a lie.
That's always fun.
Internal medicine is...
boring.
Between smokers
and obese diabetics,
seems like all I'm doing is
protecting people from themselves.
As a surgical resident, you
never treated drunk drivers
or extracted random
objects from guys'...?
- I get it. People are stupid.
- Not my point, but true.
Not the same adrenaline rush,
but internal medicine
can be rewarding.
Given time, if you're patient.
Thanks.
That is not how I thought
this meeting was gonna go.
I thought one of the nurses
complained about me.
Wasn't just one.
If it happens again,
this meeting will go exactly
how you thought it would.
Sorry. I should've just
canceled the appointment.
You were right.
Dizziness went away
as soon as I stopped drinking
coffee and Red Bull all day.
No worries.
- Can you lie flat on your back, please?
- Yeah.
You get that scar in a fire?
Sort of.
A homemade Roman
candle when I was 12.
You'd be surprised how many of us
at the firehouse were pyros as kids.
I made a potato gun for
my sixth-grade science fair.
Almost got me
kicked out of school.
You'll have to come visit us
sometime. You'd fit right in.
- You see something?
- Don't talk. Just breathe normally.
You have a large tumor
on the wall of your heart.
Cancer?
I don't know.
But you're definitely gonna
need surgery. As soon as possible.
I appreciate you letting me share
your case with the whole class.
No problem. I stopped being shy
after the hundredth time I had to do this.
I'll be using a version of
Lejour's technique I've adapted.
We'll divide the breast
into three pedicles
and then redistribute the
tissue and insert saline implants
to correct the tuberous
breast deformity.
Why would you want breast
implants? You're beautiful.
And your breasts look
fine just the way they are.
No, no, they don't.
The base is constricted,
horizontal
development is deficient,
and the nipple-areola complex...
Murphy.
It's okay. He's right.
That's why I'm here.
Thank you. I know that
you're trying to be nice.
My friends and family have
been telling me for years,
"You're beautiful
just the way you are."
But I don't feel beautiful.
You're 17. Every girl
your age feels like that.
That can't be true.
Tuberous breast
deformity is a rare condition.
We're not going to
debate a personal decision
the patient's already made.
I've been thinking
about this since I was 13.
Every time I look in the mirror.
I'm about to start
college, and there's no way
that I'm gonna begin this
new chapter until I'm fixed.
Great.
You thinking median
sternotomy or right thoracotomy?
I'm thinking I should finish
my review of the imaging.
Sure. No rush.
Actually, there is a bit of a
rush. But you know what I mean.
So, newbies. What
up? Where you all from?
- Like hometowns or...?
- Med schools.
- Why would I care where you grew up?
- Stanford.
- Uh, NYU.
- Harvard.
- Preferred specialties?
- Ortho. All the way.
Neuro.
I'm planning a dual specialty in
neonatal and pediatric oncology.
Impressive. Also unlikely.
I know it's a ton of work, but
I'm pretty good at multitasking.
In med school, I did
a combined MD/PhD...
- What's your mom do?
- My mom?
- Don't stall. Just answer.
- She teaches high-school French.
- Homemaker.
- Surgeon.
Ouch. Dad?
- Also a surgeon.
- Double ouch. And yours?
- Hasidic rabbi.
- You've left the nest.
Actually, the whole forest.
And yours obviously
works on Wall Street.
But not a trader. I'm
guessing an M&A lawyer.
How do you know?
She's read your résumé,
researched your social media.
She's probably run
a credit check too.
And you're under 50 but wear
Brooks Brothers button-downs.
Are you done yet?
Left thoracotomy
with a possible incision
into the right atrium and
interatrial septum as needed.
Left atrial approach
through Sondergaard's
groove makes more sense.
Not to me.
- He's my patient.
- But you're not a surgeon.
Which is why there's no
reason for you to be grilling them
or picking the approach.
Stop worrying about
protecting your turf.
Stop stepping all over it.
You're looking at tests
I did for my patient.
How am I stepping
all over your turf?
I think what Dr. Browne
is trying to say is,
given there's no perfect
approach, maybe it's best to defer
to the surgical department's
recommendation.
Did he just mansplain?
- Not at all. I was just...
- So you're just gonna do it again?
- No, I'm just trying to...
- Shut up.
We're gonna go in
through a left thoracotomy.
Not my preference,
but it'll work.
What were you thinking?
You thought you'd impress me
by undermining the patient's
confidence in my judgment?
I'm sorry. That
wasn't my intent.
And you're supposed
to be a mentor now,
modeling professional behavior,
not making it worse, Murphy.
She questioned your
surgical plan, I defended it.
- How can we both be wrong?
- I don't need you to defend me.
And I never want to have a
surgical debate in front of a patient.
We're not in front
of the patient now.
The patient's breasts are
small and a bit asymmetrical,
but no woman's breasts
are perfectly shaped.
You're wearing Prada shoes
and a Dolce & Gabbana blouse,
which cost more than
most med students' rent,
so clearly you understand
your appearance has
a tremendous impact
on how people treat you.
There's a difference between
nice clothes and a major surgery.
And I also understand the
cosmetic surgery industry
is dominated by male
physicians with a sexist bias.
I've invited you to observe
as a learning opportunity.
So I'd suggest less
lecturing and more listening.
We'll access the
tumor via an incision
in the chest wall
between your ribs.
It'll be an easier recovery
than if we opened your sternum.
Are you sure you don't
want us to call your family
before we put you under?
Why? So they can
freak out and worry?
I'd rather give them the
good news when it's over.
It is going to be
good news, right?
With a bit of cardiac rehab
and a positive attitude,
which I know you have,
you'll be back sliding
down the fire pole in no time.
Our firehouse has stairs.
Hmm. Bummer.
It's a social media group
where we all pretend to be ants.
Why?
Because ants don't care
about politics, sports teams,
or anything else people
get so savage about.
Male ants develop
from unfertilized eggs,
which means they don't have
a father and can't have sons,
but they do have grandfathers
and can have grandsons.
Interesting. And confusing.
Is it just me, or are those
doctors watching us?
They're the new
resident applicants.
They're here so Park, Claire and
I can evaluate them for Dr. Lim.
So why are they
standing over there?
Park had a video chat with Kellan,
and I had a real lunch with you.
Shaun, you can't just have
them stand there while you eat.
Part of being a good
boss is being a good host,
so you need to
introduce them to people.
Like me. Right now.
Come here, please.
Dr. Allen, Dr. Lundberg,
Dr. Guerin, this is my girlfriend, Lea.
She runs the IT
department now. Okay.
Nice to meet you
all. Please join us.
Shaun's been telling
me all about you.
Mm. No, I haven't.
So I hope Shaun's not
being too hard on you.
No, he's been great.
And the case we're
observing is really interesting.
We're correcting a 17-year-old
girl's tuberous breasts
with saline implants.
Dr. Allen told Dr. Andrews
it was unethical.
He got mad.
I didn't say it was
unethical. I just...
I suppose I shouldn't
have interfered.
Well, I don't know what
a tuberous breast is,
but I think implants
are way overrated.
That's because your
breasts are excellent.
Thank you. That's
exactly my point.
Mine aren't huge,
but every guy who's ever seen them
up close and personal has been thrilled.
I definitely was.
I am thrilled by every
part of your body.
Sorry, my bad. Total TMI.
I'm not even bothered
by your adenoidal voice.
Except when you talk to
your mom on the phone.
But I just put on headphones.
At least you'll know he'll
be a totally honest boss.
The incision is
extended superiorly
to meet the atriotomy, and then
the interatrial septum is opened up.
Retractor.
A Carpentier retractor is used
to visualize the mitral valve.
That will allow a
clear view of the tumor.
Can we turn the channel?
Color commentary's
getting a bit annoying.
With the right
atrium opened obliq...
How's Team Browne?
Any early standouts?
Jackson's a bit
timid, but smart.
Wolke is definitely
enthusiastic.
And your star recruit is...
pretty full of himself.
I'm looking for surgeons,
and according to his recs,
he can dissect and
suture like a pro.
I thought you were
also looking for our input.
He's ranked first by
every top program.
You really think they're
all wrong and you're right?
So, what brings
you all to the biz?
Had my ACL
reconstructed in high school,
both my rotators in college.
I love the idea of fixing people,
helping them be the best they can be.
Surgeons are the ones
with the God complex, right?
I have that.
I spent my life speaking
Yiddish and studying the Talmud
and not shaving
the sides of my hair
because someone up
there supposedly cares.
But then I realized...
no one's up there.
No one cares.
No benevolent higher power
is going to save us, so...
we have to save each other.
Can you top that?
- Definitely not.
- Try anyway.
You're obviously smart. You've
got two degrees from Harvard.
My parents are Harvard alums,
so I'm sure that helped me get in.
You're not gonna get hired
by undermining your own ex...
Something went wrong.
They nicked a pulmonary artery.
If they had, Browne
would be suctioning,
instead of Lim reaching
in with her hands.
What are they doing now?
Nothing.
We can't access the tumor
without compromising his
entire cardiac outflow tract.
What about going in
the way I suggested?
The median sternotomy.
The tumor's too far back.
We need to close him up.
Proton beam radiation
would be too toxic to the heart.
Well, so is immunotherapy.
We can't access the
entire tumor surgically,
and we can't kill it without
killing his heart along with it.
What if we cut out the
parts we can access
and try our luck with
chemo on what's left?
IV doxorubicin and ifosfamide
might slow the growth,
give him a few more months.
I'm not sending my patient
home with just a few extra months.
It's better than nothing.
- What about a transplant?
- Not an option.
Heart tumors are
a contraindication.
What if we transplant
his own heart?
If we take it totally out of his chest,
we'd have access to the posterior heart.
We could excise the tumor,
fix the defect left behind,
and then put it back in.
Cool.
Not cool. At least with a
normal heart transplant,
you'd be getting
a healthy heart.
Her idea keeps the risk
of removing the heart
and adds the risk that the
heart we'd be putting back in
has just been severely compromised,
having had a tumor cut out of it.
He's young, and the part of his
heart not infiltrated with tumor is strong.
Do a cardiac MRA
and see if the tumor's
infiltrated the coronary arteries.
If it hasn't, Morgan's
idea could work.
I'll schedule it.
Dr. Murphy is dividing
the breast parenchyma
into three pedicles.
Anyone know where this
technique is derived from?
Breast reduction surgery.
That's right.
And why would I use a
breast reduction technique
to make the patient's
breasts larger?
The technique
frees up the tissue.
You can bring the pedicles
together to make the breasts smaller
or spread them out over an
implant to make them larger.
Very good.
And now I'm going to turn the sound
off. Don't worry, nothing's wrong.
I just wanna talk about you
behind your backs for a little bit.
So first impressions. Murphy?
I like Dr. John Lundberg.
I haven't even
heard him speak yet.
He has the highest USMLE scores.
And that's important to you?
Yes. It shows he has a
broad knowledge of medicine.
What is important to you?
Well, I'm more interested in what
they can do with their knowledge.
Which is why, so far, I'm most
impressed with Jordan Allen.
No. No. You said
she undermined you.
Which takes courage
and an assertiveness
that will serve her well.
Then why did you tell
her to stop lecturing you?
It's easier to teach an
aggressive resident restraint
than a passive one
to assert themselves.
How about you, Park?
What's important to you?
I want to know who I can stand
to be around for 80 hours a week.
One thing I learned as a cop,
you don't really know a person
until you've had a
few drinks with them.
LAD and circumflex look clean.
What's with the right coronary?
It looks narrowed at the origin.
It's a bit narrow, but
looks like a normal variant.
Yeah, but it seems hazy,
like there could be
some tumor infiltration.
What do you guys think?
- Us?
- Yeah. Come take a look.
I guess...
- It's angiogenesis of the left...
- Stop.
Interrupting a female coworker is
almost as annoying as mansplaining.
This isn't a rowing race.
You don't always
have to speak first.
I... do not love
the interruption.
But... I like the enthusiasm.
What were you gonna say?
First, uh, I'm not sexist.
Of course not.
He's shifting from right-
to left-dominant circulation
to feed blood to the tumor.
- Angiogenesis.
- I doubt it.
Surgery showed his tumor
extending to the right as well.
What were you gonna say?
The pulmonary artery is
right behind that vessel.
It's causing radiographic
scatter in this area.
The haze is just an artifact.
His arteries are clean.
- I think she's right.
- Hmm.
Your idea might just work.
If you invert the sutures
and bury them under the skin,
the scar will be invisible.
No one will ever
know we were here.
Nice work, both of you.
Her BP's dropping.
Push fluids, start IV pressors.
Check for bleeding. She's in
V-tach. Move in the crash cart.
No bleeding. No hematomas.
Charging.
Clear.
Sinus rhythm. Her
BP is stabilizing.
Get her to the ICU.
I want post-op labs, CTA chest,
and full 24-hour
cardiac telemetry.
We need to figure out
what just happened.
She's stable, but diffuse
delta wave slowing,
minimal brain activity.
An undiagnosed metabolic disorder
could've caused an adverse reaction
to the anesthesia.
Yeah, but her pre-op
labs were all normal.
It's gotta be some sort
of hidden heart condition.
You're big on opinions.
How are you with ideas?
What would you do next?
I'd check train-of-fours
and reverse the
paralytics with neostigmine.
If Dr. Murphy's right,
she should wake up.
Smart. But risky. The
meds will stress her heart.
If Park's right, she
could arrest again.
I saw a similar case
last year in Borneo.
- You interned at a hospital in Borneo?
- Uh, no.
I volunteered at an
orangutan rescue foundation.
Our guide, a local
villager, fell out of a tree.
He was like 80 feet up.
How is falling out
of a tree similar
to a patient arresting during
breast reconstruction surgery?
Well, he broke his back, but
when we got him to the hospital,
I found he also had heart
damage from rheumatic fever
and metabolic abnormality
from iodine deficiency.
It's rare here, but
it's common there.
We only realized it when we
ran a nuclear perfusion scan
of his entire body.
Good catch.
But a scan that extensive
requires multiple radioactive tracers.
You think her heart
could handle that?
Not tonight. I'll get
consent from the mom.
We'll do it first
thing in the morning.
Once we confirm atrial closure,
we'll put the heart back in.
Dr. Lim will reconnect the aorta
and the superior venous connections,
while I connect the inferior.
During my sub-internship, I
assisted on multiple heart transplants.
Even sutured the
atrial cuff in one.
I got to scrub in on a
liver transplant once.
- The patient died.
- What'd you learn?
That bile duct leaks are a lot
harder to detect than bleeds.
Good. Next time I'd lead with
that instead of the patient's death.
- Are you all done yet?
- Why?
Dr. Park wants everyone
to join him in the break room.
I'm Alex Park.
I'm a former amateur
martial-arts competitor
who once thought it'd be fun
to spar with a pro boxer
visiting my dad's gym.
And that guy was,
uh, Mike Tyson.
Who's Mike Tyson?
Uh, guy from The Hangover.
With the tiger and
the tattoo on his face.
Nice. You've just revealed
you're crazy and old.
I've seen the musical
Wicked over 50 times.
The San Francisco tryout,
Broadway, Chicago...
I've even seen a friend's
boyfriend's niece play Glinda
at Stagedoor summer camp.
Nerd. Next.
I'm Claire Browne. Um...
I love music, but hate musicals.
And, um, I don't...
I don't really like to talk about
myself, so it's Shaun's turn, yeah.
My name is Dr. Shaun Murphy.
I used to not like music,
but my girlfriend, Lea,
she changed my mind.
I also like to watch the
Weather Channel on TV.
And...
ooh, I think pickles
are disgusting.
Cops know how to manage up.
Managing down's another story.
Well, he's mature, thoughtful,
doesn't have an ego.
Neither does Murphy, but
do you think that qualifies him
to supervise first-years?
Well, Murphy's smart, brutally honest,
has no regard for social convention.
- Hmm.
- It works for Bill Belichick.
The Patriots are the most
corrupt, dishonest organization
in the history of the NFL.
Well, the Seahawks suck.
So how's your
experience been here?
It's been good.
Did you consider any other
programs, or was this your first choice?
This was my only choice.
Why do you hate God?
Oh. Uh, actually, I don't
believe there is a God.
I thought maybe it was because
you believed he hated homosexuals.
I don't think this is something that
we should be discussing at work.
Mm.
Why not?
Well, because it's... personal.
Do you have a boyfriend?
I'm sorry, but you can't ask
that question in a workplace.
Dr. Park, he wants
us to get to know you.
How can I do that without
asking personal questions?
I have a girlfriend, and
she is very important to me.
It affects my life in every way.
Probably should've
thought of that
before you told her how
much her voice annoyed you.
I said it didn't bother me.
It... It was a compliment.
What I heard is you
criticizing her voice,
and you bringing
her mother into it.
You're in trouble.
What about Browne?
She may have as much
problem being a leader as Murphy,
and without his gifts.
She has her own gifts.
Yeah, dealing with
patients and their families.
But with her colleagues,
she can be insecure.
Her assertiveness has
always been a question mark.
They've all got areas
that need improving,
but I've gotten to know Browne a
bit better these past few months.
She's stronger than she looks.
When's the last time you saw
anyone dig a ditch in a suit?
Surgeons don't dig ditches.
They help people at the most
vulnerable time in their life.
And you shouldn't
take the responsibility on
if you're not fully
committed to it.
You're entering a new
phase in your career,
a position of authority.
Maybe my clothes are
making you feel disrespected.
But the truth is, I just hate wearing
anything that makes me feel like...
a suit.
Great news. I was able to get
Sowinski on anesthesia for tomorrow.
Uh, why? What happened to Foley?
Nothing. I just think
Sowinski's better.
And we definitely
need the A-team on this.
Yeah, I agree.
Which is why I went out
of my way to get Foley.
But Foley doesn't do
well under pressure.
- Remember that ti...
- Morgan.
You need to butt out.
You're not a surgeon.
This is not your job.
My job is to help my patient
through the entire treatment process.
The best anesthesiologist for
transplant surgery is Sowinski.
I've already cleared it with
Lim, so that's who it's gonna be.
Deal with it.
Are you mad at me?
I said your voice
doesn't bother me.
It was a compliment.
Actually, what you said is that
you love my breasts so much
that with the help of
noise-canceling headphones,
you're willing to put up
with my annoying voice.
Yes.
Not a compliment.
Oh.
- So you are mad at me?
- I'm not mad, Shaun.
I'm just busy trying to keep
like a billion bots and hackers
out of our network.
Actually, no, I'm not
doing that. Gonna go home.
You want to have some tequila,
stat? We also have some pizza left.
- No. I don't want tequila or pizza.
- That must mean you're mad.
I'm just upset. And confused.
And I really don't think there
is anything you can do about it,
so you just need to stop
trying and leave me alone.
- She's not mad at me.
- She's definitely mad at you.
She doesn't usually
hide what she thinks.
She's not mad at him.
She knows how
he is, how he talks.
She's mad at
herself. And scared.
We all have stuff that
we're insecure about.
That's why it's so
risky falling in love.
We all hope that when
we let our guard down,
it's for the one person
that doesn't see our flaws.
So, what do I do?
You were being honest.
You can't apologize that away.
You gotta figure out what she needs
to feel secure in the relationship again.
Don't look at me. I'm single.
It's not my place to
comment on your personal life.
You have an
opinion. Let's hear it.
Fine.
Can you zoom in
on her skull base?
I can, but why?
We're worried about her heart
and metabolic abnormalities.
We shouldn't be. Not anymore.
You and Dr. Murphy
were both wrong.
She doesn't have a
cardiac or metabolic issue.
She has poor blood flow
in the artery supplying blood
to the area of her brain
that controls consciousness.
A small clot in her
artery of Percheron.
If we don't remove it fast,
she's never going to wake up.
That's amazing.
No, it's not.
The heart's totally outside
of the body and still beating.
It's like it has a
mind of its own.
She should've started
the reimplantation by now.
Is everything okay, Dr. Lim?
The tumor had tendrils
invading the right atrial wall.
We took so much tissue to get a
clear margin, there's not enough left
to reconstruct his
heart's inflow chambers.
How about expanded PTFE graft?
There's not enough atrial
remnant to attach the graft.
You can use the septal wall.
He's got dense
conduction fibers there.
- It could cause heart arrhythmias.
- Not if you...
He's got low arterial pressure.
He's springing leaks
at the cannulation sites.
It's a bleeding disorder
caused by prolonged bypass.
You need to get his
heart back in ASAP.
Morgan, we can't put the heart
back in with two missing chambers.
It's a rare complication,
but a blood clot is
a risk in any surgery.
It's too deep in the
brain for open surgery.
If we go rooting around in
there, we'd damage the PCA.
We'd kill her.
We could inject a
dissolving agent into the clot.
There's a 50% probability
it won't fully dissolve,
which could leave her
with permanent weakness
and cognitive difficulties.
Assuming she wakes up at all.
We need to remove the
clot with a stent retriever.
If we rupture the
posterior cerebral artery,
she'll die on the table.
Or total recovery.
That's how she came into this
hospital. That's how she's leaving.
Prep her for stent retrieval.
Hanging platelets and
fresh frozen plasma.
His pressure is
still in the toilet.
But the bleeding
is slowing down.
Not for long.
Small intestine submucosa
has the right compliance
to shape the
chamber walls, but...
There isn't enough to
cover that much area.
Use too little and he'll
have heart failure in a month.
I know. That's the "but."
How thick is his deep fascia?
If it's over 2 millimeters...
Morgan, get out.
- I'm sorry. I'll be quiet.
- No, you won't. You can't.
So leave the OR gallery.
Now.
We need 2.6-millimeter-thick
tissue with perfect compliance
for arterial filling and
contractile pressures.
If it was just the valve, we'd
use a bovine pericardial graft.
But cow heart tissue is not durable
enough to do an entire chamber.
But pig bladder
tissue is just right.
I've used it for bladder
reconstructive surgeries,
but never hearts.
Let's rebuild the
entire atrial walls with it.
Get down to the
tissue procurement lab
and get 200 centimeters
of porcine bladder tissue.
Her EEG delta waves
are slowing further.
She only has one vessel
feeding her thalamus.
That's why the clot
landed where it did.
I'm approaching the
artery of Percheron.
I'm one millimeter
from the clot.
Stop right there.
If we disrupt this clot, we could
cause a shower of emboli into her brain.
Deploying the retriever.
- EEG just went flatline.
- Calm down. I'm almost...
Got it.
Blood's flowing
through the artery.
Her brain tracing's
looking better.
This should fill the gap between
the inferior and superior vena cava
when the new
chambers get sewn in.
Where's that graft?
I need more sponges. The
bleeding is getting worse.
Ah, he's tanking.
Can you push epi?
I already did. He's maxing out.
I'm running out of ways
to keep his pressure up.
I got it. They had
205 centimeters of it.
Thank you.
If you want to gown up, you
can watch from down here.
Definitely. Thanks.
I thought telling her how much I
love her in front of other people
would make her feel good.
But Dr. Guerin said I made
her feel insecure and scared.
Women are sensitive.
When commenting on their flaws,
total honesty is a
high-risk procedure.
That sounds sexist.
Aren't men also
insecure about their flaws?
Men are much, much worse.
And also, we're really stupid.
Okay, what can I do now?
I've already said
my stupid stuff.
I don't want her to
be upset with me.
I have a thought.
I think this run of sutures
will hold it to the annulus,
but I'm worried about leaks.
We can put a second row of pledgeted
sutures to make sure it's hemostatic.
That is unreal.
It's a work of art.
Now let's get it back in
while we can still get
him off bypass alive.
Reperfusing the heart.
We've got a rhythm.
Hey.
There was a complication
during the reconstruction surgery.
A clot, which caused
you to lapse into a coma.
We performed a second surgery
on your brain, which was successful.
Um...
You're gonna be fine.
But my breasts?
The clot occurred after we
finished inserting the implants.
I think you're gonna be
very pleased with the results.
Thank you.
Yeah.
I think I'm sorry.
Dr. Guerin said I should
never say anything
that might sound
negative to a girlfriend.
And Dr. Glassman said total
honesty is a high-risk procedure
with a girlfriend.
It's better to show my
love than try to explain it.
But I want to be
totally honest with you.
I don't like your body...
because it's excellent.
I like it because it's yours.
And I love hearing you talk.
When I hear your voice,
especially when I've
had a difficult day,
I find it comforting.
Now I want to hug you. Can I?
I'd like that.
I love you.
Thank you...
for your total honesty.
Your surgery went well.
With some time and rehab, you
should be back to work in a month.
Thank you.
Don't thank me.
Thank your surgeon.
She did all the important stuff.
Lim's golden boy is in.
Nothing we can do about that.
So that leaves three openings.
The thought of working with Will
Hooper for the next two years...
If Dr. Lim thinks he'll
be a good resident,
I'm sure she has good reasons.
She probably thinks arrogance
is helpful to a surgeon.
Well, we could try
to change her mind.
Nah, she asked us to
evaluate the applicants, not her.
She asked us to
be totally honest.
Yeah, "totally honest"
is a relative term
when you're telling your
boss she's totally wrong.
So Hooper's in. Who else?
Dr. Andrews likes
Dr. Jordan Allen.
I do too.
She's confident, driven.
She won't take a
lot of hand-holding,
and keeping Andrews
happy keeps us happy.
- Mm.
- That leaves two more. Who's next?
Asher Wolke is very
up-front about who he is.
I like that.
He's definitely eager.
And he couldn't be
more open to learning.
Ah, agree. That leaves one more.
John Lundberg.
Smart, professional,
mature. He's a no-brainer.
Lundberg's in.
Lundberg's out.
He stopped by my
office before he left,
said he's no longer interested.
He said you all
were unprofessional.
Drinking at work.
Asking inappropriate
questions. Dating drama.
Mm-hm. So who's your alt?
Olivia Jackson or Board Shorts?
Olivia knows her stuff,
but she's a bit insecure.
Her answers
sound like questions.
I like Board Shorts.
He's sensitive.
Like a woman.
I vote for both of them.
That's not an option.
We don't have the budget.
Hooper is the worst.
The person I said was the best?
He is arrogant and obnoxious.
If he works here, we'll
hate him, the work will suffer,
and we'll either kill
patients or we'll kill him.
And there is no way
that you don't see that,
which makes me think...
you do.
This was a test.
You just wanted to see
if we'd be totally honest.
Well done.
Hooper is definitely the worst.
I only let him shadow as
a favor to a board member.
I figured I'd give him a second
chance after his obnoxious interview.
And also do a little experiment.
So...
it's Jordan,
Asher, Olivia and Enrique.
To the next phase of
your surgical training.
You helped pick them.
As senior residents, it's now
your job to help train them.
And don't take this
responsibility lightly,
because if you don't train
them well, people will die.