Previously, on
"The Resident"...
Trevor, no one here
needs to know
that we're related,
that you're my biological son.
I need to talk to the state
medical board.
Dr. Bell asked me to write him
a recommendation for it.
He told me Robert Porter...
is angling for a seat
on the board.
He has to be stopped.
He raped me
when I was 13 years old.
Withdraw the complaint.
Say you lied for Dr. Bell, and
you'll never hear from me again.
You're scared.
Withdraw it
or I will destroy you.
I'm fully aware
of your mistakes.
I'll expose all of them,
and I will take away the
very thing you love the most,
your career.
♪ I got eight
on the shot clock ♪
♪ Boy, I'm not missing this ♪
♪ This is Mayweather sauce ♪
♪ With a jab,
I keep hitting back ♪
♪ Look at me now, drip down ♪
♪ Thought I was kidding, huh? ♪
You ready
to tap out yet, Hawkins?
No way.
You?
No, sir. I can do this all day.
Saved by the bell.
Ooh!
I've seen that smile before.
Getting in shape
for a lady friend,
- perhaps?
- Oh,
- is that a clinical diagnosis?
- 100%.
You know, I passed by Marion
headed to your house
this morning.
How's she doing?
Touché.
Oh, no.
What's wrong?
Breakfast potatoes,
turkey bacon, toast, eggs?
- What's the occasion?
- No occasion.
I just wanted to do
something nice for my sister.
Someone died, didn't they?
Was it Uncle Ishman?
Okay, Uncle Ishman
will outlive all of us.
But, um,
since today is the last day
before Devon comes home
from his conference,
uh, there's actually something
I wanted to talk to you about.
Padma, I got to go.
- Do you have to?
- It's kind of an emergency.
And we will talk later, okay?
And thank you. And I'm so sorry.
- What's up, Janice?
- Hey.
- What's all the commotion about?
- You haven't seen?
It's all over Twitter.
Apparently,
Dr. Sutton cut unsupervised
when she was a resident.
Ended up paralyzing a patient.
Why are we concerning ourselves
with a few inflammatory tweets?
If by "a few" you mean hundreds.
Are they wrong?
Did you not promote Dr. Sutton
knowing full well
she had been fired
for misconduct?
All doctors make mistakes.
Billie was promoted
because she deserved it.
Did she deserve it
over our surgeons
with more experience
and seniority?
What you should be asking
yourself is why these reports
are surfacing now, years later.
Dr. Voss is right.
There clearly is
an ulterior motive here.
Dr. Sutton filed a complaint
against a powerful doctor.
If I were to guess,
this is a smear campaign
designed to turn
the public against her.
Keeping Chastain under
this intense public scrutiny
is not something
we can risk right now.
Then what do you suggest?
You know how much this board
respects you, Dr. Voss.
But I think you should be
relieved of your CEO duties.
Just until we get
this situation handled.
- You want to fire me?
- No one's being fired.
We can mute the outrage
by putting someone in your seat
that can take the heat
off the hospital.
Even if we were considering
this, which we are not,
who would that person be?
Dr. Bell
is the obvious candidate.
I think we should take a vote.
All in favor
of putting Dr. Voss
on a temporary leave of absence.
"Groove Me"
by Fern Kinney playing...
♪ Hey there, sugar dumpling ♪
♪ Let me tell you something ♪
♪ Boy, I've been trying
to say now ♪
♪ You look so sweet and you're
so doggone fine ♪
♪ Just can't get you
out of my mind. ♪
AJ, did you talk to her?
I talked. Billie, not so much.
She needs to know
we're here for her.
This is wrong.
Those pansy-ass
keyboard crusaders
only show courage
behind a computer screen.
Or not.
I don't think
they're here for Billie.
I'll call EMS.
Tell them to hurry.
We have no idea how long
- she's been up there.
- She's not moving.
No doubt the blood has already
started to pool into her legs.
If she passes out, she'll
develop suspension syndrome.
That could kill her.
We need emergency services
to Chastain hospital now.
Hold on! We're getting you help!
Try to keep your legs moving!
- Gather around, y'all.
- Incoming trauma.
We need all
available hands on deck.
- Is this everyone?
- Dr. Pravesh won't be back
from his critical care
conference until tomorrow.
- But where are all the nurses?
- Dallas, Newark, L.A.
- Take your pick.
- Ugh, these travel contracts are no joke.
Last week I was offered
$130 an hour in Key West.
Housing, meal stipends.
If it weren't for Riley's
school, I'd have taken it.
We are fielding offers
left and right.
It's a national problem
hospitals are desperate to fix.
Same kind of nurse exodus
happened at Atlanta General.
Led to some pretty unsafe
working conditions.
Which is why Chastain
should cough up
the funds to keep us.
Instead, we get travel mugs
and back-to-back surgeries.
Speaking of which, I'm needed
in the OR five minutes ago.
Go. We'll make do.
- Bay 10.
- Window washer took a fall.
- Caught by her harness.
- Tachy to 130, BP 80/50.
Sats stable post-intubation.
One, two, three.
- Bolus a liter of LR. Let's get some norepi.
- Mm-hmm.
I'll get labs and EKG.
Let's get her
out of this harness.
Whoa, whoa.
That harness is
acting like a tourniquet.
- Restricting blood flow.
- And allowing toxins to accumulate.
- Remove the tourniquet and...
- Pop goes the weasel.
- Those toxins flood right into the body.
- Right.
We need to prepare
for the worst.
Say whatever you want,
there's a reason
Sutton was made
chief of surgery.
Hey.
We heard. I'm so sorry, Kit.
This won't stand.
It's a wrongful dismissal.
There's more to it than that.
This all leads back to Porter.
I'd put money he pushed
the board to suspend me.
But the real question is,
how are you doing, Billie?
Well, I feel awful.
This is all my fault.
No, none of this is on you.
Listen, Porter came
to see me last night.
He threatened to come after me
if I didn't withdraw
my complaint.
But I never expected this
to blow back on you.
He's trying to discredit you,
take away your allies.
- We can't let that happen.
- And Marshall called.
They want to install me
as interim CEO.
Do it.
We need you as a shield.
Well, better you
running the hospital
than some Porter ally.
Oh... Okay, I'll do it.
Oh,
please say it's not about me.
Another OR nurse
just handed in their notice.
Dealing with this
nursing shortage
was top of my priority list.
So this is your way of saying
it's my problem now?
Unfortunately for you,
but lucky for us.
Bicarb drip going up
and the calcium chloride's
- ready to push.
- Let's get some vasopressin in our back pocket.
- Just in case.
- Already ahead of you.
FAST is negative.
BP is stable.
We've done everything we can.
It still might not be enough.
Say the word.
Here we go.
BP is tanking, 60/20.
Her heart rate is skyrocketing.
Potassium is high,
which makes sense.
But her hemoglobin is 5.
She's profoundly anemic.
We need two units of blood.
Where's it all going?
Her FAST was negative,
but that doesn't rule out
a pelvic fracture.
Well, if she fell with enough
force to fracture her pelvis,
there's no telling
what other damage might be done.
This is as stable
as she's gonna get.
Let's get her to CT and figure
out what we're dealing with.
Uh, Hundley, page Kit.
- Tell her to meet us there.
- Okay.
The Sutton stuff is wild.
And beyond cruel. Poor Billie.
I read that she was banned from
practicing medicine in the U.S.
Come on, Janice.
That's not true.
How do you know?
I know, okay?
Can't you tell
these are all lies?
I didn't realize
you were such a fan.
I thought you didn't like her.
I don't like unwarranted
character assassinations.
- Preach, Trevor.
- You do realize people are trying
to destroy her reputation with
no proof and you're piling on.
When hundreds of people
are all saying the same thing,
you can't just discount it.
You can't blindly
believe it, either.
All I'm saying is that
where there's smoke
there's usually fire.
Hey, Hawkins.
Do you know what's up
with this Sutton thing?
- I assume it's getting worse.
- By the minute.
I know she's your friend.
Is there anything I can do?
Shut down any rumors
you hear around this place.
The gossip mill
is amplifying everything.
Yeah, that intern Trevor
was pretty upset.
Trevor?
- Why?
- I don't know.
But he was defending
the hell out of her.
- Hey.
You know I care about you,
right?
What is going on here?
Hmm, I wish I could
tell you, Conrad.
You can.
Uh, you won't understand.
Actually, the only person
who ever did
was Nic.
Times like this,
I really miss her.
Nic wouldn't want you
to carry this weight alone.
Talk to me.
I filed an ethics complaint
against a doctor
who's up for a seat
on the state medical board.
And now he's trying
to destroy you?
What kind of ethics complaint?
Uh, it was a...
"Me Too" kind of a thing.
I am so sorry.
When did this happen?
A long time ago.
- Too long ago.
- Doesn't matter.
We will fight back. Go public.
- Out him for the monster he is.
- I can't.
Why not?
It's complicated.
Please just keep this
between us.
- Promise me.
- Of course.
But if you're going into battle,
I want to be your wingman.
So, our window washer, who took
an unexpected bungee jump,
she has a spinal compression
and a pelvic fracture.
The spinal compression
appears minor.
No reason to believe
it wouldn't heal on its own,
but that pelvic fracture,
that's a different story.
Marshall told me what happened
with the board.
We are all standing
by you and Billie.
What he said.
We got your back, Boss Voss.
Just let us know what you need.
This.
Tara needs an open reduction
internal fixation
on her pelvis immediately.
It will be a brutal operation.
Incredibly long.
And I can't wait.
This is the best medicine
for Tara and me today.
I'll take it from here,
gentlemen.
Well, all right.
- Is it true?
- Depends. Which part?
Are you really a card-carrying
member of the Illuminati?
That's ridiculous.
We don't carry cards anymore.
I've had Internet mobs
come after me.
It can happen to anyone.
Oh, yeah? What did you do?
Uh, something to do with
Christmas being a pagan holiday.
You know, nothing to do
with baby Jesus.
I didn't realize
I'd be unleashing Armageddon.
Well, I could have
told you that.
But this...
this is a little different.
Wait, uh...
So, were you really cut
from your residency
for harming a patient?
Mostly true.
'Cause I opened and closed for
my attending on a regular basis.
I'd done that procedure for him
at least a dozen times.
So, when he was late,
I started without him.
And it was a terrible call.
I'll live with it
for the rest of my life.
But I was young and arrogant.
Can't really dock you
for youthful arrogance.
It's kind of my signature move.
But are you okay? Seriously.
Like you said,
it can happen to anyone.
Don't worry about me.
Double shift's almost over.
How you holding up?
My feet are killing me.
And I'm too tired to rub them.
Message received. Scoot.
- Come here.
- Hmm.
Another recruiter reached out.
This time to talk about a travel
nurse gig in Sacramento.
Did this one take no
for an answer?
I, um...
I might not have told her no.
I thought we agreed
moving wasn't an option.
Chastain is our home.
It's starting to feel like
a shelter for battered nurses.
You know I love Chastain,
but I don't know how long
I can take pulling triple duty.
This nursing shortage
has been hard,
- but it's temporary.
- Which means
it could be two weeks
or two years.
So you're going to meet her?
I won't sign anything
without talking to you first.
I just want to see
if the grass is any greener.
Okay.
Hey, you're just
the person I wanted to see.
Kit brought me up to speed
on the nursing shortage.
I know you've been
stretched thin.
More like flattened
to a pancake.
Well, I think we found a way
to lighten the load.
There's a handful
of nursing students
who can start
as early as tomorrow.
I appreciate the effort,
Dr. Bell,
but nursing students
aren't nurses.
They're just more work for us to train.
But they're extra hands
that we desperately need.
Which reminds me, can you
scrub in on a pelvic fracture?
Uh, I wish I could.
My shift just ended
and I have an appointment.
- Can't you reschedule?
- No, actually,
and that's what I want
to talk to you about, Dr. Bell.
I'm meeting with a recruiter.
- You're leaving us?
- No.
I mean, not yet.
I'm-I'm just testing the waters.
Jessica, you are a crucial
member of this team.
Especially to me.
Of course, but I...
I know I speak
for every other surgeon when
I say you hold tremendous value.
I know.
That's why I have
to explore my options.
Mrs. Wharthon? You can't leave.
You're supposed to be getting
prepped for your laminectomy.
That's cancelled.
- I don't understand.
- Look, I would have to be
a fool to allow myself
to be operated on
by a surgeon
who killed a patient.
At the very hospital
that turned a blind eye.
Hey, Irene, Irene...
I hear your concern.
But neither
of those things happened.
You expect me to believe that?
Pelvic reduction
forceps, please.
You know, this lack of
support is really killing my vibe.
With all the scrub nurses gone,
who's going to remember
to feed your ego?
Oh, I can tell you've
had a rough day today, Dr. Voss,
so I'm gonna let that one slide.
Randolph.
Did we call
for a general surgeon?
No, just filling in for Jessica.
Randolph Bell.
The man, the myth,
the scrub nurse.
Ever think you'd gain
two jobs in one day, darling?
Uh, let's hold off
on the pet names for a sec.
Looks like we got a problem.
Must have injured a vessel
pulling the anterior
pelvis together.
Yeah, the pulse is present.
But she must not be getting
any venous drainage to her legs.
And here I thought
my services were not needed.
Nurse Bell, scalpel.
Thank you.
Dissecting for proximal
and distal exposure.
Retractors.
Huh. Hmm.
New job looks good on you.
Don't get used to it.
All right.
All right, well,
there you have it.
All credit for the save
goes to our exceptional
new scrub nurse.
I'll be right back
to check on you, all right?
What now?
As hard as this is to say,
you were right.
I shouldn't have said
anything about Dr. Sutton.
Yeah, you think?
Everything okay?
Dr. Sutton submitted
an ethics complaint
against a very powerful doctor
who's trying
to get on the state
medical board
and now he's retaliating.
Whoa, wait,
an ethics complaint? When?
Apparently it was
a long time ago,
but that's not the worst part.
The complaint was that
he is a sexual predator.
Give me your phone so I know
you're not recording this.
Now yours.
Okay.
Here's the offer.
You pull your name
out of the running
for the state medical board,
I'll say it was a case
of mistaken identity
and withdraw my statement.
Why do you care so much
about the state medical board?
A predator like you has
no place passing judgment
on the ethics of other doctors.
We remember the past
very differently.
I was 13. The law is clear.
You're in no position
to give me ultimatums.
You have no proof,
not one shred of evidence
to back up your accusation.
What you do have
is a checkered past of your own
that includes malpractice.
I was a resident,
and my attending
was legally responsible.
But I already paid the price
for that. It's long over.
Clearly, that is not the case.
Otherwise you wouldn't be here.
I am one of the most prominent,
revered doctors in Georgia.
Your word against mine,
you lose every time.
- Then why are you here?
- I want my record cleared.
Withdraw the complaint.
That is enough of a bargain.
You have an impressive résumé,
Jessica.
There are a dozen hospitals
that would kill
to have you on their roster.
Any of these hospitals
happen to be in Georgia?
Atlanta, specifically?
Currently, we're only looking
to fill positions in Sacramento.
Which is far away.
Look,
I have the greatest respect
for nurses. My sister is one.
I know all about the scut work,
the-the double shifts.
You're not appreciated
as you should be.
And you're certainly
not compensated as such.
But that is changing.
FHM will not only cover
your relocation expenses,
we will pay you $7,500 a week
for only 48 hours of work.
Comes out to $150 dollars
an hour.
With unparalleled
health benefits,
and we will pay for your housing
as long as you're with us.
- Wow.
- Not to mention,
in California,
nurses are unionized,
so if you decide
to stay longer...
This is an intriguing offer.
But I need to think about it.
Well, my flight leaves
in six hours,
so I'll need an answer by then.
Oh.
Okay.
Is the pain normal?
Unfortunately.
You underwent
a massive pelvic repair.
The harness that saved you
almost cost you your life.
It may take you a while
before you're scaling
the sides of buildings again,
but give it time.
And, until then,
we'll try to keep you
as comfortable as possible.
Thank you.
That's all right, dear,
just let it out.
Sorry about that.
The anesthesia used in surgery
makes most people nauseous.
Surgery? Who had surgery?
You did. After the fall.
Don't you remember?
Tara, can you tell us
where you are?
This might be uncomfortable.
Absent gag reflex. Confusion.
This could be a sign
of cerebellar herniation.
What exactly are you saying?
I'm withdrawing my complaint
against Porter.
Why?
If he was so sure
of his position,
he wouldn't have met with you.
He's scared.
- So am I.
- Of what?
Of where this is heading.
Don't let him
get into your head.
Look, I am willing
to take any blow myself.
I'm tough enough to handle it.
But I can't inflict damage
on you or Chastain.
I won't fight a battle
I can't win
if it ends up hurting
the people I love.
- We're not afraid.
- We're fighting with you.
Billie, has something else
happened?
I got pregnant when I was raped,
and I had the baby.
Uh, we've reconnected.
But he's starting to ask
questions and figure things out.
If he finds out
how he came into this world,
it might destroy him.
I have to protect him.
I have to put an end to this.
We'll stand with you.
Whatever your decision.
Hey. I got your text. What's up?
Did you know Billie
had filed a complaint
against a state
medical board nominee?
What are you talking about?
He's the one coming
after her online.
Because of some interaction
they had a while ago.
I think I figured out who he is.
Listen, Trevor,
you need to stop. All right?
- If Billie didn't tell you any of this...
- Yeah, that's the point.
Why would she hide it?
Why would she...
Why would she care if I know
about an ethics complaint
against some-some random doctor?
I am advising you,
as your mentor
and your friend,
you need to drop this.
There are only two nominees
to the state medical board.
Bell and this guy.
His name is Robert Porter.
And that's not all I know.
I, um, I did this deep dive.
It turns out Porter lived
in the same town as Billie.
Same neighborhood.
Until her family moved away,
and you know when they did that?
Six months before I was born.
- All right, that's enough. That's it.
- No, no...
You don't know
when to quit, do you?
See, that's your problem.
You don't know anything
- about boundaries, Trevor.
- Boundaries?
Boundaries?
Really?
There was no high school romance
with a football player,
was there?
No accidental pregnancy.
You know the truth.
You need to tell me, um...
Robert Porter is my father,
isn't he?
She was 13.
He was an adult.
He forced himself on her, and...
I'm the product of a rape?
Trevor.
All this time she was
protecting me from the truth.
That my biological father
is a monster.
Trevor, listen to me.
You are the product
of your own actions.
- You hear me?
- No.
Trevor. Trevor!
How's Billie doing?
- Is she joining us?
- I don't know.
There's a lot going on.
None of it good.
What's the story?
Tara made it through
an extensive orthopedic
and vascular surgery.
Then she developed signs
- of cerebellar herniation.
- What do you see?
Right here.
A traumatic Chiari malformation.
It's subtle.
Trauma CTs can easily miss it.
But how did it happen?
There wasn't any direct trauma
to her head.
She did have that
spinal fracture.
- It looked stable, but...
- That can cause a tear
in the dura, allowing
spinal fluid to leak out.
So we need to close the leak.
First with a spinal surgery,
and then the brain.
I can do it.
Are you sure
you're in the right headspace?
No doubt.
Well, I'd never bet
against Dr. Billie Sutton.
As Dr. Voss is aware,
I have a hard out,
so I'll take Tara to the OR now.
Is she gonna fight?
No.
The fight is already lost.
All we can do is respect
her decision and her privacy...
...and back her.
Glad to have you
back in the OR, Dr. Sutton.
We missed you.
We need music.
"Groove Me"
by Fern Kinney playing...
Whoa, that's
under a lot of pressure.
It is. And you're gonna open it.
Efficiently,
so that the cerebellum
doesn't herniate out
the dural opening.
I'm on it. 15 blade to me.
♪ Uh, ooh... ♪
Let's start at the bottom.
Get it open within ten seconds.
♪ Come on, baby... ♪
If we're lucky,
fluid will release
and the brain will decompress.
♪ Let me tell you
something, boy ♪
♪ I've been trying
to say now... ♪
Uh, she's still herniating.
We have to access
the spinal fluid.
How do we do that?
We need to cauterize the bottom
of the cerebellum.
That's the only way
we can decompress this.
Electrocautery to me, now.
♪ We can do it, we can do it ♪
♪ We can do it,
we can do it ♪
♪ Come on, I'm feeling it ♪
♪ Come on, come on, come on... ♪
That was amazing.
If anyone ever questions
your competency again,
I'm gonna tell them about this.
♪ I need you to groove me... ♪
You're a force of nature.
♪ Now, darling. ♪
So...
Well, what number
did they give you?
I want to know what Chastain
is offering first.
HFM's offer was double.
You can't be serious.
But the cost of living
in California is higher, so...
to adjust for that,
I'd need at least...
And you have to hire
five more nurses.
- Real ones, not students.
- I...
No more three-to-one assignments
in the ICU.
And stop the mandatory overtime.
Kit has given me
this much room...
and that's it.
You can have three nurses.
And... let me just say
that this family
is more than the sum
of its parts.
It's like any family.
So do we have a deal?
Okay.
Oh, Kit told me that you
scrubbed in, in my place.
It made me feel
warm and fuzzy inside.
Yeah, it was a humbling moment
in my career.
And one of
the most enlightening.
I'm glad you're staying.
Me, too.
It's gonna be fine.
Don't worry.
This seat taken?
You didn't have to come.
Yes, we did.
We're a team.
Teams stick together.
- Hey, buddy. Thanks.
- Hey, how are you?
So, Dr. Sutton,
you called this meeting.
You have something
you want to say,
now is the moment.
I'm here
to withdraw my complaint
against Dr. Porter.
Dr. Sutton, you owe
this board an explanation.
Why come up with this heinous
lie against a fellow doctor?
A pillar
of our medical community?
- A...
- Pedophile.
This is a private
meeting, young man.
I'm sorry, but...
but who the hell are you?
My name is Dr. Trevor Daniels.
I was born August 3, 1995
to my mother, Dr. Billie Sutton,
and Robert Porter, who raped her
when she was 13 years old.
Okay, this...
this is a ridiculous stunt.
Test my DNA against his.
I am the living proof that
everything my mom says is true.
Oh, my God.
- Is this number real?
- Really real.
- And Bell signed off on it?
- Uh-huh.
Aren't you gonna say something?
- This is more money than I make.
- I know. Are you mad?
Are you kidding me?
I have a sugar mama.
Yes! Hello!
I'm so proud of you.
We can set up
your weekly allowance.
- You can buy me a new car.
- Okay.
Hey.
How was work?
You rushed out pretty quick
this morning.
Yeah, I know.
Today was weird.
But I'm here now.
Are you buying a house?
Are you leaving me?
We need to talk.
Please don't go.
Look, I know
I bailed on you earlier.
And I'm always grumpy.
And I think about strangling you
every time I step
on one of your crystals.
Okay, they have
to charge somewhere.
Not on the floor.
The point is,
I love having you here.
In Atlanta, close to me,
so if you're
trying to run away, please stay.
I'm not running away, Leel.
I'm... adulting.
Okay.
Well, that's great.
I've been thinking
a lot about my future.
And while #VanLife
has its perks, it's holding me
back from what I actually want.
A child.
I want to have a baby.
But I thought
with the leukemia, it's...
I can't get pregnant on my own.
That's... that's why I wanted
to talk to you.
Do you want to adopt?
Or look for a surrogate?
I could gather resources
from Chastain.
Um, no, I, um,
I want this baby to be
100% me.
And since we're
identical twins,
I was wondering...
would you give me
one of your eggs?
My eggs?
In your body?
It makes perfect sense.
You and I are
genetically identical.
It would be no different
than me using one of my own.
I understand, it's just...
It's a lot
to wrap my head around.
And...
in a very real way,
it would be my kid, as well.
And who would
take care of it...?
Adulting, remember?
This is... about me growing up.
Anyone home?
Just think about it.
- Hey.
- Hi.
Did I miss anything?
What did the
lieutenant governor say?
Well, Porter's out.
And, hopefully, when the results
of the DNA test come back in,
he'll lose
his license to practice
in the state of Georgia.
I wouldn't mind seeing him
behind bars.
Does this mean you'll be
on the medical board?
Looks that way.
Thanks to Billie.
You didn't have to do that.
I did.
You were incredibly brave.
So were you.
I'm sorry I couldn't
protect you from this.
But I'm proud
of how you handled it.
Are you okay, Trevor?
I...
honestly, I-I don't know.
I'm sorry, I-I think
I just need some time.
Away from all this.
Okay.
Thank you.
And I'm here if you...
Okay.
Hey.
You okay?
Yes.
Or, at least, I will be.
You know, tomorrow's my day off.
My dad has Gigi.
You want to go somewhere
with me and just...
talk?
I don't want you to be alone.
I'd like that.
Captioning sponsored by
20th CENTURY FOX TELEVISION
and TOYOTA.
Captioned by Media Access
Group at WGBH access.wgbh.org