I am fine.
I am happy to be here.
Truly, I have
been through a lot,
and I'm lucky to be alive, and
I'm lucky to be okay, and I get that.
So, yes, I'm just
happy to be here.
Great.
You know, Doctor,
most surgeons, uh,
get kind of rankled at
hospital-mandated therapy.
Bailey's just
looking out for me.
I know the drill.
So, this should be quick.
You know, you
chose the short straw,
or the... Is it the long straw?
Whatever the good straw is.
Lay off the damn horn, will ya?
God, carpool sucks. Hang on.
Is Wilson coming?
I think so. What do
you mean you think so?
I can't... She's
all over the place.
I don't even know why she
let me back in the house.
I mean, we barely talk,
which is probably good
because it's fewer chances
I'll piss her off again.
That's pathetic.
What's her problem?
She's in a mood.
Still?
I said to tell her that
I needed a minute.
You didn't tell me that.
- Yes, I did.
You didn't listen.
So done with carpool.
Incoming.
Twenty minutes, chest pains.
I'll take it. Page cardio.
Anyone but Riggs.
Page Riggs.
He just said...
I can hear.
You know that Dr. Hunt
punched Dr. Riggs.
The only way they're
gonna learn to work together
is if they work together,
so any cardio consults that get
paged to the pit, you page Riggs.
You know, this is my one
happy place right now?
Please don't make
it a crappy place.
Oh, Kepner, I feel you. I do.
Page Riggs.
Hi. Maya Roberts.
Dr. Karev. I know.
Uh, this is my mom, Judi.
Thank you for making the
time to see my daughter.
Have we met before?
I looked you up.
And you are? Uh...
Cross. Dr. Cross. Go.
Right.
"Maya Roberts, 15.
"Status, post below-knee amputation
of the right leg two years ago
"after diagnosis of bone cancer,
"now recurring in
the ribs and sternum."
I know why I'm here.
I just wanted to talk about you.
It says here in your CV
you made buttholes for
babies who didn't have them.
Hang on. That's...
Listen, I'm 15 with
a chest full of cancer.
This hospital is known for
making miracles happen,
and I'm looking for
an epic-size miracle.
According to my
research, it looks like
you're the guy who
can make it happen.
I am confused
about the buttholes.
Strange detour. So, discuss.
Or how about you
humor me and let me
pretend like I'm in
charge for a sec?
Now, uh, Ms. Roberts...
What do you want to know?
Two years ago, I felt
a pain in my right tibia.
She's got a real
mind for this stuff.
They did labs, PET
scan, the works.
Turns out I'm one in, like, a
bajillion kids to get chondrosarcoma.
So, chemo and radiation
weren't an option.
You get points.
Sweet. Hmm.
Sorry.
Hey, remember,
we said no crying.
I know. I'm sorry.
There was a one-in-four
chance of recurrence,
so it's not a huge shocker,
but it is back, and it's
bigger than ever in my chest.
We have our work cut
out for us, gentlemen.
Uh, Robbins is
going out tonight.
Do you want to maybe
come over when you're done?
Yeah. No, crap.
We have a Mer thing.
Again? Yeah.
Come over after?
Yes. Okay.
Go. Fix your hair.
Chest pains, huh? Yep.
So, what's he doing
here? Kepner, I told you...
I know you did, but
this is what's happening.
- I gave you a direct order.
- Come on, Hunt.
You've turned everyone
here against me.
The least you can do
is let me frigging work.
You have no business
being here at all!
Guys, come on.
You know, I'm sick and
tired of hearing about it.
Why don't you find
someplace else to work?
Oh, yay! Someone's hurt.
Male, 55, complaining
of tightness in the chest.
Sir, do you have any
pain in your left arm?
No, not really.
My chest hurts
like hell, though.
Riggs, you can go. I got this.
Chest pains. I'll take it.
Sir, what did you
eat this morning?
A burrito. Two burritos.
It's probably not surgical.
I'll page someone
if it is. Let's go.
How about you let me do my job?
How about you
get the hell away...
How about you both shut up?
Cover him!
Oh, God!
Boom, I'll be in, I'll be out.
These sessions
shouldn't take all that long.
But before we start, Doctor,
I was assigned your case,
and if you would prefer
a female therapist,
I would be totally
comfortable with that.
Oh, because it was a man
who attacked me? Yeah.
And it's important that you feel
that you're with
the right person,
that you feel comfortable,
that you get what you need.
I appreciate that. I'm fine.
I just need a tape-and-glue guy.
Tape and glue?
Yeah, just, you know,
ask me a few questions
and patch me up and
send me on my way.
I've been to therapy
before. Uh-huh.
I've dealt with the big stuff.
This isn't the big stuff
that we're dealing with.
Meredith, you were
attacked in your own hospital,
and you consider
that small stuff?
Have you read my file?
You're saying that
you've been through a lot.
I am, and I have.
My mother died of Alzheimer's.
My stepmother
died of the hiccups.
My sister died in a plane crash.
My husband was hit by a semi.
That file, it's a
real page-turner.
Meredith, something
terrible happened to you.
It did.
And terrible things
happen every day.
What the hell was...
- Coming through!
Oh, my God.
Shepherd, with me, Trauma Two.
All right, take him
into Trauma Three.
Tell any incoming to
go somewhere else.
Keep everyone out
of the ambulance bay.
I need a trauma panel, lap
pads, and a surgical tray.
- Someone notify the OR!
- Right away, Doctor.
Hold on. You're next.
I should've gone somewhere else.
What the hell was that?
- Ambulance exploded.
- What?
Partial thickness burns
to the upper chest.
Follow the light with your eyes.
Okay, good.
What happened?
Your rig exploded,
but don't worry.
We've got you, okay?
You're gonna be okay.
Oh, Shepherd, they
need you in Trauma One.
Mmm-hmm.
They figure out
why that rig blew up?
Uh, fire department's
looking at it now.
Oh, God.
It was me.
I didn't secure the oxygen tank.
Johnny's always saying...
He's gonna kill me.
It was an accident,
he knows that.
He's gonna kill me.
Don't arch your neck. All right.
There's a lot of venous
blood in the upper chest.
The lac extends
deep into the liver.
Okay, let me get in there
and establish vascular control.
No, we're gonna pack
him and take him up.
And then we'll be able to
see what the hell's going on.
He's open right
now. Just let me work.
He is hemorrhaging like crazy.
I'm not gonna let him
bleed out down here.
Suction. More laps.
He's got a depressed skull
fracture. He needs a CT.
Look, Owen, you
know I can do this.
Let me stabilize him.
Riggs, this is the plan.
Get on board, or get out.
Your plan's working great.
Better still, just get out.
Kepner, over here.
To hell with this!
When you first woke
up after the attack,
what is the first
thing you remember?
People.
People running
around everywhere.
Who, specifically?
It was pretty crazy.
Oh. Thank you.
You, sir, have indigestion.
DeLuca here will
get you an antacid.
Sorry, sir.
And, uh, also schedule an
upper endoscopy, please.
DeLuca, do you have
somewhere to be?
No. Then put the
damn phone away.
Okay, he'll, uh, get you
the rest of your meds,
and you just sit tight, okay?
DeLuca!
Torres is on her way.
Oh, okay, thanks.
Hey, uh, listen,
do you think tonight
maybe you and I
could just... I don't know.
Oh, actually, I'm having
some people over tonight.
It's... It's nothing big, just
Steph, Blake, and Warren.
Okay, yeah.
I mean, I get off late,
but I can pick up
something on the way home.
No, I meant, uh,
I'd kind of just like to spend
some time with my friends.
Oh.
Yeah, no.
I got something
later anyway, so...
Oh, great, so you
have someplace to be.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, I
got someplace to be.
Finally, uh...
Can you, uh, look at these?
Mmm-hmm.
So, how old is this patient?
Fifteen going on 35.
Standard titanium plates, right?
Unless her parents will go for a
stem-cell scaffolding in the chest.
Well, it's, uh, just the mom,
and, look, I don't
want to leave this girl
with an unprotected
heart for years.
I need to make a recommendation.
Well, we could look
into new technology.
No, I want the safest option.
Then you go with plates.
Tried and true.
So? Hit me.
Well, I, uh, consulted with
our ortho and cardio chiefs,
and, uh, the best solution is a
titanium-plate sternum and ribcage.
Okay.
That's... That sounds good.
How many revision surgeries?
Probably once a year
until you reach full growth.
And if I get hit with, say,
even a Nerf ball to the chest?
Well, we'll just be
very careful, won't we?
Just answer my question.
It's very dangerous, yes.
So, we're talking
multiple surgeries?
You're just gonna open
and reopen my chest?
I'm... I'm sorry.
Can you explain what she...
A zipper scar.
Oh.
Oh, honey, I...
We'll need to go in a few times,
but I assure you it's
the safest, best option.
I figured out how to do
it all on a leg and a half,
and now you want to limit
everything I do for my entire childhood?
This is how you get the
rest of your childhood.
I'm trying to save
your life, Maya.
Sweetheart, we should
consider this. Maybe...
I went to three different
hospitals before I came here,
and they all said
the same thing.
They said, "Go to Grey
Sloan. Go to Dr. Karev."
So, now I'm here, and
this is all I get, just this?
I'm disappointed in you.
Dr. Karev, you're off my case.
I'm sorry?
You're fired.
A terrible thing happened.
I did get knocked around.
But nobody died.
And any day where nobody
dies, that's a good day.
So, when you were laid up
healing, who visited you the most?
Alex.
Remind me, Alex is...
Alex is the one who
proposed to his girlfriend.
Right. And she said no.
Well, see, she didn't really
say no, and she didn't say yes,
and then she booted him, and
then he came back to live with me.
Alex was there when you woke up.
I delivered him on
a silver platter to her.
And he still managed
to screw it up.
Ugh. You said he
moved back in with her.
I mean, to the place.
They're together, but
they're not together,
but they could
be together. It's...
They're stupid.
You have feelings for Alex?
Are you in love with Alex?
Do I have feelings for Alex?
That's funny.
No.
I'm sorry.
I'm just trying to understand
why we're talking about them.
Because he's being stupid.
Uh, can she actually fire us?
She's a kid. Oh, shut up.
She's older than you
are, and she's smarter.
She'll cool off.
She'll come around.
Go check my post-ops.
I've never been fired before.
Does this go on my
permanent record?
God.
Look, you have to
stop paging me, okay?
I'm getting in trouble now.
I was trying to find
out if you were...
"You okay?" "Are you okay?"
"You okay?" Yes, I'm okay.
Why wouldn't I be okay?
I thought you got blown
up by an ambulance.
What? I wasn't even...
You were worried about me.
Aw.
Oh, crap.
A consult. Mmm-mmm.
Mmm, okay. Now you're
getting me in trouble.
Mmm.
I mean, who cares if
DeLuca is an intern?
It's all sexy and
secret at first,
and then it's just
a pain in the ass.
So, they should just
bring it out in the open.
That's what Derek and I did, and
we have three beautiful children.
And is Maggie the one in
AA? Or is she the hoverer?
The hoverer.
That's the other thing.
If she was getting it regular,
maybe she would stop
hovering all the time.
Oh, sorry. Oh, hey.
Um...
How are you? Are
you... You good?
Did you hear about
the ambulance?
Oh, yeah, I know.
That's so crazy, right?
Well, I mean, fire, O2 tanks,
poor maintenance, cigarettes.
I'm sorry?
Reasons ambulances explode.
It happens all the time,
actually, which is weird,
considering that their
job is to not kill people...
but it happens just like...
Yeah, so, um,
are you good?
I'm okay.
Uh, I should...
I didn't screw them up.
I was nice.
Penny killed my husband.
I took her in, I'm teaching her.
I am trying to make
something good out of it.
That was very cool of
me. I didn't have to do that.
No, you didn't, but why did you?
And now Callie thinks
I'm coming between them,
and Blake thinks
so, too. I can feel it.
And it's just not true.
I did not come
between their great love.
Wasn't me.
I'm sorry.
Who's Callie again?
Callie is my friend in ortho.
Ah, yeah.
Come on, keep up.
ICP is normalizing.
This drain is doing the trick.
We'll observe him tonight,
and I'll take him up to the OR
tomorrow and repair the liver lac.
Kepner, you free?
Uh, yeah. Just let
me know. Great.
I will scrub in and remove
the drain at the same time.
Thanks. Mmm-hmm.
So, you still living
with Richard?
I'm crashing here.
It's a better commute.
Amelia, you know
you can stay with me.
It's not a good
idea for my sobriety.
Right.
I'm gonna need dinner, though.
Great.
Dinner tonight?
Okay.
So, Hunt and I will do
the liver lac tomorrow.
How is the, uh, partner?
Stable.
Worried about his friend.
You should have
cardio there, too,
so bring in Riggs
just to be safe.
Come on.
I'm sorry?
You know there was an
explosion in the ER this morning.
I just really don't want to see
another one over
an open patient.
You make a good point.
Wait, so it all comes
out in one piece?
Exactly.
That's so freaking cool.
What's going on?
Oh, um, Dr. Karev, uh, these
two are gonna make me those.
Pierce and I had an idea.
'Cause they're geniuses.
Well, she kind of is, too.
It does sound pretty amazing.
You just took over my case?
She paged us for a consult.
Yeah, no offense, but
you're not my doctor anymore.
But I think when you see
this, you're gonna want in.
Can we show him this?
Yeah, mmm-hmm. - Yeah, hit it.
Okay, so, I can
excise Maya's tumors,
but instead of the traditional
titanium reconstruction,
I can 3D print a new
sternum and ribs.
They'll be molded to her
exact body specifications
so she can move
around more naturally.
Have you ever done this?
It's only been done
once before on an adult,
but I can modify it for a child.
Yeah, I'll be the first.
I'll look like the
Terminator, which is badass.
Can I see you two outside?
You said yourself titanium
plates are the best option.
That was before
I knew that Callie
could print her her own ribcage.
It will be fewer
surgeries in the long run.
You're not experimenting
on some kid.
She may think she
knows what she wants,
but she's not old enough
to understand the risks.
She gets it. Trust me.
I know a little something about
being labeled too
smart for your age.
I love her.
I'm not signing off on this.
You're not on the case anymore,
and her mom has
the consent forms.
Oh, you know as well as I
do she's freaking useless.
I mean, you can't even...
Karev, Karev. Hey.
Ms. Roberts, please.
This is a dangerous
experimental procedure
with zero proof that it'll work,
let alone keep your kid alive.
Trust me when I tell you
you don't want to do this.
Please, Mom.
It's what she wants.
You swiped her.
We didn't swipe her.
She fired you and asked us.
Look, no one's
looking out for this kid.
Not her mom, not anyone.
Um, we are, Alex.
And I wouldn't have
even suggested it
if I didn't believe that it
was the best thing for her.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
No arguing. Fun.
Remember? Fun?
For Meredith, for support.
I postponed sex for this.
Maggie's a hoverer.
God, she hovers all the time.
Does it bother
you, the hovering?
No, she's just being
sisterly or whatever.
Why would you say that?
So, how long is
this going to last?
Come on. It's fun.
I want to go to bed.
Well, I do, too,
and I can't go home.
I don't want to go home alone.
I miss Penny.
I miss having sex.
Oh, Penny and I
had the greatest sex.
It was that
journey-of-discovery,
great sex you have
in the beginning.
Jo and I had sex
like that all the time.
And now no Penny, no
sex. No sex with Penny.
Nothing.
Okay, let's not talk about sex,
because the chief is here.
I'm just eating my pizza.
Besides, it sounds like none
of y'all are getting any anyway.
- Pierce is getting some.
- No, I'm not.
Don't say that.
Forget he said that.
So annoying.
She has people
over all the time,
like if I'm alone, I'll
explode or something.
They won't go away.
Okay, but, guys,
really, you can go.
No, we're here because it's fun.
No, really, it's okay.
Are you sure? I can...
'Cause you seem a
little... Cranky as hell?
Which is totally understandable
with everything
you've gone through.
- Of course you would be.
- We're worried.
You don't have
to worry. We know.
And I'm not cranky.
I know.
Except you are, all the time.
Do you want to be alone?
Well, I'm a widow.
I'm good at it.
I really just want... What?
Well, then tell them to go away.
Well, no, because
they're just trying to help.
What do you want?
What can we do?
But they're not being helpful.
And it's all right for
you to tell them that.
Leave my house.
Get out.
I mean, thank you,
but really, just go be with
whoever somewhere else
so that I can go to sleep.
Leave.
You seem angry.
I'm not.
My bad.
I took your advice.
I kicked them all out
of my house last night.
And?
It worked. They left me alone.
Well, that's what you wanted.
I know.
Hey. Dr. Webber.
Arizona's just gonna
be a second, so...
All right, thanks.
Hey, let's get a move on!
Trivia's starting in 15 minutes!
Coming!
Hey. You looking sharp.
You got a hot date?
Uh, yeah, something
like that. Hmm.
She's, uh... We're
kind of keeping it quiet.
Oh, secret romance.
I'm guessing she
works at the hospital?
I mean, she...
Relax, son.
I get it.
You know, it's been a few years,
but if yours is anything like
mine was, keeping it a secret
makes it just that
much more exciting.
You know, you're totally right.
I mean, she... She keeps it so
together in front of people at work,
but then, when we're alone...
She's a wildcat, huh?
How do I look?
Do I look hot?
Yeah, yeah, yeah,
you're very hot.
Can we go now?
Thank you. Whoo.
Okay. See you later.
You have fun, too.
All right, have fun
tonight, DeLuca. Thanks.
Oh, and, uh, you
can't tame a wildcat.
It's infuriating.
Because I know that our problems
haven't just
magically disappeared.
Thanks. Mmm-hmm.
Hey, uh, when are the
rest of the guys coming?
This is it.
All right.
Why did you let him move in?
Because he showed up at my door
all sad with his big, sweet face
and made me forget everything
that was wrong with us.
I know.
I see Callie walking
down the hall.
She and I are barely
talking, and I still get stupid.
Ugh.
I want to get stupid
over somebody.
All I ever feel is smart. - Mmm.
I just want to take his
dumb, gorgeous face,
and I just... I want
to... I want to pummel it
and kiss it and marry
it, and just pummel it.
I get that, too.
Mmm.
Not the pummeling,
but the kissing.
Mmm.
I thought you didn't
even want to marry him?
I don't know what I
want. I can't be trusted.
I wonder what guys want.
Hey, Warren, Warren.
You're a guy. What do you want?
Um...
You know, that's,
uh... That's tough. Um...
Did anybody see that an
ambulance blew up in the ER today?
No, we're serious.
What do guys want?
Out of this conversation.
Oh, um...
I just got an important
text, and I have to go.
Oh, you are impossible.
Oh, women are
just as impossible.
Really?
Look, I, uh...
I can't speak for all men.
I'm just a guy who wants
to go home to his wife.
Sorry. Good night.
Oh.
Screw Bailey.
Aw, she got the good one.
She did.
Mmm.
Ho-ho!
Looks like you owe
me another beer.
Oh, hell.
Hey, no one forced you to
take bets you couldn't win.
What is the deal, Nathan?
No deal.
Go again?
I talked about Owen dozens of
times when we were over there,
and you never even
mentioned knowing him.
Well, I didn't want
to talk about it.
So, what, you guys have just,
like, always hated each other?
I never hated him.
We became doctors together,
went through school, field training.
There was no one I trusted more.
We were like brothers.
What happened?
You're up.
Okay, so we're not
talking about this?
We're playing darts.
How'd you get so
good at darts anyway?
You pick up some things
when you have no
reason to go home.
So, what are you gonna do?
You gonna sign the papers?
We're playing darts.
Fine with me.
Hey, you ready? I'm starving.
Listen, can we do
this another night?
Uh, okay.
I'm not hungry,
and I don't want to...
What's wrong? Nothing, nothing.
Just be better
another night, okay?
Is this about Riggs?
Can you...
I'm not getting into it.
Everything doesn't
need to be talked about.
Okay.
Yeah, I understand.
So, another time, you will
call me, and we'll go out.
But you won't, will you?
Or you will and I
will cave and go
and I will talk too much
and you will say nothing.
And I'm...
I don't know how to
do this thing that you do
where you make me feel like crap
and there are no words
coming out of your mouth.
So, whatever.
You'll call me,
maybe, or maybe not.
And maybe I will not care.
I had a sister.
Megan.
She was three years
younger than me.
Smarter than me, funnier than
me, better person than me, okay?
But she did everything I did.
We went to med school together,
and that's where we met Riggs.
Nate was my best friend.
And Megan loved him.
And he was with her
the day that we lost her.
I trusted him with her, and
he was like a brother to me.
And he should've...
But he didn't.
And I don't talk about it.
Okay.
Can I say one thing?
She loved him.
There's a reason.
She loved him for a reason.
That's what I hold on
to. Derek loved her.
Your sister loved Riggs.
So, there's good in there.
That makes him family.
And that means that maybe
he deserves another chance.
Are you still hungry?
What are we eating?
I could go for a pizza.
Me, too.
What are you doing here?
Hanging.
I kicked you off my case.
I know. I'm not
gonna operate on you.
Then what are you doing here?
I'm holding your hand.
Figured you'd want
someone to hold your hand.
I mean, if you have
nothing better to do.
Okay, Maya. We're ready to roll.
Dr. Karev.
All right, everybody,
clear the room.
Give her a minute.
Okay.
You want me to get your mom?
No, no. She'll just freak out.
She was practically my
age when she had me.
And she works two jobs to cover
my bills and the good insurance.
She tries.
If something happens to me,
will you tell her that there's
an envelope under my bed
with bank statements
and the deed to our house?
Just don't forget, okay?
Hey, none of that.
Oh, God, I don't want to die.
You're not gonna die.
We both know you
can't promise anything.
You good?
Yeah.
Let's do this.
Um, do me a favor, though.
If you're not too busy
making some kid a butthole,
can you keep my mom company?
Okay.
Thank you.
You said you were
good at being alone.
Will you stop
saying what I said?
Okay.
So, why are you so angry?
I'm not.
Okay.
So, how was it?
It was fine.
I checked on the kids, I
read a book, I went to sleep.
It was good advice.
I got what I needed. I...
It was...
What?
Mmm.
They left me alone.
You said the first
thing you remember
after the attack was...
Pain.
Everything hurt.
No, actually, you
said it was people.
Everyone was there, you said.
Yeah. Every time
I opened my eyes,
it was like the
freaking Wizard of Oz.
Everyone was there.
Maggie was there,
Richard was there.
They were there to help.
I mean, they were
doing their jobs.
Just being good doctors?
Yeah, doing their jobs.
Looking good. Drain is out.
So am I.
All right, wound vac is out.
Let's remove the liver packing.
Damn it. Blood's not clotting.
Laps.
Clamp.
Clamp what? I can't see a thing.
There, right there. APRIL:
Wait, where are you going?
Clamp what? There's too much
blood. That, that. Right there.
Clamp there. APRIL:
Okay. All right, all right.
Okay, I got the IVC,
but he's still bleeding.
There's too much damage.
- More laps.
Keep packing. Faster, faster.
- I'm trying.
I'm gonna have to open him up.
- Wait, what?
- Scissors. Betadine.
- Why? Why?
He needs a venovenous bypass.
Have you ever done that before?
- In the field.
Come on, there's no time.
Well, okay, then we're gonna
need another set of hands.
Someone page Pierce.
No. Riggs. Get Riggs.
Are you sure you want...
Somebody get Riggs!
- Right away.
Scalpel.
Thank you.
All right, template.
Okay. Bone saw.
Okay, hang more
FFP and platelets.
Keep compressions.
Got it. I got it.
There's damage to
the retrohepatic IVC.
- The liver is just...
- Yeah, I got it.
All right, you want to do
an end around the liver?
That is what I was thinking.
Okay, set up the Bio-Pump.
We're gonna need venous cannulas.
- On it.
You got the portal? - Yep.
I'll get the SVC.
Here. NATHAN: Cheers.
Hunt called for him?
Yeah, this could get ugly.
If you want, I can...
Clamps. NATHAN: Forceps.
Okay, I'm gonna need...
Metz.
Potts. OWEN: Mmm-hmm.
We're gonna need to do a...
Purse string after bypass.
- Mmm-hmm.
I can help you
guys if you need it.
Here, you can hold the cannulas.
Okay.
And set here.
And go.
Lines up.
Clamping.
There you go.
All right.
Good. OWEN: Okay.
Good. NATHAN: Set.
- And three, two, one.
- Three, two, one.
Flow.
Not bad.
3-0 Prolene.
Meredith, how
did it feel for you?
You know, stuck there, can't
move, can't hear, can't speak,
just watching everyone?
Crappy.
You use that word a lot.
Can you try a different one?
I don't know. Open,
exposed, alone.
Yeah, but you weren't alone.
They were all there.
They all had you.
So, I ask once again,
how did it feel for you?
Yeah.
Crappy really is the best word.
Wow.
Thank you.
Okay.
Oh, shoot!
Shoot. Damn it!
What? What's going on?
- It's... It's not fitting.
- How is that possible?
It's custom-made for her.
No, it's... The rib's fine.
It's like a fitted
sheet on a bed.
You know, once
you attach one side...
The other side pops out.
Yeah, and another set's
gonna take 14 hours to print.
Can we leave her open for that long?
- No, no.
It will leave her at risk
for post-op infection, clots.
So, now what?
Uh...
They want to
retract her rib cage,
pull it open to make enough
space for the new ribs to fit.
No.
I mean, they could slip and
puncture her lung and her heart.
We know. Or crack her ribs.
And if she's under too long,
they'll never get her off the vent.
Alex, either this or we
go back to the plates.
Which is exactly
what she doesn't want.
That's why they wanted to
check before they went ahead.
I don't want to wake
her up and ask her.
She signed a consent.
We don't need her permission.
They want to check with you.
My mom was just like her.
I had to take
care of everything.
Makes a girl glad she was
left in a stroller at a fire station.
Made you tough.
Hmm.
Maya's tough.
She can do it.
Okay, on my count.
One, two, three.
Careful not to
compress her heart.
I'm trying.
Wilson, I know that you
can pull harder than that.
Okay. CALLIE: Again.
One, two, three.
- Come on.
- Okay, come on.
Oh, crap.
She's been under too long.
She's fluid overloaded.
Her heart's beginning to fail.
And done here.
Good?
Kepner, would you
finish up closing?
Uh, yeah. Yeah, of course.
- Great.
Uh... That was...
Insane.
Have you ever seen
anything like that?
It's like they formed
one super-surgeon.
That was a thing of beauty.
It was like watching ballet.
Uh, Kepner, I think
you owe me an apology.
Just because we
saved a patient together
doesn't mean things are back...
Do I, though?
I don't trust you.
You didn't screw this
up because I was there.
If I wasn't there...
Whoa, whoa, whoa, stop!
Yeah, okay.
So, you can tell
me what to do...
All I know is when they're all
at my house, I want them gone.
And then, when they
leave, I don't feel any better.
So, what, does
that make me crazy?
I was gonna say it
makes you human.
I am very good at being alone.
I've taught myself how to do it.
And I don't mean my kids.
I love my kids.
And I have my class and my work.
I have moved on.
You see, but a widow
really hasn't moved on.
She's still sort of married.
She's just married
to a dead guy.
You're not married anymore.
And you're not a widow anymore.
So, what are you?
I don't know.
Okay, so what happens now?
That's up to you.
She did great.
They were able to do
exactly what she wanted.
You can go in.
She just looks so...
Well, why don't you
go get some coffee
and meet us back here
when you've had some time, okay?
Oh.
Come on.
Surgical incision looks good.
I put her on a Lasix drip,
and I'll be back in an hour
to check her I's and O's.
Thanks.
Okay.
Your mom will be back soon.
Check this out, Iron Man.
You were a badass today.
We can keep going.
Or I feel good.
You feel good? I don't.
I mean, I feel comfortable
signing the papers for Dr. Bailey.
You show no signs of PTSD.
And you're certainly capable
of taking care of your patients
and yourself.
But I feel terrible.
I came in here,
and I felt great.
And now I don't know
who I am or what I want.
Well, you wanted a
tape-and-glue guy.
And I think you're
holding up pretty well.
Richard. Pierce.
DeLuca. Good night.
Sir. Night.
You're really bad at this.
You should have gotten a woman.
What do I do now?
I don't know.
I miss you.
Meredith, you got really
good at being alone.
But something terrible
happened to you,
and they were all there.
And they still are.
Are you saying I can't
be alone anymore?
No, I think you can.
I just don't think
you want to be.
Can we go?
No, he's... He's coming.
He's coming.
What do you have to do?
Oh, you have someone to do.
We are not talking about that.
Are you okay?
Finally.
What?
Oh, come on.
It's been a long
day. Can we just...
You told me that any day
someone doesn't
die is a good day.
You are alive.
So, have a good day.
What are we doing?
Do you want to hang out?
But what the hell do I do now?
Well, the truth
is a little scary.
The truth is,
you can do anything you want.
What do you want to do?