There are moments
when all the stars align.
When everything
seems as it should be.
Your life seems to
have sorted itself out.
It's not like all our
problems go away.
- Oh, no.
- What?
- We fell asleep.
- Oh, we fell asleep?
Yeah. My kids will
be up. They'll see you.
Is that such a bad thing?
- I've been over here
a lot lately.
- And they've never seen you.
Do you think that's an accident?
- What, so you don't want me
to meet them?
- Not in my bed.
- Okay, I understand.
- Okay.
Not yet.
- Just tell me where to go.
- Down the stairs
- and out through the back door.
- Okay, I'll be quiet as a mouse.
It's just that the problems
are suddenly manageable.
It feels so good,
you wonder if it's real.
And if I've learned
anything, I can tell you, it is.
It's very real.
- But it will not last.
- Are you Major Owen Hunt?
I am.
Sir, I'm Major William Allen.
This is Chaplain Jane Roosevelt.
We're with the Army
Human Resource Command.
Is this about my sister, Megan?
Major, we have
reason to believe that...
Just tell them I'll need to push
my three o'clock lecture to four.
Thank you.
Aren't you supposed
to be at counseling?
I went. I went three times.
I barfed up all my childhood
sadness, I told them all my demons.
I participated. I feel
like I got enough out of it.
- Edwards...
- What I did was wrong.
I know. I'm sorry.
But I don't think I should miss
out on another day of education
because I didn't get a
stupid piece of paper signed.
- You feel calm? You feel controlled?
- Yes, yes.
How's your throwing arm?
Retired.
Give it to me.
Now get back to work.
- And if Doctor Minnick...
- I will talk to Doctor Minnick.
You are the one true king, sir.
Get out of here.
What do you mean
you're there? Where?
I hired a guy who gave me
his name and where he works.
It turned out he
was scheduled to do
a minimally invasive
conference here in L.A.
So you're there, and
Jo's husband is there.
- Yeah, I'm looking right at him.
- Alex! What are you doing?
I don't know.
I don't know if I'm
gonna do anything.
Sorry.
- Come home.
- I can't yet.
I gotta go.
What do we have?
Uh, BP's 95 palp. Somnolent,
but responsive to painful stimuli.
SATS are 92 with a
100 percent oxygen.
On my count. One, two, three.
It's an MVC?
Sort of. Two people in one car.
Drove off a cliff on Admiral Way.
Do we have a name?
Haven't seen an I.D. yet.
- They didn't find a purse?
- No, they didn't even
find a blouse.
She came in dressed like this.
Why are people driving
around with no clothes on?
Passenger's next
door, maybe he knows.
- Talk to me.
- Male passenger, thirties,
unconscious and
intubated at the scene.
Vitals are stable. Large
bruises right chest and abdomen.
- Was he dressed?
- Except for his pants.
So these two were not
driving. They were parking.
The theory is they got overexcited
and popped the car into gear.
Premature acceleration. You
know happens to a lot of guys.
People need to get
busy where God intended,
in parking lots.
Where it's flat.
He's got a head lac and they
both have abdominal injuries,
Bailey's here and I
paged Doctor Grey.
You can jump in if you
want, but I think we got it...
Somebody please help my baby.
Please. Please,
someone help us, my baby.
- Here, right here. She's
choking on something!
Oh-two and cric kit, please!
Is she dying?
She's choking on
something. It's okay.
Move. Move.
- Oh, my God!
- Hey, stop!
You're okay. You're okay.
- How long has she been choking?
- I don't know. A few minutes? Five?
Page neuro. Your baby's brain
may have been deprived of oxygen
for too long. Next
time, call an ambulance.
What?
Lower extremity deformity
with a large hematoma.
- I can't find a pedal pulse.
- Trauma panel,
- type and cross for eight.
- I hope the sex was good.
Is sex in a car ever that
good? All those windows.
Hey, miss. Hey, you're okay.
You're at Grey Sloan Memorial.
I do need you to keep
still, though, okay?
Abdomen's very distended.
Bring me the ultrasound now.
Is he alive?
- Can you tell us your name?
- Alison.
Please, is he alive?
Rapid intubation.
- Okay.
- I need a seven-oh E.T. tube.
She has a lot of
blood in her abdomen.
Alison, we're gonna take
you up to the O.R. now.
- Pressure's dropped! Seventy over 40!
- She's bleeding out.
Hang blood on the infuser and
prep her for a REBOA catheter.
No hemotympanum. Battle's
sign behind the right ear.
- He needs a head CT.
- I need you to explain
- why you're here, Edwards.
- Yeah, I got a six centimeter
oozing forehead lac here.
I'm gonna need a suture tray
- when you're done.
- You assigned counseling.
- I've been counseled.
- Lactate two point one,
- crit is 42. Labs are good.
- I'm seeing fluid
- in Morrison's pouch.
- You went to counseling
for a minute.
My paper's been signed
by Doctor Webber.
Oh, of course he did.
We need to clear him for a liver
lac. And until we rule that out,
- DeLuca, we need to keep him
on close observation.
- No, DeLuca.
- That's all you, Edwards.
- I can't, I'm on neuro.
You were. And now
you're on babysitting duty.
I'm sorry, two horn dogs
crash their sex mobile,
and I don't get a
surgery out of it?
Well, lucky for you, you
can sew up my head lac.
I should have just gone
to the stupid counseling.
- Damn right you should have.
- Page me when you get the scans.
Woah! Woah! Hey!
- What does that do?
- This is epinephrine.
It's for cardiac arrest.
Do you know what that is?
Okay. So we'll just
put that back there
and find out who you belong
to. Where are your parents?
Over here.
She's breathing fine. I think
you could start to feed her.
Yeah, what about her... her brain?
The other doctor said the oxygen...
I think I found
something of yours.
- Oh, my gosh. Where have you been?
- Please keep a close eye on her.
- It's very busy in here today.
- Yeah, yeah.
- Gary, put the phone down!
- Well, I'm texting Karen.
Why are you texting the
nanny? She's off this week.
Yeah, but there's like a lot going
on, right? So maybe she could just...
Erin, you have to
stay with Daddy, okay?
Her neurological exam looks fine.
Her reflexes are good, she's alert.
I'd like to keep her here for
a few hours for observation
- as a precaution. Alright?
- Yeah, okay.
Um, the other doctor, the
one who, pounded on her.
What's his name?
- Was that Doctor Hunt?
- Yes.
We'd like to talk
to him if we could.
I'll tell him to come by.
- What was that about?
- I don't know.
Hey. What are you doing?
Okay. Ahh, did you treat a
choking baby this morning?
- Are we not speaking now?
- Yes! Why?
Ahh, baby's in the PICU for
observation. She looks good,
but the parents
want to speak to you.
- Why?
- I don't know.
I don't know if they're
upset or if they...
Upset because I
saved their baby?
Look, I am just the messenger.
They want to speak to you.
- I'll talk to them.
- Fine.
So, thank you, and I'll
see you on Saturday.
Sorry to bug you. Are...
are you Paul Stadler?
- Uh, do I know you?
- No. But I know you.
I couldn't put down your
paper on new approaches
to antibiotic resistance
to pathogens.
Ahh, yes, thanks. That was fun. It
was part of a whole W.H.O. thing.
Listen, I am this close to
a grant for I.B.S. research,
and your stuff...
I'm sorry. I'm Alex Stevens.
Can I buy you a drink?
Yeah. Absolutely.
God! Stop calling!
I told my girlfriend that I
will see you on Monday.
But every 20 minutes, she's
like, "What are you doing?"
Out of town means
out of town, bitch!
- Paul.
- Alex.
- This is from your wife.
- What?
You doing a single
interrupted suture layer then?
- No, running a subcuticular.
- Oh, even better.
- Not conscious yet?
- Nope.
- The girlfriend?
- Still in the O.R.
His head CT is clear. He
has a grade three liver lac.
Doctor Grey wants
serial abdominal exams
and six hour crits.
- Oh. Alright, sir.
- Hold on.
- Hold on. Alright,
I'm gonna get this out
of your throat, okay? One
second, I'm gonna count to three,
and you're gonna blow it
out. One, two, and three.
There you go. Great job. Okay.
- Get your head up. Clear that airway.
- What's happening?
- Okay.
- What are you doing?
Sir, you're in the hospital,
okay? You had an accident.
Let's get started with your
name. What's your name?
- Keith.
- Okay.
Keith, Keith, you're safe. Okay?
- We have Alison here too.
- Alison?
- Mm-hm.
- She's here? Is she all right?
- Did you talk to her?
- She was unconscious
- when she came in.
- Alison has pretty
severe internal injuries. We
got her in surgery right now.
Alison's in surgery?
- Okay, uh... when will she be out?
- Well, that's hard to tell.
- I have to go!
- No, no, settle down.
- I have to go see her!
- Settle down.
You need to stay
in bed. Hold on.
You need to lie in bed, okay?
You have an injury to your liver.
If you move, it could
make it much worse.
- I have to. Look, we
are gonna make sure
to let you know how she is
as soon as she's out, okay?
Right now, I need you to relax.
Okay.
- Okay?
- Okay.
- Thank you.
- Thanks.
Great. Alright.
- You're right. It perfed the esophagus.
- So do you need to open him up?
No, I think we should wait
a day and keep him on TPN.
I know this girl. She's trouble.
Hey, Erin. What you doing?
- What does this do?
- This...
does that.
- Woah! Is that his ribs?
- Mm-hm. That's his ribs!
- What's that?
- That little thing is a bullet.
- Nuh-uh.
- Nuh-huh.
- It broke his rib.
- She's better at this than you.
Did he die?
No, no, no. I mean,
it hurt a bunch.
But I think he'll be alright.
My dumb baby sister
almost died. She choked.
And where are your
parents? Are they in the E.R.?
In the ICU.
- I saw a man with only one ear.
- Wow,
really? Well, I'd like to see
that. Would you like to see that?
- Sure.
- Yeah, maybe you could show us
the one eared man on the way
back to your folks. What do you say?
- Yeah? Okay.
- Yeah, come on!
Okay. This is him? Sir?
Ahh, we think this might belong to
you. I think we found your radiologist
- in training.
- Yeah. Thanks.
- You're welcome.
- Sorry about that.
No, no. No worries.
That bloke is losing his mind.
Yeah, some people
just need a nanny.
So, do you want to... come
over for dinner tonight?
- What about the kids?
- With the kids.
You seem to like kids.
They seem to like you.
Yeah.
Yeah, sure. I mean, maybe
I could bring something,
- then you wouldn't have to cook.
- That's okay. I'll make something they like.
After they go to bed, you can...
stay.
Not all night. Just for a while.
Yeah, sounds good.
Sounds good.
Edwards, I assume your
patient's awake and stable
- if you felt comfortable
leaving him.
- Alert and oriented times three.
Lacs are repaired.
Vitals are stable.
He's looking for an
update on his girlfriend.
- Oh, hey, is she awake?
- Not yet. How is her boyfriend?
- Husband? Driving instructor?
- Definitely not husband.
Doctor Pierce repaired an
aortic injury, but she's not out
of anesthesia, yet.
Why not husband?
'Cause car sex is
only for when it's new.
- Or it could be cheating.
- Or why do it?
Someone is always uncomfortable
with the gearshifts and the consoles.
- There's limbs everywhere.
- You people need bigger cars.
Keith was asking about
her as soon as he woke up.
- Keith?
- Yeah, the co-pilot.
She did the same thing,
she asked about him first too.
They're in love. That figures.
That figures? What do you mean?
Well, two people who are in love
would wanna go to a beautiful place
to share their love.
It figures that they would wind up
bleeding in the bottom of a canyon.
- Wow!
- So cynical.
- That's what happened!
- Keith wants to be here
when she wakes up, okay,
but Grey wants him immobile
- for 24 hours.
- Guys, maybe it wasn't love.
- Doctor Avery?
- Alright? That's not romance
we're talking about here,
it was emergency sex.
And they were just too damn
horny to remember the parking brake.
- That's super cynical.
- What is wrong with you people?
- Seriously, wow.
- You should let him see her.
- She'll figure it out.
- Why,
because Prince Charming's kiss
is gonna wake her up? Prince
Charming has a grade three liver lac
that could kill him if he moves.
- Cynic!
- That's not... whatever.
Amelia.
Okay, so this is fun.
Owen is giving me
- the silent treatment now.
- No.
- Not you, me. I need your help.
- What?
I invited him over tonight.
- Nathan?
- To meet the kids.
- Wow.
- No, I feel...
- Nervous?
- Nauseous. I feel... really sick.
Because you think
the kids will like him,
and then it'll fall apart,
and he'll be gone,
and the kids'll be sad.
- No, it's not that.
- It's that.
I know this because I'm the
queen of thinking this way.
I always think
everybody's gonna die.
Yeah, but you're
crazy. I'm just...
sick.
Derek is dead.
Maggie is fine.
There's nothing in
your way, but you.
Let yourself have this.
Look at you, being the sane one.
Moments. I have moments.
Doctor McCullough,
Doctor Kevin McCullough
to the I.C.U. Doctor
McCullough to the I.C.U.
- Doctor Hunt?
- Yes, you asked to see me?
Yes.
Um...
This morning...
this morning...
You saved her.
You saved our baby girl. I never
could have done what you did.
Thank you, Doctor Hunt...
Stop.
We thought we lost her, but
you brought her back to us.
Stop it!
Two soldiers came
to the house today.
They said they found her.
They said they found Megan.
Owen, I'm so sorry.
At least you know.
Maybe you can find some peace.
They said that she's alive.
They said...
they found her in a basement
in a rebel held neighborhood.
There was a raid and
they just left her there.
- She was there for...
- Where is she now?
Germany, Army hospital.
Did you talk to her? How is she?
- When is she getting here?
- I haven't. No, I haven't.
Oh, my God, Evelyn!
What did your mother say?
- Ha... Have you told her?
- How do we...
how do we even know that it's
her? What if it's not? What if they,
what if they got it wrong?
-I mean, -Owen.
They might have!
This might not be true.
- Okay.
- It might not be true.
Well...
let's find out.
Let's find out for sure.
Doctor Stadler's work combined
the worlds of fiber optics
and abdominal surgery...
forging the way for an
almost new specialty.
He started his research
when he was still a student
at Johns Hopkins,
showing an early
interest in new...
- Good luck out there.
- Thanks.
You nervous?
No, I'm good, I'm just
about to make a speech.
I'm a friend of Brooke's.
Your wife. Brooke Stadler.
The one who left you.
Yeah. How's she doing?
Where is she now?
You don't get to know that.
You don't get to think
about her ever again.
And if you come near her, I
will find you and I will kill you.
Do you understand?
- Who are you?
- Doesn't matter.
I know your name.
I know who you are.
And I'm watching you.
Doctor Paul Stadler.
Good luck.
Hey, Jo! It's me!
Hey, Alex.
Found her.
Thanks.
Whoa, whoa, no! No, no, no! What
did I tell you? What did I tell you?
- I have to go.
- Lie down. Lie down.
You're not supposed
to move for 24 hours.
Your liver could start bleeding
again. You could bleed out.
- No, let me go, okay?
- I can't.
I was the last
face she looked at.
Now, she's gonna wake
up in a hospital with a tube
in her throat and no
idea how she got here,
and surrounded by strangers,
and probably hurting like hell.
She's gonna be so scared. You...
you don't know how that feels.
- Yeah, I do, actually. I do.
- Then let me be there for her.
Let me be there
when she wakes up.
I... if she can just see me
first, she'll know she's okay.
She... she'll know. A...
and she won't be so scared.
Please? Let me do that for her.
Help me.
Please.
Yes. I'm calling on behalf
of Major Owen Hunt.
- I'm looking for a patient.
- Ask for Teddy Altman.
- What?
- Ask to talk to Doctor Altman.
Is there a Doctor Altman there?
Yes, I'll hold.
You speak German.
Hey, Doctor Altman,
this is Amelia Shepherd
from Grey Sloan Memorial. I...
I work with Owen Hunt.
Yes.
No.
- One sec.
- No.
I'm sorry, he won't.
I'm... I'm calling
about his sister.
Okay. We just need to confirm.
Right.
No, could we transfer her here,
as soon as she touches down?
Yes. Transfer to Grey
Sloan. Thank you so much.
She said she tried to call you.
Megan is being transferred
from Landstuhl now.
She will land at Madigan.
- And then we'll bring her here.
- We don't even know if it's her.
Owen, Teddy knows her.
Teddy saw her.
I called Merritt Campbell.
She's the best PTSD
expert there is right now.
- She'll be here in the morning.
- Yeah, well, let's just wait
- and see how Megan is.
- Okay. But I meant for you.
For you too.
I got married right over there.
Then I got divorced.
Then I got married again.
And I went on with my life.
And I left Megan in
a hole in the ground,
for almost ten years.
Weeks would go by, and
I didn't give her a thought.
I couldn't spare her a thought,
when she was being
held and... tortured.
And I don't know what.
I stopped looking.
I gave up.
I gave up on her. I gave up.
I gave up on her.
- So Alison's waking up?
- Oh, you're not cynical.
No, you're the
one that's cynical.
Maybe they were in love or
maybe they were just horny.
- It doesn't matter.
- Okay.
We all love. We all get
horny and we all get hurt,
and then we come
through the other side.
And we get to help them do that.
We get to help them love again.
Or screw again,
either way, win-win.
But I... I think they're
in love. I choose love.
- Yeah.
- What do we have
- to be cynical about,
is my point.
- Oh, that... that's your point.
- Got it.
- Shut up.
Is she waking up?
Yeah, starting to. Avery,
you need something?
- No, just curious.
- Okay, Alison.
Alison, you with us?
- What happened?
- You were in an accident.
Is he dead?
- Did I kill him?
- Oh, no, no, no, it's okay.
- You didn't do anything.
- Please, tell me I killed him.
- What did you say?
- There was a man in my car.
- Yes... Yes, he's here,
we have him.
- No, he got into my car
and he put a knife to my throat.
He made me drive to the woods.
He was trying to rape me.
And I thought, "No. No,
I'm not letting you do this.
"I'm not gonna let you do
this, not even if it kills me."
And I hit the gas.
Please, tell me he's dead.
- Call security.
- Stephanie's with him.
I am breaking the rules for
you. So be very still, okay?
Thank you so much.
You are a lifesaver.
Alright. Let's get
you out of here.
Oh, sorry. I thought
this was mine.
You going to the airport?
You want to split it?
Nah. I'll let you have this
one. I'll get the next one.
Thanks, man.
Airport, please.
ICU is reserved for family
only, so I'm gonna fudge it.
Just follow my lead, okay?
Brody, Brody, Brody.
What's going on?
Someone was assaulted.
- What?
- Yeah, I heard a patient
got raped.
They're looking for the guy.
Hey, no, no! Don't
get up. Don't get up.
Now you're gonna show me
the way out of here, okay? Okay?
Okay, backpacks upstairs,
let's get you guys changed.
Mommy has a friend
coming over for dinner.
- Is it Owen?
- No, it's someone
you haven't met.
Then why is Owen here?
I don't... what's going on?
Why don't you get the kids
squared away and we'll talk upstairs.
Okay. Alright, let's
go, guys. Come on.
This guy's been an
absolute train wreck.
- He said he'd need...
- I told you.
Someplace where people don't go,
- like a service elevator.
- I know. I know.
- Are you screwing with me?
- No. We just...
- 'Cause if you are...
- We just have
to get past him, okay?
Then we're fine.
I said, I don't know how he could
have broke it playing ping pong.
But, you know, just give
him a script for Keflex...
You got it. Thanks, doctor.
Hey, um, you need a hand?
No. No, we're fine. We're good.
Liver lac. Taking
him for a test drive.
- Really?
- Yeah, Minnick's orders.
Alright.
- Hey, where are we going?
- Here.
- You think you're funny?
- No, this goes straight down
- to the loading dock.
- You think it'll be funny
- when I cut your throat?
- It's either this or...
You told me I can't walk
and now you're sending me
down the stairs?
You're trying to kill me!
No, it's either this or the
elevator with the police!
This is... This is
what you want.
No!
No. No, you're not gonna run
and tell them where I
am. You're gonna help me
down the stairs.
Alright? Move! Come on.
I want someone with
that woman, every second.
- I want two officers
on this door.
- The patient's gone.
So is Edwards. I can't
find her anywhere,
she's not responding
to any texts.
Call a Code Orange.
Lock this place down.
Oh, will you quit that praying?
- I'm not praying.
- Then what do you keep saying?
I'm saying, "Please bleed
out. Please bleed out."
- Yeah, I guess
I kinda am praying.
- Shut up.
I said don't try anything!
See? See what happens? If you...
In here.
- Oh, evac.
- Yes.
- Hi.
- What the hell?
You need to go, you need to go
out that door, okay? Right now.
- It won't open again.
- Shut up.
- Hey, sweetie, what's your name?
- Don't tell him.
- Erin?
- Erin, where are your folks at?
In the ICU with my
baby sister who choked.
You need to go, okay,
and I'll let you out.
Hold on. Hold
on! Stop it. Stop it!
It's alright, sweetheart.
Just don't, don't, I'm
just gonna let her out,
and then you and I can keep
going where we're going. Okay?
- She'll tell them what she saw.
- She doesn't know what she saw.
- I want my mom.
- Okay?
Then we'll just go. We'll
go. Leave her locked in here,
and we'll go down the stairs,
and by the time they find her,
you'll be long gone, okay?
- Yeah, okay.
- Okay.
Okay.
No.
- No, no.
- Open it!
I can't! I can't. I can't. It's
locked. We're in lockdown.
Why?
Because a rapist
is in the hospital.
- What, we're trapped in here?
- We're trapped in here.
- So, and you're sure it's her?
- It's her.
The Army won't tell you
unless they're certain.
- And when is she coming?
- Now.
Tomorrow.
- Does Nathan know?
- No. Owen hasn't
even told his mom.
So, no, Nathan doesn't know yet.
I'll tell him.
Well, if he's coming
over, just wait.
No. If Derek were alive, I
would want to know right now.
- Can you watch...
- Yeah.
Okay, Ellis needs her
stuffie. Story and bed by eight.
Yup.
- Have they found him yet?
- No.
And no word from Edwards?
No. And I can't go looking
for her. I'm stuck here.
Sit down. Sit down.
Look...
there are cops everywhere.
- They'll find her.
- I know, I just...
I left her in the room with him.
You know...
he probably got out before
they even called the lockdown
or they would have
found him. He's long gone.
Well, if that's true, then why
isn't she answering her texts?
Maybe it's locked on the other
side of a door from where she is.
I can't get to my
phone right now.
Yeah, maybe so.
I mean, maybe.
Hey, she's okay.
Edwards is fine.
Alright? She's fine.
You're not cynical.
I'm not cynical enough.
I was actually rooting for them.
You made up a good
story about a patient.
Every one of us has done that.
I liked your version a hell of
a lot better than the real one.
Why is he so mad?
He's having a bad day.
Let's just stay quiet, okay?
I want to go to my mom.
I want my mom and dad.
There's gotta be a way out of here!
There's gotta be a way to open it!
There isn't or I
would have tried.
- You open the door right now!
- I can't! Okay? I can't.
Nothing is gonna open those
doors except security calling off
the lockdown.
- Or... or, like,
emergency services.
- What... what do you mean?
It's like a fire, a
fire or something.
Come on. Come on! Come
on! Come on, come on!
Give me something
that I can start a fire with.
No... No. You can't, you're
not, you can't start a fire in here!
Shut up! Okay? I'm just
gonna set off the sprinklers.
Make the doors open.
There'll be an evacuation.
- Now, what can I use?
- No, that's crazy.
- You're gonna kill us all.
- Will this work?
Will this make a fire?
You're a good girl.
Yeah.
You got it, attagirl.
Bring it here.
- Set it on the floor
right there.
- Stop it. Stop it.
Now, go in there and get
one of those blue things.
- Stop making her help you.
- You can help me,
and I can stand here
with her. Either way.
Now, now squirt that
stuff all over the blue thing.
Don't do it! Don't do it,
Erin! Don't do it. Don't.
- She's not starting a fire
for you.
- Damn it!
- Don't do it.
- Come here, come here.
- Come to me.
You stay right there. Right
there. You stay right there.
- I don't like him.
- It's okay. He's gonna go soon.
Okay, okay. okay.
Now, when the doors unlock,
I'm gonna take your card
- and the girl.
- What? No! No, no.
Nobody's gonna stop a guy
carrying a kid out of a burning building.
- No, she stays with me.
- No, you stay here.
Someone'll find
you at some point.
Okay, Erin? My name is Stephanie.
I want you to do me a favor, okay?
I just want you to turn
around and cover your eyes.
- Like hide and seek.
- Okay.
Okay, turn around.
- Keep them covered.
- There are days
when you feel like you
can conquer anything.
Yes. Yes!
Come on. Come on.
And it feels like
everything will be okay.
Like I told you, the
feeling doesn't last.
I'm not trying to be
cynical. It's just that,
even when a day
starts out so, so well...
It's okay! It's okay! You're okay,
aright? You're okay! We're okay!
We're gonna go. We're gonna take
you to see your parents. It's okay.
Oh, God.
Oh, no.
What is it?
Go, go, all the way over
there. Okay? Stay over there!
- No, Stephanie!
- I'll be right back, okay?
That day can end...
so, so badly.