♪♪
This is a really nice room.
Yeah, it sounds thick.
Too bad he's not coming.
Look, I talked to him
myself. He'll be here. Right.
You're the one who
said that the song could
use a horn part, so I
got the best—John Henry.
You think I'm stupid? Of course
I do, but that's not the point.
He'll be here, okay?
Take a left up ahead.
South Street? I
canceled this gig.
You said you didn't want to
do any sessions for a while.
For a while. I called
her. I uncanceled it.
- Are you up to it?
- Let's find out.
♪♪ ♪ You lied to me ♪
♪ John Henry's never gonna
show up ♪♪ Will you stop?
It's been, like, two hours.
And we will keep waiting.
You've heard this guy play,
and you know what he does,
so can you just shut up, Tommy?
- Oh, my God.
- Am I late?
♪♪
You need to hear it
again? Nope. I get it.
Let's try one. See
what we get. Let's do it.
♪♪
John! You okay?
You okay? I can't
breathe. I can't breathe.
Call an ambulance!
Now!
I want in.
- John Henry Giles? You a fan of his music?
- He's a musician?
That paralysis thing— Guy
can't walk for two years.
Nobody knows why. It
seems mildly interesting.
Forget his paralysis.
Tell that to the rest
of his bowling team.
As far as this hospital is concerned,
this is a simple case of lobar pneumonia.
- Boring.
- But that not-walking thing—
That could turn into something serious.
Marty Hamilton is his
primary physician out in
California. He's dealing
with the paralysis.
Know all about it. Multiple
treatments, multiple surgeries...
He's making real progress.
Fixed everything but the legs.
Dr. Hamilton already called
and asked for your team.
And by team, I don't mean you.
Like I always say,
there's no "I" in team.
There is a "me" though,
if you jumble it up.
Foreman did his
residency with Hamilton.
I know. I accidentally glanced
at his résumé before I hired him.
He wants someone he can trust.
He must've spoken to
Foreman's parole officer.
Someone who will
stick to the pneumonia.
John Henry's on an experimental
protocol for the paralysis. I respect that.
I'm not gonna get in his
way. It's Foreman's case.
It's pneumonia.
He can handle it.
Guy's already paralyzed.
How badly can he screw it up?
So,
- what are his sats?
- Staying in the 90s
on the nasal cannula.
Coughing up sputum?
Almost none. He
seems stabilized.
- Dr. House, is there
anything back from micro?
- Not yet. You gonna fire me?
- You can make up for it
by washing my car.
- Oh, this is fun.
Okay. Let's keep him on the
broad-spectrum antibiotics.
And since he's displaying
septic physiology,
draw blood for adrenal
and thyroid function.
- What about the paralysis?
- We're sticking to the pneumonia.
Well, you certainly are, boss,
like a wet tongue sticks to dry ice.
The paralysis has already
been diagnosed by Dr. Hamilton.
- It's A.L.S.
- Lou Gehrig's disease.
It's a lovely diagnosis.
They make movies about it.
No tests, no treatment—
It's a disease of exclusion.
- Because Hamilton has
excluded everything else.
- I haven't.
What else could it be?
- Guillain-Barré,
which would be reversible.
- Excellent.
No. The progression of the paralysis
would be symmetric. His wasn't.
- Transverse myelitis.
- Hamilton tested for it. Negative.
And he was negative
for masses and A.V.M...
Antibodies could be attacking the
nerves. Multifocal motor neuropathy.
Uncommon, but it fits.
It's also treatable. Did Hamilton
try putting the guy on I.V.I.G.?
- No, because the M.R.I. showed
no— - Well, let's do an M.R.I. of our own.
Guys, it's my case.
A. L.S. fits. It even predicts the
pneumonia. The paralysis is progressive.
It's a death sentence.
That doesn't make it wrong.
♪♪
So you think the breathing
stuff is connected to my A.L.S.?
It makes sense.
So it's just gonna
get worse, huh?
- Well, Dr. Hamilton—
- Great guy.
Really smart doctor, and his
treatment obviously isn't working.
Do you think I'm gonna die here, or
you think I get to go back home first?
An M.R.I. would give us a better idea—
Oh, an M.R.I. Come on. For pneumonia?
Dr. House thinks we
should test for other— House?
Yeah, I heard about him.
Obsessive son of a bitch? That's him.
So who do you think is
right, Hamilton or House?
Hey, they're both
excellent physicians.
Come on.
One of 'em says A.L.S.
The other one says not A.L.S.
You gotta pick one, son.
Everything points to A.L.S.
Then no M.R.I.
And I want one of them
papers that say, uh, I
don't want nothing
done if something go bad.
A D.N.R.? Mr. Giles, you
don't want to rush into...
It's been two years. I ain't
rushin'. I want to sign one.
Now.
While my arm still works.
♪♪
He signed a D.N.R.
♪♪ He rhymes with dinner?
Oh. That makes more sense.
- You tell him
it might not be A.L.S.?
- No.
Well, no wonder he
signed. Who wouldn't?
I started him on I.V.
steroids and Synthroid.
Great. If it was my case, I'd be
adding a little I.V.I.G. to the mix.
- For his pneumonia?
- That's my story, and I'm sticking to it.
He doesn't want anything
done. No treatment.
D.N.R. means "Do not
resuscitate," not "Do not treat."
You do nothing, doesn't
matter which one of us is right.
And hang on to that D.N.R.
That signature could be
worth a lot of money real soon.
♪♪
This is Dr. Foreman.
What is Mr. Giles's status?
Okay. Increase the steroids to 100
milligrams every 12 hours and, uh...
start him on I.V.I.G.
Yeah. Yeah, I'm sure.
One gram per kilo.
My nature isn't
what it used to be.
The little man has lost
some bounce in his step.
He needs to crank it up, have
himself some fun this weekend.
He wants the blue pills. You're taking
about your penis in the third person.
Me and him—two people.
Separate vacations? That'd
be a drag for one of you.
I don't think you need the pills. I
think you have a conflict in medications.
- You need to up your insulin
to chocolate chip ice-cream levels.
- Insulin?
Yeah. You remember. That's
the stuff you take for the diabetes...
that you forgot to
tell the nurse about.
Your hands...
No hair, which
means nerve damage.
And your shoes look
about two sizes too small,
which means you've
lost sensation in your feet.
And then there's your pants.
My pants tell you I have diabetes?
No. They tell me you're an idiot.
Powdered sugar
on the right pant leg.
Based on the two
napkins in your pocket...
I'd bet it's not your first
doughnut of the day.
You're giving me the
pills? Sure. Why not?
If you've got heart disease from
ignoring the diabetes, they'll kill you.
Otherwise, you two
have a fun weekend.
O₂ sats are dropping.
- Breath sounds?
- Junky.
Mucus plug? No,
it's our mistake.
Sludging from the I. V. I. G.
Blood can't get to his lungs.
Start heparin—500 c.c.'s I.V. push.
He won't last long enough for it to work.
We've got to intubate him stat.
We can't. He's D.N.R.
What?
Someone likes music. Oh, yeah.
His sats are in the 70s.
How long's he been like this?
Ten minutes.
- Why aren't you— - The I.V.I.G.
put him in respiratory failure.
- You put him on I.V.I.G.?
- We did this.
So undo it. Chase?
- It's too late. We killed him.
- Nobody killed him. He's not dead.
- Chase, intubate him.
- He's D.N.R.
What are you doin'?
You can't do this!
- Bag.
- You can't do this.
Bag!
He had a bad reaction to
some medicine we gave him.
What did you just do?
He saved his life.
He's stable on the
ventilator, oxygenating well.
The I.V.I.G. made him worse,
which means multifocal motor
neuropathy was a bad diagnosis.
Okay, what's really wrong with
him? What's wrong with you?
Everyone knows what's wrong with me.
What's wrong with him is more interesting.
You tubed him, and
he didn't want to be
tubed. He has a legal
paper saying just that.
To intubate or not to intubate—
That is the big ethical question.
Actually, I was hoping we could avoid it
and maybe just practice some medicine.
There is no question.
It's the patient's decision.
If the patient is
competent to make it.
- If his thyroid numbers
aren't making him sad.
- Oh, my God. You don't believe that.
- His thyroid levels were a little—
- It's nothing. Do not defend him!
- Why did he sign that D.N.R.?
- I-I didn't talk him into...
No. He signed the D.N.R. 'cause he didn't
want a slow, painful death from A.L.S.
- What was happening had
nothing to do with his A.L.S.
- Exactly! It's the I.V.I.G.
You screwed up! You're not gonna
let him die because you screwed up.
Technically, your
case. You screwed up.
Is that what this is about— Looking
bad in front of your old boss?
You assaulted that man.
Fine. I'll never do it again.
Yes, you will. All the more
reason this debate is pointless.
His lungs are
worse. Any theories?
Oh, I'm sure he just went to the
little boys' room. Come on, people.
- Um, vasculitis?
- Wouldn't likely hit both lungs.
It could be Wegener's
granulomatosis.
Dr. House?
Cuddy sent me a stripper again?
Love that woman. So thoughtful.
Sorry.
There are case reports of Wegener's
hitting both the lungs and the spine.
Well, it's not great, but it's better
than A.L.S. At least it's treatable.
It's a restraining order. You're not to
come within 50 feet of John Henry Giles,
and they've asked the D.A. to
file criminal charges for battery.
Cameron, test the
blood for C-ANCA.
These are criminal
charges. They're not
gonna let you take
blood to make more tests.
He has blood left in the
lab. Just add on the C-ANCA.
- Foreman still got you doing bronchoscopic
suctioning for the pneumonia?
- Every four hours.
Well, while you're
down in his lungs, grab a
biopsy. We'll need it
to confirm Wegener's.
- And move the patient
to the second floor I.C.U.
- Why?
It's right above the clinic. I'm pretty
sure it's 50 feet in any direction.
It's nice having a court order saying
you don't have to work clinic duty.
Dr. Cuddy! Excuse me.
You paged me. Why the yelling?
His bed is behind that
wall— The plaintiff's.
I can't, you know,
come any closer.
It's right over the
clinic. Very cute.
Can we get the lecture
over with 'cause I've gotta...
Actually, I've got nothing
to do. Take your time.
You need a lawyer?
You don't have a
problem with what I did?
When I hired you, I knew
you were insane. I will
continue to try and stop
you from doing insane things.
But once they're done,
trying to convince an insane person not
to do insane things is in itself insane.
So when I hired you, I also set aside
$50,000 a year for legal expenses.
So far you've come
in under budget.
Great. Any chance you
could help me run some tests?
Dr. Foreman called Dr. Hamilton.
He's flying in from
L.A. You can talk to him.
Dr. Hamilton is flying in
as a friend of John Henry's...
to pull the plug.
Yeah. I need a lawyer.
Your Honor, on behalf
of Gregory House,
we have convened an
emergency session of this court...
to bring a motion requesting that
John Henry Giles remain on life support.
Mr. House faces criminal
charges for battery against...
John Henry Giles.
You beat up a guy
in a wheelchair?
Dr. House is alleged to have forced a tube
down Mr. Giles's throat against his will.
A medical tube, saving his life.
Dr. House, please let
your attorney speak for you.
I'm sorry, Your Honor.
I was way out of line.
So, uh, your client forced
the patient into this position,
and now he wants a court order
to force the patient to stay that way.
Without the tube, there's a high
likelihood that Mr. Giles will die.
Well, I assume the patient
knows that. He had a D.N.R.
That's why your client is
facing criminal charges, right?
Exactly. And Mr. Giles's death will
violate my client's Sixth Amendment right.
His right to face his
accuser. That's clever, huh?
Your Honor, in Commonwealth
of Pennsylvania v. Hoselton,
the Third District ruled that a defendant
may not use that status to rule against—
Why are you doing this?
It's not gonna keep
you out of jail. No.
Even if you win, the
restraining order and battery
charge stay in place, so
what have you gained?
Time.
To diagnose him?
You can't get near him.
I don't want to be near him.
Well, some doctors have the messiah
complex. They need to save the world.
You've got the Rubik's complex.
You need to solve the puzzle.
Are you done? Or do you have
more references to 1980s' fads?
I'm trying to listen to this.
That D. N. R. may not be valid.
The patient was suffering from depression
brought on by a thyroid imbalance.
The D.N.R. order
was witnessed...
by Dr. House's own
staff, a—a—a Dr. Foreman.
My staff are idiots. I'm sure you
know what it's like, Your Honor.
Sit down.
The validity of the D. N.
R. Is a question of fact.
Dr. House should have the opportunity
to make his argument at a full trial.
And this poor guy has got to stay on
life support until we can schedule a trial.
- Your Honor— - Dr. House,
I will hold you in contempt
if you don't sit down.
I have a medical issue.
If it pertains to this
case, your attorney...
It doesn't.
Do you have any history of
heart disease in your family?
- Your Honor!
- Your fingers—
They show signs of clubbing,
which indicates a heart problem.
Remember Bart Giamatti? Same
thing—Just dropped dead one day.
- Please see your doctor.
- He's admitted this isn't relevant.
Can we get back to the motion?
- Of course. I-I'm sorry.
- Your Honor,
a person's right to control the
treatment of their own body...
is fundamental to
understanding this case.
A long line of cases, both
federal and state, stand to—
Congratulations.
Impressive legal argument.
I watched Matlock
last night. Say no more.
I didn't notice any clubbing on
the judge's fingers. Neither did I.
So the family history thing...
Every family has some
history of heart disease.
And mental illness.
Biopsy only shows inflammation.
Start him on Cytoxan.
You're diagnosing Wegener's
based on a little inflammation?
Well, unfortunately, I think we've
exhausted all the tests we can do...
in our capacity as the
doctors that he doesn't
want doing tests on
him. Well, you don't...
We'll know I'm right if he
starts walking. We can't
do any more tests, but
you want me to treat him?
Medicine's in the pharmacy.
Patient's immobilized in the I.C.U.
Sounds like a simple
geography problem.
Are you asking us to jeopardize our
medical licenses for this treatment?
Can I help you?
Uh, I'm Dr. House. I...
Greg, right? I'm Marty
Hamilton, John Henry's doctor.
We should talk.
Appreciate any list of, uh,
medications— Anything like that.
I've started him on Cytoxan.
For Wegener's, right?
Look, Greg.
I checked you out, you know?
I know you're a good doctor, and you have
to appreciate that I'm a good doctor too.
Why? Wegener's is one of
the first things I looked for.
The biopsy and the blood test
were negative, just like yours.
There's an error rate, Marty.
And there's a time to let go.
Look, I'm gonna take
him off the ventilator, and
John Henry's going to
die. He's accepted that.
Dr. Hamilton. Hey.
How you doin'?
Hey, how you doin'?
- I'm sorry. I should have never
put your patient on I.V.I.G.
- It's not your fault, Eric.
- No, it's mine, Eric.
- That's not what I said.
- Everybody asks about you out in L.A.
- How's the old place doin'?
Oh, this is wonderful.
But before you guys break
out the oil, I should point
out that you can't pull the
plug. I have a court order.
You used to, but...
I have the right to face
my accuser. Judge said so.
Not if no one's accusing you. All
the charges have been dropped.
He doesn't have to die.
It's not Wegener's.
If it's Wegener's, his lungs
won't be able to handle it.
Soon as they pull
that plug, he'll die.
That's why they call
it "pulling the plug."
I'm gonna miss you.
- He's still breathing.
- His O₂ sats are holding.
- He's holding his own.
- He's still breathing.
It's not Wegener's.
Wrong again.
He's stable, but one of
his arms is now paralyzed.
The real question is,
why is he still alive?
Do you think he's
just being stubborn?
He's alive because you were
wrong. It's not Wegener's.
Yeah. Seem to be doing that a lot lately.
People keep living because of my mistakes.
Progression of the paralysis pretty much
confirmed Hamilton was right. It's A.L.S.
- Assuming this is
a progression of his paralysis.
- He can't move his arm.
Yes, his arm is paralyzed.
Yes, his legs are paralyzed.
Why is everyone so gung ho
to connect those two conditions?
You can think I'm wrong, but
that's no reason to stop thinking.
- How about this one? He's not our patient.
- Nope. Not good enough.
He could've suffered a
stroke when he was intubated.
Well, blood clots are
common in paralyzed patients.
The inactivity causes—
Not interested in why.
- Let's get an M.R. angiogram,
check for an embolic stroke.
- He doesn't want you treating him.
- They dropped the court order.
- Yeah, and that girl dropped
the charges against Kobe.
- Doesn't mean he should call her
and see if she's free to get a sundae.
- Good point.
But I can go within
50 feet of him now.
You need me, you have
'em page me. Anytime.
Okay.
- Get out of here.
- Sure. That makes sense.
You hate me for
saving your life.
Well, in fairness to your side, you
were also dying because of me, so...
- You knew I didn't want to be saved.
- That's what's interesting.
Your thyroid was low, but not
enough to cause depression.
So you came here
to tell me that even if I
can't walk, I can still
hear the birds sing,
enjoy a rainbow, the feeling
of sunshine on my face?
Those things are fun.
Okay. Life sucks.
Your life sucks more than most.
It's not as bad as some,
which is depressing all by itself.
But do me a favor.
Just let me find out
what's wrong with you.
Then if you still
want to kill yourself,
I'll give you a hand.
- That sound fair?
- Yeah. Sure.
I'll stick around to
indulge your obsession.
It's over. I lost my air.
The session the other
night with those kids...
That was a test to see
if I could still play. I can't.
And that's all you
are, a musician?
I got one thing, same as you.
Really?
Well, apparently you know
me better than I know you.
I know that limp.
I know the empty ring finger.
And that obsessive nature
of yours— That's a big secret.
You don't risk jail and your career to save
somebody who doesn't want to be saved...
unless you got something—
Anything—one thing.
The reason normal people got wives
and kids and hobbies— whatever...
That's because they ain't
got that one thing that...
That hits 'em that
hard and that true.
I got music. You got this...
The thing you think about all the time,
thing that keeps you south of normal.
Yeah. Makes us great.
Makes us the best.
All we miss out on
is everything else.
No woman waiting at home after
work with the drink and the kiss.
That ain't gonna happen for us.
That's why God made microwaves.
Yeah.
But when it's over,
it's over.
Yeah.
What're you doin'?
It's not over for me.
Either you're gonna call the
cops again, or we're doing this.
You want to die, you can do it just
as easily inside an M.R.I. machine.
So when I go back to L.A., I'm doing
the Dana lectures again this year.
Wow. Thank you.
Thanks. That's quite
an honor. It's all political.
Don't be modest.
You've earned it.
I got lucky on a couple
studies I was doing.
It all sells tickets. You remember
last year's lectures, don't you?
- I remember the cigar bar afterwards.
- The only reason to attend the thing—
cigars and pool.
You enjoy working
with Dr. House?
Not the word I'd use.
We work too hard not
to enjoy ourselves, right?
- Mmm. You seeing anybody?
- Kinda, sorta.
- Serious?
- I don't know. It could be.
You think she'd, uh, enjoy L.A.?
Hamilton offered me a job.
You gonna take
it? I haven't decided.
You already have the most prestigious
fellowship. It's a partnership...
Three times the money, car allowance,
moving expense, pension plan,
the chance to work for a
guy who gives a crap what
people think. Why didn't
you just tell him yes?
I made a commitment here. Right.
House would let you
out of it in a heartbeat.
Or he wouldn't, just
to jerk me around.
Would you guys
have taken the job?
Don't need the money. We're
not like you. I don't hate House.
You guys really don't have a
problem with him, with what he did?
He knows we
disagree with his choice.
Choice? Chase, it's not apples
and oranges. It's right and wrong.
And he does it like he doesn't
care. He assaults the guy...
and moves on to the next
differential diagnosis like it's nothing.
What do you want from him?
Hand-wringing? Torment?
You want him to cry himself
to sleep at night? Yeah!
Yeah, I want some
clue that he knows it's a
big deal. That it scares
him, that it matters.
Whoa, whoa. What's that?
It was a stroke.
Well done, Cameron.
House called it. The arm
and legs are unrelated.
Oh, you make enough calls,
one of them is bound to be right.
Yeah. He's just
a lucky, lucky guy.
Listen, listen. I just think it wouldn't
hurt him to learn a little humility.
So what's the verdict?
Embolus. The arm problem
was caused by a clot.
There's a good chance we
can bust the clot with T. P.A.
Do it. See what
happens to his arm.
We found a blood
clot in your brain.
We'd like to start you on
heparin. It's a blood thinner.
- What are the side effects?
- Well, your lungs are kind of
chewed up from the pneumonia.
- Good chance there'll be an effusion.
- Bleeding?
Into his lungs. It's our best chance
to give you back the use of your arm.
I don't need my
arm without my air.
- The damage would likely be minimal.
- No.
It's his call.
Or we could do an embolectomy.
Basically, we go in
and pull the clot out.
He's saying no to drugs, and
you're recommending brain surgery?
Bypasses the risk to the lungs.
- It'll either help your
arm, or— - Or it'll kill me.
From your point of
view, it's a win-win.
Okay.
We'll set up the
procedure for today.
We're in your carotid artery.
This is gonna take us all
the way up into your brain.
You all right?
Yes.
The sludge is
blocking the blood flow
to the part of the brain
that controls your arm.
All done. You still okay?
I think so.
I don't know. I guess...
it's just with Dr. Hamilton here,
I-I noticed a difference in styles.
His style involves humility?
Another difference
in our styles...
I don't care much for
apologies. You can go.
I didn't know you were standing
there when I said that, okay?
It was completely rude. Do
you mean genuine humility,
you know, with all the self-doubt
and the self-questioning,
or Hamilton's polite, patronizing,
"Aw, shucks" humility?
You're both excellent
doctors. Thank you.
And humility is an important
quality, especially if you're wrong a lot.
You've been wrong
every step of the way.
Course, when you're right, self-doubt
doesn't help anybody, does it?
We gotta go.
Congratulations, Greg.
Congratulations. Why, Marty?
John woke up. He
can use his arm.
Thank you.
Now, look, I know we've
had our differences,
but I think when a person does
something well, it ought to be recognized.
The phone works.
Next time you want to make me feel
all warm and fuzzy, leave a message.
Don't get me wrong.
I'm overcome with joy.
- Doc.
- Yeah.
- What?
- You just touched my leg.
What, are you gonna
charge me with assault again?
No.
I felt it.
He now has feeling all
the way up to the calf.
This is the way
medicine evolved.
Patients sometimes get better.
You have no idea why, but unless
you give a reason, they won't pay you.
Anybody notice if
there's a full moon?
You're saying he just
spontaneously got better?
No. I'm saying, let's rule out
the lunar god and go from there.
Something he's on is working.
The enzyme replacement protocol
is working, reversing the A.L.S.
The timing doesn't
seem suspicious to you?
Do you think Dr. House'll see it that way,
figure it's his medication doin' the job?
I'm sure he will.
It's one of ours. How do we figure
out which drug is doing the trick?
Easy. We just stop all of them.
- One of those drugs is helping him.
- And the rest...
Steroids, antibiotics,
anti-inflammatories...
They're toxic, if we
leave him on all of them.
- He'll walk again.
- Yeah. To his own funeral.
But if we stop everything,
he'll get worse. True.
We'll add our medications
back one at a time.
When he gets better,
we'll have our answer.
- And if he doesn't get better?
- Then we're in trouble.
Not as much as he is.
But I suppose
that was your point.
I assume you want me to convince Hamilton
to stop his treatments too. Don't care.
At least five of the medications
are a part of his protocol.
If his stuff was helping, the guy
would be playing tennis months ago.
It's our round of
treatment that's helping.
Right. So that's
what you'll stop.
It shouldn't be more
than 15 or 20 minutes.
So your philosophy
is, if they don't want
treatment, they get it
shoved down their throat,
- but if it might cure their paralysis,
whoa, we better slow down.
- Yeah.
Yes, Doctor, I love it. My old
philosophy used to be live and let live.
But I'm taking this needlepoint class,
and they gave us these really big pillows.
- What's your philosophy
on employee relations?
- That's a very tiny pillow.
Great. It sounds like you
know what you're doing.
Greg.
- Can I have a word?
- Can it wait for the commercial, Marty?
Say hi to my friend Jimmy.
Pleasure.
Your diagnostic trial...
Seriously, commercial's
in about five minutes.
- That's a dangerous game.
- Only if we're watching in the bathtub.
I need to know exactly what
medications you were giving John Henry.
Forget it. And if Foreman tells you
what John Henry used to be on...
- You're gonna fire him?
- Nope.
I'll make him live out every
day of his two-year contract.
- Foreman asked to leave?
- Not yet.
- But how do you know I made him— - You're
a polite twit, but you're not an idiot.
I need to know what medications
you've taken him off of.
Wait a second.
You're not an idiot.
You need to know what
medications I've stopped...
because...
He's getting worse.
Right now you still
work for me. Come on.
No feeling. No wiggling.
Bad news is John Henry's back where he
started. Good news is Hamilton looks bad.
Yeah, it's not whether you win or
lose. It's whether the other guy loses.
What was the first thing we put
him on? Steroids, for the pneumonia.
Well, put him back on them. Give
him 24 hours. See what happens.
His lungs aren't great. They might
cause another respiratory collapse.
Sure hope not. I didn't
much like that lawyer.
And get an M.R.I. He
already got one, and an M.R.A.
Well, obviously something
is different now. Do it again.
Chase, take care of the scan.
Cameron, put him on the steroids.
We should probably talk, huh?
Thin cuts. What levels?
T-9 through the cauda
equina, same as the last time.
You really think House would let
Foreman out of his contract? He has to.
If he doesn't, he's telling Foreman
he needs him. House can't handle that.
Oh, my God.
I checked him out.
He's a great doctor.
- You think he's better than I am?
- This about your ego?
Answer the question.
It's not gonna change how I think about
myself. Might affect my opinion of you,
but that shouldn't affect
your opinion of yourself.
Now I'm getting confused.
If you think he's a better doctor than
I am, then you should take the job.
Otherwise, you should get
him to buy you two or three
more nostalgic lunches
and then politely decline.
It's that simple? I should just
ignore the mockery and abuse?
- Oh, how do I abuse you?
- How do you not?
- If I make a mistake— - I hold
you accountable. So what?
Dr. Hamilton forgives.
He's capable of moving on.
That is not what he does.
I screwed up his case. He told
me— He never said you were forgiven.
I was there. He said
it wasn't your fault.
- So?
- So, it was.
You took a chance.
You did something great.
You were wrong, but it was still great.
You should feel great that it was great.
You should feel like
crap that it was wrong.
That's the difference
between him and me.
He thinks you do your
job, and what will be will be.
I think that what I do
and what you do matters.
He sleeps better at
night. He shouldn't.
- Arteriovenous malformation.
- Intradural. Compressing his spine.
Causing his paralysis.
How could Hamilton
have missed an A.V.M.?
Well, we missed it too,
'cause it wasn't there before.
Are you saying it
just grew overnight?
No.
It was on the spine.
It wasn't on the M.R.I.
- Same anatomic location.
- It's not there.
- Well, what is there?
- Nothing.
Or something that
looks like nothing.
- Background noise. Static.
- Scar tissue? Inflammation?
If it's inflammation, the
steroids would've shrunk it down.
Revealing the A.V.M.,
which has always been there,
hiding behind its own swelling.
We remove that,
he'll walk again.
♪♪
Dr. House.
Cora's meeting me
outside with the limo.
I'm bein' discharged.
Fifty bucks says I can
beat you to the curb.
Thanks for stickin'
with the case.
I can't do anything else.
You're much more easily
amused when you can walk.
How bizarre.
I'm guessing that you
weren't exactly Mr. Sunshine...
even before your
leg got messed up.
I want you to have this.
Wow.
You can sell it if you want to.
Just promise me you won't play it.
How many of those
pills you takin'?
I'm in pain.
Yes.
Aren't we all?
So, uh, where do you buy these
things? Do they have cane stores?
Ah, don't worry about it. You'll be
jogging before you need a second one.
See you tomorrow, Eric.
That's some bad hat, Harry.