Previously, on New Amsterdam...
You have cancer.
Squamous cell carcinoma.
I want to try precision
targeted therapy.
Chemo's gonna take the life out of me
and I wanna keep running this hospital.
It's too big a risk.
Dr. Bloom asked me to
consult on a hematology patient.
Her file says that she received
her heart from a "Luna Goodwin."
Your sister... She
gave me a beautiful life.
She had me arrange this.
Max?
Baby!
Oh, my God. Help!
Help!
We've got Marina
Latimer, mid-60s.
Been down for three minutes.
It's her third time
here this week.
She went back into V-fib
right after I shocked her.
Charge to 200.
Clear.
Okay, I've got a pulse.
Her heart's a ticking time bomb.
Let's put V-fib pads on
her and find Reynolds.
He needs to put
in an ICD, today.
Yo, Dora. Where's Max?
Out of pocket for
a few hours. Oh.
Okay. Well, I have a patient
who needs an ICD surgery.
Her insurance won't cover
it so I'm just gonna charge it
to the Community Care Fund.
Max is the only one who
can approve surgeries
from the Community Care Fund.
He's out of pocket
for a few hours.
Can this wait until it
doesn't get me fired?
Um... Look, whenever there's
a surgery that needs to be done
I just give Max a heads-up
and I do it, all right?
He dots the "I's" and
crosses the "T's" later.
We got a whole system.
He's been here
for like three weeks.
Yeah, that's how
efficient we are.
Dora, hi.
Just on my way to
Max's office right now.
Yeah, he's out of
pocket for a few hours.
He's what? Oh, shoot.
No, really?
Uh, as the nurses'
union liaison,
I need to tell him that
the hospital-wide walkout
was authorized
just now, for today.
No, no, no. It's a good thing.
Max gave them the idea.
Of course he did. Yeah, yeah.
I probably should
have led with that.
Did you know that insurance
has covered over-the-counter
emergency
contraception since 1996,
and now all of a sudden,
out of the blue, they're like,
"No. Uh-uh. Not
without a prescription"?
That's not fair, right?
There's no way we're
gonna let that slide.
And yes, for the record,
Norma Rae is my favorite movie.
Go, girl.
Dora, uh, I've been texting
Max, but he's not responding.
He's out of pocket
for a few hours.
But I need to talk to him.
I've basically authorized
a surgery that's not covered
by insurance, and I'm about
to endure a walkout
from the nurses,
so whatever you need right
now, I'm sure I can handle.
It's private. Dora.
Dora, I've been looking for Max.
Okay, I'm only gonna
say this once more.
Max is out of pocket
for a few hours.
Please, save your
news, questions,
mysterious personal
requests, or whatever it is
that you need, for
his return. Thank you.
Code Grey, Northwest
Tower. Code Grey.
Dr. Panthaki. Thank you for
picking up Max's samples in person.
But to be clear, this cooler
is full of Miller Lites, right?
Yes.
Yes, because I'm the
type who drinks domestic.
So tell me, will this
be your first time
seeing Lauryn Hill in concert?
Actually, no. I've
seen her several times.
But never on a date.
So in your head,
this is a date, huh?
That's interesting.
Just give me my ticket.
Actually, let's
do this properly.
Get dressed up. Dinner.
Okay. Great.
Well, I should go now.
Me, too.
Oh, and we're going Dutch on dinner,
so make sure you bring some cash.
Max, are you on your way back?
Helen! Helen!
Helen, can you hear me?
Georgia? What's wrong?
It's Max. He collapsed.
He's not moving.
Does he have a pulse?
Okay.
Yes. Did you call 911?
They're coming but,
um, the call dropped
and I just didn't
know what to do.
Put your cheek over his mouth.
Do you feel air moving?
Uh...
There is a whistling,
raspy sound.
Put the phone
next to his throat.
Georgia? Yes?
Georgia, Max's
throat is blocked.
What? You need to make
a new path so
that he can breathe.
Okay. You're gonna
cut a small hole
in his throat... What?
No. No, I can't.
Yes, yes. Yes, you can.
You can, because
I'm gonna help you.
Find something that
can cut a hole in his throat
and a tube to slide through it.
Find something. Okay.
Oh.
Uh, I have a...
I have a pocket knife. Oh, God.
And a plastic straw.
Use the knife to
cut, um, three inches.
It doesn't have to be exact.
Okay.
Here we go, Georgia. Okay.
Use your index finger. Okay.
Find Max's Adam's apple.
Okay, I found it.
Feel down from there until
you come to a little indentation.
Make a half-inch, horizontal
cut through that indentation.
What if it's... What
if it's not clean?
What if I give him an infection?
Georgia. Georgia,
Max can't breathe.
You need to help him breathe.
You can do this.
Okay.
Oh, God.
I did it. I did it.
Good girl. Good girl.
Now, pinch the
far edges together.
Use your finger to
keep the hole open
and slide the tube halfway in.
Oh, God. Okay.
Air should be coming
out of that tube.
It's... It's not...
It's not working.
God, it's not working!
It didn't work! It didn't work!
You might just need to
help his lungs expand.
Blow into the tube.
Come on, come on.
Oh, come on, come on.
Come on. Come on. Come on.
Oh, he's...
He's breathing. He's breathing.
Oh, my God.
Oh, good.
How long was his
airway obstructed?
How long was he
not breathing, ma'am?
Six or seven minutes, maybe.
We got a possible
cerebral hypoxia.
Let's pick up speed!
What does that mean?
Means there's a big difference
between six and seven minutes.
Mr. Mokrani? Yes.
How are you? Not great.
Yeah, let's have a look.
Does that hurt,
right there? Yes.
Yeah. Fell during a show?
No.
At the after-party. Ah.
I challenged another dancer
to a fouetté competition.
Mmm-hmm. I can
fouetté in my sleep,
but in my sleep,
I'm neither wasted
- nor on a pool table.
- Oh, please.
I was just as drunk and
on-a-pool-table as you were.
Know that you did
not out-dance me.
Basem, I out-danced you so bad,
you're in a hospital.
Yeah, well, I don't know
if it counts as out-dancing
if he fell off a pool table.
Yeah, but I didn't.
So, I out-danced him.
Dancing is the
art of not falling?
I'm sorry, who are you?
Uh...
Yeah, I'm...
Just a guy
challenging you to a...
Fouetté rematch.
Don't worry, I took
dance all through...
Never.
Hello? Yeah.
Don't you have some
medicine to practice?
Mmm-hmm. Uh, so, you
have a dislocated elbow.
Go ahead and take this
pen with your left hand.
Now, grab it tight. Hang on.
Okay?
Better? Yeah.
Yeah, good. Okay, he's okay. I
was thinking loser buys dinner.
Really?
I mean, yeah. I'm not
scared if you're not scared.
That's good.
That's very, very
good. Okay, you go.
My turn? Yep.
This is embarrassing,
'cause I actually thought
"fouetté" was a French dessert,
so I didn't know that it
was that spinny thing.
That was way better
than what I thought it was.
But, uh...
Excuse me.
Uh, you're gonna go ahead and ice
that elbow and you're gonna be fine.
Are you coming?
Um...
It's 2:00 in the morning.
Yeah, but I gotta be back here
in three hours anyway,
and full disclosure,
I can't afford a
real restaurant,
so we were just headed
to the cafeteria regardless,
but the Jell-O is phenomenal.
You in?
Hey.
What's with the T-shirts?
You said you were gonna take
time off to take care of yourself.
I am, and I will.
I tried to talk to Max this
morning, but he's not here.
He's always here.
Well, right now he's
not, and I can't just
stop running the ED, can I?
I feel so bad, all the
work you do on me.
I've become this
burden to everyone.
No, no, you're not a burden.
It's just that you have
mediocre insurance,
and I think you should
be treated like you have
Cadillac insurance, so
we're gonna cover you
for an ICD implant.
Today. For the whole surgery?
What about the anesthesiologist?
Sometimes they get you
with the anesthesiologist.
For the whole surgery.
So glad Gertie is doing better.
Bye.
Hello. Oh, nice T-shirt.
Thank you. Power
to the people, Vijay.
Ella was telling me
that I helped her save
her crazy Chihuahua. Oh.
All right, Ka-pooch.
I didn't know you
did work on canines.
That's cool. I don't.
I gave her a little
money for the vet.
How much? $2,000.
American?
I gotta go, but I'll
see you in prep.
Sharpe! What's the code?
It's Max. FROME:
I'm sorry, what?
What happened?
I don't have all the
details, but he's collapsed.
He's in a medevac
on his way here now.
Is it serious? I should
get the trauma team.
They'll be here in two minutes.
There's something else, something
that you all need to know in order
to treat him properly
when he arrives.
All right, Sharpe,
what's going on?
Max has squamous cell carcinoma.
Advanced stages.
The trauma team's
gonna meet us here.
No, whoa, hold on a second.
How long have you
known about this?
Since his first day.
Since his first day?
Look, I know that this is shocking,
but whatever we're feeling,
we're gonna have to put it
aside because we need to focus.
Hey, clear a path!
O2 sat's dropping. Okay,
let's up oxygen to 100%.
Push more fluid.
Does anybody know
how long he was out for?
Okay, everybody
out of my ED, now!
Should I page
Dr. Candelario? No.
Yes, yeah. Page her, please.
On three. One, two, three.
Monitor for ischemic cascade.
Why hasn't he started chemo?
In two weeks he starts
an immunotherapy trial.
What? Huh?
Well,
that's what he wanted.
That's what he
wanted? Yes, Floyd.
He's the patient.
Yeah, but he's also
the medical director
of this entire hospital.
Am I the only one who's
wondering what happens next?
What... What... What
are you doing out here?
Candelario is working on him.
Why?
Because I just got off
of back-to-back doubles,
and Candelario is
an excellent doctor.
You pull doubles all the time.
Max deserves to have
a doctor with fresh eyes.
Do you disagree?
How is he?
We don't know yet.
Might be hypoxia.
So, like most of you,
Dr. Sharpe told me
about Max's condition,
and needless to say,
I was a bit shocked,
but we don't have
time to be shocked,
or angry, or upset.
We all have a hospital to run,
and while Max is in there,
we need a leader out here,
and that's gonna be me.
Until further notice, I am
the new medical director
of New Amsterdam.
I need surgery schedules, staff
rotation. I need the minutes from the last
department chair meeting.
That's gonna take a
little while to put together.
Okay, then let's start with
what Max was overseeing today.
His hot list. Yeah.
What's the hot
list? It's his to-do list,
but with a cooler name. Ah.
I'll call it something
else. Thank you.
Don't worry, I'm only temporary.
I have several calls out for
more permanent replacements.
Dean Fulton, all this
is incredibly premature.
When Max wakes
up... If Max wakes up,
he will still have cancer.
He certainly didn't
expect to continue this job
while undergoing chemo.
Ah-ha.
Of course he did.
So all you care
about is business.
Let me tell you something.
Every single day, 10,000 patients
walk into this hospital and its clinics.
Our annual budget
is $1.5 billion,
and the governor is
demanding that we cut it by 10%,
which is really tough,
because our expenses come in
well over $1.8 billion.
Our infrastructure report
after Hurricane Sandy
told us that we were
sinking into the East River,
and will need $100 million
infused within the next two
years so that we don't end up
like Bangladesh after a monsoon!
And the one guy who's in
charge of this whole show
is lying in Trauma One
with a tube down his throat.
And what about a
succession plan?
He knew he was sick.
You knew he was sick.
Someone should have
had a plan in place.
Right?
What?
I just made us the greatest...
Max has had a set-back.
His throat closed up.
Where is he?
In the trauma unit.
Well, is he responsive?
Still unconscious,
but at least he's
breathing again.
How long was he down?
Six or seven minutes.
I need to ask a favor.
Anything. I need you to move up
Max's start date.
To when?
To tomorrow.
Helen, I just got the cells.
I know, I know I'm asking
a lot, but if Max is gonna
keep running this hospital,
then he needs to be
in your trial.
Let me see what I can do.
Monitoring.
Decompression.
Dr. Candelario is
suctioning Max's lungs.
He's really lucky
you were there.
Stand by.
Hey, you want to step outside?
Get some fresh air?
What's the difference
between six and seven minutes?
"Six and seven minutes"?
EMT said he might have hypoxia.
I don't know how to pray.
I'm not religious, but I
wish I knew how to pray.
We've got blood.
What's happening?
Could be ARDS.
Oh, God!
Hey.
Oh, you're seriously
taking me to the theater
in your scrubs. I'm on call,
but when I put this
jacket on, like so...
You're looking at me
like you can't quite believe
you're dating
somebody so stylish.
Just like looking at you.
Mmm.
So, are you excited to see
Pina Bausch's company?
My God, I can't stop saying
it. Pina Bausch. Pina Bausch.
Pina Bausch.
Hey, you wanna know an
interesting thing about Pina Bausch?
Pina Bausch?
It's super rare for her company
to be performing on a Monday.
Oh, is it? Weir-sch. Mmm-hmm.
Theaters are dark on
Monday. Did not know that.
You wanna know
another thing? I sure do.
Her company performed just
last night at the Kansallisooppera.
And that's even more fun to say.
It's also in Finland. Really?
Mmm-hmm. Now, it sounds
like you don't think we're going
to see Pina Bausch.
What is this?
What's that? What? Oh.
Uh...
Yeah, you got me.
There's no show.
Just a guy who can't
quite believe his luck.
Really?
Really.
Will you marry me?
Not even gonna check that.
I'm not even gonna look
until you say something.
No rush.
Someone could be dying...
Right now.
Yes, I'll marry you.
Yes.
Oh, my God, it's beautiful.
So beautiful.
Dang, I gotta go. I gotta go.
Go, go, go. Jacket.
Yeah, but I... Yeah.
I'll make it quick, I promise.
She said yes!
You know... Hey, hey, I've
been thinking about this.
This kind of explains
a lot, don't you think?
What? All the crazy changes
he made around here.
That explains a lot of it.
Yeah, I mean, like, who...
Who forms a cardio unit
that doesn't care about money?
Or who puts fruits and
vegetables in vending machines?
Who encourages their
own staff to stage a walkout?
Do you know what I
mean? It's... It's a dying man
saying "screw you" to
the system, that's who.
What do you want me to say?
I don't... Anything. Just
join the conversation, man.
Or are you just gonna
stand there staring at me
like the old Kapoor?
I was not aware there
was a new Kapoor.
Oh, yes. No, there are
two very distinct Kapoors.
The old Kapoor was this solemn
fellow who rarely spoke to people,
and then Max comes
on the scene and bam,
all of a sudden
you're smiley-face guy
who randomly lends
$2,000 to the coffee girl
for her quote-unquote dog.
You have no right to
talk about Ella's character.
Except I do, because
she took $2,000 from you.
I gave it to her,
and for the records, there
is no old or new Kapoor.
There is only Kapoor.
Doctor...
So I see that your
patient, Marina Latimer,
is scheduled for an ICD.
Yes.
Why is it being charged to
the Community Care Fund?
Because her
insurance is garbage.
Oh. Mmm-hmm.
I don't see Max's signature
anywhere on the document.
Right, yeah, he would have
approved that had he not collapsed.
Right. Is she stable?
Yes.
This is not a necessary surgery.
Okay, Mrs. Latimer
has been in and out
of this hospital more
than her own home.
This ICD will completely
change her life.
Doctor, a public hospital's job
is not to change people's lives.
It's to save people's lives.
We will not be
paying for this surgery.
Oh, Dean. Hey, Dean,
hi. You wanted to see me?
Yeah. Hi. What's up?
How you holding up,
kiddo? Uh, you know.
Terribly.
We go way back,
don't we? Mmm-hmm.
Am I fired?
Ignatius, come on.
Well, usually when people
say "we go way back,"
it's because you're
not going way forward.
This is about the
nurses and the walkout.
Oh. Oh, good, right. Yes.
Um, HCC needs to come back to the
table so we can make some progress.
They're not coming
back to the table.
Well, if the nurses stand
together, we have a shot.
They're not coming
back to the table.
HCC wouldn't tell
Max, but they told me.
If the nurses walk,
then I have no choice.
I just have to replace
them. You can't.
You can't replace 1,600 nurses.
So I'll have to close the
wards that we can't staff.
I'm gonna have to send the
doctors home, send custodial home.
People are gonna lose
their jobs, and for what?
We work in healthcare,
and we can't provide
our own people with
comprehensive healthcare.
I want you to listen to me now.
With Max down, this
is not the right time.
Convince the
nurses to stand down,
or else everyone,
patients included,
everyone is gonna pay the price.
Fine.
All right, fine.
Hey, uh, can I get an update?
For Georgia?
He's still unresponsive.
We're having a hard time
getting his heart rate up.
Well, maybe I can help.
He's not your patient.
He's my friend.
Can I talk to you, please?
Then why did you pass him off?
Max...
Max needed fresh eyes.
I've known you six years
and I have never once heard
you refer to your eyes as not fresh.
My shift was over.
Lauren.
Why did you pass Max off?
I've been working at
Bronx General a lot,
and working here a lot.
I don't know, the last...
Last few weeks it was...
It was too much.
I hit a wall.
Okay.
And...
I've been taking
a little bit more
Adderall than prescribed.
How much more? I don't know.
Just more.
But I'm handling it, okay?
I'm gonna take some time
off, I'm gonna figure it out.
I was gonna talk to
Max this morning, but...
Anyway...
That's why I passed him off.
So, do you really think
Ella doesn't have a dog?
Are you serious right now?
Is that a serious question?
New Amsterdam is
upside down right now.
Max is in the ICU, the dean
wants me to tank the walkout,
and you're focused on
some woman's Chihuahua?
Come on, man. So you
do think she has a dog.
I don't care.
Dog, no dog, it doesn't matter.
It matters to me.
Why?
Why does it matter?
Because...
There is a new Kapoor.
I think there's a new Iggy, too.
So what do you think this
new Iggy and new
Kapoor should do?
Are you Dr. Goodwin's wife?
Yes.
I... I just want to say that your
husband is the first man in his position...
To care about the janitors.
We wait for good news.
Hey, hey! I come bearing
the sweetest cantaloupe
you have ever had.
I know your cravings
haven't started yet,
but when they do, I
feel like they're gonna be
really melon-heavy.
I don't know why,
I just get that vibe.
You okay?
What's wrong? Is it the baby?
When I came home there
was a FedEx waiting...
With contracts from New
Amsterdam Medical Center.
Good news.
You got the job...
That I didn't know
you'd even applied for.
I didn't... I didn't
apply, it just happened.
When was the interview?
A week ago... A week ago.
But, uh, look, the dean
of medicine called me
out of nowhere and he said,
"I need an answer right away."
And I figure why tell
you... "Why tell me"?
If I don't know... We
made a promise, Max.
Remember?
We were going to
raise this child together.
We were going to put
our careers second.
I gave up everything.
This job is the
opposite of that.
I'm gonna make it work.
Really?
It is the largest public
hospital in the country.
And I'm gonna figure out
how to squeeze everything in.
Oh, great. Will you, Max?
Will you figure out how
you can squeeze me in
and your child?
That's not what I meant.
Well, that's what's
gonna happen.
By the time this baby
gets here, I'm gonna have
this place running smoothly.
I can come home early.
I can take weekends.
You won't.
Not unless I'm sick, not
unless the baby's sick.
That is the only
way you will stop,
and just...
Be.
And just be what, Georgia?
This is... This is
the life of a doctor.
This is my life.
No, it's not.
It's not.
We know doctors, we
know dozens of doctors,
and this is not their life.
You're obsessed, Max. You are.
It's not healthy.
It's like an addiction.
I know you love me.
But when the hospital calls...
It always wins.
I can't let my daughter grow up
feeling like she's not the most
important thing in her father's life.
I can't do this anymore, Max.
Georgia.
With your permission, I
would like to provide Max
with a small prayer.
What is that?
Did I hurt him?
No.
I think you might
have just saved his life.
It's called a
paraneoplastic syndrome.
The way his skin got red and
swollen where you kissed him?
That's happening
everywhere in his body.
Everything's becoming red
and swollen, and shutting down.
From the cancer?
Yes.
But now that we know
what it is, we can treat it.
And he'll be okay, right?
Uh...
We'll have to wait and see.
Let's let the HCC
know what we want!
We'll march all day!
We'll march all night!
'Cause birth
control is our right!
We'll march all day!
We'll march all night!
Louder!
All right, come on! This
one's for the one and only
true Medical Director
of New Amsterdam,
Max Goodwin!
Let's make it bigger!
March all day! March all night!
You know, I just... I... I
think Max would have hated
to see a bunch of clever
homemade protest signs
go to waste, you know?
You look like you're
a small. Right, sir?
There. That's for you.
March all night!
'Cause birth control...
Forceps.
Suture.
Reynolds?
Is that Marina Latimer?
It is.
So you're willing to risk
your job for one surgery.
I'm willing to risk my
job for one patient.
Now, the ICD is
implanted, and I'm using
a 4-0 nylon suture for closure.
When I am done, she'll
spend 24 hours in recovery.
Then I am sending
her home without a bill.
If the hospital won't pay,
bill me.
What if I'm wrong
What if I've lied
What if I've dragged you here
To my own dark night
And what if I know
What if I see
There is a crack
Run right down
I'll give you a moment.
The front of me
So that's my wife.
What do you think?
Not bad, right? I did okay.
She would have loved you.
Thing is, I...
I almost blew it with
Georgia a few months ago.
She, uh, saw right through me.
She figured out that everything
I do is because of you.
I just keep trying to save you.
Over and over, that's all I do.
And I never...
Never will.
So now I have a wife...
And a daughter
on the way, and...
I'm always gonna love you. I...
Always...
But I need to start
living for them, too.
Georgia.
Ten thousand cars
Oh, my God.
It's okay.
To run away
Okay.
Not Cohen's hound
If I be wrong If I be right
Let me be here
With you tonight
Dr. Reynolds.
Is the dean looking for me?
I'm sorry, I can't seem to stop.
Max is awake.
I should have told
everybody from the beginning.
Um...
But I've been wrong before.
Sharpe.
I want to start chemo.
No clinical trials, no risk.
I don't want to risk...
Losing you again.
That's my priority.
Which means... SHARPE: No.
No, you're not resigning.
I have no choice.
You will if we help you.
I mean, if you're willing to
delegate, we'll all have your back.
Like you had ours.
Yeah. Yeah, yeah, count me in.
Me, too.
I don't mind putting
in the extra time
if it means keeping you around.
Guys...
You're not hearing me.
I think they're hearing
you just fine, Max.
These are your people.
This is your hospital.
For better or worse,
there's no going back, Max.
Georgia, help me out.
Max is about to start the
most intense fight of his life.
And above everything...
He has to take care of himself.
Which is why he's not quitting.
Let me be here
With you
If I be wrong
This job?
This job is who you are.
In some ways...
It's who you've always been.
I honestly believe
that by staying here,
working, helping...
Will keep you alive.
If I be right
Let me be here
With you
Tonight