Curiosity killed the cat.
I still don't get it.
It also killed a lot
of ancient Greeks,
when Pandora had
to open that box,
full of death and
pestilence and stuff.
Why did Diane want
to be buried here?
She's not from here.
It's weird.
Maybe so she could be
close, so Maggie could do this.
What's "this"? What
does she get out of it?
Don't ask me.
Why do we have to know
what's behind door number three,
even when we're pretty
sure it'll be bad for us?
I guess it's better
than the way I did grief.
- Which time?
- The time with the Oxy binges.
I go a little dark and twisty.
- But then I come back.
- "A little dark and twisty"?
You disappeared.
You had a secret baby.
Please don't refer to your
niece as my secret baby.
I mean, maybe this
is what grief looks like
when you've lived
a whole, healthy life.
You know, before
anything terrible happens.
Like watching your father
get murdered when you're five?
Or like watching your mother
bleed out on the kitchen floor.
We're more alike
than we realize.
Come on. We
don't want to be late.
Are you ready for
your first day back?
So ready.
Weird.
- Morning.
- Hey, you guys carpool. Nice.
- Yeah, it's nice for the trees.
Brody, hold up. Not that one.
Let's go to exam four.
Bigger, more comfortable.
No. You don't have to do that.
Well, if I can't pull strings
for my friends, then...
Hon, take the upgrade.
- How do you all know each other?
- Owen rebuilt my hand.
He gave me a new
leg and saved my hip.
Not my spleen, though.
He threw that out.
Yeah. We spent time
together at the VA hospital.
Uh, and each other's weddings.
How is Amelia? We keep
missing her whenever we're here.
Um...
She's... she's good.
Yeah? You guys knocked up yet?
Leo, you cannot just ask
people if they're knocked up.
What? I mean, he used
to ask us all the time.
Because we would tell him
we were trying all the time
until we finally did it.
How's the baby doing?
Dr. Robbins placed
a shunt last week,
to help with the baby's heart.
Yeah, so she's gonna
make sure it's all working.
Fingers crossed.
Chief Ortho resident to the E.R.
- She's at 29 weeks now?
- Yeah.
I placed a pericardio-amniotic
shunt last week.
All right. So, as long as the
tumor doesn't grow too fast,
we can push surgery
till the baby's bigger.
I mean, ideally
until after she's born.
Yeah, fingers crossed.
It wasn't a carpool.
- Sorry?
- Me and Minnick in the car.
Oh, yeah I... I got that.
We're sort of just
keeping it to ourselves.
I got that, too. That's why I
said the dumb carpool thing.
- Yeah.
- Give you an out.
It's just people are so
full of opinions about Eliza.
You and her is
between you and her.
- Yeah. Whoa.
- People should
keep their opinions...
- Damn it!
- Ooh.
It's grown.
I mean, it's nearly twice
the size of the heart.
Yeah. The shunt's gonna be
no match for a teratoma that size.
Yeah, no. We have
to operate today.
- Yup.
- Hey.
- Hey, you're back! How are you?
I'm good. You know,
as good as... Thanks.
- What are we looking at?
- Riggs and I are excising
a fetal intrapericardial
teratoma for the first time,
- so... Sorry?
- Ooh, me?
This is exactly what I
need. It's perfect. I want it.
- Please.
- Pierce.
No, I know. I'm your
boss, but I can't just take it.
No, I'm taking it. I need it.
I'm sorry. You can watch.
Unless you have any objections.
It's your first day back,
- and I think that...
- It's a pretty big
operation, Pierce.
Yeah, yeah, exactly.
So, send me the chart.
Well, it was nice
almost working with you.
- Yeah, next time.
- Mm-hmm.
Satellite pharmacy,
extension 4977.
- Hey, general consult?
- Abdominal pain, bed three.
Okay.
Good morning.
- Cross, you can't sleep here.
- I'm not sleeping.
I'm your patient.
For real?
As Dr. Minnick would say,
"This one's all yours, Edwards."
Enjoy.
Anyway, so, I wasn't
sure if Maggie was okay,
but I think she's
fine, and if she's fine,
then it's okay for
me to go to dinner.
If Maggie's fine,
you get to eat?
Dinner with Riggs.
- Oh.
- You know, I was holding off,
because I didn't
know if she'd be okay.
But I think she's fine.
So, I think it's fine
if I go to dinner.
With Riggs.
When did you become a grumpy
old man who doesn't like people?
I like people. I
don't like Riggs.
If you want to go to dinner
with the guy, go to dinner.
If you don't, don't. But
otherwise, pick up the pace.
- Why are we
stapling these again?
- Minnick's got me teaching
NICU procedures to
interns, so the sooner I start,
the sooner I can
get out of here.
Wait! Did I say
you could come in?
Go outside! Wait.
You are this close to telling
the kids to get off your lawn.
Stop acting like it's
something new... Go.
Once we access the
fetus, we'll excise the tumor,
giving your baby
instant cardiac relief.
We'll take your baby out of
the uterus, but only partially.
We'll remove the tumor, then
tuck her back in safe and sound.
We know. Dr. Robbins explained all
this when she diagnosed the tumor.
But we were hoping the
surgery could wait until
Jenna was further along.
I mean, is she
even strong enough?
Of course, I am.
- I meant the baby.
- I'm afraid
we don't have a choice.
Without surgery, the
baby will only get sicker.
Jenna, they wouldn't do the
surgery unless they had to.
She has to fight
before she's even born?
- And I can't help her do it.
- We can.
Dr. Pierce and I can.
What? What? I thought Dr. Riggs
was operating on the baby.
- So did I.
- Actually, Dr. Pierce
took over your case.
She's the chief of cardio.
- Well, why the switch-up?
- Is this another upgrade?
It is. Yeah, you're being bumped
to first class. I would take it.
Excuse me.
Robbins.
I know what you're gonna say.
This is Pierce's first day back.
She can't just swoop in
here and steal this surgery.
We all steal surgeries.
Listen, Riggs has followed this
case. He's studied the procedure.
- They know him. They trust him.
- Okay, Owen, I'm not...
I'm sorry, but Riggs is
the better choice here.
Well, then why isn't he the
one who's doing our surgery?
- Listen, Leo...
- Owen, tell me.
So, Dr. Hunt told you what?
I was talking with Dr. Robbins,
and I raised a concern.
We are going to stick
with the original plan.
Have Dr. Riggs do the surgery.
I'm sure that you're
a great doctor,
but this is just
too big of a deal.
I agree.
It is a very big deal.
I know that Dr. Hunt
is your friend...
- Owen is like family.
- Even better.
So, as your family, Dr. Hunt
is looking out for you.
But you should know that
his concerns have nothing
to do with my
surgical skill, do they?
No, of course not.
He's worried about me
because my mom died recently,
and he is worried that
I won't be able to work
through my personal
pain to get the job done.
But I can, or I
wouldn't be here.
Owen is... is that what it is?
I'm just...
concerned.
Well, so am I.
This is scary as hell,
which is why I
don't need a doctor
that has a happy
and perfect home life.
- I just need her to be the best.
- That's me.
That's why I'm the
chief of my department.
And, frankly, my
part of the surgery
is a walk in the park.
Your baby's mass
is easily extractable.
The truly risky part of the
surgery is when Dr. Robbins
has to open you up
to get to your baby.
- Wait, what?
- I know. Leo,
Dr. Robbins is good.
She is, and I am not
worried about her skill,
and she is not
worried about mine.
So I just want you to have
the facts before you choose.
You, please.
And Minnick and I are meeting
with the attendees next week
to review their
procedural checklists.
Oh, yes, let me see this.
Hey, I'm excited to
see where this goes.
And I'm excited to see
you and Minnick
working together,
that the trouble's behind us.
Um... Sure.
For the most part.
"The most part"?
What's the other part?
Uh...
You have yet to say it.
What have I yet to say?
- That you were wrong.
- That I was what?
Enjoy your day.
I'm recently divorced.
Okay.
- Congratulations?
- So, it's new. Me and Minnick.
Right. Well, like I said,
it's none of my business.
I'm just...
I wasn't ready for it.
That's all I'm saying.
I mean, I wasn't trying
to make it happen.
I mean, I thought that it would
happen sometime, but not now.
No. I know the feeling.
I, uh...
I lost my fiancée. Years ago.
And I wasn't looking
for anything, either.
And you're right. You know,
it's a surprise when it happens.
Doesn't matter
how long it's been.
- So you're seeing someone, too?
- Yeah. Well, maybe.
I mean, we're trying.
I am, anyway. She...
We'll see if it goes anywhere.
Well, I hope so. Keep me posted.
- Wait, I'm keeping you posted?
- Yeah. This is happening.
We're now friends.
So, you know what?
You don't even need to
keep me posted. I'll ask you.
Why do I get a PEDS gown?
It's what they
brought. Symptoms?
Fatigue, night sweats.
Do you think it
could be Crohn's?
So far, it sounds
like menopause.
- Nice ducks.
- Why are you here?
I paged him because
one cure for internitis
- is peer humiliation.
- Internitis?
Yeah, it's a special
variety of hypochondria.
Cross here has abdominal
pain, and it is nothing,
- but he thinks it's everything.
- It could be something.
Cross,
you're an intern.
You're trained to find
the rare, special case.
It is the goal, it's the mother
lode, but this is not that.
You're just not that special.
What? What if I am?
Let's find out, shall we?
Okay. All right.
Dr. DeLuca, would you
like to do the rectal exam?
- No. Nope.
- No. No, no.
Okay, well then,
you can observe.
Cross...
roll over, baby.
I mean, so Maggie's doing
fetal surgery. So what?
I got next.
I mean, she's jumping
back in. What's the big deal?
Well, maybe Maggie should
wade back in with a, you know,
- a valve replacement, or...
- Is Maggie back?
Yeah.
- How's she doing?
- She's fine.
- You sure about that?
What do you think you're
doing? You can't cut.
- For half a turkey sandwich?
- You may cut.
- Oh, no.
- Seriously, though, you guys
should not try to tell Pierce
when and where she can operate.
I've made that
mistake with April.
I know, and I hate it,
but these are my friends,
- and it's their first baby.
- Is this Jenna and Leo?
Yeah. The tumor is growing
too fast. The baby needs surgery.
- Oh, my God.
- Yeah.
Oh, they asked for
you. You should...
You should go see them.
Anyway, Maggie
can do it. I mean,
she's buried her
grief in one place.
She goes and visits
it, brings it flowers,
and then she goes
about her business.
- It's weird.
- No, it's healthy.
I mean, Owen, do
you hear yourself?
Yeah, I know, but...
it's risky for Maggie, too.
I mean, what if
something goes wrong
with this high-risk
fetal surgery?
She just lost her mother.
She doesn't need this, too.
- It wouldn't hurt to check in.
- We work through stuff.
I have operated
through a miscarriage.
That's not normal.
Okay. So, we check in.
Hey, we heard.
Open fetal surgery.
Exciting, huh?
Yeah, that'll be the tiniest
heart you've ever operated on.
It'll be the tiniest heart I
have ever operated on.
You guys talked to Hunt, huh?
Yeah, we're just checking
in. I mean, it's a big operation.
A risky one.
I mean, it's an
ambitious first day back.
We want to make
sure you're okay.
Would you stop?
How is this supposed
to help me be okay?
to help me go in there,
and do the impossible?
Now's the part where you guys are
supposed to tell me how awesome I am,
like I do for you all the time.
- I'm sorry.
- You are awesome.
I was having a great day.
I found a special surgery
that I was excited about,
that I knew I could excel at,
and I wasn't worried
for one second
about whether I'd
be able to perfect it.
Not for one second,
until you guys got here,
and now I'm a little worried,
so thank you for your support.
I don't understand why
you just can't say the words.
- I was not wrong. You were.
- Well, how was I wrong?
You refused to acknowledge
that I am the chief.
Bailey, I made you chief! I...
Look, I can't acknowledge
it any more than that.
You could treat me like
I'm the chief, but you don't.
You treat me like I'm your kid
that you got a summer job for.
And then you watch
me and you wait for me
to screw up and shake your head
and assume that
I'm still learning.
Well, you are!
You think you have
all the answers?
Well, it took me years.
And it'll take me years,
but I have to cut the
cord in order to do it.
And I can't keep
running every decision
past gnarled Old Man Wisdom!
Oh, that's how you think
of me, huh? Gnarled?
Cross would like
me to remind you
that he's allergic
to iodine dye.
I would like to remind you
that I am allergic to Cross.
I'd like an MRI next.
Do you have any idea
how expensive that scan is?
I have Obamacare,
I have a year
left, and I need...
- Look, an MRI wouldn't hurt.
- It would hurt me,
because there's zero
indication he needs one.
Smoking-related mesenteric
ischemia. It could be that.
Do you smoke?
My grandmother did.
Secondhand exposure.
No.
- No, no, no. No!
- What? Is it that bad?
- Yes, diverticulitis.
- Diverticulitis...
- is not even that bad.
- I know.
Except it is, 'cause now
I have to live in a world
where Cross was right.
Ten blade.
You watching to see
if Pierce melts down?
No. I'm just interested.
It's a very rare surgery.
A tumor inside a fetus?
Inside a womb inside a woman.
Yeah, it's like a nesting doll.
It's like nesting
dolls. It's fascinating.
Why are you here?
Uh, yeah. Same.
God. Why so many people?
- Well, it's pretty rare.
- It's fascinating.
Right.
She's gonna do fine.
Brody, next step?
You'll open the uterus
and exteriorize the baby.
Good. Then?
Dr. Pierce will perform
a fetal sternotomy,
then excise the tumor.
This is kind of the
point of no return.
Are you seriously
asking me if I'm okay?
We are about to take this
child from her safe, warm home.
She's leaving the
mother ship into cold,
dark space, and I want to
know that we can bring her back.
I want to know that
everything is okay.
Okay?
Okay.
Isaac, you have
perfed diverticulitis.
Diverticulitis? That's it?
Dr. DeLuca is prepping
an O.R. for Dr. Edwards,
who will be your lead surgeon,
and I will be there
the whole time.
It's just run of the
mill diverticulitis?
- Not even Meckel's?
- Okay, I wish
it were something cooler, too,
for my sake, but it's not.
I just had such a bad feeling.
That feeling is
called being an intern.
Okay, okay.
Dr. Shepherd, I discharged
your glioma resection.
And 2243's ICPs are coming down.
Okay. Keep me posted.
They are friends
of yours, right?
Yeah. Owen met them at the VA.
Jenna and Leo were in
the same unit in Afghanistan.
She literally dragged him
out of a collapsed building.
Yeah, and then they got married.
Then they got pregnant,
and then the kid has
a tumor in her heart.
I thought you had a TMR.
Yeah, I thought you had
a ventral hernia repair.
- I did. I pushed it.
- Me too.
- Robbins has you on standby?
- No, I wouldn't say that.
Well, I think it's a good idea.
Just in case.
Red rubber catheter, please.
Start the pump. Does
anyone know what it's for?
For irrigation to replace
the lost amniotic fluid.
- So cool!
- IV?
All right. Pulse aux
and IV in place.
Dr. Pierce, you are up.
Bovie.
Mayo's.
Retractor.
- That's the teratoma?
- Yeah, it's a big one.
- It's a monster.
- Let's slay a monster, then.
And...
there.
Monster slain.
Three-oh PDS.
Hmm.
- Now I'm just jealous.
- See, I told you. Healthy.
The baby's getting
bradycardic. All right, Pierce.
Pierce?
Dr. Pierce?
She's decompensating.
Dr. Pierce, what's
your move here?
Dr. Pierce, you
need to do something.
Dr. Pierce!
There's something
that needs to be done.
All right, push ten
cc's of saline now!
- Why isn't she moving?
- Come on. Is she freezing?
No, she can't. Riggs?
Come on, Maggie. Move.
Dr. Pierce, do
something! I'm not asking!
Baby's heart rate's dropping.
Well, go down there
and do something.
No.
Just wait.
All right, point-one
of atropine. Don't.
Don't push that IV.
All right, what's your
plan here, Pierce?
Do something!
- I'm not asking, Pierce!
- I hear you.
My plan is to give her a minute.
She just lost something huge,
something that has been
with her since day one.
Her heart just needs
to learn how to beat
without that extra load.
She just needs a
little time to adjust.
Heart rate's going back up.
Okay, little one, let's...
let's get you closed up.
Three-oh PDS again.
See? Pierce doesn't need backup.
He's actually not so
bad when he's quiet.
Suction. Lap pad.
Moving the bowel.
Wait. What are...
- What are all these...
- Huh.
- Has Cross traveled recently?
- No idea. Why?
Because it would appear that
he has abdominal tuberculosis.
So, we just opened
a big box of TB?
Wait. TB's transmitted
through the air.
Should we close? I
mean, are you sure
- we're not exposing ourselves?
- Well, I've already
been exposed.
I have the antibodies.
Also, I'm not a gutless wuss.
So, pick up some Metz.
I don't have the
antibodies. Do you?
- TB can kill you.
- Cross may have killed us?
You're not gonna die from someone
else's abdominal tuberculosis.
I mean, there's a remote possibility,
but it's not gonna kill you now.
Right now, you get
to fix someone's TB.
Isn't that worth it?
- I'm sweating. Are you sweating?
- No. Stop it.
Are they sealing off the exits?
Okay. Never mind.
Go away, both of you.
Someone page Dr. Warren.
Laparotomy closed.
Fetus and mom stable.
Nice work, Dr. Brody.
And welcome back, Dr. Pierce.
- Tonight. Sabrina's Restaurant.
- Sorry?
Let's go have a drink
and have a conversation.
- Like a date?
- No, it's not a date.
It's two people hanging out,
to see if we enjoy hanging
out, before I tell Maggie.
Oh, so when it goes
well, then you'll tell Maggie.
It could go either way. We
could end up hating each other,
and then there would
be nothing to tell.
- You don't hate me.
- I could hate you. I have before.
Eight o'clock.
- It's a date.
- It's not a date.
Kepner, start talking.
AFB stain came back.
Cross definitely has TB.
How did he get TB?
Uh, where are your residents?
Kicked 'em out
for being annoying.
Plus, I figured, fewer people
in here, the better. Suture.
- You good to finish and close?
- Yup.
All right, so what do we do
now? Does Cross get quarantined?
No. That's pulmonary TB.
Well, he's been walking around
treating patients while he's had TB.
- Yeah, there's protocol
for all that.
- And what's the protocol?
Just...
It's protocol, all right?
Just simmer down.
Well, I'd like to
know what it is.
I don't... remember.
I'm trying to remember
what the protocol is,
and if you stop with the
questions, I might remember it.
You're sure there is a protocol?
- I mean...
- Stop.
Oh, there's a protocol.
Hey, don't mind me. I'm
sure you have all the answers.
I'll just be over
here, all gnarled up.
Do you know what
the TB protocol is?
Well, in fact, I do.
Would you like me
to tell you what it is?
Yes. The answer is y...
What is happening right now?
I feel like I need ten showers.
It's TB. It's not
gonna just wash off.
What is happening? Are
we being quarantined?
Are they gonna stick
us in a bubble room?
- No, that's not happening.
- Oh, I think it's happening.
- No. No! No quarantine!
- No, not you. The O.R.
No one new is coming
in until it gets fumigated.
Okay, well, what happens
with Patient Zero in there?
He gets heavy antibiotics in
an isolation recovery room,
and you two get
to go get PPD tests.
I'm gonna kill Cross.
Hey, hey. Not so
close, not so... Easy.
Hey.
Congratulations. That
was something to watch.
And defied all
your expectations.
Come on. Nobody
thought you couldn't do it.
You just said I
couldn't... all day.
Maggie, I think people
were just surprised,
you know, that you
were doing so well.
I'm not doing well.
I'm doing my job.
I feel awful.
But... I'm doing my job
while everyone is staring
and telling me that
I am not up for it.
I am doing my job, 'cause
that is what we all do, right?
Right?
Right.
When someone
comes to us for help,
we find a way, we figure it out.
How to help them.
We don't give up.
We don't tell them
that there's nothing left to do.
- Maggie, look...
- So why couldn't you
do your job?
My mother came to you for help,
and you said that you would help her.
That is the job.
So why the hell
couldn't you do it?
Cross?
Cross. Hey.
- Hey! Hey, Cross.
- Hey.
Am I dead?
If you were dead, I
wouldn't be visiting.
Hey, have you left
the country recently?
Uh...
Just a Baja cruise with my mom.
Hmm.
Oh, and India... for
a month volunteering.
Nobody noticed I was gone?
- You got TB, pal.
- TB?
Wow!
- Wait. You fixed me, right?
- Well, Dr. Kepner did.
Listen, I just wanted to apologize
for giving you a hard time earlier,
and for sticking
you in a duck gown.
You're really sexy...
and pretty...
and smart. Wait.
Don't tell Dr. Wilson I said that.
She and I have a little thing on.
Goodbye, Cross.
- Enjoy your isolation room,
buddy.
- Thanks, buddy.
I just don't understand that...
stubborn, stubborn man.
Everyone's getting along,
and he just wants to bicker.
It's like he enjoys
pressing my buttons.
It's like he likes to fight.
Huh.
- What? Do you think he's right?
- Uh, no.
Good.
But have you considered
that he might just be lonely?
No.
I had not.
You do me.
So, we got to wait
another eight weeks
and then inject ourselves again
just to see if Cross gave us TB?
I mean, are you
sure we don't just
hit ourselves with a dose of
rifampin and get ahead of it?
Uh, it doesn't work
that way, I'm afraid.
And you know this.
You're a doctor...
ish.
Thank you.
That's a good catch
today, Edwards.
You know, undiagnosed,
Cross's TB would have
only gotten worse with time.
Yeah, I didn't
catch it. Cross did.
- Well, how is that?
- I thought it was internitis.
I made up my mind about it
before I even took his temperature.
- Well, it was still
a good outcome.
- Yeah, despite me.
I was an obstruction
to his care today.
Cross advocated for
himself, and I just dismissed it.
Just like those doctors used to
do to me when I was a little kid.
How did I get like this?
Edwards...
there isn't a doctor
in this hospital
who hasn't found themselves
making the same mistake.
You were wrong today...
but you're able to admit
it, and you'll learn from it.
And, you know, it's
an admirable quality.
Not everyone can do that.
You never went to
see Jenna and Leo?
No.
They'd like to see you.
You don't have five minutes?
They're your friends, Owen...
from...
before.
They're your friends.
Hey.
- Hey, you saved a family today.
- I did.
Well, things are
looking up for me, too.
- I got a date tonight.
- Is it someone in the hospital?
- I didn't say that.
- Your face did. Who is it?
I'm not gonna say.
If she wants to, she can,
but it seems like she
doesn't, so I won't.
- Noble. Is it Kepner?
- No.
Is it Edwards? Reaves?
Wilson? Is it Hunt? Is it Hunt?
Is it Hunt? Yeah? No. No.
- Um, Bailey?
- Nope, she's married.
Yeah, the heart wants
what the heart wants.
All right, moving on. Shepherd?
Grey? V... Your
face twitched at Grey.
- I did not twitch.
- Is it Grey? Is it Meredith Grey?
- I never said that.
- Oh, my God!
I mean, I understand why
you're into her. She's hot. Wait.
She likes you?
What? Okay, I'm gonna
try not to be offended at that.
No, no, no. No.
It's just that Derek...
Derek was epic for her.
They were the great love story.
I mean, that girl's heart beat
for Derek Shepherd. It's just...
It never occurred to me that she
would ever be with anyone else.
He was perfect. He
was everything. I mean...
that man turned her world. It...
I spooked you.
Don't be spooked.
No. Don't be spooked. Do
not be spooked, okay? This...
This is good. This is good,
because you know what?
Love is good, right?
Right.
Wow. Don't you look nice?
The babysitter is
upstairs. I'm going out.
Out? "Out" sounds
like a date. Out where?
- I am going out.
- And that
is a date-worthy outfit.
- Bye.
- Who's your date with, Mer?
I want my mom.
I don't know what
to... what to do now. I...
What do I do?
It's okay.
Hey.
- I can't go.
- Okay. Why not?
Because Maggie came home from
work early, and she's very upset.
I thought she was doing fine.
- No, she's not fine. She's a mess.
- Okay. Can we reschedule?
I have... You can't
be here. Goodbye.
Come on.
"Come on"?
Okay, you weren't
supposed to hear that.
- Her mother just died.
- I know.
But, come on, you and I both
know how grief comes and goes.
Look, Pierce will be going
through this the rest of her life.
I know you think she needs
backup, but she can handle herself.
I have people to take care of,
and you are not one of them.
Get up.
- What is happening?
- Come on. Get up.
- What? Mer.
- Come on. We're dancing it out.
- Oh, God. Really?
- Yes, really. It's this or cry.
Come on. Get up.
Oh, there she is. The
woman who knows everything.
I'm willing to
admit I was wrong.
Oh, really?
Under two conditions.
- Name 'em.
- One...
I'm willing to admit
this over dinner tonight
while we iron out all of our
differences and move past this.
- I could do that.
- And, two...
you also have to
admit you are wrong.
- Well, how am I wrong?
- Are you back home
with your wife?
Yeah, I didn't think so.
Look, you have your work wife
back. Now get your real wife back.
I am not wrong.
Well, then, you buying dinner.
Hey.
I don't want to...
talk or discuss or
dance or whatever.
Okay, um...
How about Diane's
medical records?
Your mom knew she was sick.
She knew even before I did.
By the time she came to
me, these were her charts.
All of this?
She was pretending that
she didn't know she was sick.
Maggie, she lied to both of us.
She didn't want it to be true. She
thought her doctors were wrong.
Yeah, I think you're right.
Oh, there's more.
How could there
possibly be more?
When did she do all of this?
After she found out
how sick she was.
- Is she...
- Skydiving.
- My mother is afraid of heights.
- Well...
- This is insane! She's insane.
- In the best way.
She gave these to you?
She didn't come to see
me because I was the best.
She came here because
she knew that she was dying.
And you and I...
we're kind of like family.
She figured I would do my best
to take care of you
and she was right.
She asked me to
hold on to those...
until you needed them.
I think you needed them.
Put yourself in Pandora's shoes.
She's given a gift,
a wondrous box,
filled with things she
never even knew existed.
Of course she opened it.
Wouldn't you?