- I've been down an assistant,
and I need someone
who can keep the trains running
at one of the most
complex health institutions
in the country.
- I have specialized
in logistics
at not-for-profits with
client bases north of 100,000.
- Well, I oversaw
operational budgets
at best-in-class
public hospitals
in Boston and Philadelphia.
- Boston andPhiladelphia.
Uh, you'll need
to be proficient
in a bunch of boring yet very
complicated admin software
that, uh, frankly,
I don't know how to use.
- I have four years experience
consulting on
next-gen EHR coding.
- Well,
I've secured multiple grants
to install electronic records
systems at rural hospitals.
- Wow, is that a pie chart?
- Mm-hmm.
- It's very...detailed.
- I don't own a computer.
- You don't, um...
Any medical sector experience,
or?
No, sir.
- No.
It's, uh--
- Todd Benson.
- Todd Benson, yeah.
Uh, quick question, buddy,
I don't mean to be rude,
but are you sure
you're at the right interview?
- Yes sir, um,
I've had a little trouble
transitioning from my last job.
- Which was what, exactly?
- Well, on a given day,
I would organize
information flow
between the British,
the French, the Afghans,
and 90 Chinook helicopters.
- You're a veteran.
- Yes, sir.
Army, four tours.
- Is that on your, uh, résumé?
- No, sir.
I found that it
freaks some people out.
Oh, right.
Well, uh, Todd,
I'm sorry to say this,
but I don't know
if you're the right...fit.
As much as I'm deeply indebted
for your service.
- I need this job,
Dr. Goodwin.
My VA insurance
can't cover a gopher hole,
and more than that, I...
I need a place
to feel useful again.
- Well, um, how about this?
Why don't I have HR keep you
in mind for something that, uh,
better suits your skill set?
- I spent six years
in the Middle East,
coordinating four languages,
$3 billion worth
of military gear,
and the lives of my friends.
I may not know computers,
but if there is one thing my
skill set definitely includes,
it's knowing how to
make the trains run on time.
All I'm asking
is you give me a shot.
- Welcome to--
- I am so sorry,
but in order for
the drug tests to be valid,
I have to, um, to watch.
- Well, I have peed in front
of you a million times.
You just weren't the
deputy medical director then.
And, my job didn't
depend on the results,
and you know what?
I kinda wish I hadn't worn
such sexy underwear.
How about we
change the subject?
I'm thinking about adopting--
- I have been having sex
with my physical therapist.
- What?
No.
Zach Ligon?
- I know, I know, I know,
he's the worst.
- He is smug and shallow, and--
- I needed a distraction, okay?
- He's your doctor!
- He's my colleague.
Who then tragically
became my doctor,
but you know what?
I'm totally over it and
it's never gonna happen again.
- I mean, I shouldn't judge.
After all, this is the most
intimate I've been anybody
since Akash and I broke up.
- Then I am glad that
I wore my sexy underwear.
Oh...
I don't know.
Before the crash, I thought
I'd figured it all out.
Not just with him,
but as a doctor.
- You know what?
Don't do that.
Look, it didn't work out
with a guy you were dating.
Join the club.
You're killing it as a doctor.
Look how much money you raised
for precision oncology.
- "Dr. Helen" raised
that money, not Dr. Sharpe.
- Oh, God.
Don't be so quick
to discount your celebrity.
'Cause life...
it's a little bit
like a drug test.
It counts more...
when people watch.
- You have the face of a man
who just paid off
his student loans.
- Hey, Evie's coming back
from San Fran tomorrow.
- Been six weeks already?
That went fast.
For you.
I'm planning a wedding
by myself.
I can't relate
to people in love.
- Renée, Renée, Renée...
- Don't say it, Dr. Reynolds.
- Well, what's it been?
Two weeks since our
coronary artery bypass?
Looks like you reopened the
vein at the extraction site.
- I fell.
- Well, that's quite a fall,
Renée.
- The fall wasn't so bad.
It's just that
I couldn't get up.
- How long
were you on the ground?
- 14 hours.
- Renée.
- I know, I know.
Ever since Patrick passed,
it's just been me.
- Well, who found you?
- The delivery man.
He knocked on my door
by mistake.
He was looking
for my neighbor.
It was so humiliating.
- No, come on.
No, hey...
I'm here.
I'm gonna get you fixed up,
all right?
Vince Martinelli, 47.
BP 80 over 40, he's tachy
with a heart rate of 130.
Diaphoretic and showing signs
of dehydration.
Found him collapsed at a
construction site over on 19th.
- Thanks,
we'll take him from here.
Mr. Martinelli?
My name is Dr. Bloom.
- Am I dying?
- Not if I can help it.
Let's hang
a liter of PlasmaLyte.
We're gonna run another EKG
to figure out what's going on
with your heart, okay?
Has this ever happened to you
before?
- No, never.
Been feeling like I was coming
down with the flu all week,
and then this happened.
- Well, good news is you're
not having a heart attack.
- When can I be
back on the job?
- One step at a time, okay?
- No hours, no pay, Doc.
- I get it, but there is
something going on.
You notice
anything else recently?
- Yeah, well...
My pee...
I've seen some blood in there,
too.
That's bad, right?
- Todd, I know that
your military service
has instilled in you
a deep respect for rank,
but if you're gonna replace
my old assistant,
then I need you to be
way less respectful.
- Yes, sir.
- No, sir!
See, there's no sir-ing
at New Amsterdam.
Just loosen up,
speak your mind, you know?
- Yo, Max,
wait up.
- Yeah, see, Dr. Reynolds
is a perfect example
of our informal,
laid-back vibe.
- Uh, permission
to speak freely?
- Granted.
- Todd--
- I got a post-op patient
who has just readmitted
after falling.
Now I gotta stitch up
her graft on her leg, again.
- Medicare should cover
the surgery.
- Well, they should.
What they don't cover
is the in-house checkups
my patient really needs
to make sure
she doesn't come back again.
- You're talking about
a live-in nurse?
- No, no, Max,
just check-ups.
Look--this isn't the first time
this has happened here.
Unless we do something,
it won't be the last.
- All right, I'm on it.
I will take it to the board
this morning.
- Yes, sir.
- Nope, don't start that.
- That's not a thing!
Is it possible
we got the wrong day?
Or...time or, uh, place?
Is this the right room?
- Well,
you're five minutes early.
- How did that happen?
- Punctuality shows discipline.
If you can't rely on someone
to be on time, how can you rely
on them for anything else?
- Guess we've just been...
kind of winging it, Todd.
- Vince Martinelli's labs,
hot off the press.
- Normal, normal, normal,
within range...
wait, wait--
his cobalt serum value
is 60 micrograms per liter?
- Cobalt poisoning.
How'd he get that?
- Okay, uh, page Sharpe
and get the Department
of Public Health on the line.
We may need to shut down
his construction site.
- Resolve to renew
our partnership
with Le Bernardin
for next year's gala.
Second?
The motion proceeds.
All in favor?
Then très bien
for Le Bernardin.
Next item, the gala's theme.
I'm thinking...
masquerade.
- Point of order, uh...
Sorry,
am I saying that right?
Is it point of order?
- It's a thing you can say.
- Good, point of order.
This is a waste of time.
Uh, masquerade,
no masquerade--
doesn't really matter.
I'd like to talk about
Renée Hamrick.
- Max, we have an agenda--
- Renée Hamrick
had heart surgery here
three weeks ago,
and she made it.
But because
of nonexistent post-op care,
she ended up back
in our hospital today,
to do it all over again.
So I would like to propose
the New Amsterdam
Visiting Nurses Agency.
We sent select nurses
to our patients' homes
to provide after-care check-ins
and at this year's gala
we can all raise a glass,
knowing that
what happened to Renée Hamrick
will never happen again.
All in favor?
- Someone has to second.
- Can I get a second?
Can I get a second?
- No second.
Dr. Goodwin's
characteristically uplifting
yet exorbitantly priced
proposal is rejected.
Selecting
our newest board member.
- That's it?
This is our--
- The binders in front of you
have a bio
of Lamont Hallstrom.
Lamont is a top dog
at AQP's hedge fund
and he's eager to serve.
Now, we vote tomorrow morning,
10:30 sharp.
But since
he's running unopposed--
- Yeah, actually,
he's not running unopposed,
and correct me if I'm wrong,
but our by-laws state that any
member can nominate candidates,
so as a member...
I happen to have
the perfect candidate in mind.
- So, who's your
perfect candidate?
- No idea, Todd, but I've got
24 hours to figure that out.
- Oh, so you lied
to your superior?
- The board is what you get
when power is in the hands
of rich people whose only
friends are other rich people
who've never even met
a regular guy like you or me.
- But you're rich.
- Me?
No, not by a long shot.
- Are you debt-free
and making six figures a year?
- Uh, well--
- Then you're rich.
- Yeah, but not, like,
rich-rich.
- Are most of your friends
other doctors?
- I mean, kind of, but--
- So then
your friends are rich.
What are you getting at, Todd?
- Well, actually,
you're a lot like the board.
- I'm like those guys?
No, no, no.
They--they're board people,
okay?
They all went to Harvard.
- Where'd you go?
- Brown,
but that's liberal Ivy.
It's totally different.
- Okay.
- You know what, Todd?
You're dismissed.
- Rohan Beta!
Is there a game tonight?
Did I forget to put it
in my calendar?
- No, no,
we didn't have plans.
I have some news.
- News?
Come, sit, sit.
What is your news?
- Um...my band...
we, uh, kind of have
this cool thing going.
- What cool thing?
- It's a tour, a big tour.
Huge, actually.
We're gonna be on the road
for months.
Now,
I know you don't approve--
- No, no, no, no.
You're following your dreams.
I'm very proud of you, Beta.
I would like to help.
Can I send you some money
while you're on the road?
Isn't that what you call it?
On the road?
- Yeah.
But no,
I need to do this on my own.
There's one thing
you could do for me.
- Anything you need.
- Look out for Ella for me.
I don't want her
to feel too alone.
- Oh, of course I will.
- You guys are so annoying--
seriously!
- No, guys, we have to start
over--he didn't say anything.
- It doesn't matter!
- Yes it does.
that's the point of the game.
Say something!
- Okay.
- It's always the same thing
with her--it's like she's
the only one with problems.
- Okay, okay, Shoshanna.
It's fine to have
emotions in here.
Obviously, that's
the whole point,
but let's try to remember
intent versus impact, okay?
Emily, what's going on?
What's happening with you?
- I just feel alone.
- Why do you think
you feel alone?
Come on,
back in the circle here.
- Nobody cares
what I think.
I don't matter
to anyone.
- #truth.
Shoshanna, please.
You know,
it's okay to feel alone.
We all feel alone
from time to time, right?
Even when we aren't, right?
Daniel, what about you?
How do you feel?
- Yeah, I guess
I feel alone sometimes.
And I...
and I just...
- Ooh, hold on.
Emily?
You okay?
- Something...
something smells weird
in here.
Like rotten eggs.
- Okay, well, I'm--
I don't smell anything, so--
- I smell it, too.
Like,
really gross rotten eggs.
- Um, you're all smelling it?
Okay, uh, let's be safe.
Everyone, come on,
let's get up.
Up and out of the class.
We will go
to a less stinky locale.
Come on, Emily, you'll be okay.
Come on.
All right, everybody down.
Yep, you know where to go.
- Something wrong?
- Um, maybe, yeah.
Can you get maintenance?
We may have a gas leak.
- Great news
for Renée Hamrick.
- Oh, the board approved
visiting nurses?
- Not yet,
not by a long shot.
But, once they approve
my new candidate,
I am confident they will.
- That's fantastic.
Who'd you, uh, sucker into
signing up for that?
No, no.
- Yeah.
Just hear me out,
because I need
an ally on the board,
one of us, someone who can
make sure that
when programs like the Visiting
Nurse's Agency come up,
Brantley can't just--
brush 'em aside.
- What time are the meetings?
- 10:30 on Wednesday.
- Look, Max, I'd love to help,
but the reason that the board
meets at 10:30 every Wednesday
is because
they don't have other jobs.
I have surgery.
- It would suck
to miss surgery,
but, it could mean that
the next Renée Hamrick
wouldn't need
additional surgery at all.
So, think about it.
Come on buddy,
what do you say?
Me and you,
shaking things up.
- All right, I'm in.
- Yes, yes!
Thank you.
- Dr. Reynolds?
- Mm-hmm.
- No.
- No?
- $4.75.
- Keep it.
- Oh, thank you.
- No, don't thank her.
she's undermining elections.
- No one's undermining
anything, Max.
- Mm-hmm.
- I'm giving you reality,
a thankless task
which appears to be my lot.
- Dr. Reynolds is accomplished.
He is dynamic, he knows
this hospital inside and out.
- Can Dr. Reynolds raise
seven figures?
No.
Can he donate it himself?
Ergo, he's out.
Money is how programs
like the Visiting Nurse's
Program gets funded.
If you want to play this game,
bring me a candidate
the board can actually use.
- Like another rich sycophant?
- Like a CEO, a hedge fund
manager, or a celebrity.
Better yet, all three.
Happy hunting!
Oh, oh.
- Okay, um...
- Is Emily gonna be okay?
- I'm handling it, Daniel.
- You didn't exactly
answer the question.
- Okay, you know what?
That's enough.
Head to the classroom,
everybody.
Thank you, I'll be there
in a second.
Thank you.
Here, yeah, come on.
Take a seat.
Not feeling any better, huh?
- My head still hurts
and I'm seeing spots.
- Yeah, you know, natural gas,
it can deprive
our body of oxygen
and it causes all these
nasty little symptoms.
It's called hypoxia.
- No gas leak.
- I'm sorry, what?
No gas leak?
Um, hang on.
Just keep breathing,
okay kiddo?
What are you talking about?
Emily is literally retching
her guts up on the floor.
- Building services checked
the entire floor twice.
- All right, page Kapoor.
Thank you.
- I don't want any trouble.
- I understand that,
Mr. Martinelli,
but we need you to tell us
what you've seen
at your construction site.
- Any old signs of labels
talking about cobalt,
or other heavy metals?
- No, nothing like that.
- What about old insulation?
- They're running
a clean shop, I swear,
and they're square by me,
especially how they treated me
since my accident.
- What accident?
- I was welding early on
on the joists,
fell 10 feet
and shattered my hip.
- Gosh, you're lucky
that was all.
- And I was out a while.
But the foreman,
after my hip replacement,
put me on site hauling.
He didn't have to do that.
- Um, what do they have
you doing as a site hauler?
- Driving the trash away.
It's the cushiest job
I've ever had for the money.
- Mr. Martinelli, are you okay
if we check something?
- With that?
- All you're gonna feel
is a slight pinch
and some pressure.
- Bloom, that's not blood.
- What the hell?
- Mr. Martinelli,
you're being poisoned
by your artificial hip.
- Emily's symptoms could be
caused by any number of things.
I need to order
some further tests.
- Oh, come on,
don't give me that.
Your beautiful mind
already has a diagnosis.
No.
I have a hypothesis.
I suspect Emily is suffering
from a complex migraine.
- A complex migraine?
- Iggy!
Come quick,
something's wrong.
- What?
- Oh, whoa.
You might need to revise
that hypothesis.
- So, Renée Hamrick is here
for an I&D
in the primary closure
of her left leg's
saphenous vein graft site,
and the position
looks good to me.
We're ready to proceed.
- Okay.
- Alicia, go ahead and start
the general anesthetic.
And for you,
I've got some good news.
- Usually you wait till
after the surgery to say that.
- I was just appointed
to the hospital board.
And for my first act in office,
I intend to make sure
you have someone
to check on you post-op--
free of charge.
- You can do that?
- Oh, absolutely.
See you when you wake up.
- Dr. Reynolds!
- I'm in the middle
of something.
- Okay,
I have some bad news,
so I'm just gonna say it really
fast: you're not on the board.
- What?
Well, who'd you get?
- No one.
They just, you know,
didn't want you.
Max, I just promised this woman
that we would look after her
this time around.
- And we're gonna
keep that promise.
- How, exactly?
I think I know.
- Do you know how hard
the FDA makes it
to answer one simple question?
- What's the question?
- If we put this hip
into someone's body,
will it kill them?
- Is that a real question?
- The FDA stopped approving
metal-on-metal hips in 2016
due to higher risks,
but how does that help
the 3,000 patients that we gave
these hips to before 2016?
- I am so glad you asked that,
because that is
exactly the kind of issue
that you are gonna be solving
when you are on the board
of New Amsterdam.
- On the board?
You're my first choice.
You don't want Dr. Sharpe,
you want Dr. Helen.
- Yes, that is true,
Brantley needs a celebrity.
- Max,
when you first got here,
you asked me to scale down
on publicity
and scale up on medicine,
which gave me purpose,
a renewed sense of self,
something I could really use
right about now.
- I know, but I really need
one of us on the board
to make a difference,
someone who
represents our views,
and Brantley already
nixed Reynolds.
- Oh, gosh, I thought
I was your first choice.
- First in my...heart.
- Oh Max, I would love
to help you and this hospital,
but Brantley
will never approve me,
celebrity or not,
because effective chairmen
only approve board members
that they agree with,
and that's most definitely
not one of us.
- Okay.
- Dr. Goodwin.
- Whoa.
It's not a covert operation,
Todd.
- You need anything?
- Nope, I'm all good,
and by all good I mean all bad,
but in your free time,
feel free to run some errands
or stop by the VA.
- Unless I have
six weeks of free time,
I won't be able to deal
with the wait at the VA.
- Oh, well, let me make a call.
I'll get you in.
- Nope, thank you--I don't
want any special treatment.
It's what you get
with socialized medicine.
- Oh, and you're not
a fan of socialized medicine.
- It's un-American.
- It's un-American?
What could be more American
than helping people?
- A system
that embraces competition
rather than relying on
a captive patient population.
- We are standing
in a public hospital,
and as the guy
who runs this place
chock full of
socialized medicine,
let me assure you, Todd,
we're doing a good thing here.
- But in a socialized market,
there's no incentive
for hospitals
to provide better care.
- This hospital
has 1,000 beds,
sees over 100,000 emergency
room visits every year.
We don't--
- Max!
Max! Hey, hi!
We, uh--hi.
So, we feel obliged to tell you
that we may have an outbreak
of Legionnaire's disease
in the hospital.
But, uh, it's cool.
We have it
totally under control.
- Uh, we don't.
Not yet, but very soon.
- Yeah, it's, like,
old water systems,
faulty AC units, you know.
It was only a matter of time.
- Good, got it?
Okay.
- You were saying?
About this hospital?
- Okay, this plasmapheresis
machine will filter your blood
and it'll help save
your remaining kidney function.
- How is this
even happening?
- The ball joint and the socket
of your artificial hip
are made of a cobalt alloy.
The metal parts
are rubbing against each other
and the friction is causing
the cobalt to flake off
into your bloodstream.
- How do you stop it?
- We are, uh, going to need
to replace your hip, Vince.
- Ah, no.
And how do we know
this won't just happen again?
- Wedlow Medical,
the manufacturer,
claims to have
fixed the problem
with their newer models.
- Claims to have fixed it?
This is my body!
Who's gonna pay
for the surgery?
Or the time I'm out of work?
It took eight weeks last time.
You think my worker's comp
is gonna cover this again?
No way.
- Vince--
- No, this'll bankrupt me.
- Listen to me,
Mr. Martinelli.
That is not gonna happen,
I promise you
I'll make sure of it.
- And then who the hell
is gonna pay?
- They are.
- The antibiotics
aren't working.
Symptoms
are just getting worse.
- For which patient?
- For all of them.
- Fevers are all over 100,
Daniel's vomiting
has increased
and Shoshanna's
shortness of breath--
- Um, where is Shoshanna?
Shoshanna,
what are you doing here?
- "Low stimulus room."
- Okay.
- I couldn't take any more
of the crying and the puking
and "Will Emily be okay?"
- How are you feeling?
- Fine.
- Fine?
- May I?
Breathe, please.
Once more.
- No bronchial constriction.
Any nausea?
- No.
- Normal.
- Hey, Shoshanna.
How long have you
been in here?
- Not long, I just needed
someplace quiet to journal.
- How come
she is the only one better?
- You keep journaling, okay?
- Iggy, this is hardly
any time for stress eating.
- What?
No, I'm not stress eating,
Vijay.
I think I know
how I can fix this.
- How?
- With these.
- You really think
this is gonna work?
- Well, you know what they say
about a spoonful of sugar.
- Okay.
- Yeah.
You have something called MPI,
but this
will make you feel better.
- When?
- Almost instantaneously.
- ♪ I do declare you're gonna
miss your candyman, yeah ♪
- Is this candy?
- Nope, it's medicine.
Fast-acting.
- Just one pill?
- Just one pill.
- Can I chew it?
- No.
- ♪ I do declare you're gonna
miss your candyman, yeah ♪
♪ I'm keeping you
safe and warm ♪
Swallow.
- ♪ Yeah, baby
♪ Keeping you out of harm
- Are you sure
this isn't candy?
- Yes.
- ♪ Yeah, baby,
keepin' you out of harm ♪
♪ Where you gonna go
when it start to storm ♪
- Should I take one, too?
I could've been exposed.
- No, no, no,
you're too old to contract it.
- Too old?
- Yes, MPI stands for
"Mass Psychogenic Illness,"
also known as Collective
Obsessional Behavior,
also known as...
- Mass hysteria?
- Bingo.
Yes, MPI tends to crop up
in isolated, pressurized
groups of young people,
much like
fancy boarding schools...
our psych ward.
- Or Salem.
- Yeah, and once
it gets rolling,
it transmits by line-of-sight,
much like an actual
physical virus.
That's why Shoshanna improved
once she was isolated.
- So wait, after all this,
no one was actually sick?
- Well, I wouldn't say that.
And the symptoms are about
as real as they get, clearly.
But, um, a psychological
problem requires...
a psychological cure.
Preferably cherry-flavored.
- Hi, uh--oh, sorry.
You okay?
- I'm working on it.
- Good, 'cause I'm in
a bit of a pickle.
Um, so, I need help filling
an extra seat on the board.
- Oh, I'm in.
Oh, thank you.
You know what?
The busier I am,
the less pain I feel.
- Actually,
I was kind of hoping
to fill it with your mother.
- My mother?
- Yeah, okay, hear me out.
You said that she runs
in wealthy socialite crowds,
right?
Which is great,
because Brantley will assume
that she is one of them.
But here is where
the plan gets really good--
she will secretly
be working for us, right?
Our man on the inside.
You can tell her
how to vote and what to back
and what to bring
to the floor--
- Like a puppet?
- Yeah,
more like a Trojan Horse,
but for the good guys.
Max.
She can't be trusted.
- Well, that's okay, I mean,
even if she doesn't go with us
every time, it--
- No. No, I mean
she can't be trusted
to show up, anywhere.
Except for maybe
a hosted bar.
And even if we programmed her,
she would still vote
for whoever was doing
the shaking and the pouring.
- Got it.
I didn't know that, sorry.
- No, no, don't be.
No, it helps to be reminded
I am genetically
predisposed to it.
Guess you're gonna
have to go with plan B.
- Yeah, plan B failed...
several plans ago.
- Paging Dr. Goodwin.
- Page me
as soon as she wakes up.
- Will do.
- Evie.
- Hey babe, how's it going?
- Well, I, uh,
just had to redo a surgery
because our health care system
only goes halfway
when it matters.
- That sounds frustrating.
- Oh, well, it is.
But I'll be all right,
you know why?
Because you are coming home
to me tomorrow.
Evie?
- Okay, so don't freak out,
this is good news.
HHC is so impressed
by my work,
they've asked me to stay here
for two more weeks.
- Two more weeks?
- I know, but I have to
see this job through.
What's the point of only going
halfway when it matters, right?
I gotta go.
Floyd, wait, I--
- Vijay?
- Ella?
- Have you seen Rohan?
He was supposed to meet me here
two hours ago.
- Yes, I saw him.
He came to say good-bye
before he left on the tour.
- What tour?
- Um, his tour on the--
with the band?
- Oh, my God.
For the last two hours
I've been trying to convince
myself this wasn't happening.
I should've known
he couldn't handle it.
But to disappear
like a coward?
- I don't understand.
- There's no tour, Vijay.
He lied.
He bailed.
- W-why would he do that?
- I'm pregnant.
- Dr. Kapoor, Dr. Kapoor!
- Get me Ativan, now!
- 1 mil Ativan.
- I thought everyone
was getting better.
- They were.
Everyone else is,
just--Emily...
- 60 lpm, high flow 02.
- Pulse ox 95.
- What's wrong with her?
- I don't know!
- She's stabilizing.
I-I'm sorry.
- Because you personally
brought this to our attention,
Wedlow Medical is willing
to cover the cost
of Mr. Martinelli's
new hip replacement.
- And?
- We'll also cover
Mr. Martinelli's rehabilitation
and lost wages.
- Yeah, no, that's not
gonna work for us.
Because I discovered
that when the FDA banned
metal-on-metal hips,
your company simply coated
those defective hips.
Mr. Martinelli would like
your 100% ceramic hip.
- The one that won't poison me.
- Those are triple the cost.
- Oh, I wasn't done.
We'd also like Wedlow Medical
to provide the ceramic hip
free of charge
to any new patient
who suffers a malfunction
of your coated devices.
- Dr. Sharpe, we don't have to
offer your patients anything.
We're in full compliance
with the FDA, in fact,
we only took this little
meeting because, frankly,
we're big fans of Dr. Helen.
Brilliant.
Then Dr. Helen will go on TV
and broadcast to the world
how Wedlow Medical's
poorly designed products
harm patients.
And perhaps I'll bring this
to drive my point home.
It's joint fluid.
We found it inside
Mr. Martinelli's body.
- You do that,
and we'll crush you
with so many defamation suits,
you'll never
practice medicine again.
- I'd like to see you try.
- They'll destroy you.
They have bottomless pockets
and a fleet of lawyers and
they will destroy everything
that you have ever worked for.
- They only see me as
Dr. Helen, a TV personality,
so I intend to put
that personality to good use.
- Yeah, and what about
Dr. Sharpe?
- She is out
fighting for her patients,
something that you do
every single day, and yet,
you're asking me
to pull my punches.
Why would you do that?
- Because this will
end your career,
and I can't do this
without you.
I'm not...
fully...
here.
Part of me is still...
on that ambulance.
- You push me away,
and you expect me
to understand.
And then you need me?
And you use your feelings
as leverage.
- You think I'm using Georgia
to manipulate you?
- I don't what you're doing
because you won't ever
talk to me.
- I can't talk to you.
- Why?
- Because I'm trying
to spare you.
I don't want you to feel...
this.
I don't want you
to experience...
this...
and it's not fair.
I know.
- None of this is fair.
We can just toss "fair"
out the window.
Max, when you need me,
I am here for you.
For all of it.
But not at the expense
of my patient.
- As awful as it sounds,
in regards to
some of the larger
medical device companies,
we've just become guinea pigs
for their inferior products.
- It's not as if
it's a microwave
that you can return
or get recalled.
- Exactly.
We're talking about products
that are surgically implanted
into your body.
In your spine,
your heart, the hip.
And if these products fail,
you get sick.
Or worse, you die.
I have a brave,
hardworking patient
whose life has been
turned upside down
by one of these products.
The time has come
to make a stand.
- When we come back,
Dr. Helen will reveal which
company to avoid and why.
- And, we're out!
- And we're back in 3, 2...
- Welcome back
to "The Night Shift".
I'm here with Dr. Helen,
who has come to warn us
about a company that harmed
one of her patients.
Dr. Helen?
- I'm...
actually not here
to shame any one
particular company,
because in truth, they're all
in compliance with the FDA,
and that's where
the real fault lies.
- So you're taking on
the FDA?
- It appears that way,
doesn't it?
The FDA need to enact real
regulations on medical devices
that protect patients,
not corporate profit.
We need clinical trials
before implanting heavy metals
into our body.
We need oversight.
We deserve that much.
- So what can our viewers
at home--what can they do?
- Call your representatives,
demand to be heard.
If we want change,
then we have to be
the ones to initiate it.
- Dr. Bloom,
we don't have a session today.
- We do.
For the next seven minutes.
- Remember to sit still,
Emily.
Dr. Kapoor,
the results are up.
- You have what is called
a meningioma.
A tumor on the lining
of your brain.
It's been causing
all your symptoms.
- Yeah, that sounds a lot worse
than it actually is.
- Meningiomas
are usually benign.
Once we remove them, you
will be back to your old self.
- Did everybody have one
of these tumors, too?
- No, they didn't.
They saw you getting sick
and then they believed
that they were sick, too.
- So I did this to them?
- No.
Emily, you didn't do anything.
They saw you and
they were affected by you.
You know what that means?
- That they all hate me now?
- No, it means that
you're not alone...
That we're all connected.
- Main hoon na.
- What?
- In Bollywood movies,
they would say,
main hoon na.
- Vijay, if you're here
to make excuses for your son,
you should leave
before I lose it.
- I went to Rohan's apartment,
to his office,
called up his sponsor...
I couldn't find him.
My son is gone.
- Yeah, well...
- When life overwhelms him,
he...
he always runs away.
But not me.
I wish for you to know that.
- Vijay?
- Main hoon na?
What does that mean?
- "I'm there for you."
It's time
for the board meeting.
- Ugh, we promised we'd
help that woman and we failed.
I don't have the votes for
the Visiting Nurse's Program.
- Well...
a nanny state program
like that
probably wouldn't have
worked, anyway.
- I get that we
all have different...
political beliefs, Todd,
but that woman needs help,
and she needs it now.
- I understand that.
And self-reliance is the key
to a good life,
and it doesn't take
taxpayer money to achieve.
- Okay, okay, what about this?
What if instead of wagging your
finger or disagreeing with me,
what about you help her?
Give me a self-reliant solution
that helps Renée Hamrick.
- Get her a dog.
- Get her...a dog.
- Adopt a dog for her.
Then you hire a dog walker
to come by once a day.
- To...check on her.
- Twice, pick up and drop off.
How much
was this nurse's agency
gonna cost you per day?
- Um, around $200.
- I bet you can get
a dog walker for $20.
- Todd...
have you ever thought about
being on a board?
A CEO, a celebrity,
or a hedge fund manager.
That's what you said, right?
That's what this board needs,
a leader.
Uh, someone acclaimed
or someone rich.
Sergeant Todd Benson
is a leader.
He asked for loyalty
in a setting
more intense than any
boardroom, and he got it.
And--
you don't get more acclaim
than a veteran
with a Purple Heart and
a host of other decorations.
- You left one out.
I respect your service,
Sergeant, we all do,
but the category
Max conveniently skipped
money.
Having it, donating it,
raising it.
That's what
a board member does.
- Yeah,
that's why you need Todd.
Todd did something today
that most of you
would call impossible.
He changed my mind.
And he did it using the kind
of insight that you get
when you spend your life
making more out of less.
Economic diversity can lead
to innovative solutions
to dollars and cents problems.
Yes, money,
that's what boards do.
That's why this board
needs someone
who knows what it's like
to not have it.
- How do we know he's not just
going to vote however you say?
- Him?
No, he's gonna vote with you
more than he votes with me.
We can barely agree on, um...
literally anything.
Yeah, but we do agree
on one thing,
and that's that we both
want to help.
He just helps in a way
that's less "one of us"
and more like the people
that New Amsterdam
is trying to serve.
- Before we vote
on Lamont Hallstrom,
resolve to nominate Todd Benson
to the board of
New Amsterdam Hospital.
Is there a second?
The motion proceeds.
All in favor?
The votes have it.
Welcome to our newest board
member, Sergeant Todd Benson.
- Congratulations.
Oh, and the board
is an unpaid position,
so I think in this case
we can make an exception.
Salary equal
to what he's surrendering
as my assistant seems fair.
Can I get a...
second?
- There you go, yep.
- Evie, hey look,
before you say anything,
I've gotta apologize.
I just, uh, I miss you.
- I miss you, too.
And I'm so lucky
to be marrying a man
who is excited to plan
our wedding while I'm here.
I just...
I feel so far away...
you know?
- Well, there's gotta
be something we can do.
One second.
- ♪ But no matter
what you do ♪
♪ Even pray to heaven above
- Caterer needs a decision
by tomorrow.