The Apgar test.
The Whipple procedure.
The DeBakey clamp.
So many of the tools we use
in our hospitals every day
are named after the people
who invented them.
♪ Knockin' at your door
Even diseases
used to be named after
the people
who discovered them.
♪ The world outside
is waiting for ya ♪
But a medical board
in the 1970s
discontinued that practice...
♪ But you never know nothing
if you never did ♪
...claiming that
no one could "own" a sickness.
♪ Woah
♪ What, me worry?
♪♪
♪ House is burning down
As altruistic
as the profession is,
doctors are human.
♪♪
♪ I ain't even trippin',
I ain't trippin' ♪
♪ I'm just dancing
through the door ♪
Game Day.
You ready?
I was ready
the first time.
If we do something that could
change the face of medicine,
we want our name on it.
♪ What, me worry?
♪ Burn, baby
♪ We can burn it all down,
a millions pounds, baby ♪
♪ Join the KLF
and sail us up the Congo ♪
Hey.
Hey, Amelia said
you'd already gone.
I went for a hike.
That's...different.
Yeah, well, you know,
the silence,
the fresh air,
it clears my head.
I need to clear my head.
Before the big
groundbreaking surgery
that none of us can watch?
It's fine.
You go make history.
I'll get the kids
to school.
Well, someday
you'll make history,
and I'll watch your kids
and we'll be even.
Unusable.
Completely unusable.
Zola's watching
the Whipple tape.
Again?
Change of plans.
Suction here.
Hi. Retract that, please.
Clamp.
She was great,
wasn't she?
She was.
Not as good as you.
You better
go get ready for school.
Hi.
Hi. So it looks like
I'm not gonna be able
to make it down to Seattle
for your big day.
I'm sorry.
Did I invite you?
True. I'd probably just be
a big distraction.
You know, these eyes
looking down at you
from the OR gallery as
you try to focus on Hamilton.
I understand.
A little full of ourselves,
aren't we?
Not unlike my patient.
No, I'm headed in
to see a patient
with end-stage
liver disease.
Primary sclerosing
cholangitis.
He's been waiting on a liver
and he was starting to give up,
but then -- plot twist --
storm dumps eight inches
up in Bemidji last night,
teenager hits a patch
of black ice and...
well, that's not
the funpart of the story,
but my guy's getting
a new liver.
Mm,
bittersweet congratulations.
Yeah,
Arthur's a sweet kid.
Good luck today.
Send me pictures?
O-Of the surgery.
Doc pics.
Doctor pictures.
You know what I mean.
I'll see ya.
Bye.
Morning.
Oh, you changed
your hair.
I did.
It was obviously
a mistake,
so I pulled myself together
and fixed the mistake.
Oh, well,
this looks nice, too.
Long night?
Placenta previa,
which wound up a C-section
at 4:45 a.m.
Mother and baby
are doing great.
The OB resident
is fully wiped.
You've been working
a lot of nights lately.
A lot of babies come at night.
Yeah, of course.
It's just -- You're not
avoiding me, are you?
No!
Are you avoiding me?
Not at all.
Okay.
Great.
Okay, I'm gonna go
and order
the greasiest egg sandwich
they have at Joe's
and then go nap at home
and then come get Luna.
I'll get Luna.
Oh, okay.
Great.
Thanks.
Okay.
Sounds good.
Everything's good.
Yeah, I understand,
and I am absolutely flattered,
and I-I'll let you know.
Okay.
Huh? They finally restocked
on the unsweetened almond milk
after I gave them
a little nudge yesterday.
You're
the only one who cares.
Now walk with me.
Everything okay, Chief?
A med school friend
just called.
I haven't spoken to him
in months,
but he works with NASA, at the
Aerospace Medicine Fellowship.
They do research --
On innovative devices designed
to identify and combat
spacial disorientation
and vestibular abnormalities?
Of course
you would know that.
I-I just read a paper about
how they've received funding
to start new oxygen-delivery
systems on aircrafts.
Yeah.
In aircrafts.
Yes!
Yeah, it's a program
that combines the two things
I've dreamt about
my entire life --
medicine and space.
And at the worst possible time
in my life,
I've been asked to run
their clinical training.
W-Wait. Hold on, wait.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Chief --
Chief Bailey, you --
you just got an offer
to go to space.
I mean, just when I thought you
couldn't get any more amazing,
you go and break
the stratosphere?
I did do that, didn't I?
Pre-op labs, EKG, CXR --
all clear.
Abdominal incision
is healing nicely
without signs of infection.
Pre-op MRI scans are done
and ready to upload
to the robot.
Cell vials are all within
the temperature range.
Watching the team
come together
to realize
my remarkable vision,
I'm humbled
by how far we've come since --
What are you doing?
What -- What is this?
Oh, it's for my book.
What book?
How do you think history books
are written?
Someone makes a record
for posterity.
We will. Myself,
Dr. Shepherd, Dr. Bartley --
we will publish
in medical journals.
And congratulations, you will be
in there as Patient X.
Is there a bigger room available
to accommodate all these egos?
Despite how you have treated me
and the entire team,
I'm still here,
as I was 11 days ago
when your arrogance
and dishonesty
nearly sank
the entire project.
Let's make sure
they're ready upstairs.
♪♪
Oh, your -- your --
your mother let me in.
I thought
that you and I could talk.
♪♪
Every time I close my eyes,
I see blood pouring
out of Devon's body
while hearing his voice
inside my head.
I don't mean to be rude,
Dr. Webber,
but talking about it
doesn't help me.
This game helps me.
♪♪
Listen, no.
It's okay.
If we can just get it done,
it -- it'll be over quickly.No.
Look, your muscles will atrophy
if you don't mobilize them.
I can do this on my own.
I need to start my gym routine.
I've had PT much more strenuous
than this.
You know what?
I can take it from here.
Wound check.
Thanks so much, Eric.
I need someone else.
You've had three different
physical therapists in 10 days.
There's a rumor
you made one cry.
Link, all day, I see people
go past that door,
patients that
I could be helping.
All night, I hear rigs
pulling up outside.
It's torture.
I haven't even graduated
to the treadmill.
You know how you graduate
to the treadmill?
You put in the hours.
I'm trying to,
I just --
No, you either cancel
your sessions
or you yell at the people
leading them.
A solid support system is a
major factor in patient outcome,
especially in long rehabs.
Is Teddy coming by soon,
or...
I'm not sure.
Okay.
Alright, Hunt,
in the chair now.
Let's go.
I had my own Devon.
So I know exactly
what you're feeling.
My patient was
Chuck Higgins --
cannery worker.
We met when my wife Adele
made me go on
a food-and-blanket drive
for homeless people
that he organized.
Guy with a big heart,
terrible card player,
great taste in music.
One day, he came in
for a bowel obstruction.
He didn't like hospitals.
I remember the fear
in his eyes
when he was told
that he needed surgery.
But when I told him
that I would do it,
the fear went away.
He told me how comforting it was
to see me,
someone who looked like him,
in a white coat.
Three hours later,
there was a horrible error
in communications
in the OR,
and as a young attending,
I was too inexperienced
and timid to speak up and...
And you killed him
like I killed Devon.
We all kill people.
Schmitt, we don't always
kill people we feel close to,
like you felt with Devon,
like I felt with Chuck.
It makes the loss
unbearably worse.
And it's not even his death
that haunts me.
It's the relief
in that man's eyes
when he saw
that I was his surgeon,
the trust
that he put in me.
That's what stays with me,
even today.
He thought
I would take care of him...
and I didn't.
♪♪
Order for Wilson?
Yep, let me check.
Okay.
♪ I keep waiting, waiting,
waiting ♪
Hey.
♪ I keep waiting, waiting, oh
I haven't had a day off
in 35 days,
and I was on all night.
My kids are with
my mother-in-law and I'm just --
I'm going through some --
some stuff.
You want company?
No judging?
As long
as it goes both ways.
We're day-drinking.
♪ Always working on
some bigger plan ♪
♪ But living life by rote
Alright, first step --
we are ditching
the hospital gown.
I don't understand.
Well, the gown makes you feel
like you belong in bed.
As professional as I am,
I don't need to see anything
falling out of this gown.
Put these on.
They're mine.
These don't look clean.
They're clean enough.
I'm not sure
we're the same size, okay?
Listen, isn't there somebody
in Seattle
who has a broken bone
or a twisted ankle?
Okay, I don't know what's
going on with you and Teddy.
It's none of my business,
but I just repaired
your tibial plateau fracture
beautifully,
and I refuse to see my hard work
go to waste.
So put on the clothes.
I'm not sure gym clothes
are gonna help, okay?
People I've worked with
for years,
they see me
in this chair now,
and they just walk
right by.
They've written me off
as a surgeon.
Alright,
you want to get stronger,
you got to change the way
you are thinking.
Starting now, you are no longer
a patient in a hospital gown.
You are a world-class athlete
on the injured reserve list.
You are rehabbing, okay?
So stop pitying yourself --
get back on the field.
Dr. Park to Labor and Delivery.
Duda, Arthur.
Hello.
How we feeling?
Any nausea, fever, chills
in the last 24 hours?
Nope.
Haven't even thrown up
in a couple days.
Oh, hey, that's great.
Yeah, I'm thinking about using
that as my new pick-up line.
Okay, well,
sense of humor's still there.
That's good -- check.
Uh, new SLAM magazine.
Nice article on the Wolves
in there.
I don't know if, uh --
if Edwards and KAT
can stay healthy,
we might have a good chance of
making the playoffs this year.
What do you think about going
to a game sometime?
I'm down.
Okay, good.
Can we not?
It's hard enough
without the false hope.
His numbers
have been terrible.
Mom, it's just fun
to think about, okay?
Look, hey, hey, hey.
I know that the wait
has been hell,
but I'm still here.
I'm still in this.
Okay?
I mean, look,
do you blame her?
This is, what, Day 137
on the transplant list?
Of course you would know
the exact number, geez.
You'd be surprised.
Yesterday,
did I know it was Day 136?
I didn't.
But today's different.
I mean, you always remember
the day you get your new liver.
♪♪
What?
That's right.
Dr. Marsh.
Wait, what?
Arthur, you are getting
a new liver today.
I'm off with the team
to pick it up.
In the meantime,
you get plenty of rest.
No food, no water.
Happy Day 137.
137?
H-Hey,
have you heard from him?
Oh, come on, you know
how stubborn Richard can be.
Okay, he just can't take off
as he pleases.
So I'm down
yet another surgeon
right when I was offered
the opportunity of --
Oh, you have got to be
kidding me.
Bailey, it's a pleasure
to see you.
As a member
of the Fox Foundation,
I have to say, your residents
seem mopey, overworked.
Are you concerned
about, uh, burnout?
We're only getting
simple procedures,
which feels like punishment
for something we didn't do,
and Levi's just gone.
And now Dr. Webber
isn't even showing up,
so we're not sure what
we're supposed to be doing.
I mean, Dr. Webber still is
our residency director, right?
You know, I was residency
director for a hot second once.
Loved the parking space.
The work? Meh.
Is he here to give me
another heart attack?
Uh, he's on my team.
He's...
And what role exactly
do you have
on this groundbreaking
VIP project?
Ah, see, if we told you,
we'd have to kill you.
Oh, wait,
that's your resident's job.
Oh, too soon.
What?
Mm.
Why don't you all come
with me?
Bye-bye.
♪♪
Hi, David.
Full disclosure,
I had nothing to do
with this.
You are taking a giant risk
by volunteering
to be the patient here,
and we can't thank you enough
for that.
Mm.
But you are in my hospital,
and in my hospital,
we teach.
What are you saying?
I'm saying
let's throw our egos aside,
and let's open up
this historic surgery
to every attending,
every resident in the hospital.
And you're already
filming it,
so why not share it
with the world?
Why not teach the world?
♪♪
Okay.
Thank you.
♪♪
Our patient
is Dr. David Hamilton,
62-year-old male diagnosed
with Parkinson's disease
eight years ago.
He's currently
on levodopa and carbidopa
and is here for a pioneering
cell therapy surgery.
I haven't been to a bar
since I got Luna.
I mean, I-I-I love her
so much, but --
She's boring.
She only likes two songs,
and she doesn't want to read
any other book
except
"Where's My Belly Button?"
And then -- And then the diapers
and sleep regression.
The rage I have
for sleep regression...
Just wait till
she starts walking
and you wake up to her playing
pots and pans at 3:00 a.m.
No!
No, no, no, no, no.
Let's make a deal.
Okay.
No more saying
"I love my children, but..."
We can love our kids
and still need
a five-minute break
and a drink.
Yes!
Love this deal.
Almost as much as I love
the ratio of this vodka to OJ.
I just -- I couldn't go home
to Allison and Leo this morning.
I couldn't walk in the door
and hug them
and tell them everything
is okay another time.
I just -- I'm...
I'm exhausted from it.
I am exhausted from lying,
I mean,
but they're children,
and we have to lie
to children
because they can't know
all of the horrible thoughts
that are going on
inside our heads.
Are you okay?
No.
I'm -- I'm gonna get
another drink,
and I'm gonna play darts,
'cause throwing sharp objects
at something
sounds really good.
Too much pressure.
10 more seconds.
It hurts because you've been
in a bed for almost two weeks.
It hurts because I was in a car
that somersaulted down a ravine.
Hypothetical --
you're with someone,
and they know you
completely,
despite everything
and everyone you've done.
And it's great
until suddenly,
they don't even want to be
in the same room as you.
I really don't want
to talk about Teddy.
No, neither do I.
Wait, I thought
you and Amelia were done.
Uh...we are.
Okay, I'm confused.
Trust me, so am I.
Dr. Bowman to Cardiology.
Heads up, when you get
your organ, head out the back.
Grieving family
just arrived --
nothing worse than
having to walk that gauntlet.
Got it. Thank you.
I'm gonna take
a quick walk.
Let me know
when we're up, okay?
Sure.
Okay.
Okay, Helm,
how do we get the cells
that we inject
into the patient's brain?
From his skin?
That is vaguely not wrong.
We take stem cells
from a skin biopsy,
and then we reprogram them
through a complex process,
and then differentiate them
into dopamine-producing cells.
And by injecting them
into the forebrain,
we are hoping to improve
the dopamine levels
that decreases in patients
with Parkinson's.
What else?
C'mon, there's no such thing
as a stupid question.
Just a stupid resident
who asks it.
Dr. Bartley is the one
who perfected
the injection technique.
Would you like to say
a few words, Dr. Bartley?
Mm.
In order to maximize
surface area volume ratio
and avoid cell death from
lack of access to nutrients,
we created an injector
that could evenly distribute
the cells
along a cylindrical track,
which gives about
a 30% improvement
in survival of the cells.
Yeah, that's all.
Thank you.
♪♪
I chose research
for a reason.
Mice are more forgiving
than students. And cuter.
You were charming.
Well, and
you're a horrible liar.
Thank you, Dr. Bartley.
That was very informative.
Now, please take your seats,
and we can get started.
Are we sure all these people
even work here?
Oh, boy.
Um, hey, excuse me.
Oh, wow.
Excuse me.
Oh, my gosh.
Hi, hi. Excuse us.
I'm with them.
Excuse me.
Excu--
Oh. Okay, uh, we've set up
a video feed
in the west lobby
for overflow.
I'm not asking.
Thank you.
- Thanks.
- Appreciate it.
- Nice. Good.
- Hey. Come on, come on.
Oh, excuse me.
Whoa, i-- is that
a robotic micro-injector?
Hmm. Looks like a Da Vinci
married C-3PO.
You think?
It looks a little more
like Johnny 5 to me.
G-Genius.
Mm-hmm.
Yeah, the --
the little circle things
could be the eyes.
Could be the eyes,
yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
You like robots,
Dr. Pierce?
I like Wall-E.
Uh, you know
who also has robots, huh?
Hmm?
NASA.
Hi.
My name's Dr. Nick Marsh.
I'm here to recover
your son's liver
for a transplant patient.
I just wanted to come over
and tell you
how sorry I am
for your loss.
Thank you.
Mm.
James.
His name is James.
Okay.
I know
this might sound strange,
but is -- is there anything
you'd like to share about James?
He was always singing.
His first words were sung,
not spoken.
And the voice was so...
...powerful.
You could hear him
two streets over.
I, uh --
I-I always thought
he'd be a rock star,
but he liked opera,
and whenever my friends
were over,
he would sing it
so loud
and I'd get so embarrassed,
and I'd tell him to shut up.
It's okay. It's okay.
♪♪
And then when he auditioned for
the San Francisco Conservatory,
uh, he asked me
to drive down with him
so he could practice
his aria,
the "Una furtiva lagrima."
He was so good.
And I was so proud
of him.
Yeah.
Thank you for sharing that.
I really appreciate it.
♪♪
Dr. Marsh.
Yeah.
They're ready for you.
Okay.
I'll be right in.
♪♪
Thank you.
I'll be thinking about James
when I operate today.
♪♪
Okay, the --
the aliens attacked and --
and blew up your universe
and left you nothing
for the third time?
Y-You don't get bored?
You're stuck
in this endless loop
without ever
achieving anything?
In the time I've sat here,
you were killed by aliens
who you left behind.
You found a map
to their home planet,
but exploded in a trap,
and you didn't even inspect
the plans to build the --
the space thing
with the solar shields,
which, quite frankly,
is driving me mad.
And I'm just not sure
I get the point
of playing something
where you die over and over.
Because you learn
from it.
You use what you learn
before each death.
No matter how many times you die
or how many other people die,
you always get a do-over.
♪♪
Nice work.
Give me 20 more.
Wait, what?
I'm kidding. We're done.
Alright,
let's get you up, slowly.
Yeah.
You and Altman
were friends first, right?
Yeah.
How long did it take
to change?
I don't know, 20 years.
Right.
Was it awkward
when you, uh --
Ow!
What's wrong, you dizzy?
Ow.
A shooting pain right --
Ow! --
right behind the eye.
Alright,
let's lay you back down.
Yeah.
Oh, it feels better
when I lay flat.
Okay.
Significant swelling
around the incision.
Oh, damn it.Alright, alright,
we're going to CT right now.
♪♪
I-It's something
she -- she does.
Supposedly,
superhero pose --
Lowers cortisol,
increases testosterone.
Less stress,
more confidence.
I read the study.
Right.
Good for you.
Personally, a long shower
does it for me.
Oh, and here comes
the guest of honor.
David,
how are you feeling?
Like a bit player in a drama
suddenly.
Well,
you can just relax.
You got the finest neurosurgeon
in the country right here,
and I've got Shepherd
helping out.
I'm gonna go scrub.
Try not to drive
the patient away till I'm back.
We have issues.
He won't get far.
♪♪
First we position the patient
and secure his head
in the base frame.
♪♪
♪ I've been playing
with the weight of the world ♪
♪ Inside my head
♪ Praying for a change,
I lay awake all night again ♪
Okay.
Ready for cold perfusion.
So, we always start
dissecting the organ
under normal circulation,
and then we inspect
the organ
before the cardiac team
comes in
and takes
the heart and lungs.
♪ Feel like I'm falling short
♪ Electrified, I'm just a light
dimming in the dark ♪
♪ I'm an anomaly to myself
Pink, plump,
and perfect size.
Ready to go.
♪ Feel like I'm falling short
♪ Feel like I'm falling
We then perform a CT scan,
and the robot uses the images
to give us
an interactive 3-D roadmap
of the brain.
♪ Falling
♪ Feel like I'm falling
♪ Short
♪ I've been looking
for an answer ♪
♪ I don't know where to turn
We apply a local anesthetic
and make an incision
and prepare to drill
the burr holes.
I like to think of it
as creating
2/3 of a bowling ball.
That is not at all
what it's like.
♪ Short
♪ Supernova in my soul
Finished removing
the heart and lung.
Liver's all yours.
Dr. Shepherd
will direct the robotic arm
to bring the metal cannula
into place...
4 millimeters shy
of our target,
while I will adjust
the coordinates.
♪ Burning bright,
burning slow ♪
♪ It isn't every day
I feel so low ♪
♪ Supernova in my soul
♪ Falling, falling
Dr. Bartley will remove
the cells from the cooler
and place them
under a microscope
while we wait
to confirm viability.
Which is torture.
♪ Feel like
I'm falling, falling, falling ♪
IVC dissection complete.
Portal vein and GDA
are divided.
Good.
♪ I've been playing
with the weight of the world ♪
Okay, here we go.
We gently lift.
Okay.
♪ Supernova in my soul
Thank you, James. Good.
♪ Burning bright, burning slow
♪ Supernova in my soul
♪ Burning out, burning low
Cell viability
confirmed.
♪ Supernova in my soul
♪ Burning bright, burning slow
♪ It isn't every day
I feel so low ♪
♪ Supernova in my soul
Thank you.
♪ Feel like I'm falling,
falling, falling ♪
We're gonna load the syringe
into the micro injector.
How are we doing,
David?
Can you hear my voice?
♪ Falling
♪ Feel like, feel like
I'm falling, falling ♪
They're paging
Dr. Shepherd
to OR 2 immediately.
Patient
with a CSF leak.
Please. Someone with
training wheels can handle that.
It's not like Shepherd's
sitting around doing Sudoku.
The patient
is Dr. Hunt.
♪♪
Shepherd,
syringes are locked and loaded.
Owen is my patient.
He could be suffering
a complication
from a procedure
that I've already done on him.
Are you seriously considering
leaving this room?
Tom knows the procedure
as well as I do.
Amelia.
Fact.
Meredith, it's Owen.
No,. It cannot be you.
If you were to walk out of here
right now,
we will lose
the FDA approval,
the funding will stop,
and this whole thing
would've been for nothing.
What? Y-You want me
to miss this epic surgery?
The genius who provided you
with the 3-D hydrogel brains?
The needle is locked on target
and motorized injector is ready.
Would it help
if I said please?
Fine.
But you owe me
way more than one.
I want to be paged
the second you finish.
I want to be credited
the second you publish on this.
♪♪
Proceed, Dr. Bartley.
Locking the differential
on the injector.
We're set for
two microliters per minute.
♪♪
Injecting the cells.
How's Owen doing?
Don't know.
Okay. Yeah, we don't have
to...talk about it.
♪ 'Cause you know
I ain't no superstar ♪
I think I'm done.
Yeah,
probably for the best.
You don't want
to...kill anybody.
Done with my marriage.
♪♪
♪ Take a little sunshine
You and Owen went through
a terrifying experience --
the -- the accident and then
Farouk's heart transplant.
I think if --No, that's not it.
It's...
Owen's done something that
I can't even begin to --
I mean, it's not like
he killed people.
Mm.
But let's just pretend
it's that bad.
And I am tired,
and I am angry,
and I don't know how long
I can keep this thing inside.
♪♪
I slept with Link.
And I-I may love him,
because when you have sex
with your best friend
and the intimacy
and generosity
and orgasms
are...earth shattering,
it is very, very hard
to go back.
♪♪
But he  --
he doesn't love me
because he's too busy
loving someone
who doesn't love him back.
Maybe this is what happens
when I don't go to a bar
for a really long time.
♪♪
Hello?
Okay, Owen,
Teddy is on her way.
You called her?
Typically, I inform
a patient's family
of an emergent surgery.
I'm a softie like that.Thanks.
Okay. Hopefully, we're looking
at a simple dural patch
to repair the CSF leak,
won't take long.
And look,
I know I might not be
your first choice
of neurosurgeons,
maybe not even
your, uh, 10th.
It's fine.
Hunt, don't make me cry
before I open you up.
I sob with my whole body.
All of your cerebrospinal fluid
would be gone
before I get myself --Tom.
Alright, see you
on the other side.
♪♪
You're extremely
talented, Wright.
Alright,
but it's creepy, huh?
Look, look,
it's a drawing of masked beings
letting a giant robot drill
metal tubes into a man's head,
injecting him
with an unknown substance.
Well, Meredith's
groundbreaking surgery
looks like the next installment
of the "Alien" franchise.
You like "Alien," too?
Well,
get out if you don't.
It's a sci-fi classic
and one of the best
horror movies ever made.
Thank you. They truly perfected
the jump scare.
Yeah. The -- The -- Ah.
Okay.
Five years ago,
this surgery would've
seemed like
science fiction.
Makes you think
about what's next.
Space.
Right, Chief?
Who's going to space?
No one.
Hit it.
Patient's name?
Arthur Kyat, 21.
End-stage liver disease,
secondary to Primary
Sclerosing Cholangitis.
Patient's getting orthotopic
liver transplant today.
Good.
Donor's name?
James.
His name is James.
You know, I've stood next
to a hundred different doctors
waiting in line
to retrieve organs,
and that's what it is
to a lot of them --
an organ that will help
save theirpatient,
but it's not just an organ,
is it?
It was somebody's life,
somebody's brother,
somebody's child.
It's the greatest gift
a human being can give
to another human being.
And if you want to be
a great transplant surgeon,
can't forget that.
You cannot forget the person
who gave the gifts.
Okay?
We're ready.
Scalpel, please.
♪♪
Setting the robot
for trajectory number three.
♪ M'ama!♪
♪♪
Okay.
You okay?
Yeah, I just --
I need a minute.
♪♪
Have you heard anything
about Owen yet?
No.
You could check on this
later.
'Cause while someone you care
about is in another room
getting surgery right now,
someone I care about has
his brain open in this room.
♪♪
Ready for the third injection
for this side of the brain.
Here we go.
♪♪
Dr. Kassulke to the ER.
Dr. Kurt Kassulke to the ER.
You're here.
People do crazy things
when they're triggered,
or in
a mental-health crisis,
and...
When my phone rang today
and it was Tom...
...I remembered that I made
decisions when I was triggered.
And those decisions
didn't take you
or our family
into consideration.
I remembered how much
you'd forgiven me for.
But...
I don't -- I don't know.
I don't know if I can forgive
you for this, Owen.
But I know
that we have to --
we have to talk.
We have to try.
I'm not triggered, and I'm not
in a mental-health crisis.
I stand by what I did
and how I did it.
♪♪
But I love you, Teddy.
I love you,
and I'm glad you want to talk.
♪♪
♪ I'll wait for you
on 7th Avenue ♪
♪ We'll leave behind
all of the things we knew ♪
So, assuming
normal recovery,
he should be walking around
in a few weeks.
And then at a Wolves game
with me in a month or so.
♪ All of the things we knew
Hey.
♪ Your turn, your move
♪ I followed all the clues
- Thank you.
- Hmm.
♪ Tickets for two
♪ I saved a seat for you
I don't know
how to thank them.
♪♪
♪ I saved a seat for you
How do I thank the people
who lost their son today?
♪ So when lights go down
♪ And we're the only sound
♪ No one will find us now
♪ I get lost with you
All day long,
I've been racking my brain
trying to figure out
who in their right mind
would have left that surgery
the way you were prepared to.
♪♪
♪ The secrets that we keep
And then it dawned
on me --
you are someone who loves
her people so hard and so much
that the second
they're in trouble,
everything else
just...falls away.
♪ And messed up everything
Guilty...as charged.
I've never met
anyone like that.
It's...
Infuriating?
Well...
I was gonna say inspiring.
But yours works, too.
♪ I get lost with you
I can't believe
we did it.
♪ I get lost with you
Believe it.
♪ No one will find us now
♪ I get lost with you
Oh, my God, Link!
Oh, crap!
You scared
the hell out of me!
What are you doing
in here?
Sorry, your water pressure's
so much better,
and I thought you were out,
so I decided to take a shower.
Yeah, I can...
I can see that.
♪ I'll wait for you
on 7th Avenue ♪
♪ We'll leave behind
all of the things we knew ♪
♪ All of the things we knew
♪ So when the lights go down
Sorry.
♪ And we're the only sound
Me, too.
♪ No one will find us now
♪ I get lost with you
How are we gonna do this?
I don't know.
♪ I get lost with you
You want me to move out?
No!
♪ No one will find us now
Maybe.♪ I get lost with you
♪ I get lost with you
Some people don't like
open-world role-playing games
because there's
too many choices,
but the beauty
of the game design
is that...you get to create
your own character.
You get to be
whoever you want to be.
You level up, um, abilities
to be anyone you want to be,
and if you fail,
you get to try again
in a completely
different way.
Y-You can go
somewhere else
or take a different path.
Possibilities are endless.
That beauty's
in medicine, too.
No, well,
th-- think about it.
When you have
foundational knowledge
and skill set,
the possibilities
areendless.
You can choose your specialty
or a form of research,
whether you want to teach --
multiple paths exist
to save lives.
Schmitt, you belong
on one of them.
Come back.
You and I can find
our way together --
a new way.
I appreciate you coming here,
Dr. Webber,
trying to salvage my career,
rescue me.
But you're too late.
I've already bled out.
There's nothing left
to save.
♪♪
I'm gonna, um, lay down.
You can play if you want.
When people hear our names,
what will they remember?
♪ Would you meet me
in the middle... ♪
♪ ...if I gave you
all my time? ♪
What did we leave behind?
♪♪
♪ We could try
to make it simple ♪
♪ But we'd probably
lose our minds ♪
So?
When does it start?
Uh, when does what start?
The flight surgeon
training.
You got to get
board certified
in aerospace medicine first,
right?
Please tell me you said yes
to your friend.
Of course I did not.
Oh, Chief Bailey,
he called you!
You can't say no.
What if...
W-What if --
hear me out.
What if
you're the Chosen One,
the only one
in the galaxy
who can take the job
and restore it to order?
I prefer to think of myself
as Rey.
And Rey isthe Chosen One,
after Luke's fall.
Disagree.
Okay, that was --
hey, that was
a faulty prophecy.
Mm.
But, Chief,
you said it yourself.
It's a dream of yours
to work for NASA.
I'm not in a place to be making
decisions based on dreams.
♪ Oh, there's nothing left
to lose ♪
You have no idea.
Only bright spot around here
lately has been you.
♪ And I passed out
on your lawn ♪
I'm...sor--
Oh, whoa.
I must've misread
the situation.
Uh...good night, Doc--
Chief Bailey.
Goodnight, Chief Bailey.
Did we blaze trails?
Did we guide
a new generation?
Did we bestow
all the wisdom we could?
♪ And I,
I don't think I want to ♪
Have we paved a legacy?
♪♪
♪ And I
Oh, my Lord.
Hi!
Surprise.
Feel like
I'm still dreaming here.
How are you?
I'm good. How are you?
Good.
I just thought
I would come and give you
the surgery update
in person.
You pulled it off,
didn't you?
We did.
I never had a doubt
in my mind.
There was just
one small hiccup, though.
Oh, yeah? What's that?
That the only person
I wanted to celebrate with
lives 1,500 miles away.
Oh, what a jerk.
Seriously.
Maybe instead of wanting
to be known
for what we've done...
But wait.
Y-You were dreaming
about me?
No! I --
You said you were.
No, I knew I shouldn't have
told you that.
Come in.Okay.
...let's be known
for who we are.
♪♪