Previously on ER:
You can't let this happen, Tony.
No. Come on, Mom.
You gotta wake up.
What they got you for?
I helped some people get
some medications they needed.
Thanks for bailing me out, I'll make
sure you get your money right back...
Greg. I told you to shut it
down. Why didn't you do that?
Oh, my God.
I got a little boy and a
man with extensive burns.
- It started downstairs.
- In my apartment.
I want you to put your
hand in that vice there.
I want you to feel that.
Plenty more where
that came from.
There we go. Here.
Come on. Come on, eat.
I've been slaving over a hot
griddle all morning for you.
Please, at least try. Okay?
There you go. Hold your fork.
- Satisfied?
- No, I'm not.
I'm not gonna be
satisfied until I hear:
"Wow, I can't believe you made
me your world-famous pancakes."
Wow, Tony, I can't believe you
made me your world-famous pancakes.
Okay, here's your
lunch. It's time to go.
Are kids gonna act
weird to me today?
No.
I don't wanna talk about Mom.
You don't have to.
Are you sending me to live
with Grandma and Grandpa?
Why do you ask that?
Isn't that what you were
talking about at the funeral?
We were talking about a
lot of things at the funeral.
I don't wanna live with them.
I wanna stay here with you
and your crummy pancakes.
Come on.
- Bye.
X-rays show your
lungs are improving.
Oh, good.
I need to inhale.
Well, if your oxygen level stays
up, you can go home in a few hours.
Tell Timmy. He's been
worried sick about me.
So has Alex.
How is he?
He's, uh...
He's been acting weird.
You think he did it, don't you?
I know I blew out those candles.
I don't believe it.
He's a good boy.
You know, he's stealing
Dr. Morris' credit card...
he's disrespecting you.
I don't know what to think.
If he did do it, I'm sure
it wasn't on purpose.
Do you think Alex started
that fire by accident?
I think you should continue to
take him to that therapist lady.
As far as the police go,
they think it was a candle.
Let it go at that.
Well, I'm glad to
hear he's doing okay.
Yeah, he just needed a
little time for the hand to heal.
Look what we have here.
Not one, but two late doctors.
- Blue Line was stuck.
- Some bozo jumped in front of the train.
- Where's your main man?
- Um...
- He's gonna take one more day.
- No problem, got it covered.
Cover this. Some suit
came from upstairs...
and said to give that to
whoever's running the floor.
- Damn.
Where's Pratt?
You suck balls.
Hold still, ma'am.
Hold still yourself, bitch.
Can we give benzos IM?
- That'll take a half an hour to work.
- Okay.
All right, I got access. What
do you want? Four Ativan?
- Ativan?
- Haldol, what?
You're ruining my
high, you retard.
Pratt, we need to talk.
I'm a little busy here, Morris.
- Give me midazolam. Faster onset.
- Okay.
- Knock her down in a minute.
- Can we step outside?
Sure. Soon as she settles down.
- Settle on this.
- Watch out.
I'm really sorry,
but I have to ask...
You're gonna
have to wait, please.
- One minute.
- Let go.
Pratt. HEATHER: Scum.
- Pratt.
- What?
The Medical Board
suspended your license.
Hey, can we talk?
Yeah, sure, what
can I do for you?
I was Pratt's accomplice.
- Excuse me?
- I helped him at the clinic.
- What?
- I know, I know.
It seemed like the right
thing to do at the time.
I can't believe this.
Look, I told Pratt that he
didn't have to protect me...
but he wants me
to stay out of it.
Well, you listen to Pratt.
- I'm gonna burn in hell, aren't I?
- No.
I mean, you might have
some explaining to do.
Hey, I'm sorry about this, man.
Thought I could work half
a shift before the hearing.
It's just a formality.
They'll reinstate you.
GI bleeds from NSAIDs
happen to thousands every year.
Morris, Abby's asking for
you. Her guy in 1 is throwing up.
Be strong, brother.
Fight the power.
- Liter wide open?
- Yeah.
And 10 of Reglan. Okay.
- Does it hurt here?
- Aah.
No, but if you tug on willy, I'll
sing Dionne Warwick's greatest hits.
Tempting, but no, thanks.
No, really, I... Aah. I thought
that's why you put the gloves on.
Seriously, I have
a latex fetish.
I even tried to give myself a
Brazilian using rubber cement once.
Didn't work, but I got into Hustler
as one of those guys who has three...
- All right, I get it.
- Ever had food poisoning?
I puked once after biting into
a Red Hot with stretch marks.
Okay, uh, we have to run some
tests to rule out anything serious...
like appendicitis, but after that,
hopefully, we can discharge you.
- What's up with this guy?
- Vomiting, low fever, exam is equivocal.
Doc, doc, you gotta
get me out of here, man.
I got a hot date tonight.
Does, uh, she take
air or helium? Ha-ha.
She takes Visa. That was funny.
- Can I use it?
- Sure.
Do you want me
to image the belly?
Hydrate him. He may spiff up.
Uh... Four of
morphine, antiemetics.
We'll get you out
of here, just sit tight.
Okay, you're about
to meet the Grassos.
She's been on
dialysis since 2002.
He's got a kidney,
but they don't match.
Our exchange pool paired
them up with two cousins...
who are in the same situation.
Yup. Kidneys for everyone.
Hi.
You guys set?
You bet.
No more dialysis, no
more infected shunts.
This is Dr. Rasgotra.
- She'll be assisting on the transplant.
- I am?
Well, someone's about to
get some A-1 kidney meat.
I'm like a racehorse.
- I could drink a six-pack without peeing.
- Honey, gross.
Micturation capacity is related to
bladder size and neural sensitivity...
not renal function.
- Then we'll give them some bladder too.
- Ha-ha.
Okay, I'll see what I can do.
You guys have any questions?
Concerns? No?
Okay. I'll see you in the O.R.
Our goal is to enroll
200 donor-recipient pairs.
By mixing and matching, we'd find
kidneys for almost 50 percent of them.
I'll introduce you to
the Herrero cousins.
Marina's getting a kidney from one cousin
and Thomas is giving his to the other.
- Yep, kind of like a kidney key party.
- Key party?
Except donors and recipients aren't
allowed to meet. That could get messy.
It's the ER. I'll
catch up to you.
What's a key party?
Oh, it's a little gimmick to help
swinging couples pick their partners.
Forget it. Before your time.
It sounds dirty.
- Ow!
- Okay, Jessie, come on. Hold still.
If he's got lice,
you're cutting his hair.
I'm a doctor, not Vidal Sassoon.
Abby, I need you. Funny
boy keeps throwing up.
Okay, Ray. You got this, right?
Hey, no, no, no.
Don't leave me here.
- Did you give him the Reglan?
- An hour ago.
Okay, it's probably
just gastroenteritis.
And if your labs are
okay, we'll get you home.
Forget home. I
got a gig at 10:15.
The big room at Zanies.
I've been trying to get in
there for a couple of years.
You're a comedian?
Aspiring.
You should aspire
a little harder.
Oh, a heckler.
Don't make me go
Kramer on your ass. Aah!
Hey, blondie, no
need to get violent.
Four of Zofran. Repeat p.r.n.
Jeez. May I?
Lay down, Simon.
Oh, my gosh.
I gotta practice my routine,
I gotta change my clothes.
I was gonna wear this shirt, but
now I got chow mein all over it.
- We're trying to get you better.
- Oof.
How long you been doing standup?
Moved out here from
Detroit a couple of years ago.
- Very courageous.
- Yeah, my old boss pushed me into it.
Because you were funny at work?
No.
Because he fired me twice.
Hated my guts.
My dad also had
a lot to do with it.
He hated you too?
No.
He died.
Life took on a whole
new perspective.
I'm gonna call the lab and
see what's taking so long.
Just relax.
I will try to relax.
I will.
We spent four weeks
e-mailing each other.
We finally meet and he
sticks me with the bill?
So you chased after him
and you fell into a hydrant?
Would've caught him
had I been wearing flats.
All right, breath sounds
are perfect. Lay back.
So what if I told him I
looked like Cindy Crawford?
- He said he looked like Matt Damon.
- Did he?
More like Matt
Damon's fat uncle's ass.
Pulse ox, 98 on room air.
- Tell me if this hurts.
- Aah! Yeah.
All right, you
have a broken rib.
I'm gonna give you something
for the pain and take an x-ray.
Percocet, CBC
and two-view chest.
- Hey.
- So you out of here, man?
Yeah, guess so.
Well, hopefully, it
will just be temporary.
Yeah, that will
be too bad for you.
- Good luck, Dr. Pratt.
- Thanks, Timmy.
- Dr. Pratt.
- Yeah?
You're gonna be okay.
God is on your side.
Yeah, well, let's hope so.
Okay, I could go with
you. I just did the overnight.
- I'm almost off.
- Hope, go home.
Get some sleep, okay?
Dr. Pratt?
What are you doing here?
Uh...
I'm going with you to your
Medical Board hearing.
No, I'm okay, really. Please.
Hope, come pull the
PICC line for the guy in 2.
Okay, I gotta take this.
What about it, Greg? The
church's support couldn't hurt.
You're still operating the
clinic that got me in this mess.
Look, I'm just trying to
better the community.
Yeah? What are you doing
about black-male incarceration?
I have a sermon on it next week.
Make sure you tell them
how you got me there.
Greg, I just wanna help.
My license is suspended,
I'm facing jail time.
I think you've helped enough.
So how did it go
with the counselor?
It wasn't what I expected,
but nothing in my life ever is.
What did she say?
She, uh, wants
me to enroll Alex...
in an academy for at-risk youth,
which is code word for nutjobs.
My kid is not a nutjob. He's
just going through some stuff.
Well, maybe it's some
stuff that he can't handle.
I know about those places.
They starve them and beat them.
I can't send him there.
I could help you check some out,
see if there's any that might be okay.
Thank you.
But I, uh, need to do it alone.
I'm sorry that I dragged you
into everything in the first place.
Don't worry about it, Sam.
I rea...
I really like you...
but I have to focus
on Alex right now...
and I don't have time for
any kind of a relationship.
All right.
I get it.
- You do?
- I do.
Your kid comes first.
So take as much
time as you need.
Is there any discomfort here?
No.
Do you have a boyfriend?
Uh...
- Not exactly. We're still defining it.
- Mm.
A girl like you doesn't
need the Internet.
I haven't had a valentine since
Jimmy Bachner in sixth grade. Ouch!
She's into S & M. If you want
her to stop, say "mayday."
It's the safe word.
Mayday. Mayday.
There's no right upper-quadrant
tenderness, liver is fine.
Let's observe
her for two hours...
check another CBC
and follow serial exams.
Hey, wait up.
You okay?
Yeah. You?
Yeah, came home from
Wisconsin yesterday.
How is Sarah holding up?
It's not gonna be easy.
I can imagine.
- Listen, I should've called.
- Look...
- I'm sorry.
- No, I should've called.
- The funeral was awkward, the relatives...
- It's okay.
- No, Neela.
- No, I'm fine.
I'm sure you've got
a lot on your plate.
I mean, you've probably got
two plates and a little saucer.
Yeah, a heart-shaped saucer.
Valentine's Day, Wednesday.
Let's have a quiet dinner, huh?
- Yeah, we'll see.
- Hey, guys.
I've got surgery.
Neela?
Is she all right?
I don't know.
What about you?
Lockhart, your comic's CBC
is back, and it ain't funny.
White blood count 32,000
with 60 percent blasts.
He has leukemia?
With immature white cells,
he's anemic, neutropenic.
Oh, great.
Did you see the AMJ's
article on integrative medicine?
You know the world
is falling apart...
when a study on Reiki
makes it into the journal. Ha-ha.
It's sexy, but the
Dana wouldn't touch it.
The design is totally flawed.
- Excuse me.
- Hi.
Hey.
Are you Dr. Williams
from Evanston?
Uh, no, I'm Dr. Pratt
from County.
Take a seat.
I've isolated the artery.
All right, Neela, clip it.
- You're letting her?
She knows what she's doing.
What are the pertinent
anatomical relationships?
Anterior to posterior, it
goes renal pelvis, renal vein...
and then artery, which is clipped.
- Good.
Any third-year medical
student could've answered that.
What structures
make up the cortex?
The what?
Cortex. It's that bean-shaped
thing you're cutting into.
You mean, like, the proximal
tubules and the distal tubules?
And renal corpuscles. Medulla?
- Loop of Henle and...
- Mm-hm.
Your valentine needs
a surgical consult.
My valentine? Gates?
Oh, young love is so sweet.
He's not smart enough for you.
- You don't even know him.
- Come on, Gates is easy math.
Okay, that's enough.
Artery is ligated.
Dr. Dubenko, the donor kidney
is prepped and ready to go.
Excellent timing.
Have them send it in.
How did Mr. Herrero do?
No complications, minimal
blood loss. They're closing now.
That's great.
Hey, hey, hey, where you going?
Where you going?
Is that where you
do the anal probe?
Sam, can you grab the Zosyn?
I liked the other room.
No need for an upgrade.
- Three-point-three-seven-five?
- Yeah.
- Simon.
I need to talk to you
about something important.
I can feel it too.
I wasn't gonna say anything,
but I do feel the sparks. Ha-ha.
Your blood tests show
that you have leukemia.
Thank God.
I thought you were
gonna tell me I had cancer.
Leukemia is cancer of the white
blood cells in the bone marrow.
That's great.
So give me Viagra, send
me home and we are all good.
This isn't funny.
- I know.
- You're gonna need IV antibiotics.
I know, I know, I know.
I got leukemia about a year ago.
I had induction chemo and
a bone-marrow transplant...
and now a year later, it's back.
Why can't cancer be like herpes?
I got that once and
it never came back.
Herpes doesn't go away.
This is Zanies, doc.
You jam there, you get
invited to Second City, to SNL.
You could get a
spot on Letterman.
You know, my dad, he
put hubcaps on Buicks.
Buicks.
Before he died, the
last thing he told me was:
"Don't be another auto worker wishing
you could've, would've, should've.
Don't be like me, son."
- I have to get you started on antibiotics.
- Hey, hey.
I go on at 10:15. At
10:35, I'm all yours.
There's not gonna be a
show tonight. I'm sorry.
If you wanna make
it to next month...
I have to get a CT, a surgical
consult, and check on chemo.
Sorry.
Hey, Timmy, can you call GI
and order an EGD report for me?
No problem.
Hey, you got time for coffee?
Yeah. Everything good?
Yes. I just had the coolest
surgery and I figured we could talk.
Sure.
- Dr. Kovac?
- Hello.
I thought you weren't coming.
I heard you were short
Attendings and I got bored.
You okay? You look good.
- You good?
- Yeah.
What are you doing here?
I talked to Timmy and he said
you guys could use some help.
Um, Neela, can you look at this?
My patient Simon's CT is back.
Gates, some school
principal's on the phone for you.
Appendicitis?
Hello.
She's crying?
No, I understand. I understand.
Let me talk to her, please.
Look at his cecum. There's
wall thickening and distension.
Hey.
No, I told you you didn't
have to go to school.
I'll get you. Let me
talk to the principal.
Hello?
It's typhlitis.
Immuno-compromised
hosts can get a cecal infection.
- Yeah.
- Surgery?
Treat with IV antibiotics
unless he perforates.
And then, would you operate?
Well, normally.
Given his leukemia, I
doubt he'd survive, so...
So?
No, no. Thank you for calling.
So nothing. No surgery for him.
Okay. Thanks.
I'm sorry. Sarah's
having trouble at school.
- Gotta pick her up. I'll call you later?
- Okay.
Um... I'm gonna go and grab a
coffee. Do you want anything?
Yeah, I'll tag along.
These people don't have
insurance, can't afford a doctor.
Some can't even buy medicine.
That's not the point.
I thought, with some guidance,
the clinic could be a good thing.
Why not send them
to County Hospital?
Have you ever been to County?
Trained there 20 years ago.
Well, nowadays, we're
filled with critical patients.
People come in for a prescription
refill, they wait up to 12 hours.
So this was about convenience?
This was about helping people.
There are programs for that.
Yeah, you're right. If you're over
65 or you have dependent kids.
Regular folks with low-paying
jobs, they don't qualify.
This clinic took care of those
who fell through the cracks.
Four O.R.s, four patients, four kidneys,
all being worked on at the same time.
Went like clockwork. We
were this fine-tuned machine.
I mean, this morning, two
people were wasting away...
waiting for a kidney they
thought would never come.
Now they're upstairs with their
donors, eating Jell-O, done with dialysis.
- It's amazing, right?
- It's pretty cool.
This is what it's all about, man.
This is why I became a surgeon.
- Hey, Ray, you wanna give us a hand?
- I need to take this, okay?
I thought, "What's a
14-year-old doing with strokes?"
I figured there's gotta be more to the
story, so I went back to the parents...
and, yes, kid's adopted.
- And?
- Undiagnosed sickle beta thal.
- Kid didn't get screened at birth.
- Wow.
- Nice pickup.
- Thank you.
Oliver Miles, burned his hands trying to
cremate his dead cat in the microwave.
I tried the fireplace,
but I couldn't get it lit.
Partial thickness to
the hands and forearms.
Tachy at 120. BP, 130/78.
Pulse ox, only 91.
Okay, let's start him on
five of albuterol by neb.
So I thought a crematorium
is just a big oven, right?
Another four of IV morphine.
I don't know what he ate last.
It was like he just exploded.
Oh!
I got it. I got it.
Do you know if
someone has my cat?
ABG with carboxyhemoglobin level,
portable chest and 125 of Solu-Medrol.
No problem. Trauma 2.
I'll be there in a second.
- Are you okay?
- I'm fine, Morris.
Your hand is not.
No, this was just an accident.
Go home. Rest.
- I promise we'll be okay.
- Yoo-hoo. Ha-ha-ha.
Hey, Luka. I didn't
know you were back.
I'm not.
- How are you doing?
- Better now.
Take care, Gracie.
Sure you don't
wanna wait till I get off?
I don't really feel like
sending you home by yourself.
I'm not going home, Sammy.
I'm taking a little cruise. This
way, you and Alex can bond.
We can bond with you here.
You need time to
sort through all this.
Oh, God, Grandma.
All I ever wanted to
do was raise a good kid.
He got the crazy gene.
Oh, thank God, it skips a generation.
You and I were both spared.
- You think?
- Ha-ha-ha.
It's gonna be all right, Sammy.
He's going through a phase.
It's rebellion, and then
he'll come back around.
The good ones always do.
Yeah, well, what if
he's not a good one?
He's yours, isn't he?
You're going with Timmy?
The lido deck awaits.
Only old people
take cruises alone.
Hey, Abby.
Which one do you like better:
"Thank you, folks. It
was great to be here"...
or just, "That's all, folks. Now
go home and beat the kids"?
You have an infection in the cecum where
the small and large intestines join up.
Maybe I'll just say:
"Go home and beat the kids,
but don't forget to tip the wait staff."
Listen, did you hear me?
What I said to you earlier?
Yeah, yeah, yeah. I feel better.
I just need you to buff me up.
Well, I can't, because you
have no immune system.
- You cannot fight this infection.
- I don't need my immune system tonight.
I need my funny bone.
I spoke to your oncologist.
You're out of treatment options.
You have a poor prognostic karyotype.
- Eleven-Q-23 translocation.
- Exactly.
And because leukemia's
recurred twice...
you don't have any
options for chemotherapy.
Okay, okay.
Okay, so just put
me in some trial.
Make me a guinea pig.
I've always wanted to run on a
wheel, drink from a drip bottle.
There isn't any trial.
And it's probably a matter
of weeks, not months.
Is there anyone
you want me to call?
Yeah.
- A cab.
- What are you doing?
- I'm getting the hell out of here.
- Look, you can't, Simon, you can't.
What do I have to lose, huh?
I don't wanna walk on the
moon or bang Barbara Bush.
Look...
I wanna get on that stage
and make an audience laugh.
- You can't go.
- I have to go.
Have you ever wanted to do something
that just scared the hell out of you...
but you knew you had to do it?
Well, this is it for me.
All right.
Maybe a blood transfusion will give
you some more energy. Come on.
I just need to be
able to stand up.
Or sit down.
Maybe I could be
a sit-down standup.
All right.
I'm gonna have to have you
sign out against medical advice.
If I just took
anyone's advice...
I'd still be checking
taillights in Detroit now.
And if anybody asks,
this is not my idea.
Shh...
How do you keep
track of your patients?
I used 5-by-7 cards
for patient information.
And you have a complete
H & P on a 5-by-7 card?
Well, we had limited records,
just the important information.
Where did you keep them?
- In a box.
- A box?
And if your patients had
medical care other places...
was there a system for other health
professionals to access this box?
No. But they could
have paged me, I guess.
Would you say your records system met
the standards the Medical Board has set?
Come on. We were in a church.
And did you log the drugs you
dispensed? Did you record the lot numbers?
- No, not fully.
- Not at all, isn't that right?
Are you aware that this is a violation
of the Medical Practice Act, Dr. Pratt?
I never claimed that this was
a full-service medical center.
I didn't charge any money. I
was trying to help these people.
And do you think you helped Edgar
Dixon when you prescribed him Renuvium?
GI bleeding is a common
side effect of NSAIDs.
The same thing could've happened to him
if he'd been prescribed the med anywhere.
But it didn't happen to him anywhere.
He went to you, and it killed him.
Are you aware that diversion of
narcotics is a felony, Dr. Pratt?
I didn't steal...
You don't recall providing hydrocodone
and ibuprofen to Ms. Nancy Campbell?
Mrs. Campbell had gallstones.
So you took a narcotic medication sample
logged into the Emergency Department.
This is a felony punishable
by imprisonment, doctor.
Yes, she was suffering.
I wanted to help her.
I volunteer for a free clinic
myself and we follow the rules.
We keep accurate records...
we dispense medication with
proper safety precautions...
and we're there for
our patients, Dr. Pratt.
You remember the part
about doing no harm?
Well, that applies
to you too, sir.
- Excuse me, I'm sorry.
- We're in a meeting.
I'm Pastor William Watkins
of First Mission Baptist.
I'd like to speak on
behalf of Dr. Pratt.
Sorry they haven't taken
you back to your room yet.
I just got a new kidney.
- I'm not gonna sweat the small stuff.
- Oh.
Hello.
Happy Valentine's Day.
Nothing says "I love
you" like a bag of urine.
How did my donor do?
They're fine.
But because of everybody's privacy,
we're not really allowed to discuss it.
Listen, this person
saved my life.
I wanna see him.
Or her. Just once.
So I have a face to
think of in my prayers.
How is it going?
Okay, so the Democrats took
over the House and the Senate.
How long before the Republicans
jack up the rent and evict them?
- That's pretty funny.
- Why aren't you laughing, then?
- I am.
- No, you're not.
HemoCue is up to
11 after two units.
Antibiotics?
- Zosyn is in, tobra's infusing.
- Oh...
I gotta go pee-pee.
- That's good. Your kidneys are working.
- Aah.
Hello? Hello?
Quiet on the set.
Thank you very much.
Doc, I can't pee in bed.
I've been standing
up since I was 4.
Pressure's been
pretty good, 101/68.
All right, get him a screen.
- Sit up and dangle your legs.
- All right.
- Let us know if you're feeling dizzy.
- I'm good. I'm good.
I got a little flop sweat, but
that happens to the best of them.
- Someone's gotta go with you.
- No.
I got a nervous bladder
and a neurotic sphincter.
Seriously, it sucks.
I can't pee in public and I'm
afraid to fart in case I start a fire.
We'll wait on the other side.
It'll be a good test.
Of what?
The Emergency
Broadcast System. Oh...
That is good.
Man, this will work.
Pee is funny.
Bedpans, funny.
Catheter, not so funny.
Maybe we can downgrade
to Tele from ICU.
- Oh, God.
- Okay, I got him.
Get him on the bed.
Come on. One, two, three.
- Pressure's down, 60/40.
- Great, he's septic.
- Another two units of packed cells.
- Start dopamine at 10 mics.
- Simon, can you hear me?
- Open your eyes, come on.
- Hear me?
- Sats are dropping.
Put him on 100
percent non-rebreather.
Open an intubation
kit. Come on, buddy.
Come on, there's a spotlight on the
curtains and they're calling your name.
Hey, baby girl.
Dopamine at 12 mics.
Systolic's up to 110.
Good. Run in the fourth unit.
Hey, am I on next?
How is it going?
- What happened?
- You took a little nap.
Okay, little prick.
It's just because
it's cold in here.
All right, you gotta
keep that on, okay?
You know, sats are
a hundred... Hey.
Why don't we try a
nasal cannula? Five liters.
Hey, Abby, how about our deal?
Working on it.
What deal?
I thought we could try to buff
him up so he could perform tonight.
He's septic.
His BP's dropped so low, he
needs continuous IV pressors.
What does that mean?
- It means you're not going anywhere.
- Can we talk outside? Please?
You realize you are asking me to break the
most central rule of this entire program?
It's a dumb rule.
Why is this so important to you?
Because it's important to her.
Part of him is gonna be part
of me for the rest of my life.
Oh, come on, Manish.
- Okay, fine. If Dubenko finds out...
- Dr. Rasgotra, what are you doing?
We're just waiting on some labs.
What? Doesn't even make sense.
Couldn't you do better
than "waiting on labs"?
I'm not a doctor.
Can I talk to you for a minute?
- I know we're not supposed to do this...
- Yeah.
But this guy saved her life. She wanted
to be able to see him in her prayers.
- Yeah, Nee...
- Dr. Crenshaw...
Dusty, I mean.
I know it's unethical,
but it's nice...
and sometimes people like to do
things for other people, just to be nice.
Neela, have I mentioned how
well you're coming along? Yeah.
Okay, we're good.
Okay. They're right over here.
Which one is he?
He's the one on the left.
Your husband's kidney
went into the other guy.
Thank you.
You know, Morris, it's
his dream. He's gonna die.
He's gonna do it here, not
on some comedy-club floor.
Blood count's okay.
He's had antibiotics.
- His pressure's dopamine dependent.
- What about intermittent pressors?
- There isn't one.
- Epinephrine?
- He can't leave here.
- I could give him six EpiPens.
- Point-three mgs each. Gives himself...
- Are you out of your mind?
- Why not try it?
- No. I'm not doing it.
I'll find another Attending.
- I'm running the floor.
- Then get some balls.
- I've got balls.
- They're no good unless you use them.
Fine.
Fine, you wanna
play Superdoc? Great.
Turn off the dopamine, give him epi, show
me his pressure can stay for 20 minutes.
- Fine.
Nobody builds hospitals
or clinics in the inner city...
because they know these
people don't have any money.
They're leeches on the system.
So they go out to the burbs...
and put up medical facilities
on every corner like Starbucks...
leaving us with a hospital that's
overrun, understaffed and underpaid.
There are free clinics.
Most think they're for
people with drug problems...
and sexually
transmitted diseases.
We're talking about
regular folk here...
black and brown people
who just need prescriptions.
Dr. Pratt knew the system was
flawed and tried to help mend it.
I've got a whole congregation who will
attest taking away this man's license...
would just be another demerit on a
system that has already failed them.
The EpiPen is spring-loaded...
so all you have to do is press it
against your thigh and it fires off a shot.
Ah. Sounds like my
high school years.
Can I use it during my act?
As long as you pull
your pants down.
Luckily, that's my big finish.
Or should I say my
average-size finish?
- Oh! All right.
- His pressure dropped again.
- How long since his last epi?
- Six minutes.
Push 0.2, start dopamine,
mix up Levophed.
- Damn.
- This was a dumb idea.
Epi has a one-minute half-life.
I have a body part
with that same problem.
Ha-ha. That was a good joke.
BP, 89/64.
You know what the best
thing about getting leukemia is?
Hang another liter of saline
and a unit of packed cells.
Everybody comes to see you.
The guys from the plant came,
my ex-soccer coach came.
Even Father Dunleavy came.
Took three orderlies to get
him out of the Pedes ward.
That's a keeper.
You know, I was
gonna kill tonight...
and instead, I'm dying.
Sats are dropping,
92 on five liters.
I would've left your
name at the door...
but something tells me
I'm not gonna make it.
Finish your act.
- Hey.
- Hey, I, uh, bought you some food.
Thank you. That's sweet.
- Come on in.
- Thank you.
- Sorry I couldn't talk earlier.
- Oh, it's okay, forget it.
Everything all right?
Yeah, I just, uh,
came by to say hi.
Hi.
Uh... Is Sarah okay?
We're just sitting down to
watch a movie. Wanna join us?
Uh... No. I'm not gonna stay.
Listen, can I talk
to you a second?
Yeah.
I've been wanting
to tell you this.
You remember the night we
were out there with Meg in the car?
At one point...
she grabbed me and
pulled me down to her...
and she said, "Tony,
Sarah is yours."
"Sarah is yours."
Is it possible?
It was 13 years ago.
You know, we were messed
up, the three of us, high.
Keith would disappear for
days and, you know, Meg and I...
It just happened.
It wasn't a secret.
So you mean she
could be your...?
And that never
occurred to you before?
Yeah. I mean, I thought about it
at first, but then years went by...
and I just believed what
everyone else believed.
- Tony?
- That she was Keith's.
I should go.
That's who I used to be.
It's not who I am anymore.
No, it's okay. It's no big deal.
Go watch your movie.
You know you
didn't have to do this.
Well, you know, that whole
black-male incarceration bit got to me.
You'll be okay, Greg.
There are laws in this
world that we have to follow...
but then there are God's laws.
He'll have the last word
in this. Just you watch.
- Hey.
- What are you doing here?
- You covered for me.
The least I can
do is support you.
All right, come on, sit down.
Dr. Pratt.
The board finds that you have
violated the Medical Practice Act...
and believes that these transgressions
are adequate justification...
to suspend your medical license.
However, in light of your
attempt to help your community...
we have decided to put
you on probation for one year.
Practice will be monitored...
you will need to perform 100
hours of community service.
Perhaps finding a way to legalize
a certain church-based clinic...
would be a good
use of your time?
Thank you.
Thank you. Thank you so much.
Dr. Pratt.
Hey, how did I do?
You brought the house down.
Thank you.
You've been such
a great audience.
- Hey, you.
- Hey.
I decided to put
our CDs on the iPod.
- We don't need all these anymore.
- I need to talk.
- Is everything okay?
- Um...
You know, when you were on the roof,
I was thinking about what I would do...
if Joe didn't have a father
and if we didn't have each other.
I realized if we could get through this,
we could probably get through anything.
What's going on?
I mean, have you ever
wanted something so much...
but it scared the
hell out of you?
See, here's the thing. I just...
Well, I changed my mind...
and I was wondering if
you could ask me again.
What?
Ask me again.
Ask me to marry you.