Hey, Carol?
Hmm?
Carol, I got an idea.
Two more minutes.
It's beautiful out.
Let's call in sick.
Take a day trip somewhere.
A trip?
Yeah. We'll... We'll play hooky.
We'll just jump in the car,
and we'll head North
and find a lake
and just sit there.
Mm...
I can't skip work.
I need the hours.
Please?
The thought of
having to cart around
the wretched of the
Earth all day long
with Reilly yapping in my ear
about his stupid
beer can collection.
I can't. Not today.
Oh... You go. You go.
I don't want to go without you.
I mean, that's the whole idea.
I want us to get away together.
We'll just go someplace
where there aren't
any sick people, and...
just... just cows.
Healthy cows.
Good cows.
Someplace where
we can, you know,
make love in the grass.
In front of the cows?
Sexy cows.
We could take a
trip this weekend.
Yeah?
Sure.
Well... I might be persuaded
to be a little late for work.
Next.
I repacked Mr. Otto's abscess.
Is it granulating?
Quite nicely, thank you.
Give Mr. Otto my
best. What else?
Mrs. Mendoza in 2.
She's had two days
of vomiting, diarrhea,
and periumbilical pain.
Her vitals? Normal.
The onset began after
dinner in Mexico City.
She and her husband
came straight in
from the airport.
White count?
12,000. No rebound or guarding.
Well, it sounds like
Montezuma's Revenge.
Give her Loperamide
and start her on
a clear liquid diet.
Do you want to see her?
No, you can, uh, send her home.
Peter...
You won't be scrubbing in
on Dr. Heizenbach's jejunostomy
this morning.
Why not?
He won't work with you.
The word's out
about your difficulty
with Doug Ross.
It's spread to
the surgical floor.
The prevailing view is that
you betrayed a colleague.
Is that what you think?
I think maybe you're
in for a chilly summer.
We still on for tonight?
If you'd tell me
where we're going.
No, it's a surprise.
Well, how am I going
to know what to wear?
Dress nice.
Ah, Carter...
you've got a call
confirming your reservations
for the Moonlight Dinner
Cruise on Lake Michigan.
Thanks, Jerry.
Ah, sounds romantic.
Oh, remind me to bring
my seasickness pills.
Harper!
Dale!
I've been looking for you, kid.
What are you doing here?
Trauma Sub-I until June,
then I start my Residency.
You matched here?
I did.
In medicine? Surgery.
John Carter.
He matched in surgery here too.
Dale and I went
to college together.
Ah, and you're coming from...
Boston.
Meaning... Harvard?
Go, Crimson.
So the last time
you e-mailed me,
you were about to take out
your first appendix.
That's right.
You took out an appendix?
Yeah. They let us
do appys, lipomas,
pilonidal cysts...
All that small stuff.
God, it's great to see you.
You too.
I don't know, Doug.
You, me, Inga, Hulda,
and a Chinese restaurant.
What's not to know?
Inga's not really my type.
That's what you said
about Kathy Snyder.
Yeah, well, I am
going to get out there,
just at my own pace...
Word to the wise...
Prostates don't last forever.
Hey, Dr. Greene,
does this loan
application belong to you?
It's mine.
Buying a car?
No, you know that
kid I misdiagnosed?
I'm helping out with
his cancer treatment.
Hey, Mark, I have to bail
on M and M's this afternoon.
Can you change the meeting?
No, and I don't
have a lawyer yet.
Do what you have to do.
Thanks. I'm on till 2:00.
What's that?
She's meeting with a judge.
Chloe wants visitation rights.
God bless the child.
Good morning, guys.
Oh, I'm sorry I'm late.
Traffic was a bitch.
Hey...
Peter...
Let me just clear
this out the way...
Mrs. Garvey, I understand
you're having chest pains...
Where the hell have you been?
And irritability.
I've waited so long, the
pains have gone away.
She just got here.
I'm burning with fever.
The temp's normal.
Oh, sure, after sitting in
your drafty waiting room.
Your pain's gone?
Oh. It's coming back.
Okay, let's get that EKG.
What's that?
It monitors the electrical
activity of your heart.
How?
The leads carry impulses
from your heart to the monitor
where we can read them.
I don't understand.
Explain it again.
We just want to make
sure that you're okay.
Don't patronize me.
You doctors are all the same.
I came in here for stitches.
I had to come back five times,
and my leg's never
been the same.
This place is filthy!
Mrs. Garvey, your
EKG is abnormal.
We're going to have
to draw some blood.
Why?
To check your cardiac enzymes.
What are those?
Elements in your blood
that'll tell us if you've
had a heart attack.
I don't understand.
Explain it again!
I may be the only
fourth year in the country
who hasn't done an
appendectomy yet.
Uh, I doubt it.
I'm about to start my Residency,
and I'm three steps
behind the curve.
GSW to the chest coming in.
ETA two minutes.
Let me run the code.
Carter...
No, I'm ready, and I
need the experience.
All right, everybody, listen up!
Carter's going to run the code.
All right, everybody. Gown up!
What do you want
us to do, Carter?
Uh... Malik, you start the IVs.
We have IVs from the field.
Scratch that. Malik, you scribe.
Man, I don't wanna scribe.
Do it.
Okay, A... Airway.
Dr. Greene will intubate.
B... Breathing.
Haleh, call Respiratory.
Tell them to get
their ass down here.
Chuny, you set up the Dynamap.
Aye, aye.
C... Circulation. You!
On the rapid infuser.
D... Disability. Benton!
Dr. Benton.
Check the DTRs and
the Babinski, if that's okay.
All right. What's left?
Foley.
All right. Who wants to
hook up the Foley cath?
You're the only one left.
What's coming in?
Gunshot wound.
Dale! Hook up the Foley cath,
and Harper, just
jump in as needed.
They're here.
All right, man your stations.
Female found down,
GSW to the chest.
Traumatic full arrest.
Heart sounds?
No. Asystole. Gave
atropine and epi in the field.
Oh, man, she got
it right in the heart.
Let's get the
rapid infuser going.
Let's get some O-neg down,
and let's get a gas cooking.
Let's move it, people!
Monitor's going. Flatline.
Let's go with the epi,
five milligrams, IV Push.
Pulse ox? 40.
40? That's the lowest
pulse ox I've ever heard.
Where the hell's Respiratory?
You know, she
looks kind of stiff.
Let me see.
Look, her jaw won't move.
She looks really cyanotic.
Boxcars in the eyes.
Let's get the O-neg
going! Let's go!
Should we even be doing this?
Pickman, how long was she down?
It could have been a long time,
but I thought I
should run her in.
From the degree of lividity,
I'd say she's been
dead at least three hours.
Let's move with
the O-neg! Let's go!
I agree with Dale.
All right, Let's call it.
No, I wanna crack her!
Time of death...
No, I'll do it.
Time of death... 10:32.
What a gyp.
She's got an engagement ring,
but no wedding band.
She had a little boy too.
No...
Yeah. 47 brought him in.
The boy wasn't hurt?
Well, There doesn't seem to be
anything physical,
but he hasn't spoken
since they picked him up.
It could be
post-traumatic shock.
Did his mother make it?
Mm-mm.
Anybody know what happened?
Yeah, the neighbor said
she heard the mother
and her boyfriend
fighting this morning.
Poor kid must have
seen the whole thing.
What's his name?
Where is the boyfriend?
In the wind.
Hey, buddy, I'm Doug,
and that's Carol right there.
What's your name?
I'm going to listen
to your heart, okay?
Doug... his name's Jeremy.
Jeremy...
Can you hear me?
Good reflexes. It's non-organic.
I'll call Psych.
Why don't you see
if you can track
down a relative?
He witnessed a murder.
The boyfriend could come back.
Okay. We'll get the
cops to post a guard.
Hey...
Peter, come quick.
What?
It's Mrs. Mendoza,
Who?
The woman I sent home
with Montezuma's Revenge.
She's back. Pain's
moved from mid-abdomen
to the right lower quadrant.
Are you a doctor?
I'm a surgeon.
Oh, my God! She's
in so much pain.
It's her appendix.
You sure? Don't
worry, Mr. Mendoza,
We're gonna take it out.
Let's get her up to Surgery.
We were here earlier, but
that nurse sent us home.
We never even saw a doctor.
Don't worry, Mr. Mendoza,
we're going to take care of her.
Clear! Clear!
So did Psych come
down to that boy?
Yeah. She's in
there with him now.
Jerry, will you fax
this for me please?
A loan application? Sorry.
No more personal use of the fax,
per the Weaver.
Jerry... just do it.
Jerry, call Pathology
to take that lady's body
out of the trauma room.
These video people
need to get in there.
What video people?
You didn't read the memo?
No.
I want to start
videotaping the traumas
so we can critique our work.
I don't think this
sounds like a good idea.
Well, David Morgenstern
thought it was.
He wrote the memo.
On a trial basis.
Fine.
Path's backed up.
They asked if we can
keep that DB down here.
Put her in Exam 3.
These guys need to get to work.
Come on.
Gown me quick! Is that the appy?
Knife.
What, I can't do it?
No.
I've seen dozens.
I said no. Carter,
go cover the E.R.
All right, here we go.
Retract the fascia.
Can you see?
Suction.
Pulse is up to 120.
Here we go.
Ah, damn it.
Belly's full of pus.
She perfed.
She done perfed good.
All right, let's
load her with amp,
gent, and Flagyl.
Give me a liter of warm saline.
We got to irrigate
before she goes septic.
What a mess.
Yeah, it's too bad
she didn't come in sooner.
Damn.
Mrs. Garvey...
You've got some nerve.
"Patient is uncooperative,
"demanding,
prone to exaggerate symptoms?"
Can I have my chart back?
Give me a pen.
Mrs. Garvey...
I want this changed.
"Doctor is unprofessional,
openly hostile."
Mrs. Garvey,
your enzymes
suggest a heart attack.
We need to do an echocardiogram.
What's that?
It's like an ultrasound
of your heart.
Why do I need one of those?
We need to make sure that
your artery is not blocked.
I don't understand.
Explain it again.
This is your heart.
This is an artery
going into your heart.
If it is blocked,
it can explode,
causing a massive heart attack,
which would kill
you within minutes!
You are a sick woman.
People said they heard fighting.
Did your mom and her boyfriend
have a fight this morning?
Is that what happened, pal?
Is that what it was?
Detective?
Yeah.
Can I talk to you
outside, please?
What are you doing?
Trying to talk to him.
What did you say?
I just asked him what happened.
This boy's had a
psychological trauma
that's left him
practically catatonic,
and you could have
set him back weeks.
I didn't know that.
Well, now you do. Okay?
Hey, where's your e-mail pal?
He took a hernia up to the O.R..
You're kidding.
Yeah, about an hour ago.
He should be back soon.
Seems like a great guy.
He is.
So are you guys went out?
Uh, we never exactly went out.
Didn't go out, but you, um...
Once. One night, anyway.
Harper, guy in 6 needs a rectal.
Ooh, I have to take these bloods
up to the lab.
See ya.
Carter?
Pass.
Abdominal pain.
Could be surgical.
Haleh, have you seen
that cute guy from Harvard?
Yeah. He just came down.
Try the desk.
All right.
Whoa! I'll take
it. I'll take it.
Thanks.
Max, try the 15
millimeter for me.
Tilt down.
Get the whole bed in the frame.
Good. Pan left.
Iris...
Oh, Dr. Greene.
I would've thought
we were small potatoes
for an infomercial director.
I do educational tapes,
equipment rentals.
I'll take your money
any way I can.
Would you zoom into a
medium shot for me now, Max.
How's your eye?
Oh, fine.
Nice profile.
You sure you
won't go on the air?
I wouldn't feel right plugging
your hair growth products,
since I don't believe
in them myself.
Well, you're more
secure than most men.
And you looks like you're
in pretty good shape.
You exercise?
Run, push-ups, a little. Why?
I'm just about to go national
with a new exercycle,
and I haven't found
a pitchman yet.
You, uh, interested?
He's had periumbilical pain
localized to the
right lower quadrant.
Rebound and guarding,
nausea and vomiting.
What's his white count?
9,000. I'm thinking appendix.
Appys usually
present a bit lower,
but they can fool you.
Let's take him up.
Can I do the procedure?
Does Benton let you do appys?
We've talked about it.
Well, there's a first
time for everything.
Mr. Kennerly, you're
going to the O.R.,
but there's no reason to worry.
Everything's going to be fine.
You clean her out yet?
I've still got to
drain the abscess.
She's tachy. 180.
Temp's 104.
I'll get a cooling blanket.
This is making
me nervous, Peter.
Just hold on.
Peter, isn't that your
med student next door?
What?
What's going on over there?
Another appendix.
When it rains, it pours.
Somebody close those blinds.
Run of five. Your
time's about up, Peter.
Ah, just give me two minutes.
Too late!
She's fibrillating.
Goddamn it.
Charging at 200.
Come on, don't do this to me!
Clear!
There are three enzymes
that are released by the heart
after a heart attack...
CKMB, AST, and LDH.
By graphing the
levels of each enzyme,
we can determine
that you had your
heart attack back here
at approximately
4:00 this morning.
Oh, thank you, doctor.
She's the one.
Susan!
Yes, Kerry...
One of the nurses alerted me
that Ethel was about
to sign out ANA,
which, in her condition,
might well have killed her.
I thought it best to indulge her
in order to save her life.
Good thinking.
I know it's frustrating
dealing with difficult patients,
but you have a tendency
to become anger-locked
and inflexible.
Thank you for pointing that out.
If you feel yourself
getting dug in,
just call me.
I'm here to help.
Retractor.
Expose the internal oblique.
Can I have some suction?
Good. Now, cut it open.
I'm in.
Okay, now, put your
hand in the peritoneum,
and feel around until
you find the appendix.
I got it.
Okay. Let's see.
Well, that is the pinkest
most healthy
appendix I've ever seen.
But he had all the symptoms.
They can fool you.
Well, as long as we're here...
Better not.
Besides, I think I see the cause
of Mr. Kennerly's bellyache.
What?
Toothpick...
in the terminal ileum.
I think if you pull
on the gold tassel,
it'll slide right out.
Congratulations, Mr. Carter,
on your first toothpick-ectomy.
Now, let's start irrigating.
Mr. Mendoza...
Yes?
Your wife is out of
surgery, but she's very sick.
Her appendix burst
before I could remove it,
and, uh, the bacteria
invaded her bloodstream.
We're giving her antibiotics
to fight the infection.
I expect her to pull through it.
Are you saying
that she could die?
It's a possibility.
When we first came in,
was there no way to tell
that it was the appendix?
Well, the symptoms and the
story suggested food poisoning.
That woman sent us home
without ever seeing a doctor.
She consulted a doctor...
who ordered your
wife discharged.
How could this happen?
Hey!
How's the kid doing?
Oh, the same.
Think I could take
a peek in there,
give him this?
Yeah. Sure.
Did you draw that yourself?
I did.
Hey...
Where is he?
I don't know. Jeremy?
Oh, man.
Jeremy?
Oh, no.
Jeremy!
Jeremy! Jeremy...
Hey, have you seen the kid?
What kid?
The one that won't talk.
No.
Jeremy! Oh, God...
Jeremy!
Jeremy...
Hey, sweetie...
Hey, come on,
let's go back to
your room, okay?
Come on.
Okay?
The Pedes attending's
name is Keller,
and there's a med
student named Amber
who said she'd sit
with him for a while
until his aunt came
to pick him up.
Okay, you got it. Thanks.
Hey, um...
who does this belong to?
I told you to hold onto him.
I just turned
around for a second.
We picked him up in the
middle of Michigan Avenue.
He's zonked out of his gourd.
He's tachy, diaphoretic.
Could be coke, PCP.
All right, well, let's
get him a room.
Hey, Dr. Ross...
Yeah. What's this?
Some guy dropped it off for you.
Want something from
Psycha-Deli? I'm starving.
No.
Could someone
release the guy in 4?
I gotta get out of here.
Sure. You okay?
I'm having a walking
anxiety attack.
Call me.
Hi. You're all wired up.
Oh, great.
I'm gonna show you
how all the bells
and whistles work,
but I want to eat something.
How about you?
Uh... I'm not really hungry.
Oh. Okay.
So what's wrong with her?
What is this?
I don't know. Check it out.
Yowza!
"25,000 in ca..."
It was a gift from the
old man. 10-1, it's dirty.
Looks like your cancer
treatment fund just got richer.
It's going back.
Penance doesn't mean
anything if it's that easy.
Yeah, what do you
know about penance?
I used to date a
lot of Catholic girls.
You want their numbers?
Her lungs are
filling up with fluid.
I have to put in a swan.
How is she?
She might not make it.
Oh, God...
How could you miss the signs
of appendicitis?
Periumbilical pain,
localizing to the right.
She told me the
pain was diffuse.
Did you check for
rebound and guarding?
I told you I did.
Well, I'm asking you
if you actually did.
Yes, and if you had any doubts,
you should've
examined her yourself.
Well, I trusted you to do that.
You know how difficult
appendicitis is to diagnose.
I asked you if you wanted
to see her, and you said...
The appendix that wasn't.
Well, there'll be plenty
more ahead of you.
I wish I had at
least one behind me.
It is cause for concern,
what with the pyramid system.
Pyramid system?
From now on, all surgical
interns will be ranked.
Those who fall
in the lower third,
won't be asked
back a second year.
Come on. You gotta
help me out here.
Hey, come on, bud, cooperate.
There's the Rolling
Stones. That's a cool one.
"Ban the bra."
"All the way with LBJ."
What's that about?
I won't hurt your
buttons. I promise.
I'll give your
buttons right back.
You just gotta take this off.
Hey! Security!
Let go of her!
This sucker's strong!
Hey!
Shep, I don't think
he's breathing.
Shep! Shep!
No pulse. He has no pulse.
Get the crash cart.
Get CPR!
Come on!
What are you doing
to my crash cart?
Where's the ET tube?
Wait, wait, wait, wait,
wait! He's got a pulse.
He's back.
I got it!
Security! Security!
Hey, did they call us in?
Oh, relax.
We still have a few minutes.
Where's mom?
Uh, she went to Northfield
to see Sally.
Called that one right.
This is very
upsetting for her...
and for me.
When you have to choose
between your own daughters,
it's not right.
What do you mean?
I'm not going in.
Dad!
I don't want to take sides.
For three weeks, you have
been promising to back me up,
and you decide to
change your mind now?
You haven't spent
five minutes with Chloe.
You haven't met Joe.
Unbelievable.
I'm telling you, your
sister is like a new person.
She went out and got
a job the first morning.
She insists on
paying for the food.
Joe is a good guy.
Did you check his rap sheets?
He's a cop.
What?
I'm not going.
Look, it's all set.
Inga's counting on you.
I'm not going.
What's the problem here?
I was married for 11 years.
Uh-huh.
To be faced suddenly
with dating again...
Okay, you're over-thinking this.
You just got to follow your id.
It's more complicated than that.
No, it's not.
Okay, what is about
to pass between us
must remain
in the strictest of confidence.
Okay.
When I first met Jen...
Mm-hmm?
When you first met Jen...
I'd never had sex before.
Right. You were 17, right?
16.
And through all those years,
I've always been faithful.
Mm-hmm.
Are you telling me
that you've only
had sex with Jen?
That so unusual?
In the 20th century? Uh...
Yeah, you're right.
See? I'm a freak.
Well, that's a little strong.
No, no. It's true.
I've only had sex with my wife,
and the thought of being
intimate with a stranger, I...
What if she can't arouse me,
or, you know, I
can't please her?
The thought alone
scares me to death.
Well, you're right.
Inga's not for you.
Uh...
County, this is unit 52.
We have a 16-year-old male
beating victim
multiple injuries to
the face and torso,
broken tib-fib,
difficulty breathing.
Dr. Ross, 16-year-old trauma.
BP's 80/50, resps
are shallow at 53.
Do you copy?
We copy, 52. What's your ETA?
We're a ways out.
I'd say 15 minutes.
Copy that.
Dr. Ross, I'd like
to run this trauma.
Sorry, Carter, I promised Dale
he could run the next trauma.
Jerry, page me in 10 minutes.
These Kurley B lines...
What you looking at?
Pulmonary edema.
Man, I'm hungry. You
guys had lunch yet?
We were just
going to go in a few.
Care to join?
Well, I really should go up
now. I got some labs coming.
Well, Doc Magoo's?
Why don't we do the lunch room?
It's Nuremberg chicken day.
On October 10, 1994,
Chloe was arrested for
drunk and disorderly conduct.
At this time, she swore that
she would seek treatment.
Six months later,
she was arrested for
driving under the influence.
Dr. Lewis,
we are here to
explore the possibility
of you and your
sister settling this
without the court's help.
I take it you're not interested.
No, Your Honor.
And on the issue
of visitation rights?
No. I don't trust her.
Based on?
Based on her history of
drunkenness, addiction,
and false claims
of rehabilitation,
as outlined here.
I have a copy.
Chloe, is there anything
you'd like to say?
Well, everything Susan
said about me is true,
but I've never stayed in rehab
more than a week before now.
And you've been free
of alcohol and drugs for...
Five months.
Um, here are the
urine test results.
You've barely started
taking responsibility
for yourself.
How do you expect to take
responsibility for a child?
I ask myself that a lot,
but I am on the right track now,
and I never, ever
want to go back
to who I was,
and I feel that with
the help of God
and my friends...
and... my family...
that I can be a good
mother to my baby.
And you've been employed
as a claims adjuster in Phoenix
for the past four months.
Yep.
Here are the affidavits.
They're holding a job for
me, and I got a job here.
Um...
could you step outside, please?
I want to speak
to Dr. Lewis alone.
I am going to allow your sister
three overnight visits a week,
starting tonight,
pending resolution
of the adoption issue.
What's more, I'm telling you now
that if you proceed
with the custody fight,
you will lose.
Chloe's the mother,
and as far as I can see,
she presents no
danger to a child.
Given that,
I want you to consider
the cost of proceeding...
Not just financially,
but in terms of the disruption
to your life, to Chloe's life,
and to the baby.
We should've gone fishing.
We could be sitting on the
pier with our toes in the water,
drowning a couple of worms.
Instead, here we are,
two urban casualties
of the button man.
My throat's fine, by the way.
We're not raising our kids here.
We're... we're not?
No. Definitely not.
Okay.
What happened here?
Appendix ruptured. She's septic.
I took a look at her chart,
and lo and behold,
you sent her home
without examining her.
Well, nothing in the PA's
exam suggested appendicitis.
I disagree.
"Abdominal pain,
cramping, fever."
You should've laid hands on her.
That's what a surgeon does.
You were quick to assign blame
when Doug Ross made a mistake.
But when your
ass is on the line,
you hide behind excuses.
If this hits the fan,
don't expect your colleagues
to line up with support.
Reap as you sow.
$7.43.
I got it.
No...
No, no. You get it next time.
Why don't you go ahead.
Oh! Damn it. Labs are up.
They can wait 10 minutes.
Better not.
You guys go ahead.
I'll catch up to you.
Your soup's gonna get cold.
16 years old,
multiple lacerations
and bruises to face,
chest and abdomen.
Possible fractured left
tib-fib and facial fracture.
Excuse me!
Yo, anybody seen
Dale? You got that?
This guy sure
pissed somebody off.
Kids at the scene said he
got jumped out of a gang.
Can I do something?
You want to run it, run it.
Airway?
Patent. No tracheal deviation.
Bruises on chest and abdomen.
Let's get a C-spine,
chest and head CT.
Pupils?
Uh...
round, equal and reactive.
What's your name?
Virgil.
BP is down 60.
Carter?
He's bleeding from somewhere.
Where?
Good breath sounds.
That clears the chest.
There are no marks on his back.
Must be the belly.
Lavage kit!
Lavage kit, please.
Number 11 blade.
You ever done this before?
Not until today.
Well, Mr. Carter,
I see you're finally
getting a procedure.
Okay, go.
Make sure you're
into the peritoneum.
I'm in.
Hook up the saline.
And... extension tubing.
Almost looks like he
knows what he's doing.
How is she?
A little better.
I put a catheter in her artery
to make it easier to draw blood.
I don't see any other doctor
sitting by her bed all day.
Thank you for taking
care of my wife.
Mr. Mendoza, um...
when you asked earlier
if the appendicitis
could have been caught,
I didn't, uh, give
you a full answer.
I'm the doctor who
discharged your wife.
If I'd examined her
I probably would have caught it,
but...
I didn't.
I made a mistake.
I'm sorry.
Nothing. No blood in the belly.
BP's down to 40.
Where the hell's the bleed?
You check his back?
Take a look.
Here we go.
This doesn't make sense.
Maybe it's a faulty
pressure cuff.
Foley's clear.
Whoa! Spoke too soon.
Must have blown a clot.
Where is that damn wound?
What's that?
That is a very small
puncture wound,
probably an ice pick.
Went right by me.
Me too.
Let's get this kid
upstairs, patch him up.
Where do you think
he took it, Carter...
Kidney or renal artery?
Uh, renal.
Want to come up and find out?
Sure.
Nice catch.
Thank you.
What's going on?
Oh, stumbled
right into a trauma.
Ice pick to the kidney.
We're taking him up now.
Hi.
This is weird, isn't it?
Uh, yeah.
You haven't really met Joe yet,
have you?
Hi, Susan.
Hi, Joe.
I brought extra
diapers, and, um...
some baby Tylenol
in case she gets a fever,
and, uh...
Oh. Mr. B.
She can't go to
sleep without him.
What's her bedtime routine?
Um, well, a bath, and then, um,
we read two picture books,
and, uh, a bottle while
she's getting rocked,
and usually, I sing to her.
All right. I better go.
We were hoping
you'd stay for dinner.
No, I don't think so.
Oh, please.
I know little
Suzy'd want you to.
She doesn't know who I am.
Come on.
First, let's review
a relatively simple trauma
led by our own Mr. Carter.
Note the uneven distribution
of personnel, screen right.
Everyone clumped together
like a herd of wildebeest
getting in each other's way,
while the left side
is under-utilized.
How's it going?
Very enlightening.
Next, we'll see an example
of poor trauma hygiene.
Observe Mr. Carter
wiping his nose
with his gloved hand
just prior to
grabbing the scalpel.
Let's look one more time.
The... wipe, and now, the grab.
One more time.
Wipe...
and grab.
Good.
Now, let's take a look at
a more organized trauma
led by Dale earlier in the day.
You want to have dinner tonight?
Love to.
Are you saying
that you have never had sex
with anyone but Jen?
Is that so unusual?
Uh, in the 20th century?
See? You're right. I'm a freak.
I may have gone too far back.
What if she can't arouse me,
or I can't please her?
The thought alone
scares me to death.
Well, you're right.
Inga's not for you.
Oh, man.
Oh, my God.
Mrs. Mendoza's doing better.
Yeah, I know.
I spoke to her husband.
He said that you told
him it was your fault.
It was my fault.
Peter, do you hate me?
No.
You don't even look
at me when we talk.
It's been like this all year.
Look, I'm sorry that I hurt you,
but I thought by
now, we'd be past it.
I am past it.
Way past it.
You have to admit, it was funny.
It was the most
humiliating moment
of my life.
Uh, Dr. Ross, this came for you.
Bad news?
Well, I've been denied a loan
by a company whose motto is,
"We lend money to anyone."
There's always your dad's dough.
Then I'd have to thank him.
Penance has its price.
Ready?
As I'll ever be.
How's your appetite?
Uh, good.
Look...
Oh, thanks.
It's strong.
It's all right.
I hate to bring up
the elephant in the room,
but I think you did
a wonderful thing.
You mean taking care of Suzy?
I didn't have a choice.
Even so, you gave
Chloe a chance.
When she first came to AA,
she had as low an
opinion of herself
as anyone could,
but she wanted to get well.
I thought you were a cop.
I'm also a
recovering alcoholic...
Nine years.
To be honest,
the program frowns
on old-timers like me
getting involved with newcomers,
but we fell in love.
We won't get married
for a while, though.
Not till Chloe
gets her year cake.
If she makes a year.
Hey...
Hi.
I thought you were going
to go home and change.
I did, but I changed my mind.
You don't want to go?
No.
I already bought the tickets.
Well, normally that
would bother me,
but considering the
occasion, I don't really care.
What occasion? My dumping you.
You're dumping me?
Yeah, and I gotta tell you,
I feel pretty good about it.
What's going on?
You know.
No, I don't. I don't know.
Get out of here.
Look, we both know
that you lured Dale
and me upstairs
so that you could
do a procedure,
which is all you care
about these days.
That's not true. Yeah, it is!
You're a weasel!
All that matters to you
is making suck points
with surgical Residents.
Look, let's go
someplace and talk... No.
Harper, please.
No. It's too late.
I don't even know
who you are anymore.
Hey...
Hey, you ready?
Almost. Where's Reilly?
He's at Magoo's
with that cute tech he's after.
The boy doesn't waste much time.
Yeah. Good luck.
Hey, doc,
you hear?
No, what?
That kid that saw
his mom get shot?
He finally started talking.
Turns out that the boyfriend
was slapping mom around,
so the kid runs,
gets a gun from the drawer
He's gonna protect
his mom, right?
Only he's not such a good aim.
No...
Yeah. Killed his own mother.
Nice world, huh?
I feel like I just
plucked the virtue
of a virgin.
I'm so glad you did.
Want to do that again?
I need a minute to recuperate.
Okay.
You let me know.
In the meantime,
we can play back the tape
and critique your technique.
Relax, sweetie. I'm kidding.
You're awful quiet.
Just thinking about that kid.
He will never get
over what happened.
He will be, for
the rest of his life,
damaged goods.
He'll probably end
up like the button man.
No, he won't.
Oh yes, he will.
He is a button
man in the making.
Hey, what's going on here?
Idiots!
Unit 47 requesting police
backup at 46th and Hutchins.
Couple of guys
bonking each other over
the head with cue sticks.
Hey!
Jeez!
Come on!
What are you doing?
What's wrong with you, huh?
You son of a bitch!
Hey, Shep! Shep!
Get back here! Shep!
What are you doing?
Shep!
Shep! Shep, stop!
Stop!
For God's sake, Shep! Stop it!
Get off of me!
Hi.
Hi. I'm looking for Ray.
He's not here.
Okay.
Oh, come on in.
I'm Karen.
I'm Doug.
Can I get you
something to drink, Doug?
Uh, no, thank you.
Do you have any idea
when Ray's gonna be back?
Not tonight.
I'm his son.
Oh, I know.
I saw you the night
you came into the bar.
Oh, that's right. He said
that you were his boss.
Yeah.
I try to remind him of
that every chance I get.
So are you his boss?
Why don't you just come
right out and ask me?
Ask you what?
Do I sleep with your father?
Do you?
I'm not going to answer that.
Well, I only say that
because it's unusual
that your boss would be
living in your apartment.
What's this?
Scotch.
Who said I lived here?
What are you doing here?
I'm staying here tonight.
I have no idea.
What's this?
Names, dates,
case numbers that Dr. Vucelich
dropped from his study.
I'm going on record to
show that the man is a fraud.
Why are you doing this, Peter?
Like you said, it's, um...
easy to make excuses
for not doing the right thing.
No more excuses.
She takes four
ounces of milk at night,
heated for 40 seconds at 50%.
Okay.
I'm so glad you stayed.
I know everybody thinks
you've changed, Chloe,
and I hope to God that you have,
but forgive me
if I'm not rejoicing just yet.
Maybe I can't be objective,
because I've been so
angry at you for so long.
I mean, do you really think
you can be a good mother
to this little girl?
Yes.
More than anything,
that's what I wanna be.
Well, I can finish up in here.
Thanks.
I'm so glad Suzy's got an aunt
that'll always be there,
who's smart and a doctor
who's going to give
you good advice.
Yes.
Hey, you wanna say good night?
Yeah, yeah.
Good night, sweetie.
Blackbird singing
In the dead of night
Take these Broken wings
And learn to fly
All your life
You were always waiting
For this moment to arise
for This moment to arise