- Previously on The Resident...
- Top of your class,
followed all the rules,
and you think that puts you
at an advantage. It doesn't.
It just means you have
more to unlearn than the guys
- who weren't paying attention.
- I need a new resident.
- Mine's impossible.
- You got Conrad.
- Watch and learn.
- Start compressions.
I will do whatever it
takes to get you back.
- Hey.
- You're here.
Lily means a lot to all of us.
From now on, she's your patient.
What are my odds?
The next few
months will be rough.
But you can beat this.
All we want to do
is help our patients,
but what they don't
teach us in medical school
is there are so many
ways to do harm.
You got the best
hands in the business.
But he's still the most
requested surgeon.
Did you hit an artery?
On an appendectomy?
Maybe he had a heart attack.
- That's exactly right.
- You need to consider a change
- before you kill any more patients.
- How dare you.
Is your pride really worth
more than the life of a patient?
You watch yourself, Conrad.
Career day. Exciting, right?
Time for you guys to
think about your future.
And I want you to aim high.
For example, you
could be a doctor like...
Dr. Hawkins here,
who diagnosed my
heart condition early.
And, God willing, he's gonna be
the man that
saved my life. So...
let's give him a warm welcome.
Okay, one more
time or we're gonna
do a pop quiz on
the periodic table.
All right. You guys
are wound up now.
They're all yours. Good luck.
Wow.
When I was about your age,
I was driving with my dad.
Guy on a moped
swerved in front of us,
right into the path
of an oncoming car.
Wham. The impact
threw this guy's body
onto the pavement.
He must have slid 50 feet.
And my dad, he just sat there,
pissed at being held up.
But a woman in the car
behind us jumped out,
and she worked on that kid
until the ambulance came.
This incredible
woman had the ability
to save a life
right in front of me,
and I knew, in that moment,
that I wanted to be a person
who could jump out of
the car to help people.
So that's what I do.
So, has anyone thought
about becoming a doctor?
I've thought about
becoming a millionaire.
That's not a career path.
So, do you cut people
open and take them apart?
That's...
a surgeon, Treena.
I'm an internist.
Someone has to first
figure out what's wrong.
- Micah?
- Yeah...
I got you.
Someone call 911.
No cell phones...
allowed in class.
It's my teacher. Please help.
It's his heart. Sanford High.
The rate's too
fast. I got to slow it
to get more blood
into your heart.
Grab that funnel
and some tubing, on the counter.
You. Balloon. Go.
Get the nurse.
- What are you doing?
- Makeshift stethoscope.
I hear a friction rub.
Might be an effusion.
Hang on, hang on.
Don't worry. We got you.
Pulse is getting weaker.
Elevate his legs.
Elevate-elevate his legs.
Blow as hard as you can.
Stay with me. Stay with me.
Stay with me.
Coming through.
Okay.
Lost his pulse. Back up.
Back up, back up,
back up. You stay.
Stay.
28-year-old
pre-transplant patient
with V tach arrest.
Take him to Chastain.
Am I... out of time?
Not yet.
♪ ♪
Remember, once
we get the signal,
we get into position.
Mitch and I fire first.
Keep the muzzle of
your gun pointed up.
Last thing you want
to do is shoot your dog.
- And don't mess with Lane.
- Oh, I'd never.
She saved my
sister-in-law's life.
Breast cancer.
Okay, I'm ready to
see some quail now.
Wow.
That was fun.
Oh, my God.
Trip shot Mitch.
- Trip?
- It's okay, it's okay.
Mitch, you're gonna
be fine. Hold on.
- He's pulseless!
- Take a deep breath.
- He's had a heart attack!
- Calm down. I'm right here.
I love hearing your voice
first thing in the morning.
Conrad, listen.
Breakfast at the cafeteria?
- Hard pass.
- Grits.
Pancakes. Sausage.
Just like old times.
- That's not why I'm calling.
- I don't care
why you're calling.
Just that you're calling.
I have your heart.
Always.
Your patient's heart.
♪ You know ♪
♪ That the heart feels better
when the beat goes on ♪
♪ The beat goes on,
the beat goes on ♪
Where have you been?
No one's telling me anything.
I'm dying of
suspense, literally.
We heard from UNOS.
This time it's a perfect match.
♪ Walk home alone ♪
Oh.
When-when can
we do a transplant?
As soon as the heart gets here.
There's a short window
when a donated heart is viable.
Transplant team
has been called in.
I will be with you
every step of the way.
- Okay.
- Recovery from this kind of surgery
can take months. You
sure you're up for it, Micah?
With me and my God,
there's nothing we can't handle.
♪ Dance ♪
New heart. New heart.
New heart.
Thanks.
- Trauma One?
- Right, straight into one.
Witnessed arrest outside of
the hospital, now unconscious
with a thready
pulse. He's critical.
Page cardiology.
- Here I am.
- Second patient.
Gunshot wound to the buttocks.
Get surgery here for Trauma Two.
It's okay, Mitch.
You're gonna be all right.
Have two litres of O neg
standing by... is that enough?
Check glucose and blood.
Must have had a
heart attack in the field.
- Is that Congressman Dunlap?
- Yep.
- How long was he down?
- Two minutes.
Witnessed, we achieved
ROSC in the field.
Any medical history
we should know?
Well, hypertension,
high cholesterol.
Not sure of anything else.
EKG showed Q waves, which means
there was an MI
in the past, as well.
Well, I'm surprised he
survived another one.
Yeah. We'll do a...
echo and a cardiac cath,
- figure out what's going on.
- ST depression.
- What's going on?
- Not sure yet.
I just heard it was
some kind of accident.
Dr. Hunter and Bell were there.
Victim must be a VIP.
That's the head of publicity
for the hospital.
Clean up on aisle nine.
How is Congressman Dunlap?
Medics stabilized
him in the ambulance.
Peterson's gonna
run a bedside echo,
and we'll know more soon.
Mitch's wounds are superficial.
Hey, how you doing? Dr. Hawkins.
- Hi, Doctor.
- Nice to meet you. Brody, how we feeling?
I'm just gonna lift up
your shirt here,
check things out.
This is a PR disaster.
We take a congressman
and our lobbyist out hunting,
and they both end up in our ER.
Well, we can still
change the narrative
if we can save 'em.
Did you hear what happened?
Yeah. Remind me not
to go hunting with you.
Dr. Hunter, so
pleased to meet you.
I'm Dr. Devon Pravesh,
and I just read your paper
on aggressive treatment
of stage IV bladder cancer.
- Are you done sucking up yet?
- Nope. A five-year survival
was higher with
platinum-based therapy.
It's incredible.
Oh, man. My new intern.
- He's a real gunner.
- Cancer is fascinating to me.
And you are the top
oncologist in Georgia,
so... maybe if you have
some time someday...
Absolutely. I'd love to help.
Sucking up works for me.
I think Dr. Feldman could
use some help in Trauma Two.
It was good to meet you.
Roughly 200 bird shot
evenly distributed
across the buttocks.
He's sedated and prepped for you
to start removing the
pellets, Dr. Okafor.
These are superficial wounds.
You don't need a surgeon.
Any fool could do this.
Got to go.
The OR just paged me.
Dr. Pravesh.
Just the man.
Divide and conquer.
You take the right
cheek, I'll take the left.
Conrad.
Micah's heart's arriving
earlier than expected.
- The medevac's five minutes out.
- Don't leave.
I need you.
Sorry. Got a situation here.
Devon, come with me.
Seriously? Seriously?
I've got a case that's
gonna take my full attention.
I know you'll be crushed
to hear you're on your own.
It's Independence Day.
What's Independence Day?
Your first day as a
doctor without my help.
Start by handling sign out.
Doctors at the
end of their shifts
must debrief you
on all their patients.
You write down every
single word since you know
absolutely nothing
about these cases.
You'll be covering
20 patients solo.
- No backup.
- Poor bastard.
What do you mean, "no backup"?
You'll have Nic. Page me
if there's a serious
problem, but remember,
that's a sign of weakness.
Don't let him kill anyone.
I'll do my best.
How many surgical
residents did you beat out
to scrub in on a
heart transplant?
All of them.
You excited?
Don't I look it?
No.
I am excited. For Micah.
I want him fixed.
Me too.
Oh, my God.
Um... uh, my name
is Dr. Devon Pravesh,
and I'm handling sign out today.
- -Dr. Pravesh.
- I've never done this before,
so please, uh, speak slowly,
uh, one at a time,
and-and be-be patient.
First patient is Leona
Bates, 62-year-old female,
status is post
appendectomy in 1991.
- This is her EKG from admission.
- All right.
- Slow down, slow down.
- And then from ten minutes later,
- and then from an hour after that.
- Okay, okay.
Uh...
- All right, go ahead.
- 39-year-old male with a history
of diabetes
mellitus, pancreatitis
due to increased
triglycerides presented
with abnormal LFTs and a
heterogeneous liver mass.
Lucinda Cooley's blood
glucose level is in the 50s.
She was getting
way too much insulin
because the nurse was telling me
- that she'd been hypoglycemic...
- Due to acute illness.
Which super pisses me
off. That's Nurse Raymond.
Watch out for him,
okay? He's a total dick.
All right.
Olivia Coffin,
76-year-old female.
She's a mess.
- Also a whiner.
- And a talker.
On the pain-in-the-ass scale,
- she's ten. -Probably about a ten.
- Super complicated...
Micah Stevens' heart, Doc.
Hey.
Mitch.
I-Is Mitch all right?
He'll be fine. Don't worry.
We have the results of
the cardiac catheterization.
There's good news and bad news.
You had a very
serious heart attack,
and the only reason
you're still with us at all
is because you
were with these two.
What's the good news?
That is the good news.
The bad news is, your
heart was badly damaged.
The ejection fraction
is severely reduced.
What that means, Trip,
is... you're gonna
need a transplant.
Oh, good Lord.
We'll contact UNOS immediately.
You'll be status 1A.
So that'll put you at the
top of the organ donor list.
- You'll be top priority for a new heart.
- Well, how long is it
- gonna take to find one?
- Well, unfortunately,
finding the right match can
take weeks, sometimes months.
Well, maybe.
We do have a new heart
at Chastain. It just flew in.
- That organ is already allocated.
- Well, let's
just wait, see if it's a match.
And if it is, we
will un-allocate it.
Right?
Ready?
- Here we go.
- Yeah.
Gonna get you
back to your class.
- Got to teach those students, right? They need you.
- Yeah.
Yeah? Okay.
- Let's do this.
- Sorry, Micah. I need Dr. Hawkins
- for just a moment.
- Okay.
Is everything all right?
- Micah's surgery was canceled.
- Why?
His heart was reallocated
to Congressman Dunlap.
They can't do that.
Yes, they can. The hospital
went through proper channels.
- They got the okay from UNOS.
- You mean they pulled strings.
Look, I'm pissed, too, but
they didn't break any rules.
Dunlap has higher priority
than Micah because he's sicker.
There's nothing you can do.
Says who?
I called Dunlap's wife.
Turns out they're separated.
The daughter's coming.
Flying in from California.
Divorce blowback. You
get sick, you're all alone.
Yeah, could happen to us, too.
How many exes have
we got between us?
Four, last time I counted.
Unless, of course,
you've been busy.
No. No.
But I still haven't
given up hope.
Me, I'm off the romance
track permanently.
From here on in, I'm
married to my work.
Never say never.
There's Conrad.
He's the resident in
charge of Micah's care.
Don't I know it.
Go easy on him.
Dr. Hawkins, I know
you're upset. I would be, too.
This is against all
protocol, and you know it.
Micah's waited two
years for a heart.
You can't just cut in line
for a VIP who hasn't waited
- two minutes.
- Well, they-they both need a heart.
There was only one.
It was a tough decision.
My patient is 28, with his
whole life ahead of him.
That heart could give
him 50 more years.
Trip Dunlap is 63 and a smoker.
His body's far more
likely to reject the heart.
And even if the transplant
takes, what does it buy him,
- ten more years?
- Look, Dunlap is critical. I mean,
he could die tonight. And
Micah, he's waited this long.
- He can safely wait a bit longer.
- His quality of life
is zero. He was an athlete.
He's a science teacher.
Loved by his students.
I know him. We all do,
because he's been in
and out of here so often.
Three times we
thought we had a heart.
Three times he was sent home.
Zero complaining
or self-pity, ever.
This guy, he's golden.
You want to tell
Dunlap's daughter
her father is less deserving?
Why? Because he's a VIP
who can help out Chastain.
You really speak your mind.
It's just, it's a juvenile habit.
The decision was made
for medical reasons alone.
- I think we both know that's not the truth.
- I'm gonna
cut you some slack
because you're upset.
Chief of surgery,
resident.
Try to remember that.
All good news, Mr. Ramirez.
Your EKG looks normal,
- and you should be out of here tomorrow.
- Thank you.
You forgot to listen
to his heart, Doctor.
I don't need to listen to his
heart. I looked at his EKG.
Why didn't the murmur
show up on his EKG?
Occasionally, you can
get a normal reading
in patients with
significant heart disease.
Always use your stethoscope.
If you don't, Conrad
will ream you.
- Do you have to tell him?
- No, because I know you're never
gonna skip listening to
a patient's heart again.
Devon, I want you to call
the OPO every 15 minutes.
- We need to find another heart.
- Can you get
a physician's assistant to
do it? I'm handling 20 patients.
Most people take a few
hours to fail Independence Day.
You just broke the record.
What has it been, 40 minutes?
- I smell carbs!
- Chad, you have surgery
scheduled today to remove
that foot. You can't eat.
No pizza. Take it back.
How 'bout chocolate pudding?
Four or five cups
should slay the beast.
You can aspirate
food under anesthesia
and die. Even chocolate pudding.
- I told him that.
- Well, I didn't believe him.
Is he a real doctor?
Tachycardia 5918.
Doobie's heart rate's spiking.
I want you to call the OPO every
15 minutes. And don't page me
about a patient unless it's
an emergency. It's a sign
- of weakness.
- It's a sign of weakness.
What's going on, Doobie?
Nothing.
His heart rate's falling.
Are you all right?
Are you ready
for your injection?
I don't care if you are.
You're getting it.
"Naughty Nurses"? Really?
When in Rome?
You are recovering
from major heart surgery.
Get the mittens.
Mittens?
Do you like it?
Do you like that?
- Do you like it? Yeah! Yeah!
- Oh...
Where have you been?
I paged you three times.
I'm already on your cheek.
- Nic is really good.
- You just noticed?
Why didn't she
want to be a doctor?
Because she's smart.
Nurses get to spend time
with patients. We don't.
They have a strong union,
earn overtime, make good money.
For all of residency, if you
figure the hours we're working,
interns and residents
make minimum wage.
Well, I still think she'd
make a good doctor.
She's working on her
doctorate. Doctor of Nursing.
How long has he been coughing?
A while. His heart rate's
- over 100.
- O2 saturation 93.
He's been immobile
for several hours.
I'm hearing some
abnormal breath sounds.
- Pleuritis?
- I think it's a possible pulmonary embolism.
Let's get him to CT, stat.
♪ When other helpers fail ♪
♪ And comforts flee ♪
♪ Help of the helpless ♪
♪ O abide with me. ♪
I take it you
haven't told him yet.
That we're sending him
home for a fourth time? Not yet.
Do I have to?
Yeah.
This isn't like you.
How's my shadow doing?
If you mean
Dr. Pravesh, quite well.
- Don't change the subject.
- I want to change the subject.
Let's talk about anything else.
- It's not your fault.
- It feels like it is.
I come up against
Bell... He's like a wall.
I look for a work-around, a side
door, a window... there's none.
You'll find one.
You always do.
God, I love it when
you believe in me.
I never stopped
believing in you.
This the lobbyist who got shot?
Yes.
Filling defect in the
right pulmonary artery,
- suggesting...
- Massive lung clot.
Nice catch.
Particularly
impressive for an intern.
His pressure just dropped.
Let's get him out
of there. Mitch?
Hey, Mitch.
Mitch? He's unconscious.
He needs thrombolysis.
Activate the
interventional team.
No. His pressure's
70/30. Page surgery.
Why? I can do the thrombolysis
with a local catheter right now.
It won't work with this patient.
We have to crack his chest open,
remove the clot, and save
whatever lung can be saved.
That's extreme and way
too big a call for you to make
without backup. Page Conrad.
- I'll page him.
- No. I know exactly what to do.
We've got IV access.
Let's give him a stat IV direct
thrombin inhibitor. Tell
the OR we're coming.
On my call. One, two, three.
- Two.
What's happening?
You've got a blood clot
in an artery in your lung.
We're taking you to
emergency surgery.
Am I going to die?
No. You're gonna be fine, Mitch.
You better hope you
made the right call.
♪ Happy birthday to you... ♪
Yes, uh, I'll pass on the
information. Thank you.
♪ ...to you ♪
♪ Happy birthday, dear... ♪
Hey. You finally
get through to OPO?
I did.
And they have a heart
that's a match for Micah.
That's great news.
Why do you look like
you're going to a funeral?
It's Chloe.
My first medical error.
You told me to stop
CPR, and I didn't do it.
Rule one: do what
I tell you to do,
- no questions asked.
- Conrad, ease up.
She's brain-dead.
Neuro confirmed.
They did a full workup.
That's no longer a human
being... That's an organ farm.
- What's the problem here?
- Her mom called the OPO about
- donating her organs, and then she backed off.
- Why?
She can't accept the diagnosis.
Is there any chance that
something good can come of this?
Yes, so many people could
receive her other organs, too.
If the family can be
made to face the truth.
Want me to speak to them?
-No. -No. -No.
- Then you speak to them.
- I can't.
Not anymore. No
doctor whose patient
could benefit from an organ
donation can make the case
to a family to
withdraw life support.
It's a hard and fast
rule, and a good one.
The hospital, on the
other hand, could step in.
Ugh.
Before you say anything,
I'm not here to argue.
I have a solution.
You have one minute. Go.
There's a brain-dead patient
in the ICU. Chloe Gellar.
Her heart could
save Micah's life,
and you are the only
person I can think of
who can convince the
mother to withdraw life support.
So... so your solution
is to have me walk in
and ask a grieving
mother to unplug her child?
Her child is gone.
- The answer's no.
- No one is better
at communicating than you.
Thanks for the
compliment, but no.
Chloe's organs would
save so many lives.
You know, humanitarian
considerations aside,
to force a mother's hand
- would risk a lawsuit.
- So Chloe stays
on life support in
our ICU indefinitely?
If her family can
handle it financially, yes.
In other words, it's all
about the bottom line.
You would gladly step in
if Chastain weren't
making 100 grand a week
on Chloe's
gold-plated insurance.
The whole world is
about the bottom line.
Your white blood cell
count is improving, Lily,
but still a bit lower
than we'd like to see.
I think you need to
stay here a little longer.
No, please, Dr. Pravesh.
I just want to go home.
Dr. Hunter already
said that I could.
I'm not sure she's seen
your most recent numbers.
Your immune system is
still badly compromised, Lily.
You could easily get
another infection and
- end up back in the ER again.
- And that's a huge risk
with leukemia and what
brought you to the ER
- in the first place.
- How we doing in here?
Dr. Hunter, hi!
How you feeling, darling?
Better. Really, so much better.
Well, no fever.
- She did have one this morning.
- Exactly.
That's why I'm trying
to get her out of here.
Lily's more likely to
get another infection
here than she would be at home.
One in seven patients end up
with a hospital-based infection.
People on chemo are most at
risk for everything from the flu
- to MRSA.
- That's why I get my chemo at Dr. Hunter's clinic.
Makes sense.
It does, doesn't it?
Excuse me.
I haven't had the
chance to thank you
for taking such good
care of my patient.
- Of course.
- Wow. That's high praise.
She doesn't trust
anyone but Conrad.
Well, now I can
trust Dr. Pravesh, too.
And back in the day,
of course, we had no
way to retract skin flaps
without holding your arms
in an extremely uncomfortable
position for hours at a time
until I invented... this
automatic retractor,
which the company
named the "Bell."
Out of modesty,
of course, I demurred,
but they insisted.
Dr. Bell, can I speak
with you a moment?
Of course. How is
Congressman Dunlap?
Well, there was a complication
with his pre-op tests.
- That's concerning.
- And it appears when he fell,
he fractured a rib,
lacerated his spleen.
We can still do the transplant,
but he'll need a
splenectomy first.
And your outcomes
after splenectomy
set the national standard.
Can we count on you to scrub
in with the transplant team?
I'd love to.
All right. Thank you.
♪ ♪
Well, you know,
when I was your age,
we did not have this
technology to practice on.
I used to practice making
stitches with my hands
jammed inside a tin can, just
to simulate that tight body cavity.
Could you back up?
Your cologne.
I came to offer
you an opportunity.
I'm doing a splenectomy prior
to Dunlap's heart transplant,
and I'll need to be quick
with zero pancreatic injury
to keep his outcome in line
with my past successes,
and you are welcome to observe
and possibly even assist.
You blackmailed me.
You wouldn't help me get my visa
unless I did the robotic surgery
you were supposed to do.
Then... you took all the credit.
I'm never saving your ass again.
How's Mitch doing?
He's not dead yet.
Wait. What do you mean?
Were there
complications in surgery?
The clot was extensive.
I'm monitoring his vitals.
I'll give him another
arterial blood gas in an hour
and adjust his ventilator, but
he's not out of the woods yet.
I couldn't discharge
him, Conrad.
He's getting steadily worse.
I can barely feel his pulse.
His hands and feet are cold.
I can't... lie down.
When I do...
- it feels like I'm drowning.
- Your lungs are
building up with fluid,
because your heart
is struggling to
pump efficiently.
- I'm scared.
- Oh, you got
to hold onto that
faith of yours, Micah.
You got to stay strong.
I don't know... if I can.
Where's my miracle, Dr. Hawkins?
I'll find one.
There you are.
We're running out of time.
They're prepping Dunlap
- for surgery in an hour.
- I know.
- What are you doing?
- Nothing you need to know about.
Who's Samuel Poole?
Whatever you're
doing, don't do it.
Hey, Noni.
You are looking
lovely today, as always.
Pretty lovely yourself.
What is it? What...?
Those are cute earrings.
So, um, I need a favor.
Name it.
Can you get me
two blood samples?
I have to verify they
weren't hemolyzed
in case that messed with
the analysis, and I would
consider it a special favor
if you would do it
for me while I wait?
Anything for you, Conrad.
Trip Dunlap, the congressman?
- Mm-hmm. Mm-hmm.
- And Samuel Poole.
Okay.
All good, Noni.
- Thanks.
- Mm-hmm.
These aren't
consistent with Trip's
blood tests you
ran earlier today.
No, the incompatibility
is a rare one
that didn't show
up the first time.
Randolph, this HLA
result means that...
Oh, he'd have a life-threatening
immune reaction if exposed
to this particular donor heart.
The heart would be
destroyed in the process.
We both know this heart
won't work for Dunlap,
but can, however, still
work for Micah Stevens,
the patient who was supposed
to get it in the first place.
And Stevens doesn't
have the same HLA issue?
- No, he doesn't.
- Hmm.
This is quite a save.
What inspired you
to run the test again?
Well, I can't take the credit.
Conrad Hawkins asked me to do it
as a precaution, which leaves
us with a pretty big problem.
The press is outside waiting
to report on Dunlap's surgery.
He's in critical condition.
Who's going to go
out and tell them
we don't have a
heart for him anymore?
Nobody.
♪ ♪
To me, the people who...
He could talk a
dog off a meat truck.
Will see the gift.
He's finally helping
us do the right thing.
For all the wrong reasons.
♪ ♪
I hear Chloe's mother
agreed to donate her organs.
That's nice work, Bell.
No, I believe the
credit's all yours.
You found a patient with
an HLA incompatibility and
the same blood type as Dunlap's,
you switched the samples,
and then you told Peterson
to run the test again.
- Mm. Prove it.
- I'll have them check the vials
- for fingerprints, and then I'll run the DNA.
- Go for it.
- Micah will already have his heart.
- And you
will never practice
medicine again.
Two patients are getting
organs, two lives saved.
If you want to dirty this win
with a scandal, be my guest.
I don't.
I'll do nothing.
If I get what I want in return.
- Hi.
- Good luck, Micah.
- Mina?
- What's up?
I have to scrub in
for Micah's surgery.
I want you to take
Bell's offer instead.
Don't let him screw up the
congressman's splenectomy.
Why would you, of all people,
want me to help HODAD, the hands
- of death and destruction?
- It's not about helping him.
I'm thinking about the best
way to advance your career.
Bell's still the most
requested surgeon at Chastain.
He gets the most
interesting cases,
and he trusts you to
operate beside him.
You need the practice.
Win-win situation.
Congressman Dunlap,
he doesn't deserve to be
harmed by a botched splenectomy.
You could
potentially save a life.
Isn't that what
we're here to do?
You had me at
"advance my career."
♪ Seconds ♪
♪ Ticking off the clock ♪
♪ Counting ♪
♪ Down to when I walk ♪
♪ It's easier to
go than to stay ♪
♪ Just watch me
take that flicker ♪
♪ To flame ♪
♪ Sometimes... ♪
Dr. Okafor. Now, my approach
to this complex procedure
will die with me if
it isn't passed on
to the next generation.
We are a teaching hospital.
See one, do one,
teach one. It's our tradition.
Don't be nervous.
I'll talk you through it.
Careful not to
avulse the spleen.
♪ ♪
♪ Standing in the smoke ♪
♪ Fading into ruin ♪
♪ Nowhere left to go ♪
♪ Hanging on a feeling ♪
♪ Losing all control ♪
♪ Cannot find the healing ♪
♪ Done it all before ♪
Avoid injury to
the splenic vein.
♪ I can't help ♪
You see that? That
pulsing little worm?
That's an extra abnormal artery.
And if you don't ligate it,
the field will get bloody fast,
and you won't be able
to see what you're doing.
♪ Than I can count ♪
♪ All the bridges ♪
♪ I have found ♪
♪ I can't help
burning them down ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ Oh, oh-oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ I can't help
burning them down ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh-oh, oh ♪
♪ I can't help
burning them down. ♪
Where's Lily Kendall?
She went home.
Nic?
Dr. Hunter. I just want to
make sure you're aware
- that Lily's absolute neutrophil cell count...
- Was much better.
Really? 'Cause I
saw the numbers, and,
I mean, I just glanced at it,
- but I'm pretty sure...
- I did another draw late today.
Her count improved
substantially.
Oh. That's terrific.
Please don't question
me in front of the staff, Nic.
Oh, I'm-I'm sorry.
- I didn't mean to.
- I know you didn't.
And I know you won't
let it happen again.
Thanks.
So they let you keep the foot?
Yeah. Not ready to part with it.
Is that weird?
Well, I hope you like pepperoni.
Not with pineapple.
All right.
Give it to the nurses, then.
You leave with that pizza,
and I'll put one of
your feet in a jar.
Sit down.
Grab a slice, Doctor.
Better not be one of them
cauliflower crusts, either.
Good night, Nic.
Good night.
♪ ♪
♪ All my life I've
been searching... ♪
Nic wants a greyhound.
- Uh, no, I don't.
- Yes, you do.
Beer. Whatever's on tap.
She's being difficult.
She wants a greyhound.
Great day.
New hearts beating
in new chests.
Outlook for both
patients: highly optimistic.
And I hear Devon crushed
Independence Day?
Day's not over yet.
Hmm. Be right back.
♪ ♪
Something's wrong.
What is it?
Dr. Hunter
discharged Lily today.
But her white blood cell
count was still really low.
She said it had recovered,
but I went to check Lily's files,
and... they were missing.
Dr. Hunter keeps her
patients' records separate
on her own server at her
clinics, not at the hospital.
Why would she do that?
Most of her people
are in clinical trials,
and the drug protocols and
combinations are patent-pending.
So she owns them?
Yeah.
And stands to profit from them?
Absolutely. Anyone who discovers
a new weapon against cancer
deserves a reward,
don't you think?
♪ ♪
Can I buy you a drink?
Sure.
Bubbly water for me.
Don't tell me. You're in AA.
No, nothing like that.
I'm on call.
Oh. You're a doctor?
Oh.
Cameron.
Irving. Nice to meet you.
Hey. I'm Kyle.
Mina.
You work around here?
Yes, at the hospital.
So you're a nurse?
No. I'm a surgeon.
♪ I swear I'll be true ♪
♪ I love only you. ♪
♪ ♪
- Everybody's having a good time?
- Thank you.
Isn't that our song?
We don't have a song.
Well, let's make it this one.
♪ I ♪
♪ May not be ♪
♪ All... ♪
Thank you for today.
Every day, actually.
♪ That's worth more than gold ♪
That's it? No second
chances with you?
One strike and I'm out?
Oh, you whiffed the
ball a number of times.
How?
No sense in talking about it.
Oh, come on, Nic.
If I don't know what
I did, how can I fix it?
You can't.
It's who you are.
♪ And I'm not ashamed to say ♪
♪ That I'm gonna
love this girl... ♪
- You took a big risk today.
- And it paid off.
Yeah, well, what if
Chloe's mom hadn't agreed
to donate her
organs... What then?
Micah would have lived, and
Dunlap probably would have died.
♪ We just got to ♪
You don't have the
right to play God, Conrad.
♪ Whoa... ♪
I'm bad.
I'm so bad.
- Exactly.
- Oh, come on.
You know I'm right.
- Uh, incoming.
- In the ER,
I caught Mitch's PE,
which Irving missed,
and then I handed off 30
patients to the next shift
with no issues, and
I did the whole thing
without asking you one question.
Mm. Okay, well, are you
looking for an attaboy?
'Cause you won't get one.
You should have asked a question
before you sent Mitch for
an unnecessary thoracotomy.
Did you even see a
thoracotomy in med school?
It's when they cut someone
open in the middle of their chest
laterally all the
way to their back,
and then they peel back the skin
and literally crack
open their ribs
to get to the pleural cavity.
And poor Mitch could have
had a noninvasive femoral cath
and been home in a few days,
but now he's gonna be in
the hospital for at least a week
- enduring a hellishly painful recovery.
- Wrong.
You didn't check
Mitch's records. I did.
And it turns out he has a
hereditary platelet dysfunction,
which means a femoral cath
would have caused
him massive bleeding,
and he would have died.
So I made a fast call,
and it was the right call,
that may have saved his life.
- And you know how I know that?
- Hmm?
He's doing great in
recovery right now.
Look at this guy. He
forgot rule number one.
I didn't forget it.
I broke it.
And I will again.
Because you are
not always right.
No one is.
That's why this job
is so difficult.
And when you're wrong, I
will be the first one to tell you.
And if you don't like that...
cut me.
Right now, right here.
I don't care. End my career.
Because I am not your slave,
your shadow, or your echo.
Devon!
Congratulations, you just
passed Independence Day.
Captioned by Media
Access Group at WGBH