Previously on ER:
You're a proponent on
the National Health Plan?
If we had one, this guy'd be home with
his kids instead of fighting for his life.
That was gold.
I want these two out of my
O.R. Shirley, call Security.
Nice working with you guys.
- Bovie. Stand back.
- Wanna hook up?
- Hook up?
Prep for the M and M. I'd give you
a heads-up before I kick your ass.
Uh, is Tony there?
Sorry, he's busy right now.
- Nobody here goes to the doctor?
- Hell, no.
I just don't know
how to fix this.
Yo, Dr. K.
Hey, hey. What's up, guys?
Oh, my God, he's
so cute. Hi, Joe.
Don't let the looks fool
you. He's a tough one.
Takes after his mom.
Ain't that the truth. Let
me give you a hand, doc.
Thanks.
Babysitter couldn't make it again.
We finally decided to hire a nanny.
My mom raised eight
kids all by herself.
- Don't know how she did it.
- She available?
- What about SBO guy?
- Waiting on Surgery.
- And your chemo boy in 4?
- Oncology about a half hour ago.
Who's this, the new chief of ER?
Yep, training him
so I can retire early.
Good. We could
use some new blood.
- I'm new.
- You're too old to be new, Gates.
Excuse me, Dr. Weaver. Hi,
Courtney Brown, Channel 5.
- You got a minute?
- No. Give me a half-inch.
The station loved you and
our segment that we did.
They've given us a green
light to do some more.
Wow, that sounds cool.
Yeah, I don't think so. I'm an
ER doc, not a TV personality.
Exactly what we're
looking for. Someone real.
You'd be really great. That
piece you did was so good.
You know what? Why
don't you take over?
Pack all four quadrants
and Dawn can help you.
- Wouldn't require much time.
- Gyn has a bed but can't take PID.
- Dr. Weaver, Radiology on 2.
- Gotta take this.
I get it, you're
swamped. I'll try later?
I think he has Abby's eyes.
- Yeah, and his dad's head.
- Yeah.
- Heh.
- What? He'll grow into it.
Could you guys keep an
eye on him for a minute?
- Yeah.
Mr. Ames?
Luka.
Can I...? Can I help
you with something?
No, no.
Got a meeting with
Angela Gilliam upstairs.
Give me the other
bearing, Steve, would you?
That one should fit.
About my appeal.
- She didn't tell you?
- No, no.
Yeah.
Had to gather
some hospital files.
You're appealing the case?
Only if I have to.
You know, a settlement will save the
hospital a lot of time and a lot of money.
Look, this hasn't been
easy on any of us...
least of all you, but...
But what?
Maybe it's time to move
on. Put the past behind you.
I couldn't agree more.
I'm gonna hop up the stairs.
I'll see you around.
Can you smell my...?
You can't, but I can.
I can hear now.
I can smell it. I mean,
you can't smell it.
I can smell it.
I can smell it. I can smell it.
Tight. Keep that thing
pressed to your nose.
- When?
- I wouldn't.
- Real nice.
- Yeah, it's cool.
Score.
And the big top winner wins.
Go.
Win.
Hey.
Are those Hot Wheels?
- Want one?
- Yeah.
I got lots of Hot Wheels too.
What does this one have?
I don't know.
Number five.
- Ha-ha-ha. Beautiful.
- Get off the floor. Come on.
- Don't make me embarrass you.
- Mom, I'm racing.
Get over here now.
Come on.
Out of the way, man.
Hot oil. Third-degree
burns to the hands.
Let's go, let's go.
Exam 3's open.
You can't, but I can, you know.
I can smell them.
I know you're coming for this.
Hey!
Maybe you haven't noticed,
but you got people waiting here.
You actually got any
doctors working back there?
What is it, golf day?
Sir, please sit down.
Don't "sir" me, bitch.
Just let me see a damn doctor.
Calm down or I'll call Security.
Oh, go. Oh, oh, oh, call them.
Go ahead. I'm right here. - Hey.
- What?
- Calm down now.
You are not the only
patient here, okay?
Yeah, I can see that.
I can see that.
- You sign in?
- Signed in what?
All I got is a
little congestion.
You think you morons
can handle that?
Fill this out.
Sit down and shut up. I'll
bring you back in a few minutes.
I just got the flu,
for God's sakes.
I wanna apologize in advance
for the smell in the break room.
- Luka changed Joe's diaper in there.
- How bad is it?
- We got a men's room.
- Not carrots? I hate carrots.
You know, I said I'm
sorry. My babysitter flaked.
I feel bad enough
dragging him in here.
Hey, has Radiology
called back yet?
I don't think so.
Excuse me.
I'm here to see Dr. Luka Kovac.
How long have you
been congested?
I don't know. Does it matter?
No, I'm just making
conversation.
About a month or so.
All right, what have we got?
Temp's 99. URI symptoms.
The flu.
Deep breath for me, please.
Get that damned thing
off of me, it's freezing.
I have to take a listen, sir.
I told you,
assholes, it's the flu.
Now, just give me some antibiotics
or something and let me out of here.
Listen, Prince Charming...
quicker we check you
out, the quicker you can go.
I need to check the
oxygen in your blood.
Part of the exam.
Omit that part.
All right, look.
You have the flu...
that's an easy fix,
then you can go home.
Believe me, I want you to go.
I need you to go.
Wow, Rio.
So Chicago must be a big change.
- Mm-hm.
Have you been
here for a winter yet?
No, but I love the cold.
In Brazil, it's always sunshine.
Jeez, that must have
been hard to manage.
Why did you leave your last job?
I didn't really like New York. I
wanted a change around the scenery.
Change of scenery. You
wanted change of scenery. Heh.
Ah. Sorry. My English...
I still make mistakes. Heh.
Great. Thanks for coming by.
Discipline. Discipline.
Especially with the little boys.
This is key.
Amway money ran out
along with my husband.
So I ask myself, "Jackie,
what do you love?"
Kids. Love kids.
Crazy little bastards.
Oh, hey. Can I smoke in here?
It was the best 10 years of
my life. I really loved those kids.
I don't wanna brag, but for
all the families I've worked for...
the kids always end up calling
me Mommy by the third week.
- Ha-ha.
- Okay, great. Thanks for coming by.
What, you get lost?
Seems to be a little
problem with your heart.
That from the flu?
Normal heart's about the size
of a fist. Yours is twice that big.
I don't think you have flu.
Your congestion, shortness of
breath, definitely because of your heart.
Sorry, couldn't
find the SonoSite.
How many times do I have to tell
you? Lay down, put the gown on.
- I ain't wearing that dress.
- Then lose the shirt.
You gonna at least
buy me dinner first?
Hey, you get in a lot of fights?
Have an accident or something?
You got what look
like old fractures.
A lot of them. Few ribs.
Collarbone. Your arm.
I was an active kid.
How about the scar
and those burns?
Yeah, well...
My pop had a
two-pack-a-day habit.
Whoa, he's got a
pericardial effusion.
- A what? SAM: Fluid
around your heart.
Restricts blood flow, makes
it hard for you to breathe.
IV, two of Ativan, set
up for pericardiocentesis.
Hang on. What are you doing?
We need to do a procedure where I place
a needle into the sac around your heart.
- It's no big deal.
- What?
No. No way.
- You need this procedure.
- No, I don't.
- Yes, you do. You could die.
- No. No, not a chance.
Son of a bitch.
Where'd you get the doctor
degree, through the mail?
Hey, get out while you can
before Kevorkian starts sticking you.
Let me the hell out of here!
Now!
What can we do
for you today, sir?
Need my cholesterol
prescription filled.
Cholesterol, silent killer.
It's good you're being vigilant.
Dr. Wong from the Family Medical
Center prescribed this for you?
- And why didn't you go back to her?
- They can't take me for a few months.
Supposed to get a blood
test to check my liver...
You need to see Dr. Wong.
I'll call up, make sure they know
to give you an earlier appointment.
Doc, please. I don't know
when I can take another day off.
I work two jobs. I got his
grandma watching him all the time.
I'll call now and let them
know you're coming over.
Hope, please discharge Mr. Batista
and point him to the Family Center.
Hey, Morris, why is
Grasso still in Curtain 2?
Vertigo guy is still here?
You know, mine felt better after
meclizine. OTD in 45 minutes.
It's a first shift in a month
he hasn't killed anybody.
- My case is more complicated.
- He have an abnormal neural exam?
I just have a clinical hunch,
okay? Takes years to develop.
CT results from Radiology.
That for your vertigo guy?
It's normal, isn't it?
And we can all sleep a
bit better tonight, can't we?
Sam, could you get something
from the drug-sample closet?
There's limited samples.
Ask an Attending to...
Dr. Weaver asked me to
get it for one of her patients.
Oh, okay.
No, yeah, it's
Batista. B-A-T-I-S-T-A.
Okay, thank you.
That TV news girl,
Courtney Brown, called again.
Whoa, Channel 5 Courtney
Brown? What did she want?
She offered me a
job as a reporter.
What, you?
Of course you. What did you say?
I turned it down.
Turned down a chance to
be the next Sanjay Gupta?
Are you insane, woman?
I have no interest in fluff pieces
about sunburns and bee stings.
What's wrong? Half the patients
that come are fluff. I'm the king of fluff.
You're the best fluffer in town.
Hey, Hope, you ready
for the fecal impaction?
Sure am.
Ha.
This is an extremely
uncommon error.
Our personnel were clearly
distracted by the ongoing debate.
Reason why ER docs
should remain in the ER.
I know ER sounds a
lot like O.R., but it's not.
Our guys were there trying to
keep you from making mistakes.
Based on the information, our
decision to operate was correct.
You know what, you didn't
have sufficient information...
because you didn't allow
us to complete an evaluation.
This isn't a witch-hunt. We're here to
learn from our mistakes and improve.
You mean, their mistakes.
Okay, let's not forget that
we're on the same team here.
Oh, Dr. Gates, come on in.
- You missed the case presentation.
- Sorry, I had a patient.
You know, sorry. I just gotta...
No, that's okay. Timely
enough, Dr. Gates. No need to sit.
Come on down.
Why don't you tell us what
the differential diagnosis was...
when this patient presented?
Um... Triple A was
on the top of our list...
but there were
other possibilities.
Should have stayed a Resident.
No responsibilities, just
heal them and deal them.
That was the life.
Morris?
- Can I tell you something as a friend?
- Hmm.
Sometimes you
are such a little bitch.
You make three
times as much as I do.
And for what? To give
orders instead of take them?
Boo-hoo for you.
Mr. Batista.
We got a double coming.
Might wanna jump on.
I'll be right there,
Dr. Morris. Mr. Batista, wait.
I called the Family Care Center.
They can't take you for a month.
I'm very sorry about
all that. The system's...
Well, it needs work.
Lovastatin. Thirty pills,
20 milligrams each.
Shh. This should hold you
till your next appointment.
- Thanks a lot. HARMS:
I got a present for you.
This is us, Hope.
Unidentified male, early
20s, altercation on a bus...
blunt trauma to
the chest and face.
Ray, Malik, you take
this. Trauma 2 is open.
Sam, Hope, you're with me.
He's tachy in the 120s,
resps in the 30s, BP, 104/56.
CBC, IV, type
and cross. Let's go.
Fred Douglas, 38, blunt
trauma to the face with epistaxis.
- Son of a bitch broke my nose.
- Keep pressure.
He was yelling at some lady.
I tell him to shut up, next thing
you know, he's throwing punches.
How you doing in there, Ray?
- I'm doing good.
Could probably use a
hand when you're done.
Guy I got in a fight with, I
didn't hurt him bad, did I?
HemoCue's 12.8.
First, we look for an obvious source
of bleeding that can be cauterized.
Is it broken, doc?
It sure fee... Ugh.
God bless you.
Snuck up on me. Sorry.
You need a definitive
triple A diagnosis...
before committing an unstable
patient to major surgery.
Mortality ruptured
triple A, 90 percent.
- We don't have time for tests.
- Ultrasound can be done at the bedside.
Theoretically. Not in this ER.
Every textbook and
print says this patient...
Ultrasound in ER is
new, not in every textbook.
- Studies show it's very accurate.
- Ignore experience because a new toy?
People die with delays.
Valentine paper, 1993...
found that most patients without triple
A's still need surgery for one thing...
Most, not all.
With severe heart failure,
surgery can be fatal.
Guy's lucky all you
did was torch him.
You could've killed him.
Okay. What is your experience
in the ER with bedside ultrasound?
It's been going
on for a few years.
He's cute, but I hear
he lives with somebody.
Really?
I think he has a kid.
With final radiology interpretation,
no significant clinical disagreements.
What about for a
triple A, specifically?
Uh... Heh. I don't
know, exactly.
Though finding a gallstone is one
thing, ruptured aneurysm, quite another.
Well, if we'd seen a normal
aorta with an enlarged liver...
we would've saved the
guy the risk of surgery.
- You couldn't do it in a reasonable time.
- We weren't given a reasonable time.
He was unstable,
surgery was necessary.
- Lighting the guy on fire was necessary?
- A Bovie wasn't grounded.
- Whose fault?
- Yours.
Shouldn't even been in O.R. You
were there being a pain in the ass.
- We have protocols. You interfered.
- Our duty doesn't end.
Okay, okay. That's
enough. That's enough.
Thank you, Dr. Gates.
I think we can all see what
the real problem is here.
Providing the best care
requires communicating openly.
And when we fail to
do that, lives are lost.
I think that's something we can
all learn from today's M and M.
Crenshaw is such a little prick.
You know what? I bet
I could take him too.
I definitely think I could take
him, and you could kick his ass.
- Luka.
- You're scaring me.
I was looking for you.
Sorry I didn't get back earlier.
- Angela, you remember Abby?
- Sure. Nice to see you back at work.
Nice to be back.
So I probably should have warned
you Curtis Ames was coming in.
Okay, what's all this
about settlement?
There is no settlement.
We agreed to the meeting
as a show of good faith...
in case we went back to trial.
But don't worry, the
appeal's never gonna happen.
Ames can't even find a
lawyer to take the case.
- We're not settling. It's over.
- Good.
All right, what do we got?
Okay, hypotensive secondary...
to what looks like a
traumatic pericardial effusion.
Wow, guy's got a lot
of fluid around his heart.
Looks like I'm gonna
do a pericardiocentesis.
BP's still dropping, 88/52.
- So weird, I had one this morning.
- Okay, Malik, set me up.
- How's your guy?
- Just a bloody nose.
You say there's something
wrong with my heart?
He's awake.
Sir, I'm Dr. Morris,
Attending physician.
Wait a minute, it's
you, from this morning.
- You know him?
- Yeah... No, no.
You were here earlier?
No, I wasn't.
- Hey, Sam?
- Yeah?
He's our AMA patient
from this morning, right?
Yeah, the flu jerk.
I don't know what you
people are talking about.
I don't have the flu.
And I've never been here before.
Joe. Hey, what's it gonna be?
Good-looking Brazilian
or big mean Russian? Ooh.
Joe...
Okay. Go home.
Say bye.
Bye.
We use an ultrasound to see...
while we insert the needle into
the pericardial sac to drain the blood.
You use sound to see?
That's fascinating.
Just like bats and dolphins.
It'll release the pressure on your
heart, make it easier to breathe.
And I won't feel a thing?
Not a thing.
- Can I watch?
- Yeah, sure.
Okay, cool.
Oh, come on.
This morning, bats-and-dolphins
here was ready to rip my head off.
- What are you trying to pull, buddy?
- Why is he so angry?
Prep his chest, have
two of Versed ready.
Mr. Payton, we'll be right
back. Morris, can we talk?
Morris.
I don't know what his game is...
His game is he's kooky from a blow
to his head. He could be amnestic.
He's gotta be on
something. He's different.
Give the guy a break.
He got his ass kicked.
He didn't want that
procedure this morning.
Maybe he's really pissed off at
you, Archie. Wouldn't be the first time.
Now, I know this may
sound a little corny...
but I always catch more flies
with honey, you know what I mean?
That's good. That's good, Ray.
I like that approach.
You'll make a great
Attending someday, my man.
I'm sorry, I know my
wallet's in here somewhere.
Damn it. AMES: I got that.
- And can I get a Polish please?
- No, that's okay.
Don't worry. I insist, really.
It's not necessary, really.
Well, you got your hands
full. It's the least I could do.
It's just a hot dog.
My mama taught me random acts of
kindness make the world a better place.
Well, I can't argue
with that. Thank you.
- What is he, about 6 months?
- Five and a half.
- He's really cute.
- He's got pipes you wouldn't believe.
Are you driving your
mom crazy? No, no.
Hoo. Hoo.
Frog. Ribbit.
This one yours?
Here you go.
- Excuse me, Dr. Weaver?
- Yeah.
Something is weighing on my
heart, and I just can't take it anymore.
What's the problem?
I gave Oscar Batista
Lovastatin samples.
That sweet, hard-working man, I
was afraid he would stop taking pills...
and come back here with
a heart attack or stroke...
- Hope.
- That little boy.
Reminded me how
moved I was by your piece.
- Thought some act of kindness might...
- Okay, okay, okay.
- And please forgive me, doctor...
- Okay, okay, stop.
You did a good thing.
Really.
There might be
hope for you, Hope.
You told me those drug samples
were for Dr. Weaver's patient.
Well, they were, technically.
Well, technically,
you lied to me.
There are rules for breaking
the rules, and rule number one...
is that you never, ever lie
to the nurses, you got me?
I'm so sorry.
Fell off a ladder at work.
Dude wasn't paying attention,
so I had to pay the price.
Oh, sounds like a dangerous job.
No, carpenter.
It's tough doing it
with one arm, though.
Well, sprains
heal pretty quickly.
Yeah, that's what they
told me at the hospital.
Uh... I'm headed
for the red line.
Oh, I'm headed this way.
Well...
- Nice to meet you.
- Ha-ha. You too.
- And thank you for the hot dog.
- It's my pleasure.
Catch you later, Joe. Ha-ha.
Hey, any messages
for me yet, Frank?
No, Morris, the TV-producer
lady has not called back yet.
You ask me one more time, I'm gonna
slap you so hard you turn brunette.
Have you got that?
- Position's been filled.
- What position?
Stop calling the station.
I'm getting complaints.
Oh, that position,
right. They filled it, huh?
- Mm-hm.
- Who did they find so fast?
- Me.
- You? I thought you turned it down.
Yeah, well, I changed my mind.
Figured it was about time someone
put something worthwhile on television.
So, Smitty, how long
you had the rash?
About two weeks now.
- Got any food allergies?
- No.
- You on any medications?
- Just my blood-pressure pills.
All right, come on. Have a seat.
What kind of pills?
Right.
Oh, you see, that's the problem.
Rash is a common reaction to enalapril.
Who prescribed these?
Doc up at the clinic put me
on them about 10 years ago.
This and something else.
- Ten years ago? Who gave you these?
- Mm-hm.
See, my man, T-bone. You know T.
Smitty, you can't take other people's
medications, man. It's not safe.
- Everybody does it.
- Everybody who?
Up at First Mission Baptist, Pastor
Watkins does a drug-exchange program.
You come up there sometime,
man gives a powerful...
Okay, hold on, hold on.
He does a drug-exchange program?
Hell, yeah. I ain't
got insurance.
You know how
much this stuff costs?
You can't possibly think
ultrasound was contraindicated.
- I do if it can't be done immediately.
- Could've told me before M and M.
Didn't realize I had to
point out the obvious.
I can't win with you.
- Oh. Finally, we agree on something.
- Finally.
- Yes.
Don't take piss out of me.
- Piss? Piss?
- Yes. Yes.
Yup, you've got a nice fluid
pocket. This is gonna be a snap.
Sam, draw up
some 1 percent lido.
Whoa.
- You're gonna feel a pinch.
- Okay, before I start, just a few things.
- I don't want a shot.
- Main risks here, bleeding and infection.
You could infect my heart?
Sterile technique makes it unlikely.
- Mickey, calm down.
No. Aah.
Look, what about bleeding? I
have trepidation about bleeding.
Well, it's only a minor risk, because
we're using such a small needle.
Well, not so small, but thin.
And you'll be all numbed
up so you won't feel a thing.
- Relax.
- No, no. Stop it.
Okey-dokey, let's do this.
Get that thing away
from me, you clown.
I told you, I don't want that.
- You agreed to the procedure.
- Screw that.
Mr. Payton.
And stop calling me that.
My name's Clyde Sandberg.
You people got short-term
memory loss or something?
Huh?
- You ambushed me.
- You were spewing absurdities.
- Do you not like me?
- You're a wanker.
- A wanker. Ouch.
- Yeah, you're cocky, arrogant.
- And you're not smooth as you think.
- I'm not?
- No, you're not.
- I never said I was.
- Mm.
I called the other night
and a woman answered.
Yeah, I can explain that.
Now would be a good time.
Here, here, bats-and-dolphins
guy, I figured it out.
- It's DID.
- What?
Dissociative Identity Disorder.
Multiple personalities?
Psych make that diagnosis?
No, I paged them.
They haven't come.
So this is based off of what? Your
extensive psychiatric expertise?
No, he's a classic presentation.
Old abuse injuries,
keeps changing his name.
Maybe it's you that
needs a psych evaluation.
No, I'm serious, Ray. We
have to double-doctor this guy.
Listen, he keeps refusing
treatment, that effusion will kill him.
Who knows how long Psych will take?
By the time their Resident sees him...
they present to the
Attending, could be hours.
Double-doctoring,
that's a big deal.
Can't we treat with
NSAIDs and steroids?
He's refusing vital treatment. And
that is grounds for a double-doctor.
Come on, get with me here.
- What, so I'm back on the case now?
- Yeah.
Huh.
Look, I'll tell you what.
I'll talk to him.
I'll try and get some sort of read,
but maybe you should hang back.
You already pissed
him off enough today.
So I have a few
questions for you.
Can you tell me what day it is?
Thursday.
Month and year?
You know, they got this new
thing out called a calendar.
My freaking God.
November, 2006.
- Do you know where you are?
- What is this, Romper Room?
I see stupid and
retard and jerk-off.
I'm at County General Hospital.
- I'm not double-doctoring.
- He's gonna get worse.
He's hypotensive with
reduced cardiac output.
He hates doctors,
especially you.
You wanna tie him, stick
a needle in his chest?
- If it'll save his life, hell, yeah.
- Ha-ha. I am out, Archie.
Fine, I'll get somebody else.
Hey, Pratt.
No, no, no. Hasta la bye-bye.
Pratt, I need you to sign
off on a double-doctor.
- Got a foster kid?
- No, he's a competent adult.
Got pericardial effusion
and doesn't want treatment.
Morris wants to get
medieval because he thinks...
- I think he's DID.
- Multiple personalities.
Yeah, I know.
What did Psych say?
They're MIA.
You know that
multiple personality...
Dissociative Identity Disorder.
- Yeah, some docs don't think it exists.
- There's ton of literature to support it.
- Okay, his vitals?
- Systolic's holding in the 90s.
- And mental status?
- Alert and oriented.
Tox screen and CT?
Clear.
Gotta treat him conservatively.
Wait for Psych, it's their call.
You want me to be thorough.
That's what I'm doing.
Pratt, listen to me
for one second. Pratt.
If patient presents within a week of
surgery, it's considered bounce-back.
Make sure bounce-backs...
Hey, can I speak
to you for a sec?
Wound seroma. Removing the
staples and packing the dermis.
I wasn't actually
talking to you.
Oh. Um...
Okay, go ahead.
I'll just get started.
So how's Surgery treating you?
Like a stepchild.
Radiology's looking
better every day.
It'll be over soon enough. I
hated my surgical rotation, anyway.
So do you like hockey?
Tonsil or ice?
- Ice.
- Oh.
Mm. Too bad.
But, yeah, I'll settle
for a Hawks game.
He's still refusing treatment?
Last BP was 84/50, and he's
developed pulsus paradoxus.
I found his old file.
Willis Payton is his real name,
probably be the host personality.
This Clyde character
must be one of his alters.
He was here a bunch of
times between '88 and '96.
Foster kid, abuse-related
injuries, some bad ones too.
It's classic DID history.
Psych's still a no-show?
I know everybody down
here thinks I'm a joke.
You know, if Pratt said
DID, he'd be a genius.
But I know that
I'm right about this.
And all I can do is suck
on it and watch this guy die.
You did what you could.
And you're not a joke, Archie.
You're an Attending.
Thank you.
Was a time when that
mountain seemed so high...
like it stretched up to the
pearly gates themselves.
Promised land seemed like an idea,
like no matter how hard we worked...
it was only sand
between our fingers.
But we're still here.
Proud and strong, Lord
have mercy, we're still here.
But we got a whole
lot of work to do.
Because the more things change,
the more they stay the same.
Young brother in the back.
You're new. Stand up
and introduce yourself.
No, no, you. Ha-ha-ha.
Evening, everyone.
I'm Greg Pratt.
Welcome, brother Pratt.
Come up front. Nice to see young
folk in the evening service, ain't it?
Your heart's getting
worse, you know.
Here we go again.
No. You need me to spell it?
If you keep refusing treatment,
it's gonna go down one of two ways.
One, doctors are gonna come in
here, tie you down and do the procedure.
They can't touch
me, I got rights.
Or two, we get to watch you die.
Fun for you.
There's a third option.
You give consent, we fix
your heart and you go home.
All we wanna do is help.
Yeah, you've been
loads of help so far.
- I know you're scared.
- No, I ain't scared of nothing.
I know you've been hurt...
a lot.
But you are safe here.
I know you don't wanna
trust us, but you can.
I promise.
I was...
Was...
Was I sleeping?
No.
I lost time.
I lost time again.
Willis?
Yeah?
Clyde's been giving
us a hard time.
Oh.
I thought he was gone.
You know about Clyde?
Yeah.
My friends told me about him.
He's very negative.
Well, Clyde doesn't
want us to help you.
So all we could do was
give you some medicine...
but that's not working too well.
Um... Wha...?
Can you...?
Can you still fix me?
Willis, I need
Clyde's permission.
I can't make him
do anything. I can't.
We can't start and stop
again. We're running out of time.
No.
No, no, no.
Willis.
Damn it, let me talk
to Clyde right now.
Do not make me hurt
you. Let me talk to Clyde.
How many times I gotta
tell you to get off me, bitch?
Huh? How many times? Huh?
I saw Willis.
- He's letting us do the procedure.
- He's a pansy.
Yeah, well, he's brave enough
to let us stick a needle in his heart.
Piss off, bitch.
Fine.
You be a tough guy all the
way to your funeral. I'm done.
Hey.
You stick my heart, that
means I get out of here, right?
Yup.
Do it. I told you, I
ain't scared of nothing.
The drug-exchange program is only
for people who have prescriptions...
but can't afford the drugs.
Smitty's prescription was 10
years old, and he had enalapril.
Enalapril is not the first drug of choice
for black folks with high blood pressure.
Look, I suggest that you
start an exercise program.
Get your congregation to stop eating
salt and fried foods and start exercising.
Trust me, you'll do a
whole lot more good.
We don't just help people
with high blood pressure.
We have diabetics,
asthmatics, you name it.
Look, what you're doing
is dangerous, okay?
Not to mention illegal.
I have an obligation to
this community, Dr. Pratt.
These people are shackled by a
system over which they have no control.
- Yeah.
- The one thing I will not do is nothing.
Excuse me, Dr. Morris?
- Can I ask your advice on something?
- Yeah.
I lied to Samantha about something,
and now she's really steamed.
Oh, bad move.
Piss one nurse off, piss
them all off, like the Mafia.
You know, whenever I'm
in a precarious situation...
I always ask myself,
"What would Jesus do?"
Right.
What would Jesus do
if the nurses hated him?
Well, he would do the
right thing, of course.
That's the problem. See, I
thought I was doing the right thing.
I guess I just did
it the wrong way.
Hey, the story of my life.
You know, sometimes it doesn't
matter how much we kick and scream.
Even when we're right.
The prophet is without
honor in his own land.
Matthew 13:54.
Oh, I love that one.
Big Matthew fan.
You have a good
night, Dr. Morris.
Feeling better?
Drained half a liter of fluid
from around your heart.
Blood pressure and
pulse are back to normal.
Soon as a bed opens up,
we'll get you upstairs to a room.
So you're doing great.
You got my glasses?
Let me check. Yeah.
Okay.
That kid gonna be okay?
Who?
Yeah. I'm sure he is.
Looks like he's leaving.
He was racing a Hot Wheels.
His mom, she was mean.
Um...
Willis?
My name's Andre.
I like Hot Wheels.
I wish his mom wasn't so mean.
Hey, hey.
Don't tell my dad
I'm here, okay?
He can be pretty mean too.
Yeah.
Your secret's safe with me.
Okay?
It's kind of dark in here.
You're not gonna leave, are you?
No.
No way, buddy, no.
I'm here all night.
That's good.
So, what kind of
Hot Wheels you got?
All kinds. I collect them.
Yeah?
I used to collect them too.
What kind you got?
I used to have a '57 Chevy.
- Heh. I got that one.
- You got that.
Shelby Cobra.
Got it.
Okay, all right.
'65 Mustang Fastback.
Heh. I got two.
- You got two?
- Yeah.
Wow.
I used to have three, but
I gave one to my friend.
You'll have to give one to me. I
don't think I have mine anymore.
Okay, I'll give it to you.
What else did you have?