Previously on the resident...
So that means we're going
to have to talk about
hospice. Don't. Not yet.
Oh, you can have
hospice for months.
It's a great service
that most people.
Wait too long to use.
I wouldn't mind a
kid a lot like you.
You want me to be
your sperm donor?
Thank you, Emily.
We'll pass this up To
the complaint division.
And discuss the status
Of the investigation.
How is she?
Well, I'll let her
tell you herself.
- Hey, carol.
- Conrad.
Come and meet my hospice
nurse. This is janaya.
Hello, dr. Hawkins.
We met years ago,
When my father was A
patient before he passed.
Darius purcell.
Yeah, I remember him. You
were in nursing school then.
Now she takes care.
Of dying folk like me.
Mom.
Aj gets prickly when
I use the "D" word.
Dr. Austin, I need you.
To help me review
some med dosages.
And update carol's charts.
Before I go.
Hey, I'll be right back, mom.
Mm.
Anything I can do for you?
Oh, I have everything I need.
It's aj I'm worried about.
He wanted me in hospice,
But now he can't seem.
To face what we
both know is ahead.
This is very hard
for him, Conrad.
Well, of course it
is. He loves you.
And he has been in the
business Of saving people.
For a long time.
I'm a realist.
I have one clear goal.
I want all the time I have
left To spend with him.
And no pain. That's all.
But he can't seem to
stop trying to fix.
What can't be fixed.
I'll talk to him.
Good news, dr. Devi.
Your body's responding
well To the hormones.
Your follicles
are maturing well.
We should be able to retrieve
The eggs within the week.
I can't believe this
is all happening.
We hope. But a
first-time course of ivf
- only has a 33% success rate.
- Dr. Devi is correct.
It's important to manage
Your expectations, padma.
The path to motherhood Is
not always an easy one.
I know, I know. I just...
- I want this baby so badly.
- It's all I want for you, too.
Once we have the
eggs from dr. Devi,
We can fertilize
them and choose.
The viable embryo To
be implanted into you.
Uh, one last question: Will
your donor sperm arrive
- in a test tube or...
- oh, no, no, my donor's here, in the hospital.
- He's a, he's a doctor.
- Great.
And he is available to come
in During the egg retrieval.
So we can create embryos
As quickly as possible?
I hope. He has a
personal situation.
Which makes it a
bit complicated.
Yeah, if he's, um, unavailable
Due to a family emergency,
Can we... Can we wait?
I'm afraid not.
In that instance,
We would have to
freeze the eggs.
What's wrong?
I haven't been able to reach
Aj yet to finalize details.
- What details?
- Just little things.
You're blinking.
Too many blinks.
Come on, that's your tell. Talk.
Aj hasn't fully committed
To be the sperm donor yet.
We just lied to dr. Johnson?
Okay, calm down. She's
a doctor, not a pujari.
Have a little
faith. The universe
- has a way of working things out.
- No.
You need to work this out.
The universe is not
paying attention.
Talk to dr. Austin today.
Okay? If he's not all
in, You need to know.
You're so bossy.
Okay.
Hey.
My mother is taking
Escalating doses of morphine,
And we don't even know
Her kidney function.
You think maybe I should
Switch to hydromorphone?
Uh, that depends.
Are you worried about
Long-term complications.
Or focused on keeping
her Comfortable for now?
I-I don't think there's
Any harm in running labs.
To check her kidney function.
Well, there's no harm,
But I think the key.
Is to ask yourself,
Is there any benefit?
Will this bring her
More comfort or less?
Look, I-I know there's no fix.
I-I know where this is going,
I just want to spend as much
Time with my mother as I can.
There's nothing
wrong with that, man.
Of course not, but your
mom Is worried about you.
More than anything else.
She's worried about
How you're taking this.
She told you that?
What was that? Mom!
Oh, she's seizing.
Let's get her on her side.
- Hospice left you lorazepam, right?
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
It's in the, uh, It's
in the medicine cabinet.
Okay.
Hey, mom, you're
gonna be all right.
So, tell me what happened
On your camping trip.
I was heading to the
river For a morning dip.
When I caught my
big toe on a root.
I felt a pop in my
ankle And I went down.
- And you were barefoot?
- Bare everything.
- Oh.
- We're not nudists.
We were earthing.
Reconnecting to earth's
Electromagnetic field.
Through bare skin.
Sounds silly, but it works.
101.2.
Patient is spiking a fever.
That can't be from his ankle.
Bp is 83/50.
- Um, okay, uh...
- and dropping.
- Uh, it's...
- dr. Pravesh?
What's the problem?
Bp is dropping rapidly.
Dr. Pravesh is here
To take a closer look.
Do you hear that ringing?
- He's going down.
- One liter of lr.
And get that norepi pump
Next to his bedside.
Let's go.
I think it's best To
call the hospice nurse.
Have her come back
and take over.
Yeah, but what if
it's a brain bleed?
We know the cancer has
spread To her brain,
So then that wouldn't
be unexpected.
She could be hyponatremic.
She hasn't been taking
in Enough electrolytes.
- Aj...
- no, if there's any chance
I can get her a few extra
weeks, A few extra days,
Even a few extra hours...
Any intervention now
could cause harm.
Well, I got to try.
As an investigator For
the state medical board,
My job is to weigh The
merits of the case.
And this case is clear.
Emily benesch was irreparably
Injured by dr. Bosley.
When I reviewed common outcomes
For the surgery in question...
Spinal, neurological,
high risk...
It appears miss
benesch's outcome is...
Is not at all unusual.
Paralysis is not unusual?
I mean, surely you know
How ludicrous that sounds.
Did you even speak with Emily?
The goal of my investigation
Is to remain impartial.
And unbiased.
Right, well, you only took
Statements from experts.
Provided by the defendant.
You've become emotionally
Involved in this case, dr. Bell.
It's blinding you
to the reality.
That what happened To this
patient, while tragic,
Is not the fault of her surgeon.
This case is closed.
Bryce came in here with A
pulled tendon in his ankle,
And has developed fevers,
Hypotension requiring pressors.
And increasing agitation.
The broad-spectrum antibiotics.
Haven't really helped
With what's going on.
This muscle spasm
happened In the past hour,
So I checked his electrolytes,
And they're all in normal range.
His-his thyroid is normal, too.
Have you been doing.
Any intense exercising lately?
I meditate, go for walks.
We've been working
Through the kama sutra.
Sounds like quite a regimen.
Percussive myoedema.
Touch your chin to
your chest for me?
The stiff neck is new.
Bryce, we're gonna
run some tests.
To check for an infection In
your central nervous system.
And we're gonna start With
a lumbar puncture, okay?
There you go. Breathe.
Good, good.
Just breathe.
There you go.
- I almost got it.
- Breathe.
I brought kale and apple.
Oh, my god. What are
you doing to him?
I'm needle-phobic.
I can't watch.
- Here.
- No, get that away from...
I feel sick.
He really doesn't
like that drink.
It's triggering a
physical reaction.
He's afraid of it.
Hydrophobia.
Bryce, we have to
test you for rabies.
Just one second, love.
I got you.
I got you, I got you.
I know, I know. I got you.
Just a little bit.
- Mm.
- It's okay.
She's not getting
enough calories.
I've tried five other flavors
And she wouldn't touch them.
But this one, chocolate
raspberry chia,
I think this is the one.
Uh, you might want To
stick it in the freezer.
She just fell asleep.
She could be tired
from the pain meds.
And I know that also
affects appetite.
Or her body is
requiring less energy.
Less input, less output.
As she begins to enter
A hibernation state.
Dr. Austin, I'm not just
here For your mother.
I'm here for you, too.
So, if you have any questions...
How much longer does she have?
Could be a week, or a few days.
Her metabolic functions
will be telling.
But she'll also give
us signs as well.
She may want to
open up and start.
To talk about things She's
never discussed before.
She may get a burst of energy.
We call that "Planes,
Trains and automobiles."
If your mom starts
Making plans for a trip,
That usually means
she's ready to go.
I don't know how you do it.
You know, your job
Seems incredibly hard.
And being a surgeon is easy?
I can solve problems
with a scalpel.
You know, I can find a cure.
There's always an answer.
But waiting for death to come.
A-and not trying to do
Anything to stop it, I don't...
I don't know how to do that.
All you have to do Is
follow your mother's lead.
He's positive.
- Bryce has rabies.
- Rabies?
But that's so impossibly rare.
The odds of a doctor seeing A
rabies patient over the course.
Of their career is
one in 325 million.
O-okay, we know the
rabies virus spreads.
To the brain through
the nerve cells,
- and once it's there...
- it multiplies rapidly,
Causing severe inflammation
In the brain and the spine.
It's 99.9% fatal if it's not
Treated almost immediately.
Only 11 patients have survived.
Clearly the odds Aren't
in bryce's favor,
But people have
been saved before.
So, now it's all about When
Bryce contracted the virus.
Uh
- What?
- During intake,
He told me that he went camping.
Naked. No tent, no sleeping bag.
It's some kind of
an earth-love thing.
He could've been bitten By
a bat and never noticed.
I wish you told us this sooner.
I didn't think...
I'm sorry, I screwed up.
Let's find the bite.
The further away From the
central nervous system,
The longer it takes the virus
To reach the brain, okay?
Every second counts.
Why is he being tied up?
Bryce never hurt anyone.
You're making him
feel claustrophobic.
I know it's hard to
see him like this,
But rabies can cause aggression.
It's safer for everyone,
Including Bryce.
We're gonna give him lorazepam
- to relax him, okay?
- Bryce, we're looking for a bite.
It may be so small,
like a scratch,
Something you wouldn't
Have even noticed.
I don't know. I don't know, I...
Bryce, tell me,
how do you sleep?
What do you mean?
With my eyes closed.
He means back, side,
- stomach?
- Side.
- Okay.
- Let's go.
All right, here.
There's some puncture marks.
We need to get as
much hrig as possible.
Into this infected
area Beneath the bite.
Bryce, we're gonna give
you A series of injections.
A vaccine and some
immunoglobulins.
We're gonna repeat
them every 12 hours.
You're gonna get pretty sore.
Those needles are huge.
And if he's already sick,
- then why are you giving him a vaccine?
- Janice.
We're trying to stop the virus.
From spreading to
his nervous system.
If we can slow The
progress of the virus,
Then we have a chance
at treating him.
That'll work? You'll cure him?
If he got here in time.
Oh, god.
No, I-I... I can't...
I can't handle this. I...
I can't watch him
get worse and worse.
Oh, my god.
The board lied.
Promised the patient
A fair investigation.
Instead, case closed,
no further review.
Unbelievable.
So I did more
investigating myself.
And the names of the same Five
doctors, including bosley,
Come up again and again.
These are career bad apples
With multiple complaints.
Of the worst kind.
You remember that surgeon
They called dr. Death?
Of course. He maimed And
killed patients in Texas.
His colleagues knew it. They
took it to the state board.
And the state board did nothing.
But he got caught.
When someone leaked
The story to the press.
There you are.
I've been texting you nonstop.
I know. I got your
5,000 messages.
Don't worry, I didn't call aj.
I heard about his mom and
I'm respecting their privacy.
Good.
Okay, so... Next steps?
We call dr. Johnson and we tell
Her we're freezing the eggs.
I'm not willing to give up On
this cycle of ivf just yet.
It's not giving up.
A lot of people
freeze their eggs.
They do it because the timing.
Of making a baby
is just not right.
Last week, I went to
the farmers' market.
And I got bagels.
Okay? They were fresh
Out of the oven, perfect.
But I didn't think I'd be
able To eat them all in time.
Before they went
stale, so I froze them.
And guess what
happened the next day?
You microwaved one and ate it?
It wasn't the same.
Padma,
That is a ridiculous metaphor,
And you cannot expect a donor
To just fall into your lap.
It is really hard for me to talk
To you when you get like this.
- Get like what?
- Overly logical Leela.
Trust the universe. No freezing.
He snapped the restraint.
Push two of lorazepam
And five of haloperidol.
On it.
We're treating him
too late, aren't we?
I hope not.
This virus is a
terrible way to die.
Hey. What are you
doing on your feet?
Dust inflames my sinuses.
I thought I told you last night.
You need a haircut.
Well, you also called me dad,
So I figured I
would let it ride.
And come on, you really should
Get back in bed, mom, come on.
Okay? Come on.
Jana ya said your peach
tree Was blooming.
I'd like to see it.
Okay.
We'll get you in the wheelchair.
And we'll move
you to the window.
No, son.
Hear my words. I feel good.
I want to go outside.
Okay.
We'll make it a field trip.
All right, let's do it.
So far, I've identified.
Two major hurdles
in rabies protocols.
We have antiviral effectiveness
And neuroprotection.
So once the virus enters.
His spinal cord or the brain,
The antivirals are ineffective.
The meds can't pass through
The blood-brain barrier.
- Patient dies.
- So, what if we made
- the barrier more porous?
- How?
Something I learned
in clinical trials.
Some brain cancer studies
Show that mannitol.
Can actually poke
holes in the barrier
- so that the chemo can get in.
- Yeah, poke enough holes.
In the blood-brain barrier and
The antivirals can seep through.
That's an incredible long shot.
And it doesn't explain
how we preserve.
The nervous system Long
enough for it to work.
So we need to figure out
A way to cool him down.
Without heavy sedation.
What if we lower his
temperature From the inside out?
We place an iv cooling
probe In a blood vessel.
Warm him from the outside.
With blankets and
meds for shivering.
So we take the existing
rabies protocol.
And tweak it just a bit.
I mean, it could work.
I mean,
It has never been done before.
This is completely hypothetical.
And the minute Bryce was bitten,
Hypothetical became
his only chance.
- Thanks for coming.
- Flattered you remembered me.
You wrote that "Dr.
Reality star" piece.
I framed it.
That's kind of you,
since it was, uh,
Shall we say, a
balanced profile?
Well, I appreciated
your honesty.
- That's why I called you.
- Look, we've sniffed around.
The medical board's
incompetence Many times before,
But without any proof,
We never get anywhere.
I have case files.
And patients that all
Are willing to talk.
And I thought if you
published Their stories...
The board is appointed
by the governor,
Approved by the state senate.
You understand
that, by doing this,
You'll be rocking
a very big boat.
Oh, yeah, it's an ocean liner.
You know, all doctors
Benefit from the shield.
The white coat provides.
And I have, too.
Malpractice breaks Our
oath to do no harm,
But it also destroys the public
Trust in even the best doctors.
And the-the bad ones are few.
But they need to be weeded out.
And the guard dogs
need to be reminded.
Of who they're meant to protect.
You mind if I record this?
I'm counting on it.
Heavenly.
You have a green thumb.
Well, I have a
well-paid landscaper.
You've got your career,
Your beautiful home,
Your well-paid landscaper.
Is that all you need?
Well, if-if you're inquiring
About my dating life,
I-I assure you,
it's-it's quite robust.
Dating is fine.
But you have to open
Yourself up to love.
What about a family?
Bah.
Don't you worry about me, mom.
- Mm.
- I'm gonna be okay.
I want you to be more than okay.
You know what we need?
A trip to butter bean
beach in savannah.
We haven't been in so long.
Yeah, I don't think We
can manage that, mom.
I've turned a corner, aj.
We'll bring home
a pile of shells.
Come on, baby. Let's go.
Mom, you... You okay?
Need some water?
Can you get me back inside?
Yes, yes, yes, yes.
Rabies.
Crazy, huh?
I heard you did the intake.
More like blew the intake.
I'm trying to convince myself.
That it wasn't what will Kill
him because no matter what,
Too many days had
passed since the bite,
And he came in too late.
All right.
Temperature probe is set.
We're gonna start Cooling
you down now, okay?
In order to protect your airway.
We're gonna intubate you
With a breathing tube.
And you'll enter A
light hibernation state.
You'll feel drowsy.
And your breathing And
heart rates will fall.
Like a bear. Love bears.
Yeah, like a bear.
But we need to keep you awake
As long as possible. So,
Dr. Bonner is
gonna sit with you,
And she's gonna perform
Serial neurochecks.
Basically, that just means
She's gonna talk to you.
And keep you awake. All right?
Listen, we-we were
just outside, right?
- She-she was lucid, she was happy...
- remember what I said.
At the very end,
patients can rally.
And have their best
day in a long time.
Your mother is
dying. Maybe today,
Maybe tomorrow or the next
day. We don't know when.
She is accepting,
no longer fighting.
That is a huge win.
Now, dr. Austin, it's your turn.
What-what should I do?
Don't burden her
with your grief.
Honor all that she
is and has been.
Say any words left unsaid.
The last thing they
lose Is their hearing,
So talk to her, if you wish.
Hey, ma.
You know, I don't know...
If I've ever said
thank you enough.
Everything that I have become...
Is because of you.
I think all this time
I've been afraid of losing you.
But these last couple of days,
You have shown me that
I can never lose you.
And...
You will not lose me.
'Cause I will be
here by your side.
I'm not gonna leave you.
We've done all this...
And it looks like Bryce
is gonna die anyway.
Should we have already quit?
You're tired.
You haven't slept in days.
Come here.
How's padma?
Depressed about aj.
Feeling the loss of this chance.
But she'll understand The
story is just beginning.
She'll come around
to freezing the eggs.
Hmm.
What if I offered to
be the sperm donor?
You can't be serious.
Why not?
Doesn't it solve
everyone's problems?
Wouldn't it help us, too,
In the end?
No, Devon.
My egg and your sperm
Would make our baby.
We couldn't give that baby away.
Well, I agree it would be
Complicated, but hear me out.
We would be the-the
fun Uncle and auntie.
Everybody wins,
especially the kid.
You're tired.
I'm going to have to
Believe that because this is
- a truly awful idea.
- Why?
Because I couldn't handle that.
And I'm utterly
astonished that you can.
It puts my sister between
us In a bizarre way.
It affects my relationship
With her profoundly,
And with the kid,
and with you and me.
Can't you just
discuss it with her?
No.
I don't want to talk
about Any of this at all.
You like music? You
have a favorite band?
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Stay with me. Uh, how about
I try to guess what it is?
Grateful dead?
Okay, um, how about phish?
You seem like a phish guy.
Oxygen is dropping.
The vent's starting
to take over.
Page pravesh and Hawkins.
Let them know he's got
signs Of papilledema.
Increased pressure in the brain.
I think we need
neuro right away.
Good call. Not
very many doctors.
Would have caught it off
of Such a subtle finding.
Can you give him The
extra ventricular drain?
We can, but there's a limit to
How much csf fluid he can lose.
If the pressure shoots
up Too high, too fast...
I'm not sure I'll
be able to stop it.
This patient is young,
Otherwise healthy.
He's got good brain plasticity.
No signs of herniation.
So you're saying
we risk the evd.
I am.
We push ten milligrams
of Ketamine.
And midazolam to drop his
Temperature by two more degrees.
Okay, let's do it.
Mom?
Devon.
What?
He's getting better.
His antibody titers are rising.
His body's fighting
this infection.
His intracranial pressure
Is in normal range.
This is amazing.
We won't know what deficits
He'll have until we.
Bring him out of the
Hypothermic state, but...
These are really good signs.
Okay, uh, we start slow.
We raise his core
body temperature up.
Half a degree at a time until
He regains consciousness.
Frank, how's the
morning treating you?
How dare you go to the press?
You've had it in
for other doctors.
From the moment you
set foot On our board.
Not true. I love
doctors. Good doctors.
You think I can't
get a story out.
To counter the one you leaked?
You want to start a
media war, Be my guest.
And we'll be asking The
governor to relieve you.
Of your position.
Enjoy your little
victory While it lasts.
No, it's our little
victory, frank.
Bad doctors will now
be Brought to justice.
That's what we
all wanted, right?
That's the job.
Leela.
What's this?
An apology.
I've had time to think.
Freezing is the right option.
It's also the only option.
Apology accepted.
I would have loved to
find Another donor.
A doctor or a nurse,
Or just a nice guy
hanging around.
You're so lucky to
have found Devon.
You have no idea, Leela.
I know he's not perfect, but...
But he's gonna make A
great father one day.
And you'll never have to
wonder About who's gonna be.
Part of your baby.
If you ever decide To
have a family, that is.
You'll find a new
donor. Someone great.
When the time is right.
And he's back.
Welcome back, buddy.
Welcome back. I'm Kimberly gund
- shh!
- Joined now by dr. Randolph bell,
chastain memorial surgeon
And now former member
- of georgia's state medical board.
- Thank you for having me.
There's quite a
scandal unfolding.
Lack of oversight.
Doctors who should
lose their licenses
are still practicing.
The board doing nothing
To protect the patients
- they are tasked to protect.
- Oh, it doesn't end there.
The governor and politicians
All over Georgia,
who are supposed to make sure
That the board does its work,
are bought and paid for
By every single entity
that stands to lose
In a malpractice suit.
And there are many.
Hospitals, doctors, insurance
Companies; The list is long.
- And it is full of deep pockets.
- Finally!
The medical industrial
complex Gives more money
than any other single
donor, Including the nra.
It just has to stop.
I understand only 2% Of
all malpractice cases
are ever reviewed By
the state medical board.
Break down for us, if you will,
how everyday citizens are
Supposed to get the attention
- of the board.
- Well, that's at the very - heart of this, isn't it?
Because most people don't know
That the state medical board
is there to protect patients.
Who knew?
He just called out The
whole medical board.
He just called out
The freaking governor.
That's my man.
You're tracking
much better, Bryce.
And you have some
intentional movement.
In all four of your limbs.
And it may not seem like it yet,
But that is monumental.
The virus did a number
On your nervous system,
But you just beat one of
The most fatal diseases
- on the planet, man.
- Yes, you did.
And you're a young guy
With a young brain.
With the ability
to rewire itself.
I spoke to the rehab facility.
They're gonna roll out The
red carpet for you, Bryce.
You're a medical celebrity.
You know, people are
saying You ought to have.
A whole wing dedicated
To this success story.
The Hawkins-pravesh
rabies Treatment facility.
You mean the
pravesh-Hawkins facility.
Ha-ha, I like hers better.
But honestly, if I never see
Another rabies patient again.
It'll be too soon.
Excuse me a sec, guys.
Congratulations.
I'm so proud of you.
It was a team effort.
So, uh
- are things weird between us?
- Not weird.
And we don't even
have to discuss it.
Because padma agreed
To freezing the eggs.
Oh.
I thought you said Her
biological clock was ticking.
What can I say?
She hit snooze.
You know my sister.
Hmm.
Devon, did you really want
To father my sister's child?
No, I-I...
I don't know, I just...
I don't know, I just want
To help in any way I can.
I have to get to surgery.
Congrats again on your patient.
Hey.
- Look at that.
- Italian. Gigi's favorite.
And she insisted It
was your favorite, too.
Of course. Come on in.
- Hey.
- This is for you, dr. Austin.
I'm sorry about your mommy.
Oh, thank you, double-g.
Oh, I really appreciate it.
All right, you guys come on in.
Oh, these flowers are
So nice. Thank you.
Everyone at chastain misses you.
I feel that.
I'm not ready to come back yet.
You know, I...
I'm used to checking on her.
You know, listening
for her voice,
For her every move.
Now it's just silent.
And I'm all alone.
I could lend you gigi.
Daddy!
Daddy needs a break.
I'll pick you up in.
Say, what, about a week?
What do you say, uncle aj? Yeah?
- Are you nervous?
- Why would I be nervous?
Because it's hatch day.
Time to find out If
you're a good chicken.
Dr. Austin.
I didn't expect to see you here.
I'm so sorry about your mother.
Me, too. How are you?
Grieving.
It's gonna take
some time, right?
But it's time that a woman
women going through ivf.
Cannot afford to waste.
So, padma, if it's not too late,
I would like to be
your sperm donor.
And you didn't think The
universe would come through.
Yes. Yes. Yes!
But there is a condition.
Now that I'm alone in the world,
I realize I-I don't
like being alone.
So if we're going to do this,
I don't want to just be a donor.
I've got to help
you raise this kid.
I want to be a father.