Surgeons are detail-oriented.
We like statistics and checklists
and operating procedures.
Our patients live because
we enjoy following the steps.
But as much as we'd love to
always rely on the numbers, the plan,
we also know that some of
the greatest medical discoveries
have happened by accident.
- Karev, you still
need a lift...?
- Oh, my God!
- What are you doing?! Get out!
- Uh...
- Why are you naked?
- I should go.
Oh, God... No, please, don't be
mad. Derek was supposed to be Alex.
OK, well, Alex left
ten minutes ago.
Since when are you two still...?
Since you caught
us the first time.
Mm-hm. Lexie, this is
Alex we're talking about.
Emotionally, he's like
me three years ago.
You can't be having feelings
for him. You realize that?
Of course not. No, it's just
sex. There's no feelings involved.
Right, because you are
a no-feelings type of girl.
Your heart lives in your vagina.
It does not. I swear. It's...
- Not this time.
- OK.
Sure.
My heart does not
live in my... vagina!
Mold, penicillin.
Poisonous tree bark,
a cure for malaria.
A little blue pill for high blood
pressure, impotence be damned.
What's going on? Huh?
- Oh, my God!
- Dude!
Why is this my morning?
So I flip the patient
into Trendelenburg,
Teddy yanks out
the arterial cannula, -
connects the arterial line
to a venous line, and then
sets up retrograde
cerebral perfusion.
I mean, she was on fire, I was
on fire, the whole OR was on fire.
What?
Nothing, nothing.
Just... you two are...
You two are friends now.
Yeah. Hey, you know...
you can be her friend, too.
I never asked you not to be.
You decided that
all on your own.
So be her friend.
It's hard for us to accept that
it's not always the hard work...
- Thank you.
- Or attention to detail
that'll get us the
answers we're looking for.
Dr. Hunt! I... I just paged you.
There's a trauma
on the way. Here it is.
We got a 41-year-old motorcycle
daredevil with a closed head wound,
penetrating neck wound
and multiple blunt trauma.
- What was the dare?
- Riding without
a helmet, apparently.
He's still got some
brainwaves left, but barely.
That sometimes we just have to sit back,
relax and wait for the happy accident.
- Oh, my God!
- That isn't gonna help.
- I'm on Trauma. This one's mine.
- I touched him first.
Gary from legal. I need a statement
from one of you about that fall.
- You two decide.
- You're not
even wearing scrubs.
- Damn it! This is not over.
- Have fun with Gary from legal.
OK.
One, two, three.
Teddy, hey, I have an
old patient up in oncology,
and I know you're really busy with
surgeries and... staring at Owen Hunt.
- What?
- I've tried to ignore it,
the staring,
but since Christmas with the
guitar and singing and stolen looks.
Well, I noticed it and
I can't un-notice it.
It's just, I kind of...
Well, I like to fix things.
People. I like to fix people.
- Oh, no. Dr. Hunt and I...
- Don't.
'Cause then you're just
lying, and that's no good.
My point is, you're
staring and you're sad
and I think you need
friends that aren't Owen.
That's where I come in, with the
fixing. You're going to be friends with me.
- I am?
- Yeah. I'm an awesome friend.
So tonight you come out
with Callie and me. Girls night.
Oh... Ooh. Maybe
Bailey'll come, too.
Huh.
- Say yes to girls night.
- Yes to girls night.
- Yay!
- Oh, yay.
Problem solved. Now,
for my patient, Elliot Meyer.
- He needs a lung transplant.
- Oh, hey!
Uh, I'm down with
a lung transplant.
Oh. No, you slept with my girlfriend
and I find that when I look at you,
- I want to hit you
with a brick.
- That was, like, years ago.
Maybe. But jealousy is
a green-eyed monster,
and, if you ask any one of my kids,
there's no reasoning with a monster.
Dude, run away
before I find a brick.
As my new friend,
don't judge me for that.
So, my patient...
I get it, you're upset
Little Sloan is gone.
But screwing drug reps is
not gonna make you feel better.
Yeah, it is.
No screwing drug reps in
my hospital. Are we clear?
You were much more
fun when you weren't chief.
Get out of here.
Ah, Dr. Webber, welcome back.
- Thank you, Dr. Sloan.
- Richard, how's your
first day back?
Oh, well, so far so good.
- I had to drop this off.
- I'm sorry you have to do this.
Drug testing is part
of the rehab program.
- Just run it under a John Doe.
- Of course.
Whatever you need
today. And I mean that.
A low stress day,
let's start there.
Routine surgeries, a light
schedule, home by five.
Done.
Yeah, I said that. She slipped.
The only person liable here is
you for keeping me from my surgery.
Call my driver and tell him
there's still time to make my flight
- if he comes straight here.
- You passed out in a restaurant
and you have abdominal pain.
You're not getting on a plane.
The pain's gone. Whatever's
caused it can wait till I get home.
- Let me off of this thing.
- We're done here, right?
Sir, I need you to
move to this gurney.
I've got this.
You're not in scrubs.
You need to stay calm so I
can do a proper examination.
Tell this lady to
back off, Jackie.
- Jackie?
- Whatever. That's not...
Look, I already paged
Bailey. He's not cardio.
- You can lose interest.
- We'll see about that.
Sir, I'm a surgeon.
A very good one.
So is my grandson. So why
don't you take your hands off me.
- He's your grandfather?
- I can handle this
- till Bailey gets here.
- No, you're not allowed
to treat family. He has mid-epigastric
tenderness and guarding.
- It could be
ascending cholangitis.
- Ascending cholangitis? Really?
With only one of the
symptoms of Charcot's triad?
- You're a doctor?
- Apparently a much
better one than you.
Dr. Harper Avery.
And your name, doctor?
- Harper Avery?
- Uh, no, that's my name.
- As in the Harper Avery Award?
- Bingo.
Get a new surgeon, Jackie.
One with a pulse this time.
You're Harper Avery's grandson?
I misdiagnosed Harper
Avery. In front of Harper Avery.
Know what that does to my chances
of one day winning a Harper Avery?
He could die before then.
He could die today even.
I need to operate on my
motorcycle daredevil and I'll be fine.
Is it true Harper Avery's here?
So Derek walked in on her
naked this morning in Alex's bed.
Meredith! God!
I'm just cheering her up. She's
having a bad day. Be generous.
You know what? You can't
be having feelings for Karev.
- He's like Meredith
three years ago.
- I said that.
I don't have feelings for Alex.
You do. Your
heart's in your vagina.
- I said that!
- You are both monsters.
Yang, I heard you
met Harper Avery.
Did you know that Pretty
Boy's grandfather was God?
I didn't know. That's
kinda cool, though.
No, it's not cool. He's an
entitled brat with no skills,
- except a really
good bloodline.
- It is not Jackson's fault
that he's related
to Harper Avery.
Whatever, Ellis Grey's daughter.
- Huh?
- How do I look?
- Chiefly?
- What, are you nervous?
He's one of the most powerful
surgeons in the country.
He's just a guy who happens to
have an award named after him.
Whatever, Ellis Grey's daughter.
Admit it, you wanna meet him, too.
Hell, yeah.
Hey. Where are we on him?
On his way to the OR
and he started bleeding out.
- Wanna give us
a hand here, Yang?
- Oh.
Big boy needs a
little help. No problem.
Watch and learn. Clamp.
- This is why I don't
want you to drive!
- I had to get my medication!
- The store was gonna close!
- I'm sorry,
can we not yell, maybe?
No, actually. My mother's
almost completely deaf,
a fact she refuses to accept, which
is why she won't learn sign language
or get a hearing
aid. So we yell.
- Don't talk to her! Talk to me!
- I'm telling them what
happened!
She stole my car. Again.
There's tenderness over the
zygomatic process and hematoma
- to the left temporal area.
- Run a head and face CT.
I'll get Sloan and Shepherd. She's
got a ruptured tendon in her knee
that will need surgery. So she'll
be off her feet for a few weeks.
So more waiting on
her hand and foot?
- Brilliant.
- I saw that, Kathy!
They're taking you for
scans! That's all we said!
So quiet down, let the
nice doctor do her work!
Why is this taking so long?
Is it me or are those two
women terribly annoying?
My apologies. We're working on
getting you up to your own room
- as soon as possible.
- You said that before.
Are you the same Shepherd who
did the clinical trial on the gliomas?
- Yes, sir.
- You brought me a neurosurgeon
- for some abdominal cramps?
- No, I...
Dr. Shepherd is our
chief of surgery, sir.
I don't need a cruise director. I
need an experienced surgeon.
Page Dr. Grey.
I'm Dr. Grey.
Either the world's most talented
plastic surgeon works here,
- or you're not Ellis Grey.
- She was my mother. She passed away.
Oh.
I didn't know. My condolences.
Who else then? Does
Richard Webber still work here?
Yes, uh...
Unfortunately, he is...
He is not available today.
Push two of Ativan!
Percy, get him on his side.
- Cristina, watch that neck.
- Oh, my God!
- What are they doing
to that man?!
- OK!
- Applying pressure...
- I'll page Dr. Webber.
As you can see,
you've got dilated bowel
here and here,
indicating an obstruction.
It's good thing that our young
Dr. Avery brought you straight in.
Dr. Bailey can do
the surgery right away.
Was it a student, Webber?
A board member's wife?
- What?
- No one gives up
a chief of surgery gig.
And they don't oust you
unless it's for something juicy.
- So who were you
slipping it to?
- Grandpa!
- I'm sorry, Dr. Webber.
- It was a joke. He doesn't get me.
So, Webber?
Dr. Webber decided
to focus on his research.
Oh, the "research"
line. Well, either way,
at least you'll be
free to do my surgery.
Dr. Bailey is more than capable
of performing the surgery.
I want Webber.
- No offense.
- None taken.
And I want to watch.
- What?
- I'm going to be awake
for my surgery.
Watch.
So much for the low stress day.
A year after Mr. Meyer's
lymphoma went into remission,
he was diagnosed
with pulmonary fibrosis,
a condition he developed
as a side effect to the radiation
he received during
cancer treatment.
This isn't new information.
I thought you said
they could help.
But they're new to the case. It's
important to review the entire history.
Great. Can't you do
that on your own time?
Jill. Sorry. My sister usually
waits a few more minutes
before going full
bitch on you guys.
All right. Let me
tell you what I know.
It is gonna be very difficult
to find you a new set of lungs.
Donor lungs are scarce.
Eighty-five percent get thrown
out because they get too inflamed
while the donor is brain-dead. And
because your cancer could come back
with the immunosuppressants
you'd be on,
you are considered a
very high-risk candidate.
There are just too many other
patients on the list that are lower risk.
Elliot survived
leukemia and lymphoma.
Nobody does that, but
he did. He deserves lungs.
Unfortunately, these are the
rules the transplant board sets out.
I...
I'm sorry.
Have you looked into the research
they're doing with ex vivo transplants?
- Ex vivo?
- It's a procedure
where they take
damaged donor lungs, ones we'd normally
throw away, and repair them on bypass.
- Are we doing one?
- Let me guess.
You want on my service to make up
for the fact that you humiliated yourself
- in front of Harper Avery.
- How'd you hear about that?
- You made fun of me.
- OK.
Fine, yes, I humiliated
myself in front of Harper Avery.
And my daredevil gorked
before we could operate on him.
So I am available for
your ex vivo lung case.
I don't have an ex vivo lung case. It's
only been done in Switzerland and Canada
on patients in much better
shape than our patient.
Yes, but... performing a
procedure as hardcore as this,
while Harper Avery is in the
hospital, well, he could hear about it
and like it. And he's a
god who hands out awards.
- I don't care about awards.
- Only people who never
win awards
ever say that.
This could be an
ex vivo lung case?
I do not have feelings for Alex.
I do not care.
Here we go.
- He's giving them the speech.
- What speech?
About the wonders of medicine.
About how, as surgeons,
we're meant to push boundaries,
- and do what
no one has ever done.
- Sounds motivating.
It's cheesy, is what it is.
You hear it enough times at
your grandparents' dinner table,
you can't help but wanna be
a surgeon when you grow up.
You had a dinner table? I didn't know
world-class surgeons had dinner tables.
I feel gypped.
That's 'cause you haven't
heard the speech yet.
To be awake for my own
surgery? An opportunity like this?
To be a student again,
get a new perspective.
It's what we got into this
business for in the first place.
Those moments that
challenge and terrify and dare us
to reach the potential that
we were meant to reach.
So let's stop the talk and get
into that OR and teach those kids,
teach ourselves...
what it means to be great.
I'm sorry, I can't authorize
an awake surgery, no matter...
We can do it.
- Derek, we can do this.
- - That's what I like to hear.
That's the way a chief does
things. Shepherd, take note.
- Dr. Webber.
- Derek.
- I know what
you're going to say...
- No.
As the sole person in this hospital
assigned to look out for your welfare,
I don't support this decision.
I apologize... Chief Shepherd.
- You really
wanna do this thing?
- I do.
It's on you then.
Thank you for your
help on that project.
- Same time tomorrow?
- Yeah.
Oh, let me guess. Still
no call from Little Sloan?
Nothing. But it's
OK. I've moved on.
OK, yeah, getting out of bed and not
wearing sweats around the apartment
all day is a sign of progress.
Sleeping with the nurses? Not so much.
I wouldn't have to sleep
with nurses if you'd put out.
I'm in a committed,
loving, adult relationship.
- Tried that. Didn't work.
- OK, whatever.
Just come take a look at this
face CT on my patient. Come on!
Get the hell out of here, Karev!
- What?
- Get the hell out! Now!
- What was that?
- I don't like that guy.
He slept with Lexie once,
Mark. You two were broken up.
Actually, he's... Never mind.
You don't sleep with another
man's girl. I learned that the hard way.
- Well played.
- Don't buy that. He's acting out
because he can't deal with
the human emotions he's having.
Ask him how many
nurses he's slept with today.
- You're sleeping with nurses?
- You said no drug reps.
And I'm a grown man! I
can screw whoever I want!
- Not in my hospital.
- What are you gonna do, fire me?
- Maybe I will.
- Enough with the testosterone.
- Mrs. Nelson's scans are up.
- No bleed, no fracture.
- She's good.
- She's deaf.
- Yeah. How'd you know that?
- She's got otosclerosis.
Abnormal bone growth in the
middle ear. If I remove the bones,
- she'll be able to hear again.
- You can restore her hearing?
- Yeah.
- But she's been deaf for years.
- Yeah, she doesn't have to be.
- Just because you remove
the bone?
What did I just say? She
doesn't have to be deaf anymore.
I can fix it. I'm that good.
You still wanna fire me?
Not a bad-looking
bowel, is it, Webber?
No, sir. If I had to guess,
I would say it was the
bowel of a 50-year-old.
- Suction, Dr. Grey.
- Dr. Grey.
I've got a question for you.
- It's of a personal nature.
- Yes, sir?
If your mother was
still working here,
would you have chosen
to study at a different,
lesser quality hospital
in order to avoid
the advantages of her legacy?
I'm waiting here, Dr. Grey.
Um...
Dr. Webber, what do you
think about intraoperational dye
to help determine
intestinal viability?
Well, they say that it enhances
clinical judgment. I'm not really sure.
I don't get it. Why
does he get to scrub in
on his own grandfather's
awake surgery?
The same reason Harper Avery
personally requested Meredith Grey
- to be his resident.
- Nepotism sucks.
Hey, you wanna go grab a bite?
No. Actually, I am full.
Really? 'Cause you
didn't seem full last night.
I said no! OK? I'm
not hungry. At all.
- So just go eat alone.
- Excuse me. Sorry.
- Hey! Down in front, bigfoot.
- It's bigfoot now?
Well, you know what they
say about guys with big feet.
Shouldn't you be off
learning how to be a surgeon
- after you let
my daredevil die?
- My daredevil? He didn't die.
After you left, I personally
helped preserve his heart function.
Now, he's an organ donor.
- BP's dropping!
- I think I've got
a bleeder. Suction.
- Did you check the SMA?
- Yes. It's OK.
- Dr. Avery, stay calm.
- I'll be calm
when you find the damn thing.
What's going on, Kathy?
You're serious?
All this time I just needed
to make her go to the doctor?
That doesn't matter. What matters
is Dr. Sloan can do the surgery
right after I operate
on the knee.
That accident might have been the
best thing that ever happened to you.
- What's going on?!
- Who are you?
You're like some miracle
worker or something.
Thank you. Thank you so much.
What the hell is going on?
- Mom, Dr. Sloan can give you...
- Don't you dare sleep with
that woman.
- What?
- No?
No.
Dr. Sloan, come
and tell her yourself.
Mrs. Nelson, I'm Dr. Sloan!
I have some very
good news for you!
- Shouldn't we put him out?
- Don't put me out.
Hang another unit of FFP.
Maybe... you should consider...
- Eighty over 50.
- There it is. I've got it.
I've got it.
OK.
How are you feeling, Dr. Avery?
- Heart rate's stabilizing.
- Hang in there just
a few more minutes.
- OK? 3-0 silk.
- Silk?
No. Use chromic.
- Don't get lazy on me.
- Yep, he's fine.
Right. Chromic instead, Bokie.
You paged?
Oh, my God! Are you
doing an ex vivo lung repair?
- My daredevil turned
out to be a match.
- You stole his lungs?
No, I did not steal them.
The transplant team rejected them and
were gonna send them to medical waste
so I just redirected
them to medical research.
Does Lexipedia want to be
bad-ass and help on this thing or not?
- My God. Yeah!
- OK, so...
I ventilated the lungs
with CO2 and nitrogen...
- Hey.
- Hear about Harper...?
- Your motorcycle...
- You go.
- No, sorry.
I was just gonna say it's kinda
cool, Harper Avery being here.
Yeah. Yeah, it is.
- And your motorcycle guy?
- Uh, we lost him.
- But he's a donor.
- That's good.
You should come over
sometime for dinner.
Cristina, she doesn't cook, but if
you remember, I do a mean lasagna.
- Sure.
- Really?
- Yeah. Sounds fun.
- OK.
- Uh, I gotta go.
- All right.
- Talk to you later.
- OK, I know you love Yang.
She gives you the warm and fuzzies
with her magical, special heart skills.
But those lungs you're transplanting
belonged to a patient of mine,
and it'd mean a lot to turn his
death into something meaningful.
I'm sorry. What lungs?
You went behind my
back. You used my name.
We followed the protocol,
didn't tell the patient.
You stole lungs!
Which they were about to
throw out. She was being green.
Great! Then I don't have to worry
about the thousands of dollars you spent,
and the fact that no one in this
hospital has ever tried this before.
Oh, my God. This is
about Harper Avery, isn't it?
- That's why you did this?
- Why is that such a bad thing?
- The point is that we... You can pull this surgery off.
- Oh, wow, thank you.
Who needs Harper Avery when they've
got the Cristina Yang seal of approval?
- That's not what I was saying.
- All this ambition of yours,
this desperate
need to win prizes,
- it means
your priorities are off!
- Hey.
- Prizes push us to be better.
- They push us to be monsters!
- Hey.
- Is the status quo not trying?
- That's worse!
- Hey!
The lungs, look!
They're... They're viable.
A transplant with repaired lungs has
never been done in the United States.
The risks are tremendous, and with the
amount of radiation that you sustained,
there's no way of knowing
how friable your tissue is
or if you can even
sustain a transplant.
Wait, I'm sorry. Are you saying
you recommend it though?
No, they're saying they want to
give us a pair of hand-me-down lungs.
- The ones no one else wants.
- These are good lungs.
This procedure has
allowed us to repair them
- so they're
virtually the same...
- No. We'll wait.
We'll wait until you get
the lungs you deserve.
You're so used to fighting,
you don't even realize.
This is it.
I'm sick and I'm
tired and I'm ready.
No matter what happens,
my affairs are in order.
Your affairs are not in
order. Don't you dare say that.
Dr. Robbins, please.
Is this my best shot?
I'm not your surgeon here,
Elliot. I have to defer to Dr. Altman.
It's your only shot.
Then, yes. Do it.
Give me the hand-me-downs.
Dr. Sloan, good timing.
Dr. Karev and I are done.
- What the hell
are you looking at?
- Nothing.
- Get out of my OR, Karev!
- Mark, you're way out
of line here.
It's fine, I'll go.
He's got serial-killer eyes.
I'm almost done here anyway.
- You're sure?
- Yeah.
- That is enough!
- It's funny. Did you see his face?
It is sad and pathetic. And
you have a choice here.
Sloan and her baby leaving you
can either be the worst or best thing
that happened to you. You can grow
up, find a woman to love and have a baby,
or you can be the ass
attending who abuses residents
and screws whatever
walks into this hospital.
So just pick one.
Drape the ear, please.
Look, it's not gonna happen.
Five minutes with your
grandpappy, that's all I ask.
Right, because the two of
us are such good friends.
- This would go
a long way to help that.
- Back off, Karev.
- If anybody's
a friend here, it's me.
- You're not meeting him either.
- What happened to
"Mercy West forever?"
- That was never a thing.
Now, leave.
I hate it.
I hate it when they
know I'm related to him.
The way they treat me, the way
they watch me as soon as they find out.
I know the name has
helped, but he is not easy.
Brilliant, but really not
easy to be related to.
It's him. 911.
What is it? You paged?
You're OK?
We never got a chance to
finish our talk from this morning.
- Our talk? Are you kidding me?
- You brought Dr. Grey.
That's good, actually.
Answer me this time, Dr. Grey.
If a spot was being held for you
to study at the greatest hospital in
this country, would you turn it down?
- A spot? Well...
- Yeah, he saved a spot for me
at Mass Gen ever
since I graduated.
The only reason he came to visit,
to try to convince me to take it. Again.
- It's an incredible
opportunity.
- An opportunity I don't want!
I don't want to work for you. I
don't want your help. I don't...
- It's enough...
- No!
I decide when I've said enough!
You think I am arrogant
and overbearing,
and you've made
that clear. Maybe I am.
But I am also your
only living grandfather,
and it has become very clear to
me today that my time is coming.
I... I can't leave...
Grandpa? Grandpa?
- V-tach!
- No pulse! No pulse. Get a crash cart in here!
Your CT shows that
there's been a complication.
Dr. Webber will take you back
into the OR and fix it right away.
Fine... But you're
not putting me out.
Clearly, a mistake was made.
I'm not letting that happen again.
That's not gonna happen this
time. You're in my hospital today.
You will abide by my rules.
That means you go under general.
Your grandson will be in the waiting room
as family. If you refuse, then
I'll personally declare you unfit
to make decisions
regarding your own care.
That is how a chief
does things. Take note.
- Have Bailey do the surgery.
- Richard.
It could've been my
mistake in there, Derek.
Do you understand what this would
mean, making an error on this man?
I want a drink. Not operate, not
hold another man's life in my hands.
So, please, let Bailey do it.
Bailey will assist.
Two months ago, you never
would've told me you wanted a drink.
You would've had one.
You can do this, Richard.
I get it.
You got used to being the
one person she could count on.
Now, suddenly, you're
supposed to just move on.
Get a life that doesn't involve
taking care of the one person
you thought needed
you. That's hard.
OK. Yeah.
Except no. I am not gonna
miss taking care of her.
I wasted years of my life.
And I was miserable. But now...
I can do anything.
Right? I mean, I
can... I can move out.
Get my own place.
Have men over.
Men that look like you.
I was taking care of
you, you little tramp.
Mom?
No one asked you to move in.
You were getting a divorce and you
had no place to go, so you came home.
I didn't need you to take
care of me. I was fine. Happy.
But I let you because I
was taking care of you.
You heard all that?
Mom, you can hear!
- I can?
- Yeah!
Oh, my God, I can! I can!
- Say something! Say something else!
- OK!
- I'm moving out, Mom.
- I heard that.
- Whoo!
- Shh!
Sorry.
- Damn it.
- What is it?
The tissue is falling apart,
the clamp's not holding.
Get me some umbilical tape.
This is why I hate awards.
They don't make us better,
just more competitive and stupid.
And for what? To put on a
dress, and eat a bad piece of fish
and take home an ugly paperweight
that's gonna sit on your mantle
for the rest of your sad,
empty, misguided life.
- Do an interposition
vein graft.
- What?
- You have something to add,
Dr. Yang?
- No, just...
You've already gotten this far,
you could repair the PA with a graft.
- Maybe.
- No.
I could do a pericardial patch. I could
use his pericardium to do the repair.
Start cooling him.
Arrest the heart. How are
we doing on time, Grey?
Cold ischemic time
three hours so far.
Which means we still have enough
time to save the lungs if we hurry.
All right, Yang, get in
there and help me. Clamp.
Good. Here we go.
His bowels are all swollen and
hardened, the anastomosis is leaking.
Which explains why
he went into shock.
All in all, I'd say this
is about the best news
- we could've asked for,
Dr. Webber.
- I don't understand.
His bowels are perforated.
He's leaking intestinal contents.
Because Dr. Avery was
allergic to the chromic suture.
He didn't know because he was always
wearing gloves in his own surgeries.
And you couldn't
have known either.
Which is why I am
smiling behind this mask.
Get the 3-0 silk ready, Bokie.
OK. This is it.
Let's take him off bypass and see
if these lungs can work on their own.
Clamping.
There.
Come on. Breathe.
Breathe. Breathe, damn it.
I just spent the past
five hours trying to be
OK with the fact that my
only brother was dead, and...
You're saying it worked?
He's gonna be OK?
- Barring any complications...
- He's gonna be OK, yes.
- Would you like to see him?
- Yeah.
OK, come on.
Hey. So he's fine. It was an
allergy caused by the suture.
It was his fault then. Wow.
That's awesome. Why
don't they publish that story?
Yeah, I know. I get it.
The famous grandfather.
The legacy he's trying force on
you. You didn't ask for any of it.
Trust me, I get it.
You're putting up walls
and avoiding him and you don't
want to introduce him to your friends.
It was the same with my mother.
But if she were here right now,
in a room upstairs, I'd want to go
see her and make things right with her.
And I definitely would
want to go learn from her.
And you still can.
Guess who just helped save a guy's
life by suggesting a highly experimental,
- awesome procedure...
- Did you tell Sloan
we were together?
- What?
- Look, I like you.
You're a great time in bed. But
don't go telling your ex we're together
so you can make him jealous.
I did not tell Mark
that we were together.
- I am not trying
to make him jealous.
- Yeah, right.
I'm getting kicked out
of ORs for a reason.
For once in my life, for once, I am
doing something that is only for me.
And it has nothing to do with
me having feelings for you.
Or for Mark. Or anyone, really.
This is about not feeling.
You make me not feel.
If you can't handle that, if you
can't handle being used for sex,
then please just tell me so
that I can find a guy who can.
I'm all about not feeling.
- You've been through
a lot, I...
- Don't get all mushy on me.
I'm just saying we're on the same
page. And I got a free 20 minutes.
You wanna go not have
feelings somewhere?
Excuse me, Dr...
It's really bad form to cancel plans
with new friends. You know that, right?
I'll meet you in 15.
- Hey.
- Hi.
So... I heard about
the lung transplant.
- Cristina said that
you were amazing.
- No, Cristina was amazing.
You tell her I said
that and you're dead.
You wanna grab a beer,
celebrate? I was gonna head to Joe's.
I've got plans,
actually. Ladies night.
I'm a little scared.
I'll see you tomorrow, Hunt.
No matter how many plans
we make or steps we follow...
See you tomorrow.
We never know how
our day is going to end up.
We'd prefer to know, of course,
what curveballs will be thrown our way.
Karev!
Look, dude, she's
not my girlfriend.
Whatever business
you have to work out...
I'll stop. The yelling, throwing
you out of ORs, it's over.
Hey.
It's the accidents that
always turn out to be
the most interesting
parts of our day.
Of life.
How's your regenerative
medicine research going?
Uh... I put it on the
shelf a few years back.
Got preoccupied.
Huh.
That research put you on the shortlist
for my award several times, Webber.
Maybe it's time to dust it off.
Maybe it is.
The people we never
expected to show up.
- Grandpa, I...
- Ah.
Wanted to introduce
you to some friends.
If you feel up for it.
Bring 'em in.
All right. Hurry up. Come on.
We met... already
this morning, I know.
But you weren't...
There was so much going on.
Start with your name,
and we'll go from there.
- Cristina Yang. It's an honor, sir.
- It's nice to...
- Thank you so much.
- Officially meet you.
- And the rest of you.
- Lexie Grey.
The turn of events we never
would've chosen for ourselves.
- You won't make that.
- I'll make it.
I told off one of my heroes
today, I can do anything.
You know Teddy did an ex vivo lung
repair today? It was pretty incredible.
I slept with my patient's
daughter, just now.
After restoring her mother's
hearing. Don't worry, Derek.
I promise never to do it again.
Wow. We suck.
- They were just leaving.
- We were?
- Yeah.
- Right, we were.
- Good night, Webber.
- Good night.
I had to pee in a
cup today, Derek.
I had to pee in a cup.
And it was humiliating.
And, what I did today,
agreeing to the awake surgery,
I know I overstepped, but...
I needed to feel something
other than humiliated.
I understand.
Tomorrow's another day.
Thank you.
All of a sudden, you
find yourself somewhere
you never expected to be.
And it's nice.
Or it takes some
getting used to.
Why couldn't we have
gone dancing for girls night?
- Or bowling?
- We took a vote.
You lost. Besides, it's fun.
- Says who?
- Bailey's face. Look at it.
Go, go, go! Come
on, come on, come on!
That's right!
Still, you know you'll find
yourself appreciating it
somewhere down the line.
I'm in love with
Teddy. I love her.
You're like Lexie with the inappropriate
feelings for inappropriate people.
What can I say? My
heart lives in my scalpel.
- Those were trick balls.
- - Bailey, you gotta be taller!
- I got it.
- Let 'em go.
So you go to sleep each
night thinking about tomorrow.
- That's what I'm talking about!
- Yes!
- Beat that, Yang!
- Oh, no, it's Teddy's turn.
- Going over your plans...
-  Gonna feel great
when you connect.
- preparing the lists...
- Like making your first
incision.
Take it. Just you,
the bat and the ball.
Yeah, I'm a badass chick,
Cristina. I've swung a bat before.
OK, let's see it.
And hoping that whatever
accidents come your way...
will be happy ones.