Ready? KOVAC: Yeah.
Good afternoon, everyone.
Welcome to another fun-filled
Morbidity and Mortality.
All right, medical
record number 549274.
"R.K. was a previously
healthy 19-year-old male...
who presented with fever,
myalgias and a temperature of 102.4.
CBC revealed a white blood count
of 85,000 with 60 percent blasts...
consistent with acute
myelogenous leukemia.
The attending
physician, Dr. Kovac."
- Need some help?
- No. I got it.
Stay out of this room for
a few days though, okay?
No paint fumes. Okay?
Are you nesting?
I'm painting a room.
Nesting.
Don't you have to go to work?
Chicago's toughest firefighter braves
burning buildings and dirty diapers.
- Get out of here.
- Hey!
I hope you don't
treat the baby like that.
You drew bloods, but didn't
send them for two hours?
We were swamped. And the
man looked like he had the flu.
I told her we can't do big
workups on every kid with the flu.
Something all doctors
say at one time or another.
The intubation
problem. Dr. Lewis?
Because of the thrombocytopenia,
there was hemorrhage in the hypopharynx.
- We attempted...
- But could you see the cords, Dr. Kovac?
No.
Dr. Kovac felt he'd performed
an endotracheal intubation.
"Felt"?
He listened for breath sounds.
Did he use an end-tidal
C02 detector to verify?
- When I walked into the trauma room...
- I made a series of critical errors...
including depriving
the patient of oxygen.
I refused to let Dr. Lewis take over
and proceeded to put the Shiley...
in the pre-tracheal space.
The only thing I didn't do was
put a bag over the guy's head...
- and hit him with a brick.
- We're not assigning guilt.
In a teaching hospital, we learn from
complicated cases and their outcomes.
I had two hours sleep. I was hung-over.
I should have admitted I couldn't work...
but I didn't. I was
sloppy and arrogant.
Abby warned me the boy
was sick, and I ignored her.
So fire me, take my
license, shoot me, whatever.
But let's just not pretend
there's anything to learn here.
I killed him.
The patient isn't dead.
Did anyone bother to verify that there
really are medical schools in Croatia?
Anyone?
Don't let Romano get to
you. It only encourages him.
They were more than fair.
I appreciate you
standing up for me.
I told the truth.
You tried to cover for
me. You didn't have to.
It could have
been any one of us.
Time to get back to work.
You think I still work here?
- Yeah, your shift started 20 minutes ago.
- Check with Weaver.
She just asked for you.
Twenty-eight-year-old, Chip
Mealy, insomnia times three days.
- He called 911 for insomnia?
- Big red taxi.
- Sorry.
- Also complains of obsessive thoughts.
Thanks. What's up,
Chip? Can't sleep?
I took, like, five of those
p.m. things. Nothing.
- Can you give me something stronger?
- Five sleeping pills?
- Were you trying to hurt yourself?
- No. I was trying to sleep.
You stopped sleeping three
days ago. Something happened?
Problem with my girlfriend.
Okay. Sit tight and we'll
get someone to talk to you.
- Can you give me a pill?
- No.
You have to talk to a
psychiatrist first, drugs second.
Chuny, can you call
Psych for Mr. Mealy?
- Sure.
- All right, thanks.
- Did you get a Beta HCG on Mrs. Wilkes?
- No.
- Why not?
- Ha-ha, because Mrs. Wilkes has a penis.
- Excuse me. Come back here.
- It's just my cell phone.
- I set this off every day.
- I'm just gonna look.
Look, I'm Dr. Pratt.
I told you it's my cell
phone. Now I have patients.
- Let me look inside the bag.
- You don't need to. You're new, right?
- Doctors just get to go through, okay?
- It's not okay.
You hear what I
said? Don't touch me.
Hey, hey, knock it off.
It's okay. He's a doctor.
- He set off the metal detector, all right?
- Okay. What's the deal?
Look, I was gonna
give it to a real cop.
I found it outside behind the
garbage can on my way inside.
I figured somebody must
have stashed it coming in here...
and planned on picking
it up later after they left.
You have a license for this?
I told you I found it.
Well, I'm not gonna
leave it outside.
Sir, you're carrying a
concealed, unlicensed weapon.
I'll have to call
the Chicago P.D.
Got a drive-by here. Need a doc.
- Keep the damn gun.
- Where's he going?
Whoa, whoa. He's not going
anywhere. He works here.
You got the gun. Just get his
name and information, leave it at that.
No, no, don't move him.
- Airway's good.
- Name?
I don't know. I hired him
to cut down a dead tree.
- What happened?
- He was on a branch...
starting his chain saw and
slipped. Fell 20 feet onto my roof.
You drove him in?
Why didn't you call 911?
- I thought this would be faster.
- Pulse is 90.
Let's get a C-collar and a backboard.
- Where is Rico?
Mr. Gilman has chest pain...
and shortness of breath
during sex with his wife.
- Sex with his wife?
- BP, 130/82.
- How old is he?
- Ninety-three.
- One, two...
- Koko!
Dr. Kovac, could
you give us a hand?
- Koko!
- Sir, it's okay.
- Ready?
- Yeah.
- Go.
- Koko?
She's on her way. - Usual panel.
- His wife.
- Start a nitroglycerine drip.
- Twenty mics per minute.
- Gallant.
- Passing notes in class, Gallant?
- Nitro and a Foley.
It's from Harkins.
She's going home today.
I've been helping her
with her assigned reading.
- You still need me?
- No.
Oh, but could you check...
- post-intubation film in ICU?
- Patient's name?
Exposed bone.
Multiple abrasions
to scalp and face.
- I asked if they knew what to do.
- You speak Spanish?
No.
Oh, my God, this is bad. I
have to go call my husband.
Pelvis is stable but very tender
at the ASIS. Probably a fracture.
Dr. Pratt, these guys keep
insisting that we come get you.
Prep the chest and
open a 32 French.
I understand you blew off
Officer Robbins, Dr. Pratt.
- Can't you see I'm busy?
- Jerry, page Ortho and Surgery...
and keep the militia out? Get someone
who speaks more Spanish than we do.
- I need to speak with him.
- Out.
Okay, guys. Come on. Let's go.
It's not what you think.
- Chip. Chip, it can't be that bad.
- It is.
- Nobody's come to talk to you yet?
- No. I just wanna go to sleep.
- I'll see what's keeping them.
- The design is flawed.
Should be a straight
line from the door...
Where you going?
What are you doing?
Wow. Your face is
beautiful. Is it square?
I never know what that means.
It's not true mathematically, but your
face is quadrant enough to be square.
Sorry. She's one
of my Mathletes.
Anastasia, you're gonna have to
go and sit with the rest of the team.
- Mathlete?
- Yeah. She's on the math team.
They compete in
math tournaments.
Oh, yeah. We used to call
them geeks. What's she on?
Tox screen hasn't come back yet.
How many cubic inches in the ER?
Is, uh, my face square?
Hi. I'm looking for a portable
chest film on Moriguchi.
Dr. Weaver coming back up?
She's a little busy.
You should pull the
tube back 2 centimeters.
Just write the order.
- How's Kendrick doing?
- Who?
Teenager. Presented
with flu but it was leukemia.
They think he
needs dialysis now.
Mrs. Kendrick? I'm Dr. Kovac. I
treated Rick when he first came to the ER.
I've wanted to meet you.
I'm so sorry about your son.
He was such a funny kid.
He'd have been a good man.
- Did he know about the leukemia?
- No.
By the time the tests came
back, he was unconscious.
- Was he afraid?
- I don't think so.
As he was going under with
the medicine, he made a joke.
He smiled and told Laura she
could sell her engagement ring...
if she needed the money.
That's Rick.
A little humor to get
him through the day.
Dr. Kovac?
- Excuse me.
- Sure.
What are you doing, M
and M with the mother?
- She wanted to know how her son died.
- Peacefully. Leave it at that.
She deserves to know... - What?
What, the truth? The truth is you
killed her son. You gonna tell her that?
The word you're looking
for is "no." Come here.
You wanna flagellate yourself in
front of colleagues, that's one thing.
But you admit guilt to this
woman and who suffers? Huh?
Huh? Not you. What's she
gonna do, take your car?
Her lawyer slaps the county and hospital
with a multimillion-dollar lawsuit.
Our premiums skyrocket, and
where's that money come from?
Cutbacks in personnel and essential
equipment, affect whom? The patients.
You control your emotions or you will
harm more patients than just this one.
I'll tell you what. You're
off the rest of the day.
I'm fine. ROMANO: Go home.
Oh, and if I see you with this
patient's family again, you're fired.
Look, I know you're on the edge.
Not sleeping makes you feel crazy.
I know how that is.
But Psych's backed up.
We can't give you any meds
until someone's seen you.
It's a liability thing because
you took pills earlier.
I know it wasn't a
suicide attempt, but...
Oh, God.
We'll get you something
to help you sleep soon.
Everyone will hate me.
Why?
Why will everyone hate you?
Did you do something?
To your girlfriend?
No.
What?
What happened?
She walked in on me.
With someone else?
Another woman?
No.
- I don't think she realized.
- Another man?
He's only 10.
Who?
Her son.
You were...?
- Did you do something to him?
- No.
I was going to, but...
I would have, but she walked in.
I don't wanna be like this.
I don't know if I could
have stopped myself.
- What happened?
- Lost the pulse.
Still V-tach.
Charging to 300.
Bag him on 100 percent,
push an amp of epi.
Clear.
- Got a rhythm.
- Good femoral pulse.
- Welcome back, Mr. Gilman.
- His wife here?
- Not here yet.
- Maybe we should check on her.
Make sure she survived
their sexual encounter.
Dr. Weaver, your coat. You
brushed against some blood.
Get a pressure.
Keep him on lido,
two mgs per minute.
He have experience
cutting down trees?
Are they fresh off the boat?
He's only been here about two weeks.
His uncle's been in the U.S. three years.
Is there any family
we can call for Jose?
We... You're illegal.
Tell him anything that he needs
he can get done here, no charge.
Hi, Dr. Lewis again. Listen, I
know you're really backed up.
But I have a patient Dr. DeRaad
needs to see immediately.
No, don't put me on hold.
Hey, what are you doing? Jerry.
- Ah, that's my board.
- Anastasia, no. Ugh.
- You've erased all our patients.
- Can I write on the board too?
Jimmy, sit back down.
- Why did you do this?
- Ergo, God.
Ergo, Ritalin. Your blood
test says you're on Ritalin.
You took it for the
math competition?
These numbers, discovered
in different cultures...
in different centuries, all add to
zero, proving the universe is perfect.
Proving the existence of God.
Hey, I can't even
prove I paid my gas bill.
Jerry, just get the charts
and put all the names back up.
- Make her do it.
- Alphabetical or chronological?
Alphabetical's good.
Do we have any wound-care sheets?
- Yeah.
- So you buying me lunch today?
- Ha, no.
- Hey, it's your turn.
- Dr. Pratt?
- What does "appy" stand for?
- Appendicitis.
Is now a good time?
Sure. I don't know why you guys
are making such a big deal about this.
Where'd you find the gun?
- I told them...
- Look, I know, but he's unstable.
I'll walk him up
myself. Don't hang...
Chip? Where'd he go?
- Who, your weeper?
- He was just here a minute ago.
Oh, damn it.
Uh, excuse me.
I need the SonoSite.
I can't find the heartbeat.
Here, let me try.
- How many weeks?
- Fourteen.
I think...
Try a different angle.
I'm sorry.
- Try again.
- Okay.
It's not there.
Are you bleeding?
A little.
I thought I was just spotting.
Do you want me to call your OB?
No, I think it's better
if it happens naturally.
Can you get me some scrubs?
Dr. Weaver, you should go home.
Just, um, bring me some
scrubs when you get a chance.
Hello. Um, they brought my
husband in. Daniel Gilman.
Uh... Um...
- Yeah. The 93-year-old?
- Is he all right?
- I'll take you to him.
- Thank you.
- You guys are pathetic.
- What?
If you stare any harder, her
ass is gonna burst into flames.
- I'd put that fire out.
- Stop, drop and roll.
He has a dilated cardiomyopathy.
We're gonna treat it very aggressively,
but the, uh, prognosis is not good.
He could have a fatal
arrhythmia at any time.
Oh. Danny.
Excuse me?
When can I bang her?
What did he say?
Uh, he wants to know when he
might be able to, ahem, have sex.
We're trying to have a baby.
Uh-huh.
Uh, when you can walk up, uh...
two flights of stairs
without getting winded...
go for it.
Okay.
- Dr. Weaver?
- Yeah.
Uh, security
needs to talk to you.
I'll be right there.
Wow.
Hey, that's great.
It's my own variation on Buckminster
Fuller's geodesic dome design.
Ugh. Anastasia, I told
you to wait in your chair.
- Sorry.
- No. It's no problem. This is...
- This is very cool.
- A geodesic dome...
Oh, um, they took Jose up to
Radiology to embolize the pelvic bleeders.
Triangles, squares
and rectangles.
What are you doing?
Hi. Just getting
a cup of coffee.
While you were in here with your Lincoln
Logs, security told me about Pratt...
- smuggling a weapon into the hospital.
- That was a misunderstanding.
It's an automatic suspension.
He found the gun in the bushes.
The interns are your
responsibility, Carter. I hope...
I know, I know. And I'm taking
care of it. Um, it's taken care of.
- Hey! Hey! What are you doing?
- Move.
- You can't leave. You didn't pay them.
- Out of my way.
- Damn it, stop this car.
- What do you want from me?
- I don't even know these men.
- Stop this car. Stop it.
- Pratt.
- You see what I'm dealing with?
Hey! Hey!
- Stupid bitch!
- What the hell are you doing?
- What?
Your patients know where she
lives. Just report it to the police.
- Yeah. Like they give a damn.
- Like you do?
Look, you come in constantly late.
You're leaving whenever you feel like it.
Hot-dogging patients.
Never follow orders.
- Now throwing rocks and bringing guns.
- Hey, I explained about that gun.
- I've seen your type before.
- No, you haven't.
You don't know
anything about me.
I know what I see.
Oh, yeah? What is that?
Someone throwing
their career away.
One, two, three.
- ID says Rosemary Bell, 18.
- Why is she in restraints?
She was flailing and incoherent.
Witness reported she collapsed,
cracked her head. LOC, one minute.
CBC, lytes, BUN, creatinine,
Foley with dip, and ICON.
- Pulse, 122. BP's 86 systolic.
- She looks kind of familiar.
I think maybe Dr. Lewis
has treated her before.
Airway intact, normal cephalic.
Rosemary, follow the light.
- Sats 98.
- Rosemary, can you understand me?
Call X-ray. Get me a
setup and a red top.
Do you want me
to go get Dr. Lewis?
- Dr. Weaver?
- No. Thanks, Abby. I've got this.
Um, where does it hurt?
Yeah, your head? Wait, wait, wait.
Slow down. Slow down. Slow down.
Your head, yeah. And your back?
Here. Your kidneys?
Okay.
Burns when you pee.
What's her temperature?
- 103.2.
- She passed out because she's septic.
Can you read lips?
Good. We're going to
take care of you. Okay?
- No. I don't want a lady doctor.
- Jim.
Uh, it's nothing personal. I'm
sure you're very competent.
- I'm just old-fashioned.
- Huh. We call it sexist.
What about junior here?
- Would you take care of...?
- In a minute.
- Oh, forget it. I'm out of here.
- No, your leg's bleeding.
Let's take care of that first.
McNULTY: You don't deserve
to call yourselves physicians.
- Let him go. WILSON:
Oh, Dr. McNulty, wait.
McNULTY: You people
should be ashamed.
You've perfected a medical system that
breaks the spirit, humiliates the body...
- and enrages the mind.
- John.
- Yeah, yeah. You're a doctor?
- Thank you.
- I got a stethoscope older than you.
- Kids broke into our clinic for drugs.
I hid. But Mr. Former Marine
decided to take them on.
They're lucky my sciatica was
acting up or they'd both be in traction.
They hit him on the
head with a baseball bat.
More a bunt than a full swing.
He fell on broken glass and was
unconscious for several minutes.
- I was assessing my wounds.
- Okay, okay.
Then you may be seriously hurt.
- Negative Romberg, no pronator drift.
- Blunt head trauma, prolonged LOC.
- You need a head CT.
- For what?
- To rule out any brain injury.
- I told you I don't have any.
Then what's it
gonna hurt to check?
Oh, please, Jim.
Just get the CT.
Ten bucks says it's negative.
- You're on.
Abby, this is Dr. McNulty,
formerly of Curtain 2.
He needs a head CT,
CBC, Chem-7, urinalysis.
McNULTY: I didn't agree to that.
When was your last tetanus shot?
October... 1949.
Well, you might need another
one. I'll be with you in a moment.
Do you have to pee in a cup?
- Yes, he does.
Okay, start peeing, count to
three, pee a little bit in the cup...
- put the lid on and you're done.
- Wash my hands, right?
- You got it. I'll wait for you right here.
- Okay.
Did you dispo your tree
trimmer without my okay?
- I signed off to Chen.
- I was the physician of record.
- What's this?
- Drunk bumsicle with a head lac.
- Hey, I'm not throwing my career away.
- Uh-huh. Did you close the galea?
Yeah. It wasn't my gun. I was gonna
throw it in the river after my shift ended.
- Why didn't you do it on the way in?
- I was late.
Titrate five of MS and
get films on that ankle.
Can you give me a hand?
- In a minute.
- You haven't seen my insomniac?
- He went in there.
- Oh, thank God.
- Something wrong?
No. I thought he skipped.
- What are you doing?
- Waiting for a urine sample from a kid.
There's a kid in there? - Yeah.
- God.
- What? What's wrong?
- What's the matter?
- Chip? Chip Mealy?
- Hey, I'm in here.
- Unlock the door.
- What are you doing?
- Are you all right?
- I got some on my hands.
- That's okay. Let me take it.
Did anybody...? Did you
see anybody else in here?
No.
Okay. Go outside.
You want me to call Security?
No. Are you sure
he came in here?
Chip?
Chip.
- Did you do anything to him?
- No.
But I wanted to.
Pressure's dropping.
Dr. Weaver, you okay?
- She's down to 80 systolic.
- Give her another liter.
Amp and gent are both finished.
You have a bladder infection
that spread to your kidneys.
Give her two grams cefotaxime. If
she doesn't perk up, we'll add dopamine.
Are you sexually active?
How many partners?
And how long has it
burned when you pee?
Two weeks. Why
haven't you told anyone?
Do you live with your parents?
And you don't want them to
know that you're having sex?
All right. Your parents
don't need to know.
But we do need to tell...
We need to tell
them that you're sick.
For at least six hours.
And if the antibiotics don't
work fast, it may be overnight.
It's okay. It's okay.
Haleh, take her to CT.
This could be more
than simple pyelo.
- You all right?
- Yeah. I'll talk to you when you get back.
Dr. Weaver, can you look at a
possible erythema nodosum?
- Get Carter.
- I think he's busy.
Then find another Attending.
What are you doing?
- You can't do that in here. Will you stop?
- Don't stop.
- Get off of him now.
- No!
For crying out loud, he
just had a heart attack.
- Oh, relax. He needs his Viagra anyway.
- Not while he's on nitro.
- I want my Viagra.
- Only if you wanna die with an erection.
- No. I want my Viagra!
- Are you out of your mind?
He needs to recuperate.
- I was trying to make him feel better.
- Look, he is in critical condition.
What did you do to him?
My father did not give
her power of attorney.
- Procedures have to be okayed by me.
- These are Mr. Gilman's kids.
- Bob, he is really sick.
- I know. I know, honey.
You treating him?
- I'm one of the...
- I want this slut out of here now.
I have patients and no beds. He'll
have to get help as an outpatient.
What's wrong with his forehead?
He cut the word "evil" into
his skin to scare people away.
It's not a suicide attempt,
and he hasn't hurt anyone.
Fine, let's toss him your son.
- Abby.
He needs to be kept away from children.
Can't rehabilitate child molesters.
He hasn't molested anyone.
He needs medication. He
needs to be in a regular program.
I can't commit people
for thoughts. I can't.
If this guy walks out of here,
he's going to attack a child.
This is our chance to intervene,
save this guy, protect his future victims.
He's clearly a threat to others.
He has to say it.
If he articulates a plan,
I'll put him on a hold.
He won't. He's too frightened.
All right. I'll talk
to him again.
The parents and principal
will meet us at school.
- How far is Olney?
- Five hours.
Oh, I think they'll
sleep all the way.
- Mathletes.
- I take you were never on the math team.
Oh, no. I was on a real team.
I think we called it, uh, football.
You were a jock. Ooh.
Well, better to be
a jock than a nerd.
- Are you insinuating that I'm a nerd?
- Yeah, but you're a really hot nerd.
- Ha-ha.
- Phone call, Pratt.
All right.
Where's Weaver? I need some
help with this old guy's family.
- Koko and Captain Viagra.
- It's common knowledge that...
the crazier the woman,
the better the sex.
Just keep your head down.
- Try not to get stabbed in the neck.
- Ha-ha.
Can you call Legal? I need
some help down here now.
Hello? No, I can't come.
Just wait right there, all right?
Just calm down. I'm on my way.
You just stay
right there. Jerry.
- Everything all right?
- I have to leave. Cover for me.
Not again. For how long? Pratt?
Hi.
- Hi.
- How long have you been cramping?
About an hour.
How much bleeding?
Four pads.
Okay. We need to get you upstairs.
Do you want me to call Sandy?
- She's at work.
- She'd wanna be with you.
I can't. I don't wanna
check in upstairs.
- I don't want it all over the hospital.
- I think you need a D and C right away.
No. Just...
page me if the OB resident
comes down for another consult.
I'm calling Maynard.
- Hey, have you seen Kerry?
- Yeah. She's on break.
- Where?
- What do you need?
- I need Kerry.
- Hey, what are you doing?
You can't suture yourself.
I have patients waiting
for me back at my clinic.
- Where did you get these supplies?
- The nurse set them up for you.
Forty-five minutes ago.
Nice eversion. Still,
can't let you do it.
Hey, Dr. Carter.
Can't find Dr. Weaver, and Mrs.
Gilman has a special request.
My attorney's on her
way over right now.
Mattie, he wants to do it.
- So do I.
- What?
Koko wants to collect
semen from her husband...
who is 93 and just had an MI.
He was trying to give me a baby.
Don't debase my
father any further.
- He's senile.
- He is not senile. He's horny.
Uh, Mr. Gilman
has agreed to, uh...
electroejaculation.
- Come again?
- I'm an electroejaculation technician.
Your parents must be very proud.
I have to ejaculate
him before he dies.
Otherwise, I have to do
a seminal-vesicle harvest.
We wanna make sure
that he doesn't die.
Well, we can still get it now.
Oh, it was always about
the money, wasn't it, Koko?
If she doesn't get pregnant before
he dies, she doesn't inherit anything.
- Inherit? BOB:
Seven million, roughly.
My husband signed a release. I
know my rights. I want his semen.
Okay. Well, what exactly
is it that's, um, involved?
A rectal probe is inserted, causing
contraction of the vas deferens...
seminal vesicle
and the prostate.
Called a reflex ejaculation.
Okay, good.
Uh, excuse me...
Did you call Legal?
Well, they're sending somebody.
- Carter!
- Three-story fall from a skylight.
- Good luck, Gallant.
- Hey, how should I handle this?
- Gently.
Full trauma panel, Foley and
NG. He needs a central line.
Decreased breath, both
sides. Bilateral chest tubes.
Squeeze in two of O-neg,
type and cross for four.
He's got a dozen
deep lacerations.
Pumpers we have to
clamp off or he's gonna leak.
- We need another doctor. Weaver?
- I don't know. Romano sent Kovac home.
Pressure's dropping. Sats down to 82.
- Right AC is blown.
- Okay, get Pratt.
- He left.
- What?
- He had an emergency again.
Leon.
Where are you, man?
What happened to you?
Did you pass out? Huh?
- Stabbed me and stomped on my hand.
- Did you pass out? Huh?
- I'm dying, G.
- Who did this to you? Dukey and them?
- Yeah.
- Yeah?
He wanted the gun.
- Shh.
- They're gonna kill me.
You have to be
quiet. I have to listen.
They wanted it. And I didn't have it. I
got scared. And they're so mad at me.
It was Dukey's gun,
right? They stabbed you?
- Where did they stab you?
- In the ass. In the ass, G.
Come on. We got
to go to the hospital.
No, no. Where's the gun, G?
- They're outside.
- We have to go to the hospital.
- No. They're gonna kill both of us!
- Nobody's gonna kill us.
No... Okay, okay,
okay, okay, okay...
Where are we?
Don't even bother gloving up.
Time of death, 18:44.
Ugh. Sorry. I came
as soon as I heard.
It's not your fault.
Carter, labs on your
cranky old doctor.
- McNulty. Thank you.
- But he's MIA.
He's diabetic. Get him on the
phone. He needs to come back.
I tried. I keep
getting a machine.
Tell him his blood sugar's
435 and to get back here.
And page Dr. Pratt, 911.
I'm gonna have you on the
IV for about another half-hour.
Everything's fine.
- Kerry, you should really think about...
- Pelvic rest.
Return with abdominal pain,
fever, increased bleeding.
Methergine.2 milligrams,
p.o. q.i.d. I know what to do.
I was gonna say you
should take some time off.
Come see me in three days.
Can I get you anything?
You want me to try
and call Sandy at work?
Okay.
Abby.
I can give you a ride
home in about an hour.
Thanks.
We were lucky to capture
that retrograde ejaculation.
- Lucky. We're moving him to CCU.
- Oh, Mattie and Bob are with him.
I have to go. I
ovulated this morning.
Let's go. We're
killing spermatozoa.
- Did he just say "spermatozoa"?
- That man has an electroejaculator.
- Electroejaculator?
- Does that come with a costume?
- Nope. An extension cord.
- Oh, the mighty Gilman pulled through.
- An inspiration to us all.
- Gallant, Pratt for you.
Abby, have you ever heard
of an electroejaculator?
- You just like saying that word.
- No.
I had an instant ejaculator once.
Tommy Reynolds, 10th grade.
- Poor kid never made it out of his jeans.
- Ixnay on the jaculator-ay.
- Hey, has anybody seen Pratt?
- Uh, Gallant's on the phone with him.
- I don't feel comfortable doing that.
- I want to talk to him.
- Dr. Carter wants to talk to you.
- Where the hell are you?
Pratt?
What's going on, Gallant?
I'm only gonna ask you once.
Ah! It hurts, G.
All right, there he is.
Lay on your stomach.
It hurts all over, G.
Gallant, what took
you so damn long?
I see I got through
to you earlier today.
- Running a clinic out of the apartment?
- Come on.
Who's hurt?
It's my brother, Leon.
Who are you?
- G?
- Don't worry. He's a doctor too.
Looks like he should be in the hospital.
- No, man. I heard that.
- Calm down. We're not going anywhere.
- I ain't going.
Just calm down. Listen,
we're staying right here.
Either you're gonna
help or you're not.
This is not smart, Pratt.
Everything in my life
is not smart, Carter.
- How long ago did you get hurt?
- Three hours ago, but he's okay.
Gunshot?
Stab wound.
Also fractured fourth
and fifth metacarpals.
He's got broken ribs, bloody
nose, no septal hematoma.
Listen to me. Um, I'm good, I
got this. I mean, you can go now.
All I needed was a suture kit.
Why don't you wanna
go to the hospital?
- You don't want the assault reported?
- They gonna kill us.
Nobody's gonna
kill us. Let it go.
Why'd you get beat up?
I didn't have the gun
when they asked for it.
We gotta get it
back, G. They want it.
Holding the gun for
someone else, huh?
My friends.
Some friends.
I'm a danger to
myself and others.
If you went home,
what would you do?
I don't know.
- You have to tell him what you would do.
- Stop coaching him.
Where are you going?
- I have patients.
- Chip, listen to me right now.
If you don't tell the
truth, we can't help you.
This is your last chance.
I'm picking up my
ex-girlfriend's son from school...
and having sex with him in my
car behind the baseball field...
as soon as I leave here.
Okay, I'll make room for him.
How are you feeling? Good.
Uh, did you call your parents?
They're gonna worry about you.
What did she say?
Uh... "They'll worry about me
more if they know I have a boyfriend."
What?
She doesn't want to disappoint
them more than she already has...
by being deaf.
No. You can't go home.
You have to stay here tonight.
I'll call.
Why was I a patient?
You saw me?
I was...
Leon, he's your brother?
No.
Well, yeah, kind of.
He came to live with me
and my mom when he was 9.
I was 6 then.
I idolized him.
Then when I was 15, my
mom died of liver cancer...
and Leon took care of me.
Made sure I went to school.
So when I was in college, one day
he got into a fight in a bar in Detroit.
Ha, believe me, this is
one tough son of a bitch.
I'm trying to tell you, I mean, he
survived a 9 mm bullet to the brain.
But in turn, his IQ
dropped about 40 points.
Do you have any help?
No. I've been doing it
on my own for years.
I'm good at that.
Well, we work as a team.
We cover for each other.
We lean on each other.
The job's too big to do solo.
And if you can't get that...
maybe you should be a surgeon.
Or a superhero, or something else
that doesn't require trusting people.
I've never been big on trust.
You know what that turns into?
Nobody trusts you either.
Look, self-sufficiency's a good
thing, but it's not the only thing.
Asking for help
when you need it...
doesn't make you weak.
Um, maybe I
should go inside now.
All right.