- I was late.
- It's okay, sweetie,
- it's not your fault.
- I just wanted to play
one more game at Gary's.
What? You did great,
you called 911 right away.
- He looks dead.
- Daddy's not dead.
He's gonna be okay, right?
- He had a stroke.
- That's not possible.
Well, the CT confirmed
a ruptured aneurysm.
We have to operate
to clip the bleeding
- and reduce intracranial pressure.
- No, he had a stroke six years ago.
They put him on diltiazem.
We're gonna take
good care of your dad.
Naja Modi, 28 years old,
suffered a burn to her left hand
as a result of a cooking accident.
Are Jared and I being punished?
This is not a very
interesting case, is it?
Lesson one.
Don't suggest to the head of Surgery
that working with the head of Surgery
is a form of punishment.
Dr. Melendez is very
unhappy with Jared
for how he got his job back.
And Dr. Melendez is unhappy
with me for taking two days off...
I don't think he wants
to talk about this, Shaun.
I was an idiot.
It's on the stove. Of
course, it's hot, right?
You wouldn't believe how often
we see these types of accidents.
Well, there are a lot of idiots.
Okay. What do we
need to do here, Murphy?
A superficial partial-thickness burn
should be managed conservatively.
Cleanse the area,
debride with soft gauze,
and then cover with an
antimicrobial petroleum dressing.
All of which means this should
heal with minimal scarring.
Naja, are you having chest pain?
I think I'm having a heart
attack. It's hard to breathe.
Just relax if you can.
Put her on oxygen, a 12-lead EKG,
and order a portable chest X-ray.
Murphy, let's move. Come on.
Her vitals are stable.
- What the hell's going on here?
- I don't know. But it is interesting.
We've got a
subarachnoid hemorrhage.
Suction. I need to
isolate the aneurysm.
Poor kid. Imagine
finding your dad like that.
Well, that's exactly
how I wanna die.
If the dad doesn't make it,
the kid will always
remember that moment,
be traumatized by it.
Because he loves him.
The idea of dying without
anybody getting hurt...
There's nothing sadder
than an empty waiting room.
Okay, what do you see?
A bulge on the anterior
communicating artery.
Yeah, the ruptured aneurysm
is compromising blood flow
to the frontal lobe.
Prep an eleven-millimeter
standard clip.
- Are you married?
- Not anymore.
Turns out he had even
worse judgment than I did.
Speaking of creeps. You
hear Coyle got transferred?
I'm so glad they shut him down.
Yeah, I guess.
Just wish they'd spent the
money on a pediatric trauma pod.
They gave him a raise.
Clip.
The EKG confirmed you
weren't having a heart attack.
I wasn't faking. I
wouldn't do that.
We know.
The imaging also confirmed
that you have considerable
lung inflammation.
Is it possible you
inhaled smoke?
Well, I guess I must have.
There was a minor grease fire.
- What happens now?
- You need a bronchoscopy.
We put a camera down your throat
to see how much damage there is,
and what we need
to do to repair it.
But don't worry,
you'll be sedated.
Please don't.
Oh, I'm sorry, the test
is absolutely necessary.
The test is fine. But,
please don't touch me.
Except for medical purposes.
Yeah, of course.
That does not make sense.
A number of religions
have rules about touching.
- I don't quite get it, but...
- That makes sense.
People shouldn't touch people
unless there is a very good reason.
Okay, then what
doesn't make sense?
The grease fire.
The grease fire
explains the whole thing.
The burn, the smoke.
She told us she forgot
the stove was hot.
How can you forget
something's hot when it is on fire?
Shaun, I'm sure we would
have heard more of the story
if she hadn't suddenly thought
she was having a heart attack.
Why didn't you fire him?
Because his story
was different than yours.
And you believe his story?
I believe your story.
But you can't prove it,
and we simply can't make a
policy of believing every woman
who files a complaint
against every man.
After a few thousand
years of doing the opposite,
it wouldn't kill
us to overcorrect.
And the fact that your
boyfriend assaulted him
took away any leverage I had.
I did what I could.
I got him to take a position
where he has very little contact
with staff, with patients.
Outreach chair.
And it's a lousy assignment.
Sooner or later,
he's gonna quit.
And get a job somewhere else.
If you have any better ideas,
I look forward to hearing them.
You're very lucky.
The aneurysm was in a
small communicating artery.
We were able to restore blood
flow to the impacted brain areas.
He's gonna be okay.
Thank God.
Is this what life is gonna
be like from now on?
Are these things just
going to keep happening?
We're gonna keep
him here for a few days,
do some follow-up testing,
make some adjustments
to his medications.
Hopefully we'll find
out why this happened.
I have to go.
- Another one?
- Post-operative imaging showed
a 26 millimeter aneurysm
in the basilar artery.
That size and location,
we're looking at a
high risk of rupture.
He must have a
genetic predisposition.
Maybe a
connective-tissue disease.
All academic till we repair it.
Through the pharynx
and over to grandmother's
house we go.
There's the epiglottis
and the vocal cords.
I know you're not happy
that I sued the hospital,
but I'm not gonna
apologize for that.
That makes it simple.
I did it because I
want to be here.
I believe I can learn a lot from
you. Even from your doghouse.
I just hope you give
me a chance, sir.
There's the carina.
I'm gonna pass into the
mainstem bronchus of the left lung.
Is breaking up with
your fiancée traumatic?
When I saw a woman get shot,
everyone told me it was traumatic
and that I should be going home.
Should you be going home?
Give me a mucosal brush
- for a cellular sample.
- Loading it now.
How long does it take to get over a
breakup with the woman you love?
I'm seeing a lot of inflammation,
but no smoke damage.
That makes sense.
I thought we were doing this
because she inhaled smoke?
She said she inhaled
smoke. I didn't believe her.
Whatever the cause, the
inflammation and the damage are real.
Let's get a mucosal biopsy.
If I move down here...
The scope breached
a bronchial wall.
- She's hemorrhaging.
- This is bad.
Prep the OR.
Type and cross two units
of blood. We've gotta move.
We know there was a burn.
Was it something
related to the grease fire,
or a separate,
coincidental injury?
You don't have a theory?
Or are you refusing
to talk to Jared?
I didn't answer
because it doesn't matter
until we can
repair this puncture
before bacteria passes
through and spreads an infection.
That's true.
Cut this suture.
Let's approximate
the edges with forceps.
Are you and Jared even now?
He made a mistake, so did you.
Exactly what mistake did I make?
This breach was your fault.
Is that traumatic?
I had breakfast by myself.
Where were you?
I'm sorry. Were we supposed
to have breakfast this morning?
I had an early consult.
Yes. We always have
breakfast on Mondays.
- We do?
- Every Monday.
Every Monday.
Thank you.
Well, I guess our streak
has been broken then, huh?
If someone punctures
the bronchus
during a routine bronchoscopy,
that's a mistake, right?
Well, I can't imagine
how it wouldn't be.
Why? What did you do, Shaun?
I'm wondering if I need
to report Dr. Melendez.
Dr. Melendez did that?
The protocol is very clear.
I need to report it.
But I've seen how
Jared is being treated.
Will Dr. Melendez treat
me badly if I report this?
He shouldn't, obviously. But
human nature being what...
Human nature?
Shaun, you know what? You
should make this decision for yourself.
In fact, you should make
all your decisions
yourself from here on in.
That's what we agreed on, right?
Have you considered an
endovascular embolization procedure?
I have. It's a little less risky,
but I haven't done as many.
So, I'm not sure which
way we're better off.
You want me to check the roster?
See if there's somebody
available with more experience?
I would like to assist, but yes.
Okay, here we go.
No, he's not available.
So make him available.
I got a husband and father
who presented with two
aneurysms in the last 12 hours.
I'd rather not. This
particular surgeon
was recently transferred.
Not a chance.
Coyle is the best available
surgeon for the job.
Coyle should have been fired.
And if he'd been fired,
he wouldn't be available.
And if he wasn't available,
you would be the
best person for the job.
Our ultimate duty
is to the patient.
No, it's not.
You agree he should
have been fired?
- Of course...
- Even if he was the best doctor
in the hospital, he should
have been fired, right?
Yes.
So some things have to matter
more than who is the most skilled.
If we forgive Coyle just
because he's good at something,
what does he do next?
Either he matters, or we matter.
Were you upset
during the procedure?
Did Murphy tell you
that I was traumatized?
You think that I might
have almost killed a person
because you dumped me?
The fact that you're
describing it as me dumping you
suggests that you are upset.
Look, I'm fine, you're
fine, nobody's upset.
Great.
But you do understand that I
have to ask you these questions?
That I need a
statement from you?
Yes. Here's my statement.
I wasn't distracted.
I didn't screw up.
Did you get all that?
Your bronchus was
punctured during the procedure,
- but it's been repaired.
- How? How could that happen?
Why did you lie?
You said that you inhaled smoke,
but there was no evidence of smoke.
So, what do you gain
by lying to your doctors?
I wasn't lying. I was
just confused, I guess.
I was in a lot of pain and it
was all happening so fast.
My stomach...
Naja, what are you feeling?
It's really sore and I
feel like I'm gonna...
Can we get some help over here?
Four milligrams of ondansetron.
Airway inflammation,
abdominal pain, nausea...
We need a full blood panel
and abdominal ultrasound.
The procedure will
seal off the aneurysm,
but there will almost certainly
be some brain damage.
Anything from mild visual
or speech disturbances
to significant paralysis.
But without the
surgery, he'll die.
No.
I won't consent
to the operation.
There really isn't
a lot of choice here.
- Without the operation...
- After his first stroke,
it took him so long to recover.
It was frustrating
and painful for him.
But he did recover.
He made it clear he'd never
want to live compromised.
Excuse me.
Thank you for having
breakfast with me.
My pleasure.
People lie a lot, don't they?
No, I meant it, Shaun. I'm
happy to spend time with you.
There are seven reasons
that I've thought of.
There may even be more.
Do people ever lie
without a reason?
No.
Reason number six.
I think you just lied.
I think you just lied
to avoid something.
- You don't like this conversation.
- Shaun? Shaun, I'm sorry.
I'm just... I'm just
a little distracted.
My aneurysm patient,
we're treating him
with blood pressure meds
to try and avoid a rupture.
You should do an
endovascular embolization.
He doesn't want one. It could
leave him with brain damage.
- I thought he was unconscious.
- He is.
But his wife knows
what he wants.
It's amazing. I just...
I don't think I'd
be able to do that.
She's sacrificing her
happiness, her future,
- just because she knows...
- She's lying.
She's lying. It could be
either reason number four, or...
No, she's not lying,
Shaun. She loves him.
- She doesn't love him.
- You haven't even met her.
You haven't seen
what she's like with him,
- with their son...
- I'm not good at reading people.
- Well, I am...
- I think people-reading
embraces personal biases.
I think we should
try to avoid biases.
Knowledge of human behavior
can help us make
informed, intuitive decisions.
My way is better.
It's based on
actions. She's lying.
Okay.
If you love someone,
you'll do anything to
prevent their death.
This situation, there seems
to be a conflict of interest.
So, I would like to bring in
someone else from legal to handle it.
Yeah, I agree.
You're an excellent
lawyer, but...
But what?
Do you think this is my problem?
It's understandable.
Forty-eight hours
ago, we were engaged.
And now, suddenly you're
supposed to be investigating me?
Yes.
And doing crazy
things like expecting you
to give me complete answers
to appropriate questions.
You were trusting Murphy's
judgment over mine.
His judgment about my demeanor.
Seriously?
I asked you a question.
You wanted me to screw up.
You did screw up. So what?
So we just deal with it.
But if you can't even admit
- that you're not always perfect...
- I am not perfect!
Clearly, I have made
mistakes in my life.
But not this time.
That punctured
bronchus was not my fault.
The nurse says his
vital signs are stable.
- No change.
- That's good.
It's such a great sacrifice
to respect his wishes
enough to let him go.
You must love your
husband very much.
But, there could be
another explanation.
Either you love him
enough to let him die,
or you hate him
enough to let him die.
You don't know what
you're talking about.
There is a doctor
here who harassed me.
He made me feel
vulnerable, worthless.
Neither of which I am.
But he never hurt me.
I can't imagine how
I would feel if he did.
What I would do.
What I would want to do to him.
What did your husband do to you?
He's a good father.
No, he's not.
A good father
doesn't hurt a mother.
Payton loves him.
- All the more reason...
- No.
Payton doesn't know
anything. He never can.
I know you're afraid
he'll come after you,
but there are
people who can help.
Payton is better off with the memory
of a loving father than the truth.
Let him die.
Methanol is causing
her abdominal pain.
She drank wood alcohol?
People drink whatever
they can drink.
Well, she's Muslim.
Wouldn't let me touch her.
Religious people aren't
immune to hypocrisy.
There are other ways to
explain the presence of methanol.
It's also produced by the liver
when the body is exposed
to certain caustic chemicals.
If inhaled, caustic chemicals
could also inflame the lungs.
And caustic chemicals also burn.
So it would explain all her symptoms.
Do you happen to have a list of
which caustic chemicals do all that?
Dimethyl sulfate.
It's used in the
pharmaceutical industry.
- She's a school teacher, Murphy.
- It's also used in water treatment,
industrial pesticides
and chemical weapons.
She has no reason
to be involved with
water treatment or
industrial pesticides.
But she could be a school
teacher and a terrorist.
So, what do we do?
The surgery.
We don't have her consent.
Technically, the issue is
we don't have his consent.
We go to the wife
because we can't get his.
The assumption being that she's
operating in his best interests.
Pretty sure that's
not happening here.
Go back to the wife, get
her to change her mind
or we'll take it to court.
Okay.
Hey, you look annoyed.
I'm annoyed we're sending him
home to keep abusing his wife.
She's a world-class liar.
I mean, for all we know,
she wants her husband dead
so that she can run off
with her Pilates instructor.
- I'll get the consent.
- Thank you.
She refused initial treatment
for methanol toxicity.
It's ethanol. Because she's
Muslim, she can't consume it.
She has alcohol in her system,
but won't let us put alcohol
in her system to treat it
because she doesn't
want alcohol in her system.
- We put her on...
- Dr. Murphy.
Is this part of your evidence
that she's a terrorist?
Because she's a Muslim?
There are billions of
Muslims that aren't terrorists.
Is that part of your
evidence that she's not?
I think she's a terrorist
because it's the easiest way to
explain her symptoms and her lie.
Do you have a way?
She had an
accident, it scared her.
Maybe we scare her.
Hell, maybe this
whole place scares her.
There are a lot of reasons
people don't tell the truth
other than criminal activity.
Six other reasons.
If a person comes in
with a gunshot wound,
we have to report it.
Why don't we have to report someone
who might be making chemical weapons?
Because unfounded accusations
can destroy people's lives.
Well, what does it matter
what people speculate
as long as the truth comes out?
Because people make up their
minds before the truth comes out.
Says the guy who played the race
card when he needed an advantage.
Even if you're right,
she's not making bombs
while she's in our ICU.
Also, you're wrong.
Keep me posted. If she's not
better in the next two hours,
I wanna know.
We need you to consent
to your husband's surgery.
I said no.
There's a better way, Tessa.
Leave him.
Start a new life.
I'm afraid.
I know.
But this,
this isn't the answer.
If you don't consent,
we'll take this to the court.
We'll tell a judge what we know.
I told you those
things in confidence.
You are not my
patient, your husband is.
Two things will happen.
We will get the consent and
Payton will find out the truth.
Tessa...
You are stronger
than you think you are.
Your methanol
toxicity is abating.
The treatment's working.
Great.
Do you think that I'll
be able to leave soon?
All of your symptoms are consistent
with exposure to dimethyl sulfate.
- I've never heard of dimethyl...
- Dimethyl sulfate is used
to make chemical weapons.
I didn't expect this from you.
I made a statement.
But you're different.
I have autism.
You've experienced bigotry.
Yes.
Have people
refused to serve you?
Have you seen people change
their flight because of you?
Have people cursed you out
before you've opened your mouth?
I'm not prejudiced,
I have evidence.
Nobody's prejudiced,
everybody has evidence.
And I'm always brown.
Maybe you're not so different.
You're sweating.
Perspiration is a
sign of dishonesty.
My chest...
Chest pain can be
brought on by anxiety.
But this time, you are
having a heart attack.
EKG, stat!
The endothelial lining
had moderate inflammation
that appeared acute,
and there was evidence
of mucosal edema.
I made no extraordinary motions,
nor did I apply any
unnecessary force.
And yet the bronchus
was punctured.
Which is a risk, albeit a small
one, with this kind of procedure.
Well, thank you.
I appreciate the
thoroughness of your answers.
Not sure I understood it all...
But I think I've
got what I need.
I probably shouldn't
say anything,
but I know you and Ms. Preston are
going through something right now.
- That really wasn't relevant.
- I know. I know. It's just...
I know she'll get
through it, but,
it's good you're
handling it better.
It's one thing to be distracted
while drafting a contract,
and a whole other thing
entirely doing what you do.
Inject dye.
Injecting dye.
Hanging a left at
the vertebral artery.
Okay, withdrawing
the guide wire.
Inserting the platinum matrix.
I mean, sometimes
you do the right thing
and things get a little better.
And sometimes things still suck.
Entering the aneurysm.
Okay.
- Blood pressure's spiking.
- Wait, why?
There's no rupture,
no bleeding, no stroke.
If his BP goes up any
higher, he will have a stroke.
I'm terminating the procedure.
Push 20 milligrams
of labetalol, stat.
We need to stabilize him
before we can retry the procedure.
Which means we need to
figure out what we missed.
This wasn't our fault.
His BP was stable going in.
He's been on calcium
channel blockers
- the last six years...
- Well, we missed something.
BP doesn't skyrocket
for no reason.
Run a full workup.
Why would a 28-year-old
with no risk factors
have a heart attack?
Mm.
Her heart is burning.
Burning?
From the caustic chemical.
- Murphy...
- It's going through her system.
Unlike thermal burns, chemical
burns get worse over time.
And it also explains
the punctured bronchus.
The caustic chemical
thinned the bronchial walls.
You did not make a mistake.
That's not the only explanation.
But I'll shut up now.
You think you have a good idea,
but you're going to shut yourself up?
It could be caused by an infection
from the bacteria that leaked,
as a result of the puncture.
The treatments are
diametrically opposed.
Antibiotics if it's infection,
steroids if it's inflammation.
If we give antibiotics and
she needs steroids instead,
it will suppress
her immune system,
causing the infection
to flourish and kill her.
If she needs steroids and
we give her antibiotics, then...
- I get it, we better be right.
- Yes.
Sir, I think we should bring
another senior attending in
- to consult on this decision.
- Why?
Because if Shaun's
right, you're exonerated.
And if I'm right, you may
have made the mistake
that could kill this woman.
You don't think I
can be objective?
I think you're
incredibly professional...
Shut up, Jared.
It is possible
that I screwed up.
Let's put her on broad
spectrum antibiotics.
You're wrong.
Making a decision on the assumption
you made a mistake is a mistake.
You're very arrogant.
It helps you be a great surgeon.
Fortunately, I don't
need your approval.
We've determined what
the underlying problem was.
What caused your husband's
aneurysm to rupture,
and why his blood
pressure spiked in the OR.
According to his labs, he
hasn't been taking his meds.
As far as I know, he has.
I mean, that's
just not like him.
We don't think
it's like him either.
You think I had
something to do with this?
That I what?
Threw his meds away?
He'd just order more.
But if you emptied his capsules
and filled them with
sugar, or even better, salt...
It would end your nightmare.
I was willing to let him die.
But I could never...
If I were strong
enough to kill him...
Is there a chance your son
knows more than you think he does?
Her heart rate's 90.
That's in the normal range.
But it was 83. It
should be going down.
All her other signs are normal.
You were right, this
is the proper treatment.
Ninety-five.
I'm switching her to steroids.
If we give her steroids, it will
suppress her immune system,
causing the
infection to flourish...
I'm gonna push 40 milligrams
of methylprednisolone.
And she'll die.
This is on me.
I know.
We switched her to
methylprednisolone.
It's working.
You were wrong.
Yeah, I got that.
Just about the treatment choice.
You didn't do anything wrong
- in the OR.
- Don't kiss my ass.
Jared saved her life.
If he hadn't acted so
quickly, she would've died
and that would've
been your fault.
- Yes, it would've.
- You should thank him.
Thank you, Dr. Kalu.
Hey. Can I help you?
I'm Dr. Shaun Murphy.
You're my new
neighbor. Number 34.
Yeah. Cool.
- Do you wanna come in for a beer?
- No.
Nice work.
You, too.
You can have the honors.
This is the first time
I'm not looking forward
to telling the
family it went well.
You're going to be fine.
The treatment worked?
The second one did. The
first one almost killed you.
The fact that you're
alive right now is evidence
that you were working
with dimethyl sulfate.
You're a terrorist, aren't you?
My brother works
for a drug company.
They use dimethyl sulfate to
make one of their medications.
He stole some for me.
So you could make
a chemical weapon.
So I could make perfume.
Smell that.
It's beautiful.
But very stupid.
Yeah.
Especially since my brother would
get fired if anyone ever found out.
You believe her?
Protecting someone.
Reason number three.
So, we good?
The thing is, I'm not
sure it really matters.
I've been told I can only
have three residents next year.
- That's great.
- Not really.
Because of Coyle's
transfer, I have to take on his.
Reznick?
She's a pain.
Pain can be a
hell of a motivator.
Good luck.
You were right.
And I think you were right
that I wanted you to be wrong.
And I'm sorry.
You were right, too.
I kept telling myself
that I'm fine, but,
it's been hard.
Got me second-guessing myself,
maybe affecting my
judgment, I don't know.
If we're hurting so bad,
maybe we made a mistake.
No.
It just means that
what we had mattered.
It doesn't mean
that it was right.
I've also been thinking that
arrogance does make
me a better surgeon.
But it's not gonna make
me a better husband.
I'm sorry.
Kristin?
Hey, I'm Claire.
Hi. Thanks.
I am doing some
research on Dr. Coyle.
On the women who worked
with him and then quit.
I got another offer at SF Muni.
I was harassed by Dr. Coyle.
And I think you were, too.
Doing the right thing can
make things a little better.
Especially if we do it together.
Yeah.
I have a new neighbor.
Hmm. So, Lea's really gone, huh?
So, can we have
breakfast tomorrow?
I'd love to, Shaun, but...
We, um...
We talked about this, right?
I said that I would back
off if you stayed, right?
- More space, less fathering?
- I don't need a father,
I hate fathers.
- Right, so...
- I need a friend.
Shaun, I am someone who
can't help but give advice.
You know, I don't
know if I can not do that.
So, you think I can
change and you can't?
I think that we have a
certain kind of relationship,
and we can call it
something different if we want,
but we can't magically
make it different.
You said that you wanted space,
you said that you needed space.
I think you should be my friend.
Shaun...
Okay.
What are you smelling right now?
Pine trees.
Mm.