MEREDITH: Love.
Neuroscience tells us it activates
the same parts of the brain
as habit-forming addiction.
It makes us feel like
we can do anything,
be anything, achieve anything.
And once we taste it...
(GASPS)
We want more.
(BOTH PANTING)
You want to go again?
(BABY CRYING)
I guess not. Bailey's up.
(SIGHS)
What if I change my flight?
I could come by the hospital
before I get to the airport,
and we could find an empty
on-call room and... Huh?
I have work to do at work.
I can't do you, too.
Okay, well, then it's settled.
Let's go again now. Come
on. No! Absolutely not!
Come here. You are terrible!
Terrible influence!
We are getting up now.
Come on.
I know. What?
Why don't you
make yourself useful
and go change Bailey's diaper?
(SIGHS)
You're a tease.
(CRYING CONTINUES)
And you are terrible!
(CHUCKLES)
Have you seen my phone?
It's in your hand.
Not this one. This one's mine.
The government one,
the one I have to return.
I don't know where I put it.
Couch cushions?
Hey, Zola, hurry up, honey, or
you won't have time to eat breakfast!
Are you nervous?
It's not like you go to prison,
if you don't return the phone.
I mean, I don't go to
prison for that, right?
No, I meant resigning.
Giving up your job
isn't a small thing to do.
Well, it is. In comparison
to everything here, it is.
But... Meredith,
I meet with the president's
council in the morning.
I give them my final report,
my official recommendation,
and then I'm done.
I'll be home before you know it.
It's good. It's time.
(DOOR OPENS)
Oh! Hey!
You're here.
Yeah, we live here.
But you had a flight.
And, you, yesterday
you were going on and on
about some early
surgery that you had.
The point is, you're not
supposed to be home.
(CHUCKLING) So...
My surgery got pushed, and...
Weren't you wearing
that yesterday?
Amelia, you forgot your...
Hmm. Hey, uh...
I was just, um...
Her cell phone was...
Thank you. Yeah. Yeah.
Who wants breakfast? Anybody?
We have coffee.
Well, I should...
Yeah, I'm gonna go.
(CHUCKLES)
(BABY LAUGHS)
Hey, little guy!
Look who's here!
Want to go find your sister?
All right. Let's go.
(DOOR CLOSES)
So your sister and Owen?
She told me last
night. You knew?
Your sister's doing Owen
and you didn't tell me?
I was supposed to tell you that?
Yes!
I don't even remember
where I put my phone.
Now I have to remember
someone else's sex life?
I got to get to...
I'm gonna be... Oh, okay.
So we're gonna go again, huh?
(MEREDITH CHUCKLES)
Oh. Hey.
Best wife ever. Hmm.
I just wish, I don't
know, you could stay
or I could come with
you or something.
I'll be back soon.
You know that.
I know. I know.
I just feel like I just got you
back, and now you're going again,
and I just have to stay here.
You're right. You do.
You have to stay here.
Don't move.
Wait for me.
I'll be back before you know it.
Okay.
(ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)
Oh! Hey!
(WOMAN SPEAKING
INDISTINCTLY OVER PA)
Did you see that?
See what?
It was like he
didn't even see me.
I was supposed to
see a guy not see you?
No, no. We went on
a date, Ethan and I.
It was a good date. We had fun.
We talked for hours. We laughed.
But then at the end of the
date, there was no kissing.
(SIGHS) And you're pissed.
No, there wasn't even
an attempt at kissing.
See, you're pissed if we try,
you're pissed if we don't try.
No, but then no
phone call, no text,
no, "Hey, second date?"
And now he is
actively not seeing me.
Hmm. I'm actively not
seeing my cop anymore.
You guys went out already?
Yep. We went out
on a date. It was bad.
Well, at first, it
wasn't that bad.
He was all, "I save lives,
and I wear a uniform."
And then I realized I save
lives, I wear a uniform,
and I'm not boring.
No second date for him.
Okay, so, uh, what is
it? Tell me. Lay it out.
Am I hideous?
Am I... Am I... Do
I have bad breath?
What is the problem here?
Why me? Because you're a guy.
Exactly. I'm a guy.
Just tell me.
Go away!
(PAGER BEEPS) Oh.
MEREDITH: Hey.
So you and Owen...
Uh...
Is there an end to that?
I don't know. You tell me.
I don't know what to tell you.
Um, Owen and I are
getting to know each other.
How well?
"Pants on" or "pants off" well?
Is it just sex, or is
there something more?
Meredith, what is this?
I don't know. I'm asking you.
I don't know what we are yet.
Okay, well, that's
what I'm afraid of.
Listen, Cristina asked
me to watch out for him.
I promised I would, so I
just want to make sure that...
That I don't ruin him?
Is that what you mean?
That you're careful for
your sake and for his.
Hey.
Uh, I am on your service
today. You got anything good?
Ooh! Is that a split spine?
A complete spondylolisthesis?
Is that what we're doing today?
No. Oh, okay.
Well, then, what are
we doing? Nothing.
You and I are doing nothing.
I don't want a resident today.
I don't need company,
so you should go.
But I'm on your service...
For the love of God,
just do something else
and stop bugging me.
Marissa McKay,
arrived complaining of
severe lower back pain.
Her pediatrician dismissed it
as a combination
of growing pains
and soreness from
athletic activity.
Marissa's one of the best
junior golfers in the country.
The... The best.
It's true.
First place in the
NJGAs last year.
Marissa, honey... What?
Coach Rubin said there's no
apologies for being excellent.
And I am. I'm excellent.
What's wrong with that?
CALLIE: Absolutely nothing.
However, your x-ray does show
a severe misalignment of
your spine right here, okay?
It's supposed to look straight
like a piece of bamboo.
But yours is completely
bent. See that zigzag?
You've seen swinging
a club with this?
I try to tell her to
take it easy, but, uh...
You've been pushing
through the pain.
If I played football or soccer,
you wouldn't be surprised.
You'd be impressed.
I haven't lost a
tournament in four years.
I'm up for five athletic
scholarships at schools
none of my genius friends
can even get accepted to.
So what can we
do to fix her spine?
Well, Dr. Torres and I will
have to do a few more tests
before we can come
up with a plan of attack.
As long as it doesn't
affect my game, I'm in.
We will see what
we can figure out.
Excuse us.
Mmm.
She just kicked
you off the case?
No, first she bit my
head off for no reason.
Sometimes she
can be a little crazy,
and I just don't know if I'm
equipped to work under crazy!
Oh, wah.
The new neuro-god's protegee
can't handle a little inconsistency.
Shut up.
So maybe you're not
Shepherd's protegee.
Maybe Herman's surgery
was a one-time thing.
Have you thought about
other options besides neuro?
What do you feel
really good about?
That's the problem.
I'm really good at everything.
WOMAN: Help! Please! Help us!
He's hurt! We need
a doctor! Somebody!
(SLURRING) I can't...
I need to sit down.
It's okay! I've got you, Chef!
Sir, you need to let go so we
can see where the bleeding is!
Ahhh! My wife!
Here. Take this.
Sir, please hold still. My wife.
Your wife is fine,
sir. Just hold still.
Here.
Okay. Please lie back down.
We need to check out this cut.
My wife!
Were you and your
husband in an accident?
He's not my
husband. Here. Just...
APRIL: Edwards, anything?
No, no visible abdominal wounds.
Sir, would you please let us...
My wife! We can call your wife.
No! No!
My wife cut off my penis.
Here.
(GASPS)
(MAN GROANING)
Well, that's a big one.
MAN: Oh, God!
(SCREAMS) Let's run a CBC CHEM-7
and get two units
of blood ready to go.
What's the penis status?
Dorsal veins look good.
Get it debrided and
in saline gauze quickly.
Oh, God! (GROANING)
More pain meds! Fentanyl 150 IV.
And we need to pack him.
Cellulose polymer. Gauze!
And as you can see,
Dr. Kepner is doing the
groin tourniquet method
as I was telling you about,
and Dr. Edwards is attending
to the severed appendage.
Bleeding's under
control for now,
but we're gonna need
a specialist to reattach.
Catherine Avery's
on the West Coast
at a conference in San
Francisco this week.
I thought I'd see if
she could come up.
(GROANS) Is she good?
She's very good,
but so is Dr. McMurdo
in our urology department here.
Call him instead.
The urethra is very ragged.
Catherine's skin flap
reattachment technique
would greatly increase the odds
of a successful reattachment.
Well, then I want that!
I want the one with
the superior technique!
I've worked with
subpar technicians,
line cooks who
couldn't put out a plate.
I assure you, Dr. McMurdo
knows all the techniques.
Okay, but I... All
right, everybody.
Let's give them some
room to work, okay? Let's go.
Have you finished
prepping the phallus?
Just about.
Okay, then I need you
to get it to Jackson ASAP.
While everything
is still viable.
Every second we wait,
more healthy flesh dies.
He's in Procedure Room 4.
He knows you're coming. Go!
Excuse me! Pardon me!
That's a hell of a gash.
Did his wife do this, too?
Sort of.
I was the one who found Thomas.
And I went to put my
knives down at my station,
and there he was,
lying in a pool of blood.
He wasn't moving. I didn't
know, if he was alive or dead.
I ran over, and it
was so slippery,
I fell, too, and hit my face
on the damn induction range.
Marcia is a crazy woman.
THOMAS: She's not crazy.
She attacked you
and injured you badly.
I know, but I don't
want to call the police.
I don't want to press charges.
Excuse me! Pardon
me! Move, move!
Coming through! Coming through!
Thomas didn't deserve this.
All those great reviews
are not because of her.
Marcia is an owner.
Thomas Archibald is an artist.
I can't let this get out.
Bad for business.
Wait. Thomas Archibald,
as in the Thomas Archibald?
I've been trying to get a
reservation at that place for months.
He's on his way up, and
he's taking me with him.
I'm his sous-chef.
(ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)
WOMAN: Marcia is trying
to destroy everything.
Uh, okay.
And by the way, it wasn't an
accident that after she cut it off,
she dumped it into the
stock pot at my station.
THOMAS: You know what happened.
Do you want to eat food
from my kitchen now?
MIRANDA: So...
Are you two together?
Will it still work...
After they put it back on?
Coming through! Move!
WOMAN: Watch out!
MAN: Hey, slow down!
She has a temper.
She's insane.
THOMAS: She's not a criminal.
WOMAN: She should be locked up.
But she won't hurt me again.
I'm here. I got it.
I got your package...
I mean, your patient.
The penis.
Your patient's penis. (SNIFFS)
In the package.
I mean, not your penis.
Can you give it to me?
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
You already irrigated the
urethra and the vessels?
Yeah, in the trauma
room. Nice work.
That makes a big difference
with dismemberments like this.
Sure. No problem.
It wasn't hard.
I mean, it's not a big thing.
I mean, it was easy.
I was just in and out.
Okay. Yeah, okay.
I'm gonna go now. Please.
(SIGHS)
Let's get PA. And
lateral chest x-rays.
And, you, sit tight,
and we will figure out
what's going on, okay?
(SIREN WAILS IN DISTANCE)
Will you go get those
films for me? Why?
Oh, right. 'Cause the
radiologist doesn't like you.
(CHUCKLES) Maybe
no one likes me.
Maybe I'm unlikable.
And I will die alone,
and my vagina will dry up
and grow brittle
and turn to dust
and just blow away
in a soft breeze.
And no one will know.
Oh, God.
I know. I'm
hideous. I'm a troll.
All my orgasms are gonna be
self-made, handcrafted ones.
I'm all I got.
Dr. Webber, did you always know
you were gonna
do general surgery?
Uh, I knew pretty
early on, yeah.
Okay, but how did you know
it was the right place for you?
Did you ever consider
anything else?
How did you choose it?
Well, I guess I didn't, really.
(SCOFFS) It chose me.
Uh, the patient was
a 54-year-old man.
A small bowel obstruction,
nothing out of the ordinary.
My attending allowed
me to resect, and...
That's when it happened.
The clamps were in,
cuts had been made.
I reached into the body cavity,
past the omentum,
around the liver,
and lifted the intestinal loops
from that living,
breathing body.
And that's when I knew.
I mean, holding those...
Those loops of
intestines in my hand,
the weight, the warmth...
I looked down at that
miracle in my hand,
and I just knew.
General surgery had chosen me.
Mmm.
(SIGHS)
(CHUCKLES)
Well, one day, you'll know, too.
AMELIA: So I'm seeing two
rods on either side of the spine
to preserve nerve root function.
CALLIE: Yeah,
no, I get that. I get it.
But I can do a
graft on two levels.
But then I can place a frozen
graft directly into the spine
and then add a
metal support plate.
That will give her
way more stability.
And you'd be severely limiting
the range of motion in her spine,
when the point is to
keep her swinging, right?
This defect is so pronounced,
she might need to let that go.
I don't know if I'm
ready to let that go.
I mean, you're looking
at gross bone function,
but not thinking about the subtleties
of possible nerve impingement.
No, I think it's more that I'm
looking at the stability she needs
to keep her from
being paralyzed,
and that's where neuro can
sometimes underestimate
the fundamental biomechanics.
And I think that's where ortho
can tend to go a little overboard.
Ha! Well, we know
bones. We do stability.
You guys do brains.
And we do nerves.
That's why you wouldn't hire a
carpenter to rewire your house.
Whoa. Whoa. What
is the real issue here?
What is this patient after?
(SIGHS)
Well, she wants to play golf.
No, she's a
teenaged golf prodigy.
Totally badass. But unfortunate...
So she wants the maximum
preserved mobility
we can offer her.
Putting her at risk
for a far worse injury.
Well, it seems like
Shepherd's plan works.
Chief Hunt, I
think that her plan
underestimates
the severity of...
We should do the
minimum possible
to maintain the mobility
this patient wants
and then work up from there.
Right.
Well, back to the
sawmill for me.
(HELICOPTER BLADES WHIRRING)
How is it?
It was only in the stock
pot for two minutes!
Okay, good. Then I
want to see this penis.
But first I want to see the
man that it belonged to.
(GLOVE SNAPS)
That is a nice, clean cut. Mmm.
THOMAS: I keep my knives sharp.
Huh. Well, it will make
reattachment much easier.
Will it ever work again?
Mr. Archibald, I don't
want you to worry.
I've reattached many phalluses.
This situation is not as
uncommon as you might think.
Your vessels and
nerves are intact,
so chances are very
good that when I'm finished,
you'll be able to go right back to
doing whatever it is you were doing
before you got
yourself into this mess.
Jackson's prepped the phallus,
and it's in the OR waiting for you.
And I'll be assisting
during surgery.
His corpus cavernosum
looks pristine. I'm impressed.
You must have gotten
it debrided very quickly.
STEPHANIE: I ran.
With the penis.
Really fast.
(KNOCK ON DOOR) Huh.
Following up on what
we saw in the ER...
Dr. Avery. What a surprise.
It can't be too
much of a surprise,
considering that I am one
of the world's leading experts
on penile reattachment.
Since I happened to
be in the neighborhood,
I just got on the first flight
here as soon as April called.
Well, then, how
fortunate that she called.
We hope this
approach will give her
the mobility she
needs to keep playing.
At the same level I was?
That's hard to say.
With adequate recovery
time and rehab...
State's coming soon.
How soon will I
get my swing back?
We'll just see, honey,
when they're done.
Right.
We know athletic
performance is your priority.
It's ours, too.
I am gonna do everything I
can to get you back on your feet.
And back on the fairway, right?
You know, it wouldn't be
the worst thing in the world
for you to take a
little break, sweetie.
And do what? Go to the mall?
Pick out seven shades of
the same stupid red lipstick
like everyone else my age?
I take time off, I
don't make state.
I don't make state,
forget nationals.
The sooner you fix me, the
sooner I'm back on my feet.
Let's do it, Dr. Shepherd.
Sure. You heard her.
Whatever she'd like.
Okay. I'll see you in there.
Catherine.
Richard.
Where are your minions?
Prepping for my
gallbladder removal in OR 3.
You do understand
that I'm only here for...
The man who had
this penis cut off?
Of course.
When I heard about
it, I thought of you first.
Hmm. As you should.
I am his best hope of
being a whole man again.
Patient's very lucky
that I was so close.
Well, in his position,
I have a hard time
calling him lucky,
especially given his
regrettable choice in women.
Best of luck in there.
(SIGHS)
And here are your chest films.
Thank you.
No.
No, thank you.
You went on a date with me,
and you never called me back,
and I think that is very
rude and very hurtful.
And I know that that is a thing
that people do sometimes, but...
People have feelings, you know?
And maybe you don't
care, but I have feelings.
And, you know, the
least you could do
is not ignore me in the hallways
and make me feel like
some kind of pariah.
You're doing it again.
Doing what? Talking.
You never stopped talking.
On our date, even for a second.
You talked the entire time.
From the minute I picked you up
to the minute I dropped you off.
You never shut up.
And amazingly,
in all that talking,
you never asked me one question.
You don't know a
single thing about me.
I didn't need to be there.
It wasn't even a date.
It was a monolog.
You went on a
date with yourself.
And then you paid. You paid.
You did all the talking,
you ordered for me,
and then you paid, so...
Okay.
God, this is so much more
severe in person than in the scans.
Can these rods
hold through L5? No.
Shoot.
Shoot. What?
I can't torque down the screws.
This won't keep the vertebrae
from slipping apart again.
So what do we do?
We need to drill
through the sacrum
and into the next vertebrae
and then insert a piece
of bone to anchor L5 to S1.
That sounds like exactly what...
Exactly what Torres
was saying, yes.
Yeah, but can you do
that? Put in a bone graft?
No, Warren, I can't.
I don't do bones.
Torres does bones,
so we need Torres.
So you're looking at...
I'm looking stupid
is what I'm looking,
but I would rather look
stupid than paralyze this girl.
Go scrub out and find her.
Tell her that I think
she's right and great
and smart and pretty.
I'm saying suck up a little!
(MONITOR BEEPING)
(SUCTION SLURPING)
It's gonna take them at least
10 hours to reattach that thing.
And what? It took his wife
like, what, a minute to cut it off?
She must have been really mad.
Ugh. You know, how
do you get that mad?
MIRANDA: Not long
after I discovered
my ex-husband had been
e-mailing another woman,
we met for breakfast.
That was a big breakfast.
Stacks of pancakes, eggs,
and all kinds of fancy jams
he thought would
somehow make it okay
that he was e-mailing another
woman, while he was married to me.
CALLIE: Hmm.
I remember staring
at the butter knife
I used to spread my fancy jam,
and for half a second,
imagined what the side
of his neck might look like
with the butter
knife in it. (LAUGHS)
Fancy jams dripping
down the side
of his fat, e-mail
cheating neck.
Yep, I've been that mad.
I thought Derek was cheating
on me, and I got that mad.
"Two trauma surgeons and
an orthopod" kind of mad.
Hmm. No comment.
You know, cutting off a penis
isn't actually that big of a deal.
I mean, it's not like
he needs it for survival
or to think or, like, I
don't know, to walk.
What?
Hey, it's my leg.
And, you know...
And for the record,
I only thought about
maiming you once, Callie,
and I told you that
the second I thought it.
Thank you? (CHUCKLES)
Look, the difference
is, we may think about it,
but we don't actually
dismember our spouses.
No. BENJAMIN: It's good to know.
Dr. Torres, Dr. Shepherd
needs you in the OR.
As soon as possible.
It's for Marissa.
We can't get spinal alignment.
Oh, damn it.
(ALARMS BEEPING)
CALLIE: Whoa! What's happening?
Spinal cord function
is completely gone.
We need to decompress.
Warren said that you couldn't
get the spinal alignment.
After he left, the rod slipped.
The L5 joint was more
unstable than anticipated.
She's gonna be paralyzed.
Unless we get in there now.
All right, prep the table.
We need to flip her over.
What?
The only way we can stabilize
her is with an anterior approach.
I need to get to her spine
through her abdomen.
AMELIA: Okay, I need to close.
No, no, no. We don't
have time for that.
Just shove a bacitracin
sponge in there.
Move that C-arm.
NURSE: Over here.
All right, I need to get in there
now, if she's gonna walk again.
BENJAMIN: We
can't just turn her over.
One wrong move, we could
sever the spinal cord completely.
AMELIA: We don't have a
choice. We have to move fast.
Let's get ready to log-roll her.
CALLIE: All right,
everybody get into place.
Watch those IV lines.
We need sterile towels.
Okay, I'm gonna pull the frame.
Warren, you catch
her, okay? On it.
All right. On my count.
One, two, three.
Oh, the annulus is
completely disrupted.
AMELIA: I need a visual
confirmation the nerves are free.
Warren, I need more retraction
on the aorta and the vena
cava. AMELIA: No, wait, not yet.
Warren, I need you to set up
an intraoperative myelogram.
Uh, we can't wait for that.
The spine's too unstable.
Warren, I need an
interbody spacer.
If the nerves are trapped
when you apply the spacer,
she will be paralyzed
permanently.
Warren, I need you to...
BENJAMIN: Okay, stop.
Stop.
All due respect, but I
can't set up a myelogram,
retract vessels, and get
a spacer simultaneously.
Now, I used to be
an anesthesiologist.
I have logged I don't know
how many hours in the OR.
And believe me, this is not
the first time that I've seen
two brilliant surgeons
duke it out over a body.
I am not getting in
the middle of that.
So I'm gonna stand here,
and I will happily proceed
as you both see fit,
but you are gonna have
to agree on what to do first.
Explain to me quickly why you
think we need to do a myelogram.
It's the only way
to know for sure
if any of the nerve
roots are trapped
before we realign the spine.
Okay, so I could start removing
the disk, while you do an ultrasound?
Yes, and then you
could reduce the spine
and hold it in place,
while I check the image.
Fine. Let's try it. Warren.
Get the ultrasound probe draped.
Right away.
And remind me to put Warren
on scut when we're out of here.
Will do. CALLIE: Mmm-hmm.
Can you do me a favor, dear,
and just retract that a bit further?
Thank you.
Could you do me a favor?
If Dr. Webber asks,
maybe could you tell him
that the patient requested you,
so I sort of had to call...
April, I'm not gonna lie.
You made the right call.
He's just gonna
have to deal with it.
Edwards, join us
at the field, please.
What year are you?
Third, Dr. Avery.
Okay, have you ever
done a phalloplasty before?
No. Not yet.
Well, it's high
time you learned.
First, you take a saphenous
vein graft, like this.
Mmm-hmm.
And you attach it
to the neophallus.
This will provide the new
penis with a profuse blood flow.
Now you. (MONITORS BEEPING)
Okay, first, anchor the stitch.
Good. Now run the suture.
Good.
You might be aware, Edwards,
there's a shortage of
women in the urology field.
But there's no shortage
of female patients
who might prefer a physician
that has a more personal
understanding of the anatomy.
Okay, Edwards. That was...
Above average.
Oh.
You do understand that that's just
about the highest compliment I give?
Ever.
(WOMAN SPEAKING
INDISTINCTLY OVER PA)
(CLEARS THROAT)
Surgery went well?
What do you think?
Why do I even ask?
My work was impeccable.
It's all up to him now.
How do you mean?
When one suffers an
injury to his manhood,
recovery is always challenging,
sometimes hopeless.
(SIGHS) You all
hold on to so much
of your fragile, little
self-esteem down there.
It's possible you may
never bounce back.
Mmm.
Sad, really.
The defect in your
daughter's spine was
more extensive than we thought.
But we were able to realign
her spine, and with therapy,
she should be able to
walk again, even run.
So she'll never play golf again?
But she'll be alive.
She will be mobile.
I wish that were
enough, but it's not.
This is all she wants.
The only thing.
And I'm the unsupportive mom,
(VOICE BREAKING) who
hired the crappy doctors,
who couldn't deliver
the one thing she wanted
more than anything
else in this world.
I'm so sorry. I
will talk to her.
My daughter
was excellent.
You were supposed to be, too.
(SIGHS)
Excuse me. Hey.
Amelia...
We did everything we could.
Come on.
We should have done it
your way from the beginning.
We should have started there.
She would be better off.
That is not true. Her defect...
My approach made things worse.
No, it didn't.
Amelia.
(TELEPHONE RINGS)
There you are. How
did the surgery go?
I can't do this.
You okay? No.
(CHUCKLING) No, I am not.
(SNIFFLES)
You shouldn't have weighed in.
I wish you hadn't. Excuse me?
You should have
stayed out of it.
My approach was inferior.
And it cost my patient in...
Terrible ways.
What are you talking about?
Can you tell me honestly
that you siding with me today
was only about that patient?
It had nothing to
do with you and me?
Your plan was smart and solid
and more in line with
what the patient wanted.
But why were you there?
Why... That is why I suggested...
The only reason you
even walked into that room
was because you heard my voice
and you wanted to check on me
and see me, because
of your personal feelings.
I know, because I would
have done the same thing.
Because we can't help
it. We are hard-wired.
Our brains change when we...
When we fall for another person,
our neurological
pathways get altered,
and we make choices.
We make decisions,
whether we want to or not.
This... This is
why it is not smart
to mix personal
and professional.
Amelia, that is not
what happened.
I left my home.
I left my job.
I have been trying
so hard to start over.
I have been fighting so hard
just to be taken seriously,
to do this job well.
That mom thinks that
I am a crappy doctor,
who screwed her kid out of a
future, and she is not wrong,
because all of this
could have been avoided,
if I had just...
(SNIFFLES)
If we had just kept our
professional lives professional,
but we didn't.
(SIGHS)
It was a mistake.
This is a mistake.
(SIGHS)
ALEX: He's full
of crap. Let it go.
(SUCTION SLURPING)
All right, look, when you
get going, you can talk, a lot.
But it's not like
you talk too much.
(SIGHS)
Say something.
It was humiliating.
Why? Because you have
more to say than him?
Look, he's probably intimidated,
'cause you're smarter
than he is and funnier.
You're funny as hell.
You make me laugh
every time we hang out.
You've got that
lispy thing and...
Look, you're never
gonna meet a guy
who doesn't like
that lispy thing.
They'll never tell
you to your face,
but it makes everything
you say sound good.
It's, like, cute and sexy and...
That... That... That smile
and that hair and, you know...
Look, there's nothing
wrong with you.
This is not your
problem. It's his problem.
You talk, yeah, but he
should want to listen.
Anyway, something's
wrong with the dude.
Tell him to piss off.
Mayos.
There is still slight edema, but
that should resolve with time.
The phallus is pink,
not blue or gray.
That indicates good blood flow.
Which means that things are
progressing much better than expected.
And you are a lucky man.
Is it gonna work?
I'm optimistic that you'll get
back most of your normal function.
(SIGHS) MARCIA: Baby?
Marcia.
Wife.
Quietly, carefully,
slip out of this room.
Call security right now.
I've been so worried about you.
Ma'am, I don't know
how you located this room,
but I'm gonna need
you to wait outside.
THOMAS: No.
I called her.
I'm sorry, sweetheart.
I never should have...
It's my fault. We
had an agreement.
Waitresses and hostesses
were okay, nothing else.
She's your sous-chef.
I know. I know. It's not okay.
I'm sorry.
No, baby, I'm sorry.
Sweetie.
STEPHANIE: I don't get
it. How is he kissing her?
How's he kissing
the woman who...
Sometimes, it takes
crazy to love crazy.
I can't explain it.
Is security on their way?
Oh, yeah. Be here any minute.
(RORY SOBBING)
(WOMAN SPEAKING
INDISTINCTLY OVER PA)
Kepner!
Dr. Webber. (TELEPHONE RINGS)
I've been teaching
here for a very long time.
I present salient points
with clarity and authority,
which is why I am very
interested in understanding
why the hell you
called Catherine Avery,
when I explicitly
told you not to!
All right. I'll tell you.
My patient today
had a terrible injury.
The very best person to treat
that injury was Catherine Avery.
Now, I don't know what
personal stuff is going on
between the two of you
exactly, but whatever it is,
I will not allow
it to compromise
my patient, his
care, or his penis!
And for what it's worth, I think
you two are good together!
Also, Catherine Avery
is my mother-in-law,
so I'll call her any
damn time I feel like it!
Understood. All right.
(SIGHS) Need something?
'Cause I was just
headed out for the night.
Yeah, I brought the thunder.
Sorry?
I brought the thunder.
It's what I call it.
Only, I mean, it's
very effective at work.
It's totally
inappropriate on a date.
I was nervous.
I didn't socialize
a lot as a kid.
I kind of spent all
my time in books,
and you don't have to socialize
with books.
So when I get nervous,
I tend to cover it
up by talking a lot
and being really
loud and definite
and being in charge...
So no one will see
how scared I am.
And on our date,
I was terrified,
because you're very handsome
and nice, and you're great.
And I'm dorky.
I'm nerdy. I'm me.
So I brought the thunder,
and I'm so, so sorry,
because I really liked you.
Um...
I just wanted you to
know that I wasn't...
I mean, I'm not... I'm... I'm...
Uh...
Anyway...
Bye.
Maggie.
Next time, I'll
bring the thunder.
(CRICKETS CHIRPING)
(SIGHS)
Look, I appreciate that you
are looking out for Owen.
I do, but what I
do and who I see
are, quite honestly,
none of your business.
Wow.
Okay.
I was only trying to...
I moved here to start something,
to build a new life.
You don't know me.
Not really.
You don't know where I've been
or what I've had to overcome,
because you have never had to.
You've never lost
the love of your life.
You have never cried
over the body of the person
you love most in this world.
You...
You don't know how
that messes a person up.
You've never had to claw
your way back from that.
But I have.
I'm still trying to
pull myself together,
and I am doing the
very best that I can, so...
Until you've done that,
until you've had to
walk in my shoes,
I need you to cut me some slack.
And back the hell off.
(FOOTSTEPS RECEDING)
The microvascular
work is amazing.
I mean, every tiny, little
incision has to be perfect.
Did I tell you
Catherine Avery told
me I was above average?
Yeah, yeah. You mentioned it.
This might be it. I might
have found my specialty.
Thank God!
I've been worried about
your specialty all day!
Shut up. (THOMAS SCREAMING)
MAN: What happened in there?
(GROANING)
She cut it off! She cut it off!
What? Your wife?
It was my sous-chef! Oh, God!
(GROANING)
Come back with that penis!
(ALL MURMURING)
Okay. Hold it right there.
Okay, Rory. Hand it over.
No.
Don't be scared, all right?
Give me the penis, and
everything will be fine.
Stop. Don't come any closer.
Just put it in my hand...
I said stop.
I swear to god, you come
any closer, I'll flush it.
Okay.
Okay, everything's
gonna be okay.
No one wants to hurt you.
All you have to do
is just give it to me,
and everything will be fine.
(VOICE BREAKING) I was
more than his sous-chef.
He said I was his
heart, his muse.
We were gonna open
another restaurant,
our restaurant,
together, as co-chefs.
He was gonna leave Marcia.
I believed him.
(CRYING) I believed in him.
But then...
She cut off his penis,
and he still took her back.
That's not fair.
No, that's not fair.
All you wanted to
do was be together.
I don't understand.
(SOBBING) It's okay.
Come on.
(SIGHS)
You are a woman of rare talent,
a forward thinker, a warrior.
You saw my masterpiece
in the hands of a thief,
and you ran to its rescue.
You charged into
battle. Thank you.
You're exactly the kind of
surgeon that I need in Boston,
bold, fearless.
And when you're
looking at specialties,
I hope that you will consider
a urology fellowship with me.
Wow.
That... That's... Wow.
You deserve it, Edwards.
Without you, this man's specimen
would have turned
into a sad, old bagpipe.
(LAUGHS)
So you finish up here,
and I'll go check on
our patient in pre-op.
Do you need something?
I need to make one thing clear.
My manhood has not
been damaged here.
You may think I have a problem
with powerful women, but...
You're having one right now.
No. Right now, I am
having a problem with you.
We are having this problem.
And the problem is, I hurt you.
I hurt your feelings,
and I'm sorry.
I came to you last year
intending to propose,
but I let our professional
differences stop me.
We love our work.
It's everything to us,
so it's easy to prioritize it.
I made that mistake before.
I don't want to make it again.
Let me stop you right there,
because I don't
think I can do this. I...
It's just happened
too many damn times.
With Jackson's father, with you.
You work... You work to
make something better,
and then it just all... It
just falls apart every time.
I know. It's true.
In fact, the only thing
I can truly promise
is I'll probably hurt you again.
Well, that's really enticing.
And you'll hurt me,
and I'll come right back
to you again when you do.
I'll accept the risk,
because you are worth it,
because you matter to me.
Because I love you.
And I'm not going anywhere.
CALLIE: Hmm.
You okay?
What do you think?
I think there are
probably a hundred things
that you'd be great at that
you haven't even tried yet.
My mom thinks I did all this,
because I get some
kind of weird high
off being better
than everyone else.
And don't get me wrong.
Being excellent is...
Amazing.
But that's because I love this.
Loved this.
Even if you're both right,
that I'll find something else,
I'll never really love it.
Not like this.
Maybe not, but I believe (SIGHS)
we get more than
just one thing to love.
And one day,
(CHUCKLES LIGHTLY)
something will click.
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
And you'll know you found it.
I have to believe that.
BENJAMIN: So hang on. Hang on.
So you just chased after her
as she ran down the hall
(CHUCKLING) with his penis?
Tell me again about the gloves.
How on earth did you
think to grab gloves?
Instinct, I guess.
So when do you leave for Boston?
I don't know. Can...
Let's not talk about it.
(SIGHS) I can't believe she
handed the penis over to you,
just like that.
So lucky.
Yeah, she did.
She handed it to me.
Severed penis.
I was standing there holding
a severed penis in my hand,
and all I could think was,
"This isn't why I
became a surgeon."
I do not love this penis.
I do not want a
career in urology.
I mean, I don't
know what I do want,
but I know I don't want that,
'cause that thing was gross.
(CHUCKLES)
JO: Hey, are you hungry?
I hear it's tots day
in the cafeteria.
WOMAN: No. No, no, no,
no. (ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)
MEREDITH: The
thing about love is,
when it's good,
it's so very good.
What? Nothing.
Let's get some tots. Okay.
And when it's bad,
it hurts so much.
Hey, can we talk?
Uh, actually, I was just...
What's really going on?
I need you to tell me, 'cause...
(SIGHS)
You say one thing,
and I think you mean
something else entirely,
and I want to understand.
I am trying to.
Because I want
what we started here.
I do.
But I need a little help.
(TELEPHONE RINGS)
I don't think
that this is really the place
that we should be talking...
Dr. Shepherd? You
have a call on Line 4.
I got to get that.
And if you can't find a way to
balance all those ups and downs,
it will make you crazy.
Hello?
Oh, no, sorry. You want
the other Dr. Shepherd.
Here's his wife.
Hi. This is Dr. Shepherd's wife.
Uh, no, he's not here. Can
I take a message for you?
Okay, sure.
Oh.
I thought he was there.
Okay. Sure. No problem.
Okay, thank you.
Bye-bye.
Well, that was weird.
What was? Nothing.
Just that was the
White House calling.
Derek never showed up
at his meeting this morning.
Oh, yeah?
I'm sure his flight got
delayed or something.