Very good.
My turn now? My turn?
Did he finish his breakfast?
No, but I got him to
eat some strawberries.
Ah, Cleo, he's supposed
to have hot cereal
before he gets treats.
These are just as
nutritious, if not more so.
And they're yummy too.
At least tell the babysitter to
make sure he has a good lunch.
I cancelled the sitter.
What?
I'm off today.
Cleo, Reece needs
a lot of attention.
Peter, I'm a pediatrician.
All right.
Hey, see you, man.
Say, "See you at
the game, Daddy."
What? I didn't say I
was gonna play tonight.
You're not. You're going to
sit in the bleachers with Reece.
Come on. It'll be fun.
I'm playing first base.
Yeah, he doesn't
have a jacket here.
I'll go to Carla's
and pick one up.
No. You know what? I'll do it.
I can go.
I said I'd go.
I'm on the cell.
Okay.
Wanna play trains?
God, I slept so great.
And the dreams.
It's so wonderful to
be able to dream again.
Obviously, the therapy sessions
are helping, and these walks.
Good.
You know what?
You don't have to
stay home all the time.
I'm sure Luka would
love to see you.
It's only been a
couple of weeks.
He's a good man. Yeah.
So is your friend John.
Yeah.
Must be fun to have two
men interested in you.
Ma! Mom!
I've had men interested
in me all my life, you know.
Just not good ones.
Actually, I think your
father was the best
compared to all the rest.
But I certainly blew that.
Think we should head home?
Why is it we can't talk?
We're talking.
No. I mean about
important things.
You know, Dr. Legaspi
says it might be easier
for us to do it in
a therapy session.
Do what? Talk.
She wants you to come
to one of the sessions.
No. I don't think so.
I want you to come too. Please?
You could come
during lunch break.
I'm gonna head back.
Abby, will you come?
I'm gonna go to work.
Come on. Just... Just
think about it. All right?
Hi.
Can I help you?
Uh, I was just
dropping something off.
For Kim? She's in the shower.
I can give her that if you want.
No, thanks. Uh,
I'll pass it on later.
You're welcome
to come in and wait.
No. That won't be
necessary. Thank you.
Give me your name. I
can tell her you stopped by.
Dr. Greene? Huh?
Yeah, sorry. Oh.
I need to get some lab slips.
Oh, sure. Sorry.
Baby keeping you up, huh?
Oh, not really.
She slept for six
hours last night,
10 minutes at a time.
How long we gotta wait here?
I've been in the
hall for five minutes.
I can't find a doc
to save my life.
What do you got?
Seven-year-old boy tried
to put out a fire in a can.
Thickness burns on both hands.
Need some help?
Sure. BP, 110/60.
Is that him? He sounds agitated.
You could say that.
Hey. I'm Dr. Mark Greene.
You wanna tell me your name? No!
It's Ben.
I want this out of my nose!
That's to help you breathe.
It's only for a little while.
Are you his mother?
Neighbor. He's a
friend of my son's.
No answer at the kid's house.
Good air entry.
Both lungs are clear.
Any way to contact the parents?
He just has a father.
I left a message.
I wanna go home!
Let's go. Get it out!
What do you see me in?
A Beemer or a Porsche?
Most of the time
I see you walking.
Okay. You can
forget about a ride.
Carter, buy or lease?
Dr. Dave behind the wheel, huh?
This is topaz-blue metallic.
What do you think?
I think it's out of
your price range.
I'm moonlighting at a
doc in the box, my friend.
Figure three months, I
got my down payment.
Ooh, then what happens?
Ah, fake my own death.
Hey, uh, you
playing ball tonight?
We'll kick Sanitation's ass.
Maybe.
Neck pain in Curtain
1 is asking for you.
I'll be right there.
Black or sand interior?
Malucci, I hope you're
not keeping patients waiting
while you shop for a car.
No, no, no. I'm all
over that board, chief.
Don't worry. He still has
to pass his driver's test.
Dr. Carter, can I
speak to you a minute?
Sure.
Morning.
Morning, Dr. Chen.
Hey. Deb.
Could you excuse us a minute?
Oh, sure.
Your application was
intercepted by administration.
Processing time has improved.
You realize you're still
in a probationary period?
Which will be
completed by the time
the chief resident's
slot needs to be filled.
Why do you wanna do this?
Well, it gets me closer
to a junior faculty position.
Looks good on the CV.
No. I mean why risk
compromising your recovery
by taking on a new and
very demanding position?
I guess I don't
see it as a risk.
Having teaching and
administrative responsibilities
along with your clinical shifts?
I'm in the program. I've
been managing my stress.
I got myself back up to speed.
Carter, you'd all but give
up nights and weekends.
It's a tremendous
amount of work.
I'm ready for it.
We can't just gloss over
what happened last year.
Neither can the committee.
You're returning my application?
Did you honestly think
that you'd make the first cut?
Get your hands off me!
He's all yours.
Here. Let me take a closer look.
Don't touch me!
It'll feel better in a
second. I promise.
Mild erythema, no blistering.
It hurts! Stop!
Let the doctor finish. Okay?
You wanna tell me
what happened? No!
I think he lit the fire himself.
Shut up!
Why don't we get
a burn tray for Ben?
Sure.
He's home by himself a lot.
I said shut up!
I just wish he would stop
hanging around my son.
Hey. Good news.
Our second baseman
has the stomach flu.
Luka, I'm not playing softball.
Well, you don't
have to be great.
It's just for fun.
Actually, I happen
to play very well.
So go. It'll be good for you.
I can't.
One night away from your
mother isn't gonna do anything.
I miss you.
Have a good time tonight.
Conni, can you dispense
some ketoconazole to Exam 1?
Sure. Thanks.
Emergency ringworm, huh?
Yeah, pretty hard to avoid.
The guy has 40 cats.
You might wanna give him
a flea bath while you're at it.
So, what was going on
between you and Weaver?
Not much.
Except for her denying my
application for chief resident.
Apparently, I still have
a scarlet A on my chest.
Oh, wow. I'm really sorry, John.
Don't be. It makes
you a shoo-in.
There are other candidates.
Not really.
I guess congratulations
are in order.
Congratulations. You deserve it.
Thanks. Not as
much as me, but...
Yeah, right.
Hey. It's on the chair.
I put a cap in there too.
Good.
Just stay a while, and
have some coffee, maybe.
You know what?
I need to get back.
You all right?
Yeah.
Roger moved out a few days ago.
I'll be okay.
Are you sure?
It would have saved us
both a whole lot of trouble
if we had just stayed together.
You know, Peter?
Would have been
better for Reece, anyway.
He said he never loved me.
You know, Carla,
people say a lot of things
they don't mean
when they're fighting.
I don't know.
I think, uh, it's true.
Maybe we never had anything.
It'll work itself out.
You and I...
we had something.
Didn't we, Peter? Hm?
Hm?
Sometimes I think we still do.
I'm not doing this, Carla.
Peter, don't go.
Yeah?
That's a nice hello.
Cleo.
Did you make it to Carla's yet?
A few minutes ago.
Good. Hey, how about picking
up deli on the way home?
We can have a
picnic on the field.
Uh, sure. Yeah. Whatever.
You all right?
Yeah, why?
I don't know. You sound funny.
Is she giving you a
hard time again? Who?
Carla.
You know, I'm sorry.
I'm just in a rush.
Reece, wait!
What's he doing?
Hang on, Peter. Oh, my God!
Cleo, what happened?
Is there something wrong?
Read it and weep.
No bleeding, no
hydrocephalus, no midline shift,
no subarachnoid hemorrhage.
Okay. Do an LP.
You got a chronic
neck pain patient.
Wait. You want me to give a
Demerol junkie a spinal tap?
CTs are only 95
percent sensitive, Dave.
What are you two? A tag team?
I know what I'm doing.
Oh, to be a junior
resident again.
Not.
Dr. Chen, can I see you?
Sure.
Good luck.
Thanks.
As you know, Chief residency
is typically an extra year
completing the emergency
medicine program.
In rare cases, we
make an exception
and allow a senior to be
promoted into the position.
Right.
Unfortunately,
your maternity leave
put you three months behind
on shifts and procedures
keeping you just
shy of senior status.
But I'm in the process
of making that up.
Yes, but the academic
year ends June 30.
And I'm planning on
working every weekend
and every holiday until then.
Hospital policy actively
discourages work weeks
in excess of 60 hours.
And given that limitation,
it doesn't seem feasible
that you'd succeed in
making the deadline.
Oh.
And as a result,
I'm afraid you
won't be a candidate
for chief resident this year.
I'm sorry. I know it
doesn't seem fair.
Wait. This is completely
sexist and discriminatory!
Excuse me?
You all but offered
me this position
prior to my pregnancy.
Yes. And at that time
I anticipated your
completion of the program.
I had a baby.
I think I made a choice that
was both legal and responsible.
Of course you did.
I made a sacrifice,
largely for the
sake of my career
and becoming chief
resident is a huge part of that.
Jing-Mei.
I'm a good doctor.
I've offered to make
up for lost time.
And I didn't screw up.
Under the circumstances,
I think I deserve a chance.
I appreciate your thoughts.
And I'll take them
under advisement.
I'd hope you would.
What is that stuff?
Thermazine cream.
Make you feel better,
and it helps keep it
from getting infected.
My fingers feel funny.
How?
I can't feel the ends.
No?
Maybe with this hand.
Hey!
You know, that's not funny.
Everything okay in here?
Yeah. Little Ben here
just tried to grab me.
She was hurting my hand.
Oh, yeah? Let me take a look.
He says he can't
feel his fingers.
Here, let me see your hand.
What's wrong?
Ouch!
Oh, it hurts there,
huh? Did you fall?
I don't know. Maybe.
Let's get an x-ray of
this left hand just in case.
Ouch! Ow!
Hey, hey, hey.
Settle down.
My head. Yeah.
Okay, let me take
a look at your head.
Okay. Do you remember
when you hurt your ear?
Huh?
You got a pretty
bad bruise back here.
Six-disk CD changer, tinted
windows. That's... Hello?
There's an ACL tear in Exam 2.
Yeah. I was on my way, chief.
Yeah? Dr. Malucci,
you're a resident.
You can't afford a car!
What was all that about?
Uh, misguided
sense of job security.
Lot of that going around.
I heard you came by the house.
Yeah, I was in the
area, and on a whim,
I thought I'd stop by.
Lori said that you had a letter,
but that you didn't leave it.
It just didn't seem like
the timing was very good.
I can see how you
would feel that way.
How long have you two
been seeing each other?
Not long.
I'm sorry. I know this
must be painful for you.
No, I'm fine. I mean, it's fine.
Okay.
Kerry?
You take care of yourself.
You too. Okay.
I'm sorry. I didn't
mean to interrupt.
You didn't.
You two okay?
Oh, Dr. Legaspi.
Hi. Hi.
I was wondering
if you could tell me
how it's going with my mother.
Oh, I'm sorry, Abby.
I really can't discuss
her therapy with you.
Even if she said you
said I should attend
one of her sessions?
I think that it would be
mutually beneficial. Yeah.
Okay.
Could you give me a little
bit of an idea what to expect?
Well, it's not an ambush.
I'm sorry. It's just
that she lies a lot.
We meet at 1.
You don't have to
come if you don't want to.
Still hurt? I'm sorry.
Oh, baby! Look at you.
Ugh, it's all right.
Your mommy's here.
How bad is it?
He's got a fracture
of the fifth metacarpal.
His hand is broken?
He's gonna have to
wear a cast 6-8 weeks.
How is he gonna sign?
He's not.
All right. It's okay.
Mommy's here.
I'm sorry. I just looked
away for a second,
and he was at the piano.
Listen, why don't you give
us a few minutes, okay?
Mm-hm. Of course.
Hey. This is your
fault, you know.
I am so sorry. Mm-hm.
Reece is not like
other children.
I know.
Then how come you
didn't stay in his eye line?
It was an accident, Carla.
I don't know what else to say.
I feel horrible about this.
I want you to stay
away from my son.
Carla, can we just...?
What would have happened
if you turned away again?
What would have
happened if Reece
had run out into the
street? He is deaf!
You cannot just call him!
You have to be with...!
All right, Carla.
I don't wanna see this bitch...
I said back off!
Anywhere near Reece again!
Go.
Hey. Hi.
Hit and run. ETA's five minutes.
Kind of like waiting for thunder
after the lightning strikes.
Dr. Legaspi and I...
It ended.
I'm sorry.
Something changed?
Yes.
Do you love her?
Then you should
go forward, not back.
Fifty-year-old male
changing a blowout
got sideswiped by a car.
LOC at the scene, but started
coming around in the rig.
Obvious femur fracture. Vitals?
Initially, 90 palp.
BP's up to 115/70
after 1500 cc's of saline.
Sir, can you tell us your name?
Jim Vogel. God! My legs!
Trauma 2. Go.
Serial crits, type
and cross times 4.
We got one more, doc.
She won't come out.
Restrained, but got a
forehead lac from the mirror.
Brother says she's
developmentally challenged.
What's her name?
Won't say. I'm not sure
she understands the question.
Hi. I'm Dr. Weaver. Can
you tell me who you are?
Jim's sister.
Okay.
We need to make sure
you're not seriously hurt.
Can you come out?
I wanna go again.
I'm sorry?
On a ride. It's fun.
She's been smiling like
this ever since I got her in.
Here we go.
Crepitations on the right,
with decreased air entry.
I need that chest tube.
Tachy at 110. I'll set it up.
God, I can't stand it.
What do you got so far?
Pneumo on the right,
unstable pelvis
fractured right hip.
Where's Bonnie? She all right?
Is that your sister's name?
Yeah. Another doctor's checking.
She appears to have
only minor injuries.
Mr. Vogel, does Bonnie
have any medical conditions
other than her
developmental delay?
No. She's always been healthy.
Okay.
Sorry I'm late.
It's fine.
We're glad you could join us.
Hi. Hi.
Please know that
we both understand
how awkward it can be
to step into someone
else's therapy.
It's okay. I'm fine.
Maggie, do you wanna continue?
Sure. Um...
So, uh, Dr. Legaspi
and I were talking about...
Well, we talked about a lot.
But we were talking about
ways that I could stay healthy.
You know, how to position
myself to get it together,
keep on track. And, um...
part of that is that I've
decided to go home.
Have you talked to Eric?
No, not Florida.
Um, "home" home. I'm
going back to Minnesota.
Uh...
Uh... You haven't been to
Minneapolis in 15 years, Mom.
I know that. I know. I haven't.
But I grew up there. And
I feel like I belong there.
I've got a little bit of
family and some friends.
What friends?
Gina.
You remember Gina?
Well, I'm gonna stay with her.
She has a spare room.
She thinks she
could get me a job
in the convalescent
hospital where she works.
Really? When did
you arrange all this?
Last week. I...
She accepted a collect
phone call from me.
She was glad to
hear from me, Abby.
She was glad to talk to me.
Anyway, I... I'll... I'll
save enough money,
and I'll get a place of my own.
A place of your own?
Yes. A place of my own
with no roommates, no men.
Just me. Maybe a cat.
A cat? That would
be a great pet. Cat.
Abby, are you reacting
to your mother's plans?
I'm not reacting.
I'm just...
Just... Just what?
Nothing.
Abby, I can't stay
here in Chicago.
I don't wanna go to Florida.
It's just too easy for me
to be a drain on you and...
You know, I think we're
way past that at this point.
What is your objection to
your mother going home?
Nothing. It's very romantic.
You're not happy about it?
I don't know what...
What you want me to say.
Yippee, she's going home?
Fabulous, that solves
all the problems? What?
Then what is your solution?
I don't have a solution.
I... I don't... I don't
think there is a solution.
To talk about this as if it were
some life-management problem
that you can plan your
way out of, well, it's absurd.
Then what do you suggest?
I... I don't know.
Y... Uh, you know
what? I don't know.
I don't know. So I
guess you're right.
You have to do
something, Mom. Good luck.
So, what? You're leaving?
You wanted to tell
me. You told me.
Well, I'm not going
for a week or so.
Okay, great. See you later.
When did Ben
Fossen's father arrive?
A while ago. Someone
should have told me.
Hi. I'm Dr. Greene.
Derek Fossen.
Thanks for taking care of him.
Sure. Can we talk outside?
Yeah. We'll be
right outside, Ben.
Mrs. Shayatovich
told me about the fire.
Your neighbor?
Yeah. He's always
getting into trouble.
Yeah?
Yeah. His mom's
out of the picture.
And I think it
makes him act out.
Well, those burns will heal.
Good. Thanks.
I'm just waiting
on the psychiatrist
to come talk to Ben.
Psychiatrist? Why?
We found some unusual
bruising on your son, Mr. Fossen.
Do you know about that?
No.
You've never
noticed the bruises?
Well, he gets into
scrapes at school.
Fights? Yeah.
Any serious injuries?
No more than any kid.
Well, I'm sure he'll
tell that to the doctor.
Look, he doesn't
need a psychiatrist.
And I have to get
back to work. So...
I know. I know.
This won't take long.
We're supposed
to be at the park.
Is that where you were driving?
Two to 4:00 we go to the park.
But we had a crash.
I know.
My parents had a crash.
When's Jimmy coming back?
I don't know.
Did they die in the crash?
Your parents?
So, what do you do
in the park, Bonnie?
The slide.
Anything else?
The swing. You know,
Jimmy pushes me.
Not too high, though.
Do you have any other
brothers or sisters?
Nope.
C-spine is clear.
No perihepatic fluid but
I can't see the spleen.
Where's Bonnie?
She's fine. She's
getting some sutures.
Oh, thank God.
Minimal blood in the Thora-Seal,
but his repeat crit is 34.
He's bleeding from somewhere.
Probably here. What's wrong?
You shattered your pelvis.
That'll heal though, right?
Yes. But the edge of the
bone may be cutting an artery.
We need a CAT scan to see
where the bleeding is coming from.
Lydia, call Radiology.
Tell them we need abdomen
and pelvis with contrast.
Will I need surgery?
We'll know after the scan.
I can't be laid up. My sister...
Yes, I know.
We'll try to stop the bleeding
by injecting a clotting
agent into the artery.
BP's down to 95/60.
Okay. Hang another two units.
And call for six type-specific.
Okay. We need to go now.
I'm gonna bring Carla home,
and then go by your
place and pick up his stuff.
Fine.
Listen, I told you.
Reece, he needs
special attention.
Peter, I know that.
I made a mistake.
All right.
You know, but you're acting
like I deliberately
let him get hurt.
I'm sorry about what happened.
Carla gets upset.
Well, I don't get called
a bitch by anyone.
Bonnie,
where are you supposed to be?
Finding my brother.
Okay.
Jing-Mei?
Bonnie, you're supposed
to stay in that room.
I have to tell my brother
what I want for dinner.
Why is he back?
He dropped his
pressure upstairs.
There he is. Jimmy!
BP's only 80 palp.
Hang another two
units on the infuser.
What did the scan show?
He crashed before we
even got him on the table.
Dr. Weaver?
Open a peritoneal lavage kit.
We'll go supra-umbilical.
Lydia, drop an NG.
My sister has special needs.
Let's worry about you right now.
HemoCue is ten.
Okay, we need central access.
Somebody get Dr. Chen!
There's no one else but me.
Okay, Jim. Dr. Chen,
put in subclavian.
Got it.
Pressure's down to 70.
Pulse ox dropped to 84.
Jim? Jim?
He's not breathing.
Give me a 9-0 tube.
Bag him on 100 percent.
Get in that line!
Luka, if the tap is positive,
he goes to the O.R.
If not, maybe we can
embolize the pelvic bleeders.
I'm in.
Squeeze in all
the blood you can.
Call for eight more units.
Well, the hand's okay.
Look at the wrist.
Is that a Colles' fracture?
Ben says he
never hurt his wrist.
Maybe he's too
young to remember it.
His dad doesn't
remember, either.
How did your talk go with him?
Well, he's a pretty hostile kid.
Clammed up when
Dad showed up though.
Yeah. It was
hard to talk to him.
His dad was standing
outside the whole time,
and Ben knew it.
He's terrified of him.
I think he is.
But, uh, he says there's
no violence in the home.
You saw that bruising.
That's him getting
pulled by his ear.
He says he doesn't
remember how it happened.
You don't forget a broken
bone or bruising like that.
Lost his pulse.
He'll never make it to Angio.
Pump in that blood.
Order two units of FFP.
He's in V-fib!
Starting compressions.
Okay, charge to 200. Clear.
V-fib.
Thoracotomy tray.
It's blunt trauma.
It's an isolated
pelvic injury. Clear.
Lydia, close the
blinds to Suture.
Still in fib.
Three-sixty. Clear.
I'm starving.
We could pick something
up from Doc Magoo's.
You know, if I were smart,
I would have gone to lunch
instead of getting reamed
by my mother and Legaspi.
I don't get it. A week ago
she wanted her committed.
And now she's
completely on her side.
It's not about sides.
Well, it felt like it was.
All of a sudden it
was all about me.
What was my problem
that I couldn't get onboard
with this plan she figured out?
Would any plan have
made you happy?
No.
When was the last time
your mom was in therapy?
I don't know. Like 10 years ago.
That's different.
Yeah. So you got a choice.
You can either hope that she
makes it this time or give up.
Right.
Doesn't seem like
you wanna do that.
I don't know what I wanna do.
Weaver dropped a
bomb this morning.
What happened?
She bagged me
for chief resident.
Really?
Apparently my rehab
has caught up to me.
Oh, no. I'm sorry.
It's not your fault.
Not exactly.
I guess part of
facing the problem
is accepting some
people won't get over it.
I'm sorry, John.
Me too.
For you.
Get a 10-pack of platelets.
Heart's not filling.
Units 9 and 10 are in.
Hold compressions.
Still in fib.
Vasopressin? Onboard.
Another 100 of lido. I'll
take the internal paddles.
How long has he been down?
35 minutes.
Charge to 20. Jimmy?
Bonnie, you have to go outside.
Clear.
I don't like that.
Charge again.
Lydia?
I don't want you to do that.
We're trying to help him.
But it hurts him. Clear.
It hurts him.
Charge again.
Clear!
Heart's empty. Asystole.
Should we try pacing him?
Okay. That's it.
Time of death 17:10.
Can you close the chest up?
Yeah.
Clean him up but leave
the tubes in for the coroner.
I'll tell the sister.
Want me to come with you?
Yeah.
I'm tired of it here.
I think Jimmy and
me should go home.
The doctors are going
to talk to you now.
Hi, Bonnie. Hi.
Bonnie, this is your
brother's doctor.
Is he ready to go?
Bonnie, Jim was very hurt.
And he couldn't
recover from his injuries.
Cover? Get better.
Your brother died,
Bonnie. I'm sorry.
Do you understand?
Like Ernie.
He died.
Um, who's Ernie?
My hamster.
We put him in a box.
Okay.
Well, like your hamster, Jim
won't be with you anymore.
I got a new hamster.
His name is Ernie too.
You know how your
parents went away?
In the crash?
Jimmy went away like that too.
But it's library night.
I know.
And I get scared at night.
Bonnie, you're gonna
have to be very brave.
Where's Jimmy?
There you are.
Hi.
Do you have a minute?
Sure. Am I in
trouble or something?
I don't usually do this.
But I think it's important.
Okay.
I think you need to give
your mom one more chance.
Didn't I just do that today?
Well, you started to.
And then you ran away.
Maybe because I've heard
it about 100 times before.
I think this time's different.
Do you? Why?
Well, she hasn't been willing
to go to therapy for 10 years.
Now she's embracing it.
I'd love to believe
that meant something.
Don't let your mom go away
without being able
to really talk to you.
That won't make
either of you happy.
I don't think "happy"
is on the table.
Why not?
Look, I'm not in therapy.
Fair enough.
But I'll consider it.
What you said.
Okay.
She has the mind
of a 7-year-old.
And no other relatives?
Her brother was her only family.
I've tried ARC, Protection,
and Advocacy. No luck.
The facilities are all full.
She'll have to take a temp
place at a group home.
No. I don't want her
sent to a place like that.
There's four or five
people in every room.
Unless you take her
home, this is all I can offer.
Okay. But I don't wanna
hear about her sleeping
on the couch or on the floor.
Well, I'll pass that along.
You'll have to get
her there yourself.
They're too backed up.
Oh, come on!
I'm just the messenger.
Look, in time she'll adjust.
Adele, this stinks.
They have got
job-training programs.
Hopefully she'll learn a skill.
Adele, ready? Yeah.
Sorry.
It's about time.
Ben has not eaten since noon.
We'll get him something.
We'd rather just go.
This is Adele Neuman.
She's a social worker.
Hi. Hi, Ben. Hi.
Look, my kid does not need
any more counseling or whatever.
I'm afraid Ben's gonna
have to stay for a few days.
What?
We're taking him into custody.
What are you talking
about? What for?
I'm not comfortable
with the bruising.
God forbid you're
not comfortable.
I also found evidence
of a broken wrist
which neither of you mentioned.
I told you that he fights!
Would you tell
them? I fight a lot.
If that's true, then you'll
get to go home in three days.
But now I need you
to come with me.
I don't want to.
Whoa! You're not
doing this to us!
Security!
Get your hands off of me!
You don't have a choice here.
If you think I hurt
my kid, you're crazy.
I suggest you contact a lawyer.
To sue your ass!
For your protection.
I don't wanna go away!
Please let me stay with him!
I'm sorry.
Leave him alone!
No! Dad! Please!
You bastard!
Please! Dad!
Why are you doing this?
Dad!
Hi. Hi.
Guess what? The super
finally fixed the stove fan.
So I cooked dinner.
Cucumber soup, a little salmon.
Why don't you
invite Luka to dinner?
He's playing softball.
That sounds like fun.
Are you gonna go?
I don't wanna play. Um...
The reason why I ran out today
like that is because
it's just, um...
It's scary to hope
too much, you know?
Yeah, I know.
I know I might not make it.
But, Abby,
something happened
to me in that ICU room.
I realized I don't wanna die.
And more than that,
I don't want my little
girl to watch me die.
I can't do that
to you. Not ever.
That's what I wanted
to tell you today.
I'm gonna handle my life.
And I want you to
get on with yours.
Okay.
You can't put your
life on hold anymore.
It's not on hold.
You won't play softball
with your boyfriend.
So? I don't wanna play.
Stop sitting things out, Abby.
I don't.
Yes, you do.
You can't use me as the reason
for not doing the
things you wanna do.
Go to medical school.
That's not so easy.
Get married. I was married!
Get pregnant. I was pregnant!
What happened?
I had an abortion.
Some people aren't
meant to be mothers.
Abby...
I was a lot younger
than you are now
when I had my
first manic episode.
I've watched you since
you were a little girl.
You're not bipolar.
No. But my kids could be.
But they might not be.
They could be anything.
And you will just
love them. That's all.
You never even
told Richard, did you?
No, I...
I think that was the
beginning of the end for us
because we just stopped
talking about everything.
I just was too scared.
I cou... I couldn't risk it.
I just... I didn't want to...
Turn into me? Yeah.
Or have to end up
taking care of another me?
Oh, honey.
Oh, sweetie, sweetie, sweetie.
That's all there is is risk.
You just have to take a
chance and leap into life.
Otherwise, sweetheart,
you're gonna miss out
on all the great things.
Abby, you deserve
all the great things.
Do you hear me?
But I like my home.
Someone there will
take good care of you.
This man's gonna
drive you, okay?
Jimmy was gonna
make me hot dogs.
Take this woman to this address.
Make sure she's met by
an adult before you leave.
Yeah, all right.
Will they have hot
dogs? I don't know.
But I'm sure they'll
have something good.
Here you go.
I had better go to my home.
I'm sorry. You can't.
But I like my home. I like
my bed and my blanket.
Bonnie, you can't live alone.
But I need my blanket.
Jimmy always
gives me my blanket.
Someone there will give you one.
And he gives me
hot dogs when I want.
I like my home. I
don't want a new one.
Bonnie...
Zip your jacket,
sweetie. It's chilly.
Hey, batter, batter.
No batter. No batter.
Strike one!
That's good, right?
That's good.
Put it right here, doc.
You got it, big guy.
That's strike two.
That's all right.
Luka, look alive, man.
Hey, batter, batter.
No batter. No batter.
You change your mind?
Yeah. I even
brought my own glove.
Hey, Abby. You playing? Yeah.
Pick your weapon because
you're up after Carter.
All right. Keep your
head in the game.
You brought your mom?
Go get 'em, John.
Thank you, Maggie.
All right, Carter.
Get in there, man.
Luka, I didn't know
you played softball.
I don't. I'm last in
the batting order.
You should put Abby up.
She was an all-star on
her Little League team.
How about you?
I'm just gonna watch.
All-star?
I like you in that hat.
I almost look American, huh?
Almost.
Some vocabulary
for a 7-year-old.
Bone survey turned up
bilateral healed spiral
fractures of the radius.
So you were right.
Pin a rose on me.
Kim?
Hi, Kerry.
Um, this is for you.
What is it?
It's how I feel about
things, about you.
And I never really told you.
And maybe it doesn't matter now.
But I wanted you to know.
Okay.
You broke both your arms, Ben.
No, they're fine.
These are your x-rays.
These lines are fractures.
That was a long time ago.
I tripped at school.
No. You don't get these
kinds of breaks from falling.
After I tripped, I
fell down the stairs.
No, Ben.
You know what I think happened?
I think somebody grabbed
your arm with two hands
and then twisted it like
you do with a wet towel.
I'm bad a lot.
You are?
I make too much noise playing.
I leave messes.
And your Dad punishes you?
Well, how does he punish you?
Sometimes like you said.
He calls them Indian burns.
Yeah?
It's my fault.
He wouldn't do
it if I wasn't bad.
No, Ben.
Nobody should break your arm
no matter how bad you are.
You understand?
I don't care. I just
wanna go home.
You can't go home
right now, Ben.
I'm sorry.
Come on, Malik! Show
'em where you live!
Run, Abby! Run, Abby!
Get in there.
Abby, go! Abby!
Woo! Way to go!
Brought your
cheering section, I see.
That's my girl! That's great!
Go get 'em.
All right, Luka.
Just meet the ball like
we talked about, all right?
Hey.
Strike one!
You were so great.
You were great.
Did you hear me cheering?
Yes. I think everybody
heard you cheering.
Strike two.
Luka, don't crowd the plate!
What?
The plate! Get back!
He's very cute but
he's no Mickey Mantle.
No.
Ball one.
Are you cold?
No, no. I love it.
Thank you for bringing me here.
You looked like
you were having fun.
I was.
That's good. That's really good.
Foul ball.
That's a foul ball.
That's a foul ball!
Where are you going?
I don't think he knows that.
Run, Luka! Run!
Luka!