- I feel like I'll
say the wrong thing.
- You really can't.
There are no wrong answers here.
- Okay.
His kindness.
He's very kind.
- Something you love and
appreciate about Maggie?
- Yeah.
I guess I am...
Well, I love... I love that
she's here this morning,
because that means that
she's finally admitting
that we need help communicating.
So...
And I...
I appreciate how
hard Maggie works.
- How is that a bad thing?
- How is what I said bad?
- Every life on the planet
begins as a single cell,
which splits and multiplies
over and over again.
Each cell has a purpose.
- Okay, the kids are
dressed and ready,
and you're... still not up.
- I can't. I feel awful.
Can you take Luna to day care
for me so that I can sleep?
- Yeah.
- Thank you.
- And as it forms, internal
and external forces
converge on it.
- I know what you're doing.
- What, trying to spend
a little more time
with my wife?
- Now, you're gonna
have to go home
and then come back at
the end of the day.
- Yeah, well, I got the
day off, so I got time.
- Two extra trips,
more carbon footprint,
killing the planet...
Think of our children.
You see?
They've extended the
security perimeter,
perfectly safe.
- Signaling to the cell
what it will become.
We call this process
differentiation.
- Thanks for the ride.
- Love you.
- It'll be fine.
- An arm, a bone, a brain...
- Hi, good morning.
- Perfectly safe.
- All cells take a journey
from generalized to specialized.
- Sorry, sorry. I know
I'm a little late.
I have roommates,
tandem parking.
Anyway, I am here for
my plasma donation.
- We don't call it a donation
when you're taking $75 for it.
- Fair point.
- They go from nothing
to something...
- You're three
pounds underweight.
Can't give plasma today.
- Not possible.
I do this every two
months. Check your records.
- Check the scale.
Come back when you qualify.
- Or what you could
be to what you are.
- Hey.
- Good morning.
Do you want to meet up
if you have a break,
on-call room on four?
- Sounds fun.
Might take me a
while to get there.
I'm in Phoenix.
- Why?
- Because that's
where my next job is.
I finished my gig in Seattle.
- What?
You never said anything.
I was with you two days ago.
- Well, you always
seem more interested
in the on-call room on
four than actually talking.
- I...
- I got to go.
Let me know if you're
ever in Phoenix.
- I mean, I'd just
as soon elope,
but Trey and his family...
Super into tradition.
When he asked his brother to
be his best man, he cried.
My sister and I
hardly speak, and...
- She's trying to say that
she needs a maid of honor.
- Oh, I like you so much, but
I would be bad at that job.
- Hey, what the hell?
You left me again.
- Be on time.
- You know, if your
silver-spoon, nepotism ass
isn't in the seat by
7:00, you are out of luck.
- Tough, punctual, efficient...
There's your maid of honor.
- What?
- Forget it.
But you said 6:45.
- Yes, because we
gave you a fake time
that's 15 minutes before we're
actually planning to leave.
- And yet, you
still can't make it.
- Well, you could
have woken me up.
Does anybody have my back here?
- No.
- Oh, okay. Yes, I understand.
And I appreciate it, but...
Okay. Thank you.
- Busy morning?
- How come no one ever mentions
that part of the chief job
is actually being a reference
for other institutions
who are looking to
poach your surgeons?
- Not following.
- Harvard Med, NYU,
Heart Center of Chicago,
they're all on my call list
because they are
interested in Pierce.
How long has she
been working here?
Maybe there is something
in her contract
that prohibits her from leaving.
- Leaving? Maggie?
- Yeah.
That article has given
her a lot of attention.
Look, I don't wanna hold anyone
back, but we just lost Grey.
I mean, how do we
get Pierce to stay?
- Yeah, I'm on it.
Oh, great. Thanks.
I'm sorry... yeah, hi.
This is she.
- So cough and
sniffles, bed six.
- Nothing like half a
decade of medical training
to use on a runny nose.
- You know, I had a
patient who had sniffles.
Turned out he had a CSF
leak in his brain, so...
Uh, oh, complex trauma
case transferred
from a rural hospital.
Kwan, you wanna see the helipad?
- Oh, yeah.
- Just Kwan or...
- Adams, code phlegm.
Bed five needs a Neti pot.
Thank God you're here.
- Ma'am, please try
to keep your mask on.
- Agh, help!
I need a doctor.
- Move.
- I saw him first.
- Nope.
- No...
- Hey, hey.
- Have you been injured?
- Okay, rodeo wreck...
Rider in Oregon
got bucked off and stomped
on by a 1,000-pound bull.
- It's barbaric... bull riding.
Nothing but testosterone addicts
getting off on torturing animals
because it makes them
feel more like a man.
- Huh. Let's go.
Kay, what do we got?
- Georgia Arkins,
16. Crush injuries
from being trampled by a bull.
GCS 15, CT scan shows
a retrohepatic hematoma
from an IVC tear,
multiple lumbar burst fractures.
Vital signs are stable.
- She's been given
sedatives for transfer,
so she's a little out of it.
Local hospital didn't
feel equipped to handle
her complex injuries.
- Thank you.
- Can I go again?
The bull, can I go again?
I only got to 5 seconds.
- So anything you want to add
to your initial
assessment, Kwan?
Look up for me.
- He's exaggerating.
- Ever since the
interview, she's received
half a dozen amazing offers,
including a position in
bioartificial heart research.
- So we inject an
extracellular matrix
of a pig's heart, which
serves as, like, scaffolding,
with human stem cells,
that it can grow
cardiac muscle tissue.
- And then we electrically
stimulate them to twitch,
cell by cell, until they
start to beat together,
essentially as
one beating heart.
- It's beautiful.
- Yeah, which means more hearts
for people who need them.
- The research is at the
Heart Center of Chicago.
- Oh. Well, that's
a fantastic city.
- Yes, it is!
It's the Art Institute
and Steppenwolf,
deep dish pizza.
- You can keep those
winters, though,
with the wind just ripping
in off the lake like that.
- That's what parkas
and mittens are for.
- And it's weak pizza, really.
It's just quantity over quality.
- So are you considering it?
- Well, I might like to, but...
- Look, I've already
moved across the country
for you once.
And then, when I tried
to change my specialty,
also for you, you lost
all respect for me.
So...
- Please don't put
words into my mouth.
- Those are your words.
You put those words
in your own mouth.
I have to go.
- You have to go now?
- Can we pick this up?
- God's sake, Maggie,
I have waited weeks,
weeks of just tiptoeing around,
going along with this
ceasefire that you proposed
until we could get in
here and try to fix this.
And now you're on the hot seat,
so you just want to walk out?
You know, no, I'm not even
that surprised by this.
- I'm on trauma call, Winston.
Please excuse me.
- Hey, what are you doing here?
The kids okay?
- Everyone's fine, except you.
You're not fine.
And you're also not sick.
- I am sick. What
are you doing here?
- I took the kids to day care,
and I took a personal day,
because your body does this.
- My body does what?
- It aches so that you'll
rest because it's learned
that if it aches,
you'll stay in bed,
when nothing else works
to keep you in bed.
You need a day off,
but you're not sick,
which is why you get a latte
and...
The little doughnuts
with the pink frosting.
- You took the day off?
- Yeah, I figured you
could use the company.
Plus, after I eat three boxes
of these, I'm no good at work.
- You ate three boxes?
- No, but I'm about to.
You might want to look away.
- I'm just gonna go.
No.
- Ow!
- Any feeling of nausea?
Ah, not really.
Is there anything you
can do about the pain?
It feels like someone's
dicing my intestines.
- We'll take care of
that for you in a moment.
But I need to finish
this physical exam
before we can...
- Look, I came here
because Grey-Sloan's
supposed to be the best.
So please, you gotta help me.
- It could be a
positive McBurney sign.
- Which could be caused by...
- Appendicitis.
- Diverticulitis.
- Yo! What the hell?
- I was seeing if the
pain was exacerbated
by jostling movements.
- Can we wait to play school
until I'm not in agony?
- Let's get him comfortable.
We'll send him up
for the basic labs,
and then let's take him
up to CT for some scans.
- Did I hear correctly, a bull?
- T-bird. He's feisty.
I just didn't get out over
his front end in time.
- When T-bird
trampled over Georgia,
he crushed her liver
and likely tore her IVC.
There's a big hematoma in
the retrohepatic space,
which it looks contained
for now, stable HNH.
- She's got unstable T10
through L3 burst fractures.
- Please don't tell my parents.
They freak out whenever
stuff like this happens.
- This has happened before?
- I had a huge cut on my back,
a broken wrist, a broken leg.
Oh, and I have
this massive scar.
- Whoa, whoa!
- Push two of midazolam.
- Okay, this burst L3
fracture is too unstable.
Without immediate surgery,
we're talking about paralysis.
Once Maggie goes in
and repairs the IVC,
I will stabilize the spine.
- I don't think I should go in.
- There's a massive hematoma.
- And it's sitting
in a minefield.
The hematoma is stable for now.
But you should go in
and repair the spine,
and I will be there
to monitor her.
Just use a posterior approach
to avoid rupturing it.
- What if it happens anyway?
- Then we'll flip her,
and I will control the bleeding.
- No, I'm not sure
I should go in.
- If you don't, she
never walks again.
- Are Georgia's parents here?
- Look. All I need
is antibiotics.
It'll clear up in
a few days or so.
- Maybe.
But I am hearing some
wheezing in the left lung.
Okay.
We should get a chest
X-ray, make sure
we're not looking at pneumonia.
- No. No chest X-ray.
- There's no
discomfort involved.
- Until the bill comes.
- When my husband died,
I was lucky enough
to find work in a bookstore.
It's lovely.
The owner is kind, but
low wages and no...
No benefits.
- Without the
X-ray, I can't tell
how serious this is, so...
- I can hardly
afford antibiotics.
Anything else is
out of the question.
- Look, I'll get
you the antibiotics,
but just stay here.
Okay? I'll be right back.
- Dr. Sutton, Dr. Tracy,
psych to recovery.
Dr. Sutton to recovery.
- He didn't even tell
me he was leaving.
He insinuated that
I wouldn't care
because I only
cared about the sex.
I didn't use him for sex.
He used me for sex,
and then he left.
I'm the victim here.
- You're the doctor.
He's the nurse.
You've got all the power.
- You clearly don't
understand gay male culture.
He's hotter.
He has all the power.
- Doesn't sound like
he felt that way.
- Why aren't you sad for me?
I'm the nice guy who,
once again, got left.
- Well, the interns
who have come in here
after working and being
yelled at for 16 hours
definitely don't feel
like you're the nice guy.
- I don't yell!
That wasn't yelling.
That was loud talking.
I'm nice.
- I love you. I mean it.
- If the hematoma ruptures
while you're fixing the spine,
she could die.
- But if it doesn't rupture,
it could heal on its own?
- That's right.
- The safest option is to just
monitor Georgia in the ICU.
- She may not walk again,
but she would be alive.
- Sounds like this thing
could rupture any time.
I mean, hell, it could
be rupturing right now.
Cody... She...
- He's not wrong.
- Do the spinal surgery.
- Sir, I wanna make sure
that you understand...
- We do.
Save our daughter's
ability to ride.
- No stranding,
appendix looks normal.
No evidence of colitis.
- That's an awfully
quick assessment, Adams.
You know, scans are
like a piece of art,
a still life, say.
Maybe you first look
at it and you shrug.
Looks like a pear, or tulip.
But you sit with it for a while,
learn to open up your mind,
and maybe it might
guide your eye
to something that the
artist wants you to see.
- Hold up.
It turns out Seth's been to
five different Seattle ERs
in the past three weeks,
all discharged with a script
for controlled pain meds.
- Seattle Pres, two
nights, Pacific Gen, one,
St. Anne's, two hours.
- Okay.
I get what you're implying.
- And according
to their records,
you have a history of drug use
that you didn't bother
to tell us about.
We can't help you if you're
not telling the truth.
- Oh, my God. I...
I don't have...
Back in the day, I did
Adderall to stay up.
I'm a private equity analyst.
All-nighters go
with the territory
when you're starting out.
But I haven't done it in years.
And I didn't tell you
because I didn't want you
to write me off like all
those other hospitals.
- We're not writing you off.
Addiction is a disease.
- It's a disease I don't have.
- And your scans are clean.
And I got on the
phone with colleagues
of those other hospitals,
who also found
nothing on your scans.
- Maybe they didn't sit
long enough with the scans.
- These aren't interns, Adams.
These are world-class surgeons
with decades of experience.
- So you're just gonna
kick me out on the street
like everyone else?
- No, we are gonna
exercise our due diligence
and take extra tests,
and if they show nothing,
then we will discharge you
with a referral to an
addiction specialist.
- I should never have
admitted I ever used drugs.
You screw up once, you're
a screw-up forever.
- She's about prepped and ready.
Why didn't you tell me
about all the job offers?
- Offers come in
every time I publish.
Happens to everyone.
- Not like this.
Look, it doesn't matter
where you are, right?
I mean, it matters
what you're doing.
If you just ask Teddy or Richard
for whatever you
need research-wise,
they will get it for you.
You don't have to move to
do your next big thing.
Meredith and I
managed to pull off
the Parkinson's procedure
right down the hall.
- She's ready.
- All right.
- So when you all told
me about those 8:30
surgical study sessions,
what time were they really?
What do you think
about Chilaiditi
syndrome for Seth?
- Thinking it's
usually associated
with ascitic and
cirrhotic patients.
Also, we would have
seen it in the scans.
And we have our answer.
All those tests came back
clean, except his urinalysis,
which is positive for opiates.
- Because all those other
hospitals gave him meds.
- Webber said to discharge him.
I'm gonna discharge him.
- Tessa Hobbes.
- Why would you bring up Tessa?
You know that still hurts.
- Because my gut told me
that we should have taken her
straight to the OR.
You heard me say it, but
I didn't fight for it.
And now my gut's saying that
Seth's telling the truth.
- Nothing I've seen makes
me think Webber's wrong.
- Yeah, but do you
think there might be
a chance that I'm right?
I mean, I've always
had your back.
Could you at least have mine?
- I'm already on my
second residency.
- He's not gonna fire us.
- Have suction ready.
- Blood pressure's steady.
- Chief, I have a wheezing
60-year-old patient in the ER,
possible pneumonia.
She needs a chest X-ray
and a nebulizer treatment,
but can't afford it.
Can we do it pro bono?
- You'll have to fill out
the forms with accounting.
They're gonna want
to confirm her income
and make sure that
she qualifies.
It may take a day or so.
- But she needs
to be treated now.
- If we break the
rules for one patient,
it's not fair for the others.
I was eating doughnuts
from the trash
because I need to gain weight
in order to be eligible
to donate my plasma
because I am broke.
So is my patient.
I don't need your help,
and I am not looking
for handouts.
I just want to take
care of my patient.
- I'm sorry.
You have to go through
the proper channels.
Yasuda, I have protein
bars in my office.
You're welcome to them any time.
- Removing the lamina.
Can't stop thinking
about that father.
I'm reconstructing a spine just
to have her go back out there
and wreck it all over again.
- Yeah, lots of parents
live out their fantasies
through their kids.
- So her last shock panel
showed a hemoglobin of 11.
So the bleed is stable.
Just be careful with
your instrumentation.
- I'm not sure you hovering
is gonna make things
go more smoothly.
- How many times have we
fixed up a pro football player
just so he can go back out
in the field in the hopes
of making the playoffs?
- Don't get me
started on football.
- Except rodeo is the only gig
with a poor animal out
there against their will.
It's cruel.
- Can we keep
all nonessential
chatter to a minimum?
Georgia has a giant
bleed hanging over her
that could burst in any second.
- Pedicle screw, please.
- I think it's a
connection. I think...
- Adams, Griffith!
- Is everything
okay, Dr. Schmidt?
- Just checking in on
how you two are doing.
How's life?
What's up?
- I don't understand.
- What are you working on?
- Okay, we... we know Webber
said to discharge him.
But we really think
that there's something
more to this patient.
And if we could just
have a little more time
to study his case,
we can figure it out.
- Okay. No.
You're interns.
It doesn't matter
what you think.
If you can't be trusted
to follow instructions,
then you can't be
trusted in the OR.
Discharge the patient.
And never question
Dr. Webber ever again.
- I should probably go
to work and check on Tia.
- Tia and her baby
are both okay.
I've checked.
A car drove into human beings
and tried to kill
you and your friends.
You've earned a day off.
- Why is it so hard
for me to rest?
How am I supposed to know that?
- Because you knew
that I wasn't sick
before I even knew
that I wasn't sick.
- I've known you a long time.
You notice things about somebody
when you've known
them a long time.
- You knew what my
favorite doughnuts were.
- Same answer.
- So why is it so
hard for me to rest?
You don't have a theory?
I could tell you why I think
it's hard for me to rest.
Would that help?
- Yes, please.
- Well, I was a pretty
happy go-lucky kid.
I got cancer, and my parents
started to fight all the time.
And I was sick, stuck in bed,
listening to my parents fight
through the walls.
So I think I associate
rest with misery.
- I don't think that's it.
- Okay.
You know me better
than I know me.
- I've known you a long time,
and when you've known
someone a long time,
you notice things.
- So what do you think it is?
- I think you only
have trouble resting
when you're not taking
care of somebody else.
You'll lay around all day
with a baby on your chest
if that baby needs you.
You lay in bed with me with
doughnuts if I need you.
And when you got cancer
and your parents
started fighting,
you started to take care of them
so they wouldn't split up.
You learned to
take emotional care
of the people who are supposed
to be taking care of you.
And that's why it's
hard for you to rest
when you're by yourself.
You don't feel safe
when you're not
taking care of somebody else.
That makes you anxious.
- And I think you can't rest
because you never had
anyone to take care of you.
So you stayed busy all the time
taking care of yourself.
And when you're still,
you feel that pain.
- I need a nap.
- Want me to go?
- No.
That feels nice.
- Harborview Med, last
Tuesday, 2311, nothing.
- If Webber or Schmidt
finds us, we're fired.
- Yeah, well...
- You'd think
that'd be annoying.
- It clears my mind,
helps me unwind.
You have anything like that?
- Ice skating.
What?
I just... I wasn't
expecting that.
- Well, you don't know
everything about me.
- True.
I never pictured you as the type
to have a big fancy wedding
or matching dresses.
- I don't want either.
I want the marriage, but not
the pomp and circumstance.
- Not even a little pomp,
like meat on a stick
or chucking a bouquet at
your girls, group pics?
- I truly hate you.
I think it's sweet
that Trey wants
to create a moment in our lives
that we're gonna
remember forever.
But he's a romantic.
Even when we're just
out getting pizza,
he's like, "I wish I could
freeze this moment forever."
- Oh, wait. Wait. Wait.
That's it.
Moments... that's..
Okay.
These scans... They're
not works of art.
They're... they're moments.
They're frozen moments in time.
- Oh, good. Glad
we cleared that up.
- Okay, look. Here we go.
There and there...
- Do you know where they came
up with the eight seconds
as the time the rider
has to stay on the bull?
It's because the bull
starts to lose its strength
to fight back and
they stop bucking.
The official line is that it's
for the safety of the animals,
but it's really because
they become so weakened
that we stop being entertained.
- BP's dropping.
- Pierce, is that
what I think it is?
- She's bleeding out.
- The hematoma ruptured.
Stop the fusion.
We need to flip her.
- Her spine is exposed.
- It doesn't matter.
Pack it and throw
some ioban on it.
Hang 2 units of blood.
Prep for an x-flap
and a sternotomy.
Every second counts
here, people.
Until we get this bleed stopped,
this is my OR.
- Okay. This is it.
When we get in there, Kwan,
you're gonna alternate
cardiac massage with Millin.
Scalpel.
Okay, Georgia, here we go.
- Scalpel.
- ♪ I've been
looking for a sign ♪
♪ Now I see a shining light
- Get the saw ready.
- Starting pressors.
- ♪ Set me free
- Send a TEG.
- She's becoming more acidotic.
- We can't lose her.
- I need more suction.
- Still no pulse.
- ♪ Head under water
and I can't breathe ♪
♪ Pull me up 'cause
I'm too deep ♪
♪ I've been looking
for a sign ♪
♪ Now I see a shining light
♪ Oh won't somebody
come and set me free ♪
- Okay, I've got
the infrahepatic IVC
and Pringle. Lap pads.
- I've got the cava
and the pericardium.
- Millin, switch with Kwan.
- We've maxed out
on her pressors.
- Pickups?
- Still no pulse.
- I feel the heart. I'm there.
- I see the hepatic vein injury.
Ligating, push epi.
- Packing the
retrohepatic space.
- Come on, Georgia.
- ♪ Set me free
The nurse brought
the antibiotics
and the inhaler.
I'm off to my shift.
- Please don't go
before getting an X-ray
and the nebulizer treatment.
We could do it pro bono,
but we just need to
fill these forms out.
- If I miss work,
I don't get paid.
And if I don't get paid...
- You can't pay your
bills. I get it.
- No...
- But...
- No, you don't.
You're a doctor
with a cushy salary.
- Well, I am a surgical intern.
My salary is government
funded, and it is not enough
to keep me from
drowning in loans.
Between undergrad
and med school,
I owe more than
two grand a month.
That doesn't even account
for what I send to my parents
to help them with
their mortgage payment
because they co-signed
all of my loans.
I literally sell my
blood in order to get by.
And if I thought that I had
pneumonia that could lead
to sepsis and
respiratory failure
that could prove fatal
if left untreated,
or, at the very least,
keep me out of work
for eight weeks,
I would get the X-ray
and the treatment.
And when the bill came, I
would pay the bare minimum.
And if it went to the
collection agencies,
I would pay them the
bare minimum too.
And it might be a huge,
long, pain in the ass,
but I would be alive.
- Where do I go for
the chest X-ray?
- Pick it up, guys,
a little faster.
- You know what they called
me when I was chief resident?
The Nazi.
- That is wildly
inappropriate...
- Yes.
- On so many levels.
- I mean, I wasn't
a tough child,
not in the obvious ways.
I was sensitive all
through high school
and undergrad and med school.
So as a resident, even
more so as chief resident,
I thought I had
to overcompensate.
And for a while,
I became someone
people didn't like very much.
- And what did you do?
- Well, I realized
that my idea of myself
had come out of sync
with who I had become.
Schmidt, you are
chief resident now.
You are no longer an underdog.
It's time for you to stop
seeing yourself that way.
- You're saying I
shouldn't demand
excellence from the interns?
- I'm saying there's
many ways to do that.
And the one that will
work best for you
is likely the one
that lets you be you.
I mean, you said you want us
to be the vagina of the program
because vaginas are so strong.
Well, vaginas also
bring pleasure.
They bring joy, bring life.
You got to be the whole vagina,
Schmidt, not just the muscle.
- It's like we were staring
at a single cell of film
and trying to watch a movie.
We have to look at all the scans
in order to see if
they tell a story.
Okay, look... Look
here, four to five.
There's a slight thickening
in the cecal wall here.
Yeah? And then
six and seven...
- No more thickening,
but mild fat stranding.
- Yeah.
And then eight, nine, ten,
the pattern reappears.
The flare-ups come and go,
but the CT scans only
capture one moment in time.
Now our little film
tells a different story.
I mean, there's gotta
be something in there,
a foreign object
causing these reactions.
- Like a fish bone, maybe,
or a piece of cartilage
that wasn't digested properly?
- You want to tell
me why the patient
I told you to discharge hours
ago is still stuck in my ER?
- So she's gonna be okay?
- Uh, yeah.
Georgia did well under
the circumstances,
against all odds.
- But we would like
to speak with you
about the bull riding.
- I should wait for my husband.
- We would like to have
a minute with just you.
- Oh.
Georgia's father, her
grandfather, her uncles...
They are all champion riders.
But Cody never wanted
Georgia to go near a bull.
Every Christmas,
he would give her
a dollhouse, ballet
slippers, a soccer ball.
She wouldn't touch them.
She wanted boots,
spurs, a saddle.
Cody thought when she
took her first spill,
she'd lose interest, but...
but when she got laid up
with a crushed trachea,
we said no more.
Guess what? She wouldn't eat,
wouldn't speak, couldn't sleep.
The light in her
eyes was just gone.
- To keep doing this will
very likely kill her.
- You think I don't
worry about that
every single day of my life?
But to take her dream
away from her...
That would for sure kill her.
Excuse me.
I'm gonna go find my husband.
- Nothing is harder
than parenting,
but you have to be the parent.
- Would it have worked on you
when you were a teenager
doing hard drugs,
risking your life?
Was your mom able to stop you?
- I was using drugs to mask
some very real pain in my life.
- Maybe it's the
same for Georgia.
Maybe she's masking the
pain of having found
her one true passion
and hearing everyone around her
tell her that she is
selfish for chasing it.
- Oh, no, no, no,
no. Georgia, no.
- She's pulling the tube out.
- Increase her O2
and draw an ABG.
Hey.
- Georgia, you're okay.
Just take a breath.
- Georgia, calm down. I need
you to put this mask on.
Your body needs
additional oxygen.
- I've had kids
self-extubate before.
Instinct and adrenaline kick in.
- How long... How
long will it take?
- You will be up and walking
in four to six weeks.
- Ride.
- Georgia, going back to
rodeo would be a mistake.
Most people do not
survive the surgery
that Dr. Pierce just did.
- I'm not most people!
Would you be saying the
same thing if I was a guy?
- Georgia, I'm not like
most people either.
I was really good at something
when I was your age too.
I skipped grades, I won prizes,
and everybody thought
it was my parents
that were pushing me, but
it was me. It was all me.
So I get your focus.
I get your passion.
And I certainly get
what it's like to be
a girl in an all-guys' world.
Maybe you'll ride again someday.
But a few hours ago, you were
almost dead and paralyzed.
Stop fighting us and let
us save the possibility
of your future.
- There's the ileocecal valve.
- I hope we didn't
just put a tube
into a patient for no reason.
- Whoa, whoa, what's
that in the distal ileum?
- Move the camera down and left.
- There!
- Is that a...
- Toothpick. I'll be damned.
- Oh, my God.
How did it not shred his
esophagus on the way down?
- Well, it perfed the bowel.
Then it impacted into
the intestinal wall,
where it hid from
the scanner's radar.
Adams, what's the game plan?
- Use the endoscopy forceps
to fish it out carefully.
- Being careful not to break
it and leave a piece behind
that could cause
an abscess later.
- All right, hold it steady.
- Will this take away
all of this pain?
- It absolutely will.
Almost there.
Incredible save, Adams.
Incredible save.
- Have I mentioned
that I had my hand
on an actual beating heart?
- Only about six times.
- But hey, I heard you found
a bobby pin in some guy's ass
or something, so also cool.
- I convinced a patient
to get a chest X-ray.
- Hey, congratulations, Adams.
Yasuda's day was
sadder than yours.
- Yeah.
- Hey, thanks for
everything today.
If you need anything,
I got your back.
- I do need something.
I know this might be weird,
and if it's still hard
for you, you can say no.
But you know me better
than anyone here,
better than anyone at my
old program, actually.
And I could really use a friend
to help me get through this.
I'm asking you to
be my man of honor.
- Yeah, of course.
It'd be an honor.
- Thank you.
- Hey, everyone,
I want you to know
I heard you all did
some incredible work today.
And so, if you're up for
it, I would like to invite
you all out for drinks.
I'm actually serious.
- Uh, oh.
- So just, you know,
meet me at Joe's.
- Free drinks.
- Yeah.
- Any chance you need
another bartender?
- When would you sleep?
- I'd figure it out.
- Uh, yeah, yeah.
The manager is hiring
for the late shift.
I can put in a good word.
- Thank you.
- Okay, people,
this is my treat.
- Thank God.
- Yay, thank you.
- You're welcome.
- Thank you.
- Thanks, Dr. Schmidt.
- Cheers.
- Yeah.
- Welcome.
- Thank you.
- Mm-hmm.
- Mm.
- Oh.
- Chaser?
- Mm-hmm.
- What are you, her babysitter?
- Man of honor, actually.
- Oh, thank God.
I didn't wanna have to carry
around those blood vials.
You mix them together,
and you pour them
out at the altar.
- Why do you think a
maid of honor does that?
- My mom did it at
my uncle's wedding.
- I cannot overstate
how not normal that is.
- Whatever. I'm
going to order food.
Anyone else?
- Can you get me some fries?
- I'm starving.
- So when's the wedding?
- Next month.
But it's in town so
no one has to travel.
And I don't need
any extra time off.
Trey is gonna take care
of most of the logistics,
so you won't...
- Griffin, I...
I was just asking.
- Sorry, yeah.
- That's okay.
- Next month.
- Okay.
- Wanna get out of here?
- I can't.
We said no feelings,
and unfortunately,
I find your staunch
support of animal rights...
hot.
- Okay.
What if I have no feelings?
- That works.
- You wanna pick up takeout?
I kind of feel like Italian.
- I already ordered,
Chang's Garden.
- Right, of course you decided.
- Stop.
Stop. I need to look at you
when I say this.
- Okay.
- You invited me to
dinner with your family,
and then you abandoned
me when things got tough.
- What? When?
- The first time that
I met your family,
your father showed up,
and you became unhappy,
and then you logged off,
and you left me there.
My mother always used
to quote Maya Angelou.
She used to say, "When someone
shows you who they are,
believe them the first time."
Why didn't I believe
you the first time?
You showed me who you were,
and I just didn't wanna see it.
- And who am I?
- You're a person who retreats.
When the going gets
tough, you retreat.
You quit. You disappear.
You protect yourself, no matter
what it costs anybody else.
- You're the one thinking
of taking a job in Chicago.
- A job in Chicago
is nothing, Winston.
Marriages can easily
survive a job in Chicago.
But you don't seem to
want us to survive.
You just seem to want to
punish me with your absence.
- I'm right here!
- But you're not.
You're not.
You took your love,
and you retreated.
You disappeared inside yourself.
When the going got tough,
you protected yourself,
no matter what it
cost anybody else.
I am right here.
You are gone.
You couldn't even think
of something nice to say
about me this morning.
Even when you wanted
to quit cardio,
supposedly to save our marriage,
that was you quitting.
That was you retreating.
That was you giving up your gift
so that you could
avoid direct conflict,
and that is what
I don't respect.
It isn't your heart,
Winston, it's your cowardice.
- Oh, wow, really, Maggie?
- And the pizza in Chicago
is the best in the world.
So I'm gonna go there.
And I'm gonna take my
extraordinary passion,
and I'm going to use
it to build hearts
that will save
thousands of lives.
And you can stay here,
and you can pretend
like it was you
who was abandoned,
but we both know the truth.
- At a cellular level, we are
made of forks in the road.
A generalized cell is born,
and it splits and splits,
not having much
choice in the matter.
Eventually, it's a body.
Eventually, it's you...
- Come here, Scout.
- Out in the world.
- He was down.
How are you feeling?
- I...
I feel...
- Better?
- ♪ If we survive
- Yes, better. I feel better.
- Hear that, Scout?
She feels better. Whoo-hoo!
- So maybe you are who you are.
- All right, can
you say whoo-hoo?
- Maybe you can't choose who
you love or what you want
any more than a cell
can choose to be
a liver, a lung, a heart.
But cells only take you so far.
- Rough day?
- Oh, thank you.
Oh, it was humbling.
I missed a diagnosis and
almost lost a patient.
- But?
- I was bailed
out by a Shepherd.
- Hmm.
- You?
- I'm afraid I might be
losing another sister.
- In the end, you
create yourself.
And your life is the
life you've made.
- ♪ But you hold your breath
♪ If we survive
- What the...
Hey! Hey!
- ♪ If we survive
- Hey! What the...
Oh, no.
- Ben?
Ben, what's going on?
- ♪ I'll look for you
- Miranda.
- ♪ On the other side
- We are not fine, Miranda.
- But no one said
it would be easy.
- ♪ On the other side