Rage, agitation
angry outbursts at
patients and staff...
obsessional negative
thoughts about work
the, uh... the hours
ludicrous staff meetings
the stink of the halls
and the patients...
the patients.
You find yourself
searching for ways
not to hate them.
You know, little
tricks like, um...
she shares a birthday
with your mother
or he looks like a
brother of a friend.
It doesn't work.
You feel nothing.
Every drop of pleasure
has drained from your life.
You can't sleep
you can't think, you
can't concentrate...
Trouble sleeping?
Oh... Well, I was just...
catching up on some work.
I worry you're not
getting enough sleep.
Are you okay?
Fine.
What are you working on?
Um, a patient history.
Div...
Listen, you go
back to bed, okay?
It's late.
Captioning sponsored
by WARNER BROS.
Who is it?
Do you think I could, maybe...
Come in?
Thank you.
Rain stopped.
It's going to be
a beautiful day.
Have you seen my razor?
I don't think so.
Sorry about the mess.
I'm just always amazed
how much stuff women
can fit in their overnight bag.
Just the bare essentials.
"Hydrating Eye
Mask Number Four."
Takes five years off.
Really?
Are you all packed?
We're going to
be rushing tonight.
Yeah, except for my razor.
Good. Oh, Mister
Button missed a hole.
Come here.
I'll pick you up after work.
We'll be in Nassau by morning.
And the next three
days... you're mine.
Sounds good to me.
I got to tell you, I feel funny
about you paying for everything.
Oh, please.
We both know you
don't make any money.
You're a resident...
a pediatric resident.
You know what?
I think that blue Armani
shirt that I got you
would go better with this tie.
Happy Thanksgiving.
Hey, Malik, Happy Thanksgiving.
You, too.
Hey, nice shirt, doc.
Thanks.
Hi.
Uh, excuse me.
Um, what's your name?
Bob.
Happy Thanksgiving.
Happy Thanksgiving to you, Bob.
Uh, these are
Halloween decorations.
We just took those down.
No, I... put up.
See?
Yes, I see.
Carry on.
Ah, Dr. Ross.
Hi, Jer. What's the good word?
Well, got a little interoffice
minutiae for you here.
Is this your contribution
to the potluck dinner?
It's pecan pie.
I bought it myself.
Don't be shy, Jerry.
Just help yourself.
Thanks.
Dr. John, what do
you got over there?
I'm practicing sutures.
What is that?
Huh? Oh, it's a pig's foot.
The elasticity is
comparable to human skin.
It's great for practicing.
I've got about half a dozen
of these in my freezer at home.
Carter, are you
snacking between meals?
See what's holding
up the blood gases
on that wheezer in three.
You got it.
Hey, Doug.
Morning, Carol.
So, you still going to Bermuda
or can you work Saturday night?
The Bahamas, and forget it.
I'm gone.
Jen and Rach coming down?
And her folks.
Dinner with the Reverend.
Kid with the croup in three.
Thank you, Lydia.
Terrific.
I got it.
When things slow down,
I need to talk to you.
Oh, okay.
All right.
Carol...
Thank you.
Who put this here?
I believe it was Bob.
Can we move it somewhere?
We can certainly try.
Thanksgiving.
What a farce.
I mean, what do we got
to be grateful for, huh?
Rwanda? Flesh-eating bacteria?
Entertainment Tonight?
Mr. Luck, quiet.
Piss off.
That's ironic coming from
a man with no kidneys.
Labs are back.
He's uremic.
Blood alcohol's 250.
And the media...
Brainwashers, all of them.
Just filling the kids'
heads with filth.
"I love you, you love
me, we're a happy family."
Mr. Luck, how long has it been
since you were dialyzed?
Those Nazis at the clinic
won't let me in the door.
Apparently, Mr. Luck
as been banned
for repeatedly
abusing the staff.
I got a right to my
opinion, don't I?
Mr. Luck, you're in
end-stage renal failure
but don't worry.
We're going to save your life...
such as it is.
Prep him for dialysis.
I'll get the portable machine.
You know what really gets me?
All of this talk about an
information superhighway.
Ha! 500 channels of crap.
You know, the more I see
of people, the more I like pigs.
42-year-old woman
lost control of her car
and hit a bridge abutment.
She's alert and oriented.
Vitals are normal.
So, should I bring
anything for tonight?
Tonight?
Thanksgiving dinner.
Your mother invited me.
Carter, my mother isn't
in control of her faculties.
So, I'm not invited now?
Don't your parents
want you at home?
Actually, my parents
are in Switzerland
visiting my sister.
Switzerland, huh?
Have you seen
Mookie this morning?
No.
Hi, Mrs. Carleton.
I'm Dr. Benton.
We're going to look you
over and just make sure
that you don't have any
serious injuries, okay?
Carter, take a look at the head.
This isn't going to hurt a bit.
Okay, do you feel
any pain here, ma'am?
No.
Okay. What about here?
No blood in the canals.
Excuse me.
Oh, we've got a deep lac here.
About ten centimeters.
Don't worry... there
won't be much scarring.
Penetrating lac
on the right side.
Ma'am, we're going to
have to remove your clothes.
Carter.
Okay...
if you could just turn
on your side, please.
Okay.
Lower back looks good.
Upper back looks
good, a few scratches.
Contusion to the left scapula.
Uh... Dr. Benton?
Abrasions along T-3.
We seem to have a new
piece of information here.
Superficial bruises along
the cocc... cocc... coccyx.
Could somebody
please get me a gown?
Mr. Carleton...
I go by "Miss."
Big trauma coming. M.V.A.
Three people. All critical.
All right, uh...
Carter, take her next
door and sew her up.
Um... okay.
Uh... by myself?
High speed collision.
Two teenage males in one car.
Both unrestrained,
thrown from the vehicle.
This one's unconscious...
Massive head injuries.
Vitals?
No vitals. Looks like a loser.
Doug, we need your help.
What do we got?
You guys take this one.
Connie, talk to me.
Traumatic full arrest.
Here comes the second one.
Clear the way!
He's conscious.
Broken right femur.
Pressure 90/60,
pulse 110. Let's go.
Someone call ortho.
It hurts!
Where does it hurt?
My gut.
What happened?
Ran a red at high speed,
hit a 22-year-old girl.
Is he the driver?
Don't know.
Car belonged to
a... Larry Parks.
Are you Larry Parks?
No, Andy.
That must be the girl.
That ain't her.
They left her at the scene...
decapitated.
Okay, Andy. Andy,
tell me where it hurts.
Here? Here?
Everywhere!
Carol, we need to hold him down.
You gotta stay still.
It hurts!
Can we give him
something for the pain?
Yep. 50 milligrams of Demerol.
All right, let's
prep for lavage.
I need a catheter. I got it.
Any heart sounds?
Negative.
Give him another
milligram of atropine.
We got a lot of
gray matter here.
Oh, God.
Is he salvageable?
Call neuro.
All right, let's get the
saline and tube ready.
I'm not giving up yet.
What are you doing?
Andy, relax.
They gave you an anesthetic
so you won't be in pain.
Why are they cutting me?
Listen to me. My name is Carol.
And I'll tell you what's
happening, all right?
The doctor's made a
little nick in your belly
so they can fill your
abdomen with fluid.
Once it's full, they'll watch
as the fluid drains out.
If blood comes out, that means
you have injuries
inside, and will need
to have surgery.
What do you think?
All right. Call the OR.
Tell them we're on our way up.
You're going to surgery now.
God!
Larry!
Time of death, 9:33.
Oh, God.
Let's roll.
I'll make sure we got a room.
We got him, Carol.
Carol, it was me.
What was you?
I was driving Larry's car.
It's my fault.
I killed him.
Oh, God, I killed him.
The space shuttle...
Now there's a bright idea.
Let's spend $50 billion
so six guys can sit in a
tin can and test the effect
of weightlessness
on fruit flies.
The kid who went up...
Is he going to make it?
I think so. One out of three.
What a waste.
Every time I see a
kid go up there, I think,
"There, but for
the grace of God..."
Tell me about it.
When I was in high school,
we used to race this guy's
TR-7 up on River Road.
Pin the speedometer at 120.
We used to climb
those giant TV antennas
all the way up to the top.
Must have been 200-300 feet.
You did that?
Otto Jevtich... his dad
was a demolitions expert.
So we used to steal boxes
of dynamite and play chicken.
I don't believe you guys.
The worst thing Howie
Dolan and I ever did
was Chinese fire drills
at the Velvet Freeze.
I guess you and Howie
were born to be wild.
Did I miss something?
No. I'm just being
publicly ridiculed.
Oh. So how about some coffee?
Sure.
Hey, Doug.
John, hey, listen, I'm
glad you showed up.
This kid's got an elbow the size
of a grapefruit.
Sure. Just give me
one second, huh?
Yeah. I'll just go
through my mail.
Hey.
Sorry, Lydia.
Don't be. That's the best kiss
I've experienced in months.
So, did you find somebody
to cover your shift?
Not yet. Keep trying.
Mom's not going to
start supper till 7:00.
She's really looking forward
to spending some time with you.
I'll try.
I gotta go, but, uh...
I'll see you.
Bye.
All yours.
Yeah.
Hey.
So, what's your name?
My name is John Carter.
You've grown awfully
quiet, John Carter.
Oh, I see.
I had a friend once.
We would go to lunch,
Happy Hours, shopping.
Over drinks one night,
I told her about myself.
She stood up, left the table
and never spoke to me again.
I used to feel those
things made me stronger
more sure of who I was.
These days...
I spend three hours
putting on my face
before I dare go outside.
Plucking and waxing...
and even then,
someone always notices.
I can see by the
look in their eyes.
The disgust.
Maybe they're right.
Maybe I am disgusting.
Can you turn your head
back the other way, please?
Thank you.
Hey, Lydia.
Hey, Al.
Whatcha got?
Guy needs to be
cleared for booking.
He's bleeding all
over my squad car.
Doctor Ross. Got a patient.
I'm not a grown-up doctor.
We all know that
but there's no
one else available.
What happened?
He was attacked by a turkey.
A turkey.
What's open?
Trauma one.
See, Francis here is
an animal-rights nut.
Activist!
Whatever. There's this
Thanksgiving display
at one of the shopping malls...
You know, dried corn, straw,
guys dressed like pilgrims.
They've also got this real,
live, big mother of a turkey.
They were exploiting the
bird for commercial gain.
It was disgusting!
So, Francis here
decides to steal the bird.
To rescue it!
You grabbed the bird,
you threw it in your car
and you took off.
That's stealing.
It was being abused.
Now comes the good part.
During the getaway,
the turkey attacks him...
Starts clawing and pecking
at his head.
So what does Francis do?
He breaks the bird's neck.
And the upshot of it is
you guys get a fresh
bird for your party.
Oh, my God!
Al, maybe you better
take that outside.
Is that a Narragansett tom?
It sure is!
Hey, he's a big fellow, too.
I kind of doubt if Dietary
will want to prepare it.
Heck, I'll do it.
I used to pluck birds
all the time as a kid.
This one's a beaut.
No, there's no question.
He was listing all the symptoms
of a major depression.
That would explain a few things.
Look, I know you've
never liked Div,
but he's been
really sweet to me,
so I'd appreciate it
if you wouldn't run
him down in front of me.
Sorry.
It just hurts to
see him like this.
I don't know what to do.
If he's clinically depressed,
he needs psychiatric help.
I know, but I don't want
to back him into a
corner if he's not ready.
Well, someone's
got to say something.
If he's really that bad,
he shouldn't be
treating patients.
You know, your concern
for Div is really touching.
Thanks for the advice.
I just think he
should see someone.
I got that.
You should have seen
the condition of his cage.
It was like a cell.
His water dish was dry.
That's no good.
People forget that we share
the same biological heritage
as every creature on the planet.
That first lizard who
crawled out of the ooze
is a distant cousin to us all.
I never really thought about it.
You don't keep your cousin
in a cage with no water!
You don't eat your family!
Oh, my God.
Could you...
could you please shut the blind?
Sure, Francis.
Francis, are you okay?
Doctor, can I tell
you something?
When I was under attack...
my most primitive fight-or-
flight instinct kicked in.
And, in that moment,
I was a beast,
and when I grabbed
the bird's neck,
and when I heard it snap...
there was a part of me that...
that secretly enjoyed it.
Is your father still living?
Yes, he is.
I didn't really know my dad
until just a few years ago.
I hadn't seen him
for ten years when,
out of the blue, he called.
Said he wanted to see me.
He had no idea.
So I put on a jade green,
short-sleeved silk dress,
and that's how I
answered the door.
You know
what he said?
He said, "Are you
Henry's girlfriend?"
I said, "No, Dad.
It's me."
He said...
"You look just
like your sister."
Then he said the reason
he came to see me was
because he was dying.
Before he died, he said, "Henry,
"you may wear a dress,
but you're still my son."
Okay, I'm done.
You should probably stay here
for about a half hour
so we make sure there's
no reaction to the antibiotics.
Dr. Greene.
Morning, ma'am.
What kind of thread you using?
Four-oh absorbable sub-Q.
Nice apposition,
well-spaced. Good job.
Thanks.
Bravo.
Thank God.
God? There is no God, lady.
When can I get
the hell out of here?
Very soon.
It took some doing,
but I talked the clinic
into taking you back.
Wha...? Who asked you?!
You have an
appointment next Tuesday.
Yeah? Well, I ain't going.
Mr. Luck, if you don't
go, you'll come back here,
and neither one of us want that.
Shove it.
Excuse me?
What, are you deaf, too?
I said shove it,
you little pinhead puke.
Oh...
Excuse me.
I'm trying to find my son.
What's his name?
Andrew Bohlmeyer.
Andy.
Yes. Is he all right?
Your son was taken to surgery.
They're removing his spleen.
Oh, my God!
I'll take you up.
Please.
Edie!
I went by the house.
I was at the store.
Where are they?
Where's the other
boy... Larry Parks?
Are you Larry's mother?
Yes.
Where is he?
What?
Mrs. Parks...
your son was brought in
with severe
injuries to his head.
Are you telling me...
His heart wasn't beating.
He's dead?
Yes, he is. I'm sorry.
I am not a baby!
For God's sake,
can't you just put
it in my mouth?
Hospital policy, Mr. Luck.
I'll be back in ten minutes.
Wait a minute! How
about a little privacy here?
What's so funny?
You people never seen a guy
get his temperature taken before?
Andy.
How are you doing, honey?
Tired.
Numb.
Not in any pain?
Not really.
The girl...
is she okay?
No, she's not.
How did it happen, honey?
Larry ran a red light.
He was trying to beat it.
I told him to stop, but...
he said he could make it.
Oh, Andy.
Sweetie...
thank God you're all right.
I never said you were boring.
You implied it.
Mark, I think that you're an
extremely dynamic individual...
Especially in those glasses.
What's wrong with my glasses?
They're perfect.
Going to surgery.
Back in college,
every Friday night
I used to go to the Rathskeller
and drink beer...
Lots of beer. Pitchers.
You're right. I'm boring.
I've never done anything
irresponsible in my life.
Trust me. "Irresponsible"
is overrated.
I've never been arrested.
I've never gone out
and spent money
on something that I didn't need.
And I have never been to Bermuda
with a horny drug saleslady.
It's the Bahamas.
Trust me, I wouldn't be
going if she weren't paying.
She's paying?!
Everything... dinner, clothes...
I'm beginning to
feel like a kept man.
I've never been a kept man.
Dr. Greene, she came
in with chest pain...
Collapsed in the waiting room.
How long have you
been in pain, ma'am?
An hour. I was in the
kitchen, cooking dinner,
and the pressure
started right here.
Is it a heart attack?
I'm not sure.
Have you been sick recently?
I was diagnosed
with lupus last year.
She's been in remission.
Call Cardiology.
We need to get a consult.
Get an EKG, cardiac
enzyme and a chest film.
Sir, you're going to
have to wait outside.
No! I want him here.
All right, all right.
There we go. Sit down.
Lie back.
Just relax.
Breathe easy.
We're going to take care of you.
He told you he was driving
and you didn't tell anyone?
Who am I supposed to tell?
The police, for one.
Carol, the... the kid
committed manslaughter.
He killed two people.
I'm not sure it's my place.
Well, you know how it is.
Patients come in here,
scared, thinking they're dying,
and they tell us
things they wouldn't tell
their husbands or
wives or their priests.
This kid unburdened
his soul to me.
I just don't feel
right passing that on.
Please, honey, make sure
you tell the kids
not to eat all the...
Mark.
You guys moonlighting
as cardiologists?
Gurunian and
Bell are in surgery.
Kayson's on his way
from Highland Park.
Until he gets here, we're it.
Patient's 40. History of lupus.
Treated with Prednisone.
Presented with chest pain.
Heart rate's 112.
Pulsus paradoxus.
EKG shows an ST elevation.
You think there's an effusion?
I do. Sarah?
There's a silhouette sign.
Her blood pressure's dropping.
She needs a pericardiocentesis.
You ever done one?
Lots of times.
She's unconscious.
Move her to Trauma Two.
We can't wait for Kayson.
Peter, I'll need an
18-gauge PC needle
and an alligator clip.
What's happening?
There's a very thin
sac around the heart.
It's called the pericardium.
Your wife's is
filling with fluid.
It's squeezing the heart
so it can't beat properly.
We're going to insert
a needle in the sac
and drain the fluid out of it.
Stick a needle in her heart?
Near her heart.
You know, Sarah, I've
never had an opportunity
to do one of these procedures.
Since you've done a lot of them,
I was wondering...
You want to do it?
Do it.
I'll back you up.
Hey.
Oh.
That's funny.
I was just thinking about you.
Pleasant thoughts?
Very pleasant.
Have a seat.
Um... actually...
Whew!
I, uh...
I feel like I owe
you an apology.
Um... I know that
lately I've been difficult,
to put it mildly.
And uh... I'm-I'm... I'm
sorry if I've embarrassed you.
You haven't embarrassed me.
I'm worried about you.
Well, I've been, um...
I've been pretty depressed.
Have you thought about...
talking to someone?
A therapist?
Things are starting
to fall into place.
I... I wouldn't worry too much.
So, are we still on for dinner?
With your sister
and her new beau?
I wouldn't miss it.
Maybe we can talk afterwards.
I'd like that.
Mrs. Parks?
Can I get you anything?
Call you a ride?
What? Um... no.
If I, um... could just sit down.
Sure. Sure.
I just saw my son.
He was so cold.
I looked at his face,
and all I wanted to do
was to slap him.
To hit him, and to say
"You stupid boy!
"How could you do this...
"to yourself?!
"That poor girl...
how could you leave me?!"
Oh, dear God.
What's wrong with me?
You seen my patient?
Middle-aged...
She-male?
Mm-hmm.
Must have gone
to the ladies' room.
Insert the needle
at about 45 degrees,
gently aspirating as you go.
When you reach the pericardium,
you'll begin to draw fluid.
The EKG will let you
know if you touch the heart.
I got to be getting close.
Anything?
No.
Pull back.
You've hit heart muscle.
What's going on, Sarah?
Nothing's coming out.
The pericardium
must be infected.
The fluid's too thick
for the needle.
She's fibrillating.
Clear!
Sinus.
We got a pulse.
We should crack her.
Crack her chest, and
morbidity goes through the roof.
If we don't release the
pressure in 30 seconds,
Do a window.
This lady could die.
Make an eight-centimeter
cut at the xyphoid. Do it now.
Okay.
Now open the diaphragm and
cut out a window of pericardium.
Maybe two inches...
Not too big... or her heart
will jump out.
You can do it, Peter. Do it.
That's it.
Keep going.
All right.
That's it. Suction.
Okay, here it comes.
We got fluid.
We got a beat.
Oh, man.
Pressure's back.
Throw a couple of
stitches around the tube.
I think you can take
it from here, Peter.
Andy?
How are you?
I'm okay.
The police talk to you yet?
They will.
Andy, I heard what
you told your mother
and I understand why.
You're in a lot of pain,
and you don't want
to bring on any more.
Do you think it's fair to
let Larry's mother believe
he killed that girl?
I know you feel guilty, Andy,
but it's only going
to get worse.
I know.
I've kept things from people,
and it makes you hate yourself.
It makes it hard to
live with yourself.
Ever kill anyone before?
No.
But I've done things
to hurt people...
People close to me.
And you told them?
Not everything, no.
It's not so easy...
is it?
What's going on, Jerry?
Jumper on the roof.
Some lady.
Looks like she's going to go.
Oh, God!
Excuse me.
She's my patient.
Miss Carleton, please.
Please.
Don't come...
Don't come any closer.
Okay. Okay. Uh...
uh...
Miss Carleton, I know
you must be feeling
really terrible right
now, but, uh... but...
but there's people...
there's people in the
hospital that can help you.
I can't pass for a
woman anymore.
That's all I've
ever wanted to be.
Could you just look at me?
Just look at me and talk to me?
We can talk about it.
Carter.
Oh, thank God.
Would you like to introduce me
to your friend?
Miss Carleton, there's a
doctor here who can help you.
Is it okay
if he talks...?
No, don't!
Oh, God!
Mmm. That looks good.
This is really good.
Hey!
Stop it.
Party time!
All right!
Hey, Haleh, pass
the yams, please?
It's a buffet.
Get your own yams.
Hi.
You heard about the...?
Yeah. Awful.
Any luck getting off?
No.
Can we take a walk?
Sure.
Great.
You ready, sweets?
Ready as I'll ever be.
Okay. Here's your ticket.
Yeah.
Oh, my God. These are coach.
Hold on, huh?
Oh, to be a kept man.
Not one complaint out of you.
Because, in an hour,
you're going to
be sitting at a table
with your beautiful wife
and your beautiful daughter
and your family all around,
and I'm going to
be at 30,000 feet
sucking down vodka gimlets
with a woman who dresses me.
Do you have any idea
how lucky you are?
If you don't want
to go, don't go.
A little late for that.
Shut up. Here she comes.
All fixed.
Okay.
The limo's waiting.
Well, happy Thanksgiving.
Okay. Happy Thanksgiving.
Thanks.
Bye.
So, is this good news or bad?
Oh, boy.
I need to talk to you
about something.
What?
During the time that
we've been going out,
I slept with Doug Ross.
When?
Last winter.
Before you took the pills?
Yeah.
Since then?
No.
But, two weeks ago...
he kissed me and I let him.
Tag, wait.
Just go to hell,
okay? Just go to hell.
Just because you
try to kill yourself,
I'm supposed to
sit back and smile
while you screw
your old boyfriend?
What more do you
want from me, Carol?
I've been patient.
I've been faithful.
Should I treat you like
garbage like Doug Ross does?
Is that what you want?
No. I want you.
Why would you tell me
something like this anyway?
Because I've been dishonest,
and I need for you to know.
Okay, great. Now I
know, okay? I know!
What am I supposed to do now,
okay?
Tag!
Hey, Sarah.
Yeah?
The, uh... heart
lady is doing fine.
She's going to be home
with her family tomorrow.
Good.
So, uh... you
start the fellowship
next week, huh?
I leave tomorrow.
Yeah.
Well, I'm sure
you'll be just great.
Probably.
See you.
Uh... Sarah? Um...
I, um...
Thanks, you know, for, uh...
letting me do the procedure
and, uh... you know...
backing me up when
things got crazy today.
This is a teaching
hospital, Peter.
Helping those under you,
looking out for each other...
That's what it's
supposed to be about.
Yeah.
Peter?
It was a great save.
I'll see you in the spring.
Carter...
if anybody's
responsible, it's me.
She came in here
because she crashed
her car into a bridge.
Now, I should have
recognized that
as a suicide attempt,
but I didn't.
So, next time,
we'll both be more attentive.
Come on, Carter. Let's go.
What?
My family... they're
holding dinner until 7:30.
If we hurry up, we
can catch the prayer.
Thank you, Dr. Benton.
I think I just want to be alone.
Carter, you promised
my mother, didn't you?
What are you going to do?
You going to back out?
Come on.
Grab your coat.
Let's go.
Let's go, Carter.
Come and get it!
Ronnie, come on.
Turn off the damn TV.
I guess we shouldn't
wait for Div any longer.
You snooze, you lose.
I'm starving.
Chloe, how long did
you cook this turkey?
I don't know. A couple hours.
A turkey this size
needs at least six hours.
Try some. It tastes good.
It's teeming with bacteria.
I'm putting it back in the oven.
If we're lucky, we
can eat at 10:00.
Maybe Div will be here by then.
Wait a minute. You
got to be kidding me.
What's the matter? You
can't read a cookbook?
Why don't you shut up?
All you did all day
was sit on your
ass and watch TV.
That's what I always
do on Thanksgiving.
That is Thanksgiving to me.
Besides, who
bought the groceries?
Who bought the beer?
Did it just walk in?
With my money!
Shut up, both of
you. You act like
two-year-olds.
Come on.
Come on. Come on! Come on!!
Captioning sponsored
by WARNER BROS.