Look, I know we haven't
talked in a while, but...
I have to tell you this, and...
I don't know, you
might not like it.
What do you get when you
cross an elephant
with a rhino?
Hell if I know.
Yeah.
That's my first dad joke.
Did you just kick?
Hi, Luna.
You know,
three months from now,
we get to do this in person.
It's pretty cool.
Time for our song.
Your love
Is lifting me higher
Than I've ever
Been lifted before
So keep it up
Quenching my desire
And I'll be at your
side forever more
You know your love...
How can I help?
Well, there's candy
machines in the pediatric ward.
You know what's not good
for kids before 9:00 a.m.?
Does it start with C and
end with childhood obesity?
Yes. Consider them gone.
I'm hiring six new therapists
with training in CBT and DBT.
And I'm starting a
patient advocacy division
because when I say
things like CBT and DBT,
patients have no idea
what I'm talking about.
Will this cost more money?
Yes, but...
Who's with me?
Ooh. We need to talk
about my waiting room.
Thought we got rid
of your waiting room.
Well, the plan was for nurses
to move patients straight to beds.
Okay, I'm not seeing a problem.
The plan requires nurses.
Got it. More nurses.
And you know he never
showed his face again...
Health care is the number one
cause of bankruptcy in America.
Wow, you really know how to
bring things down, don't you?
Patients should know that their
hospital bills are negotiable.
We should revise our
Patient Bill of Rights.
Love that idea. Way to
bring things back up again.
We need to provide better
care with fewer resources.
But I need your help.
I need your ideas.
Okay, I'm just gonna do
this until somebody speaks.
Is this jogging
anybody's... Anyone?
I'm gonna go ahead, it's
gonna become a robot now.
It's just gonna go
downhill from here.
I'll just keep on doing this.
Does anybody have
anything? Just one idea?
What about group appointments?
Thank God. Yes. Please, share.
You give people with related issues
like diabetes or high blood pressure...
and I'm so glad I
finally found you
Yes, my one in a million girl
So I wrap
My loving arms around you
And I can stand up
And face the world
Time to go to work.
Thirty-two-year-old
woman collapsed
with extreme shortness
of breath and chest pain.
Heart rate 140, respiration's
34, BP 90 over 60.
Took 100% O2 to
keep her sats over 90.
Where's Reynolds? Did
anyone see what happened?
I'm her father. We
were at a fund-raiser.
Jozette was accepting an award.
Then she just shook and fell.
We didn't know what to do.
What you got?
Holosystolic blowing
murmur at the apex.
What took you so long?
Well, I'm the department
chair now. I've got stuff to do.
Like what?
As soon as I figure
that out, I'll let you know.
You're right. Acute
mitral regurgitation.
Trauma One. REYNOLDS:
Get a central line kit.
Lisa, prepare me a Levo drip.
Titrate to systolic at 90.
On the count of three.
One, two, three.
Watch out.
Yeah, oh, my
gosh, my girls tested
for their orange belts
last night in karate.
They're complete
savages. I had no idea.
I looked at... I took
a video of it. Here.
I'll show you.
Or wait, did I email
it to myself already?
That's okay, I can imagine it.
Okay. Well, remind me
to show it to you later,
because it is intensely cute.
Gosh, I'm always talking
about my kids. What about you?
How come you never
talk about yours?
I don't have any.
I'm sorry, I just
assumed that you...
Life had other plans for
me, and then it got too late.
Okay, well... Speaking of which,
based on your extensive experience...
You mean to say "old."
Yes. Exactly.
How long do you
think this Max guy
can shake things up
before the Dean steps in?
Not long. Dean of medicine
does not like things shaken up,
based on my
extensive experience.
All right.
How you doing? I'm Dr. Frome.
But you can call me Iggy, all right?
No need to be so formal.
All right, so...
I had a chat with your mom,
and she told me that you're
having a hard time staying awake
and that you've
been wetting the bed.
Is that right?
Okay.
No big deal, you know?
We can get to the
bottom of this, easy-peasy.
Okay?
Let's see what
we're looking at here.
All right, says here you've been
on Zotepine for the last few years?
Is that right?
Did something happen at school?
No? You sure about that?
'Cause zotepine, my friend, that is...
That's big-time.
That is no joke.
Nothing happened that
you want to tell me about?
No.
Okay, cool. Fair enough.
All right. They've
also got you on
Sertraline. Huh.
And Zolpidem.
Oh, my gosh, they have
you on Atomoxetine as well.
Okay. I mean, uh,
who needs breakfast, am I right?
Fistful of pills like
that every morning?
Yeah. And I see
that, um, you also...
You lost your dad
a few years back?
Yeah.
Yeah, that's really
tough. I'm sorry.
You know what, Leo?
I want to try
something different.
Instead of adding more medication
to your already impressive roster,
why don't we try
this for a plan?
Let's take you off all
of your medication.
I just want to know how
much this is gonna cost me.
I'm sorry, but I
can't tell you that.
So I can compare prices on my Subaru
and not on my wife's double bypass?
You know, it's funny,
Congress actually made it illegal
for hospitals to
disclose prices to you,
so it's the only industry in
America with a non-compete clause,
but, hey, call your
congressperson. Resist!
You're running late. - For what?
For everything. Dora,
I'm educating patients.
You're inciting riots.
Dean of medicine
called again. Pass.
You can't keep
ignoring him, Max.
When you fire half the staff,
disembowel an entire hospital,
you have to expect your
boss is gonna be on you...
To what? Re-bowel it?
Sounds gross, doesn't it?
Max!
Dr. Sharpe, back in the
trenches. How's re-entry?
I wouldn't know.
You didn't show up to your
appointment this morning.
Well, I had a department chair
meeting. Which you missed, I believe.
Because we had an appointment.
What? How... Did
I forget something?
No, no, just, Dr. Sharpe
and I have a little thing.
Very informal.
It's not informal.
It's quite serious.
How serious? Not
very. I'm taking care of it.
Are you? Mmm-hmm.
Have you eaten today?
Does espresso count?
Dora, would you mind
getting him an apple?
An apple? Mmm.
He'll be in my office.
I can't. I got a full schedule.
Your 2:00 p.m. just canceled.
Thank you, Dora.
Thought you were
getting me an apple.
Max. You have can...
We have 1,500 patients.
I don't have time
to be one of them.
You better find the time
before you run out of it.
One of the valves that
controls the flow of blood
through Jozette's
heart is broken,
and blood is backing up into her
lungs, which is why she can't breathe.
But how could this
happen? Jozette is strong.
She's an aid worker
for the people of Haiti.
I have to get to Jean-Rabel.
This week, a
mudslide hit our village.
So many people have died.
That might explain
what happened.
You thinking takotsubo
syndrome? Yeah.
That sounds bad.
Another name for it is,
uh, broken heart syndrome.
The mudslide may have
caused Jozette so much grief
that it actually made her
heart beat so hard that
it tore the muscles
that hold it together.
I hate to feel helpless.
I'm sorry.
Well, the good news is,
I can fix a broken heart.
Now, we're gonna get
you prepped for surgery
and get you home
as fast as we can.
First may we perform a Gad Ko?
I'm sorry, a what?
It's a protection ritual.
We make a cut in
the skin, rub in herbs.
Oh, no, that's... That's
out of the question.
Any cuts to the skin can
introduce infection, so...
Gad Ko attaches Lwa to me.
Protects me from accidents.
Okay, look, Jozette, there
won't be any accidents, all right?
Now, if you'll excuse me,
I have to prep for surgery.
It's true. He used
to be energetic.
Silly.
But you can't just take him
off of all of his medications.
Doesn't he need them?
Honestly, I don't know.
I don't know what he needs.
He's on so many
counterintuitive drugs,
I can't see the real issue.
I want to try
behavioral therapy.
Talk therapy.
He had, um,
outbursts at school... Physical.
And when the school psychiatrist
started him on the Zotepine,
they completely stopped.
That drug may have succeeded
in curbing your son's behavior,
but it did nothing to address
the underlying issues.
Zotepine also causes
lethargy, apathy.
So when he was prescribed a
stimulant, that led to his sleep issues.
And accelerated his weight gain,
which developed
into Type 2 diabetes.
That's why he's wetting the bed.
He has diabetes
because of the
drugs that he's on.
My God, I didn't...
I didn't know.
I mean, they told me
that he needed them.
I was just... I was
trying to help him.
Of course, you were. That's
what we all would have done.
Yes, absolutely.
I'm sorry, I just...
Let me pull him off the meds.
You know, let me talk to him.
I really just want to talk to him.
When was the last time
you saw your son smile?
Dora, are you stalking me?
It's definitely beginning to feel
that way, isn't it? Mmm-hmm.
Dr. Sharpe's office
called. I got pulled into OB.
Tell that to Dr. Sharpe.
I got you an apple.
You know, I'm really more of
a Golden Russet kind of guy.
Maybe keep that to yourself. What
do you have against Golden Russets?
Nothing, my issue is with people
who can identify Golden Russets.
Dr. Reynolds. What up?
Now eat the apple.
Got you an apple.
Also, I got a call from
Jozette Pampil's family?
Apparently they're upset
that you won't let them
perform some kind
of protection ritual?
That's correct. Even
though they believe
it's gonna help keep your
patient safe from harm?
You fired the entire
cardiac surgical department
because of the
high infection rates,
and now you want me
to let a family member
cut open my patient
and put dirt in her wound?
Well, a superficial wound with a
sterile blade under your supervision.
Is this my call, or are
you overstepping me?
It's your call. Good.
Then no one's cutting open
my patient but me, okay?
Hello. BLOOM: She's ready to go.
All right. Wow.
Expeditions to the North
Pole traveled lighter, huh?
Looks like V-fib.
There's no pulse. Defibrillator.
200 joules.
All clear.
Okay, got her back. I'll
back off the Levophed.
That should stabilize her.
You're good? Yeah.
Back in V-fib!
I don't have a
pulse. Let's go 300.
All clear.
Okay, I got her back.
What the hell?
She's too unstable
for transport.
Maybe you should do the ritual.
Because Leo is on multiple medications,
we must devise a regimented detox program.
The stimulant should
leave his system overnight,
but the psychoactive medication
will require gradual tapering.
What, you don't
agree? No, no, I do. I do.
Just, um, for
whatever it's worth,
I think you would have
made a really good dad.
No, I wouldn't have. Why
do you say crazy things?
A word, you two? FROME:
Let me ask you something.
Don't you think Kapoor would
have made, like, a totally rad dad?
Come on, please...
Dr. Villarreal, this is...
Look at this dad face.
Hey! This is Dr. Kapoor, head
of our neurology department,
and this is Dr. Frome, head
of our psych department.
Gentlemen, this
is Dr. Villarreal.
She's the psychiatrist for all
the public schools in Queens.
Including Leo Chen's.
His mother alerted me to the
changes you're making to his treatment.
Yes, we were just
discussing his detox schedule.
Well, you should know that if Leo
Chen stops taking his medication,
he'll no longer be admitted
back into his school
or for that matter, any
New York public school.
I'm sorry, how can you force
a child to take medication?
Easy, it's the law.
Prohibition on Mandatory
Medication Amendment.
It passed in 2004.
It is illegal for public
schools to force a student
to take a controlled
substance to attend class.
Unless the mother signed an
Individualized Education Plan
agreeing to the medication.
She did? It's right there.
Not only are these medications
causing Leo physical harm,
but nobody has even studied
their long-term side effects.
Well, the school board
doesn't seem to agree with you.
Max, I can get through to this kid,
just not with all the drugs in the way.
Okay, okay. You really feel
that you can help this kid?
I do.
And you think you can
wean him off the drugs safely?
He does.
What? You gotta
talk faster. I do.
Then present your
evidence to a judge.
If you believe this is the best
thing for your patient, prove it.
Take the New York public
school system to court.
This pacing wire should get her
stable long enough to get her to the OR.
Or you could do the ritual.
If I believed in rituals, I
would have become a shaman,
not a surgeon.
You're about to
fix her heart valve.
If I were you, I'd take
all the help I could get.
You know, if a patient feels like
they've got to chant or knock on wood
or get their prayer warrior to lay
hands on them before I operate,
then that means they
don't trust me, you know?
They don't have
faith in my abilities.
Normal paced
rhythm with capture.
See? Pacing wire
is all the faith I need.
O2 sats are falling!
She's tanking.
Pulse ox dropping.
Jozette, I'm gonna sit
you up so you can breathe.
I need to intubate.
I hear rales.
Edema? Backing up in her lungs
because of that valve.
Here, toss me the
furosemide. I'm already on it.
The pulmonary are compromising.
Monitor.
You know, that's gonna take
a while to dry out her lungs.
Well, I can't operate until
I get this under control.
So then maybe you
do the ritu... Don't.
Don't even say it.
Normalizing. Standing back.
Administrating
now. Okay, look...
The ritual isn't even about you or
what you believe or your abilities.
It's about her.
It's about what she believes,
what she needs. I mean,
why can't you
just give her that?
So, Millie, I've read your file.
Not so good, huh?
Well, your chemotherapy hasn't
been as effective as everyone hoped.
Starting tomorrow, I'd like to
put you on a different regimen.
I wish I could
offer better news.
No.
It's okay.
Well, at least I
got to meet you.
Sorry? I've seen you on TV.
Oh.
If I had known I was gonna
meet the real Dr. Helen today,
I would have done my nails.
Your nails look fine, Millie.
No.
None of me looks fine.
I look like a cue ball.
Like a little, shrunken,
nubby-nailed cue ball.
Hell, I tried to wear a wig.
It just kept falling off.
That was embarrassing.
Even my kids made fun
of me, which I let them,
because it blows off steam, and
I figured if
they were laughing,
they wouldn't be thinking
about me keeling over dead.
I just wish that everything
didn't make me nauseous.
Food makes me nauseous.
At first, I thought, "Well,
I just won't eat anything,
"so what could I throw up?"
But I was wrong. I'm sorry.
Will you excuse
me? I need a moment.
You okay, Dr. Helen?
Yep, I just need...
I just need my diary.
Please tell me you're joking.
Green Jell-O?
Well, yeah, but we make
the food this bad on purpose
so that nobody wants to stay.
Well, it's working. Yeah.
Tell you what. I have an apple.
What about you?
I'll be all right.
How are you?
Don't you have more
important patients to see?
Nope. Max. Go.
Look, I just wanted to tell
you that I'm not the same
as that last job. I can be here
for you, with you.
Max.
It's not just...
Look, even when you
were there, you weren't.
I, um...
Sorry, I have to... Go.
But when you come back,
let me in.
Promise.
Thank you for doing this. I had
no idea this was even possible.
Yeah, yeah. You know what?
New Amsterdam was
actually the first hospital
to put a courtroom
in the building
so we could, um, advocate for
our patients in real time, you know?
Which is pretty neat.
Leo, come on through here.
You know, in the 1940s,
uh, New York was having a bit of
a mental health moment, if you will,
and this psych department was
completely overworked and underfunded
and, uh, exactly like it is
today, come to think of it.
Dr. Frome. Please. Yeah.
Oh, right, sorry.
Time to shut up now.
Mr. Bishop, as
Dr. Frome already knows,
I like to keep my
court informal,
so we're just going to jump in
unless you have any objections.
None, Your Honor.
Dr. Kapoor, we'll
start with you.
I've read the file.
You have a course of treatment
you want me to rule on. I get that.
Tell me why all
this is necessary.
Good morning, Your Honor.
Leo Chen is only 10 years old,
and he's on four different medications,
many with very damaging side effects.
But none of the medications are
actually treating his root problem.
Which is what? KAPOOR: Uh...
We don't know. I mean...
We won't until Dr. Frome can
provide the therapy Leo needs.
And you don't think that's
possible while he's medicated?
Over-medicated.
I don't envy
Dr. Villarreal's position.
She's responsible for the mental
health of more than 3,000 students.
Prescribing medication is faster
than painstakingly evaluating
each individual student's needs.
That's quite an indictment.
It's not meant to be. It's
simply the reality of the situation.
There are too many children
in the public school system
in need of psychological help
and not enough mental health
professionals to help them.
But you think you
and Dr. Frome can.
Yes.
In a way that won't further
endanger Leo's physical health.
We shouldn't have
to choose between
the physical and mental
well-being of our children.
Thank you.
Let's get her to the OR.
Let's go slow.
There we go.
Easy. Okay.
The ritual worked.
Just don't tell Bloom.
Hey, how's it going?
Oh, my gosh, it's so good.
Kapoor nailed it, man. He was
like a slow, bald ninja out there.
Nice. Ready, Your Honor.
Okay, let's start with
the treatment plan
Dr. Kapoor lays out in Leo's
file seems very reasonable.
What's wrong with it?
I'm sure it sounds reasonable,
Your Honor, on paper.
But I'm sorry, if Leo Chen
is taken off his medications,
he poses a significant threat to
the rest of the student population.
- That's an exaggeration.
- If I may, Your Honor,
this is video footage
of an incident at school
prior to Dr. Villarreal prescribing
the medications in question.
Hey!
No!
No! Stop him!
You're right about
one thing, Dr. Kapoor.
I am responsible for
over 3,000 children,
and I have to protect the
physical well-being of them all.
Hey. They told me
there was a fight.
But I have never seen that
video before, and I just, I don't...
I know. It's okay.
I know this looks bad.
I'm not sure "bad" is the
right word to describe it.
But what we saw on
that tape was rage.
Okay, and there's
usually a reason for rage.
It's situational.
It's not chemical.
How will you prove that?
Well...
Just give me a second,
okay? I'll be right back.
So listen.
Do you think maybe you could
tell the judge what you felt that day?
You know what I mean? You can
tell her why you did what you did
in your own words.
Okay. He can't.
Not on all these
meds. There's no way.
There's just... There's no way.
There may be one.
"Thank whatever gods may be
"for my unconquerable soul.
"In the fell clutch
of circumstance...
"I have not winced,
nor cried aloud."
I heard you did the ritual.
I'm glad it helped.
I'm pretty sure it was the
Levophed, the pacing wire,
and the furosemide that helped.
How many times did
you scrub each finger?
What? How many times?
Ten.
Why not nine or eleven?
Superstition?
Routine.
What was that thing
you were just reciting?
Invictus.
Oh. Do you always recite
Invictus while scrubbing in?
I do. Hmm.
Kinda like a prayer.
Habit. Ritual.
Loosen up, Dr. Reynolds. Not everything's
gonna go according to your plan.
Or everyone.
Wanna tell me what's going on?
Rapid detox dialysis.
I heard that. I can see
that. And then I thought,
"Surely, they can't be crazy
enough to do something like that
"in the middle of
court proceedings."
It's the fastest way to get
psychotropic drugs out of Leo's system.
Right, but if we lose this case,
they are not gonna let
Leo back into school.
You told us to put the patient
first. That's what we are doing.
Off these medications, Iggy
will be able to work with him.
Yeah, if he can't,
do you have any idea
the kind of liability you are
opening this hospital up to?
Oh, I see. What?
It's about now the new
medical director gets his first visit
from the Dean of medicine.
Or did the Dean already come?
There you are. They
need you in Hematology,
and you owe Dr. Sharpe a call.
So patient first or job first?
I think we broke him.
If you're looking for a
hideout, this one's taken.
Who are you running from?
Patients.
You?
Doctors.
One in particular.
I shouldn't be here.
Well, that makes two of us.
I really didn't expect
to care this much.
That's exactly why
you should be here.
What about you?
I made a promise
to my wife
that I would slow down.
Before this, I ran a clinic in
Chinatown, and it almost broke us.
I mean, Georgia...
Georgia couldn't go
through that again.
And I promised that
she wouldn't have to.
I promised her that
I would be there...
So we could start a family.
So I asked Georgia if she
would slow down with me,
to stop dancing, a
career that she loved,
that she's really,
really good at.
She did
for me
to be a mom, you know.
So we got pregnant,
and then I got the call
about New Amsterdam.
If Chinatown was K2,
then New Amsterdam was
Everest.
Who can resist climbing Everest?
Lots of people.
I wish I were one of them.
But I said yes
without telling Georgia.
She didn't like that.
You betrayed her.
But that doesn't mean
that you don't belong here.
The changes you've made are
gonna help thousands of people.
What about the one I married?
Oh, Max. You haven't told her
that you have cancer, have you?
What are you waiting for?
To not have cancer?
You can't carry
this load by yourself,
not as a medical
director, not as a patient,
certainly not as a
husband or father.
You've been telling
everyone, "Put the patient first,"
so why don't you
take your own advice?
Consider this your
first appointment.
And your first order of business is
to tell your wife that you have cancer.
Dr. John, how am I doing on
my suction? Capillary leak only.
Good. Okay.
Can you give me a
2-0 polyester on a stick?
Suture.
All right.
There we go.
Snip.
That should hold
nicely. That's the goal.
Okay, go ahead and restore blood flow
from the bypass machine through the heart.
Valve open. Unclamping the aorta
now.
Hmm.
Sutures holding.
Blood flow should
stimulate the heart to
start beating on its own.
Vicky, D-fib. I'm not
seeing anything on monitors.
Okay, let's give
it a little help.
Okay, here we go.
Charge to 20. Charging.
Clear. Clear.
No visible beat.
Let's do it again.
Clear. Clear.
Still no heartbeat. Gonna
need something stronger.
Intracardiac high-dose EPI.
Give me 10 mls and a syringe.
Dr. Reynolds... I
need it now, people.
Ten mls cardiac needle.
Where does she stand with gas exchange?
- Producing adequately.
Leo, can you tell Judge
Hayashi what you told me?
It's okay.
She's a friend.
It was my fault.
What was your fault, Leo?
My dad died.
My fault.
Can you tell us the rest?
We were going to Sheep's Meadow
in the park.
That's where we
went to build LEGOs.
Then what happened?
Forgot them...
The LEGOs.
So my dad went back to get them.
And he didn't come back.
You live on a
fifth-floor walk-up, right?
Yeah, sometimes it was hard
for his dad to walk all those stairs.
He had asthma
and a heart condition.
And that day when
he reached the top,
he had a heart attack.
And Leo found him.
And the video?
Can you tell me what happened?
Ryder...
He always said I should
be dead like my dad.
That day, I finally...
I had to make it stop.
What are you
proposing, Dr. Frome?
Well, Leo needs to be able to
process all this displaced guilt.
And he can't do that when he's
buried in a drug-induced haze.
He needs to be able to feel.
He needs to be able
to talk to somebody.
Let him talk to me.
Let me help him.
Charged to 20. Charging.
Clear.
All right, paddles in place.
How long do we keep this up?
Paddles in place! Nurse, loupes!
Charged to 20. Clear!
Still nothing.
Dr. Reynolds.
Do we call it?
What are you doing?
Trying cardiac massage.
That's not going to work.
All I need is one beat.
Just one.
Dr. Reynolds.
Hold on.
I think I feel something.
I feel something.
She's back.
You did it.
Pulse ox 97.
So...
The Gad Ko worked.
Back down
Down to the downtown
Down to the lockdown
Boards, nails lie around
I crouch like a crow
Contrast in the snow
For the agony
I'd rather know
'Cause blinded
I am
Blindsided
Peek in
Into the peer in...
Please leave your message.
I know it's been a long time.
Too long.
Please call back.
I'm here.
I am
Blindsided
Would you really rush out?
Max. Hi.
How is she?
Better, but I'm still concerned.
She needs to be on bed
rest until she stops spotting.
Okay.
She can't be put
under any stress...
Physical or emotional. It
could hurt her and the baby.
Understand?
Yeah.
Would you really
rush for me now?
Taut line
Down to the shoreline...
Hey.
Hey, what's wrong?
The moon is a cold light
I, um...
Hey.
Remember?
You promised
to let me in.
'Cause blinded
Just tell me one thing.
Just one true thing.
Blinded
I love you.
I was
Blindsided
Blinded
I was
Blindsided