This is Auggie.
The foster family
felt he would be
too much to handle.
We'll do it.
We'll foster him.
I have to make
some changes around here.
The ED has not been running
as effectively as it could be.
A good leader takes
responsibility for everything
that happens on his watch.
I'm testing a brand-new
heart failure drug.
With some hard work,
we could fill this trial
in a matter of weeks,
not months.
Why do you do
the one-night stands?
They all end up the same.
With you alone.
There she is...
...our fearless leader.
Returning from exile.
How you doing, Michael?
You look good. You look fit.
Mmm-hmm.
Moving back home,
solid meals
instead of take-out.
The only positive thing
about being furloughed.
The hospital lifted
restriction on non-essential
personnel onsite.
Mmm-hmm.
Device reps are being
allowed into the OR.
Gotta go, Ma. Catch you later.
All righty.
Doc C.
I'll see ya.
Oh, Sharon.
It is so great to see you.
To see you.
Yeah.
In the flesh.
Thanks, Daniel.
And it's about time.
COVID protocols have been
working for months.
Even with my diabetes,
there was no reason
for me to stay at home.
Watch out, Med, she's back!
You care to join me
for a nasal swab?
Would love to.
After you.
Ooh. Sorry. Good morning.
Oh. Hi.
Good morning.
Sorry. Didn't see you
coming out.
I didn't see you going in.
No harm, no foul.
Mmm-hmm.
See you around.
Yeah, catch ya later.
See ya.
Okay.
I'm not gonna say anything.
But I saw that!
You saw what?
We just caught each other
by surprise.
Right. And did you want me
to pass him a note
in homeroom, too?
Ha-ha.
Maggie?
One second.
We're friends. That's it.
Mmm-hmm?
Mmm... Hypothetically
though, if there were to be
that kind of attraction,
what do you think?
I don't know, Nat...
Crockett?
Is he really your type?
Oh.
Sorry... Just gotta
deal with this before
it gets out of hand.
Done.
Last time I pick up
the phone. Promise.
Trust me. I know how
busy you are.
I just really appreciate you
making the time to check in.
Only way to cross it off
the list is to get it done.
Like dealing with expense
reports, managing doctor
and nurse staffing levels,
let alone a distribution plan
for a possible COVID vaccine.
Wow. A lotta stuff.
Yeah. But I can handle it.
I guess my years
on active duty,
the COs I learned under,
Chief of the ED
is what I've been trained for.
You know, this is
an opportunity for
everyone to step up.
We need to do the job
better than ever.
Buddy, I think it's such
an admirable attitude,
you know?
It just might be
a good idea to keep in
the back of your mind,
not everybody is
as, um, combat tested,
if you will, as you are.
People are just exhausted.
For most of them,
doing "better,"
I mean, it's like,
getting through the day.
Yeah.
Listen.
My first tour,
I really struggled.
Far from home, no sleep,
Marines dying every day.
I went to my CO,
told him I was exhausted.
You know what he said?
"Now's not the time, Choi.
You can rest when it's over."
I get it.
Look, Dr. Charles,
I know I'm not gonna
be able to please everyone.
But that's not the mission.
I was promoted
to right the ship.
You wanna get that?
I gotta cut this short.
Do your thing, man.
Appreciate you stopping by.
Sure thing.
Dr. Driskell,
what do you got?
Drew Corbett.
62-year-old male,
eight days post presenting
with COVID symptoms.
In and out
of respiratory failure
the past three days.
Okay.
Drew married his
high school sweetheart.
His wife, his two kids,
his three grandkids
FaceTime him every day.
Labs?
Suggestive of
a cytokine storm.
We're trying to get it
under control, but his
vitals are still unstable.
What do you wanna do?
Keep him on a high flow O2,
start him on a COVID cocktail.
Good.
V-tach.
No pulse.
Open his airway, bag him.
I'm on compressions.
No. Hold compressions.
Charge to 200,
draw up an amp of epi.
But he's unstable. Needs to
maintain cardiac perfusion.
No compressions.
Hospital policy.
CPR aerosolizes the virus.
Puts you all at risk.
You know that.
Paddles.
Clear.
Amp of epi,
recharge the paddles.
Shock him again.
Clear.
Please, let me
do compressions.
It'll keep his
heart alive.
No. Run it again.
Clear.
We did everything we could.
Miss Goodwin, welcome back.
Thank you.
I haven't had a chance yet to
compile the nightly numbers,
but I'll get them
to you ASAP.
No hurry. We could
go over them later.
I'm just making rounds,
saying "hello" to everyone.
Mags, who's up?
Uh... Treatment 5.
Just sent it to your iPad.
Thanks.
Hey, I'd like to get
the treatment rooms
turned over
within ten minutes of
a patient being discharged.
With UV sanitizing?
Yeah.
I can't get it in under 15.
Try.
And please make sure the
equipment carts are restocked
three times per shift.
Okay.
Hey, Mr. Lowry...
Dr. Lowry.
Plastic surgeon.
Excuse me. Dr. Lowry.
What's going on?
I became lightheaded
during a surgery.
Minor procedure, too,
a lipoma removal.
Fatty tumor.
Stain on the body.
It had to go.
Anyway, I felt myself going
limp before I could remove it.
I didn't lose consciousness.
Nevertheless, my surgical
assistant overreacted,
called 911.
She did the right thing,
for your safety
and your patient's.
I am the patient.
I meant, who you
were operating on.
Yeah, that's me.
You were operating
on yourself?
Of course.
I'm not gonna settle for
anything less than perfection.
May I?
Mmm.
I'm seeing other scars here.
Are these pectoral implants?
Indeed. I'm very
proud of them.
Oh. Liposuction?
Had a six pack,
now, it's an eight pack.
Filler, too.
Can't tell, can you?
Everything you've
done here looks...
Perfect.
I told you, I know
what I'm doing.
Even so, your BP is soft.
Likely hypovolemia
from blood loss
during the procedure.
I'm well aware.
I am a doctor.
So, hang a liter of LR
and I'll get out of here.
Actually, I prefer
normal saline.
Also, let's type and
cross two units of blood
to replenish the loss.
As for the lipoma,
we can finish that up.
I'll call Plastics
for a consult.
No, thanks. You do it.
It's best a surgeon
handle this.
Disagree.
Surgeons don't take
advice very well, especially
from other surgeons.
It's okay,
all you have to do
is follow my instructions.
Dr. Charles, I've got
a patient for you.
Todd Lowry. 43.
Plastic surgeon.
He's been operating
on himself. A lot.
Doesn't think twice
about the risks.
Interesting.
Doctors...
We know best, right?
Diagnosing ourselves,
writing our own scripts,
been guilty of both myself.
Sure, we take some liberties,
but Todd is way past that.
These aren't just
Botox injections,
they're invasive operations.
Huh.
Let me have a chat with him.
Check back with you.
Thanks.
Does that hurt, Isabella?
Sort of.
Um, it's not pain as much
as just tightness.
All right, I'm not
feeling anything overt,
but you are really
clenching your ab muscles.
Why don't you try to take
a deep breath, and relax?
Relax?
Yeah, I wish.
2020 kinda took
that off the table.
Stomach's been a mess
for a few months now.
I should have come in sooner.
You're here now.
All right, we're just
gonna do a quick X-ray.
So, if you can stay
still for a second.
So, um, what do you see?
Your bowel
does look distended
and there is a moderate
amount of stool.
When was your
last movement?
A few days ago.
Actually, they've been here
or there for a while.
Could I just be constipated?
I do want to run
some labs and get a CT,
but yes, this could
just be stress
causing you to clench
the muscles in the back,
the way you're
clenching your abs.
Not the "tight ass"
I would have wished for...
But then again, it's still
a Zoom-world, so, no one's
really looking, anyways.
There you go.
All right, a nurse will be by
in a minute, okay?
Thank you.
Yeah.
Ah. So, Doris, I need...
No.
Mmm. That's your sweet voice.
I know what that means.
What's he want now?
I put together a list.
I was never a fan
of Dr. Lanik.
But Ethan...
Whatever that means.
That he sucks.
I've been learning Italian.
Oh.
I noticed.
You're planning a trip?
I took an Ancestry DNA test
a few weeks ago.
I knew my grandparents
were from Chile.
I had no idea, though,
that their grandparents
were from Naples.
Oh, that's cool.
I've never been to Italy.
It's on the list, though.
Until then? You, Trini and
Hank, take the first three.
I'll take the rest.
So, no running
on the treadmill?
Nope. Only blood work
and an echo, Mr. Gessner.
But what
about the meds?
Hospitals push an aspirin
for 30 bucks a pop.
Heart disease pill
you're selling,
bet I'd probably
need a second mortgage
to pay for that.
If you qualify,
the pharmaceutical company
covers all costs.
I like that.
So, uh, what do you say?
Can I enroll you?
No, sorry. Too risky. I...
What? How? Mr. Gessner...
You know, my ticker's
not great, but the pills
I'm on, are working.
COVID, though, that bug
is a wildcard. I...
No. No hospitals till
I've gotten the vaccine.
Please don't hang up.
The COVID ward
is completely contained.
No contact with where
you will be in the ED.
Yeah. Says you.
It's the truth.
I'm there all day.
I've never felt safer.
Okay, I guess I can
come in this afternoon.
Mr. Gessner, thank you.
I'll see you later.
Nice job.
He almost got away.
God, too many of them have.
That's why I'm behind
on my quota.
Millions suffer from
heart failure, April.
I had no idea how difficult
it'd be finding them.
I don't get it. We get cases
in the ED every day,
not to mention Cardiology.
And they've thrown me
a bunch of files.
Unfortunately, the study's
exclusionary criteria
weed out a lot of patients.
I am meeting a cardiologist
at Chicago Congress
later this morning,
hoping he'll throw me
a few patients.
And I'll keep pitching
the Med patients
that are left.
I'd like to help.
Yeah?
When I was
on the COVID ward,
I felt like I was
a part of something
so much bigger
than myself.
I'd like to feel that again.
I'll make time.
Welcome aboard.
All right.
So, why don't you focus
on your meeting,
and I will reach out
to the rest of these
Med patients.
All right.
Great.
Dr. Manning,
all this, it's...
Tumor.
Her abdomen
is full of cancer.
Cancer... um,
I don't understand.
I'm only 21.
I should've come in the moment
that I felt something was off,
but, um, I live at home,
both my parents
are high risk for COVID.
I just didn't want to
bring it into the house.
We understand.
You thought you were doing
what was right.
Am I gonna die?
No, hey. Look,
we'll confer with Oncology,
but I believe that, um,
this section
and this section, too,
are amenable to resection.
Resection, um...
That means surgery, right?
That's right.
The more tumor I remove now,
the better you're positioned
for cancer treatment later.
Okay.
Hey. I know you're scared.
But you can win this fight.
Wow. That's impressive.
Not just the attention
to detail, but the focus
that must be
required to achieve that.
Flattery, really?
You're the head
of Psychiatry.
I figured you'd use something
a little more clever
to get inside my head.
Oh, come on. We're just, uh,
having a little chat.
Okay. Fine, I'll bite.
But scrap the pats
on the back.
I know I'm good,
you don't need to tell me.
You mind if I sit?
This is invasive.
The tumor already has
a blood supply, has invaded
the surrounding tissues.
Yes, but there's two
clear areas of focus around
the left lobe of the liver.
And the same
with the inferior poles
of the kidneys here.
I don't think so.
My experience,
CTs are rarely as accurate
as they appear.
Tumor already looks
like a nightmare,
what's actually going on
inside is a disaster.
Okay, look, all due respect,
Dr. Gillin,
I'm not pushing to operate
to boost my resume.
I want to save
Isabella's life.
So do I.
This CT, though...
Worst case territory.
A biopsy
and appropriate chemo regimen
are the safest first step.
Perhaps, surgery
down the line.
"Perhaps"?
She's very sick, Dr. Manning.
If we'd been able
to treat her earlier...
We weren't.
I understand.
And in that time, her
cancer progressed too far.
So, that's it?
Dr. Gillin has her opinion.
I have mine.
So, how'd it go?
Did Dr. Lowry,
plastic surgeon,
shrink himself?
Not really his priority.
Putting him
on a five-day, then?
A psych hold? Why?
Dr. Charles,
he cut himself open.
Yeah. Because of
body dysmorphia,
which is driven, ironically,
by a desire
to perfect his body.
Not to hurt himself.
Maybe not intentionally.
But that perfectionism
clearly clouds his judgment.
We need to step in.
Thing is, BDD isn't
something that we can
just fix. You know?
Todd's gotta develop
an entirely new perspective
on his body.
It's gonna take time,
you know?
You know a guy like Todd
isn't gonna go
into therapy voluntarily.
We intervene now,
or this just gets worse.
I hear ya.
And we'll take that
under advisement.
Hey, Mags, where are we
on those changes
to the nursing routine?
Ethan,
we're short-staffed.
I'm doing what I can.
The other nurses, too.
It's Ben.
Give me two minutes?
Yeah. Just get
the changes done, okay?
Yeah.
Hey, babe, what's up?
Auggie's not feeling so hot.
Temp's a little high.
He hasn't thrown up,
but feels like he might.
How's his energy?
Low.
Doesn't even have
enough strength
for Minecraft.
That's a red flag.
Can you put him on?
Sure.
Hey, little man.
Sorry for bothering you
at work.
There's nothing
to apologize for.
Can you do me a favor,
can you lean in real close
to the phone?
And look into the lens,
so, I can see your eyes.
Okay. Thanks, honey.
You can go back to resting.
So, what do you think?
Natalie needs
to take a look.
Okay.
I'll bring him in.
Yeah.
Are we there?
I hope not.
You've been
seeing results?
So far, yes.
Study's still small,
but the data has been
very encouraging.
It always is
in the early phases.
But I've seen a lot
of heart failure trials
come and go.
Is this the real deal?
I hope so.
Yesterday, I treated a woman
in the ED, massive MI.
She's now on a vent
in the CCU and the odds
are not on her side.
But if this
oral inotrope works,
what happened to her
may not have to happen
to anyone else.
Okay, sold. I'm in.
Wonderful.
Thank you, Dr. Mayfield.
Your patients will really
help the study.
That's great
for your hospital.
Now, let's discuss mine.
How's 30% sound?
Sorry, uh, 30% of what?
Your patient enrollment fee.
A kickback?
That's a harsh word.
I prefer we call it
"quid pro quo."
Call it whatever you want,
it's unethical.
I can't do it.
I'm afraid
I can't help you.
Look, I'm from Canaryville,
I get that one hand
washes the other,
but that's
neighborhood politics,
this is science.
Yeah. This isn't
Chicago Med, Dr. Halstead.
There's no university backing,
or Wall Street investment
or billionaire benefactors.
I cannot afford
to give away patients
for free. I'm sorry.
Good luck with your trial.
Appreciate your time,
Dr. Mayfield.
Miss Goodwin, I've discussed
all the risks with Isabella.
She wants to proceed
with surgery.
And I'm confident
I can do it.
This isn't about
your ability, Dr. Marcel.
It's about the state
of Isabella's cancer.
Dr. Gillin is the head
of Oncology. I will not
override her decision.
Miss Goodwin,
without being able
to resect part of the tumor,
the chemo won't work.
Please,
we are where we are
because she was
protecting her family.
She deserves our help.
This virus, not only
is it still killing people,
but it's forced
thousands of others,
like Isabella,
to delay or even
interrupt treatment.
Not just cancer,
but all chronic illnesses.
Look, I wish I could
help every patient,
but the honest reality is,
some won't be able
to be saved.
World kinda sucks
right now, Miss Goodwin.
Yes, it does.
Thank you.
I'll call over
to the Mayo Clinic...
Sloan Kettering.
See if they'll do
the surgery.
Yeah. Worth a try.
Uh, I'm gonna
fill in Isabella.
Oh, I'll come with you.
Oh, actually,
if you don't mind,
I'd like to do it alone.
I sold her on the surgery.
It's up to me to tell her
I spoke too soon.
Okay. Yeah.
Thanks.
Pull slowly and evenly.
I am.
No fragments?
No. All clean.
Okay, we can move on.
Easy.
I'm controlling
the bleeders.
No, you're frying
healthy tissue.
All right,
I'm calling Plastics.
They'll finish up.
No, look, we're almost done.
I don't have the energy to
start over with someone new.
Then please
let me do my job.
Rather you use
absorbable sutures.
Can you grab 3-0 absorbable
Vicryl sutures off the cart?
Actually,
Monocryl instead of Vicryl.
We don't have that in the ED.
I'd have to call OR,
have them sent down.
I just want it done right.
Me, too.
But second guessing
every move I make
isn't gonna get us there.
Fine.
Vicryl will do.
Let's see.
Okay.
I'm sorry, Auggie,
I know that we're doing
a lot of poking around.
That's okay. I trust you.
I'm gonna go talk
to Dr. Manning
for a minute, okay?
All right.
Okay.
His liver's failing.
Yes.
He's stable, though.
Adjusting his meds
will ease his discomfort.
But...
It's time to admit him,
get him
on the transplant list.
I knew this day would come.
I've been preparing.
I thought I'd be ready. I...
I know it feels like
you're alone right now,
but you're not.
I am here for you, okay?
Last one.
Good?
The nurse
will dress the wound.
That guy is impossible.
On me the entire procedure.
Well, he is challenging,
I'll give you that.
And he's a doctor.
If he's reckless
with his own health,
he could be reckless
with patients.
He shouldn't be practicing.
Except that people with BDD
tend to be pretty rational.
Except when it comes
to their own bodies.
And that tracks
with Dr. Lowry.
Talking with him,
it's clear that
he just doesn't have the same
issue with his patients
as he does with himself.
Maybe the medical board should
be the one to decide that.
Well, I think
I'm pretty qualified.
I...
He's more unstable
than you think, Dr. Charles.
Ooh. Look on that face,
I'm guessing the meeting
was a bust.
Huge.
Doctor over there, Mayfield,
he's got a ton of patients.
But he won't share any
unless I pad his pockets.
So, I walked out.
Good.
You shouldn't partner
with someone who's just
in it for a payout.
Of course,
turning him down means
I'm back to square one,
short on candidates.
How'd the rest
of the Med files go?
I called them all.
There was definite interest.
No one committed,
but I told them
you'd follow up.
Fingers crossed.
Hey, it was a tough morning,
but Ed Gessner's
coming in, right?
Still a win to be had.
Yeah, you're right,
keep looking forward.
Yeah.
Maggie, you've got
to understand,
Auggie has a rare blood type
and no family
to reach out to
for a direct donation.
Sharon, please don't be
an administrator right now.
You're my friend,
just level with me.
How long might it be
before Auggie gets a liver?
I'm not sure. Gift of Hope
oversees the transplant list.
The hospital has no influence
over that process.
But you know the system
inside and out.
Experience must be giving you
some kind of a gut feeling.
Auggie's not critical,
so, I imagine at this point,
he's low on the list.
So, we have to wait
for Auggie to get sicker
and the donor's liver
is gonna be hard to find.
It might not happen...
will it?
I don't know, Maggie.
I'm sorry.
No, I understand.
The spread is extensive.
Yes. Mmm-hmm. That is
the plan our oncologist
recommended as well.
Okay. Thank you, Dr. Webber.
Dr. Manning...
Um, just one sec...
I'm sorry,
but this can't wait.
Where?
Six.
Oh, my God, Crockett,
you've gone rogue?
Have you lost your mind?
I've overstepped, okay?
But the bigger issue is this.
Dr. Gillin was right.
Deeper I go,
the more tumor I find.
Peritoneal studding,
carcinomatosis...
there's cancer everywhere.
Yeah.
Her kidneys are overrun.
My first instinct was to
remove them, but that'd
tie Isabella to dialysis.
No way she'd be able
to tolerate the chemo then.
If you can't leave
the kidneys in and you can't
take the kidneys out,
then what's left?
Ex-vivo.
Remove one kidney,
debulk it of as much
cancer as possible,
then re-implant,
reattach and repeat
with the other one.
Crockett, ex-vivo surgeries
are still experimental.
There is no guarantee
the kidneys will work
once you put them back in.
Maybe.
You didn't call me up here
to debate this, did you?
Natalie, if we don't
do this, Isabella dies.
I'll scrub in.
Hey.
How'd the follow-up calls go
to the Med patients
I reached out to?
Two outta eight.
That's something.
There he is...
Mr. Gessner!
Hey, Mr. Gessner?
Welcome.
Here we go.
Okay, clear him out of this.
What the hell?
Why isn't the ambo
using the COVID entrance?
I don't know,
must be backed up.
What's he doing?
No, no, no.
No, no, no, no...
Hey, Mr. Gessner,
wait, please.
You said it was safe!
It is! I swear.
Hey, the ED is nowhere
near the COVID...
I don't care!
Please, please, don't.
Mr. Gessner. Hey, I just...
Okay.
You can let
Commander Choi know
treatment rooms are
being turned over within
ten minutes as ordered.
Okay. Great.
While I've got you,
I have a cousin
in Rockford
who needs a hand, pregnant,
three kids in homeschool...
I know it's a pain,
but can I get
a few days off next week?
Yeah, sure...
All right. All done.
You see? That only
took two seconds.
What's it for?
To find you a liver.
All right, sweetie.
Right kidney's
looking good.
Great.
Seems luck
is on our side.
Just gotta finish
closing the capsule,
then we can re-implant and
move on to the other one.
Dr. Marcel, you scheduled
a central line insertion.
We had a complication.
Had to expand.
Okay.
You scheduled
a central line insertion
as a cover to book the OR?
I needed the room with as
few questions as possible.
Figured I'd cross this bridge
when I got to it.
We're there.
And it doesn't seem like
she's gonna be looking
the other way.
Only a matter of time
before we're found out.
Yep.
What are you doing?
I don't like
your wound eversion!
No, no, no. I closed
all the dead space.
It will heal seamlessly.
There'll be a dimple!
They need to be fixed!
Don't! Don't!
Get off!
Get off of me!
Please. Please.
You're hurting yourself.
Need some help in here.
This is all your fault.
They're not perfect!
Hey, Dr. Lowry...
Stop, stop. Soft restraints.
No. No restraints.
No restraints.
Get off of me!
Need five of Haldol.
Not yet.
He needs to be sedated!
Ethan!
I'm gonna be the one
who makes that call.
Okay? Let me handle this.
Hey. Hey, Todd. Look at me.
Look at me. Right here.
What's going on, buddy?
Breathe with me,
all right?
In through the nose.
Look at me.
In through the nose,
out through the mouth.
And push out.
He's a lot calmer...
Don't you ever interfere
with the treatment
of my patient again.
Buddy, you're way
out of line.
Me?
The guy's ripping himself
to shreds. I told you
he needed to be on a hold.
You shot that down
and here we are!
That's right.
And locking him up
still isn't the answer.
Neither are restraints
or sedatives.
How can you say that?
He's harming himself.
If you would have just
helped me, we wouldn't be
in this situation!
How's the left kidney?
Pinking up yet?
No. Still purple.
Orientation is good, though.
No rotation,
inflow artery isn't kinked.
Doppler it.
Doppler...
Sounds monophasic.
There's blood flow,
just not enough.
Okay. Marty, get her
blood pressure up,
five thousand units
of heparin, let's go.
Meds are in.
No change.
Look,
we've been able
to resect a lot of tumor.
Two kidneys would be ideal,
but one's enough for her
to tolerate chemo.
Last knot.
Snip.
Moment of truth.
Unclamp the vein.
Nice and easy. Easy, easy.
Then the artery.
It's pinking up.
Strong blood flow.
There it is.
I am gonna have you
both fired.
How is she?
In great shape.
We're about to close.
Glad to hear it.
Nevertheless,
she's the last patient
either one of you will
ever see at this hospital.
Dr. Mayfield,
thanks for seeing me again.
Of course.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
So many patients,
it's always something.
Don't have to tell you
that, though. We're all
in this together, right?
To that end, I've had
some time to reflect on
our earlier conversation,
realized
there's always a way
to find common ground.
That is, if you're
still interested?
I am. Come on in.
We'll talk details.
Yeah.
Hey.
Um...
I just wanted to apologize
for my behavior.
I overreacted.
Apology accepted.
Appreciate you coming down.
What did you, uh,
do to your hand?
Rough day.
Tell me about it. Right?
After I, uh...
...left your office
this morning,
there was a patient,
Drew Corbett. He died.
Acute respiratory failure.
When Drew coded, the resident
wanted to do compressions,
but that's against protocol,
so, I held them back.
Okay.
I stood outside
the treatment room
and I watched Drew die.
I wanted to pound
on his chest.
But I just stood there
and I did nothing.
Same as yesterday.
Same as it'll be tomorrow.
Man, I'm just, uh...
I'm just so sorry
you gotta go through that.
You know,
maybe the reason that
you got so upset
at Dr. Lowry
is as simple as this.
I mean,
it's very easy to look
at body dysmorphic disorder
as physical,
about the body, right?
But it's actually
a control issue. Right?
Not unlike feeling responsible
for every patient's outcome.
Or wanting to keep
an ED functioning perfectly
in the middle of a pandemic.
Lives are at stake,
Dr. Charles.
I have to be effective
at what I do.
But what if that's
not always possible?
So, what? I'm just
supposed to give up?
Accept failure?
No.
Accept being mortal.
Remember when we were
dealing with your PTSD?
The, um,
Serenity Prayer?
How'd that go again?
"Grant me the serenity
to accept the things
I cannot change,
"the courage to
change the things I can..."
And?
"And the wisdom
to know the difference."
But even if they put his
DNA into their database,
doesn't it take
a really long time
to get the results back?
I'm expediting
the order.
Rush processing.
It's gonna cost us triple,
but we'll have an answer
by this week.
I realize Auggie is low
on the transplant list,
but pinning our hopes
on finding
some long-lost relative?
Ben, the Internet
is flooded with stories
of people who have
found family members
through DNA databases.
This is gonna work.
How can you be so sure?
Because
it has to.
You get Goodwin's text?
"My office. Now."
So, I guess this is it.
Yep, let's get this
over with.
Okay.
You know, Manning,
I put you in an impossible
position today.
When Goodwin
lays the hammer,
I take the fall.
Noble,
but I chose
to scrub in with you.
So, whatever happens,
happens to us both.
Okay.
I don't even know
where to begin.
My dismay at the risk
you put your patient in,
or the headache I have
from Dr. Gillin screaming
about how furious she is!
And by the way,
her anger is justified!
That said...
Incredible job.
We're not fired?
Trust me, you came
very, very close.
The board was with
Dr. Gillin, they wanted
to see you two gone.
But I helped them see
there's no PR value
in a successful
ex-vivo surgery
if you fire the two heroes
of the day.
Thank you, Miss Goodwin.
Thank you.
Hey, Ma.
Ready to go home?
Yeah.
Get outta here.
Ma'am.
Good night.
Oh, so, that's where
you've been.
You okay?
It is what it is,
but a hundred patient
files here,
and more on the way.
Still, I'm sorry. I know
you had to make a deal
you didn't really want to.
End of the day,
it's about saving lives.
Hmm. The trial needs
a chance to prove
the drug can work.
Mayfield's patients
guarantee that.
Well, I'm done for the day.
I can help you start sorting
through those files.
Thanks, April.
Oh, my God, I thought
it was over for us today.
Yeah. Me, too.