♪ Ohhh ohhh ohhh ♪
♪ I'll never know
how we ever... ♪
Welcome home, stranger.
How was Seattle?
It was good.
It's always a little weird
going back, but it was good.
Uh, your brother says hello.
Mm. How's Derek?
He's, uh...
Derek?
If you and Sam have time
for breakfast,
I can scramble up
a few more eggs.
Um...
Sam's not here.
Good not here,
like you're making him wait
to see you
because it's extra hot
to delay homecoming sex,
or bad not here,
like things are not good?
I gave him a choice
before I left.
I said, we either have a baby
or we end things.
Wow. Uh, and?
And, uh,
he thought it was best
to stay at his place
until he makes his decision.
Yay for love.
Right?
Why aren't you ready to go?
We're already late.
These wedding invitations were
supposed to go out a week ago.
Why didn't you send 'em?
I'll start on 'em today,
okay?
No, not okay. We're falling
behind. If you had sent them,
I could've told my mother it was
too late to invite aunt Zelda,
but now she apologized
to my mother
for saying that her brisket
was too tough,
and now we have to invite her.
Fine. She can sit next to
buster Hodges.
Uncle on big daddy's side.
Mama wants to add him.
Where would one find
a buster Hodges?
Oneonta, Alabama.
I'm sure his address
is in my old book.
Here.
Wow. Did that come
with your, uh, trapper keeper
in eighth grade?
Coming from the man who still
has a magic wand collection.
Wh--oh, sweet mother.
Who's this guy?
It's no one.
Whoa.
No one that you kept...
Come on.
In your...
20-year-old address book?
It's Billy.
Ex-husband Billy?
Why'd you keep that?
The man cheated on me.
I hate him for it. End of story.
I just--i don't...
Get why you keep a picture
of somebody you hate.
You seriously want to
discuss this?
You made me throw out pictures
of every girl I ever looked at,
and I did it because I assumed,
if I didn't,
it would make you feel like
I still had feelings for them.
Okay.
Fine.
Hey.
Hi.
You're--you're back.
Yes, last night, late. I'm--
I would've called, but--
no, no, no, no.
I missed you.
I--hey. Yeah.
I missed you, too.
How was, uh,
how was your trip?
It was good.
Yeah, it was good.
Look, Sam, the--
I w--sorry.
You go.
What you asked me before
you left...
I know that you expect
an answer,
and...
I just don't have one yet.
You need to decide.
And in the meantime?
You have a singles table
when you're 25
and still want
to set your friends up.
I'm just saying,
if bubba's coming alone--
his name's buster.
Whatever. If he's coming alone,
and aunt Zelda is coming alone--
are we allowed to bring
a date to your wedding?
No.
Sure.
Yet another advantage
to being married--
not having to fly solo
at your friend's wedding.
Mm. Amen.
Amelia, if there's somebody
that you'd really like to bring,
it's fine.
Sheldon,
are you bringing anyone?
You mean, do I have
someone special
that I really want to bring,
someone I'm happily dating,
perhaps a fellow therapist/
book reviewer?
Unfortunately, no, I don't.
Well, you like southern accents,
don't you, Sheldon?
I'm sure Charlotte has some
friends that you could date.
Yes, and some of them
even have all their teeth.
I swear, Cooper--
hey. Good morning.
Hey, you're back.
How was your trip?
Hey.
It was good. You know,
I managed to safely deliver
the baby of an old friend,
and, yeah,
ended on a high note.
Excuse me, I'm looking
for Dr. Violet Turner.
Uh, I'm Dr. Turner,
but our receptionist
signs for all the packages.
I don't need a signature.
You've just been served.
Have a great day.
"Liability for breach
of confidentiality."
"Recently published book
"violates continued duty
of confidentiality
in regard to plaintiff."
That's crazy.
Who would sue you for that?
The woman who attacked me.
I'm being sued by Katie.
Katie.
The plaintiff is Katie.
"After 18 months
of psychiatric care,
plaintiff
now emotionally stable"--
she attacked Violet
and they let her go?
After only 18 months,
they let her go,
and now she does this?
"Book is inhibiting
the progress
of plaintiff's
continued mental recovery."
Okay, this has gotta be
some kind of joke.
It doesn't sound
very funny to me.
No, it's not funny.
"Seeks immediate cessation
of publication,
marketing, and sales
of aforementioned book."
She's demanding you take
your book off the shelves?
Ugh. I'm sorry. I-I have to
deal with a patient.
Uh, vi, if you need
anything from me, okay?
It's just been so long,
I thought Katie was gone
from my life forever.
Well, they can't seriously think
you have a responsibility
in her recovery
after almost two years.
Of course not.
She's your attacker.
You owe her nothing.
It's not that simple.
Doctors have certain
obligations to their patients
even after they finish
caring for them.
No, those rights disappeared
when she walked into
our living room and--
Pete.
No, she's a criminal!
She should've been put away
for the rest of her life.
I agree. No court is gonna
side with her on this.
This is ridiculous. I'm gonna
get our lawyer on the phone.
Pete. Hang on.
Back off, Sheldon.
Even though Violet changed
Katie's name in the book,
she does still talk about
Katie's personal trauma--
what are you saying?
That anyone who's seen
the local news
or read a paper or uses Google
is gonna know
that Katie's the one that
Violet's been talking about.
Are you siding with Katie?
Of course not, but we have to
consider for a moment
that the doctor-patient
confidentiality
might have been violated.
Violet is not
necessarily innocent here.
I did nothing wrong.
And shame on you
for saying otherwise.
Val. Hey. We didn't have
an appointment today, did we?
Uh, it's not a baby thing.
Dr. Bennett was doing
his routine checkup,
and he noticed my glands were
swollen, so he did a biopsy.
He said
it's probably nothing,
but just in case,
I've made it very clear
who Gary can and cannot marry
the second time around.
There's a list.
Hey, guys. I, uh,
I have val's results.
You want to step
into my office?
That can't be good.
Uh, val has
Burkitt's lymphoma.
That's cancer
of the lymphatic system.
How...
How bad is it?
Well, given that there
was no evidence of it
on her last visit,
it means it is aggressive,
so we should get you
into the hospital right away
and do some more testing.
This can't be happening.
Honey, what do you always
tell me?
Don't borrow trouble.
We can fight this.
So what, surgery?
Well,
with this type of cancer,
surgery and radiation
are not viable options.
Chemo has proven effective,
but cannot be administered
while you're pregnant.
Okay, so i-in a few months--
no, we don't have
that kind of time.
We should deliver the baby
right away.
I'm only at 25 weeks.
I know,
but the baby is viable.
Dr. Bennett,
you don't agree?
Well, if you deliver
your son now,
uh, he's likely to have
serious health problems--
neurological, muscular,
his sight could be impaired--
and that's assuming
that he survives.
He could die?
Yes, but so could you.
Val...
I know that this is
a horrible choice
to have to make, but--
there is no choice.
We can try again.
But right now,
we've gotta worry about you.
No.
Y--
not this time.
After all the miscarriages
and leaving work and bed rest...
We did everything
we were supposed to do--
everything.
We can't start over now.
Maybe we should take some time
and think about this.
No.
I'm carrying this baby
to term.
I choose him...
Even if it kills me.
Sam, we always save
the mother first.
Val is making
the wrong choice here,
and her cancer
is spreading fast.
Maybe, but every day makes
a huge difference to this baby.
Right now
his lungs haven't matured.
His visual and auditory systems
are still developing.
But if we wait
just two weeks,
the chances of him surviving
increase 80%.
In two weeks,
val will be much worse.
She's becoming hypermetabolic,
and the cancer is already
overtaking her system.
Guys, hang on. If this woman
were hemorrhaging
and a split-second decision
needed to be made,
it would be a no-brainer, but in
this case, she's conscious.
I mean, she's aware.
It's her body.
Thank you.
It's her life. If she wants to
give it up for her baby,
that is her choice.
Without intravenous
or intrathecal chemo
administered immediately,
val will die.
Okay. So let me understand.
You're saying that
even though this woman
has explicitly stated the fact
that she wants to have a child,
no matter what the cost--
Sam--
you're suggesting
that we disregard that.
It is not the same.
Well, from my perspective
in this situation,
there's nothing left
to be said.
So I talked to the lawyer.
He thinks Katie
might have a case.
What are you doing?
I'm gonna find every reference
to Katie in the book,
and I'm gonna figure out
if I violated any privilege.
Look, I don't want you to worry
about this. We're gonna fight--
I can handle this, Pete.
Just give a minute
to figure out what the hell...
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
I just never expected this
to happen.
How could you?
I mean, I-I didn't do
anything wrong.
I didn't do anything
to hurt Katie.
And yet...
I think
I should go talk to her.
No. Absolutely not.
She's dangerous.
Maybe we could come
to some kind of understanding.
Oh, for god sake, Violet.
That's why we have
a restraining order
against her in the first place.
Pete, she's not gonna be
the same Katie.
I mean, no,
if they're letting her out,
that means
she's done a lot of work
and she's ready
to reintegrate.
I'm sure she has a therapist
and a drug regimen and...
Violet--
she'll be closer to the Katie
I knew when I worked with her.
Yeah, and look how well
that turned out.
She knows me. Pete, no.
And whatever else has happened,
that doctor-patient dynamic
is still in place,
and that means maybe
I could get through to her.
Let the lawyers handle it.
No, that's just gonna
alienate her even more.
Violet, remember when you told
me to sit down with my mother
and make amends
before she died?
I was not there yet,
but I trusted you.
Please trust me.
No matter what you say to her,
it's not gonna change things.
It's just
gonna make things worse.
I'm telling you,
leave it alone.
How are you feeling?
Better than Gary.
He's usually the calm one.
I need him to be
the calm one.
Give him some time.
I'm not good at that.
Think about what I do--
trading commodities.
It's a frantic business.
It never stops.
I never stopped.
Until Gary made you?
The baby made me.
And Gary, I guess...
Well, he made it possible.
He doesn't want to lose you.
On our first date, he told me
that he was really okay
being with a woman
who had a career,
but that no kids
would be a deal breaker.
I promised him.
I can relate.
Sometimes, wanting a baby,
it's, uh...
Well, it's like
nothing else matters.
But you have to think about
what you two have been through
and that you could die.
Yeah...
I guess I could.
Val, what's going on here?
I want to give Gary
a baby.
And you've tried,
but i--
is Gary pressuring you?
No, no. It's not that.
It's just...
I did something once,
and, uh...
What?
Five and a half years ago,
Gary and I had settled
into being married.
I passed my series 3,
and I was finally
getting a shot
to trade with the big boys.
I was stressed
and I wasn't eating,
so... I wasn't worried when I
missed a couple of periods,
but...
You can't become
one of the guys
and then walk around
with a baby inside you.
You had an abortion.
Did you tell Gary?
I couldn't.
Well, you've gotta
tell him now.
I mean, that was years ago.
He won't understand.
Maybe not at first, but you'll
help him to understand.
Not a lie like this.
I'm not saying it's gonna
be easy, all right?
But what if you don't tell,
if you continue to hide this?
What do you think that'll do
to your relationship? Val?
Val, talk to me.
I need help in here!
Look at me.
Give me your hands. Breathe.
Breathe. Good.
Okay, okay, breathe.
Hey.
Um...
Are you still in love
with Billy?
What?
Your ex-husband,
do you still have feelings
for him or...
He broke my heart, Cooper.
Right.
But you kept his picture until,
you know, this morning. Why?
You really
can't let this go?
Honestly, no. You're dragging
your feet on the wedding,
the invitations still haven't
gone out, and every time
I bring it up, you look at me
like I'm the crazy one.
And now there's this photo.
Look... I found it
a few weeks ago
when we started
the invitations.
I don't know why I kept it.
I just did.
So does he still
mean something to you?
Is that what you think?
All I know is, we're about
to start this life together,
and this feels weird.
So what, y-y-you want
to break up with me?
Maybe call off our wedding?
Of course not.
I just want
to understand this.
It's history.
It's done.
I don't understand. What--
I mean, look at her.
It's called s.V.C. Syndrome.
It's a blockage of the vessels
that drain the neck and head.
It's causing pressure
and lack of oxygen
to those areas.
You could stop breathing.
Is this
because of the cancer?
It is. This is why we need
to start treatment immediately.
After the baby's born.
Please, baby.
I can't lose you.
I need to come home
and hear about your crazy day
with the mouth breathers
at your office.
I need to replant our garden
every year and surprise you.
You need to be a dad.
Not alone. I don't want
to do it alone.
Do something.
Val...
Dr. Montgomery,
don't do this.
You two have a deal, right,
the truth no matter what?
I...
I had an abortion.
When?
I had just started trading,
and I couldn't.
But I could've.
Why would you do that?
I would've stayed home.
I would've done everything.
I'm so sorry.
Please.
You have to forgive me.
I don't--i don't know
if I can.
Am I completely crazy
for doing this?
You really want me
to answer that?
You're a little bit crazy,
but I know you,
and I know you're not gonna
be able to let this go,
and you think you can
help her, so...
That's why
you're my best friend.
Okay. Okay, I'm gonna be sitting
right here watching you,
so if you feel threatened
at all, you give me the sign,
and I'm there.
Bye.
Katie.
Oh, my god. W--
What--
what are you doing here?
You can't--
We need to talk.
No, no, no. My restraining
order--i could get in trouble.
Don't worry.
I came to see you.
That's not
how they'll see it.
You have to go, now.
Please. I just need--
Give me a minute.
Oh.
Um...
Uh...
Despite what you may think,
I always tried to be
a good doctor to you.
I always worked with the goal
of getting you well.
I even kept you out of jail
so that you could get
the treatment that you needed.
Yes, and I will always
be grateful for that.
Then why are you doing this?
Why are you...
Attacking me again?
I'm not attacking you.
I'm standing up for myself.
I spent 18 months
in an institution,
working on my recovery,
dealing with my past
and all the mistakes I made,
and it was hard.
But I did it because I wanted
a future for myself.
And then when I got out,
I-I did all the right things.
I got a therapist,
I got this job.
I-I even met a guy--
Justin...
A really great guy.
He had no idea who I was
or what I had done.
He just cared about me--
this me.
And then...
Justin's sister...
She read your book.
She read your book
and... she put it together.
And she told him,
and he was...
He was gone so fast.
Do you understand
what...
What your book
is doing to me?
It's--it's taking away
my clean start.
I-I changed the name. I tried
to protect your identity.
People read the newspaper,
they watch the news,
they remember what I did.
It's not hard to put together
those stories with the book.
The book is the story
of my life,
of all the things
that happened to me.
And that night, what...
What you did to me,
that is part of it.
How can I write about my life
if I don't write
about that night?
But that's me anymore.
You know that.
I do know that.
So then that book
is our past, right?
Yours and mine.
I need to be looking forward.
As long as that book
is out there, I can't heal.
Charlotte kept a picture
of her ex-husband
who cheated on her,
and I confronted her about it--
ooh, that's unlike you.
She won't tell me why she
kept it, and I'm worried.
She's lied to me before
about this guy.
Am I crazy
to make a thing outta this?
Uh, sit down.
Uh...
Has she had any contact
with her ex-husband
since the divorce?
As far as I know,
they have not talked since
the day she walked out on him,
but, you know,
they moved here together,
and... I looked him up.
He's still here.
He's a mechanic
in north Hollywood.
Well, she might
still care about him.
You think she still
has feelings for this guy?
Yes, yes, but not necessarily
the way you think.
Okay, I don't understand.
Charlotte might be
holding on to that picture
not because she still cares
about her ex,
but because she still cares
about why he cheated on her.
She loved this guy,
and he deceived her.
And no matter how much people
tell her it wasn't her fault,
somewhere deep down,
Charlotte probably wonders,
if on some level
it was her fault,
if she did something
to push the guy away or...
So how does she
get past it?
Well, either she confronts him
and tries to understand--
that's never gonna happen.
Or she lives with it.
People live with all kinds
of frustrations, Cooper.
You know, believe me.
Uh, if this is
a violet/marla thing--
Violet plays it down,
acts like it's nothing.
But it's not nothing, Cooper.
It's something to me.
And to spitefully suggest
that a woman like Marla
can be swapped out
for a friend of Charlotte's--
I mean, no offense--
when I'm in love...
You're in love with Marla?
Maybe, but the point is,
I'll never know.
This whole "living
with frustration" thing,
maybe it's not
such a good idea.
Yeah.
Excuse me.
Do you know where I could find,
uh, Billy Douglas?
Right over there.
Tall guy.
Uh, name tag says "Billy."
Hey, uh, Billy Douglas?
What can I do for you?
Uh, I'm Cooper Freedman,
and this may sound strange,
but I'm engaged
to Charlotte king.
And I need to talk to you.
Why did you push her?
I didn't push her.
Yes, Addison, you did.
She was a wreck. The secret
was eating away at her.
She was willing to risk her life
to make it right with Gary.
I thought
he'd at least listen.
Well, he did listen.
Yeah, right before
he walked out the door.
Val lied to him.
Val made a choice.
A unilateral choice. She didn't
discuss it with her husband.
She didn't even tell him
what she was doing.
She just--she just did it
and expected him to say
it was okay.
But when--when you're in love
with someone, Addison,
when you're
in a real relationship,
you don't do that.
Our relationship is real.
Sam, I love you.
Then why did you give me
an ultimatum?
We discussed it.
We did not discuss.
You said, either we have
a baby or we end it.
That's not a discussion.
I can't date Marla
if Violet hates her.
Why not?
It'll create work stress
and personal stress,
and people will be,
well, unhappy.
Violet will be unhappy,
just like you are now.
Yeah, well--
yeah, well, what? How much
do you like this woman?
Well, given the short amount
of time I've spent with her,
it's a lot.
And how much do you think
Violet cares about
Marla's review of her book?
Honestly? A lot.
How much should she care?
Not much.
Well, then tell Violet.
The problem is not
gonna fix itself, Sheldon.
If it's bothering you
this much...
♪♪♪
Ha. Spying on
the boy next door?
No. I--no. I was, uh--
spying on the boy next door.
I get it... if you and Sam
were in the sixth grade.
Why don't you
just go talk to him?
And say what, sorry I forced you
to choose between having a baby
you may not want to have
or losing me,
but, you know, tick tock, Sam?
Well, are you really sorry,
Addie?
I love Sam.
I want things to work out.
Well, as much as you want
a baby?
I don't want
to have to choose.
So that's why
you're making him do it.
♪ My soul ♪
♪ and the sail needs the wind ♪
♪ 'cause I get so lost ♪
Oh. He's finally asleep.
Whew.
Oh.
Violet, again? Why are you
doing this to yourself?
Well, I may have to accept
some culpability in all this.
I don't know, maybe I-I should
pull the books from the shelf.
Look, the book
helped you heal.
And who knows how many
other people it will help?
Maybe not everybody,
but taking it off the shelf
is not the answer.
According to Katie,
it didn't help her heal.
I'm sorry.
I-I know you didn't
want me to go see her.
You're doing it again,
exactly what you did
during Katie's trial--
look where that got us.
Well, I had to try something.
So irresponsible of you to put
yourself in jeopardy like that.
Do you remember that I found you
bleeding on the floor?
You have me to think about.
You have Lucas to think about.
Katie was fine.
She was better than fine.
She has her life together.
She was--she was doing well.
How can you still
have sympathy for her?
Because she's my patient.
Because she will always be
my patient.
And turning my back on her now
makes me a hypocrite.
She is not your patient!
She stopped being your patient
when she cut out our son
and left you to die.
You can't fix her.
No matter how hard you try,
you cannot fix everyone, Violet.
The sooner you accept that,
the better off we'll all be.
♪♪♪
You busy?
Yeah.
Oh, that's too bad,
because there's someone here
that wants to speak with you.
Hey, Charlie.
Hey.
You been here all night?
I don't know
what to say to her,
but...
I couldn't leave her
either.
You know, val told me
that you wouldn't forgive her,
and I thought...
I don't know.
People come to us all the time,
wanting to have a baby
because they think it'll fix
what's wrong in their marriage
or fill the void
in their lives,
but... with you guys,
the love is there.
I mean,
it's always been there, right?
Val made a mistake.
She works
with a bunch of jerks.
And every day she comes home,
and I cook dinner,
and she tells me
what they've done,
and I give her perspective.
Usually I say...
"It's not cancer"
or "at least
you're not married to them."
And she laughs.
And she relaxes.
It's hard to explain,
but when val and I
are together...
We just fit.
And I used to think
that meant...
That we could
overcome anything.
Now...
I don't know.
Gary, val is willing
to give up her life
to make things right
with you.
What are you willing to do?
You should know
that even though it was hard
for me to stop seeing Marla,
I did it because of
my friendship with you.
And I realize now that if
we were really friends,
you never would've asked me
to stop seeing her
in the first place.
Mm-hmm.
You would've set aside
your grievance--
even though I understand it--
when weighed against my personal
happiness, would seem petty.
I'm the one that got hurt here,
not you.
And I think it's high time
that you recognize it.
You finished?
Yes.
Okay. Well,
here's how I see it--
if you were
a really good friend,
you wouldn't make this
an issue right now.
Out of all the women
in the world,
you wouldn't have chosen
the one--
the only one, I might add--
who essentially
assassinated me in print.
You would've said,
"Marla thompkins, dead to me,"
and that would've been it,
because that's what
good friends do.
Then I guess the only thing
we can agree on
is that
we shouldn't be friends.
Your boyfriend's brave.
He's my fiancé.
And, yeah, he is.
But believe me when I say,
I did not ask him
to do this.
I know...
We kinda just left things--
you cheated on me, Billy,
six months into something
that was supposed to be forever.
Shame on me for not realizing
that "working late"
meant working on some girl
called Trixie.
Tiffany.
Her name was Tiffany.
I don't give a damn
what her name was.
She wasn't your wife.
I know this isn't gonna
make you feel any better,
but I didn't sleep with her
because I didn't love you.
You're right.
That doesn't make me
feel better.
Look...
When we first moved out here,
I didn't have a very good sense
of who I was.
But now I do.
Good for you.
I'm gay, Charlotte.
Get out.
You're mad that I'm gay?
I'm mad that you're
a liar and a cheat.
Turn around,
walk your ass outta my office,
and don't you ever
come back.
You should not have
brought him here!
Before you say anything,
I was trying to help you.
I don't need
that kind of help.
Yeah, you do.
He hurt you, Charlotte,
and you never knew why,
and that created anxiety.
You felt it. I felt it.
And now you know.
You know it was nothing
you did to push him away.
There's nothing wrong with you.
This is good, Charlotte.
This is closure.
I wish it were
that easy, Cooper.
We're doing the c-section?
Yes.
So you convinced val?
I didn't.
What did you say
to talk him into it?
I told him that unless
he wanted to risk losing her,
he had to say something.
What if he said no?
He wasn't going to.
He loves her.
Did you take her?
I do not want her
anywhere near that woman.
It's Violet's decision.
You put her in danger!
We both know that she was
gonna go no matter what, okay?
We both know that.
At least I was with her.
We're on--
we're on the same side here.
Okay? The last thing
Violet needs right now
is the two of us fighting.
The truth is,
I'm angrier at her than you.
She does what she wants
when she wants.
Hey,
that's what makes her Violet.
Hey.
What happened with cancer mom
and her preemie?
Uh, Addison did the c-section.
Mom's okay.
And baby?
Uh, we'll see.
You know, no matter what is
happening with you and Addison,
it doesn't have to be awkward
between you and me.
Oh, yeah, well, uh,
I-I just got
a lot on my mind.
More than just Addison?
Amelia, please.
Sorry. Forget I asked.
She gave the ultimatum,
you know,
not me.
I know that.
The fact that we are whatever
we are right now is on her.
Until you answer.
She didn't have to do it
like this.
Maybe not,
but she knows what she wants.
I mean, do you?
Not yet.
Do you think
maybe that's your answer?
Mr. Douglas.
You've always had a temper.
Yeah, well...
It wasn't my idea
to come see ya.
But your guy Cooper...
Can be very persistent.
I know that.
Why didn't you just
tell me you were gay?
I was confused.
I thought that...
I wondered if the problem
was you.
That's what Tiffany
was about,
trying to see
if I felt different
with another woman.
I didn't.
You realize,
that doesn't make it okay.
The fact that you never
told me...
Yeah.
I didn't mean to hurt you.
I-I know that sounds stupid,
but it was nothing you did.
You...
Are an amazing woman.
Was I kidding myself
to think you'd feel relieved?
It's just, uh...
Back then...
You were the right choice...
The perfect guy.
My parents loved you,
my friends loved you...
I loved you.
And now knowing...
That I fell in love
with a man
who could never love me back...
Not the way I needed--
I never thought of myself
as a woman
who makes bad choices.
Is that what this is about?
You feel like an idiot?
You couldn't have known.
Hell, I didn't know.
But this time...
Don't you think
you got it right?
I'm risking everything
coming here.
Oh!
Katie, what are you...
I know you didn't write
the book to hurt me.
You needed to heal, too,
and--
Katie, you shouldn't
be here.
Oh, but it's okay for you
to come to my work?
What I did to you...
It was wrong, and I know
I can never make it right.
It's with me all the time.
It's--it's like...
It's like this wound
that never heals,
no matter how hard I try.
I relive it in my sleep.
I agonize
over it when I'm away.
- I forgive you.
- That's just it.
I can never forgive myself.
Well, it--it'll...
It'll just take some time.
I've caused you
so much pain.
All my problems...
It was wrong for me
to take them out on you.
I'm sorry.
I'm--I'm really so sorry.
Hey.
I let my own insecurities get
in the way of your happiness,
and that was wrong.
I mean, it's my problem,
and I-I shouldn't have
taken it out on you, so i'm...
Sorry.
And if you like Marla,
you should go for it,
with my blessing.
How many chances do we get
at love, right?
♪♪♪
♪ there you are
on the crowded street ♪
♪ so far ahead of me ♪
♪ how I want it just to be ♪
You got some time?
Uh, I'm supposed to go to a peds
meeting at the hospital.
Yeah, I rescheduled that.
♪♪♪
I really want to get
these invitations out.
♪ ...closer in, each step ♪
What is going on?
You came home late.
You left early.
I just needed
some time to think.
Are you not
mad at me anymore?
Depends.
Are you prepared to lick?
Sure thing, Charlie.
♪ There was nothing... ♪
You call me that again,
you will be hobbling
down that aisle.
Ow!
♪ 'Cause you stole ♪
♪ my heart ♪
♪ away ♪
Violet.
Katie dropped the lawsuit.
Our lawyer just called.
He doesn't know why.
She just dropped it.
I knew I could
get through to her.
But I'm still so, so worried
about her, Pete.
I wish there was
more I could do.
She needs help. She--
there's more.
Katie dropped the lawsuit,
but not before her lawyer
filed a complaint
with the medical board.
They've launched
an investigation into whether
or not to suspend your license.
♪ Then for just
one split moment in time ♪
Hey.
♪ By my side ♪
♪ but I drifted off in mind ♪
♪ to my... ♪
Look, I realize
that I'm asking you
for everything, Sam.
But I feel like if I don't
ask for what I want,
then what's the point?
I want you
and I want a baby.
I want you and a baby.
I just... I do.
I know.
And?
I have that.
I have you and Maya
and Olivia--
well, then you can understand
why I would want that, too.
Th-there's no way that...
You can't compromise?
Look, we can't just take
a little bit more time
and--and figure this out
as we go?
No, my mother killed herself,
Sam.
No, she spent her entire life
never being who she really was,
never saying out loud,
"this is who I am,
and this is what I want,"
and then when she finally did
get the courage up to go for it,
it was too late.
She waited too long.
Sam...
I... have already waited
too long.
You know, first it was "wait
until you meet the right guy,"
and then I met Derek,
and then I told myself,
"Addison, be smart. Wait until
you finish med school,"
then "wait until you finish
your residency,"
and then "wait until you finish
your fellowship,"
and my marriage exploded,
and then I had an affair,
and then it was,
"oh, no, not now.
You can't have Mark's baby.
That would be unseemly."
And I waited and waited
and waited
until I only had
one egg left.
I mean, it's not
that I didn't want kids.
It's because I took
having kids for granted,
because a 13-year-old girl
can do it,
because a 75-year-old man
can do it.
You know who can't do it?
An overeducated, talented,
strong, powerful woman
in her 40s.
How ridiculous is that?
How mad am I at my body?
I waited too long. Okay?
And now it's time.
I have a clock
inside of me, Sam.
It's not just ticking.
The alarm is going off.
It's screaming. It's time.
I can't wait. Not anymore.
♪ Breathingwithout my lung ♪
I'm sorry. I...
I know that was a lot,
but, uh, you understand?
Do you get it?
♪ ...of you ♪
Yeah.
Okay.
Are we breaking up?
♪ Pieces of you ♪