I made you blueberry pancakes.
Would you prefer cauliflower?
Nope. Shaun, that's our baby.
I'm 36 weeks.
The baby is the size of
a head of cauliflower.
Our baby will not be this bumpy.
I am very... happy.
Me, too.
We're having a baby,
I have an amazing job,
you're an attending.
We have a new family car.
Dr. Glassman has
moved down the hall.
Jared is coming back to
work at the hospital.
It is great that he's back.
But, you know, the dynamic
might be a little different.
Research has shown that
when working with friends,
you get more done in less
time and have fun on the job.
But Jared will be working
for you, not with you.
It can be different when
you have to manage a friend.
Lines can get blurred,
and that can be hard.
The lines are not blurred.
They are very clear.
♪ This is a world premiere ♪
Hey, there, Loverboy.
Give me the details.
Are you and Jerome
exchanging keys,
or are you getting a
whole-new place together?
Yeah, no. He did not
ask me to move in.
Then what did he want
to talk to you about?
I... I don't want
to talk about it.
Okay, now I want
to know even more,
and my interrogation
will continue until...
You going to the club or work?
Yeah, these early calls are
gonna take some getting used to.
Hmm. A little Kendrick's
the perfect pick-me-up.
Never mad at Kendrick.
Yes. Nice shirt.
Tom Ford?
Yeah, my good luck charm.
Figured it couldn't hurt
on my first day back.
For $700, it should
give you more than luck.
On occasion, it has.
See you guys in
there.
♪ But it can do what it
want whenever it want ♪
The car is a bit much,
but the fashion is lit.
Now, Mr. Grumpy, what's
going on with you?
Goodbye.
Dr. Kalu is not your
peer, not your friend.
He is your employee
and you are his boss.
I am confident that
Jared will do a good job.
That's exactly what
I'm talking about.
He is not "Jared."
He is "Dr. Kalu."
I do not always call people
by their professional titles.
Sometimes I call
Dr. Allen... Dr. Murphy.
An informal communication
style with Dr. Kalu can create
a perception of special
treatment and favoritism.
I do not plan to give
Jared special treatment.
That doesn't mean Dr. Kalu
isn't expecting it.
And if I see it, it won't
be good for either of you.
She has bruising and pain even
with passive range of motion.
Some bullies at
school chased her.
She fell down the stairs
trying to get away.
That's not even how it happened.
I knew we should have
stuck with homeschooling.
She insisted, and look
what happened.
You need to be still.
Your shoulder is fractured.
Ultrasound the patient.
Why are you laughing?
Sh-She can't help it.
Yara has Tourette syndrome.
It's why she got into
the fight at school.
Mom, he was asking me.
You never let me
speak for myself.
It wasn't a fight.
Some kids thought it would be
funny to point and stare at me,
and I thought it would be
funny to egg their lockers.
Then my stupid tics
messed up my getaway.
There's significant
tissue swelling
and massive hematoma at
the proximal humerus.
The fracture has caused an
acute compartment syndrome.
You need surgery right away.
- Captions by VITAC...
What were you doing when
you started getting dizzy?
I was sitting in gym class,
and then the room
started to spin.
And then I threw up.
But I wasn't doing it.
I just introduced Carter
to the Wonder Woman comics.
He's been trying
to learn the twirl.
I don't blame you.
The twirl is awesome.
Where's my little guy?
Hey, Mama E.
Hey, Carter G.
You should have
called me immediately.
Elaine's my mom.
And I don't need your permission
to bring my son to the hospital.
Actually, you do.
I'm his legal guardian.
What's wrong with him?
Uh, his heart rate
is... is quite low.
What does that mean?
It looks like Carter
has an abnormality
of the electrical signals
controlling his heartbeat.
We need to run some tests.
Echo and
electrophysiology study.
The prodigal resident returns.
Aha. Lovely to see you
as well, Dr. Reznick.
Will the hospital be
getting a new wing
in the Kalu family name?
My family are doing
well. Thanks for asking.
And I was recruited to
return based on my training,
breadth of experience,
and willingness to take a
demotion back to a first year.
Ooh, it's gonna be hellish
being bossed around by newbies
and people who used
to be your peers.
Grab me that box
on the top shelf.
I missed you, too.
You know, while I was away,
I learned how to read
emotional energy.
And sniping at people's
your love language.
Happy to know you still care.
Good luck, newbie.
Thanks.
I, uh... I gotta get to surgery.
Enjoy.
Your control of
the shaft segment
is very precise.
Thank you.
Brown retractor.
No brown retractor.
I thought I put it on your
tray from the supply room.
All of my tools must be
individually selected,
sterilized, and
placed in my tray
before I begin the surgery.
Understood. Got it.
That will do.
Further expose the
proximal humerus.
Place sutures in rotator cuff
to mobilize humeral head.
Sorry for dropping the
ball with your tools.
Rookie mistake.
Don't sweat it.
You're BFFs with
the boss, right?
I treat every resident the same.
Dr. Allen, place
Steinmann pins
proximal to biceps tendon.
Dr. Kalu, you are on suction.
Oh.
Catheter placed in
the axillary vein.
I feel bad for Carter's mom.
I can't imagine
trying to raise a kid
with my mother backseat
driving my every move.
Well, maybe if
Bianca told Elaine
that she was taking
Carter to the hospital,
she would trust her more.
Pacing wire.
Bianca was probably doing
what she thought was best.
Withholding information
is never for the best.
Advancing to the
right ventricle.
Everything okay between you two?
We're... fine.
That can't be right.
I need contrast to clear up
what I'm seeing on fluoroscopy.
L-transposition of
the great arteries.
The ventricles are...
inverted.
His heart is... backward.
Your surgery went well.
We were able to
decompress and release
your compartment syndrome
and stabilize your
humerus fracture.
Great. When can I
go back to school?
You'll only be out a few days.
Just be sure to wear your sling.
You're not going back to school.
Why not? It's not safe.
I'm not sending you back
so they can hurt you again.
I'm not a baby. I can
take care of myself.
I just need to take your vitals.
If you could take
care of yourself,
we wouldn't have ended
up in the hospital.
Going to school is
literally the only thing
that I do that is normal.
I don't want to be...
I don't want to be
stuck at home with you.
You never let me do
anything by mys...
Yara?
She's having a seizure.
We need 2 milligrams of
lorazepam and MRI, stat!
She's sleeping like a baby.
You should've used
propofol instead of Versed
to sedate her.
Versed is old school.
Same effects, none
of the overshooting.
Why are you changing
my settings?
Peds case.
Shorter duration
imaging sequences
cuts the time in half.
It's your first day, remember?
You could probably
use a refresher
before trying a shortcut.
I'm a little out of practice,
but I've still got a
few tricks up my sleeve.
Says the guy who has
to repeat a year.
Ow. Mm-hmm.
Shaun will appreciate getting
Yara's results back faster.
Trust me.
You know him better than me.
Was the patient properly sedated
before you began this MRI?
Yeah, of course. I used the standard
pediatric protocol with Versed.
Did Dr. Allen tell
you about our revised
Propofol protocol?
Yeah. But in my experience,
Versed provides better...
You should have
listened to Dr. Allen.
I know how to perform
an MRI, Shaun.
You apparently do not.
There is too much
motion degradation.
These images are unusable.
Dr. Allen, please
go redo the MRI.
Dr. Kalu, we need
to speak privately.
You cannot take shortcuts.
You're right. I'm sorry.
You cannot expect
special treatment
because you are my friend.
I'm not expecting
special treatment, Shaun.
But I don't appreciate being
treated like an intern, either.
I know, technically,
I'm a first year,
but I've been a doctor
for as long as you have.
We are not peers.
I am your boss, and you
have a lot to learn.
Dr. Andrews said he is
judging my performance
off of your performance,
and your performance
is not good.
Okay?
Okay.
Good.
You need to go
practice basic skills
and observe our current
standardized MRI process.
Heart block plus
inverted cardiac anatomy.
What's your plan?
Intravenous pacemaker is out,
but we could open him
up, place it surgically.
That doesn't address
the underlying anatomy issue.
The defect could lead to heart
failure as he gets older.
It could, but he might be
fine with just the pacemaker.
But if he's already developed
arrhythmia, not a great sign.
I'd recommend the double
switch reconstruction,
redirect blood flow to
the right ventricle.
I have Carter's BMP
and cardiac labs.
Yeah, I already
received them digitally.
But the hard copies
are always appreciated.
Trouble in paradise?
Everything's fine.
They've been in this passive-
aggressive fight all day.
We're not fighting.
No, that would require
you talking to me.
You don't have to share, but
you do have two divorcees
with a sadly ample amount
of experience between us.
Was one of you secretly
in contact with an ex?
Took a job out of state without
including you in the process?
Jerome lied to me, about
something very important.
I didn't lie. A lie of
omission is still a lie.
It's not that simple.
You should have told me.
I wanted to. Yes,
but you didn't.
Because I was afraid
of how you'd react.
But you're right.
It should never
have been a secret,
because there's nothing to hide.
I'm HIV positive.
Thanks to my meds, my viral load
has been undetectable for years.
I'm poz undetectable.
I can't transmit the virus.
You should go talk to him.
I have work to do.
Present the double switch
surgery to the family.
If they agree, I'll scrub in.
On it.
No. How did we get
from a pacemaker
to reconstructing his heart?
The procedure may sound drastic,
but it will greatly reduce
his risk of developing
heart failure.
Can't we just give
him the pacemaker now,
and do the bigger surgery
if the problem gets worse?
At the point he starts showing
signs of heart failure,
it'll be too late to
do the reconstruction.
We should fix it now.
This isn't your decision.
You are still making me
pay for mistakes I made
when I was 17.
And 18, 19, 20...
I've been back for two years.
How can I be a mother when you
won't even give me a chance?
Mama?
Mama E?
I don't feel good.
It's okay, baby. I'm here.
Honey, what's wrong?
My chest hurts.
The heart rate's 40 BPM.
BP 73/45.
We need a decision soon before
his condition deteriorates.
I wanted to apologize
for earlier.
It was unprofessional.
You have nothing
to apologize for,
and no duty to disclose.
Undetectable equals
untransmittable.
I appreciate
you saying that.
Give Asher some time.
He's a doctor.
He knows there was
never any risk to him.
What people know and
how it makes them feel
are often two very
different things.
You've had years to
process your status.
Allow Asher to process it, too.
Please do not say,
"I told you so."
I won't.
But I'm gonna think it.
You seem a little spoiled.
You don't know me.
You come from money,
and you haven't had to
work hard for anything.
You made it through med
school. Bravo to that.
You got kicked out
of this program,
but landed on your feet
taking care of a billionaire.
And when you got tired of that,
you were welcomed back
here with open arms.
You come in with your fancy car
and your old tricks, and think,
"Ta-da, I'm a surgeon,"
but you're not... yet.
You're the new kid.
Shaun is the boss,
and I have seniority.
You should listen to Kendrick.
Be humble.
I just want to prove
that I belong here.
To Shaun, to everyone.
But you're right.
I know.
The image is still not
high enough resolution.
Have you finished
redoing the imaging?
Yes, and I followed
all the protocols,
but the image still
doesn't look clear.
The image is clear,
but Yara's diagnosis
was incorrect.
She does not have Tourette's.
She has a brain tumor.
I don't have Tourette's?
No, you have a
hypothalamic hamartoma.
Your tics aren't tics.
They are gelastic seizures
caused by the tumor
in your brain.
Tumor? Does that mean cancer?
The tumor is not cancerous.
But a Gamma Knife radiosurgery
should stop it from growing
and treat the seizures.
Will it stop this?
Not immediately.
And possibly not at all.
There are other options you
can consider in the future
if you don't see improvement.
Or we could consider them now.
A successful resection
could stop the
seizures immediately.
That procedure is very risky.
But that means I can
go back to school.
I could learn how to drive.
I could take care of myself.
Mommy, please.
I just want to be normal.
Tumor resection can cause
stroke, partial paralysis,
learning deficits, meningitis.
The Gamma Knife is much safer.
Yara, I'm sorry. I can't.
You can.
You just won't let me.
Please go ahead
and schedule the
Gamma Knife procedure.
Have you made a decision?
I'm afraid of exposing
Carter to any more trauma.
What trauma?
He was left by his mother.
I left him with you.
Expecting me to pick
up all the pieces
and fix everything, like always.
I knew he was safer
with you than with me.
But I didn't know that.
I gave you too much freedom,
wasn't involved enough,
and look what happened.
My mistakes were
mine, not yours.
I was supposed to protect you.
And we lost you.
I have to do better for Carter.
Well, the surgery is
what's best for Carter,
long-term.
That kid is my heart.
I'm gonna trust you to fix his.
Lunchtime!
I'm starved. I am not hungry.
Well, it's not good to deprive
your pregnant wife her lunch.
I thought it would be fun
working with a friend.
It is not fun.
It is difficult.
I do not want people to think
I am giving Dr. Kalu
special treatment,
because I am not giving
him special treatment.
In fact, I am being very firm
because he has already
made several errors,
and I do not understand why.
Well, he's a new resident
on his first day.
There has to be a bit
of a learning curve.
Mm, he is not acting
like a new resident.
Well, he's your friend.
And he knows you
expect a lot of him.
No one can follow the rules
if they don't know
what they are.
Atrial septum excised.
Starting venous reconstruction.
There may not be enough
tissue for redirection of flow
to the tricuspid valve.
We can use pericardium
to create a baffle.
Metz.
You make up with Jerome yet?
He betrayed my trust.
Alright, securing
edge to atrial septum.
You've never hidden
anything from him?
I'd never hide
something like this.
Congratulations. You
win the virtue contest.
Possible prizes include the
end of your relationship.
Or you could just talk it out.
Dividing the aorta.
He is the one who
changed things.
I mean, why is it
on me to figure out?
The question is, do
you love Jerome enough
to change with him?
Suturing distal aorta
to pulmonary valve.
Coronary arteries are patent.
Anastomosis looks great.
I never met a teenager
who wanted to go to school
as much as you.
I hate school.
But I hate not being
able to control
anything in my life even more.
Egging those lockers
made you feel in control?
Kinda. Hmm.
Those bullies messed with
me, I messed with them back.
Like normal kids do.
I was bullied a lot
in high school, too.
I was scrawny with
braces, a lisp...
Basically a target on my back.
But my mom helped me.
Gave me her credit
card to buy them off
with pizza and candy.
My mom is too helpful.
She won't even let
me make my own PB&J.
She thinks I'll tic out and
hurt myself with the knife.
When my body isn't
controlling me, she is.
When you said you can cut
this tumor out of my head,
for 30 seconds...
I could imagine only laughing
when something was funny.
Think I found a solution.
Oh. I have found a
solution, as well.
I have made a list of
boundaries and rules
to make our working
relationship better.
You need to study them.
What have you found
a solution for?
I think I found a better
resection technique.
Has a lower risk profile,
closer to that of the
Gamma Knife radiation.
And it offers a better
outcome for Yara.
I presented the safest
option to the patient,
which she agreed to.
And you should not have
presented the tumor resection
without consulting me.
That is an important boundary.
Number two on the list.
I thought you'd be happy I
was thinking outside the box,
like you.
You are not me.
You are here to learn. Yes.
I'm also here to help
people like Yara.
You need to respect that
I am your attending.
Number six on the list. I
don't have to be an attending
to know that she's sad,
lonely, and depressed.
We cannot make medical decisions
based off of the
patient's emotions.
Well, sometimes the emotions
are just as important
as the medical.
You are making my job very hard!
Number 10...
At work, follow my
instructions precisely.
If you cannot comply, you
will be out of the program.
I really messed up.
I should have trusted you
and been upfront
about everything.
Yeah, you should have.
After my diagnosis, it
took a long time for me
to feel comfortable dating,
or even being around people.
I spent so much time alone,
and when I finally put
myself back out there,
there was a lot of rejection.
Guys just didn't want
to deal with my status.
So, when this adorable,
brilliant doctor
popped into my life,
and I liked him so much...
I was too scared to
tell him the truth.
I'm sorry.
This doctor sounds pretty great.
He is.
I made sure we always
used protection,
encouraged you to stay on PrEP.
All to make sure
that you were safe.
That was a decision that
you made for the both of us.
You did all those things to
make yourself feel better
while you took away my choice.
How could you have
known me and loved me
and think that this
is something that
I-I couldn't accept?
When I first had to
make this decision,
I didn't love you.
I barely knew you.
And I'm not sure I know you now.
I made a mistake.
That doesn't change who I am.
No, but maybe it
changes how I feel.
I'm sorry that I put
you through this,
but I'm still the one
living with this disease,
and it's not easy.
It's Carter.
I have to go.
He woke up
from the surgery,
and he was laughing
about his comic book,
then he started to turn blue.
Oxygen saturation
at 80%. 120 BPM.
Blood pressure's dropping.
Alright, administering oxygen
and 250cc normal saline bolus.
Why can't he breathe?
I thought the surgery was
supposed to prevent this.
Normal lead impedance.
The pacemaker is
functioning properly.
Something else is going on.
We need a cardiac echo, stat.
A kink in Carter's
reconstructed atria
caused the clot in his heart.
He's stable, but he
needs another operation
to remove the clot and
repair the conduit.
Are there other alternatives?
We could use a catheter
to dissolve the blockage
with medication,
but that still leaves the risk
of a clot forming
again down the line.
I knew doing this was
the wrong decision.
We both want what's
best for Carter.
But I'm the one who is
responsible for him.
And I'm sorry I put that on you.
I will never forgive
myself for losing out on
those years of Carter's life,
but I've realized that I need
to try to let go of that.
Let go of my regret and
focus on what I know...
That leaving him with you was
the best decision for him.
That will never change.
And this surgery is the
right decision for him, too.
You're his mother.
You know what's best for Carter.
I want my son to
have the surgery.
You were right.
I usually am.
What was I right about, exactly?
I came out of the gate too hot,
annoyed Shaun,
screwed things up for Yara.
Agree.
I gotta figure out my next move.
Listen.
This whole case,
you've been pitching
and shortcutting
and trying to be
Mr. Fix-it for everything.
Stop flexing and listen.
Mom, let me try the
tumor resection surgery.
Please. I'm sorry. No.
We're ready for you.
Alright, baby.
But first, I, um...
want you to tell your
mom what you told me,
about what you're dealing with.
What this surgery means to you.
I know what she's dealing with.
I see it every day.
But have you listened
to how it feels to her?
She doesn't care.
Of course I do.
You just want to boss me around.
I'm just trying to help,
but no matter what I do,
you're always so angry at me.
I'm angry...
I'm angry at everything.
I'm angry at my body for not
doing what I want it to do.
I'm angry at other
kids for being jerks.
And I'm angry at you...
for acting like the only way
for me to survive in this world
is by you protecting me.
I feel like I'm a puppet
and somebody else is
constantly pulling the strings,
yanking me all around.
Getting this tumor removed
is the only way for
me to cut the strings.
Okay, don't... don't...
Don't take her yet.
We need to talk.
I need you to scrub in
on a hypothalamic
hamartoma surgery.
Okay. I had planned to
use Gamma Knife radiation,
but Dr. Kalu violated
rule number two,
and now we have to do
his tumor resection.
You're upset with Jared
because he changed
your surgical plan?
He overstepped with me
and the patient and her mother.
Well, a tumor resection seems
like a pretty good idea.
Are you planning on
letting Jared scrub in?
Yes, he will be on suction.
That's an insult.
He has to learn to follow rules.
He has made my job
very difficult.
Shaun, sit down.
When you were a resident,
you did things
completely your own way.
You still do.
You rubbed everybody
the wrong way.
You made everybody's job more
difficult, especially mine.
You were a pain in the ass.
But we gave you
the space to learn,
and we learned from you.
And you turned
yourself into an asset.
Give Jared the same opportunity.
Okay, he overstepped.
Give him a chance to learn
and to prove himself
to be an asset.
Even if you think he's
a pain in the ass.
I will take it
into consideration.
Okay.
Please scrub in
for that surgery.
Advance the catheter
and endoscope
gently into the ventricle.
Suction and irrigate
more aggressively
so she can see
what she is doing.
Proceed along the midline
posteroinferior floor
of the third ventricle.
Oh, there's the tumor.
We can begin excision.
Bipolar scissors.
Micro forceps.
I'll take the
specimen to pathology.
No.
You are going to close.
Are you sure?
This was your surgical plan.
You will become a better surgeon
by getting a fair
shot to be an asset.
I will take the specimen.
Dr. Glassman will supervise.
I'm hungry.
That's a very good sign.
I'll run down to the café
and grab him some food.
Any restrictions? He can have as
many chicken nuggets as he wants.
I'll go down.
I'll get something
for you to eat, too.
You haven't left his
side since we got here.
Comes with being a good mom.
I had a great teacher.
You know, a little birdie
told me that the gift shop
just got in the latest
volume of Wonder Woman.
Really? Can we get it?
If your mom is okay with it.
Of course.
But no twirling just yet, okay?
Dr. Murphy was able to
remove all of the tumor.
Yara?
Dr. Kalu.
Memory is intact.
The light didn't
provoke a seizure.
And your tics are gone.
Thank you, Dr. Kalu.
Thank you, Yara.
Dr. Andrews.
I heard about your work
on the Fields case.
Good job. Thank you.
I just came in to
ask you for a favor.
Please judge me for my
work, and not Shaun.
Shaun's part of the
reason you're back here.
And I appreciate him for that.
But I want to stand on my own.
And if I sink, I don't want to
take my friend down with me.
I'm ready to prove myself as
an asset to this hospital.
I'll be watching.
Thank you.
I'm sorry for being such a jerk.
You opened yourself
up, and I shut down.
And I should've trusted you
that we could figure
this out together.
Yesterday, you said
you didn't know me.
That adorable doctor can be
kind of an ass sometimes.
I've never been in
love before you.
When I was 16, I'm pretty
sure I ran over a raccoon,
but I didn't stop to check
because I was running late
to a baseball game.
Also...
I love a pumpkin spice latte.
Agh.
Even though I know it's basic.
You know those cufflinks I wore
to Shaun and Lea's wedding?
Yeah.
I bought them for you,
but I liked them so much,
I kept them for myself.
That explains so much.
But you can totally
borrow them...
sometime, probably
not.
I love you.
I need you to believe that.
Just, uh, came to say goodnight.
And thank you.
Why are you thanking me?
For not going easy on me.
I was wrong to expect that,
even if we are friends.
You are a good doctor.
And I would like to
continue to be your friend
and your boss...
with boundaries.
You're right.
And I'm studying your list.
Oh, there is one rule
that is not on the list.
It is a rule for me.
I will refer to
you as "Dr. Kalu"
when I am being your boss
and as "Jared" when
we are in friend mode.
Yeah, that works for me, Shaun.
Good.
Jared, I would like to
take you out for drinks
to celebrate you being
back at St. Bon's,
but Dr. Kalu,
when I checked on
Yara postoperatively,
I noticed you only used
eight sutures when you closed
and she had a small bleed.
You should have used 10.
You need to go work on
your suturing technique.
Happy to... to practice,
but I only replaced
the small bone flap.
Dr. Glassman closed
the galea and skin.
Dr. Glassman
skipped two sutures?
I guess so.
Um, meet you for
drinks in an hour?
Okay. Okay.