Previously on ER:
Oh, uh, Dr. Kovack,
I'm Eve Peyton.
- Our new nurse manager.
- It's Kovac.
You can educate the nurses
about inferior alveolar dental blocks.
What?
Is there some sort of history
between you and Dr. Kovac?
It's not appropriate for
you two to work together.
That's two less than
I'm already doing,
which I can't afford.
I'll never see my kid.
One thousand, two thousand,
three thousand, four thousand...
- What are you doing?
- Five... I'm counting.
Yes. That part, I get.
The time between the
lightning and the thunder...
tells you how far
away the storm is.
- Getting closer.
- That's great.
You're going outside?
Yep, drew the short
straw for the coffee run.
Where are you going?
We're getting slammed here.
I'm not on for six minutes.
I'm going out for coffee.
Then be a Flower Drum
Song and grab me a bear claw.
Hi, I'm Dr. Morris, chief resident.
What brings you here today?
- Some guy rear-ended me.
- Ew. Ouch.
- I hope you were driving.
- We're getting a little backed up here.
We can clear some of
these necks clinically.
We? Okay, I think it's best if we
left that decision to the doctors.
If patients meet all of
the NEXUS criteria...
What do you know about NEXUS?
As research
coordinator at Emory, I
enrolled 2000 patients
in the initial study.
That's really interesting. Maybe you can
bring it up at your next Nazi nurse rally.
Dr. Morris, my knowledge
of the human anatomy...
is so extensive, I could
kill you with this finger.
Somehow I find
that hard to... Ow!
- Ooh!
- Whoa!
I saved your life. Been telling
them to keep these floors mopped.
Maybe it's time I
fired a janitorial staff.
It's time you cleared
some patients.
Glad you're back in
the trenches with us.
Makes one of us.
What's the problem here?
We've had like 20
paramedic runs in the...
Every ED in the city is closed to
saturation, which means we're all open.
Fender-benders are clogging the hallways.
I'm not sure they all need a C-spine film.
Of course not. Get with it, Morris.
Half these patients don't need x-rays.
- Start clearing necks.
- All right, so they've...
What the hell's your problem? You
can't wait for a little break in...? Hey!
It's a crosswalk, you asshole!
Diverticulitis grandma is
being admitted to Medicine.
My mandible fracture's
going to the OR with OMF...
and Mr. McKay goes home
with rest and ibuprofen.
On that note, I'm out of here
with no pass-ons, thank you.
- Thought you'd help Neela clear necks.
- I did.
- Doc Rock will help you.
- I'm not working here today.
I start my Toxicology elective.
I picked Neurology,
didn't get an elective.
You need to complete Pre-Hospital
Care Training Requirements.
- My what?
- Your ride-alongs.
You never did them as an intern
and you've 24 hours in the field.
- I've been meaning to do that.
- Come see me when you do...
- then we'll discuss your elective options.
- Where'd you go for coffee, Milwaukee?
The donuts are soggy.
God forbid you don't get your
morning ration of deep fried fat, Frank.
Maybe I can dry
them in the microwave.
You okay? ABBY: Yeah.
Nothing a week in the Bahamas
wouldn't cure. What about you?
Eve stuck me on nights. Now I get less
sleep, less money and I barely see Alex.
I have to have a
babysitter spend the night.
What is it about rain that turns
residents of this city into idiots?
- Tell me about it. PEYTON:
Haleh, what are you doing here?
- Connie asked me to cover for her.
- I warned you about your overtime.
I'm just trying to help her out.
You should've told her
to call someone else.
You want me to go back home?
Unless you want
another letter in your file.
Have a great day.
Sam, can you cover for me
until I find someone else? Sam.
Why not? It's not
like I'm gonna be...
home in time to see my
kid off to school anyway.
- Who's this?
- Blaire Collins, 29.
Sent in from Lakeshore Gardens
for infection around her G-tube.
- Does this hurt, Blaire?
Ma'am? MEDIC: She's in a coma.
- Since when?
- Six years.
No, come on. No way. No
way, guys. We don't have room.
She doesn't need to be here.
They can give her IV antibiotics
and they can change her G-tube.
- What are we supposed to do?
- I just told you, take her back.
We don't get paid
for round trips.
Hey, guys. Hey!
What's wrong?
Nursing-home dump.
What else is new? Come on.
I think Trauma Two is open.
Check the lobby. We
could use a nurse in Triage.
- You've gotta be kidding me.
- It's okay. Don't worry about it.
No, this is ridiculous.
- Hey, Kerry? You gonna do something?
- About what?
The way she's
managing the staff.
If it's a nursing issue, it's Eve's
rice bowl. You two work it out.
- Morning rounds are at 10 a.m.
- Ten. Ten is good.
We discuss our toxicology
consultations from the entire county.
You will carry the
pager every third day...
and research conference
is Thursday afternoons.
Check it out. Is it poisonous?
Venomous? Yes. I'm studying
neurotoxic factors in crotalid venom.
How cool.
- Cool.
- Please, but... Don't do that.
Your main focus will be
our Poison Control Center.
Calls come in from both the
public and other health care facilities.
You have online access to an
international POISINDEX database...
and we're here to back you up.
You're number two.
Judy Anderson, 31, head-on
collision, auto versus cinderblock wall.
- My baby? Grace? Where is she?
- She's coming soon, ma'am.
- Any belly pain, Judy?
- It hurts when I breathe.
- Driver with chest pain, good vitals.
- Any victims in the second vehicle?
- Only one car.
- They forced me off the road.
- Who?
- They were driving like maniacs.
- They hurt my daughter. Where is she?
- Baby's with Rescue 73.
I'll take this one so
you can take the baby.
Sure.
- Nice work. Is that custom?
- Yeah, Spanish Revival.
Ancef's onboard.
- Watch it, this thing's attached.
- He missed the femur.
He bagged the femoral
artery, got a cold foot.
Give him 50 of fentanyl
and we'll take him upstairs.
I'll be right back.
Dr. Dubenko. DUBENKO: Yeah.
Is everything else okay?
He should be back to
work in a few weeks.
- Well, I meant with you, actually.
- Oh.
I know this is none
of my business...
but I was up in oncology
last week with a patient and...
Oh, oh, oh.
I had my annual PSA screening.
Oh. Duh.
- Sorry.
- It came back 6.5.
- It's a little high.
- Needle biopsy...
showed a moderately
differentiated prostate cancer.
- I am so sorry.
- No. It's okay.
We caught it early, stage T-One.
Good prognosis with surgery.
I gotta get your ischemic
foot boy upstairs.
Um, Lucien?
If you want to talk with someone
or have a coffee or something...
Yeah, all right, maybe.
That would be nice.
Okay.
Hi, Frank. Anything
besides fender-benders?
Well, the guy in Number Four got
scalded while driving by the hospital...
by some crazy broad
who was throwing coffee.
He thought she was a nurse.
Probably someone from
ICU. They're wacky up there.
Abby! Chest pain.
- When did it start?
- Ten, 15 minutes ago.
- We came right in.
- What does it feel like?
Heavy, heavy... Here.
- Are you on any medications?
- Lipitor and aspirin.
All right. First
day labs, 12 lead.
- Lopressor and nitro.
- Got it.
- Is he having a heart attack?
- We have look at his EKG to tell you that.
Three-months-old passenger.
Multiple lacs to the head, face and chest.
- Looks like she was ejected.
- Car seat wasn't anchored down?
Looks that way.
Heart rate in the 160s.
- Access? MEDIC:
Tried twice. IV blew.
Are you good with tiny veins?
- Maybe. WEAVER:
I'll take that as a yes.
- C-spine's clear. Get her off the board.
- Pulse ox 97 on two liters.
When you say a truck, do you mean
they were driving an SUV or a pickup?
SUV. It was blue or black.
It was definitely black.
- Okay, Judy, we're gonna sit you up a bit.
- Ow, my chest.
Did you see the driver
or the passengers?
There were at least two of them.
The driver was a young teenager.
- White, Black, Hispanic, Asian, what?
- White. I'm not sure about the passenger.
- Lungs are clear.
- BP, 112 over 78.
It hurts when I breathe.
- Stop!
- I think you've broken your breastbone.
Add a sternal view, troponin,
CT of head, abdomen and pelvis.
- What can you tell us about their vehicle?
- There is a bike rack on the roof.
They tried to force me off the
road. They wanted to steal my car.
- Am I bleeding?
- You hit the window. It's not too bad.
- Will I need stitches?
- Yep.
Did either of them
have a weapon, ma'am?
I don't know. It happened so fast.
I just wanted to get out of there.
Enough for now.
She's had a concussion.
You need to let her rest
before she goes into the CT.
- We're working here. WEAVER:
Sorry, Luka. Got a trauma.
We need the room.
Hey, here we go. Gently.
I've got the neck.
On my count. One,
two, three. Here we go.
We're out of the
infant c-collars.
Luka, do you know if
we have infant c-collars?
- You can use towel rolls.
- I'm gonna ask Peyton.
Can't hear breath
sounds. Do we have a sat?
- Won't pick up. KOVAC:
Kid's pink, sat's fine.
Twenty-four gauge
going on in the right.
You want me to take
this? I don't mind.
Why, you think I'm rusty?
Superficial lacs, no step offs,
left frontal-parietal hematoma.
Call CT and let them
know we need a head.
Finally calming down.
Or going apnic. Come
on, baby, wake up.
Wake up.
All right.
Inez, miller one and a
four-0. She needs a tube.
The kid's screaming.
The airway's obviously fine.
She's got a good mechanism
for a head injury. She needs a CT.
You'll subject her to
the risks of intubation...
to make things easier
for the radiology tech?
- She'll settle down.
- She doesn't have time.
Agitation could be an
early sign of a head injury.
Or an appropriate response
to a stressful situation.
- Babies cry when they're scared.
- Thank you, Dr. Kovac.
But this is my patient and her
mental status is waxing and waning.
- She could go apnic in the scanner.
- Then you bag her through it.
Point five of versed and vec.
You lose your neuro exam if you
sedate. Observe until Trauma gets here.
And watch her bleed into her brain?
No, thanks. Push the meds, Inez.
Look at her. She's alert,
pupils equal, good tone.
- Do it now.
- Point five versed, going in.
Kerry, we've seen enough head trauma
to develop gut feelings about these things.
And my gut says
intubate. She needs a tube.
Giving the vec.
Suction.
The scope.
- Where are they taking my daughter?
- She's going up to the CT.
What are all those tubes?
Why isn't she moving?
The tube helps her
breathe. It's just a precaution.
Sometimes babies have to
be sedated for CAT scans.
It doesn't mean
anything's wrong.
- Have the police found anything?
- It's still early. They will.
I should have waited
until it stopped raining.
No one can control the weather.
The good news is that your
brain and belly CT are normal.
You've broken your breastbone
and we'll need to monitor your heart...
- to make sure it wasn't bruised.
- But I didn't have to go out.
I could have waited.
Grace was fussy all night.
Sometimes a car ride settles her down.
I'm gonna numb up the cuts
on your face before I suture.
- What am I gonna tell my husband?
- You need a new car?
You're gonna feel a little pinprick
and then some burning before it kicks in.
You have a bunch
of phone messages.
No, no, no. Tell Kayson
to stop bothering me.
I'll call Anspaugh back
when I get a chance. Oh, crap.
Henry's got a birthday
party tomorrow.
Hey, Jerry. Could you go down to that
toy store on Michigan Avenue for me?
- You want me to go outside?
- Yeah, it's just a few blocks.
I need a King Funshine.
I'll write it down for you.
- In the storm?
- What, you afraid you'll melt?
What about the
lightning? I'm a big target.
Well, then I suggest you try
running in a zigzag pattern.
Dr. Weaver? The results are back
for that little girl ejected from the car.
- Is she awake yet?
- Not yet.
But I'm gonna double check.
- Hey.
Baby's head CT is negative.
- Just some soft tissue swelling.
- Is she awake?
- No, she is still sedated.
- Then you can't follow her neuro exam.
She'll wake up
and we'll extubate.
This is Bradley Anderson. His
wife and daughter were brought in.
The police said
there was an accident.
Yeah, they're doing well.
Come on, I'll take you to them.
Aren't you two supposed to
keep 50 feet apart or something?
- Bite me, Frank.
- Ask me, you're better off.
I didn't.
Second EKG is unchanged
and troponin is negative.
He's pain-free after
nitro and metoprolol.
So he's okay?
Well, doesn't look like a heart attack,
but I think he has unstable angina.
One of the arteries
may be closing down.
You have to stay in the hospital
for observation and more tests.
- For how long?
- Could be just a day or two.
- You okay with that?
- Like I got a choice?
You hang in there.
I'll stop by later if I can.
Um, excuse me.
Excuse me, hi. It might
be better if you stayed.
The cardiologist
is gonna have...
questions and instructions
for you and your husband.
I'm not Lee's wife.
I'm his therapist.
Are you a doctor?
I am his satisfaction
facilitator.
What is that exactly?
I have a select group
of clients like Lee...
who require something
they're not getting at home.
Something sexual?
I provide the one
thing that's missing.
Which allows them to live
happily ever after with their wives.
- Really?
- I help women too.
- You call me if he needs anything.
- Okay.
Sixty cc's of gastrografin
and check KUB.
What's this?
Nursing-home dump.
I'm changing G-tubes
on comatose patients now.
- How's your MI?
- Unstable angina.
Just out of curiosity, what type of
guy hires a satisfaction facilitator?
I believe that's the politically
correct term for call girl these days.
A smart one? We
have a saying in Croatia:
You know, if it
floats, flies or...
- Fornicates?
- Rent it.
- Hey, Dr. Kovac.
- Hello. Hello.
I thought I might take you
up on that offer for coffee.
- If you've got a minute.
- Sure. Page me if you need me.
How many stitches?
Let's see. There's seven on
the forehead. Five on the cheek.
That's 12 altogether.
That's not so bad.
Neela, this is Brad,
Judy's husband.
Hey, baby.
- Honey, I'm so sorry.
- Come on, it wasn't your fault.
The police told me what happened.
The bastards should be shot.
- I tried to get away and I lost control.
- You did everything you could.
Don't worry. The cops
will get these guys.
- Have you seen Grace?
- She looks good.
- They think she's gonna be okay.
- Really?
We have to run a few tests.
Everything looks good,
but soon as I can...
I'll bring her down so
you can be with her.
Thanks.
I'm gonna go back and stay with Grace
until they're ready to bring her in here.
- I love you.
- I love you too.
Your husband
seems like a great guy.
- It's okay. Everything's gonna be okay.
- I'm sorry. I'm not usually like this.
Okay, well, the Venus
Fly Trap is non-toxic...
so it's not a
lethal if ingested.
However, the larger ones
are extremely dangerous...
and have been known to
devour pets and small children.
No, no, no, I made
that last part up.
Uh...
I'm sorry. Ma'am, I...
You're absolutely right.
This is not a venue for humor.
I understand. I apologize.
You too.
Do you need any
help with the snakes?
- We could have gone to the cafeteria.
- This one. Their coffee sucks.
You didn't mention seeing me upstairs
to anyone else by any chance, did you?
No.
I mean, I...
I wouldn't have said
anything to you...
but I thought you might wanna
talk to someone or something...
- Yeah, no, I appreciate the gesture.
- Okay.
- So, what are your treatment options?
- Well...
I've opted for a
radical prostatectomy.
My urologist, Dr. Peter
Singh. You know him?
No.
He does a bilateral
nerve-sparing procedure...
for patients with
low volume disease.
- That's great.
- Even in the best of circumstances...
there's a 25 percent chance
of loss of erectile function.
Yeah. Then you're looking
at penile injection therapy...
intraurethral pharmacotherapy,
vacuum erection devices...
or a penile prosthesis to
achieve an adequate erection.
Well, I... Then the good news is that
there's 75 percent chance of success.
Well, the procedure also
eliminates the ability to ejaculate.
Uh-huh.
But the chance of urinary
incontinence is low...
so I won't be wearing a diaper
or need an artificial sphincter.
Well, there you go.
- Yeah.
It is... It's just...
It's rather daunting, knowing
that you may never have sex again.
Well, it sounds like
you're in good hands.
Yeah.
Look, I know this is rather unconventional
and under different circumstances...
I certainly would have employed
a more traditional approach...
with regards to courtship
and romantic methodology...
and assuredly enjoyed
all the ritual of that.
But given the
time constraints...
and obviously what I'm
potentially faced with...
You know, you might
just wanna kind of take...
Look.
If I'm going down, I
wanna go down swinging...
and I'd like it to be with you.
So you want me
to sleep with you?
Yeah.
Well, that's
something. That's...
I'm flattered, I think. But I...
- I can't do that.
- No, no. I understand.
- Nothing personal.
- No, I understand.
I was asking purely
from a scientific approach.
What about after?
- After what?
- The surgery.
To see if anything still works.
I'm gonna have to
take a pass on that too.
Yeah.
Abby, you want this?
GSW to the upper chest.
I gotta... I better go
back. You wanna hop on?
I mean, are you coming?
To the... For the...
Place the chest tube, call me if
the initial output is over 500 cc's.
How's Grace?
We moved her to one of our
exam rooms, so we'll take you too.
I've brought some mug
books for you to look through.
It all happened so fast, I'm not
really sure what I remember seeing.
Take a look, maybe a
face will jog your memory.
I can't.
- Why don't you give us a few minutes?
- Sure.
I don't wanna look
at those books.
You might identify the
men who drove you off...
I can't.
- Why not?
- It was pouring rain.
I could barely see
out the window.
Car started to skid,
and I don't know.
I saw the wall coming, and I
didn't stop. I just kept driving. I just...
What are you saying,
Judy? What happened?
I didn't know that Grace's
car seat wasn't clicked in.
I would never do
anything to hurt my child.
Did you do this on purpose?
Sometimes, I...
I can't help it. Sometimes...
It's like I don't know
how to snap out of it.
It's like everything's coming at me at
once and I just want it all to go away.
- Judy, did you try to hurt yourself?
- I just wanted it to stop.
- Do either of you have a moment?
- Shoot.
My MVC mom's suffering from
severe postpartum depression.
- Dr. Weaver?
- Just one second.
- It's the baby, Grace Anderson.
- What about her?
She's waking up. You
might wanna extubate.
- Yeah, I'll be right there.
- What are her symptoms?
She drove head-on into a
wall with her baby in the car.
I think it was intentional. I'd
like to put her on a psych hold.
- Dr. Rasgotra?
- It's the husband.
Get Psych down here.
Can my wife go home now?
- Not yet.
You moved Judy out of the trauma room.
I thought that meant she was good to go.
We needed to clear the room.
We have to rule out
a cardiac contusion.
We need to monitor her heart
to make sure it's not bruised.
For how long?
I'm not sure. It
could be a while.
Mr. Anderson...
Does Judy drink alcohol?
No. I mean, she has a glass
of wine now and then. Why?
What about drugs?
No. What's this all about?
Just routine questions
for her chart to avoid...
any drug interaction,
that sort of thing.
Have you noticed any
change in her mood lately?
Like what?
- She seem depressed?
- No.
Any loss of appetite
or trouble sleeping?
You're kidding, right? We
have a three-month-old baby.
When Gracey doesn't
sleep, none of us do.
The sooner I can get them both home,
the sooner they can start getting better.
I don't want to send her home
until I'm sure there's no danger.
No, of course. You're
right. Thank you.
Dr. Kovac, could you
help me clear some beds?
- I thought I was.
- If we work together...
Look, what's going
on in Exam Two?
DUB needs an ultrasound
to rule out fibroids.
Good crits, vitals stable.
How about an outpatient
scan and GYN referral?
- Well, if you can get her in this week.
- Done. Okay, next. Buster Freeman?
Dirty puncture wound to
the foot, waiting on IV Ancef.
Can he sit in a chair for
that? It frees up a bed.
- Crystal Marranachio?
- Waiting on an ortho consult.
She's been cleared.
I called the attending.
You what?
It's a new policy. When
we call for a consult...
the resident has 60 minutes to respond
to the page or we call the attending.
All the department heads signed off
on it except Psych. Crazy bastards.
- Blaire Collins has been here forever.
- I've called the nursing home twice.
They were supposed
to send a ride for her.
Well, if they're not here in
10, I'm putting her in a cab.
- She's comatose.
- I was kidding, Dr. Kovac.
Frank, call Blaire Collins'
nursing home again...
and tell those idiots she's been
ready to go home for the last four hours.
- Tell them yourself. I'm busy.
- Dr. Kovac?
I think I'm one of those idiots.
Trish Gorham, assistant
director from the nursing home...
- that's been caring for Blaire Collins.
- I didn't mean that.
It's our policy to check
on patients prior to transfer.
- I gather she's well enough to return.
- Yes, she's right over here. This way.
To be honest with you, all she
needs is a course of IV antibiotics.
And the G-tube could have
been changed at your facility.
We're not staffed well and the
gastroenterologist doesn't come out.
The earliest I could get anyone
to see her was in two weeks.
- She have any family?
- No.
Her mother died from
the crash that did this.
There was a boyfriend, but he
stopped coming around years ago.
He didn't even try to stop.
Somebody call my son.
A 47-year-old, victim
of auto vs. pedestrian.
I just ran out to get the kids some
pizza. He didn't even slow down.
Systolic's only 80 after a liter.
Pulse, 140. Pale and diaphoretic.
Ecchymosis across
the abdomen and pelvis.
Four units of O-neg and
prime the rapid infuser.
Am I dying?
No, but you may have
some internal bleeding.
Resps are shallow.
Let's set up for intubation.
- How often are you sad?
- Not often.
- What makes you happy, Judy?
- Being with my baby, my husband.
Why are you asking me all this?
We ask all patients
these questions...
to assess mental status
following a head injury.
Well, my mental
status is fine. Really.
Any thoughts about
wanting to hurt yourself?
Not unless you count wanting
to take a carving knife to my hips.
Do you ever think about
wanting to hurt your baby?
Of course not.
What did you tell him?
Judy, you said you were upset
and that you couldn't snap out of it.
What are you talking about?
You felt like everything was coming
at you and that you wanted it all to stop.
No, no, I said that I lost control
of the car and I couldn't stop.
You're putting
words in my mouth.
It's not uncommon for new
moms to have bouts of depression.
The first year with your
baby can be very stressful.
I'm not stressed and I'm not
depressed although I will be...
if I have to spend
any more time here.
So stop accusing me of
being crazy and let me go.
Nobody's accusing
you of anything.
We have to be extra careful
whenever there's a child involved.
Look, I don't know. I
appreciate your concern, really.
There's nothing wrong with me.
I've had a rough day...
and I just wanna take my
baby home and get some rest.
Well, I hope you have a
speedy recovery, Mrs. Anderson.
So are we good to go?
Not quite, but you can go
back inside now. I'll be right in.
She's changed her story.
There are no vegetative
symptoms, no anhedonia.
She doesn't have a depressed
affect. She's in good spirits.
Something's going on. She as
much as confessed to crashing her car.
- But she's not saying that now.
- She's lying.
She's a prime
candidate for severe...
I wanna be sure
she doesn't have...
postpartum depression
just as much as you do.
But it can be
difficult to diagnose.
If the patient is in complete
denial or lying to me...
not only can I not tell,
but I cannot hold her.
I gave her every opportunity
to let us know. I'm sorry.
Whoa.
- You need a hand?
- I need eight.
- God, it hurts.
- What's this?
Driver of our auto
versus pedestrian.
The guy ran out in front of
me. Please, give me something.
No neck pain, no chest pain, good vitals,
but complains of bilateral thumb pain.
Look at this, I can't
even make a fist.
- We're out of beds.
- I'll see what I can do.
Dr. Weaver, Psych's refusing
to admit Judy Anderson.
- Psych?
- Her collision was a deliberate act.
I know you suspect postpartum
depression, but did she admit it?
Practically. She drove
head-on into a wall.
The baby's seat wasn't properly anchored.
She's obviously overwhelmed at home.
ER, please hold. Please hold.
Please hold. Has anybody seen Jerry?
I sent him out on an errand,
but he should be back by now.
- You sent him out?
- You don't send Jerry out in the rain.
- I've heard that too.
- Maybe I should get DCFS involved.
Have you talked to the husband?
Maybe he can convince her.
A voluntary admission
would be better.
- I'll try.
- Frank, where's Jerry?
- Dr. Weaver sent him on an errand.
- Oh, no, you didn't.
What's the big deal?
Big man does not do
well in the wet weather.
What the hell does that mean?
Excuse me. Could you
help us find our dad?
- Lawrence Digby? He was hit by a car.
- The doctors are treating him.
- He got hit while crossing the street.
- Yeah, he was...
Guy was talking on his cell
phone, wasn't paying attention...
went right through the
crosswalk. I'll take you back to him.
You can go home. I
got a float from the ICU.
I'm gonna stay and
help with this guy's kids.
You're welcome to do
so, but you're off the clock.
- Fine with me. Come on, you guys.
- Can I take her home now?
We'd like to keep her overnight.
- Oh, come on. Overnight? Why?
- I think your wife needs some help.
I've tried to talk her
into getting a nanny...
but she doesn't want another
woman raising her daughter.
It makes her feel like she's
less of a mother or something.
I don't mean that kind of help. I think
Judy needs some psychiatric help.
- What?
- Mr. Anderson...
Brad, why don't we sit down?
It's not uncommon for new
moms to get overwhelmed...
with all the challenges of child
care, especially in the first year.
So why are you making
a big deal out of this?
Usually, it's short-lived and goes
away after the baby falls into a routine...
and the mom's
hormones stabilize.
But occasionally, it lasts
longer, becomes more severe...
and develops into something
called postpartum depression.
Yeah, yeah, but that's not Judy.
Judy's not depressed.
Not like that.
I mean, sure, she's
anxious to get back to work...
and sometimes she's a little
down about that, but that's normal.
Purposely trying to hurt
herself and your baby isn't.
What are you talking
about? She had an accident.
Some creep tried to
run her off the road.
I don't think she was
forced off the road.
Dr. Rasgotra. Nosebleed
on Coumadin in Two.
Okay. Please, talk to your wife.
Ask her yourself. Ask her
what really happened in the car.
- Sux onboard.
- Yankauer.
- Assist ventilations.
- O-neg's going on the right antecube.
- We're going to need rapid infuser.
- Curtain four.
- They did an in-service. I got it.
- Okay, let's take a look.
- Sats down to 92.
- Turn on the suction.
- It's on.
- No, it's not.
- I have it on high.
- I'm not getting anything here.
Inez, why don't you go next door and
help Dr. Lockhart with the chest tube?
I'm not allowed to work
with any of the nurses now?
Patient is paralyzed,
I can't see the cords.
- I need suction.
- Hold your horses.
The suction container
wasn't sealed properly.
- You're welcome.
- Tube.
- I found it. KOVAC:
Two units on the infuser.
Set up for a subclavian.
Okay, bag him.
- End tidal CO2 is yellow.
- Yellow is good. I'll be right back.
All right, hook me up.
O-silk is next.
- O-silk. Come on.
- Here you go.
- I wanna auto-transfuse this guy.
- Okay.
You need a side
collector on the thoraseal.
Just go help Dr. Kovac
with the rapid infuser.
No problem.
- What do you need?
- Central line, supraumbilical DPL.
- Rapid infuser and a TPOD.
- What's a TPOD?
- Fine, I'll get it. Again.
- What do you want to do first?
- Prime the O-neg.
- Everything okay in there?
For the time being. Call
for four units of type specific.
- As soon as I get this up.
- Hey, Sam.
Hypotensive pelvic
fracture. He needs the works.
- Those are his kids out there.
- Hey, Frank.
Bring those guys
to the family room.
- Sure, come on, kids. This way.
- I'll be right in.
Great.
- Guidewire.
- I'm getting error signal.
That's because there's not
enough water in the warmer.
- Thanks.
- Cordis inducer.
Stitch.
- Where's Dori with the TPOD?
- TPODs are in the bottom shelf.
Update his vitals.
- Okay, infuser is on.
- Looks good.
- Cath... INEZ:
Pressure's up to 95 palp.
- No gross blood. PEYTON:
Where do you need me?
- We're all set.
- She's good.
Thanks, Sam. We'll
take it from here.
- I'll go check on his kids.
- She's really not sure...
what happened. She gave
herself a good whack in the head.
We can't do anything if she
doesn't identify her assailants.
That's okay. Like I said, she's
not sure what she remembers.
She's not even certain
it was intentional now.
Fine. Let me know if
she changes her mind.
You did the right thing.
Next is get your wife help.
No, the next step is
for me to take her home.
My wife is not crazy. She
had an accident. It happens.
I'd rather she chose to stay than
have Psychiatry put her on forced hold.
She's gonna be with
me. She's gonna be fine.
Just leave us alone. I mean it.
Pressure's up to
100 systolic, crit's 28.
Send another four units to angio.
- Daddy?
Your dad has a broken pelvis...
which are the ring of
bones around his waist.
Some of his blood vessels
have also been damaged.
He's bleeding inside.
Can you fix it?
We're gonna try, but he's
lost a lot of blood already.
It's very serious.
It was supposed to be me.
I was supposed to get the pizza,
but I didn't wanna go out in the rain.
It's not your fault and
it's not your dad's fault.
- Hey, jerk-off.
- Jason.
I can't drive for a week. Not that
I could anyway. My car's totaled.
What's so important you
had to be talking while driving?
- What was so damn important?
- Hey, that's enough.
- Hey, get that guy away from me.
- Shut up.
Jason, I know you're mad, but
your father's condition is very serious.
And your brother and sister
need you right now, okay?
Come on, Jason, I'll take
you to the family room.
Dr. Kovac, one of your
patients is getting agitated.
- Which one?
- The girl from the nursing home.
- She's in a coma, Inez.
- Not anymore.
- Blaire?
- Where...?
I'm Dr. Kovac.
Where's my mom?
Okay, keep your hands
up as if you're holding a tray.
What's wrong with me?
What's the last
thing you remember?
My mom and I were going to
the mall and it was snowing.
And...
Were we in an accident?
Is she okay?
I didn't treat her, but...
Let me see what I
can find out. Okay?
Okay.
- How is she?
- She doesn't remember anything.
What are you gonna tell her?
I don't know. Your mother's dead
and you've been in a coma for six years?
- How are those kids doing?
- They're hanging in there.
I got ahold of an aunt and
uncle. They're with them now.
- Inez, walk with me.
- Do I have to?
- You have fantastic potential.
- I better get into this.
But in every spare moment,
you've got to be honing your skills.
- Got a second?
- Not really.
If you're so concerned
with efficiency...
then allow those of us who work
well together to continue to do so.
If you want us to act like professionals,
then you need to treat us as such.
You saw me with Dr. Kovac
and how well we worked together.
If that doesn't prove we
can work the same shift...
then you don't know your
job as well as you think you do.
Feel better?
FYI, I already changed the schedule.
You're back on your old shifts next week.
Thank you.
When I first started, I
could barely hook up an IV.
It's all muscle memory.
You'll get it. I know you will.
I felt like an idiot. I didn't
even know what a T-POD was.
Everybody needs help with
stuff. When you do, come find me.
Thanks.
- Page me when he's out of surgery.
- Will do.
- You're back.
- Had a cancellation.
He's this way.
I tried Lee's cell but
he wasn't answering.
- Is everything okay?
- He's doing great.
We're just waiting for them
to take him to the cath lab.
That sounds ominous.
They're going to do angioplasty, which is
a procedure where we insert a catheter...
into a blood vessel in his leg,
thread it up to his coronary artery...
which inflates a balloon
that will open up the blockage.
Guess those cheese
steaks caught up with me.
I've been telling him
to eat better for years.
Lee?
Hey, you. Hey.
This is my wife, Viv.
- Hi.
I'm Dr. Lockhart. I've
been treating your husband.
- Hi.
- Everything's okay.
I've got a little blockage,
but they're gonna fix it.
I didn't get your name.
Shawna. Hi.
And you are?
Therapist.
From cardiology.
Really?
Your husband has to
undergo an angioplasty.
We insert a catheter into
a blood vessel in his leg...
and use it to inflate a balloon that
will hopefully open the blockage.
- Oh, okay.
- Well. Good luck, Mr. Rappaport.
I have to get back to my other
patients. It was nice to meet you.
Excuse me for just one second.
That was close.
Thanks, I really owe you one.
Hey, listen. If you ever
need a sex therapist?
I think I'm good.
But now that you mention it, do
you ever do any pro bono work?
I spoke to your resident. He
felt a hold was unnecessary.
I disagree and all I'm asking...
is for a second assessment
from another attending.
Watch it. No,
Dr. Wakita, not you.
Where have you been?
I was worried about you.
Everyone was acting as if
I'd sent you out in a hurricane.
Are you okay?
What the hell happened
to King Funshine?
Did you get hit
by lightning again?
He didn't get hit by lightning.
Here's your change.
Okay, let's get you
on a cardiac monitor.
CBC, chem panel, EKG, CPK,
troponin, UA and myoglobin...
I realize that, I'm sure he is. But
this isn't about me or him, or you.
It's about the welfare of
a mother and her child.
You will? Great.
Thank you so much.
Psych attending will
assess Judy Anderson.
If Dr. Wakita asks, you agree
with my assessment, right?
Yeah, you got it.
Mr. and Mrs. Anderson,
I have some good news.
One of the attendings
agreed to speak with you.
- I've seen enough doctors today.
- We're going home.
- He's on his way down.
- We've been here for hours.
- This will only take a few minutes.
- I'm tired.
I just wanna go home and have a dinner
and a bath and put Grace in her own crib.
- You want what's best for baby, so do I.
- Then leave us alone.
- Speak to someone.
- She just needs to rest.
You don't wanna hurt yourself or
Grace. You need professional help.
- Do you have children?
- No.
- Then how do you know?
- I'm a doctor.
- But you're not a mother.
- Judy, listen to me.
Please, don't go.
My wife has a touch of the baby
blues and you wanna lock her up.
No one's locking anyone up. Just
want her to get the help she needs.
- By giving her drugs?
- Maybe.
Ignoring it is not
gonna make it go away.
It needs to be treated the
same as any other disease.
Now, this could happen again.
Only next time, it could be worse.
Judy, Judy, please. You could
die, Judy. Your baby could die.