Previously on ER:
- Hi, Mom.
- Do I know you?
You were gonna stay until we got
her settled into the nursing home.
I can't, Sammy.
- This is my new partner, Ed.
- I hear you're looking out for her.
- She looks out for herself.
- It festers in you.
You know it's wrong.
You... You need to talk
to somebody about this.
Well, what was it like when you were
a kid? You never talk about that stuff.
I was barely living
before I met you.
I need a kidney, and I came
back to the States to get on the list.
Good job today.
Like you never left.
Sit?
Do you want me to sit?
- Yeah. We're rolling.
- Okay.
It's a little warm in here.
Must be the, uh...
All right. So you guys
started yesterday, huh?
You can relax, Dr. Carter.
And you're interested
in, what? Life in the ER?
We're documenting
the challenges...
of emergency care
in the 21st century.
And you wanna know what?
About you. The people
who work here. What you do.
Okay.
How long have been at County?
I started about 15 years ago.
That's actually kind
of hard to believe.
Wow.
- Can you focus here?
- Yep.
Oh, here? Yep.
Sorry.
Oh, uh, I was a med
student then and, uh...
Well, the thing that you realize
pretty soon is that you see it all...
you see the whole spectrum
of human experience.
Does that sound
a little pretentious?
It did, right? So pretent...
Uh, well, you guys are
gonna probably... Anyway.
- Go on.
- Yeah? Good?
Um, well, whatever you
can imagine, it happens here.
Sometimes you're there for the
end, and that part never gets easier.
Uh, it can be the
loneliest place in the world.
Or where you go
for a second chance.
And every once in a while, if
you're smart, or lucky, maybe...
you find exactly what
you need right here.
- Come on, you can be a little late.
- No, I can't.
- What's so important?
- Um, a murder investigation?
Oh, that's the best
you can come up with?
Ha, ha, you're cute.
Hey, did you mean what you said?
You hate the way this
place is decorated?
You're a man, okay?
Just get rid of the futon.
I love that futon.
What's with this paint?
It's like shades of feces.
- You know, that's all I'm saying.
- Ha, ha.
I was a bachelor
till very recently.
Don't worry, Archie.
I'll whip you into shape.
The one thing that
you keep learning...
is that you can never think
that you know what's coming.
Because when the rig rolls
up and the doors pop open...
you have no idea what's inside.
Diaz? Diaz? Talk to me.
10-1, 10-1. B5412,
my partner's been shot.
I'm at 2549 West Harrison,
third floor, rear landing.
Returned fire, officer needs assistance.
10-1, 10-1, officer needs assistance.
So the only rule is...
- Dr. Carter?
- Never relax.
Sorry to interrupt. Two
GSWs, five minutes out.
One's a detective,
multiple wounds.
All right. Set up both trauma
rooms and call for some O-neg.
I gotta go. Ahem.
Uh, can we finish this later?
Yeah. If you can find me.
The most common
thing I see? That's easy.
Rectal insertions.
Seriously.
I say "stat"... Yeah, I
say "stat" quite often.
This guy, he was, um, high on PCP
but he was, like, over seven feet tall...
and we had him strapped
down on a gurney.
I mean, the funny part is,
is that it doesn't matter...
if it's a shampoo bottle, a
light bulb, a whisk, whatever...
they always tell you the
same story: "I fell on it."
Thoracotomy, stat, ha, ha.
"I fell on it"?
And that guy got up...
and he had the gurney
strapped to his back, ha, ha...
and he was chasing us
all up and down the hall.
Men.
People in Australia can
understand me, which is good.
I've got an accent.
Yes I have, um...
"Just clerks"? Those were
his words. "Just clerks"?
He said that we didn't count as
emergency healthcare providers.
- "He"? Who is "he"?
- The writer, I think?
Of a documentary?
Documentaries have writers?
- Well, he pieces it together or something.
- "Pieces it together."
- That's what's wrong with television.
- He seemed like a pipsqueak to me.
So you've met him?
He interviewed us yesterday.
The nurses? Got their own day?
Get over it, Frank.
We go to school for this.
That's it. If they can make their
own stupid reality show, so can I.
Can't argue with that.
Uh, I... I don't think
that's such a good idea.
Here. Press and point. You
know how to work these things.
Okay, okay, but there's nothing wrong
with a life lived out of the spotlight.
A stack of files, a broken
stapler, a three-hole punch.
But lives are saved
and lost right here.
It's a desk, Frank.
Admit, the nerve
center of the ER.
What you're about to see is a document
of those who serve as the gatekeepers.
My name is Martin, Frank Martin.
Jerry Markovic.
The few, the proud...
The desk clerks.
That film crew get to you yet?
They just asked me boring questions
about the effect of the economy.
The effect is that
people get poor...
then they use guns to get
money, the ER stays busy.
Now you tell me.
What we getting?
- I heard officer down.
- Detective.
- How'd he get shot?
- He's a she.
This one's ours.
Perp's coming behind.
- Okay, we got this one.
- Claudia Diaz. I think you guys know her.
- She and Morris have a thing.
- A thing? Is that what it is?
What happened here?
Son of a bitch shot me
when I was walking away.
I bit my damn tongue.
Lucky you had your vest on.
I feel real lucky right now.
Here's the shooter.
Took multiple shots.
Get chest and abdominal
films. Type and cross...
- Type and cross for four.
- You all right, boss?
- Yeah. Work on access when we get in.
- Does Archie know?
My partner's still on the scene.
- He said he'd call him.
- I'll try to, just to be sure.
Thank you for
bringing breakfast.
You know, this is
nice, what you're doing.
Oh, you like it?
You know, I was torn between an
eggshell white and something bolder.
Like a robin-egg type thing.
I sound gay. Not that there's
anything wrong with that.
You're nervous.
Well, it's kind of risky, asking her
to move in. Maybe she'll say no.
I think any girl would appreciate
a guy willing to repaint for her.
How are things going with
the Wonder From Down Under?
Good, I guess.
As long as we don't talk much.
Typical guy.
Fellas have to have your
deepest thoughts and feelings...
pried from your cold,
dead fingers, but...
Still, he's hard to figure.
Well, it's understandable.
You know, with what
happened to him as a kid.
I told him he needs
to see somebody.
You know, if you've been hurt
like that, you know, sexually...
at a young age, it doesn't
just go away on its own.
Well, it's, um, good
he confides in you.
It's been hard for him moving to
Chicago. There's you and there's me.
That's basically his whole circle
of friends. Real ones, anyway.
Right.
Wait, you didn't...?
- He never told you?
- It, um...
- Neela, I'm sorry. I didn't mean to...
- It explains a lot, um...
I have get to work by 9.
We've got a complicated triple-A
repair Dubenko wants me in on.
- No, Neela...
- I'll see you later.
Hello?
Decrease on the right.
Ten blade, sterile 8's and a...
And a chest-tube tray.
Hey. She took two shots. One in
the buttock, one in the shoulder.
- An exit wound in the chest.
- I told you to get a desk job.
Oh, uh...
- Bastard shot me in the back.
- How's your partner?
- All right.
- You were covered?
- Any pain here?
- Oh, yeah.
- It wasn't like that.
- How do you know?
- It was clean.
- Four milligrams morphine IV.
- We're out of 28. Is 32 okay?
- It's not okay. It's too big.
Let's get the films.
I'll do the chest tube.
I'm okay.
- Just dig up a 28 someplace.
- Sats, 88.
Are you sure you're
okay with this?
- It's all you guys.
- I'm sorry, this has to stay on you.
Somebody get the
sterile 8's, please, ahem.
- Bullet crossed the mediastinum.
- Well, that doesn't sound good.
- Probable aortic injury.
- I need a 28.
- Try the hallway.
- Whoa, whoa, half a liter out.
All right, hold compressions.
He's still asystole.
Okay, start up. Let's
hang another unit.
- Should we do a thoracotomy?
- Aorta's transected.
- There isn't much point.
- It's worth a shot, isn't it?
When you're new,
everything's a question.
Even when you know
you know something...
you say it with an inflection.
It's never, "Thoracotomy."
It's more like, um,
"Thoracotomy?"
You got my smokes?
Hi.
The orderly said he could get me a
carton of Salems for the right price.
That was two days ago.
I hate smoking these
things. Taste like wet leaves.
Where's Carlos?
I was, uh, kind of hoping today
would be the day you remember me.
I remember you well enough.
I'm your daughter. I'm Sam.
I said, I know who you are.
They told me you've been around.
That's good. You're more alert.
Yeah, this place is
like a dream come true.
I feel like I won
the Super Lotto.
Turn off my tank
for me, would you?
You can't smoke in
here. It's against the rules.
What?
So it's your turn
now, is that right?
I just wanna make
sure that you're okay.
Kelly and I both do.
Kelly never left.
Kelly stayed home and took care of
me. I don't know what you've been doing.
- You kicked me out.
- I didn't.
You called me a
whore and a slut.
I didn't belong to you anymore.
You didn't care what happened to me.
You were always dramatic.
You told me no one would
even notice I was gone.
I was 15 years old.
What happened to
that baby of yours?
His name's Alex.
Alex?
When a head injury rolls into
the ER, every minute counts.
- And, um...
- Delays. Talk about delays.
A delay of even 15 minutes can
mean the difference between life...
- Hey.
- And death.
Here's the pelvic film.
Brenner's calling it next door.
The guy lost a lot of blood.
Ahem, how we doing in here?
I can't stay. I'm
late for a meeting.
- She's not lucid.
- They lose him?
- Yeah.
- Well, I bet no one will miss him.
Hey. Come on, the guy died.
Bullet traversed the
pelvis. Could have hit it.
Or the bladder or the
uterus on the way through.
- Where's Surgery?
- In the OR.
They promised they'd send
someone in a few minutes.
- There's fluid around the liver.
- Tachy at 134.
Hang a unit, type specific.
Gonna need an ex-lap.
Maybe not. Let's CT her. It's
gonna take time for the surgeons.
She could be out of the
scanner in 10 minutes.
- Christ. Mac 4 and 7.5.
- You're gonna intubate?
We gotta protect her airway.
Her airway's fine. Her
lungs are re-expanded.
- This isn't the time.
- This is the time.
- He's right. You're right.
- Laryngoscope and a tray, please.
- How's she doing?
- How's it look?
- Hang in there, Diaz.
- What happened?
We were taking statements
on a murder case.
Some guy started
shooting through the door.
- Can I get that laryngoscope?
- Where were you?
Right next to her.
Not a scratch. What a lucky guy.
- Problem?
- Not as long as you had her back.
- Think about slowing your roll.
- Is that what I wanna do?
Take it from me. A badge
beats a lab coat any day.
Band of brothers, right? Where's
your chief? The department?
On their way, pal. Ease up.
This guy always such an asshole?
Hey, come on. You
wanna get into it with me?
All right. You got us
both in frame there, Boris?
Composition not ideal.
You are freakishly tall...
and Frank's head is
square like block of wood.
Thanks for the input, Spielberg.
In this segment, we are going to highlight
some of the unsung heroes of the ER.
First up is Sadiq,
the computer guy.
Sadiq Gilbran-Hassani,
I'm not just the computer guy.
My family has illustrious history
in Syria before we were forced out.
Uh, let's just try to stay
on point, Sadiq, okay?
Without me, there'd be no timely
lab results or x-ray readings...
which are crucial
in the saving of life.
You let me know when I can
speak again, hey, Uncle Sam?
- Thank you, Sadiq.
- You're the boss.
And this is Crystal
Hung, pharmacy tech.
Okay, when a doctor says, "I need an
amp of lidocaine," a nurse goes to get it.
If there's no lidocaine,
it's a problem.
I put the lidocaine in the cart,
every damn day. So that's that.
Interesting. Very interesting.
And here we have good
old Fred Tennyson...
custodial service engineer and
catcher for the ER softball team.
I switch out whatever's
broken. Like light bulbs.
Without light bulbs, it's hard
to see. And doctors, they...
Well, you know,
they need to see stuff.
And, uh, here we have, um...
uh, from the cafeteria.
And without food...
we would all go hungry.
And on, uh, camera...
we have Boris from,
uh, Media Services.
Please leave me out
of this. This is horrible.
When was your last dialysis?
- Dialysis? MORRIS:
Banfield thought I should know.
It was two days ago. I'm
not due for another four hours.
Must be fluid overloaded
since he's not making urine.
- Waiting on a kidney transplant?
- Yes.
- Any fever?
- No.
Increased salt or fluid intake?
Maybe an extra sip of coffee, a
handful of popcorn. Nothing crazy.
Sometimes this kind
of thing is idiopathic.
- It can happen when on chronic dialysis.
- I know.
- Systolic's down to 92.
- Let's get Nephrology here.
And grab the ultrasound. If there's
a big effusion, we need to tap it.
Get my nephrologist, Gustavo
Petrov at Northwestern.
Anyone else you want us to call?
No.
I'll be right back.
Pelvic trajectory goes
through the soft tissues.
- It could've bagged the...
- I need the ultrasound. How's she doing?
- She needs angio.
- She should go to the OR.
- Didn't enter the peritoneum.
- We don't know that.
Okay. Let's not argue here. I'm not
denying she needs surgery. I'm saying...
- that let's look at the iliacs first.
- There's no hematoma.
- What if she starts bleeding in the OR?
- We'll deal with it.
- You've got vascular standing by?
- Did you listen to a word?
- You're not thinking things through.
- No?
- No. We've got time to be systematic.
- Systematic?
Angio, retrograde cystogram.
- Let's not lose our head...
- Calm down and make a decision.
Archie, it's your call.
Angio or surgery?
You guys need to decide this.
Bone fragments in the
bladder wall. She needs the OR.
The pace down here is visceral.
It demands being instinctive...
in the moment.
I prefer having time to
think something through...
hash out different possible
versions, make a plan.
I mean, that's why I'm
better at being a surgeon...
than I was strictly
working in the ER.
You're gonna get in trouble
if they catch you doing that.
Maybe they'll throw me out.
You know, if you don't want
me here, you should just say so.
It's not like I'm gonna leave,
but at least we could talk about it.
Why don't we just try to forget our
mistakes and wipe the slate clean.
Mistakes? What mistakes?
- The ones that we both made.
- Speak for yourself.
All right, you know
what? I'm not gonna sit...
and play along with you as the
martyr and me as the evil child.
You don't have
to sit here at all.
I was young and dumb and in love,
Mom. I believed everything he said.
I raised you better than that.
No, you didn't.
You actually know you didn't.
What is this? It's all wet?
Did you spill something?
Leave it.
- I'll get somebody to clean it up.
- No.
It's what they get paid for.
I don't want the staff
in here. I said stop.
- It's disgusting.
- It's not.
Leave it. Would you please
get out of here, you bitch?
- Get out. Get out of here.
- Give it to me.
- Get out.
Mary, I was coming to get you
for Flex and Fun. You ready?
Do I look like I'm ready
for Flex and Fun, you idiot?
- Thanks.
- Yeah.
So your mother's stroke affected her
frontal lobe. Do you know what that is?
- Yes, I'm a nurse.
- Oh, I thought you were in fashion.
No, that's my sister.
Heh. I didn't realize
there were two of you.
Anyway, what we see with frontal
lobe injuries is the filters come down.
The ability to self-censor, be empathetic,
sensitive, all tends to be affected.
Yeah, I know what
you're getting at.
So the things that she
says, it's not really her.
It's the stroke talking.
It changed her.
I appreciate what
you're saying, I do.
But the thing is, uh...
my mother hasn't changed a bit.
What you see in there,
that's who I grew up with.
That's exactly how
I remember her.
A bit more angle on the needle.
- Eureka.
- Good. I'll be right back.
We'll, uh, do a liver lac,
then explore the pelvis.
Urology will fix the bladder.
GYN will scrub in to
address the uterine issue.
- Primary repair will get it done?
- I hope so.
She may need a hysterectomy.
- Well, whatever you have to do.
- Okay.
She has four units cross-matched.
We'll have them sent up with her.
OR's ready.
I hate the fact that you put
yourself in danger every day.
Every time you do,
I'm so proud of you.
Okay, let's go.
- How's it going? GATES:
Fluid is serosanguineous...
and Johnny boy here
is a backseat driver.
- Dr. Carter?
- John?
Dr. Carter? MORRIS: John.
- He's in V-tach.
- No pulse.
- Did I irritate his myocardium?
- It's not your fault.
Five hundred of calcium
gluconate, amp of D50.
We don't know
his potassium level.
It's high if the kidneys
can't excrete it.
All right.
- Charged to 360.
- Clear.
- Still V-tach.
- Again. Clear.
Again.
- Hi. You guys have a consult for Renal?
- Mg of epi, 150 of amiodarone.
- Excuse me, Dr...?
- Emily Haverman from Nephrology.
Gates, switch.
- You're a student?
- Fourth year. I'm doing a rotation.
That is an ER Attending
coding on the table...
and this is not a teaching case.
So, please, turn around, walk out...
get your attending,
and come back now.
- Dr. Wheeler would prefer if I examined...
- I'm trying to remain professional.
If you're not walking away
within three seconds...
I swear to God, I may start
doing compressions on your head.
I spent a lot of years in the
Army, jumping out of choppers...
and I thought I
was a team player.
But I wasn't. Not
until I got here.
Whoa. K's 7.6.
- Calcium's on board.
- Going again. Clear.
Back in sinus.
- Carotid's good.
- Recheck the lytes now and q30.
I'm Dr. Wheeler from Nephrology.
- My attending.
- Perfect timing.
Morris.
You saved me? I'll
never live it down.
Mom?
I gotta get to work.
When's Kelly coming back?
A week, maybe.
I must have spilled some water on
that blanket or something. I don't know.
I'll take care of it. I'll
get it back to you tonight.
I'm gonna keep coming
here. No matter what.
You won't go through this alone.
You do what you gotta do.
We all have our cross to bear.
The UNOS list can take a long time.
Have you thought about direct donation?
- Yeah, I've considered it.
- And? Your wife not a match?
If not, we have a paired
organ-donor program.
- The two of you could qualify.
- Yeah, I'm aware of that program.
I just haven't talked
to Kem about that yet.
There's very
little risk in testing.
Well, it's just not something we're in
a place to get together on right now.
Oh.
Does she know about your status?
She knows that I have
some medical issues...
and I came back to Chicago.
She's in France.
She's visiting her family.
I left the whole
thing kind of vague.
Okay. I will shut up now.
I'm just kind of tired.
- I'll split.
- Pull that curtain for me?
You got it.
Hey, I didn't realize
you were coming in.
Yeah, me either. I got paged for
an organ transport. Heart donor.
- Plane leaves in two hours.
- How's your mom?
Visiting her makes me feel like
Jodie Foster in Silence of the Lambs.
Fun. Hey, no offense,
but this smells like piss.
I'm supposed to bring that to
her but I'm not gonna make it.
- I'll take care of it for you.
- Really?
- Yeah.
- All you do is send it up to Laundry...
- and drop it off on your way home.
- Not a problem.
- You sure don't mind?
- Did I not just volunteer?
You know, you're not such
an ass as some people say.
Thank you.
Um, what were we talking about?
Oh.
But, you know, eventually, I started
to figure things out as a doctor.
You know, and how I fit in
professionally with this place...
in this community
of people, you know.
That's a big, big
part of it, for me...
is, uh, being good
with yourself...
and who you are, and
who you're meant to be.
You know, finding yourself.
And then there's the
next step after that...
which is finding somebody else.
And sometimes you think:
"You know, that's just... That's
never gonna happen for me."
Then you meet someone...
who makes you feel...
you know...
Who gets you...
and you get her.
Someone you can imagine...
S...
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
People think all we do is scrub
poop and vomit off the floor.
But I refill the paper
towels, the toilet papers...
stock the soap, the dispensers.
Without clean hands, you
get lots of bad infections.
She's right.
Nosocomial infections cause over
30,000 deaths in the U.S. each year.
He knows.
So, boys, what's this all about?
Oh, the interview guy said
that we were non-essential staff.
- Non-essential?
- We're offering a rebuttal.
You're essential.
You're quintessential.
- Um, yeah.
- I'm sure you'll set him straight.
- Let me get a little rest, eh?
- Yeah.
Hey, hey. I think this lady's having
an allergic reaction or something.
Uh, okay, we'll page somebody.
Let's put her right over here.
- Let's get Morris.
- Morris is upstairs.
- How about Brenner?
- Uh, critical ICU.
How long have you had this rash?
An hour.
- Oh, she's having trouble breathing.
- Peanuts.
- Did she say "penis"?
- This is getting weird.
Peanut.
Peanuts. It's a peanut allergy. I
knew a kid who had this in school.
- And?
- He died.
- Oh, man. She's not moving any air.
- We need help.
Uh, uh... No, we don't.
Thank you.
Yeah?
- Oh, in your face, reality boy.
- Yeah. Do we look non-essential now?
I thought you'd be
upstairs working on Claudia.
Uh, Urology is doing the
bladder reconstruction.
They swapped me out
for their own resident.
- Ah.
- I'm, uh, going on a heart retrieval...
so I figured I'd grab a
coffee before the airport.
A heart retrieval for Joanie?
- Yeah, it's good news.
- That's fantastic.
The, uh, heart's in Seattle, so we won't
be back until the middle of the night.
Are we all right?
What do you think?
Well, um, that
something's bothering you.
Clever twist.
Forget it.
Explain it to me.
Hey, how is my being
worried about you a twist?
Because you keep
turning everything around.
I, uh... I don't think I'm
smart enough to fight with you.
Like that.
You're plenty smart
enough, but right now...
it's easier to make me
seem hyper-analytical.
This morning, it wasn't going
your way, so I was irrational.
- I never said you...
- I'm the one bothered by something.
I'm the one refusing to have
a reasonable conversation...
and I'm the one who
doesn't make sense.
- It's all a defense mechanism.
- Defense? Defense for what?
I don't know.
Something you haven't told me?
I don't tell anyone everything.
Then what are we doing?
We hit a speed bump weeks
ago and you react by disappearing.
We see each other all the
time. We talk, we sleep together.
There's a way to do all those
things and still disappear.
Why would I wanna do that?
Tell me.
Now, Neela, there are things
that should be kept private.
Not between two people trying to
figure out if they belong together.
- Now, I am comfortable with you.
- Well, maybe that's not enough.
Not when I have
to find out things...
important things, about
you from other people.
Oh, so that's
it, that's it, is it?
I'm not chatty enough
so you go snooping...
- trying to get under my skin?
- It's not like that.
Make me be what you think a boyfriend
should be? Sharing my emotions...
and talking about every stupid
damn thing that bothers me? No.
No!
Look, a terrible thing
was done to you.
I understand that.
I hate that it happened.
But somewhere in all of what's gone
on between us, one thing is clear...
we're not meant to be together.
It doesn't mean we don't
care about each other deeply.
You know, I truly believe...
there's something better
out there for both of us...
whenever we're ready for it.
Better?
Something more right.
- Northwestern, huh?
- Too good for County.
Well, what can I say, Frank.
I've seen how you care
for your patients here.
Dr. Morris says to make sure
they check another potassium...
- as soon as you get there.
- Thanks, Haleh.
We're gonna see you soon, right?
Not if I see you first.
Folks, it's only a mile away. You can
visit him when we're not on the clock.
Um...
Primary repair worked.
So I guess the world
can look forward to...
a gaggle of
olive-skinned kids...
with red hair and freckles.
You know, if that's
something that you want.
The life you lead, the things
that you have been through...
they define how you do your job.
The quality of...
The quality of your work.
Especially in a place like this.
So at the, uh...
At the end of the day, you
choose to, ahem, deny or deal.
And which do you choose?
It's evolving.
I'm evolving. Um...
All I know is that I know, um...
that there is a lot of
work that I need to do.
Can you be more
specific about that?
No.
Not with you.
Mrs. Taggart.
Hi. I'm Tony Gates.
I work with Sam.
I used to play.
You know, at Christmas
time, I'd play the carols.
It's all gone now.
Yeah, well, Sam wanted
me to get this back to you.
Well, she said
she was coming by.
Well, she, uh, can't
tonight. She's on a work call.
Uh-huh.
- And you are?
- I am a friend.
A friend? Uh-huh.
- Do you smoke?
- No, ma'am. I don't.
That's too bad.
You're a good-looking
fella, though, aren't you?
Hmm. Must be
the lighting in here.
Do you know that out of
all these people in here...
I'm the youngest one
by about 15 years.
What the hell did I
do to deserve this?
I can't imagine.
I don't want her to stop coming.
So if she thinks that's
so, you tell her it's not.
Okay.
You know, Sam's
an amazing person.
She's very strong, she's
overcome a lot of obstacles.
You get to know her,
you'd be very proud.
- She hates me.
- No, she doesn't.
- Well, she thinks that I hate her.
- Then change that.
Sure.
Ta-da.
Change.
Well, it's up to you.
Have a good night.
Hey.
You're not lying, are you?
She's gonna come back tomorrow?
When Sam makes up her
mind, nothing stops her.
I love helping people.
You know, originally,
I wanted to be...
the first baseman
for the Chicago Cubs.
The thing I hate most about my job?
- Mm-hm.
- The smells.
Human body's got some
pretty interesting smells.
What's the dating life like? Ha.
Well, I'm not gonna tell you.
It's personal.
A patient is a patient. Um,
pain is pain. It's universal.
And I reached a point
about five years ago...
where I started to feel that
every day was the same thing.
And I'd had enough.
But I've been through
a lot of stuff since then.
And now...
I try to embrace the idea...
that everything that happens
has never happened before.
Like that saying that you can't
stand in the same river twice...
because by the time
that you come back...
it's not the same river.
And you're not the same man.
Anyway...
I look around this place now and I
can't imagine ever finding it boring.
Because right at the moment
that you think you've seen it all...
something happens that you
never could have expected.