So I was thinking of new ways
to generate business for the practice.
How about billboards, right?
What? Bad idea?
- I don't know, Sam.
- I mean, cut expenses, right?
I cut expenses. Even still,
profits are only up 2 percent, so...
I mean, the consults should help,
don't you think?
Yeah. Yeah, they should.
It's a lot of pressure.
You know, making these decisions.
A lot of pressure.
- Hey.
What are you doing here so early?
Running.
You're running like
you're trying to get someplace.
Naomi still isn't talking to me
outside of work.
- And that makes you run?
- I'm her friend.
Friends are supposed to talk.
So, yeah, I'm here.
Running.
Avoiding the office.
- I have to force myself to go in.
- Yeah, the office has been odd.
It's kind of like
we're going through a divorce,
only we have to keep living together.
- You running to get somewhere?
- No, l...
Do you think I'm old?
Tell me you did not sleep
with that temp.
You.
You slept with Jodie the temp.
Hey, it seemed like a good idea
at the time.
Yeah, well,
at least you're getting out there.
- Me? Two dates seems to be my limit.
- The cop?
He didn't call after our last date,
so I called him.
Left him a message,
a horrifying, embarrassing message.
Probably scared him off. Not that I care.
Now I'm glad to not be talking to him.
You know,
at least he didn't tell you you were old.
Although she did say that I was great.
ADDISON:
I'm fine.
COOPER: Ever feel like
you're not pulling your weight?
Everybody at work's
talking about you behind your back?
How the hell did my perfectly arched back
make you think of that?
Um...
Loofa to scrub, scrub to surgery, surgery
to patients, patients to my lack thereof.
We're drowning.
I'm drowning. I am making us drown.
And when the raft is sinking,
who gets thrown overboard first?
Oh, the pediatrician
who can't bring in the bucks.
Stay here and drown, I'm going to work.
- Dell? What are you doing here?
- I work here.
Wow.
Gotta pay the rent and eat and...
What are you doing here?
- Where's...? Where's the patient?
- I am the patient.
- I hurt my knee. It's not... Just...
- Okay.
You didn't wanna get this patched up
at the office?
You know, well, it's just silly.
It's just... They're very busy there.
You know, it's great.
It's great that you're here, you know?
Hospitals are great.
- Used to be my happy place.
- How's...? How's everyone?
You mean, how's Naomi?
Misses you.
CHARLOTTE: Montgomery.
- So you're good?
- Yeah.
- Right. Okay.
- Dell works here.
- Who?
Blond, receptionist.
He was the talking human
who greeted you
when you came to the practice.
Never mind.
Just had a surgeon called away
last minute.
Patient needs a myomectomy.
- You interested?
- Can't.
Got a whole fun-filled day
back at the ranch.
Come on, Montgomery.
You love surgery. It's messy and bloody
and you get to save lives.
Not to mention the coin.
I'll give you your own O.R. For a day.
No. No.
I am off to work.
Fun-filled work.
- There you go. Good luck to you. Okay.
- Thank you.
Hey. It took you 45 minutes
to write that prescription.
Consults are supposed to take
15 minutes max.
- You're a stalker, Sam.
- Fifteen minutes, 180 dollars.
Four consults an hour,
720 dollars each hour.
- Do I look like a money machine?
- You look like you could be working faster.
I agreed to do consults,
I did not agree to do malpractice.
And I'm not gonna write a prescription
every time someone's doctor or therapist
says they need Prozac.
I need to do a history, and...
Do the history, all right?
Just do it in 15 minutes.
Did someone shove rocks
down his pants on the playground?
He's compensating, all this bossiness.
I liked him better
when you were in charge.
I'm sleeping with him.
- You're...?
- Sleeping with the enemy.
- So let me get this straight...
- He went behind my back,
took my job, made me feel like crap...
- And now you're sleeping with him.
- Yeah. What's wrong with me?
What's wrong with you?
You're a traitor.
And you are letting him run all over you
and change everything about this place.
He sits there and he asks me questions
about the practice.
Like, what should he do.
As if these aren't things
I hadn't thought of when I was running it.
- He's using you as a sounding board?
- I can't stand it.
And Dell's gone and Addison...
I have no one to talk to.
And I know it's wrong.
It's just that Sam has this way...
You know what? I don't wanna know.
- No, no, no. It's that he really...
- I don't wanna hear.
- I'm just saying that he...
- Well, don't say.
ADDISON [ON TELEVISION]:
That's what we do.
We're a family,
and this practice is our home.
COOPER:
The life we save could be your child's.
SAM: Your wife's,
- Your husband's.
At Oceanside Wellness,
our family takes care of your family.
- Morning.
- Sorry, not in the mood.
Hey, Nai.
Hey, I saw Dell today.
He's working at St. Ambrose.
Dell's working at St. Ambrose?
- Coop, hey, morning.
- Not now. Can't talk.
- You're still talking to me, right?
- No time. No money, no time.
I'm gonna go do a surgery.
Surgery brings income.
It is messy and bloody
and a whole lot more pleasant
than being around here.
Okay, thanks. Okay.
"Okay, thanks."
"'Morning. How are you, Addison?"
"I'm great. And you?"
How are you, Mr. Scrub Cap?
You having a tough time?
I hate this time of year.
Brushfire season,
everyone's a little on edge.
- Panic attacks again?
- No. No blackouts, no nightmares.
Mostly I'm handling it good.
I was out at that the 1500-acre burn
in Santa Cruz last month.
Everyone made it out,
but it was a lot like...
Malibu. Yeah, I saw the news.
You should be proud of yourself
for making it through, though.
Posttraumatic stress
takes some people years.
Yeah, well, all that stuff you gave me,
herbs, exercises, acupuncture,
it helped, but the stress
started creeping up on me.
Every time
I saw my men go into the fire.
But you got through it.
I did, because I found something else
to help me cope.
So what's the problem?
I'm wearing bras and panties now.
I need you to cure me.
- Addison.
- Oh, hey, it's you.
SWAT guy.
Yeah. Hey, hey, listen,
about that message I left.
- Yeah, that was...
- Humiliating.
- No, I liked it.
- Yeah.
Oh, God, well, that explains a lot.
You torture women
to the point of them calling you
and leaving horrifying messages
because you like it.
- You're... You're sick.
- Yeah, I'm sorry.
I've been working like a dog.
I get on a case and...
I promise to do better.
- I came to woo.
- Woo?
- I got sprinkles.
- This is you, wooing?
This is me being charmed
by your rambling and incoherent message
- and asking you to lunch.
- Yeah. I'm off to surgery.
Don't write me off.
Get to know me.
VIOLET:
Okay. Your doctor sent over your file.
- You've been having trouble sleeping?
- On a good night I get four hours.
I figured sleeping pills might help.
Any idea of what's preventing you
from sleeping?
Two jobs, past-due bills, a teenage son.
Oh, a teenager.
That would do it right there, huh?
And how long has this been going on?
The insomnia?
Since my husband died last year.
- But lately it's worse.
- Anything changed?
Aren't you just supposed to
write a prescription?
Sure.
I think it's important to understand
what's behind the insomnia.
To talk about it.
I...
Yeah, I really...
- I just need to sleep.
- Linda, the medication will help,
but whatever's keeping you from sleeping,
it's not gonna take that away.
Talk to me.
See if I can help.
I'm afraid of him.
Afraid of whom?
My son. I think he's a sociopath.
He killed our dog.
I just... I found it in the garage.
He was wrapped in a blanket
and I think his neck was broken.
And it was just a little beagle.
Why do you think
Jesse would do something like that?
- I don't know.
- Did you ask him?
Yes. He just looked at me,
he gave this funny look.
He's the only one
who had access to the garage.
Is he ever violent?
Have you ever seen this before?
No. See, that's the thing. He was so...
When his father died, he changed.
He got cold.
Like he...
He doesn't react.
He doesn't laugh, he doesn't cry.
He just has this cold, hard stare. And l...
You know, he's my own son,
and I can't...
Everyone has their own way
of responding to grief.
It's not grief.
- I just need to sleep.
- I'd like to talk to him.
No. I really want those pills.
Linda, you don't need the pills,
you need some help.
Let me help.
[MONITOR BEEPING]
Fishing, the boat, the sun on the water.
If any of my guys find out,
it's gonna be the end of me. Done.
Keep trying to relax. Focus on fishing.
It doesn't work anymore.
I need the panties and bra.
How did this start, Frank?
It was just knee-highs
around the house at first.
And then I got my hands
on a mail-order catalog.
And pages and pages
of pretty little things.
Lace bras, silk panties,
garters.
I see what you mean.
I have to live with these guys
24 hours at a time.
I almost got caught twice already.
If they find out...
My credibility?
They won't trust me, they won't listen.
And if I have to look at a man's family and
tell them he's not coming home because...
Cross-dressing
could go to something deeper.
- Something a therapist could help with.
- No.
- I can't tell anybody else.
- Frank, l...
Please. Look, I trust you.
You helped me before,
I know you can help me now.
You have to or I'm done.
How'd it go?
The fibroid's history.
It was nice
to be back in the saddle again.
I have a newborn with a diaphragmatic
hernia being airlifted in.
Don't you have someone else?
I do have patients.
Double board-certified
neonatal surgeons
aren't exactly walking the streets,
Montgomery.
I hate to take you away
from all the fun at the office,
but on the bright side,
you get to save a life and work with me.
Okay, I'm in.
Charlotte, that newborn being airlifted?
You don't have somebody else.
- You knew I'd say yes.
- I hoped.
You're wooing me with surgery.
I am.
Hey, did you hear about Dell?
- He's nursing at St. Ambrose.
- So now you want to talk about Dell?
- Well, yeah.
- Naomi...
Hey, Nai, Addison's staying at the hospital
to do another surgery.
Could you cover her patients?
- Sure.
- Cool.
Sam. Good old boss Sam,
you'll be glad to know
- I have a new patient.
- Hey. One new patient.
Maybe we can build a new wing.
What about you?
Don't you have a consult?
I can't do it.
My morning consult? Major drama.
May take the rest of the day,
so cancel everyone else you had booked.
I know he's only a year old.
But you wait all this time to have a baby,
you want him to be perfect, and I'm...
I'm just really worried that he's...
That there's something wrong with him,
you know,
- with his head.
- His head?
- His head.
- What's wrong with his head?
It's big.
Not big for a 1-year-old-body big,
but big-for-anybody's-body big.
Babies are sometimes born
with large heads.
But if you give it some time,
they usually grow into them.
- It's not...
- It's a really big head.
Let's take a look.
Hey there, little fella.
[BABY COOING]
You know, just to be on the safe side,
I'm gonna run some tests
and see if there's anything going on.
So your mom said it looked like
the dog's neck had been broken.
Any idea how that happened?
It was in your garage.
Any idea about that?
It was a beagle.
Right? Dodger?
Your mom said
you had it since you were 6.
Is that right?
Okay.
The dog's too loaded a topic.
Why don't we talk about your father.
Were the two of you close?
Did he coach any of your teams?
I hear you're a great baseball player.
Okay, I get it, you don't wanna be here.
A lot of people don't like to
talk about difficult things.
But I have a job to do.
And that is to find out
if there's a problem here.
And to do that, I need for us to talk.
About anything.
I want to get to know you, Jesse.
Can I go now?
Please?
NAOMl:
Dell?
Hey.
So you're working here.
- You look nice in your scrubs.
- What are you doing here, Naomi?
I just came by to say hi.
It's great to see you.
We've missed you. I've missed you.
I really can't talk right now,
I've got a ton of patients.
- Dell.
- I'm sorry, I gotta go.
I just saw this kid
who had a head the size of...
It was ginormous. It was huge.
Which is bigger, ginormous or huge?
- Who's the truant?
- Consult's son.
He won't talk so I'm letting him stew.
- Is stewing a real therapeutic technique?
- Usually works with you.
What's he stewing about?
His mother thinks
he killed the family dog.
Oh.
Step one, right? I mean, that's what
they say about serial killers. Am I right?
- Oh, he's not a serial killer.
- Not now.
- I don't know if he did it.
- Is the mom lying?
She believes he did it.
I don't know his side
because he won't talk to me.
His father's dead, his dog is dead.
He's got a lot of reason to be angry.
His mother thinks he's a sociopath.
She goes on the Internet,
- she puts together the signs.
- Is he?
I don't know.
I guess I could test him.
Give him the MMPI.
Be so much easier if he just had
a pipe bomb in his book bag, you know...
Do you know how rare
a true sociopath is?
You don't wanna be the one
that missed Columbine.
You don't wanna talk.
I get it.
It leaves me with a problem though.
I have concerns about you.
And I'm not comfortable
with just watching you walk out that door.
Don't talk to me, just fill this out.
True, false.
Or we can sit here all day.
Okay, just so we're clear.
This is not a date,
this is a sandwich between surgeries.
Point is, it's getting to know each other
without all that date crap.
Mm. Tell me about this case
you've been working on.
- The one that's kept you from calling.
- I watched two people die.
- It kind of made for a bad week.
- Yeah.
I've been having a run of those myself.
Not people dying,
just people not talking to me.
People not talking to each other.
All the people in my office
are walking around pissed off
and nobody's talking about it.
- It's why I'm here, cutting people open.
- Getting out your hostilities.
Actually, you put a scalpel in my palm
and I feel centered.
All the other problems in the world
just fall away.
- It's hard to explain.
- Well, you can explain it to me
tomorrow night when I take you out.
- You're taking me out?
- I am.
- On a date?
- Yes.
CHARLOTTE:
You're not going anywhere.
Pregnant lady with ovarian torsion.
O.R.'s ready.
- You up for it, Montgomery?
- Yeah.
- Yeah, no, go. Cut people open.
- All right, I'll see you tomorrow night.
- Tomorrow night.
- Okay.
- You know, we could use you.
- Sorry. Excuse me?
Here.
You could be a surgeon,
I can keep the O.R. Full
and the board happy.
It's a symbiotic relationship.
- I have a job, Charlotte.
- You're a surgeon, Addison.
I'll think about it.
Big.
- How big?
- Like Mount Rushmore big.
I'm thinking, like, Paget's disease
or acromegaly or tuberous sclerosis.
I mean, this poor kid's gonna be, like,
a bobblehead if I can't fix him.
At least he won't be wearing a bra.
Unless it's to give
his head more support.
I keep telling you, it's not that unusual.
It's a coping mechanism
and you said he's coping.
- Yeah, but...
- I got a maybe sociopath
who maybe killed his dog
who maybe I should lock up.
You got a bra and panties.
You wanna trade?
- What happened with your test?
- It's inconclusive.
Does he like to smash things? Yes.
Does he feel anger? Yes.
The only way to know
if he's a true sociopath
is to do a comprehensive clinical
evaluation and the kid's not talking.
So based on this test, he doesn't meet
the criteria for me to hold him.
He's not a clear danger to anyone,
there's not a credible threat.
Except I still don't know
what happened to the dog.
Does anyone
have anything helpful to say?
Yeah,
at least he doesn't have a big head.
Or wear panties.
ADDISON: Resected the cyst,
just have to detorse this ovary.
CHARLOTTE: Montgomery,
they need you in NICU now.
The baby you worked on before,
O2 sats are dropping.
ADDISON: Crap.
Okay, let me just finish ligating this vessel.
Let me just take a look at the baby,
make sure it's okay.
Done.
Go ahead and close her up.
Doctor.
Oh, she's fine.
I untwisted the ovary, removed the cyst.
The baby's doing well.
- They're gonna be okay.
- Is there any way I can...?
- Not now, maybe later.
- What if I just...?
I'm in the middle of an emergency,
but I'll come back to you.
- How many surgeries have you done?
- Four.
- What about your knee?
- Can't even feel it.
Wow, you're a badass.
What, all you thought I did
was deliver babies?
NAOMl:
Okay.
SAM:
Hey, Nai.
So what's up?
I just finished going over the budget.
I can't believe there's all this paperwork.
I feel like I'm doing six jobs now
and none of them is seeing my patients.
You know, well,
it's tough being the boss.
What do you think about hiring
a marketing consultant?
If you think it'll help.
- Right. All right, thanks.
- Okay.
Can you believe him?
I mean, does he not think that I did the
exact same things when I was in charge?
Only I wasn't stupid enough
to try and do it all by myself.
At least I had Dell to help manage,
to run things, so that I could see patients.
I saw him today. Dell, at the hospital.
- It was really weird...
- I have a patient.
I gotta go.
So you're telling me he's normal?
One test over one hour
is not gonna answer that.
But this does evaluate personality
and psychopathology...
What about the dog?
He won't talk to me about that right now.
But maybe if the two of you
came in together...
No, I can't confront him.
You told me to bring him in here.
You said that you could help me.
And now he knows
that I'm scared of him, it's...
- No, I didn't tell him.
- He's smart.
You think he's not gonna
figure this out?
Look, l...
He had that dog for ten years and he...
He didn't shed a tear when it died.
He snapped its neck
and hid it in the garage,
and he didn't shed a tear
because he didn't care.
- Linda...
- I can't sleep.
I can't sleep.
I lie awake with a...
With a hammer under my pillow
because I'm afraid
of what he's gonna do to me.
And now you're telling me
that you can't help me?
You told me you would help me.
You should have given me those pills
because I could have buried it.
I need you to help me. Please.
I'm afraid of my own son.
Dell.
Um, I know you were busy before
and had to see some patients.
- And I thought you might be getting off.
- I'm doing a double shift.
I took you for granted.
I didn't listen and I should have.
You were trying to help me
and I didn't let you.
I want you to come back.
I have a job, Naomi.
A place where I'm respected.
The practice has been adrift, Dell.
Since you left, I've been adrift.
You know, I'm not talking to Addison.
Barely talking to Sam,
and Violet doesn't wanna hear from me.
You're not there to talk to.
No. No, I'm here.
Doing things I love and learning a lot
from people who aren't afraid to teach me.
- Dell.
- I'm working, okay?
I work here.
Excuse me.
I think he's happy here, Nai.
Seems like a lot of people
are happy here.
- Just trying to do my part.
- That's nice.
Thanks for doing that for me
when I was in charge.
You never asked, Naomi.
That's the problem. You never asked.
- You're in a good mood.
- Your Montgomery is a real star.
Cash cow for me today.
She really making me look good.
I'm glad someone does.
Stop moping. I don't like moping sex.
I have a kid with a big head,
who as it turns out
has nothing wrong with him.
Except he's gonna be mocked and ridiculed
and looked down on for the rest of his life.
- And that's your fault?
- No, that's me.
I'm the one who doesn't fit in,
who's gonna be first out of the practice,
because they don't want me on their team.
I'm the big-head kid.
Oh, my God, you're pathetic.
You are crazy and pathetic.
A big head is not a problem,
it's a virtue, moron.
You know who had a big head?
Lincoln, JFK, Elvis, Einstein.
Plenty of people have big heads
and they don't sit and mope
that they have a big head.
So don't you sit and mope
that you're a pediatrician.
Do your job, do it well,
and screw everyone else.
You're the big-head kid.
More power to you.
Can we get our clothes off now? Hm?
SAM: Oh, I rescheduled your consults
for tomorrow.
No.
- No?
- Life is not 15 minutes, Sam.
This woman and her son
cannot be fixed in 15 minutes.
Well, I'm sure you did everything
that you could.
Not yet.
Tomorrow, I'm going to the kid's school.
I'm talking to his teachers
and his counselors.
And I'm trying to get answers to the
questions he won't talk to me about today.
Cost effective? No.
But if it helps the kid...
I'm sorry if this does not fit into
the new way of doing things.
- Where's the fire?
- It's no joke. A fire captain, he's in the ER.
[SIRENS WAILING]
Hey, Pete.
- Hey.
- What are you doing here?
Firefighter patient. I got paged.
What about you?
- You've been here all day.
- Yep.
You ever gonna
come back to the practice?
Maybe, one day.
- See you.
- Good luck.
Dr. Montgomery, the ovarian torsion you
fixed, her pressure's down to 80 over 40.
- Post-op crit's 26 and dropping.
- She's bleeding out.
- What about the baby?
- It's in distress.
- Open the O.R.
- Extensive partial-thickness burns,
but he won't let anybody touch him
except for you.
He's over here.
I'm here, Frank.
- Couldn't let anyone see me.
- Okay.
Get a blood gas kit
and run a carboxyheme level.
I need chem panel, CBC and chest x-ray
and set me up for a subclavian.
Five-story blaze.
Beam came down.
Everybody get out okay?
[CHOKING]
You're not getting air, Frank.
Just stay with me.
Hang on.
Almost there.
[GASPS]
You're gonna be okay.
No.
I'm done.
Are they okay?
Uh. Your wife had some post-op bleeding.
But she's safe
and the baby should be fine.
When you came out of surgery before,
you said they were fine.
They were, but your wife started
hemorrhaging. I had to go back in.
It's not because
you ran out to some other surgery?
No.
- No, it's not.
- What about now?
You're saying she's fine now,
but how do I know?
Right now, your wife,
she's doing as well as she can.
She's a fighter.
She's gonna come through this.
What's her name?
- Excuse me?
- My wife's name.
I mean, you keep talking about
"she" and "her" and "your wife."
And you're
running up and down this hall,
and you're popping in,
and you're cutting people open.
And you're talking about her
like you know her,
but you haven't mentioned her name.
I...
- I don't know her name.
- It's Heather.
Her name's Heather. And this is
the third time she's been pregnant.
We lost two babies before.
She keeps redecorating the nursery
hoping that that's gonna change things.
It's red now. Who...
Whoever heard of a red nursery?
But her students... Her students told her
that it would be good luck.
She wanted to believe them.
You operated on her twice today.
You should have known her name.
PETE:
You're doing well, Frank.
A few weeks,
you should be up and around.
Then what? I told you, I'm done.
- I can't believe that's true.
- I'm resigning.
These guys depend on me.
They can't feel comfortable with me
if they think I'm a freak.
We all feel stress, Frank,
you more than most.
But you know what?
You found a way to deal with it.
Some people drink too much,
some eat too much, some people run.
I wish I had a thing that worked.
When everything around you is falling
apart and you need to keep it together,
a thing is good.
So I wear a bra and panties forever.
Maybe if you talked to someone,
maybe if you didn't shoulder all of that
stress yourself, it might be better.
Fine, I'll go to therapy.
But it's still too late.
You run into burning buildings
and save lives.
How many of your men
have you gone in after?
If it's me,
I don't care what you're wearing,
as long as you get me out alive.
Six surgeries in 24 hours.
What's it like?
- To be a surgeon?
- To be the best?
I came here to get away
from a bunch of people not talking,
and I ended up
being the one not talking.
Not talking to a single patient.
I cut them open, sewed them up,
and I didn't have any idea
who they were.
That's not a doctor.
And it's certainly not the best.
Thanks for the job offer, Charlotte,
but I have a job.
A home.
I've run every lab I can think of,
there's nothing wrong with Miles' head.
So it's...
- That's just the way he is.
- Your son's fine and he may grow into it.
What if he doesn't?
You must think I'm awful.
I should be elated that my son is fine,
it's just...
- He's different.
- Yes.
Me, I was slow.
The other kids could all run faster,
I hated P.E.
My best friend, Brad,
he had two teeth that never grew in.
He's the CEO
of a Fortune 500 company now.
And I see a lot of kids, and they're all
different in one way or another.
- He'll be picked on.
- Maybe.
Maybe he'll be a bully,
maybe he'll be president.
You know a lot of the presidents
had big heads: JFK, Lincoln.
He's on Mount Rushmore now.
Thanks.
JESSE:
You made my mom cry.
What did you say to her?
I told her that I didn't think I could help you
if you wouldn't talk to me.
What are you doing here?
- Trying to figure out what you won't tell me.
- No. You let this go.
My job is to help people,
and I want to help you.
And I am not gonna stop
talking or asking questions
until you answer some.
What happened to the dog?
What happened to the dog, Jesse?
Jesse, you loved that dog, didn't you?
You loved that dog, you didn't shed a tear,
and I wanna know why.
- Tell me why.
- Do you know how much it costs
to put a dog down?
Do you? He had cancer.
It was thousands of dollars to treat him,
and she was gonna do it.
My dad's cancer almost bankrupted us.
But she was gonna do it
because she couldn't bear to see
another thing die again.
She didn't want me
to have to go through it again.
We couldn't afford it.
It was 385 dollars to put him down,
we didn't have that either.
So I did what I had to do.
My dog.
I killed him.
Because my dad said
I had to be the man.
I had to be responsible.
WOMAN 1: The schedules.
WOMAN 2: Okay. All right.
- Still here?
- Just leaving.
Naomi wants me to come back.
She misses you.
She just wants me to come back for her,
not for me.
Dell, when a friend asks you
to step up, you do it.
It's just what you do.
You're part of the family.
Ha. Yeah, I'm the part of the family
they're embarrassed by.
That is not true. You ran away.
You got your feelings hurt
and you ran away.
Now, you may have reason,
but hiding out here,
avoiding your problems,
not talking to the people that need you?
How are you ever
gonna get what you want?
Talking is important.
- Okay.
- Because when you don't talk,
- when you don't say what's on your mind...
- What are you talking about?
I mean, you told me
not to talk to you about Sam,
and when I tried to talk to you
about Dell, you walked away.
Because you were using me
as your Addison.
I'm not your Addison. Not anymore.
I used to be, before Addison got here.
And then you just started
talking to her.
You hurt my feelings.
And I know I'm a therapist
and I'm supposed to say that it's all right,
but it's not all right.
And you can't just
make me your Addison again
and think that makes it all better.
Work it out with Addison.
And for God's sake,
stop sleeping with Sam.
Unless you can tell him
how wrong this all is.
His stealing your job
and using you as a sounding board.
And then come talk to me.
When you want to talk to me.
You came back.
- Yeah.
- So is this the new you?
You gonna hide out and do surgery
and leave your old friends behind?
I wish I felt like my old friends
were my old friends.
You did what you had to.
Telling Sam,
breaking your word to Naomi.
I never said that.
I thought I should say that.
Thanks.
Please.
- Well, this is nice.
- It's nice. Yeah.
Us as friends.
We're past all that, you know,
awkwardness.
- Yeah.
- It's good.
And if we keep at it for a few months,
we could be old friends.
Dell.
SAM:
Yeah.
- I hear you're in charge now.
- Yeah.
- What's this?
- It's a list of demands.
- What I need to come back.
- Patients?
Supervised. I need the hours
for my midwife's license.
- Sorry, no.
- Sam.
- Hey, he walked out.
- And it's been worse since he's been gone.
No, we can't afford it.
Could you give us a minute, please?
- Naomi, we can't add staff...
- I am talking now.
You took my job.
You went behind my back,
conspired with my best friend,
took over the practice,
and now you think you can just
unilaterally make decisions, or worse,
run ideas by me
like none of it ever happened.
Well, guess what, Sam,
I don't wanna hear your ideas.
I'm not your sounding board
and I am not going to help you.
You find somebody else.
At least I was smart enough
to find the person
who is standing right outside your door.
You start today. You see patients
only supervised by Naomi
or Addison or Pete, and we see.
- I can live with that.
- You resume being office manager.
Vendors, filing, equipment leasing,
scheduling, ordering supplies.
That's yours.
That's what I need from you.
And one last demand. It's not on the list.
I want scrubs in a better color. I'm a man,
I'm not wearing those damn pink scrubs.
Welcome back, Dell.
Good. You're here.
Can you get your clothes off?
- What's wrong?
- Nothing.
There's something wrong, I can tell.
We don't do the talking thing, Cooper.
Yes, we do. You yelled at me,
you confirmed I had a big head,
made me feel better.
Let me yell at you, make you feel better.
I'm not letting you get a piece of this
until you start talking.
I offered Addison a job
and she turned me down.
Can you take your clothes off now?
You like knives, I like guns.
- Centered?
- Mm.
Wow. All that not talking.
Talking is overrated.