It's impossible to describe
the panic that comes over you
when you're a surgeon
and your pager goes off
in the middle of the night.
Your heart starts to race.
Please don't be mine.
Your mind freezes.
- Your fingers go numb.
-  Not mine.
Wake up!
- I'm up.
- They're paging you.
You're invested.
I'm sleeping!
They're someone's mom,
someone's dad, someone's kid.
And now it's on you.
Because that someone's
life is now in your hands.
Robbins, Karev's with your
patient. Torres, come with me.
We have a 15-year-old female,
she fell off the roof of her house.
- Now, I think that...
- She's gonna be OK, right?
I just need to know,
is she gonna be OK?
And this is her mother. Mrs. Boyd, I
need to bring Dr. Torres up to speed.
She's never been in
any accident before,
she's never even
broken any bones.
Oh. You paged me here at 4:00am
for a couple of broken bones?
More like 50.
As surgeons,
we're always invested
in our patients.
Laura Young, 30 weeks pregnant. Car
accident, head CT showed a subdural.
Shepherd's coming in. Baby's
in distress, OB on its way.
- It really hurts!
- Hold on. Move the wand up.
- What?
- OK, baby's brain
is hemorrhaging.
She needs a crash-c while
Shepherd handles the bleed.
Grab the wheel
and start running.
But when your
patient's a child...
Get another unit of packed
cells, meet me in the OR.
- You're not just invested...
- - We need the OR!
- You're responsible.
- We're already on our way.
There's only one OR
prepped this time of night.
- Which is why we need it.
- Mine's got a subdural.
- Fifty broken bones!
- Stroke in the womb!
- Oh!
- Whoa!
All right. Get another
OR ready now!
Responsible for whether
or not that child survives,
has a future.
And that's enough
to terrify anyone.
- What's her status?
- Mom's heart rate and BP
has been fluctuating,
but she's ready for you.
Let's prep her for a craniotomy.
Apgar's only four.
Get to NICU now.
- Drain's in a good position.
- She's breathing over the vent.
- Maybe we should extubate her.
- But watch for apnoeic episodes
and keep an eye out for her CBC.
Too much blood
draining from her head.
- What time is it, Karev?
- Uh, half past eight.
Half past eight. I've
been awake for five hours
and my day hasn't started.
Rough way to start your morning.
A stroke before you're even
born. Rough way to start a life.
Yeah.
Hey. I brought you some coffee.
- Oh. You already have one.
- I want your coffee,
need your coffee.
When we see Cristina, she's
gonna be mad. Mad at me
for not paging her here.
Possibly mad at you
for not waking her up
either. I'm handling this.
Do not engage her,
do not provoke her.
Simply ignore. All right?
That's your plan? Ignore
the scalpel-hungry animal?
Yep, until I come up
with something better.
OK. I know this is the first time on a
Peds rotation with me for some of you.
Not for others.
But I wanted you to understand
that I run my Peds unit
differently than you're used to.
This is not general
surgery in miniature.
These are the tiny humans.
These are children.
They believe in magic.
They play pretend.
There is fairy dust
in their IV bags.
They hope and they cross their
fingers and they make wishes.
And that makes them
more resilient than adults.
They recover
faster, survive worse.
They believe.
In Peds, we have...
miracles and magic.
In Peds, anything is possible.
- Morning, Dr. Robbins.
- Morning,
Dr. Wallace.
You've introduced yourself
to Mr. and Mrs. Boyd?
Yes. Reminds me
of Hillary at that age.
Such an overachiever.
Dr. Yang, why don't you present?
Yeah.
Excuse me, little...
doctor boy.
Uh, Hillary Boyd, 15 years
old. Fell off the roof of her house.
Fifty-two acute
fractures were diagnosed
when she was
admitted last night.
An intricate and extremely
challenging ORIF surgery
was performed by Dr. Torres
and Dr. Hunt this morning.
- Before rounds.
- Thank you, Dr. Yang.
If she fares well enough
today, I'd like to go in tomorrow
to repair her
subtrochanteric fracture.
Can anyone tell me the proper dosage
of ceftriaxone for a pediatric patient?
- Fifty milligrams per kilogram per day.
- - Mm-hmm.
Dr. Wallace, can you tell me
the proper dose for this patient
if she were 42 kilograms?
Two point one grams per
day, if you carry the decimal.
- OK, who's presenting?
- I am, Dr. Robbins.
- Proceed.
- Wallace Anderson.
Ten years old, almost 11.
Been here for seven months, in
and out over the past two years.
Suffers from short gut syndrome,
which means he can't absorb nutrition.
Exactly. Dr. Percy?
Fifteen intestinal surgeries to date
plus a bowel lengthening procedure
which helped for a while,
but recently had to go back
to being fed through TPN.
- Yum.
- How'd he do this morning?
We covered some advanced
algebraic conversions.
Dr. Robbins helps me with
math and science homework
- by letting me go on rounds.
- Fascinating.
We try to keep his life
as normal as we can,
even living in a hospital.
But I can skip my
homework on Friday, right?
- Since it's my birthday?
- Since it's your birthday.
What about Dr. Robbins?
It is her birthday, too.
I'm afraid I can't skip
my homework, Wallace,
but I can come celebrate
with you like I promised.
Dr. Robbins.
We've requested a
meeting with Chief Webber
and a representative
from the hospital board.
And we'd like you there, too.
OK.
They didn't give you any indication
as to what this meeting was about?
You know as much as I do.
You treated their son, right?
You better pray you didn't
do something to piss them off.
God knows this hospital can't
afford another misstep right now.
It's a pleasure to
see you again, Paul.
Bethany, you look lovely.
We didn't think Wallace
would see his ninth birthday,
let alone his tenth.
And now this week, his eleventh.
Which is why we'd like to offer Seattle
Grace Mercy West's Peds Program
a gift... of 25 million dollars.
Twenty-five... million?
Half to research, to continue searching
for a cure for Wallace's condition,
and half to the hospital itself.
Uh... I... I'm...
I mean...
- Twenty-five million dollars?
- Happy birthday, Arizona.
I knew Wallace's parents were wealthy,
but not 25 million dollars wealthy.
That's
libraries-named-after-you money.
Save-babies-in-Africa and
has-dinner-at-the-White-House type money.
People don't give
me that kind of money.
You have an unfair advantage,
you work with children.
Oatmeal, side of fruit,
wheat toast, hold the butter.
- Thank you.
- That money is gonna make
such a difference for so many
patients. It's really amazing.
Maybe I should start
doing more cleft palate kids.
Everyone's a sucker for those.
Cheese omelet, extra butter,
cinnamon toast, crispy bacon.
- Mine!
- Twenty-five million
is cool, right?
- Best birthday gift ever.
- Birthday gift?
Yeah, because
the money's a gift.
It's for the hospital,
not Arizona,
but since your
birthday's on Friday...
Um... How does Little Grey know
about your birthday and I don't?
Birthdays are just
days like any other days.
I don't like them, don't
celebrate, no big deal.
Twenty-five million?
That's a big deal.
Crap, I'm gonna be late.
I will see you there.
Mm-hmm. Hmm.
She's downplaying it, right?
I'm her girlfriend. I have to
do something for her birthday.
- Yes.
- No.
Of course you do.
Oh, a surprise party!
Whoa, whoa. Bad idea.
Surprise parties are
hostile. They're dark.
People jump out
and scream at you.
They never come to any good.
Karev.
Morning, chief.
When you're free, come find me.
What's that all about?
He fired me. I
refused to be fired.
So I say hello to him every
morning and he says not a word.
- Sounds familiar.
- Haven't heard from Stevens?
Not a word.
They'll come around
when they come around.
Chief, you need me?
Uh... I wish I didn't have to
saddle you with
this, Karev, but...
- What is all this?
- As Stevens left
no forwarding address
and as you are
officially her next of kin,
this is her unpaid balance
of her medical bills.
Unpaid balance? I don't get
it. We work at the hospital.
And insurance doesn't
take care of everything.
I'm sorry. Accounting's been
pressuring me since the merger
and I can't ignore
it any longer.
What's yours in for?
Delivered her yesterday,
stroked out at ten
weeks premature.
- Yours?
- Born with its insides
on the outside.
Two days post-op.
Resilient little guy.
More bleeding overnight.
- Should we try FFP?
- At this point,
we should try anything.
Get me a repeat MRI and page
me if she becomes bradycardic
or starts having apnoea
spells. I'll be on rounds.
- Hey.
I was picking up some
labs from Dr. Bailey
and I saw you had these waiting.
Thought I'd bring them
by, save you the trip.
Thanks.
Are you OK?
I overheard a little bit of your
conversation with the chief...
I'm trying to save a baby
here. Get out of my face.
Oh.
Got it.
- He's still sleeping?
- No.
- He had a bad night.
- I can still go on rounds.
- I feel better. Just give me a second.
- You know what?
How about if you
take a rest for now,
and you can join me for
evening rounds instead?
OK.
He listens to you more
than he does to me.
Well, yeah. She's a doctor, Mom.
And you're just... a mom.
Oh. OK. How about
you close your eyes
and you let me do
what moms do, OK?
Bad dreams, bad dreams, go away.
Good dreams, good
dreams, here to stay.
Bad dreams, bad dreams, go away.
Good dreams, good
dreams, here to stay.
You have to do it
three times for it to work.
One more.
I want you to repeat his chemistries
and get an abdominal series.
He's had bad nights before, but I want
to make sure we're not missing anything.
- How's she doing?
- Touch and go. How's the baby?
- Same.
- Any news from the family?
I left a message.
Haven't heard back yet.
ICP is elevated,
BP won't stabilize.
A hundred mikes of
fentanyl, please. Laura?
Laura, can you hear me?
My baby... Where's my baby?
- She's struggling,
but hanging on.
- Can I see her?
Sorry, no. You're
too unstable to move.
- And so is the baby.
- I just want to hold her.
Please, I want to hold my baby.
- I need you to stay calm, OK?
- What if she dies,
before I get to
hold her? She can't.
She can't go before
she's ever even been held.
It's OK, it's OK...
Push ten of diazepam and
get me some supplemental O2.
Crap. 911. It's her baby!
She's bradying down
and she lost access.
- I'll start a CPAP.
- Dr. Robbins?
- Not now.
- You'll want to see this.
- It's the X-rays
on Wallace Anderson.
- Show me.
- See? He has dilated
loops of bowel.
- Flip.
Flip.
Damn it. Damn it. He has
another bowel obstruction
- and he's not compensating.
- I got this, go.
- A nurse just checked that.
- A nurse checked it.
I'm gonna check it. Three other people
in the OR will check it. We're thorough.
Honey, please let
them do their jobs.
Mr. and Mrs. Boyd?
We thought you should know
that Hillary's tox
screen from yesterday
showed signs of psilocybin
in her bloodstream.
- What does that mean?
- Well,
it means that when
she fell from the roof,
- she was...
- Shrooming.
- Yeah.
- Magic mushrooms.
- What?
- Hillary!
- Mushrooms?
- Can everybody
please chill out?
- What in God's name
were you thinking?
- I can't believe...
You're a disappointment, young
lady. A big, big disappointment.
Dad, please, OK? The last
thing I am is a disappointment.
I get straight A's.
I'm on honor roll.
I run the student council. I
basically am the school paper.
I tutor kids with
reading problems.
OK? I'm every parent's dream
come true, including yours.
I was exploring the
bounds of my consciousness
with the help of a mushroom. I made
a calculated risk going on the roof.
Falling off, well, that was
a low-probability event.
Even low-probability
events occasionally occur,
and this one did.
So, yeah, you're
bummed I miscalculated
'cause it reminds you
of your own fallibility.
I'm bummed, too.
Let's just leave it at that.
Cap refill's five
seconds. Push one of epi.
It's not working. Heart
rate's down to the 60s.
- Starting compressions.
- Can I help?
Doubt it. At this rate, this kid's
not gonna last more than an hour.
She's only 30 weeks.
Pretty young to survive.
So, what? You're just gonna
stand there and watch her die?
- Pretty much.
- That sucks!
It is what it is. It's protocol.
Beeping drives me nuts.
- That...
- Kid's gonna die.
Deal with it or get out.
Hey there, girl.
I got you. Yeah.
It's OK. You're not alone.
No, you're not.
You're not alone.
Wait. Hold on.
Are you saying you can't do
more surgery on him or you won't?
It's not a question of if I can.
It's whether or not I should.
In my opinion,
Wallace isn't strong enough
to handle another operation.
But with surgery, how
long would he have then?
I'm not confident that he'll
even make it off the table.
But if he did, how long?
- I strongly advise against...
- How long?
Maybe two months.
I'm... sorry,
but the moment that we've
been fighting for two years...
it's here.
So you need to
prepare yourselves,
and you need to prepare Wallace.
You think I've been pouring
all this money into research
so you can find a cure
for some other kid? No!
- You have to do this surgery.
- Mr. Anderson...
You buy our son two more months!
You buy him more time so
that we can buy him a cure!
I'm sorry.
What are we gonna do?
Robbins.
These aren't people
who hear the word "no."
If they want surgery for their
son, they'll get surgery for their son,
whether or not
you're the one to do it.
You've been with
this boy since day one.
I believe you can
do this successfully.
Don't walk away now
unless you know beyond a
shadow of a doubt that you can't.
- The surgery's
a bad idea, chief.
- But is it impossible?
In your hands,
is it impossible?
- OK.
- OK?
OK. I'll do it.
I'll try.
- Oh, is that the preemie?
- Yeah. I was just...
I tried everything.
I just thought maybe somebody
should hold her before she...
- Kangaroo.
- What?
The way you're holding the
baby, it's called a Kangaroo hold.
There's been cases where the
Kangaroo has helped babies thrive.
But look, Karev. Look at
the numbers. Look at this.
- Huh. Heart rate's going up.
- Yeah, it is.
And her temperature is normal.
Karev, you may have just
kick-started this baby's entire system.
Just by holding her?
- Take off your shirt.
- What? No. Take off your shirt.
No, no.
The Kangaroo hold
is most effective
when there's
skin-on-skin contact.
It's usually the mom, but
you're gonna have to do.
I'm not kidding!
Take off your shirt!
Looks like you used pretty much
every piece of hardware in the hospital.
Makes you think twice
about shrooming on a roof.
Some mouth on this one. If I
talked to my parents like that...
My father would've... You
don't even want to know.
I had perfect grades.
Perfect record.
I said whatever I wanted,
did whatever I wanted.
Parents couldn't
do a thing about it.
Wanna hear about my childhood?
No? OK. I'll just... think
about it quietly in my own head.
Nail's in. Everything's
tight. Let's take a look.
Fantastic.
End-tidal CO2 just
dropped from 34 to 22.
Come on, give me
a break here, Hillary.
She has a new murmur.
- An air embolus in her heart.
- - Flood the field with saline.
Bone wax, page Cardio
and set up a chest tray.
And put her in
Trendelenburg. I can aspirate it.
No, no. We wait for Cardio
and we try to find the source.
It'll take me 30 seconds. It might
take Cardio half an hour to get here.
I've done this before!
I know what I'm doing!
She could arrest at any moment!
Dr. Yang, no! End of discussion!
See, it's the
skin-to-skin contact.
The baby can feel
your warmth better,
sense your heartbeat better.
See that? The baby's own
heart is picking up in response.
Karev, what are you doing?
He's saving a baby's
life, that's what.
Dr. Bailey, I... Oh.
No shirt. He's wearing no shirt.
- Have you started to lactate?
- Bailey made me!
Is this the room for the calendar
shoot? I was told it was downstairs.
That's enough. Everybody out.
Let Karev do what
he's doing in private.
- What is he doing, exactly?
- Out.
Out.
This is ridiculous.
You're wasting time here.
We should deal with
the heart problem.
We're following protocol.
Cardio's on its way,
and we can find the source
of the embolus this way.
Screw it.
Dr. Yang, the
patient is not coding.
- You're not qualified
to do this.
- Opening the left chest.
- Yang, really?
- Turn on the fluoro.
- Dr. Yang!
- Will someone
step on the fluoro,
or do you want
me to go in blind?
Dr. Yang, put down that scalpel!
- Thank you.
- Cristina!
- Scissors.
- Cardio's here, Yang.
It's done. I'm done.
Air embolus out.
- The patient was crashing.
- She was not crashing.
It was a procedure I've done
before. I handled it, she's fine.
What if she wasn't?
You could've lacerated her
heart or cut the phrenic nerve.
She could have
died on that table.
It would have been your license!
All so you could
prove what, exactly?
I did it to stabilize the patient.
You were watching her vitals drop.
Waiting for a CT surgeon,
who would have taken a more
minimally invasive approach.
I could've done a
thoracotomy myself
if I had thought
it was indicated.
I've been around the
block once or twice!
I kind of know what I'm doing!
- I'm aware of that,
I was just...
- You just thought every...
You just thought everything
would be better if you took charge.
You know I have to
report this to the chief,
at a time when he is scouring
this place for people to fire.
Well, he's not gonna fire me.
Oh.
Of course not, 'cause
you're invincible!
He's not firing me because the
last time I did an open thoracotomy
for an embolus was
with him, in his OR.
Only he was giving me
words of encouragement,
not screaming in my ear!
For the record,
you rocked in there.
Hunt's jealous he
didn't do it himself.
Shut up.
OK. You won't believe what
just happened in surgery with...
Hey. You OK?
Tell me I'm great.
- What?
- I need for you
to tell me I'm great.
- You're great.
- I mean really tell me.
Because I'm about
to go in on a surgery
I'm not sure I should
be going in on,
and I can't think
like that, right?
I can't go into the
OR feeling like... this.
So... I need you
to tell me I'm great.
Make me... Make me hear it.
You are great.
You... are... great.
Thank you.
Hey, there. You ready to go?
I'm gonna take you
to the OR myself.
I've been here a while now.
And I've seen kids
go home and go away.
Like Evan, the kid from down
the hall, with asthma, last month?
He died the day before he
was supposed to be discharged.
- You're not Evan.
- And Chloe, the heart girl?
She was here for three
weeks before she died.
- No one says you're gonna die.
- I've been here for seven
months.
I've been here the longest of
anyone on the floor, by double.
- Wallace...
- They say it's
like going to sleep.
Maybe it is.
But what if I go to sleep
and I have nightmares?
More traction, please?
Damn it. The
mesentery's really friable.
Percy, a little help
on the suction.
This is not a good idea.
This surgery was
not a good idea.
Can we get a washcloth
for Dr. Robbins?
- No, it's fine.
- Just take a moment.
Thank you.
Pickups, please.
- I left two messages.
- I'm sorry. I was in surgery.
- There were complications.
- I don't care.
I operated on Wallace
tonight when I knew better.
I keep retracing every
step, every suture,
going over it and over it.
- He didn't make it?
- He did. He's in recovery.
Not the point. What I
needed from you tonight
was a little support for
once, and you weren't here.
OK, you're scared.
So you're picking a
fight. You get that, yeah?
Yeah. Yeah, fine. Whatever.
But I've helped you
through crisis after crisis,
and once I thought that I
could come here and get...
- Let it go! It's done!
- I have every right to be mad.
You never pulled a stunt like
that with another attending.
I seem to recall Callie was
there, she still didn't stop me.
- Guys, not now.
- You took advantage of me
- and of our relationship.
- The kid was dying.
- What kid? What happened?
- You didn't hear?
- No, I didn't.
- Cristina performed
an unauthorized and unnecessary
thoracotomy against my orders.
- She what?
- I saved the patient's life.
- You didn't tell?
- I was going to,
but you were all,
- "Tell me I'm great."
- So it's my fault
Yang went rogue
- on a child?
- It wasn't rogue. It was brilliant.
It wasn't! You know? I'm done.
You got lucky today, Cristina,
and you may think
you can get away
with whatever you want,
but one of these days,
that luck is gonna run out.
Look... Wha...?
Oh! OK. So you're leaving, too?
Yes, because I have a patient.
Bitches.
All right, start
an epi drip now.
More irrigation. Keep it coming.
Give me a Babcock clamp.
I can't have a light... Can
somebody get me more light?
Pressure's dropping to
68 over 40. Pulse is racing.
Come on, Wallace.
- What happened
to the Anderson boy?
- He's in septic shock.
His body was too unstable,
what I said in the first place.
- Maybe I can help.
- No! No, you can't.
As long as you're
breathing over my shoulder,
I feel like I'm operating
on a stack of bills.
25 million dollar bills.
What I need to be
invested in is this kid.
So get the hell out of my OR!
More suction now!
How'd it go?
Damn it.
I'll let them know you
did everything you could.
Wait, Dr. Robbins. Don't we have
to tell the parents, let them know...?
- No.
- What do you mean, no?
I mean no.
I will not be speaking
to Wallace's parents.
Mr. Jennings and the
chief will take care of that.
As far as they are concerned
and as far as the
Andersons will be concerned,
I just killed their
son. I'm a liability.
Because if they were
to ask me, the truth is,
I'd tell them I did
just kill their son.
And they should
sue. I am responsible.
But that's not in the best
interest of the hospital.
- Am I close?
- I think we're
on the same page.
My luck will run out? It
has nothing to do with luck.
He's just being an ass.
I rocked that embolus.
- What?
- He cares about you.
- So?
- So maybe he's
a little bit right.
I get it.
I mean, I'm dying to get
out of this bed and cut.
But you did an unauthorized
procedure in an OR.
You're an amazing surgeon,
but if anything had gone wrong,
that would have
been your career.
He cares about your career.
He's in love with you.
I hate married, happy you.
Go to work. And don't cut
anybody open without permission.
You should have seen Yang in
that surgery. She was fearless.
And you are hopeless. She's
completely out of your league.
I'm hopeless?
I'm just stupid.
He's married. And have
I mentioned, a total ass
to pretty much
everyone at all times.
Karev? Did you
stay here all night?
Uh, yeah. I guess I did.
Go home, get some rest.
The nurse will take over for you.
No, I'm OK.
I'm good here.
You'd be good in
Peds, you know that?
You get invested, you
have good instincts,
you stick to your instincts.
You'd be good in Peds, Karev.
Yeah, I know, they say I
can have visitors tomorrow.
Cool. And...
Do you have any loopies?
Or whatever you have.
They only have me on two
milligrams of morphine at a time.
I know. How lame is that?
Hey, little pusher girl,
I'm Hillary's doctor,
and now I have Hillary's phone,
so I'm gonna give this
number to the police.
How lame is that?
- What the hell?
- OK.
I know you think you can do anything
and say anything and handle anything.
And that's almost true.
Except for the fact
that you fell off a roof.
Because you were
so high, that you, what,
you thought you could fly?
In surgery, you almost
died of a heart complication,
because your body is so
strung out from the crap
you've been putting in it
that it almost shut down.
That doesn't make you
smarter than everyone else.
It makes you an idiot.
The only reason
why you're alive is...
You know what? It's
'cause you're lucky.
So just... grow up.
Surprise!
I...
I... I...
Oh.
Told ya.
In retrospect, I realize now
that surprise parties are hostile.
This was a bad idea.
Please, stop crying. I'm sorry.
- I'm sorry about the party.
- Wallace died.
He was supposed
to be turning 11 today,
and instead, he's
lying in a morgue.
Oh... God.
Um...
I'm... I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. I can't stay.
No, it's OK. It's OK.
I'll take care of it.
You don't have to stay.
Just... I understand.
We're all surgeons.
Everyone will understand.
- All right.
- OK. Just go.
- Might as well
take advantage, huh?
- What?
Party's a dud, but at least
there's free booze, right?
Right.
Go ahead and gloat. Surprise
parties never come to any good.
- I think this party
speaks for itself.
- I don't get it.
The best birthday of my life
was the surprise party
that my parents threw.
I loved it. So much.
How old were you at this party?
- Seven.
- Mmm. Like I said.
Speaks for itself.
If there's anything we can get
for you, help you with, please,
just let us know.
I'd be happy to
oversee any packing
you need done from his room.
I've already arranged for a car.
It's ready to take
you home anytime.
- Arizona.
- Dr. Robbins, this is
a sensitive time.
- Let her be.
- Excuse me?
I said...
let her be.
It just doesn't feel real.
Any of it. It just...
Bethany, would
you like to see him?
I have to admit, I'm impressed.
I never would have pegged
you for the babysitting type.
- Are you heading home?
- No, I got the baby.
I'm sure somebody
else could take a shift.
I can't leave, OK?
Wow.
Are you really so messed up you
can't let one person be nice to you?
Ever?
I can't go.
I can't go home, I can't
get Izzie to call me back.
She's gone.
Could be dead, for all I know.
She left me with a
$200,000 medical bill and I...
I can't do anything about it.
About any of it.
But I can sit here and
I can hold this baby.
That I can do.
Then I'll sit here with
you for a little while.
Yang! Doctor...
Can I "Cristina" you,
or are we not there yet?
That's a no? OK.
Dr. Yang, let me
just tell you that
that was incredibly
hot in the OR yesterday.
Very, deeply hot. It
was hot! You are hot.
You're drunk and
you're in my room.
I am in fact inebriated,
but it's legal, you know,
and even if I wasn't,
you're the rule-breaker, which I
think we established in surgery.
Really? You think that was hot?
Would it be really,
really bad if I just...
'Cause of the embolus thing,
and you in general,
could I just...?
Uh, no! I'm involved.
I'm involved.
Time to meet your mommy.
She's so beautiful.
They say the bigger your
investment, the bigger your return.
- Surgery yesterday?
- Mm-hmm.
It wasn't just...
It was me. Can't you see that?
See what?
See what? I...
I can't just ignore what
happened, Cristina.
OK.
I'm sorry. Look, I know, um...
I know I overstepped.
Come home with me.
Please?
But you have to be
willing to take a chance.
OK.
Bad dreams, bad dreams, go away.
Good dreams, good
dreams, here to stay.
Bad dreams, bad dreams, go away.
Good dreams, good
dreams, here to stay.
Bad dreams, bad dreams, go away.
Good dreams, good
dreams, here to stay.
Stay.
- You have to do it three times for...
- - For it to work.
I know.
She is the reason that
we will still be giving
Seattle Grace Mercy
West 25 million dollars.
Not because of you
or your ass kissing.
It's because of her... her.
You have to understand...
you might lose it all.
The chief still
won't talk to me.
He will.
When did you become
such an optimist?
This is married, happy me.
Can we...? Are you OK to...?
Yes, we can.
But if you take that chance...
- Are you healed?
- I'm healed.
If you invest wisely...
the payoff might
just surprise you.
Oh! I'm awake!
I'm... See? I'm...
I'm totally awake.
I'm... There's... hats!
And gifts! And... And donuts!
And lingerie.
Really?
I love you.
You do?
I do.
I love you, too.