Previously on The Good Doctor...
You need to take a break, clear
your head. You need a vacation.
I'm gonna quit my job.
I'm not looking forward to
moving to Hershey, Pennsylvania.
I don't want kids, ever.
I've just been fired for physically
assaulting an employee.
Go ahead, chop us in half.
When will they wake up?
They should've already.
We were worried about you,
Jenny. So glad you're back.
I am gonna give you three
words. Try to remember them.
Apple. Ball. House.
Can you count back
from 100 by seven for me?
I'm going to Harvard, you know?
Ninety-three, 86, 79,
72, 65.
And what city are we in?
San Jose.
And what were those three words?
Apple. Ball. House.
Look out, Harvard.
We'll be doing a lot more
tests to know for sure,
but your heart
does sound better.
How's Katie?
You woke up before
her, so, too soon to tell.
There's virtually no
alpha or beta brain activity.
We must have missed something
during the separation surgery.
- We didn't.
- Katie's BP was steady,
sats were fine, regional blood
supplies were reconstructed.
Just like Jenny. Yet, she's
awake, Katie's in a coma.
Katie's got the
new sagittal graft.
A problem with blood flow in
that vein could cause her condition.
An MR angiogram should
tell us if the graft is open or not.
Hello.
I will proceed with
the angiogram.
Murphy, you've been gone for
two days. How about we start there?
Okay.
Just because you
talked to the president
doesn't qualify as permission.
Okay. Yes, I will
notify Dr. Melendez
next time I go on a road
trip with my girlfriend.
Amazing.
"Road trip"?
Dr. Glassman said you were
dealing with a personal crisis.
That is true.
Do you know the definition
of "personal crisis"?
Yes. A stage in a
sequence of events
at which the trend of all
future events is determined.
- A death, an illness.
- Yes.
No, not a road trip.
Okay.
You and Dr. Browne get
going on Katie's angiogram.
Unless, of course, you have any
personal emergencies to attend to.
No, my crisis is over.
Come in.
Hey.
How are the twins doing?
Jenny's in recovery.
Her numbers look
good, she's talking.
Katie not so good.
We need to talk about Murphy.
I told you he's
on personal leave.
Yeah, well, that's
not what he said.
You talked to him?
Yes. In the surgical
unit, five minutes ago.
There is the sagittal vein
graft we constructed for Katie.
It's open with good flow.
Graft is fine.
Which means we still have
no explanation for her coma.
Go in closer.
The middle cerebral vein, it
has low flow out of the brain.
You're thinking low flow
out means low flow in?
Yes, that is what I'm thinking.
We should look at the
arterial inflow phase.
We'd like to look at the
arterial inflow phase, please?
So, what'd you do on your trip?
Sometimes, when
we take a road trip,
we're running away
from something.
I kissed Lea.
And Dr. Glassman is mad at me.
What's he mad at you about?
It's almost entirely blocked,
and there's a malformation
in the circle of Willis.
Katie is barely getting
any blood to her brain.
Excuse me. Shaun, may
I speak with you, please?
Dr. Melendez, he was not angry.
Oh, no, Shaun,
Dr. Melendez is angry with you.
He's also angry with me.
Why?
Why? Because I
lied to him for you.
Why did you run away?
I didn't run away.
When you leave without
notifying your attending,
when you drop all of your
responsibilities at this hospital...
When you leave without
telling anyone, including me,
then you are running away.
Did this trip with
this girl help?
Yes. Yes, it did.
Okay, how?
I would like to give
two weeks' notice.
Mom, can you ask them to
bring me some more ice chips?
I'll get them, sweetie.
I'll get a doctor.
No. I'm just...
When you left, there
was no one here.
For the first time in
my life, I was alone.
Sweetie.
It felt cold.
Well, sometimes it is cold.
But you know what?
Someday, you might
find that you like it.
Wrongful termination.
Dr. Kalu assaulted
an attending surgeon.
I don't think you have
strong legal footing here.
There's more to the story.
And, I am sympathetic to Dr. Kalu,
but his ends don't justify his means.
Obviously, we can't
tolerate staff members...
And yet you do. Please, read on.
The middle cerebral has narrowed,
it's less than two millimeters.
You bypass the artery
here, and restore blood flow.
Open her back up?
She's just been through
a massive operation,
the brain tissue hasn't settled.
Another could very
well stroke Katie out.
Other options?
Intravascular.
I don't see how an intravascular
ultrasound gives us a better picture.
Not imaging.
He wants to stent the middle cerebral
artery in the angio lab. I like it.
Stenting is usually reserved
for the heart and the carotid.
It's not the usual, but we
are way past the usual.
It would lower the
danger of a stroke.
Dr. Murphy, would
you like to assist?
Yes.
Dr. Melendez, would you like to
write me a letter of recommendation?
You see the narrowing
there, in the horizontal segment
- of the middle cerebral artery?
- Middle cerebral artery.
Yeah, I've heard about you.
You're the one making
the old guard nervous.
Why would I make people nervous?
Because you have a gift,
and surgeons judge
themselves against their peers.
And right now, you're winning.
We're in position.
Dr. Murphy, please
inflate the balloon.
And give us another
squirt of contrast.
And we should
have good blood flow.
Yes, the proximal end
of the artery is dissecting.
The balloon is
damaging her artery.
Waveform is worsening.
The stent won't hold. She's
gonna stroke. I'm aborting.
Okay.
Waveform is normalizing.
We're right back
where we started.
Katie's brain is starving.
I want to see Katie.
I know she's in a coma, I
still need to see her. I miss her.
We can't risk contamination
for either of you.
She needs to know I'm there.
- We understand.
- You can't understand, no one can.
We have always been
there for each other,
and now when she needs
me most, I'm not there.
You've just been
through a 40-hour surgery,
we need you to focus
on your own healing.
And what about her heart?
We're going to do a
cardiac catheterization test
to see if her heart
circulation has improved.
Inject the contrast to evaluate
the heart's blood supply.
How's my soul looking?
That's a different specialty.
Katie says the eyes are
the window to the soul.
I say the eyes
lie, it's the heart.
Well, then so far your
soul is looking good.
Strong unobstructed blood flow.
The ventriculogram will tell us
how the muscle function is doing.
So quiet. Is everything okay?
The ventricle's strained and dilated.
We're hoping for some improvement,
post-separation, but
it's barely pumping.
It just doesn't make any sense.
The separation was supposed to
relieve the stress on Jenny's heart.
Half the need, half the work.
Jenny's heart is even
sicker than it appeared.
It seems we couldn't see
that because Katie's heart
was doing all the
work for Jenny's.
What can we do to fix it?
Give her a new heart.
We're not gonna find
a donor match in time.
Yes, we already have
the perfect heart for Jenny.
The sisters are monozygotic,
and therefore, a genetic match.
On the other
hand, Katie's alive.
She is GCS 3.
Her heart is still beating.
Yes, but she is unresponsive,
and I don't see a way to
return blood flow to the brain.
In all likelihood,
Katie's not coming back.
Yes, Katie very well may die,
but we can't predict when that'll be.
It could be today, it could
be 20 years from now.
If Katie stays
on the ventilator.
That's not up to us.
I know.
But I also know that,
based on these scans,
Jenny might not make
it through the night.
We need to propose
this to the mother.
There's no chance
Katie will wake up?
We can't say with
100% certainty,
but from what we saw
on Katie's brain scan,
we have little reason for hope.
But what we can
say with certainty
is that without Katie's
heart, Jenny will die.
Can we wait?
Just a little? Maybe
you'll know more?
Maybe something will change?
If we don't do anything, Jenny's
heart will stop before the morning.
How do you...
Would it be painful?
No. We simply power
down Katie's ventilator.
Once off life support,
she will peacefully pass.
Do you want us to
explain this to Jenny?
I'm sure she'll
wanna be present.
No.
I put trust in them
from an early age,
thinking responsibility
would build strength.
I think it worked.
But this? No.
Jenny can't be part of this
in any way. It'd destroy her.
I'll tell her Katie died.
"Dr. Shaun Murphy exhibits
technical skills beyond his years."
You wrote that?
Yes, that's why I signed
my name at the bottom.
You think Shaun survives
at another hospital?
I didn't think
he'd survive here.
Without your endorsement,
Shaun isn't going anywhere.
I may have my issues with him,
but no matter how
stupid an idea this may be,
I'm not gonna stop him from
going after what he wants.
There's another
signature line next to mine.
It's where the president
of the hospital has to sign.
The chief oncologist,
this is before I came here
in December of '14.
Dr. Marshall shoved
a scrub nurse during a
post-op discussion of some sort.
Do you remember that?
- I do.
- Your response was to settle with
the nurse while Dr. Marshall
was let off with a warning.
There's another, almost identical
instance earlier in that year.
In both cases, the doctors
in question were white.
They were censured.
Dr. Kalu was fired.
You think this was
a racial matter?
Do you think I'm racist?
That I favor white people?
Then why the leniency
then, and not now?
They're stars that
happened to be white.
Doctors like Marshall
allow Saint
Bonaventure to compete
with other West
Coast institutions.
So, that's our defense?
We're not racist, we just allow
our doctors to assault people
as long as they bring
in enough donors?
They were reprimanded, and
there were no further incidents.
And how do you think all of
this is gonna play out in court?
Settle.
Okay.
Hi.
Floor?
Four.
Shaun asked Dr. Melendez
for a letter of recommendation.
Yeah.
All I have to do is
sign it, and off he goes.
I think
he might think that
you're mad at him.
If you don't sign, it
reinforces what he thinks.
But, if you do, it lets him
know that you believe in him.
Can I touch her?
Of course.
Goodbye, baby.
Are you ready?
Yes.
She's stabilizing.
I don't understand.
What's going on?
Katie's not ready to go.
She's breathing on her own,
which means Katie has normal
brainstem function, correct?
When a ventilator is
removed, life can continue.
It's rare, but it could happen.
It doesn't change the
prognosis for awakening.
Off the ventilator with normal vitals
suggests long-term vegetative state,
- right?
- Yeah.
We just lost our
remedy for Jenny's heart.
What about ECMO?
Use the machine as a
replacement for Jenny's heart.
Buys us two weeks of life?
I don't like it.
ECMO requires blood-thinners.
She just had brain surgery, it
could cause a catastrophic bleed.
ECMO and its complications
may be our only avenue.
Re-conjoin them.
You want... You wanna put
their heads back together?
Not the heads, the thighs.
The femoral vessels.
Is it a funny idea?
I think it's funny
that I didn't think of it.
The girls' blood is identical. No
need for anti-clotting meds, so,
no possibility of a bleed.
As long as they're attached,
Katie's heart will beat for Jenny.
When Katie dies, we
sever the femoral connection
and transplant Katie's
heart into Jenny.
We just spent 40
hours separating them,
and now we wanna
put them back together.
- You tried to kill Katie?
- No.
You took her off life-support.
What do you call that?
Mercy. Not just for her.
You need a heart
or you're going to die.
Katie's alive.
She was then and
she's even more now.
Katie's alive in the sense that
she has basic organ function.
But she has no higher
cognitive brain activity.
She's surviving...
But she is not living.
Hours ago,
you thought she'd die as
soon as you pulled the plug.
You were wrong.
How do I know you're
not wrong this time, too?
The demand on Katie's heart
is minimal in her resting state.
She can easily
tolerate helping you.
I won't ask Katie to be
my life-support machine.
Dr. Andrews.
Let's put the sisters in
the same room overnight.
I don't think that Jenny sees
herself as an individual yet.
You know, I'm thinking the only
thing that'll change Jenny's mind
about the
re-attachment is Katie.
Being close might help
Jenny to see her as lifeless.
It could backfire,
and cement her feelings
that she's killing her sister.
Yeah, possibly.
And then, we're in the
same position anyways.
- Okay, do it.
- Okay.
Well, what about baseballs?
That this girl caught
at a Giants' game.
Signed by Mr. Hunter Pence.
He didn't hit it, but
that doesn't matter.
So, where is the
sporting-goods one?
There.
Oh, no. That does not
go in sporting goods.
It doesn't?
I'm applying to move my
residency to Hershey, Pennsylvania.
Really?
Yes. Penn State Medical Center.
Are you following me?
I need to make sure you're not
just doing this to stay close to me.
No.
Shaun?
I want my own life.
I want a life that I
control, not Dr. Glassman.
Dr. Glassman is
just trying to help you.
I don't want help.
But what if you need help?
How will I know if I stay?
Too much stuff. You
have too much stuff.
We should book a trip.
Maybe somewhere warm.
Wow, you are so slow.
You're only folding
underwear. Underwear is easy.
Mmm-mmm.
Okay.
No. You know
what? I don't want to.
Fine.
- Let's go, Preston.
- I'm ready.
Go.
Boom. Oh.
You're the only good
thing about my day.
I couldn't sleep last night.
I couldn't even
close my eyes until
I could feel Katie's
heartbeat in my hand.
If I do this, at some point,
Katie's heart will
beat for me, right?
That's the plan.
Then wherever I go, she
will always be with me.
Okay, I'll do it.
How you doing, Jenny?
I can't feel anything.
That would be the
magic of local anesthetic.
The vessels are
clamped. Okay, Doctor.
We're ready to proceed
with the anastomotic grafts.
It's done, isn't it? I can tell.
Let's put both the girls' vitals
next to each other, please.
Come on now.
Give it a few cardiac
cycles to adjust...
How'd we do?
You did great.
Why Hershey?
Lea is moving there.
Ah.
Well, they make good candy bars.
I don't like candy bars.
I love pancakes.
Well, they make those, too.
I brought you here because
I thought this place would provide
a challenge for your abilities.
But I realized I really brought you
here because I thought you needed me.
This is a now-signed
letter of recommendation.
But, I don't want you to go.
If you stay, I'll back off.
I'll let you make your own
choices, your own mistakes.
I believe in you, Shaun.
Their blood pressure dropped.
Five millimeters of mercury.
I like when you say "their".
You're gonna see
some fluctuation.
BP drops five millimeters every
complete cardiac circulation.
Shouldn't the fluctuation
be inconsistent?
Maybe Katie's heart isn't picking up
the workload for Jenny as expected.
Jenny.
I'm right here, Katie.
Right next to you.
Take Murphy and get a
shotgun work-up on Katie.
I want everything. EKG, EEG
and labs. And an echo on Jenny.
Now.
Katie has an awake alpha rhythm on
her EEG. She's doing remarkably well.
We're still not entirely sure what
caused Katie to regain consciousness.
Attaching them again could
have redistributed fluid into
Jenny's system, possibly
decreasing the swelling in Katie's brain.
We just don't know.
I know.
They need each other.
They always have.
The issue right now
has become Jenny
and her heart. When
Katie was in a coma,
the metabolic demand
on her heart was very low.
But now that she's
alert and active,
there just isn't enough
heart for both of 'em.
What does that mean?
We're awaiting test results.
We're not sure how
long Katie's heart
can tolerate the strain of
supporting Jenny's circulation.
We'll closely monitor them
with cardiac labs and echoes.
We need to find a donor heart
for Jenny as soon as possible.
No.
"No"? I've had CEOs settle
for half of what I just got for you.
I don't care about the money.
That's beautiful.
It's admirable, even.
But you see, this
is how it works
because we live in
a civilized society.
They hurt you, we hurt them by
making them cut you a massive check.
I don't want them to hurt, I want
them to give me my job back.
A third of your job back is, by
my calculation, almost nothing.
I'll pay you a third
of this settlement.
What are you talking about?
You'll be paying me more
than you earn in a year.
I want my job back.
Lunch is on you.
Lunch is on me.
Dr. Parker, please
report to Gynecology.
Are you moving to
Pennsylvania to be with Lea?
Does she know that?
Lea knows I'm moving to Hershey.
Yeah, but does she know you're
going there because she is going there?
I'm not.
Lea makes me happy.
Well, Lea's not the
only one that can do that.
I'm gonna miss you.
Your BNP.
Jenny Kunkler's cardio
protein levels are...
I've never seen
anything like it.
That's because the levels
are for two hearts, not one.
Now Jenny is killing Katie.
What's going on?
We've gotta separate them now,
or we're gonna lose them both.
- We got the twins on the way?
- In transit.
JL's gonna do
a local on the fly.
On my count. Three, two, one.
We can't do this. You'll die.
We're gonna do it.
No. We're in this together,
the way we've always been.
The way we were meant to be.
It's Jenny. She's in V-fib.
Push a milligram
epinephrine, now.
Prep an epi bag.
Murphy, start
chest compressions.
It's Jenny.
Her heart had
nothing left to give.
Katie?
She's stable.
Her vitals are good.
But we have an issue
that we need your help with.
Okay.
Um, Katie won't allow us
to separate her from Jenny.
If she doesn't acquiesce,
Katie will clot and die.
Heparin, 10,000 units on board.
We'll clear out and
give you some privacy.
Baby.
We have to let her go.
I won't let them separate us.
I never wanted to do this.
You used to say we were
made this way for a reason.
I won't let them do
this. Even if it kills me.
I want you to
look at your sister.
Look at her.
I can't lose both
of my daughters.
Dr. Andrews.
Evening. I checked
out the twins' file.
It's an amazing case.
To be clear, Jared, I
don't want you here.
What we presented to
Ms. Preston was the truth.
I understand that.
And those problem doctors
and the ways we police ourselves
will be dealt with, should have
been dealt with a long time ago,
but you stepped over a line.
- I fought for my job.
- You compromised your integrity.
The incident with that jerk Coyle
had nothing to do with black or white,
but that's what you and
your lawyer sold for leverage.
And when you misrepresent
racism for something it's not...
It sets us two steps back.
She's ready.
Jared, you're on suction.
Mayos.
I'm cold.
Gone fishing.
The store's closed.
I spoke to Claire.
Hey.
I wanna break up.
Why?
Because I love you.
That's a hell of a reason
to break up with somebody.
I want you to have
everything in your life.
Which includes kids.
I told you I was
willing to not have kids.
You're gonna regret
that decision one day.
- I won't.
- Yes, you will.
You're just too decent
to think it, but you will.
So what?
We all have regrets. I wanted
to play third base for the Astros.
It's not the same.
That is a child's dream.
This is your life.
This is my life.
And it'd be more devastating
to be resented by you
than to have my heart broken.
And you are going
to be a great dad.
Shaun.
I wanted to give you something.
I'm letting you borrow it.
Bring it when you come visit.
Okay.
Promise. You're
gonna come visit, right?
I promise. I like Hershey.
You've never been to Hershey.
Lea's there.
Can I put my arms around you?
Are you a good doctor?
'Cause when I think
of you, I think you are.
Remember, I said "borrow".
♪ I know how it feels
being by yourself in the rain
♪ We all need someone to stay
♪ Hear you, falling
and lonely, cry out
♪ Will you fix me up?
Will you show me hope?
♪ At the end of
the day it will help us
♪ Can you keep me close?
Can you love me most? ♪