As the riders begin Lap Two,
Jeff Forster is leading the pack.
They're jockeying
for position, now...
This is so cool.
Did we miss anything?
They've got,
like, 11 laps to go.
We gotta find a good place where
he can see the sign when he goes by.
Wait up, kids!
There is a strong chase pack
forming led by Vernonski...
At this point in the race,
things are still too close to call.
It's anybody's race,
but Forster looks...
Turn six. Come on.
Mike Larson has made a
nice break from the pack
and has closed the gap on
Forster and the lead group.
That's it. Up there.
Can you see anything?
Did you bring his inhaler?
Crap!
I think it's in the
car. I'll go get it.
Are you okay? Your
dad's gonna be right back...
I can see him.
He's right up front.
Honey, you're wheezing.
Here they come. Go, Jeff! Yeah!
You're number one!
He doesn't look so good.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Forster is down.
Yeah!
We need to talk.
Oh, God. Are you pregnant? 'Cause
I really wanna finish high school.
You have to renew
your credential.
They're good for
two more months.
Three weeks. And the
paperwork takes forever.
Your application, your
malpractice insurance,
criminal records check.
And you know that's
gonna take some explaining.
You know, our relationship was way
better when we were sleeping together.
Why did we stop doing
that? Did you get married?
Yeah. Otherwise I'd be
on you like red on rice.
Look, rice
isn't... Oh, I get it.
You're also behind
on your dictations.
I don't do dictations.
Cameron does them, or somebody.
And you can't have your
sole female employee
doing your clerical work, which
you'd know if you'd attended
the required sexual
harassment seminars.
Now, I'm gonna pause so you
can make a crack about harassment.
Joke killer.
House, got a patient.
Sorry. Can't play anymore.
My mom's calling me.
We just admitted a
world-class cyclist.
You gotta fire Stacy.
Yeah, I'll get right on that.
Jeff Forster, respiratory
arrest at 30 miles per hour.
She's loading me up
with pointless paperwork.
Well, you're way behind
on your pointless paperwork.
O2 sats are in
the... She's hostile.
You know me, hostility
makes me shrink up like a...
I can't think of a
non-sexual metaphor.
She's gonna stand over my desk
with a ruler, checking my spelling...
ER checked for lung
infiltrates. Nothing there.
Professional athletes, Cuddy. It's
like watching an old movie at 2 a.m.
Reliving all the
classic moments.
The part where
he denies it's drugs.
The part where the good
guys ride in, tests a-blazing,
prove that it is drugs.
Oscar clip. He can't imagine
how they got into his body.
It's so familiar, so comforting.
She can't handle
working with me.
Oh, right. Yeah.
She's still got a thing for you,
making it impossible for her to deal.
It makes perfect sense,
except for the pronouns.
Anyway, thanks for getting
me out of that meeting.
He's not denying the drugs.
I'm thinking he's actually sick.
Jeff Forster, this is...
I'm a doctor.
You're a sick person.
And you are a loved
one. Actually, manager.
We've been together for 7 years.
So what's the drug du jour
on the bike circuit these days?
Still erythropoietin, or are you
guys just chugging battery acid?
There's no way I'd touch EPO.
Too many guys
stroking out and dying.
Damn.
10 bucks for the ticket,
six for the popcorn.
I do straight blood doping.
Plot twist.
That's a very daring confession.
We've got
confidentiality, right?
Assuming I'm more
ethical than your client.
So, injecting yourself with donor
red blood cells for fun and profit.
Any other tricks up your sleeve?
Well, nothing much recently.
I'm in town for a charity
ride, so it didn't matter if I won.
The kids just needed to see me.
If you go slower,
they see you longer.
Let's say that our health could be affected
by things we did before last Friday.
Well,
I usually sleep in a
Hyperbaric Chamber.
I've been pumping up
electrolytes with an IV drip.
Anabolic herbal supplements,
amphetamines and diuretics.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
But why would you be sick?
I know that doping has risks. I
know that it's outside the rules.
But I do what I have to to
kick ass at my job. Don't you?
Dr. House is a firm believer in
good old-fashioned hard work.
This guy doesn't even get
sick like a regular person.
Instead of a list of
symptoms and no cause,
we have a list of possible
causes for one symptom.
Is the symptom death?
Respiratory distress.
Insanity doesn't
cause it. I looked it up.
It's the doping. Injecting extra red
cells boosts your endurance level
but it also thickens your blood.
Thick blood equals clots
equals respiratory distress.
Not with a clean
spiral chest CT.
The guy's sleeping in
a Hyperbaric Chamber.
Over-oxygenation
can cause cell damage,
and if the cells in the
lungs are damaged...
That'd cause pulmonary
edema, which he doesn't have.
The supplements he's
been taking contain yohimbe
which can cause nerve paralysis.
Tox-screen was normal.
All the tests were normal.
There's no clot, no edema,
and yet he still can't breathe.
So there's something
in here that we can't see.
Air.
Come to Papa.
This guy's been injecting
himself how many times a day?
All it'd take is one slip of the
needle to cause an air embolus.
So, air is keeping
him from breathing air.
Well, let's go with
that for the irony.
Get a VQ scan and
check his veins for bubbles.
Xenon 133.
It's just radioactive enough for us to
track the air moving through your lungs.
Was my accident on the news?
Yeah, you made
Plays of the Week.
A few more of those, and cycling
will be as popular as NASCAR.
We inject similar stuff into your
blood so we can watch it circulate.
If you accidentally
injected a bubble,
we'll see good air flow
but poor blood flow.
I'm careful, man.
With all due respect, man,
I doubt there's anything wrong
with you that you didn't do to yourself.
There's this kid in oncology, she's
got a picture of Jeff above her bed.
Mickey Mantle was an alcoholic.
At least he hit his
own home runs.
He didn't physically
alter himself.
We take drugs to help us
fall asleep, to stay awake...
Yeah, but we don't make careers
out of who can stay awake the longest.
Really? Ever been to, oh,
I don't know, med school?
Guys, he plays a game
for a living. Who cares?
You don't even like sports.
He's making millions of
dollars ripping off fans.
Anyone who thinks they
should pay a guy money
because he can throw a ball
really far or pedal really fast
deserves to be ripped off.
Yeah, stupid, stupid kids.
I've got an uncle. He can
spit a cherry pit 50 yards.
He's working part-time at
a lube shop. Life isn't fair.
Maybe it is.
You were right.
Now, there were
three wasted words.
There is a bubble in his lung. We
should do a Swan-Ganz catheterization.
I love when you do both
sides of the conversation.
It's like white noise.
It's very peaceful.
Is there a light somewhere
that goes on when I have food?
Green for food, orange for
beverages, red for impure thoughts.
That bulb burns
out every two weeks.
How's your biker?
Pumped an air bubble
into a vein in his lung.
The things people
do. Doping, Vicodin...
Hey, you're talking
about me, aren't you?
I'm just trying to function. He's trying
to win himself some little yellow jerseys.
Oh.
What?
Trouble in paradise. 2 o'clock.
Your 2 o'clock or my 2 o'clock?
There.
She seems perfectly happy.
Obviously they huddled in the
hall and worked up this circus act
on the off chance
you'd be in here.
She was unbelievably
pissy three hours ago.
Hmm.
Pissy with you, happy
with her husband.
Yes, there can only be one
possible explanation for that.
When she's angry
she gets sarcastic.
When she's annoyed she's funny.
But when she's
frustrated she gets pissy.
Yes, yes, I'm with you so far.
She's miserable with
Mark because he's not me.
So she's gotta make me not me,
so she makes my
professional life miserable.
If I can't do my job... You
really, really need to get some...
Oh, I get some
"some" all the time.
It's why I always need
to borrow some money.
Hi, James. Greg, you
gotten to that paperwork?
I've been pissy.
Pardon me?
I've been busy.
When you save someone's
life, they owe you forever.
You're right. Take Stacy.
Oh, wait, she'd probably
just leave you all over again.
How's your recovery going? Gotten
around to the small muscles yet?
It's not the size of the muscle,
it's where you get to put it.
My goodness, it's like watching Oscar
Wilde and Noel Coward in the third grade.
Excuse us.
How awkward was that?
What's he doing here anyway?
He's got physio Tuesdays and Fridays.
Mark is in group therapy for
people coping with disability.
He was thinking about
developing a drug addiction,
but that would be stupid.
Hey, you're... You, again.
You're not gonna make some
joke about Mark being in therapy?
What's there to say? He's
doing the responsible thing.
I'm sure he's got
a lot to deal with.
You're making me nervous.
Every time an athlete goes
down, you guys assume it's drugs.
Look, the doctors say
it's probably acid reflux.
Yeah, look, call me tomorrow.
There's a good chance he'll be released.
Okay. Bye-bye.
So, is this fixing him?
If his acid reflux isn't worse
than we thought, yeah.
I gotta be in
Spain in four days.
Shouldn't be a problem.
Great.
If I could just find the little bugger,
should be able to suck it out.
My legs feel weak.
You're under mild sedation
for the test. It'll wear off.
There it is.
Got it. Fantastic,
I'll pack his things.
Not yet. I wanna monitor him for a
couple of hours, make sure he's okay.
Give him time to sign a picture
for me, maybe even a jersey.
"To Doctor Chase, I
owe you everything."
It doesn't have to
be that personal.
Not too many eBay shoppers
named Doctor Chase, huh?
Still trying to unload the
Barbara Walters spit cup.
Here you go.
Seriously, anything's fine.
Jeff!
You all right?
Jeff, can you swallow?
What makes a guy start drooling?
Chase, were you
wearing your short shorts?
Muscle fatigue in
his neck and jaw.
He's obviously got something
worse than an air embolus.
Why?
Because you don't
drool from your lungs?
Maybe the problem is not the
embolus itself. Maybe it's the treatment.
Maybe you hit
a nerve, literally.
The embolectomy was
clean. His legs were tired, too.
I thought it was from
the sedation, but if not,
it means he's got
something systemic.
Which means it would have nothing
to do with the stunts he's been pulling.
Lupus or polymyositis.
It explains the progressive
muscle weakness.
It could be ALS.
He's too young for that.
Some type of muscular dystrophy?
He's too old for that.
So what would be
just right, Goldilocks?
Full blood workup,
including ANA for lupus.
And get a muscle biopsy. Find out if
we're talking myopathy or neuropathy.
I'm late for my session.
Session?
It's all a part of the process.
You get angry
and then you get...
Yeah. I'm right on schedule.
So, when am I gonna be done?
No, I need to know,
'cause I got plans to make.
When can I safely
book a game of squash?
When am I gonna
stop being angry?
Not today.
I've come for the healing.
Dr. Harper, as you
know, I have a bum leg.
What you don't know is I'm
upset about it. I need to talk.
You know House. You
know we have a history.
You've been telling me for
years that I should come by.
Here I am. Hi, guys.
I've got a Thursday
group. Poker night.
Monday morning? Book club.
Well, look, if it's a problem, I'll
just go deal with my rage privately.
Wait.
If you two could
resolve this tension,
you could really
help each other.
I'm tired of fighting.
So either I say
yes or I'm the jerk?
Oh, God, I know that feeling.
I took the muscle
specimen from Jeff's thigh.
I figured that's where we'd have
the best chance at finding something.
The most painful
place to cut into.
I assume that's caffeine-free.
Wouldn't want to be artificially
boosting your performance.
Don't start her up again.
Caffeine's legal.
All about the rules, eh?
It's a bike race,
a completely arbitrary set of
rules that everyone complies with
for no other reason than that some
committee says that they should.
But that's the point.
That's what the game is.
So, if you break an arbitrary
rule, Cameron damns you to hell.
But if you break a rule
that actually has a reason
that's designed
to protect people,
Cameron develops
a crazy crush on you.
House doesn't pretend
to be some golden boy.
He does it to help people,
not to glorify himself.
So why don't you report
Jeff to the biking authorities?
Ethics.
Well, you wouldn't be
doing it to glorify yourself.
You'd just be trying
to make a better world.
At least you can still
get around on your own.
Yeah, I know.
But you're starting to walk.
You're gonna get better.
You have a job, a
way to be productive.
And you have a wife.
Which gives greater meaning?
A wife could make things
harder, too, I suppose.
This isn't about Stacy.
When it happened to
me, Stacy was great.
She kept telling
me not to rush it.
I never believed her.
She means it.
I know, but...
Stacy. She shouldn't
have to wait, right?
And you know she feels it, too.
There's more time at work.
There's more satisfaction from work.
She didn't get married
to be a nursemaid.
She wants a man.
How the hell could she have loved a
manipulative son of a bitch like you?
That's an interesting question.
Maybe she was attracted to
different things in the two of us.
She left you.
But why was she
with me to begin with?
She made a mistake.
Maybe it's that simple.
Or maybe she saw
something in me,
something she
doesn't get from you.
I'm not an ass.
Maybe she wanted an ass.
She obviously did once.
Either he goes or I go.
You think that's the kind of
thing you can just turn off?
Get him out of here! Dr. House,
cancel your book group.
You're coming on Mondays.
Here's my new theory. The
drooling's another competitive edge.
Nobody can draft behind
it. The road gets slick.
He's the only one
not racing in the rain.
He can barely move
his arms and legs.
Paralysis? No, just
general weakness.
Muscle biopsy is
negative for polymyositis.
And ALS and muscular dystrophy.
ANA for lupus, also negative.
Maybe his bike shorts
are just on too tight.
So, by your rationale,
House shouldn't use a cane.
He should just drag his bum
leg around as God intended?
House has a handicap. All
he's aiming for is normality.
And who decides what's normal?
What if we find a drug that
makes people live 20 years longer?
Should we ban that
because it's not normal?
Jeff doesn't want normal.
He wants superpowers.
So why is he normal?
Oh, God, you too?
He's shooting for extraordinary.
So why is everything
so ordinary?
I mean, this guy's breathing,
drinking and injecting himself
with everything he can find
to amp up his body chemistry,
and yet every test is normal.
He's artificially raising his red
blood count, so why isn't it raised?
Maybe his count is raised.
Maybe what's normal for
us is out of whack for him.
Can't slip anything by you.
Well, if that's true, his
white cells are up, too.
Which would point to
some kind of infection.
Muscle weakness, exhaustion.
He could have encephalitis.
That's kind of a long shot.
- Yeah.
But it's been over an hour
since we've poked the patient
with something sharp.
So, get a lumbar puncture
and order
broad-spectrum antibiotics.
No, it's not about judging.
It's just that on a dating
service you should post a photo.
I have to go.
I am so sorry to bother
you. Nope, not a problem.
I was just accounting.
I'm Jeff Forster's manager.
He's been here a whole day,
and it doesn't seem like
we're any closer to a diagnosis.
Jeff Forster. A whole day, huh?
Mmm-hmm.
I was just wondering if I
could help speed things up.
Your client's had a muscle
biopsy, a full blood workup
and he's scheduled for a lumbar
puncture at 10 a.m. tomorrow.
Jeff is in the Lucas Wing.
If Mr. Lucas showed up
needing a lumbar puncture,
would he have to
wait until tomorrow?
Mr. Lucas is dead. Good.
Then there's an opening.
Jeff is used to doing whatever
he has to to be first, isn't he?
It's been very
lucrative for him.
He feels it's important that
he give something back.
I hear you've been raising funds
for your nuclear medicine department
or whatever.
Thank you, guys,
for working so late.
Glad to be here.
The lumbar puncture will tell us
what kind of infection you've got.
In the meantime, we're
administering antibiotics.
Do you like being a hero?
It's a living.
You don't feel a
sense of responsibility?
There's kids out
there that worship you.
When I was a rookie on the tour,
I got a letter from
a guy in Wisconsin.
He wanted me to
send a note to his son.
He said he worshipped me.
You know what worship
means? I looked it up.
It means to love
unquestioningly and uncritically.
So the kid doesn't even
know me, but he loves me
unquestioningly
and uncritically.
So you decided to
take advantage of that.
What should I have done?
"Dear sir, I'm just a guy
"who rides a bike pretty good.
"You and your kid
are out of your minds."
My arms feel funny.
The sats are dropping.
He's in respiratory arrest.
He can't be. We fixed that.
Apparently not.
So glad we cured
his respiratory arrest.
It freed him up to
develop respiratory arrest.
LP was negative
for encephalitis.
The white count's
still the same,
but the red count's
fallen to 29%.
What was my theory yesterday?
That I screwed up
the embolectomy.
We'll get a chest
x-ray to check.
I didn't screw up.
Why would you...
How can you be so petty,
Chase? He's down a quart.
Either he's losing blood
because you nicked something
or he's just not
producing blood,
in which case, we're
talking acute anemia
combined with a
muscular disorder.
Paraneoplastic syndrome?
Either you screwed
up or he's got cancer.
I think I should
start smoking again.
You want a medical opinion
supporting that decision?
The symptoms started
as soon as I quit.
Symptoms meaning diarrhea.
A lot of diarrhea.
10 or 12 times a day.
It's really embarrassing.
I'm a flight attendant and...
Well, on the up side,
my hiccups are gone.
You went to his group.
Well, you were the one who was all,
"Greg, you need to confront your feelings."
That was five years ago.
Well, I've been pissy.
Fine, you don't want help. Does
that mean nobody should get it?
Mark's looking for help because,
what, he's resentful, overwhelmed?
I'm asking because I care.
Not about him.
You still wanna jump me, so
you don't care whose marriage...
Listen, I can get my
rocks off any time I want.
What I don't seem to
be able to do is my job
without you hanging
over my shoulder.
How many packs?
A bit over one a day, but
they were lights, and I quit.
You used to go out with her?
Yeah.
What was I thinking?
I'm talking about the gum you're chewing
to replace smoking as an oral fixation.
How many packs?
Six, maybe seven.
I'm trying to protect you.
Cuddy and I may be the only people
stopping you from jumping off a cliff
just to prove that
you... You're pissy.
Oh, I am angry! Pissy.
You only get pissy when
you're frustrated. Shut up.
Okay, I'm wrong.
This is unbelievably difficult
for Mark, which you should know.
Which you should be able to
summon up some level of empathy for.
Right. The crippled boys.
We should start a band.
I have a good thing with Mark.
We are handling this the
best way we know how.
And none of this has
anything to do with me?
No, nothing, except that
you can't or won't just let it go.
Let it go.
You're being poisoned.
By gum?
Sugarless gum uses
sorbitol as a sweetener.
We use sorbitol as a laxative.
This will tell you if he's
got cancer in his blood?
If he does, we'll see
abnormal cells in the marrow.
How long will the tests take?
I'll get them in
as soon as I can.
And if he doesn't have
cancer, what else could it be?
It's possible some damage was done
during one of the tests we gave him.
So either one of your doctors
screwed up a simple procedure
or he's got cancer.
We can't know anything for
sure until the biopsy comes back.
It stings, I know.
No, he wants the tube out.
I can't do that, Jeff.
If you wanna say something,
you've gotta write it down. Okay?
Here.
If it's cancer, it's possible.
There's no way to know for sure.
Phone not working?
One of the morgue attendants
asked me to bring this to you.
Wonder why they're calling me.
Yeah, me too, actually.
I was wondering why the
Times was returning your call.
You a doctor or
the bicycle police?
He's cheating. He
shouldn't get away with it.
Have you actually
told them anything yet?
You worried about the precedent?
I'm worried about you.
You gonna turn me in?
No.
He's made a mistake.
Revealing the truth doesn't undo it.
Kids love him, and he's not
who they think he is. It's not right.
Who cares if he's what he
says he is? Who the hell is?
If love is based on lies, does
that mean it's not a real feeling?
It doesn't bring
the same pleasure?
Are we still talking
about the patient?
Have you ever cheated?
Well, I have.
You wanna punish
him? Good for you.
But you can't do it without
punishing the people who love him.
Is that how you justified
lying to your wives?
I always told them.
Well, he's negative for bleeds.
Congratulations,
Chase. It's cancer.
Clean him up and let oncology
have him. It's their party now.
He doesn't have cancer. Biopsy
shows he's got pure red cell aplasia.
There's no way PRCA
could manifest so suddenly.
Unless it's drug-induced. He's
lying about not being on EPO.
Why would he lie?
What does it matter?
People lie for thousands of
reasons. But there's always a reason.
Philosophically interesting,
medically irrelevant.
Unless he's not lying.
You've got a leak. The press
is all over the Jeff Forster story.
On the off chance that one of
you was stupid enough to call
from your own office, I'm
pulling your phone records,
including your cell phones.
I assume if I point out the fact
that you have no right to do that,
you'll interpret that
as a sign of guilt?
Wilson's chatty, plus he's
got two ex-wives to support.
You want me to
tell him he's fired?
Until we figure out who's behind
this, I'm sitting in with you guys.
You have the ethics of a 4-year-old.
I'm gonna treat you like one.
How am I supposed to practice medicine
with a lawyer sitting on my shoulder?
Responsibly. You
know I can't do that.
Cameron.
I'm not the leak.
Somebody once told
me that everybody lies,
and since you're the only
people who know he has cancer...
He doesn't have cancer.
The point is, you're
his medical team.
He's threatening to sue.
Why would Cameron leak cancer?
How does cancer
make the guy look bad?
He's on EPO.
Your anemia is caused
by pure red cell aplasia.
This is gonna hurt,
but we gotta talk.
What the hell are you doing?
He'll be fine, sort of.
I just don't have time to
watch him write out answers.
PRCA comes in two
varieties, chronic and acute.
Since it came on fast,
you have the acute version.
He doesn't have cancer.
Is the good news.
The bad news is
pants are on fire.
Acute PRCA is caused by
drugs, most commonly, EPO.
Ready, and action!
But I haven't used EPO.
Okay, but this time,
with more anger.
Remember, this guy's
accusing you of cheating.
I haven't used that stuff.
I believed it. It was simple, it
was pure. Did you believe it?
I guess it's silly to cast
someone after the first audition.
Why don't you do a
reading? Give me that.
He doesn't do EPO.
What did you think?
It's a different way to go, but,
I don't know, I just didn't buy it.
Does she handle
any of your injections?
You think I'm giving it to him?
Test him.
Gee, that's a great idea.
I sure hope that EPO's not one of those
drugs that's undetectable after six hours.
Hey, you know what we
can test for? Phone calls.
Take her cell phone.
Push the redial button.
Even money says you'll be
connected to the newspaper
that leaked your cancer story.
Okay.
Okay, I should have told you.
It's not just about
the races, Jeff.
It's about your image, okay?
If you come back from cancer,
those sponsors will be all over you.
Okay, so I messed up. Okay?
But I did not give you EPO.
That stuff could kill me.
Come on, give her a break.
She was only doing what she
has to to advance her career.
Don't you have that
tattooed on your tushie?
I would never do
anything to hurt you.
Who are you gonna believe,
the manager you've
trusted for years?
I've been to college.
You're fired.
Okay.
You're basing this whole
diagnosis, everything,
on the idea that I was
slipping him illegal drugs.
You're gonna kill him.
If Doctor House is so sure,
why do you need to stay?
He's a very cautious man.
Your breathing's better.
Let the prednisone do its job.
Get some sleep.
Jeff?
His red blood cell
count plummeted to 16%.
He passed out, had to be resuscitated,
and he still can't move his legs.
That's not possible. The drugs
should be flushing out of his system.
Can't leave if they don't exist.
The EPO use explains
every one of his symptoms.
He's been lying and cheating,
and now it's coming back to bite him.
The only problem with that theory
is it's based on the assumption
that the universe
is a just place.
If it were, then his poor manager
wouldn't have been fired for no reason.
Lambert-Eaton.
His chest was clear.
So we run an
electromyography test.
You're still not
explaining the PRCA.
What's his red count now?
I had to give him
a blood transfusion.
He's back around 30.
He needed a transfusion?
Well, he was losing blood, so, I
thought maybe he needed blood.
Go forth and scan his neck.
His neck?
Or repeat everything
I say in question form.
She came into the
clinic and yelled at me.
Then she left, she came
back and yelled some more.
Hmm.
Yelling. That might be a clue.
I know what the yelling means. It's
the coming and going I find interesting.
It's not rational.
Anger is not rational.
Some anger is.
She could have pulled me
aside, screamed at me privately.
Her beef is simple
and well founded.
But she was out of control.
You're having fun, aren't you?
She's in my face. I
need to know why.
Professional reasons.
Why else?
Do you really think this is
going to end well for anyone?
After this, let's scan some
other totally random body parts.
50 bucks says we find something.
Find what?
Don't have a clue. We on?
No way.
No. We'll find something.
We found a thymoma. How'd
you know to look in his neck?
Thymoma's usually
present in the chest.
I knew it wasn't in his chest.
All we've done since he
checked in is look at his chest.
All the more reason not to think...
There are two types of PRCA.
Acute comes on suddenly,
chronic takes its time.
We all thought Jeff's was acute
because it happened right in front of us.
But what if it'd been there
for months, maybe years?
There's no way. It would
have kept him from racing.
With that kind of anemia, he
would have needed constant...
Blood transfusions.
Which he was getting in
convenient blood doping form.
He was treating himself
without even knowing it.
Up to half of patients with
chronic PRCA have a thymoma.
And up to half of
patients with a thymoma...
I've always wanted to do this.
I'm not getting any better.
Does that mean I'm...
You are healed. Rise and walk.
Are you insane?
In the Bible, people
just say, "Yes, Lord,"
and then start right
in on the praising.
First you tell me
I've got cancer.
And then you tell me
that my manager...
What did you do?
No, "What did you do, Lord?"
Thymoma is a tumor
on the thymus gland.
He's a bit of a wimp, but he
hangs with the tough guys.
PRCA and an autoimmune
disease called myasthenia gravis.
MG causes muscle fatigue
including respiratory problems
and difficulty swallowing.
And it can hit you that fast?
The treatment for PRCA
is blood transfusions.
The treatment for
MG is hyperbaria.
You were doing both as part
of your regular freak show.
When you took a break,
everything went to hell,
which is not an uncommon
reaction in Jersey.
So, the whole thing
with my manager...
Oops. No, no EPO.
This has nothing to do
with anything you did.
You can let her know
she's in the clear. I could.
Or 10% of a Nike contract
is a hell of a lot of cash.
You don't need your thymus.
If we take it out, everything
else is manageable.
Manageable? I thought
you just cured me.
Uh-uh. This is just diagnostic.
Tensilon erases the symptoms
of MG for five or six minutes.
Sometimes less.
This is exactly why
I created nurses.
Clean up on Aisle Three!
If you've come to search my
office, you should wait 10 minutes.
I'll be out of your hair.
Here, start with my purse.
Just save me some mints.
What do you wanna
know? My sex life with Mark?
My guilt over crippling
your damn leg?
Or are you just here to gloat
because you weren't the leak?
I want to apologize.
Maybe I've
been punishing you
for a little too long.
And maybe you've
been punishing me.
If we're going to work
together, I need to know.
Do you hate me
or do you love me?
Either way, I think
we've got a problem.
I hate you and I love you.
And I love Mark.
And you don't hate him.
No.
So what do we do?
We deal with each other.
Right.
That plan's been
working great so far.
It'll get better.
It'll get easier.
Why? I don't know.
That's what my
therapist tells me.
In the professional cycling
world, we are subject to
what seems like constant
witch-hunts and finger-pointing.
But I want to thank Dr. House
and the excellent medical team
here at Princeton-Plainsboro.
My hope is that this diagnosis
will put to rest any
rumors that I would ever...
He needs blood
transfusions every two weeks,
which means he
can dope all he wants.
He's got a doctor's pass.
It's medicinal.
He got away with it.
Mmm-hmm.
He cheated and won a game.
Life's more complicated than
who gets to the finish line first.
I fell in love with my
husband's best friend.
Near the end, I was at
the hospital every day,
and Joe would
come by after work.
We'd go for walks and try
to talk each other through it.
We kind of clung
on to each other.
My wife
wasn't dying. She
wasn't even sick.
Everything was fine.
But I met someone who
made me feel funny.
Good.
And I didn't want
to let that feeling go.
What happened to you?
How can anyone go
through that alone?
You can't control your emotions.
No.
Just your actions.
You didn't do it, did you?
You didn't sleep with him.
I couldn't have
lived with myself.
You'd be surprised
what you can live with.
Hey.
I need you to open a door.
It's not allowed.
Yeah, I was having
therapy in here today
and I left my cane.
Sorry.
Dude,
I'm crippled.