♪ I was bad to the bone ♪
♪ Bad to the bone ♪
♪ B-b-b-b-b-b-bad ♪
♪ I broke a thousand hearts ♪
♪ Before I met you ♪
♪ I'll break A
thousand more, baby ♪
♪ Before I am through ♪
♪ I wanna be yours, baby ♪
Ah, good morning.
How's the biker life?
Ah.
Jerry, I feel like
a Hell's Angel.
I hate to break
it to you, Dr. G,
but an Angel wouldn't
be caught dead
on a rice burner.
Goat's coming in nice.
What's it been?
A couple of days?
A week.
Some guys need more time.
♪ Bad to the bone ♪♪
Oh, uh, Mark,
we're short-staffed.
Malik and Wendy are out sick.
Call the nurses temp agency
and get some
per diems to fill in.
Are you wearing contacts?
Yeah, I thought
I'd try them out.
Why the big makeover?
No reason.
Hey, fuzzy. We
still on for The Mint?
Yeah, sure.
Jazz club.
Meat market.
Hot date?
Just a couple of single guys
hanging out.
So, leave around eight o'clock
for a nine o'clock set?
You know, I'm not
doing anything tonight.
Really, Jerry?
Good, because there's
a great game on TV.
Have you seen this
month's Journal?
No.
Vucelich published his study.
Hmm.
It's tough your name
couldn't be on it.
I wouldn't want my
name to be on it.
The whole study's a sham.
Sour grapes is one thing, Peter,
but to slander a colleague
is offensive.
Look, it's not
slander. It's the truth.
Are you prepared
to back that up?
Take it to the Ethics Committee?
Well, then keep your mouth shut.
You think it was
the ham and eggs?
Because I had two helpings.
Thanks for the concern,
but I don't think it
was my breakfast.
It's the match.
My entire future's
stuffed in an envelope.
I know I'm not
going to get in here.
Well, I hope you
do, because if not,
I'm gonna have to start looking
for a new boyfriend.
Better start looking.
They hand out the envelopes
at nine sharp.
What time is it?
8:15. Oh, God!
Hey.
Thanks for coming.
I've got five minutes.
Oh, you didn't bring her.
No.
Hi. What can I get you?
Nothing.
Okay.
Uh, I don't blame
you for hating me.
When I left last year,
I was so screwed up.
I was either
going to kill myself
or turn it around.
What kept me going
was thinking about Susie.
Yeah, right.
It's different this time.
I... I, uh...
I got into a program
and I've been clean
for five months...
I bet. And...
I got engaged.
He's a great guy, Susan.
Congratulations.
I should get to work.
What is it you wanted?
I want to be a mother
to my daughter.
Well, that's too damn bad,
because you
abandoned your child,
and that's the best thing
that ever happened to her.
Susie, wait!
Susie, please. Come on.
You can't keep her away from me.
She's my baby!
Don't say a word.
About what?
Temp agency makes us wear them.
You're the temp?
Well, they cut my hours in half
and I have a mortgage to pay,
so what am I supposed to do?
The earthworms didn't pan out?
Ha. They croaked.
What's this?
Oh, uh, Jeanie was made
Employee of the Month.
Uck.
Does anyone have an aspirin?
Carol, can you start a Foley
on a guy in 3?
I'm on in two minutes.
Ask the Employee of the Month.
You know what she looks like?
Yes.
And the other workers?
We all know Chloe.
You know, if she comes here...
I mean, if she's
peeking in that window,
I want you to page
me. Of course.
You don't know my sister.
I'm just afraid
she might try something crazy.
Security's right down the hall.
I'll talk to them.
I already have.
Yeah, but she still...
We're covered, Susan.
Go to work.
Yeah.
Bye.
Come here.
Come here, my cutie.
Yeah. Say goodbye.
Say goodbye.
Wave bye-bye to Mommy.
Bye-bye.
That's right.
That's right, little girl.
Come on.
Are you on any medications,
Mr. Bartoli?
I can't understand it.
I was feeling like a
million bucks, you know?
I was in the sack, actually,
with this knockout postmistress.
It's amazing how well you can do
just hanging
around a post office,
and then, bam, you know,
right in the chest.
Any medications, Mr. Bartoli?
Well, I got this ointment from
one of those, uh, catalogs.
Dr. Joe's Prolonging Cream?
Keeps me going all night, and...
How much did you use?
The whole tube.
Mr. Bartoli, this is digitalis.
It can cause a heart arrhythmia.
You got to stop using it.
Cold turkey? Yeah.
Doesn't this stuff
make you completely numb?
An unfortunate side effect.
Nevertheless, it
helps guys like us,
you know, make the grade.
"Guys like us"?
Bald guys.
Babes know we have
more testosterone.
They expect more.
Am I right?
Oh, no.
Bad news?
No news.
Hicks is late.
Should I grab an emesis basin?
No, I'm all right.
Resigned myself
to the painful truth.
What are you talking about?
I don't deserve to match here.
I don't.
I've been so wrapped
up in the competition
that I lost sight of
what it's all about.
I've become
this brown-nosing procedure...
whore,
treating patients
like guinea pigs.
I've been dishonest.
I've been arrogant. I've been...
Jump in if you disagree.
No, you've been a real schmuck.
I know...
but no more.
From now on,
the patients come first.
Trauma coming through!
Grandfather brought
him to the main entrance.
Paramedics bringing in two more.
I'll get Dr. Greene.
What happened?
On our way to school,
guy ran a red light.
Where's it hurt?
My leg.
Will he be okay?
Dr. Benton's the best.
What can I do?
Check Mr. Bowman's vitals.
I'm fine. I want to
stay with my grandson.
No, no, no, no. We
have to check you out.
It's okay. Carter, take him.
Why don't you come
with me, Mr. Bowman?
It's okay.
We'll take good care of him.
Freddie Robinson, 19, jackass.
Took out three cars
at Racine and Polk.
There's one fatality
on the scene.
We've pumped him
with two liters of saline
in the field.
Vitals?
Uh, BP 140, resp 22.
24.
BP's 140/100, pulse is 90.
It hurts.
Any meds?
Yeah, we found some
in the car. You got it?
I left them in the rig.
Well, why don't you go get them?
New guy, huh?
Hey, I'm a baby-sitter,
not a fireman.
I'm going to die.
One, two,
three.
I'll get him.
Let's get that O-neg down here.
Mr. Bowman,
you're not letting me finish
my physical examination.
I'm going to see my grandson.
Hey, Lydia, need any help?
Sure.
Take Mr. Phelps
to the bathroom...
and check the board!
My pleasure. Hi.
I'm John Carter.
All right, let's get
his clothes off.
Where is everybody?
Short-handed. Just us.
Here. Start cutting.
Well, it's hard to do my job
when I have to do
everybody else's.
So, you have noticed
that we do something
around here.
How is he?
Uh, did Carter check you out?
I'm fine. How's my boy?
I'm okay, Grandpa.
Sir, could you
wait outside for us?
I'm staying with my grandson.
It's okay.
How you doing, buddy?
My leg hurts so bad.
We'll get you something
as soon as we can.
Hurt that same knee
four months ago
playing basketball.
Jeanie, call up his old chart.
C-spine, chest and AP pelvis?
That's right.
Better add a femur film.
He's got a fracture.
Soft-tissue swelling.
He's got a big ecchymosis
of the left thigh.
I don't feel a fracture
but you're right.
It could be broken.
Doug, need your help.
Let's give him Toradol
after we clear the C-spine.
Barry Meeks, 8-years-old,
restrained in the back seat.
Car was T-boned.
Used the Jaws of
Life to cut him out.
BP's 60 palp.
Difficult airway.
Can't get a line.
I'll do a saphenous cut down.
He's bradycardic, 40.
.5 atropine. Get that
O-neg down here.
What's happening?
Nicole. Nicole, can you take her
to the waiting room?
Abdomen's rigid.
Damn. Could be
a ruptured spleen.
Lily, cut down tray,
Number 15 blade,
and a Kelly, please.
Need a cut down tray.
Check next door.
It hurts!
Hold still. Hold still.
What are you doing?
Is he the guy who got T-boned?
No, he's the T-boner.
Ran a red, decapitated
a pedestrian,
and smashed up our
other two customers.
Yeah, a real prince.
DPL's positive.
Okay, we'll take him to the O.R.
as soon as I do a central line.
Heart rate's up to 130.
It hurts!
Are you on any drugs?
No. I'm clean.
Track marks on the left arm.
Oh, here too.
I'm clean. I swear.
Yeah, right.
Okay, give him Narcan,
two migs, IV push.
I'm going to try
a straight blade.
Give me cricoid pressure.
How you doing, Doug?
Almost there.
Lily, give me an O-silk tie
and a 14-gauge
angiocath, please.
Here you go.
Are you in?
Yes.
I'll bag him.
Uh, Mark, guy's crashing in 2.
Doug, you okay?
Yeah, he's out of the woods.
Dropped his pressure,
just tubed him,
pumping in the O-neg.
How's it going?
Uh, swell.
First, coffee with Chloe, now
chest trauma with Freddie.
Sounds like a nice way
to start the day.
Oh, yeah.
I don't feel a pulse.
These chest films just came in.
Damn. Widened mediastinum.
Probably ruptured his aorta.
10 blade.
Oh, labs came back.
Coked up, blood alcohol .322.
Rib spreader.
Looks like Freddie had a party,
maybe his last.
Suction.
Man, that's a lot of blood.
Okay, I've got the aorta.
Clamp.
Two more units O-neg.
Got it?
Yeah.
Nice work, Susan.
Yeah, great.
I just saved the
life of a murderer.
And take a deep breath.
Um, you know what?
Um, I've had enough of this.
I've got a deposition.
I still hear wheezes.
I'd like to take a full history.
Well, okay, but if you can do it
in the time that it takes
me to get dressed,
you can be my guest.
Does asthma run in your family?
No.
Have you ever had
any other symptoms?
Coughing, difficulty breathing,
fatigue, weight loss?
Yeah, fatigue, you know?
But I mean, I've been up for
two days preparing for this brief.
I'm concerned
about these attacks.
Look, um, I am up
for partner, okay?
One screw-up now, I'm finished.
You're here now. Why
don't you let me run
a couple of quick tests,
so you don't have
to come back, huh?
How long?
45 minutes.
Ugh. Uh...
I wouldn't feel right
about letting you walk out.
Okay, well, make
it snappy, okay?
We're lucky
the Bowman kid came in.
Why? What's he got?
No fracture.
What's that?
Looks like an osteosarcoma.
You have his old
chart and films?
Yeah. Here.
Mm-hmm.
There it is.
What?
The beginnings of a tumor.
No mention of it in his chart.
When was he brought in here?
November 20th.
No, they should
have caught this.
Who was the doctor?
Doug Ross.
There it is, right there.
Periosteal reaction.
He missed it.
Couple of millimeters.
Easy to miss.
We both see it.
Sure.
Today's x-ray tells
us where to look.
Okay, but you
can't change the fact
that he misdiagnosed the kid.
I'll talk to Doug.
Have you told the family?
No, not yet.
Good. Don't.
I'll take it from here.
John Carter?
In the drug lockup.
I'm in! I'm in! I'm in!
I knew you'd make it.
Yes! Are you off?
Yep. Come with me.
But you're not off.
We're going to celebrate.
I got one more
patient to get rid of
and then I can take lunch.
Where did you match, Carter?
Here.
Congratulations.
Labs on your asthma guy.
Uh-huh.
Uh-huh, uh-huh, uh-huh.
Damn.
Bad?
Ah, he's just gonna
need more tests.
I should do a blood smear.
I'll turf him to Hematology.
Give me five minutes.
Coming through!
Look out, we're coming through.
Ah...
Hugo's back for spring cleaning.
Oh, man!
Sores are infected.
Carol, I think it's your turn.
Uh-uh. I took that
crazy rabbit guy.
Haleh?
No way. I took the
guy with the maggots
last week.
Well, don't look at me.
Girls, girls,
there's plenty of
me to go around.
There's only one
way to settle this.
Ready?
One, two, three.
Best out of three?
Come on, guys.
Hey, Jeanie.
Yeah?
Hugo here needs
to be cleaned up,
and we're really busy down here.
Can you do it? No.
That's a nurse's job.
My mother was a nurse.
Great. That's great.
Ah, Dr. Lewis.
Yes?
Can you talk to that lady?
Who is she?
The mother of the junkie
that ran the red light.
Ma'am...
I'm Dr. Lewis.
Oh. You worked on my son?
Yes, I did.
They told me you saved his life.
Thank you.
Did they tell you what happened?
Yeah. Some idiot
crashed into him.
No. He ran a red light.
There were eyewitnesses.
Your son was under the
influence of alcohol and cocaine.
My son doesn't use drugs.
Tell it to the police.
The police?
Yeah. His tox
screen was positive.
You reported him?
It's required by the law.
The test was wrong.
Your son was drunk,
coked out of his mind,
got behind the wheel,
put three people
in the hospital,
and killed a little girl.
Dad, did you hear what I said?
Dad?
Oh, I'm losing
you. I'm losing you.
Can you hear me?
All right, well, you've got to
call me when you dock, okay?
A hematologist is gonna be down
in a few minutes.
He's gonna want to
run some more tests.
A hematologist? Yeah.
What is that?
It's a blood doctor.
Why do I have to see him?
You are severely anemic,
and we need to find out why.
I'm not understanding you.
Well, Dr. Berenson is
gonna explain it all to you
when he gets here.
All right. What is the
treatment for anemia?
I really couldn't tell you
without doing more tests.
Hold on a second.
How serious is this?
I wouldn't even hazard a guess.
Dr. Berenson is gonna
explain all this to you
when he gets here.
I've got another patient.
Excuse me.
All set?
Where are we going?
Surprise.
He came in for a sore knee.
Anyone could have missed that.
He could lose his leg.
Dr. Greene?
Dr. Ross?
Kathy Snyder, hospital counsel.
I asked her to come down.
So I guess I'm looking
at my first malpractice suit.
Not necessarily.
It's my understanding
that the patient and his family
are unaware that the tumor
was visible on
the earlier x-ray.
Yes.
There's no legal obligation
to make them aware of it.
So we don't say anything?
What good will it do?
Will it change the treatment?
No.
You comfortable with that?
I don't see any
advantage in telling them.
There is none.
So, where's the kid?
He's been moved to Exam 4.
Does the grandfather
know about the cancer?
I haven't told them yet.
I'll do it.
That's not a good idea.
You should disengage
from the case.
Kathy's right,
Doug. I'll handle it.
My case, my responsibility.
Ah!
♪ Younger than springtime am I ♪
♪ Gayer than laughter am I ♪
♪ Angel and lover ♪
♪ Heaven and... ♪
Raise your arms, Hugo!
♪ Am I with you ♪♪
Oh, man.
Use a lot of soap down there.
I'm a mess.
Yes, you are. Scrub really hard.
When you're done,
we're gonna get you
some clean clothes.
Can I keep my lucky shoes?
If you use more shampoo.
We need a nurse in 2.
Aah!
Oh, I am so sorry.
They need the beds changed.
I'll be right there.
Hey. I've been looking
everywhere for you.
Yeah, I'm hiding out.
You want some juice?
Sure.
I hear you got in a slap fight
with a patient.
And lost.
Oh, man,
I just want this morning to end.
What happened with Chloe?
Oh, she wants to
play Mommy again.
I called my lawyer
and the police. Police?
Yeah. What if she
tries to take her?
I don't know. Maybe
I can buy her off.
Does she know that
you're adopting her?
No, and I'm not
going to tell her.
Wait a minute.
What?
I thought your eyes were brown.
Oh.
For 15 extra bucks,
they can be blue.
Does it look dumb?
No.
I like blue eyes.
Now what?
Oh, my God.
Call security to daycare.
Looking good, Hugo.
We'll call you a cab,
and they'll take
you to a shelter.
What about my shoes?
What about them?
I need some tape.
Oh. Here.
Patient in 3 needs a nurse.
I'm busy.
Excuse me. I need scissors.
This particular patient
is puking his guts out.
Well, what do you
want me to do about it?
Why don't you get
him an emesis basin?
That's a nurse's job.
Well, can you
find another nurse?
Excuse me. They're all busy.
Excuse me. What?
I cut my finger.
Oh, Hugo, you're
gonna need stitches.
That's a P.A. job.
Oh. Jeanie, Hugo. Hugo, Jeanie.
Watch it! Watch it!
Sir! Sir, please!
I need your help. Come on!
Where's Susie?
Calm down, Dr. Lewis...
Don't tell me to calm
down. Where is she?
She's taking her first steps.
I didn't want you to miss it.
Oh, yeah.
Susie.
Yeah.
Oh, yes!
Oh, yeah!
Oh! Oh!
Oh, that's my girl.
Oh, yeah, that's my big girl.
Mr. Bowman?
Can I see you out here, please?
Oh.
Dr. Ross, right?
You're the same one
who took care of Brett
when he was in here
a few months ago.
That's right. Yes, sir.
Uh, I'm afraid that
the news isn't good.
His leg is broken?
No. His injury alerted us
to a much more serious problem.
He has an osteosarcoma.
It's a bone tumor
in his leg, above his knee.
A tumor?
It's a form of cancer.
Oh.
Uh, how bad is it?
Well, we need to determine that.
There's an oncologist
on his way down here.
He's a friend of mine.
He's one of the
best in the country,
and he's had great success
with these kind of cases.
My boy has cancer.
We'll be leaving
as soon as we talk
to the oncologist.
Thank you.
Mr. Bowman.
Hi.
Did, uh...
Dr. Greene talk to you?
No. Dr. Ross.
Oh. So, um...
he explained the situation.
He did, but I don't understand.
Brett was in here
four months ago.
He was okay.
This cropped up so fast.
I'm sorry.
Um, what exactly
did Dr. Ross tell you?
That my boy has got cancer.
That is what we're
talking about, isn't it?
Yeah. Yeah.
Excuse me.
What's happening
with the Bowman case?
Excuse us.
Doug's handling it.
Well, I just got finished
talking to the
kid's grandfather.
Doug didn't tell him
that he missed the diagnosis.
Hospital counsel
advised against it.
You're not going to
tell them the truth?
It's not going to change
the boy's diagnosis,
and we're under
no legal obligation.
What about an
ethical obligation?
Peter, you are not
the original physician
on the case,
and you're not on it now.
They have a right to know.
It's none of your business.
We made a
decision. That's final.
Lucky the kid came in.
Can you take him, Frank?
I'd like to,
but they don't have insurance.
Why? Are they friends of yours?
No, they just need a break.
Well, sorry. There's
not much I can do.
Okay, well, I guess
I'm going to have
to send my referrals
elsewhere, then.
Doug, I didn't say I
didn't want to help.
How about waiving
your professional fee?
I could do that,
but the chemotherapy's
expensive.
Ballpark. How much?
12,000.
That doesn't cover surgery.
Okay, how about I give you 5000,
I work in your clinic
on my days off?
If you do this
for every patient
who needs a break...
Would you do it?
Okay. One day a week.
Four to five months
ought to just about cover it.
Deal. Okay. Thanks.
Jerry, have you seen Susan?
Not for a while.
Hope nothing happened upstairs.
What's so funny?
Right after Jeanie
stitched up Hugo's finger,
he tripped on the way out.
Yeah?
Well, now she's got
to stitch up his head.
Susan...
is everything all right?
It's great.
What happened?
It's amazing.
What?
Susie took her first steps!
Two little steps!
Oh, you have crumbs.
Hazards of the hirsute.
Dr. Benton?
Yes?
I want to thank
you for everything
you've done for my grandson.
We'll be leaving
as soon as we talk
to the oncologist.
Well, good luck.
Thank you very much.
Mr. Bowman...
I think there's something
you should know.
Just follow my finger.
Okay.
Yep.
Extraocular
movements are intact.
We were dollying
in for a close-up
when we hit a sandbag.
Eyepiece smashed
right into my eye.
Oh, so you're a cameraman...
woman?
Director and producer
of infomercials.
You ever see
"30 Days to a Tighter Butt"?
No. Uh, missed that.
Hey, uh, can you
raise your eyebrows?
Smile.
Nice teeth.
Cranial nerves are intact.
You ever do any modeling?
Me? No.
Been on camera?
You made that teaching
video a few years back.
Yeah, well, I'm, uh...
the star of "How to Intubate."
So, you do have
on-camera experience.
Oh...
I'll just take a quick look
at the other side here.
Where in the hell is he?
Who?
Who? The damn medical student.
Carter.
Yeah, Carter.
He has kept me waiting here
for two hours.
Now, I would like
my test results.
Okay. Please calm down.
I'll page Dr. Carter.
Fax this to my office.
The number is on the top.
Dr. Ross?
Oh, yeah. Good news.
I spoke to the oncologist.
He can take care of Brett.
You missed it
and didn't have the
decency to tell us.
I'm sorry.
No, you're not.
You're trying to cover your ass.
At least let me
set the oncologist
up with Brett.
I don't want you near my boy.
Hi.
Sorry, I don't have
anything on me right now.
Uh, catch you later?
Your CT looks normal.
Ooh.
Ooh, is that my brain?
Yes, it is.
How's it look?
Perfect.
So, have you thought
about my offer?
Yes, and your project
sounds intriguing.
Well, we'll discuss
it over dinner.
What do I have to do?
Just be yourself.
You'll be a spokesperson
for a new FDA-approved drug.
What sort of drug?
A more potent
version of minoxidil.
For high blood pressure?
Yeah, that's the one,
but we're more interested
in promoting it for
male pattern baldness.
I see. Uh...
You know, I thought...
I mean, I read somewhere
that women find
baldness a sign of virility.
Oh.
Who told you that?
Some bald guy?
Hugo needs a ride
back to the shelter.
Call him a cab.
Jerry's got vouchers.
That's a nurse's job.
I'm on a break.
Hugo will wait.
The nurse will
be right with you.
I wait here the whole damn day
and all you can
say is you're sorry?
I have your tests.
I called in a hematologist...
See, now, that is exactly
what the damn
medical student said
three hours ago.
Now, this had better
be worse than anemia.
I'm afraid it is.
Mr. Ledbetter,
your blood smear shows evidence
of acute myelogenous leukemia.
What?
We need to admit
you to run more tests.
Is there anyone I should call?
Excuse me. Mr. Ledbetter?
Your office just
faxed this over.
To the future.
To surgery.
To my future in surgery!
Ah.
Do you realize
that you're taking a bath
with one of the most
sought-after residents
in the country?
I have goose bumps.
So I see.
Is that you?
Not me.
Oop...
Oops.
Where is it?
10-year-old girl,
fell off a balance beam
and hit her neck.
Her throat's too
swollen to tube her.
Vitals? Get them right.
BP's 70/50.
Pulse thready at 180.
Cyanotic.
How's the air exchange?
Bad. She's hard to ventilate.
Damn it, her IV's infiltrated!
I thought you got it!
I did!
Gonna need an
airway. I'll tube her.
All right.
What do we got?
One, two...
Buckle my shoe and kiss my ass.
Haleh, get me a
pertrach kit, please.
Why don't you move over
and let the nurse do that?
I can get it.
I said, let the nurse do it.
Take your beef outside.
Why don't you go with him?
I've done more of these.
Sterile gloves, please.
You hand him
those sterile gloves,
and you're both out of here.
Give me that.
Thank you.
Okay. You ready?
Trach tube introducer.
Okay. Bag her.
Look, the family
had a right to know.
You're right, Peter.
Look, you made a mistake.
Why don't you just own up to it?
Why don't you just
get out? Settle down.
Peter, Doug can handle this.
Go on.
Jerry...
I think I was paged.
Mm-hmm. Indeed you were.
Four times from Dr. Lewis,
twice from Dr. Hicks,
and twice from Hematology,
and from Morgenstern,
a congratulatory
basket of muffins. Oh.
Dr. Morgenstern leave a note?
Carter!
Where the hell have you been?
Lunch.
For three hours?
Long lunch.
Well, you left
Mr. Ledbetter waiting.
I'll go see him now.
Don't bother.
I admitted him
upstairs with leukemia.
Leukemia?
I didn't think it
was that serious.
Yeah? What are you, first year?
He had low crit
and fatigue,
and you didn't work him up?
Is that alcohol on your breath?
It's champagne.
From your mom and big Roland.
Carter, I've been paging you
for the last three
hours. Sorry, Dr. Hicks.
Well, you're in luck.
I have an emergency
appendectomy in 10 minutes.
Kindly scrub in.
Dr. Hicks.
Dr. Hicks,
I better think I not...
I think I, uh, better not.
Why?
Well, I went out to lunch
to celebrate
and had a little champagne.
You drank during rotation hours?
Uh, yeah.
It's bad enough you failed
to answer your pages,
but the use of alcohol on call
is inexcusable.
I'm sorry.
It's grounds for expulsion.
But...
But I just matched!
Another basket of treats
for our fallen med student?
I'm afraid so.
Look, I'm gonna have
to beg off for tonight.
Our friendly in-house attorney
wants me to file
an incident report.
I was thinking
about canceling too.
No, don't. You go.
Have a good time.
Don't let that
goatee go to waste.
Did you hear about
him and Benton?
Hear about it?
I saw them
practically duke it out
in the Trauma Room.
Benton's right.
If it were my kid,
I'd want to know.
Thanks.
Carter?
You got another basket.
Leave it outside.
Hmm. What have we got?
Paté, smoked oysters,
pickled quail eggs...
You all right?
I really screwed up.
I neglected my patient,
got really out of control.
What you did was
incredibly stupid
and you're in big trouble,
but Hicks can't expel you
without an
administrative hearing.
Will I lose my match?
I don't know.
Oh, God!
I'll see what I can do.
The note says, "Love,
Nana and Poopie."
Hey, Carol.
Yeah?
I need some help.
What is it?
My partner backed over a bum
in the parking lot.
Are you okay, sir?
I didn't see you.
I'm sorry. Oh, God, I'm sorry.
Hugo, are you all right?
What happened?
I was fixing my shoe.
You forgot to call me a cab.
Oh, God.
He was sitting on the curb
and I didn't see him.
I'm sorry. I'm really sorry.
Listen, just stay out here
and don't hurt anyone else.
Cut the kid some slack, Shep.
Come on.
It looks like a
fractured tib-fib.
My friends were right.
This is a dangerous place.
Oh, Hugo, I am so sorry.
Me too. It's our fault.
Go check on your partner.
We'll take care of Hugo.
Hey, and go easy on him.
I told you not to say anything.
Yeah, well, I didn't
agree with that.
No, you took it upon yourself
to tell the family,
the ramifications of which
affect Doug, me,
your colleagues,
and the entire hospital.
Look, if Ross had
caught it four months ago,
that kid might not
be losing his leg.
Now, don't you think the family
had a right to know that?
That wasn't your
decision to make.
Oh, so I tell the truth and
what, break some kind of code?
This isn't about truth
or any kind of code.
This is about your
guilty conscience.
You didn't have the guts
to speak up about Vucelich,
so you blow the whistle on Doug.
The truth is a
lot easier to tell
when it's not your
own career on the line.
Hey, where's your partner?
The moron?
He's upstairs drinking cocoa.
You really shouldn't
ride him so hard.
The department
throws me a rookie.
I guess it's their
way of punishing me.
They giving you a hard time?
They say
they would have
done the same thing.
You don't believe them?
What are they supposed to say?
Nobody blames you, Shep.
I led Raul into that fire.
You saved three kids.
And I killed my best friend.
Hey. How's it going?
Uh...
I saw 48 kids that day.
That's about 12 minutes a kid.
I only gave the Bowman kid
about 10.
I guess I should have
given him a couple more.
Benton was out of line.
He just told the truth.
Now you have to pay for it.
No, it's the kid who
has to pay for it.
How you doing?
Oh.
Excuse me.
I'm sorry.
I think I lost my contact.
Dr. Greene?
Kathy?
What are you doing here?
Uh...
same as you, I suspect.
Hi.
Here, let me help you.
Don't move.
Are you sure it's
not still in your eye?
Uh, I don't know.
Open wide.
You have one blue
eye and one brown.
Yeah, well, for 15 bucks,
they throw in the tinted pair.
I need my glasses
if I'm going to find this.
Um, do you have lens insurance?
No.
Well, then, we'd
better keep looking.
This is so embarrassing.
Wait. Don't move.
It was caught in your goatee.
Yeah.
Thank you.
What do you want
for dinner tonight?
You want some smooshed carrots?
I have to talk to you.
There's nothing more to say.
Can't I just look at her,
please?
Stay away from us.
Oh, she's so beautiful.
She's so big.
Is she crawling yet, or...
Chloe, I mean it.
I know I can't change
what's happened,
but let's not fight, okay?
I saw a lawyer today.
She said I could file
for visitation rights.
I'm adopting her.
No...
She is my baby, Susan,
and I want her back.
Yeah, I'm sorry.
Hi. Hi.
Soup of the day to go.
Sure thing.
Hey, Peter.
Hey.
Rough day.
You did the right thing.
Yeah, well,
not according to everybody else.
I broke the code.
You okay?
It's kind of like that
Boys Club camp.
Did my mother tell you
everything about me?
You were what, 12?
10.
Yes, 10.
She said a kid ripped
off the equipment fund,
showed you the money,
you turned him in...
Yeah, and nobody spoke to
me for the rest of the summer.
I thought they broke your nose.
I told her I took a curve ball.
She knew.
Yeah, well, I guess
you never learn.
"Good night, room.
"Good night, moon.
"Good night,
"cow jumping over the moon.
"Good night, air.
"Good night, bears.
"Good night, chairs.
"Good night, stars.
Good night, noises everywhere."