♪ Ohhh ohhh ohhh ♪
I think I'm done
with therapy.
I mean, I am...
So, so...
So grateful,
you know,
but I have...
Everything I've ever wanted.
I mean, isn't that
the point of therapy,
to make your life into
what you want it to be?
I have everything.
I have it all.
♪ I'm a seeker ♪
♪ true believer ♪
♪ a long time ago ♪
What are we, uh,
what are we doing?
We're making out.
The same thing
that we have been doing--
just making out.
Mm.
♪♪♪
I should probably
close the blinds.
♪♪♪
Okay.
To be continued.
Hi.
I don't want to bother you.
Oh, you're not
bothering...
Are you okay?
I'm having a baby
with no brain.
I'm fine. I'm great.
I'm... horrible.
I'm devastated...
But okay.
We talked about this.
It's traumatic.
And so it's perfectly natural,
in the weeks
prior to your due date,
to... develop feelings
of--of fear and despair...
No.
And--
i'm--I'm having
the baby right now.
I'm in labor, Jake.
I don't need
to be here yet.
I'm barely dilated.
I could wait it out
at home--
actually, you, uh,
you do need to be here.
You paged them?
Yep.
And what did they say?
I'm going to go talk to them
as soon as I leave you.
Okay.
No drugs.
No epidural, no pain meds,
no sedatives.
I mean it.
Okay.
I want you to move me
off the o.B. Floor
the minute
I'm done delivering.
I-I don't want to be
on this floor.
Okay.
And wrap his head
right away.
I don't want to see it.
Okay.
Just take him away...
Before I can see him.
I-I don't want
to hear him cry.
Just--before he cries.
Amelia...
Right.
A baby without a frontal lobe
can't cry.
I saw one once
when I was an intern.
They make this kind of
squeaking noise.
Brainless babies squeak.
I mean, it's the only way
you can describe
the noise they make,
but...
I mean, you'd think that
it would be awful,
but actually,
it's kinda...
Life will out, you know?
I know.
Anyway...
Take him away
before he squeaks.
So Pete's just gonna admit
that he took his patient
off the ventilator?
Yep, he's convinced
he did the right thing.
It's gonna make it hard
for his lawyer.
What's going on? Is something
wrong with Pete?
No.
Amelia's in labor.
Oh, god.
Okay, i-I'm gonna go see--
Jake says we should
all stay here.
Well, he might need a consult.
Amelia made it clear that she
doesn't want you in there, so--
really, Sam?
Hey, hey.
Is she in labor?
Yeah.
Where's Coop?
He's with Violet.
Woman nearly broke down our door
at the crack of dawn,
wanting to scream
about Pete.
How is she?
How do you think
she is?
Terrified,
blaming everyone but Pete.
Jake...
Just give me a minute.
Okay, first I want to say,
that as Amelia's doctor,
no one goes near her
unless you're sure
you can be supportive.
Why wouldn't
we be supportive?
Jake, what are you
talking about?
Amelia wants to donate
her baby's organs.
How long have you
known about this?
Since she chose me
as her o.B.
That's murder.
Sam, please, do not get
religious on me here.
This has nothing to do
with religion.
The American academy
of pediatrics states...
I know what it states.
That a declaration of
brain death has to be made
before procuring the organs.
And since there's no brain
in a child that's anencephalic--
and still medical ethicists
are split
on whether it's acceptable
to retrieve organs from them.
Why not just wait
till the baby dies?
Because by then,
it'll be too late.
The organs will deteriorate,
and they will no longer
be viable for transplant.
I need to go consult
our lawyer.
Charlotte,
Charlotte...
We're talking about
Amelia here.
I know it's Amelia,
which is why I'm not revoking
your privileges
and throwing you out of here.
This is a person I love.
I need to consult the lawyers
that represent this hospital
to see what they think,
because I think
this is killing a baby.
Calling the case
of Peter Wilder.
Counselors.
The state contends
that Dr. Wilder showed
reckless disregard both for
the life of his patient
and for the laws of this state
when he intentionally--
he pulled a Kevorkian?
My client followed
the instructions--
a Kevorkian? Are you serious?
Pete.
Dr. Wilder.
My patient did not want to be
kept alive by life support.
Stop talking.
Your client killed a guy.
He doesn't look too sorry.
Your honor, if you--
I'm not sorry.
Oh, Pete.
I am not sorry.
Good. You made this easy.
Bail is denied.
You have something to say
or are you
just gonna watch me?
'Cause this gown is backless,
so when I turn around
to go that way,
you're gonna get a really great
view of my maternity panties.
That was quite a bombshell
Jake dropped on us today
about you donating
the baby's organs.
I'm like that...
All bombshell-y.
I was wondering how you
came to your decision.
To my decision?
My decision to donate
the organs
of my brainless baby?
Amelia.
I'm... having...
A contraction.
Is there...
Can I do anything?
It hurts.
Don't touch me.
Are you all right?
I'm fine.
Contractions come and go.
That's what happens
when you're having a baby,
even a unicorn baby.
A unicorn baby?
Well, that's an interesting
choice of words.
Sheldon, I'm doing
a thing here.
What do you want?
Sometimes people think they can
circumvent the grieving process
by focusing on
an external goal.
And... while concentrating
on the benefits
of organ donation
is a perfectly valid
short-term coping mechanism,
it can't replace the work
you need to do
to deal with your own
profound loss.
The work I need to do?
The...
Are you freakin' kidding me?
Look at me.
This is supposed to be
the happiest day of my life.
I'm having a baby.
I'm in labor.
Yay. I am dealing
with my loss, Sheldon.
I am swimming in it.
I just wanted to make sure
you thought this through.
I... I just want
to help you--
no, you just don't want
to feel guilty.
Get out. Please.
How do you even declare
brain death
in an anencephalic child?
Lack of reflexes,
pupillary responses.
No. Those criteria
don't apply here.
They indicate an absence
of brain stem activity.
Amelia's baby has
a rudimentary brain stem.
It'll never
gain consciousness.
Exactly.
There is zero chance
it will ever have
any kind of meaningful life.
Will you stop saying "it"?
Because the baby
will be alive.
It's not a life I'd want,
but it's not a life I'd kill.
Stop saying "it."
Say "he."
Say "him."
You have to kill him
to recover the organs.
Look, Sam, I need your help
to harvest the heart
and the lungs.
Amelia needs your help.
I want to help,
and I-I don't know how.
Should I call Derek?
No, she expressly asked me
not to call her family.
She wants to do this
on her own.
Well, I have to do something.
I can't just--
I-I have to do something.
You want to help?
Sam is the best cardio guy
at St. ambrose.
Get him to harvest
the heart and lungs.
Do you need anything?
No.
I made my cell mate my bitch,
so I'm good.
Little prison humor.
Sorry.
Roberta's gonna appeal
the judge's decision.
She says you should get bail.
She said that the judge
was prejudiced.
That judge was an ass.
Hey, Pete, I'm freaking out
here, okay?
I'm freaking out. I--
okay, okay.
Hey.
I love you.
How's Lucas?
He's good.
He misses you.
I told him that you were
out of town for a while.
We shouldn't lie.
We shouldn't lie?
What should I tell him,
Pete?
Really, what?
Daddy's in jail because that's
where they put...
Accused murderers?
I did the right thing.
You did the right
thing by your patient.
You did not do the right thing
by our family.
by our son.
You need to cooperate.
I will not say
that I'm sorry.
Pete, I get
that you're not sorry.
I don't need you to be sorry.
I need you to not be in prison.
So please say whatever
you have to say.
Cooperate.
Bail was denied entirely?
Yeah, entirely.
But they're appealing that,
right? They can appeal that.
They are.
Because it seems
a little extreme.
Well, he did kill someone.
S-Someone who wasn't
going to recover,
someone who's partner
had asked him to--
Pete knew the law.
He broke the law.
And he put himself
and the hospital at risk
when he did it.
This is not helpful.
Can we not--
can we just not...
Debate it for once?
This is a mistake.
Amelia's in a very bad place.
Did you just see her?
I couldn't stay away
even though it's just possible
that she hates me
enough to kill me.
Yeah, if I don't do it first.
I told you not to go see her
if you couldn't be supportive.
- I was supporting her.
- The argument is pointless.
The hospital still hasn't signed
off on the organ procurement.
And they shouldn't.
Do you know
how many babies die ever year
- waiting for organ transplants?
- Charlotte,
you have to fight here.
Who thinks this is
a good idea?
Who's against?
We know how Sam feels.
We're split
right down the middle.
Aren't we a microcosm
of the medical community?
I hate my job.
Sam, this organ procurement
has to be flawless.
Every surgery
I know. It's just...
It's her baby's heart.
It's a baby's heart,
and when we get one...
Look, if it were me,
there's no one I'd rather have
holding the scalpel than you.
Well, it's a good thing
it isn't you, then, isn't it?
Oh, Sam.
Look, Amelia's situation
is tragic.
But just because her baby's
going to die
doesn't mean that it's okay
for me to...
Rush the process.
Sam, I know I'm asking you
to do the hard thing here,
but when people we love
need us,
sometimes
we have to compromise.
Today's lecture's
on compromise?
Because I remember
the last one,
you said, uh,
if I wasn't all in,
then I had to just walk away.
So which one is it, Addison?
I know you saw
me and Jake,
and I probably owe you
an explanation--
no, no, you don't
have to explain
why you gave an ultimatum,
and when I couldn't answer
for five seconds,
you immediately moved on
to someone else.
That definitely, definitely
doesn't demand an explanation.
Your inability to answer,
Sam,
that was my answer.
Look,
I don't want to talk--
I will recommend
several excellent
cardiac surgeons to Jake.
But beyond that,
I can't be a part of this.
I can't.
♪ was once done to me ♪
♪ such a wicked, wicked ♪
Hey, handsome.
How was play practice?
♪♪♪
What was that about?
There was a mother's day
lunch at school.
All the moms came in,
the kids gave 'em
these scrapbooks
that they made.
You gotta be kidding me.
Why didn't you tell me?
I woulda gone.
I didn't know.
Well,
we spoke to his teacher.
She shoulda said something.
She sent an invitation
with a note on it.
Mason never gave it
to us.
He threw it out.
♪ I watch you fall away ♪
♪ fall away ♪
I'm not praying.
This is the only position
that doesn't make me insane.
Whoever decided a baby
is supposed to tunnel its way
out of my body
through my vagina,
I would like to have a serious
conversation with them.
I think the only way to
actually have that conversation
is in fact by praying.
Don't be a wiseass.
Amelia, you understand that
without any drugs,
any intervention, you..
You could be in labor
for another 20, even 30 hours?
♪ The darkest staircase ♪
At least let me help you.
Right there?
♪♪♪
No. Stop.
Don't touch me.
Amelia--
if you touch me,
I will cry.
I know I will.
It's stupid and it's weak,
but I can't help it,
and if I start crying...
I want to be strong.
I want to be strong
and I want
to get through this
and I don't want
to feel too much.
I don't want to cry.
You're in pain.
Please, just don't.
♪♪♪
Ohh.
Aah.
Screw it. Cry, Amelia.
No.
I'm not letting go.
I've got you.
♪ Am I hopeless? I trust you,
but where are you ♪
It's okay.
♪ Walking to? ♪
I'm shocked.
Genuinely just...
Just shocked by how much
I love him.
I want to take his pain away.
And I know I can't.
And it kills me.
It just...
It kills me.
You take my pain away.
Aw. I remember kissing,
back from when my husband wasn't
separated from me by glass.
Mm. Any news from the lawyer?
Uh, yeah.
The lawyer's trying
the best she can.
But Pete is...
I don't know.
I'm afraid he's gonna
destroy himself.
I mean, he's stubborn.
He's so stubborn.
I'm afraid he's gonna stubborn
himself into a life sentence.
He'll come around.
Well, his mother
went to prison.
I mean, families
perpetuate patterns.
Unintentionally, unconsciously,
we repeat patterns.
What am I gonna tell my son?
Hey.
Addison.
Hmm?
Stop trying to read
Amelia's chart.
How is she?
She have any decels
on the fetal monitor?
Is she progressing?
I know she says she doesn't
want drugs, but I think--
what are you doing?
I'm asking.
You know
I can't tell you anything.
I just want to help her.
I told you,
you want to help her,
get Sam to harvest
the heart and the lungs.
Sam said no.
I tried.
But he said no.
Oh.
What?
There are nine cardiothoracic
surgeons in the area
certified to do this kind
of pediatric procedure.
I've been rejected
by eight of them.
Sam makes nine.
I've been calling surgeons
all day long.
Nobody wants to do this
because they're cowards
or they're...
I don't want to do this.
But I said that I would.
I told her I would do this
for her.
Damn it. She's in there
doing the hardest thing
I've ever seen, and I...
I promised her.
You been in
to see her yet?
She doesn't want to see me.
Huh.
What?
The Addison I know
is a pushy bitch
who would've given
that fancy-pants, snooty,
"double board certified
neonatal surgeon" speech
as an excuse
and shoved her way into
that room no matter what.
I just--i just...
Every time I try--
I mean, I've dealt with cases
so much worse than this, but...
Every time I try
to go in there, I just--
I just...
Can't get myself to do it.
I can't do it either.
Been avoiding it.
I was trying to figure out why,
and then...
This morning,
I was looking at Mason,
and I realized--
you're a mother.
We can't go in there
because we're mothers.
Mason's changed me.
Henry's changed you.
We're softer.
I just realized, this past year,
that you and I
both became mothers
without ever giving birth.
And she's gonna give birth...
Not get to be a mother.
Did Violet send you to tell me
to cooperate?
No.
To tell me
to keep my mouth shut...
No.
Or better yet,
to tell me to apologize?
My son's mother died.
I know. I-I was there.
She doesn't get to go to
any special lunches at school,
or see the science projects
he brings home,
or see him in the school play,
or drop him off at boy scouts.
And what do you think
she'd do
just for a chance
to be there,
to see all that?
You think maybe
she'd swallow her pride?
Do you think
she'd keep her mouth shut?
maybe she'd even apologize
even though she doesn't think
she did anything wrong?
I hear that,
Cooper, but--
there's no buts, Pete.
The--
I get you.
I am you.
I'm proud to a fault,
I'm stubborn as hell,
I'm willing to do the wrong
thing for the right reason.
I get you, mostly.
But...
You have a wife
who loves you
and a son who needs you,
and you have a chance
to be there
with them, for them.
I don't get you throwing away
that chance.
♪♪♪
Don't throw them away.
How much time do I have?
You're going to help?
I'm gonna pull in some favors
and get you some surgeons.
I'm gonna fight the lawyers,
but I can't promise anything.
Thank you.
You still need
a cardiothoracic surgeon.
You still need Sam before I can
declare a full transplant team.
Okay.
Lawyers may still say no.
But you are going to fight?
But I am gonna fight.
♪ I don't wanna be
your buddy ♪
♪ I may come around again ♪
So I just want you
to understand why...
Why I can't be a part
of your transplant team.
I understand.
Okay, because, um--
you're gonna say
it's because, technically,
a child
with a working brain stem
can't be declared brain dead
even though he'll never
walk or talk
or move or eat,
even though he's missing
the parts of his brain
that he needs to have a life.
Not just be alive,
but have a life...
To love,
to think,
to know words
and feelings,
to be conscious.
You're gonna talk to me about
medicine and technicalities
and the failings of science.
Yeah.
But the thing is, that's not
why you won't do the harvest.
Well, until we know,
uh, with...
Medical certainty,
you know, until the law--
it's because
it's unimaginable.
What I'm asking you to do
is unimaginable.
It's horrible.
It's excruciating.
I'm asking you to help
dismantle my baby for parts.
And there's no piece
of anyone's soul
that can hold that
and feel okay.
But I'm asking.
I'm asking you.
I'm his mother.
And I'm asking you
to do this.
And you want to know why?
It's because I did
a little research, Sam.
Science.
In Chicago, there's this
baby girl, 6 weeks old,
with pulmonary hypertension
who needs new lungs.
Outside Detroit there is
a 10-day-old boy
who was born blind, but could
see if he had new corneas.
I read this blog about
this 14-month-old kid
named Gideon in San Diego
who's been on
a heart-lung machine for months
because he needs
one tiny valve in his heart.
There's burned babies
who need skin.
There's infants
who need livers,
and toddlers
who need kidneys,
and there's even this one
4-month-old girl named Lulu
who needs
a multiple-organ transplant.
My baby...
Could save
all of those babies.
He could be responsible
for kids leaving the hospital
and going home
and growing up
and falling in love
and having sex
and arguing
with their boyfriends
and making mistakes
and living
and maybe not ruining
their lives with drugs.
What I'm asking you to do
is unimaginable.
But it's also everything
those other mothers
could ever imagine.
I'm his mom.
And I'm asking you
to do this.
If I can get there,
why can't you?
I mean,
does it occur to you
that somebody else
might want some of those?
No. I mean, the hand to
the mouth to the box, it's...
Any news--
babies, bail?
You think we'd be standing here
if there was any news?
Amelia's still in labor,
Pete's still in jail.
Oh, cookies
for breakfast?
It was his idea.
Hey.
Is that yours, Addison?
No.
No, that's me.
Violet?
Charlotte. Amelia's
6 centimeters dilated.
Baby's on the way.
Are you coming?
The hospital lawyers haven't
signed off on this yet.
I can still do
the delivery.
I'm just saying,
you can't harvest any organs
until we get
explicit permission.
Fine.
So you're not
gonna do anything--
Charlotte, I heard you.
Jake, I want to go in
with you.
No.
Jake--
until she asks for you,
the answer is no.
Sorry, Addison.
Jake.
I'm right here.
Aah!
Ah!
Oh, well, we should
call Violet,
let her know
what's going on.
Yeah.
You know,
women who use cocaine
are at greater risk
than the rest of the population
for all sorts
of complications.
You know,
there's placental abruption,
and--and--and...
Why do you know that?
I did a lot of research
after Amelia told me
she was pregnant.
Oh.
It was my way
of being supportive.
Not that she wants
my support anymore.
Mm.
It was oxy.
What?
Amelia's drug of choice...
She was doing oxy,
not cocaine.
So?
So maybe everything
will turn out all right.
Well, sure, because oxy's
like a prenatal vitamin.
Prenatal--
Somebody really should
redecorate this waiting room,
you know?
Come here.
I'm sorry
you have to be here.
I don't mind.
♪♪♪
Oh, god!
Oh, make it stop!
No, I don't want to do this.
I don't want
to do this anymore.
You're doing great, okay?
But I-I need you
to stop pushing for a while.
I have to. If I don't push,
it hurts too much.
This is a unicorn baby.
I shouldn't have to do this
with a unicorn baby.
I want this to be over.
Ryan should be here.
I want Ryan.
Amelia,
you're almost there.
No.
No, this is too hard.
I have to push.
No, no, no. Not yet.
Not yet.
Oh, god! It hurts!
I want some drugs.
Hang in there.
I can't.
I can't do this.
Yes, you can.
Addison--
I don't want her here.
Yes, you do.
I don't. I don't.
I don't want you here.
Yes, you do, Amelia.
♪♪♪
Addie...
My baby's gonna die.
I know.
I am so, so sorry.
I'm calling him
a unicorn baby.
You are?
That's great.
I have to push. If I don't push,
it hurts too much.
We need to control
her labor.
Okay, Amelia, look, I know
that you want to push,
but you have to wait.
No.
Amelia, yes.
Ohh!
Hold on to me.
Addie...
Addie, I want to push.
I know.
I want to push.
Just wait.
Wait.
Wait. Shh. Wait.
Okay, now, Amelia.
Push.
Aah! Aah.
♪♪♪
♪ with the world outside ♪
♪ into arms so wide ♪
Oh, my god.
How did you--
why aren't you--
bail. I kept my mouth shut.
I cooperated.
♪♪♪
♪ I knew you ♪
You did a good job.
Is he...
How is he?
He's okay.
We're going to take him now.
And I'm going to move you
off the obstetrics floor
as fast
as I can manage it, okay?
Wait.
I want to see him.
Are you sure?
Are you ready?
Yeah.
♪ Keep you awake ♪
♪ baby, close your eyes ♪
♪ I'll take the weight ♪
He's beautiful.
♪ If I go to speak ♪
♪ I will refrain ♪
♪ and be the song ♪
♪ just be the song ♪
♪ when inner scars ♪
He's the most beautiful baby
I've ever seen.
♪ Show on your face ♪
Shh.
It's okay.
♪ Your sense of place ♪
Hey.
Are you...
Uh, waiting for Charlotte,
just like you are.
What changed your mind?
I don't know.
I just...
I got there.
Hey, Charlotte.
Did they say--
did they agree to do it?
No.
You're kidding me.
I'm not.
Screw it.
We're gonna do it anyway.
♪ Inner scars ♪
♪ show on your face ♪
♪ and darkness hides ♪
This is my son.
♪ Your sense of place ♪
What's happening?
What--what's wrong?
He's in respiratory distress.
No.
Not yet. I'm not ready.
It's okay
to change your mind.
If you want to just hold
your boy for as long as he has,
we'll do that.
If not, we, uh,
we need to give him to
the transplant team right now.
♪ Flow down all my mountains ♪
♪ darlin' ♪
♪ fill my valleys ♪
♪ flow down... ♪
Your father's waiting
for you.
His name is Ryan,
and he's waiting for you.
So you won't be lonely.
♪ Flow down all my mountains ♪
♪ darlin' ♪
♪ fill my valleys ♪
♪ And when you run ♪
♪ far from my eyes ♪
♪ then I will come ♪
This is for Sacramento.
Sacramento.
♪ But I won't speak ♪
This one's for San Diego.
San Diego.
♪ Light ♪
This is for Boston.
Boston.
♪ Song ♪
♪ flow down all my mountains ♪
Syringe.
♪ Darlin', fill my valleys ♪
♪ flow down ♪
♪ all my mountains ♪
Turn that thing off.
♪ Fill my valleys ♪
♪ flow down ♪
♪ all my mountains ♪
♪ darlin' ♪
♪ fill my valleys ♪
♪ flow down ♪
That's for Chicago.
Chicago.
♪ Fill my valleys ♪
We should tell Amelia.
We should stay--
no, I got this.
♪ Darlin' ♪
Thank you.
♪ Valleys ♪
♪ flow down all my mountains ♪
♪ darlin' ♪
♪ fill my valleys ♪
♪ flow down
all my mountains ♪
♪ darlin' ♪
Thank you.
♪ Flow down ♪
♪ all my mountains ♪
♪ darlin' ♪
♪♪♪
I just want to go home...
And hug my kid.
Yeah.
You--you knew what she meant
when she, uh,
when she called it
a-a unicorn baby?
When she was 12 years old,
she was...
She was obsessed with unicorns
because they were magical
and they could do
great things, you know?
This baby, its, uh...
Its organs are gonna go
all over the country
and do great things.
It's--it's magical.
It's...
It's her unicorn baby.
♪♪♪
So you, um...
You maybe wanna...
You wanna
get something to eat?
I mean...
If you're hungry.
Yeah, I am.
Um...
I have to get back
to see Henry
and relieve my nanny.
Yeah, I have some stuff
I can take care of here, too,
but, um...
I can, uh, I can
meet at your place.
Say an hour and a half,
bring Chinese?
Yeah, I'd like that.
Did your dad tell you
what was going on?
He said a baby
was being born mostly dead.
So they're donating his organs
so other babies can live.
That's right.
That baby over there,
she was born so premature,
her lungs never had a chance
to form properly.
And because of science,
because of medicine,
she got some new lungs,
and now she's gonna live
a whole life.
She shoulda been dead.
If she was born ten years ago,
she would've been dead.
And now she's alive.
Miracle.
You think if my mom got sick
ten years from now,
she'd still be alive?
I don't know.
But I think that idea's
what might make you
an incredible doctor
one day.
You think
I could be a doctor?
I know you could.
I'm not good with nature
or soccer
the way your mama was.
But you're a good doctor.
I am.
Is this weird that I took you
to see the sick babies?
No, it's not weird.
I don't know
what to call you.
I already have a mom.
And I don't want to take
your mama's place, Mason.
But I am happy
to stand in for her
any time you want to let me.
How about mama?
What's that?
I already have a mom,
but how about
I call you mama,
like you call your mom?
That sounds, uh...
Yeah.
Okay.
All right.
♪ to take me ♪
♪ to take me, too ♪
♪ after so many words ♪
Hey.
♪ Still nothing's heard ♪
What time is it?
Uh, it's...
It's about 9:00.
♪ So if someone
can see me now ♪
♪ let them see you ♪
You know,
I've been here all day,
just in case
you were wondering.
Worrying about me?
Well, you're my best friend,
which is sad,
because you're 8 years old
and... you don't return
my affections,
but ah, well, there it is.
You're my best friend.
It's okay to laugh.
It happens.
♪ So if someone
could help me now ♪
I had a baby, Sheldon.
♪ Mm ♪
For a few minutes there...
I was someone's mom.
♪ See you through ♪
You're still someone's mom.
He's just not--
not here anymore.
♪ We've all gotta do ♪
I missed you.
♪ Ooh ♪
♪ and so you wouldn't
be wrong ♪
♪ bein' free, you and me ♪
It's okay to cry.
It happens.
♪ Mm-mm ♪
♪ mm-mm ♪
♪ ah ♪
Are you okay?
♪ Ohh ♪
What if I blew it?
♪ Ah-ah, ahh ♪
What if I have to go
back to prison...
Like, for a long time?
♪ Mm-mm, mm-mm ♪
♪ mm-mm ♪
What if I blew it, Violet?
♪ Mm-mm ♪
Hey.
Where's keisha?
I sent her home.
Why?
Because after the kind of
day that I had--
that we've had...
Hi, baby.
You want to see your kid.
Well, he's not your kid,
remember?
Ooh, boy.
You are gonna make this
as difficult as possible,
aren't you?
You know what?
We're both exhausted, Sam.
It's been a really long day,
and I don't have the energy
to fight.
Well, I do.
Sam--
all right, I have the energy
to fight for you.
I'm--I'm fighting for you
right now.
What?
When you asked me if--
if I was all in,
I-I should've said yes,
so i'm--I'm saying yes now.
Well, it's too late.
I love you.
You know, I just told you,
it's too late.
I'm in love with you.
It's not too late.
No--
it's never too late.
When you had the chance,
you didn't want me,
you didn't want to have
a family,
but then you see me
with Jake, and then--
I don't care about Jake.
You've been with him,
what, two minutes?
Look, you were right.
I... I didn't want a baby.
And I don't.
I don't want a baby.
I want this baby.
I want Henry.
And... I want you
and me and Henry
to be a family.
I was afraid of that before.
I just--
I couldn't imagine
being a new father
and having a whole new family.
It was unimaginable,
but...
♪ I let 'em in ♪
But I can imagine it now.
I can see it.
So...
I'm all in.
I'm all in
and I'm fighting for you.
Look...
I know that this is, uh--
Sam, what are you doing?
Wait. Wait a minute.
This is not,
as, uh, traditional,
but for now...
Uh, Addison Forbes Montgomery,
I love you.
Will you marry me?
♪♪♪