The human brain.
This is the reason
I asked Dr. Grey
if I could fill in for
her this morning.
Nature makes a
beautiful machine.
Don't you think?
You might be surprised,
but anatomy classes can be
uncomfortable for surgeons.
Ready to take it apart?
We're trained to put
bodies back together.
We prefer our
tissue warm, alive.
See how easily the
blade slices through?
Comes apart like warm butter.
This big ball of jelly
is the essential
element that makes you,
you.
Here's a fun fact.
If left to decompose,
the brain actually liquifies.
Usually when a surgeon
is staring at dead tissue...
Look out! Was it
something I said?
It means that something
is very, very wrong.
Oh, God.
Oh, God, please, please.
Please, please, please.
Oh, no, no.
No! Whoa.
Hey.
Oh, we had sex?
We had sex. Yeah,
we had so much sex.
Yeah, we did. And it was great.
I don't mean to
rush out, but, uh...
There are people in
this house and, um...
We had sex and
you're an intern... Yeah.
So you have to get out.
Yeah, okay. Bye.
Stop. You... There
might be people out there.
There might be kids.
You have kids?
My sister has kids.
My sister could see you.
I mean, I don't hear anyone.
I think we're okay.
Are you sure?
Yeah. We're fine.
Well.
Good morning.
Hey. Good morning.
You said you were drunk.
Can I at least ask if
you used a condom?
Shut up.
Look, there is a jumbo box of
condoms under the bathroom sink.
I share. They are for everyone.
"Jumbo"? Seriously?
I was being optimistic.
Wait.
That was you making
all that noise last night?
I thought that was Amelia.
Well, you aren't shy. And
you have a filthy mouth.
Okay, can we
not talk about this?
Please. I am begging you.
So, the intern was good in bed.
Intern? What intern?
Maggie, what intern?
Alex can hear us.
Alex doesn't care about
this. Do you care, Alex?
Do I care about any of
this conversation? No.
Did he visit lady town?
Because I find if they don't go
down to lady town the first time,
there should be no next time.
She's right about
that. No more talking!
If either of you
says another word,
I will jump out of this
car while it is moving.
And lady town is just
as bad as lady place.
Geez. So sensitive.
Just trying to be nice.
Take an interest. God.
Hey, what time do you want
me at your house tonight?
Why are you coming
to my house tonight?
You're having a dinner party.
Oh, the dinner party.
No, that's not tonight.
No, that's weeks
away. It's on the...
Dinner party's
on the 14th, Alex.
Today is the 14th.
You people need
adult supervision.
I don't think I'm gonna go
to this dinner thing tonight.
I think I'm gonna work.
Jo, they don't hate you.
They don't like me.
They're your friends.
They're my bosses.
It's like I'm on
call all the time.
They treat me like a resident,
not like a person,
not like your girlfriend.
'Cause they only
ever see you here,
'cause you never
go to their parties.
Go to the party. I
want them to know you.
It'll be fun, I promise.
Fun like a barium enema.
What?
Your boyfriend's little
posse controls this place.
Jo, you have an
invite to the inner circle.
You go to that party,
you make friends
with the chiefs of neuro,
cardio, and general,
you would be unstoppable.
Every surgery in this
hospital would be yours.
That dinner,
I'd kill for an invite.
You're a little bit
scary right now.
Edwards, my dear.
Let's roll.
Maybe I'll get an invite after
all. First neuro, then the world.
He didn't mean it, right?
I mean, you don't just toss the
word "divorce" out there like that.
It was just the heat
of the moment, right?
Maybe he was just mad, or...
I'm the one who's mad.
Divorce? No. I refuse
to accept it. Refuse.
Do you think he's going
to that thing tonight?
Oh, God. Probably.
Are you going? Please
tell me you're going.
I don't know. I mean,
Callie's gonna be there.
Since when's that been
an issue? It's not. It's just,
I don't want to make her new
girlfriend feel uncomfortable.
You know, intimidated by me. I
mean, if she's even bringing her.
I don't know if she's
bringing her. Do you?
Well, she's right over there.
Do you want me to ask her if
she's bringing her girlfriend?
Yes, please.
You ask about Jackson,
I'll ask about Penny.
10-4.
Oh, hey, um, about
that thing tonight,
I'm not so sure
any of them cook.
Should I bring food, just in
case, so none of us starve?
You know, I think it's gonna
be fine. Um, do you know if...
Do you know if
Jackson's coming tonight?
Uh, no idea. Are
you bringing Penny?
Oh.
I hadn't...
Uh, I didn't know if
you'd be okay with that.
And, uh, yeah, I didn't
want it to be awkward
or uncomfortable
for her, you know.
Okay? Me? Mmm-hmm.
Oh, I'm fine.
Are you kidding?
No, bring her. Totally.
Bring her, 'cause, I
mean, I want to meet her.
I mean, I think that
we all want to meet her.
Yeah. I mean, not just me.
Mostly me, 'cause I...
I know that I would
really love to meet her.
Yeah. I mean...
Mmm-hmm.
I will see if she's available.
Cool, cool.
Mmm-hmm. Yeah.
See? I can do this.
I can do this. I'm
excited. It's cool, I'm cool.
Yeah, cool people
don't say they're cool.
Rachel Bishop, 32,
post-op day one following
decompressive craniotomy.
Isn't able to respond verbally,
but is arousable and
following motor commands.
Excellent.
She is the perfect candidate
for early ambulation.
You want to get her on her feet?
She just had surgery yesterday.
That's exactly the point.
New studies are showing
that if we get neuro
patients up and moving
as soon as possible after
surgery, they recover faster.
They have a greater
return to function.
But the protocol is that we...
That is the great thing about
being head of the department.
I decide what is
and is not protocol.
Yes, ma'am.
Mmm-hmm.
Uh...
Call Rachel's mother and
suggest she not come in today.
It is gonna be a little rough.
Uh, Dr. Shepherd, sorry,
but Dr. Hunt said to round
up all available interns.
Why? What's going on?
We're about to get
hit with a silver flood.
I need fiber-optic intubation
on standby for each bed.
What do we got? Silver flood.
Okay, I need vitamin K, warm
fluids, blankets, and Bair Huggers.
Uh, what's a silver flood?
A silver flood is
a fracture feast.
I need slings, splints,
and pelvic binders,
as many as you can
get your hands on.
Silver flood? Silver flood.
Oh, and page every
on-call X-ray tech.
Haven't seen one of
these since Mercy West.
This will be fun.
Yes, but what is it exactly?
A silver flood is no
regular day in the pit.
Patients might be agitated,
angry, possibly even violent.
Use soothing tones, but
do not speak too softly.
Do not administer
unnecessary fluids.
If you see bruising, think
bleeding. No narcotics, no benzos.
Any questions?
Yes, what is a silver flood?
I spent good money
on that damn cruise,
and the shuttle bus crashed
before we even reached the port.
Damn driver was fiddling with
his phone the entire damn way.
So, he was texting?
Not on your life.
The way he was staring at
that thing, it had to be porno.
All right, call the OR.
Tell them they need to have
it ready for me yesterday.
Go!
Oh, silver flood.
Well, what did you think it was?
Why do you need a code
word for a bunch of old people?
What? We're not old people.
We're senior citizens.
Disrespectful.
Calling people old.
Who do you think you are?
- I'm not old.
- You don't know old.
- You are rude.
That's why. Have fun with that.
I want to speak
to your supervisor.
Thiazide for the blood pressure,
metformin for my diabetes.
I also take another
pill for my arthritis.
Great, so... I'm not done.
Also some kind
of cholesterol pill
and a baby aspirin.
That's it.
Eddie, are you sure
you're not forgetting
some of the medications
you might've been on,
like, say for, I don't know,
erectile dysfunction?
Do I look like the kind of guy
who needs to pop a
pill to pop a woody?
Well, you know,
I'm just gonna ask.
'Cause if you were
on one of those meds
and you didn't tell us,
then that could have
a very bad reaction
based on any medications
we might give you.
You could have a
drop in blood pressure,
you could have a stroke,
you could have a heart attack.
You need proof?
Watch this.
No! No, no, no! That's okay.
That's... Please don't do that.
Mrs. Margraff, we are
going to take you up to CT
and have you checked out, okay?
I'm not a missus, dear.
The gentleman and I
are just shacking up.
Oh.
How's my girl?
I'm fine, Abe.
Settle down.
Check his left hip.
He took a spill in February,
hasn't been the same since.
Hasn't slowed him down, though.
Wait, look. Don't
bother with me.
Just make sure
Gabby's all right.
These girls know
what they're doing.
I'm just banged up is all.
Okay, so tell the
nurses to monitor him
and keep him hydrated.
Abe, we are going to take Gabby
up and get her
checked out, okay?
Okay. I'll be right
here, Gabs, okay?
Will you bring her back here?
Absolutely.
Take a nap, you old bastard!
Rachel, we just need to get
you to the edge of the bed.
We get there, we can stop,
and I know it hurts, but you
got to keep your eyes open.
Brody, hold her lines
steady. Watch her IV.
Come on. Just a little further.
Maybe we should stop? Not yet.
We don't stop until we get
her to the edge of the bed
or reach her point
of intolerance.
"Point of intolerance"?
How will we know?
Uh, I think that's pretty clear.
Okay. We're gonna
let you relax now.
You did very, very well.
Let's get her cleaned up.
Stop.
I got it.
I'm gonna need
you to take the lead
on Rachel Bishop's next session.
Me?
Yeah, I have a full board,
there's a silver flood,
and if we miss a session,
we have to stop the treatment.
Well, would that
really be so bad?
Do you have something
you need to say?
I...
I don't think I'm comfortable
with this course of treatment.
I see.
We are obviously
pushing her way past
what she can handle
right now, and I just feel...
Edwards.
This protocol is
extremely difficult.
It feels traumatic.
But you have to
look at it like surgery.
Surgery is traumatic.
It is so, so hard
on the human body.
But in most cases, it is a
patient's best chance to live,
to be normal again, to heal.
This is Rachel's chance to heal.
While she vomits.
Find me when you're done.
Portable X-ray tech to ER.
Excuse me, sweetheart.
Oh, it's Dr. Sweetheart.
But what can I do for you?
Well, my lady friend,
Gabby Margraff,
they said they were
taking her for a PT.
Or something or a PP?
A CT? That's the ticket.
Oh, boy. You know, I
haven't seen her since, but I...
And I don't want to be a bother,
but nobody's said anything.
Okay, well, hold
on. Let me see. Um...
Oh, yeah. Okay, so according
to this, she's still in CT.
Okay.
Oh, okay, good, good.
Great. Is there anything
else I can do for you?
You got Jell-O here, right?
We do. Indeed.
Diaphragmatic contour
is abnormal on the left.
It could be a rupture.
Any abdominal strain
and she could pop her
guts right into her left lung.
I think there might be a
splenic hematoma also,
but I won't know
until I get in there.
Any way you can
do it without a scar?
We'll do the best we can,
Gabby, okay? You just sit tight.
Are you okay? Yeah.
What's the matter?
Um, no, I'm having flashbacks.
Sex flashbacks.
Oh, oh. Hey, Wilson, would
you step outside, please?
Okay, you were
saying about the sex?
Meredith. There was so much sex.
Hot, hot sex.
Everything hurts.
My back, my hip,
the top of my head.
I feel like I'm 80.
Oh, my God. He's an intern.
Who does that?
Who screws the interns?
What kind of person does that?
The father of my children.
Oh, Meredith.
Okay, I didn't mean, you know
I didn't mean... I'm very sorry.
It's fine. Just relax.
You think you're the first person
to have inappropriate work sex?
We all do it all
over the hospital.
I mean, we even
did it in here once.
You know, I haven't
thought about it.
Sex.
I haven't thought
about it at all since
that last morning,
the morning of the day he died.
Mags, I'm a widow.
Meredith, I'm so sorry.
We don't have to
talk about this. Um...
I can't believe I even
opened my stupid mouth.
Do you want me to
get Alex or something?
I'm so sorry. No, no. It's...
I'm a widow.
I mean, like in the
books and the movies.
You don't think that
that happens, but it does.
It's just... I'm
closed for business.
Vagina city's a ghost town.
Orgasm train doesn't
roll through here anymore.
That part of my life is over.
You know, eventually,
you'll... When you're ready...
No. I don't want to.
It's fine.
I'm okay. I'm good.
So, tell me about the hot,
hot sex with the hot intern
and how he did you sideways
because I am widow
Grey, dead inside.
Honey, no.
That is the saddest
story I've ever heard.
Gabby.
Honey, you're breaking my heart.
The orgasm train should
never stop running.
I've had an orgasm
every day since I was 15.
Well, when I was 15, I was
scrapbooking with my mom.
We had nine different
kinds of glitter.
Now, see, that is hot to me.
Orgasms are wonderful.
I had two this morning
before we got on the bus.
How long has he been
down? Ten minutes.
I ran through the ACLS
v-fib protocol twice.
Okay, charge to 200.
What happened?
He was having chest pains,
so I gave him some nitro.
His BP bottomed out all at once.
I'm worried he was on
ED meds. We asked him.
Well, was he? Clear!
What happened?
He insisted he wasn't.
We asked him several times.
We told him what could happen.
Clear! He probably lied.
Why would he do
that when we told him?
People can be stubborn, even
when it's the worst thing for them.
We told him. Time
of death, 12:19.
What do...
What do we do now?
You notify the morgue.
That's it? That's it.
Excuse me. Can you help me?
They said my father
was in the accident.
Can you tell me
where I can find him?
What's his name?
Edward Squire. Eddie.
He only answers to Eddie.
Uh... Okay.
I should, uh, you
know, I'm gonna...
Let's find someone
who can talk to you.
What? Why?
Is he hurt?
He, um... I'm really sorry,
but I don't think I should be...
Just tell me.
He had a heart attack.
Oh.
Is he all right? Can
you take me to him?
No, I can't. I can't.
What do you mean you
can't? Just tell me where he is.
Your father's... He...
He passed away.
What?
We think he lied about the
medication he was taking.
What are you talking
about? He's dead?
My father is dead? No,
please just come with me.
And we can find
someone who can...
Don't you touch me!
Whoa, whoa.
Sir, sir.
He said my father was dead,
and he won't tell me where he is!
I am so sorry. He
said my dad was a liar.
Sir, come sit down.
I will tell you everything
that happened
and I will take you
to your dad, okay?
Okay. Please, please.
Get him a chair and bring
him some water. Right.
Thank you. That was...
What did you do?
What did you say to him?
Dr. Hunt, I... What
the hell did you say?
I thought the point of a singles
cruise was to meet other singles.
Exactly.
Where do you think I met Gabby?
Five years ago
almost to the day.
Really? Mmm.
Absotively.
I didn't even want to go.
But my sister wouldn't
get off my back.
"Go out, meet people.
"Don't just sit at
home in that chair."
It's a nice chair?
The best.
Oh, you press a button
and your feet go up.
And there's a... And
there's a warmer in the seat.
And a little cubby
for the remote.
Sounds like a dream.
Now I'm living a new dream.
I got the chair. I got the girl.
Here, but let me
show you something.
Oh, Abe, this is all too sudden.
I barely know
you. I just met you.
You know, you're a
wise ass. But I like that.
Mmm.
It's beautiful.
Gabby's beautiful.
I was gonna propose on the boat.
On the third night,
there's this big dance
in the main dining room.
Huge ice sculptures and a
dance band and everything.
That's where I first saw her.
Whoa.
The dress she was wearing.
I got so dizzy, I
just had to sit down.
I closed my eyes for a second,
and when I opened them...
Oh, gosh dang it.
Abe, I'm so sorry. Duty calls.
Oh, you kidding? Go.
You got more important things
to do than to listen to my stories.
I am getting the
rest of that story.
I will be back ASAP.
Bring another Jell-O with you.
Oh, okay. Wait, hold
on. Raspberry or lime?
Surprise me.
Okay.
Okay, Gabby, we're going
to put you under now, okay?
I need to tell Abe.
Abe is downstairs.
We're gonna tell him
everything that's going on.
No, I need to tell him.
He'll crap his pants if
he thinks I'm in trouble.
I can grab an intern to...
Bless his heart, he may
actually crap his pants.
He's 90.
Okay, the sats are down to 87.
Gabby, I'm gonna need you
to take some deep breaths.
Let's get her under right now.
Wilson, go down and
find someone to tell Abe
that Gabby's in surgery
and she is just fine.
I was gonna scrub in.
Wilson, we have enough
hands here. Go cover the pit.
You'll see him when you wake up.
Listen, Rachel, I
know this is hard,
but this is how
you're gonna heal.
Okay?
Here we go.
All right, let's try
for a step, Rachel.
Can you give me a step?
One step.
You give me a step, you
get in that chair, we can stop.
Step, the chair, we stop.
It's okay.
Come on. We got you.
You can do it. It's okay.
Come on. Step, chair, stop.
It's okay.
I got you.
Step, chair, stop.
That's enough.
That's enough for now.
Put her down. Dr. Edwards?
That's okay. That's
good, Rachel.
That's really good.
Let's get you back to
bed. Let's get her in bed.
We haven't reached
her point of intolerance.
Dr. Shepherd... I
said we're done.
Okay.
Legs.
You did so good.
You did really good.
Really good, okay?
Want to go grab
some food with me?
I have no appetite.
Shepherd's making me torture a
patient who just had brain surgery.
Because she likes you.
She got a funny
way of showing it.
At least she lets
you torture a patient.
Grey and Pierce just
threw me out of the OR.
They hate me.
You know, I need
to be more like you.
You make the system your bitch.
If I could get an
attending to look at me
the way that
Shepherd looks at you...
Okay, Rachel, Dr. Edwards said
that we just need to
get you into this chair,
so that's what we're gonna do.
All right.
Okay. Ready?
Wilson?
A word, please?
I'll be back.
Dr. Shepherd,
I was just about to
get Rachel on her feet.
Where the hell is Edwards?
There were 40
passengers on the bus.
Eight of them died en route.
We've lost six in
the ER already,
and many more are in surgery
or in critical care in the ICU.
All of these peoples' families
are on their way to
this hospital right now.
When they get here,
you will be responsible
for informing them
that their loved ones have died.
What?
Why us?
Because after what
I've seen today,
you clearly need to practice.
Now, there are
four steps to this.
Location, language,
body language, and leave.
We think of them
as the four L's.
The first "L," location.
Bring them to a quiet,
comfortable place
where they won't be disturbed.
Looking for the family
of Nestor Rodriguez.
Family of Emma Pritchett?
June Napali?
That's me.
Ah, sir, can you
come with me, please?
Just a minute.
Okay, here, let me...
Get your damn hands
off me. I can do it.
Next, language.
We used all our capabilities.
Don't sugarcoat it.
Don't leave anything
open to interpretation.
Unfortunately, we were
unable to resuscitate him.
And despite our best efforts...
You have to use the word "died."
Franklin is no longer with us.
Grandpa left? Where'd he go?
What? Can we go there?
Oh, I'm sorry.
That's not what I...
Are you going to take
us there now? Uh...
Third, body language.
Often a comforting
touch can help.
A hand on the arm
or on the shoulder,
if it feels appropriate.
Grandpa's in
heaven now, sweetie,
with your turtle.
Why are you still here?
And finally, leave as
soon as you're able.
You've done what you came
to do, so excuse yourself.
Get out.
You know what?
We're just gonna do this here.
Hi. Hey.
Hey, hey.
Abraham.
Hey, who was
monitoring this man?
I checked him five minutes ago.
He was fine.
Oh, Abe.
I cannot fathom
what possessed you
to abandon your... My patient.
Dr. Shepherd...
Why are you talking?
No one is talking to you.
You, speak.
I did not abandon her.
Dr. Wilson is an excellent...
I didn't choose
Wil, I chose you.
I gave you specific
instructions.
I couldn't do it.
I'm sorry. I couldn't
put Rachel through that.
Okay, okay.
Okay, okay, okay.
Edwards, why?
There has to be a
good reason why,
because you are
too smart for this.
So, tell me.
Look...
When I was a kid,
I was in a clinical trial
for sickle cell anemia.
What? I was five.
They held me down, the
nurses and the doctors,
sticking me with needles
and taking my bone marrow.
You can't imagine the pain.
And my mom would
be saying over and over,
"Honey, it's for your own
good. It's for your own good."
I screamed and I
kicked and I fought,
and so sometimes they
would strap me to the table,
which they were right to do.
For my own good.
I was five.
I felt like I was being punished
for something that I didn't do,
for something that
was inside of me.
And I'm not gonna do
that to somebody else.
I'm sorry.
I can't. I won't.
Hey, Hunt, um, I need to
find a patient, Gabby Margraff.
Oh, she's in surgery with Grey
and Pierce. What do you need?
I need to tell her her boyfriend's
dead. He coded in the hallway.
Well, how did he...
I mean, he's 90.
Could've been a stroke or
an MI. He just fell asleep and...
Robbins, I'm sorry.
We'll take care of it, okay?
Mmm.
Okay. Thanks.
Oh, God.
What happened?
Nothing.
Nothing. I'm fine.
What happened?
I don't know. I don't
even know why I'm crying.
He wasn't even my patient.
He wasn't even a
baby. He was 90.
Who was 90?
Abe.
He was...
in love.
He met the love of his life
when he was 85,
and he was gonna propose to her.
But he died.
Oh. I'm sorry.
God, I felt like I could
talk to him forever.
He made me feel like...
You know, I never really
believed that I'd find love again.
Not anything real or true.
I thought that I had
it and I screwed it up,
and that was over.
Then he was madly in love at 85,
and that is proof that there is,
there is more love out there.
Callie might've found
hers and I can find mine,
even if it's in 60 years.
I don't want to find a new
soul mate when I'm 90!
I met mine already
and he wants a divorce.
Oh, sweetie.
This is about me.
This isn't about you.
Sorry.
What the hell was that?
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean for you to get
thrown under the bus like that.
I don't care about that.
How could you make
up a story like that?
What?
Working the system is one thing.
You want to tell a little lie to
get your labs run faster, great.
I'm on board.
But that, what you did in there,
the violin you played for
Dr. Shepherd, you can't do that.
You can't manipulate someone
like that. You crossed a line.
Don't you even
have a conscience?
Well, it worked, so maybe
I'm better off without one.
Hey.
I owe you an apology.
I... You were helping
out a friend. I overreacted.
Don't worry about it.
If I'd known about Edwards,
I would've approached
the whole thing differently.
Um...
We're having this thing
at the house tonight. Um...
You two should come.
There's gonna be food, booze.
She could probably use it.
Dr. Shepherd.
Yeah?
Stephanie's a liar.
She was never sick.
She made the whole thing up.
Check the drains for
blood every two hours
and page me when she's awake.
Okay.
I'm gonna go let Abe know.
Okay. Oh. Oh, my God. He's here.
What? Who? He's here.
He's here, and he's hot. Oh,
my God. Help me. Save me. Help.
Hey, Dr. Pierce?
Uh, what does he
want? What do you want?
Is that your patient,
Gabby Margraff?
Why? Why?
I'm supposed to notify
her that her husband's died.
They were not married.
They were just shacking up.
Okay, but he put her down
as next of kin on his forms, so...
Why are you... You are
an intern. Give me that.
Yeah, she's not your patient.
This isn't your job.
Who sent you up here?
Dr. Hunt ordered me.
It's a teaching thing.
And I know the four
L's. Oh, you know what?
Stop talking. "Four L's"?
She's not even your
patient. Don't touch her!
Don't go near her!
I'll deal with Hunt!
Geez, what's her problem? It's
not like I want to be doing this.
Her problem is
that there are rules
and boundaries.
And some people think that
you can just ignore all those rules,
that you can cross
those boundaries,
but just because protocol
is broken once in a...
No, no, no. Once!
Once.
That the rules go out the
window, but they don't, okay?
Her problem is that
hot people should know
that just because a person
does something that is reckless
and likes it
does not mean that they are
going to keep doing that thing, okay?
Her problem is that maybe she
is tired of scrapbooking and glitter,
but she does not know
who she is anymore,
and everyone needs to just
give her the space to figure it out
and stop asking her questions
and talking about jumbo condoms.
That...
is Meredith's problem.
Understand?
Yeah, I think
that... Okay, good.
Great.
Dr. Shepherd, I promise
you... I've heard enough.
Dr. Shepherd.
Uh, Grey tell you that I subbed
in for her class this morning?
And I think I did the
neuro department proud.
Dr. Webber, as
residency director,
you should know...
Dr. Edwards abandoned
a patient this afternoon,
and when questioned
about it, she lied to my face.
A truly offensive lie
about being sick as a kid,
and I bought it.
I...
I believed you.
She told me... Dr. Shepherd.
What do you want me to do here?
She doesn't believe
me on her own.
When she applied
to this program,
I got a call from Keith
Wagner at St. Jude's.
That sickle cell trial was
a milestone in his career.
Wanted to tell me how
proud he was of her
and how lucky
we'd be to have her.
Hers was one of the few success
stories to come out of that trial.
I don't understand why
Wilson told me you lied.
Because Wilson doesn't know.
Because I don't talk
about it anymore,
because I'm not
a patient anymore.
I am a surgeon.
And when I do talk about it,
I only tell people I can trust.
Why didn't she just...
Why didn't she just tell me
to confirm the story with you?
Why did she let me... God.
How many hours?
How many days?
How many surgeries have
you spent with Edwards?
She's been your right hand.
So why was it so easy
to question her integrity
based on the word of a
doctor you hardly knew?
God.
Okay.
Keep him in NPO... Hunt.
What the hell is going on?
Sorry? I have an intern who says
you sent him upstairs
to tell my patient...
I did. I'm giving them a crash
course in breaking bad news.
They need it. Oh.
"A crash course."
Is that how this goes?
No, it's not how this goes.
That is not how this works.
Grey, this is a teaching hospital.
We teach from experience.
Now, I've given
them the four L's...
The four L's are not enough.
These interns, they need a lot more.
Of course they need more.
That's why they have to do it.
They have to experience it.
They have to live it.
And to learn it, they have to
be up close and personal with it.
When you walk into a room
to tell someone that
their loved one has died,
it's more than just a list of
bullet points you've memorized.
Yours is the face they will
remember for the rest of their life.
They were fine
before they met you.
They picked up their
children from school,
they made dinner,
and they got a call.
The police showed up at their
door and brought them here
with those children to this room
so that you can give them the
worst news of their entire life.
You are changing this
person's life forever.
You are responsible
for this moment.
For the instant that person
goes from wife to widow is you.
All you. Nobody but you.
So, this person isn't
an inconvenience.
They are not a box on
a list to be checked off.
You are a part
of their life now.
Your words, your face.
So take that seriously
and recognize the
importance of your role.
And respect the fact
that that person's pain
is the biggest
thing in the room.
You got it?
It's not closed forever, right?
The orgasm train will
chug into the station again.
It just...
I'm just not wondering
what's out there.
Not feeling like I'm
missing anything.
I've had that great,
amazing love.
And that part's behind me now,
and I have the kids and
you guys and surgery, and...
I'm happy.
And I never thought I
would be again and I am.
And that's all I need.
So, you just need to watch
those lines just like before.
Good, good.
Okay.
There you go.
There you go, okay?
Okay.
I know this sucks.
But we're gonna get
you in that chair, okay?
Okay.
Go on. Keep hitting me.
Keep hitting me.
We're almost there.
Keep hitting me. Focus on that.
Focus on that.
You don't stop now until
we get you into this chair.
Come on. You're
almost there, Rachel.
Come on.
Keep going. I know.
You're almost there.
Come on.
Come on, Rachel. Just one step.
There you go.
Okay. Good. Good.
Good job, Rachel. You did good.
It's okay. You're
okay. You're okay.
You did it.
I need to step out
for just a moment.
You did good.
You did it. Good job.
That was excellent.
You saw?
I did.
Very, very well done.
I'm sorry
that I didn't believe
you. I should have.
Thank you.
Wait, aren't you supposed to
be throwing a party right now?
Oh.
Crap.
DeLuca.
Hey, look, I'm sorry, okay?
I didn't mean to cross
boundaries or not do my job,
and I clearly pissed
you off and Dr. Grey.
So I'm sorry, and if it's
about last night, I'm...
Shh!
Shush.
Um...
Um, okay, actually, I was
coming to apologize to you.
That yelling was
not about today.
It was about last night.
Yeah, I knew that.
Right, well, um,
last night is not
going to happen again.
It was very nice.
Was better than nice.
But,
I don't do this.
Hey, look, I don't
do this either, okay?
I don't. But at the
bar, you were just so...
You were so, also.
And, uh, you're very...
Thank you. Um, so are you.
So, uh, it was a slip.
Right. I get it. And,
you know what? I agree.
Okay, it never happened.
Deleted.
Thank you.
There are some things in life
that simply can't be avoided.
No matter how
uncomfortable they make us.
And there can be rewards in
stepping outside of your comfort zone.
Even when the thought of
it makes us want to puke.
No, those are for the guests.
Yeah, we came early
to eat the best part.
Hey, where's Maggie?
She was supposed
to be here with the ice
and people are
already showing up.
Maggie got held up at work.
She said she's on her way.
Uh, the dryer finished
a little bit early,
but the tablecloth's still damp.
It's fine. Just put it
on the table. Okay.
Even when we want nothing more
than to run
screaming for the hills.
Oh, is that Jackson?
No, it's Callie.
Oh, God.
I didn't know her new
girlfriend was a redhead.
Oh, no. I need more
liquor. I'm not ready.
Whoa.
I'll get it.
That's why people
love to say that
what doesn't kill you
makes you stronger.
Welcome. Hi,
Meredith. This is Penny.
The call to not get a
head CT was a bad call.
I'm so sorry.
It was my job to
save him and I failed.
Penny, this is Meredith.
But I brought some wine.
But sometimes...
I'm so sorry.
Those people don't know what
the hell they're talking about.