People often ask
what I've learned
from surviving COVID.
I know they mean well, but it's
a really annoying question.
Being away from work,
my children,
getting hooked up to a vent...
it's not exactly a masterclass.
Though it did teach me
something.
It taught me
that I'm still alive.
Did you know that every avocado
sold commercially
originates from a tree this one
dude had in his backyard?
No, but did I know
that an avocado has
more potassium than a banana.
Well, did you know that
if you ate 400 bananas,
you might overdose on potassium?
Why would you say that?
You know I worry about dying.
Okay, whoa.
We'll shut up.
Please don't evict us.
That's not our stuff.
Are you evicting yourself?
I'm smart and I'm capable
and I have made livable homes
out of the humblest of places,
including my car.
But I deserve more
than just livable.
And so does Luna,
so I am fighting for her.
I'm rich. Ha!
Technically, I am rich.
I own part of the hospital.
So I'm gonna sell my shares
and hire a lawyer
to help me adopt Luna.
And then, I'm taking
whatever money's left
and moving to a place
where I don't have to listen
to people argue about fruit!
♪ Yeah, yeah
Dibs on the bed.
But explaining that
to my ex-husband
was like a full-time job.
Sounds like it.
You paged? Oh, hey.
Dr. Altman, this is, uh, Sophie.
She was in a little
fender bender.
She's all clear except her
heart rate is a little high.
So I thought you should
check on her EKG.
I told him it's probably just
white coat syndrome.
One look at him and
my heart's off to the races.
Oh, sorry.
Keep forgetting it's COVID and
you can't just touch people.
Don't worry, I'm wearing
protection.
Okay.
I, uh... I'll come back
and check on you.
See you soon, Sophie. Hope so.
Oh, you're wearing protection?
I didn't mean it how it sounds.
Well, she's throwing herself
at you.
No, she's just nervous.
Well, I can give her
your number, if you want.
Oh, really? No.
Now, look.
As Residency Director,
you're not only teaching them
to do surgery,
but you're...
You're guiding them.
When a resident loses a patient,
it's your shoulder they cry on.
If they succeed,
you're their cheerleader.
So, essentially, they...
You're on call 24 hours a day.
That's the way you always
described it to me.
I appreciate the advice.
I do know how to do the job.
I've been watching you do it
my whole career.
If I were you, I would be
doing the surgeries
that I don't get to do.
Well, you're the only one
I wanted for the job.
We'll see you at the wedding.
So, you gonna give
Richard's speech
or did you write your own?
No speech. No... No speech?
No.
No, no, no, no, no.
Okay, we admitted 10 patients
last night with COVID symptoms.
What are the statuses
of all 10 patients?
- Cardio tech, room 342.
Give the O2 a minute, Gerlie.
We'll increase it if your sats
don't come back up.
Or you could present
the patient to me,
and I could decide if we should
increase it right now.
Present, Schmitt.
Gerlie Bernardo, 37,
admitted this morning
with sats of...
88. Temp was 102.
Heart rate 105, BP 96/54.
Dehydrated.
I'm a nurse... long-term care.
Gotten pretty good at knowing
when to call the ambulance.
Private or at a facility?
Lakeforest... assisted living.
I'm guessing that's where
I picked this up.
But I've helped take care
of Earl for 7 years.
Even when he has COVID,
I'm still helping him
to the bathroom.
He's 96.
The kindest person I know.
My parents were
at Silver Villas.
They were hit hard.
Yes, they were.
So, let's put her on high-flow,
order chest films,
and start steroids
and Remdesivir.
How did Luna do?
Couldn't have been better.
Hate that CPS made
the poor thing wait a week
before approving
her surgery, but...
Nurse Kaiser to the OR.
Your name will be
back up there soon.
I don't know.
They gave me an office.
And a desk. Mm.
And a chair.
Wow, a chair?
They must really fancy you.
You could have just
said no, you know.
When I asked you out
for a drink.
You didn't have to pass out and
spend two months in the hospital
just to avoid turning me down.
That seems like
a lifetime ago.
Mm-hmm.
Did I hear you?
Did you come to my room
and tell me to fight
and talk about my kids?
Couldn't have been me.
I'm far too busy
to do sickbed visits.
Must have been
some other Irishman
hanging around around here.
That being said, I am glad
you didn't die, Grey.
Me too.
You'll get back there soon.
I should get going.
My sister is getting married.
Mm-hmm.
...as long as we both
shall live.
Now, very important question.
Is there anyone here
who objects to this union?
Oh, well, we do!
He... He was kidding, Nana.
Well, we aren't.
I'm sorry, Maggie.
Wait, is this real?
Mommy,
what's happening? I'm not sure, sweetie.
Winston,
I've been waiting for this day
since I could cradle you
in my arms.
And I know you went to a lot of
trouble to get us here,
but this... This is broke.
Ha!
Oh, I am so sorry.
Oh, I'm so sorry.
No disrespect, Meredith.
You have a lovely home.
But Maggie, your own sister
isn't here!
Amelia had to be on call today.
Right, should she let someone
die of a stroke
just to be here with us?
But even if she was here,
you have more family.
You have uncles, aunts, cousins.
I have a savings account
for your wedding,
to do this right.
In a church.
Or at least with more
than 10 people.
Do you know how proud we are
of you two?
We want the world to see.
But it isn't safe
right now, Nana Ante.
We can't do it that way.
Well, then wait.
What's the hurry?
You all are already
living together.
So, uh... we wait?
Yeah, I guess so.
I'll get the champagne.
- Yeah.
- Vodka, please.
Can I cut the cake? Just wait a minute,
okay, honey?
You can do whatever you want,
sweetie.
Okay, she said
you can go get cake!
You wanna take this?
Great, thank you.
Champagne, anyone?
I'll take that.
Thanks. Mm-hmm.
Bottoms up, everyone!
Dr. Sellers,
Dr. Mari Sellers, 4619.
Uh, technically, I still haven't
signed the discharge paperwork.
I... I know, but I've never
missed a month of work
in my life, and they need me.
I heard Earl took his pants off
during Arts & Crafts.
Twice.
You were on a vent
for two weeks.
I know at your facility
it's all hands on deck, but...
Take it easy and go slow.
Yes, Dr. Bailey,
I know the recommendations.
Oh, so you know
they apply to you also?
Mm-hmm.
Come on, let's have
one last listen.
May I take a listen
first, Chief?
I don't have a lot of experience
listening to lungs that have
recovered from COVID,
and I think it'll be really
beneficial to my education.
Fine. Yes!
Just take a few deep breaths
for me, please.
Love.
Does that mean I can go?
Uh, no, I'll still need to take
a listen of my own.
"Love."
The rush I felt
when I watched that woman,
who'd been in a coma for weeks,
whom I could only
talk to via MRI,
leave the hospital
with her father...
The relief and the joy
and the hope...
I mean, I felt that for, like...
30 seconds.
And then just...
all the worst-case scenarios
started screaming in my head.
I mean, not for her,
for... for me.
For my family. My son.
And I don't know why my thinking
is so dark, except...
addict.
But it's been a year. Um...
So much. So much fear.
So much fear.
And I know you guys all get it.
And my boyfriend,
my, um, child's father...
he is not one of us.
And I am so glad
that he does not have to
go through life like that.
Um, but...
sometimes, there's a part of me
that wishes he got it.
You know, just, uh...
really got it.
I feel lonely in it.
So...
I'm here.
Thanks, Amelia. Jason?
Hi, I'm Jason. I'm an addict.
"And all the king's men
couldn't put Humpty
together again."
Hmm.
Huh.
Should've let the women try.
What do you think, Luna?
All this talk of eggs
is making her hungry.
Can I get her bottle?
Humpty Dumpty's an egg? Isn't he?
Looks like someone's got
an appetite.
Yep, eating like a champ.
I'm glad. Everything else good?
Yeah. Just checked her vitals.
How long until she's discharged?
She's still pending
an upper GI study
and pre-albumin
we need to monitor, so...
But if you had to ballpark it.
Days, weeks, months?
I'm sorry.
It's too early to say.
I know you want to get started
with a placement.
I've already got
a family interested
in fostering to adopt.
They're perfect.
They don't mind the extra
attention that she's gonna need,
but they did ask for a timeline,
so keep me posted.
You want me to foster Luna?
Just on paper.
I would do all of the work.
All of the... everything.
I... I know that
I'm asking a lot,
but I am out of options
and time.
And you... you are...
You are stable and good.
You already have a kid.
You're a doctor,
which might be a plus
for a baby with medical issues.
And unlike me, your background
check will be spotless.
Link,
I have never loved anybody
like this,
and the idea of her going to
live with somebody else,
it just... it carves out
my stomach.
I can't lose her.
I... I can't.
I-It's... It's temporary?
It's temporary!
A-And... And we will eventually
transfer custody to me.
And... And you probably won't
even have to take her home,
because she can't leave
the hospital yet.
Please, Link, please.
Jo...
I-I'm saying yes.
Amelia...
You know, w-we'll figure it out.
Hell, she'd probably do
the same thing.
So, Jo, my answer is yes.
Of course it's yes.
It's you.
But you're cool if I change
her name, right?
Shut up. Hear me out...
Hildegard.
How could this happen?
COVID's just a numbers game.
Oh, do you think that
it's a false positive?
I don't know, that's why
I'm testing you again.
What about the kids?
What about you?
Your mom... Teddy, I'm negative.
And you don't have any symptoms.
Let's just follow the protocol.
We're gonna be okay.
What if I'm not?
Meredith was... Teddy.
We'll be okay.
Let's not worry about anything
until we have to.
Go home, get in bed.
My mom will take the kids.
I have to go. Mm-hmm.
You're adopting a baby
for your friend?
It's fostering.
It's just to get Luna
off the market
while Jo figures out
the legal stuff.
And if she doesn't? She will.
But if she doesn't?
Then I guess we'll have
a daughter.
Bad joke.
Okay, that won't happen.
I promise, Amelia,
this is just a technicality.
And really, what other choice
did I have?
We didn't think twice when...
When Mer needed our help.
Meredith is my sister
and her kids are my family.
But they're not mine.
Technically.
But I love them, so I did it.
Is this really a problem?
Of course not.
It's just surprising.
I mean, it's only
for a little while, right?
You're sure?
Go to your surgery.
I'm fine.
Thank you.
I've been in the hospital
for a month.
Forgot what the sky looked like.
COVID?
I had it, too.
Well, if you're back at work,
that seems encouraging, right?
Do you sit at a desk?
Nurse. Oh.
Everyone recovers differently,
I think.
I'm still taking it easy.
Continuing shortness of breath,
fatigue, lingering cough...
Sounds like recovery's a blast.
They don't happen all at once.
What about the survivor's guilt?
That doesn't go away.
My ride's here. Okay.
Autzen? Thank you.
Take care of yourself.
Thank you for...
For being honest.
I'm... I'm Gerlie.
I'm Meredith.
Are you okay?
Dr. Grey!
Gerlie!
Call a rapid response.
I need a gurney!
Gerlie?
Canceled? What?!
Grey...
Hey, hey.
Uh, what happened
to Grand Rounds?
Oh, well, Gerlie's
post-COVID complications
are far more instructional.
She's got a pneumothorax,
she's day 14 post-op from a very
complicated VATS procedure,
and now she has
multifocal pneumonia.
Oh, so...
Grand Rounds aren't canceled,
they're just postponed.
It would have to be a really
slow day to make it worthwhile.
But i-it's tradition.
I-I can't tell you
all that I learned
in Richard's presentations.
Yeah, but the last thing
people need right now
is to listen to someone talk
about how surgery works,
especially
after the year they've had.
If you're dying to listen to
someone talk about surgery,
I've invited the class
to watch me do Gerlie's bronch.
You're more than welcome
to attend.
You're doing it yourself?
I've been back three months
and have not operated.
Are you ready? You sure?
It's just a bronch
and some cultures.
Don't forget, you gave me
this job to change things.
So that's what I'm doing.Uh...
Dr. Blast to nuclear medicine.
Okay.
Okay, great. Thank you.
Hey, listen...
Oh, no, you first.
Okay, I realized something
that's going to make your
foster application a shoo-in...
Owning part of the hospital!
How nice of you to think of me.
Ugh! I need the money
for stupid adoption legal fees
and a family-sized home,
but nobody wants my shares
because hospitals
are just bleeding money
during the pandemic
and it's, quote, "the worst
investment of all time."
Really selling me on the idea.
Okay, I didn't want to
have to go down this route,
but as part owner,
I'm kinda your boss.
So I could just order you
to buy them.
Okay, but then wouldn't I
be your boss
and I could just make you
buy them back?
Some friend.
Sorry, Jo. Ah!
It's a no.
But I really hope you figure out
something fast because...
I got approved to foster.
What? Really? What?!
Why didn't you tell me?! You went first!
Oh, my God.
Thank you!
Okay, I have to tell Luna!
So, the social worker came
and looked through our place,
uh, so we can get ready
to foster a baby
that is never gonna be ours.
And, um, the social worker
gave us this to-do list
to get the place ready
for a second kid, and, uh,
my boyfriend is just
diving right into the project.
And, um, when I reminded him
that it was temporary,
he was like...
"Yeah, but we'll need it
one day."
Meaning, one day, when we have
a second kid of our own.
And it just feels...
It just feels like
I don't want what he wants.
And I don't know if that's
diseased thinking or...
if it's just me.
Marriage and more kids, um...
I don't want it.
And...
I can't tell him.
And I'm mad.
Not at him. He's...
nothing but wonderful, and...
I'm mad at me.
And I know that all of this
would be unimaginably worse
and more confusing
if I was high, so...
since I can't be sure
of anything,
I'm just being sure of that.
Owen?
Happy end of quarantine.
Maybe we should wait
one more day.
Teddy...
I mean, just to be sure.
Listen. The kids are fine.
We're all testing negative,
and there's no patients
testing positive.
Okay. Good.
That's... That's good.Yeah.
How you feeling?
Got my energy back.
And no fever, no cough.
I mean, I did sneeze maybe once.
Teddy, come out.
Okay? You're safe.
And Leo made me bring you
a very special celebration meal.
Mac and cheese? Yep.
In a mug.
He was very adamant about
it being in a dinosaur mug.
I miss them.Yeah.
Okay...
Here we go.
Hey.
You look tired.
You look beautiful.
Owen, I just...
Wow. Two weeks is
a really long time.
Schmitt, look at all this
fibrosis and scar tissue.
I can't believe it's this bad.
Culture tube.
Dr. Grey?
Is everything okay?
Saline flush.
And someone get me a wheelchair.
Okay.
What's going on?
Phew. I'm dizzy.
My breath is shallow.
My heart rate has gotta be
in the 100s.
Should we page Chief Bailey?
I'm coming in.
We maxed Gerlie out on the vent
in the middle of the night.
She still wasn't
saturating well.
Then about an hour ago,
she coded for the second time.
Why didn't you call me
when she coded the first time?
It's Christmas Eve!
I thought you'd be
with your kids, or, you know,
wrapping presents,
baking cookies... Stop talking.
You put her on ECMO?
She's young, I saw no other
comorbidities in her chart,
and I've seen patients
walk out of here
weeks later after being on it.
I'm sorry, I know that
Gerlie is your patient,
but it was an active code.
No, it's okay.
It was the right call.
Alright.
Uh, I'll see you tomorrow?
Yes, of course.
Merry Christmas, Altman.
Merry Christmas.
Merry Christmas!
These guys will keep you company
and play you music
and stimulate
your extraocular muscles.
Jo. Yeah?
What do you think?
I thought it was pretty clear
we were just doing
the baby thing.
That would be funny
if I wasn't worried
Amelia was gonna say it.
Wait, you guys haven't
talked about marriage
since she said she didn't want
to get married?
She also said that she didn't
notwant to get married.
She just didn't want it
to feel compulsory,
and I've been planning this
for weeks.
It's too small, right?
You got another diamond ring?
I'm not stupid.
I got a sapphire, too.
Okay, stop.
This is getting weird.
I need your advice! Okay, I...
I am yourbest friend, not hers,
so I'm not sure
which one she'd like.
Um, you know, she's...
They're all so beautiful.
She's gonna love
whatever you pick.
Should I have gotten a fourth?
Okay, you're literally holding
the value of three of my lofts
in your hand.
Here goes nothing. Wish me luck.
Good luck. And merry Christmas!
Holidays are hard. Huh?
For me, anyway.
It's when I miss Abigail
the most, you know.
Oh. Yeah. Joy to the world.
I was just hoping
that dying patients
who've recovered from COVID were
eligible for lung transplants.
What a world that would be.
Got you a present.
Might help.
A present?
It's open and half-empty.
Short notice.
Unless you'd rather
pass out again
to get out of this...
Sláinte.
Whatever you said.
♪ Paper and ribbon
♪ Candles glow in window panes
Bailey, wait your turn.
Okay, Leo, this one
is from Auntie Amelia.
And Uncle Link.
Uh, no, this one is just
from Auntie Amelia.
- Whoa!
- It's a brain!
Yay! It's educational andfun.
Yep, that one is definitely
just from Aunt Amelia.
Now, uh, I've got one
for you, Amelia.
Whoa, look. It's snowing.
- Snowing!
- It's snowing?
What? What?
Why is it snowing
only in the backyard?
That's weird.
Let's go see what's up.
Come on. Let's go.
♪ Sending cards to loved ones
we never get to see ♪
Look at this!
Why is it snowing
outside my bedroom?
What's happening?
Look at this!
Do you believe this?
You got me snow for Christmas.
It's snowing!
Oh, my God.
Oh, come on, man. Oh, my God.
Theodora Grace Altman...
Now, this is not the first time
I've asked you this.
And we've hurt each other,
I know,
but we have forgiven each other.
We may not make sense
to the rest of the world,
but we make sense to us.
So I am asking you,
in front of everyone...
Including your ex-wife.
Would you please continue to
make me the happiest man alive?
Yes. Yes.
- Yay!
- Oh, my God! Wow!
Whee!
Yes, yes, yes.
♪ Paper and ribbon
seem to be everywhere ♪
♪ Hey!
♪ When you're looking up
at the sky ♪
♪ I will always be
where you are ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh,
our love carries on ♪
♪ So go, go, go
back where you belong ♪
♪ When you're looking up
at the sky ♪
♪ I will always be
where you are ♪
Well, Hunt says
that the whole staff
should have their first dose
by the end of the day.
I love needles.
♪ Back where you belong
Yes, yes.
Hi.
We need to put Gerlie
on the list
for a double lung transplant.
Grey, I am in my joy.
Do not take me out of my joy
to remind me of something
we shouldn't do.
She can handle it.
Her hemoglobin has been stable
for weeks now,
but her lungs are not improving.
If this is the part where
you remind me of her cousins
or how she rescues puppies
or buys groceries for old folks
or sends half of her paycheck
to her family in Manila
and deserves to live, I...
I know who she is, right?
The work she does,
the lives she's saved.
I-I know what she deserves.
But Gerlie recovered from COVID.
Hey, she might recover
from this.
So, why risk putting her through
a potentially unnecessary
and dangerous surgery?
So, we're just supposed to wait
and hope she lives?
Or try other treatments.
What if we wait too long
and she develops sepsis
and is too sick
for a transplant?
We're not there yet.
You took my joy.
You took mine.
There you go.
Oh, thank you.
You are welcome.
So, uh...
You didn't, uh...
Didn't share today, huh?
Have you gotten some clarity
with things at home?
Nope.
Just tired of talking myself
in circles
on a subject with no answer.
Well, it doesn't have to work.
You know that, right?
Me and Link?
You and anyone.
You have a child...
You'll always have a connection.
And I'm sure you love
each other, so...
but it doesn't have to work.
It really sounds like
you're telling me to leave him.
But that also doesn't sound
like something you'd ever say.
I'm definitely not
telling you that.
You know, something
I've noticed in recovery...
You know we...
We get it in our heads
that the addiction is the only
reason our lives were a mess.
So we think, "Well,
I'm... I'm sober.
It should be working."
And that's not always the case.
And I'm not saying
that either one of you
are doing anything wrong.
But you're allowed
to want what you want.
Even if it's not what he wants.
Ah.
Anyway, that's my two cents.
That's like a billion cents.
Eh, it's some advice
I wish I'd have been able
to take in my life.
Giving yourself permission
for it not to work...
might give you peace of mind
to stay.
Thank you. Thank...
Thank you so much, Anne.
This... This means
the world to me.
Okay. Alright, bye.
Sounds like good news.
Luna's lawyer is a shark.
I am definitely getting custody.
Oh, congratulations, Wilson.
Oh, I'm so thrilled
for you and Luna.
Hey, if you need a character
reference or whatever,
just let me know. Thank you.
Alright.
She isexpensive, though.
Is this you asking me
for a raise?
No, this is me telling you
that I sold my shares
of the hospital.
And you're... wincing?
What, bad price?
Maybe I should just let the
person who bought them tell you.
Hmm?
Miranda!
Did you hear the good news?
Wilson. You didn't.
You know, it's easy
to push for change
when you don't feel
the consequences.
I wanted some skin in the game.
I offered you
a character reference!
You won't even know I'm here.
Aside from board meetings,
expense reports,
weekly progress reports.
Okay, talk to you later, Tom.
Wait, I...
Should I...?
Yeah, I should just...
Thanks again.
Thank you.
Wha...?
Gerlie has shown no improvement
since going on ECMO.
Oh, she's alive.
That's an improvement.
So, treatment options.
Double lung transplant.
Yes, but since she could suffer
additional bleeding
or sudden death,
that is not an option.
But it could be.
If you made it one.
Thank you, Helm. Who else?
Uh... Ortiz.
So, at first, I considered
monoclonal antibodies.
Mm-hmm. But then it hit me...
Double lung transplant
makes the most sense.
Anyone have any suggestions
other than
double lung transplant?
Thank you. Perez?
Uh, we transplant
her right lung,
and... also her left.
We could also try
a double lung transplant.
I'm sorry.
Dr. Grey said we literally
couldn't stop pitching it.
Thank you, Schmitt.
This was in no way obvious.
Move.
Just tell me before you do it.
I'm already done.
So, just ice it and drink
plenty of fluids, okay?
Oh, thank you, my boy.
You're sure I didn't steal it
from someone?
It was extra.
I actually called
our entire waiting list
before I called you.
If you hadn't gotten here
when you did,
I would have had to throw it
in the trash,
which feels like a sin.
The more people that get this,
the safer we'll all be.
And how long 'til I can hug you
without a mask?
Two weeks after
your second shot, so soon.
Did I miss it?
Oh, I missed it.
You can give me
my second shot, dear.
Okay, not only did you
take my joy,
I now have an army of interns
trying to do your dirty work.
Double lung transplant
is her best option.
You are supposed to be
teaching them, Grey.
This is me teaching them.
We have to stop thinking
about COVID
in terms of who survives
and who doesn't.
There are millions of people
who are going to be suffering
from the aftereffects of COVID,
and we need to advocate for them
as hard as we advocate
for everybody else.
It is risky, but it is also
her best shot.
So, you teaching them is just...
you breeding an army
of little yous?
No respect for legacy?
Richard Webber made you.
He made me.
And he's going to die someday.
And one day,
you're going to die,
and one day, I'm going to die.
And if this year
has taught us anything,
it's that that may happen a lot
sooner than any of us want.
So I'm not going
to waste any time
teaching anything other
than what matters most.
And Bailey, you know
if this was me or your mother,
you would be screaming
from the rooftops.
You know that, right?
Just please call UNOS.
Okay.
You can make changes
and still honor
what made you.
I don't know what that means.
It means I'm gonna make
the damn call,
but you're starting back
Grand Rounds.
Or you're fired.
Mom!
♪ Talk
♪ Let's have conversations
in the dark ♪
♪ World is sleeping,
I'm awake with you ♪
♪ With you
♪ Watch
♪ Movies that we both
already seen ♪
♪ I ain't even looking
at the screen, it's true ♪
♪ I got my eyes on you
♪ And you say that
you're not worthy ♪
♪ You get hung up
on your flaws ♪
♪ Well, in my eyes,
you are perfect ♪
♪ As you are
♪ I will never try
to change you, change you ♪
♪ I will always want
the same you, same you ♪
♪ Swear on everything
I pray to ♪
♪ That I won't
break your heart ♪
♪ I'll be there
when you get lonely, lonely ♪
♪ Keep the secrets
that you told me, told me ♪
Can everyone
take their seats, please?
Thank you.
♪ Your love is all you owe me
♪ And I won't break your heart
It is my absolute pleasure to be
gathered with you today.
♪ On Sunday mornings
we sleep in 'til noon ♪
To love and to cherish.
♪ Well, I can sleep forever
next to you ♪
♪ Next to you
In sickness and in health.
♪ And we, we got places
we both gotta be ♪
In Scripture, a young person
about to embark on married life
says, "I have found the one
whom my soul loves."
Maggie, Winston, this is
our prayer for you...
That you may love one another
with your entire souls.
♪ But in my eyes,
you are perfect ♪
♪ As you are
I now pronounce you
husband and wife.
Go on, kiss her.
♪ I will always want the same you,
same you ♪
♪ Swear on everything
I pray to ♪
♪ That I won't
break your heart ♪
♪ I'll be there
when you get lonely, lonely ♪
♪ Keep the secrets
that you told me, told me ♪
Let's jump that broom.
♪ And your love
is all you owe me ♪
1, 2, 3!
♪ I won't break your heart
Alright, now, everyone, um,
these two have to stick around
to take some pictures.
Would the rest of you be so kind
as to head to
the reception area?
♪ I won't break your heart
Excuse me.
Hey, so they found
a donor for Gerlie.
We have to go.
What... Oh, my God.
I'm sorry we have to leave you
like this.
Yeah. Okay.
So, can you please tell Maggie
what happened?
Mm-hmm.
And can you watch
the kids?
Of course.
Yeah. Go, go, go.Okay. Alright.
Thanks. Okay.
You better give me a good price.
The economy is trash.
You're lucky I'm even looking.
Yeah, well, now that you
actually have some money,
maybe you'll, uh,
figure out how it works.
I really hope
you get a new joke.
Alright.
I gotta get back to work.
Welcome home, Jo.
Welcome home.
Welcome home, Luna.
What?
I have a village of people in my
life who wanted me to recover,
pulling for me
at every complication.
I could literally hear them.
And it helped.
And Gerlie's people can't be
here, so we're her village.
We're her village.
Stay with us, Gerlie.
We got you.
Scalpel, Bokhee.
♪ I don't fear
♪ 'Cause it won't be long now
♪ 'Cause it won't be long
'til we're out of here ♪
Ready for the specimen?
I'm ready.
♪ I'm gonna take you home
Ready for the donor lungs.
You okay? You need a break?
No, why? Do you?
No.
Bokhee, irrigation, please.
♪ Home
♪ I'm gonna take you home
Whoo!
You've got this.
What's going on?
Well, you said you didn't
want compulsory,
so here we go.
I wasn't sure
what style you'd like,
so I-I thought you could pick.
Or you can just have all four.
Link... Amelia,
I-I know that this last year
has been intense.
Everything about us
It's... It's kind of our thing.
I don't think it makes sense
for us to wait
until life settles down,
because knowing us, it won't.
But I do know that
no matter what happens,
I want to go through it
with you.
You... challenge me,
you... you thrill me,
you impress the hell out of me.
There's definitely no one
on Earth like you,
so please,
will you do me the honor
of marrying me?
♪ When the world was ending
I'm still alive.
♪ And we talked about the places
we'd never been ♪
People often laugh at that
answer, but it's not a joke.
♪ When the world was ending,
we'd hold on to the past ♪
Are you responsible for this?
♪ 'Cause it's all we thought that
we would ever see ♪
You do things your way,
I'm-a do things mine.
Being alive... it's everything.
♪ Another day to begin again
♪ To begin again, to begin
Okay, everybody, louder!
♪ And cry because I'm happy
♪ And hold my friends
like long-lost lovers ♪
Time to celebrate.
♪ Be kind to me
and love each other ♪
♪ The world keeps spinning on
And yes, time for pain.
♪ When the world was ending Oh, Link.
I'm so sorry.
Do you have someplace
I can crash?
Yeah.
♪ So far from comprehending
♪ They'd lift us to the stars
Time to change.
♪ Never seen each other
from so far away ♪
To grow.
To love.
♪ It's alright, it's okay
♪ We will get another day
♪ To begin again,
to begin again ♪
♪ To begin again
Meredith.
Gerlie!
How are you feeling?
You're still here?
I'm still here.
♪ To begin again,
to begin again, to begin ♪
♪ To live and love
And time to give.
♪ And breathe again
>>>>oakislandtk
www.opensubtitles.org