Previously on Grey's Anatomy...
Alex, you have a father.
I know, and he's a dirtbag.
Mr. Evans? I paged
you to get Yang.
Yang's at the wedding. I'm here.
Dr. Derek Shepherd? DEREK: Yes.
Please hold for the
President of the United States.
I cannot believe
we're doing this!
All this blood...
Doctor? Bypass...
I have it! 2-0 silk!
Maybe it's time we talked about uh,
why the hell you up and quit surgery.
What do we got here, son?
I did this. It's my fault.
I love you, April.
I always have.
And I think that you
love me, too. Do you?
Every day, a surgeon
makes decisions
that can go one of two ways,
either very good or
very, very, very bad.
The problem is, the
epically great decisions
and the epically bad ones
look exactly the same
when you're making them.
April, do you...
Do you not want to do this?
Drive the car.
Meredith, when the
President of the United States
calls you on the
phone... I get it.
You can't say no to the guy.
Nope.
I mean, when they start
putting government money
behind a program like that,
mapping the human brain,
the impact that that
has worldwide is just...
Big impact. Get me
my curling iron, please.
The weeping sisters have gone
through every tissue in this building.
Did you get the mother
to calm down, at least?
I tried. But how was I
supposed to pretend
that what just happened wasn't
the coolest thing I'd ever seen?
Cristina...
You know, I've always been
on the fence about Kepner,
but now I'm not just
a friend, I'm a fan.
Was that about me?
No, it's about me.
The President called, and I have to
go back on a promise I made to her.
Oh, good. Better you than me.
President? Of the United States.
You are not serious. Mm.
Something's going
on at the hospital.
I want him fired! OWEN: Karev...
I want him arrested!
Webber is watching over
your father like a hawk.
His vitals are stable, and we're gonna
do our best to keep it that way, okay?
What the hell was
this kid thinking?
He wasn't thinking.
Yeah, no kidding.
He was hallucinating.
He had no idea
what was happening.
He thought the patient on
the table was Heather Brooks.
Oh, my God. What?
He showed me how to fudge
your hours in the system,
so you can continue working
without having to sleep.
For God's sakes...
I'll find him.
Cristina's on her
way. She's gonna...
No, Yang is not touching
him. Alex, I think...
If that kid messed
up, it's on her.
She lets him think
he runs the place.
Why do you think he hacked
up Jimmy's heart all on his own?
Let's just wait until
we get all the facts...
She's screwing him!
Would you just take
a breath for a second?
This one doesn't
even have a card!
How is April supposed
to return her gift
if we can't even manage to
keep the gifts with the card?
Okay, we'll find the
cards. Arizona! Stop.
We will fix it. No! We won't!
That's the whole problem.
You've been trying
to fix it, our marriage.
You've been trying to fix
me, and you're so good!
You're killing
yourself just to fix me!
You don't have to apologize...
I'm not! That's the point!
Because I'm not the same
person that I was before,
and I don't want to apologize,
and I don't want to be fixed.
Whoa, whoa. I'm
not the same person
I was before, either,
but that doesn't...
It's not working,
and you know it!
You knew before I did.
Okay, can we just go home
and sit down and
talk about this?
It's not my home anymore.
Maybe you could
stop acting like a child...
Now I'm a child. That's
great. That's great.
I'm childish. I caused your OCD.
What else you got? Did
I cause global warming?
Maybe I killed JFK! That
would explain a lot, right?
You quit surgery!
See, this was supposed to be
different than my first marriage.
I thought you understood
what it means to be a surgeon!
Until you dropped it!
And now, here I am, once
again, married to a man
who's waiting to see
me at the end of the day,
waiting to see what I'm gonna
do, when I'm gonna come home!
You think I was happy to walk
away from a surgical residency?
You think you were, what, a
convenient excuse to dump it?
Well, yes. No, I
was a damned star!
I had found what I'd been
looking for, for decades,
and I walked away from it, yes,
because I wanted
to be here with you!
And it was the hardest
choice I ever had to make.
You didn't want
to leave surgery?
No! I did not want
to leave surgery.
Hey. Still no Shane. I'm
gonna try his apartment.
If he's dead on the side of
the road, I am going to lose it.
Could you take her home?
She's had a rough day.
At a wedding? What, you
drank too much champagne?
You have blisters on your
feet from all the dancing?
My boyfriend ran
off with the bride.
What? There was no dancing.
I'm gonna find you a ride home,
and as soon as things calm
down with Alex and his dad,
I'm gonna come over and we're
gonna drink a lot and burn things.
Can you wait five minutes?
Jackson, pull over.
Jackson, just pull over the car.
Just... What is it?
Jackson, please, just
pull over the car now!
Relax.
Just calm down. Calm down?
What are we doing?
Is there a plan?
There's no plan.
You think I would plan
to ruin your wedding?
No, no! That doesn't
seem like you.
All right, April, look...
I can't. I'm sorry. We
can't do this. I can't.
They'll fix the gutters,
the water damage in
the bedroom, all of it.
You know, I rarely see a
deal go through this fast.
You were really ready to move.
Yeah, sometimes you
just need a fresh start.
Congratulations.
Um, I'm not sure we should be
popping the champagne just yet.
There's a man-sized
blood stain in the bedroom.
Now, they said they'd
replace the carpet
before the close of escrow.
It's rust.
I think they said the
carpet guy's coming today.
Let me call them. Yeah.
It's beautiful. And
it's gonna be ours.
It's a murder house.
Callie. Try.
It's...
kind of beautiful.
Paging Dr. Man...
Dr. Sharp-Dressed Man.
I have kind of a
big thing today.
Me, too.
Rounds with Webber in
20, followed by an ER shift,
that, fingers crossed,
could lead to my assisting
on any number of grisly
traumas this afternoon.
What's your thing?
I'm being vetted
by the White House.
So it's kind of a big
day for both of us.
If Steph doesn't
want to talk about it,
we can't force it.
It's been three
weeks, and we haven't
been able to get
one scrap of real intel
on what happened
between Kepner and Avery.
They're avoiding each
other, she's avoiding us,
and nobody's saying anything.
Warren, you sit at
the grown-ups' table.
You have to know something.
Mm-mmm. I don't like gossip.
I don't like you.
Steph! Oh, my God, hi!
You came out of hiding! Yay!
I haven't been in hiding.
Okay, I've been
in hiding, but...
Time heals wounds or whatever.
Really? Yeah, absolutely.
That's Shane's gear. Is he back?
I haven't seen him.
I can't believe the board
decided to let him come back.
Yeah, I bet a couple
weeks' rest did him good.
He's a good kid who
went down a bad road.
Can it, Pops.
How old do you
people think I am?
Forty-nine.
Ben Warren, you
forgot your lunch.
You didn't have
to do that, baby.
I was gonna go to the cafeteria.
You do that, you're gonna
grab a pizza or a burger
and then come complaining
to me about heartburn,
and I don't want to hear it.
Can I change my answer?
'Cause now I want
to say you're 12.
You told her what?
She's been dodging
my calls for weeks.
Someone needs to take
responsibility for Jimmy,
and it's not gonna be me.
Technically, they're still married.
Yeah, but you can't just lie.
Turns out I can.
It's really easy.
Good God, you look
just like your father.
Sorry. Alex. This is
my fiancee, Jo Wilson.
Naomi. Right.
Well, we're gonna walk this way.
MVC pileup at the
downtown waterfront.
We've got multiple victims
coming in here, people! Be careful!
Cars took out a bunch
of pedestrians, too.
Was she conscious
in the field? Nope.
Okay, let's get her
to trauma room four.
Ross! I need hands.
Ross, stay where you
are. You're with me today.
Edwards, go help Avery.
Avery?
No. Sorry... Not Edwards. Okay.
Warren, Avery needs hands.
Now, hang on a second.
Warren's with me.
You can't break up the big dogs.
Webber, I'm having
enough trouble
juggling who can work with who.
Don't make it any harder.
For God's sake,
I'll go with Avery.
Wouldn't want to break up
the "old dogs" or anything.
It's "big dogs."
No, not a dog.
It was a cat. A really big cat.
- Coming through!
- Another incoming!
Pedestrian, hit by a
car, vitals are stable.
Possible fracture
to the right arm.
Holy crap!
You know, it's not my face
that's injured. It's my arm.
Meow.
Over there.
Oh, okay.
Dr. Shepherd. Miles
Green. This is Rita Belmont.
Nice to meet you,
Miles. Rita, pleasure.
Sorry I'm late.
Yeah, we knew you'd be late.
We've been tracking your
phone since last we spoke.
No, I'm messing with you!
We don't track your phone.
Come on, have a seat. I'm sorry.
But don't kid yourself,
because we do know a crazy
amount of stuff about you.
Now, the White House requires a
deeper-than-normal background check
on anyone associated with
the President's programs,
so this process can
get a little personal.
I understand. Great.
So, you know, let's just
ask you a few questions, eat a
little lunch, and go home happy.
What do you say? Okay.
Let's start with your wife.
So, you two met when she was
a student of yours, was she not?
Yeah, I suppose.
Hmm.
Is that bad?
Hey. You feel like getting
out of the lab for half a day?
I've got an aortic
aneurysm repair.
Really? You want
to do it together?
Unless you're busy
or don't want to.
No, I'd love to.
Sure. Are you sure?
Positive. It'd be fun, right?
Okay. Great.
And I was just
walking down the street
and some chick blows
through a red light.
Six-car smash-up.
One even comes
up on the sidewalk
and takes me out.
Stupid woman.
His pupils are unresponsive.
Those are contacts, right?
Yes.
And the teeth are...
Veneers, permanent.
Whiskers, piercings.
Ooh.
So, you guys gonna
doctor me up or what?
He complained of
abdominal tenderness.
Right, get a CT to
rule out internal injuries,
and then we'll fix the arm.
You know what?
There was a little kid out
there, cracked her head open.
Is she okay? We can find out.
Yeah, you know what?
Let's just worry about
getting you out of here with
all of your nine lives, okay?
Hustle up, Ross. You're trying to
protect her airway, not make it worse.
Epiglottis is in the way.
I can't see the...
Dr. Warren, take
over for Dr. Ross.
I'm sorry.
Mm-hmm.
Now, that is how a
second-year resident intubates.
Okay, Ross, go find her phone.
See if she has any
emergency contacts listed,
unless you want Dr. Warren
to show you how to do that, too.
Ross is still a little fragile.
That kind of tough
love may wash him out
before he has a chance
to get back on his feet.
You don't mistake
any of this for love.
If I had my way, he
would not be here.
If the board want to go
against my recommendation
and bring him back, that's fine.
But I'm still the
Chief of Surgery,
so I will deal with
him as I see fit.
You didn't bring your son.
Wasn't any reason
to bring Nicky.
I'm really only
here for that guitar.
You can do whatever you
want with the rest of his stuff.
Keep it, toss it.
Dealer's choice.
What the hell is
this? He's not dead?
No.
You lied to me. Yeah.
You know, this is our first surgery
together since everything fell apart.
I know. I'm enjoying it.
Me, too, but I have a question
that might ruin the mood.
Well, just ask your question.
Where is Shane?
After the way you pushed
us all to let him come back...
You were right about him.
I should've seen it coming.
I am so pissed at him,
I'm afraid if I see him again,
I'll rip his arms out by the root.
Plus, Alex just started
talking to me again.
The parenting books say when
your kid does something wrong,
you have to put your anger
aside when you talk to them.
Is that how you're
dealing with Derek?
Totally.
And what's awesome is, the
nicer I am, the guiltier he feels.
It's the only fun I have lately.
Mer, the President
called him personally.
You really want to defend him when
we were having such a good time?
You're right. Screw the guy.
Thank you.
A proposal's a big deal.
You remember a proposal.
Was I drunk? Do
I drink too much?
You do drink a
lot. Screw your life.
Screw your perfect little life.
What part of "accidentally
engaged" sounds perfect to you?
Oh, my God. It
was at the wedding.
Stop talking about
weddings and engagements.
She just got left at the
altar. No, she wasn't.
She was left near an altar.
Ow! What?
Sorry, I just... I needed
the CT. For a patient.
My patient needs a CT.
We're almost done.
Great! Cool. Take your time.
I want you to have it, really.
I'll just come back later.
What a bitch. Totes.
You need closure. Why don't
you just go talk to Jackson?
Why don't you just
go talk to your fiance?
This can't be legal.
You can't just call someone up
and say "he's dead" if it's not true.
Well, he is dying.
He's septic. His
organs are failing.
He's got a few days at the most.
Look, he knows you're coming.
So, what, I'm supposed to
sit in there, hold his hand,
and kiss away his tears like
he wasn't a complete bastard?
That guitar belonged
to my father.
Left me three of
them when he died.
Jimmy pawned the other two.
One day, the third one
disappeared. And so did he.
Look, it all started
because he came in here
trying to get clean
for you and Nicky.
I mean, it was
hell, but he did it.
At this point, I think
you're the only reason
he's still trying to hang on.
Don't bail on him now.
I was with Jimmy for five years.
I know what it sounds
like when he's full of crap.
You are 100% his son.
It took 15 surgeries total.
Wow.
Spent everything I had.
How many people do you know
that are unhappy with who they are?
And do they do
anything to change it?
'Cause, see, I
didn't like who I was.
But I had the balls to
become who I wanted to be.
I committed.
Some people get
a gym membership.
You went all-in. I like it.
How's it go over
with the ladies?
Well, you know, I had a
girlfriend when I started all this.
She loved it.
You know, but that ended and...
Listen, let's just
say the Cat Man
gets more than his
share of tail, okay?
Okay.
That's all I'm saying. Yeah.
Ow. Ow.
Hey, what's the word on that
little kid? She wake up yet?
Well, I am so sorry, but patient
information's confidential, so...
It's bad news, then, huh?
All right, you can go ahead
and remove those clamps.
Is there something you need
to say to me, Dr. Murphy?
You couldn't have
given her a heads-up,
in the months you
were seeing each other?
She was worried about Kepner.
She asked about it, and
you didn't say anything.
What, were you just waiting for the
right time to publicly humiliate her?
I could've just kept working.
I didn't even have to ask you.
Why the hell did I ask you?
I guess you have a
problem with impulse control.
I have been trying to
apologize to her for weeks now.
She walks away the
moment she sees me coming.
I am miserable
about what I did to her.
I had no idea I was gonna do it.
Not till the moment it happened.
Still, Steph's alone,
Kepner's alone, you're alone.
Everybody's pretty miserable.
Seems like it all worked
out really well, doesn't it?
Dr. Murphy, I'm gonna get
back to fixing this man's arm.
Now, you can glare
at me all you want to,
but you are gonna help.
They were all just
staring at me, judging me,
with their little resident eyes.
Like they used to stare
at you. Cheater eyes.
Ooh, yeah, cheater
eyes are the worst.
But it's not like you
deserve it, right?
I mean, you and Jackson, it's
not the same thing. I mean, is it?
Well, I...
Hey, Renee called. The
carpet's gonna be done by 3:00,
and then we have an
appointment with the notary at 5:00.
You guys are signing
papers on the house today?
That is so great!
Well, maybe not.
There's no way I can be
out of here before 5:00.
No, it's fine. He's
a traveling notary.
He can come to us. Splendid.
And I have this ice-cream maker
I couldn't figure
out how send back.
That'll be your
housewarming gift!
Congratulations!
I told you we should've
kept track of the cards.
What happened? Did you
get the dirt on her and Avery?
I've been trying to get Ben
to do recon with the residents,
but he's all, "I don't
like to gossip." What?
Dr. Torres, Robert Fischer's
missing from his room,
and nobody knows where he is.
The Cat Man! The cat got out.
Dr. Ross, how about a
little lunch with the big dogs?
Dr. Hunt wants
me to triple-check
all of Penny's labs before
we take her to surgery.
Well, we're not taking
her into surgery for a while.
You have time to sit down.
Besides, Dr. Warren could
use some friends his own age.
How old do you think I am?
Is that a dinosaur?
"Have a wonderful
day, my special boy.
"Don't forget to
wash your hands."
I obviously have
Tuck's lunch by mistake.
Yeah, I'm getting a burger.
It's Chief Hunt.
I really need to get those
labs. I'll see you in surgery.
I'm sorry, kid. I just
want to say I'm sorry.
This is all my fault.
So get better, okay?
Just... Just get better.
Uh-oh.
Hey! Hey! What are
you doing in here?
I'm sorry!
It happened before
Kepner's wedding, didn't it?
You said all that
stuff about being
together forever
and having a family.
That was you proposing.
Are you serious right now?
What do you think it was?
I thought that you were
upset about your dad.
Proposals usually end
in "Will you marry me?"
If I'd understood, I
never would have said...
Well, great.
Naomi's walking out on Jimmy,
and now you're walking out on me.
It's freakin' kismet.
Listen to me!
I'm not walking out on you.
But we can't get married just because
you're screwed up about your dad.
Don't use him as an
excuse for cold feet.
If you don't want to
get married, just say so.
I don't! I'm not ready. Okay?
But that's not the point.
This isn't about love.
This is about grief...
I'm not grieving!
Alex!
Damn it!
Well, your sister's drug
problem's under control.
She's sober, still
going to meetings.
She is? Yeah.
She doesn't concern us.
Hiring undocumented workers,
now, that'll get you the boot.
That and outstanding debt,
but you're good there.
No student loans, even.
Dr. Shepherd, what can you
tell us about Michael Boetcher?
Michael Boetcher.
Is Michael...
Is he relevant to this?
Let's start with why you've
been sending his mother
$3,500 every month.
You're here. Are they?
No, they're not here.
I'm afraid if I told you
how much it means to me
that you got them
to come on a plane,
you might call them
and tell them to forget it.
Take it easy.
I still don't know how you
managed to convince them to come.
I told them you were dead.
Wishful thinking?
Where's my guitar?
I threw some of
your stuff in storage.
Oh, Alex.
Can you bring it back down?
It belonged to Naomi's dad.
I took it.
Of all the crap I've done,
that was one of the lowest.
I want to give it back.
Please.
Make sure I'm awake
when they get here.
Well, looks like the
bone's still intact,
so you didn't do
too much damage.
I never should've done it.
You think?
I never should
have left the house.
This whole accident happened,
all these people were
hurt because of me!
Because of some stupid
thing I've done to myself!
You know, when I started
this, my parents, everybody said,
"You think you're gonna
like this in 20 years?"
I thought I would. I
thought I knew who I was.
I was 19.
So now I work from home,
same data-entry job for 16 years.
I can't date.
The kind of women who find me
attractive scare the crap out of me.
I don't have friends.
People stare, people laugh.
People punch.
And time goes by, and I realize
I haven't left my house
in a year and a half.
I said to myself, "Rob,
you got to do something.
"You got to try and live again.
"Just go out. Just
go for a walk."
That was this morning.
We're just gonna
finish splinting this up,
make sure it's stable, okay?
Can you make it quick?
I just want to go home.
Jimmy's BP's gone to crap.
In and out of consciousness?
Yeah. This is it, isn't
it? He's out of time.
You okay?
What? Give me a
break, Mer. Not you, too.
You of all people
should understand.
You think there's
anything you can do?
He has a DNR. I don't think so.
Let's finish up here
and go take a look.
Okay.
More suction. Got a
bleeder. Clamp, please.
Hold on. Dr. Ross, take over.
Which blood vessel is that?
It's a branch of the
superior mesenteric artery.
And how are you gonna repair it?
I'm gonna throw a surgical
tie around the clamp.
3-0 silk on a passer.
And what does the superior
mesenteric artery supply?
The midgut. And what is
the origin of the midgut?
What?
The embryology.
Dr. Hunt, I think he could probably
do the tie without the anatomy lesson...
Dr. Webber, I think a surgeon
should be able to demonstrate
a complete understanding
of the part of the body
before he operates on it.
The midgut is formed from the...
The primary
intestinal loop and...
And?
I'm sorry.
And the cephalic limb develops
into the distal duodenum,
jejunum, and ileum.
You're about to place a
stitch into this patient's body
and then seal her up, and you
can't tell me the basic anatomy
that you're
repairing? I'm sorry.
Do not apologize to me one more
time. You don't owe me an apology.
You owe one to the man
whose heart you ripped apart
because you didn't know
what you were doing,
just like you owe an
apology to this girl,
who is laying on this
table, losing blood,
because you don't know
how to do a basic tie.
Leave the OR, Dr. Ross.
Dr. Warren, do the tie.
Hi.
Hey.
It's really good to see you.
You know, I've been
calling... No, I have a patient.
And he's done all these
surgeries to look like a cat,
and he doesn't want to
look like a cat anymore,
and he doesn't have any money,
but you could fix him, pro-bono.
Steph, I need to explain.
You telling me that you
feel guilty only helps you.
Not me.
If you want to do something
useful, fix the Cat Man.
Dr. Karev?
Walk away, Ross.
Dr. Karev, I owe you an apology.
I owe you both...
What the hell? Wait! Alex, stop!
Alex! Alex! Alex! Alex!
Alex! Get off!
Ross, get up, get up!
Stop it! Stop it! Go!
Stop it! What is going on?
Let's go! Come on!
Alex, please. Please.
I thought if I came back,
kept my head down,
did the work, I
might be able to...
Not fix it,
but start to make up for
what I did to Karev's dad.
I don't deserve to feel better.
I deserved this.
Yeah. You really did.
Baby Nathan's mom sent me this.
It's one of those
annoying pictures
all mothers think are cute of
their baby with food all over its face.
Except this one, it's not cute.
It's miraculous. Revolutionary.
You saved a baby, Shane,
because you had the
idea to 3-D print the conduit
and wouldn't stop
pushing until I came around.
You made some bad choices,
but that was a good one.
Moving forward,
make more good ones.
Everywhere you see a
red tag, sign your name.
Okay.
Um...
I know you're excited.
You've been smiling
since we found the house,
and I have missed
that smile so much.
But three weeks ago, you were
convinced we weren't gonna last.
I'm worried that you're thinking
about how good it feels now
and not thinking about the
fact that I come with the house.
You know why I smile when
I think about that house?
Hmm?
I look at that house
and I don't see a hospital
bed in our bedroom,
and I don't see a shower
that you had to drag me into
because I wouldn't
do it on my own.
I see a tire swing
and a tree house.
We may wake up in a year and
realize it was a huge mistake.
But if it works... Oh, my God.
Just thinking about it makes
me smile so hard my face hurts.
Kissing the bride isn't enough.
You have to actually
sign the papers.
Aah!
What happened? Are you okay?
It's my fault.
I knew I shouldn't
get involved with him.
I knew it was a mistake,
and I did it anyway.
It's too hard being
here around him.
I should leave.
I could transfer.
Leaving's not the answer.
He took advantage here, not you.
He's your boss,
and he chose to
start dating you.
And then he chose
to humiliate you
in front of all of
your co-workers.
He did that. They all do it.
Arizona did it to me, and
Yang did a number on Shane.
They are our bosses, and
we're expendable to them.
But we shouldn't be.
You could do something about it.
You should do
something about it.
That was vicious.
He was drowning in there,
and you were enjoying it.
Well, I'm sorry my
style of leadership
doesn't involve
taking Ross to lunch.
Tell me this isn't about
who he was sleeping with.
You really think I would let that
interfere with the way that I do my job?
I wouldn't have
thought it before today.
Chief Hunt, there's someone
from HR looking for you.
I'll be right there.
Alex?
Naomi and Nicky
are on their way.
They're coming?
They're on their way.
When?
Their plane was delayed. I
told them about the guitar.
They're coming?
They're coming.
I, uh, told them about
the guitar. I told them...
I told them that you love them.
You told them?
I told them.
They know you love
them. They know.
It's okay. It's okay, Jimmy.
It's okay. They
know you love them.
They know.
You can go.
They know. You can go.
You son of a bitch.
Hey, hey.
Uh, did you get anything out of
Edwards about Avery or Kepner?
Hello, honey. How was your day?
Come on.
A resident went off the
rails and nearly killed a man.
I didn't see that coming.
People are buying houses
and running out on marriages.
Things are topsy-turvy
all over the place,
and I don't understand
any of it, so spill.
There's nothing to spill!
And even if there
was, I wouldn't tell you,
because I need these
kids to trust me. Oh!
And the only reason why
there's a spot for me to fill
is because one of
their friends died.
I have my work cut
out for me as it is.
Fine.
You had pizza for
lunch, didn't you?
No.
Okay, you don't have to
gossip with me, Ben Warren,
but you'd better
not start lying to me.
It was a burger. Ha!
The plot thickens.
They found something.
I played hockey in high school.
I have a lot of slides to
get through here, Derek.
There was this kid,
Michael Boetcher.
He and I were the most
aggressive guys on the team,
and one day at practice, I
cross-checked him into the boards.
We both went down, both got
back up, we continued to play.
Boetcher didn't come
back to school the next day.
He had a brain bleed that night.
He died? It was worse than that.
It was a pontine bleed,
so he couldn't move,
couldn't communicate.
All he could do was blink.
So the President's people
found out about this, or...
He's been in long-term
care ever since.
I send his family money.
They wondered why.
So your deep, dark secret is
that you've spent the last 30 years
paying for an accident that
happened when you were a teenager?
Because I put him there.
And then you became a
neurosurgeon, like a superhero.
And now, the President
of the United States
has handpicked you to carve
out the future of medicine.
I have no room to be angry
here, but this is infuriating!
Well, if I could turn
it down, I would.
You know what would help me?
If you would just stop talking
about your duty to God and country
and just admit that
you want to do this.
I do. Of course I do. Yes.
Yeah, see, somehow, I
thought that was gonna help me,
but it only made me angrier!
Hello?
Uh, no, Dr. Shepherd cannot
come to the phone right now
because he is
fighting with his wife.
Who is it? It's the White House.
Give me the phone!
Give me the phone.
It's Owen. Do
you think I'm nuts?
They're calling an
emergency board meeting.
Is this about what happened
with Karev and Ross?
What happened
Nothing.
One of our surgical residents
has lodged an official
complaint with Human Resources.
Three separate
complaints, actually.
Directed sexual harassment,
quid-pro-quo harassment,
and hostile work environment.
What? Who? Directed at whom?
HR won't release that or
the name of the resident.
"Hostile work
environment"? Come on.
Does she have a case legally?
Okay. Is there
way that we could...
Or maybe I could
talk to this person?
You know, we could
just clear the air
before it gets
out of proportion.
He shouldn't talk to
her without legal present.
Well, if she's
filed a complaint...
You're all missing the point!
This is not about one person.
This is a complaint about this
hospital and this teaching program.
We are too often letting our
personal lives disrupt our work.
None of us are guilt-free...
Myself included.
Now, HR have recommended
a clear, zero-tolerance policy.
"Excluding those of
pre-existing married couples..."
"Relationships of
romantic or sexual nature
"between superiors and
subordinates will not be allowed."
It is restrictive, it
is non-negotiable,
but it is fair and, better
still, it is unambiguous.
I urge you all to vote
to implement this.
Looking back, it's easy
to see when a mistake
has been made.
To regret a choice that seemed
like a decent idea at the time.
Hope you're okay with spaghetti.
I had to ditch that
leftover chicken.
I found a home for
the ice-cream maker.
I thought we were keeping it.
Hope we didn't go
through all that for nothing.
Hey!
Mmm.
We had a board meeting tonight.
I don't think we're gonna be able
to keep this a secret much longer.
A meeting about us?
Kind of.
What happened?
I'll tell you about
it after dinner.
April, get back in the car!
You can't just walk back!
Why?
Bears?
Matthew doesn't deserve
this! And Stephanie?
What are we supposed
to say to them?
My parents? Your mother?
Oh, my God. My mother...
How do we explain
that we just destroyed
two perfectly lovely people
so that we could, what, date?
Okay, the best solution is never
to speak to any of them ever again.
Or...
Or we get married. I...
Because that's
easier to explain.
No. No, 'cause
you're right, all right?
I don't want to just date.
April, I want the
whole damn thing.
We can get to Lake
Tahoe in 13 hours.
How do you know that?
Do you want to get
into that right now? No.
No, you don't
want to get into that,
or, no, you don't
want to get married?
But if we used our best judgment
and listened to our hearts,
we're more likely to
see that we chose wisely.
Yes.
Yes!
And avoided the deepest,
most painful regret of them all,
the regret that comes from letting
something amazing pass you by.