.
- Previously
on "New Amsterdam"...
- Your husband is very lucky.
If only I'd met you
15 years earlier.
- How does your girlfriend
have a residency slot here?
- I made a donation, okay?
- You know,
when the staff finds out,
you're gonna lose
all their respect.
You already lost mine.
- If this child isn't yours,
there's no shame
in stepping away.
Lyn and I will be just fine.
♪
- ♪ Shake your groove thing,
shake your groove thing ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah
♪ Show 'em how to do it now
♪ Shake your groove thing,
shake your groove thing ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah
♪ Show 'em
how to do it now ♪
♪ Show 'em how you do it now
- ♪ Let's show the world
we can dance ♪
♪ Bad enough
to strut our stuff ♪
♪ Let's show 'em
that we can dance ♪
♪ We do more out on the floor
- You ordered another one?
- Yes, yes.
- You know how many calories
this one has?
- No, get off!
- Oh, my God.
This is amazing.
- No more alcohol for you.
- Oh, come on.
- ♪ Shake your groove thing,
shake your groove thing ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah
♪ Show 'em how to do it now
♪ Shake your groove thing,
shake your groove thing ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah
♪ Show 'em how to do it now
♪
- Hi, how are you?
- I smell of airplane.
- I don't care.
Can we get out of here and--
- Hold that thought
for a couple of hours.
The next round's on me!
♪
- Oh, no way!
- Where are we going next?
- You're ridiculous.
- No, I'm done.
I might be done for good.
Lauren?
- Oh, no, I'm sorry.
Elizabeth, I'm dying.
I can't.
- Oh, no, no.
I'm dangerously close
to forgetting my own address.
His liver...
- Good night, everyone.
- See ya, guys.
- Night.
♪
- No, even that's too loud.
- Oh, my...
What were we thinking?
- That we're still 28.
- But we're not.
Anybody our at age
who drinks that much booze
and thinks they still
can be okay is a liar.
- Who's still got it?
We still got it.
What's up, fellas?
- Oh, no, no, no, no.
- Why is everyone screaming?
- You guys are as bad as Helen.
She couldn't even
get out of bed this morning.
But I'm gonna need you to dust
off those cobwebs, all right?
Break through that wall, yeah?
- Yeah.
- How are you not nauseous
and dying?
- Well, I've got English
tolerance now.
More than that, I've got the
greatest hangover cure
in the world--purpose.
Today is a big day
at New Amsterdam.
- Yeah, you don't work
- Yeah, you work
at a third-tier
urgent-care center
inside New Amsterdam.
- Yeah,
but Urgent Medicine, Inc.
has a, um, bold vision,
not to mention a seat
on the board at New Amsterdam,
which happens
to be meeting tonight.
So tonight we're gonna
take Veronica down.
- All right.
- Yeah.
- Guys, guys, great news--
board meeting got bumped,
so we get to go home early,
and I can finally set
this taco hat on fire.
- "Bumped"?
Today was my day.
It was my whole thing.
I was gonna do my whole...
- Yeah, well it's gonna
have to wait two weeks
till Veronica's back
from whatever conference
is more important
than running this hospital.
- What am I supposed to do
for two weeks?
- Well, you do work
at Urgent Medicine, Inc.
- Theirs is a bold vision.
- Thank you.
- Look, I know that the clinic
may not be glamorous,
but we get to help people,
so just grow up and--
Oh, God.
- Jeez.
Um...
That was close.
- What was that?
- Well, if I'm ever gonna
get back together with Leyla,
I have to make it crystal clear
that I am not pursuing her.
I can't have fake accidentally
bumping into her, can I?
- No, 'cause that
would make you look crazy.
♪
- Which way is
the stupid clinic anyway?
- This way. We have to take
the service elevator,
and we're not allowed
to talk to anyone.
- Help.
Help.
Can somebody help me?
- Let's get him into a chair.
Sir, what's your name?
- Uh, Max...
Max Bloomstein.
- Um, why don't you
have a seat?
- Okay, how were you injured,
Mr. Bloomstein?
- I slipped in the shower.
Aah! Ah!
- Let's get him
into a procedure room.
Tachy's at 110.
Let's hang a bag
of normal saline, wide open.
How's the wound look?
- Pretty extensive.
And there's a superficial
retained object.
- What is that?
- I don't know, an antenna?
- Uh, all right,
uh, let's, uh--
Tachy's up to 130.
Let's hang a second bag
of normal saline, wide open.
- I got it.
- Max...
he's lost a lot of blood.
- Yeah, he needs
a unit of packed red cells.
- We don't have
anything like that.
- No, but New Amsterdam does.
I'll ask Wilder.
Excuse me.
Hey, uh, Ben, Elizabeth's not
responding to any of my texts,
and I really need a bag
of O negative.
- Uh, I'll have some sent up.
- Great, thanks.
You okay?
- It's, uh...
Five years of working together,
Elizabeth's never been late,
not once.
- Oh, well, she went pretty
hard at karaoke last night,
so I'm sure
she's just sleeping it off.
Let me know.
- Mm-hmm.
♪
.
- Just one patient left?
- Just got to wrap a cast.
- Great,
that shouldn't take long.
So, um...
how do you feel about duets?
Specifically "Reunited" or
"Nothing's Gonna Stop Us Now"?
- I'm not going
to karaoke night.
- But everyone's going.
-  Exactly.
- Look, there's gonna be
so many people there,
you probably won't
even see Dr. Bloom.
- An old army buddy's
leaving town,
and we're grabbing a drink,
preferably where people
aren't singing.
- Well, how about a drive-by?
Well, that's what
it's called, right?
When you just stop by...
Please, just for me.
- Fine, fine.
A drive-by.
- Ah.
♪ La, la, la, la
- No singing.
- I'll take it.
- Jiminy Constantinople?
- Yes.
- Hey, I'm Casey.
I'll be wrapping your cast
this evening.
♪ Boots were made
for walking ♪
♪ And that's
just what they'll do ♪
♪ And one of these days
these boots ♪
♪ Are gonna walk all over you
- Hey, I got my digital card
right here.
Just hang on.
It's connected to this stupid
app that never frickin' works.
- ♪ You keep lyin'
when you ought to be truthin' ♪
- Yeah, don't care, man.
- Dude, I have two shots
and a booster.
I-I'm a nurse at a hospital.
- Like I said, don't care.
Go on in.
- ♪ You keep samin' when
you oughta be a-changin' ♪
- Um, I realize
the irony of this,
but you really
shouldn't let anyone
without a vaccine card in.
♪ These boots are made...
- Casey in the house!
♪ One of these days
these boots ♪
♪ Are gonna walk all over you
- ♪ Time to make a new path
I have never seen anyone
down three Flaming Zombies,
and I'm Australian.
- Yeah, please.
- Yeah, take it.
Cheers.
- Whoo.
- Nice.
- Oh.
- Hey, sorry.
- Oh, hey.
- Hey.
- Uh, it's just water, so--
- Okay.
♪
- How much longer?
- What?
- How much longer
am I gonna be in the doghouse?
Like, a month, a year?
Give me a ballpark figure.
- Okay,
can we not do this here?
- I screwed up, okay?
I know that I screwed up,
but I'm doing everything I can
to make it right.
You know I am.
I lost everything--
Leyla, my job, my best friend.
I'm a shell of a person now.
Is that not penance enough?
- No, it's not.
- Why?
- 'Cause honor matters.
- What, are we in "Serpico"?
- Okay, now I'm leaving.
- No, no, no, no, no, no,
wait, wait, wait.
I'm sorry, I'm sorry, okay?
I know how you feel
about Sidney Lumet.
I will do anything, anything
to get you to talk to me again.
- Wear that hat
for the rest of the night.
- Done.
- And all day tomorrow, too.
- Absolutely not.
That is just bad doctoring.
- Oh, maybe if you explain
to your patients
why you're doing it,
they might smile.
Maybe even humanize you.
Hi.
Uh, I would like to purchase
the taco hat.
- No, but you can win it
if you finish a fry bucket.
- Why is it a taco hat?
- It just is.
- Lauren, forget it.
I'm just being dumb.
- No, never mind.
Let's do it.
Let's get the hat down,
'cause honor matters.
♪
- No way!
That is ridiculous!
- Where we going next?
I'm done.
I might be done for good.
Lauren?
- Oh, no, I'm sorry.
Elizabeth, I can't.
I dying.
- Oh, no, no.
I'm dangerously close to
forgetting my own address.
- I got to call it
for, like, my liver.
- The livers--take care
of your livers, everybody.
- Bye, guys.
- And then he took out
the magazine...
- Oh, and a gallon
of sand poured out.
Oh, my God.
- Oh, man.
That fool's lucky to be alive.
- Oh, we all are, man.
- Yeah.
- Yo, man, it was so good
to hook up with you
before you head out, bro.
♪
- Hey, um, Houston's
not happening, bro.
- What?
♪
- I don't want
to talk about it.
- Well, how about that job
I hooked you up with, dude?
- Just leave it, okay?
- Oh, listen, bro,
if you're scared of missing out
on the support group,
I can find something out there
that would--
Hey, man! Yo, whoa, bro.
Whoa, whoa, man.
Yo, hey, take it easy.
Take it easy, man.
- I don't want to talk
about it, all right?
♪
- Ronnie, you high right now?
Always on my case,
man, always.
- Stop, stop, stop the car--
stop the car, man.
- Stop?
How fast you want to stop?
- Ronnie, Ronnie,
to pull the car over now.
- Want to stop the car?
You want to stop the car
so bad?
Let's stop the car.
Casey, let's stop the car!
How much you want to stop?
- Ronnie, stop!
- Hey, baby, I was just
thinking about you,
so I made us a reservation
for tonight,
somewhere, uh, cozy
and a little sexy.
- Max.
- Uh, text me when you wake up.
Love ya.
- I cut you off at "sexy"?
- Sure did.
- Sorry about that.
I need you to sign off
on transferring
Mr. Hoffstettington
to my floor.
- Mister--
- Hoffstettington,
aka Max Bloomstein,
aka Jiminy Constantinople.
- Right, right, right, right.
Wait, uh, I thought
you already took him?
- No, why would you think that?
- Be--
- Oh.
Damn it.
- He was just here.
- Where could he have gone?
- Uh...
- Max.
♪
Oh, my God.
- What?
- He's climbing.
♪
- Look out.
- Casey, I ate the fries.
I'm wearing
the stupid taco hat.
You're supposed to be
talking to me again,
not sending me to voice mail
every time I call.
Where are you?
Call me back.
♪
.
- Hell, yeah.
♪ Uptown girl
♪ She's been living
in her uptown world ♪
♪ I bet she never had
a backstreet guy ♪
♪ I bet her mama
never told her why ♪
♪ I'm gonna try
for an uptown girl ♪
♪ She's been living
in her white-bread world ♪
- Oh...
so you're the one
hogging the songbook?
- I have so much
to narrow down.
Why? Are you seriously
gonna sing another one?
- Uh, Adele's
"A Million Years Ago,"
but I need to know
what's after that.
- I have to say,
I think this Urgent Medicine,
New Amsterdam team-up thing
is so cool.
I just--I love to see
everyone together.
- No, look, I-I've been trying
to put together
a karaoke night for years--
nothing.
Elizabeth mentions it once,
half the hospital shows up.
It's messed up.
♪
Why--why you looking at me
like that?
♪
- You're definitely
tan dominant,
but there's encroachment
of red and blue in your aura.
- What?
- Your aura is troubled.
I mean, I don't know
about troubled, but...
- What if I could make you
feel better in five minutes?
♪
These are Vaccaria seeds.
You place them
on pressure points
along the earlobes
for ultimate clarity.
All you have to do
is squeeze them.
- Oh, my goodness.
- You try it.
This is insane.
- Right?
- Yeah. Wow.
You ever do this on yourself?
- Sometimes, but for clarity,
my go-to is meditation.
It has to be on the water.
Have you been to the pier
in Long Island City?
- The new one?
No.
- I love it so much.
Sorry. Hold on a sec.
- Yeah.
♪
- You all right?
- Uh, yeah, I'm fine.
- You look like
you could use a drink.
- I don't drink usually.
♪
Excuse me.
- Oh, my God, no way!
That is ridiculous!
- I'm done.
I might be done for good.
Lauren?
- Oh, no, I'm sorry.
Elizabeth, I can't.
I'm dying.
- Oh, no.
Oh, no.
I'm dangerously close
to forgetting my own address.
- I got to call it for,
like, my liver.
- For the livers, everybody.
- Bye, guys.
- Love you, guys.
♪
- Hey!
- Whoa!
- Hello.
♪
- Hey, uh...
Max or--or--or Jiminy
or whatever your real name is,
please, come inside.
- I couldn't do it.
I couldn't--
- That's good.
That's good you couldn't jump.
- You're not hearing me.
No psych ward.
I can't be locked up.
I have to climb.
- Okay, okay, you don't want
to be confined.
I understand that. Just please
give me your real name, okay?
Give me that.
Just give me your first name.
♪
- I have to climb.
- No, no, you don't.
You don't.
You have
a serious injury, okay?
We need to come inside.
- I can't go back.
I won't go back.
- That's fine.
You don't need to go.
Just--just tell me why.
Okay?
Just--just--just tell me why,
and I can try to help you.
- The toilet.
- What--
- Excrement
higher than the rim.
People have weapons.
They hurt you.
- You were in jail.
- I can't go back to Rikers.
- Okay, Gustavo,
you're at New Amsterdam.
You're not in Rikers.
- I will always be at Rikers.
- Wait, wait, wait.
♪
I want you to
give me your hand.
- I can't.
- Yes, you can.
Yes, you can.
Look at me.
Hey.
I'm right here.
- Please, give me your hand.
♪
Out of the way! Iggy!
- Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
I got you, I got you.
Hey, hey,
what were you doing out there?
- I wasn't trying
to kill myself.
I was climbing.
When I climb, I'm at peace.
- I need
a full trauma team now!
- You all waiting
for Dr. Castries?
- Yes, and I'm first.
- Lady, no one is trying
to steal your spot.
- You stole my spot.
- Uh, I just wanted to
quickly thank Mia for her help
with some seeds, but it looks
like she's swamped.
- She's not here.
She hasn't been in all morning.
And she's not picking up
her phone.
- Oh.
♪
.
Very nice.
- Oh, very dignified.
- Ah, yes, champagne.
It's my secret weapon.
Has zero effect on me.
I can drink this entire bottle,
which I will...
- Yes.
- And, uh, still have 100%
mental clarity and judgment.
- Since we're
telling secrets...
- It's not exactly a secret,
but, yeah.
- You're on my vision board.
- I was--
Oh.
- No, I'm--I'm serious.
- Okay.
- I really admire you.
You have it all and
make it look so bloody easy.
Respected,
successful therapist.
- Yeah, well, that's all--
that's very flattering, Trevor.
Thank you.
- No, I mean it.
You--you're the full package,
Dr. Iggy Frome.
- Um...
To, um...
to friendship.
- Yes.
- Okay?
- Friendship.
- Here we go.
- Count me all the way in.
- ♪ All night long
♪
♪ All night long
- Bartender, one extra-chilly
bottle of champagne
for me, please,
and, um, a shot of your choice
for the gentleman
in the green frock over there.
Thank you.
Gladys!
Hi! Oh, my God.
Oh, I love you.
- Oh, I love you, too, Iggy.
- You do?
- Yes.
- Which is why
I'm expressing my concern.
- You are?
- You've had a lot to drink.
- Oh, please.
First of all, champagne
has zero effect on me.
Okay?
Facts.
- This was made in New Jersey.
- Mm-hmm.
The region of Nouvelle Jersey.
It's wonderful,
wonderful new region.
And, secondly, I, uh...
I don't remember
what my second point was
at this very moment, but
that may prove my first point,
because maybe
there never was a second point.
- Okay, are you sure
you know what you're doing?
♪
Hmm?
- Oh, that?
That?
You're concerned about that?
- Yes.
- Why?
For what? What are--
Trev and I are, uh...
We're here with colleagues.
We're all here
having work drinks together.
What are you--
we're rocking some 'raoke.
And Martin, uh,
I would've invited him along,
but he wanted
to stay home tonight.
He wanted a night in.
- So you didn't invite him?
- No, I didn't invite him,
okay?
Because he literally said,
"I would prefer
to stay home tonight."
All right, would I have even
considered inviting him
if I was hiding something?
Come on.
- Uh, no more alcohol for you.
- Gladys, no, Gladys.
- Hey.
- You are--hey, hey.
You are harshing my vibe.
You're killing my vibe.
- Your vibe has had two bottles
of very off-brand champagne.
- It's not that off-brand,
and I like it.
- Bartender,
cut off for the night.
- No, no.
I'm not.
- Thank you.
- That's ridiculous.
I'm not. I'm not.
- He's done.
- I'm not--That's not my mom.
- ♪ All night long
♪
♪ All night long
- Oh, my God!
That's ridiculous!
- Where are we going next?
No, look, I'm done.
I might be done for good.
Lauren?
- No, Elizabeth.
No, I'm dying. I can't.
I can't. I got to go.
- I'm dangerously close
to forgetting my own address.
- I got to call it
for, like, my liver.
- The livers--for the livers!
- See ya later.
Bye, guys.
- Love you.
- See ya.
- Whoo!
Oh, what a night.
What a night.
- I didn't want that to end.
Yeah, well, you know,
all good things, right?
- Yeah.
- So till tomorrow.
- Till tomorrow, yeah.
- I'm down here,
the uptown six.
- I'm six, downtown.
- Same station.
- Different directions.
Yeah.
- We're walking this way,
so we can just
keep walking this way.
- I mean, look-it,
we're already--
- We're doing it.
- Hey!
- Whoa! Hello.
- Watch it, lady. Damn.
- That lady is
either incredibly drunk
or just learning
how to ride a bicycle.
- Or both of those things.
- Oh, my gosh.
I don't remember the last time
I was out this late.
- Oh, really?
- What time is it?
- I love the city at night.
- I do, too, but,
you know, it's been a while.
Believe it or not, there was
a time when, uh, yours truly
took in more than
his share of sunsets--
sunrises, I mean.
- Oh, really?
A bit of a party boy.
No, no.
- Yeah.
- No, not me.
No, I was a--I was a good boy,
but I did get around, you know?
Burned a hole in my Eurail pass
after college--
just go to a new city.
- Yeah.
And I would just walk
into the night, you know?
- Nice.
- I'd get lost.
And I would just
meet these people.
- Nice.
- It was great.
It's not as great as you think.
- What, getting lost?
- No, I love that part.
- My, uh...
my life.
It's not as great as you think.
The domestic parts,
they just--they just take over,
and Mark and I rarely
go out anymore, if ever.
The kids are just full--
full-time, man, you know?
They're amazing.
But spontaneity is
just out of the question.
Even our responsibilities
have responsibilities.
I love so much of it, you know?
But I'd be lying if, um,
I didn't say
that there are moments
where I feel like
I'm missing something.
- Spontaneity.
- Yeah.
Spontaneity feels like
a thing of the past.
- Well, there's only one way
to find out.
♪
- He climbed up five flights
outside the building?
- Yep.
- Looks like we're clear
of adhesions to the pancreas.
- Hmm, good to go.
- All right, suction.
I heard Lyn
started back up today.
- Yeah, just part-time--I'm
sure she'll ignore that part.
Also, I was offered
a chief of surgery position.
- Claude, that's fantastic.
- Beaumont Medical
in Denver.
♪
- So...
- Yeah, we're moving
to Colorado.
♪
- They're very lucky
to have you.
- Thank you, Floyd. Thank you.
- Yeah.
- Suction.
BP's dropping.
- We got a bleeder.
- Lap pad.
- Oh, there you are.
- Ah, uh...
- I need you to sign off
on Julio Rilian Humperdink,
or whoever, ten minutes ago.
- Right, yeah.
Sorry, that's my fault.
I've been avoiding my office
all day.
- That have anything to do with
yesterday's trip to Tipsy Town?
- Um, yes, Gladys, it does.
You were right.
I was making a fool of myself.
- We're all entitled
to one of those--you're fine.
Nothing you did at the bar
was beyond the pale.
- Yeah, it's what happened
after the bar
that I'm worried about.
What?
What is this?
What's happening?
- We're backed up.
We've been scrambling
without Trevor.
- Where, uh--where is Trevor?
- No idea.
Didn't come in today.
- Uh-huh.
- What happened
after you left the bar?
♪
.
- ♪ Now, baby
♪ So don't complain
or drive me ♪
♪ Drive me insane
♪ Baby
- Mm...
- ♪ I don't
♪
♪ Spend you around
♪ Baby, tell me what
- Ouch.
- ♪ and I'll tell you
what I want ♪
- Yeah.
- ♪ Girl, you came,
so don't complain ♪
♪ Just tell me
♪ Come on, get up
- ♪ Come on, get up
♪ Just get on down,
just turn it up ♪
♪ Spin it around
- ♪ Get on down,
and let's get up ♪
♪ Now, baby
♪ So don't complain
or drive me ♪
♪ Drive me insane
♪
♪ Baby, I'm down
♪ Just spin me around
- Mm-mm.
- ♪ And I'll surely be found
♪ I said I'm up and I'm down
♪ So spin me around
- Okay.
- ♪ Get on down,
come on, get up ♪
♪ Just get on down
- You--
- ♪ Spin it around
♪ Get on down
- Oh, my God!
No, that's ridiculous!
- Where we going next?
Oh, I might be--
I'm done.
I might be done for good.
Lauren?
- Oh, no, I'm sorry, Elizabeth.
I'm dying. I can't.
- I can barely remember
my own address at this point.
- I'm gonna call
for, like, my liver.
- For the livers, everybody.
- Bye, guys.
- Good night, everybody.
- See ya.
♪
- What an awesome night.
Gladys cannot sing,
but she puts on quite the show.
- And you are awfully quiet.
- Well, it could be the
singing or the drinking
or the fact that I just really
want to get you home.
- Oh, fair enough.
Well, here I am.
- Wow.
- Whoo!
- My goodness.
- I had no idea.
- Yes.
Is Luna home with the sitter?
'Cause I really want to
wake her up with some kisses.
- Yeah. No, she's with
Gwen and Calvin this weekend.
- Oh.
I really miss my little girl.
- She misses you.
- Well, maybe we can drive up
and see her?
- Yeah.
Yeah, we should.
What?
- Sure you're okay?
- I'm good.
- Yeah?
- Why do you keep asking me?
Mm.
Mm-hmm.
Mm, mm, mm.
-  Wow.
- You all right?
- Mm.
It's just been
a really long night.
- Well, booze and jet lag
and...
That fourth shot
really didn't help.
- I should get you to bed.
- Bed.
- Mm-hmm.
- Yeah.
- Sleep.
- Mm-hmm.
- No.
- No?
- 'Cause I've waited
for tonight for a long time,
and I'm not giving up now.
So I'm gonna go in there
and get ready.
And you're gonna come
join me in there.
- Be right there.
Just be a minute.
Okay.
Do you want to--
do you want to--
Do you want to get married?
I think we should get married.
Do you want to get married,
because I--obviously I do,
'cause I got the ring
and everything,
and I was just wondering
if you did,
'cause if you did, I would.
Pop it out. Don't catch it.
That's stupid.
Just open the frickin' thing.
There you go.
But don't--What is that?
Slow is nice.
Can't even
open the thing--idiot.
Just ask her.
Simple.
I--
Will you marry me?
♪
Surgery went well.
You know, you can tell me
your real name if you want.
Secret's safe with me.
Uh, so how long was
your sentence at Rikers?
- 90 days...
For writing one bad check.
But COVID slowed my trial down,
and I couldn't make bail.
I was in Rikers for six months.
- Wow.
- And I kept thinking
someone would try
to come and get me.
This can't be right.
- Then you get out,
and you start thinking
any second someone's gonna
come and take you back.
♪
- I keep hearing voices
in my head
saying, "You're trapped.
You're trapped."
And when the voices get loud...
I have to climb.
♪
It's the only thing
that makes the voice stop.
♪
Here, I want you
to do me a favor.
Take a picture.
Don't think about it too much.
Just pick anything in the room
and snap an absolutely
incredible photo.
Just do it--
simple assignment.
♪
- Like this?
- You tell me.
Is that the best photo
you can take of that window?
Is the lighting good?
Is the framing good?
- I mean, it's dark in here.
- All right, well,
I think we can handle that.
♪
Let there be light.
All right, then you go ahead
and you mess with
all the setting on there, okay?
Go on.
Do your thing.
♪
The thing about climbing--the
only thing you can think about
is where your hand goes next,
where your foot goes next.
That's it.
If you don't, you fall.
It doesn't allow you
to think about the past
or anything else, really.
- Yeah.
- Don't look at me.
Focus, you know.
Literally, look.
Your background's
getting all wacky.
- The light's too high.
All right, well, fiddle with
the lighting settings in there.
That's on you, man.
♪
- Like this?
- It's your picture.
♪
Not too bad.
Actually, that's really nice.
- Thanks.
- Yeah.
So, tell me, at what point
during that process
did the voices
stop bothering you?
♪
- How...
how did that happen?
- Well, trauma
locks you in the past.
Climbing keeps you
in the present.
That--that's not the only thing
that can do that, though.
That camera,
it doesn't see the past
or the future or anything.
It just--it just sees
what's right in front of it,
right here, right now.
What do you see?
♪
Maybe you even see a way out?
Not literally.
That window is locked.
- So, you know...
♪
- Gustavo Moro.
- It's a pleasure to meet you,
Gustavo Moro.
♪
- Well, just call me
when you know.
♪
Why are you in a plant?
- I dropped something.
- Was it your taco hat?
- Yes.
Found it.
- Okay.
Good.
- I'm trying to give you space.
I really want
to give you that...
even if it means
hiding in a plant, so...
- Thank you.
♪
- You okay?
- There's a problem
with my visa.
- What kind of problem?
♪
- I think I'm being deported.
- Hey.
-  So nice seeing you
around here again.
-  Floyd, I need to--
- It's all good.
Claude already told me
about Colorado.
- He did?
- Yes, and...
You know, I'm happy for you,
for both of you.
You know, you deserve
a fresh start together and--
- Stop, stop.
- What?
- The baby is yours.
♪
- You okay?
- No, I'm not.
I'm getting hit from, like, a
thousand different directions.
- What's going on?
- Well, for one thing,
Casey never showed up today.
He's not answering his phone.
- Well, they were
both drinking.
- Who's they?
- Wilder.
She never showed up either.
Hey, have you heard
from Elizabeth?
- Uh, or Casey?
- Uh, no, why?
- Neither of them came in.
- That's weird.
Mia didn't either.
- Hey, I got your page.
What's going on?
- Half our karaoke party
is missing.
No Casey, Elizabeth, Mia.
- No Trevor.
- All right, well,
this can't be a coincidence.
- Did--did anyone speak
to any of them today?
- No, and I've left Trevor
a ton of messages.
- Okay, we were all
in the bar last night.
Why is it just
those four missing?
♪
It's not just four.