The Phoenix Suns.
- Is that a crime?
- You root for the Phoenix Suns?
- I paid attention to basketball there.
- You grew up in Chicago.
- I dated a guy with tickets.
- You didn't pay attention to the Bulls?
- Whatever. I'm starving.
Big Diamondbacks
fan too, aren't you?
- I'm gonna get breakfast out of this deal.
- Sorry. My manners.
- Roach coach?
- You live in a mansion...
- you're buying me a doughnut?
- I'll spring for the coffee too.
Hey there, big spender.
Hello. JACK: John, it's Dad.
- Hey. How was your flight?
- How's Gamma doing?
Yeah. No, she was walking
around a little bit yesterday.
- Great.
- I meet her for lunch.
- You wanna hook up there?
- You're getting me a yogurt too.
What's that? Grab me a bagel.
- For the holiday.
- Really.
- No, that's great.
- See you at the house.
- Yeah, okay. I'll see you there.
- Bye.
- They're staying for the holidays.
- Your parents?
First time in nine years.
- Just like sex, isn't it, Peter?
- What?
Vascular surgery. Messy, fun, and
when done right, you leave satisfied.
D5 half-normal, 125 cc's per hour.
- Surgery.
- Real good hands in there, Peter.
- Thank you.
Which is why you get to assist
me in the Millburn surgery.
Fifth District alderman wants
his cardiac bypass done here.
Why?
The correct response is,
"Thanks, Dr. Romano. I'm honored."
- I am...
- Clear his calendar for Monday afternoon.
- I need to talk.
- He's on trauma call in the ER.
Dump that on Corday. She
actually likes it down there.
- I have a situation with my son.
- What else is new?
- I need more flexible hours.
- In by 12, out by 4...
- we all make the evening news.
- I'm not just talking about this surgery.
If you're not interested, Peter, pass.
I've got 20 guys who'd kill for this gig.
- I didn't say I wasn't interested...
- So are you in or out?
- I'm in.
- Did I ever tell you you're my hero?
Ho, ho, ho, merry
Christmas! Ho, ho, ho.
- Feed the poor? Feed the poor?
- Sorry.
- Hey, feed the poor?
Come on. You think it's easy being
a female Santa in a man's world?
Sorry, no soliciting. You
have to leave the premises.
- I work for the Salvation Army.
- Oh, do you? Let me see your ID.
- Okay, I eat at the Salvation Army.
- Get out of here. Hey!
I'm gonna call the cops.
Stop ringing that damn bell!
- Luka, you're late.
- Sorry.
Don't be sorry, be punctual. This
is a hospital, not a department store.
- When's she on Christmas vacation?
- Scrooge? Never.
- Merry Christmas. County.
- I think she thinks you were shopping.
Shopping for what?
It's a joke.
What's going on?
I went to the bar. No
one's heard anything.
- About Nicole?
- Yeah.
They said she took
money there too.
Guess you were right.
She lied about everything.
Hey, Abby. Can you run
Cynthia Cohen's sputum?
I got a couple of kids with
snow-related injuries! Quiet!
- Freak, freak, freak, freak...
- Hey! Shut up! Both of you, shut up!
Be glad you're not sleeping in
a grate or eating out of the trash!
Nyah!
- Haleh, get them out of here.
- Stop!
- You, this side. You, over here.
- Freak, freak, freak, freak...
Since when did Fire and Rescue start
transporting pediatric walk-in cases?
Since these two took
headers out by the firehouse.
- You notify the parents?
- Yeah, I left word.
- Hey, you didn't call.
- Sorry?
About getting together.
You change your mind?
- No, I was just...
- Dr. Weaver, Exam 1 has chest pains.
- Be right there.
- Dynamic changes on the EKG.
I'll let you get
back to work, okay?
Three nitro sprays and
titrate six of morphine.
Cops found him wandering around O'Hare
with a suitcase but no ticket and no ID.
He fell on the escalator
trying to get away.
I'm missing my flight.
Lacerations down to the galea.
I go home for Christmas
every year, I think.
- Looks intact. No sign of fracture.
- Which doesn't explain the amnesia.
Doesn't know who he
is, where he's going.
I know there's
lots of kids around.
And the women make
a wonderful supper.
Blood supply looks good.
Well, Plastics should be
able to tack it back down.
We still need to get a head CT.
Boys and the men, they settle
around the TV watching sports.
You think his memory
loss is temporary?
Peter?
He's 4 years old.
And deaf and traumatized
by the death of his mother.
- I emphasized all of that. Thank you.
- Well, then appeal it.
- I can't.
- What am I paying you for?
He denied the motion,
Peter. It's not irreparable.
The hell it isn't. He's asking my son
to decide which of us loves him more?
It won't be that specific.
Will he ask who makes
better macaroni and cheese?
Judge Alter has feels that interviewing
Reece will provide relevant insight.
Reece knows what's
going on. He can sense it.
How much more damage
do you want to inflict on him?
Hey, I agreed to represent you.
You're the one who's choosing to fight.
You can preempt this. His
attorney approached me yesterday.
No.
They'll make a revised
visitation request.
I said, no.
And I need to be honest.
We don't have the edge here. On paper,
Roger comes across as the better father.
If I were his attorney, I would
advise him to give you no more deals.
Yet you're advising
me to accept one?
I am advising you to
at least listen to one.
- You're still here.
- I was on my way out.
- Keep those kids from killing each other?
- Yeah. One has a corneal abrasion...
the other has a strained
wrist. Look, hey...
- I'm not very good at this.
- What, follow-up?
Want to have lunch tomorrow?
- No sushi.
- What?
- I don't like sushi.
- Okay. Anything you want.
I'm gonna remember
you said that.
Why is he here? Somebody
finally kick his butt?
- Who?
- Mr. Karaoke over there.
How about a little "Jingle Bell Rock"?
- You know him?
Oh, yeah, Stan? He lives behind a
dumpster on 57th and Dorchester.
- He's homeless? LOPEZ:
Unless you count the dumpster.
Hello. STAN: Hello.
- Where you going?
- Whatever that lady said, it's not true.
- Your name isn't Stan?
- No, no, no.
- You don't live at 57th and Dorchester?
- I don't remember. That's why I'm here.
Mm-hm.
This Stan character sounds
rough. Bet he's got a record.
- I wouldn't be surprised.
- And no family to speak of.
- No place to spend the holidays.
- You know, if he was smart...
he'd clean himself up, get
himself a suit at the Goodwill...
And go to the airport.
You mind if I stay a while?
It's kind of Christmassy here.
The alderman thinks you're such a
brilliant surgeon, then you operate.
- Where are they?
- I don't know.
Hey. What's going on?
- Waiting for Roger and his lawyer.
- I thought we were seeing the judge.
- We're hoping that won't be necessary.
- Peter, what's going on?
- They wanna talk about some deal.
- Sorry we're late. We ran into traffic.
We don't have a lot of
time. What have you got?
Visitation every other weekend,
plus two weeks during the summer.
- One week during the summer.
- No.
- We only ask for 38 days.
- 31 days.
- I said, no.
- Peter, it's only 31 days.
- I'm not doing this.
- Peter, listen to me.
No. You listen to me, all of you.
I'm not negotiating over my son.
Rather take your
chances with the judge?
A martini in first class works
just as well and takes less time.
Like you, I enjoy the occasional
drive. Gives you time to clear your head.
- Hey, Dad.
- John.
Did you know your father's
been here since last night?
Late last night. He
went straight to the hotel.
- Oh, God. Am I dying?
- Rigor mortis hasn't set in just yet.
Why else would my son deign
to spend Christmas with us?
Mom's coming too.
- I knew there was a catch.
- Eleanor will be here later this week.
- You'll stay at the house until then?
- Sure, why not.
Wonderful. Here's Helga
to turn me like a pancake.
- We'll give you some privacy.
- I'd settle for a little dignity.
Believe it or not, she's thrilled.
This means the world to her.
- This year more than most.
- Well, I suppose.
Means a lot to me too.
Yeah. It should be fun, huh?
Reece, I have to
make a decision.
I need you to help me by
answering some questions.
Can you do that?
Okay...
Who's that?
Daddy.
And who's that?
My other daddy.
You love both your
daddies very much, right?
He says he doesn't know.
When you are sick, who
makes you feel better?
Mommy.
Which daddy gives you the best
care when you get a boo-boo?
He has Band-Aids with cartoons.
Right now, I'd say
he needs consistency.
Reece, Carla and I. The
three of us were a family.
That's how we planned our lives.
That's how we approached
every day, every week.
I've been with Reece
through earaches...
flus, almost every
scrape he's ever gotten.
If you count the hours that
I've spent with my stepson...
it far exceeds the time Dr. Benton has
spent with the child he believed to be his.
Reece and Carla were my life.
And now Reece is my life.
He comes first.
Ahead of my personal
needs, ahead of my job.
And I think that's
in his best interest.
- Oh, John. Diverse selection.
- Burgers are good.
You already know what you want?
I'm still working on what to drink.
This is nice. Haven't
done this for a while.
Had lunch together?
Or Christmas?
Both.
So...
What kind of business keeps
Mom in Costa Rica in December?
How's the chopped salad?
She broke her hip, Dad. Mom
can't spend five minutes with her?
Is she gonna avoid
her for the whole month?
Your mother's not coming.
John, we're getting divorced.
- What? Divorced?
- It's amicable.
After 30 years?
- What happened?
- This probably isn't the best...
- Is there somebody else?
- Neither of us is running off with anyone.
What is it, she's not happy? She's
bored? Wants to stay in Europe?
I'm the one who's leaving, John.
This can't surprise you.
You saw it before I did.
- Can I take your order?
- I was suffocating. I think we're ready.
Chopped salad, please.
Burger medium-rare, please.
I agree that consistency is the
best thing for Reece right now.
See, I...
I let Carla take on a lot of the
parenting while I pursued my career.
But I did that because it felt right
to leave Reece in his mother's care.
But all that's changed now.
And my responsibilities
have changed too.
Because of that I've made
arrangements to work fewer hours...
so I can become
Reece's full-time caretaker.
- At County General?
- Yes, sir.
What sort of hour reduction
are we talking about?
7 a.m. to 5 p.m.
weekdays, weekends off.
You can provide proof
of this new schedule?
Yes, sir. Yes, I can.
Have it in my
office by day's end.
Unless there is anything
else, court's adjourned.
I need to talk to him
now. Well, pull him out.
Fine. Let him know
I'm on my way.
- Going back to work?
- Get out of my way.
- Got another shift?
- Roger, get out of my way!
Where's Reece? Let me guess:
Jackie. No, Cleo. A nanny?
- You want me to hit your car?
- You lied, man.
On top of everything else,
you're a liar. And a perjurer.
You know what?
You need to back off.
Whatever it takes, is that
it? He's not a trophy, man!
You can't win at any cost
to give your sister a son!
- You gotta raise him!
- You know...
Go ahead, get in
my face. Come on.
- Roger, you need to shut your mouth.
- Think, Peter.
You can't change who you are.
I'm sure it was on this block. It's
called Nazim. It's got a blue awning.
- Well, I don't see it.
- We must have missed it.
- I don't like Indian food anyway.
- Why didn't you say something?
- I just did.
- Why don't we go to that Italian place...
- across the street. Great risotto.
- Wait a minute.
- That'd be great if it weren't closed.
- You're a pain in the ass, you know that?
- Well, some say.
- I'm starting to regret this whole thing.
- Too bad. I'm starving.
- Forget about looking for a decent place.
- Why don't we go home and order in.
- I like a take-charge kind of girl.
- My apartment?
- Lead the way.
- Dr. Romano.
- You hear something?
- I need to talk to you.
- That's a doctor who breaks promises...
then hangs up on the guy
he breaks the promises with.
- I need to talk to you now.
- Talk is cheap, Peter.
I need to scale back my
hours and I need it in writing.
- "To whom it may concern: No way."
- I'm serious.
- Is this about your kid?
- Yeah.
What do you need?
Every other Saturday?
No nights. No weekends.
Good one. I like the one
about the rabbi and the goldfish.
- I need to spend more time at home.
- Never needed to before.
- His mother died.
- His stepfather is still alive.
Split custody, keep
doing what you do best.
I'm not asking for your advice.
News flash! This is
an urban trauma center.
Until people plan their MVAs and
GSWs better, you won't punch a time clock.
That's not me being a hard-ass,
that's the job. You are a surgeon.
- Are you gonna do this for me or not?
- Not. Work when I need you or not at all.
Then consider
this my resignation.
All right, all right, all right.
Don't go getting dramatic.
- Weekends off.
- And what about weekdays?
It's my best offer,
Peter. Take it or leave it.
I'll finish out the week.
Are you really gonna do this?
Throw your career to play Mr. Mom?
What a waste!
- Hi. Newborn for the nursery.
- Hey.
- Birth in the ER?
- Marshall Field's.
Mother was last-minute
shopping. She's on her way up.
- The paramedics delivered?
- No, a shoe salesman.
Wow.
- Room 424, do you have a chart?
- Was she an ER patient?
I just have to follow
up on something.
- How far along was she?
- Eight weeks. No complications.
- She's in Recovery for a few more hours.
- Thanks.
- Dr. Finch, please.
- I'm not sure she's here. Let me check.
All right, thanks.
- What are you doing here?
- I need to meet the Surgicenter director.
- You gave him my CV, right?
- Yeah, but...
- I quit County.
- Romano wouldn't give you the hours?
You said there's a
position here. I want it.
- I'll introduce you tomorrow.
- I gotta show proof of employment now.
- Peter, he's probably gone for the day.
- Check, please.
- I just started, he barely knows me.
- Cleo, I need to talk to him.
- Hi. I thought you left.
- Tonight.
Luka has been looking for
you. Could you wait, please?
- Do you need something?
- You told him you weren't pregnant.
- I'm not.
- I don't understand.
You don't need to.
- Look, I'm sorry. I was wrong.
- No, you were right.
He did everything he could. I thought
his kindness was love. But it's not.
Abby, he deserves not to know.
Thanks.
Tuesday's impossible. He's
got colorectal procedures then.
Fissurectomy at 7.
Hemorrhoidectomy at 8. Another at 9.
And it looks like he's squeezed
in an inguinal hernia too.
- Maybe for lunch?
- No, he's got a lunch date.
- After that?
- After that, he sees patients until 5.
- How about Thursday?
- Thursday might work, actually.
Judge Alter! Judge Alter!
I got that employment
letter for you.
- I wanted this yesterday.
- I know. It came in after-hours.
- This is not your hospital.
- No.
- Schaumburg Surgicenter?
- I worked out a better situation there.
- All in the last 12 hours?
- It was always a possibility.
- It just needed to be ironed out.
- You didn't mention it yesterday.
I know. I said I'd cut
back my hours and I did.
- True.
- I'm now working 8 to 5, no weekends.
- This letter confirms it.
- That may be so.
But you told a different story
yesterday. And I don't like being lied to.
I'm doing what I
have to do for my son.
Hey, Elizabeth.
You sneaking coffee?
Tea. You look nice.
Are you going on a date?
No. Court date.
- Right. What's the latest?
- It's out of my hands now.
- It's best to keep busy while you wait.
- I owe a lot of hours before I go.
- Before you go?
- Yeah. End of the week, I'm out of here.
- What?
- Yeah, I had to quit.
- You're not serious.
- I need to change my life.
Romano won't cut me any slack.
Yeah, but I'm sure he'll
make some accommodation.
No. I asked. He won't.
You'd really leave County?
I gotta go.
How'd he fall?
Hanging lights on the house.
Parents are signing him in.
- What do we got?
- Fell from a ladder.
- Parents are here.
- Is he okay?
- Has he been unconscious?
- His sister put the hose on him.
- He woke up for a second.
- Did he hit anything?
- A bike. CARTER: I
got involuntary guarding.
He's waking up. That's good, yes?
- Coming through.
- What do we have?
- Possible liver or splenic lac.
- Stable, but might need to go to the O.R.
- HemoCue?
- Second is eight from 10.
- Does your belly hurt?
All right. He's stable
for CT. Control the pain.
- Watch him overnight.
- He has free fluid by ultrasound.
I won't remove the
spleen before we have to.
- Remove?
- He can still live without one.
- I can give him mine.
- That's not necessary.
- Someone'll match.
- We don't transplant spleens.
I'll show you where the waiting room is.
- We can at least give blood.
She's going down. JOE: Amparo!
Ma'am, you okay?
- Have you fainted before?
- Never.
How do you serve
Christmas dinner for them?
Start cooking early. No problem.
O.R.'s got elective cases they
can push. How's she doing?
- Please, I'm fine. Tell me about Ben.
- Blood counts are stable. Good.
His first CT only
shows a small injury.
His school band plays in a
concert on New Year's Eve.
I don't want him to miss it.
- How long have you had this node?
- I don't know.
Is this tender?
You don't have to
examine me or run tests.
I know I'm sick.
Have you been
diagnosed with something?
Lymphoma.
I'm sorry.
- Don't tell them, though.
- Your family doesn't know?
There will be plenty of
time to talk after Christmas.
Dr. Benton? Janice Prager called.
She wants you to meet her in court.
- Go. I'll get another surgeon.
- Your son will be fine.
Good.
- They got me right in the store.
- It's tough to hide two pairs of skates.
- The guard jumped me in front of my kids.
- Can we keep the ice skates?
No.
They hate getting used
stuff. I thought for Christmas...
They wanna take you
to the station house.
I know.
Do you have someone
to stay with them?
Their mother?
I'll be right back. Abby?
- Are you gonna be in jail for Christmas?
- I don't know.
Maybe I should
post bail for him.
They have no money. Do you know
where they've been living? In a motel room.
- Probably can't pay a security deposit.
- No, he has a job. But it's $5.15 an hour.
He has to steal to get his kids
a decent Christmas present.
- Could call the food bank.
- No, they help out this time of year.
What happens to
them in three months?
There's only so much you can do.
Yeah, I guess.
I just...
Miss your kids?
Yeah.
Sorry.
It's worse at Christmas.
Oh, right.
- Where's the judge?
- In chambers.
- Gentlemen, your counsel with you?
- They're on the way.
While we wait for Ms.
Prager and Mr. Wharton...
I was wondering if I could
talk with Reece once more.
- Only if you both agree, of course.
- Sure.
- I don't see why not.
- Thank you.
Nancy, will you ask
him to come with me?
It's okay.
Go on.
It's okay. Go, go.
Just Reece this time.
He'll have exploratory surgery.
They'll repair any injuries he might have.
- He'll be home for the holidays?
- Wait and see how he does.
So we celebrate a day or two late.
It doesn't matter. Thank you, doctor!
- Did you get him upstairs?
- Along with his parents, aunts, cousins...
Hope they all fit
in the waiting room.
You ready for this?
God. I forgot. I mean, I didn't
forget. It's at home, yours.
I don't know where
my head is at, though.
Do you wanna open it anyway?
- Can we wait?
- Sure.
Sorry.
Is something wrong?
- I'm having family problems.
- Your grandma?
No, no. It's my mother.
She's not coming home for the
holidays. She and my father are...
splitting up.
- Oh, no.
- I don't think it's sunk in yet.
- Maybe it's a blessing in disguise.
- How do you figure?
- Did you ever meet my parents?
- I met Cookie.
Right. She and Henry aren't
divorced, and they should be.
- Still, I'm sorry.
- Thanks.
I'm so self-centered. I thought
it was something to do with me.
No. You're about the only
thing going right in my life.
- You shouldn't let this happen.
- Didn't want to be defensive.
- What did he think of your new job?
- He wasn't overly impressed.
There you are.
Thank you for all rushing over.
Be seated.
We are in a unique situation.
In a traditional custody
case, win or lose...
the parents maintain...
the title given to
them by their biology.
They're still Mommy and Daddy.
Here I'm asked to declare that one
of these two men is not, in fact, Daddy.
But they both love Reece and
have made sacrifices to be with him...
though I will say Dr. Benton's
effort was late in the game.
And I am uncomfortable
about the way he handled it.
Not convinced he was
exactly forthright with the court.
But the fact is that I do believe Reece
would thrive in either of your households.
And that makes my
decision even harder.
But based on the evidence
provided by Dr. Benton...
that he will be more available
as a parent in the future...
and the fact that Reece has
always believed him to be his father...
the court grants
custody to Peter Benton.
Mr. McGrath will be given visitation
with Reece every other Saturday.
The court calls a
20-minute recess.
We might have to go get one.
- Use the angel.
- No, I always have a star.
Okay, here we go. One, two, three.
- Yay!
Yes, it is pretty.
You finish your part?
Hey, baby. Come here. Come
over here. Come lay under the tree.
- You should get going.
- I got a half an hour.
- Going to be late for your last shift.
- What are they gonna do? Fire me?
- What are we doing?
- It's the best way to look at a tree.
When I was Reece's age,
I used to do this for hours.
- It's beautiful.
- Yeah.
Hey, how long is the
commute to Schaumburg?
- Depends on when you leave.
- I was thinking, if we both work there...
Yeah?
Maybe we should relocate.
We?
Yeah.
This whole thing
has made me focus.
It's like all my life I've
been chasing something.
That time when I can...
make it into the end
zone and spike the ball.
It took almost losing
my son to realize...
the end zone's not out there.
It's right here.
You're good raw material.
I can work with you.
- Oh, you can?
- Yeah. I have to get you in shape.
- What kind of shape?
- Ay-ay-ay.
- Hey, you found it.
- I knew it was in one of those boxes.
Want to put it up
there? All right, come on.
Yay. That's good.
- I'm working New Year's Eve?
- Someone has to.
- Someone else. OLBES:
Six-year-old, GSW.
- Please save him.
- What happened?
.38 caliber, right thorax,
crossed the midline.
- Vitals?
- BP, 70/30. Pulse, 130.
He's so pale.
You his mother? What's his name?
- What's his name?
- Teddy.
Decreased breath sounds. Full
trauma panel. He needs a chest tube.
- It's the two of us.
- How did it happen?
I shot him.
Surgery. Yes, that was
Matt on the pay phone.
Peter.
I guess I should
say congratulations.
Did you really get a new job?
You gonna call me a liar again?
- Here you are, Christmas Eve.
- Yeah, well, it's my last shift.
What's your excuse?
I wanted to give you
Reece's Christmas presents.
You can leave them over there.
- See you in two Saturdays.
- Yeah.
Merry Christmas.
Hey, Roger.
Come over to the house tomorrow
and give them to him yourself.
Thanks.
I'm not doing it for you.
Surgery. Dr. Benton, the ER.
- Sux on board.
- Our tree's by the window.
- 5 1/2 ET tube. PAULA:
There've been many break-ins.
- O-neg's running. Systolic's at 70.
- Call for a vent.
- I was sleeping. I had the flu.
- 10 blade.
- He was supposed to be in bed.
- Long vascular clamp.
He dropped an ornament. I
thought someone was breaking in.
I'm in. Bag him.
- GSW?
- 6-year-old accidentally shot by his mom.
Heart rate's down to 30.
- Lost his pulse. Starting compressions.
- Thoracotomy tray.
- What does that mean?
- We'll open his chest, repair the damage.
- Four more units of blood.
- Scalpel.
- Oh, God! CARTER:
Paula, come with me.
500 cc's out the right side.
- Ready with the rib-spreader.
- Suction on high.
All right. Hang on, hang on.
Crank it now. Come on.
Looks like two liters in there.
- Damn it.
Pericardium's filled
with blood. 15 blade.
Call the O.R. We got a
red blanket. Page Romano.
- Who shoots a 6-year-old?
- Thought he was a burglar.
A burglar shaking presents?
- 10 blade.
- I'll clamshell the chest.
- Sternal saw.
We going through the motions?
BENTON: Knife back. Metz.
Guess we are. BENTON:
Pick-ups. Come on, pick-ups!
Damn it. Here's a
fragment of the slug.
- Looks weird.
- Saw. Let's move.
Black Talon. Fragmenting bullet.
Fragments at the hilum.
Like razor blades all over him.
- That's the point.
Order more FFP? - On its way.
Lost cause. Fragments
in all chambers.
God knows what
hit the great vessels.
Dr. Corday is here.
She'll love being
brought in on this.
What do we have? - Organ donor.
- BP dropping, 60/30.
- Hang two units packed cells.
- He'll go into DIC.
- We'll stay ahead with platelets.
We've got other surgeries.
Looks like a transverse
colon injury and dead bowel.
I'm still in the chest. Repaired
defects to the left ventricle, right hilum.
- Brought your magic wand?
- Help me or get the hell out.
Knock yourself out, Peter.
Either way, you're gone.
We need to rebuild the IVC
from the kidneys caudally.
More 2-0 silk on a Teflon pledget.
Come on. Keep them coming.
Peter. BENTON: We
can do this, all right?
Prep a venous cardiac snare.
Did I kill him?
We don't know
what his chances are.
But he does have the best
surgeons I know working on him.
How could I do this?
You were scared.
- I keep telling God how sorry I am.
- That's all you can do.
I don't even believe in God.
Teddy never gets up from bed.
I just wanted to protect our
home. I never thought he'd...
You want me to
take you to the O.R.?
- Turn off the heat.
- Another Vicryl.
GI stapler. CORDAY: Not
much stool in abdominal.
Good sign. I expected more.
Gut's done. What's the pressure?
80/40. Well, that's something.
Let me get another clip.
- Not much.
Here we go. SMV is done.
Cut.
Shirley, take down the
balloon on the Pruitt.
Here we go. Catheter out.
- Balloon down.
Throw in a good knot,
see if he stops bleeding.
Come on, Teddy.
Come on, man. Come on.
Look at that.
- Yeah.
- That's incredible.
Yeah. Well, all right. Here
we go. Releasing the clamp.
How the hell did you do that?
- I have no idea.
Let's make sure of the count.
Is that the mother? - Yeah.
You go tell her. I'll close up.
- Okay. Thanks, Elizabeth.
- Peter, that was remarkable.
- Little going-away present.
Despite anything Romano may say,
this place is really gonna miss you.
I wish I could say the same.
- Wasn't all that bad.
We had our moments.
Your son lost a lot of blood. However,
we were able to repair the damage.
He's got a long road ahead
of him, but he's gonna make it.
I don't know how to thank you.
Just get the gun
out of your house.
I guess Santa didn't buy
you that bike you asked for.
- Carter, what are you doing here?
- Cleo told me this was on your route.
- Come on. You want to join me?
- No.
If I wanna get my heart rate
up, I'll have another cup of coffee.
Got your message.
Guess there's no way
to talk you out of it, huh?
No. Done deal.
I got you something.
- Carter...
- Open it.
You're a tough guy to shop for.
An El token?
Second week of my surgical
internship we got 11 traumas in one night.
5 a.m., we were still patching together
a girl that had been dragged under a car.
I was so tired I couldn't see straight.
I asked you if I could take a break...
and you kicked
me out of the O.R.
I couldn't drive home, I was
exhausted. I started crying in the hallway.
You came out of surgery
and you gave me that.
You said I could use
it to go home. Or...
I could commit to what I was doing
and use it to come back the next day.
No Rolex, huh?
If you get tired of Schaumburg,
you can use it to come back.
- Carter, they don't use tokens anymore.
- Then call.
And I'll come pick you up.
- Look, I want you to know...
- I know.
That I owe you.
Carter.
Getting cold. I better move on.
- Merry Christmas.
- Same to you.
Hey, Peter.
I'm a good doctor
because of you.
No, you're not.
But keep trying.