♪ Ohhh ohhh ohhh ♪
Did you ever read
"the lady, or the tiger?"
No.
There's a Princess who
falls in love with a guard,
which is, you know,
inappropriate.
So when her father,
the king, finds out,
he throws the guard into
some kind of arena.
Okay.
Behind one door
is a tiger
that'll tear him to bits.
And behind the other
is a lady
with whom he'd be free
to live the rest of his life.
♪ ...Pretend,
I know my faults ♪
The Princess is...
Forced to sit
in the stands
and choose his fate.
What does she choose?
The author never tells you.
What do you think
she chose?
♪ ...can't hide them ♪
Everything looks okay, Jodi.
I thought I should check
when Zach mentioned
you were having some cramping.
Where is Zach?
He's down the hall,
talking to Dr. Wallace.
Who are you?
She lives in a loop.
Some days,
Jodi forgets the question
while she's answering it.
But she does remember
events and people
prior to the car accident,
though, right?
Yes.
Uh, but she can't form
new memories.
Most of the time,
she bears no resemblance
to the woman I married.
I am Dr. Montgomery,
your ob-gyn,
and I'm taking care
of you and your baby.
I'm pregnant?
Mm-hmm.
Oh.
Oh, Zach and I, we've been
trying for so long.
I wish we knew Jodi was
pregnant before the accident
so at least
she could remember that.
♪♪♪
What helps you
get through it?
When I tell her the story
of how we first met...
She--she lights up.
And for a moment,
it's like she's still in there.
Wait.
When did I get pregnant?
Almost nine months ago,
but you keep forgetting
because you had a car accident
eight months ago,
and you got hurt.
You suffered a brain injury.
Who are you?
Some days I wish...
That Jodi had just died
in the accident.
What does that make me?
Human.
How, uh...
How do we have a kid?
I-I don't even really...
Remember you.
We were hammered,
and it was nine years ago.
I mean, you're sure,
he's--he's, uh--
positive.
Uh, yeah, i--
I-I mean, maybe
it could've been--
you might want to rethink
calling the mother
of your child a whore.
No, that's not what I meant.
Okay?
Um...
So why did you... come?
I mean, now.
Mason asks about his dad...
A lot.
And he's older now.
I can't just distract him
and hope he forgets.
I just wish you had called me
when you found out
you were pregnant.
Why, so you could
tell me to take care of it?
No.
Uh, because I wish
I had known sooner.
Well, you know now.
Yeah.
So...
You're a pediatrician.
Yes.
Want to start with a checkup
and go from there?
I... y--
wait. What?
I'm saying, do you want
to meet your son?
I don't need a babysitter.
And I am not here
to babysit you.
Sheldon is taking over
my patients,
and I just need
to update their charts, so--
you can't do that from home?
Why would I do that from home?
Because you don't happen to
work here at the moment.
Pete, I get that you're angry.
I understand that that's
a necessary phase--
oh, do not tell me
how I feel.
Hey, Dr. Turner.
Hey, Jodi.
How's the pregnancy?
What pregnancy?
It was just
a checkup,
but we now know
she's gonna have a boy.
Mm. That's amazing.
Hi, Zach. How are you?
Dr. Turner,
nice to see you.
How are Jodi and the baby?
Everything's great.
They're both on track
for the c-section next week.
Honey, you're--
you're having a baby.
We are?
Oh, my god.
Jodi, look at me.
Okay, do you remember
the first time we met?
You came in
with all your friends.
I was your waiter.
Yeah, that's the way
you smile.
Let's go home. Okay?
Come on.
Zach, you'll call, and we'll
finish our conversation
about how she'll handle
the baby and breast-feeding.
Uh, Dr. Turner, would you take
Jodi to the lobby, please?
Absolutely.
Be right there.
We don't need to talk.
What do you mean?
After Jodi gives birth,
I'm taking the baby.
I'm taking the baby,
and we're leaving her.
Sheldon.
Did you tell Zach
to leave Jodi?
Who are Zach and Jodi?
Jodi is eight and a half months
pregnant, with the worst case
of anterograde amnesia
I've ever seen,
and Zach is her ass of husband
who is waiting for her
to give birth
so he can take the baby
and leave.
What did you say
to my patient?
Wait. You asked Sheldon
to cover your cases.
Doesn't that make Zach
his patient?
Zach made his own decision.
I'm helping him come to terms
with it.
Jodi's very sweet,
but it is kind of like
living with a parrot.
What? It's true.
So she's supposed to just
carry the baby, deliver it,
and then he just gets to
take the kid and go?
That does sound
pretty harsh.
Jodi won't even remember
it's her kid.
That's not gonna
matter to the kid.
Not for a while, anyway.
A child needs a mother
to bond to.
Yeah, but they don't need
to be traumatized.
What about
what a wife needs?
I mean, Zach can't just
abandon her.
People have left for less.
He's--he's just angry.
Just a phase.
She's all alone. He has
an obligation. He married her.
I love you, Addie,
but you're not really gonna
preach about the sanctity
of marriage, are you?
Rude.
What if she had cancer?
You think he'd walk out then?
This is different. Cancer is
often a death sentence.
Zach is living life
without parole.
And there's a third life
to consider here.
Sheldon, in many, many months
of talking to Zach,
he never once said
that he wanted to leave.
But now suddenly,
talking to you--
I'm certain Zach contemplated
leaving long before today.
And I imagine he actually
would've told you
if you hadn't confused
your own convictions
with a patient's needs.
Maybe he's in
an angry phase, too.
Hi, Mason.
I'm Dr. Freedman.
Okay.
I realize I can't compete
with seadra.
You don't know pokemon.
You read it off the card.
Oh. Okay.
Well, cover it.
Hmm. Let's see.
Seadra hp70...
Attacks...
With smokescreen
and razor wing?
Yeah, see?
Stick out your tongue.
Stick it out. Ahh.
Ahh.
Okay.
Mom says it's not allowed.
It is when the doctor asks.
So if the doctor asks me
to say "crap"--
Mason.
I'm just saying.
When was his last exam?
A while ago.
It's expensive
without insurance.
Yeah.
Mason,
I'm just gonna take
a little blood.
Ooh.
Can you, um...
Show me seadra again...
Real quick?
It's gone.
Hmm.
How'd you do that?
Magic?
It didn't even hurt.
Good.
Cool.
So where's my card?
You should check
your pocket, man.
Whoa.
I need you to choose.
Okay.
Yeah, it's bedding.
Bedding?
Yeah.
I mean, there's your bedding,
and there's my bedding,
but I thought
it would be nice
if--if we had
our bedding.
Really?
Yeah. Actually, no.
Uh, our sheets are ratty,
and there was a sale.
But I-I tried to be romantic.
Yes, i-i...
But then you had to come in...
Called you on it.
And call me on it.
Mm-hmm.
And that was uncool,
so just choose.
Fine.
Uh...
Green.
Can't you be a little bit
more enthusiastic about it?
I'm sorry. I just--
would you leave me
the minute I have a baby
if I had a brain injury?
What--what--
what's wrong with your brain?
No, not my brain.
My patient's brain.
I'm fixated.
Wait. Did you just ask me
if I was gonna leave you
when you have your baby?
No, Sam. I'm not talking
about us.
I was--i am...
Worried about my patient.
Okay?
By the way,
I'm not even pregnant, so...
Well, was that
a-a possibility,
you being pregnant?
No. I haven't started yet.
Started...
Fertility drugs.
Right.
Whatever. You know, I wasn't
talking about us, so...
Okay. Okay.
Uh, Addison...
Are you--are you worried,
uh, that I'm gonna leave you--
no. Sam, come on.
I chose. Green.
Get out.
Okay.
Okay, I am gonna
tell you something
that has the potential
to make you angry.
But it--it--it shouldn't.
I mean, I understand
why it could,
but it--it could also
be great, amazing.
And I realize it's gonna
change things--
just say it already.
I have a son.
Mason. He's 8.
Uh...
There was this woman,
and we were together
nine years ago.
And it was--
it was one night, and--
and she got pregnant.
Uh, her name
is Erica Warner.
Y-You were only together
one night,
and you trust this Erica
because...
The minute I saw him,
I knew.
I mean...
He's a mini Cooper.
Did you take
a paternity test?
Uh...
A woman shows up,
tells you you're the father
of her 8-year-old child,
and you just
take her word for it?
Cooper...
You're an idiot.
I married an idiot.
Hey, I was just coming
to talk to you.
And somehow I anticipated that
and decided to leave.
Sheldon,
I resent the implication--
the very public implication--
that I cannot be impartial
with my patients.
I'm sorry.
Thank you.
I am sorry.
That was rude of me.
But since
we're being reasonable,
why don't we discuss
the public implication
that I would assert
to my patient
what he should or shouldn't do
with regard to his marriage?
Fine. I am sorry.
Thank you.
Just one more thing.
Did you even entertain the idea
that Zach could talk to you
about leaving Jodi
because it's easier
for him to talk to a man?
Violet, I don't want
to discuss this with you.
But I knew
Zach and Jodi before.
They--they came to me
for infertility,
which, as you know,
can destroy a couple.
But they never blamed
one another,
the never gave up
on one another.
They were really,
truly in love.
And you never got
to see that.
I read your notes, Violet,
your very sparse notes.
So that's all I had to go on.
I'm updating my notes,
Sheldon.
Well, that's helpful. Late,
but helpful. So thank you.
Well, how the hell was I
supposed to know
you were gonna take over
my patients?
You just gotta
keep on walking, Sheldon.
Excuse me?
Pete--
I'm saying, she's like
a dog with a bone.
She won't stop,
so at some point,
you just gotta keep on walking.
Are you okay?
Uh, he's in anger.
It's a, uh...
It's a necessary phase.
He'll move through it.
It can't be easy,
being the target, though.
I...
Zach's feelings are--
are cyclical, Sheldon.
He does not want to leave.
Violet...
Perhaps I wasn't clear.
As long as your license
is suspended,
Zach is not your patient.
He's mine.
Yeah, right.
Yeah.
So imagine
this scenario--
a woman shows up
out of nowhere
and tells a guy that
he's got an 8-year-old son.
Ooh.
When Jodi goes into labor,
what risk does her
brain injury pose?
Mm. Fluid may build up
during delivery,
increasing the pressure
in her brain.
If you're asking, I should
be in there with you.
What--Cooper has a kid?
What?
No.
How'd you find out?
Sam texted me.
Mine's from Sheldon.
Cooper and his big mouth.
Oh, my god.
Did you hear?
Yeah.
Oh, Cooper's gonna be
a great dad.
That is a stupid thing
to say.
Mason is this kid's name,
and, you know, she says
that he wanted
to meet his, uh... me.
I'm supposed to believe he's
the only one she slept with?
So how's that gonna work?
She probably just
looked up the guy she screwed,
saw that Cooper was a doctor,
and bingo--names him daddy.
Cooper's a sucker.
Would it really kill you
to be its other mommy?
Might kill the kid.
Everybody just
slow the hell down.
We don't even really know
if this is Cooper's child.
Paternity test.
Okay?
Oh, I know, but, you guys,
this kid--
he's got my hair,
he's got my eyes,
he's got my sense of humor.
It's--
you really think
she'd lie to him?
Yeah,
she'd lie to him.
And the other thing is...
She never forgot my name.
We did it once, nine years ago,
back of her car.
Once, and she remembers me.
That's gotta say something.
I'm just saying.
What?
Everything okay?
It's great.
Everything's great.
Uh, I know it's none of
my business, but...
I get it.
There's this kid
that you wish would disappear,
and that makes you feel guilty,
and worse, he could end up
being a part of your life
even though he's not yours
and you didn't ask for him.
You do have a choice,
you know?
I made my choice, Sam,
months ago.
I chose Cooper.
That means
taking whatever comes
together...
Unfortunately.
♪ is it really
that much sweeter ♪
♪ on the other end ♪
So what is he like?
He's, like, nerdy but cool,
and he's smart, cute,
fresh-mouthed.
He's basically me.
You do not have to worry
about me.
You seem so excited,
and if you--if you took
the paternity test,
then you would know.
So why don't you
just take it?
I have no blood relatives.
And... for the first time
in my life,
I look at Mason, I see...
My hair, my eyes.
I look at Mason,
I see my biological son.
I get it.
I know blood doesn't matter.
I mean, I have
an amazing family.
♪ Well, I ain't that... ♪
But...
♪ Special someone ♪
You need to think he's yours
just a little while longer
just in case he's not.
♪ Someone who makes two
become one ♪
♪ I'm already yours ♪
And I know
it's only been three days--
almost three days--
but it's three days sober,
which is a start, right?
Right.
Okay.
What's going on?
What?
You're keeping a secret,
aren't you?
We all download to you,
but just once, you need
to let it out, don't you?
I want to strangle Violet.
Well, you better hurry
before Pete does it.
Sorry. Continue.
She can't stop micromanaging
and--and telling me
how to treat Zach
and--and prodding me
for details of the case.
Well, have you told her
to back off?
Yes.
And did she back off?
Yeah.
So what's the problem?
She's Violet.
She's not done.
♪ Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ oh ♪
♪ la, la, la, la ♪
Really?
Oh, shut up.
No, I mean, you're a surgeon?
People let you cut them open?
Fine.
You try it.
What's so funny?
Let's see. Time of death--
all right. Go. Thank you.
Oh.
Oh, don't look at me
like that.
We were just...
Forget it.
So I'm about to overstep.
You think I'm crazy
for trying to compartmentalize
having a baby
and a relationship with Sam.
N-No. I wanted to talk
about Zach and Jodi.
Oh.
So Zach is making
a mistake,
and I would tell him that
if the law didn't prohibit me
from speaking to him,
and Sheldon's not gonna tell him
that he's doing anything wrong.
Oh. You want me...
To convince Zach
to stay with Jodi?
I used to make fun
of Jodi and her lists.
Even before the accident,
there was a pad
in every room.
Now the post-its are...
Helpful.
And so are you.
Being here for her,
loving her--
it helps.
Zach, is there...
Is there any way you don't
have to leave completely?
I didn't sign up
for this.
Yeah, but isn't that
the point?
We sign up, we never know
what we're gonna get,
but you...
You stay, you stick it out.
You want to know
what staying looks like?
Jodi...
Honey, you're pregnant.
What?
That's amazing.
Yeah.
But I'm leaving you,
and I'm taking the baby.
Y-You can't.
I-I can't live without you.
And the baby, our--
Zach.
My baby...
This is what it's like,
Dr. Montgomery, every day,
over and over.
Jodi.
Hmm?
Honey, you're pregnant.
But I'm taking the baby
and I'm leaving you.
All right, Zach,
stop it.
This is my life.
And I hate myself.
I-I hate who I've become,
because living like this
has made me hate her.
My wife has become
my child.
Doesn't that change
the rules?
I want our kid to have
a normal life,
and how is that possible
with Jodi...
I can't
take care of them both.
I just... I can't.
Okay, look,
somewhere...
Inside of there
is the woman that you love.
I mean, you have to stop.
You're hurting her.
Why? She won't remember.
Zach, I...
I-I don't know
what's happening.
Jodi, you're okay.
Everything's gonna be okay.
Who are you?
I'm Dr. Montgomery,
and you're having a baby.
No!
What the hell
is happening to me?
You're having a baby, Jodi.
You don't remember
because you were
in an accident.
Pulse pressure's widening.
Where's Zach?
I need Zach. Dr. Turner,
where is my husband?
Zach will be here
very soon.
It hurts.
Why does it hurt?
You are having...
A baby.
Who are you?
That's Dr. Montgomery.
She's gonna deliver your baby.
What baby? Where's Zach?
Jodi, I need you to push.
Ah! I can't. It--it hurts.
No. I'm--I'm scared.
Her heart rate's dropping.
It's a cushion reflex.
It's a sign that there's
a critical rise in her I.C.P.
I want Zach!
He came to the hospital.
I haven't seen him since.
Did you talk to him?
Yes, I tried.
But he's made up his mind.
Oh, this is Sheldon's fault.
I'm sure he was trying
to do the right thing.
Okay, you know what?
I am legally blocked
from talking to Zach,
but you can talk to him again.
And--and the great thing about
you not being a therapist is,
you can say
whatever the hell you want.
You--you can yell at him,
you can shame him,
you--you can--you can say
e-every messed up thing
that you ever wanted to say
to any guy who abandoned you
or didn't show up for you,
but get him back in here,
because his wife
needs him, now.
I'll get it. Okay, Jodi.
Can you breathe?
Can you look at me?
I can't. I can't.
Hey.
So, um, he doesn't know
who you are,
and I'm not ready
for him to know,
so you take it slow?
I-I will.
You're just the doctor,
right?
Yeah.
Hey, look who I found.
Dr. Freedman.
What are you doing here?
I get junk food 'cause I
let you take my blood.
Well, you didn't
really let me, but okay.
So what are you
doing here?
I love junk food.
See, mom, he eats it
and he's a doctor.
Yeah, I'm sure
he doesn't do it often.
No, no, your mom's right.
It's not good for you.
And I-I don't come here
all the time.
Just to celebrate.
And, uh,
don't tell
my other patients, okay?
So what flavors
did you get?
Oh, I got vanilla,
chocolate, and strawberry.
Can I have the strawberry?
Strawberry's
my favorite, too.
Y-You're never
gonna believe this.
You have another kid.
You know how I dip my fries
in my shake,
and it drives you crazy?
Mason dipped his fry, same way,
except here's the thing--
it wasn't just any shake.
I bought
all three major flavors.
And do you know
which one he picked?
Do you?
Strawberry.
What kid doesn't pick
chocolate or vanilla?!
D--
my kid. That's who.
I mean, he's so my kid.
I'm gonna go
to the toy store later.
Erica said Mason
doesn't have a lot of toys.
I don't think...
They have a lot of money,
really.
What do you think?
Whatever you think,
Coop.
What the hell are you doing
out here?
Jodi's in labor.
She's scared and confused.
You think
you have to tell me that?
The baby is coming now,
Zach.
And Jodi, the unlucky one
who suffered the brain injury
and has carried your child
for the last nine months,
is about to deliver.
And she's not gonna understand,
Zach, why it feels like
her insides
are being torn apart.
She's gonna be
even more petrified
and confused and alone.
She's not alone.
You'll be there,
and Dr. Turner will be there.
No, don't, Zach.
She is alone, okay?
The whole hospital could be
there, and she'd still be alone,
because there's only one person
who can make her not feel alone.
There's only one person who can
calm her down, and that is you.
So if you ever loved Jodi,
for the next 12 hours,
be the man
you promised her to be.
Be there for her.
All right, and then--
then you can go.
You asked me to come.
What do you want to know?
Well, you can start
by explaining
why you didn't tell Cooper
about Mason.
I was young.
I liked to party.
I was tending bar,
and we did it in my car.
I know that sounds bad,
but--
you think Cooper
was my first?
Well, a month or so later,
I realized I was pregnant.
And I thought about calling.
But I was scared.
Well, somehow getting knocked
up's always a woman's fault.
Right.
And if I did call,
and he wasn't that guy,
then we would've been stuck
in each other's lives, and...
So why show up now?
I'm here for my son,
not for me.
How much?
What?
You're protecting your son.
I'm protecting my husband.
20 grand should go
a long way.
You run out, let me know.
Otherwise...
Stay the hell
away from us.
♪ yeah, yeah ♪
Ooh. Hook shot.
♪ Ahh ♪
Uh-oh. That's nice.
I still got it!
♪ How can I explain it? ♪
Good take, good take.
♪ You got to get it, baby ♪
♪ yeah, yeah, yeah,
yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ can't you see
you're only chasing? ♪
It's been 20 years, you still
got that weak-ass d.
Talk all the trash you want.
I'm still up.
♪ You're too slow, boy ♪
♪ well, if you wanna keep up ♪
♪ you got to move
a little faster ♪
♪ yeah ♪
Loser buys.
Oh, you feelin' flush?
Yes, I am.
Huh? You feelin' flush?
Come on.
♪ ...a little faster, yeah ♪
Let me ask you something.
What can you tell me about women
on, uh, fertility drugs?
Seriously?
Yeah, seriously.
I'm up to my ass in ovaries
all day long,
and you're asking me
about I.V.F. Here?
Okay, just--
just humor me.
Well, it depends on the woman,
you know, but, uh,
it can be pretty brutal
on 'em.
"Brutal"? Like what?
What are we talking,
p.M.S. Crazy or worse?
I.v.f. Can make a woman
padded-room, hide-the-belts-
and-shoelaces crazy.
And, you know, it's hard
to watch the woman you love
go through it.
Especially if you're not
the one who wants a child.
♪ If you wanna keep up, you got
to move a little faster ♪
You know, usually I tell
the dads that, uh,
it's worth it
once the baby comes.
But I'm guessing that's...
That's not gonna help here,
huh?
♪ You're too slow, boy,
if you wanna keep up ♪
♪ you got to move
a little faster ♪
♪ yeah ♪
♪ oh ♪
Oh!
You buy.
♪♪♪
Hey.
That was some greeting.
Oh, no. I just...
Erica's bringing Mason by.
I thought--
I figured.
Maybe she changed her mind.
No. Lunch was great.
And not just
with me and Mason,
all of us.
She is 20 minutes late.
Do you think I should call
or is that...
Cooper...
The woman never told you
she was pregnant,
and then shows up
after almost a decade.
What would make you think
she's consistent or reliable?
Why would you say that?
Charlotte?
'Cause I don't trust her.
And I don't want you
to get hurt.
B.p. Is dangerously high.
Jodi, Jodi, I need
you to stay calm, okay?
For you and for the baby.
What baby? I-I need Zach.
I'm right here.
Oh, oh.
Pl-please don't leave me.
I'm not going anywhere.
Zach, I need her
to push now.
Okay, you hear that, honey?
You're having a baby.
You need to push.
You can do this.
I-I can't. I can't.
It hurts. It hurts, Zach.
Please.
Okay, hey, I remember
walking over to the table
and being annoyed that
it wasn't even my section,
but I came over, and the only
face I saw was yours.
I can't, Zach. Please.
Look into my eyes.
Look at me.
And I was trying
to write down all the orders,
but my hands,
they were shaking so much.
And I knew then
at that exact moment
that I was totally
and completely in love with you.
But I was too scared
to ask you out.
And so you came into
the restaurant
every week for two months
and you sat in my section.
Yeah.
And on the busiest night of
the year, 300 reservations...
You asked me out.
Pressure's coming down.
Her heart rate's normalizing.
Zach, I need her to push.
Okay, Jodi, honey,
we are having a baby.
You trust me?
Yeah.
Okay.
Then you gotta push.
Ready?
Good, Jodi. Good.
Okay, one more big push.
Dr. Montgomery, we need to
give her the baby right away,
before she forgets.
Hey, Jodi. Big push now.
All right?
We're having a baby.
In a few seconds,
you're gonna hold our baby.
You can do this.
Do it for me. Okay?
Come on.
Good, Jodi. Good.
You hear that?
Zach...
- We...
- Oh, my god.
We did it.
Our baby.
You did it.
I love you so much.
Hi.
Hi, buddy.
What a beautiful baby.
Whose baby is this?
You know,
the more I think about
my relationship with Violet,
the more I wonder
if it was ever good.
Well, as someone
who competed with you
for Violet's affections,
I can say with certainty that
this is revisionist history.
Right, but she can't stop
shrinking me.
She can't
stop patronizing me.
She can't stop telling me
what phase I'm in.
Well, those are just
her defense mechanisms.
She has every reason to be
a little defensive
these days, you know?
Hey.
What are you doing here?
Uh, Jodi went into labor.
She needed
a familiar face around.
I-I held her hand.
That's all.
You're on a very thin line,
Violet.
Yes. Well, since you encouraged
her husband to leave her,
she needed me
on that thin line.
But she's not your patient,
Violet.
So you really have
no business--
no, you have no business,
okay?
You're not in this argument
right now.
You are not a therapist,
so you don't get an opinion.
And if you did need
to have one,
then why don't you take
my side?
Violet, I'm just saying--
you are my husband, Pete.
For one damn minute, be
my husband and take my side.
Wow. Wow.
Who's in the anger phase now?
I know this is hard.
It's not hard, Sheldon.
It's impossible.
He's not just angry.
It's like...
It's like he hates me.
And I...
I don't feel like
it's safe to breathe.
I can't... breathe.
What are you saying to him?
I care about you, Violet.
I'm trying to help you.
But I can't break confidence,
so--so--so stop asking me.
I think it was good
that you held Jodi's hand.
I...
It was good of you.
♪ To the bee ♪
♪ Whose sting protects ♪
Hey. I was starting
to think you bailed.
Yeah, I thought about it.
Well, I understand that
you're trying to protect Mason,
but you came to me.
I-I think I deserve a chance.
Yeah, I thought you deserved
a chance, too,
until I met your wife.
Do you know what I could do
for Mason with that?
I could get a car,
a better place.
But I'm not a whore.
N-No, wait.
Wait, wait. Wait, wait.
Erica.
You can't buy me off,
Cooper.
And the fact that you sent
your wife to do your dirty work
so that you could be
the good guy--
stop. No.
I had nothing to do with this.
You have to believe me.
And I promise you,
I will never hurt Mason,
ever.
♪ When church bells
make no sound ♪
You better not.
♪ In hollow towers ♪
♪ and empty hives ♪
I thought you were leaving.
♪ With a fear of heights ♪
You want to know why
I couldn't come in here
when Jodi was in pain?
♪ Just a grain of sand ♪
Because I knew that as soon
as labor started,
it would end,
and when it was over,
I'd have to take the baby
and go.
So now you're not leaving?
♪ The smartest thing... ♪
I just don't know.
I love her.
♪ Is that I don't have ♪
Maybe you were right.
♪ Just a little light ♪
No.
Now I'm beginning to think
I wasn't...
And I just needed
a happy ending.
♪ To the overarching shadows ♪
I thought it'd be easier
to leave after he came.
♪ Reignite the sun ♪
But...
♪ And swallow darkness ♪
You know, we made him.
Jodi and I,
we made him.
Now I get to introduce
my son to his mom.
♪ ...a cold blindfolded kiss ♪
And I get to introduce Jodi
to our boy.
Of course, I'll have to
keep doing it,
over and over.
So what are you gonna do?
♪ An unwanted emphasis ♪
♪ on how
we should have lived ♪
I'll stay
until I can't anymore.
♪ Life is a gorgeous ♪
♪ broken gift ♪
♪ six billion pieces ♪
What the hell is wrong
with you?
You wrote her a check?
One of us
had to be an adult here,
and you couldn't,
so I had to be.
Uh-huh.
Erica is a gold digger.
She gave the check back!
Because she knew
you'd be ready
to give her everything
without taking the test.
Is that it?
Are you jealous that Erica gave
me something that you won't?
Is that why you're trying
to ruin this for me?
Yeah, Charlotte,
you married an idiot--
a man who's excited about
the idea of being a father,
a man who loves kids
more than anything,
but who loved you enough
to wait, to put it off.
Yeah, you married an idiot.
I married a miserable bitch.
♪♪♪
Hey.
I'm not your therapist,
Pete.
I'm your friend.
And since the lines
have already been blurred,
I'm about to cross them.
Say whatever you want.
You're being an ass
to Violet.
You say your problem is,
she won't stop shrinking you,
but when does she stop,
when she finally breaks,
you--you still
just walk away.
Great. So now
you're on her side.
No, it's not about sides.
It's about you getting that
you're going to burn down
the one thing
you say you care about.
You're burning down
Lucas' happy home.
I don't know how to stop.
I feel like I hate her.
You have a lot of rage.
And she's right that
this is a necessary phase.
But you have to find
a new place to direct it.
Pick a new place, Pete,
because Violet is flawed...
For sure,
but she's not your enemy
and she's not your mother,
and if you drive her away,
if you--
if you break Lucas' home,
you...
You're on a brink, Pete.
You're at a precipice,
and if you go over,
I don't know
if you'd ever make it back.
And you need to get
a therapist.
You don't want to hear
from me anymore, huh?
I do want to hear
from you,
but I want to be able
to talk back to you like this,
like a friend,
because you're gonna need
one of those, too.
Go home to your wife,
Pete.
Make yourself remember
the things you love about her.
I want to ask you something
as a friend...
A male friend.
Okay.
Fine.
I have other friends
that are men,
you know,
but I just feel like,
given what you do,
you could give me a...
Male perspective on it,
but also understand
the female part of it, too.
Am I making any sense?
Sort of.
Do you want to just
ask me the question?
Yes, I do.
No, I-I do, but...
I want to say things to you
that I haven't even said
to Sam,
and that feels
a little weird
because...
I-I don't know anything
about you.
Well, if it makes it
any easier,
you can--
you can ask me anything.
Or I can just tell you.
I am the oldest of four,
three sisters.
Father left when I was 9.
Mother died when I was 18.
College had to wait
because I didn't want
to split up my family.
So I worked three jobs--
bike courier, bellman,
short-order cook.
At one point,
I even sold my sperm.
Probably not a genius move,
given Cooper's
current predicament,
but I did what I had to do.
I had a free ride to college,
put myself through med school.
There have been
a lot of women.
But I've really only
been in love once.
So now you know me.
Okay.
Is Sam gonna leave me
if I go crazy on hormones?
Uh...
Look, I can tell you what
it's like for a man
on the other end of that,
I can also tell you what
it's like for a woman.
But what you're asking me is,
how is Sam going to take it?
♪ And wait ♪
Here's what I know
about Sam.
He's, uh, he's fast,
got a pretty decent
jump shot,
not a great rebounder.
And he's always seemed like
a stand-up guy to me.
♪ A chain reaction ♪
♪ a loose thread ♪
Okay.
♪ That we must pull ♪
Hey, Addison.
♪ ...of religion ♪
What you're asking,
your instinct is probably
going to be a better guide
than...
Any guess I could make.
♪ But all desperation ♪
♪ leads to ♪
Thank you.
♪ A fork in the road ♪
♪ we live for understanding ♪
♪ or for ♪
♪ control ♪
♪ so very ♪
♪ carefully ♪
♪ we'll cut the wire ♪
I like your haircut.
Thanks.
It's easier to handle.
I'm sure.
♪ Life is a series ♪
♪ of narrow escapes ♪
♪ a chain reaction ♪
♪ A loose thread ♪
Well...
I'm gonna go to bed.
♪ ...must pull ♪
♪ the birth of religion ♪
Good night.
♪ The challenge of the unknown ♪
♪ But all desperation ♪
♪ leads to a fork ♪
♪ in the road ♪
♪ We live for understanding ♪
I did the paternity test.
You took Mason's blood,
so I took your toothbrush
to my lab.
♪ So very ♪
You were right.
He's your son, Coop.
You're a dad.
♪ With one eye closed ♪
♪ we'll draw back ♪
♪ catch our breath ♪
♪ and let go ♪
♪ time is the string
in between ♪
♪ the arrow and the bow ♪
♪ if there's one thing ♪
Say it.
♪ We've learned ♪
I'm worried you'll leave me
if I have a baby.
I know.
I know you are.
♪ Timing ♪
♪ is everything ♪
♪ ooh ♪
♪ it's everything ♪
Well,
when I was younger,
when I read the story,
I thought the Princess
chose the tiger
because who would want
to watch the man you love
spend the rest of his life
with another woman?
I mean, honestly,
I've been there,
and it's, uh...
It's really...
Well, it's...
It is too cruel.
And now?
What do you think now?
♪ ...to the wire ♪
Well, now, um...
I guess I'd like to think
that...
The Princess pointed to...
The lady,
because I'm starting...
To think that love
might mean...
Wanting the other person
to be happy,
even if that means
they can't stay with you.
♪ We're down to the wire ♪