Previously on Grey's Anatomy...
I want a wife and a
house and a family!
Amelia and Owen's
wedding today, I want that!
I can't marry him, because
I'm already married.
Don't do that, okay?
Let's get you into bed.
All right. Stop!
- Dr. Karev,
hold on! Okay?
- Hey!
Alex!
You made an astonishing
error in judgment!
If you had been anyone else,
you wouldn't have been suspended.
You would've been fired!
I'm done talking about this.
Church and state!
My baby is dying! Its blood
supply is cut off and it's going to die!
You saved two lives today.
- I like him.
- Who?
Riggs. I really like him.
Don't you wish you
could just, take it back?
That thing you said?
That thing you did?
They look very happy. They do.
Yeah, that won't last.
I'm not saying I don't want it
to. I'm not just being an arse.
- Actually.
- It's never been
my experience of happiness...
That it lasts.
There's no undo button.
There's only hoping we can
learn, we can change. Right?
We can do better.
Has it been yours?
- But we have to do this
right now? You're right...
time and place, my bad.
They did literally
just get married,
so let's try to be happy for
them for, like, five minutes.
- Absolutely!
- Okay.
Yes! Let's be happy.
You want to dance?
I'm not that happy.
All right. Well, then... you
want to get out of here?
- And do what?
- Be somewhere... else. Together.
Can't take back what we've done.
- So are we doing this?
- Doing what?
Dancing! It has been
a very stressful day,
and now it is over. The newlyweds
are wed, mission accomplished!
And now is traditionally the time
when we dance. So who's with me?
- Not her.
- I guess it's you then.
We can't undo the past.
'Cause the future
keeps coming at us.
- What we got?
- Male, mid-twenties,
status post blunt trauma
to the face and neck.
Oh, my God, DeLuca.
Possible zygomatic
fracture, a broken nose.
- He might have a brain injury.
- What happened?
We'll need a CT. All right,
let's get him to Trauma One.
- Let's go.
- Page Avery!
- Two champagnes.
- You got it.
I thought you were
dancing with Maggie.
Ah, Webber cut
in. Where were we?
- You have to stop.
- Stop what?
You have to stop being
where I am, talking to me.
Sounds unreasonable, with our jobs.
Besides, I like being where you are.
Stop. We have a
problem. I have a problem.
- What's that?
- Hold this. My phone is ringing.
Jo. Hey, Wilson. What's up?
Wilson? Slow down, slow
down, slow down. Take a breath.
What happened to DeLuca?
You're too good! I
can't keep up with you.
You should have
seen me in high school.
In high school, I only
danced in my room.
Meredith's a good dancer! Meredith's
always trying to get people to dance.
Something has
happened to DeLuca.
- What?
- He's in the ER.
He's been hurt.
That's all I know.
- I should go. Should I go?
- Go.
She's been drinking.
Can you drive her?
- Sure.
- Where are you going?
- God!
- What happened?
Broken nose, bleeding
posteriorly. I paged Avery.
No, Karev, what happened to him?
He's got a hyphema.
The anterior chamber of
his eye is filled with blood.
DeLuca, look up for
me? Yeah, it's entrapped.
DeLuca, DeLuca!
- It's all right.
- He's bleeding into his airway.
- He's aspirating.
- We need to intubate him.
Push 20 of etomidate.
Chief? The police are here.
-Where's Avery? ISAAC:
I put a call to plastics.
I didn't ask for plastics,
I asked for Avery!
I'm here, I'm here.
What the hell?
Looks like orbital floor
fracture with entrapment.
Who did this? Well, head
and face CT are pending.
Look, can you just
reset his nose, please?
What happened, Jo?
He shouldn't have come back
here. Shouldn't have come back here.
- Who shouldn't have
come back here?
- Here you go. Just take it easy.
- Jo, where is Alex now?
- Now's not the time.
- Will you stay with her?
- Me? She called you.
I need to reduce this
fractured septum...
bruising around the clavicle. There's
an obvious deformity. He broke it.
All right, let's
get a chest film.
Start him on a lorazepam drip.
All right, on my
count. One, two, three!
CT's ready.
Alex, may I speak
to you for a moment?
- Ready to go?
- I got it.
- Alex?
- All right, let's go.
- Alex!
- I got this.
- Now.
- All right. Let's move him.
- Say something.
- What do you want me to say?
You think no one is gonna realize
this is you? Look at that hand!
You could go to
jail. This is assault.
I'm a doctor. I have a
duty to report you to Bailey.
I came home. He
was on top of her.
Jo was drunk.
He was... he...
Mer, come on.
You're gonna turn
me in to Bailey?
You slipped in the rain.
That's how you hurt your hand.
Mer! Hey! Have you seen Andrew?
- I heard it's bad,
they said it's bad.
- They're taking him to CT.
Oh, my God! What happened?
I don't know.
- DeLuca. He's a surgeon here?
- Uh, he's a surgical resident,
yes.
You don't know the
nature of the incident?
Well, his face is
smashed in, so...
- I mean as it pertains to...
- That's all I know.
It might have... He
might have been mugged.
Might've been a bar fight.
He was with one of our doctors
when he came in, Dr. Karev.
That's...
K-A-R-E-V. I'll
tell him to find you.
Seattle to 11-93.
Excuse me. Tatum, go ahead.
Chief, you want me
to page Dr. Hunt?
On his wedding night?
Why would you that?
Kepner's out. Hunt's out. I'm just
wondering who's covering trauma.
Uh...
uh... looks like it's you.
Come on.
What, you mean
it? I'm coming back?
I said it looks
like you, didn't I?
Um, look, if you see
Karev, have him find me.
Why? What do you think happened?
I don't know what happened,
that's why I want to find Karev.
Miranda.
What?
Nothing, nothing.
All right.
DeLuca came into the ER,
apparently beaten pretty badly.
Can you tell me what happened?
I don't remember anything.
Was he here with you?
Jo... did DeLuca hurt you?
Do I need to call the
police? Did he try...
No! No, no. He... It wasn't
his fault. It was my fault, I...
I ruined it, I
ruined everything.
- How?
- He brought me home
and then I told him...
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
- What? You told him what?
- I have to go to the hospital.
I have to see Alex. I
have to talk to him...
No, you're not
gonna go anywhere.
Now, is there someone I could
call? Your mom or your dad?
I don't have... You
don't know anything.
I'm sorry.
- Wilson, who can I call?
- Just please go.
No. Not when you're like this.
Yes, because I am drunk and
gross and I am your surgeon.
I'm one of your surgeons.
I'm a good surgeon.
This isn't me. So I just...
I'm okay now.
So I will see you again,
when I am a surgeon, okay?
- So just please go.
- No, no, you drank too much,
okay.
You screwed up, and now everything
is crashing down around you.
Just go.
Hey, well, you
came to the right guy.
Because I've done it
more than you ever will.
And I can tell you
from experience.
With a little coffee,
and a little sunlight,
your troubles will get smaller.
And the world
will keep standing.
I promise. Okay?
Okay.
- I have coffee.
- Good.
We'll get you some
food... and some aspirin,
and... you'll feel better.
You know it'll...
come back to you.
And whatever
happened, you can tell me.
Or you can tell me
who you'd like to talk to.
Sound all right?
Well, hell.
Go around the block!
69-06. Dr. Marlin...
What's wrong?
Nothing. It's
just... It's weird.
We broke up... Badly.
I'm not sure I'm the
person he wants to see.
Forget it! I'm being crazy.
- Huh.
- What?
No, I thought you
were still with him.
With DeLuca? Me?
No. You thought that?
Yeah, I mean, you were very...
No! No. He broke...
We broke... It ended.
- Okay.
- Yeah, a while ago.
- It was just too hard, you know,
with us working together...
- Yeah, well, I get that.
- Not that it couldn't work
at work with work
people. I think it can.
It could! With the
right work people.
Oh, God!
Hi. It's Maggie. I'm here.
Has he been conscious?
He was on intake,
but we had to tube him.
- What's it look like?
- His head CT's clear,
but he does have an
eight-ball hyphema.
- Who did this?
- We don't know.
Karev brought him in, but we
haven't heard what happened yet.
We should find out
who we need to call.
I'm gonna go grab
his personnel file.
His mother. She's
probably at work.
I'll call her. She knows me.
How is he? Is
there a brain injury?
- He just got out of CT.
- Did you see his scan?
Well, no, but the
radiologist said they're clear.
Will you look at it yourself?
- Alex, they said...
- What if they missed something?
What if he has a delayed bleed
and he drops dead tomorrow?
I will. I will look
at the scans.
Alex, this is really bad.
It's bad. I know. I know.
I just... I went
crazy. I just... I...
What if I talk to DeLuca, just,
you know, before he says anything.
Maybe you should
talk to the police.
No, no, no. Can we wait
until we find out how bad it is?
You know, just... go... Go
check his scans, please.
I will go check the scans.
Hey, um, have you
talked to the police yet?
Uh, yeah. Uh, no.
I mean... Uh why?
Miranda said you
should come see her.
- How's the hand?
- What?
It looked like it was
giving you trouble earlier.
Oh. I slipped in the rain.
Look, man, uh...
DeLuca's gonna clear everything
when he gets out of surgery,
- so... is there anything...
- There isn't.
Okay.
You know, I got the guy
here. I helped him, okay?
Hmm...
This eye's a big problem. His
pressure is getting out of control.
Need to get him to OR
with an ophthalmologist.
- Could he lose his eyesight?
- The thing is the eye
is paralyzed.
Trapped in the fractured socket.
We get in there, we free
it, then we drain the blood.
I've called in Jan
Reger, she's great,
- but she's in Whidbey Island. So...
- You can't do it?
Uh, technically,
yes, I could do it.
Then, why wait for Jan Reger?
She's an ophthalmologist.
I'd rather have...
It's his eyesight. It's his
career, Jackson. Let's not wait.
She's right. Avery,
if you can do it, do it.
I'll do it.
- How's Kepner doing?
- She's good. She's sleeping.
What are you doing?
Hey! I'm here, I'm here.
She was just
fussing a little bit,
so I thought you could use the
sleep, and I just swooped her up.
We are bonding.
Somebody's just fascinated
with their grandma.
Riveted! Yeah!
- How are you feeling?
- I'm okay. Hurt.
No doubt. April, I can't
believe what you went through.
It was worth it.
She's beautiful. She's
just absolutely beautiful.
Mm-Hmm.
I just wish I knew
what to call her.
- Jackson didn't tell you?
- No, I just got here.
He'd probably want
to be here to tell you.
We don't have to wait for him.
Well, uh...
We wanted something
strong... memorable...
Is it Catherine? Are
you little Catherine?
We thought there could
only be one Catherine.
Her name is Harriet.
Harriet!
Mm-hmm.
I like it. Tubman.
Exactly. Tubman.
Also The Spy. Which
is a very good book.
I love it. Harriet Avery.
It's beautiful, it just flows!
I'm sorry. Who said
her name was Avery?
Are those Andrew's head
CTs? I thought they were clean.
Yeah. I'm just double-checking.
I want to make sure
we didn't miss anything.
- They look good.
- Thanks.
God! What do you think happened?
I don't know. Maybe a
mugging or something?
I just got off the
phone with his parents.
And, apparently... he neglected
to tell them that we had broken up.
Oh, God.
Mer, was I really crappy to him?
DeLuca? He broke up with you.
He's a good, good guy.
Am I being stupid?
Chasing after Riggs, when
DeLuca was right there?
- I mean, am I being stupid?
- I don't know. Maybe.
I was gonna talk
to Riggs tonight.
At the wedding, while we
were dancing, I was gonna say,
"Hey, how about you and me?"
And then Richard
Webber jock-blocked me.
Of course.
And now, Riggs thinks
I'm in love with DeLuca.
I swear, maybe this is just...
Hey!
What are you doing in scrubs?
I thought I'm going in on Avery.
Yeah. I'm going in.
Not to operate. Just...
- I don't know.
- To hold his hand.
- I guess so. Yeah.
- Yeah.
- It's stupid.
- It's not at all! He's a good guy.
Nothing wrong with that.
I know, but I'm
not... I don't...
Come on, he's gorgeous.
You can't do much better.
Good luck. I hope it works out.
Okay.
Thanks.
Hmm. You all right, then?
Thank you for bringing Maggie.
I said "Are you all right?"
I'm fine. You don't need to do
that. You don't need to check on me.
What? I'm a nice
guy. I'm being nice.
- It's what I do.
- You were very nice.
You did a nice thing for
Maggie. But now you're ruining it.
You okay?
Listen, Alex, it wasn't...
You were drunk. It
wasn't your fault, I know.
What are you talking about?
DeLuca. He pushed
himself on you, right?
You were drunk, he
tried to take advantage...
No! No, no, no, no...
Alex. I was drunk, yes,
because I was upset
you had left and I...
You were upset
about us? About me?
Yes, of course!
This is what you do? You bring
this guy back to our place to screw?
If you would just let me talk...
- Oh! 'Cause you were upset.
- Just listen to me!
You know what? Forget it.
It's like I said... you can't
help it, it's not your fault.
It's easy for you to
throw people away,
to just move on
when things are bad.
It's not you. It's the way
you were raised or not raised.
I wanted to marry you.
I was asking you for
something you're not capable of.
I should have known better.
Okay. So, first, the muscle
of his eye... is trapped here...
in the bone fracture, so
I'm just gonna... pop it out.
There we go. All right.
- Micro scalpel, please.
- Will he see again?
We'll see. Once I am able
to flush the blood out of there,
his intraocular pressure
should come down,
and his vision should
return. But don't worry.
His eyes should be
just as pretty as ever.
Will everyone stop doing that?
I want his eyes to work
because they're his eyes.
Sorry. You're right.
And he's a surgeon. He can't
be one with one eye. Okay?
It doesn't mean that I love
him or I miss him or I'm pining.
He's a friend.
No, he's not a friend because
the breakup was a train wreck,
and he probably hates
me, but he is a person,
or was a person, that
I was personal with.
I mean, you had feelings.
You had huge feelings,
you can't be expected just to
turn those feelings
off like some robot.
Especially if you've been through
something horrible together.
- I get it.
- Yeah, you do.
- Try having a baby with him.
- That's okay. I'm good.
- Fair enough.
- How we doing?
Good. Almost done here.
How is he?
He's got a grade four hyphema.
Dr. Avery's trying
to drain it now.
- But?
- I'd be worried about re-bleeds,
- long-term vision loss.
- Which would mean...
Whoever did this just ended
his career as a surgeon.
You know, I, um... I
think I know who it is.
- Why haven't you said anything?
- Not sure.
I think because I can
guess what he did.
He reacted. In a split
second, in the moment,
and a horrible thing happened.
I know what that's like.
What about you?
Is it just blind loyalty?
It's not blind. He's earned it.
When I first got here,
he was one of the worst
people I had ever met in my life.
And now he's one of the best.
And I know both of those
people are still in there.
I just want to make
sure the right one wins.
Well, anyway, I... I don't
think it should come from me.
Me, either.
- Okay. There you are.
- What are you doing here?
Webber called, said he
thought you might be with me.
He said DeLuca got beat
up, and then you ran off.
Look, I'm here 'cause I'm your
friend, dummy. What happened?
- What are you doing?
- I'm leaving.
- Okay, fine. I'll drive you...
- No, I'm leaving, leaving.
- You're quitting?
- Yeah.
You're quitting the program.
And you're not gonna
tell me what this is?
- I can't.
- You... Okay, hey!
What the hell? Jo.
What happened with
DeLuca? You can talk to me.
I'm the one that left you
at the bar with him. What?
She was upset about Karev.
She was also really drunk.
- So you left her with DeLuca?
- To keep her safe, yes.
I didn't want to
leave her there alone.
He made sure she got home
okay. And you have to understand...
I do! She wanted
to hurt Alex back.
But she may have hurt
him for good, this time.
I mean, this could
end his career!
I mean, this goes well beyond
just sleeping with another guy.
- She didn't sleep with DeLuca.
- Did he force himself on her?
No, he... He kept her safe!
He got her home, he
made sure she was okay.
DeLuca was kind and
nice and thoughtful.
And DeLuca was trying to
keep her from getting hurt,
or from hurting herself.
And then you walked in.
Okay, how do you know Edwards
isn't lying about the whole thing?
Because I wanted her
to be. Which is awful.
But I was hoping for some reason
that you beat that man half to death,
that doesn't make you a monster.
You know she wasn't lying.
Is DeLuca out of
surgery? Did he wake up?
You have to go to
Bailey and say something.
- If he presses charges...
- He should
press charges.
He's not the bad guy here.
And Jo isn't the bad guy.
We're the bad guys,
really bad guys.
If I don't say something, if
you don't say something...
- I want to run.
- You can't run.
I thought I'd grown up. I
said this to Jo yesterday.
I went back there to talk to
her and make things right.
To do the grown-up thing.
Alex...
Let me talk to DeLuca.
Just let me try. Okay?
Wilson.
Did you hear what happened?
Not yet. But I know it's
not worth leaving here.
I made a mess. I can't fix it.
I can only make it worse.
So I am walking away from it.
It's better for everyone.
Okay? Move, please.
No! I don't know what happened,
but whatever it is, you won't
get it fixed by running from it.
And you won't gain
anything by quitting.
We don't quit!
I won't let you.
Now, you ditched me once today.
I'm not gonna let it happen again.
I mean, she's your baby. You
can call her whatever you want.
Just as long as it's Avery.
I'll say this... Avery
wasn't my name either.
But I took it on and
built it into something.
And the name that I built,
will open doors for this girl.
I'm just thinking of her future.
Yeah, well, the name
Kepner means something, too.
What?
Where I come from, it means
good people. A tireless work ethic.
A fair and honest
price for quality pork.
The people you call
when you're in trouble.
Yeah, it may not open doors,
but Kepner means something!
Now, can I have my...
It's all right. It's all
right. I've got her.
No, Catherine, I can
hold my own baby.
No, April, you
can't. No, you can't!
You nearly died bringing
her into this world.
You did something superhuman,
so now you get to rest and heal.
Harriet's just fine.
She's got her grandma,
that's what grandmas
are for. So now, just relax!
Sleep for an hour. You're gonna
have her whole life to hold her.
Rest and heal. She's
gonna need you.
Couldn't you hyphenate?
Avery-Kepner?
- We are hyphenating, Mom.
- Oh.
- That's what we decided. Right?
- Yes. Kepner-Avery.
Well, why didn't you say that?
Because she's my baby.
That's your baby.
She is my baby.
Dr. Leone, call the pharmacy.
Who's there? Who is it?
- Is somebody there?
- I'm sorry.
- Jo. Are you okay?
- Am I okay?
You were pretty drunk and... I was
out. I was worried that he was gonna...
No, I'm, I'm fine. I'm
perfectly fine. How are you?
You tell me. How am I looking?
You look... Really ugly.
Don't make me laugh.
I'm sorry... for putting
you in that position.
Don't. It was just...
Wrong place, wrong time.
No, you were trying
to help me. And I just...
Jo, it wasn't you. It was him.
Please don't tell anyone...
What I told you
about... That I...
- That you're married.
- Yeah. Please.
Oh, I see. That's
why you came here.
Huh? I thought you came
here 'cause you cared.
No, that's, that's not... I...
Jo, I know it. Don't worry. It's
cool. Your, uh, your secret's safe.
You know, you
could pick better guys.
- Jo?
- What are you doing here?
Can I talk to you, please?
Get... get away
from me. No! Please.
- Listen, DeLuca, I didn't know.
- Go away! Get out of here!
- You came to my house...
- Leave!
- I saw you on top of her.
- Alex, go!
- Somebody! Somebody!
- Go!
- Help! Help!
- I'm sorry.
- Call security, somebody?
- Sir, just calm down, all right?
Let's calm him down.
You all right? Oh, sorry,
nope. Forget I asked.
Well, you can tell Maggie
that her boy's angio
showed no vascular
injury, so... no worries.
Thanks. He's not her boy.
He's hurt. She's
just being kind.
All right.
I have to do something.
That I don't want to do.
- Then don't do it.
- I have to.
Then do it.
I will.
Nathan...
Come and sit with me a while.
What? Grey, what?
I don't have time to...
- It was Alex.
- What was Alex?
The person who beat
up DeLuca... was Alex.
Dr. Ryan, Radiology.
- When did you know?
- I knew!
Something happened
between Wilson and DeLuca...
Oh, stop. Just stop!
- Dr. Bailey...
- Hey, call security.
Tell them to find the police.
Tell them Dr. Karev does
not leave this hospital.
What? Meredith. It's Alex?
Yeah, come on.
You knew it? And you
didn't say anything?
Karev.
What's going on?
You're under arrest for assault.
He walked up and turned
himself in. Made it real easy.
He'll be in city lockup. You
have the right to remain silent.
Anything you say can be used
against you in a court of law.
You have the
right to an attorney,
and to have an attorney
present during questioning.
If you cannot afford an attorney,
one will be appointed for you.
Do you understand these
rights as I read them to you?
Yes.
You were just gonna
lie to everyone?
- Did you know about Karev?
- No! I didn't!
Not for sure.
Ben Warren!
I have been lied to by so many
people today. If you lied to me, too...
Look, I guessed,
okay? I had suspicions.
What? And you didn't tell me?
Because I didn't know.
You can tell your wife
when you have suspicions,
but you can't tell the chief.
And you weren't my
wife. You were the chief.
Church and state.
I wasn't going
to lie to everyone.
You lied to me.
I asked you what
happened and you lied.
Alex and I were trying to...
Trying to what?
Trying to figure out a way to justify
the beating he gave to Andrew? What?
I don't know.
I poured my heart out to you...
all day... and you knew this.
It wasn't about you, Maggie.
I am your sister.
- I know.
- Do you?
'Cause it means something different
to me. You encouraged me to stay.
You offered me a home
and a family, and I accepted.
And I wasn't kidding, I will
go down swinging for you.
It means something to me.
I thought I could trust you.
You can.
From here on out.
Don't do it again.
Don't lie to me again.
Okay.
I'm, I'm gonna get that.
Oh, God. What
are you doing here?
- I want to know
what the problem is.
- What?
At the wedding, you
said we had a problem.
I want to know
what the problem is.
The problem is you
showing up here, looking for...
- What are you looking for?
- I'm not looking for anything.
It's right here.
Meredith! Hey, listen.
- There's something
happening here.
- Shh.
We both know it.
So, what's the problem?
- Someone is going to get hurt.
- Well, I can handle it.
Not you.
And from what I can see,
you seem indestructible.
So, what's the problem?
Tell me.
The problem is... You're wrong.
I don't feel the same way.
So, let's just drop it. Okay?
Good night.
Best to keep the
past in the past.
Move on. Learn from it.
Who was that?
Oh... that was no one. It's just
someone looking for directions.
Where are you going?
If we don't learn
from our mistakes...
we wind up locked into a
future we'd never choose.
- It was nice knowing you.
- Shut up.
What, you think I'm keeping
my job? Or my medical license?
We don't know what's
going to happen.
I'll tell you what
isn't gonna happen.
Me ever setting foot
in that hospital again.
- I'm sorry.
- Why?
You didn't punch the guy.
- But I told Bailey.
- You did?
Yes. I had to.
I know.
It's better. You
did the right thing.
Right now, being the guy who
got beat up would feel better.
You said it yourself.
We're grownups.
We can't run. We have to face
up to the stupid things we do.
Supposedly, if you face up to
them, something good comes out of it.
- I don't know what, but...
- Fifteen to 20, probably.
- I'm sorry.
- Shut up.
The past is written.
There's no changing it.
What's done is done.
But the future is ours to
choose. For better or worse.