[ADDISON MOANS SOFTLY]
- What?
- It was really just work?
[SIGHS]
- You've gotta be kidding.
- I'm...
I'm just saying, you were out late,
you didn't answer your phone,
you didn't call.
Oh, we've had this conversation
every day for a week.
[ADDISON SIGHS]
I had to go back to the office for work.
I'm sorry, I should have called.
- What?
- I do this for a living, Addison.
I read people.
What aren't you telling me?
I am telling you everything.
Take your clothes off.
You think I don't know
a diversionary tactic?
[PHONE VIBRATING]
Sorry.
[ADDISON SIGHS]
ADDISON:
Hey, you look great.
You got a date tonight?
- Um... No, not a...
- Last night?
Not a date. Just, um...
Um, met a colleague.
Oh, a male colleague?
Handsome male colleague?
Tell me yours, I'll tell you mine.
There's a yours?
You have a guy? I was joking.
Did you or did you not sleep
with Wyatt Lockhart?
We have a mom in labor, waiting.
I have to go scrub in. Ahem.
Okay, you're doing great, Judy.
Just keep breathing, okay?
Okay, okay, okay.
She's fully dilated.
Contractions every two minutes.
Where are Matt and Carrie?
This is their baby, they need to be here.
Just keep breathing, okay?
Promise me they'll take the baby away
as soon as it's out.
- I don't think I can look at him, then let go.
- I know, I know, I know.
I really want the Sinclairs to have it.
- Okay, okay, okay.
- Get down there. Go, go, deliver.
- Come on.
- Okay, okay, okay.
- Get ready to start pushing, okay?
- Okay.
NAOMl: Come on, come on, come on.
- Oh, thank God.
We ran without the video camera.
No, not for now. For later.
- I can't believe this is finally happening.
- Here we go, ready? Big push.
Okay.
[SCREAMS]
Okay, I can see the head. Okay.
- Okay.
- All right.
Aah! Okay.
[BEEPING]
Yeah, I think it's...
What? What's wrong?
- Dell, press on her stomach.
- Okay.
[GROANS]
Judy, your baby's shoulder is stuck
on your pubic bone. He's in distress.
I have to insert my hand,
push the baby back in.
You wanna put it back inside of me?
Judy, the baby's oxygen supply
is compromised, okay?
We're gonna get you to the hospital,
do a C-section.
- What?
- Everything is gonna be fine.
- We're gonna take care of everything.
- Okay, you ready?
- You're gonna be fine, okay?
- Okay.
Here we go.
[SCREAMING]
[GASPING]
- Is it me or is it better?
- Oh, better.
Hasn't been that long.
It must be a long time.
Which is good, been a long time
and this is definitely...
- Better.
- Mm.
Things feel
as if they're different this time.
I feel like we're different.
I feel so good.
- You feel it?
- Feeling it. Feeling it.
Okay.
Let's get married.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Oh, yeah.
I'm the groom, you are the naughty,
naughty maid of honor.
And you have wanted me for years.
You can't hold back any longer.
And I'm in the laundry room wearing
nothing but my black silk boxers
and I'm putting on my groom socks.
And you just come in there
and you just grab my...
Cooper?
You're serious?
SHELDON:
You know what I was thinking,
we need to heed our own advice.
Take a mental health day,
forget about our clients for a while.
Live for us.
[VIOLET SNORTS]
Not that this isn't living for us.
I mean, this is great.
[LAUGHING]
I mean, I'm not just talking about the sex.
Although that is excellent.
And did I mention I tend to ramble
when I'm enamored?
Or when I'm nervous.
Which I am right now, a little,
because you've been in there a while
and you're making odd noises.
[VIOLET SNORTS]
Violet? Is everything okay?
I'm fine. I've never been better.
[LAUGHING]
DELL:
You're doing great.
I keep trying to think about the beach.
Anywhere else but here.
Okay, Judy, here we go.
I'm going out of town when this is all over.
After finals, I'm gonna
do a semester in Australia.
You know, maybe even move there.
- I just want this to be over.
- I know.
ADDISON:
There we are.
Zero Vicryl, close her up.
Get the baby up to NICU. Set up
a pediatric vent and an incubation tray.
What's wrong?
The baby's having trouble breathing.
Judy, it's most likely
a diaphragmatic hernia.
- It's a birth defect of the muscle
- What?
That separates the chest
from the abdomen.
- No, no, no.
- You have some choices for surgery.
- You have options.
- I'm not the mother anymore.
You need to talk to the Sinclairs.
Until the adoption is finalized,
you're the legal guardian.
No, no, it has to be the Sinclairs.
[COOPER SIGHS]
Don't you wanna know
what's wrong with me?
You wanna know
She proposed.
Charlotte, she proposed.
To me. Yeah, I know.
It's like one week we hate each other
and then her dad kicks and she cries,
and it's like the floodgates open.
Sex, emotion. Marriage?
- Am I ready for this?
- I don't know. It's very real.
- Are you?
- I don't know. I wanna run,
but I don't.
Um... And what's wrong with you?
Hey, Coop, have you seen...?
Oh, I'm sorry, I didn't know you were...
Oh, no, it's okay.
I, um, actually wanted to talk to you.
Talk?
Oh, right, that's my cue.
Awkward silence.
Uh, we have much to discuss.
All right, all right.
It's been weird between us.
It's been two weeks of weird.
You're dating Sheldon.
You made a choice.
- I'm an adult.
- Good.
Yeah, I just don't want it to be weird.
Between us.
I mean, not now.
I mean, it's good.
Good.
- Giving you any relief?
- Mm.
In my younger days,
I'd probably grin and bear it, handsome.
But could you turn
whatever you're doing up?
My gut's on fire.
You got it.
Pancreatic cancer sucks.
- I wish I could do more.
- You've done wonders.
If I had your knack for the needles
back in the day,
I'd probably have done
something like you.
Alternative instead of radiology.
Do you know how boring radiology is?
I mean, looking at films all day?
Don't start. I know you, you were great.
I did it because it was easy.
A good doctorial profession for a man
who liked to sleep in and party.
Well, maybe you got it right.
- Living in the moment.
- Ah.
My even more handsome doctor.
And whoever thought that was possible?
You've got the serious face, Sam.
How much time do I have, doctor?
The chemo hasn't helped.
There's been no change.
There's nothing else.
So I'm a dead man.
No need to sugarcoat.
I know the drill.
Cancer attacks my liver, my liver fails,
painful death.
Um... Three, four weeks, give or take.
Three hellish weeks.
- I'm sorry.
- I'll do whatever I can to help the pain.
- I'll come to your house.
- We'll do whatever we need to do to help.
That's good.
That's very good,
because I'm gonna need your help.
I want you to help me die.
Okay, the crib'll be delivered tomorrow.
I called my mom, called your mom,
my sister.
I can't believe he's finally here.
MATT: What's wrong?
- Oh, my God, something happened.
- She changed her mind.
- No. No, it's not that.
ADDISON:
Your baby's in the NICU.
He was born with a thoracic hernia.
The organs below the diaphragm
are pushing into his thoracic cavity,
and he's having a hard time breathing.
But the baby's supposed to be healthy.
I know this is a lot,
but Addison needs to do the surgery
quickly to help the baby to breathe.
ADDISON:
Now, there are two surgical options.
The first is relatively simple
and will correct the problem for now.
But as the baby grows,
he'll require more surgery.
And the second is higher risk,
but it will be a more permanent solution.
- I can't believe this is happening.
- What does Judy wanna do?
Well, she wants you to decide.
- The adoption isn't even final.
- Yeah, which is why I'm here.
Since the birth mother
is abdicating a right to decide,
the hospital will honor your wishes
about what to do.
- But we need a decision now.
- I don't know.
What I would recommend
is the more aggressive approach.
- But he could die?
- Yes.
Um, I can't do this.
You can. Just trust Dr. Montgomery.
I'm sorry, I can't.
I'm sorry.
CHARLOTTE: If that baby boy has no
guardian to make decisions for him,
then the hospital has to
until the state gets involved.
And I can't approve surgery
that's outside the standard of care.
ADDISON: Look, he has a hole
in his diaphragm, Charlotte.
A standard procedure will hold
for a few years, maybe.
But if I go in and do
a muscle transfer and nerve implant,
he has a chance
at a normal, healthy childhood.
- My hands are tied.
- All right, let me talk to the Sinclairs.
- I know them. I can explain this.
DELL: No.
First sign of trouble, they gave up
on this kid. I'll talk to Judy.
If Addison thinks that her surgery is best,
I'll get Judy to authorize it.
- Dell.
- Someone needs to convince someone.
Okay, talk to Judy.
But listen, Dell, I want Violet there.
You know how Judy feels about this.
I want her to be protected.
[PHONE RINGING]
Hey, Nora.
- I made it.
- You made it.
- You're doing great, Mom.
- Let's go back.
- So you must be the fiancé.
- Tomorrow, the husband
and beloved son-in-law.
Definitely beloved.
He's been part of the family for years.
He's gotten used to my difficulties.
- She's losing it.
- She's here.
It took both of us
to get her out the door.
Well, agoraphobia's tough.
She's been entrenched for a long time.
TINA:
I've heard that for years.
I heard that when she missed my violin
recitals, my school plays, my graduation.
I'm getting married tomorrow.
I want my mother there.
Please, you have to make sure
she doesn't back out.
Oh.
I'm so sorry.
There's an emergency.
Nora, I have to go to the hospital,
but I can be back in less than an hour.
It's okay, I'll go.
No, no, no.
This could be good.
It's an exercise.
Because you're out in the world,
but you're in here safe, secure.
You can practice your breathing,
your visualizations.
- I can't.
- Mom, please, you need to do this.
PETE: It's not that simple, Sam.
SAM: It is.
Doesn't matter how long we've known him
or how much we wanna spare him,
we cannot have a hand
in ending a man's life.
- He's asking for a prescription.
- Which he knows how to use
to kill himself.
Now we know he knows
and we know what he's gonna do,
so let's just stop pretending.
There are laws
against assisted suicide.
There's no one coming after us, Sam.
There's no family to consider.
There's just Alexander,
and he wants to die.
- Who wants to die?
- Patient with pancreatic cancer.
Stage 4-B pancreatic cancer,
and he's a doctor.
Well, if he's a doctor,
he's gonna find a way.
- He wants morphine.
- Which we should give him.
That's kind of going out
on a limb there, Dr. Kevorkian.
He's gonna do this.
Will you really sleep better
knowing that we stood passively by
rather than actively help him?
I will sleep better if I know that I took
seriously the oath to first do no harm.
Well, what does more harm,
helping him die or letting him live?
Exactly. Alexander has nothing left
but the chance to control
when and how the end comes.
This is... It's mercy, this is not murder.
It's a fine line, boys. A slippery slope.
SAM:
Look, I understand the concept of mercy,
but letting nature run its course
is different than helping nature along.
It doesn't matter
how we try to rationalize it.
There is no moral difference
between writing him a prescription
and buying him a gun.
I won't do it. The practice won't allow it.
The Sinclairs, they're probably
not gonna go through with the adoption.
What?
Because he's sick?
Let's not worry about them right now.
- What's gonna happen to him?
- We'll find other good parents.
VIOLET:
But right now, he needs surgery.
And without your consent,
the hospital won't allow Dr. Montgomery
to do what she thinks is best for him.
She told me before, I had to choose.
I don't think I can choose...
I don't think I can choose and then let go.
I think you've been choosing
what's best for the baby all along.
You've been planning
the best life possible
and all Dell is asking is
that you plan one more thing.
You just need to sign a form.
Okay, one form.
And you'll have an incredible team
of doctors looking after him.
He needs you. One last time.
Paper's signed. You're good to go.
- Judy came through.
- Yeah, for now.
I'm still hoping
that the Sinclairs will come through.
They walked in a crisis.
- Would you want that for your kid?
- We should talk about something else.
Like who you're dating, the colleague
you refuse to tell me about?
Well, you're one to talk.
What about Wyatt?
Why is everyone so stuck on what did
or didn't happen with Wyatt?
Well, who else is stuck on it?
You didn't tell Kevin?
No, there's nothing to tell.
It didn't happen.
I didn't cheat, I didn't go out on the date.
- I just went into his office and kissed him.
- Pardon me?
And then I walked out.
So technically, it wasn't cheating.
Technically, you walked into his office
and you kissed him...
And stopped, and I left,
and I have not seen him since.
Kevin keeps asking where I was,
and I keep telling him I was working,
and I divert him with sex,
but it was nothing.
Well, if it was nothing,
then why did you wait a week to tell me?
[EKG BEEPING]
Baby's sats are falling.
Getting hard to ventilate.
Take him off the vent and bag him.
I gotta go in now.
[SIGHS]
Nora, I'm so sorry, I was just...
Nora?
Have you seen your mother?
She's not in your office?
Maybe she's in the bathroom.
Nora, are you in there?
NORA:
Yes.
Do you wanna come out?
No.
Sorry.
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
It's open.
Peter, lovely to see you.
I'm treating myself
to chocolate pudding.
My favorite.
You brought my medicine?
I wanted to tell you in person.
I'm sorry.
We just can't prescribe drugs
to help you kill yourself.
I understand.
Yeah, I wasn't counting on it.
In my day, it might have been different.
A doctor's job was to preside
over life and death.
I know what you want,
but you are still alive.
You're still handling the pain,
and you have time.
Not much, but time.
And what would I do with this time?
- I'm 73 years old.
- You could
get closures, say your goodbyes,
enjoy your last days.
Peter, I'm the last of my friends
left alive.
I have no lover, no children, no one.
In the coming days,
I'm gonna gradually...
...fade away.
I'll either be in extraordinary pain
or I'll be so high on drugs
that I might as well be dead.
I don't believe those are last days
I'd like to enjoy.
Well, you're enjoying sugar.
Oh, this isn't sugar.
It's a mixture.
Sixteen alprazolam tablets
from my bathroom,
12 dusty codeine tablets
from the hall bathroom,
a couple of muscle relaxants,
some sleeping pills,
and a tiny bit of LSD leftover
from a fabulous party in 1972.
- Alexander.
- No, don't bother.
It's okay.
I'm already on my second bowl.
I told you.
I'm gonna die.
COOPER: Hey. Look, I really need
your advice. I am in a situation...
- Cooper, not a good time here.
- Okay, not how I imagined it.
Not that I ever imagined being
proposed to. That's kind of crazy, right?
I don't know if I can trust her,
but I love her, I think.
I do. No, I do.
And I am happier now than I was before.
I mean, I was miserable before.
I don't know if I'm really ready to...
Cooper, I am with a patient.
Oh, the agoraphobic?
Sorry. You should come out,
weddings are great.
VIOLET: Sorry about that interruption.
NORA: That's okay, I don't mind.
I'm guessing it's uncomfortable in there.
Let's... Let's try and get a fresh start
on the couch.
I'm not coming out,
and I'm not going to that wedding.
I can't.
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
Baby's out of surgery.
Okay, it went well.
Addison was amazing,
so I thought you'd like to know.
Dell, I can't stop thinking about him.
All I wanna do is not think about the baby,
and I can't stop.
Every time I move, I feel it here.
I feel this physical need to hold him.
How am I supposed to
not think about him?
He's going to have a good life.
You are going to have a good life.
- I know, I know.
- Okay.
Is it scary in there? In the NICU?
Is there someone talking to him?
It's not a scary place?
I just have these terrible images of him
all alone,
and I can't stand it.
I can't.
You wanna see him?
Oh, God.
Hey. I was saving that bottle
for an occasion.
Oh.
Yeah, occasion.
- Are you having pain?
- It's okay.
Mm.
Except for drinking alone.
Oh. I know you're uncomfortable.
You don't have to stay.
I do. If I walk out the door,
all I'll do is think about you.
Here, dying alone.
I lived alone.
You reap what you sow.
Sow carefully, my friend.
[IN RUSSIAN ACCENT]
You don't want to end up tragic like me.
It's small, contained, secure,
but you're alone in there, Nora.
I'm here with you,
but I'd be more here if you came out.
NORA:
I can't.
What are you afraid of?
Everything.
I feel it in the pit of my stomach.
It consumes me.
People look at me, all those people.
- And I feel scared.
- You're letting it get big.
Let's break it down.
I can't. Don't you see that?
I'm letting my daughter down,
I'm letting everyone down,
and I feel so scared.
I mean, you've never felt this.
How can you know?
I'm gonna break all the rules,
and I'm gonna tell you something
about me.
[SIGHS]
I am more afraid
than I've ever been in my life.
I'm pregnant.
And that is paralyzingly,
terrifyingly scary for me.
But I got up this morning
and I came to the office,
because people needed me.
And that's good, to be needed.
To help you.
And I'm using that to fight back my fear.
NORA:
Motherhood is great.
That's nothing to be afraid of.
My daughter is the best part of my life.
Then shouldn't you be at her wedding?
We all have fears,
me, you, your daughter.
Your daughter's scared her mother won't
be at her wedding, when she needs you.
Maybe there's something scary
to be needed like that.
Maybe that's why I'm scared.
But we all have to face our fears.
[SIGHS]
And I think we both know that
my closet's not the answer.
Well done.
He's breathing much better now.
[BABY COOING]
Some things I can fix.
Shh.
I freaked out.
- I couldn't think. I didn't know what to do.
- I called them.
CARRIE: We made a mistake,
but we're here now.
We wanna adopt him.
We've always wanted to adopt him.
I'll talk to Judy.
No. No.
Judy, we screwed up.
We know what you must think.
That you want him now,
when he's fixed?
- It's not like that, Judy.
- You made me wanna give him to you.
I thought you were the answer.
And then when I needed you,
when he needed you...
Uh, Judy.
[GASPS]
I'm keeping my baby.
I'm keeping my son.
Hi.
VIOLET: Who can tell who's gonna be
a good parent and who won't?
There's no litmus test and
it's really not our job to determine.
She had the baby, it's her baby,
that's the way it works.
It's an impulsive decision, and becoming
a parent should not be impulsive.
But it is. Fate happens.
No matter how much you think you
know what you want, things happen.
And the best you can hope is that
people adjust to that change.
I'm just worried because Judy was so clear
that she wanted to give up this baby.
Actually, not so clear.
After the Sinclairs got involved,
Judy's been on the fence.
- And you withheld that?
- I didn't wanna make you nervous.
Look, she stepped up when
no one else would. I mean,
maybe it's for the best.
[COOING]
Hi.
- Is Vi...? You seen Violet?
- I think she left for the night.
- Is everything okay?
- Yes.
No. Well, I don't know. Um...
How do you know if
someone's the right person?
Setting love aside because love
and rightness, two different things, right?
You know what? Never mind. Thanks.
I think they're the same,
love and rightness.
They should be the same.
[INDISTINCT DIALOGUE OVER PA]
Can you tell me if Dr. Wyatt Lockhart
is working tonight?
KEVIN: You are still here.
- Oh.
Where else would I be
when I say that I'm working?
You know what people
with a guilty conscience do
when faced with having to lie?
They ask a question back at you.
Look, I'm not...
- I'm kidding, Addison.
- No, you're not.
What do you wanna hear, Kevin?
What do you want me to say
that's gonna make you feel better?
I have to go check on the baby.
SAM:
Alexander? Pete?
Oh, uh, you never came back.
And you didn't answer your phone.
No, I didn't.
What's the...?
- Is there a problem?
- No, there's no problem.
Pete's just keeping me company.
He is Charon,
guiding me down the River Styx.
And he didn't give me the prescription,
rest assured.
I used alternative methods.
- Wait, so are you saying...?
- He's dying, Sam.
He made a choice.
He's committing suicide
and you're just standing th...
I'm calling 911.
He doesn't want the hospital, Sam.
This is a crime. This is a man's life.
This is death.
He's doing this his way, Sam.
You really wanna put him through hell,
pump his stomach,
only to put him through hell
in a few days or a week?
I'm not gonna sit here and let you...
[RETCHING]
PETE: Here.
- This doesn't...
It doesn't have to be this way.
You can go, Sam.
Just don't call anyone.
Don't take it upon yourself to try
to fix something that can't be fixed.
- I can do this alone.
- Okay.
All right? Okay.
It's not exactly what I pictured,
but let's do it, Charlotte.
Oh, it's gonna be...
Oh, it's gonna be great.
The Cuyahoga County Freedmans
meet the Kings from Monroeville.
And we could,
like, do it halfway in between.
How do you feel about Nashville?
I thought I said Vegas.
Well, I mean, we only get to do it once.
Why don't we do it right?
A Vegas wedding is doing it right.
We gotta get... How we gonna
get all our families to Las Vegas?
I don't want anyone there.
I wanna marry you. Tomorrow.
Tomorrow?
- Oh, my mother...
- Families complicate things.
Family is messy. Let's do this.
Marry me, Cooper Freedman.
[SIGHS]
[ALEXANDER GROANING]
Oh.
- Oh!
- What's wrong? What do you need?
- What can I get you? What can I get you?
- Oh, no.
Just the pain.
Comes and goes in waves.
[WHIMPERS]
Oh, now it's going.
[GROANS]
I hate seeing you like this.
It's not my favorite thing either.
It's not like I wanna die.
If I could live like I lived when I lived...
And I lived, let me tell you.
I thought once I might fall in love.
I had lots of sex.
[MOUTHS]
A lot.
[LAUGHS]
I guess I was just far too good-looking
for my own good.
You and Naomi split.
- You got a girlfriend now?
- Kind of.
You like her?
A lot.
How's the sex?
[LAUGHS]
I'm a dying man. Indulge me.
Well, actually,
we haven't reached that level yet.
[CLEARS THROAT]
Taking it slow.
I suppose that's the way you find love.
Just don't end up like me, Sam.
It's not that good to die alone.
[GROANING]
I'm gonna go for a walk.
- You stop by the hospital?
- Yeah. Baby's good.
Judy's tired, but she's doing it, so...
You didn't go by?
No, I had a breakfast.
Some things for the baby.
- She's not changing her mind.
- Dell.
No, it's all right.
He has every right to be angry.
They weren't to change Judy's mind.
They were things we bought
that we wanted him to have.
- He should still have them.
- Well, we'll pass them on.
CARRIE: For what it's worth,
we know how badly we screwed up.
After the miscarriages
and the adoptions that fell apart,
we felt like we lost those babies.
And the thought of this baby...
CARRIE:
We were afraid of not having him.
And now we don't have him.
We've lost another child.
And it's our own fault.
[SIGHS]
Didn't mean to startle you.
- What are you doing here?
- Looking for you.
Receptionist said th...
Are you okay?
Yesterday you seemed...
You never called so l...
- I'm fine, I'm fine.
- Yeah, well, you seem...
PETE: Violet, Sheldon.
- Hey, Pete. You okay?
- I'm fine.
- You sure?
- I'm sure. Are you okay?
- Me?
That's what I was asking,
if she was okay.
- Is something wrong?
- What? I'm...
[PHONE RINGING]
I can't even get a snack
without being interrogated.
- What is it?
- I have to go to a wedding.
VIOLET:
Tina.
She won't get out of the car.
It's my wedding day and
she won't get out of the car.
I can't get married without her there.
I won't. Please.
Don't worry, she's gonna be there.
Just go.
So you got here.
That's a huge step.
- I'm sitting in the car.
- Outside your daughter's wedding.
Where you want and you need to be.
So you beat back your fear,
you got dressed.
You look beautiful, by the way.
You came across town.
When was the last time you did that,
outside of coming to my office?
It's not enough. I'm a failure.
Look out the window
and tell me what you see.
A church, people in tuxes, dressed nice.
It's a perfect day, and I'm gonna ruin it.
I'm tired of being this way, afraid.
L... I tried to...
But my heart just goes upside down.
I panic.
I'm gonna ruin it.
If I go in, I'll ruin it.
If I don't go in, I'll ruin it.
[SIGHS]
I used to think I was a...
I was a good mother.
Now she'd be better off without me.
Trevor. I'm going to call him Trevor.
Do you think that's right?
Yeah, Trevor's a good name.
NAOMl:
Judy.
Did Dell tell you that the Sinclairs came by
with some things for the baby?
- Some blankets and clothing.
- Yeah, but they bailed, so there's no...
Dell, can I talk to you for a minute,
please? Excuse us.
[DELL SIGHS]
- What are you doing?
- Protecting her.
No, you're not. You're pushing Judy
to do what you think is right.
- It is right.
- You need to listen.
If you'd listened, you would have heard
how scared the Sinclairs were.
- No, I heard...
- Yeah, no, Dell, you walked out.
They didn't run because they didn't
want a sick child, they were afraid.
They were afraid of becoming
attached to him and then losing him.
Just like she is.
Can't you see she's terrified?
Listen to her, Dell.
Isn't that what she's been telling you
all along?
You don't think I should keep him?
That's not mine to say.
If you know that this is right,
keeping the baby, then it is.
It's right, period.
You just need to make sure that you're
doing it for the right reasons.
Not because you think you have to,
or because you think
that others think you should.
Because you want to.
God, I don't know what I want.
I spent months deciding that
giving up the baby was right,
but now...
I know. Now it's hard.
It's hard because you've seen him
and you've bonded with him.
If you commit to this
because you feel like you have to,
and not that you want to,
that's not good for anyone.
You should go.
I like it here.
I'm considering moving my practice
to this car.
[BOTH CHUCKLE]
When my husband walked out,
I couldn't believe it.
I kept thinking
that he was gonna come home.
I wouldn't leave the house,
in case he came back.
- I had to be there.
- So you got stuck.
Because in some ways,
you couldn't let go of that idea, huh?
That he'd walk through that door.
I'd kill him if he did.
He did this to me.
No, he didn't.
You're doing this to yourself.
Punishing yourself
or depriving yourself.
He went out and got a life.
And your daughter's doing
the same thing today.
And I know how hard it must be for you
that she's walking out too.
But sitting in this car doesn't change
the fact that she is getting married.
So you wanna become a part of it
or stay alone?
So maybe your life didn't turn out
the way you thought it would.
You can embrace this.
Create the next step.
Starting today.
Why are you afraid of being pregnant?
I'm afraid that I'll fail.
I'm afraid that I'm not good enough.
I'm just afraid.
But I'm not gonna let that paralyze me.
I'm not that brave.
You raised a daughter.
In my book, that is incredibly brave.
Help me.
Help me do this.
How do I do this?
I will be with you every step of the way.
This feeling in my head.
Do you think more of the merlot
could help?
- I wish it would.
- Right.
Of course. Cabernet.
You were gone for a while.
- Pete.
- It'll take away the pain.
You stole morphine
so you could euthanize a patient?
I'm a doctor, Sam.
I'm supposed to help people manage pain,
to beat illness, to stay healthy,
and I'm not doing any of that.
I need to help him.
We need to help him.
[SAM EXHALES]
Pete and I are going to sit
and we're gonna talk.
And it's possible
that we won't pay attention
to what you're doing.
Is it enough?
It's enough.
Better than a Petite Sirah, my dears.
L'chaim.
You can squeeze my arm
as hard as you like.
One step at a time.
Deep breaths.
People are staring.
They're staring at me.
They're wondering who is walking
the mother of the bride down the aisle.
[BOTH CHUCKLE]
- Here we go.
- Okay.
["PACHELBEL'S CANON"
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
[CROWD GASPING, MURMURING]
I did it.
Yes, you did.
No, I mean her.
If I had missed this...
You're going to be a very good mother.
- I love you, honey.
- I love you.
- You're in the closet.
VIOLET: I'm seeing
if it's any less scary in here.
[COOPER SIGHS]
- I like it.
- Me too.
I'm getting married.
[VIOLET LAUGHING]
Tonight.
[COOPER CHUCKLES]
I know, you think it's impulsive,
I think it's impulsive too.
But you know how I feel about her.
Just ignore me. It'll pass.
Me getting married is funny?
Yeah. I mean, no, no.
I mean, yeah, it is.
But, no, it's just that...
I'm pregnant.
You're pregnant?
[VIOLET LAUGHING]
And I don't know who the father is.
Okay. Should I slap you, like in a movie?
Cooper, we are two of the most emotionally
stunted people I've ever known.
We've never made any progress
in our personal lives.
We don't do personal growth.
And now here you are getting married
and I'm pregnant.
- And we're just growing all over the place.
- Okay, okay.
Shh, shh, shh.
Okay, breathe.
Just breathe.
Breathe, breathe.
Let it out.
[EXHALES DEEPLY]
There you go.
[WHISPERS]
Okay.
- Wanna talk about me or you first?
- Me.
- Okay.
- No, no, no, you. No, me.
Okay, um...
Well, I think you have to
ask yourself a question, Cooper.
Why now?
Why is Charlotte asking you now?
When her father has just died,
when she's full of grief.
She's hurting,
and she doesn't wanna hurt.
And this will make it all go away.
- I love her, Violet.
- Well, I'm not saying she doesn't love you.
I mean, you're lovable. It's just,
don't let her do this for the wrong reason.
Now me.
A baby.
- What do you wanna do?
- I don't know.
- Just stay in the closet a little bit longer.
- Okay.
[BOTH LAUGHING]
[PETE SIGHS]
How's he doing?
His respiration is slowing.
It shouldn't be long.
We're doing the right thing, Sam.
No, no, not that.
It's...
What if things don't work out
with Sonya?
- You're getting serious about Sonya?
- Well, any woman.
I mean, look at him. He's all alone.
He's me.
He's me in like 40 or 50 years.
He's more me than you.
At least you have an ex-wife, a child.
I have nothing.
I'll kill you.
When you're old.
I mean, if you wanted me to.
- Well, I'll kill you too.
- So it's a deal?
- Yeah, deal.
- Okay.
ALEXANDER:
Peter.
Peter, something's wrong.
My body feels heavy, heavier.
I don't think... Something's wrong.
It's not... I know it's not right.
Nothing's wrong. You're dying.
If this is what it feels like to be dying,
I don't like it.
It's...
Make it stop.
Please make it stop.
SAM: I have some Narcan in my bag.
- Make it stop.
- It reverses the effects of morphine.
- It's not too late.
- Make it stop.
Alexander, look at me, look at me.
Do you wanna do this?
Yes.
[ALEXANDER SNIFFLES]
- But I'm...
- You're scared.
I'm so scared.
You know, there's no one.
All the people are on the other side.
They're all dead.
Even when I was taking care
of my patients and watching them die,
I never knew how it was to die.
To die alone.
It's okay, it's okay, it's okay.
The world is gonna spin without me.
No one will remember I was here.
It's like I was never here.
You were here.
It's okay.
- He's gone.
- You were here.
You were here.
- He's gone.
- You were here.
- Pete.
He's gone.
He was here.
He was.
[SIGHS]
[SOBBING]
[COOING]
I love him.
Do you think he knows it?
That the person
giving him away loves him?
I think they're gonna
make sure he knows it, okay?
Okay.
Just make sure he studies.
Schoolwork
probably won't be his first priority.
He's got my nose.
And my dad and my brother
have the same nose,
and none of us
were very good studiers.
You're gonna have to watch him.
- Okay?
- Okay.
She's brave.
It's hard to do the right thing.
[SOBBING]
I let it go.
I'm not going to ask anymore.
I'm...
I'm sorry I kept asking.
I kissed another man.
Last Friday,
I walked into his office and...
I knew it.
And I wanted this to work,
but it's not working.
Because you kissed this other man.
No, because the kiss...
The one hour
you keep asking me about
is the one hour this past month
that I haven't had a knot in my stomach.
[SIGHS]
It's a nice place, Addison.
I hope you find someone who fits in.
[SIGHS]
Thong or floss?
You don't wanna marry me.
Spending the rest of my life with you
would be amazing.
But...
But I can't marry you
because you need to escape.
[SIGHS]
- I'm not trying to escape.
- Well...
Why don't you want any of our families
there? Why Vegas? Why right now?
Please.
You spend too much time with Violet.
- Stop trying to shrink me.
- Then tell me why.
This... I wanna marry you.
I wanna marry you.
Under a huppah,
with you in a big white dress,
in front of everybody I know.
- I can't do that.
- Why not?
Why not?
Because I can't walk down the aisle
without my father. Satisfied?
Is that enough shrinking for one day?
Because Big Daddy's dead,
and I won't go down an aisle without him.
[SIGHS]
So you wanna marry me or not?
- You're grieving, you need time.
- I don't need time.
If we do this now,
I think you're gonna regret it
and I think it's gonna end badly,
and I don't want it to end ever.
You need to grieve.
Your wedding day
should be the happiest day of your life.
Our life.
And I want you beaming
when you come down that aisle.
That's how our marriage should begin.
[GRUNTING, MOANING]
NAOMl:
Oh, my God.
[ARCHER CHUCKLES]
Hi, sis.
How do you like my new office?