- Previously on The Resident...
- Dr. Okafor frightens me.
- I want her to be my right hand.
- My thoughts exactly.
Who are you? Ms. Booth
works for QuoVadis Labs.
It's a cutting-edge
medical device company.
Medical devices are
even bigger than pharma.
Pacemakers, cochlear implants...
The kid was dying. I had to cut.
You don't make the
decision to cut. I decide that.
Tell me exactly what happened.
Who made the first cut...
You or Conrad Hawkins?
- Marshall is our new
chairman of the board.
- It's time to put this hospital
on a firm financial footing.
Stick to what you know,
and leave the business
to the big boys.
You better open your eyes.
He's certainly here
to scorch the earth.
You're a lot more like me
than you realize.
State your name for the record.
Dr. Conrad Hawkins.
You understand that
you're under oath?
I do.
Remember: "yes," "no,"
"I don't recall."
Where were you on the first day
that you encountered my client?
♪ All right, here we go ♪
♪ Hello, stranger ♪
When did the dizziness start?
About 15 minutes ago.
Aw, you're just a
little dehydrated.
I should have you back
out before the encore.
You said volunteers got in free.
And here you are.
In the parking lot.
What'd you think... You'd
be onstage with the bands?
I thought I'd me
able to see the bands.
The bathrooms
have a better view.
Then drink your way
to a bathroom break.
Ah, good, we can
use some extra hands.
Sorry, but I am
here for this guy.
Let's go.
One of the other
doctors called in sick.
- So...
- You took their shift.
Just a couple more hours,
and then I'm all yours.
No, that's fine. I'm sure,
uh, after a few beers,
any guy out there will seem
like a good dance partner.
- I'll dance with you.
- See?
Not dehydrated, you won't.
But seriously, if
you guys need help...
Go.
Somebody should
have some fun today.
I'll see you later.
I'll find you.
God, I really wanted to
see Scott Weiland live.
Well, that'll be tough,
since he's dead.
You're thinking of the
guy from Soundgarden.
No, that's Chris Cornell.
You're thinking of the guy
from Stone Temple Pilots,
who is Scott Weiland.
They're both dead?
Are you two done?
Oh, my God.
Somebody get help!
Nic! Nic!
The exit's this way, come on!
Go, go, go, go!
Nic?
- What happened?
- I found him like this. No pulse.
- I started compressions.
- Switch.
Yeah. I'll get help.
♪ ♪
32-year-old male found down
without a pulse. Now with ROSC.
- Multiple external injuries.
- BP 105/80. Heart rate 110.
- Did he get any fluids?
- Two liters. He needs a pan scan.
- Do we have any idea
what happened?
- Radio said
a couple speakers blew, but
everyone thought it was a bomb.
Blunt abdominal
trauma, hypotensive.
Are ambulances on a level zero?
- Yeah, patients
going all over town.
- Get ready
for a full house, people.
Open-arm fracture
and hemoptysis.
I need another large-bore I.V.
One, two, three.
I heard you need extra hands.
Bleeding's controlled.
All right, it's getting
pretty crazy in here,
but, uh, no more
improv surgeries, okay?
Our gunshot kid
during the blackout...
- He made it, didn't he?
- Yeah, but you barely did.
Bell put me on the spot,
asked me who made the first cut.
What'd you say?
Nothing.
But don't make me
cover for you again, okay?
Thanks.
Dr. Hawkins, they want
you in the VIP room.
Yeah, I'm a little busy.
- Well, someone's got to go.
- Hey, I got it.
I was about to go onstage,
play my set.
That's when I heard that noise.
Is everyone okay?
Let's focus on you
right now, Mr. Barrett.
Looks like you got
stomped on pretty bad.
Actually, I just
tripped backstage.
Is someone in the bathroom?
Hey, Tony.
Doc, this is Tony,
my sober companion.
Tony, this is Doc.
Tony's just making
sure the room's clean.
You'd be surprised what
people leave behind in hotels.
It's a hospital.
Maids leave stuff all the time.
How long have you
been sober, Mr. Barrett?
Almost a year.
Got to get that chip.
It did get ugly, though.
The more records I sold,
the more drugs I took.
I nearly drank myself
to death a few years ago.
Had to quit the tour,
take some time to dry out.
That show today was
supposed to be my big comeback.
You have a
possible tibia fracture.
While we get your X-rays
we'll get you on oxycodone
- for the pain, okay?
- No, no, no, no. No pills.
No booze, nothing.
Only vice I've got
left are these babies.
You want one?
I'm good.
We'll be back.
- Does he seem a little drunk to you?
- Yes.
Add a blood
alcohol test. Tox, too.
Got it.
Mm. So, Julian,
what do you advise
for an abdominal wall
this well-upholstered?
Try these retractors.
They're non-slip.
Designed for bariatrics.
I'm glad Prince Abdulraheem
requested you
personally, Dr. Bell.
We miss you down here.
Well, thank you, Jessica.
I love the Saudis.
Ideal patients.
They pay same day,
full price, in cash. Mets.
Pick-ups.
We still on for tonight?
Mm-hmm.
Dr. Bell is meeting my
boss tonight, Gordon Page.
He's throwing a
party for the CEOs
who do business with QuoVadis.
Yeah, I'm betting that a guy
who went from med school dropout
to start-up billionaire
in five years
can entertain like a rock star.
His open bar is epic.
He flies a mixologist
in from Miami Beach.
Oh. If you need a
plus-one, I'm free.
The pick.
See how we mind
the patellar tendon
as we saw the posterior tibia.
Retractor, please.
PCL, right?
That's right.
Oscillating saw's best
to resect damaged areas
of the proximal tibia.
Then we size the implants
and cement the components.
Oh, it's a beautiful
procedure, isn't it?
Go ahead, you try.
Get in there and
do the next cut.
You all right, dear?
♪ Well, I'm tired, so sick,
tired of breakin' down... ♪
♪ When you come around ♪
♪ And crossroads, alleys
and empty streets... ♪
Don't be too hard on yourself.
But time for a gut check.
Not too late to go
into dermatology.
Dr. Bell. Randolph. My man.
- Make an appointment.
- Amazing thing.
I checked the schedule, and
we're both available right now.
I'm on a much-needed break.
Which you'll share with me.
I let you get away
with this why?
Hmm.
I need to establish better
boundaries with staff.
Why, dear man, did you assign me
yet another moist
towelette of a resident?
What, Coleman? He graduated
Baylor at the top of his class.
He nearly fainted in my OR.
We're a teaching hospital.
Teach him, he can learn.
Who's this douche?
Head of the hottest new medical
device company in the country.
Also the most eligible
bachelor, I'm told.
Oh, come on, Bell.
We all know you're the
most eligible bachelor.
All our residents are standouts,
or they wouldn't be at Chastain.
I love Atlanta.
The street art, the craft beer.
A rough-but-ready Irishman
in Buckhead I've been
spending a lot of time with.
But have you seen the
surgical suites at Walter Reed?
Mayo and Stanford
keep calling, too.
I-I don't know how
they all get my number.
I may be able to find
you a replacement.
What? What is it?
A piece of bone.
Ah. It's an occupational hazard.
Keep me happy, Randolph.
What's your full name?
Josh Robinson.
Do you remember where you
were when you lost consciousness?
Uh, at a concert in the park.
Reviewing your chart, you've
had quite the interesting life.
How did you get
so many injuries?
Uh, well, this one,
heli-rafting in Queenstown.
Um, mountain biking in Morocco.
Heat stroke, passed
out. And, uh...
Death Drop in
Zambia, two years ago.
Still can't bend it right.
Someone knows how
to use their vacation time.
I'm a professional
adventure guide.
- Seriously?
- Yeah.
I just took a group free diving.
- Wow.
- Oh, nice.
You on any medications?
Uh, yeah. It's in my bag.
Oh, there it is.
- Do you mind?
- No.
You have injuries to
mark your experiences.
I get tattoos to mark mine.
I don't see any
prescription drugs.
These are all supplements.
Oh, Pharma. Bad juju.
Josh.
Do not get me
started on Big Pharma.
Milk thistle, kava
kava, omega-3.
Ironic you take all these
supplements to stay healthy
and you end up stampeded
by a bunch of drunk music fans.
Stampede? What stampede?
And that's when you
realized that my client
- passed out before the stampede?
- Yes.
And how many patients did
you treat that day, Dr. Hawkins?
I don't recall.
More than five? More than ten?
I'll tell you. 20.
Chastain strictly adheres
to ACGME guidelines.
How can one resident
possibly provide
the standard of care
to that many patients?
We do it every day.
Disturbing footage today
from the Hotlanta
Music Festival.
Liver and kidneys
have seen better days.
History of Crohn's, too.
So, lots of signs
of the rock star life.
I'm worried the swelling
from his injury could cause
too much pressure in his leg.
Could lead to poor blood
flow and muscle necrosis.
Compartment syndrome. So
if we don't relieve the pressure,
he'll lose the leg.
What's your plan?
Fasciotomy. I had Ortho
come check his pressures.
- Good.
- They're only at 20.
Well, watch it closely.
If it hits 30, they'll need
to operate right away.
Which is why I have
him on the OR's radar.
But the anesthesiologist said
he'd like to have him sober.
Well, his blood alcohol
concentration is .04.
Give him a few hours.
He says that he hasn't
had a drink in a year.
But his serum alcohol
level tells us he did.
Tests don't lie. Alcoholics do.
Yeah, maybe sober
companions, too.
How does one man
take all of these?
Those are just the supplements
that our adventure
guide remembers taking.
Kava kava was banned in Europe
for causing liver toxicity.
That might explain
all the bleeding,
- but not why he passed out.
- If I had to guess,
supplements and dehydration
caused an arrhythmia.
- Knocked him out.
- I'm glad you called.
My firm has over 50
years of experience
with neck injuries, right?
You say the ER doctor
didn't even order an MRI?
That's malpractice.
You know, I'm all for patients'
rights, but doctors' jobs
are hard enough without
these vulture lawyers.
And who gets sued
the most? ER doctors.
Patients need to be able to
sue. It's their only recourse
- for medical error.
- It's abused, and it leads
to cover-our-asses
overtreatment and overtesting.
Forcing doctors to
practice defensive medicine.
Well, let's just
focus on our patients
and ignore the vultures.
Thank you.
I understand that you and
Nurse Nevin are in a relationship.
- Correct?
- That's irrelevant.
Do you think working
with your girlfriend
could possibly have
affected your performance?
Objection. Argumentative.
No. Never. There is no better
nurse practitioner than Nic.
Your client was
lucky to have her.
Wouldn't you agree, Josh?
Easy.
Isn't it true
that you have a history
of deviating from protocol?
I know what you're trying to do.
You're suggesting I
put my patient at risk,
but you don't know a
damn thing about medicine.
Let's take five.
- Conrad.
- I know, I messed up.
I don't need to
hear it from you.
This lawsuit could
end your career.
You could even be
found personally liable.
And the hospital
won't stand by you.
Not everyone at
Chastain is on your side.
- But you are?
- Yes.
You have no idea
what this is like for me.
I know exactly
what this is like.
I get sued all the time.
Yeah, you probably
win every single one,
no matter what you say or do.
Oh, don't be naive.
What happened doesn't matter.
A doctor can do everything
right, and still get screwed.
Just control your emotions,
and let the
lawyers do their job.
I have to tell the
truth, no matter what.
Then you'll lose.
Maybe.
This metalhead is lucky
you brought her to me.
That paper-thin portal vein
could easily be ripped
by a mere mortal.
I can do the Pringle Maneuver.
I can do it better.
Observe. Right angle.
Well, I've done it before,
- flawlessly.
- Well, if there's nothing
left for you to learn,
Dr. Okafor, why are you here?
Good question.
Pressure's still dropping.
We must have another
bleeder in there somewhere.
- Give me another right angle.
- She's losing too much blood.
- Let me help.
- Too many cooks.
Can we think about the safety
of the patient and not your ego?
Yeah, in the words of
my colleague Dr. Seuss,
"With this brain in my head
and this blade in my hand,
I shall save every man,
woman and child in the land."
- That is not Dr. Seuss.
- It's an adaptation.
Let me break it down,
Okafor: my house, my rules.
Pressure's coming back up.
Course it is.
Oh, it's so good to be king.
I'm getting sick of the king
treating me like his valet.
I'll tell you what:
you can close.
Your life can
change in a moment.
Levi was born with a
congenital corneal disease.
He'd never seen his mom,
until a synthetic cornea
from QuoVadis made it possible.
Utilizing advanced
nanotechnology,
we provided better bio
integration, quicker healing...
I don't like being summoned.
You see, at QuoVadis,
we measure our success
by how much we improve
the quality of people's lives.
Which is why I'm so passionate
about our latest
breakthrough device:
a safer, a more effective
vagus nerve stimulator.
Remember that rep serving
free lunch with her device demos?
- Mm.
- This is her boss.
He's barely 30. His
company valued at $4 billion.
He's a salesman, Dr. Bell.
The first thing they
sell is themselves.
This talk of his has
over a million hits.
I find it quite moving.
What am I doing here?
Oh, I'm assigning you to Ortho.
Ha. Bell just made a funny.
I-I am not changing
my residency.
Well, no one said you
were. You're just rotating
through a different
surgical specialty.
This is a teaching
hospital, and when we said,
"See One, Do One, Teach One,"
we didn't literally
mean just one.
See mine, do mine, be mine.
Okafor belongs to me.
I belong to no one. I
chose general surgery.
Me, not you.
Well, my bad, Dr. Bell.
I now see the value in
Okafor doing a dance
with our friends in Ortho.
Happy hammering.
Dr. Okafor, lovely to meet you.
You come highly recommended.
What did Dr. Austin really say?
That you're extremely demanding,
and in need of an
attitude adjustment.
Also too talented for Ortho,
which he called
glorified carpentry.
That was rude of
him, but accurate.
You know what's
beautiful about Ortho?
When something
is broken, we fix it.
First up, full hip replacement.
Shall we go and give the
patient the ability to walk again?
Come on, just let
it go. Relax, relax.
LFTs just came in.
Let me guess.
Alcoholic liver disease?
Early stage.
Relax, relax, let it go.
Ingrid, what's going on?
We're having a party.
Are you sure all
he's had are IV fluids?
Oh, I never took my
eyes off him, I swear.
Does this thing
have a gas pedal?
Hey. What'd you slip him?
A drink? Pills?
Let me have a look at that leg.
I'm not drunk. I'm
sober as a judge.
Pressure's too
high. We can't wait.
All right, we need to
get him up to surgery,
or he'll lose his leg. Let's go.
It's his leg, but if he keeps
drinking, it won't matter.
You're up.
You want me to do the impaction?
Mm-hmm.
This hip replacement
needs to be attached firmly.
Think of something
bothering you.
Pissed you got reassigned?
Get out those frustrations.
The news reports
said hundreds of people
were injured at the concert,
most of them seriously, so
why am I only seeing 40 admits?
Where are the brain
injuries, the skull fractures,
the ICU admissions?
My understanding is
the serious cases all
went to Atlanta General.
All of them? We're a
level-1 trauma center.
Why are the EMTs not
sending us the serious cases?
Because Atlanta General
has a new EMT lounge.
They have a 72-inch
TV with sports channels
and a popcorn
machine with real butter.
They have a lounge
just for the EMTs?
I heard Trinity Memorial
is building a better one.
We don't even give
them stale bagels.
It's no wonder the ambulances
are going elsewhere.
Give us the room.
Maybe it's time you
start doing your job
and let someone else cut
open obese Saudi princes.
He requested the
chief of surgery which...
is me.
I've been doing due
diligence for the board.
Our costs are rising
and our profit
margins are shrinking.
Yeah, which is why
I have a meeting
with Gordon Page tonight.
Let me guess,
Chastain agrees to use
only QuoVadis medical devices
and in exchange,
Gordon gives us...
A 20% price cut to
boost our profit margins.
Strong deal for both sides.
I need a better one.
I've already told the board
not to worry because if
you can't land Gordon, I will.
I didn't have time to
go home and change.
Is this too wrinkled?
- No.
- Thanks.
There isn't a full-length
mirror in the ladies room.
I'll get right on that.
This party of
Gordon's is a big deal.
I don't get a lot of face
time with him. He's too busy.
I want to make a
good impression.
Oh, come on, Gordon
can't be tougher
than some of these
doctors at Chastain.
And you've been winning us
over since you walked in that door.
You got this.
I hope so. If I can be the one
to bring Gordon
and Bell together,
I could be looking at a
bonus, which I really need.
I'm helping my parents put
my little sister through college.
You're gonna do great, Julian.
Thanks.
Oh, hey, could
you do me a favor?
Sure.
I heard you're treating
Rhys Barrett in VIP.
If I confirmed that, I
would be violating HIPAA.
Just blink if he's here.
My parents would not
stop playing his albums
when I was a kid;
his songs are basically
the only ones I knew
until I dropped
out of high school.
I'm still not telling you.
Pretty please.
Wait, you dropped out?
I went back. Anyway,
I'll always have
a special place in
my heart for Rhys.
I know he hasn't
toured for years.
Drugs and alcohol, I guess,
which is such a shame,
but I will always be a fan.
I'd love to meet him.
So who's my biggest competition?
Trinity Memorial beats you
on cochlear implants by 15%
but doesn't come close
on caths or aortic valves.
St. John's will make a play.
Yes, but with the VNS,
Gordon wants
high-volume pilot hospitals.
- More patients, better outcomes.
- Well, for a guy
who just moved to Atlanta,
he certainly has settled in.
Gordon.
I'd like to introduce you
to the CEO of Chastain,
- Dr. Randolph Bell...
- Randolph Bell.
I've been looking forward
to meeting you, Dr. Bell.
Hope Julian here has
made herself useful.
Oh, she's been invaluable.
So I've done some reading
on your vagus nerve stimulator.
Is it everything I hear?
More. Yeah, we just
wrapped our European trials.
It exceeded all
our expectations.
We're gonna help so many people.
Well, I'd love to see
the data from those trials.
Previous VNS stimulators
have all had issues.
Not ours. But we'd
value your thoughts.
- Hey, Gordon.
- Ooh.
Can I introduce
you to the governor?
He's on our board.
His son suffers from
refractory seizures,
so we might have
some answers for him.
Governor.
You're even better
than your reputation.
I need opportunities
to hone my skills.
Lately, Dr. Austin
would rather show off his.
AJ does seem like
a grade-A narcissist.
He's also the most brilliant
surgeon I've ever seen.
No offense.
Well, you haven't
got to know me yet.
There are things I can teach
you even the Raptor doesn't know.
I'm listening.
♪ ♪
And one for you,
fresh from Havana.
Thank you.
Awful, what happened
today at that music festival.
Yeah, thank God no one died.
You know, you're
the only CEO here
who didn't tell me in
the first two minutes
how much they made from it.
Well, don't give
me too much credit.
To be perfectly frank,
we didn't do so well.
I'm impressed by your honesty.
I'm interested to
know more about you.
Were your parents in medicine?
My parents...
ran a hardware
store on Peachtree.
Worked seven days a week,
not that it got them anything.
- You wanted more?
- You know,
I just wanted them
to wake up one day
and not have to go in,
not have a job to do,
no bills to worry about.
And being a doctor seemed like
the hardest, best
thing I could become.
I'd have the power to
change their lives and...
Did you?
Well, they died while
I was still a resident.
They'd be proud if
they could see you now.
Look at you.
You're at the top of your game.
Well, I'm not done yet.
Look, I want Chastain to
handle the launch of your VNS
and-and I want us to negotiate
a financial relationship
that benefits us both.
I'm talking to several
CEOs who want the same.
Tonight? Enjoy the party.
I'm not ready to
make my decision.
They fixed his
leg, but get this:
Rhys's blood alcohol
actually rose during surgery.
He's telling the truth.
He's not drinking.
Which means to save his liver,
we have to figure out
what's really going on.
And...?
There's no explanation.
And what? We've
been watching him.
The only thing he's put
in his mouth is licorice.
And?
Those vines...
They're pure sugar.
I'm gonna order an EGD.
You snowboarded down a volcano?
- Yeah, I did.
- How is that even a thing?
You're a hell of a
risk-taker. I respect that.
You guys ever take,
uh, adventure vacations?
Last year I went to Rwanda
to volunteer with
Partners in Health.
That's the kind
of vacation I like.
Yeah, he slept in a tent, made
friends with the village goat.
Yeah, they gave
him to me as a gift.
They had this whole amazing
ceremony and everything,
but obviously, I couldn't
take him with me.
Hmm. And when
Conrad left, they ate him.
No.
I don't like to talk
about that part.
Wait a second.
What's going on here?
Mr. Robinson's arm had a clot.
- Correct?
- Yes.
I suspected disseminated
intravascular coagulation.
It's a blood
disorder that causes
simultaneous
clotting and bleeding.
Why did you think DIC?
The liver toxicity from
the supplements combined
with the traumatic injuries
from being trampled
used up his blood's
clotting factors.
His blood work
later confirmed it.
This is life-threatening,
correct?
It can be.
So you alerted your attending?
I did not alert my attending
because Mr. Robinson was stable.
The next step was
to remove the clot.
Continue advancing
the cath to the cloth.
And this is where we
confirm placement?
Yes. Inject contrast.
Once we get this clot,
we'll go down and
get the one in your leg.
So, you're saying
what's wrong with me
was caused by my supplements?
Aspirating.
Ah, it's an easy mistake.
Supplements are
completely unregulated.
People hear "natural"
and they think safe.
Good.
- So what's next?
- I want to monitor you
on low-dose heparin before you
go back to conquering the world.
Thanks, man.
You're a great doctor.
And if any of y-y-you...
What's happening?
Slurred speech.
Right-sided weakness.
There might be
another clot in his brain.
We need to get him to CT now.
How you doing, Josh?
Okay, one more minute.
Josh's heart rate's slowing.
His respirations are irregular.
And severe hypertension.
Cushing's triad.
That's not a clot.
That's a massive hemorrhage.
He needs surgical
decompression. Page Neurosurgery.
- He's starting to seize.
- His ICP's going up.
- Where's Dr. Jacobs?
- In a resection.
It'll be another ten minutes.
No, that's too late.
We need him now.
- Left pupil's blown.
- He'll never make it.
How long did you
wait for Dr. Jacobs?
The CTs show that
Mr. Robinson's hemorrhage
would have rendered
him brain-dead.
We have a right to know how
long Dr. Hawkins waited for Neuro
before taking matters
into his own hands.
It was an emergency. He
wasn't watching a clock.
Ju... Move on.
The burr should've
been performed
by a trained
neurosurgeon in the OR,
not a third-year in the hallway,
where my client was more
likely to contract the meningitis
that would put him on
a long road to recovery.
I had done them in Afghanistan.
You're not on a
battlefield, Dr. Hawkins.
Now answer the question.
Seconds?
Think back.
How long did you wait?
- How long...?
- I didn't.
Scrapings from
your stomach lining
stained positive for an
overgrowth of fungus.
Something called A.B.S.
I have abs?
Auto-brewery syndrome.
Sounds fun, but
I'm guessing it's not.
One cause of A.B.S. is
consuming so much alcohol
in the past that yeast
builds up in the stomach.
That yeast now turns
carbs into alcohol.
I'm making beer inside me?
Yeah, and these were making it
worse because sugars are carbs.
Well, they ought to
put that on the label.
We'll get you on an antifungal.
Cut carbs, stick to
meat and vegetables.
In a few hours, you'll
be sober again, for real.
Did you say, uh, low carbs
or no carbs?
You can thank me later.
For?
For talking to Bell
tomorrow and persuading him
to send you home to my OR.
I don't want those hands
picking up any bad habits.
I'm fine where I am.
My mentor, Dr. Abe Benedict,
studied under DeBakey himself.
It's a sacred lineage,
a genealogy of giants,
and you belong in that line.
I'm not interested
in being in your
line of giants. I am the first
of my own line... an ancestor,
not your descendant.
♪ ♪
How's the low-carb life?
I'll take it.
Good news is you'll recover.
And so will your
liver... if you stay clean.
I will. Thanks, Doc.
You all right?
Yeah.
I was pretty far gone
before I met Tony.
Honestly, I don't think
he thought I'd make it.
He couldn't get through to me,
but in the end, my fans did.
I started getting all these
tweets and DMs, letters.
I never realized
how much they cared.
Saved my life.
But some of them got
hurt at the park today.
Accidents happen.
It's not your fault.
I just wanted so badly
to hit that stage again,
to feel that crowd out there.
People who actually
came to hear me play...
I let them down.
No. No, you didn't.
Feels like it.
- Dr. Okafor's a natural.
- Give her a week.
She'll be missing
the delicate artistry of
our body's vital organs.
- You're worried I'll ruin her.
- She's an artist,
likely to become one of the
great cardiothoracic surgeons
of her generation.
Don't take that from her.
Did you ever think
maybe the best decision
is her decision?
You said we're
going to the cafeteria.
I lied. I had a better idea.
Because this hospital was
founded on a simple idea:
improve the health
and well-being
of Atlanta, and today,
Chastain's commitment
to this community
is as strong as ever,
which is why we are
forgiving the medical bills
of every single patient of ours
who's been affected
by this tragedy.
And we're asking all Atlanta
hospitals to do the same.
And we have a really
special surprise for you.
Mr. Rhys, I'm
Dr. Bell. Thank you.
They're all yours.
What do you think?
Good enough place
for a comeback?
You've earned it.
I know some of you
have been knocked down
and you're-you're hurting.
This is a song about how
we can help each other
get back up.
♪ I did everything I could ♪
♪ I did everything ♪
♪ I thought I should ♪
♪ I closed my eyes
so I could see ♪
Not bad.
♪ But in the dark I
could not breathe ♪
♪ I screamed until
I had no voice ♪
♪ I screamed and then I had ♪
♪ No choice... ♪
So you couldn't tell me
before that Rhys was here,
but now you can
tell the whole world?
I didn't call them.
Bell probably wanted
his philanthropy televised.
He always brings out his
best self in front of the cameras.
Forgiving patient bills
won't cost us much.
How much will the
other hospitals lose?
Millions.
And I hear the EMT lounge
you're building puts theirs to shame.
Oh, it'll pay for
itself in a month.
How about Gordon?
I'm closing in on him.
♪ Home again ♪
♪ I screamed ♪
♪ Until I had no voice ♪
♪ And then I had no choice ♪
♪ Signs along the
road are hard to see... ♪
- How's Josh?
- Not out of the woods yet.
At least he has
a fighting chance.
♪ Hey ♪
♪ Carry me back,
carry me back... ♪
You only came to that
festival to see me, didn't you?
Because I volunteered
on our day off.
That's not true.
I love live music.
You never go with me.
'Cause you sway the whole
time. It's like being on a boat.
- It's annoying.
- I do not sway.
You're a swayer.
Really?
Yeah.
All right, well, now
you're swaying.
♪ From myself... ♪
I won't make the same
mistakes. I will make time for us.
We're busy.
We both know what we
signed up for, but I will, too.
♪ Set me free ♪
♪ Yeah, you... ♪
Every day, doctors
make decisions.
Sometimes they're hard,
sometimes they're easy, but...
this is one of the easy ones.
Josh is here
because I took a risk.
I broke a rule to save a life,
and if I hadn't, he'd be dead.
But...
you know that.
We're done here.
You were right.
And it's time I stop
telling you what to do.
Will this be harder
to win at trial? Yes.
But we are both fighters.
We will win this your way, son.
And I will be with you
every step of the way,
if you will let me.
Thank you.
I get it.
A doctor saves you,
you come home grateful,
but rehab gets
hard, money dries up
and your future
doesn't look like
you hoped it would.
Soon, the doctor
who stuck his neck
out to save your ass
starts to represent
an opportunity.
It's not personal.
It is for me. Conrad's my son.
So here's what happens next.
I am having a nondisclosure
agreement drawn up as we speak.
It will be delivered
to you within the hour,
along with a generous check.
It is an off-the-record
settlement
that Conrad will
never know about.
You will sign it.
My son will be in the
cafeteria getting a coffee
before his next shift.
You are going to go
find him, apologize,
tell him you will not
be taking a dime,
shake his hand, and leave.
- And if I don't?
- Mr. Robinson,
I am a man of almost
unlimited means,
and I will use them
to keep you in court
the rest of your natural life.
Now, you seem like a nice kid.
I would hate to see
you broke, on the street,
buried in legal bills
you cannot afford to pay.
Because the truth is,
you can't win a
lawsuit that never ends.
So, the next time
someone saves your life,
just... say thank you.
♪ ♪
Captioned by Media
Access Group at WGBH