Throughout history,
traumatic experiences
have caused physiological
responses long after
the events themselves
have passed,
racing heart, pupil dilation,
nightmares, panic attacks.
How do you have so much energy?
Didn't you get home
at, like, 3:00 a.m.?
Exhaustion is a construct.
Mind over matter.
Stethoscopes or diplomas?
No.
Are those clip-ons?
You cannot wear those to
stand up in my wedding.
My dad likes to
commemorate accomplishments
with formalwear.
Your dad has questionable taste.
That's what my mom says.
We're going shopping.
My treat.
Oh, since you're
treating us to things,
can toilet paper be a treat?
Because we're out.
Mesopotamian soldiers depicted
these symptoms on cuneiform
tablets over 3,000 years ago,
yet post-traumatic
stress disorder
wasn't introduced as a
diagnosable mental health
condition until 1980.
Doing anything tonight?
Why?
Well, there's a new bar that
opened in my neighborhood.
It looks pretty cool.
I give it about a week before
the tech bros take it over.
Want to check it out?
Sounds like a date.
Nope, not a date.
Just two coworkers
getting a drink.
No, thanks.
Hey, look.
Would you really
rather be hanging out
with your 80-year-old
roommate and her friends
than get one drink with me?
Yeah.
It's a lesson we
learn in medicine
time and time again...
Just because we
don't have the words
doesn't mean the
symptoms aren't real.
Hey, Scout.
Should we show Jo and Luna what
we've been working on, huh?
Let's do it.
Ready?
A, B, C, D...
You've been learning
sign language?
I... I found an app that
teaches the ASL alphabet.
Now your face is telling
me that I screwed up.
Did I screw up?
I told you that I
needed more time.
We don't even have
her MRI results back,
her genetic testing.
You're... you're
learning sign language?
Ben, now, first you
save this man in a fire.
Now you're sitting
at his bedside?
You want me to sit with you?
No, you... you've got a crisis
of your own to deal with.
We're going to get through this.
All of it.
Yeah.
Mm.
What the...
Well, who let you in here?
Well, I had to restock the PRT,
so I thought I'd swing
by and say hi to you...
Hi... and my favorite patient.
You're so adorable, huh?
Yes, you are.
You couldn't get
supplies in Illinois?
Well, I could.
But Illinois just doesn't
have Connor, so...
No, they don't.
All right, you've had your fun.
My turn.
Come on, up, up, up.
Aw.
How is his mom doing?
Better every day.
OK. Up now.
Any pain there?
No.
Is there any way
to speed this up?
There's somewhere I have to be.
I'm going as fast as I can.
Oh, Dr. Adams, Dr. Millin.
This is Matt.
I just cleared his
C-spine, and I just need
you to get him up to CT.
How'd you hurt yourself?
Took a sword to the neck.
A foam sword.
It has a plywood core.
LARPing accident.
Why do you think I
would know what that is?
Live-action roleplaying.
The guys in the park
with the swords?
Now I see why you think
I would know that.
If his CT is negative, just
keep him here for observation,
to make sure that the
swelling in his trachea
doesn't compromise his airway.
Page me if you need anything.
Can I please just go now?
I feel fine, and
this is my only shot
to usurp the game master.
If I don't get back to the
park before sunset, that's it.
Well, if your trachea swells up
enough that air doesn't reach
your lungs, that is also it.
Statistically, what are the
chances of that happening?
Look, no disrespect, but
this game is make-believe.
Is it worth risking
actual death?
Depending on the
statistics, maybe.
Oh, I get it now.
This is about a girl.
Oh my god, not
everything is about love.
Princess Astrid of Dungeness.
See?
Unbelievable.
It was love at first sight.
For six years, I've loved her.
Today I shall declare it.
She is my destiny.
Good morning, Mr. Porter.
I'm Dr. Webber.
This is Dr. Yasuda.
We're going to be doing
your colonoscopy today.
Yasuda?
Russell Porter, 31.
Experiencing unintentional
weight loss and anemia.
Has a family history
of colon cancer.
Referred by his PCP for
a diagnostic colonoscopy.
Are you doing OK?
He doesn't like hospitals.
I'm fine.
Well, in about 15
minutes, you're not
going to know where you are.
It will be the best
nap of your life.
Sounds great.
Can I get a colonoscopy too?
Where are we?
We're in the hospital, baby.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Get this off of me.
- Look, Russell...
- Get it off!
- Russell, you're OK.
Who are you?
What... what's happening?
Why doesn't he
remember who I am?
Let's forget about
the colonoscopy.
And let's get a head CT.
And page Dr. Shepherd, OK?
- Yeah.
Hi, I'm Dr. Yasuda.
Do you want to just
come with me...
Get away from me.
Don't come near me!
OK. Oh my god.
Get away from me.
Any nausea?
Oh, yeah.
And the pain on your side
on a scale of 1 to 10?
7 most days, 9 on a bad day.
It's got to be stones, right?
I've always had trouble
with my kidneys.
What kind of trouble?
Had the right one removed
several years back.
But the pain is
currently on the right?
Left.
I had the left one removed.
Oh, I'm getting old.
Let's take a look.
Hey, is Dr. Bailey
working today?
I was looking on the internet.
It says she's the best doctor
here for kidney problems.
Think I could see her?
She's busy, but
I'll put in a page.
In the meantime,
we'll take some urine
samples and some images,
and we'll know more.
Oh, thanks.
I just don't want to mess
around with the only kidney
I have left, you know?
What are you doing?
Exercise.
Tox screen is negative.
Bloodwork only shows anemia
and mild renal impairment.
Hmm.
Grace said Russell's
been experiencing
some brain fog lately.
Pretty mild, until today.
She chalked it up
to a stress at work.
Ah.
Well, head scans are negative.
Are those what I think they are?
Russell, we see some
bullets in your scan.
When did you get shot?
11 years ago.
Went to the grocery
store for taco seasoning,
came out with three
gunshot wounds.
Can you imagine?
Surviving a shooting
and then having
to walk around with
metal inside you
for the rest of your life?
What were his symptoms, again?
Anemia, fatigue, weight loss.
And now he's exhibiting
brain fog, confusion.
I'll... I'll go test
his lead levels.
Put a rush on it.
He's been off the oscillator
for three days now,
and they're minimizing
the vent settings.
You're still getting calls?
You know, someone's
heart stops on my table,
I'm cool as a cucumber.
But the phone rings, and I...
Shake. I... I shake.
Because it's terrifying.
They're harassing you,
and it's relentless.
Ben almost died on duty
the other day, again.
So terrifying in
my life has layers.
Like, when the phone rings,
I don't know what I should
be panicking about first.
And it never stops ringing.
I just hope to
god these lunatics
will move on before I have
a second heart attack.
Wait a minute.
You had a heart attack?
How did I not know about this?
When?
Years ago.
It... look, it's... it's fine.
I'm fine.
Everything is fine.
If you're using
fine as a stand-in
for another four-letter
word, I can get
on board with that analysis.
OK. Nothing's fine.
This helps, though.
Yeah. Well, I find there's not
much that a roomful of babies
can't fix.
And old friends.
This is Dr. Hunt, our
head of trauma surgery
and an expert at
treating gunshot victims.
I don't understand.
What does this have
to do with his colon?
Nothing.
As it turns out, based
on his bloodwork,
Russell has lead poisoning.
The bullet fragments
in his chest
and his spine have
been leaching lead
into his bloodstream
and his spinal fluid.
That explains all
of your symptoms...
The intermittent confusion,
the forgetfulness.
Just like the episode
you had earlier today.
But the surgeon said it was
riskier to take the bullets
out than to leave them in.
Most of the time that is true.
The body forms scar
tissue around the bullets,
preventing lead from
getting into the blood
and the spinal fluid.
But in some cases, like
yours, that scar tissue
never forms and the best course
of action is to remove them.
So you remove the bullets
and my symptoms just go away?
Within a few days, your
lead levels will drop
and your symptoms will
gradually improve.
And what about his confusion?
There are no guarantees.
It could take weeks,
months, even years
for the encephalopathy
to subside, if at all.
So I can go through
all this and still
can't remember who my wife is?
Hey, it's OK.
I'm not going anywhere.
I'll just keep
reminding you, OK?
When I heard the gunshots,
I was in the cereal aisle.
I tried to find a place to hide,
but there was nowhere to go.
It was a grocery store.
I was totally exposed.
So I got down on my
knees, and I prayed
that I'd make it out alive.
But if I would have known
how much I'd suffer...
I know that feeling, Russell.
Listen, I am a survivor
of a shooting too.
Too many of us are.
It is a lifelong
struggle whether you
remove those bullets or not.
So in a way, you
have nothing to lose.
And who knows...
if we can take away
some of your physical
pain maybe that
could help take away some
of your other pain too.
OK.
Let's take them out.
- OK.
Dr. Shepherd?
It's Mika Yasuda
from Grey Sloan.
Dr. Hunt and Dr. Webber
told me to come get you.
We need a neuro consult.
Also, I really have to pee.
Bathroom's over there.
- You know what?
It was a false
alarm. I'm good.
Should we get you dressed?
Because... wait, wait!
Ow!
Dr. Hunt says I can't
leave without you.
Call the backup
neurosurgeon on call.
We have a patient
with a bullet embedded
in his thoracic spine.
It has to come out.
Dr. Hunt says you're the
only one who can do it.
Please.
- Fine.
- Great.
Uh, my van is out front.
You have to kind of,
like, lift and kick
the door at the same
time. But you know what...
I'll drive myself.
I'll see you there!
- Hey.
What are you doing here?
You hate pregnant women.
Don't say that.
It makes me sound
like an awful person.
But I do feel hives coming on.
- Yeah.
Uh, I'm just checking on you.
Well, I am waiting for
Luna's test results
to determine whether
her hearing loss is due
to an underlying disease.
Yeah, I know.
At daycare this morning,
there was this mom,
and she was fighting
with her kid
about taking off
his bike helmet.
And I just... I just
wanted to scream,
"This is not a real problem."
And I know it's all relative.
And the truth is,
is, I would love it
if my biggest problem
right now was Luna refusing
to take off her bike helmet.
Yeah, and don't we want to
encourage helmet wearing?
I'm going to stop trying
to make you laugh.
I might have all of these
decisions to make...
Hearing aids, cochlear implants,
sign language, things
that will affect her
for the rest of her life.
And it's not like
I can just ask her
what she wants in 20 years.
My job as a mom just changed
in the blink of an eye,
and I don't know if I'm
going to be very good at it.
I'm not a parent, but
I do have to deal with
the parents of my
patients a lot.
So I'm kind of an expert.
And what I know is that you
are not only good at it,
you are great.
And you're going to
continue being great.
You are a great mom.
Thanks.
Oh, and um, if you need
help with sign language,
I do know happy birthday,
my name is Levi, and, um, butt.
There. I did it.
My work here is done.
Watch where you're going!
What?
Hey.
Did Meredith tell you
to come check on me?
No.
I was actually
worried about Bailey.
Why do I need to check on you?
Uh, you know, I'm... it's fine.
Hey! Come on, Amelia.
It's me.
Spit it out.
Um, Mer moved, and
then Maggie moved,
and then Kai left me.
And so I've, um, pretty much
been abandoned by everyone.
And you know how well I
do with abandonment, so...
Amelia.
I have a consult.
We need to remove the
spinal bullet first
since it's most likely
causing the encephalopathy.
What about the scattered
fragments in the lung?
Can we do a
non-anatomic resection
of the affected lung tissue?
Yeah, good.
Please, go ahead.
Start without me.
We did.
Sorry, I got here
as fast as I could.
My van doesn't go
over 45, and I'll...
I'll stop talking now.
Assuming you can remove
the bullet in the spine...
Assuming I can?
You woke me up.
I assume that you
know that I can.
Amelia, we really don't have
time for whatever this is, OK?
You'll go first.
We'll remove the
bullet from the spine,
irrigate, close, and
flip the patient,
and then I'll start
the thoracotomy.
Anything else I should know?
Did you want to pick the
music for the OR as well?
Are there any other options
you would like to discuss,
Dr. Shepherd?
Nope.
Dr. Ndugu seems to
be in charge here.
Let's go with his plan.
OK.
Was that...
Definitely not about you.
All right.
OK.
Are you experiencing
an increase in pain?
Nope.
I feel great.
Whoa.
Whoa, where are you going?
To the park.
Do you know where my shoes are?
- Hey, no.
We need to keep you
a little longer,
just to make sure
you're out of the woods.
You're really going to
make me wait a full week
to tell Astrid I love her?
What's one more week?
Today when I almost died...
It was a foam sword.
I fought to keep breathing with
every molecule in my body.
I couldn't let myself
die without telling
Astrid how I feel.
You probably think
it's crazy, but I
don't even know her real name.
But I know her smile, and I
know what makes her laugh,
and I know her heart.
And I have to tell her.
Oh, you are full of
adrenaline right now.
You are not thinking clearly.
Or maybe he's thinking
clearly for the first time
in his entire life.
I mean, what if you go to
the park and Princess Astrid
doesn't feel the same way?
Or maybe she's been in love
with you this whole time too.
Yeah, I prefer his take.
Stop encouraging him.
This game is clearly your...
Your happy place.
Do you really want to trash
all of that for a girl whose
real name you don't even know?
You look like a princess, but
you have the heart of an ogre.
Correction... I
look like a goddess,
and I have the heart
of a person who
tells sad men the whole truth.
Or a troll.
She has the heart of a troll.
I'll give you your shoes
back when I discharge you.
The urinalysis and X-ray
both came back negative.
Next steps?
Run an ultrasound to fully
rule out kidney stones.
Good.
What do you need me for?
He said he only had one kidney,
but there are clearly
two in the films
and he doesn't have
any surgical scars.
Also, he asked for you.
I told him you were busy, but...
Is it... hello, sir.
I'm Dr. Bailey.
Go ahead, Kwan.
Been looking forward
to meeting you.
I'm, uh, flattered.
Dr. Kwan is one of
our finest interns.
He's going to be
doing an ultrasound...
How are the kids?
Oh.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Have I treated you before?
No, no, no, no, no.
Just a... just a fan.
How's the new place?
Boys settling in OK?
Excuse me?
Young Pruitt's been
through so much.
I mean, it would be a real,
real shame if something else
were to happen.
Ultrasound is negative.
Uh, you can discharge him now.
Oh, now, hang on.
Is that how you
treat your patients?
Sir, sit back... sit down.
Or do you only extend
common courtesy
to other murderers, huh?
Come back here.
I'm not finished with
you, Dr. Baby Killer!
Call security!
Hey!
This isn't over!
Just stay down.
You know, I thought
we were friends.
Or at least colleagues
who respected each other.
Amelia, what is going on?
What's going on is, you
let one of the only people
in the world who cares
whether I eat a hot meal
or sleep for more than
four hours in a night
move to Chicago.
You know as well as I do
that no one let Maggie move.
You're her husband, and
you let your ego destroy
what was once true love.
OK.
I get that she's your sister,
so there are sides here.
But that is an
oversimplification.
Maggie will rise
and rise and rise,
and she will go on to
do even greater things,
and you will always
be in her shadow.
And she may go on to
forgive your smallness,
because that is how great
she is, but I'm not.
I won't.
If you need anything
to make sure
that Dr. Bailey is covered at
all times, just say the word.
Thank you.
Chief Altman, I
wanted to apologize
for attacking that patient.
I know there are protocols
in these situations...
The patient wasn't attacked.
He fell while he was
attacking Dr. Bailey.
Um...
That is the story as I heard it.
So this won't go in
my file somewhere?
I'm confused.
Did something happen between
you and the abusive patient?
If so, I know nothing about it.
Is that him? Is that him?
Yes.
But, Warren, listen to me.
We both know that that won't
help either of you, OK?
That intern over
there, he's the one
who took the bastard down.
Why don't you put this manic
energy to better use and go
over there and thank him?
- Fine.
- OK, great.
But if you wouldn't
mind telling the bastard
that Dr. Bailey's husband
is a firefighter who breaks
into houses with
his ax for a living,
and I'm going to find out where
he lives, I'd appreciate it.
OK, I got it.
I got it.
Thank you.
Yasuda, slowly retract
to help expose the dura.
I need better visualization.
Retractor.
Yasuda.
I'm so sorry.
I don't know what happened.
I'll tell you what happened.
You were not paying attention,
and our last sterile retractor
is on the floor. Pick it up...
OK.
And get out of my OR.
Is that really necessary?
We can get a replacement
in one minute.
Do you want to be
kicked out too?
I really am so sorry.
It won't happen again.
Not with me, it won't.
You are no longer
welcome on my service.
Out!
Is he... He's doing great.
Dr. Shepherd
successfully removed
the bullet from his spine.
She's finishing up, and
then Dr. Ndugu will start
on the fragments in his lung.
OK.
That's good, right?
Very good.
OK.
I'm sorry.
No. No apologies.
It'll be a few hours if you want
to go home and get some sleep.
You know, he never told
me what happened that day.
We were newlyweds, and he calls
me from the hospital saying
he was grocery shopping
and a guy comes in
and just opens fire.
And that's all he ever said.
He didn't want to talk about
it, he didn't want to feel it.
But I knew he did, because we
were planning on having kids.
And then after that
day, we weren't.
I've tried so many times
to talk to him about it,
because how can
somewhat live with all
that trauma inside of them?
I always worried that
it was eating away
at him emotionally, you know?
I never thought that
it could be killing him
slowly, physically.
We're going to make sure
that does not happen.
Sorry.
I know you're busy.
Go. Go, go.
It's OK.
I have a few minutes.
Thank you.
Hey.
Hot chocolate.
Figured you could
use some good juju.
If you wanted something else,
you could have just said so.
Thought that would
make me feel better.
OK.
Come on.
Yell at me.
Pretend I'm him or them.
All of them.
What do you want to
say? Yell it at me.
No, I'm not...
Miranda, he knew your
daughter's full name.
He knew my daughter's full name.
He threatened my child.
You... you would hurt
a four-year-old girl
in the name of life?
As if you give two craps
about life or about children
or about the welfare of
any other human other than
your own self-righteous...
I mean, as if you actually
cared about making
the world a better place.
As if... as if you
listen to anything
your own religion tells you.
But you would hurt a child...
My child... for what?
Just to prove a point?
And then you have the nerve
to call yourself pro-life?
Well, shame on you.
No, you are what is
wrong in this world.
Not me, not my family, not my
child, you sick son of a...
No. No.
Because my mother used to say,
"Kill 'em with
kindness, Miranda."
I just wish that I could
kill them with the truth.
Maybe there's a
way we can do both.
He was a huge guy, and I...
I should have been scared,
but all I could think about
was saving Bailey.
You're so brave.
Look at her.
She's practically salivating.
And over Kwan?
Yeesh.
- You jealous?
- No.
Hmm, kind of seems like you are.
I'm embarrassed for her.
It's not a character flaw
to want to be with somebody.
Are we still talking about me,
or are we talking about you now?
We lost his airway.
Code blue!
- We'll get him on oxygen.
Come on, man. Come on.
Come on. Come on. Come on.
Code blue. Code blue.
No pulse.
We need to intubate
him now. Start CPR.
All right. Starting
cardiac compressions.
All right.
Code blue.
There's too much swelling.
I can't visualize the cords.
We need to crike him.
We're interns.
We have to wait
for Dr. Schmitt.
Page Dr. Schmitt.
Page everyone.
I can't do this. I
can't watch him die.
We'll be fired!
You can leave if you want to.
I'm saving his life.
Code blue.
There's a crike
tray in the drawer.
All right, but wait.
We should put an IV bag
underneath his shoulder blades.
I saw Dr. Hunt do it.
It'll open up his neck.
Code blue.
Does anybody see Dr. Schmitt?
OK, let's do it.
Just don't kill him.
Thank you, Dr. Shepherd.
We'll update you
when we're finished.
She's angry that
my wife left me.
Doesn't seem quite fair.
When Amelia is angry,
she is rarely fair.
Yeah.
All right, Griffith.
Talk me through this.
What's the move?
Use the cautery to
demarcate the line,
and then pass over it
with the GIA stapler.
Good.
Now show me.
You want me to do it?
With all due respect,
are you sure?
Dr. Pierce always said that...
Dr. Pierce doesn't
work here anymore,
and I think you're ready.
GIA stapler.
Position the
stapler, and fire it.
Uh, the edge is bleeding.
OK. How do you stop it?
Ndugu, there are
multiple bleeders.
Maybe you should take over now.
Hunt, kindly back off.
Griffith, listen to me.
If you stop now, the
next time this happens,
you'll panic even more.
You can do this, all
right? I know you can.
Just focus.
Take a deep breath and think.
2-0 vicryl on a pass, stat.
Forceps.
Come on.
Come on. Come on.
Sutures are holding.
Well done.
Let's proceed.
Is he going to be OK?
When something goes wrong,
your job is to page me and do
nothing until I get there.
I paged code blue, but
he was dying, so...
Is he OK?
I need to be sure that you
understand that if he doesn't
make it, your career is over.
All that training for nothing.
All you had to do
was wait two minutes.
He didn't have two minutes.
If Adams hadn't stepped
in he would be in a coma
right now or worse.
It's tough enough
to pay back student
loans when you are a doctor.
When they pull your
license because you sliced
a patient's neck with no
one there to supervise you,
it's way harder.
You did the crike well.
You saved his life.
I'm admitting him to the ICU.
Oh, thank god.
Oh my god.
That fear you're feeling?
Remember it next time and wait.
Um, thanks for
sticking up for me.
Well, we couldn't let him die
without declaring his love
for a fictional character.
What's your deal?
Are you really just,
like, anti-love?
I went to med
school in Colorado.
I had a crush on
a guy in O-chem,
and that's where he was going.
My mom encouraged me,
because according to her
love is not only everything,
it is the only thing.
And first semester, I
failed gross anatomy,
because I was at
his birthday party
instead of studying
for my final...
His birthday party
where he called me Jane
and then made out
with my best friend
at the end of the night.
My grades recovered,
but surgical internships
are so competitive.
That's why I'm in the program
for rejects and losers.
Because my parents
taught me to value
an obsessive crush over
my grades and my medical
school aspirations.
Have you ever thought
that maybe there's
a difference between a
stupid, obsessive crush
and actual love?
You sound exactly
like my mother.
Oh, hey.
You will not believe what I
have been dealing with today.
You OK?
We removed, uh...
bullet fragments
from a mass shooting
survivor today.
And while we were in the OR,
there were two more shootings.
I... I don't recognize
our country anymore.
Weapons of war in
grocery stores,
at parades and schools, active
shooter drills in third grade.
We used to be
horrified, you know?
We used to grieve as a nation.
But now... now it
happens so frequently,
we don't even blink.
And nothing changes.
And I feel hopeless.
Hey.
So I have an idea.
You're either going
to love it or hate it.
Dr. Shepherd, I just want
to reiterate how sorry I am.
You lost focus while I had
my hands inside a man's back.
He is the one that you
should be apologizing to.
He is the one who trusted
you while he was unconscious
on an operating table.
You don't let yourself
get distracted when
people are depending on you.
When they are
vulnerable and scared,
that is when you give them
everything that you've got.
That is when you stay
alert long enough not
to drop a sharp metal
object while someone's
spine is exposed.
I... I didn't drop it in him...
I'm sorry, you're
defending yourself?
What is wrong with you?
I'm really asking.
Yasuda, what is wrong with you?
Do I really need to answer that?
No, you don't, Yasuda.
You can go.
You, come with me.
- Addie?
- Richard, Uh, yeah.
I'll find you later, OK?
Are you high?
No.
Is that the truth?
No, I'm not high.
Are you using again?
No. I can't sleep,
I... I can't eat.
I am a wreck.
I am not using. God.
OK, great.
Then I'm going to go ahead and
love you enough to tell you
to pull your head out of
your self-obsessed ass
and get to an AA meeting,
because the world
is already on fire.
We don't need you burning
anything else down, all right?
And I know you're in
pain, and I know that you
feel it more than most.
But get to a meeting,
say a damn prayer,
call your sponsor, then eat
something and figure out a way
to be of service to
this broken world,
instead of adding
to everyone's pain.
Because it starts with you
trashing everybody else,
and it ends with you back in
rehab again, if you're lucky.
No one has abandoned
you, Amelia, OK?
Everyone is just doing
the best that they can.
I love you, and everyone else
is just barely surviving,
and it has nothing
to do with you.
I love you, and you need
to make the decision
to stop the spiral.
And if you can't do it,
you need to find someone,
get someone to help you stop it.
I love you, Amelia.
And you've got to
get off the damn ride
before it's too late.
I know that we've all been
worried about Dr. Bailey.
What she is going through
is frightening and invasive,
and how it's not against
the law is beyond me.
What I do know is that it
is easier to hurt a stranger
than someone you know.
Dr. Kwan is handing out
lists of Dr. Bailey's
most frequent callers.
If you're wondering what
you can do, call them.
Talk to them.
Be respectful, be kind.
Be familiar.
And maybe they will
think twice about picking
up that phone again.
Ooh ooh ooh ooh
Dr. Bailey would
like you to know
she's praying for you too.
Mm-hmm.
Talks about revolution
But even though she
disagrees with you,
Dr. Bailey respects
your beliefs.
I'm a better surgeon because
Dr. Bailey is my teacher.
Well, you know, when I
see Dr. Bailey in the ER,
I feel better, because I know
my patient is in good hands.
And, Linda, the
clinic she founded
is for so much
more than abortion.
We deliver babies there.
I'm sorry it freaks
you out, but how
do you think Dr. Bailey feels?
Your prayers have been received.
And we are praying
for you as well.
Dr. Bailey loves her family
and wants to keep them safe,
which I'm sure you
can understand.
Above all else, Dr. Bailey
is an incredible person,
and I am privileged
to call her my friend.
This is Dr. Winston Ndugu
calling from Grey Sloan.
Colleague of
Dr. Miranda Bailey's.
I understand you were
trying to get ahold of her.
We wish you and
your family well.
All right. Take care.
Watching the world
wake up from history
How are you feeling?
Better.
A little bit better.
Can I help you?
I... I'm looking for, um...
This is going to sound so weird.
I don't know his name.
Would you happen to
be Princess Astrid?
He talked about me?
He's sedated right now.
But when he wakes
up, I'm sure he'll be
very happy to see you.
I had wondered what
was done to you
To give you such
a taste for flesh
Are they all gone?
We got every last piece.
You did great, Russell.
Didn't feel
much of a choice
Russell, you OK?
I didn't realize how
much I hated having
those bullets inside of me.
And now they're gone.
They're finally gone.
Baby.
Hope your memory is
less vivid than mine
And is free from that
awful maple light
Hello?
Speaking.
Just done it in the dark
So the pictures
didn't burn so bright
OK.
Thank you.
But I forgive you now
Excuse me.
Sorry.
Release you from
all of the blame
Link!
What happened?
She's OK.
Luna's OK.
She's... she's healthy,
and she doesn't have
tumors or cancer or anything.
So it's just isolated
hearing loss?
Yeah.
And the technology's
come a long way,
and we can learn sign language.
And you did learn sign language,
because you're so wonderful.
And I... I was an
ass, and I'm so sorry.
I did a stapled lung
resection today.
Whoa, are you serious?
It was terrifying and also
the coolest thing I've
ever done in my entire life.
OK, I hate you right now.
But congratulations.
- Thanks.
I, um, did an
emergency crike today.
It was pretty badass.
- What?
- Yeah.
Why didn't you open with
that? Did you get in trouble?
That's Trey.
I got to call him, but
don't forget anything.
I want a full play-by-play
when I get home.
I need you to be
Simone's maid of honor.
No, thank you.
I'll do all your scut
until the wedding.
Even my disimpactions?
Yes.
You must really love her.
You sound just like your mom.
Hey.
I haven't been to this
bar, so if it's bad...
Dramatic events
are turning points.
There's a before and an after.
It might all fall apart
Built this house
on quicksand
Sometimes it's hard to remember
who you were before.
- Come in.
- Hey, do you have a minute?
One.
I'm about to run out the door.
- OK, I'll be quick.
I just wanted to make
sure I'm being considered
for chief of cardio.
I have a sterling record, and
I'm committed to teaching.
I think I'd be good at it.
I want it.
I'll take it into consideration.
All right. Thank you.
Yeah.
Helm.
What are you doing here?
When I burned out,
nobody stood up for me.
So I'm standing up for Yasuda.
Because if she can't afford
to pay her student loans
and also eat and
live while she's
learning how to save
lives, there is something
wrong with the system.
And I know... I know it's
been broken for a long time,
but that is not a
reason not to fix it.
And you're chief of surgery.
So hey, congratulations,
it is your job
to figure out how to
support your interns instead
of using and abusing
them and then throwing
them out with the trash.
Please please
And it's even
harder to figure out
who you are after.
Well, so far, so good.
I mean, Chicago is freezing.
It is no joke.
But, um, the lab is incredible.
Well, that's good.
Are you making friends?
Yeah, everybody's been
pretty nice so far.
And is your apartment good?
Oh, I have floor-to-ceiling
windows with a lake view.
Honestly, I think
everybody complains
about the weather to keep
the real estate a secret.
Uh, Maggie, I got to go.
It looks like your sister
might need a friend.
Thank you for
looking out for her.
Yeah.
Dr. Shepherd?
You keep holding on
I am also in an alcoholic,
self-obsessive spiral
about abandonment, and I
could really use a meeting.
Let me exhale
But if you look for your people
and hold them close...
I still can't believe you
drove all the way out here
for one day when you could
have had everything you
needed shipped right to you.
Were you doing a
wellness check on me?
What, do you think I
could stay away when
you're going through hell?
No way.
We're in this together.
You exhale
"This should keep you
in business for a while.
"Keep fighting.
Yang."
All right.
Let's load her up, then.
Let me exhale
You will find your way again.
Ahh.
All righty.
Fantastic.