That's okay, Eileen. I got this.
You sure?
Yeah, you get home.
Thanks, Danny. See
you in the morning.
I'll be here.
Food's gone,
Daryl. We're closed.
You wouldn't happen to have
an extra coat in there, would you?
You're wearing a coat. A
winter coat, man. It's cold.
Come on.
Here.
Rangers? You expect
me to wear this in Jersey?
Come on, man, where's
your sense of humor?
Good night, Daryl.
Go away.
That's not funny, freak.
No one is laughing, Daniel.
You doing anything Friday?
I'm taking a lovely young
lady to the Philharmonic.
Is that your way of saying
you're having sex with a hooker?
Two. Can't create a
harmonic with just one.
Well, I was hoping you might be
available for Rachel's Simchat Bat.
It's a...
Jewish baby naming ceremony.
A time-honored tradition, dating
all the way back to the 1960s.
My house at 7:00.
It'll just be the rabbi and a
few friends and some family.
Nothing like welcoming
a baby into the world
with a completely naked
display of hypocrisy.
There'll be plenty of wine
and nice people
you can quietly mock.
Wish I could,
but I already put down a
deposit on 16 crates of Jell-O.
House.
It's one evening. I'd
like you to be there.
Religious hokum against sponge
bath. Can I get back to you?
Can I help you?
Just browsing, thanks.
Happy to be
underachieving again?
Running the ER
is slacker heaven.
Looking for anything
in particular?
Not anymore.
Where's this guy? Why?
'Cause he's my next patient. It'd be
rude of me not to introduce myself.
He's a drunk priest
who hallucinated Jesus.
Afraid you might have
missed something?
Afraid you're wasting
everyone's time?
It's obviously either
alcohol or exhaustion.
So, you admit you
have no idea which?
I admit that I'm too busy to
care who you're screwing with.
Don't thank me.
Just knowing I can be of
assistance is thanks enough.
You went out of your way
to pick him? This is nothing.
There are no small cases...
Any guesses where
this joke is going?
Could be psychomotor epilepsy.
Could be alcohol.
Shouldn't we let the ER
rule the obvious out before...
Could be atropine
toxicity, occipital lobe tumor.
You know something about
this case you're not telling us?
Why would you think that?
'Cause you wanna screw with us.
Or screw with a
hallucinating priest.
Both are possible. There's
only one way to find out.
Run an EEG for epilepsy,
CT his brain for tumors.
And go check his
house of God for toxins.
Fourteen, hold up.
This department is broken,
and I'm not going to take
a real case until it's fixed.
Job or relationship,
your choice.
What?
To put it in terms you
might better understand,
if you don't split,
you must quit.
The drug trial is
over. I'm out, she's out.
Don't care.
We're adults, we
can handle this.
You just have to
give us a chance.
No, you're not, no, you
can't, and, no, I don't.
Mull it over. You got till the
end of this fake case to decide.
I wasn't drunk.
I had one or two drinks.
People often underestimate
alcohol's effect on their...
I was on my way to six. I
know how alcohol affects me.
This wasn't the alcohol.
You lived in Manhattan for
three years, then a year in Oregon,
18 months in New Mexico,
less than a year in Wisconsin,
and now you've been living in
Trenton for the last six months.
Yeah.
The more we know about you,
the more likely it is we can help you.
Mmm. It's not
medically relevant, so...
No way to know, unless
you went to medical school.
Four years ago, a teen in
a youth group at my church
accused me of
inappropriate contact.
I was innocent, but the
church decided to transfer me,
said it would be
easier for all involved.
When the parishioners at the new church
got wind of why I'd been transferred,
they were unhappy.
I was sent off again and again.
And how is any of
that medically relevant?
So, the kid lied?
He was confused.
Confused whether you
molested him or not?
Okay, you wanted to know why I
moved around so much, and I told you.
How about telling me
why I was hallucinating?
Syphilis could explain
the hallucination.
I'm not sexually active.
You don't have to admit
you did anything with the kid.
You weren't always a priest.
I wanted to be since I was 12.
I entered the seminary
when I was 17.
Maybe it wasn't a hallucination.
Maybe it really was Jesus.
I'm not insane.
Seeing Jesus makes you insane?
Bit of an odd attitude
coming from a priest.
Well, it's just a job now. The
fairytale ended a long time ago.
You're a wuss,
part wimp, part puss.
I have no choice. I'm
part of the ceremony.
I thought you were
already circumcised.
It's one night for a friend.
What about the friend who has two
tickets to see Brubeck at the Blue Note?
I thought you had
an orgy planned.
I lied.
Are you lying about
the Brubeck tickets?
Yes, but only to save
you from yourself.
I'll be fine, and so will
Cuddy, if you don't show up.
I'm surprised she
even invited you.
It is oddly flattering.
God, I'm so sick
of his stupid stunts.
Everybody has to put up
with their boss' stupid stunts.
No, they don't. There's HR,
there's Cuddy, there's other jobs.
House doesn't listen to HR, Cuddy'll
let him fire us before she fires him,
and I don't want another job.
Why do you cling to him?
Why do you defend him?
Just because I don't want to be
unemployed doesn't mean I'm co-dependent.
I'm not saying you're co-dependent,
I'm saying you're scared.
You know what? You're right.
So, you wanna quit?
No, I wanna stop a stupid stunt.
House doesn't want either
one of us to quit. He wants this.
He's got two lab rats in a maze
and thrown in one piece of cheese.
So, what do we do?
Nothing.
Cool.
It's cool he's a child molester?
It's cool that a priest
doesn't believe in God.
It's cool that God did to
him what he did to the kid.
Allegedly.
You think he's innocent?
He had honest eyes?
And you think he's guilty, which
explains why you're dying to discharge him.
I'm dying to discharge
him because he's not sick,
not because he's a
pedophile. Allegedly.
You actually believe
the kid got confused?
If everybody lies, that
includes teenage boys.
Aren't we lucky to have
such an interesting patient?
Had. There's nothing
wrong with him.
World's most boring case
just became a page turner,
and you want to tear
out the last chapter?
You want to examine his
character, go to his soup kitchen.
We're done testing him
for things he doesn't have.
Bad news for
Foreman and Thirteen.
Case is over.
We're not splitting up.
So, which one of
you is taking a hike?
And neither of us is quitting.
Interesting.
You were fine with Chase
and Cameron dating.
You obviously don't
actually have an...
You're fired.
How long you gonna keep this up?
We know you're
not... Wrong. Again.
In fact, in the last few weeks,
it's hard to remember
a correct call you made.
If Chase had compromised his
professional judgment to help Cameron,
I would have fired his ass, too.
When my mistake blew up,
you did everything to keep me
from contacting the drug company.
To save your
license, not your job,
and definitely not
your relationship.
So, badge.
Fine.
Why don't you see if you
can find us a real case?
How can you discharge me when
you have no idea what's wrong?
We know what's wrong, and
now that you've slept it off...
It's not just the hallucination.
I feel nauseous, my foot feels
numb, like it's fallen asleep.
You didn't mention that before.
I didn't notice it before.
Are you hiding from someone?
Why are you so
intent on staying here?
I don't feel well. I know there's
something wrong with me.
Which foot?
My left.
Oh, God.
What the hell is
that? What is that?
Your toe just fell off.
Must be my lucky day.
New symptom means the old
symptom was a real symptom,
and I get to keep our
pederast priest after all.
Where are Foreman and Thirteen?
They left.
Leprosy could cause
necrosis and hallucinations.
Why would they leave?
Because Foreman
doesn't work here any more,
and Thirteen is
mad that I fired him.
Don't worry, she'll be back.
She'll be pissed off,
she'll want to take a stand,
and then Foreman will
convince her there's no reason
both of them should
be out of a job.
Leprosy's a bad fit.
Why'd you fire Foreman?
I gave him a
choice, split or quit.
He chose neither.
How about ergotism?
He's giving up
his career for her?
this career for her.
No, normal white blood count.
Carbon monoxide poisoning?
They're good doctors.
Separately, they're
great doctors.
Better than you.
Together they're morons.
Go, check out the house that they would
have checked had this been a real case.
And page Thirteen, tell
her to run the blood for CO,
and get the priest in a hyperbaric
chamber before anything else falls off.
So, what are we gonna do now?
I get a letter of recommendation
from Cuddy and find a new job.
Oh, that's it? You're
just gonna give up?
House was right. Our
relationship did affect my judgment.
Then I should quit. It'll be
easier for me to find another job.
Not like this one.
We should both quit.
What's that gonna accomplish?
Don't worry, I'll be fine.
We'll be fine.
Go ahead.
I'll see you tonight?
I'll be home early.
You really think House
is done with Foreman?
If you ask me, Foreman
should be done with Thirteen.
He's not gonna get a better job,
which means he'll end up
resenting her for losing this one,
which she'll end up resenting.
Or the hardship will
bring them closer together,
she'll invite friends over
for Foreman to share.
No leaks from the heater.
She's not a nympho,
she's bisexual,
which, by the way, means
she's accustomed to partners
who don't need a map
to find the treasure.
CO poisoning might have
come from these cigarettes.
Not unless he was
smoking them in a bell jar.
And even if you know
where the treasure is,
it can still be pretty hard
to dig it up without a shovel.
You can buy a shovel.
Let's see, how do I keep House
from ruining my precious
display of religious hypocrisy?
I know, I'll pressure
him to attend,
knowing that he'll never agree to
anything I actually want him to do.
I didn't pressure
you, I invited you.
And there's nothing hypocritical
about recognizing your heritage.
So, you keeping kosher now?
Wearing four-cornered garments?
Slaughtering heifers
to the god Ra?
Wait, is that one
of your people?
Do it all, do
nothing or option C,
you're a liar and a hypocrite.
House, for better or for
worse, you are a part of my life.
It isn't a ploy, it's
a sincere invitation.
I honestly want you to come.
Wouldn't miss it for the world.
I'm glad.
You idiot. I was free and clear.
Now he's coming,
and it's your fault.
Since when have
your failed attempts
at communication through
lies become my fault?
Since you forgot how
to keep your mouth shut.
You messed it up, and
now you're gonna fix it.
And you're gonna
keep my name out of it.
- How is he?
- Stable.
Necrosis doesn't
look to be spreading.
I was talking about Foreman.
Is he really gonna leave?
That's usually what people
do when they get fired.
Why are you biting my head off?
I was just wondering
what he was gonna do.
You're right, I'm
sorry. It's not your fault.
It's not House's fault, either.
He gave you guys a
chance, you blew it.
He didn't give us a chance,
he gave us an ultimatum.
I would have thought five years
here would buy a mistake or two.
Help me!
Help me.
I can't breathe. Feels like
someone's sitting on my chest.
Looks like a heart attack.
I assume you've heard.
I can't override him.
I'm not asking
you to override him.
I'm asking for a letter
of recommendation.
Eric, the reality here is,
House should have fired you.
You falsified medical records,
put this hospital's
reputation in jeopardy.
You're lucky you
still have a license.
I can't get a decent position at another
hospital without a recommendation.
I'm sorry.
Chest pain wasn't angina.
EKG ruled out heart attack.
So, the good news is, he
didn't have a heart attack.
The bad news is, I
apparently fired the only guy
who actually knows what
a heart attack looks like.
So, the man of God who
doesn't believe in God
had a heart attack
that isn't a heart attack.
Do I know how to pick
awesome cases or what?
Could be a clotting disorder.
Three different symptoms,
three different clots?
I know. How cool is
that? You two do an angio.
You don't want to work, so why
don't you just go get me a lottery ticket?
The sicker he gets,
the luckier I feel.
Where are you going?
I've been wanting
to introduce myself.
You really a virgin?
You have to treat me, you
don't have to believe me.
And before we treat you,
we have to diagnose you.
Not knowing whether we can
believe you is making that difficult.
Everything I've
told you is true.
You lost your faith because
a teenager got confused.
And my church abandoned
me, and my God forsook me,
and I couldn't come up with a
reason why a god would do that.
God gave the church
and the kid free will.
Their exercise of
that free will hurt you.
Means you're just a victim
of God's gift to mankind.
Oh, yeah. God wants
life to have meaning.
Life's meaningless
without free will.
With free will, there's always
suffering. So God wants suffering.
I got tired of that argument
before I even finished saying it.
And even if I bought that, what the
hell is God doing? Just the big stuff?
The acts of God, the
hurricanes, the earthquakes,
the random killings of
millions of innocent people?
Then we better damn pray.
God, I wish you
weren't a pedophile.
Lungs are clean. No embolism,
no pleurisy, no pneumonia.
I'm sorry, this
is going to hurt.
No, it's fine.
No pain at all?
No, why?
Because there should be.
You feel that?
No.
Regional anesthesia's
a new symptom.
Unless the chest pain is
related to the numbness.
It's not circulatory,
it's neurological.
Run a nerve conduction study.
And be careful. If you kill him,
he'll be dancing
with the Dark One.
Why the hell are you going
to Cuddy's baby naming?
It's a religious
ceremony, it's boring.
Why waste a good evening
that could be much better spent
in a drunken stupor,
feeling sorry for yourself?
Okay.
Okay? Okay, you won't go?
Okay, your obligation
to Cuddy is fulfilled.
Why are you doing this?
Why did Hillary conquer Everest?
You always have a reason. It's
usually a bad one, but a reason.
She's being childish.
See, that's an example from
the bad category. Is it resentment?
The stork brought home a new baby
and you don't want to share Mommy,
or you just can't stand
to see others happy?
She's trying to play me. If I let
her succeed, the terrorists win.
I heard there might be
an opening in the ER.
Foreman's a neurologist,
that's not where he...
I did an ER rotation in Miami.
If I can find another position, I
figure House will rehire Foreman.
Don't quit.
Cuddy wouldn't give
Foreman a recommendation.
He's not gonna be
able to find a decent job.
Foreman shouldn't leave, either.
You think they should split up?
Office romances are a bad idea.
We beat some very long odds.
Wow, honey, save the
gushy stuff for the wedding.
House is playing with you.
If you let him get away with it,
he won't respect you anyway.
Or House is helping you.
He knows it probably
won't work out,
and he's actually
doing you a favor.
Yeah, that sounds a
lot more like House.
I know they're looking for
someone at Mercy. I'll make a call.
Is your boss always like that?
Usually worse.
Finding a fellow atheist
always makes his day.
You think it's possible
maybe God's testing your faith?
No, I already failed. There'd be no
point in what he's doing to me now.
Got something. Looks
like intercostal neuralgia.
What's that?
Something's traumatizing one of
the nerves that runs along your ribs.
Explains the chest
pain and numbness.
Could also cause muscle atrophy.
Does it do anything to the
eyes? Why? What's wrong?
You're seeing Jesus again?
I'm seeing nothing.
My right eye went blind.
Ophthalmological exam's normal.
Nothing structurally
wrong with the eye.
His heart rate's down, sensory
loss is becoming more diffuse,
progressive muscle
weakness. He's shutting down.
It's got to be something
systemic, like autoimmune.
CSF was clear for
Guillain-Barré. Cancer?
Imaging studies have
been clear for tumors.
Then that leaves infection.
He'd be brimming
with white blood cells.
Or we're at the backstage
door of a Duran Duran concert.
Hundreds of screaming
girls clustered around.
What does that mean?
That girls like rock bands.
The presence of the fans
indicates the presence of the band.
Different night. Same
band, same door.
Now there's not a girl in sight.
What does that mean?
Sorry, I don't speak hair band.
They weren't a hair band,
they were new romantics.
The band already left?
Nope. Band's still
there, still rocking out.
When does the absence of the fans
not indicate the absence of the band?
When it's 2009. There
aren't any Duran Duran fans.
They don't make them any more.
If there's no infection, it's because
there aren't any fans, no white cells.
You think his spleen?
Why do I bother with these great
metaphors if I still have to spell it out?
Yes, I think it's his
spleen. Go get a biopsy.
I'll try to get New Moon
on Monday out of my head.
Why are you talking this time?
If I quit, will you
rehire Foreman?
Why?
He can't find
another job, I can.
And you're willing to
make that sacrifice for him?
Yes.
Does Foreman
know about this plan?
Yes.
Well, if he's okay with
it, who am I to say no?
Hold still.
You think it's my spleen?
That's what they're testing.
So, if I happen to cure
you, what happens then?
You start thinking that God
was working through me,
this is some sort of miracle?
Do you think I'm an idiot?
That's what I'm testing.
Losing my faith
wasn't a choice I made.
It happened, it's
gone, for good.
But if it can magically disappear,
it can magically reappear.
And that's what you're hoping.
Your job... Sucks.
That's my point. You could
make more money frapping decafs,
and yet you're still
ministering to the meek.
Why do the Lord's work if
the Lord has left the building?
I've been with the
church my entire adult life.
It's my only marketable skill.
I detect the stink
of leftover faith.
You want to talk
hypocrisy, what about you?
You act like you don't
care about anyone,
but here you are, saving lives.
Solving puzzles. Saving
lives is just collateral damage.
Nice try. I don't think you're looking
for somebody to prove you right,
I think you're looking for somebody
to prove you wrong, to give you hope.
You want to believe, don't you?
Yeah. I want to walk out and find
myself in a forest of whore trees.
But I don't think it's a good idea to
tell people to go fornicate with fruit.
Hey, I was just
talking about you.
Well, not you specifically,
whores and hypocrisy.
You were right. I
don't want you there.
It's a special occasion, filled
with love and acceptance,
and the last thing I need is someone there
who's filled with loathing and contempt.
Okay.
That's it?
You're really not coming?
I'm really not coming.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Gosh, I feel so grown-up.
He's obviously just
jerking you around.
Wants to see if you're serious.
If you just stick it out, I think
he'll bring Foreman back.
I don't. And even if I'm wrong,
I think you
should still split up.
It's just a matter of time
before one of you finds
the other in bed
with another woman.
This coming from
the relationship expert.
12 years and counting.
Hey, if you can make it
that long, then anyone can.
Funny how the two people in the
room who think relationships are easy
are both single.
I don't think they're easy.
That's why I think if you find
something that could be good,
you should hang on to it.
Everything could be
good, very little ever is.
His spleen is fine. Just some
insignificant traces of minor bugs.
Nothing that'd make him sick.
Which minor bugs?
Why do people suddenly find
religion when they have kids?
Fear of the unknown.
Cornerstone of faith.
I think it makes perfect sense.
So it makes sense because
it doesn't make sense?
The fact that you're railing about
it doesn't make a lot of sense.
You really got a thing
for your boss, huh?
I've got a thing
for my boss's thing.
She doesn't have a thing
per se. I'm big on metaphors.
What about you?
Twenty-nine years of celibacy.
What's holding you back now?
Who wants a
relationship with a priest?
Who wants a relationship?
House.
It's the holy water.
We assumed if it was an infection,
it had to be something big and nasty.
But he has pneumocystis,
a harmless bug that's everywhere
and never makes anyone sick,
unless they have a
compromised immune system.
So Father Nietzsche has AIDS.
Impossible.
I've never had a
blood transfusion,
I've never done IV
drugs, I've never had sex.
So prove it. Have an AIDS test.
No. I know I don't have AIDS.
We can't treat you
until we know what it is.
A negative result
proves nothing.
On the off chance
it's a false positive,
I permanently lose
any credibility I have left.
I'd say you just lost that.
I'd say I lost that with
you a long time ago.
We should start
treatment for AIDS.
We need to be sure.
The antiretrovirals could fry
his heart, his liver, his kidneys...
I'm willing to take
that chance. Big of you.
I'm more worried about
the kid he molested.
We should be finding
him and getting him tested.
You don't think he
already got tested?
Maybe he did, maybe he didn't,
but that's a chance
I'm not willing to take.
Legally, we can't inform
sexual partners about STDs.
This isn't some middle-aged
barfly who likes it bareback,
this is an innocent
kid who was molested.
You just want to rub the priest's
face in it. Get him transferred again.
Yeah, heaven forbid a
diddler has job issues.
And you get brought
up on charges.
Lost enough doctors this
week. Treat him for AIDS.
Found a job.
I didn't know you were looking.
Eggers at Mercy says
I can start Monday.
Why would you... House
says if I go, you can come back.
It's been less than two days.
You give up on me that fast?
You get a job behind my back?
You're acting like
I'm cheating on you.
I said I would handle this.
House knew you'd be like this.
Wow.
Guess House knows
me better than you do.
Too bad I don't go both ways.
Good night.
Don't you hate when they put the
mushrooms underneath the cheese?
Your attendance is
validating her hypocrisy.
If she invited you to a
ceremonial lynching, would you go?
It would depend on what she
was serving. Everyone's a hypocrite.
Why are you suddenly so obsessed
with Cuddy's particular brand?
I'm just making conversation.
Would you rather we go back to
talking about mushrooms and cheese?
You're the hypocrite.
You want to go.
You don't resent this baby,
you want to be a part of it.
Yes, but not until her 16th
birthday in some states.
This is ridiculous. You
two deserve each other.
If you want to go, just go
and act like a human being.
Wow. Solid advice.
Except for two things.
I'm acting like I don't want to
go because I don't want to go,
and I am incapable of
acting like a human being.
Ryan?
Yeah. I'm Dr. Chris
Taub. Can we talk?
Yeah. What's wrong?
In private?
Nobody's listening to us here.
I work at
Princeton-Plainsboro Hospital.
I have some news about
Father Daniel Bresson.
What about him?
We believe he has AIDS.
Okay, so?
Well, given the
incident four years ago,
I think you should be tested,
unless you've already done so.
How sick is he?
Very.
Okay. Well, thanks.
Have you been tested?
Yeah.
And?
And it really isn't
any of your business.
I want my job back.
Love, sacrifice, deception
and now betrayal.
This is better
than a telenovela.
What's going on?
Well, either Foreman is here
as the two of you discussed,
to beg for his job back in
exchange for me dumping you
or nothing.
You're trying to get me fired?
I'm suggesting
you quit and I stay,
which is exactly what
you suggested last night.
I told Eggers I
didn't want the job.
Find another one. It took you
eight hours to find that one.
The point is, why didn't you
tell me you were doing this?
Why are you here without me?
You're overreacting.
We'll talk about this later.
That's what this is about.
It's about you taking control.
It's about you not being able
to handle me saving your ass.
And you're not being
controlling right now?
Yeah, who's the
controlling bitch now?
House, shut up.
You never wanted
to take that other job.
You never wanted to save me.
You wanted to offer to save
me, so you wouldn't feel guilty.
You knew I'd say no. That's
why you're so mad right now.
You're an idiot.
Well, either you can go after
her and try and patch things up,
or you blow her off and
take your old job back.
Welcome back.
The AIDS meds aren't gonna work.
If you'd let us do a test, we could
stop treating you, or you could stop lying.
I know the feeling.
BP's climbing. You feeling okay?
No. I feel flushed.
I'm burning all
over. My chest...
It's not a new symptom, it's
just a reaction to the AIDS meds.
Yeah, he reacted by getting
worse. Means it's not AIDS.
"So went Satan forth from the presence
of the Lord and smote Job sore with boils."
You think it's Hyper
IgE Syndrome?
I prefer the colloquial
term, Job's Syndrome.
Explains the symptoms,
and my quote.
It's the first thing I checked.
IgE levels are normal.
It could be some
other genetic disorder.
Cerebral microtumors could explain
the blindness and the hallucinations.
We didn't find any tumors.
That's why I didn't say
tumors, I said microtumors.
So your explanation doesn't depend
on us being major morons, just morons?
We should start genetic
testing. Takes too long.
So we start treatment.
Treatment is surgery.
We can't open him up
without confirmation.
So your position is we
can't test and we can't treat?
My position is you're wrong.
This isn't going to work.
Are you kidding? I've
never felt more alive.
Conflict breeds creativity.
Go run the genetic test.
On it.
So, now you don't
think I have AIDS?
I still think it's AIDS. On the off chance
it isn't, we're pursuing other avenues.
Ryan.
He's... He's dying?
We don't know
what's wrong with him.
Can I speak to him? I
don't think that's a good idea.
Ryan?
Why don't I get you a... Come
on, Ryan. Now's not a good time.
I'm sorry.
For everything.
I know.
Any second thoughts about Cuddy?
No, but please feel
free to blather on.
Raising a child on
her own is scary.
She's just doing what you do, what
everyone does. Trying to avoid pain.
Religion is not the
opiate of the masses,
religion is the
placebo of the masses.
If you're saying that
she's not a hypocrite...
I'm not. I'm trying to
give you a rational reason
to overlook her hypocrisy, so you
don't feel like a hypocrite for going.
Oh. Sorry, continue.
Okay.
Even if an absolute truth
exists, we can't know all of it.
And you can't condemn
her for recognizing that.
Are you eliminating symptoms?
We can know everything.
This is medicine,
not metaphysics.
Truth is truth.
It fits.
It doesn't fit.
You can't eliminate a symptom.
I can if it's not a symptom.
Well, what is it?
Not a symptom.
You're not going to die.
You have
Wiskott-Aldrich Syndrome.
It impairs your immune system,
makes you susceptible to all the
AIDS stuff without actually having AIDS.
And you didn't catch
it, you were born with it.
Another gift from God.
You sure?
Genetic tests should confirm it,
but it explains all your
symptoms. Toe, chest, eyes, skin.
What about my hallucination?
Scotch explains that.
That was just a coincidence?
Coincidences do happen.
But that coincidence is what
brought me to you in the first place.
You promised you
wouldn't go there.
Einstein said, "Coincidences are
God's way of remaining anonymous."
A woman in Florida said, "Look,
Jesus is on my cheese sandwich."
You didn't even want to take my
case. You didn't even think I was sick.
The fact that I was wrong
is not a proof of God.
I'm just trying to understand how my life
can completely turn around in a single day.
Don't worry, your life will go
back to sucking soon enough.
Everything that happened to
you can be rationally explained.
I know. It's just...
That's a lot of coincidences.
House was right
about the priest.
Genetic test confirmed
it was Wiskott-Aldrich.
And I would've discharged him.
Everybody would've
discharged him.
House included. He only
took that case as a stall.
And yet it was a real
case, and he solved it.
By violating his own principles,
and ignoring the
admitting symptoms.
Still, he somehow
got away with it.
Saved another life.
You want him there tonight.
You should tell him.
Cold out there.
At least you have shoes
that cover your toes.
So, it's tonight?
Yeah.
Bad weather for it, huh?
Maybe you'll get lucky.
Maybe your sister will decide the
roads are too dangerous to drive on.
Fingers crossed.
Have fun.