♪ I got something that you want ♪
We've all heard the quote...
♪ I possess what you desire ♪
"Genius is 1% inspiration..."
♪ Tell me I got it going on ♪
"...and 99% perspiration."
♪ Honey, you're
preaching to the choir ♪
♪ You're having trouble staying calm ♪
Easy for Thomas Edison to say.
He had all the good ideas.
♪ I can see it in your eyes ♪
♪ It's what they call infatuation ♪
- ♪ It's like you've been hypnotized ♪
- Great.
♪ You're just a victim of
temptation ♪
♪ You're like a schoolboy
at the prom ♪
♪ And I got something that you want ♪
♪♪
- Get up!
- Mother!
- You have to go.
- I know.
I know.
No daylight hangs.
And if you know,
why did you fall asleep again?
Uh, because sometimes
humans need to sleep.
Choices, Vik.
Sex or sleep.
You can't have it all.
Go. Go.
- I'll see you tonight then?
- No.
I have Harriet tonight.
Hey, weren't you supposed to post
the contest rules this morning?
God is asleep at the wheel,
and humanity is locked in the trunk.
They can wait for
their damn rules.
♪♪
♪ I got something that
you want ♪
All right, so, is this maybe
online or something?
No, she should be here
with the rules right now.
Kepner's MIA?
Yeah, and Bailey's still out
on vacation.
"Bailey" and "vacation"
sounds weird together.
I just wish there were dates,
you know, deadlines, bylaws.
Guidelines are nice.
I've got five viability studies
going.
I need to know if I should start
making panic-based decisions.
Five?
I don't even have one.
You don't?
What's yours?
Shut up.
I mean, do you guys want
to know what you're gonna lose to,
or you want to be
surprised?
Aerosolized stem cells that
provide rapid tissue coverage
and epidermal regeneration
without any grafting.
Spray-on skin?
That's spray-on skin,
ladies and gentlemen.
Finally.
♪♪
Thank you.
- We have to write a paper?
- In three days?
- MLA or APA style?
- How many people get in?
- How many people get seed money?
- How many people get big money?
Okay, it's a brief proposal.
It's not gonna kill you.
You've known about
this contest for weeks.
You've had plenty of time.
25 proposals will be chosen
to receive $100,000
in seed money.
After phase two,
five projects
will get a million grant,
and the eventual winner
will receive $5 million.
It's all right there
in the rules.
Okay, but
who's judging this thing?
Not just you, right?
This is a world-class
hospital
and a multimillion-dollar
contest.
Of course
it's not just me.
I have assembled
an esteemed panel
of emeritus surgeons
from Seattle hospitals,
and I expect you all
not to waste our time.
So I suggest you get to work
instead of asking me questions
which are answered
by the papers in your hands!
Ow.
♪♪
Good God,
I've created a monster.
*GREY's ANATOMY*
Season 14   Episode 12
Episode Title:
"Harder, Better, Faster, Stronger"
♪ All the odds are ♪
♪ They're in my favor ♪
♪ Something's bound to begin ♪
♪ It's gonna happen ♪
♪ Happen sometime ♪
♪ Maybe this time ♪
♪ I'll ♪
♪ Win ♪
- Good job, Kimmie.
- Thanks.
This is my year.
I can feel it.
For four years,
I've missed out on auditions
because of stupid cancer.
And every year,
Suzie Oppenheimer gets the lead.
Girl cannot hit those
high notes.
Hi, Suzie. Your diaphragm is there
for a reason.
And so are your doctors.
So why don't we
let them talk a minute, huh?
Kimmie Park, 12 years old,
one-year status post resection
of a recurrent low-grade glioma.
She's here
for her follow-up head CT.
Poke me, scan me,
whatever.
Just... tell me
I can make it to auditions.
Your liver is failing
because of the cirrhosis,
and you are not eligible
for the TIPSS procedure
- as I'd previously hoped.
- Dang.
- And no transplant, right?
- Right.
Again, I'm so sorry.
Ah.
No one cries for an alcoholic
with a bum liver.
- Am I right, Richard?
- Harry, stop the pity party.
I can make sure
your pain is minimal.
No pain meds.
If I'm gonna meet my maker...
I wanna be clean
when I do it.
Sorry I don't have better news.
Well, I knew you wouldn't,
but, you know,
Harry's a friend, and, uh,
it was worth a try.
So, I appreciate the consult.
How's your project for the
contest coming?
Would you believe me
if I told you I don't have one?
Harper Avery Winner Meredith
Grey doesn't have an idea?
Well, that makes
me feel much better.
You don't have one,
either?
Well, I'm a 9th-inning,
grand-slam kinda thinker.
You know, it'll...
it'll come.
I just feel like
there's so much pressure.
Everyone's looking at me to see
what I'll do next, you know?
You see?
You're looking at me.
- You paged?
- Oh, honey, come on in.
I want you to meet
a dear, old friend of mine.
Hey, not that old.
How you doing?
So nice to finally meet you,
Jackson.
I'm Dr. Michelle Velez.
- Oh, from Cedars?
- Mm-hmm.
Of course, yes.
I've read your work
on stem-cell clone engraftment.
I'm actually pulling together a research
project kind of similar right now.
I'd love to tell you about it
sometime.
Jackson, she's not here
to work on your project.
She's here
to pitch us one of her own.
- Exactly.
- Okay.
Catherine, I know you've taken
part in several successful
gender-affirmation surgeries
for trans women.
- As has Jackson.
- Mm-hmm.
Which is why
I need you two.
To do what exactly?
A traditional vaginoplasty...
using ileum or
the sigmoid colon...
gives you the feel of a vagina,
but it's been shown
to be at high risk
for prolapse and narrowing
or obstruction.
So, the goal is to find
a tissue that's smooth,
with good elasticity,
that secretes moisture
and repairs itself.
And I believe
that tissue
is the peritoneum.
But the peritoneum protects
the internal organs.
Yes, but we'd only take
a small portion.
And it regenerates itself.
Have you thought about
how you'd harvest it?
Laparoscopically,
minimally invasive.
This technique
could be life-changing,
and not just for trans women,
but women who were born
with congenital defects,
potentially cis women who have lost
their vaginal canals to cancer.
And it would allow
for an even better orgasm.
Ooh! Now you're talking my language.
Thank you, Mom. Great.
So, I heard of this contest,
and if we work together,
we can win that money.
And if the surgery works,
we could train surgeons
everywhere to do it.
In fairness, you are one of the top
plastic surgeons in the nation,
so I don't see where I fit in.
I'm the trial subject,
and I can't operate on myself.
♪♪
And whatever work
you do on this contest
will be done on your own time.
You will still be expected
to do scut.
You will not be given any leeway
just because
you're working on a paper.
- I call Meredith Grey.
- You don't call Meredith Grey.
- Meredith Grey calls you.
- Yes, but we made a rule, Mom.
- What rule?
- The rule that says
you and I don't work together
on genitalia
- because you have no filter.
- Don't be a child.
This is our work.
We're surgeons.
The genitals is where
our work intersects.
Yes. That doesn't mean you and I
have to intersect
- around said genitals.
- That sounded terrible.
Which is why I made the rule.
Mom, Dr. Velez has a great pitch.
She does, all right?
And you guys should do it.
You should enter the contest
and change a bunch of lives.
But I already got
my own thing going on,
and, frankly, it's
a little more cutting-edge
than what essentially amounts to
an elective cosmetic procedure.
Oh, come on.
Look, my birthday is coming up.
You could think of this vagina
as your gift to me.
Now I'm gonna go smash
my head in with a hammer
and see if I can forget
that you said that.
Jackson Avery,
you are such a disappointment!
I thought you were woke!
All set. You ready?
I know the drill.
Break a leg.
Places, everybody.
In 5, 4...
3, 2...
1.
♪ ...for the first time ♪
♪ Maybe... ♪
A catchy song.
- Damn it.
- It's back.
And it's encroaching on
Wernicke's area.
- Son of a bitch.
- Yeah.
Yeah, it is.
We're gonna have to operate.
And we're gonna have to do it
while she's awake.
Um, hello?
I got to the second verse in my head,
so that's your cue
to take me out now.
♪♪
It's back, huh?
- So, you're still sleepwalking?
- It's not sleepwalking.
It's just failure to believe
that Paul's dead
and that I'm not dreaming.
Well, I had the same thing
when Derek died,
except you believe you're in a dream,
and I believed I was in a nightmare.
It's called
cognitive dissonance.
Yeah. I have bruises on my arm
from pinching myself.
Well, you should probably
stop doing that.
Judy?
I did not think
I would see you so soon.
Yeah, no offense.
Me neither.
She's complaining
of the same symptoms she had.
- I would think... spleen.
- But I took it out myself
in a dark room
with a human blood bag.
- Okay, Judy, where does it hurt?
- Uh, it just hurts everywhere.
The incision's clean.
There's no sign of infection.
No sign of obstruction.
Judy, I'm afraid
whatever this is,
it's completely unrelated
to your splenectomy.
Great.
I'm a medical mystery.
Try not to worry.
We'll get you some answers.
Let's take her up to CT,
and page me when the scans are up.
- Okay.
- Uh, Dr. Grey.
We've, uh...
we've all been wondering.
What are you doing
for the research contest?
I mean, whatever it is,
I would love to...
Hellmouth, when I'm ready
to tell you, I'll tell you.
Here I am...
in your house
In your bedroom,
with all your personal...
smells.
I need you
to bring me some things.
I thought you called me
to work on your project.
I'm on bed rest for reasons that
are far above your pay grade.
What you do need to know is that
what happens here stays here.
No one needs to know
what we do in this room.
Agreed?
Uh...
Good.
Now, here's what I need.
♪♪
I have an awake brain surgery
on a kid tomorrow,
so I'm gonna need
my beauty sleep,
which means
you two don't get to sleep
because I need you
to narrow down these
studies to two options
by tomorrow.
Do a feasibility evaluation,
including a timeline,
and don't forget to evaluate
likely subject availability
- and do a cost projection.
- Yes, ma'am.
- On it.
- More on it than him.
- Really?
- What?
It's like your fourth bag of chips.
- You counting?
- Yeah. You're a loud eater.
- And your tongue...
- Ugh! It helps me focus.
Well, it's distracting. And...
you're the one who said we
shouldn't have sex anymore, so...
Mmm.
Fine.
♪ We were alive ♪
♪ We had sparks in our eyes,
we were young ♪
- Are you serious?
- ♪ I was yours, you were mine ♪
What?
- That song?
- Mm. It helps me focus.
You... You know that...
that song is our...
Well, stop eating chips like
you're trying to seduce them.
Stop trying to seduce me!
♪ And all I can think of ♪
- Sam.
- ♪ Is holding you again ♪
♪ The way that I used to ♪
I really appreciate you
being game for this.
Are you kidding? I love this!
I love that you're doing this
for Catherine.
You know, my dad did this for
my mom for their 20th anni...
Wow!
Wow. I thought I was past
the spontaneous-tears stage.
Oh, there's no timeline
for grief, Maggie.
- And you can talk to me, you know.
- I know.
Okay.
I think it's 'cause I'm dating.
Clive. Clive the stockbroker.
- Mm.
- He's a good guy, I think.
But my mom was my barometer,
you know?
And right before she died...
and I mean right before she died...
she told me to be more slutty.
And I just wish I could call her
and tell her how slutty
I'm being.
I'd, uh... I'd... I'd rather you not
talk about that particular detail, yeah.
You know, I felt that as I said it.
Yeah.
Okay, okay, we're gonna learn
to salsa today.
♪♪
Okay.
Well, uh, my... my wife's birthday
is... is this weekend. Okay.
- And she loves to dance.
- Mm.
I'm usually pretty good
at keeping up, but this salsa...
- He struggles with salsa.
- Oh.
- I'm Maggie.
- Hi. Nice to meet you.
- Oh, sorry. Okay.
- No worries. Okay, well, look...
I'll have you salsa-ing
in no time, all right?
- Let's start with the basics.
- All right.
- Dr. Webber, take my hand. Okay.
- Okay? The other on my waist.
- Okay.
You're going to go left,
right, left,
and then right, left, right.
- All right?
- Okay. All right.
And left, right, left. Right. All right.
- Right, left, right.
- Okay, okay.
The hand goes up,
and it turns me around.
- Ah.
- Okay?
Maggie. Let's try.
Come on.
- Okay.
Hand up.
And remember... the hand shows
you where you need to go, okay?
- Oh.
- And left, right, left.
- Right, left, right.
- Okay.
The hand goes up,
and it turns her around.
Okay, but you have to turn
the other way, okay? Ahh.
- Oh. All right, here we go.
- Let's do it again.
- What'd you find?
- I'm not sure. Look.
- Wow!
- Yeah.
And here and here and here.
I mean, is that...
- Is it what I think it is?
- I guarantee it's not.
It's rarer than that.
Sometimes when a spleen is removed,
the cells mature, and they form
functioning, smaller spleens.
Um, did you forget
to take out my spleen?
Your spleen is definitely gone,
Judy.
So, these are a bunch of tiny...
What? Cancer?
Am I infested with cancer?
No. You're infested
with a bunch of tiny spleens.
♪♪
Hey.
- Hi.
- I haven't seen you.
Have you been ill?
No, I, uh, took some time off.
- To work on the contest?
- No. I'm not doing that.
But why not?
Honestly?
I barely made it out of bed
for that consult.
Oh.
It never gets easier, losing a mom.
I can only imagine.
No matter how many times, it's...
What do you mean,
"you can only imagine"?
"no matter how many times"?
- You've never lost a mom?
- Have you lost more than one?
Excuse me.
So, it's a 33 Triple-C cross-polymer.
It's the only one
that adheres to hepatocytes,
and it's the key
to my clotting-factor project.
Uh, roger that.
I'll run it down, Major.
You don't have to call me that
here... Lieutenant.
Oh, hey, Carina.
- How have you been?
- Um, fine.
- Um, busy.
- Mm.
- And you?
- Yeah. W...
Y-You're working on this contest, yeah?
Uh, yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Yeah, we're... we're...
we're working away. [Chuckles
Okay.
♪♪
Well, that was awkward,
Major.
I am aware.
The 33 Triple-C...
Cross-polymer.
ETA... ASAP.
I can feel you staring at me.
You gotta be thinking something.
I was thinking maybe
you'd be more comfortable
if we moved you somewhere else.
You mean hospice?
That's the bench for players
who gave up the game.
I'm here to fight, kid.
Is there someone
we can call for you? Family?
Richard, the other guys from A.A.
That's all I got left for family.
There's no fight left to fight,
huh?
If there was,
I would tell you.
Can I give away my organs, then?
Can I do that?
Any good ones left?
- Sorry.
- Hell.
I'm sure you hear that
from a lot of drunks.
Trying to undo all the stupid things
they did in this life.
Do... some good
before they go.
Harry, first of all,
it's ex-drunk,
and it's not your fault.
You have a disease, and you got sober,
so you're treating it.
Here are the beakers.
- And the stoppers?
- They all have stoppers, yes.
- And... Oh, the tubing?
- Oh, yeah, the...
I brought the tubing of various
gauges and thicknesses,
like you asked.
What is it
precisely that we're...
Oh! Nice.
So, is that all you needed?
Keep your pager on.
I might need you in a while.
And, hey, take off those scrubs
before you come here next time.
What's wrong with you?
♪♪
This is really cool.
Thanks. I think so.
It'll change so many lives.
That's the plan.
You're so attractive. Talented.
I meant to say "talented," but I...
confuse "attractive" and "talented"
because I find talent attractive.
Not that you aren't
already attractive, but...
Oh, my God.
Jackson. I need to speak with you.
Uh, great.
What Dr. Velez is proposing
is revolutionary.
Why wouldn't you want to be in the
forefront of something like this?
It's not that I wouldn't, all right?
I just don't have any time.
Ma, I'm making skin here.
You are years of research and millions
of dollars away from making skin.
This surgery is real.
This surgery's right now.
And we have a willing subject.
Mom, if...
Do you know
how easy it is for a man,
a cisgender man
to walk into a hospital
and get the penis enlargement
of his dreams?
- I've done dozens.
- Yeah, I hear you.
I do, okay? But come on.
Vaginoplasties already exist, too.
I do a bunch of them every year.
Just because something works
doesn't mean it can't be better.
We throw
billions of dollars a year
at perfecting little pills
to make erections.
If we know how to perfect this,
why shouldn't we?
Why shouldn't we help
people like Michelle
feel for the first time in their lives
like their bodies match
their souls?
That's what I'm doing.
Mom, that's literally
what I do every day.
Jackson, do you have any idea
the rate of attempted suicides
in people with gender dysphoria?
41%.
This surgery won't just
change lives.
It will save them.
But go on.
Make your little skin.
♪ Everybody ♪
♪ Loves a winner ♪
♪ So, nobody loves me ♪
♪ Lady peaceful ♪
♪ Lady happy ♪
♪ That's what I long to be ♪
Kimmie, we're gonna
try something else now.
The singing and
speech functions
work in different parts
of the brain, so
we test them separately
using a cortical stimulator.
Now say lyric. Don't sing.
Can you do that?
You got it.
Okay, whenever
you're ready.
- All the odds are in my favor.
- Good.
Something's bound to begin.
Okay.
Repeat that line again now.
God the bogs are cranberry.
Someday fox I'll creep.
Crap.
Bag the diamonds are umbrella.
It's too close to her speech center.
Right. Her singing is fine,
but when I stimulate the edge of
the tumor, she loses her words.
She has no idea it's even happening.
- Something's bound to begin.
- I can't resect this.
- You just can't leave it.
- Maybe this time.
If I take it out, she'll lose
her ability to speak.
Maybe this time I'll win.
♪♪
So, I'll be equipping the LVADs
with a magnetic interface
so that I can eliminate ports
and recharge transcutaneously.
Ferret. Jango. Everest.
That's what I just heard there.
I'm sorry.
Um, okay, so,
right now,
people who need a device
to help their hearts pump
have to recharge the battery
every couple of hours
using a plug-in charger.
So, I want to design a device
that charges through the skin.
So no wires, no ports,
no external batteries.
You know how to do that?
What?
Oh, my God.
Oh, shoot!
Lab emergency?
I-I forgot I have a thing.
- I'm sorry.
- Maggie, it's okay.
You can just say,
"Clive, I don't like you.
I couldn't think of
a better excuse to leave."
What? No!
I like you. I do. I...
I just have to go.
I'm sorry.
Okay.
♪♪
Thanks.
Bye.
I'm so sorry.
I double-booked myself.
- I never do that.
- I guess I'm just overwhelmed.
- Is it this contest?
- No. I love being busy.
I'm usually pretty type-A,
but I don't know.
I'm just overwhelmed, I guess.
- All right, let's do cross body lead.
- Okay.
Ready?
Cross body lead.
Here we go.
Cross body lead. Good.
Ah, ah, ah. Yes.
Ah, ah, ah.
Honey, no.
No cha-cha.
- Oh.
- This is what we're gonna do.
I want you guys to practice
just the first combo
with no music and no cha-cha.
All right. Thank you.
I'm gonna take this call.
- All right. Okay.
- Okay.
It's been close to a year, hm?
- What?
- Since your mother died.
On the one-year anniversary
of my mother's death,
I was sent to the principal's
office five times in one day.
On the first anniversary
of me being sober,
I was the most tempted
I've ever been to drink.
Anniversaries are hard.
First anniversaries...
are worse.
When I was a little,
I had a stick from the tree
in the backyard
that I used to pretend
was a magic wand.
And, um...
when I would feel like this,
I would go my room
and I would wave it and,
for a second, it would all go away.
When my mom got sick,
I wished I had that wand.
I still do.
We'll go after it
with radiation and chemo.
And in the meantime, she'll get sick,
go bald, and lose all her spirit.
Where does it end?
Well, unfortunately, at the rate
of the expansion of the tumor...
- We need to prepare ourselves...
- You listen to me.
That girl is a survivor.
Her parents never bothered with her,
either of 'em.
Kimmie survived that
before she could even walk.
And she didn't just survive it.
She smiled through it.
She sang through it.
And, yes, it drives me crazy
some days with the over and over again,
the notes
that could shatter glass.
But that girl has a spirit
that has nothing to do with me,
and I'll be damned
if I don't fight for her
or if I'll stand by
while you don't.
So, you go back
to your doctor room,
and you come up
with another plan.
Please and thank you.
Dr. Kepner,
I got you a coffee.
Stop it. Stop that.
Go away!
- Oh, hi. Sorry.
- It's fine.
So, the intern I'm sleeping with
is everywhere.
We have a no-daylight rule,
but he keeps making faces at me,
like, "I've seen you naked" faces.
And I can't do anything about it
because he has, so I'm just, like,
hiding from him by day
and then un-hiding at night.
- I'm like a sex vampire.
- These numbers are insane.
26.4 out of every 100,000.
26.4 what?
Mothers dying from having
babies.
- Arizona...
- I mean, Italy's is 4.2.
So, why is our maternity mortality rate
6 times higher than Italy's?
- What's going on?
- I am sorry
about what happened
to Karin.
I am so sorry that I can't sleep
without at least a bottle of wine.
I promise you I am punishing
myself enough without having...
This is not about you, April.
Just stop talking.
♪♪
Spray-on skin.
Of course you would come up
with something cool
like spray-on skin.
Yeah.
You don't even seem
that excited about it.
No, no, no. I am. I mean,
I feel great about it, you know?
This is the kind of thing
that wins contests.
I could definitely win
a Harper Avery with this.
There's a "but" in there.
But thanks to my mother,
all I can think about is vaginas.
Yeah.
I should explain that.
Um, my mom has this friend who's
this amazing plastic surgeon,
and she has this idea
she presented
to laparoscopically harvest the
peritoneum for vaginoplasties.
I mean, this thing would revolutionize
gender-affirmation surgery.
But the thing is,
this surgery already exists,
which is good,
but has its downfalls.
But she thinks that if we use
the peritoneum
that we're creating
the Ferrari of vaginas.
Hm.
Poor Jackson.
He has two amazing ideas,
and he can't decide
which one to submit.
The thing is,
this is the future of my specialty.
I mean,
this is cutting edge right here.
Look, trans men and women
obviously
deserve the best medical care possible,
but come on.
It's not gonna
revolutionize medicine
to perfect
an already successful surgery,
one that only impacts like less
than 1% of the population.
Well, 1% of the population
is still 75 million people.
What are you doing?
- Sam. Sam, stop that!
- I'm hot, Andrew.
You know I overheat when
I'm reading about neuroscience.
Oh, yeah, I remember.
Clotting factors?
That sounds cool.
- It is.
- I'm working with the chief.
So I think that makes me
chief intern.
What's the chief working on?
I am not at liberty to say.
Oh, that's interesting.
I wonder if...
Shut up, Blood Bank.
DeLuca, Bello.
- I was hot.
- Uh, we didn't do anything.
- Change of plans.
- Stop my viability studies.
Start looking for a way to get
a tumor out of a little girl
without cutting part of her
brain away, not a single cell.
I mean, I've never
seen anything like this.
She's grown mini spleens
all over her abdomen,
her small bowel, her ovaries.
It's incredible.
- Clamp.
- Insane.
The original organ has been removed,
yet these fragments continue
to do the job of the parent.
It's too bad she didn't grow
extras of something useful,
like kidneys or livers.
♪♪
Hellmouth, do you have
your cellphone on you?
Uh, I...
I-I'll yell at you later
for bringing it into the O.R.
- Just get it out.
- Okay.
Open
your voice-recorder app.
- ♪ Whoa, whoa, whoa ♪
- Okay.
A small multi-fragmented organ
can still provide
the same function
as a whole single organ.
Injecting native cells
into lymphatic tissue
with the utilization
of growth-enhancing...
- I'll need a biopolymer.
- ♪ Pull up a seat ♪
We need to look up biopolymers
with adherence properties.
Oh, you'll need
colony-stimulating factors.
- Did you get that?
- Got it.
By introducing liver-cell
precursors into lymph nodes,
we can produce enough small, mini livers,
which will take over the function of
the patient's original failing liver.
♪ More, more ♪
- So, who holds the patent?
- The 33 Triple-C polymer
is patented by
a Dr. M.J. Cerone in Madrid.
- And it's pretty expensive.
- So I'm screwed.
I wouldn't say
you're screwed, Major...
not to your face.
We picked him up
for a head LAC, and he started
seizing two minutes out.
- Move. Move!
- Pushed 2 of loraz. No response.
I was trying to get him an airway.
And he bit your finger off, huh?
- First week on the job?
- His second.
Okay, let's push
another 5 of lorazepam,
and hand me a laryngoscope, please.
Parker,
get this guy in trauma 2.
- Am I gonna lose my finger?
- We'll see.
I gotta get it out
of this guy's throat first.
♪ Oh, whoa, oh ♪
♪ Whoa, oh, oh ♪
What happened?
Head LAC.
Seized in the ambulance.
He's gonna a CT.
Rule out TBI.
- Page neuro, please.
- Who's in 2?
Rookie paramedic,
down one finger.
- I'm gonna need a MaGill, please.
- Yep.
You know
I stop bleeding every day.
What are you talking about?
I don't need to write papers
and file patent requests.
Every day, I compete with death,
and more often than not...
I win.
Okay, G.I. Joe.
Get this to the kid in trauma 2.
He's gonna be happy
to see that.
So, I promised my husband
- I'd stay in bed today.
- Mm-hmm.
So, um,
I need you to go to the closet
and bring a measuring tape.
And in the bathroom,
there should be
a pair of latex gloves.
And in the kitchen,
- there's a turkey baster.
- No!
I'm sorry, Dr. Bailey.
I have to speak because I have
to believe we live in an age
where I can speak the truth
- to those in power over me.
- What?
I don't know what it is we're doing,
but it does not feel good to me.
It's too much tubing and corks
and secrecy in your bedroom.
It does not feel good,
and I do not feel safe here.
No.
Oh... No, I...
I'm making my prototype.
For the contest entry!
Look. Okay.
See?
It goes in your rectum.
So, my spleen planted seeds
and grew more?
Something like that, yes.
Your spleen inspired Dr. Grey
to come up with something that might
help save thousands of people.
Wow. Really?
Can we put that on
a certificate or something?
- We need good news.
- DeLuca, go.
Right. So, I looked at gamma
knives and proton-beam therapy.
Nothing there. We checked out
high-frequency ultrasound
applications in neurosurgery.
It was utilized for thalamic
stimulation in comatose patients.
There was a study that was done in...
There was no mention in
the literature of its usefulness
as a surgical modality
in the brain. I...
- I think it's a dead end.
- So...
So, we got nothing.
I'm sorry.
"Notes that would shatter glass."
High frequencies.
They shatter the glass
because the note
has the same resonance frequency
as the glass itself.
So, an ultrasound wave,
if it was at the same frequency
as the tumor tissue...
It would shatter it without cutting.
But I-It's never been done in the brain.
Not yet.
With ultra-precise targeting
of the cancer cells,
we think we'll be able
to use it as an alternative
- to invasive brain surgery.
- Has this ever been done before?
Well, not on brain tissue,
but if we experiment on models first,
we think we could use it
on tumors.
So, you want to use my kid
as a lab rat?
No, ma'am, not as a lab rat.
She's the goal.
- I'm the lab rat's cheese.
- We're really close.
We just need a little more time to get
funding and do some more research.
How much time are we talking?
"Ready for the spring musical"
kind of time?
Kimmie, there will be more
auditions in the fall.
- I promise.
- By fall, I'll be bald.
Maybe they'll do
"The King and I."
We're really close to figuring
out a way to help you, Kimmie.
- I believe it.
- Well, we both do.
So, in the meantime...
Radiation, chemo, rinse, repeat.
Dr. Avery.
I finished the paper for
your spray-on-skin proposal,
but the other Dr. Avery asked me
to type up a proposal
for the gender-affirmation-surgery idea,
so I did both of them... in three days...
without sleeping.
Both of them.
Did I already say that?
I may be over-caffeinated.
Anyway, I know you asked me
to do this one,
but, um,
this one is really cool.
Not that you asked.
I'm gonna stop talking now.
Thank you.
I love you, too.
- Hey.
- Hi.
What's your pitch?
Let's hear it.
I want to design LVADs
with magnetic interfaces
so that we can eliminate ports
and recharge transcutaneously.
Recharging the heart
through the skin.
Yes, yes. Exactly.
- What?
- Nothing. You just get it.
- Yeah.
- It's nice.
How's Chive doing?
Clive.
Is it "Clive"?
♪♪
Really?
Lightning strike?
More like a hailstorm.
♪♪
When?
Just now.
I'm sorry.
We knew there
was nothing we could do.
I thought of something
for the contest.
It's theoretical,
but it could work.
It could have saved him.
And it could save people like him.
And it was inspired by him,
so I just wanted to let him know
that he had done
some good after all.
♪♪
- Karin Taylor was 33 years old.
- Arizona, stop!
She was in pristine health.
She gave birth to a gorgeous
6-pound, 7-ounce baby.
Stop! This is not healthy,
and it's not gonna
bring Karin back.
This is healthy!
This is my paper.
It's a verbal paper,
but this is what I am going to study!
And it may not bring
Karin back,
but it could help
a whole lot of future Karins,
- so please, please just listen.
- Okay.
Karin was healthy,
and now she's dead from an
entirely treatable condition,
okay, and it wasn't my fault,
and it wasn't your fault
that she died.
Do you hear me?
It wasn't your fault.
But that doesn't mean
that we shouldn't fix it.
Preeclampsia is...
is only one of the reasons
that we are losing laboring
mothers at an unprecedented rate.
The United States has one of the
worst rates of maternal mortality
in the entire developed world.
There is something going on
here,
and we need to fix it,
not someday, but now.
♪♪
Put that in writing.
Send it to me.
♪♪
Okay.
Okay, everyone.
Here we go.
♪♪
"Generation of functioning
accessory livers
in lymphatic tissue,
Dr. Meredith Grey
& Dr. Josephine Wilson." Wow.
I'm on mini livers?
You put me on your proposal?
But wait.
You already have Hellmouth.
I don't want you on
it as my assistant.
I want you on it
as my partner.
I mean, you found a critical
piece of the puzzle.
You're on this.
Stop doing that.
You're awake.
This is real.
Paul is dead.
And you're free.
And if there's another name
you'd prefer I put on that paper,
I'm happy to change it.
How about
Dr. Josephine Brooke Wilson?
♪♪
"A novel approach to vaginoplasty
using laparoscopically harvested
peritoneum,
Dr. Catherine Avery,
Dr. Michelle Velez, and...
Dr. Jackson Avery."
I knew you'd come around.
- Mwah!
- Oh, man.
- Okay.
- Let's do this.
Now, I'll just ask that you to keep
the orgasm jokes to a minimum.
♪♪
"The Path Pen,
Dr. Richard Webber."
Now, this is just a mock-up,
so don't laugh.
It's a pen?
Kinda, okay, but the... the idea
is that we create a file of the
chemical and molecular markers
in various types of
tumor cells,
and then we pre-program
this into the device
to rapidly identify
the different types, okay?
So you can know
in surgery on contact
where the healthy tissue is...
and where the cancer is...
and make it go away.
It's not a pen. It's a wand.
It's a magic wand.
"Transcutaneously rechargeable
ventricular assist device,
Dr. Maggie Pierce."
"The Rectal Access Port
for hydro colonoscopy,
submitted by Dr. Miranda Bailey."
And "MRI-guided ultrasound
ablation of inoperable gliomas,
Dr. Amelia Shepherd and Dr. Alex Karev."
♪♪
All set. You ready?
- Places in...
- It's okay.
You can just start.
♪♪
- Tell me we're gonna fix this.
- We're gonna fix this.
♪ It's gonna happen ♪
♪ Happen sometime ♪
♪ Maybe this time ♪
♪ I'll ♪
♪ Win ♪
Essentially, it's a jack for the rectum
that allows for an easy-access
water colonoscopy.
Ass jack.
Colonoscopies are
messy and painful,
and surgeons ruin
their shoulders with all that...
Roto-Rootering.
- Mm.
- Ew.
I'm just saying.
She's gonna be rich.
- Hey.
- Hi.
Thank you
for being worried about me.
Of course, and
you seem better.
Are you better?
Yeah. I entered the contest.
And, I mean, I don't know.
I don't know if I'll get in,
but I'm gonna study
maternal mortality.
And you're an O.B.,
and Italy seems to have it
way more figured out
than we do, so...
would you like to be my partner?
- Your partner?
- Yeah. On the study.
- ♪ It makes no difference ♪
- Only on the study?
♪ To a satellite ♪
♪ Oh, yeah ♪
We think we can can
create multiple
fully-functioning livers, like
mini livers all over the body.
- Wow.
- That is amazing.
- Thank you.
- Cheers.
- Good luck to the three of you.
- To all of us. What do you mean?
- Nope, not me.
- What?
- Why not you?
Not doing it. Didn't apply.
Research, patents...
it's... it's not my thing.
But I am rooting
for the three of you.
Uh, speaking of which,
how did you get that polymer?
- Which polymer?
- The 33 Triple-C, the cross-polymer
where you inject with the cells.
I mean, I wanted it for my thing,
but Cerone's has that patent
locked up tight.
Hunt, why don't we go,
uh, grab a refill, huh?
Yeah. Sure.
Wow! That patent must've cost a ton.
You did get the patent,
right?
I...
Okay, everyone, um...
the results are in.
- Yes!
- Yeah.
- Ah-ah-ah! Yes!
- You got in?
- Got in?
- Yes, yes, yes, yes.
We got in.
What are you doing?
What? Honey, we're not stay...
- We have reservations.
- Yeah, yeah.
Uh, excuse me.
You're on my dance floor here.
- Excuse me.
- What are you doing?
W-We are celebrating your
birthday a little early, okay?
♪♪
Come on.
Oh, my God.
- Whoo!
- Inspiration is not
some mystical, unattainable thing.
Inspiration is a seed.
Somebody been practicing.
That seed turns into vision.
- Look out, now.
- That vision turns into a goal.
Watch this one.
Oh!
And hopefully,
that goal turns into victory.
♪♪
Our paper was great.
It was great.
I can't believe it.
I can't believe we didn't get in.
What are we gonna do
about Kimmie?
I said
hopefully.
♪♪