Cat got your tongue?
No. You killed the
cat. Cut off his head.
Need to take a look at this.
Mom? Mom.
Mom, it's okay.
Just a couple of
questions before I can
authorize extending
her disability benefits.
I don't like her. She's fat.
I could lose a little weight.
You all right?
- Actually, before she signs—
- I killed the cat. Lots of blood.
It's okay.
I have a couple of questions
about some of these dates.
- The first diagnosis—
- Schizophrenia.
Dr. Walters, May 1 1, last year.
The letter's in the medical file.
And April 6— That was
the last day she worked?
But she received unemployment
benefits for that week.
We fixed that. I know we
did. We returned the money.
That's the canceled check.
Not the real one,
you know. It's a copy.
And you're the dependent?
No. That's my little brother.
I'm 18 Just helping out.
You're all set.
Just need a signature.
Hey! I'm talking to you!
The cat's first. Now
it's your turn, Lucy.
Shut up. Shut up, shut up!
It's okay. She just— She
just needs a little water is all.
I'll go get it.
Just hold on, okay? Just...
When she comes back, sign it and we're
gonna be done. We need this, okay? Please.
Okay.
The voices...
The voices aren't real.
What?
Mom? Mom.
Mom? Mom! Mom!
Thirty-eight-year-old Caucasian
woman. Status:
post-respiratory arrest in the field.
Intubated, oxygenating poorly.
Dr. Gregory House, please
call Dr. Cuddy at extension 373 1.
This is a good hospital?
Depends what you mean
by "good." I like these chairs.
How is she? Stable. Okay.
Your Mom had a small
pulmonary embolism...
A blood clot that got stuck in
her lungs, blocked the oxygen.
But the pain started in her leg.
Where the clot started— her calf.
It's called a deep vein
thrombosis. Basically, a bigger clot.
It never hurt there before.
I would have noticed.
A piece of that broke off,
went up the vein, through
her heart and blocked
the blood flow to her lungs.
No blood flow, no oxygen. Okay.
Is your Dad here? I have
some things I need to talk
to him about. Uh, my
Dad's running a little late.
He's dead. Just talk to
me. I take care of her.
All right. Your mom's blood
alcohol was .12.10:30 in the morning.
I gave it to her. Two ounces
of vodka. It cools her out.
But that's the first since
Monday. That was three days ago.
I've been real careful.
She hears voices. She's
schizophrenic. That explains the D.V.T.
The alcohol makes her pass out.
She's immobile for long periods of time.
That doesn't happen.
She's not an alcoholic.
She only drinks when
you give it to her?
We put her on blood thinners. You
can probably take her home tomorrow.
It's not the alcohol. It's
gotta be something else.
Of course it's the alcohol.
Hello!
This guy's a
professional doctor.
Plays golf and
everything, I bet.
He's not gonna tell you your
mom's an alcoholic without proof.
I'm sure he scoped for varices, checked her
esophagus, ran all kinds of blood tests.
Doctors like this, they don't make
assumptions. They do the work.
I'd be happy to refer you the case,
Dr. House. You seem so interested.
What case? It's over.
You're sending her home.
- How old is she?
- You're a doctor?
Own my own stethoscope.
Did I ask you how
old she was? I forget.
A 38-year-old woman with no
previous symptoms or history...
presents with deep
vein thrombosis.
How did she get it?
Oral contraceptives, smoking,
diabetes, obesity. What's the point here?
A D.V.T. is a D.V.T. Put her on
I.V. Heparin to prevent future clots.
- What's the big mystery?
- Fine. You're all sleepy. You need a clue.
She's 38 years old.
She's 20 years too young to
get a deep vein thrombosis.
I treated a 12-year-old girl once, a
soccer player. She got kicked in the leg.
There was no trauma. None of
the risk factors. You took a history?
I have some notes. They're
not mine, but reliable,
I think, for the purposes
of this discussion.
As for the immobility,
well, she's real active
right now, of course.
Paranoia keeps her limber.
- Paranoia?
- Oh, yeah. She's schizophrenic.
And her kid wrote this,
so it might be a little biased.
You know, having to take
care of his nutso mom and all.
You think there's a connection?
- Do we include schizophrenia
in the differential for D. V. T.?
- Well...
The answer is no.
Abnormal dopaminergic pathways
in the brain do not cause blood clots.
Schizophrenia is not
the cause of D.V.T.
On the other hand, we
don't really know anything
about schizophrenia,
so maybe it is connected.
Well, schizophrenia
explains one mystery...
Why you're so fascinated by a
woman with a bump in her leg.
It's like Picasso
deciding to whitewash a
fence. Thanks. I'm more
of a Leroy Neiman man.
And it is only about the D.V.T.
She's 38 years old. She shouldn't...
Right, solve this one,
and you're on your way to
Stockholm. We don't
even know how to treat it.
Come on. Fumigation
of the vagina?
A little louder. I don't
think everyone heard you.
Two thousand years ago,
that's how Galen treated
schizophrenics. The Marcus
Welby of ancient Greece.
Oh, clearly you're not
interested. Oh, I'm interested.
I'm interested in how voices
in the head could be caused by
malposition of the uterus.
There's a better place for it?
Now, what do we got? We've got
lobotomies, rubber rooms, electric shocks.
My, Galen was so primitive.
Where are you going?
Going to see the
patient. That all-important
human connection.
Thought I'd give it a whirl.
You won't talk to
patients because they lie,
but give you a patient
with no concept of reality...
If it wasn't for Socrates,
that raving, untreated
schizophrenic, we wouldn't
have the Socratic method...
The best way of teaching everything,
apart from juggling chain saws.
Without Isaac Newton, we'd be floating on
the ceiling. Dodging chain saws, no doubt.
And that guitar player in that
English band. He was great.
You think I'm interested
because of the schizophrenia.
Yeah, I'm pretty sure.
Galen was pretty sure
about the fumigation thing.
Pink Floyd.
- Mom, this is Dr. Gr—
- Gregory House.
Nice to meet you.
Would it be all right if we
spoke alone for a while?
Well, you're gonna need me to...
I've got your case
notes, Doctor.
There's a cafeteria downstairs.
Get yourself whatever you want,
as long as there's enough
left over for a Reuben
sandwich, dry, no
fries, hold the pickles.
Should run you
about 5.80 with tax.
I'll page you when we're done.
No...
pickles.
Nice kid.
How much do you really drink?
He's really talking
to a patient?
I don't know who I am anymore.
It's a blood clot. What's
so fascinating about that?
He likes crazy people.
He likes the way they think.
They think badly. That's
the definition of crazy.
Why would he like—
They're not boring.
He likes that.
And the meds?
Baseball. I like baseball.
Very nice. Very sad.
My boy and me, we
went to see a game.
Not "Mets." Meds. Medicine.
You take what he
tells you to take.
No one believes me.
I do.
I thought he liked rationality.
He likes puzzles.
Patients are puzzles?
You don't think so?
I think they're people. Yeah.
Well, he hates them, and
he's fascinated by them.
Tell me you can't
relate to that sentiment.
You told Luke it never
hurt before. Just rough.
They didn't hurt.
Didn't?
Don't lie to him, Limpy.
Lively Lucy never lies to Lucas.
Look what I do to him.
Radiation therapist to Oncology.
Learn anything from
the "human connection"?
Yeah. The Mets suck.
Also, for the last two
months, she hasn't shaved
her legs. Because of the
tremors, she cuts herself.
The tremors aren't new.
She must always cut herself.
Exactly.
Something changed
in the last two months.
I'm thinking the amount
of blood when she cut
herself. So let's start
with some blood work.
Collect and send for
clotting studies, P.T.,
P.T.T., factor five,
protein "C" and "S."
The whole shebang. Good luck.
No pickles, and it's cold now.
- If it's a Reuben,
that's the way he likes it.
- Everyone, this is Luke.
Allison Cameron. It's
nice to finally meet you.
Yeah. Save it. We're busy.
Luke, give us another half hour with
your mom. We need to do some tests.
Nice kid.
Take her off the psych meds. That way we'll
know what's what on the physical side.
And who knows, we
might get more out of her.
Don't worry. No pickles.
Happy birthday.
Okay. Whose?
I was going through your mail,
and it was on a form. Happy birthday.
Oh.
No! No blood! Not mine!
For the test.
Dr. House told us...
You're gonna steal
it! Sell it! No! No blood!
No! No blood! No! No blood!
Haldol, five milligrams, stat.
No! No! No!
No! No!
No! No! Oh, no!
N-No!
No.
Well, good news. The lab
says it's not strep, so we're done.
Wait a second.
No, really not strep.
The boys in the lab, sure, they're
hard drinkers, but they're pros, you know.
Plus, your kid actually has
none of the symptoms for strep.
It was quicker running the test
than arguing with you. My point is, go!
I just wanted to ask
your opinion, Doctor.
She's having a birthday
party next week, and
she's upset that I'm
getting a sugarless cake.
The other kids hate it.
This is why you're here.
Sugar is the leading
cause of obesity in America.
You want a doctor to scare
her about the dangers of sugar.
She needs to get her
weight under control.
Well, you know, I feel
sorry for those other
kids, Wendy, who don't
have a mom like yours...
A mom who knows that sugar causes heart
disease, appendicitis and athlete's foot.
That's not fair. Oh,
yes, it is. No, I get it.
You want her to slim down a little so
she can wear pretty clothes like yours.
Love the bracelets.
Hey, what about matching
outfits? You could be twins.
She can't be your daughter.
It's impossible! You
look way too young.
Happy birthday.
Get the kid a damned
ice cream cake.
Dr. Wyland to Obstetrics.
Dr. Wyland, Obstetrics.
- You drugged her.
- Actually, I didn't.
I've taken her off all medication.
Your guy Foreman gave her Haldol.
We needed blood for tests. I
assumed that was the only way to get it.
He knocked her out. Look, I have
a cane, and I know how to use it.
I hired you. You work for me.
Okay.
Can I go now, boss?
The Haldol changes her.
She says it makes her soul
numb. Don't give it to her.
"If there be rags enough,
he will know her name and be
well pleased remembering it."
You okay?
Old days.
"For in the old days,
"though she had young men's
praise and old men's blame,
among the poor, both old
and young gave her praise."
Oh!
Help! Somebody help!
So, when I said no psych meds, I'm just
curious— which word didn’t you understand?
The Haldol had nothing
to do with the bleed.
You know that. I used it
purely as a chemical restraint.
Oh, great. Well,
that's good to hear.
So she won't experience
any of those pesky little
side affects you get when
your motives aren't pure.
Oh— Those side
effects are so rare!
What, passing out, increased confusion,
depression? That's not gonna happen.
That's not gonna screw
up our diagnosis, 'cause
you just used it to
restrain her. I'm so relieved.
She spit in my face.
That must have been
so frightening for you.
What was I supposed to do, tie her
down? Yeah. Anything but give her drugs.
That's basically my point.
The clotting studies. Pretty fast.
Did you promise to date the entire lab?
No, I save that for emergencies.
I told them she bled out two units
and if it happened again, she'd die.
If it had happened at
home, she would have died.
The E.R. doc, he was
gonna send her home.
- I used my best judgment.
- It turns out your best judgment
is not good enough.
- Here's an idea—next time, use mine.
- I think they're choosing a movie.
Why did the patient bleed out?
The clotting studies
so far are normal.
Well, cover your ears if you
don't want me to spoil the ending.
Everything was normal,
except for a prolonged P.T. time.
- Which means what?
- Usually it means whoever
drew the blood didn't do it right.
Oh, that's right, 'cause
you drew the blood.
- But you were precise because you knew
the tube was purely for the P.T. study.
- That's right.
And I'm right with you. I trust
this result, for two reasons...
"A," because you
are a good doctor,
and "B," because five
milligrams of I.V. Haldol...
makes for a spectacularly
cooperative patient.
The prolonged P.T. time makes me
think she's got a vitamin "K" deficiency.
Vitamin "K" would explain
the bleed, but not the clot.
Without vitamin "K," protein "C" doesn't
work. Without protein "C," she clots.
Clotting and thinning
all at the same time.
What about another drug interacting with
Heparin, an antibiotic like ampicillin?
That would cause the bleed.
Clever, but she's not on ampicillin.
Two months ago, she complained of
a sore throat, and he got her ampicillin.
- Which she refused to take.
- He just said she didn't take it.
What is it, everybody lies except
for schizophrenics and their children?
It's more likely than malnourishment.
Why not scurvy or the plague?
Gee, I wish my idea was
as cool and with-it as yours.
What is yours, by the way?
Do you have one? Alcohol.
Simple. It causes immobility,
which explains the D.V.T.
It also causes cirrhosis, which explains
the bleed and the prolonged P.T. time.
- Let's ultrasound the liver.
- Three theories.
Check out her place
for ampicillin and diet.
Then ultrasound her liver.
Let's find out who's right
before she bleeds to death.
101.
So House says the kid is sensitive,
thinks he takes good care of her.
But if we don't find anything, why let
him know we did it in the first place?
What's the point?
Why not just make old Foreman
lift the key from the kid's backpack?
Looks like Luke sleeps
in the living room.
Nothing in there.
He lays out her clothes?
Enough organization, enough lists, you
think you can control the uncontrollable.
Fix her meds, fix her clothes,
maybe you can even fix her.
Pick that up on
your psych rotation?
Trifluoperazine,
Thorazine, Clozarile.
Whew. They tried everything.
The ampicillin—
Never touched it.
There goes Cameron's theory. Oh, God,
I hope it's not a vitamin "K" deficiency.
Damn.
Breakfast, lunch and dinner.
House was right.
That's the only
thing she'll eat. Yeah.
The problem is, you can't
actually live on this stuff.
I checked it out. I looked on the
box. All the nutritional values are solid.
There's plenty of
protein and calories.
Yeah, vitamin "A" and "C," but no
"K." That's why your mom got sick.
So what's the plan then?
Load her up with vitamin "K."
That's it? If it all checks out, you
can take her home in a couple of days.
Oh, God, you're
upset about something.
You're gonna open up to me
now, aren't you? It's all my fault.
Here we go.
Okay, I'm gonna say
this once: You have done
a very good job taking
care of your mother.
If this was all she'd
eat, then what else could
you do? Gosh, just being
a kid is a full-time job.
Shut up! I'm 18. I should be
able to take care of my mom.
I almost killed
her. Good example.
Just the time it takes to express those
ridiculous, self-centered teenage ideas.
I don't envy your schedule.
No pickles.
My mom doesn't like 'em either.
Smart woman.
Before she got sick, I didn't
like how bossy she was.
Always telling me what
to do, the right way to do it.
Never thought I'd miss that.
Oww.
You should get that looked at.
I still don't buy a vitamin "K"
deficiency. House was right.
That usually makes you
happy. Less work for us.
The kid feeds his mom a steady diet of
booze, and the problem is too many burgers?
The kid's in a tough situation.
You do what you gotta do to survive.
Feeding alcohol to an alcoholic
is not a survival technique.
Where I come from, if
it works— Yeah, right.
I'm rich. I couldn't possibly understand
what this kid is going through.
Just because you're drinking pricier stuff
doesn't mean you don't have a problem.
You've seen someone
stagger down that road?
No way vitamin "K"
is the whole story.
It's not broken.
See this, right here?
It's the epiphyseal
plate, otherwise known
as the "growth plate."
What's wrong with it?
Amazing thing, this bone.
If you know how to read it, it can
tell you how old someone really is.
- Exactly how old.
- Great.
Mmm, not even 15.
Almost though.
Two weeks away. Maybe a month.
Last week. I was 15 last week.
Happy birthday to both of us.
If you're gonna lie
though, go big. Go 21.
That way you won't need your
crazy mom to help you buy vodka.
Uh, great. Thanks for the tip.
Now, when I bring my
mom home, is there anything
I need to know about
taking care of her?
I suppose your biggest
worry isn't the booze.
You're 15, basically no mom.
If Child Welfare let
kids get away with that,
they wouldn't need
those nice foster homes,
and that would make them sad.
They'd put her someplace too.
My life is working.
Not the word I'd use.
Most 15-year-old kids are doing
what they're supposed to be doing.
You know, they're huffing
glue, catching crabs.
If you turn me in, I'll sue you.
That's privileged information.
Oh, relax. It's not
even your X-ray.
She's awfully calm.
House wrote new orders.
There's a little bit of
scarring. Not much.
Not enough to— It's cirrhosis.
Oh, but she doesn't drink.
Congratulations. You win.
Actually,
no one wins.
Tumor. Cystic?
Solid mass.
Cancer.
The vitamin "K" caused the
D.V.T. and aggravated the liver,
but the tumor's the
real reason for the bleed.
The tumor's the problem.
Mrs. Palmero, I'm Dr. Wilson.
I'm afraid I have some bad
news from your ultrasound.
You have cancer.
It's big. 5.8 centimeters.
We do nothing, she dies
from liver failure within 60 days.
- She needs a transplant.
- That's gonna happen.
- She's 38 years old. She's a mother.
- She's a schizophrenic mother with no money,
on the public dole, in fact,
who knocks back vodka every
time a breeze blows her way.
Mickey Mantle had a whole bar
named after him. He got a transplant.
Yeah, well, Lucy
can't switch-hit.
Plan "B" — Surgery
to resect the tumor.
Joe Bergin does the
gamma knife thing. Laser
cauterizes while it
cuts, saves more liver.
The tumor's way too big.
He won't even consider it.
Not a big risk-taker, Bergin. Won't
even drink milk on its expiration date.
He has no discretion. 5.8 centimeters
is past the surgical guidelines.
Would he do it at 4.6?
Why don't we just say
it's zero? Then we don't
need him at all. Tumors
grow, they don't shrink.
This one does.
Ninety-five percent ethanol.
The ethanol dehydrates
the tumor cells.
Literally sucks them dry.
It shrinks the
tumor temporarily.
How temporarily?
Well, if we're lucky,
just long enough
to fool the surgeon.
Dr. Shopius, report
to Psych Exam.
Dr. Shopius, Psych Exam.
Good morning, Dr. House.
Good morning, Dr. Cuddy.
Love that outfit.
It says, "I'm professional,
but I'm still a woman."
Actually, it sort of
yells the second part.
Yeah, and your big
cane is real subtle too.
Gotta go. Those running noses aren't
just gonna start walking on their own.
The clinic can wait.
How long? Maybe we
could catch a movie.
You should know by now my
doctors have no secrets from me.
I don't believe it.
Who came running to Mommy?
It doesn't matter who. The point
is, I know exactly what you did.
You have no idea
what I'm talking about.
Somebody knows about a bad
thing you did. That's a big field.
But somebody you think might've
told me. That narrows it down quite a bit.
Someone who views me
as a maternal authority figure.
A young person perhaps? How am
I doing? Think I'm gonna get there?
Presumably hospital business.
How many patients— It's Cameron.
She found out about my birthday.
I thought she told you and
I'd have to stand here and
smile while you gave me a
sweatshirt or a fruit basket.
You know, made me feel
that deep sense of belonging.
Actually, I was just gonna remind you,
you owe me six clinic hours this week.
Oops.
Hi, this is Dr. Cuddy.
I need all the charts on
Dr. House's current patients.
I've tried everything. Mm-hmm.
"Pulling the tongue, ice packs
on the throat, hitting yourself,
the groin pinch."
Well, you've certainly covered
all the normal medical bases.
Uh, how are you
hitting yourself though?
Is it with an open hand
or a fist? Open hand.
Uh-huh. Well, that's— that's
how they teach it at Harvard Med.
How hard though?
I'm sorry. I missed that.
Could you do that again?
Uh...
That's—That's very good.
It's hiccups.
I need to speak with
you now. Mm-hmm.
I need to go pee-pee.
Dial it up a notch and
repeat. I'll be back.
Ooh. Girl in the boy's bathroom.
Very dramatic.
It must be very important,
what she has to say to me.
Yesterday your patient's
tumor was 5.8 centimeters.
Today it's 4.6. How
does that happen?
Well, at a guess, I'd say, "That
Dr. House must be really, really good.
Why am I wasting
him on hiccups?"
I wash before and after.
You also requisitioned
20 c.c.'s of ethanol.
What patient was that for?
Or are you planning a party?
Do me a favor.
I was gonna say
leave, but that works.
- You shrunk the tumor.
- Only way to get the guy
to do the surgery.
Fraud was the only way?
There is a reason that
we have these guidelines.
I know. To save lives.
Specifically, doctors' lives.
And not just their
lives, but their lifestyles.
Wouldn't want to operate on anyone really
sick. They might die and spoil our stats.
Bergin has a right to know
what he is operating on. True.
I got all focused on her right to live
and forgot. You do what you think is right.
You really didn't know?
No, I didn't.
And, frankly, I'm angry.
Which I'm guessing
is the correct response.
- Of course, I'll know better once
you tell me what you're talking about.
- Your birthday.
Oh.
Anger was a bad guess.
Well, normally, I'd put on
a festive hat and celebrate
the fact that the Earth has
circled the sun one more time.
I really didn't think it was
gonna make it this year,
but darn it if it wasn't the little
planet that could all over again.
It's a birthday. It's an
excuse to be happy.
You think that's lame?
Why are you here?
Did you buy me a pony?
I'm just waiting
for the surgery.
Yeah, well, go scrub in.
All right, we're
done. Close her up.
The tumor didn't just walk itself into a
bar and order up a double shot of ethanol.
Someone shrunk it down.
I'm sorry. It was
very, very wrong.
House is lucky I
didn't just close her up.
He tries it again,
that's what happens.
I'll pass it on.
It looks like the
surgeon got it all,
but she's gonna have to
have some chemotherapy.
What kind is it?
Luke, stop writing.
If you stop for a second,
it's not all gonna fall apart.
Give yourself a
break once in a while.
The fact is, your Mom's gonna have
an extra drink every now and then.
No. No. She won't. She doesn't.
Fine.
There are some things you
just can't fix. That's all I'm saying.
That's how you'd handle it,
something like this? You'd just give up?
No.
I'd do it just like you.
It's an infusion. She's gonna
have a drain in her abdomen.
You're going to have to
check for possible infection.
Lucas Palmero?
Trina Wyatt, Child Services,
State of New Jersey.
Can I help you?
This is a private room.
He's only 15 years old, a minor.
He's in a tough
living situation.
We're just here to help.
I don't need your help. Fifteen?
Lucas, you're gonna have
to come with us right now.
Where are you taking him?
Until the determination is made,
he'll be housed at Children's Services.
I don't want to be
"housed." I live with my mom.
Not for the next few days.
Come on. Let's not
make this difficult, huh?
Mom?
I love you.
When the Mets
lost, you remember?
Yeah.
I remember.
I love you.
Cuddy didn't say anything about pushing
Bergin to finish the surgery? Not a word.
Some kind of mind game.
She's waiting for me to crack.
Well, either that or she's
just being nice. Yeah, right.
You said you wouldn't call.
You're a real bastard, you know.
Yeah, I get that a lot.
I don't think Mom's crazy.
"For in the old days, though she had
young men's praise and old men's blame,
among the poor, both old
and young gave her praise."
You called Social Services.
It was you.
N— No. No.
It's okay, it's okay. I get it.
He'll have an easier time
dealing with the system.
Sure, he won't be with his real
mother, but his real mother's sick.
Someone needs
to take care of him.
I'm not gonna live here.
What would his future have been,
taking you to chemo and back on the bus?
And even if the cancer's
in complete remission,
he'll still have a mother
who hears voices.
Talk no more.
"Look what I do to him, Limpy."
You said that.
I checked the phone records.
Only one call from this room.
Smart, because they
charge you two bucks a call.
It was to Social Services,
the State of New Jersey.
You're his mother. You
couldn't do it to him anymore.
Good for you.
Schizophrenics can
make rational decisions.
On the small stuff, yeah— When
to sleep, what to drink, you know.
"No lemonade, but I'll take
some hemlock if you've got it."
Huh. Your man Socrates.
But giving up your son because it's better
for him, it's so sane, it's so rational.
Self-sacrifice is not a
symptom of schizophrenia.
It excludes the diagnosis.
She's not schizophrenic? Look, she's
36 years old when she first presents.
It's a little late, but
within the parameters.
The internist sends her to a shrink.
One shrink sends her to the next.
She tells them all she's
not crazy. The drugs don't
work. And why would they
if she's not a head case?
She got clearer when I
took her off the psych meds.
You think I'm crazy. Well,
yeah, but that's not the problem.
Didn't we just leave
your office? I like to walk.
♪♪
Is that Dr. Jeffrey Walters? Hi.
My name is Greg
House. I'm a doctor...
Oh, is that the time? I'm—Yeah. I'm
sorry. My watch must have stopped.
Uh, listen, you treated a patient about 18
months ago, a woman named Lucille Palmero.
I wondered if you
recalled running any tests...
at all.
Oh, how terribly foolish of
me, Doctor. Is it that late?
Yes, I'm calling from London, you
see? Must have got my times mixed up...
I have a headache.
It's my only symptom.
I go to see three doctors. The
neurologist tells me it's an aneurysm.
The immunologist
says I've got hay fever.
The intensivist
can't be bothered.
Sends me to a shrink, who
tells me that I'm punishing
myself 'cause I want to
sleep with my mommy.
Maybe you're just not
getting enough sleep?
Pick your specialist,
you pick your disease.
If it's not schizophrenia, what
else presents with psych symptoms?
- Porphyria.
- The Madness of King George.
What about that copper thing?
What's it called? It's genetic.
The body accumulates
too much copper.
Oh, um, uh, Wilson's Disease?
Yeah. Very rare.
Nice. I like it.
- If any of us did this, you'd fire us.
- Well, that's funny.
I thought I encouraged you to
question. You're not questioning.
You're hoping. You
want it to be Wilson's.
Boom. Give her a couple
of drugs, she's okay.
July 1 7. An appointment
with a Dr. Karn.
She didn't keep it.
She never kept another
appointment with a
shrink he made after that.
Karn is not a shrink. I looked
him up. He's an ophthalmologist.
Now why would she
want her eyes checked?
Wilson's presents with
cataracts, I think. Yes, it does.
It also causes slight cirrhosis, which
Dr. Chase so eagerly attributed to alcohol.
So what are we still doing here?
Lucy!
I don't think you're crazy.
Neither do I.
But I'm crazy. Come
on. Lean over here.
Come on.
That's it.
Put your hands on the bar
here and your chin in here.
Thank you.
You're gonna see
a bright light, okay?
Your body might be
accumulating too much copper.
If it is, this should help us see
something called Keyser-Fleischer rings...
Copper-colored circles
around your corneas.
Wow.
I guess we should start
treating her for Wilson's.
That's what I'd do.
"I will talk no more of
books or the long war,
"but walk by the
dry thorn until I have
found some beggar
sheltering from the wind...
"and there manage the talk
until her name come round.
If there be rags enough, he will know her
name and be well pleased remembering it."
"For in the old days, though she had
young men's praise and old men's blame,
among the poor, both old
and young gave her praise."
Hi, Mrs. Palmero.
Ready to go home?
Almost.
Mom?
How are you?
I'm good.
Oh!
Oh...
Oh, you really need a haircut.
Dr. House.
Luke, we're making
Dr. House wait.
That's okay. We're
just here for the music.
Luke, come on.
I'm being discharged.
I heard a rumor.
Thank God I had cancer, huh?
- It's terrible having everybody
think you're nuts.
- Really?
I called to thank you.
Did you get my message?
Yes.
You're welcome.
I'm never thanking
you. You turned me in.
I told you we were doing okay.
It was none of your business.
Look, I don't care
how you were living.
I just wanted
you out of my life.
That's why I had Dr. Cuddy
call Social Services.
You okay?
You were right.
It wasn't the D.V.T. It was
the schizophrenia. I know.
She's not nearly as
interesting anymore.
Isn't it your birthday
around now?
That's some bad hat, Harry.