Previously on ER:
Are you a sociopath,
a sadist? Stoned?
I heard that you were tightly
wound, but I had no idea.
What am I giving up? A dumpy O.R.?
Overnight call? Below-market pay?
This is not what you want.
Everything was going really
well until the ambulance blew up.
Morris. Don't screw this up.
There's an open artery. I can let him
bleed out or accept the risk of a stroke.
His heart's gone, his brain's
gone. We're pronouncing him.
He was going to be
the chief of the ER.
As we embrace the memory of
our colleague and our dear friend.
Helipad access, ortho
supplies, suture cart...
Nurses' station, drug
lockup, call room.
- There's a call room?
- Yeah, but don't plan on sleeping.
- I didn't come here to sleep.
- Hey, don't be snarky, we just got here.
- Nice dress.
- Oh, Barneys sale, 1800 bucks.
Got it for four. Love that.
Okay, these are the trauma rooms,
take some time to familiarize yourself.
Ah, the new interns.
Welcome to County.
- Those are some shoes.
- Oh, I always wear heels.
Anything else hurts my feet.
Everybody get a chance
to look around Chicago?
We were at a friend's wedding in
Denver yesterday. Drove all night.
Yeah. I washed my hair in a gas
station sink and I came straight here.
You're from Texas, right?
Went to med school in San
Antonio, but I'm from New York.
- I don't speak Spanish.
- Oh.
Ah, everybody meet Dr. Tony Gates
and Sam Taggart, one of our nurses.
- Welcome. SAM:
Nice to meet you.
Gates oversees you, I supervise
him, Sam's got her eye on all.
Be careful, she'll kick your ass.
- Trust him, he knows.
- Aah!
- Security!
Charts, forms, lab
recs, it's all here.
Is this...?
Are these who I think they are?
- It's true.
- Your replacements have arrived.
- Tracy Martin. Nice to...
Oh, thank you, God. I
am not an intern anymore.
Kaya, come meet
your partners in crime.
Hey, you guys. How's it going?
You're an intern too? - Yup.
Skipped the orientation.
Y'all need to get your
behinds down to Personnel.
You can't work without IDs.
And this is Frank. Donuts
will make him your friend.
- Avoid coconut, it gives him gas.
- You can say that again.
Come on.
Hi, I'm Tracy Martin and I am an
intern in the Emergency Department.
Oh, wait. I need a touchup.
Andrew Wade, intern,
General Surgery.
- Surgeon, wow.
- Yeah.
Daria Wade, intern,
Emergency Department.
I should go find where I'm
supposed to be right now.
- Call you later, Dar.
- Honey, honey. Yeah, I know.
I gotta go now. I love you. Bye.
Ryan Sanchez, intern.
My wife's home with the kids.
Getting used to the new place.
Hello?
I did my MBA while I was at
Stanford and the program there is real...
- Hold on, I wasn't ready. WOMAN:
That's enough. You're done.
Put the little penis away.
And you, you're a doctor
now, try to look like one.
And on that note...
three-inch heels have
no place in the hospital.
Catherine Banfield, Attending
physician, chief of the ER.
Hello, everyone.
I'm your new boss.
We see an average of 250 patients
a day. Three hundred if it gets crazy.
- Few years, you can handle anything.
- I'm sure.
- So, what made you come back?
- It was time. Chicago's home.
I don't get the whole
medical-mission thing.
Why chase tragedy overseas when
we've got disaster right at our front door?
It's not for everyone. I thought
the nurse ratio was four to one.
My ex went on a
medical mission. Mistake.
Where are the nurses?
Doesn't look four-to-one here.
We're short, as usual.
This is Haleh Adams, our charge nurse.
Haleh, meet Dr. Banfield, our new chief.
- Welcome.
- Nice to meet you.
- Coffee anyone?
- I'm not into coffee, it's a crutch.
Uh, meet me to run
the board in five minutes.
- Do I know you? You look so familiar.
- I don't think so.
Ever work at St. Mark's? I
pick up shifts there sometimes.
- No.
- Moonlight in Urgent Care?
- I could swear I've seen you before.
- No, it's my first day.
Well, if there's anything you need
to know about this place, just ask.
Cuticle cream?
Latex gloves are
murder on your hands.
Think this used
to be a sandwich?
You guys get settled,
meet me out at the desk.
- You okay?
- Yeah, ahem.
You've been here for
like 96 hours straight.
- We're a little short-staffed right now.
- Us too.
Abby took a few days off with
Luka. And you look like crap.
- Look who's talking? You live here.
- Easier than going home.
- Sleep is overrated.
- Bring it on.
These patients have been
on the board since yesterday.
Hospital's full, they
never discharge at night.
Makes it impossible
to admit anyone.
I'm friendly with the nursing
supervisor on Med Surg.
- Bet you are.
- She can always find a bed for me.
Can you get her
to open things up?
- Lubricate the log jam?
- Do it.
Oh, uh, Dr. Banfield.
I wanted to let you know, I have
to take off a little early tonight.
Um, starting the nurse anesthetist
program, have to drop off my kid.
Leave when your shift's over. I'm a
stickler for that, Sam. It is Sam, right?
Yeah. It's only like 20 minutes.
We all have commitments, just
don't let them bleed into your work.
Wow, new chief seems great.
You know, Alex can hang
out with me and Sarah tonight.
- Really?
- Yeah.
I don't want to be him alone.
- No problem, I'll pick him up after work.
- Thank you. It's a big help.
James Silcott, 26, burns and minor
trauma from a chemical explosion...
- in the apartment next to theirs.
- Decca Richards, 24, same explosion.
Vitals good, abdominal pain.
- Babe, you okay?
- Yeah, I think so.
I'm Dr. Gates, what happened?
- We were reading on the couch.
- This blast came through the walls.
- Both trauma rooms are open.
- Kaya with Dr. Morris.
Gates, you're with
me, Trauma 1, let's go.
- Follow me. SAM: We're
gonna be right next door.
I'll bounce between
and supervise.
We're Attendings. We
don't need to be supervised.
Just watch this time, get
a sense of how things go.
Screw that.
Eighteen gauge in the antecube.
Tachy at 118, pulses are good.
Second degree burns to chest
and arm. Kaya, let Surgery know.
All right, on my
count. One, two, three.
- What exploded?
- I don't know.
Just heard this breaking
glass. Probably his meth lab.
- Guy's a freak.
- HemoCue, trauma panel, type and cross.
Why the ultrasound?
Explosion. Blunt
trauma. That's why.
- How's your pain?
- It's pretty bad.
- My arm's killing me.
- We can get you something.
Five of MS.
Get another set of vitals before you
go dropping his pressure with narcotics.
- Is Decca okay?
- I'll go check.
Good idea.
So, what kind of music
does your band play?
It's hard to explain. Imagine a
punk version of '40s standards.
That makes no sense.
Okay, no fluid, looks good.
You have to check
it out sometime.
- Ow!
- Sorry.
- You want me to try?
- I said stand back and watch.
I had a band once.
Bunch of sexually
frustrated adolescent boys.
All right, IV's
in, hang a liter.
Liter of what?
- Normal saline.
- So be clear.
- Everyone knew what he meant.
- We knew one song...
"You Got Lucky" by Tom Petty,
and we played it over and over.
Over and over again. I'm
not kidding you, it was sad.
- You have a patient on the table.
- A stable patient.
- It's cool, really.
- A trauma case can turn on a dime.
I know that. We're good here.
Every patient that comes through
that door is my responsibility.
And I have to know that
I can trust your judgment.
I'm sorry for
calling so early...
but I've got an obstructive
pancreatitis on the schedule.
You gotta stop
doing this, Dusty.
Would you jump straight to
pancreaticojejunal anastomosis...
or do a sphincteroplasty first?
If the proximal duct is open,
option one, otherwise, two.
Intermittent dilation, go
with a Puestow procedure.
- You are my hero.
- Yeah, yeah. I know.
I gotta run, I'm doing
grand rounds at Rush.
- Dr. Crenshaw?
- What?
Oh, finally, I've
been looking for you.
Andrew Wade, new Surgical intern.
I'm supposed to shadow you today.
- Is black okay?
- Fantastic.
Ahh.
Where is she?
- Probably should get back to work.
- It's my day off.
- I only came in because I wanted to...
- Neela, I know where this is going.
But Lucien's a fantastic
teacher. The patients love him.
And he's an amazing
trauma surgeon.
- I don't disagree.
- Then how can you let him leave?
I don't like it either,
but he forced our hand.
- He was upset. He didn't mean...
- The board voted for dismissal. It's done.
Listen, Captain Hemolysis, you
guys use the same excuse every time.
Spare me the
dog-ate-my-homework crap...
and get me the
potassium level. Thank you.
Impossible to get
anything done around here.
- You okay?
- Yeah.
When was the last
time you had a day off?
I got a guy with Bullous
pemphigoid in Curtain 3.
You should check it out.
Why don't you get
out of here for a while?
It'll be good for you. - Hey.
I need you sign off
on a bunch of stuff.
I'm all yours.
One of the nurses had me
order Bactrim on tricycle girl.
Is that approved for kids?
You're missing the
point. She asked me.
Didn't need my order
co-signed or anything.
Hallelujah. I am so sick of
getting my orders co-signed.
There's always been
someone double-checking.
Making sure we didn't mess up.
Now you feel like you're
flying without a net, right?
- Exactly.
- That's completely normal.
Now, all this
responsibility, I mean...
I want it, it's
just a little scary.
- Hmph!
- What?
If you're not ready, then
you shouldn't be here.
You're ready. It takes
time to grow into this job.
You have complete backup.
No one's expecting you
to run a code the first day.
Now, come on. Let's
start with the basics.
Fever with a murmur.
What's the workup?
Surgery wants to admit the
explosion couple for observation...
- but they have no beds.
- What else is new?
Park them in the hallway, I will
write orders for vitals and fluids.
Hey. See this guy, will you?
He's been waiting
five hours already now.
Oh, so sorry, Frank. We were
eating bonbons in a bubble bath.
Totally lost track
of time. Go say hi.
Hey, I'm Sam. I'm
one of the nurses.
Finally, I was ready
to give up on you guys.
Check this out.
- Do I have flesh-eating bacteria?
- I don't think so.
But, uh, I'll have one of
the doctors take a look.
How long is this gonna
take? I got a big test tomorrow.
And if it were up to
you? What would you do?
- I just got here thirty seconds ago.
- Sometimes that's all you get.
Okay, um, severe
cellulitis, IV antibiotics?
- What kind? SAM:
I don't know, um...
- Ancef?
- No. IV Vanco to cover MRSA.
And don't answer a question
with a question. I hate that.
- Are you gonna give me some medicine?
- What was that?
Just trying to get a sense of how
you think, what you're capable of.
Oh. That's kind of hard to
come up with a plan on...
Hard?
You're an ER nurse. You're the first
line against gunshot wounds, stabbings.
- Think bedside teaching is hard?
- Male found behind the explosion site.
- Let me go.
- Your leg's broken. You can't walk.
Minor burns to neck and
torso. Probable tib-fib, left.
Gates, take this. I'll be right in.
- Listen to me.
- Why won't you listen?
- Can I run it?
- No. I'm Dr. Gates.
- I don't need a doctor.
- Name?
- Shut up.
- We gotta call you something.
- Felix.
All right, ABCs, here we go.
- He breathing?
He's tachypneic. Could
be edema from the fire.
Ryan, on my count.
One, two, three.
Stop!
- Okay, I'm only gonna listen.
- Don't touch me.
Sat's 91. GATES: Sir,
your oxygen level is low.
- We need to evaluate your lungs.
- Leave me alone.
Let me just cut your shirt.
- Don't touch me. Don't touch my stuff.
- Sir, relax.
- Listen to me. Listen to me.
- Whoa.
- What the hell?
- Oh, my God. Now you did it.
- Is this cocaine?
- You cut through the bag.
- Bag?
- You shouldn't have.
- What powder?
- It's weaponized ricin.
- It's extremely lethal. I made it myself.
- Ricin?
- Shouldn't have done that.
- I'm out of here.
Whoa! You open those
doors, the whole ER is exposed.
I told you not to touch
me. Now we're all dead.
- ER.
- Frank, call HAZMAT.
We have a situation here.
Cops said the guy's a real wack job.
Had stuff on anthrax, botulism, plague...
Keep it down, don't
want people to panic.
We're moving people.
They're gonna know.
Environmental Services won't
touch it, they said call HAZMAT.
- Did you?
- Yes.
Fire department is
supposed to respond first.
- What's their ETA?
- Ten minutes out.
I think we should
seal off Exam 2.
With what, duct
tape? I'll find some.
- Morris.
- Right behind you.
If they get sick, we
need to have access.
- A few hours before symptoms manifest.
- We can't leave them in there.
Gotta be quarantined till HAZMAT
can figure out what we're dealing with.
- Let's just concentrate on evacuation.
- Evacuation where?
You know this
hospital, you tell me.
- Hold the elevator.
- Where are you going?
- Upstairs for observation.
- Thought you had no beds.
Well, we can't very well leave
them here in Hot Zone, can we?
Surgical lobby. Come with me.
Dr. Gates, the Hazardous
Materials team is on the way.
I have an unstable patient, three
freaking interns, please hurry up.
I knew the cops would be
all over my place so I ran.
There are no masks in
here. There's no gowns either.
Didn't count on the
fire escape collapsing.
- Shut up.
- Inhalation of aerosolized ricin...
can kill in 24 hours.
Does it say if it's
absorbed though skin?
We should all be wearing gloves.
How's his pulse ox?
God, they're
trapping us in here.
Oh, my God.
Annie, honey, I'm
with a patient, gotta go.
All right, let's stay focused.
Secondary survey, let's go.
A year's supply
of Valium in here.
Don't forget the IV tubing and infusers.
I don't know what they have upstairs.
How much would this
be worth on the street?
After today, I'm thinking
about an alternate career.
You doing all right?
I should bring some
fentanyl too, right?
He's got a phone in there.
You can call and talk to him.
No, he's busy.
I'm busy too. Gotta start my
new career as a drug dealer.
- I don't want that.
- I'm not interested in what you want.
- I didn't mean for this to happen.
- You should've told us about this.
I tried. Listen, my
leg is really killing me.
Yeah, because it's broken.
Unfortunately for you, we can't
help because we're stuck in this room.
- Please. Something's really wrong.
- Look. That doesn't look right.
Yeah. Compartment syndrome.
We have to do a fasciotomy.
You're bleeding from the
fracture into the soft tissue.
That's why blood is
not getting to your foot.
Ryan, go to the code
cart, get morphine.
- Morphine? For this guy?
- We treat everybody the same.
- What's morphine look like?
- It's a clear bottle, black top.
- Says "morphine."
- It's really killing me.
- I don't think there's any here.
- I'm sorry. This is gonna hurt.
- What's your name?
- Daria.
Daria, talk to him. - What?
- Talk to the patient.
- Oh, um...
Okay, so how did you
become a bioterrorist?
Ow!
Damn it.
Hey.
What's going on?
HAZMAT team's 10 minutes out.
Discharge whoever you can,
bring the rest to the evacuation area.
- Moved the portable monitors upstairs?
- Yeah.
Grab whatever you need
because when HAZMAT gets here...
- they're not gonna let you back in.
- Let's move the CHF-er.
- Mr. Burke, you can't leave yet.
- What's going on?
- First I heard bomb scare. Now anthrax.
- It's not anthrax.
Yeah, whatever
it is, I don't need it.
Stop. You have a serious
infection. You need to be admitted...
- to the hospital for IV antibiotics.
- I can't.
I'm supposed to take
the GED tomorrow.
- I'm gonna get my diploma.
- Sam, we're going up.
Please, don't leave. I'm gonna try
to work something out for you, okay?
Okay, go slow, he needs
an expiratory phase.
Any chance we could
use oral antibiotics...?
- No.
- He's gonna go home.
Change his mind.
I said we were taking the
rule-out MIs to Family Practice.
We don't have
enough staff to cover.
But I got the clinic nurses to help...
- Dr. Morris...
the rule-outs
will wait upstairs.
You just let me know
when you need my help.
I'm here for you.
You think the docs in that
room are gonna be okay?
I don't know. I hope so.
I, uh, heard that you worked
in Thailand after the tsunami.
Indonesia.
Well, this must seem pretty
minor compared to that.
Yeah. It is.
ICU says they're not
allowed to lend their machine.
- Don't ask, just take it.
- Intubated patients, there.
Thanks. CRENSHAW:
How many more are left?
- Another 20 or 30.
- We need to make more space.
Respiratory's on the way with more
O2 and Rehab's sending three vents.
Rehab was Marisol's idea.
- This one's a keeper.
- Sorry, gotta take this.
Hey.
Eleven hang-ups, Dusty?
We are under siege.
You do know your
number shows up, right?
I'm stuck with a new intern...
and the ER was the target
of a bioterrorist attack.
- Mm-hm. I used to call that a Thursday.
- Oh, you love this, don't you?
Me, getting my ass kicked
while you sleep in and go to yoga.
I wish, but with all the lectures,
conferences and interviews out here...
it's been grueling. Speaking
of which, I gotta run.
Yeah, okay. No, no.
Wait. Lucien? Lucien?
The ER's been attacked and
you're catching up on phone calls?
- Any headway with Anspaugh?
- No, but he knows it's crap.
- Wouldn't look me in the eye.
- A kid pulled out his G-tube.
- That's Neela's specialty.
- You owe me.
- The guys in the moon suits are here.
- Oh, good, feel much better now.
They must have an exit strategy.
Fracture must've
severed the tibial artery.
I can't see crap.
It says that low micron ricin particles
may be suspended in the air for hours.
- We're screwed. GATES:
Ryan, get me a suture kit.
I'm gonna have to make this incision
bigger to find the bleeding vessel.
Here we go. One, two, three.
All right. Get me 4-by-4s.
- I don't feel so good. TRACY:
Wait, you need to lie down.
- What are you being admitted for?
- Asthma. It's bad this time.
We were here all night, my
mom went home to shower.
- I can't get any air.
- No, it's gonna be okay, I promise.
Daria, find a large BP cuff
and put it around his thigh.
Heart rate's up to 135.
- Look in the drawer for a hemostat.
- Like a clamp?
Yeah. A needle driver,
anything. Come on.
- Do we have any albuterol in here?
- It's too much.
- He's not moving air well.
- Felix, talk to me.
- Who was the ricin for?
- It doesn't matter.
If we're gonna all die here,
you can tell us why. You owe us.
I was gonna send
it to a few officials.
- Systolic's only 84. DARIA:
This cuff is way too small.
- And I'm not finding any clamps.
- Okay.
I'm serious, this
guy needs a neb.
We don't normally keep
respiratory meds here.
- Check the cart. The bottles. FELIX:
Homeland security. What a joke.
We let anyone in. Anything
can happen. It's not right.
Neither is exposing innocent
people to a deadly biotoxin.
She has a point there, Felix.
My wife, she used to
work near the Pentagon.
She got killed by
one of the planes.
All right. I need
Prolene, get me Prolene.
What's Prolene?
Okay, so this is a dose
of Vancomycin now.
You're gonna go home
with this IV tonight.
In the morning, before your
test, come in, show your bracelet...
they're gonna give you
your second dose. Deal?
Deal. Thanks.
It's cool you're getting
your GED, you know.
I got tired of telling people
I dropped out of school.
Challenging
yourself. I admire that.
This is Devon, 8 years old.
Floor collapse, fell into a
basement. Injuries to chest and pelvis.
His mom, Hannah,
jumped to get to her kid.
- Arm looks broken, vitals okay.
- Okay. This way.
Mommy? HANNAH:
Devon, honey, I'm right here.
- Where are you? HANNAH:
Get me off of this thing.
- In a minute, ma'am.
- I need to see my son.
What's going on?
We're closed to trauma.
Accident was four blocks
away, the rig got authorization.
- I never...
- I did. Diverting an unstable kid...
across town would've been
crazy. I authorized them to come.
- Wake up.
- Sats only 82.
Throw me that. This
kid's not breathing.
Five-oh and a Mac two.
All right. I think I
got it. There we go...
God. Crap.
- Another Prolene?
- Oh, his sat's only 81.
- Turn up the 02.
- It's up. It's all the way up.
Felix? Felix?
I can't... Under...
She went out of snow.
He's altered and there's
no albuterol in here.
All right. Mac three and a 7-0.
Hang in there,
I'll be right back.
- What's a Mac?
- Macintosh laryngoscope...
size three, a 7-0 ET tube.
- Got it. We're going to intubate?
- We might have to.
- V-tach. I can't feel a pulse.
- All right. Start CPR.
I can't take my
hand out of here.
Come on. Let's Go.
Ryan, start compressions.
Daria, bag him. Tracy,
charge up the defibrillator.
Let's go. This is
the real thing now.
- Three-sixty?
- Yeah.
Put the paddles on the chest. Come
on. Put the paddles on the chest. Clear.
Go!
- Still V-tach.
- All right.
Resume compressions.
Daria, switch with me.
Put pressure on the artery
like your life depends upon it.
Tracy, give me that tube.
- It's for Jacob. There was only one.
- This guy's not breathing, Jacob is.
- He's a kid. His sats are dropping.
- Shock him again.
- Clear.
- All right.
You're gonna let some
innocent kid suffer...
and maybe die, to save a
low-life who tried to kill us?
Still V-tach. I'm sorry, but why
do you even want to save this guy?
Because we prioritize the sickest
patient. That's what we do here.
If you don't get it,
you don't belong.
Fine. Then you tell
that to the kid's mom.
All right. I'm in.
- Tape.
- Got it.
- Two milligrams?
- Yeah, give it to Daria...
and, uh, always hold the tube against
the soft palate until it's secured in.
Going again.
Clear.
- Still V-tach. Resuming.
- All right.
- What do I do with this?
- Squirt it in the tube.
- Good.
- Here you go.
That one's for Jacob,
two cc's in the IV.
Won't intravenous
epi mess with rhythm?
Maybe but it'll dilate
bronchioles, help oxygenate.
- All right. Do it. Chase it with a flush.
- Here goes.
No change. GATES: All right.
Shock him again, it might work
now with the drugs on board.
Clear.
Back in sinus.
- All right.
- Aren't we the heroes.
Come on. We just saved a guy's life.
- Dr. Gates, it worked.
Jacob's sats are coming up.
- Good.
- Hello? BANFIELD:
It's Cate Banfield.
How you guys doing?
Oh, honestly? We're
a little bored in here.
When you open the doors,
you'll be in a quarantine corridor.
What the hell?
This is so surreal.
- Gates, what do you got?
- Severed tibial artery.
- I got Vascular standing by.
- Status asthmaticus.
- He needs a terb drip in the ICU.
- I'll make sure they have room.
Four of us, dry martinis,
straight up with a twist.
You'll all be decontaminated
and admitted for observation.
I hope they've can
decontaminate our insides...
because we've been breathing
that crap for a long time.
- Ow!
- Positive Murphy sign. Any fever?
Yeah, white count's 24...
ultrasound showed
acalculous cholecystitis.
Looks like you're gonna need an
operation to take out your gallbladder.
- Will I have to stay home from school?
- For a few days.
- We'll be doing it laparoscopically.
- We'll only be making a tiny cut.
If you make a bigger cut,
could I stay home longer?
Don't like school, huh?
I just moved here and everyone
already knows each other.
- Did you write a preop note?
- Not yet.
It's hard, I know. I
just moved here too.
The girls in my new school, well,
they're all into being cool and making out.
I miss Detroit.
Listen, you don't wanna
be cool in 7th grade.
I don't? ANDREW: No way.
Seventh-grade
cool kids peak at 16.
Spend their lives
missing the glory days.
Me and Dr. Rasgotra here,
huge nerds at your age.
- Am I right?
- For sure.
- Got a trauma. They're asking for you.
- Make sure you get consent from mom.
You know, the truth is...
every cool adult will tell you
they were an unpopular kid.
- You're just saying that.
- No, it's like a rule of the universe.
- You'll see.
- I will?
Yeah. The adventure
is just beginning.
- Grab another cordis, this wire is kinked.
- Fluid in Morison's.
- He needs a repeat HemoCue.
- I'm on it.
Hey, hang in there. I
know it's hard to watch.
This is all my fault.
I took him with me
on the job. Ahem.
I don't have anyone to watch
him, stay with him after school.
Believe me, I get that.
I'm a locksmith.
The banks have us running ragged,
changing locks on foreclosed houses.
Sounds depressing.
Who knows why some people's
lives work out and others don't?
It all seems so random.
Yeah.
A subclavian's in, get the blood
bank to rush our packed cells.
Devon thought that he
saw a cat in the house...
and he went inside to see.
And the next thing I know he was
screaming through a hole in the floor.
Your tube's in the
right main stem.
- I know.
- Pull it back.
I put it there to decrease the risk
of pneumo during line placement.
- Then you should decrease tidal volume.
- Okay, you know what?
You need to stop
micromanaging everyone.
Do your job and I won't have to.
- Have this out later.
We need to get
him to surgery now.
Get Ortho in here,
reduce that arm.
- OR's ready.
- Okay, let's go. I'll update you soon.
- No, give her a moment with her son.
- You know, we don't have time for this.
Two minutes.
Listen, baby boy.
I want you to be
strong in there.
Okay?
Because if anything
happened to you...
the world would stop.
You know that, right?
We'll get them in here.
Felix made it to the OR.
Baby, they do it every
year. It's tradition.
- What about Jacob?
- Tucked away in the PICU.
They keep us overnight
the first day. It's a ritual.
Should be fun.
I love you too.
Kiss the kids goodnight.
- Why are you lying to your wife?
- She'd freak if she knew the truth.
Give her a little credit.
- Thanks.
Annie grew up in west Texas,
in a town with like 4000 people.
Never meant to end up
with a guy from Brooklyn.
She was totally against moving
to the city, but I fought for it.
Can't practice emergency
medicine out in the sticks.
Exactly.
- I talked her into this.
- Oh, boy.
She was nervous about
smog, traffic, purse snatchers.
So I can't quite bring myself
to tell her that on my first day...
I was the target of a
weapon of mass destruction.
Hey, you. GATES: Hi.
- You okay?
- Yeah.
Not coughing blood,
the night is still young.
Yeah, there's only eight more
hours till we find out if we're gonna die.
Okay, well, they're looking
for beds for you guys upstairs.
- Can I get you guys some lunch?
- Burgers, fries, onion rings, all on me.
I mean, after all, it could
be our last day this earth.
What's up, Ryan?
You a vegetarian?
Ryan. SAM: Oh!
Hey, we need a gurney here!
- Keloid cowboy can go home.
- He has a follow-up in Surgery Clinic.
Cholecystitis girl will
have to hang here.
She won't mind, she's
crushing on Dr. Andrew here.
- Too bad I only have eyes for you.
- Dusty, that boy's going to the OR.
- I'm pretty sure it's a liver lac.
- Tell them to prep. I'll be right there.
You wanna grab a coffee?
You know, after this settles down?
Or maybe a stiff drink's more in order.
- It's been quite a day.
- Yeah, it has.
I just thought we could
talk about what happened.
Don't mind her,
she's in a foul mood.
Today's her day off, she struck out
with Anspaugh, got into this mess.
- Anspaugh?
- She's on campaign to bring Lucien back.
I told her it was a lost
cause, but Neela's stubborn.
- Your uncle is worse.
- Yeah. Marisol, you work here...
Elective-surgery guys were
asking how they could help.
I suggested they take the
pancreatitis case off your plate.
That is, unless you wanted
to do that one yourself.
Are you for real?
- Got blood pressure yet?
- BP 85/51. It's too low to get access.
- Satting okay?
- Go back to the tent.
- Is it the ricin?
- You haven't been cleared yet.
- Is this what happens?
- Let's let Dr. Banfield fix him. Come on.
- Do you think it's the ricin?
- Seems early, but it's possible.
Brachial artery's here. Slightly
medial, you'll hit the vein.
Got a flash.
- Welcome back. REIDY:
Drug overdose in PEA.
Found him with a syringe
still connected to an IV.
- We're closed to trauma.
- He's wearing a County bracelet...
registered for today. Must've
wandered off for a drug fix.
- My cellulitis guy.
- All right, move him upstairs, let's go.
Resuming compressions.
Narcan's in.
- It's the fourth dose.
- Are we sure it's opiates?
Some guy told the paramedics
they shot heroin together an hour ago.
He has track marks
all over his ankles.
It's called a head-to-toe
exam for a reason.
Hold compressions.
- Still PEA.
- Another epi.
He was taking his
high-school equivalency.
He was not the type of guy
who was gonna shoot up.
You ask about IV drug use before you
sent him out with a portal into a vessel?
Not specifically, no.
You cannot judge people
based on what they're reading.
I expect you to know that.
Just heard from the CDC.
The ricin powder was
too coarse to vaporize.
No chance a toxic dose
could've got into the lungs.
That's good news, Frank.
Exam 2 needs to stay sealed
pending environmental detail.
That's a precaution.
Otherwise, we're clear.
Thanks, Frank.
Hold compressions.
No change.
- That's it, we're done.
- What?
Four rounds of cardiac meds
and still he's in agonal rhythm.
Core temp's dropping,
this guy's dead.
What's our EBL? - 400 cc's.
Not bad. Sponge.
NEELA: How's it going?
Liver lac, grade three,
just like you thought.
Repair's going
well, vitals are solid.
I think Andrew here
is a good-luck charm.
Irrigate right here.
I'll let the ER know.
Is it cool if I go, then?
Yeah, check out the sit-in
outside Anspaugh's office...
on your way out. NEELA: What?
Brenner organized
some kind of protest.
Everyone's talking about it.
- Dr. Dubenko has been an...
- What's going on?
We want Dubenko back.
Dr. Brenner says his uncle responds...
to the whole strength-in-numbers
concept. Sit down, join us.
No. I've, uh, got some
loose ends downstairs.
Be released. Not under
these circumstances.
When can I see Devon?
As soon as he's in
recovery, they'll let us know.
While you were asleep,
the police came by.
They investigated the house.
It seems the prior owner
intentionally broke a water pipe.
Flooded the whole first floor.
A "screw you" to the bank
for repossessing. We see that.
With the heat and humidity, the
floor boards rotted and just gave way.
Doesn't change the fact that
I've been dragging my son...
all over the South
Side changing locks.
He's only 8 years old.
He deserves to be
protected from the world.
You know, this idea that
we can protect our children...
you believe it
because you have to...
but it's an illusion.
So, what? It's all just luck?
All you can do is
hope for the best?
You love him, you
spend time with him...
that's all any kid wants.
One second she's
a raging bitch...
and the next she's
Mother Teresa. I don't get it.
Well, she's pretty good
at faking compassion.
Hey, I know you know this...
but what she said about
the OD, that was crap.
It wasn't your fault.
Thanks, Archie.
Hello?
Disconnected every damn phone.
Pain assessment forms?
File them next to
the H & P sheets.
Okay. Patient satisfaction
surveys? These are all filled out.
I'll take those.
And this looks like an old handout
on renal failure by Greg Pratt.
- Should I toss it? It's from...
- No, you should not toss that.
- That's his work. That's his legacy.
- Dr. Morris.
- Mind if I give you feedback?
- Here we go.
- Control your emotions.
- Can we not do this?
- Act like a leader.
- Oh, come on.
All the criticism, the bullying. That's
how you get people to respect you?
You have been storming
around, sulking all day.
You are an Attending
physician, not a toddler.
Did you think that
I was finished?
You know what, lady? Shut up.
We have been through
hell here the last few weeks.
But somehow we're getting
through it. And you know how?
By showing up here every day
and dedicating ourselves to this work!
You don't know us.
You don't know this place.
And the last thing we need is
for some stranger to come in...
and tell us how it's done.
I know that you lost a friend...
and I'm sorry about that.
But we will never have a
conversation like this again.
Understand?
- Hey.
Can I, uh, talk to you?
Yeah. I'm all ears.
Thank you for what you did.
I mean, the thing for Lucien.
I don't know if it will work,
but I appreciate it. I really do.
No big deal.
And, um, you know, maybe
I'm being presumptuous here...
but, um, if this was in any way some
kind of gesture intended for, well...
me, I guess I just
wanna be clear.
Clear?
We're work colleagues,
and that's all.
I don't wanna go for
coffee or drinks with you.
Not now, not ever. Okay?
So let me get this straight.
Me going to bat for Lucien...
is actually some sort of, uh,
romantic overture to impress you?
You've lost me there.
But, um, don't worry about the
drinks. That's, uh, message received.
Dr. Brenner, your favorite
water-skiers asking for you.
Thank you.
I've got the old records
on your thalassemia guy.
Thank you.
I called the pneumonia
kid's insurance company...
- told them we're not transferring.
- Perfect.
Uh, listen.
I know things have been a bit
rough with you and Dr. Morris today.
And I hope you don't mind
my saying, he's not himself.
He took Dr. Pratt's death
harder than any of us.
But he's a good guy,
he's a good doctor and...
I don't have a
problem with Dr. Morris.
- You don't?
- Nope.
He cares about his patients,
has an opinion, takes a stand.
And works his ass off, which is
more than I can say about you.
- Excuse me?
- You better get things in order, Frank.
It's a mess around here.
I can't believe they made
me throw away my shoes.
Louboutins.
- You know how much those cost?
- No, but I'm sure you're gonna tell us.
That was quite the first day, huh?
- You could say that.
I got to perform a liver
lac on an 8-year-old boy.
- That is so cool.
- Wait, so they're not admitting you?
No. You all heard the
ricin isn't dangerous, right?
What? So, what happened?
I mean, why'd you faint?
I was reading about psychosomatic
responses to perceived toxic threats.
Apparently, it's pretty common.
Oh, so you're a hypochondriac?
I said psychosomatic.
It's different.
Either way, you'll live to
see another day of scut.
Welcome to internship,
the dream starts now.
Cheers.
Hi. GATES: Hey.
Health Department said
you're cool to go. You're free.
- Sweet.
- Later.
See you, kids. DARIA: Bye.
Bye.
- Cute couple.
- Yeah.
- So when are you going to class?
- Forget it.
- It's a bad idea.
- What? Why?
I'm missing work, I'm
barely there for Alex.
The last thing I need
is to complicate my life.
I don't know what happened, but you're
a kick-ass nurse and a good mother...
and this is something you
should do. You'd be great at it.
- Really?
- Yes.
Besides, I wanna spend time
with Sarah and Alex anyway.
All right. I mean, I
guess I can make it...
- if I really hurry.
- Of course you can. Go.
I'm just gonna get some beer,
we're gonna play quarters...
spark up the bong.
Hey.
I'm glad you didn't die today.
The whole department was there.
Doctors, nurses, techs, clerks.
They were all sat outside
Anspaugh's office...
demanding your return.
Can we talk about this
later? I'm about to go out.
What's there to talk about?
These things
happen for a reason.
Maybe it really is
time to move on.
Time for a new chapter.
You belong at County.
You know it and I know it.
Don't make me beg.
It's healthy to change
things up, you know?
- I was stagnating there.
- Oh, that's bollocks.
That's what my yogi says, and
I'm telling you, he's always right.
Lucien...
don't be an idiot.
Come back to work.