Previously on "ER."
John, what are
you doing here?
You asked me to help.
I'm here to help.
Oh, 'cause you don't
want your mom and dad
to find out that
you've been shooting heroin.
I'm‐I'm not.
You need to find
a research grant
to cover your salary
before the end of the year
or look toward
private practice.
I'm going to
talk to her.
I know that I make him happy.
I know I do, I can tell
but he just keeps giving
me these mixed signals.
I'm like a magnet
for needy people.
‐ They find me wherever I go.
‐ Like I did?
You really
don't need to leave.
Yeah, I really do.
'You've been up all night?'
Just finishing.
Thanks, buddy. You saved me.
How many pots of coffee
did you burn through?
You should update your software.
This word processor's archaic.
Yeah, well, there's nothing like
waiting till the last minute.
‐ Nice patch.
‐ Yeah.
Well, gum
wasn't working.
Don't laugh.
I haven't
had a cigarette
for 56 hours.
So when is this thing?
‐ What thing?
‐ Your presentation.
‐ Are you going somewhere?
‐ Yeah. I'm going to work.
‐ What about the luggage?
‐ Oh, that's, uh, Cynthia's.
Airline screwed up.
San Diego.
‐ Does she know you have it?
‐ Well, she must.
Oh, and why are
you hangin' onto it?
Well, you know, she
quit before I got back.
Mark, look, if you
don't wanna see her
you take it to work,
you leave it there.
She picks it up
when you're not around.
'You don't force
her to come here'
unless of course
you do wanna see her.
You're right.
I just didn't know she
was gonna take it so hard.
Cynthia?
Cynthia, it's Mark.
Hello.
You..
‐ Moving on, Leason.
‐ Uh, yeah, that's me.
Forty six‐year‐old female
acute onset
urticaria and wheezing.
Possible allergic
reaction to the Naprosyn
she takes for
rheumatoid arthritis.
‐ Did you check her platelets?
‐ Yeah, no evidence..
Jerry, a guy from Kinko's
is gonna drop some
stuff off for me.
‐ You want a July issue of‐‐
‐ No, thanks.
‐ Does that sound right, Ross?
‐ Sounds good to me.
Did you get my memo regarding
reinstating formal rounds?
Yeah, you can't
have too many rounds.
Would you like to join us?
It's sort of
an attending thing.
Watch her with that Naprosyn.
‐ It's got a long half‐life.
‐ Okay.
Can anyone take
a transfer call?
‐ Sure. I got it.
‐ Okay. Meyer.
A 68‐year‐old male,
got kicked off a plane
because he smelled
too bad, he had a cough
and nowhere to go,
so they shipped him here.
‐ Sorry, Carter.
‐ Uh‐huh.
‐ Keep going.
‐ Matthews, little old lady..
‐ You nervous?
‐ Huh?
'Well, don't you present
your PCA research today?'
‐ Yes, I do.
‐ I read the study.
You make some
persuasive arguments.
Thanks, Kerry.
I did have a few questions
about your methodology.
You could run into trouble.
Too late, isn't it?
'You could always postpone.'
I thought you said
I was persuasive.
You were. You
convinced me PCA works.
‐ 'But you need to prove it.'
‐ I did.
‐ Sorry I'm late.
‐ 'Your control group has a‐‐'
What took you so long?
I got here before you did.
‐ Construction on South Shore.
‐ What construction?
‐ Did I miss rounds?
‐ Yeah, in progress.
Could‐could you take over?
I got a meeting.
‐ Sure. Anything interesting?
‐ Oh, Doug, good, you're here.
We got a seizing
five‐year‐old coming in.
'Code three,
suspected poisoning.'
‐ ETA?
‐ 'Right now.'
We can talk more
about this later.
Sorry, you made
your point, Kerry.
I was worried when you
were gone all night.
It took me longer
than I thought it would.
‐ Did you finish?
‐ Yeah, here we go.
Adrian Reynolds,
six years old
was found seizing by
mom near basement sink.
We witnessed two grand mal
seizures, three minutes long.
‐ Total of five‐‐
‐ Trauma two!
‐ 'Hey, Doug, you need a hand?'
‐ 'Yeah.'
Yeah, alright, send him over.
‐ No. Dr. Del Amico.
‐ I can get this.
No, no, that's okay. I'm fine.
Uh, uh, yeah, well,
we're here to serve.
‐ Okay, where are we?
‐ Done.
Guy needs a fleet's
enema in three
and I'm out of here.
I'll see you in 12 hours.
I'll be sure to have
something for you.
‐ Yeah, I bet.
‐ That was easy.
Mr. Kyle's back. End‐stage
lung cancer, exam two.
Carol told me
to give him to you.
Oh, no. Haven't you heard?
Dr. Greene kicked the habit.
Be right there, Lily.
You're still
smoke‐free, aren't you?
You got a lot of
charts there, Carter.
Guess I'd better
get started.
Jerry, what is all this?
Uh, just a little
spring cleaning.
Yeah, well,
it's still winter.
Did Cynthia leave
a forwarding address?
Uh, not that
I know of. Why?
Uh, I just got, you
know, some of her stuff..
Hmm. That's always
kind of awkward, isn't it?
What's the extension
for personnel?
Um, oh, they wouldn't know.
She came in and picked
up her check personally.
‐ When?
‐ A couple of days ago.
Ah, look at that, Twinkies.
‐ You're not gonna eat that?
‐ Why not?
They have a shelf
life of seven years.
1993, I'm in the zone.
Jerry, call
poison control.
Patch it through to
trauma two now. Okay?
Sure.
‐ Pupils are dilated.
‐ He's bradycardic.
‐ Pulse ox, 90.
‐ He's hot.
‐ Temp's 103.
‐ Any vomiting?
‐ Yeah.
‐ BP's 70 palp.
‐ Doesn't make sense.
‐ Glucose 110.
He doesn't have any
history of epilepsy?
‐ I didn't ask.
‐ He's seizing.
Hang on..
Alright, let's give
him one mig of ativan.
You've no idea
what he took?
Whatever it was, it
was in this soda can.
Let's see that.
It ain't soda.
CBC, lytes, tox screen, give
me a blood gas, blood alcohol.
Let's get that
can to the lab.
‐ Where's his parents?
‐ They were right behind us.
I told them to bring anything
that could be toxic
they have in the house.
‐ Pulse 45.
‐ 0.5 of atropine.
‐ Bring back..
‐ Lavage?
Not if it's alkali,
acid or petroleum.
What did he take?
Trust me, I took anthropology
as an undergraduate.
Cro‐Magnon man is considered
a modern homosapien
just like you.
Thank you very much.
Well, I didn't say
he was as good‐looking.
Fine, let's bet on it.
Loser buys lunch.
Look, if you wanna
take me to lunch, just‐‐
‐ If it isn't Lucy and Ricky.
‐ Pardon?
Did you read today's
"Sun Times," Peter?
There's a feature on
our little Lizzie here.
I've got
a lap choly waiting.
"Risking her own life,
the resourceful British surgeon
"refused to
abandon Leipzinger
in the twisted rubble"
blah, blah, blah.
"The doctor's
and the patient's fate
were now one."
Well, not exactly.
You're not walking around
with a prosthetic, are ya?
‐ I read the article, thank you.
‐ Yeah, I bet you did.
You probably bought
out the newsstand.
Not a very good
picture of you though.
Well, we can't
all have your
devastating good
looks now, can we?
"Despite Dr. Corday's heroic
efforts, County General surgeons
were unable to save
Leipzinger's arm."
Well, at least they
didn't mention me by name.
It's an oversight,
I'm sure.
Be sure you tell Larry King
you only fly first‐class.
Oh, almost forgot.
Your six‐month review.
I wish it could be as
glowing as the article.
‐ How is he? Is it poison?
‐ Is this from the house?
‐ Yeah.
‐ We got a soda can.
‐ What do you keep in it?
‐ Nothing.
‐ Soda.
‐ 'Oh, boy.'
BP's 70/40.
Resps, 32 and shallow.
‐ What is all this?
‐ Photography supplies.
Uh, uh, thinners,
paint solvents.
I‐I don't know how he‐‐
We need to know what he
swallowed so we can treat him.
‐ Can't you tell?
‐ He has conflicting symptoms.
It could be more than
one of these poisons.
Treat him
for everything.
The wrong treatment
could kill him.
Anna, did you approve a transfer
from Bellarmin Memorial?
A motorcycle accident?
Uh, yeah, head injury.
John Doe, no. ID.
Can the poison
kill him?
‐ 'Can the poison kill him?'
‐ 'Yes, it can.'
BP's 85/50.
Pulse 50, resps 12.
‐ What's wrong?
‐ He's unresponsive, GCS seven.
Did he decompensate
en route?
No. We picked him up this way.
They told me it was
concussion syndrome‐‐
Brief LOC, stable vitals.
‐ No CT?
‐ They said it was down.
He's uninsured,
just needed observation?
‐ What? They lied to me?
‐ Let's get our own CT.
‐ Pulse ox is falling.
‐ I can't believe they did this.
Should we control
an airway first?
I knew it was a dump,
but this is gross negligence.
‐ Anna?
‐ Yeah. Sorry.
Uh, 2 of versed,
150 sux and 10 of Pavulon.
‐ 7.5 ET tube.
‐ Got it.
I am sure once we
get you cleaned up
they'll let
you back on.
It's not right.
I sold all my stuff
to buy that ticket.
Yeah?
‐ Where were you going?
‐ Am going.
I am going.
San Francisco.
That sounds urgent.
You know, I'm gonna
get a chest x‐ray.
Check out that cough.
My daughter's there.
I was hoping I could
live with her for a while.
Yeah, maybe she can
wire you some money.
Well, I don't have
her phone number.
Do you know
where she lives?
In San Francisco.
No. I mean, do you
have an address?
Why do you care?
I don't want you
stranded in San Francisco.
What are you gonna do
when you get there?
That's my problem.
I'll meet you in CT.
Call me when
neurosurgery gets there.
I just wanna check on this.
Adrian, come on,
Adrian, can you hear me?
‐ Come on, buddy.
‐ What happened?
‐ He's waking up.
‐ Come on, Adrian. Come on.
‐ Did you find the poison?
‐ No, not yet.
Listen to me, I'm Dr. Ross.
You're in a hospital. Alright?
'Now we'll make you better. You
gotta tell us what you took.'
Adrian, it's dad. You need
to tell 'em what you drank.
‐ I don't know.
‐ 'Listen, buddy.'
Adrian? Hey. No, no, no.
Hey, stay with us. Come on.
What's in the can?
What was in the can?
‐ Eric gave it to me.
‐ Eric? Who's Eric?
Eric!
Here we go again.
Another seizure.
‐ How many is that?
‐ 'It's his fourth.'
We're gonna have to stop these
or they'll fry his brain.
‐ Phenobarb..
‐ 'Pulse ox 88.'
‐ Doug?
‐ Tube him.
‐ Keith, no!
‐ What did you give him?
‐ Hey!
‐ Keith, no.
Chuny, get security.
‐ Tell me what you said to him!
‐ Keith, stop it!
Tell me what you gave him
or I'll make you
sorry you were born!
‐ Put him down.
‐ I promise!
‐ He poisoned my son!
‐ I understand that.
This doesn't help. Alright?
He's right, Keith. Come on.
‐ Get back here, Eric!
‐ I got him. I got him.
Eric?
Eric, hey.
Eric, hey. Hey.
Hey, buddy. Hey. Eric? Hey.
'Go away.'
‐ Listen, I'm Dr. Ross.
‐ 'So?'
So‐so you and I have to talk
and we don't have a lot of time.
‐ I'm not afraid of you.
‐ It's just you and me here.
Okay? Your dad isn't here.
'He's not my dad.'
Okay.
Your..
Your brother is very sick.
‐ 'Half brother.'
‐ Your half brother.
And he could die if you don't
tell us what you gave him.
'Now, is that what
you want, Eric?'
'Hey, come on.'
‐ I don't care.
‐ 'I think you do.'
'I think you care.'
Eric, come on, buddy.
Come on out.
Buddy, come on out. I gotta
talk to you. Come on out.
There you go. Hey, there,
come here. Come here.
Listen to me.
What is it?
Your step‐father
did that to you?
‐ He's gonna kill me.
‐ No, he's not.
No. He's not.
This black bottle.
‐ Is this print developer?
‐ Yeah.
The kid mixed print developer
with insecticide.
‐ Cyanide.
‐ I'll get a kit.
‐ Where's Eric?
‐ He's gonna be alright.
We're gonna start
with inhalation.
Amyl nitrate pearl
then sodium nitrate, 5cc's
of three‐percent solution.
‐ Is he gonna be alright?
‐ 'Wait 15 minutes.'
30cc's 25% sodium thiosulfate.
What is wrong with him?
Why won't you tell us?
Don't worry, ma'am. We're gonna
take care of both of your kids.
No way, I already washed
him when he came in.
‐ What, with soap?
‐ Look, I don't lather.
I gave him the bar.
The rest was his business.
Could you also try
adjoining cities?
It's supposed to be on
Bellflower Avenue. Yeah.
Listen, if I don't
get him cleaned up
he's not getting
on the plane.
You know where
the showers are.
Dr. Greene?
‐ Carol.
‐ Malik.
See if you can get him
some clean clothes too.
‐ Don't push it.
‐ 'Hey, Dr. Greene.'
‐ Hmm.
‐ It's not due to trauma.
He's got a subarachnoid bleed.
They should have
never transferred him.
‐ What did neurosurgery say?
‐ I'm still waiting.
Well, grab them and get 'em
down here if you have to.
Find out what
happened up there.
I'm already on it.
How are you feelin',
Mr. Kyle? Better?
Steroids always
seem to help.
Can you lean forward?
Take a breath.
Again.
I think I need
a little more theophylline.
I'll check the level.
I think we're gonna need
to get a repeat chest film.
What for? To see
the same ugly spots?
'I think the effusion'
secondary to your
cancer is, is back.
And if that's the case
we'll need to tap you.
You mean stick a needle
in my chest again?
'It‐it'll make you feel better.'
No. No, thanks.
I think we're gonna have
to admit you this time.
If you were dying,
would you wanna
spend the rest
of your life here?
You could go into
respiratory failure.
Take me home, Rose.
'I don't know, honey.'
Maybe we should
listen to him.
Rose, take me
home. Please.
Your blood oxygen
level is very low.
I'd like to put you
on a monitor for a while.
Trust me, doc.
This is as good as I get.
There you are.
All ready for this
carotid endarterectomy?
Apparently, you
don't think so.
Ah, you've had a chance
to review your evaluation.
I actually thought
I was quite generous.
I'd hate to catch you on
one of your more
parsimonious days.
Let me make something clear.
'I'm your biggest fan.'
If I didn't think you
showed great potential
I never would have sponsored
you in the first place.
'Then what's the problem?'
Frankly, you're distracted.
‐ Distracted?
‐ 'Yes.'
You came here
to study trauma surgery
and lately, you
seem more interested
in, uh, vocal cords
and paramedics.
I see, so I suppose I
should refocus my energies.
Exactly, and speaking
of which, I'm starting
a new study on
the use of HemoAid
in vascular procedures.
Have you heard of it?
It's the artificial blood.
Thought you might like in on it.
We could do a paper together.
The ER at Bellarmin as much
as admitted he was a dump.
Couldn't get the prima donna
neurosurgeon to come in.
What's his name?
Zaccarria. You know him?
He has
privileges here.
It's a blown
aneurysm, alright.
Yeah.
Jerk probably heard
"uninsured John Doe"
and went right back to his
country club without a second‐‐
He doesn't want
to open himself up
to malpractice
without at least
the possibility
of getting paid.
So? It's against the law
never mind the Hippocratic oath.
Won't help much now.
He's got bifrontal
intraparenchymal edema.
I'll put in
an ICP monitor
and manage
him expectantly.
And that's it?
Well, continue
the mannitol
keep his head elevated
maintain hyperventilation
and wait.
For him to die.
Basically.
Hey, would his chances have
been better before the transfer?
It's hard to say.
You don't know when
the aneurysm blew, so..
So there's no
surgical option? Nothing?
The only thing
you could try is
a partial frontal lobectomy,
but the chances that
that would affect outcome
are extremely remote.
‐ So do it.
‐ I can't make that call.
Who can?
Dr. Mack,
and she's in surgery.
Excuse me.
‐ Hey. Time to reset the clock.
‐ What?
‐ Oh, yeah.
‐ At least take off the patch.
I did.
What are you doing?
The copy place swears
that they sent
the order over here.
‐ Your presentation?
‐ Yeah.
And Jerry said
he never saw it.
Wait, Jerry was throwing
a bunch of stuff out.
I knew it.
‐ You kept the original?
‐ No.
Can you help me out or are
you a little out of breath?
How's that poisoned
kid been doing?
He's gonna make it.
Medically, he's fine.
You know, sometimes
working with kids is great
and sometimes
it really sucks.
Yeah. Hold it,
under that crate.
Under that crate,
what's that?
Look at that.
What is that?
They don't throw biohazard
out here, do they?
No, it's probably
just somebody's pudding.
Ugh! And why were you
so late this morning?
I stopped by
to check on Cynthia
see if she's alright.
Yeah? Is she?
I don't know.
She wasn't there. She moved.
Victoria's Secret
catalogue, huh?
Look at the label. Lily.
‐ Lily.
‐ I‐I‐I feel bad.
You know, I don't think it
was fair. I was pretty selfish.
Hey, listen, I know
all about being selfish.
But what was really
wrong with her?
She was, you know,
funny, supportive‐‐
‐ Good‐looking.
‐ Yeah. Great in bed. I..
I...you know, she
was actually nice to me
which was a bit
of a departure
from most of
the women in my life.
‐ Give her a call. Call her up.
‐ I tried.
‐ She's unlisted.
‐ There it is.
I'm gonna kill him.
Hold on to that.
Jerry!
'Think he'll make
chief of staff?'
No, it's just something
to get him closer to Carrie.
Yeah. Then she'll
console him.
And then
they'll get it on.
I don't know about that.
She's in love with Austin.
‐ Huh. This month..
‐ Can't reach.
Here, it's back on.
'See, now, this is what I hate.'
'Here's Marlena
again in the hospital.'
'She's all made up, high heels.'
Nobody's that
gorgeous all the time.
You're prettier
than she is.
That's probably the nicest thing
anybody's said to me all year.
Don't get a big head.
I'm just saying.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Hey, you're all done.
Last round of
chemo. Congrats.
Maybe next week,
we can go to a movie
instead of coming here
and filling me with nuke juice.
‐ That sounds like fun.
‐ What do you wanna see?
‐ What movie?
‐ Well, um..
I don't know what my
schedule is next week.
I'm working
back in the ER.
‐ 'I'm done‐‐'
‐ Working for my dad.
You're done with your treatment.
You won't need me anymore.
Don't need you now.
You do your thing.
I'll go get your meds.
Dr. Ross,
Mary Jo Reynolds.
‐ Thank you for saving my son.
‐ You're welcome.
But you need to talk
to the people upstairs.
They won't let Keith
in to see Adrian‐‐
We are concerned
for the children's safety.
So are we. That's why
Keith wants to see him‐‐
So now both your
boys are gonna be
placed in protective custody
until Department of
Children and Family Services
can investigate. Okay?
It was an accident. Eric
didn't mean to hurt Adrian.
This is Eric's way
of‐of hitting back.
Hitting back?
Nobody hits Eric.
Well, that's for
the DCFS to determine.
No‐no one needs to
determine it, it's the truth.
‐ Okay. Excuse me‐‐
‐ No, you don't understand.
Eric is out of control.
He has terrible tantrums,
and he throws things
and he kicks things.
He lies, he kicks
his teachers.
Keith has to be strict to
keep him in line. That's all‐‐
Strict? Okay, now, burning
cigarettes into his arm.
That's strict?
‐ Eric did that to himself.
‐ Okay.
You can't keep
our boys from us.
Keith's not
gonna like this!
He's not gonna
like it at all!
Yeah, he'll get over it.
I'd avoid the men's bathroom
for a while if I were you.
Who's got the kidney
stone in one?
I do. You listen, my guy
doesn't have a lot of money.
And I'm also worried
about his mental health.
‐ 'Alright, syncope in three?'
‐ Yeah, yeah.
Can't, well, can't you
stick your head in the OR
and find out how
much longer she'll be?
No, the resident
already checked him.
Six OD's coming in,
five minutes out.
Paramedics said the site
looked like Jonestown.
‐ Some kind of party.
‐ Alright.
Call Kerry. Tell him
we'll meet them outside.
It's unlisted.
I know it's unlisted.
But listen, she's
his only daughter.
I just wanna make sure
he's got some place to go.
Your guy
passed his stone.
Thank you.
I got it. Thanks.
Don't go far. We got
multi OD's comin' in.
Yeah, this is Dr. Mark Greene
from the emergency room
at County General.
I have an older gentleman
here who has no place to go.
He says his daughter
is in the area
but he doesn't
have a number on her.
At least he says
it's unlisted.
I was wondering
if you could help me.
Hooper. Cynthia Hooper.
Okay, I've got your..
Scotty.
Excuse me. Do you know
where Scott Anspaugh went?
He went home about
ten minutes ago.
‐ I thought you were with him.
‐ Thanks.
Respiratory arrest.
We intubated.
‐ Pulse 126. BP's 30/60.
‐ What happened?
‐ Bad heroin.
‐ Six OD's.
‐ Three in respiratory arrest.
‐ Roommate found 'em.
Said they couldn't wait
to try this new mix
after they heard it killed
some guys in Detroit.
‐ Talk about a death wish.
‐ Not today.
Another two of narcan.
Prep a dopamine drip.
On my count. One, two, three.
'John? John!'
‐ Yeah?
‐ 'Come here!'
‐ Go ahead, I got it.
‐ What is it?
It's Chase.
‐ 'You know him?'
'‐ It's his cousin.'
How long's
he been down?
'I found him in
respiratory arrest'
'over 20 minutes ago.'
Asystole!
I got it. Where are we?
Epi times two, two migs atropine
two of narcan, an amp of D50.
Unresponsive to all.
Accu‐Chek the glucose.
Let's get a blood gas.
CBC, lytes, tox screen
and a chest film.
‐ I'll get the gas.
‐ Don't do this, Chase.
Damn you, don't do this.
'It looks like he aspirated.'
Amp of bicarb, high dose epi,
seven milligrams.
‐ Seven?
‐ Yes, seven, now.
Anna, take over for me.
Get the transthoracic pacemaker.
Blood gas, PO2 50,
PCO2 65, pH 6.9.
Alright, come on, let's go.
Let's hurry it up.
With that pH,
he's been down a long time.
Let's roll him.
It's not capturing.
Turn up the gain.
It's severe hypoxia.
‐ Crank it all the way!
‐ It is cranked.
Carter, he's
probably brain‐dead.
Come on, come on.
It might be PEA.
No, no, it's capturing.
There's a carotid pulse.
Alright, start a dopamine drip
ten mikes per kilo.
‐ Where's the vent?
‐ 'I got a BP, 40 palp.'
‐ How long was that?
‐ I'm calling respiratory.
‐ Told you, about 40 minutes.
I don't know how long he
was down before I got there.
Okay, call the MICU.
Tell them we're on our way.
We need an EEG and a brain scan.
So, where are
you taking me?
Uh, somewhere cheap. You know
you won on a technicality.
That statue looked
like a caveman to me.
Hah, really?
He reminded me of Romano.
That super orbital torus,
that prognathic jaw.
Yeah. So much for evolution.
Retrogression, actually.
Don't let him
get to you.
That's easy
for you to say.
You're not a kept woman.
I need his sponsorship
to stay in the US.
You know, he's just
trying to rattle you.
Okay, if he, if he gives you
some criticism that's valid
then compensate,
overcompensate.
‐ And the study?
‐ Well, do you have a choice?
‐ I mean, you do all the work‐‐
‐ 'Peter.'
You know, his name
is gonna come first.
Hey, Jackie.
What are you doing here?
Oh, arranging a natural history
exhibit for Humboldt Park.
What are you doing here?
Oh, um...uh...
settling a bet.
Uh, this is my colleague
Elizabeth Corday.
Elizabeth, this is
my sister, Jackie.
‐ Oh!
‐ How do you do?
‐ Very well, and you?
‐ Great.
Elizabeth's from England.
I was just showing her around.
Oh, lucky you.
Peter's not usually so
generous with his time.
Yeah, well, um..
...you know..
...it's important that we..
...support our colleagues.
Of course.
Yes. Uh, we support
each other quite often.
'Hi. You've reached
the Hooper residence.'
'We can't take
your call right now'
'but please leave
a message. Thanks.'
Hey, you wanted to see me?
Yeah, a four‐year‐old
came in wheezing.
Did you get the EEG?
Slow diffuse activity.
You think I pushed too far?
No. I would have
done the same thing.
I should have
gotten him into detox.
If he didn't wanna go
it wouldn't have
worked. Believe me.
'You helped him the only way
he'd let himself be helped.'
Yeah, and a lot of good it did.
‐ 'Did you call your family?'
‐ No.
His folks are in Singapore.
My grandparents
are on their way.
It's probably my neurosurgeon.
Are you gonna be okay?
Yeah. Sure.
Impending respiratory failure.
BP's 90 palp. Resps 40.
O2's at 10 liters.
‐ He fought us all the way in.
‐ 'Alright, trauma one.'
He didn't wanna come back, but
I've never seen him this bad.
‐ I had to call.
‐ Yeah, you did the right thing.
His pulse ox
is down to 88.
We started an IV, but he
wouldn't let us intubate.
Okay, Mr. Kyle, we're
gonna take care of you.
Just gonna get
a chest x‐ray
and we'll probably
have to do that tap.
Is he gonna be here long?
I promised he
wouldn't have to stay.
I'm afraid we're gonna
have to admit him this time.
Alright, everybody,
on my count.
Excuse me. Can I help you?
‐ Are you his doctor?
‐ Yes. Do you know this man?
I'm his son. What happened?
How did he get here?
Oh...we're not
exactly sure.
Uh, we don't
even know his name.
Uh, Tom. Tom Dibble.
‐ How‐how did you find‐‐
‐ The cops called.
They, uh, picked
up his motorcycle.
I would have been here
sooner, but they sent me
to the wrong hospital.
Yeah, the other
hospital sent him here.
Why? What's
wrong with him?
Uh, your father had
a brain hemorrhage.
He wasn't
wearing his helmet?
No, not from
the trauma.
He had an aneurysm.
A blood vessel ruptured
inside of his head.
It probably
caused the crash.
What do you
do to fix it?
We're trying to relieve
the intracranial pressure
with medication.
But it's not working?
I'm waiting for
the chief of neurosurgery
to take a look.
They can operate?
There is a slim
chance that a partial
frontal lobectomy
might work.
And if it doesn't?
He'll die?
He might.
That's a mess, huh? Ooh.
End‐stage lung cancer.
‐ Guy still alive?
‐ If you call it living.
‐ He's a smoker, right?
‐ Yeah.
Shouldn't you be
at a podium by now?
‐ Wait, you do present today?
‐ Yeah.
‐ Come on, Doug, let's go.
‐ Wait a second. She's going?
You use my computer all night,
you don't tell me what it is
but the girlfriend
gets to go?
Well, someone has
to hold his cue cards.
Can somebody see
this Colicky baby?
‐ The mother's driving me nuts.
‐ Ooh, hey, I'll take that.
No, no, no, I'll take it.
I wouldn't want
you to be late.
Alright, you call me if
you need a second opinion.
Yeah, I think I can handle it.
Hi, Luisa. Is Scott upstairs?
He's in the bathroom.
Jeanie! Jeanie! Come look!
I made a fort in my room.
In a minute, Evette.
I wanna check on your brother.
‐ He said to leave him alone.
‐ I know.
Why don't you get your sticker
book and I'll meet you there.
‐ Okay.
Scott?
Scotty.
You forgot your Zofran.
Where's your IV?
It was empty. I took it out.
'By yourself?'
I saw you do it
a hundred times.
You took off on me.
Ask my dad. He'll
pay your cab fare.
Scott...I don't
know what to tell you.
Your dad paid me to help
you through your chemo
but that doesn't
mean we have to stop
being friends
now that you're done.
I have friends.
I don't need any more.
Well, that sucks.
Why?
'Cause I need all
the friends I can get.
So, how about Saturday?
How about it?
I can't go to the movies next
Friday, but I can go Saturday
unless you're too cool
to hang out with me.
You are pretty sorry.
Speak for yourself,
Captain Baldy.
Next month, my
hair will grow back
and you'll still be sorry.
Yeah, well, just for that
I get to pick the movie.
No way.
No chick flicks.
Oh, right,
Mr. "Days‐Of‐Our‐Lives."
I can't believe it.
Now she's quiet.
Well, I'll give you
a fact sheet on colic.
No, please.
I've read everything.
Let me just stay
until her next feeding
so you can see
how bad she gets.
No problem. I'll, uh,
check her in a little while.
Chuny, we're slowing down.
So tell Mark I'm going over
to the med school
for half an hour.
Sure.
Hey, who called
the Grim Reaper?
Hmm?
Hey...what are
you doing down here?
I heard John Doe's
family came in.
Yeah, but we're
not ready to have
a conversation
about organ donation.
Okay, I just came down
to do an apnea test
see how close he was.
Well, he's not
brain‐dead yet.
Neurosurgery said it was
only a matter of time.
I‐I don't care
what they said. I‐‐
‐ Dr. Del Amico
‐ Yeah, hold on.
I haven't given
up on him yet.
‐ Hi.
What was that, uh,
what was that thing
that you said
that they could try?
A partial
frontal lobectomy.
No. I'm sorry.
There's really
nothing more we can do.
Uh, your resident said
it was a possibility.
‐ He shouldn't have.
‐ It's worth a shot, isn't it?
I mean, he's a teamster.
He's got great insurance,
if money is a problem.
No, that isn't it.
It's just that surgery
isn't warranted in this case.
She said he might die
if you don't operate.
I'm afraid he will die,
no matter what.
I want a second opinion.
You say one thing,
she says another thing‐‐
I understand. I'm
the chief neurosurgeon here.
You'll have to get it
from another hospital.
I want all of his records.
Sure. I'm really
very sorry.
I wish I could help.
Excuse me for a second.
Hey, uh, pardon me, Dr. Mack..
I‐I don't understand.
He's right.
If the patient's
gonna die anyway
why not at least try?
There's no indication
for a lobectomy.
Isn't it worth
the effort though?
We don't perform
invasive brain surgery
for the heck
of it, doctor.
I understand that
but someone needs
to take a risk
and try to help this man.
Bellarmin dumped him,
we wanna harvest his organs.
He deserves a chance,
not matter how remote.
There is no chance.
I appreciate that you
wanna do something
but know what the hell
you're talking about
before you play
on someone's hope.
That kid's already
lost his father.
The heroin depressed
his respiratory center
which led
to cardiac arrest.
We got his heart going again,
but...everything indicates
that his brain was
deprived of oxygen
for a significant
period of time.
But you don't
know for sure.
No, his pupils
are reactive
and he withdraws
from painful stimuli
but his brain‐wave activity
is slow and diffuse.
Speak English, son.
He has probable
brain damage.
What's "probable?"
Can't be quantified.
It could run from..
...memory impairment to
a chronic vegetative state.
We‐we ju...I don't..
Did you know
about this?
‐ The drug use?
‐ Yes, drug use!
'Oh, John.'
Did you think to do
anything about it?
Yeah, I helped him detox.
Where? Here?
No. His apartment.
"His apartment?"
What kind of medicine
do you practice?
'You know, there are
centers that take care of'
'this sort of thing.'
He didn't want it that way.
It was not your decision, John.
No, no. It was his.
It should've been ours!
'He's on heroin, for God sake.'
'He had no ability
to apply good judgment'
'but you should
have had some sense'
called your family!
We could have handled it!
‐ Sorry.
‐ I'm calling, Dr. Levy.
We're gonna get him out of here.
And only one child in the study
reached the lockout dose.
Yeah, but for example, with
your sickle‐cell patient
'with the infarcted spleen,
you advocate letting'
'them blunt their own pain
and possibly mask symptoms?'
'I‐if he had a surgical belly'
'then there would still
be guarding and rebound'
'and other peritoneal signs.'
'It'd just be
more comfortable.'
Still, pain is an important
diagnostic indicator.
We're talking about kids here.
So now you're gonna
just say, "Suck it up?"
I guess I'm just
from the old school.
I think that's probably true.
Well, thank you, Dr. Ross.
It was all quite
thought‐provoking.
Excellent work.
That's it, everybody.
Actually, Don, I had a question
for Dr. Ross regarding
the randomization
of his control group.
Sure, Kerry.
Dr. Greene, do
you have a minute?
You've been
here six months.
You can call me Mark.
Alright, uh, Mark.
I know this sounds
rather morbid
uh, but as you say,
I've been here six months
and I haven't had as
much trauma experience
as I had hoped.
So, uh, I was wondering
if you might be able
to advise me on
the times that a surgeon
might sign up
for ER coverage.
Well, I hope you don't
mind nights and weekends.
No. That's, uh, what
I'd presumed, actually.
Listen, the gunshot wounds
and the knife wounds
kind of taper off
in the winter
but spring's just
around the corner.
Dr. Greene, we need you!
‐ Trauma one, now.
‐ What is it?
Lung cancer patient's coding.
‐ What happened?
‐ I don't know.
‐ I found him like this.
‐ No pulse.
Alright, let's get
him on the gurney.
One, two, three.
What was he doing out of bed?
Where's this blood coming from?
He probably
hit his head.
Bag him.
Asystole.
Mig of atropine,
amp of epi.
‐ This looks like an exit wound.
‐ What?
Yeah. Here's the entrance.
This is a gunshot wound.
Somebody shot him?
‐ Where's the wife?
‐ Call security!
Wait, wait. Hold on.
Dude capped himself.
‐ Why?
‐ End‐stage lung cancer.
It's pretty awful.
Does suicide count as a DNR?
Time of death, 17:05.
I'll try and find his wife.
Where's gramps?
You called him away
from a union negotiation.
He'll have a strike
on his hands
starting at midnight
if he doesn't settle it
and I'm heading uptown
to this Kenner
Neurology Institute.
Alright, but Chase needs to be
stable before he can be moved.
Right now his blood
pressure is being supported
by intravenous medications
and he's having
occasional heart arrhythmia.
Thank you, John, I've
spoken to the internist.
I don't need you
to explain it.
Grandma, I'm sorry.
If I could go back
and change this
I would.
I assumed if he really
needed help, he'd ask.
He did. He asked me.
Did he tell you
what made him start?
I don't know.
Maybe he just
felt overwhelmed.
That's something
I've never understood
about your generation
or your parents',
for that matter.
In our day, we embraced
our responsibilities.
They defined us.
I don't blame you for this,
John, but I know you blame us.
‐ No, I don't.
‐ Yes, you do.
All your lives,
you've been indulged
and considered
it oppression.
You look after him tonight.
Good.
I'll be back
in the morning.
This may be difficult for you
to understand, but there are
areas of expertise
where my knowledge
and my experience
exceed yours.
I don't deny that
but you should
have consulted me.
You should have consulted me!
Whoa! What's going on?
Nothing, Kerry was
about to release
a‐a two‐week‐old
baby with sepsis.
Her temperature was only
slightly below normal‐‐
You made a mistake, right?
You made a mistake.
Yeah, I made a mistake.
But that's not
what this is about.
No, it's not about you, Kerry.
It's only about me.
I'm the screw‐up here.
Well, guys, what's the problem?
He's angry because he has
to redo part of his study
after I pointed out
a flaw in his research.
First of all, there was no flaw.
Second of all, you ambushed me‐‐
Oh! I tried to talk to you this
morning and you blew me off.
So you left
a sick kid here
to go over there
a‐a‐and undercut me
in front of all the pediatric
staff. Was that the idea?
I cannot allow you to push
the use of pediatric PCA
in situations where the research
simply doesn't support it.
So, you are the self‐appointed
authority? Is that right?
Yeah, if I have to be.
Well, today, you
didn't help any kids.
In fact today, you
almost killed one kid.
You know,
screw you, Doug‐‐
'Okay, both of you, calm down.'
Is the baby gonna be alright?
She's gonna be fine.
I gave her antibiotics.
Okay. Well, that's
what's important.
From this point on,
a pediatrician is consulted
'in all pedes cases.'
I am capable of
treating children.
‐ Apparently not.
‐ 'Look, Doug.'
I know you're angry,
okay? But she's right.
Emergency physicians
are fully qualified
to handle pedes emergencies.
Hey, hey, hey, guys.
Hey, what are you doing?
‐ What is it?
‐ Can you just wait over there?
What is it? What are you doing?
‐ Transferring him to Evanston.
‐ 'Why?'
'Because he's too
much to handle here.'
He cannot
control his rage.
He‐he was abused.
Didn't you see
the burns on his arms?
Look, they may have
been self‐inflicted.
So, you're
committing him?
Look, he tried
to kill his brother
'and he has no
signs of remorse.'
I mean, did he
show any to you?
No. I..
Look, you might
need to testify.
I'll let you know.
Hey. You okay?
How'd it go today?
Oh, fun, fun, fun.
Are we gonna
do rounds?
Beats me.
I called the organ
donation coordinator.
She's coming down
to talk to you.
Forget it.
He's getting the operation.
Uh, listen, Alex.
When your, uh..
...when your father
first came in
I was frustrated,
you know.
I...I wanted to help,
and I pushed really hard
to find anything that
might save his life.
Unfortunately, I was...
I was overly optimistic
about his chances
for survival.
There‐there is no operation.
That was one doctor's opinion.
I got a surgeon over
at Bellarmin to look at him.
'He's agreed to
do the lobectomy.'
Bellarmin?
All set.
I booked an OR.
Who are you?
David Zaccarria.
Is this the, uh, ER intern?
I'm the doctor who
treated this patient
after you dumped him.
I didn't dump
Mr. Dibble.
No! You dumped a John Doe.
Bellarmin paged you.
Aneurysm, no insurance,
no interest from you.
I'm sorry. We don't
have time for this.
I have to get
this man to the OR.
Hey! He's still
my patient.
Not anymore.
D‐d‐does Dr. Mack
know about this?
He has privileges.
Sorry.
Hello?
Hello? Mark.
Hi. Is this, uh,
is this a bad time?
'Uh, what are you doing here?'
‐ I got your luggage.
‐ Oh, right. Sure. Hold on.
How did, how
did you find me?
‐ Can I come in?
‐ Oh, um, sure. Of course.
Um, you can put
'em right there.
Thank you. I was,
uh, wondering
how I was gonna
get those back.
So...how are you?
I'm, uh, you know, good.
Same, same old stuff.
What about your mom?
Better, some days.
Good.
How about you?
I'm okay.
It's a nice place.
Oh, yeah.
I‐I got a new job.
Uh, administrative assistant
for a law firm, so..
That's great.
Yeah.
I was so surprised
when I came back
and you weren't
working at the ER.
Well, I..
...I thought I needed to..
...I needed a fresh start
and couldn't really do that
with you there, could I?
Uh...guess not.
'Mom?'
Oh, Jason, honey,
w‐w‐what are you
what are you doing up?
'I'm thirsty.'
Okay, I'll get you
a glass of water
but then you've got
to go back to bed, okay?
Jason, this is my
friend, Dr. Greene.
Hi, Jason.
Here you go.
Jump in there, sweetie.
Sleep well.
You got him back.
Yeah.
Good for you.
Thanks.
Oh, I, uh, I didn't
just come here
to give you your
luggage back.
Oh, well..
I made a big mistake‐‐
Mark, you don't
need to apologize.
‐ No. No‐‐
‐ I, uh, went after you.
I was a big girl, and I
knew what I was doing.
No, no. I think I
made a big mistake.
I mean, we were,
we were great together.
Mark, you don't love me.
I deserve better.
You do.
‐ I could, uh‐‐
‐ No.
You can't.
Uh..
I'll miss you.
Me too.
Goodbye, Mark.
Hey, I'll do that.