I've been here a month, and
already, I've been assigned
an ethics course,
pissed off the board,
and now this disaster
with Exsomadex?
Maybe you should think
about another career.
There's 40,000 single
men in Chicago,
so you've gotta click
with at least one of them.
If you wanted to go to my place,
I've got some herbal tea.
How can I refuse?
So tell me, doctor,
you deal with any
crazy people today?
Pawel! I'm sorry.
He's my brother, and we are
responsible for each other.
Hey, Lil, I think
I heard the door.
I will get it.
Pawel.
It's freezing.
Which side?
What arm?
What's going on?
My brother said he'd
hurt his shoulder.
Well, it's nothing.
But I can use
something for the pain.
Figure you keep some
goodies in the cookie jar.
Only goodies we have
in the cookie jar
are your sister's
delicious shortbreads.
You mind if I take a look?
Can I take a look?
That looks like a
dislocated shoulder to me.
How'd that happen?
Did somebody do this to you?
I slipped on some ice.
It's happened before.
I can pop it back myself.
Can't you just write
me a prescription?
I can't.
But you know, I'm headed
into work right now.
Why don't we let somebody
at Med take a look at it?
Come on. You can ride with me.
Oh, please. Let's go.
Wait, what?
He just had a cup,
and then he left?
I mean, no.
He said he had to get
up early for work,
which, basically, yes.
Nothing happened.
And you're sure
that he understood
your intentions, that...
- Maggie.
I invited him to my
apartment for tea.
Could I have been any clearer?
- That depends.
Did you do that little quote
thing with your fingers
when you asked him?
- No!
- I'm so mortified!
I've been avoiding him
for, like, three days.
I don't know. Maybe
he's just not into me.
No, I wouldn't jump
to that conclusion.
- No?
- No.
Maybe he's just
one of those guys
that doesn't wanna cross a
boundary with a co-worker.
Or maybe he's just
like a lot of men
oblivious.
Go on.
No time like the present.
Yeah, no, I don't
know. It's, um...
Hannah, you can't just
keep avoiding him.
I'm not.
You know, I just realized that
I forgot my whatchamacallit
and my thingamajig.
Can you believe how
cold it is outside?
I thought Easter was supposed
to welcome in spring.
What's all this?
Peds ward Easter egg hunt later.
We're going extra
lilac this year.
I don't really get this holiday.
The symbology is
all over the map.
Like, what's with the
eggs and the bunnies?
Because death and
resurrection aren't as fun
dipped in chocolate.
- Hey, that's for the kids.
- Ow!
Besides, you need to
keep your hands clean.
Ambo's coming in.
Okay. Okay.
Is there a different holiday
you prefer to observe?
Religion's not really my thing.
Relying on cosmic
forces to save the day?
I don't know. Isn't that
what we're here for?
I'll take all the help I can
get, cosmic or otherwise.
Carson Miller, 28-year-old male,
late-stage cystic fibrosis,
known to your
transplant service.
Trouble breathing, febrile
at home with a temp of 103.
Have him on high-flow oxygen.
All right, Carson,
I'm Dr. Tanaka-Reed.
This is Dr. Ahmad.
We're gonna get
you taken care of.
Nice and easy, everyone.
On my count.
One, two, three.
Let's get a chest X-ray stat.
He caught a bug a week ago.
Can't seem to
fight this one off.
I'm his wife, Kendall.
Okay, let's take a
listen to those lungs.
Take a deep breath for me?
I'm sorry.
That's all I got.
Sats at 82.
It was above 90 when
we left the house.
X-ray up.
All clear.
It's all whited out.
Let's increase his
oxygen to 15 liters,
draw labs and cultures.
Where is he on the
transplant list?
He's been waiting for
over three years now.
I've been holding on to faith
that I'll receive a new pair,
but the way I feel today...
No, come on, baby.
Don't talk like that.
Hang in there.
Carson, I'm gonna intubate
you to help you breathe.
Are you okay with that?
You're gonna be okay, I promise.
I'm gonna hold you to that.
20 of etomidate and 100 of sux.
You're gonna go to
sleep now, Carson.
Hello, Becca. I'm Dr. Archer.
I understand you
burned your hand.
I bumped into the coffeemaker
at work with my belly.
I keep forgetting
how big I'm getting.
How many weeks are you?
37.
I'm going to have a boy.
Ah, congrats.
Yeah. Okay.
All right, well,
the good news is,
it seems pretty superficial.
That's what I figured.
I wouldn't even come in if
my manager hadn't insisted.
Well, you know what?
Let's just ice it,
put a dressing on it,
and we'll send you
back on your way.
So is it your first?
No, it's not.
There you are, babe.
I came down here
as soon as I could.
Tyler, I already told you,
it wasn't necessary
for you to come in.
It's barely even a thing.
- And you are?
- Tyler, her husband.
So what happens now?
Do we induce or go
straight into a C-section?
Well, I'm no
obstetrician, but, uh,
from what I can
tell, there's no need
to deliver the baby today.
You didn't tell him?
Tyler, please, you need to stop.
Tell me what?
This baby needs to
be delivered today.
Why?
Tyler thinks that
he's telepathic.
I am telepathic.
So, what? You can
read your baby's mind?
He's saying that
he's in distress
and that he needs to come out.
So I want an OB down here now.
Why won't anybody listen to me?
- Okay.
Lift the line.
Help it drain.
There's enough pus in there
to fill the Chicago River.
Pretty rank.
Yeah, he's septic, all right.
Those lungs are shot.
Look, I'm not gonna be
any use to you, Marcel.
Even if I had a new pair
of lungs to transplant,
there's too much infected
tissue in there for it to take.
Only thing to do is
keep hitting him hard
with the broad-spectrum
antibiotics
and hope for the best.
Hope for the best?
Who's this?
Dr. Zola Ahmad,
third-year EM resident.
Third year.
I didn't realize I was
speaking to someone
with so much experience.
I fail to see how doing nothing
could be considered
the best option.
Ah, I see you've
already trained her
to disrespect her superiors
in your own inimitable
way, Marcel.
And I see your skin hasn't
gotten any thicker, Morris.
So run me through what
happens if his lungs come out.
Both of them?
Well, they're doing
more damage than good.
So yes, if we remove them,
then we remove the infection,
get the heart and body
a chance to heal, right?
And what do you plan on
putting in their place?
Why can't we put him on ECMO?
What happened?
They no longer teach
anatomy at med school?
When you take the lungs
out, ECMO is not an option.
There's no way to
complete the circuit.
Unless we Jerry-rig a new one.
Look, I'm aware it's a risk
but not one we can't overcome.
He'll be lucky to
survive the surgery,
let alone living long enough
for a new donor to come along.
No. I'm sorry.
You two are on your own.
So what now?
Okay, baby is in the
correct position.
Amniotic fluid looks good.
Blood pressure is
a bit elevated,
but I'm not too concerned.
So we'll see what
the labs tell us.
The blood pressure could
just be from stress, right?
Possibly, yes.
I wonder what could
be causing that.
Hmm.
Are you sure you're reading
that thing correctly?
Yes.
Maybe it needs to
be recalibrated.
Clinical engineering
just serviced
all the ultrasound
machines last week.
So you're saying it
needed to be serviced?
Enough.
You need to see a psychiatrist.
Would you be able
to make that happen?
So what do you make
of the husband?
- Telepathy?
- Yes.
Military and CIA spent who
knows how many billions
trying to weaponize
mind control.
Total waste of time and money.
Okay?
Uh...
Sorry for being a bit grouchy.
Uh, I'm supposed to meet
Margo later for lunch.
Having cold feet.
So you took my advice
and called her.
Good for you.
If it goes south,
I'm blaming you.
Hey, Dan, we have a
patient we were hoping
you could speak with quickly.
- Be right there.
Hey, Mitch, you got a sec?
Yeah.
- Have you ever met Liliana?
- Uh, not directly.
But she works here right?
Yeah, she's my girlfriend.
Anyway, her brother appears to
have dislocated his shoulder.
You want me to take a look?
- I'd so appreciate it.
- Yeah, of course.
- Let me introduce you.
- Sure.
Hey.
Hey, um, how's your hamstring?
Uh, yeah, it's still
a little tight.
But okay. Thanks for asking.
What was that about?
What was what about?
You and Ripley?
I thought I was picking up
a little something there.
Yeah, says the guy who
doesn't believe in ESP.
Trust me, there's nothing there.
Nothing.
What's going on? How can I help?
So you can hear
your son's thoughts,
and he's telling you
that he's in pain?
Yes.
Right. Going on for three weeks?
Can we wrap this up already?
Just a couple more
questions, I promise.
Um, and as much as you're
able, can you tell me,
how do you actually
experience it?
Is it like your son
is... is speaking to you?
No, no, of course not.
He hasn't developed
language skills.
It's more elemental than that.
So is it more like
like... like a radio
signal or something?
Yes.
And does it... does it
only happen with him?
Or does it happen
with other people too?
I see where you're
going with this.
You're trying to see
if I'm exhibiting
signs of schizophrenia.
I've just been down
this road before,
you know, being analyzed
by my wife and her friends.
They all think I'm
showing signs of PTSD
because of what
happened to Chloe.
Who's Chloe?
Their first child
died from SIDS?
A girl, Chloe, about four
years ago, age eight months.
Oh, God, I feel
horrible for them.
I suppose that
explains the telepathy.
I don't wanna be
tilling your field,
but doesn't that sound
like PTSD to you?
Maybe.
You know, maybe a response
to all the grief and the trauma
but, admittedly, an unusual one.
Well, is there
anything you can do?
Don't think he's gonna be
too responsive to any kind
of counseling right now, given
that her due date is so close.
I guess we just have
to wait for them
to give birth to a healthy child
in order to prove them wrong,
and that's your department.
Okay, well, I'll go
check Becca's BP,
see if it normalized.
And back.
That's not hurting him?
Not with the
anesthetic we gave him.
Now just a bit more
counter traction.
There.
That should do it.
Back in the socket.
How's that feel, Pawel?
Good.
We'll keep his shoulder
iced to reduce the swelling,
and, uh, I'll be back in
a bit to check on him.
He's been living with
this disease for so long.
I just assumed he
was invincible.
Don't give up hope yet, Kendall.
I've witnessed plenty
of last-second miracles.
My husband is the most
generous person I've ever met.
He runs a homeless
shelter, you know?
He's given so much to so many.
When is it gonna be
his turn to get...
Let's get you settled
in the waiting area.
The doctors will come and
find you when they know more.
Dr. Ahmad, we need
you in treatment six.
On my count. One, two, three.
What's going on here?
Guy was found face down in
a culvert, frozen solid.
No way of telling how
long he was there.
No rhythm on the monitor.
Not sure this guy's alive.
And the cup?
I'm guessing it
wasn't self-inflicted.
Okay, let's do an ultrasound.
Do you have an ID?
- Leo Pruitt, known scumbag.
Done time for
assault and battery,
felony sex trafficking.
Can't say there'll be tears
shed at the 23rd tonight.
His temp is
11 degrees Celsius.
I'm not seeing any
discernible cardiac motion.
Why wasn't he brought
straight to the morgue?
He can't be declared dead
until he's declared
warm and dead.
Okay.
Let's start a warm saline
lavage of his bladder.
Thaw him out.
How's that?
I cannot make a fist.
That can happen sometimes
when you dislocate a shoulder.
It can put a stretch
on the nerve.
It didn't feel like
this when I came in.
I suspect it'll improve
as soon as the
swelling goes down.
But if it doesn't get
better by, say, next week,
just come back in, and I'll
take a look at it, okay?
And a prescription for the pain?
I'll have it waiting for you
with your discharge paperwork.
Thank you, Dr. Ripley.
You're welcome.
Pawel's good to go.
Oh, Mitch, can I ask you, um...
Pawel said that he slipped
on the ice this morning.
Would you be able to tell if
his X-rays were, I don't know,
consistent with that claim?
Versus what?
I don't know, something
more intentional?
Like somebody did this to him,
or he did this to himself?
I don't know,
something like that.
I mean, I guess.
But you wouldn't be able
to tell from the X-rays.
Okay.
Why are you asking?
You know, he went through a
tough time a little while ago.
I worry about him a bit.
But, um, anyway, thanks again.
I really do appreciate it.
Yeah.
- You got it.
- Yeah.
I got it.
Okay.
Both: Ooh.
It's all so trashed.
Yeah, elution is the
solution to pollution.
So let's wash everything out,
make sure there's no
lingering bacteria.
There you go.
Get in there. Get in there.
Now all we need to do is
create a temporary bridge
between the right pulmonary
artery and the left atrium.
Dr. Ahmad, someone's
asking for you downstairs.
The neighbor said they heard
some kind of dust up
night before last.
You know, I knew it wasn't good
when I seen his favorite boots
still under the bed.
- You two live together?
- Almost nine years now.
He is my man.
Oh, no.
What, ain't nobody
gonna take that out?
I'm sorry, I should
have warned you.
We were about to remove it.
We just wanted to make sure that
it wouldn't adversely affect
your husband's condition.
- He is not my husband.
- I see.
Well, we're gonna be needing
to make some tough decisions
regarding his care soon, Kimmy.
Is there someone else we
should be speaking to?
No.
No, just me.
You know, Leo made
me power of attorney
the last time he was
in prison, so it's a
yeah, it's just me, I guess.
Okay, well, here's
where we're at.
In the process of
warming his core,
the good news is,
we've achieved return
of his spontaneous circulation.
So his... his heart's
still beating?
Faintly, yes, though it's his
brain we're concerned about.
He's been outside
in the freezing cold
for over 24 hours
in this condition.
We expect that there won't be
a good neurological outcome.
There's still a small chance
that he might come through.
But you should probably
prepare for the worst.
Do you want me to take
a look at that eye?
Um, no.
No, that's nothing.
Is there someplace
that I could go
get, um, coffee around here?
I had a long night last night.
Yeah, just around the
corner on this side.
That'll lead you to a café.
Thanks.
Okay, Becca, we
got your labs back.
And your labs all look good.
Urine doesn't have
any protein in it,
which is what we wanna see.
That's a relief.
Your blood pressure, however,
has remained elevated.
Some readings even in
a more severe range.
Now, while this very well
may be anxiety related,
I can't say for certain that
this isn't preeclampsia.
So I suggest, given
how far along you are,
that we start magnesium
and induce labor today
to prevent you from
getting sicker.
Yes, that's exactly what
we want to have happen.
Becca?
O-okay.
Okay.
Now, the delivery
rooms are all in use,
but by the time you're
ready to deliver,
one should be available.
See? What'd I tell you?
I'd prefer not to see
your face right now.
I mean it.
There's a waiting
room out front.
I know where it is.
Okay.
You're gonna be so
grateful for this.
I can't believe he's
getting his way.
Ugh.
A nurse will be in shortly
to give you oxytocin.
Drive safe, and, uh, I'll
be home in time for dinner.
Yes, sweetheart.
- Oh!
- Man.
You all right?
Yeah, yeah.
Just get this jab of pain
sometimes down my arm.
Huh.
How long has that
been, uh, going on for?
Oh, about a month or so.
I must have slept on it
funny and pinched the nerve,
pins and needles.
I, uh... I gotta
call Becca's mom,
let her know what's happening.
Excuse me.
At least we were able
to complete the circuit.
That's not gonna matter
if we can't stabilize
the heart in the chest.
What's going on with
your ECMO circuit?
I don't know. It
keeps kinking off.
Normally we take out
one lung at a time,
but since we got both out,
there's not enough there
to stabilize the heart.
Maybe with another pack.
The problem is, these pads,
they're either too firm
or not bulky enough
to keep that heart
stabilized in the center,
not without impeding
its function.
So what are we
supposed to do now?
It's just so frustrating.
I keep banging my
head against the wall,
trying to get
these big hospitals
to adjust their protocols.
Maybe you should wear a helmet
so you don't get a concussion.
You're right.
I probably should.
Uh, but Dean, I'm telling you,
if you just look at the data,
you see how much better
outcomes can be for people
suffering from opioid addiction
if they're initiated in the ED
on the day of first contact.
It's at least 50%
more effective.
I am talking too much, aren't I?
No, you're not.
No, you're passionate
about what you do.
It's good.
I do not usually
go on like this.
I barely let you get a word in.
That's okay.
So this is where you jump in.
Oh, sorry.
Sorry. I might be
a little rusty.
Uh, I haven't been on an actual
date with someone for a while.
Hmm.
I don't know if lunch
at work with a colleague
counts as a date.
- Oh, I see.
Yeah, but you know,
tomorrow night,
dinner, on the other
hand, that would count.
If you're free.
Uh...
Hey, Margo.
Hey, Daniel.
I am so sorry to interrupt,
but can I just borrow
him for a second?
Yeah, I've gotta get back
to the center anyway.
So will you call me later?
- You bet.
- Great.
What can I do for you?
Trini.
Take these to the lab.
Have them follow
my instructions.
Done.
So how's Carson?
Okay, for the time being.
For the time being?
I'm trying to find something
to fill the chest cavities
to stabilize his heart.
This should do it.
Vacuum dressings?
Are you sure?
Maybe not.
Damn.
I need something, like,
double my hand size,
firm but pillowy,
and sterile.
I think I have an idea.
Breast implants?
Yep.
Let's get a couple double
Ds at 400 CC to start.
You gotta be kidding me.
I'm not.
Go ahead and move 'em.
The other one.
Hold that there.
Good.
Let it sit. Let it sit.
Now we need one more.
Let me get, uh, let
me get a 250 CC.
They're holding it in place.
Nice call, boss.
That wasn't my idea.
Let's go ahead and
close up the best we can
and cross our fingers.
You think Tyler might have MS?
I think he could be
exhibiting early signs, yeah.
Tingling of the fingers
isn't exactly definitive.
New study found that
psychiatric issues
could very well be
the earliest tell
for multiple sclerosis of all,
like maybe as much
as five years.
Demyelinated disorders
can have a wide range
of neurological symptoms,
I'll give you that.
Processing speed, all right,
visuospatial perception,
and can alter a person's
perception of self
in relation to others.
Making someone think they
could read people's minds?
I don't know. Maybe.
I mean, the only way to
diagnose that is with an MRI,
and I don't think
you're gonna be able
to get him to consent
to getting one.
I don't think I am, either,
'cause he already
doesn't trust me.
You, on the other hand...
Me?
How am I supposed
to convince him?
How long can he
survive like this?
Well, like I explained earlier,
this is an
experimental endeavor.
So we'll see.
It could be for only a
few hours or a few days.
It's impossible to tell.
But we've bought ourselves
a little bit of time,
and, uh, he's no longer
in septic shock, okay?
Kendall, we're gonna
find him a donor.
- Dr. Marcel?
- Yeah?
I might have a lead on
a new pair of lungs.
Really?
Service contact you?
Well, the lungs
I'm talking about
aren't in their system yet.
Frozen guy they brought in?
It's worth getting
the ball rolling
to see if it's a match, right?
- Hold on.
There's a lot of boxes
that need to be checked off
before we can even
declare a guy brain dead.
- I know.
- Tell me.
First, we confirm that his
core temp's back to normal.
Then we have to
perform an apnea test
to determine if his brain
still triggers a breath.
Finally, nuclear medicine
conducts a blood flow study.
And then and only then
can we check to see
if the lungs are
an actual match.
You see, these steps
are important, Zola,
and you can't skip any.
Trying to resuscitate
that patient
needs to be your one
and only priority.
Okay, Professor Snape.
I get it.
Hey, Becca, I heard
your water broke.
About three minutes ago, yeah.
Okay, repetitive
decels to the 90s.
She's had a few variables
since the water broke.
I've tried repositioning.
Is anything wrong? It...
that doesn't sound good.
Baby's just jostling around.
It happens all the time.
But I would like to check
how you're progressing.
Can you roll onto
your back, please?
Okay, you're gonna feel
a little bit of
pressure, all right?
I feel cord.
So let me get this straight.
You're asking for consent
to scan my brain for
a research paper?
Yeah, that's right.
That you hope will demonstrate
a physiological
proof of telepathy?
Yeah, that's correct.
If you're worried about
your anonymity at all,
it's nothing to be
concerned about.
Okay, hold on. Hold on.
Do you really expect
me to buy that?
I don't have to be telepathic
to tell that you're lying.
What's this about?
I'm concerned about some
symptoms you exhibited today,
and an MRI would allow us
to rule some things out.
- Symptoms?
- Mm-hmm.
I understand you've
been experiencing
a pins and needles sensation
for the last three weeks?
So that plus your telepathy...
It's that psychiatrist
putting you up to
this, isn't it?
How have your eyes
been lately, Tyler?
Any soreness?
Has your vision
been blurry at all?
Have you experienced any
dizziness or vertigo?
We got a cord prolapse.
What's happening?
The umbilical cord slipped
past your baby's head
and is being squeezed between
his body and your cervix.
We need to deliver him
immediately via C-section.
What do you need me to do?
You ever deal with
a prolapse before?
No.
Glove up, and I need you to do
exactly what I say and
only what I say, okay?
We're gonna have to swap places.
- I'll get an OR open.
- Mm-hmm.
I'm right here.
I'm scared.
Becca, I'm so sorry. I
know this is uncomfortable.
Okay, I need to remove
my hand so I can operate.
We need to change places
as quickly as possible.
So slide your hand
in next to mine.
And we'll meet at the head so
it doesn't compress the cord.
Okay, I'm there.
Okay.
- Now what?
- Don't move until I tell you.
We need to get her upstairs.
This is not how I
wanted this to go.
Dr. Asher is the
best there is, Becca.
Just stay positive, okay?
You kept telling me
something was wrong.
I'm so sorry I
didn't believe you.
Don't worry, baby.
I'll be with you the whole time.
I'm sorry, we can't have
you in the OR, Tyler,
but we'll let you know as soon
as your baby's been delivered.
- I love you.
Medically speaking, it's
all just a coincidence,
but the guy did call it.
Tyler, Tyler, hey, hey, hey.
You all right?
I don't know what happened.
I just got dizzy
all of a sudden.
Let's find someplace we can,
uh, get you off your feet.
Come on.
His core temperature
is up to 36 Celsius.
He's still not taking his own
breaths on the ventilator.
If he was gonna come to,
we'd see signs of it by now.
Mm-hmm.
I feel pretty comfortable
calling in radiology
to confirm brain death.
I'm really sorry for your loss.
So, um, what happens now?
Well, that depends.
As far as we can tell,
Leo didn't stipulate
whether or not he wanted
to be an organ donor.
Did you guys ever discuss
anything like that?
He told me he wanted to
go to the Grand Canyon
once before he died,
but that's about it.
Would you feel
comfortable making
a decision like that for him?
You can, you know.
I don't know.
Like... if he ever found out...
He's gone, Kimmy.
You don't have to be
afraid of him anymore.
There's a young man
upstairs in the ICU.
He just lost his lungs
to cystic fibrosis.
We have him on a machine now.
But he won't live much
longer without a new pair.
And Leo's are a match?
They are.
I checked.
You wouldn't believe
this guy, Kimmy.
He runs a homeless
shelter, food bank.
His wife told me that they
hope to have kids someday.
Seems like a good guy.
I don't know many men like that.
Kimmy, I apologize for
being presumptuous,
but I get the sense that Leo
was responsible for
causing a lot of pain
and suffering in his life.
It'd be a shame if that's all
that there was to his legacy.
So is there something
I need to sign?
Scalpel.
Hey, Ripley?
- Yeah?
You don't remove your
hand from that baby's head
until you feel mine, okay?
Roger that.
Incision.
Retractor.
In the top one.
I feel your hand.
Okay, you can let go.
I've got the head.
Here we go.
There he is.
Okay.
His color looks good.
Looks like we dodged
a bullet, guys.
All right. Bring
him to the warmer.
Hey. Nice job.
Thanks, boss.
So that's why
Dr. Archer was trying
to talk me into getting an MRI?
Because you think I might
have some incurable disease?
Right, and if that's the case,
you should know they are making
great strides in therapies
that mitigate the
symptoms of MS,
especially if we catch it early.
All I'm saying is,
why not look into it
if only to rule out the
worst-case scenario?
After Chloe died, we tried
really hard to get someone
to tell us exactly
what happened,
countless specialists all
saying the exact same thing.
Sorry, we don't know what
killed your baby girl.
It's a mystery.
And now I forge a real
connection with my baby boy,
and all I have is people
wanting to give it a name
and tell me I'm wrong.
Mr. Easton, I know
that was scary,
but everything went great.
Your baby's Apgar score is high,
which is exactly
what we wanna see,
and your wife did
absolutely amazing.
Thank God.
You're welcome to come meet
your son now if you'd like.
Yes, thank you.
Congratulations, Tyler.
You know, if we
would have waited
for her water to break at home,
this might have gone a
whole lot differently.
Real good thing you were here.
We're here because I'm
able to listen to him.
I've been given a
gift, Dr. Charles.
We expedited the injectables.
Oh, hold on.
Where's he going?
Transporting our new donor
down to nuclear medicine
to get a blood flow study.
What, already?
I ticked off all the
boxes like we discussed.
No gag reflex, no
corneal reflex.
The guy is brain dead,
warm and brain dead.
The sooner we make the call,
the sooner we can
harvest his organs.
No, we wait a
minimum of 24 hours
before we go down the
brain death pathway.
That's protocol, no exceptions.
You said every hour
counts with Carson.
Transplant needs to happen now.
No, we have an obligation
to this man as a patient,
not as a donor.
We don't even know
if he's a match yet.
Tell me you don't already
know he's a match, Zola.
Hey, I don't think
this guy is dead.
CAT scan showed nothing
life threatening,
and the knife caused
only minimal injury
to your maxillary sinus.
In a little bit,
we're gonna have
a speech therapist come see you
and do a complete
cognitive eval.
But, uh, all in
all, Mr. Pruitt, uh,
considering what
you've been through,
I'd say you're a very lucky man.
As soon as you feel up to
it, I've got some questions
to ask you about the assault.
Yeah, sure, in a second.
Kimmy, where the hell are you?
Coming, baby.
If he asks, I
didn't sign nothing.
Okay, there's a version of
this where I commend you
for overseeing the miraculous
return from the dead,
but that's not how
this is gonna go.
Yeah, so what the hell happened?
From what I can tell, looking
at the course of care,
a bladder thermometer
was used throughout
to measure the patient's
core temperature, right?
Uh-huh.
So do you understand
why that might
present a problem, Dr. Ahmad?
A warming pad and
bladder irrigation
might have raised
the local temperature
around the thermometer.
So that when the thermometer is
reading 36 degrees Celsius...
The actual core temp
was probably lower.
And that the patient
was not completely warm.
No, sir.
And that's exactly why our
hypothermic protocol calls
for using an esophageal probe.
Imagine the liability this
hospital would be exposed to
if we declared this man
dead and taken his organs.
- We were far away from...
- Just go home.
Go home, Zola. Go home.
And you... you
you're supposed to
be her supervisor.
That never should have happened.
There you are.
I was looking all over for you.
Well, you found me.
That, that was such
an unbelievable rush.
Wow, wow, wow.
I've never had a feeling
like that before.
I'm thinking maybe I got
into the wrong specialty.
And... and you,
the way you took control of it,
the command, the confidence,
us working together.
Um...
Mitch, about the
other night, you know,
when I invited you over
to my apartment for tea...
You know, I was thinking that
maybe we were something...
Is this okay?
I'm not good at reading minds.
Maybe you're much
better than you think.
No, I'm not exaggerating.
We were literally rolling
him out of the room
when, bam, out of nowhere,
he just popped right up.
It was super creepy.
I was very uncomfortable.
- It's eating you up, isn't it?
- What?
Possibility that a young father
could be walking out of here
with a debilitating
degenerative disease?
Yeah.
There's a chance
you might be wrong.
Maybe.
I certainly hope so.
Well, "maybe" is the
best we can do today.
Sometimes you gotta just
live in the mystery.
You guys heading out?
Yeah.
Doing anything interesting?
Uh, don't know.
I thought maybe we
could go get some tea.
Yeah, tea sounds good.
Dr. Mitchell Ripley?
Yeah, that's me.
- You've been served.
- What?
What is it?
Good night.
Dr. Charles.
Pawel's suing me
for malpractice.
What?
Liliana!
Lil, you upstairs?
She go to supermarket.
I was just having some vodka.
Pour you one as well?
What are you doing here?
My sister is kind
enough to invite me over
to spend the night,
given my injury.
Your injury?
That's the same injury that
you're suing the hospital over?
The hospital where
your sister works?
Oh, they tell you already?
I didn't think it
would happen so fast.
When you tee up
your shyster lawyer
before you even go
to the hospital,
things tend to
move pretty quick.
I can't use my hand, see?
I think maybe your colleague
is not a good doctor.
No, he's an excellent
doctor, I can assure you.
I can't drive my car for
the ride share like this.
This is going to really
harm me financially.
You know what's gonna
really harm you financially
is when you get busted
for insurance fraud.
Now, get out of my house.
Daniel, what is this?
Why are you speaking
this way to my brother?
Because your brother
is suing the hospital.
He's suing Ripley and the
hospital for malpractice.
Get out of my house.
- Is that true?
- Get out!
- Daniel, please.
Lower your voice.
- Yes, it's true.
I saw the complaint an hour ago.
It's okay!
I don't wanna be
where I'm not wanted.
Wait. Pawel, I will
drive you home.
Zola.
What's this?
This is the HLA test you
never should have run on Leo
to see if his
lungs were a match.
I'm guessing you
already knew they are.
I know I wasn't supposed
to run the HLA test.
But I don't understand
why we're prohibited
from making a draw
in the first place.
So that your care for the
patient isn't compromised.
You knew he was a
potential donor,
so you were incentivized not to
double check his temperature.
Am I gonna get fired?
It's not up to me.
This will be my third strike
my career.
I don't know if I'll be allowed
to practice medicine again.
Well, you should have
given that some thought
before you jeopardized
a man's life.