Previously, on
"The Resident"...
You're making out a will?
I realized I don't have one.
You are not going to die.
You can't promise me that.
Chastain is performing mandatory
drug testing
on all doctors today.
Positive.
This hospital-wide drug test.
Did you name my father?
And I didn't break
that confidence.
I don't need you to save me.
Baby number one is out.
Baby number two.
The babies are in the NICU
if you want to go see them.
I've been taking
Oxaprozin for my back.
It causes a false positive.
Kit's asked me
to stop taking them.
I'll test again in a week.
Just wanted you to know.
So, how about some weather?
Joanne, you there
with our weather today?
I don't hear water running.
Those teeth aren't gonna
clean themselves.
Giorgiana Grace. Chop-chop.
We're gonna be late.
Gigi?
Hey.
What's all that hacking up here?
I feel sick.
You're not warm.
Tell me what hurts.
I think I have a cold.
Oh, no.
That sounds
much worse than a cold.
It sounds like you have
Ferris Bueller Syndrome.
What's that?
It is a very rare disease
where little boys and girls
fake sick so they don't have
to go to school.
Sounds pretty serious to me.
This isn't about school, is it?
Sounds like someone's
worried about
their belt ceremony tonight.
I don't want to do
tae Kwon do anymore.
But you love tae Kwon do.
And you've worked so hard.
Don't you want to get that cool
yellow stripe on your belt?
You only move up
if you break the board.
I've seen you do
that routine a hundred times.
What's the problem?
And I will be there
cheering you on the whole time.
Okay?
I'm sorry, Daddy.
I can't do it.
Come on.
*THE RESIDENT*
Season 06  Episode 04
Episode Title:
"It Won't Be Like This for Long"
Aired on: October 11, 2022.
Morning, Tabitha.
Ooh, love the hair.
New highlights?
- They are.
- Mm.
Funny, my husband
didn't even notice.
Sounds like your husband needs
to get his eyes checked.
Did something happen
to your eyes? They're...
black.
Oh.
Nothing.
- Annual eye checkup.
- Mm.
That's what a few drops
of tropicamide will do for you.
Hmm.
My cousin, his eyes used
to be dilated like that.
Turns out, he was
in withdrawal at the time.
You're not withdrawing
from drugs now,
are you, Dr. Sullivan?
That's hilarious.
You're hilarious.
On that note, though,
I-I do have
an important operation
that-that demands my attention
this afternoon. I'm...
I'm wondering if we can move
that drug test up
to earlier in the day.
Ideally before noon?
Oh, I'm sorry, Dr. Sullivan,
but we outsource those tests
to a third party company.
They won't be here
until your appointment at 4:00.
That's a shame.
But... I will make sure
they're still here
after your surgery.
We will get you tested, Ian,
don't you worry.
- Thank you, Tabitha.
- Mm-hmm.
21-year-old woman
with endocarditis
in the setting of IV opiates.
She's on broad spectrum
antibiotics
with stable hemodynamics.
Diana, hi.
I'm Dr. Sullivan.
How are you feeling?
My baby.
Have you, have you seen,
have you seen her?
Diana gave birth to a baby girl
late last night.
What's your daughter's name?
They won't let me see her.
Is-is she okay?
Looks like there's
a Baby Jane Doe
in the neonatal
intensive care unit.
I can pop by and check on her.
It's my fault
that she's suffering.
Everybody told me that I would
screw her up if I didn't stop.
But I didn't.
We'll get you a list
of treatment centers
once you're
a little more stable.
My baby needs her mama.
I want to get clean.
I believe you.
But first we need to get
this infection under control.
We'll be back
to check on you soon.
Uh, let's do another
blood culture on Diana.
And run a CBC, ESR, and CRP.
She's just so nice. And sad.
- I feel bad for her.
- So do I.
But right now there are
still drugs in her system.
And once she starts withdrawal,
Diana will not be as nice.
You should prepare
yourself for that.
My uncle was the same way.
He was a completely
different person
when he was trying
to stop drinking.
Addiction is a horrible disease.
Sometimes fighting it can look
just as ugly as feeding it.
Is this about
her nightmares again?
Luckily, the
nightmares seem to be a thing
of the past.
Gigi and I have
a new challenge now.
She needs some tough love.
- So, can you cover for me?
- Don't worry, man, I got you.
You sure you don't mind?
Well, it's either this
or I'm washing cloth diapers
to prep for
the twins' homecoming.
You're doing me a favor.
All right.
Thanks, man. I owe you.
And tell Gigi I hope
she feels better.
- Will do.
- Sorry, Daddy.
Did I get you
in trouble at work?
No, you didn't.
Uncle Devon's gonna
cover for me.
But don't think this means
you're getting out
of your belt ceremony.
- But, Daddy...
- No buts.
Listen, we are gonna practice
until you can do every single
take down in your sleep.
Capisce?
- Capisce.
- All right.
But you don't know tae Kwon do.
Well, then you better teach me.
All right? Now let's go.
What do you got for me, Feldman?
34-year-old female
with myasthenia gravis.
Her parents brought her
to the ED after finding her
at the bottom
of their staircase.
Classic muscle weakness.
Clearly an MG flare-up.
But what caused the flare
is your problem, not mine.
This woman was diagnosed
over six years ago.
Myasthenia gravis is chronic,
but she should be
in remission by now.
No, the treatments never worked.
Her neuromuscular symptoms
worsened to the point
that she had to move back in
- with her parents for full-time care taking.
- Hmm.
Well, looks like I've got
my work cut out for me.
Yeah, you'll like Marty.
She's a nerd. Like you.
Then we can finally see
if you can still hang
with the real doctors.
Attending
to vocational counseling...
Hi.
I'm Dr. Pravesh.
You must be Marty.
Who is Marty?
Why is Marty?
I usually reserve
my existential dread
for the end of the day.
But I think I can make an exception.
I heard you took
a little tumble.
I didn't want to ask for help.
When your 70-year-old parents
have to get you to the bathroom
every morning, you keep
the requests to a minimum.
At least
when I'm in the hospital,
they get a break from it all.
Probably a nice break
for you, too.
Well, if I could
help them out financially,
I might feel
a little bit better.
But that's the one
universal truth
they don't tell you about.
You can't get a job
with a philosophy degree.
Oh, it all makes sense.
You're a truth seeker.
Too bad the truth
doesn't pay, huh?
I'd like to get to the bottom
of your myasthenia flare.
So if you don't mind
hanging out,
I can admit you
and run some tests, okay?
Lucky for both of us,
I got nowhere to be.
I'll be back.
All right.
The twins look perfect.
Healthy weight,
strong heartbeats.
I'd say this family can
go home this afternoon.
Ah, you hear that, Padma?
We're finally breaking
you guys out of here.
That is music to my ears. Oh.
I'll see you and the boys
in a month.
You need anything, you call.
Thank you, Ian.
Strong lungs on this one.
She have a name?
This is Jane.
Well, that's what
we're calling her.
Typical NAS baby.
She just...
she can't get comfortable.
Well, I'd be miserable, too,
- if I was withdrawing from drugs.
- Yeah.
- May I?
- Yes.
I know it hurts, sweetie.
Trust me, I know.
Where's the mother?
Admitted in ICU.
Long-term heroin user.
Although "mother" is not
the word I would choose.
Neural tube defect.
Has anyone taken Jane for scans?
Well, Dr. Lawrence
said he would check her out
after he got out of the OR.
Unless you could
take a look at her
because I've had
a really rough day today,
and I just,
I could really use your help.
I'll be back for Jane.
There's something I need
to take care of.
Dr. Sullivan, everything
all right in there?
All good, Susan.
Out in a sec.
Dr. Voss is
out of the office today.
She asked me to remind you
about your follow-up
this afternoon, the drug test.
Yeah, of course.
Drug test.
Who could forget that?
They'll be ready for you
in the lab at 4:00.
4:00. Can't wait.
Oh, my God.
Oh... Nine hours.
Nine hours.
Take your test,
then all the pills you want.
Less than a day old,
and this little girl
has already been through it all.
Outside of her obvious
spinal deformity,
this is what
concerns me the most.
Proximity of her neural tissue
to the skin.
They're practically touching.
Jane needs surgery,
no doubt about that.
Preferably sooner than later.
I can book us an OR for noon,
if that works for you.
I-I'd rather do after 4:00.
That gives us time
to get an MRI under sedation.
Well, the longer we wait,
the more at-risk Jane is
for a catastrophic CNS
infection.
Her immune system is
way too fragile to fight that.
Dr. Sullivan, are you
feeling okay?
It's like a sauna in here,
don't you think?
You know, you're right.
Let's move forward
with the surgery.
I-I'll check my schedule.
I'll get back to you.
All right,
on the count of three
you can open your eyes.
One...
two...
Three.
Grandmaster Hawkins' dojo
is officially open.
In Korea they call it
a dojang.
Yeah, well,
my apologies to Korea.
And you're not a grandmaster.
We'll see about that.
You ready?
- Kamsahamnida.
Protect yourself.
- Kiai!
Kiai...
Now...
Break the board, young Padawan.
Kiai!
Daddy, are you okay?
Yeah, I'm fine.
I'll get my nurse's kit.
Artificial urine?
Okay, that's more like it.
Hey, you're running point
on Baby Jane Doe
- in the NICU, right?
- I am, yeah. Who-Who's asking?
The mother.
She's in my ICU.
I promised I'd give her
an update.
How about I come down
and talk to her?
Great. Okay.
- See you down there.
- All right.
I don't get it.
My, my baby's spinal cord is
outside of her body?
Not exactly.
Uh, a neural tube defect occurs
when the fetus doesn't get
enough folic acid
during pregnancy.
And when this happens,
the-the lower part of the spine
can't grow properly.
- Folic acid? What is that?
- Mm.
No one told me anything
about any vitamins.
Well, you know what,
they might have
if you'd shown up for a single
prenatal appointment.
What's important is that
Dr. Sullivan is going to
repair the sac of fluid
on your daughter's back.
Mm-hmm.
And me and my baby
can go home?
We will talk time lines
once both of you
are back on your feet.
What you should have told her
is that no doctor
in their right mind
would send a child home
with an active heroin addict.
And who would that help?
Diana is suffering, too.
She knows she hurt
her daughter.
Oh, does she? I heard she was
out in the parking lot
shooting up before
she came in to deliver.
And I'm horrified by that, but
both mom and daughter are here
because they had virtually
no access to prenatal care.
She was set up to fail
from the start.
I don't think she is in there
beating herself up
over what happens,
and if you think she is,
you have no idea
how addiction works.
Ever since Bell left
for Minnesota,
I feel like I've been coasting.
No other surgeon has let me cut.
I really need a challenge.
You've got this, babe.
That blood panel has really
got your attention.
Should I be jealous?
I'm sorry.
None of this makes any sense.
Marty's in her mid-30s.
There's no reason her disease
should have progressed
to need full-time care taking.
A lot of myasthenia patients
respond to plasma transfusions.
Except she's receiving plasma
every six months.
It helps until it doesn't,
as does prednisone,
azathioprine,
Mycophenolate, rituximab.
Unless... the reason none
of her treatments have worked
is... is because we're treating
the wrong thing.
And by the way,
if you want to cut again,
try working with Nolan.
Okay.
I have to go.
Marty, I think it's time
we take a step back.
Reassess the basis
of why you're here.
- Now who's the existential one?
- What I mean is,
have you ever considered
that your original diagnosis
could be flawed?
What, like I don't have
myasthenia?
On paper you fit
all of the criteria
for myasthenia gravis.
Wait, if I don't have it,
then what's wrong with me?
I have no idea.
I'm sorry, Marty, I...
I don't mean to overwhelm you.
I've just always been someone
who questions everything.
Whether there's a God
or if time is an illusion or...
But I never once thought
to question my diagnosis.
You want answers, and I want
to give them to you.
This means we have to run
a few more tests.
All right.
Let's do it.
Let's get security on standby.
That is my baby in there.
You cannot take her from me.
I understand this is upsetting,
but we have to do
what's best for Jane.
You think going to a foster home
is better than
her own mother?!
- She needs me.
- We'll make sure
- CPS finds her a safe home.
- No.
This isn't permanent, okay?
You can still make this right.
It hurts.
It all hurts!
I know. I know, Diana,
but you can still get clean.
Okay?
Diana?
What's going on?
She's in shock. Likely sepsis
from the endocarditis.
I need a norepi drip
and an intubation kit
in here now.
Is she gonna be okay?
Diana has a lot
to make up for.
We're not giving up
on her just yet.
Pupils are reactive.
That's a good sign.
BP is still low.
The pressors aren't enough.
Hand me that ultrasound.
What is it?
Diana has a splenomegaly.
Why would her spleen
be enlarged?
It's hard to say for sure,
so we need to get her
to Imaging to confirm.
We can't move her like this.
She-she could crash again.
She will eventually if we don't
get a clearer picture
of what's going on.
Page Dr. Devi and tell her
to meet us in CT.
Scans are up.
Well, the refractory fever
makes more sense.
I don't think I've ever seen
a spleen with so many abscesses.
The bacteria from her heart
has metastasized into clots,
moving from one organ
to the next.
A splenectomy might be
her only option.
- Will she even survive a surgery?
- Maybe.
Maybe not.
Looking at these scans,
I doubt she'll survive
without it either.
She's your patient.
What do you want to do?
You're right.
Let's do the surgery.
Thank you.
Hey.
Can you spare a second
to pick your brain?
- Shoot.
- My patient, she's 34
and diagnosed with
myasthenia gravis years ago.
That's a rough one.
But at least the prognosis
is decent.
Except hers isn't,
which is why I questioned
if she was misdiagnosed.
Okay, I hear you.
Have you tested her yourself?
Blood test, edrophonium test.
All point back to myasthenia.
None explain why her
muscle weakness
isn't responding to treatment.
Well, maybe the weakness isn't
coming from her muscles at all.
If that's true,
an electromyography could confirm.
An EMG will tell you
if your patient's weakness
is coming from her muscles
or her nerve cells.
If it turns out to be
a muscle issue,
then she most likely has
myasthenia gravis.
But if the EMG proves
the nerve cells are responsible,
there's no way
she has myasthenia.
An EMG is an incredibly
invasive procedure.
Not to mention
excruciatingly painful.
Yes, but if the result is
what I think it is,
we could potentially cure
her symptoms.
You know, Devon, some people
just don't respond to treatment.
We never know why.
Are you sure this is
more than a hunch?
My patient wants answers.
She'll do whatever it takes
to get them, and so will I.
So, can you do it?
I just hope,
for your patient's sake,
this is worth it.
Are you waiting
on Postmates, too?
Yep. Should be here
any minute.
Hope it's not one
of those ghost kitchens.
I've had my fair share of
pad Thai that never showed up.
Yeah, that-that won't be
a problem.
You got to be kidding me.
Yeah, ghost
kitchen strikes again.
All right,
this is gonna hurt,
but then the worst part
will be over.
Why is Billie doing an EMG
on our patient?
You mean my patient,
and this is the only way
to pinpoint where Marty's
weakness is coming from.
We know where
her weakness is from.
She has myasthenia gravis.
I'm not so sure about that.
- My gut is telling me something else is going on.
- Hold up.
You're saying dozens
of neurologists
who've all diagnosed Marty
with myasthenia are wrong,
all because you have
a Spidey-sense?
I'm sure those doctors made
the best diagnoses they could
with the information they had,
but the inefficacies
of the treatments...
This isn't about
the treatments, Pravesh.
This is about you
treating a patient
like one of your little
science experiments.
Look, I know you don't think
I'm a real doctor anymore,
but I am actually trying
to help my patient.
Does that look like
it's helping, Devon?
If you ask me,
all your clinical trials
have desensitized you to
what real harm looks like.
That right there.
That's it.
Let's check that balance,
check that balance. Here we go.
Okay, we go one, one.
And two, two.
That'd be three. Okay.
Four! Four! Kick.
Okay, here we go.
- Kiai. Kiai.
- Gigi.
♪ Why you gotta be
always talking in my face ♪
- ♪ - Talking in my face? ♪
- Here we go. One. - Kiai!
Again. One. One.
Come on, right here.
Ah! One more, one more.
Ah, oh, God, you got me.
Oh, God, you got me.
You got me.
- Kiai! Kiai!
- Oh, God.
Oh, so strong.
I'll fight back.
- I'm gonna fight back.
- Kiai! Kiai!
- Kiai!
Yeah, time-out, time-out.
Phone call.
Hurry back, Dad.
We have more pummeling to do!
Oh, boy.
So, what, you gonna
leave Chastain
and become a karate instructor?
Tae Kwon do, technically.
Turns out it's harder
than it looks.
Gigi did that to you?
It wasn't my fault.
The Popsicle-stick splint
says otherwise.
How are things going
over there?
How much time do you have?
Talk to me.
I have this patient
who I thought for sure
was misdiagnosed with
myasthenia gravis...
so I did an EMG.
Okay. What did it tell you?
Nothing.
It only reconfirmed
her original diagnosis.
You know, I keep asking myself
where the line is.
How far do I push
before what I thought
was helping
is actually harming someone?
Trust your instincts.
What's your gut say?
That I got to keep digging.
Then you have your answer.
I should probably go.
I've got time for about
six more kicks to the chest
before Gigi's ceremony tonight.
Wait, hold on.
Say that again.
Say what?
That I got about
six more kicks to the chest
before Gigi's ceremony?
Keep digging, my friend.
I got to go.
Dr. Pravesh, I know
I said I wanted answers,
but I'm not sure how much more
of this I can take.
I know, Marty.
This'll be the last thing.
I promise.
It'll be painless.
I'll be back.
Listen, I'm sorry
I came on so strong,
but I won't apologize
for what I said.
Neither will I.
I want to hear you out, Devon.
So tell me, what exactly is it
you expect to find?
That.
You're kidding, right?
You know if you do
a full body scan of anyone,
you're gonna find
something somewhere.
It's an incidentaloma.
It doesn't prove anything.
Not yet.
But a biopsy will confirm
that Marty has lung cancer.
Years ago,
a trial was conducted
to study a small-cell
lung cancer
that was known to mimic
neuromuscular symptoms.
All right,
so you're saying
it could imitate
myasthenia gravis.
It's nearly indistinguishable.
But it wouldn't respond
to myasthenia treatment
because it's not
a neuromuscular disease at all.
Well, I'll be damned.
Looks like you're still
a real doctor after all.
Oh, there you are.
Dr. Sutton's looking for you.
You don't look good,
Dr. Sullivan.
Yeah, just a little heartburn.
I-I must have eaten too fast.
Okay, well,
why don't you sit down?
- You know, I can't, I got to get going. I'm good.
- I can help you.
- Okay.
- Thank you. Thank you.
Stay here.
I'll get you some water.
Everything's fine.
They're taking Jane to the OR.
- We have to go now.
- Why? What happened?
She's showing signs
of encephalitis.
It's now or never.
All right, 3:55.
I need ten minutes
I'll meet you there.
We don't have ten minutes, Ian,
you know that.
Okay, five minutes.
Start without me.
I have an appointment
for Ian Sullivan, 4:00 p. m.
Our technician is
stuck in traffic,
so we're running a little late.
He's not here?
No, that's not possible.
I have a 4:00 p.m.
It's 4:00 now.
I'm sorry for the delay,
but if you just take a seat...
No, I'm not taking a seat.
I've been waiting all day
for the damn test.
I have a newborn, a little girl
waiting for me right now.
Can we please do the test?
You can fill this out
while you wait.
Will Dr. Sullivan be
joining us?
Okay, let's do this, please.
- Just a few more minutes, sir.
- I just need to pee in a cup.
What could possibly
take so long?!
Just a few more minutes.
Oh, screw this.
Jane's
vitals are starting to dip.
- Should we wait, or...
- No.
Let's get started.
Scalpel to me.
Dad, we need to talk.
I can't right now, dear,
I've got to get going.
Earlier with a patient,
you were having trouble.
You were forgetting things.
And it's been weighing on me.
I've got surgery now, Cade.
I can't do this right now. Okay?
I don't think
you should be operating.
This is exactly why
I didn't want to tell you
about the Oxaprozin.
Anything I do now
is gonna be under
your little microscope.
Well, can you really blame me.
- I am worried about you.
- Do not patronize me!
Is that why you came in here?
Comb through all my past.
Okay, fine, let's to that, then.
Okay, you're being irrational.
Just calm down.
Do you want me to admit it?
I was a terrible father?
That's what you tell all
your friends, right? I...
You tell them
I was a deadbeat.
- You had to raise yourself, right?
- No, that's not fair.
- I-I never meant that you...
- You know, Cade,
sometimes you are not
the victim.
Sometimes you are the problem.
You make everyone around you
feel like a failure,
Miss High and Mighty.
Do you have any idea
what having a daughter like that
does to a man?
I'm sorry I'm such
a disappointment to you, Ian.
And that concludes time-out.
Does anyone have any questions
before we begin?
Unrelated, but does anybody have
a bidet that they can recommend?
Dr. Nolan, we are ready
to proceed with the splenectomy.
Splenect-away, Dr. Devi.
If you screw up, I'll scrub in.
Just do me a favor and don't
splat yourself
all over the pavement.
Looks like you're flying solo
today, Dr. Devi.
Scalpel.
Oh. About time.
Where the hell have you been?
Vitals are dropping.
Should we push more epinephrine?
Look, I don't know
what is going on with you, Ian,
but pull it together.
Jane needs you.
Ian!
- Fever's spiking.
- Sepsis is worsening.
We have to move fast.
Clamps to me.
Diana's going into A-fib.
You hear those alarms, Devi?
You tried, and you failed.
- I am scrubbing in.
- This was always a risk.
Let me get her heart rate
under control.
She's too sick. Stop
the surgery, cardiovert now.
The only way through is to do
the surgery. Stapler to me, now.
If you do not get her rate down,
she is going to...
She's going to make it.
Heart rate
and temperature normalizing.
Great work, Dr. Devi.
See? You can get back
to your bidet now.
With pleasure.
All right, carry your incision
down into the meningeal sac.
That's it.
Mobilize the nerve roots.
Dr. Sullivan,
this is your specialty.
Dr. Sutton can handle it.
Okay, now use your sutures.
Delicately fold the neural
placode into the spine.
I know my way around a spine,
but not one this small.
Jessica's right.
You should take over.
- You're doing fine. Just keep going.
- I will.
But if Jane dies
on this table, it's on you.
Okay. 7-0 Prolene to me, please.
Better late than never,
I suppose.
See if you can get me
some exposure here.
Retract the skin edges, please.
All right.
- You see that little guy?
- Mm-hmm.
- The filum terminale?
- It tethers the spine,
as you know,
but now we need to cut it, okay?
Place back in the nerves
and then close
the dura and the fascia.
You with me, Sutton?
Lead the way.
Ah.
It's official. You don't have
myasthenia gravis.
But I have cancer.
Yes. A paraneoplastic syndrome
called Lambert-Eaton.
It explains why
your neuromuscular symptoms
were worsening
with the myasthenia treatment.
Look, I know
cancer is never good news.
But now that we know what we're
dealing with, we can fight it.
And we happen
to have excellent weapons
against this particular type.
I'm not going to lie to you, Marty.
It's a long road ahead.
But if we stay the path,
in a few years, there's a chance
that you can gain some
of your independence back.
You mean, I could move out
of my parents' house?
Take care of them for a change?
The point is,
you've had the wrong treatment
for the wrong problem,
and it was only going
to get worse.
Now there's hope.
Thank you.
Your training is complete,
young Padawan.
You ready to get
that yellow stripe?
In class last week,
I couldn't break the board.
And some of the kids
laughed at me.
That's not very nice.
We all fail sometimes.
That's how we learn.
But you never fail
at anything, Daddy.
Oh, yes, I do.
All the time. I just...
I just don't give up.
Remember when you thought you'd
never sleep in this bed again?
Because of all the nightmares?
I remember. It was scary.
Yeah, but now you sleep
by yourself every night.
Because you were brave enough
to try again.
It doesn't matter
if you break some stupid board.
What matters is
that you keep trying.
- Capisce?
- Capisce.
Jane will be okay.
But that could've ended
very badly.
Thanks for holding down
the fort.
I shouldn't have had to.
What happened back there, Ian?
Well, long story short,
I was sick and now I'm not.
Well, someday,
I want the long story.
Because that can
never happen again.
It won't.
I assure you.
Dr. Sullivan, they're waiting
for you in the lab.
Of course. Be right there.
See you tomorrow.
Excuse me?
Are you a doctor?
The nurse said they were taking
me for an MRI two hours ago.
I'll see what I can find out.
Tell me...
Mr... Sanchez.
Any history of liver disease?
Kidney problems?
- Any drug use?
- No.
Definitely not.
Great.
Ah. Your urinal's full.
Here, you know what?
Let me help you there.
That's everything.
Enjoy the rest of your evening,
Dr. Sullivan.
Oh, I certainly will.
Where am I?
You're in the hospital, Diana.
You had your spleen removed.
But you should be
feeling better soon.
Don't touch me!
Where's my bag?
Did someone take it?
They seized it when you were
admitted, remember?
I need my bag.
I want to... I want out of here.
Your daughter's out of surgery.
She's recovering now.
Did you hear me?
I want to go home.
You're in withdrawal.
You have a long road
to getting clean.
And until you are,
you won't be getting Jane back.
That's bull.
A baby needs her mom.
Not if her mother continues
abusing drugs.
And trust me,
I know what that looks like.
At every soccer game
or piano recital,
Jane will look out
into the crowd.
And see every parent there
but hers.
And she'll hate herself for it.
She'll spend the rest of her
life wondering why her mother
chose a fix over a relationship
with her daughter.
- Get out.
- She'll have a hard time trusting people,
making friends, falling in love.
Because how could she believe
anyone could love her
if her own mother doesn't?
I'm begging you,
don't do that to Jane.
- She doesn't deserve it.
- Evelyn.
That's her name.
Get some sleep.
"Wake Up!" By Purple Disco
Machine and Bosq playing...
Champagne?
What's the occasion?
Well, let's see.
Padma and the twins
are in the new condo,
safe and sound with AJ.
Which means
it's just the two of us tonight.
I like it.
And although
karma did come for my neck
when I stupidly asked
the universe for a challenge,
I rose to the occasion
and I successfully completed
my first solo surgery.
No way.
That's amazing, Leela.
Cheers to that.
So how'd it go
with your patient?
Just uncovered
a six-year-long misdiagnosis
and started her on a treatment
to cure her cancer.
So, no biggie.
Wow.
I think we're becoming
a power couple.
♪ Wake up from your slumber ♪
- ♪ E dide ♪
- Speaking Korean...
♪ Wake up from you slumber ♪
♪ E dide ♪
♪ lie ti mo ♪
♪ Ise ti ya ♪
- ♪ lie ti mo, ise ti ya ♪
- Jab. Straight.
- Kick.
- - ♪ lie ti mo ♪
Bow.
♪ Gbe'ese, oya ♪
- ♪ Oya o ♪
- Good job. Have a seat.
- Gigi, stay where you are.
- ♪ Gbe'ese, oya, oya o ♪
Bow.
♪ Wake up ♪
Hit!
♪ Gbe'ese, oya ♪
♪ Oya o ♪
Speaking Korean...
Great job! Great job!
Captioned by Media Access
Group at WGBH access.wgbh.org
Synchronized by srjanapala
Yeah!
- Great job!
- Gigi!