- I'll be right back.
- Okay.
You like macaroni and cheese?
Who, me? No.
- That's all I've got.
- What?
For dinner.
Too bad.
Well, it's not so bad if you kick in a
few bucks for a nice bottle of wine.
I've got your meds, Mr. Walden.
Are you asking me out?
- I'll pass.
- Why?
- I don't like macaroni and cheese.
- Then cook something.
- I don't think so.
- What, you can't cook?
I'm not making you dinner.
Wow. I just figured
you'd wanna eat first.
First?
You know, before
things get hot and heavy.
Ha-ha. Okay, sure.
Come on. You can't tell me you wouldn't
wanna go home, have a hot shower...
a glass of wine,
some great sex...
I can do that all by myself.
- Hmm.
Did someone say "sex"?
Do you like macaroni
and cheese, Pablo?
Oh, yeah, I love it.
You got yourself a date. - Yuck!
I don't even know
what half this stuff was.
Were you expecting someone?
- No.
Hey.
Come on in.
Hey, Carter.
Would you like some pizza?
I just came by to make
sure you were settled.
- I'm getting there.
- Yeah, I can see that.
Just a little housewarming gift.
Welcome home.
You gotta make it stop, man.
I can't help unless you settle
down and tell me what's wrong.
Need a hand?
It's in my stomach.
- Did you ingest something, sir?
- No.
My brother...
Wait. Your brother what?
Did he give you something?
No. He's inside me!
- Want me to call a Psych consult?
- Not yet.
- Are you taking drugs?
- He's trying to bite his way out.
- I'll get some Haldol.
- I didn't ask for it.
- Stop it.
- And some soft restraints?
No. EDWARDS: Oh, God.
I fly the plane, you
serve the coffee.
I think he's angry. Oh, God.
Fine, he's all yours.
Did you do a repeat EKG on Feinstein?
- No.
You need to do serial
EKGs to rule out an MI.
- His first EKG was normal.
- He could have pseudo-normalization.
I gotta get him out
before he kills me!
Calm down. Calm
down. A little help!
Hey, Haleh? Let's get hard
restraints, Haldol and a Psych consult.
Better get a wrist film too.
Did you know lesbians
are at a higher risk...
of breast, cervical and ovarian
cancers because they are less likely...
to have children by age 30?
- Is that so?
- Yeah.
Lesbians are less likely
to seek health care...
because of the
discomfort of coming out.
Why are you telling me this?
Lesbians are also less likely to
get routine gynecological services...
which means later
detection of these cancers.
- Robert.
- Huh?
- Do you have to keep saying that? Don't.
- Lesbians? I'm just reading what it says.
I can't help it. Kerry, this gets
me excited. You wanna know why?
Because this smells like money.
Your sisters are underserviced
and we can fix that.
You're trying to
exploit my lifestyle.
No. I'm trying to
accentuate the positive.
- You're chief, you're gay, challenged.
- Ah, challenged.
You can be the poster girl for
the Center for Lesbian Excellence.
- No. ROMANO: You
haven't seen the proposal.
- What proposal?
- In the press packet.
- Read it before the news conference.
- You kidding?
This is gonna be great.
What are you doing?
- Damn toaster ate my Pop-Tart.
- Is that a switchblade?
Couldn't get my brass
knuckles in the slot.
- Whose stuff is this?
- Pratt's.
I don't think Weaver's
given him a locker yet.
I hope you unplugged that thing.
Ha. Very funny.
LEWIS: Hi, I'm here.
But I'm not answering the
phone. Please leave a message.
- At least I'm honest.
- Heard about a replacement for Greene?
Your car needs a
new battery. It's $ 180.
Call me back and
we'll replace it.
$180. I barely make that...
- resuscitating somebody.
- Are you covering, um...?
Aunt Susan, are you there?
It's Suzy. My mom's
really sick. We're in a hotel.
I think she needs a
doctor. I can't wake her up.
I gotta go.
- Hello.
- Chloe?
We're not home.
But if you wanna leave a
message for us, wait for the beep.
Chloe, hi, it's Susan. Are you
there? Chloe. Are you there?
Your brother-in-law's a cop?
In New Jersey, but I
couldn't get ahold of him.
His precinct said he took a few days off,
but they don't know where to reach him.
Do you have caller ID at home?
- No.
Can't you just trace
the call or something?
- Yeah. I'll see what I can do.
- Okay.
You okay?
- I don't know what to do.
- It's nothing. Kids, active imaginations.
Dr. Lewis, Mrs. Reynolds would like
you to go over her husband's aftercare.
- I did.
- She has a few more questions.
- It's a damn carbuncle.
- I'll go talk to her.
- No, Carter. You don't have to do that.
- It's all right. I rock with carbuncles.
- What room?
- Exam 4.
I'll be right there.
- You got a minute?
- Yep. What do you need?
I need to talk to you.
- Go ahead.
- About Abby.
- What about her?
- She's drinking again. Didn't you notice?
Luka.
- Seven-year-old, 15-foot fall, headfirst.
- He was climbing a tree on a class trip.
- Page Surgery.
- Stabilize the neck.
Get Pedes Neurosurg down here.
- That spinal fluid?
- Looks like it.
Prep 30 grams of mannitol.
- Sats, 93 percent on four liters.
- Blood in the left canal.
Feels like deformity at
the angle of the mandible.
- DTR's three-plus.
- We got this, Carter.
Pupils midrange,
equal and reactive.
Probable basilar skull
fracture. 6.5 ET in a two-mac.
Pre-medicate with 40
of lido and 2.5 of Pav.
So how was it?
- What?
- Your date with Pablo.
Pretty interesting. Did you know
he used to be with a Mexican circus?
- Oh, really?
- Yeah.
Guy's had a hard life, but intriguing.
He was even shot by Border Patrol once.
You really had
dinner with Pablo?
Not at my place, at Doc Magoo's.
He was hungry and I just
can't stand eating alone.
- Where's Mrs. Pradeep?
- I sent her home.
Excuse us. I didn't
sign off on her chart.
There was nothing wrong.
She just wanted a free meal.
I sign off on every
patient you see. Even if
they stop for directions
to Wrigley Field.
- Got it?
- Got it.
Let me know if you hear
anything. Thanks, Dix. Bye.
Anything?
- Dr. Lewis.
- Yeah?
Phone company traced the call. Came
from a phone off a network in New York.
- New York?
- On the Upper West Side of Manhattan...
which is within the jurisdiction of
the 55th precinct of the N.Y.P.D.
- And they're expecting your call.
- Thank you.
Five-five precinct.
May I help you?
Yes, sir. Yes, sir.
Please hold. Bosco, you're early.
They fumigating your apartment?
Some jerk from second watch is working
out without wiping down the benches.
What do I look like,
the gym monitor?
You have to call Parking
Enforcement. We don't tow cars.
How hard is it to take a towel
and wipe the sweat off a bench?
- Five-five precinct.
- Put up a sign, he's still doing it.
I figure out who it is, I'm gonna
put his head in the squat rack.
Let me put you on with an officer
who can help you out. Bosco.
Take a missing-persons report.
- I'm not on yet.
Well, your sweaty
manhunt can wait. Line two.
Be right with you, ma'am.
Officer Boscorelli,
how can I help you?
I'm Susan Lewis.
- I'm in Chicago right now.
- Okay.
Okay, ma'am, calm down.
Ma'am, you gotta calm down.
Listen to me. When was the
last time you talked to your sister?
Abdomen's soft, no guarding.
Two-by-two abrasion over left iliac crest.
Let's hold off, give Neurosurg a
chance to see him before we paralyze.
Heart rate down to 60.
Six-centimeter scalp
lac with exposed galea.
I need 3-0 chromic on a driver.
How's Mark?
He's good. He's in Hawaii with Rachel.
He's showing her where he grew up.
Oh, that's nice.
- I didn't know he grew up in Hawaii.
- He grew up in lots of places.
- He's fixed and dilated.
- What? No.
- Eight millimeters.
- BP's up, 160/100.
Cushing's response.
Let's page Neurosurg.
There's no response
to pain. Swab.
There's a step-off.
Pretty big skull fracture.
No corneal reflex. I
think he's herniated.
All right. Let's tube him. 200
mics of fentanyl, 50 of sux.
- Won't the sux raise the ICP?
- No.
It's a myth. Besides, I
don't think it's gonna matter.
I have to go. I made four
calls to find someone to cover.
Wait. Slow down, Susan.
My sister and her daughter are missing and
the police aren't helping. I have to go.
Whoa, what's going on?
- I'm, uh, gonna catch an 11:30 flight.
- You're going to New York?
Yeah, I can't sit
around and wait.
- What are you gonna do?
- I'm gonna find them.
Jesus was a healer.
- Who let Reverend Ed in?
- You know the preacher?
- He's a pain in the ass. Get rid of him.
- Me?
In about 10 minutes he's
gonna start trying to heal people.
It's bad for business.
You see, the road to recovery begins
when you open your heart to Jesus.
Excuse me, sir. I'm afraid I'm
gonna have to ask you to leave.
You treat the body
and I treat the soul.
- Watch your back.
- Gallant!
Go with God, my son.
Stanley Sherman, 32, security guard.
GSW to the abdomen. BP, 140/80.
Pulse, 100 with a liter in.
Pay attention.
Where's it hurt, Stanley?
Where do you think? Right here.
Eyes are open. One question
and I got the airway and GCS 15.
- Is this the GSW?
- Small-caliber wound, the epigastric area.
No LOC. Good breath sounds.
Haven't see you
around this morning.
It's been busy.
This one's yours, Pratt.
CBC, lytes, BUN and creatinine, glucose,
Accu-Chek and a HemoCue times three.
- Hey, big stick, say "Ow."
- Ow!
Told you.
Lateral C-spine,
AP chest and pelvis.
Bilateral TMs are clear, head's
atraumatic. Can I do the airway?
No. He doesn't need an
airway. You can do the rectal.
The rectal.
Play nice, kids. Don't
make me stop this trauma.
There's a big gun show in
Baltimore this weekend. Interested?
- Uh, no, thank you.
- Come on.
- Come on, you can bring the kids.
- Yeah, okay. Let me call Fred...
tell him to pack a bag for the kids
so they can go to the gun show.
What's up, lieu?
Your missing-persons
report from this morning.
Who?
- The doctor with the missing sister.
- I thought she was in Chicago.
- She was.
- She flew here?
- What are you talking about?
- You brought us in for this?
What's going on?
Her sister and her sister's kid go missing
for an hour. So she's coming unglued.
Take her out and
drive her around.
You gotta be kidding.
A doctor from Chicago. That
kind of trouble, I don't need.
- Lieu.
- Hey, Bosco...
whatever you told her on the
phone, she hopped on a plane.
- She's your problem.
- I didn't tell her anything.
Maybe that's why
she got on the plane.
Wait, what's going on?
Her sister's missing?
She probably took her
to the zoo or something.
Uh, excuse me, are you the
officer I spoke with this morning?
Yeah, hi. Boscorelli. How you doing?
This is my partner, Officer Yokas.
Susan Lewis. Have
you found them?
Uh...
I made a few calls, but
I'm afraid I don't have much.
I called my niece's school. They
said she hasn't showed up in days.
I'm gonna get a cup of
coffee. You want some?
No, I'm fine.
You know, uh, Susan? - Yeah.
Uh, like, 90 percent of the time,
these things work out to be just fine.
Well, I called their home, his
work, I can't get ahold of anybody.
Well, maybe the whole family
took a trip to Disney World...
or, I don't know, went
fishing or something.
What?
- Where do they live?
- South Orange.
South Orange?
Oh. That's New Jersey.
You know what we can do?
We can call the P.D. over there
and have them send a patrol over...
- and, uh, check it out.
- You know, would you just listen to this?
Aunt Susan? Aunt
Susan, are you there?
It's Suzy. My mom's
really sick. We're in a hotel.
I think she needs a
doctor. I can't wake her up.
I gotta go.
- Did you try the hospitals?
- Isn't that your job?
Do you have pictures? - Yeah.
Uh. We can canvass
the hotels in our precinct...
- and see if anybody's seen them.
- Can I come?
- No.
- Yeah.
Thank you.
Stanley, you hear
me? I'm talking to you.
- Run in another liter. Re-page Surgery.
- BP's dropping.
Set up for a central line.
Prep the rapid infuser.
- He's not breathing.
- Bag him. What drugs you want, Pratt?
One-twenty of sux,
20 of etomidate.
- Sats coming up.
- 94 percent.
- 8-0 ET and a three-mac.
- Drugs are in.
- I thought this was my tube.
- Go for it.
- Hey, I'm running this.
- Teaching hospital, Pratt.
- Give him a shot.
- He doesn't get it, it's mine.
Don't hold your breath.
Okay, pressure's
better. 110 systolic.
All right. Keep running it in,
I'll get in and give you cricoid.
- Ready?
- Okay, okay.
Don't chip his teeth.
- Tell me what you see.
- Just the back of his throat.
- Epiglottis.
- Right. Lift towards the feet.
Harder. GALLANT: Okay.
Good.
- Okay. Yeah, yeah, give me the tube.
- Tube.
Just watch it go right
through the cords.
Okay. I got it. I'm in.
Easy intubation.
- Carter was looking for you.
- Oh, he found me.
- He didn't seem real happy.
- No, he's not.
It's gonna be okay.
When Allan fell, he tore
a blood vessel in his head.
Can't you fix it?
The neurosurgeon
will speak to you...
but the CT scan shows damage
that they feel is unrecoverable.
- But he's still alive.
- The ventilator is helping him breathe.
And we're giving him medicines to
stabilize the pressure on his brain.
But if we discontinue
them, he'll die.
I'm sorry.
Hey, hey, hey, hey. What
are you...? Nice, jagoff.
Yeah. What about Mercy?
Mercy? BOSCO: Yeah, Mercy.
Uh, let me check.
Negative. We got
nothing at Mercy.
Okay, 10-4.
There's nobody matching your niece
or your sister's descriptions or names...
have showed up at the
morgues or the hospitals.
That's good. BOSCO: Yeah.
This happens all the
time. You know that, right?
People decide to go somewhere,
don't tell family members they're going.
All right. Thank you.
Thanks for looking.
- Any luck?
- None.
Was your sister and her husband
having problems with their marriage?
Not that I know of.
Was he having any kind
of personal problems?
- Like what?
- Like drugs or alcohol or gambling?
No, he's the one who
straightened out my sister.
Straightened her out?
Chloe had a
substance-abuse problem.
She's been clean five years.
Joe helped her get her life together.
- You should've said she was an addict.
- She's not an addict. She beat it.
- She's a responsible wife and mother.
- She's so responsible, why are you here?
Surgery's on their way.
You sure you know
how to work that?
Spend almost a year at the VA,
you learn to work the hardware.
They got a whole floor of
vent-dependent gomers there.
Hey, don't call them that.
Why not? That's what they are.
No. They gave themselves
so you can live the life you do.
Nobody ever "gave" me anything.
Third unit of type-specific is up.
Maybe Carter should call Surgery again.
Only so many O.R.s.
They'll come when they can.
Run of ectopy.
Open a crash cart.
100 of lido, IV push.
- Pressure holding.
- Start a drip, two milligrams a minute.
No, no. Should I get Carter?
It's V-tach.
V-fib. Charge the
paddles to 200. Come on!
- ACLS. We both have a card.
- It's asystole, definitely asystole.
- Thoracotomy tray.
- What?
- I've got it.
- Look, I am going to get Carter.
No time! CPR, Gallant!
Get with the program!
Do not do this, okay? They
are coming. They are coming.
What's that? - Notes.
Oh, God. No, no, no, no.
See one, do one. You
heard what Carter said.
- This is a teaching hospital.
- There's no pressure.
Step back. Step back!
- Okay, fourth to fifth...
- This is so wrong.
Intercostal space,
just below the nipple.
We are not doing this. I
am not doing this. Abby!
Shut up, I'm trying
to concentrate.
Okay, anything that bleeds,
clamp it. Pass me a snap.
- Here it is.
- No. That's a Kelly.
It'll do. Give it to me.
Rib spreader.
Right up here. Yeah. All
right, come on, crank it.
Come on. Come on, wider.
Crank it.
- What are you doing?
- Go get somebody.
Crank it. Wider. All
right, there, there, there!
Carter, your students just
cracked somebody's chest.
Pericardium was full of clot.
Are you guys insane?
I need to cross-clamp the
aorta with that big-ass clamp.
You don't know what it's called,
you shouldn't use it. Satinsky.
Get out of the way.
Page the O.R., get a
trauma surgeon down here.
- Why didn't you come and get me?
- The guy was dying.
Well, if he wasn't, he is now.
All right. I'll check this
one out. Hey, Daryl.
How's my good friend?
You're looking dapper today.
I need some information.
You seen any junkies around?
I'm looking for a junkie with a
6-year-old girl. You seen her?
- Man, I ain't seen no little girls, man.
- Go get the owner.
You know, Bosco's
not as bad as he seems.
Come on, go get the... What,
are you ignoring me? Huh?
Go get the owner now
before I break your face.
Stupid-ass.
Excuse me.
- What was that all about?
- Daryl wasn't being helpful.
Did he see the mom
or the daughter?
- Did you show him the picture?
- He went to get the owner.
You know, you better tone it
down with a civilian in the RMP.
She's wasting our time.
You guys finally gonna
shut this place down?
Who are you?
- Neighborhood watch.
- Yeah?
They're hookers, you know.
I believe the politically correct
term is "street hostesses."
In and out of this dump day and night,
stopping traffic up and down the street.
- I've been documenting their activity.
- Nice work.
Been calling for months. I
didn't think you'd ever come.
Yeah? You see that drunk
outside the deli over there?
- Yeah. I called about him too.
- You got a picture?
Look, I can't arrest
him without a picture.
It might be a custody thing
with her and the husband, right?
Maybe this chick
isn't even missing.
Maybe she's hiding from
her controlling, lunatic sister...
who jumps on a plane the minute
she doesn't answer the phone.
She flew in from Chicago.
She's worried and she's scared.
Junkies go missing all the
time. We don't hunt for them.
- Well, the sister said she's clean.
- Right.
Oh, no. This is a bloody mess.
What did you use to crack
his chest, a hand grenade?
- Hey, we saved him.
- Who are you and why are you talking?
You're supposed to be
Chief Resident, aren't you?
- Yeah.
- Better start acting like one...
before your students kill
off the rest of your patients.
What's his problem?
You just hacked up a patient
you shouldn't have touched.
- The guy would've been dead...
- Shut up.
- Go to the lounge, both of you.
- For what?
For once, just do
as you're told, Pratt.
Thanks a lot.
- Hey, where are you going?
- To save some more lives.
Yeah, I rented it to
a woman on Monday.
Seemed like nice
people. Cute little girl.
Just the two of them? - Yep.
- Did they have any visitors?
- Around here, we specialize in anonymity.
Yeah, and $20 nooners.
Hello? Hello?
Hello?
The cell's dead.
Yokas?
We should have been working
this angle from moment one.
He moved a little.
It was involuntary.
Trees, monkey bars, fences.
He was always climbing.
I swear he was half monkey.
He's not gonna
get better, is he?
He's got what we
call an axonal injury.
Even if we could
remove the blood...
the force of the fall damaged
the connections of the brain.
Is he suffering?
I think he's gone.
This is just his body.
We wanna let him go.
Okay.
Excuse me.
Where's Pratt?
- I don't know.
- I told you both to wait in here for me.
Yeah. And I'm here.
- How's Stanley?
- He's still in the O.R.
That was really stupid, Gallant.
Look, it was not my idea.
- You should have come to get me.
- I tried.
If I would have left, he would have
died. What was I supposed to do?
You weren't supposed
to crack the guy's chest.
All right, you're on scut duty for
the rest of the day. Both of you.
Yes, sir.
You know Dr. Malucci?
- No.
- That's because he got fired.
He was a hotshot too.
Killed a guy because he
thought he knew everything.
You two pull another stunt
like that, you're out of here.
Look, I don't blame you for
being angry about what happened.
But, please, don't
confuse me and Pratt.
Gallant?
- I told you to get rid of him.
- I got pulled into a trauma.
Doesn't look like
you're in one now.
- Okay. I'll ask him to leave.
- Forget it.
- Pratt, turf that guy.
- Yeah, okay.
- More suction.
- This the GSW?
- What's left of him.
- What happened?
Well, he had the
unfortunate luck...
of passing through
the ER butcher shop.
Where were you? I paged
you about a dozen times.
I had to break bad news...
to the parents of a boy
with a severe head injury.
Ha! Oh, right. That old excuse.
Dr. Corday, you
have a phone call.
- She's busy.
- Take a message, please.
It's your stepdaughter calling from
Hawaii. She says it's an emergency.
Go.
Metz.
Rachel, what's going on?
There he is. Oleg?
Oleg, I wanna ask
you a few questions.
Come here. Don't make
me get out of the car.
Damn it.
Hang on.
- You seen them?
- How you been, Oleg?
Get out of there.
Stand up.
Shut up.
Oops. What do we have
here? Illegal narcotics?
I'm shocked, man!
Let's do this again.
- Look again.
- You seen them?
- I'm not good with faces.
- Keep looking.
Maybe. There's a shooting gallery
in back of the old carpet factory.
- How long ago?
- Maybe an hour.
- Was the girl there?
- No kid. Ow!
You sure? Huh?
Maybe she was there. I
don't know. I didn't see her.
Show respect for the badge, Oleg.
You're bleeding all over my car.
You may have broken his nose.
No, he was always that ugly.
Ha-ha. All right. Okay. Hey,
Carter. Pratt just did a perfect tap.
Congratulations.
Now you can go home.
- Come on, man.
- I told you to wait in the lounge.
What good does that do anybody?
You wanna stay here, you do
what I tell you, when I tell you.
It's that simple. Don't make
me be a hard-ass, okay?
Okay.
Gallant's in Exam 4. Why don't you teach
him how to drain a perirectal abscess.
Uh, did I miss something?
We need to keep our eye on him.
He's good.
He's dangerous.
Any word on, uh,
Pratt's thoracotomy?
I haven't heard.
Do you wanna talk about it?
- There's nothing to talk about.
- Oh, no?
This started after your assault?
I said I didn't wanna talk.
- You said there was nothing to talk about.
- Whatever. It's not what you think.
- I can handle this.
- I'm not throwing the program at you.
- I'm just trying to help.
- Don't need any help.
Six years, you know? You
were sober for six years.
That's right. That was then.
I'm a different person now.
What? I'm not shooting up.
I had a beer. I had a beer.
- Stop trying to make it such a big deal.
- It is a big deal.
It's not about the beer
you had yesterday.
Or the two you're gonna want
today or the six you'll want tomorrow.
It's under control. It is. And
it's not a reaction, it's a decision.
My decision.
A 35-year-old restrained
driver in a left T-bone.
Possible DUI. Ran a
red, air bag deployed.
- Can you hear me?
- BP's 110/70 initially...
now 100 palp. Pulse, 100.
Look, you guys got this?
No breath sounds on the left.
Probably put down a lung.
- Is this the MVA?
- Yeah. Drunk driver.
- Trauma 2.
- Satting at 96.
- Robert. ROMANO:
Not now, Lizzie.
I'm not having a good day.
Got beat in the stock market...
some moron from Radiology
backed into my Jag...
- I had to put that ER victim together.
- I need some time off.
I need a month in France with
Vietnamese twins. Not gonna happen.
It's Mark. He's sick.
- I thought he was in Tahiti.
- Hawaii.
Uh, he's got worse. I don't think
he's gonna be able to fly home.
- Well, you'd better go to him.
- I don't know how long I'll be.
We'll survive.
- Thanks.
- Anything I can do?
Pray.
Ha, it's not exactly
my strong suit...
but, um, in this case
I'll make an exception.
Sats are still dropping.
This guy smells like a distillery.
Better get that blood alcohol.
- Did he hurt anybody else?
- I don't know.
Well, I guess this is the
downside to the three-martini lunch.
- 7.5 tube and a curved blade.
- Better open the crash cart.
We're gonna need some O-neg...
- and a chest-tube tray.
- I got that.
Chloe!
Chloe? BOSCO: Whew, smell that?
Welcome to Urine Town.
How hard is it to find
a toilet to take a piss?
Fellas, you don't
wanna be here. Split.
Chloe! BOSCO: Get lost.
Over here. Over here.
- I think it's her.
- Let me see.
Chloe? Chloe? Oh,
my God. Chloe? Chloe.
Where's Suzy? Where
is she? Chloe, wake up.
- Is she breathing?
- Pretty shallow.
This is 55 David. I need a bus
at 1047 and East 93rd forthwith.
Ten-four, 1047 and East 93rd.
No little girl.
- She's not here.
- Oh, God.
Five-four Charlie.
- I can't get a line. Kim, stop.
- She needs more Narcan now.
- Who are you?
- I'm her sister.
I give up. Let's go.
- No. She's barely breathing.
- I.M. Narcan sucks.
- She needs a central line.
- I can do it. I'm a doctor.
- You licensed in New York?
- Ah, no.
Hospital's only three
minutes out. She'll be fine.
Watch out, she's gonna blow!
- She say anything?
- No, she's too out of it.
You need to tube her
to protect her airway.
- I know. Thanks.
- You guys going to Mercy?
- Yeah. Come on.
- Can I go? You'll need more hands.
No. It's against department
policy. Can you give her a lift?
Come on. We'll follow them.
- Let's roll.
You know what? Come
on. Jump in. Come on.
- He's dead.
- When was his last epi?
Give it up, Luka. You're not gonna
get him back. He tore out his aorta.
- Time of death: 7:33.
- What a waste.
She's a big girl, Carter.
Yeah. With a drinking problem.
- I don't tell people how to live.
- She was living in your house.
- I didn't make her drink.
- You didn't stop her.
She's not a drunk.
Yes, she is.
Are you stupid or do you
not give a damn about her?
Or do you want her
to keep drinking?
You like them a little vulnerable so you
can play the caring, brooding comforter?
- Don't push your luck, Carter.
- What are you gonna do, beat me up?
You gonna bash my
head into the ground?
Get out of my way.
If you're not helping
her, you're hurting her.
Another two of Narcan, I.M.
- What's the total?
- Six.
- What can I do to help?
- Nothing.
Sit on your hands if you
have to. We're good at this.
I promise, she's gonna be fine.
Chloe, what were you taking?
- How we doing?
- BP's 140/80. Pulse, 90.
That's high for heroin.
Chloe, were you doing
coke? Were you speedballing?
Step on it. She's throwing PVCs.
- Chloe, where's Suzy?
- Call Dispatch. Tell them that we're...
- Lost her pulse.
- Out of the way.
- I mean it. What did I say?
- She's in V-fib.
Charging.
- You need to intubate her.
- Clear!
- Nothing.
- Charging 300.
You need to intubate her now.
- No. Clear!
Pratt, I told you
to get rid of him.
- Pratt?
- I told him to do it.
What is with you people?
You can't turf one lunatic?
- He cured my sciatica.
- What?
I was tossing him out, he put his
hands on my back, my sciatica's gone.
Yeah, so's your brain.
All right. Hey, you. That's
enough. You're out of here.
Worry not, my child. And
put your faith in his powers.
- I need you to... ED:
Believe in his powers.
- Let the passion of his love heal you.
- Hey!
- Believe in his power.
- Let go. Get out. Get out.
Fear not, and put your
trust in his almighty glory.
He's gonna live.
- Stanley.
- I did the right thing.
You were lucky. It
could've gone the other way.
- But it didn't.
- Not this time.
- Dr. Weaver here?
- I'm sorry, is this an emergency?
We're from the Illinois Women's Health
Coalition. Dr. Romano said she was here.
All right, I need you to get
out. Get out. Go on, get out.
I don't wanna see you in here
again unless you're on a gurney. Go.
- You will walk by his side renewed...
- Carter.
I just wanted to apologize
if I was abrupt earlier.
Um.
But I...
I don't want you
worrying about me.
Well, somebody should.
Not you. It's too complicated.
- What's so complicated?
- You and me.
Us.
What "us"? Is there an us?
Like I said, it's complicated.
But I appreciate your
concern. And I'm okay.
Thanks.
Hi.
I dreamed you were here.
Chloe, where's Suzy?
She's with me.
She's not with you.
Did you leave her
in the hotel room?
Did you take her
with you to get drugs?
Chloe.
- I don't know.
- Chloe.
Chloe, think. Think, Chloe.
- Maybe... Maybe he took her.
- Who, Joe?
Chloe? Chloe.
He broke my heart.
Where is Joe? Is Suzy with Joe?
I don't know. I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
I screwed up, Susan.
Oh, I screwed up.
I'm sorry.
Yeah, Chloe...
you screwed up.
Dr. Lewis?
Nothing?
Uh, we've got officers out
canvassing the entire precinct.
How's your sister?
She's stable.
The detectives
wanna talk to her.
She doesn't remember anything.
Uh...
The longer she's missing,
the worse it gets, right?
Because I heard that if you don't
find them in the first 12 hours...
Do you have a place to stay? If
you want, I can take you to a hotel.
No. I couldn't sleep if I wanted
to. Where's your partner?
He's out looking.
When's your shift over?
Oh, um.
It was over a few hours ago.
She's only 6 years old.
Yeah.