In the late 16th century,
a father-son team made
a groundbreaking discovery.
We're leaving
in 20 minutes.
♪ Till it all breaks down
It's my day off.
Can't I just do this instead?
What,
look at pictures and mope?
Yes, because apparently
love and great sex
are not enough
for the mother of my child.
Have you tried
talking to Amelia?
Oh, she's still crystal clear
that nothing has changed.
And still very good
at compartmentalizing.
They found that
when they put lenses
at the opposite ends of a tube,
it enlarged objects.
♪ Will you hold me
Oh, wow.
What?
♪ So the walls don't fall?
Jimmy's Crab Shack
is turning 50.
Carolyn Martin just posted
a bunch of old photos.
My feet hurt
just thinking about
working there.
Oh, no!
There's one of us.
Their invention was the first
compound microscope.
Waiting tables is hard enough
without the added mortification
of dressing
like a shellfish.
♪ Have a
Jimmy's Crab Shack birthday ♪
♪ All the crabs
that you can eat ♪
♪ 'Cause a
Jimmy's Crab Shack birthday ♪
♪ Is a very special treat!
Whoo!
Hey.
I was still looking at that.
It's my day off, too.
We're going out.
Get the kids.
And as basic as it was,
their invention
was a game changer
for science and medicine.
♪ All we are is satellites
What can
I get you?
Can I get a double espresso
with oat milk, please?
You got it.
You forgot your wife's latte.
What?
♪♪
I thought I was supposed
to pick you up
from the airport
tomorrow.
I caught
an earlier flight.
I thought
I'd surprise you.
What if I wanted
to surprise you?
By coming to the airport
a day early?
No, with, uh, uh...
jewelry or, uh...
flowers or something
to welcome you home.
♪ Watching how it all collides
I guess we'll just have to
find another way.
I guess so.
♪ All we are is satellites
Dr. Gladsen,
Labor and Delivery.
Dr. Gladsen to
What?
Nothing.
I'm just trying
to figure out
how I'm gonna
thank Hamilton
for calling an emergency meeting
this morning.
You don't even care
about my poor kids
whose mother
didn't come home.
Nope.
I really,
really don't.
Mm.
Oh.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Hey, Bailey.
They moved our booth.
Excuse me? Our booth.
At the medical student
convention.
Yeah, you should
park in lot...Okay.
...three -- It's closer.
I'm so sorry, Bailey.
I know.
We're a top-10 ranked
residency program
and they stuck us
way at --
Wait.
Why are you sorry?
That I'm still
in Minnesota --
My trip got extended
another day and --
No, no, no.
Yeah. I texted you.
No! You didn't.
If you had, I would have
called you back immediately
and said a bunch of words
I can't say
when people are around.
I did text you,
but I forgot to hit send.
Okay.
Uh, we need to recruit
the best and brightest
medical students
to apply to Grey-Sloan.
Who better to do that
than the actual Grey?
And I will make it up to you.
I promise.
Something wrong?
Our booth is located
in the armpit of the convention,
and we lost our biggest
recruitment tool.
Dr. Grey
isn't coming?
No.
If she doesn't
win the Nobel Prize
for whatever the hell
she's doing out there,
I might just fire her.
Hey, a-and where on earth
is Dr. Ndugu?
Well, that was better
than airport flowers.
Yeah.
Yeah, it was.
I missed you...Mm.
...so much.
Mm.
Well, Bailey.
Wants to know why I'm not
at the med student convention.
Ooh!
She's not gonna
like that.
No.
Mnh-mnh.
But how much do we care?
Where's Hamilton?
Late.
Does anybody know why he called
this emergency meeting?
Because someone
needs to tell me
what I'm supposed
to do about this.
What happened?I sprained it when
I stumbled in my own bedroom
because my foot froze
when I tried to take a step.
The Parkinson's is
progressing faster than you are.
David --The FDA approved a one-time
compassionate use surgery.
I want that surgery
scheduled now.
The surgery's approval
was contingent
upon very specific
benchmarks.
We have not proven
cell viability
above 75% yet.
And I need to know why.
I've spent a personal fortune.
I've given you
every resource you've needed,
despite obstacle
after obstacle.
But what does it
actually take?
Additional lab techs?
More fancy toys?
Extra cells?
I hired you
to get things done.
I am.
We are.
This team is working
around the clock.
Groundbreaking medicine
doesn't happen overnight.
Well,
that sounds like an excuse.
Everyone knows
when Meredith Grey
wants something to happen,
she finds a way.
What are you suggesting?
Make this surgery
happen ASAP
or I'm pulling the plug.
On the project?
On you.
♪♪
Remember that guy
who used to come in
15 minutes
before closing?
And order the unlimited
Jimmy's chowder bowl?
Yeah, he'd ask
for a million refills,
extra cheesy bread,
then he'd leave a dollar tip
in quarters.
Program?
Would you like a program?
It was good for laundry.
Program?
Look, Luna.
Look at this.
This is a program! Yes!
Here. Here's a program.
We're gonna
see a play.
That's where actors
dress up in costume
and perform a story.
Program?
Are you also gonna give her
a play-by-play of the play?
Hey, I read that
talking to your baby
is important
for brain development.
Yeah, I read
that this park
has a cart that sells pretzels
the size of your head,
but I'm not seeing any.
Okay, Luna.
There's a stage
and Rapunzel's castle.
And there's a sign
that says,
"They lived happily ever after."
I'm sad,
and you brought me
to a place
with families
and fairy tales.
And apparently
no cheesy bread.
Link...
Fairy tales
give kids false hope.
It makes you think
that everything's
always gonna be okay.
In real life,
families just...
fall apart.
Oh, my God.
Will you just go get a snack?
Yes.
Excuse me.
Is your husband gonna
use that program?
Oh. Ew.
No.
What do you see?
What do you guys see?
Every time something
doesn't go his way,
he throws a tantrum.
He's Ellis.
Your mom
or your daughter?
Both.
What kind of person
keeps someone from their kids
an extra day
just so he can berate them
in person?
A man feeling helpless
while his life erodes.
Hamilton aside,
we are working on a cure
for Parkinson's.
We -- And we're actually
at 79% viability
of the dopamine cells
at injection.
Since when?
Last night.
We believe
the cells' survival rate
is related
to temperature.
Dr. Grey,
meet Dr. Gavin Hawj,
star research assistant
and tech genius.
He built
the motorized injector.
It's nice to meet you.
It's an honor
to work with you.
At least someone
thinks so.
Maybe I'll just pull the plug
on myself.
Mer,
go back to the hotel.
Take a nap.
Get a massage.
There's a cure for Parkinson's
on the line
and your idea is
to go get a massage?
Just give us the day
in the lab.
If Kai and I can't
figure it out,
do whatever you want.
You can stay
even if I go.
Well, I could,
but I wouldn't.
Fine.
End of day.
♪♪
Would she really walk?
I'm hoping
we don't have to find out.
♪♪
How long will you be gone
this time, Mother?
Not long,
my dear Rapunzel.
Now pull up your hair
and await my return.
And no more singing!
There's no telling
who might be lurking...
This is insane.
Rapunzel's foster mom...
A witch....locks her in a tower
and her only form
of human contact
is a guy
who climbs her hair.
I figured
you'd have bigger issues
with the damsel-in-distress
aspect.
How is this an appropriate
children's story?
How do you not know
"Rapunzel"?
Who would've
read it to me?
That voice!
Perhaps I can
climb up the tower
the same way
that witch came down.
Tell me he has a rope ladder.
Rapunzel, Rapunzel,
let down your hair!
That would be smart,
but no.
Eventually he goes blind
after a failed suicide attempt.
Her hair is so luxurious
and strong.
Jeremy?
Oh, my God!
Wow.
That turned dark fast.
I don't think that
was supposed to happen.
Oh, my God.
Is anyone here
a doctor?!
Yes! I can help.
Thank you for
your patience.
Um, we invite you to stay
for the Fairytale Theater's
production of "Cinderella,"
which we hope
will begin soon.
911's not picking up.
Okay. Sir?
Jeremy.
His name's Jeremy.
Is he gonna be okay?
His pulse is a little thready
and irregular.
Jeremy, hi.
I'm Dr. Wilson.
This is Dr. Lincoln
from Grey-Sloan.
Can you say something?
Oh, my God.
Please be okay. Please be okay.
He's got an open
femoral fracture
and no DP pulse.
I'm gonna have to reduce
and splint this.
Jo, can you...?
Yeah.
Alright.
Hey, Jeremy,
this is gonna hurt, okay?
But the break
is cutting off the blood supply,
so the sooner we straighten
it out, the better.
We don't want
to lose your leg, okay?
I'm right here.
I'm not going anywhere.
One...two...three.
♪♪
Okay. We lost his pulse.
Starting CPR.
He's got
a heart condition!
It's called --
I-I don't know, but --
but he wears
an emergency bracelet.
Congenitally corrected
transposition
of the great arteries.
Does that help or matter or--
Yes, it does. Yes.
Is 911 picking up?
Still ringing.
There's a thing
near the playground.
The machine
that starts the shocking.
An AED!
Oh. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Go get it!
♪♪
Thank you
for stopping by this morning.
Grey-Sloan takes pride
in our outstanding
education program,
led by Dr. Richard Webber.
I mean,
we're consistently ranked
among the nation's
top-10 teaching hospitals.
And as a Fox Foundation
hospital,
we have greater access
to resources
like cutting-edge technologies
and extensive research mat--
Why don't you
take a brochure
and leave your e-mail?
Mm.
Chicago Lutheran's handing out
deep-dish pizzas.
Ooh. Yes, please.
Hey! Hey!
Okay,
when did residency recruitment
turn into
a bribery scheme?
Look at Palley,
resorting to massages?
That's a little desperate,
don't you think?
Well,
they are highlighting
their resident
wellness program.
You think we should have brought
a dog-and-pony show?
You were gonna bring
Meredith Grey.
And Owen Hunt,
but apparently,
a trauma came in.
And Ndugu's
a no-show.
But that's not bribery.
That's -- That's
excellence in education.
There's a difference.
What about
the Webber Method?
That's not
an official program.
Well, the CAPE Clinic
is raffling off a laptop.
You got a better idea?
Hey.
I got your text.
Yeah.
Do you need a consult?
I do. Yeah.
Um, how'd your meeting go?
Well, a meeting would imply
a rational conversation.
I've managed to disappoint
both of my bosses
in the span of an hour.
So I might just quit
and move to Italy.
Right, right, right.
Um, before you do,
take a look.
Did my sister
put you up to this?
To distract me
from Hamilton?
Uh, well, I've never
met your sister.
Plus,
if I distracted you
every time
you were mad at David,
I'd never get anything done.
So, a 45-year-old male
with headache,
palpitations,
and hypertension.
Adrenal tumor,
looks like a pheo.
Yeah.
So do you think
it's possible
to do a partial
adrenalectomy?
I mean,
you would have to.
He's only got
one adrenal.
Mm-hmm. Yeah, of course.
Do you know his history?
Yeah, I do.
He's a kidney donor.
The adrenal gland
was so badly adhered
we had to take it
along with the kidney.
Did you work
on the transplant?
I was involved, yes.
So, partial?
Uh, sure.
Great.
I've already secured you
privileges,
and I'll have my favorite
resident scrub in with you.
Me?
Yeah.
There isn't anyone else
who can do this?
There are.
There are several someones.
But this guy needs the best.
He needs you.
Where am I going?
Fifth floor.
I'll take you up.
Come on.
This is amazing.
We wrapped the syringe
in a thermal coating
to insulate it.
The key is keeping the cells
cold long enough.
Is the injector speed
a factor?
Mm,
that's what we're testing.
But it's a careful balance
between speed and temperature.
Game time.
Let's see if it worked.
I'll prep
the next batch of cells.
Okay. And this counts
the viable cells?
Yes.
Healthy cells
reject the dye.
Dead cells
turn blue.
Then the software converts them
to green and red
so we can easily see
how many are still alive.
This takes
so much patience.
You prefer instant
gratification?
Not instant, but...
How long have you
been at this?
Two years.
With no guarantee
that it goes anywhere?
That's why
I like tumors.
They're there,
you cut, they're gone.
Yay.
I don't have the patience
for patients.
You never wanted to be
a clinical doctor?
My teachers encouraged it.
My mom would've loved
to have 24/7 access
to free medical advice.
But being a clinician's
not what attracted me
to science.
It was always
about the discovery,
the openness
to possibility.
And an M.D. felt
confining to me.
So I applied
to PhD programs instead.
Seems like
it worked out.
My mom might
argue with you.
What about you?
Why neuro?
No one ever
asks me that.
They just assume
that it's...
'cause I wanted to be
like my brother.
Who's your brother?
You just became
my favorite person.
♪♪
Still 79%.
Excuse me.
♪♪
Damn it.
He must've torn the SFA.
I'm gonna try to pack it.
Okay.
Let's see.
♪♪
Is this just all snacks?
You're the one who's always
talking about food.
What do you need?
Luna's cloth diapers.
I stopped packing them.
What about Scout's?
Paramedics
are on their way.
Here's the AED.
How is he?
What can I do to help?
Open the defibrillator.
And put the pads
on his chest.
Place pad exactly
as shown in the picture.
It's okay, Luna. You're fine.
Mommy's right here.
Press firmly
to patient's bare skin.
I'm just saving a life.
You want me to get her?
Yes.
Can you push her closer to me?
Thank you.
He's still bleeding.
Your belt.
I can use it as a tourniquet.
Is he gonna
bleed to death?
Not if I can help it.
♪ Someday my prince
will come ♪
Not messaging she needs
but thank you.
Okay.
Brian Williams, 45,
CT and biochemical work-up
revealed a pheochromocytoma
on the right adrenal.
BP's still elevated
despite Prazosin --
180 over 98.
Otherwise
vital signs stable.
Thank you, Dr. Wright.
Do you have pain
on the right side?
A little.
Okay.
Paige freaked out
when I had heart palpitations
at Alex's
volleyball game.
Figured it was stress
from the semi-finals.
Or from having
three teenage girls.
One's trying to get
a volleyball scholarship,
one's in callback auditions
for the high school play,
and the youngest
apparently just got dumped.
I don't know how
you keep up.
I don't.
I ended up collapsing
in the third game.
Well, this type of tumor
is extremely rare,
so it's great
we caught it now.
Thanks to this guy.
So, I'll go in from the side
laparoscopically.
It's the least invasive.
Oh, so like
my donation surgery?
Mm-hmm.
Exactly.
You'll be in the room?
Uh, I can be.
If Dr. Grey doesn't mind.
Of course.
No problem.
Yeah.
I'll see you in the OR.
Okay. Dr. Wright?
Okay.
So, tell me what we do next.
Mnh.
They're
my coping mechanism.
Left over from my days
on the swim team.
It's a problem.
There are worse habits.
Yeah, but these are like
a gateway to fries.
If Grey walks,
would you really leave, too?
She brought me
onto the project.
And she's family.
But we are gonna
figure this out because
walking boosts creativity.
I read that
in a study.
Anything?
Not yet.
You?
No. Too distracted
by the thought of fries.
Mm.
When you get stuck in surgery,
what do you do?
You cut or close.
When someone's brain
is open,
that's pretty much
all you can do.
We had to dissect worms
in 8th grade biology.
Total disaster.
Worm guts everywhere.
Cutting was
never my forte.
I remember getting
my first pair of scissors.
I was 4.
Mm.
And unstoppable?
I hated them.
They were so dull they couldn't
cut through butter.
So I stole
my older sister's.
Then I was unstoppable.
I cut the curtains,
my hair,
her favorite dress,
the tops of
her dolls' heads.
That's disturbing.
I wanted to see
where feelings came from.
What'd you find?
Cotton.
Oh.
It was very disappointing.
Ah.
Time to go back.
You have an idea?
No, but I only allotted myself
15 minutes to stress out.
And honestly,
I feel better.
His s-sword! I can use
that to secure the tourniquet.
Okay.
His heart rate's
all over the place.
His heart condition
makes him prone
to abnormal heart rates.
Could that
be why he fell?
Most likely.
Shock advised.
Stay clear of patient.
Press the flashing shock button.
He needs to be shocked.
Clear.
Now?
You want to argue
with the machine?
Clear. Deliver shock --
Shock delivered.
Analyzing.
You need to move faster.
Shock advised.
I'm almost done.The tourniquet's
not gonna matter
if his heart
doesn't start.
Clear.
Okay, I'm done.
Shock delivered.
Analyzing.
His heart's not starting.
We need epi.
Begin CPR.
Where's the ambulance?
They said 10 minutes
like 15 minutes ago.
You have to save him.
Please save him.
Alright.
Where can we get some epi?
Don't look at me.
I packed bananas
and peanut butter pretzels.
There's gotta be a kid here
with an allergy.
EpiPens!
Okay, go into the audience.
Collect as many as you can get.
Alright.
Hey. Does anyone here
have an EpiPen?
If you do,
we need one now!
Run!
Yeah, as many as you can get.
I have one right here.
♪♪
Is this really gonna work?
It's worth a shot.
Just do it. Please.
30 seconds
until analysis will resume.
Pushing 0.3 of epi.
Five...six...seven...
Ah! This is gonna take longer
than the ambulance.
Okay, Cathi.
Can you take over?
One hand over the other,
2 inches deep, okay?
15 seconds
until analysis will resume.Ready?
♪♪
Can you do that?
He won't overdose?
He would get more
in the hospital.
Shock not advised.
Okay.
He's back.
We did it.
Finally.
Okay, he's gonna need
to be stabilized.
We'll take him to Grey-Sloan.
You okay if I ride with him?
Yeah.
I'll meet you there.
Okay. Alright.
Hey!
Over here!
How's your dad?
Mm.
He's better.
He's doing way better.
I honestly think
he was better awhile ago.
He just didn't
want me to leave.
You think
he was faking it?
A little bit!
A little bit I do.
Mm.
I liked being there with him,
though.
Mm. I hated being
away from you.
You are...
my dream come true.
You know that, right?
I'm honestly not sure
I'm awake right now.
I might need
some convincing.
Do you need
to get that?
Nope.
It's cardio,
but I'm supposed to be
at the med student convention.
So let's let Altman
get this one.
Yeah.
Mmm.
♪♪
Using this teaching method,
every resident gets
their own patient
and their own OR.
Of course...They seem
to be into it.
Of course they are.
It's the future of teaching.
I'm not sure why we're letting
this particularfuture sell it.
Peer-to-peer communication
can be very effective.
So, basically,
you're unsupervised?
No.
Attendings rotate
through the carefully timed
overlapping procedures.
They're there for all
the critical parts. See?
I don't get it.
It's ORs,
residents,
attendings.
It would be
better in color.
The Webber Method
lets us finish residency
with a larger case log.
And we get more autonomy,
which helps us become
better surgeons.
That's kind of what
everyone says.
How do we know
Grey-Sloan's any better?
Oh!
Our personalized tote bag's
ready at Newport Med.
Thank you.
♪♪
Uh...
Well...
Put that down.
Good job, guys.
Dr. Wilson.
Have you heard anything
about Jeremy?
Uh, no, but Dr. Lincoln
should be operating on him
right now.
Can you check?
The front desk
can't tell me anything
because I'm not family,
but I am.
I am his family.
Yesterday we did
two shows in Boise,
then packed up
and drove here overnight.
It's not easy
sleeping on a bus,
let alone one
where you're crammed
between a plywood tower
and pile of wigs.
But we do it.
For six years now,
we do it together.
Because we love it,
and we love...
We, uh...
He's my favorite --
He's my best...
His family is
in Philadelphia,
and he hasn't seen them
for years.
I am his family.
He told me he felt lightheaded
this morning.
I told him he was probably
just tired from the travel.
♪♪
I need to know
he's gonna be okay
because if he's not,
then I'm not.
♪♪
Okay. Uh, let me go
see what I can find out.
Can you --
Can you watch them for me?
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
♪♪
Alright, I'll see if
the last sample count's done.
And prep for the next one.
Maybe we won't
need another one.
Unbridled optimism.
I like it.
You ever work
on a project for years
and then it just folded?
Years? No.
Months? Yes.
What did you do?
I rented a house in Hawaii
for the summer.
Um, learned how to surf
and grow my own pineapple,
and came back
and started again.
You ever want to give up?
Of course.
But when everything
falls into place
and all the stars align
and you find that thing
that you weren't even sure
was possible,
there is this feeling
of intense satisfaction
and pure joy
that makes all the rest of it
melt away.
And it turns all the waiting
and the setbacks
and the disappointment
into something worthwhile.
And I think that can be
as beautiful
as the science itself.
♪♪
Hey! Hey!
It's beeping!
♪♪
79%.
We had such a breakthrough
when we figured out
the thermal coating.
Nothing's really moved
the needle since.
Dr. Shepherd?
We know the dopamine cells
are cold going into the syringe
and that the thermal insulation
is holding that temperature.
But they're gaining heat
when they hit the brain,
so that has to happen
between here and here.
The needle.
What if we could
keep the cells cold
inside the needle?
♪♪
What are
you doing?
We can't fit the whole thing
in the freezer.
♪♪
Working on getting
better exposure
of the adrenal vein.
Dr. Wright, can you g--
Give more countertraction
on the liver?
Absolutely.
Let's work
on these adhesions.
You think you'll have
adequate visualization?
I do.
And you'll avoid getting
into the vena cava?
Dr. Marsh,
would you like to scrub in?
No, no, no. No, no.
I'm good. You got it.
His anatomy on the right
seems similar
to what you described
on the left.
Yes. Well, you have
to avoid the kidney.
He can't lose it.Not my plan.
He's hypertensive
and tachycardic.
Let's hit him with 5 milligrams
of phentolamine.
Why's his pressure
all over the place?
What about
pushing Esmolol?
I think you put too much
pressure on the adrenal gland.
You need to get control
of the adrenal vein right now.
BP's going down.
Okay.
Taking the adrenal vein.
Dr. Marsh,
do you need to step out?
I'm sorry.
Excuse me?
I'm asking
if you're too invested
in this patient
and need to step out.
Because you're right.
He does only have one kidney,
and right now
I'm responsible for it.
So you either
don't trust me or --
Well, I'm responsible
for the other one.
♪♪
Brian's my donor.
He's been my best friend
since we were 5 years old.
And he saved my life
by giving me a kidney.
Step out.
Meredith, I'm fine.
Dr. Marsh,
get out of the OR.
♪♪
Got your page.
What do you got?
31-year-old male with CCTGA
and an open femur fracture.
He fell about 10 feet.
Ladder?
Hair.
He's the prince
in "Rapunzel."
He had CPR in the field,
as well as multiple shocks
from an AED.
I'm almost done
with his ex-fix,
but he's having
various arrhythmias.
We already tried
transcutaneous pacing.
Well, maybe he had
a potassium surge
when you released
the tourniquet.
Alright,
we got a pulse with that?
No pulse.
Alright.
Start compressions.
Lose the C-arm.
Someone get me
antiseptic.
Bokhee,
can you gown me, please?
Let's get him Betadine
and a temporary pacing kit.
Thank you.
Do you prefer using EBVS
in these kind of cases?
I find it efficient.
We've got some oozing --
I've got
your hemostatic agent.
Okay.
Exactly right.
I can see why you're Dr. Marsh's
favorite resident.
Thank you.
That means a lot coming
from you, Dr. Grey.
You're part
of a medical legacy.
My mother was one
of the greats.
I meant that you studied under
the esteemed Miranda Bailey.
You know Dr. Bailey?
I saw her lecture
on preventing post-op fistulas
when I was in med school.
Then I watched every one
of her surgical videos
that I could find.
There's one
of this Whipple.
When she did
the mucosal anastomosis,
her PDS sutures were
all in one motion.
It's like she'd been
doing it forever.
Except she was
a first-year attending.
I'd give anything
to learn her techniques,
so assisting you today
is a highlight
of my residency.
Why didn't you apply
for residency at Grey-Sloan?
I did.
Didn't match.
Broke my heart.
Can I take two?
Absolutely.
Thank you.
Bailey! Hi!
I came back early!
Hi, Dr. Lin.
Hi.
Winston
is still parking the car.
I'm so sorry
we're late.
Pepperoni?
It's deep dish!
Chicago Lutheran
had it flown in.
Do you want a piece? I can
always just get another one --
No, I do not
want your pizza.
Is everything okay?
Okay?
No, everything is not okay,
but, hey,
now that you're here,
maybe you can fix it.
Yeah.
I mean, you're a...
world-class
cardiothoracic surgeon!
It doesn't matter
if you didn't bring swag.
Medical marijuana
is legal in Seattle.
Maybe we should have given out
weed gummies to the students.
That's actually
not a bad idea.
Stop it.
It is a terrible idea.
We never handed out pizza.
No.
We never threw
free gifts at people.
Never even
offered pens.
Because we've
been enough.
The doctors who work here
have been enough, right?
They used to line up!
They used to want us.
Now, what,
we're supposed to beg
for their attention?
And give them toys
to try to hold it?
Do you want
to take a break?
Yes, I do.
A nice, long one.
Okay.
You used a frozen needle
for this sample, too?
Yes. We are trying them
at different temperatures.
You know, when I fell,
my granddaughter
was at the house.
She's 12.
It scared her.
It scared me.
Okay. The injector's set.
We're ready for the needle.
Please, God.
How cold is that one?
Three degrees Celsius.
One degree colder
than the one in the counter.
What if it freezes
the cells?
Well, then
we try again.
Okay.
We should inject
before it warms up.
Mm-hmm.
Looks good.
Can I just confirm
that the --
Okay,
with all due respect,
we are trying very hard
to make this project viable.
And your constant questions
are not helping.
I'm sorry.
Um...
what do you
want to know?
The FDA viability requirement --
They want 90%?
Correct.
Because your last sample
is currently...
...at 92%.
Yes!
Sorry. But yes!
We might cure Parkinson's.
Oh, God, I hope
I didn't run off your sister.
♪ Take some time to get it
off your chest ♪
♪ Yeah, take it
and give it a rest ♪
What are those faces?
I-Is he...?
Jeremy's okay.
Oh, my God.
Well,
we do have to put in
a permanent pacemaker
while he's here,
but he should be fine.
Oh, my God.
Oh, thank you.
Oh, thank you so much!
Y'all are superheroes.
We're glad we could help.
Uh, can I see him?
I don't care
if he's sleeping.
He's my best friend.
I just want to see for myself
that he's okay.
Yeah.
Come with me.
♪ We looking
for the other side ♪
That woman
is not good at pretending.
That's a harsh review
for a kids' show.
No, she, uh --
she keeps saying the prince
is her best friend,
but she is so clearly
in love with him.
Maybe it's both.
What?
Like best friends
who got married?
Like Hunt and Altman?
Or, you know,
you have a crush,
and you work through it
and become best friends.
Like us.
I never had
a crush on you.
Not you.
Me.
What are you
talking about?
I had a huge crush
on you.
Why do you think
I worked at Jimmy's
the summer
after I graduated?
It wasn't for the tips
in quarters.
Then you set me up
with Bronwyn,
who eventually
broke my heart.
And you started
dating Paul.
He was such a bad guy,
I figured you needed
a best friend.
So here we are.
And thank God
because I don't know
what I'd be doing without you
right now.
Okay, um...
I'm gonna go change.
And then we can grab some dinner
on the way home?
♪ Ah-ah-ah-ah
♪♪
They're settling Brian
in the PACU now.
Tumor is out.
There was
minimal bleeding.
No damage to the kidney at all.
And he will need follow-up,
but he'll recover nicely.
Thank you.
Thanks.
We, uh, played
Little League,
went camping every summer.
When my mom died,
I basically lived at his house.
He and his wife co-parented
Charlotte with me,
and I can't tell you
how many dialysis sessions
he sat through with me,
so...
Which is exactly why
you shouldn't have
been in there.
I know. I know.
I...
♪♪
I just --
I didn't want to put
that burden on you.
I didn't want to make you
personally invested because,
if God forbid
something terrible happened,
I didn't want
to put that on you.
I'm always
personally invested.
The second I walk in the room,
I'm personally invested,
whether I know them
or not.
And if I don't know their story,
I make one up.
There is no such thing
as just a body on a table
for me...
ever.
So you can
give me the burden.
I can handle it.
When you operated
on me...
...you make up a story?
You told me
your whole life story
before I even
had your IV in.
Oh, yeah.
That's true.
Well, I owe you...
big time.
And if we're keeping score,
that's two.
And I usually
don't call in IOUs,
but today I might
actually do it.
Okay.
♪♪
"Your talents will soon be
recognized and adored..."
You're supposed say
"in bed."
Right.
In bed.
I --
I Googled Rapunzel.
After she's banished
and the prince goes blind,
he finds her singing
in the forest.
Her tears of joy
restore his sight,
and they get their
happy ending...
even though it didn't go the way
they thought it would go.
Maybe we'll still
get ours.
Hmm.
We just need
some magic tears.
I'm serious.
What if all the crap
that we've been through
is just the middle part
of the story...
the part you have
to go through
to find
your happily ever after?
Because when two people have
been there for each other
over and over,
through the worst that
humanity has to offer...
don't they deserve
to be happy?
You're right.
Jo, you're right.
I've been holding
onto a fairytale,
and it doesn't --
it doesn't have to be that.
I love...
Amelia.
And I'm -- And I'm so deeply
in love with her.
I can wait. I-I don't --
I don't have to get married now.
I just need her.
Right?
Right.
Should I call her?
S-Should I, uh,
go to her house and wait?
Oh, I-I should -- I should
pick her up at the airport.
I wonder what time she gets in.
Where's my phone?
The invention
of the microscope
turned the scientific community
on its head.
It gave scientists a whole new
way of looking at things.
For the first time,
they could see cells
and things they couldn't
with the naked eye.
I thought you never
left the clinic.
Only when I've had
a major breakthrough
and to feed my cat.
♪ That's how I know
that you won't stay ♪
You saved
our project today.
We're lucky to have you
as our lead neurosurgeon.
Oh, it was
a group effort.
And the surgery is not
the most complex part
of this project.
Maybe.
But a lot of other neurosurgeons
would have passed.
The risk of failure's
too big.
But you're driven as much
by the process as the outcome.
♪ You've got untied ends
you need to complete ♪
There's a big difference
between not giving up
and being good.
I don't think Meredith Grey
suffers fools.
♪ They will call your name
The way I see it...
is you fell in love with neuro
when you were 4
and you wanted to see
where feelings came from.
And you still love it.
Your eyes light up
when you look at brains,
even the plastic ones.
And you're unrelenting.
You don't settle.
And that's what matters
when you want
to break new ground.
I'm glad today
worked out.
Me, too.
It means we get
to keep working together.
♪ To light the way...
You want to celebrate?
Grab some dinner?
♪ ...back home
I have to catch
a plane.
♪ You and I are both the same
Okay.
But I will see you
next week.
Mm-hmm.
The simple use of curved glass
to bend and refract light
revolutionized
how we see the world.
♪ There's a world out there
and it'll come calling ♪
In many ways,
it's not all that different
from everyday life.
♪ And I won't ask for you
to stay ♪
♪ So go ahead and see
what you need to see ♪
Do you have a minute?
Not if you're
gonna tell me
that you've been appointed
Surgeon General.
I'm sorry
I wasn't at the convention.
Doesn't matter.
None of it does.
You know, for years,
I've spent all of my energy
recruiting the best.
Then I train them.
I watch their every move,
I teach them everything I know,
and then they take
all that knowledge
and go off to make
groundbreaking,
world-changing contributions
to medicine.
Meanwhile,
I'm still spending a whole day
standing on a sidewalk
next to a folding table,
trying to convince
a bunch of medical students
who look like teenagers
that I am worth
their time.
Do -- Uh,
do you need something?
I have someone
I would like you meet.
W--
♪ To light the way back home
Dr. Miranda Bailey,
I would like you to meet
Dr. Jordan Wright.
He's a resident in Minnesota,
but he would like to transfer
to Grey-Sloan.
We did a surgery together.
He's excellent.
Nice to meet you,
Dr. Wright.
And tell me why you're
interested in Grey-Sloan?
You, Dr. Bailey.
I want to learn
from you.
♪ To light the way back home
I'm listening.
♪ To the light the way
back home ♪
First of all...
Sometimes seeing life
through a different lens
opens a new world
of possibilities.
♪ To light the way back home
♪♪