Previously, on
"The Resident"...
Just an email
Ian forwarded me.
How is everything with him?
Passed his drug
test. Operating up a storm...
Fine, I guess.
Seems crazy.
But we all cover up things
we don't want to see.
The longer we look away,
the harder it gets to see
what's right before our eyes.
I know what will make me smile.
Showing you photos
of the exquisite venue
where in a few short weeks,
I will marry
the man of my dreams.
Pachelbel's "Canon in D"
playing...
Sorry, everyone.
It's the governor's office.
I have to take this.
Okay, let's, uh,
just give her a minute.
Sure, yeah.
Let's, uh, let's all take five.
Daddy, when's Sammie
gonna be here?
She and Jake are on their way.
And they're bringing
your flower girl dresses
for the ceremony tonight,
isn't that exciting?
Yeah!
So, when is he available?
Well, I certainly hope so.
Thank you.
Everything all right?
Our new governor's been
avoiding my calls all week
and now his office
won't even set a meeting.
He's probably too busy
making plans to slash funding
for public hospitals
like Chastain.
And it'll be hard to change
his mind if he keeps dodging me.
I know you're worried,
but we'll figure it out.
Just not today.
I know we will.
And I won't let anything
spoil this evening.
Hi. - Boo!
Hi,
everyone, sorry we're so late.
- Oh...
- Not at all.
Oh, it's lovely to see you.
I'm just sorry Gregg
couldn't make it.
- Yeah.
- Glad you could make it.
Oh, unfortunately,
our luggage did not.
Airline lost our bags.
Oh, no.
Our dresses were in them.
- But I want to be a flower girl.
- That's okay,
- sweetheart.
- Oh, sweetie.
It's Tracy Laybourne.
I believe God created
voice mail for times like this.
Tracy, good morning.
Ms. Laybourne is a tech mogul
from Silicon Valley,
and one of the few
prospective donors
who could keep us afloat
if our funding gets cut.
Randolph,
I'm glad you picked up.
I thought you might
be in surgery.
Actually, uh,
I took the day off.
Is everything okay?
It's my daughter.
She's not feeling well.
Okay, uh,
tell me what's going on.
Well, we were on our way
to the aquarium
and Max started feeling
sluggish and sweaty.
Incredibly tired.
I think she needs to see a
doctor, and you're the only one
- I know in Atlanta.
- Okay, sounds as though
she needs an internist.
I can
send our best to meet you
at Chastain ER
and I'll be there
as soon as I can.
Thanks.
Conrad, can you take a look
at Tracy's daughter?
- I-I could, but I...
- Go. I'll watch Gigi.
- I mean, I took the day off.
- Uh, the girls
do need new flower girl dresses
and I need a new suit.
Great. So we'll divide
and conquer.
You go get your suit
and I'll take
our little ladies shopping.
Meet back here.
You don't have to do this.
I can get a sitter.
Are you kidding me?
It'll be fun.
Shouldn't we finish
the rehearsal?
Oh, thank you, Lindsay,
but Randolph and I already have
a few weddings between us,
so I think we're good.
I'll get him back in one piece.
You, not so fast.
What was that for?
That was my last kiss
as a single woman.
And mine as a single man.
*THE RESIDENT*
Season 06  Episode 06
Episode Title: "For Better or Worse"
Aired on: October 25, 2022.
Heart sounds are normal.
And lungs are clear.
You're gonna be okay.
We'd be more than happy
to bring in
a sign language interpreter.
Oh, no need. I can translate.
And Max is a great lip reader.
Besides,
most interpreters can barely
keep up with my daughter.
Yeah.
You are too fast.
She's chatty.
Last month,
it was dinosaurs, and then
ancient history, and now...
sea creatures.
And sharks.
Sounds like
you've got it covered.
If you need anything,
let me know.
Oh, thank you.
Were Max's eyes
this yellow when she
- woke up today?
- Hmm.
I don't think so.
Is that serious?
No, there's no reason
to be alarmed.
Could mean a lot of things.
I'll rush some labs,
find out what's going on.
All right, this is the place.
Oh...
♪ Oh, hello ♪
♪ Where did you come from... ♪
Okay, so we have choices.
♪ How do you do what you do... ♪
I like this one!
Kit said you guys can wear
whatever you like tonight.
So I want each of you
to pick out your favorites
and then we can try them on.
I like this one!
Can I try this one?
♪ New best friend ♪
- Yay!
- Yeah!
Who is that walking in the door?
Dr. Bell here
on his wedding day?
I can't believe it.
Did Dr. Voss
change her mind already?
Well, thankfully, Kit has not
come to her senses yet,
so I expect to see all of you
- at our ceremony this evening.
- Oh, I would not miss it.
How's Tracy's daughter?
Her liver enzymes just came back
and they're off the charts.
How high are we talking?
So high the lab
ran them three times.
Her INR is 2.0.
She's going into liver failure.
And fast.
We need to move faster.
All right, I'll talk with Tracy
while you get Max
a bed in the ICU.
And I'll bring Ian up to speed.
If we can't figure out the cause
and reverse it fast enough,
there's only one thing
that will keep Max alive.
Transplant.
Wait...
- my daughter may need a liver transplant?
- I'm...
I'm sorry.
I wish we had better news.
Come on, honey.
Let's go.
- Take that thing out. We're getting out of here.
- We need to get her
to the ICU right away to monitor
her labs and mental status.
That's the only way to know
how fast her liver is worsening.
You know what, no offense,
but I brought Max here for a checkup,
not a transplant.
We both know that this hospital
is in financial trouble
and that's why
you reached out to me.
- I'll explain in the car.
- Tracy,
I would strongly advise
against moving her.
This has nothing to do
with you helping Chastain.
Max is critically ill.
Her condition could change
at any moment
and moving her in this state
is a risk I would not recommend.
Okay, right.
Listen.
My daughter was born
with her hearing.
But at six months old
she got an infection
and the hospital I took her to
was wildly underfunded.
They sent her home
with an antibiotic
and completely missed the fact
that she had meningitis.
That's how Max lost her hearing.
Yes.
I donate to hospitals
like Chastain
because they need the help.
But I won't let my daughter
get harmed again.
And I just had my assistant
get the number
of the best pediatric surgeon
in the country.
All right. Let's go, honey.
And we've no idea
what caused this?
Not acetaminophen, I checked.
You started her on NAC,
to be safe?
And a battery of tests.
My daughter deserves the best
and that's exactly
- who she'll be seeing.
- What's the deal?
We've got a problem.
Hello, this is Dr. Sullivan.
Hello?
You're here.
I am.
But I can't talk right now.
I'm about to meet
my next patient.
Hi.
So what happens now?
Well, first,
you have to trust me.
I do.
And I'm sorry.
- I just...
- There's no apology necessary.
Dr. Sullivan
will keep Max stable
while Dr. Hawkins does his
damnedest to try and figure out
why her liver is failing.
We find the cause,
then maybe we can treat Max
and avoid a transplant
altogether.
Give me the real.
You're not here
because the outlook is positive.
Things don't go our way,
we can list Max with UNOS,
get a liver
from a deceased donor.
But that will take time.
There is another option.
Transplant the lobe
of a living donor.
Someone related to Max who can
give a part of their liver
to her.
So, you could make
a list of relatives,
just in case,
people we can call.
There-There's no one else.
No father in the picture
and I have no siblings.
It has always
just been me and Max.
So if she needs a liver,
I will give her part of mine.
Okay.
I can take you to the lab
and get some blood drawn
to see if you're a match
and walk you through
- next steps on the way.
- Okay.
Portal vessels are patent.
Good flow. No sign of clot.
Which would be a good thing,
but, right now...
We still don't have the cause.
- Viral studies back yet?
- Well,
hep B and C are both negative.
Loss of appetite could indicate
worsening liver failure.
Or it could mean...
You don't like Jell-O?
I always get the "E" wrong.
You know how to sign?
A little.
Hey, sweetie.
How are you feeling?
Mm.
So, we can't go home yet.
Right?
The doctors,
they're gonna try to help me
to help you.
By... letting me
give a part of me to you.
You remember when you had
that Mr. and Mrs. Potato Head?
And she could give her ears
or her nose to him?
It's kind of like that.
Of course.
I will be fine, sweetie.
Your mom's liver will grow back.
That's pretty cool, huh?
That was pretty impressive
in there.
When did you learn ASL?
I took a class in college.
I don't remember that much,
but I do remember
my favorite was "microwave."
Oh.
Wait. Hold-hold on.
Do these nails match the dress
I saw in the back of your car?
I got them done for tonight.
I thought you said you weren't
a wedding kind of girl.
I... I believe
your words were...
"weddings are
a special kind of torture."
Yes. But I am looking forward
to this one.
Bell and Kit invited me.
Not just as your plus-one.
Think I'm finally
part of the group.
Means a lot to me.
Me too.
Don't tell me you've
been tweeting at the governor
- all morning.
- You know me too well.
Full disclosure, I also follow
you on social media
and I saw for myself.
This-this is how you relax?
Says the man treating patients
on his wedding day.
How's the girl?
She may need a liver transplant,
but we just found out
her mom is a match.
That's great news.
Keep me posted.
Of course.
After this echo,
you should be cleared to donate.
Mm.
Nice ink game, by the way.
Yeah, back in my 20s,
I was big into the music scene.
- And then Max was born.
- Mm.
Now I'm a little... quieter.
She's an amazing kid.
I started my company 'cause
I wanted to give her everything,
and... now I can.
Yeah, well, family
is a powerful motivator.
Mm. Mm.
What is it?
The echo is showing signs
of critical aortic stenosis.
It's a severe narrowing
in the valve that brings blood
from your heart to your body.
Uh, I have been
more short of breath lately.
Tiring more easily.
Well, an aortic valve
replacement should fix that.
But it is major.
Your heart is going to need
some time to recover before you
can safely donate
part of your liver.
All right, well, how much time?
Weeks.
Maybe months.
But Dr. Bell said
that Max may need a liver soon.
And I'm saying that
if we attempt a transplant now,
you could die on the table.
No, but...
I have to save my daughter.
I can't live without her.
She's my whole world.
So, we will find another way.
What did you find out?
Nothing.
We have no idea
why this kid's liver's failing.
No Kayser-Fleischer rings
in her eyes.
No evidence of Wilson's.
Autoimmune serologies are...
they're pending.
But it's unlikely, and hepatitis
labs came back negative.
Well, we have to hurry,
'cause I just talked to AJ
and Tracy can't donate.
Max's coags are climbing.
She could start
bleeding internally
- at any moment.
- Well, just double down.
Try harder. If you can't figure
out why Max's liver's failing
and we have no donor...
...this child could die.
"Corners"
by Book On Tape Worm playing...
Aunt Billie?
What will you wear
for your wedding?
You know, not everyone
gets married.
If you do,
can we pick your dress?
Is your daddy
gonna get married again?
I don't know.
He has a girlfriend.
Do you like her?
She's okay.
She's not like my mommy.
I mean, I don't
remember my mommy,
but it's different.
I remember your mommy.
She was really nice.
She was a nurse when I was sick.
She took great care of me.
I wish I remembered her.
There she is.
The woman of the hour.
- I'm not married yet.
- No, but you're trending on Twitter.
Yeah. Right behind
the latest banana muffin craze
and a bunny dancing
on a bed to the Beatles.
Hey, that bunny is talented.
Governor Betz has got to be
feeling the pressure
to meet with you now.
So far, no word.
But I did get a call
from a local news station.
They want to interview me live
on-air later.
And I'm actually considering it,
on my wedding day.
You're really worried
about this.
If we lose the millions
the governor plans to cut,
Chastain will become
a third-rate hospital,
and I can't stand that.
I wish I could help.
Gregg and I owe so much
to Chastain.
If it wasn't for you and Bell
and all the doctors there,
we wouldn't have Sammie.
I wouldn't have a family.
Oh!
What do you think?
- Wow.
- I love them.
They're perfect.
- Sammie insisted we try on every dress in Atlanta.
- Mm-hmm.
You know, your daughter
is very persuasive.
Yeah. Who could say no
to that face?
You're right.
Who could say no to that face?
When did this start?
A few minutes ago.
I'm ordering blood and plasma.
I'll reexamine
her belly. Hang on.
Let just see what's going on.
Mm...
So what's the plan?
Well, for now,
we try and keep her stable
while we hope UNOS
moves her up the donor list.
But that's a long shot,
isn't it?
Tell me the truth.
There's a chance
a liver may not come in time.
No.
But I am here.
I don't care about the risks.
Let me donate.
- Your heart can't tolerate...
- What my heart
can't tolerate
is losing my daughter.
I'll write a check.
How much?
- Just tell me.
- Tracy...
You don't get to tell me
that I...
can't risk my life for her.
I am her mother.
She's in A fib.
I'll page Dr. Austin.
What did you tell her?
I told I'm gonna help her.
Don't make a liar out of me.
All right.
Her A fib has slowed,
but the rapid rate has landed
her in pulmonary edema.
Tracy's in even worse shape
than we thought.
How much time you think we have
before Max's liver fails?
Based on what I've seen so far,
she has days, at best.
Look, I wasn't enthusiastic
about racing Tracy
through a TAVR even when she was
in better shape.
But now you want me
to take her to the cath lab
while she's in heart failure?
Dr. Austin, the sooner
you repair the valve,
the sooner she can recover
and be ready for a transplant.
Organ donation
from living donors
is supposed to be low-risk.
That's how we justify it.
I can't risk the mom's life.
- Randolph, you hear me.
- I do.
As surgeons, we don't risk
a living person's life
to give their organs
to someone else.
Not to mention the guilt
the child will feel
if the mother died saving her.
I'm not gonna make
that child an orphan.
Max doesn't get a liver, she
doesn't have a future at all.
It's your call, AJ.
If you can get Tracy
cleared for surgery,
I'll operate with you.
But whatever you decide,
you have my full support.
I just reached
the damaged valve.
And now I will deploy
the bioprosthetic.
And once it opens,
you should be able
to breathe easier.
Oh...
And after this?
After this, you rest.
The new valve
should make your heart relax
and the fluid in your lungs
go down.
And then I can donate
if Max doesn't get better?
We're all hoping
that Dr. Hawkins can figure out
what's going on with your
daughter so you won't have to.
But, yes,
if she doesn't improve
by tomorrow,
we will proceed
with the transplant.
Thank you.
For giving my daughter a chance.
Here you are.
Wheelchair to the cafeteria.
Hey.
I need fresh eyes.
You got a minute?
As long as it doesn't involve
more ear wax removal.
I wish it did.
I got a sick girl.
Ten years old.
Previously healthy with rapidly
progressive liver failure.
Worsening coagulopathy.
- What have you ruled out?
- Ischemia,
toxic ingestions,
viral causes, autoimmune.
Did you send CMV?
Three times.
An anti-smooth muscle antibody?
Negative.
Family history?
Not that we know of.
Uh, any ingestions?
She's a kid,
maybe she was outside.
No poison mushroom in the woods.
So you really have ruled
everything out, haven't you?
I think we both know
what this is.
It's idiopathic.
We can't find
the cause of Max's liver failure
and we'll likely never know.
Words I never thought I'd live
to hear you say, Hawkins.
Well, in over 20%
of hepatic failure cases,
we never find the reason.
Well, if we don't
know the cause,
that means it could
recur after transplant.
Yeah. But it's highly unlikely
based on everything I ruled out.
And we all know she'll die
without a new liver.
Of that, we can be sure.
So we turn our attention
to Tracy and hope that
she can recover in time
for us to attempt...
- ...we'll have less than we ever had.
- Transplant.
It's important people understand
Governor Betz's budget cuts
will have an impact
beyond Chastain,
when the population we serve
overcrowds the rest
of Atlanta hospitals.
A burden...
Aren't you marrying
that woman today, Bell?
I certainly hope so.
Dr. Voss, I understand
there's a former patient
with you who would like
to say a word to the governor.
That's right.
You ready?
Hi. I'm Sammie.
And when I was seven,
I got really sick.
Everyone gave up on me.
But the doctors at Chastain
never did.
They saved my life.
Without them, I wouldn't have
a bicycle.
Or get to cook
macaronis with my dads.
And eat way too much ice cream.
It's Max.
And play with puppies.
- She's in multisystem organ failure.
- And going into DIC.
We don't act now, she may not
make it through transplant.
- Tracy is still tenuous in the PACU.
- We all know
she'd do anything
to save her daughter.
Hawkins, can you
buy us more time?
I can't change the diagnosis.
It is now or never.
Let's get OR 1 and 2 prepped.
Meet you gentlemen there.
Bell, if you join me in this OR,
you might not make your wedding.
No one would question
you passing this case off
to another surgeon.
Saw you and Sammie on TV.
You were both great.
Well, we'll see if it works.
That's not why you're calling.
You're headed into surgery,
aren't you?
I just sent someone
to pick up my suit
so I can leave from here.
I should still
make it there on time.
But it'll be close.
Is that okay?
What matters most is you help
that mother and her daughter.
Besides, a surgeon saving lives
on his wedding day...
Sounds like the kind of man
I'd want to marry.
Good luck.
- Hi there.
- Hi.
Seems our online
ordering system is down.
Do you think you could please
fill this for a patient of mine?
Of course, Dr. Sullivan.
We are a little backed up.
Give me 30.
It-It's urgent.
They're all urgent today.
Right.
You know what?
I don't have time to wait.
Thanks though.
My patient said he had
a weird tingle in his toe
- for ten years.
- Pin.
Honestly,
I think he was just lonely
and he needed company.
And you need a drink.
Good thing
we're going to an open bar.
Mm-hmm.
Dr. Devi,
I know you already signed out,
but I have
a pediatric liver transplant
and you have a chance
to scrub in with me.
That sounds amazing.
But you know I'm not applying
for a peds surgery fellowship,
- right?
- You're chief surgical resident.
Let's see if you're as good
as everyone says you are.
OR. Now.
You want me to wait for you?
I'll just meet you there.
Pin.
Thanks.
I'll be there to help keep your
heart stable during the surgery.
While I procure a lobe of liver
from you for Max.
Thanks.
I overheard a nurse said
you're getting married tonight.
Right after this.
That's right.
I can't thank you enough.
Well, you don't have to.
I'm right where I belong.
Okay, I'm ready
to make the incision.
How's her heart looking?
Ejection fraction
is holding steady.
We can proceed.
This is our window.
Scalpel.
I've never seen a liver
this inflamed before, Dr. Sullivan.
Does this suggest anything
about the cause?
Clamp to me.
- I'll do the portal vein and the IVC.
- Vascular clamp.
And I've got the hepatic artery.
Can we get some music in here?
Cooley clamp.
Sure, Dr. Sullivan.
Any requests?
I don't care.
Just something with a beat.
And turn it up.
"In Too Deep"
by Battle Tapes playing...
music continuing in distance...
Tracy's new valve
is seated beautifully,
if I do say so myself.
Not as beautiful
as this healthy liver.
Exposing and mobilizing
the right hepatic artery now.
Identifying the portal vein.
Vessel loops to me.
♪ I know you know it... ♪
Vascular clamp.
Cooley clamp.
- Miltex clamp.
♪ Some call it flawless... ♪
All right.
Can someone call OR 2
and ask those gentlemen
what's taking so long?
♪ Even in your wildest fantasy ♪
♪ Drunk behind the wheel
from the ecstasy ♪
♪ No one in their right mind
could ignore ♪
That's an excellent graft.
Thank you very much.
♪ Blame it on the ghost
only you can see... ♪
Vitals are weak.
Well, then we're
gonna have to work faster.
But if we slip the bile
and the... vascular connections,
this'll be all for naught.
- Damn it.
- What's wrong?
This lobe is too large.
Your colleagues are used
to doing transplants for adults.
What if we just try
a retroperitoneal dissection
to make more space?
Uh... yes, of course, Dr. Devi.
Well, we can do that.
But we shouldn't have to.
The sooner we begin,
the sooner we can close.
Hey. Why don't you get out
of here, Randolph?
I can close. I'll see you
when you're a married man.
Thanks, AJ.
Appreciate it.
She's hypotensive.
MAP's in the 50s and dropping.
But we tied off all the vessels.
She must have a bleed
someplace else.
I need you back in here
with me, Bell.
I'm nearly maxed on norepi.
All right,
give me an ultrasound.
I don't see a source.
There's oozing
but no frank bleed.
That's because
there's no blood in her abdomen.
It's around her heart.
She's in tamponade.
And she's coding.
- I'll crack her chest.
- No, I don't think
there's time. I can get there
from here. Scissors.
I'm cutting
through the diaphragm.
Oh, the pericardial sac is full.
Drained the fluid.
Starting open heart massage.
An open heart
massage via the abdomen.
Damn, Bell. That's nice work.
Yeah, it's an old trick.
We still need to find
the source.
- I can't keep my arm here forever.
- All right.
Now we crack the chest.
He's still in the OR, isn't he?
I just called.
Tracy had a complication.
They're still at it.
There's no way to know how long
it'll be until Bell gets here.
Or if he makes it all.
Just a few more stitches and...
...done.
How we looking?
Pressure has stabilized,
gentlemen. Yeah.
So, how's Max doing?
Early signs are good.
- And Tracy?
- Ah, she made it.
I mean, thanks to the masterful
work of the groom-to-be here.
And if his work is done,
we need to get this man
to the chapel.
- Yeah, I'm beyond late.
- All right, let's go.
I'm gonna stay.
Look out for Tracy and be here
for Max when she wakes up.
I can sign a bit.
I can reassure her till her mom
comes out of sedation.
We can get an interpreter.
You should come.
I know how much you were looking
forward to tonight.
We can't get one this late.
I've connected with this girl.
I have to stay.
All right,
then I'll stay with you.
No, I'm sorry, this is my ICU
and I'm kicking you out.
Oh, so that's
how it is now, huh?
You've known Kit and Bell
a lot longer than I have.
You should be there.
Save me some cake?
Oh, God, you look amazing.
I'm too late.
I am so sorry, Kit.
Don't be.
Pachelbel's "Canon in D"
playing...
Everyone's still here.
I told them
you were worth the wait.
Oh, Kit.
Please be seated.
Welcome.
We're here to celebrate the love
between Randolph Bell
and Kit Voss.
They started out as colleagues,
became friends
and had the courage
to open their hearts,
take the leap
and risk it all for love.
Thank God they did.
And now the bride and groom
have prepared their vows
that they would like to share.
Go ahead, Kit.
Randolph,
you know how I like to be right.
Mm-hmm.
When I first met you, I thought
you were a bit
of an arrogant sod.
I never expected
you'd make me feel so happy,
so loved.
And I never, ever thought
you'd be my forever.
But, Randolph, you are.
And I've never been so glad
to have been so wrong.
Kit.
Thank you for
waiting for me to...
...become the man I am now.
I've made some mistakes.
Most here could name a few.
And then I met someone who...
believed I could be better.
A better... surgeon.
A better stepfather.
Just a better person.
And all I could do
was just try and become
the man that somehow...
...you knew I could be.
Kit, everything
that's good in me
is because of you.
Okay.
And now...
by the power vested in...
Okay.
"Can't Help Falling in Love"
playing...
♪ Wise men say ♪
♪ Only fools rush in ♪
♪ But I can't help... ♪
What a day.
I can't believe
everything worked out.
Well, I think both mother
and daughter are gonna be okay,
and Tracy may want
to make sure Chastain is, too.
And I heard back
from Governor Betz's office.
He's calling a meeting
so I can make my case.
You're incredible.
I'm so proud of you, Mrs. Bell.
And I of you,
Mr. Voss.
♪ Can't help ♪
♪ Falling in love ♪
♪ With you ♪
♪ Like a river flows ♪
♪ Surely to the sea ♪
♪ Darling, so it goes ♪
♪ Some things ♪
♪ Are meant to be ♪
♪ Take my hand ♪
♪ Take my whole life, too ♪
♪ For I can't help ♪
Thank you.
♪ In love ♪
♪ With you ♪
♪ Only fools rush in ♪
♪ But I ♪
♪ Can't help ♪
♪ Falling in love ♪
Want to dance?
Yeah.
♪ Shall I stay? ♪
- Oh!
- Oh.
You didn't see that coming, did you?
♪ Be a sin ♪
I'm happy for them.
- Yeah, me, too.
- Mm.
Thank you for taking Gigi.
Of course.
No.
I don't say it enough.
- I'm very grateful.
- Mm.
I know it's a lot,
and you're always there,
for both of us.
♪ Like a river flows ♪
♪ Surely to the sea ♪
It's nothing.
♪ Darling, so it goes ♪
I love you guys.
♪ Some things ♪
♪ Are meant to be ♪
♪ Take my hand ♪
♪ Take my whole life, too ♪
What a night. Huh?
♪ Can't help ♪
♪ Falling in love ♪
Yeah.
What a night.
♪ No, I ♪
♪ Can't help ♪
♪ Falling in love ♪
♪ With you. ♪
Captioned by Media Access
Group at WGBH access.wgbh.org
Synchronized by srjanapala