Now Mr. Linzer hates the food,
so he will tell
you he feels fine.
He does not feel fine.
And if you release him
before his I.N.R. stabilizes,
he will bleed to death.
Murphy's gonna
keep an eye on him.
I am gonna keep an eye on him.
Mrs. Gellman's still intubated,
but I want the tube
out by Monday.
Have the nurses page you as
soon as she starts breathing on her...
I will ask them myself.
Oh, it's not too much for you?
Not at all. And
yet, you're trying to
fob it off to Petunia here,
with her years and years
of experience in critical care.
I want you to relax
on your honeymoon.
I thought that
you'd be reassured
by having two sets of
eyes on your patients.
The notion of an intern handling
my patients is the best way
I can think of to ruin a
perfectly good Mai Tai.
Oh, are you going
someplace warm?
We don't have to talk about it.
Oh, no. I want to talk
to you about my honeymoon...
The hotel, the sights...
I'm gonna handle
Mrs. Gellman myself.
What I'm wearing on the plane,
what I'm wearing on the beach.
Leah, leave. And the wedding...
Should I get my nails done
today or tomorrow on my way
to the ceremony?
Okay, she's gone.
I got this.
The adrenal system
reacts to stress
by releasing hormones that
make us alert and reactive.
The problem is, the
adrenal system can't tell
what's a regular case of nerves
and what's a real
impending disaster.
Yo, Lefkowitz.
Did you bring it?
That's the whole thing? Yep.
Lefkowitz has gastroparesis
so he can't digest his food.
He was an epic
puker for a long time,
and now he can't
really eat at all.
So we're gonna give you
a gastric neurostimulator.
This thing, it's gonna
zap your stomach
so it remembers to push
the food down your system.
Get you back on
burgers and fries.
That's amazing.
Yeah, well, the guys
at the airport X-ray
are gonna go nuts.
That's sick.
Oh, uh, this is Dr. Wilson.
She's gonna be operating with me.
You've got a crack
team, iron man.
Hey.
Don't.
All right, all right. All
right. I'll stop. I'll stop.
Jeez.
When you and Arizona
get to the wedding
tomorrow... Mm-hmm.
Don't sit down.
What do you mean,
don't sit down?
Just find a place
and stand there.
You want us to
stand in the back?
Then we won't be
able to hear anything.
Stand in the damn front.
And block everybody's view?
I mean, if we're... I don't...
Just pick a spot. You know,
it's not complicated. Ugh!
You know, people allow you
to open them up with a knife.
If they knew you couldn't
follow a simple instruction,
they would run like
the wind from this place.
Are you... Are
you trying to say,
"Would you do me the honor
of being my bridesmaids?"
Does the whole thing
have to be about you?
Just put on a dress
and don't sit down.
Aww. We're bridesmaids.
Oh, don't even...
See? Ugh.
This is what I
was trying to avoid.
Ohh.
Now once I remove the
sural nerve from your leg,
Dr. Torres will graft it on to
Dr. Shepherd's median nerve.
You'll likely experience some
discomfort in your leg for a few weeks...
Months. Months. And
when he says "discomfort,"
it's gonna hurt like hell.
Well, you're a bag of
sunshine, aren't you?
I don't want to hear
six months from now
that you can't move and that
the ibuprofen hurts your stomach.
He makes me sound
like I'm a 90-year-old man.
Have you noticed that?
Because I've heard for decades
how I ruined your
life... Because you did.
And that Mom doesn't love
you. Because she doesn't.
I don't want to hear about
this. I think what you're trying
to say is "Thank you, Lizzie,
"for cutting off a leg
and giving it to me."
Ah. Here it is. This is how
it's gonna go down in history.
It is a nerve. It is
not the entire leg.
Okay. Let's focus. Jackson.
Um, I think
Dr. Shepherd's right.
If you're unsure,
we... Oh, come on.
I'm just winding him
up because it is so easy.
Just give me the form. Okay.
Now can I go hang out
with Zola in day care?
Oh, I'm sorry. They don't
let the adults come and go
because it's harder on the kids.
I will bring her to you later.
Grey.
Uh, when you get to
the wedding tomorrow,
don't sit down.
Call for a portable echo.
The lawyer put
together the papers.
They're gonna send
them over tomorrow.
Oh, I signed a bunch of
stuff with them last week.
Uh, not the plane
crash. The divorce.
Oh.
That was fast.
I said we wanted
to move quickly.
Apparently. It's all done.
You just have to sign.
Is that a problem? Nope.
Tomorrow, with a pen.
Okay.
Everything off
from the waist down.
Nice paper tablecloth
for you. I'll be right back.
You know, um... I
was thinking about
telling Lizzie if
you're okay with that.
Um, I think it's
still kind of early.
Yeah, but she's
doing this thing for me.
She'll tell your
whole entire family.
Well, you told Cristina.
I haven't.
Still? There's no point.
I'm probably gonna
miscarry anyway.
Meredith... I am
just stating the facts.
I have a very unstable uterus.
This baby has an uphill climb.
I am just being realistic.
Ready to take a look? Yeah.
Okay, scoot down.
Now there's still
a lot we can do
to support the pregnancy,
right, even with our history?
Of course. You've
got some risk factors.
But we're gonna
watch you like a hawk.
Okay.
There we go. Hi, baby.
Good news. Arizona and
I both have red dresses.
Now they're not the
same, but they are similar.
So it's not like matchy-matchy,
but it'll be super cute.
Now which part of my
face says I want super cute?
Ohh. Get over it
already. It's a wedding.
No one cares that it's
your second other than you.
Just hold your nose. It'll
be over in a few hours.
Sure. And then we'll be
married. And, oh, him in L.A.,
me here with my son
and a job that's known to
take up a great deal of time.
Oh, and he's an intern,
because one specialty
wasn't enough for him.
Let's get to that part.
You know, everyone's acting
like I'm some jittery bride.
Maybe I have
something to jitter about.
Well...
If it's the marriage you're
really worried about...
You can run.
Excuse me? Leave
him at the altar.
It's a clean break.
He's so pissed that you
stood him up in
front of all his people,
the whole thing is just over.
And then you're not wrestling
with a relationship
that's doomed
or tied to someone
for the rest of your life.
I mean, sure, you
love each other now.
But the next thing you know,
you are cleaning
his pee off the ground
and going to bed
with a foot-wide
demilitarized zone down
the middle of the bed.
Kidding.
I'm just kidding. I'm kidding.
No, it'll be fine.
It'll be fine.
Yeah, Ben's the...
The best. He's... He...
We have to do an open
procedure 'cause he's got adhesions
from a surgery a
couple years ago.
Once he's open, you can
take down the adhesions.
Really?
Yeah. I've never done
anything like that before.
Yeah, well, if it was me,
I'd spend the next few
hours in the skills lab.
Dr. Karev. Is this
because I told you about
when I was a kid?
Oh, yeah. I feel so bad you
were a dumpster-diving orphan,
I'm letting you hack
up a 10-year-old.
Sorry. Stupid.
Ya think?
Flowers, music... It's
a recipe for disaster.
April, you're going to be
fine. Don't worry about it.
Oh, come on. Don't tell
her she's gonna be fine.
You're gonna be
looking all pretty,
little bit of lip gloss on
your prude-y little mouth.
Jackson will spot
her across the room.
Try to look away, but he can't.
You're irresistible
in your dress.
One drink, and you're
doing the hippity-dippity
in the coat room.
The dress? Oh, God.
See? Cruel.
What?
Nothing.
So he's into you now?
Karev? No.
Uh-huh. Then why's he letting
you take down adhesions?
Have you ever removed adhesions?
No. None of us have.
Hey, Wilson.
Uh, where are Sujin
Kim's post-op notes?
I didn't finish it. I
wanted to practice for this
gastric neurostimulator
surgery I'm doing with Dr. Karev.
She's taking down the adhesions.
Really? Oh. Good for you.
He must really trust you.
Mmm.
Hmm. Um... I hope
you're not using
blunt dissection,
'cause that'll tear it.
You want nice, precise
moves with the instruments.
Okay. You sure
you're ready for this?
Yeah. You want me
to get you that chart?
No. It can wait.
You should practice.
See? She shouldn't even
be doing a move like this.
He's into her.
The last thing you want at your
wedding is to wonder if Mr. Linzer
is circling the drain
just because nobody
was monitoring his I.N.R.
So I'll just stick
around here tomorrow
and keep an eye on him.
Kepner, you broke up with Avery.
I... Yes.
Yes. I don't know
what that has to...
You're afraid that the sight
of me in cream colored raw silk
will bring tears to your eyes.
I am sure that you
will be beautiful...
I look at my father, he
kisses me on the cheek,
I turn away from him,
- take a breath.
- Dr. Webber.
I step towards
Ben... Is that for me?
- Here you go.
- Thank you.
And you and Jackson lock
eyes from across the room.
You melt into him
like snow in the rain.
I knew you would understand.
Suck it up, Kepner. If I
have to go, you have to go.
Okay.
"If I have to go,
you have to go"?
Oh, drop it. Oh, no.
That's the most beautiful
sentiment I've ever heard.
Lizzie's calves
are a little shorter
than we anticipated.
Tall girl, short calves.
So is that gonna be a problem?
No, not if we just get a little
more nerve from the other leg.
Are you saying to... - No.
Derek. Absolutely not.
No, I never liked this
idea in the first place.
We find another
donor or we don't do it.
Well, we couldn't
find another donor.
That's why we... Well,
then we're out of luck.
Can't we just... No,
we can't. We're not
gonna talk about this. We're
not gonna float this past Lizzie.
We're not cutting both
her legs to remove pieces.
Cancel the procedure.
I think you should bring a
date to Dr. Bailey's wedding.
That way we will
focus on our dates
and not on each other.
Or we could just be
focused on the happy couple.
Thank you.
I am wearing a strapless dress.
From here up, I'm
completely naked.
Just... Wear a different dress.
I don't have a different
dress. I work long hours.
I don't shop. I have
one dressy dress.
How am I supposed to find
a date with one day's notice?
Stephanie.
Hey. Um, would you like to
go to Dr. Bailey's wedding?
Oh, what?
Dr. Avery would love
for you to go with him.
That's not true.
He thinks that you'd
be embarrassed,
but you're not
embarrassed, are you?
Of course she's
embarrassed. She'll get over it.
Look, don't get
other... Strapless...
And tight.
I will pick you up
at 1:00 tomorrow
in the locker room.
What just happened?
What about you?
You got to pick mine, so
I get to pick yours, right?
Jackson.
Oh. What about Shane?
He's a good-looking
piece of man, huh?
- They're that short?
- No, they're
perfectly respectable calves.
It's just that we're not
gonna get quite enough nerve
from just the one. Okay.
I know it's a lot to ask.
No, it's, uh, fine. Do
what you need to do.
Derek thinks it's
too much to ask,
but he really needs this, so
if he comes to you and tries
to talk you out of
it, you have to push.
But don't tell him that I'm
the one that came to you,
because he won't like that.
You've got some
balls, don't you?
You know, if it's too much,
we can call the whole thing off.
You know we're family, right?
There was no wedding, Meredith.
You adopted a baby
and you never invited us
to come meet her.
You never accepted
our invitation to come see us.
All we got was a couple
of pictures via e-mail.
You know, my kids were
so excited that for months,
they walked around telling every
African-American person they saw
that we have a brown
baby in the family?
A year later, they kind of think
I made the whole
thing up. I'm sorry.
It's just, you know,
with everything
that's been going on...
No, I get that we're all busy,
but you're not shy about asking
me for a couple of body parts,
and now you want me to
cover your tracks with Derek?
If you feel like it's
inappropriate, we...
No, it's what sisters
ask sisters to do.
We cover each other's
asses. Look, if you want to be
a sister, I am delighted,
but then act like one.
My version of family
isn't like your version.
You guys give each other
crap and then you laugh about it.
You'd walk through
fire for each other.
Greys are not like that.
Derek said you had a
sister who worked here.
Half. She was on the plane?
You know, I really don't
want to talk about my sister.
My husband really needs this,
so you don't have
to like me, just him.
You have a child.
She's part of my family.
You of all people
should realize,
you need spares in
a family. You need
as many as you can get.
It was very nice to
talk to you, Lizzie.
Hey.
I stashed a little Johnnie
in case the ceremony's got
some cousin reading a poem.
Right. Uh, I meant to find you.
I'm kind of bringing a date.
Yeah, me. Two guys picking up
bridesmaids from out of town.
April's convinced that if
we don't both bring dates,
then we're both gonna end up...
Why you gotta talk to her?
She ruins everything.
How about I find
someone for you to go with?
You know, maybe
Stephanie has a friend.
Stephanie? That's
who you're taking?
You want a date or not?
No. All right.
Okay. Whatever. Just
don't get me an ugly one.
We're not doing the procedure.
Of course we're doing it.
You know what happened
when I said I'd do this?
Mom called me
three times in one day.
It just brings tears to my eyes.
She's a mess. Come on.
You're the golden child.
The rest of us are just
scrapping for second position,
and I just put a lock on it for
life. You think I'm giving that up
just 'cause you have to cut
into two legs instead of one?
Lizzie... No, we're
not discussing it.
I've decided. Get back
on the horse, Derek.
Oh, okay. So you think
I'm using this as an excuse,
that I'm too scared to
try and operate again?
No, of course not.
Nothing scares you.
Mmm.
What if it doesn't work?
Hmm? What if we
go through all of this
and nothing comes
of it? Well, then
at least we tried.
We're doing it.
Just... Say thank you.
You ready? Yep.
Bovie, please.
Thank you.
Okay, here? Yep.
Take your time. Okay.
Watch out for the blood vessels.
Wow. Look at you, all grown-up.
Up in the skills
lab, I was doing...
You put a hole in his stomach.
I haven't even...
Move, now. Move.
- All right. Clamp.
- Here you go.
2.0 Vicryl. WOMAN: I'll get it.
Suction.
Hey, Steph. You okay there?
Fine. Terrific.
I wanted to ask you...
I was gonna go to
the wedding with,
you know, a friend...
A guy, like, stag.
Yeah? And now he feels like
I'm bailing on him.
You don't have to go with me.
No, no. You don't want to go?
You have a date with a guy.
I ditched him, and I want
you to find somebody for him.
Is that weird?
Nothing about this is weird.
Terrific. Mm-hmm.
Mmm.
There's still some spillage.
Give me some lap pads...
And some 2.0 silk.
Get over here and
grab the retractor
so we can put
the device back in.
Wilson. I can't get
my hands to stay still.
Well, shake it off
and get over here.
The kid's gonna be fine,
just grab the damn retractor.
Get out.
Go!
You think Bailey will
notice if I'm not there?
She just made you a bridesmaid.
Oh, she doesn't
care about all of that.
She just wants a bunch
of people standing up there
so it won't look weird
when Ben has all his
guys standing up there.
And I have a
packed day tomorrow.
Yeah, 'cause you're
going to a wedding.
You're supposed to wear heels...
To a fancy occasion.
Oh, come on.
No, they make you
feel tall and confident
and feminine and...
And my plastic foot isn't
the right shape for... Heels.
I didn't get that
kind. Well, I mean...
It's not nothing.
I mean, why do you think women
all over the world wear them?
Because women all
over the world are stupid.
Oh, okay. So you're
gonna wear flats?
Oh, I'd be happy to wear flats.
Oh, no, you wouldn't because
then you would feel dumpy.
Oh-ho. Did you
just call me dumpy?
Can you just for one second
admit that you know what it is
I'm talking about?
Okay, I know it's hard.
It's hard all the time, and
this is just one more reminder.
But you are so, so beautiful.
Yeah, people stand next
to you and immediately
feel bad about themselves.
It's a public service
that you're a couple
of inches shorter.
It is a kindness to
every other woman
at that wedding
that you are just
one tiny bit less beautiful.
Mm-hmm. Yeah.
Are you still mad at me
because I called Lizzie?
Do you still love me?
Medium.
I just want your
hand to be better
so that we can put this stupid
plane crash stuff behind us.
Well, the lawyer called
to schedule a deposition.
He thinks we have a strong case,
especially now that Cristina
and Owen are getting divorced.
What does that have
to do with anything?
Well, it'd be a big
conflict of interest
if Owen was married
to one of the plaintiffs.
That's why they got divorced,
right? She didn't tell you?
No. Why would
she not tell me that?
You didn't tell her
you were pregnant.
Maybe things are different now.
On the morning of your wedding?
Oh, my house is
filled with my family
talking about makeup and hair.
- Just check into a hotel.
- Dr. Bailey.
Take a nice long
bath, get a manicure.
Oh, now I got you talking
about makeup and hair?
Dr. Bailey, what
are you doing here?
Checking up on my patients.
Making sure you
haven't bungled anything.
Don't mention her hair.
Why? Did something
happen to your hair?
Oh.
He probably knew it was risky,
so he wanted it on me and not him.
You have to stop. You're
making yourself crazy.
I'm gonna get
fired. No, you're not.
Just keep your head
down and do your work.
You're right.
Now I have to ask you something,
and in light of the fact that
you think your job is on the line,
it's gonna sound really stupid.
Whatever. It's okay.
Dr. Avery asked me
to Dr. Bailey's wedding.
And I can't put two words
together into a sentence
when I'm within two feet of
him, and he's bringing a friend,
and he asked me
to bring a friend,
and it'll be like a bunch of
us, and we'll all go together.
You're right. It
sounds really stupid.
But will you do it?
Please, Jo.
Somebody page cardio? Yeah,
G.S.W. to the chest.
He put up two-and-a-half
liters of blood
when we put in the chest tube.
We should move him upstairs.
There is a bullet
in the abdomen.
I can do it, or we can
call for somebody else.
You can do it. Amicable, right?
Mm-hmm. Let's move.
You're still rechecking
Kepner's work?
What I was born to do.
I have a chole in
about ten minutes.
In and out, the whole
thing should take an hour.
You want to scrub in?
Take the edge off before
you go home and get dressed?
You... Are a good man.
Dr. Webber. Oh,
the man of the hour.
Oh, tell me you're not here
to take me back to that house.
No, I'm not.
Okay, well, he, um, just asked
me to do a chole with him...
And it's the only thing
that's calmed me down
on a day full of people trying
and failing to calm me down.
Why do you think he asked you?
You called him?
Oh.
Thank you.
Both of you.
So can I have a car
pick you up at the house?
How many times do I
have to say no to that?
A person shouldn't drive
themselves to their own wedding.
Well, I like to drive.
In a wedding gown?
It's my last ten minutes
as a single woman.
You know, you both
were on a roll there.
Why are you trying
to screw it up now?
I'll see you in the O.R.
And I will see you at the altar.
Dr. Robbins.
Yeah. Hi.
Dr. Karev had me take down
the adhesions. Yeah.
Yeah, how'd that go?
Some of the adhesions
were stuck to the stomach.
The stomach was injured.
He could be septic by now.
I don't think he
had any business
having an intern
do that kind of move.
You were pretty shocked
to hear that I was doing it.
He threw me in the deep
end, probably because...
Okay, hang on.
What exactly are you
saying about your attending?
G.S.W.
Sweet. Scrubbing in with Owen,
who wants to sign our
divorce papers today.
I guess we're being
mature and moving on.
Speaking of which,
why didn't you tell me
that the divorce was because
of the plane crash lawsuit?
What? Derek told me,
so that the case is stronger.
Which is great, I'm glad,
especially if it means the two
of you are getting back together.
It's good news, and I don't
know why you wouldn't want
to share that with me?
Because I didn't know.
You ready?
What?
Dr. Shepherd's prepped? Yep.
Uh, Dr. Torres is
going over the studies.
Okay. Yeah.
Hold it together.
Well, a nerve extraction's
a pretty simple procedure.
Not that. He asked me on a date,
to Dr. Bailey's wedding.
Dr. Kepner asked me.
It's a date? It's not,
like, a mentoring thing?
How is drinking champagne
and dancing to Barry White
a mentoring thing?
I thought it was,
like, spending time
getting to know the interns in a
casual, stress-free environment.
That was the free-doughnuts
thing in the lounge.
This is a wedding.
I can't go on a
date with my boss.
I need to focus on my work,
not get all wrapped
up in the ladies.
Did you really just
say "the ladies"?
You're the one who just said you
couldn't concentrate in the O.R.
'cause Dr. Avery might look at
you with his limpid green eyes.
The eyes are really intense.
You've noticed
it yourself, right?
Get a grip. You get a grip.
Karev, did you tell Wilson
that she'd be fired for
screwing up a gastric implant?
What? Is the patient
gonna make it?
The patient's fine. What
the hell did she tell you?
She thinks that you
set her up to take the fall
on a risky O.R. procedure,
and it kind of sounds like you did.
It would've been risky
no matter who did it.
And I was standing right there.
The second it got
hairy, I took over.
She was in over her head.
And where do you think I got
the idea to do something like that?
What are you talking about? You.
I'm trying to be like
you were with me.
You let me try crap so I
got confidence in myself.
That's what I
was trying to do...
Not treat the stupid morons
like the stupid morons
that I think they are.
I gave you opportunities.
I also gave you a boatload of
encouragement and support.
I didn't drop-kick you into
the deep end of the pool...
And yell, "Swim, idiot."
You're a teacher now.
Your students
fail, you've failed.
Oh!
Glad you're driving
yourself to the wedding.
Remind me to stay off the roads.
Were you like this?
On my wedding day, I
remember staring at my socks
for a long time. I had no
idea what to do with 'em.
You know, ten years from
now, if the marriage is strong,
I'll look back at
today and say...
"It was just a little
bit of cold feet."
If we're in a nasty
divorce, I'll say,
"I knew it was a mistake
the day we got married."
You think it's a mistake?
I just feel...
Worried. I never felt
that way with Tucker.
You were a child when
you married Tucker.
You're an adult now.
You know the world's
an ambiguous place.
You know that love
doesn't conquer all.
It conquers some stuff.
The other stuff kicks
the living crap out of love.
And this is the pep talk?
Overwhelming doubt is a problem.
A little bit of doubt is just a
sign of an intelligent adult.
Is Grey gonna be in the gallery?
No. She didn't want
to make you nervous.
I told her you
don't get nervous.
You're right. I don't.
Close your eyes. Enjoy your nap.
You've got nothing
to worry about. Mmm.
Torres. Hmm?
You've got nothing
to worry about.
We good to go?
Yes, we are.
Yes. We're... Yes.
Jackson, I just
want to let you know,
I'll be here watching
the whole time.
Couldn't be happier.
No mistakes. That's the plan.
Okay.
Are you kidding me?
Get that woman
out of my gallery.
That's not a good
idea. Get her out.
I heard that, Avery. Edwards,
don't even think about it.
Now.
Edwards, you wouldn't dare.
You have years with me. I
can be very difficult to deal with.
15-blade, please.
You narced on me to my boss?
I worked hard to get here.
I'm not gonna let myself
get fired because...
Nobody's firing you.
I was trying to help you.
I clearly wasn't ready for it.
Why, because I had to take over?
Look, you can't go
crying to my damn boss
every time you get scared.
You can't cry at all
when you get scared
because it's scary
in there all the time.
I just thought, maybe
after I blew the appy,
I'd be a good target if you
needed to pin something
on someone. It's
paranoid. I get that.
I don't always trust people
who are trying to help me.
Yeah, yeah, you're a beaten dog
and you bite people
who try to feed you.
I don't give a crap
about your sad story.
You want to be a surgeon,
you need to get the hell over it.
You burned a bridge with
me. How about you grow up
before you burn a bridge
with every other attending
who tries to teach
you something?
50 centimeters of prime nerve.
Great.
All right.
Forceps, please. Thank you.
Okay.
Is no one making small talk
because this is Derek
Shepherd on the table?
This is intricate work. Small
talk is what keeps us awake.
Well, uh...
A couple of days ago,
I helped Dr. Kepner
extract a malignant
mass from the gluteal area
of a female patient.
It was an impressively
sized mass.
Who's gonna tell Dr. Shepherd
that he'll never operate again
because Ross' idea of
gossip is, he saw April Kepner
take a lump off an ass?
Brooks, suction.
All of, not half of it.
Sorry.
He's got a bunch of tattoos.
Wonder if it's some
sort of a gang thing.
I had... The chatter
isn't helping me,
and your experience
with gangland youth
has little bearing on
how we treat this patient.
What the hell was
that? I thought this was
supposed to be amicable.
We're getting divorced
because of the lawsuit?
It will significantly
increase your chances...
You didn't want to mention
it? I want you to get the money.
I want all of you
to get the money,
and I knew there
was a very real chance
that you would reject the idea
simply because I suggested it.
Oh, right. Because I'm so
simple-minded and petulant.
You've been known
to... Where do you get off
making some kind of unilateral
decision about our marriage?
How about the fact that
you moved across the country
and didn't have the
courage to do what I did
and simply ask for a divorce?
Oh, God. So this is ballsy,
you hiding behind the lawsuit?
You couldn't just admit to me,
or God sake, yourself,
that you wanted out.
You have to let this stupid plane
crash make the decision for you.
I chose the airline!
You like it better when I
decide? I chose the airline!
We had to make a
budget cut of 4%...
And we had a line item of
emergency transportation.
We never used
it, and we had a...
Fancy charter company,
and I chose a... Cheaper one.
You want to know
why it was cheaper?
You didn't build the plane.
People are dead.
Or fly it.
I thought you were dead.
You're not responsible.
Someone has to be.
I mean, it takes a
lot of small mistakes
to destroy something,
and it's really easy
for everybody involved
just to say, "I just did
this one small thing."
A bunch of people
made it possible...
For a bad plane
to take off with you, Meredith,
and Derek, and Arizona, and...
And I am one of those people.
Oh.
I think I'm having a
dream a really hot doctor
came to take care of me.
This really hot doctor is
leaving you to go to a party.
Mmm.
Callie said it could
not have gone better.
Mmm. Do you have any pain?
No.
How's Lizzie?
Uh, she's doing well.
She was still sleeping
last time I checked.
I'll swing by on my way out.
Mwah. Hey.
It may have worked.
And we're back on the shoes.
Please don't even
say it out loud.
It makes me feel
even more stupid.
Just... Tell her that
I wasn't feeling well.
You've gotta be kidding me.
Do not belittle me, okay?
You have no idea what it's like...
Oh, trust me, trust me,
I am intimately familiar
with what's going
on, and I'm over it.
You are exactly the same
person you were before,
just minus a leg.
You think it's nothing? No.
Oh, no, no, no, no. I
think it's everything.
And you know what? It
has been... For months.
And I have been
supportive for months.
But there comes a point
where you have to suck it up
and stop whining
and start living.
Okay, so you have
one leg. It's a wedding.
It's a wedding. And
weddings are sweet
and beautiful and
no one's gonna notice
the stupid leg because
everybody's gonna
be looking at Bailey,
and maybe for one night,
our lives can be about something
other than that damn leg.
My whole life is about that leg.
I haven't had sex in five
months because of the leg.
Enough about the leg!
Everything went smoothly.
Your vitals look great.
And Derek is awake,
and he's in good shape.
Meredith, I'm pushy. I get that.
Some people find it endearing,
and some people really don't,
but, um...
You don't have to want
Derek's truckload
of sisters in your life.
Yeah. You are a pain in the ass.
And I barely know you.
Okay, so...
I'm not very good at
this. But I'm gonna try.
I'm gonna show you something,
but you have to promise not to
blab it to the whole family.
Okay.
Promise? Yeah.
You?
Really?
We're having a baby.
Yeah.
Yay!
Let her drive you, Miranda.
No, Mom.
I just need five minutes
with none of you touching me.
So did she bring
her friend or what?
Oh, come on.
He's the guy?
Mmm.
All right.
Was the lawsuit the only
reason you asked for a divorce?
There are many reasons.
You were...
Done a long time ago.
I'm asking about you.
Okay, let me put it another way.
I wanted to try again.
I was gonna ask you
if we could try again,
and you said, "I
want a divorce."
Come here.
Mmm.
Oh. Sorry.
I should throw this
thing out the window.
Hello. MAN: Sir, this
is Barrett in the E.R.
Your wife is on her way here.
Paramedics say she's vomiting blood.
What? Adele?
She's hypotensive.
Um, hey, uh, turn the
car around. We need to go
to the emergency room...
Did you check her vitals?
At Seattle Grace
Hospital right now.
Wasn't this stupid thing
supposed to start already?
I'm here, sweetheart.
Why is this happening?
We're gonna find out. How
much blood has she lost?
At least a liter,
a liter and a half.
It started about 45 minutes ago.
Oh, God! It hurts.
Hang more L.R.
No, not if she's lost
that much blood.
She needs a transfusion
and an N.G. tube.
I've got this, okay?
Sir, she's your wife.
Step back. Get me
an N.G. tube, son.
I can do this. Get
me an N.G. tube
right now. Okay, I
got it. You hear me?
Oh.
Okay. Get out of the way.
Okay. Central line kit, please.
- Yes, Doctor.
Yeah, yeah, Leah. Get
me out of this dress now.
Adele, hi.
Can you look at me?
Hey, we're gonna take
good care of you, okay?
She's having
ventricular couplets.
All right, watch for V-tach.
Prep the I.J.
Okay, you're gonna be
fine, baby. We got you.
All right. Get the
guide wire ready.
She's losing consciousness.
Bailey! Damn it. All right.
Uh, Barrett, take this.
Do a femoral line instead.
Uh, Leah, intubation tray.
Oh, God, Adele.
Oh, God.
Oh, come on, come on, come on.
Oh, straight to voice mail.
Um, it's possible
that I may have, by mistake,
said that if she had any doubts,
she should flee. What?
Why?
Well, I kind of said
that marriage is like
a dance of death and
that leaving him at the altar
would be a painful
but efficient out.
Oh, that's nice. I was joking...
And she was nervous, okay?
And she wasn't sure
if it was the wedding
or the whole thing.
The marriage?
She was nervous.
How nervous?
How nervous was she, Callie?
The body doesn't
know the difference
between nerves and
excitement, panic and doubt,
the beginning, and the end.
The body just tells
you to get the hell out.
Sometimes you ignore it.
That's the
reasonable thing to do.
But sometimes you listen.
You're supposed to
trust your gut, right?
When your body says run...
Run.