[Max] Previously on New Amsterdam...
-Why'd you tell everyone we were a couple?
-Yeah, okay--
We agreed you were going
to treat me like everyone else.
As your newly-minted
psych residency director,
you will be on this ward
with real patients
and you will have me
in supervision as your teacher.
You and your girl work things out?
We did,
but still figuring out some details.
[Ben]
You want someone to replace Dr. Sharpe.
Something tells me
Dr. Sharpe is not replaceable.
Don't let her go.
-Did you find my replacement?
-I'm going with you.
♪ Walking in the stars ♪
♪ 'Cause we put some mirrors on our feet ♪
♪ The moon is the music ♪
♪ We join in and sing ♪
♪ See the turn of Earth ♪
♪ It's movin' ♪
♪ Wonder, catch me in the sky ♪
♪ Take me somewhere I would never go ♪
♪ I promise not to tell ♪
♪ If you don't tell ♪
♪ One, once upon a hilltop ♪
♪ Two, it's one for you, it's one for me ♪
♪ Three, three times we both got lost
Looking at the sun ♪
♪ Looking at what's to come ♪
-♪ Every time I get this far ♪
-♪ This far ♪
-♪ I just want to disappear ♪
-♪ Disappear ♪
♪ I want to get lost
In the world with you ♪
♪ With you, with you
That's what I want to do ♪
Oh, God, I forgot
to ask what Brantley said
when you told her that you were leaving.
Brantley? I'm sorry. Who's Brantley?
I'm not familiar.
-[chuckles] Max.
-I'm going to tell her.
I just... try to have my replacement
all lined up,
because I don't want to give her
a full-blown heart attack.
Oh, wow.
Sparing Brantley's heart palpitations have
never been a top priority for you before.
Better late than never?
Okay.
What about Luna's grandparents?
Do they know?
I'm working on it.
We leave in six weeks.
Okay, Helen, come here. Come here.
I am going to tell them, okay?
I'm going to tell everyone.
I'm going to tell strangers.
Maybe even tomorrow, but not tonight.
Because tonight, all I want...
is dim sum...
in bed...
with you.
[Helen] You are going to get dim sum.
-[Max] Really?
-And then some...
Ooh.
-Once you tell everyone.
-Oh, I see.
-Bye.
-Have a good day.
[Iggy] Hear ye!
It is that time of year again, folks.
It's the Harvest Festival
tonight at the rooftop garden.
Please join me for free drinks.
The broccoli is coming in hot.
Oh, yeah, she just turned it down flat.
Casey, have you ever seen
such ripe, tender heads pressed up
-against one another like that?
-What?
The thing, man, tonight. You coming?
Yo, if I give you some
of the best gossip ever, can I skip it?
-No.
-Come on! Damn it!
I got to tell somebody.
It's just too good.
I just saw Max and Helen
totally making out
over by the ambulance bay.
But... yeah, they're friends.
-They're good friends.
-Yeah, that were sucking face.
They're physical communicators.
They talk with their hands.
Are you telling me that you had never
any idea what was going on between them?
Casey, although it is a blessing
and a curse,
behavioral analysis
is my superpower, okay?
If there was ever any romantic inclination
between Max and Helen,
I'd have been the first to suss is out.
-Uh...
-Okay? Now just shush.
Come tonight. Eat broccoli.
I...
[sighs]
Thanks for the lift.
Best boss ever.
Yeah, well, don't thank me just yet.
Uh, Iggy is having
his weird harvest thing tonight.
As your awful girlfriend,
I am forcing you to be my plus-one.
-Sounds great!
-Does it, though?
[Floyd] Good morning, Dr. Malvo.
Morning, Dr. Reynolds.
What's with the smile?
Oh, I guess
my 6:00 a.m. spinal fusion surgery
has got me really, really happy.
Ah, well, that would sound strange,
but suddenly I find myself very excited
about my... pelvic laparoscopy.
Mm.
Assuming you'll walk with me.
I passed my elevator about 30 seconds ago.
I'll try to keep you entertained.
Well, you set the bar
really high last night.
You more than cleared it.
I have a few hours after work
and, um, maybe if you're free, we can...
[chuckles]
You just can't get enough, can you?
What's up?
I'm late for my surgery.
Yo, what'd I say?
It's unclear if you know this,
but I am actually a very busy surgeon.
Well, I have a job offer for you.
-But I already said no.
-Not to the job I'm about to offer.
Spoiler alert,
it is the best job that we've got.
[Ben] What's better than
the chair of oncology?
Medical director of New Amsterdam.
[grunts softly]
No.
-[Ben] No.
-No?
Had I known this is why
you wanted to meet again,
I would have saved you the trouble.
Um, maybe you're, uh...
Maybe you're in shock at being offered
the very prestigious position
of medical director
at America's first public hospital.
[announcement] Dr. Lu to neonatal.
Dr. Lu to neonatal.
Nah, I feel pretty levelheaded about it.
Would you, uh... would you tell me why?
Because I killed for this job.
I mean, I love this job.
This is the greatest job
in the entire world.
Catastrophic emergency, Max!
That's your answer, in a nutshell.
Makes sense. Okay, would you do me
a professional courtesy
and just think about it and take the day
and get back to me maybe...?
-[Karen] Max!
-Maybe.
[Ben] Okay! Go.
-Yes? Thank you.
-Go. I'll think about it.
[sighs]
-What was that about?
-Uh, I'm not sure.
Oh, Max, why didn't you just tell me?
Oh. Um, I don't know. I was just looking
for the right time and, uh--
It's our ICU, Max.
If it's understaffed, I need to know
before something like this happens.
Right. You're talking about our ICU.
Makes sense. I completely agree.
We are understaffed.
We should have five attendings per shift.
We're barely getting by with two.
And now those two, Dr. Perez and Dr.
Agata, are down with food poisoning.
-And there's no backup, no one to cover.
-You're saying no one's running our ICU?
This is why I keep telling you
we need more doctors.
COVID burnout is real.
You'd think they have more sense of duty
to this hospital than to just leave.
Well, it's not just about
sense of duty to the hospital.
These people face all kinds
of stress for this hospital.
They've had to question
every priority and value they've ever had.
Not to mention,
some of 'em fell in love, you know.
Finally put love first for once
instead of denying it for so...
Well, maybe, I don't know.
Uh, we need doctors.
-That's what I'm saying.
-[woman] Triage nurse to the ER...
We have 22 patients,
two transfers on the way,
at least nine procedures
piling up on the to-do list... Oh, right.
And no doctors.
Then shut it down.
Send these patients to other hospitals.
No. They're too sick.
Some of them won't survive transport.
Can't we farm them out
to other areas of the hospital?
No, they need the specialized care
they can only get here.
If this ICU fails,
the whole hospital goes down.
-We got to make this work.
-How? Who's going to take over?
I will.
Somebody help us over here.
-What happened?
-Went fishing to celebrate his retirement.
-Bluefish, stripers, some tuna.
-They don't give a damn.
-You never know what's important.
-We go every year.
-We get all set up. Nice new hooks--
-Terry, for the love of God.
And when we got to the dock,
all of a sudden Joe just stops talking.
-Okay.
-It's alarming because Joe never shuts up.
Like, never.
It's like the man gets paid by the word.
-No offense, buddy.
-He's going to be okay, right?
Joe, do me a favor.
Can you lift your right arm?
-Is it numb? Is it tingly?
-It looks like he's having a stroke.
Let's get him a CT scan.
Do you sell what you steal?
-No.
-So why steal at all?
I don't know.
The things I take, I don't even want 'em.
It's crazy, but in my head,
it's not stealing.
But, Kevin, where's the empathy?
You are stealing.
Imagine if it were someone you loved.
What if you stole from your dad?
All right, I'm going to pause you
right there. Uh, Miguel, amazing.
Great job bringing Klepto Kevin to life,
man, killin' it.
-Oh, gosh, it's such a great role.
-[Iggy] You were born to play it, clearly.
Chitto,
I'm sorry I cut you off back there,
but there was a big-time tactical error
that we need to talk about.
But he was opening up.
No, yeah, I realize that. But try not to
focus on what he was saying,
more on how he was saying it,
his voice, his demeanor, his tears.
Does all that suggest a lack of empathy?
Crap. No.
Yeah. Also, in last week's reading,
we hit on the common parental archetypes
of kleptomaniacs and the big one was...
-Withholding parents.
-[Iggy] Exactly, withholding parents.
So when you're withholding empathy
and shaming him for his dad,
in Kevin's mind, guess who you are.
His dad. Okay?
Good luck building that trust back.
This is... this is transference 101, yeah?
Okay.
Oh. All right, guys, come on.
Let's lose the long faces.
Getting adjustments is good,
as long as take what you learn here
and you apply it
to your real-life patients.
All right? That goes for everybody.
So why don't we move past these, um...
these rookie mistakes and, uh, crush one?
Miguel, ready to drop in,
find your center? Chitto?
Take two. Go.
Kevin, I think--
Okay, I'm going to jump in right here.
-Have you considered--
-[Iggy] No, not... not quite.
No! Oh, no! Mamma mia, no.
That was definitely... a choice.
Guys, guys, come on. Listen.
Listen to one another.
No, no, no, no, no. Definitely not that.
Cut! Nope.
Change tact.
No, okay, that's it. That's it.
That's enough. Stop.
-Any notes for me?
-[Iggy] No, Miguel.
You're perfection.
[sighs]
Heart attack
during a symphony concert last night.
-And this bruise?
-Oh, I fell out of my chair
when the chest pain hit. [sighs]
-Oboist screamed.
-Oh. People say symphonies are dull.
She's had several waves
of chest pain overnight.
Should I increase her IV nitro drip?
Uh, yes, let's do that.
Okay. Will do, Dr. Goodwin.
-I may be out of practice.
-Oh, you? No.
-I bring platelets.
-[Max] Great, thank you.
Today is going to be kind of a day.
I heard. And Wilder, did she say yes?
Uh, she said no,
quite a few times, actually, but I did...
-Dr. Goodwin.
-...convince her to think about it.
We still have 19 patients left on rounds.
Platelets are for bay five.
Co... Copy.
So I hear you got into
a nasty fight with a mountain.
Must have fallen, I don't know, 60 feet.
My God, how terrifying.
My partner and I, we've been climbing
together such a long time.
Do you know, is he here?
I haven't seen him.
He may have been taken
to another hospital.
Could you find out?
His name's Garrett Turner.
-He got it way worse than me.
-Of course.
Uh, Helen, two more just rolled in
and I got an acute leukemic in bay six.
Can you take a look?
Max, why didn't you pull in some help
from another department?
Uh, which one? They're all understaffed.
If I keep us afloat long enough
for Perez and Agata to recover--
Max, that was me saying I'm in.
I'm staying.
-I would kiss you, but...
-[chuckles]
[laughs]
[Floyd] I need to talk to someone.
Oh, I know.
Me too. It's amazing, isn't it?
-What is?
-Max and Helen.
I mean, finally.
All that sexual tension
just brewing for years.
Wait, weren't they already a thing?
Are you kidding? No,
but Casey said they definitely are now,
-So...
-Great. Well, they're two adults.
Nothing's standing in their way.
It's no big deal.
How do you enjoy any movie ever?
Okay, look, the, uh, woman I'm seeing,
I said I was excited to see her
and all of a sudden she just froze me out.
-I don't even know what I said.
-I'm going to stop you right there.
I'm going to save you some time.
The thing about women is
they just want to hear two words.
"I'm sorry." That's it.
It's a silver bullet to any argument.
I actually could have saved myself
three hours of processing last night
if I'd followed my own advice.
Dr. Bloom, Casey needs you.
-[beeping]
-O2 sat's dropping.
-[Lauren] CT scan?
-Negative.
Isn't a stroke and he's crashing fast.
We're back to square one.
I need more information.
Give me some history.
Nothing happened out there on the boat?
-No, nothing.
-[patient groans]
Well, how's he been feeling?
Has he been sick recently?
He's had some back pain, but that's
all of us. We work in construction.
If you collect a paycheck, you're in pain.
-What else? Think!
-He had the flu or something last month.
-Is that what you mean?
-He even called out sick.
-Stayed home a couple days.
-Yeah, that's not like Joe.
-Post-viral myocarditis?
-Worse, given the arm numbness.
Post-viral Guillain-Barré syndrome.
His whole nervous system is shutting down.
-[Max] Carla has V-fib. Epi.
-[woman] Pulseless VT.
Let's start chest compressions.
[devices beeping]
Come on, Carla.
[Lauren] I need help over here!
Hello?
I'm losing him!
Anyone?
Clear.
-[paddles zap]
-Clear.
I got a pulse.
No pulse. Going again.
-Clear.
-[paddle zaps]
He's back.
-She's back.
-[Max] Carla, are you with me?
-I think so.
-[Max] Good.
What the hell, Max?
-[sighs] We're getting through it.
-This isn't short-staffed.
-This is not staffed.
-What do you want me to do?
-I'm not going to close our doors.
-Ask for more help.
-Who? Whose help am I supposed to ask--
-My help.
You should have asked for my help.
Well, I wanted to,
but what about your residents?
They're fine.
They've got Walsh and an iPad.
I'm staying here with you.
[woman] Sleep with the boss,
ride to work in a limo.
Girl, give me that gig.
-How late you think she got to sleep in?
-Must be nice is all I'm saying.
It's more of a town car than a limo.
Hey, it isn't personal.
Then what is it?
Just be aware of your privilege, okay?
Privilege? I'm not privileged.
Six months ago I was living in my car.
[chuckling]
Well, you've come a long way, baby.
That iPad with all the emergency
medicine textbooks downloaded on it,
we share one of those
between the three of us,
so we have to study in shifts.
Yeah and we share a cruddy studio
in Morris Heights, three buses away.
We have to wake up at 4:00 a.m.
just to get here on time.
That the Littmann 3M?
I can barely hear a jackhammer
with this thing, let alone a heart murmur.
But it's all I got.
So just know, from where we're standing...
[whispering]
...you're looking pretty privileged to us.
I want to get it even more.
Tell me what it's about.
-Own your feelings.
-[chuckles]
It's a pressure inside of me and, uh...
when I see something that I can take,
it just builds and builds.
Man, that sounds really hard.
Pause. Why did you interrupt me?
Uh, I was being empathetic.
That's what you told me to do.
Your impulse is correct.
The timing is bad.
I'm in the room with you.
I can read these decisions. Okay?
All right, so why don't we explore
that pressure that Kevin mentioned?
How does that make him feel?
Uh...
You don't know, because you cut him off
before he could finish telling you.
If you'd let him finish,
he would have told you
that it makes him feel like
he wants to hurt himself.
If you cut him off, if you...
if you slam that window of honesty,
that could be it. That could be his life.
Got it?
Okay. Good.
If a patient is trying
to share with you...
listen.
-Okay?
-Yeah.
Good. Drop back in.
-Here we go.
-[exhales]
[breathes deeply]
So there's a pressure,
builds and builds inside of me and if...
I feel like if I don't take it,
something awful is going to happen.
You know, it sounds like this is rooted
in conflict with your father.
No, way, way, way too soon
to drop the dad bomb.
That came out of left field.
That's... [sighs]
You can't... You can't have
a patient's epiphany for them.
-Your job is to gently guide them to it.
-[sighs]
You got it?
No, I don't got it.
Okay.
I have been working with patients
for months.
I've helped people.
And real patients let me talk
for more than five seconds.
Okay. I can see that I've upset you.
I know this is hard. Right?
But believe me when I tell you
it is so much better to be stopped
before you make the huge mistake.
All right? That goes for everyone.
That's all of you. Not just you.
And based on what I've seen
in here today, from now on,
I'm going to be sitting in on
all of your actual sessions.
And if you're going down a dangerous path,
I will jump in. I'll be there. All right?
I know that seems like a lot,
because, quite frankly, it is.
And I promise you guys, one of these days,
you will thank me for it.
Okay? Why don't you take a break?
Next resident, please.
Come on, next resident. Don't be scared.
Come on in.
Uh, where are all my residents?
They walked out.
Hey.
Look, I know you're mad,
but I just want to say I'm sorry.
I really... I really am.
You're sorry?
Yeah.
For what, exactly?
I am sorry... for earlier.
Earlier?
[sighs]
Like, when I said that
you couldn't get enough.
I wasn't implying that
you were, like, a nymphomaniac,
or that your husband
couldn't get the job done.
This has nothing to do
with my husband or sex.
You treated this
like I'm committing adultery.
Right and I did not want
to make you feel that way.
Good.
[stiffly] Good.
Although...
it is adultery, isn't it?
That's what you think this is?
I mean, well, you are married
and also sleeping with me.
Openly.
It doesn't change the fact
that I'm the other guy.
Of course it does.
[exhales] I'm not screwing you behind
my husband's back, Floyd.
I'm in a relationship with you.
At least I thought I was.
Hypertensive patient going down fast.
Uh, yeah.
-Hm. Hey Carla, how you feeling?
-[Carla humming]
-"Flight of the Bumblebee"?
-That's right.
Reminds me of you,
running around here nonstop.
Yeah, I hear that one's
a nightmare for orchestras.
Oh, yeah. It's a beast.
But I can play it in my sleep.
Bet you can.
I'm going to start you on diltiazem drip
to level out your AFib, okay?
Yeah, it goes all over the scale
and never lands anywhere.
All that Sturm und Drang for nothing.
Hypotensive patient, bay four.
AAA about to blow.
Carla, I promise you,
this is not for nothing.
[man groaning in pain]
-Already on it.
-Ah, my leg.
Okay, swelling and bleeding are up.
Oh, it hurts, Doc.
The platelets we gave you to clot
your blood made things worse.
We need to reverse course
and give you blood thinners instead.
I'm bleeding and you'd give me something
that makes me bleed more?
-It sounds backwards, but it works.
-And if it doesn't?
Dr. Sharpe,
your leukemic patient's febrile.
Be right there. I'll be right back.
Victoria?
Have you seen any nurses?
-I'm looking for my AAA--
-Yep, Bay Four.
-GI bleed. Tachy and hypotensive.
-Uh, I'll take it.
Hey, how's life? AAA in Bay Four.
-Let's go to Six.
-On my way.
Transfer from the ED. Pneumonia on BiPAP.
Heading for a tube fast.
-I've got this one.
-What are you doing?
AAA in bay four! Going to need
an intubation kit and a vent, stat!
[patient groaning in pain]
-You going to take the new admit?
-I'm surgery.
-[sighs] Who's got the new admit?
-[whimpering, groaning]
He's got V-tach. All right.
-Young man, can you speak to me?
-Yes! Yes!
Is ICU down?
Okay, I've got this. Just take the AAA
in bay four and tell Flores she's up.
Since when do you work the ICU?
Since there's no one else.
I don't get it, Gladys.
I just don't get it.
That's not true. I do. I get it. I get...
Nobody likes having
their mistakes pointed out,
but to just get up and leave?
They just left! They fell short!
I mean, I'm doing my job.
It is literally my job to correct them.
Oh, bullpucky!
That's a little... harsh
and old-fashioned.
Your job isn't correcting them.
It's to help them become better doctors.
And since every last one
of your residents left today
wanting to throw out their career,
or throw you out a window,
what's more likely?
That you got a room full of dunces
or that the person falling short today...
is you?
Mm. [chuckles]
All right. I hear you.
I guess that maybe I am falling a little
bit short of everyone's expectations,
including my own.
But that doesn't change the fact
that these are doctors.
They're treating real people
with real issues
and I can't just risk them failing.
But, Iggy, they will fail.
[chuckles]
I mean, when you were starting out,
didn't you?
[indistinct chattering and beeping]
Dr. Sharpe.
What are you doing out of bed?
Your spleen could blow any minute!
Did you hear anything about Garrett,
my climbing partner?
He's at Baptist.
I don't know anything else.
I'm waiting for a call back
from his doctors. Now, come on.
Come on.
-We were rappelling.
-Mm-hm.
We were tied onto opposite ends
of the same rope.
Going too fast, overconfident.
[grunts in pain]
I got snagged.
I came off the line.
Garrett fell. I...
I hit a ledge, but...
he just kept going.
He just fell such a long way.
I just need to know.
I'll call them again.
[softly] Okay.
I won't be using these anymore
and I'll be taking the bus
to work from this point on.
Okay, so I guess you'll be finishing
your residency, uh, never.
You have given me access
to wonderful things,
things I've never had before, but I...
and I like them. I do.
I really, really do.
I feel like there's a but coming.
But I'm becoming like a different person,
a person with privilege.
Bay eight. Bay eight.
How do you think half the people here
got ahead, myself included?
Yes, I am a super sweet...
Hey, wait, wait. Take this. Take this.
Yes, I am a super sweet doctor
with a super sweet bedside manner,
but easy access to textbooks,
top-notch equipment,
a good night's sleep,
those things make you better.
Not a single one of those residents
would give up those things
if they had them, so why should you?
I've always scraped by,
done the best I could
with what little I had.
Now all these fancy things...
you...
make me feel like that's the reason
I'm successful, like I didn't earn it.
ER physician to 3, stat.
-ER physician to 3, stat.
-[beeping]
It's Joe.
Heart rate's slowing.
[sighs] It's not GBS. What am I missing?
[Leyla] -Symptoms?
-Back pain, ocular ptosis,
aphasia, respiratory failure,
arm weakness, now bradycardia.
Descending paralysis?
He was out on the boat with his buddies.
Bring me everything he had
out on the water. Hurry.
-[groaning]
-Why are you still here?
-Because where the hell is everyone else?
-Also a good question. What you got?
-Persistent V-tach.
-Carotid pulse is good.
But I don't have a radial pulse.
Let's check for bleeds.
-[groaning]
-Clavicle's out of alignment.
The seatbelt dislocated his clavicle,
pushed it into his shoulder
and now it's blocking the brachial artery,
which is irritating the left atrium.
[groaning]
Okay, yep. Okay, I'm going
to sit you up here, Ferris, okay?
I know, I know.
All right. You're going to feel a tug.
-[yells in pain]
-Okay.
[both] One, two...
-[cracking]
-[yells in pain]
[panting]
-Let this go.
-Whoa.
-Thank you.
-All right.
-You all right?
-[pants]
-Clavicle's back in place.
-Pulse is good.
-[phone buzzes]
All right, cool. Go, I got it from here.
Oh, yes. Yes! This is amazing,
because you wouldn't be here in person
if the answer was--
-No.
Really?
I wanted to tell you in person.
The answer is still no.
No. Uh... [clears throat] Listen.
Um...
[Ben] My brother, Adam,
my younger brother,
he's a paranoid schizophrenic.
He's been in and out of facilities
most of his life.
But since the pandemic,
he's been living with me.
It's changed us for the better.
He is my priority now.
Not my work.
New Amsterdam deserves a medical director
who's going to put the hospital first.
[pager buzzing]
[sighs]
Speaking of.
It's Carla, BP bottomed out.
-Up the Levophed.
-Maxed out.
-Dobutamine?
-All the pressers are maxed out.
-We have no room to move.
-Okay, then, um...
Then we do an intra-aortic balloon pump.
That takes the entire ICU staff
in the best of times.
Does this look like the best of times?
We're doing an intra-aortic balloon pump.
Max, you should have closed the ICU
and transferred Carla hours ago.
Now it's too late.
[beeping]
[indistinct announcements over PA system]
You can't put in a balloon pump alone.
Carla can't live
with a blood pressure of 60/40.
She needs help. I'm helping.
I don't know how to do anything else.
Well, if we're going to do this,
she needs to be maximally oxygenated.
-Thank you.
-I need you.
-Intra-aortic balloon.
-Here?
-Yes.
-You'll need ultrasound guidance.
[Helen] IABP.
-[Lauren] Right now?
-Yep.
-Where's the rest of the team?
-What you see is what you get.
That isn't enough access.
Ventricular assist.
Prepping an arterial cutdown.
Sliding in the trocar
and now threading in the balloon.
All right. Here we go.
Advancing... steadily.
Easy. Gentle.
A little further. How's placement?
South of the subclavian artery.
North of superior mesenteric.
Floyd?
[whispering] Come on.
Come on
Come on. You can do better.
[Floyd] Now we're talking.
What are you all doing here?
[relieved chuckle]
Don't worry. Going have you playing
your flute again in no time.
But, uh... not "Flight of the Bumblebee."
[serene classical music playing on phone]
[sighs]
How long have you felt like this?
Always.
[breathes heavily]
My sister thinks
I'm the one that has it together.
My sister is so brave.
She's so free.
I envy her [sobs softly]
and I hate what that does to us.
[sniffles]
What should I do?
Well...
What if you're the one
who has it together?
Joe, how often do you change the leaves?
What? It's got to steep.
I let it sit there a few days.
-That's how you got botulism.
-Botulism?
-What?
-Yep.
The bacteria was growing in your thermos
in these chamomile leaves.
Oh! Wait, wait, wait, wait,
-Joe almost died from chamomile tea?
-That's a pretty rough obituary, man.
-[all laugh]
-I mean, chamomile?
Yeah, they got it on tap at my yoga place.
Yoga? Joe.
-Who hurt you?
-[laughs]
It's called self-care, Terry.
Doc, tell him.
Yoga is great. He's right.
You should all give it a try.
Yeah. Can any of you big lugs
bend down and touch your toes?
[all laugh]
I didn't think so.
[announcement] Nuclear medicine,
please call extension 297
I wrote my resignation letter
over the weekend.
This past year's...
just been too much.
Too much grief, too much suffering.
I never felt like
I could do enough up here.
Today was supposed to be my last day.
I get it.
Just sorry it was like this.
I'm not.
You, the other docs, your friends...
[chuckles]
man, pitching in,
holding things together...
I mean...
for the first time in a long time,
I felt like we weren't alone here.
So... you're thinking maybe...
maybe...
Yeah, I'll stick around.
Thank God.
I can't fill another empty spot because
my list is too long and you're too good.
♪ We get it almost every night ♪
♪ When that moon gets big and bright ♪
♪ It's supernatural delight ♪
♪ Everybody was dancing in the moonlight ♪
[indistinct chattering]
♪ Everybody here is out of sight ♪
♪ They don't bark and they don't bite
They keep things loose ♪
♪ They keep things light ♪
So I've been thinking
about what you said earlier.
-You have?
-Yep.
Not a chance.
I am not going to let you give up
all the important things
that you need to get ahead.
-But--
-Because...
I'm going to give them
to all the residents.
New iPads, new equipment, all of it.
Everyone deserves a level playing field.
You're going to pay for that for everyone?
No. You are.
Because you are going
to start paying rent.
So you don't think
for a second that you don't deserve
all the wonderful things that you have.
♪ Feeling warm and bright
It's such a fine and natural sight ♪
Not for a second.
♪ Everybody's dancing in the moonlight ♪
[chattering]
♪ I need the meaning
When I see it all in you ♪
Iggy just described this year's harvest
to Brantley as buxom.
[chuckles]
♪ Love is back ♪
I'm sorry, Lyn.
And this time...
I know what I'm apologizing for.
I made this about sex...
because I thought
that's all I was allowed to have.
But it's killing me
because I do want more.
I want something real. I...
[chuckles] I want to hear stories
about people I don't know
and will never meet.
I want to walk out
of terrible plays with you
and... and laugh... for years.
I want all of you.
And if I can't have that, then...
We can have all that.
Yeah?
Just...
♪ For a moment, there it goes
Turn around, next thing you know ♪
...not here.
Well, let's take a walk.
See where we end up.
♪ Must have said it a thousand times ♪
♪ Can't be lying if I see the truth ♪
♪ I know who and I look at you ♪
♪ Might be too young to realize ♪
♪ If there's a mountain
I should have climbed ♪
Wrong roof.
Guess you already knew that.
[sighs]
My... my patient's climbing partner...
Garrett Turner...
he didn't make it.
They were out
on this massive rock face together,
tethered...
but they...
they just got out of balance
with each other.
Look, I know that I didn't
ask you to come to London.
That was your choice
and I am really excited
that you're making this move with me.
But it's like we're tethered together...
and we're climbing the same mountain
and we're on the same rope.
And I...
I actually don't know if I trust you...
like to... to be my partner.
You're not preparing to leave.
You're not even telling anyone.
And because we are in this together,
I, um...
I fear that you...
you're going to take me down with you.
[sighs]
We should go.
They're waiting.
-[dance music plays]
-[indistinct chatter]
-[Max] How are you?
-[chattering]
-How are you doing?
-Oh!
-Well, well, well!
-[Max] Hello.
Look who decided
to show up together, huh?
So apparently today is the day
when I get everything wrong.
Y'all do make a cute couple.
Yeah, but what's your, like, couple name?
Uh, Helmax? Goodsharpe?
[laughter, chattering]
I can't believe
I actually care about this.
[laughter]
This is amazing. Um...
We... We have
a little announcement to make.
-[all cheer]
-Speech, speech, speech!
[chattering and cheering]
[Karen] Just say it already!
You guys aren't making this any easier.
Um...
[sighs]
Dr. Sharpe...
Dr. Sharpe and I are leaving.
We're leaving New Amsterdam.
We're moving to London.
[silence]
[murmuring]
[chatter resumes]
[cell phone ringing]
[speaking Mandarin]
Um....
[chattering]
Karen, it's so nice to hear from you.
I'm a little busy at the moment.
Can I call you back?
New Amsterdam?
Well, I'll have to think about it.