Give me my next change.
I think I'm gonna puke.
Not on this dress. I'm serious.
Kate Moss was doing this at
13. You have two years on her.
Yeah, that's what I
like to see. You got this.
The next show, you're bride.
Did Austin just offer you bride?
It wasn't a real offer, Dad.
He was just being nice.
These shoes are gonna
be impossible to walk in.
You've done this 100
times before, all right?
The runway's just a
little bit longer here.
One of the girls said
Madonna's in the front row.
Sweetie, hey, come on. Are
you gonna be able to do this?
All right, come here.
Here, hold this.
The doctor gave me
these for anxiety, all right?
It'll calm you down.
Here. Come on, it's okay.
Where's Alex?
Alex, you're up!
Go! Go! Go! Go! Knock them out!
Are you okay?
Alex!
How'd you get here?
By osmosis. No helmet?
Didn't seem like riding weather.
And the fact that you can barely
stand upright had nothing to do with it?
Infarctions hurt. House.
It's what they do.
Worsening pain could
actually be a good thing.
It means the nerves
might be regenerating.
It could be good, it could be
bad. Thanks for the differential.
Any other options?
Have you ever considered a
career as a motivational speaker?
Why don't you check out some
rehab? I did the rehab thing.
One session, and you
didn't even finish that session.
The guy wanted me to
"visualize the healing".
I could do that at home. At
least let me get you an MRI.
It's a very simple equation:
more pain, more pills.
Teenage supermodel.
Presented with double vision,
sudden aggressive behavior, cataplexy.
You had me at
"teenage supermodel".
You okay? Mmm-hmm.
Wow.
You should be a model.
Are you really 15? Who are you?
I'll be the one saving her life
today, assuming she's dying.
Who are you? He's my father.
Any idea what's wrong with her?
Well, from the looks
of it, not a single thing.
I probably should stop
staring and check out the file.
So what set off the brawl?
She stand in your light?
I didn't even know her. I
didn't know what happened.
Look, I know some models
are notorious for hissy fits,
but Alex... I've never
even seen her get angry.
Even when she was a kid... I'm
sure she was delightful in her youth.
Then you passed out.
I was passed out, but I wasn't.
I knew what was going on,
but I couldn't move or talk.
Yeah, it sounds like a medical
thing. It's called "cataplexy".
Catfight and cataplexy
on the catwalk.
Cool. How much
were you drinking?
She only had one
sip of champagne.
Forget it. I'll find out
from the tox screen.
All right, look, I
gave her a Valium.
Do you think that's
what did this? No.
How long have
you had the sweats?
A couple of days.
Any other complaints?
My stomach's been bothering me
and I've been feeling a little nauseous.
Okay, here's how this works.
My lackeys will be by
shortly to draw some blood,
collect some urine,
any other fluids you got.
I'll do some other doctorly
stuff, and we'll be in touch.
Since when do you
voluntarily go see patients?
Have you seen her? She's 15.
There's something about
her, something in her eyes,
kind of a maturity. Yeah,
yeah, she's an old soul.
This is creepy, even for you.
She's a fashion model,
on the cover of magazines.
We hold her up
as the sexual ideal.
The law says we can't touch
her for three more years.
How hypocritical is that?
Did the history reveal anything,
oh, I don't know, medically relevant?
History, right.
I knew I was
forgetting something.
You should do one of those while
you're running the labs and the tox screen.
The labs show Valium
and heroin in her urine.
A supermodel on smack. Shocker.
Oh, Alex, I expected
so much more from you.
Heroin chic is
so five years ago.
Okay, let's start crossing
out withdrawal symptoms.
A positive test means
she tried it once.
It doesn't mean she's
an addict. She's only 15.
There's no age limit
on addiction. He's right.
She's never menstruated.
Sounds like a symptom
of drug addiction to me.
Or bulimia. Or her age.
Some girls don't start
till their mid-to-late teens.
Evidence to the
contrary, the rounded hips.
The perfectly-sculpted,
bountiful breasts.
Implants. I've seen
some of her photos.
They've grown dramatically
since last summer.
Symptomatic of turning 14.
Two clinic hours says that those
"love apples" are handcrafted by God.
I thought you didn't
believe in God. I do now.
You're on.
Could we talk about her
health instead of her breasts?
It could be relevant.
Come on, Cameron, there's
nothing to be ashamed of.
Many women develop breasts.
No, I'm fine.
Even if she is an addict,
a lot of her symptoms,
the cataplexy, the violence,
it could be neurological.
If we chalk this up
to drugs, we could be
releasing her with Juvenile
MS or Parkinson's...
Detox her. FOREMAN: Fine.
We'll set her up on a program,
they'll wean her onto the methadone.
And in four weeks,
we'll know you're right.
Or, we'll know that
Cameron's right
and the pretty girl will do
Milan next fall in a wheelchair.
Put her in a coma, pump
her full of naltrexone.
Cut the four weeks to one night.
The lab reports show that your
daughter had heroin in her system.
Were you aware of her drug use?
No.
We think she's suffering
from withdrawal symptoms.
Detoxing generally
takes several weeks.
The danger is that if the drugs
are masking some other illness,
it could worsen before we've
weaned her off the heroin.
Well, how much worse?
We don't know because
we don't know what's wrong.
There is a rapid
detox procedure.
We flush her system
with an opioid antagonist.
It'll end her
addiction overnight.
The process is dangerous
because we have to induce a coma.
It also means that
if she ever relapses,
there's a good chance she'll overdose
because her body won't react to the drug.
So either way
I'm risking her life.
Do you have to tell
her how dangerous it is?
Is it dangerous?
There are certain risks.
We've gone over
them with your father.
And he's not worried?
He's your dad. He's
always gonna worry.
But he knows we're gonna
take good care of you.
Everything's starting
to hurt. My legs are...
Heroin withdrawal is an
extremely painful process.
But we're gonna put you to
sleep. You won't feel a thing.
You promise? I promise.
That was a pretty
stupid thing to do, huh?
Getting hooked on drugs?
Yeah, not the best
move you've ever made.
Just, I thought it would be fun.
You don't have to explain to us.
A lot of, a lot of the
other girls were...
When you wake up,
you'll feel a lot better.
Nurse! Nurse!
You son of a bitch!
You killed her!
She's not dead. She
had a heart attack.
She's stable now.
The anesthesia...
Get her out of that coma.
I don't think so. Stop this!
All right, I don't
consent anymore.
I want her to do the slow detox.
Did you ever get a paper cut? A
really nasty one, between the fingers?
Multiply that by about a billion
and you'll just barely approach
the kind of suffering she'll experience
if we wake her up now.
We're committed to this.
She's out till morning.
Go get a book.
I haven't slept in weeks,
because my teeth hurt.
The dentist couldn't
find any cavities.
And I'm getting these headaches.
Oh! Poor you.
I think I'm going crazy.
And my stomach, I roll out
of bed and I wanna puke.
I take it you're married?
You must be psychic.
You must be witty.
When's she due? How'd
you know she was...
Because I'm doing her.
You've got Couvade Syndrome.
It's just a fancy way of saying
you should stop whining.
Millions of women have got the
same thing. They're not bugging me.
You're suffering from
sympathetic pregnancy.
Gotta go. People dying.
Whole circle of life
thing. It's all in my head?
No, it's all in your hormones.
The good news is, no one's gonna
lecture you if you smoke and get drunk.
Shouldn't she be awake by now?
It's only been a half an hour
since we stopped the medicine.
Well, you said that's
how long it would take.
I said it would take
about a half an hour.
But couldn't this mean something
more... So far, it means nothing.
She had a heart attack.
She could have brain damage.
She could have something
more... She's opening her eyes.
Alex, you okay?
Can you hear me?
I got the cute doctor.
Do you feel any pain?
Good. Let us know
if anything changes.
If your stomach doesn't
feel right, anything.
Hey.
Are you mad at me, Daddy?
I let you down.
No, no. Not at all, sweetie,
I should have been more mature. I
should have handled the pressure.
Stop, stop.
We're gonna get you better,
all right? Nothing else matters.
Excuse me.
I've got you on what
we call a "banana bag".
Plenty of vitamins, nutrients...
I got the cute doctor.
Are you mad at me, Daddy?
I let you down. What's going on?
I should have been more mature. I
should have handled the pressure.
What's wrong with her?
Anterograde amnesia,
short term memory loss.
Evidence of a
hypoxic brain injury.
It might be the result of getting cut
off from the oxygen when she flatlined.
Probably the result of that rapid
detox you told us to push on her.
You gonna put that down?
Are you gonna sulk?
I'm not gonna indulge you.
The treatment for hypoxic
brain injuries consists of...
Cameron, Chase and the Dark One.
Foreman, right?
The patient flatlined
for like, 30 seconds.
You've got to be oxygen-deprived
for longer than that
to lose brain function.
We can't be sure how long
she was... Her brain's fine.
Memory loss.
You're saying that's not
a neurological symptom?
No, I'm saying what I'm
saying. Her brain's fine.
She's faking?
She's got posttraumatic
stress disorder.
We got models
fighting in Iraq now?
Show me a woman on
heroin who looks like that,
and I'll show you a woman
who's been sexually abused.
That's your proof?
That she's good looking.
He manages her career, travels
the world with her, at her side 24/7.
He's either a very good
dad or a very bad dad.
You saw that tuchus.
Would the fact that she's
your daughter really stop you?
Her brain is running away from reality
and when the drugs can't do it anymore,
it starts to shut down.
Your theory has the advantages
of being completely un-provable
and completely exculpating you.
When you guys are done
talking, do an MRI and an LP.
When her brain
checks out as normal,
then we'll know that daddy
really, really loves her.
Where's House?
He said he was in too much
pain to work. Who's covering?
He called 15 minutes
after his shift started.
It was too late to find
anybody. Exam Room One.
Hi. Where's Dr. House?
I wish I knew.
What's the problem?
It's personal.
And it's so personal he didn't
bother writing anything in your chart.
It's getting worse. What is?
It's personal.
Fine. You can wait. Doctor!
I tell you what.
I am going to give you
Dr. House's personal pager number.
Why would your mind
go to abuse so fast?
Because I had a funny
uncle. You were abused?
What? No. Why'd your
mind go to that so fast?
I just had a funny uncle.
Great stories, always filthy.
I don't know if it's
something with this case
or you got something personal
going on, the whole breakup thing?
It's personal. House.
Your pain is affecting
your decision-making.
You got a problem with a
call I make, question the call.
Don't make it personal.
Are you saying pain
can't affect your mood?
If I'm right about the pain, you're
gonna wanna rush everything,
which is what you're doing.
Don't.
Thank you.
Are you doing your
daughter? What?
We should probably talk privately,
huh? Come on, walk with me.
Come on. He's not!
I'm sure he's not.
She is a babe, though.
We're gonna need
you to keep still. I am.
What do you think that means?
It's either neurological
or psychological.
The only thing we know for sure is
it's gonna screw up the MRI results,
which is gonna make
House think he's right.
This is a waste of time.
Let's just get the LP.
I should take your head off.
Your glands are fine.
See, now, you're my patient.
You got doctor-patient
confidentiality. No worries.
So, what did you do to her?
Why would you possibly think...
Hard to imagine anyone
not wanting to nail her.
You son of... It's a compliment.
That heart-shaped ass, those
perfect, perky, all-natural breasts.
That is my daughter
you're talking about!
No, that's your daughter
you were talking about.
"She just instinctively
knows how to walk.
"Designers just love that
heart-shaped ass, those perfect, perky..."
I'm her manager. I
have to promote her.
Oh, that makes sense.
So you compartmentalize.
When you're dealing with
the press, you're her manager.
When you're helping with
homework, you're her dad.
When you're making sweet,
sweet love, you're her manager.
All right. Do you love her?
I have never touched
her. Do you love her?
What are you doing? Are you
trying to trap me into saying...
Do you love her enough to
admit that you slept with her?
Psychological conditions can manifest
themselves in physical problems.
Sometimes these can
be extreme enough to kill.
There are treatments, but
only if there is a diagnosis.
Are you going to admit that
you slept with your daughter
or are you just
gonna let her die?
One time.
PTSD.
Get her a psyche referral,
pack her bags. He did her.
Don't think so. Daddy thinks so.
He could be mistaken.
He said he was drunk.
Maybe it was some
other daughter.
Elevated proteins in her CSF.
You're wrong about PTSD and I was
wrong about the hypoxic brain injury.
Daddy didn't do this to
her. And neither did we.
We have to call Child
Protective Services.
Doctor-patient confidentiality.
Doesn't apply in abuse
cases. You know that.
We're mandated to
report sexual abuse.
Is it okay if I save her life first
or do you want to make sure
that daddy doesn't get
visitation rights to the gravesite?
Okay, elevated proteins in her CSF
could mean dozens of different things.
Viral encephalitis, CNSV,
Creutzfeldt-Jakob disease?
So we're just gonna leave a child
molester in the same room as his victim?
It's got windows.
Fine. Arrest him. Use
Cuddy's handcuffs.
If you're too distracted to deal with
this because your leg hurts, then...
Yeah, I'm distracted!
I'm all hung up on this 15-year-old
patient who's cataplectic,
can't remember what she had for lunch
and is rapidly losing control of her body!
And I want her father here in
case he's got any more secrets
that I need to know about.
Now, if you're not too distracted,
go take out a piece of her brain,
stick it under a microscope.
Wilson! FOREMAN:
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Do you really think we need
to jump straight to brain biopsy?
Nope. Let's continue playing
"Pin the diagnosis on the
supermodel" until she's dead.
I heard you killed your
supermodel. Only for a minute.
Just for my own clarity, how many
more patients do you have to kill
before you admit this leg
thing just might be a problem?
Three.
I need your help.
We're gonna do something
called a burr-hole biopsy.
We drill a small opening
in the back of your skull.
Doctor, maybe you and I
should talk about this first.
No.
I just think Alex doesn't need
to be overwhelmed right now.
I think she should have a say
in what happens to her body.
Now, we're gonna remove
a small piece of brain tissue.
Do you have to shave my hair?
Hair grows back.
I guess I won't
remember anyways.
There's a good chance the
amnesia is only temporary.
Okay.
Find a way to kick
up the contribution.
What did House do now?
House, this is God.
Look, I'm a little
busy right now.
I'm not supposed to
talk during these things.
Got time Thursday?
Let me check. Oh,
I've got a plague.
What about Friday?
You'll have to
check with Cameron.
Oh, damn it!
She always wants to know
why bad things happen.
Like I'm gonna come up
with a new answer this time.
House.
Quick, God, smite
the evil witch!
Are you sitting on evidence that your
patient was sexually abused by her father?
God, why have you forsaken me?
Don't worry. I've contacted
child services for you.
I let you get away with more
than anyone in this hospital.
Shielding a child
abuser isn't covered.
Cooperate with this
investigation or I'll fire you.
What do you think
House is gonna do to you?
No idea.
Well, you did the right thing.
If you hadn't gone to
Cuddy, I would have.
If this guy had known
we'd have to report him,
he'd never have
told House the truth.
She's a child, she
needs to be protected.
She dropped out of high
school to make millions of dollars.
Why does she
need more protection
than some crack whore
shivering in the clinic waiting room?
I think you're just
afraid to piss House off.
There's that, too.
MRI looks exactly the
same as it did two years ago.
The nerves don't seem
to be regenerating.
I figured as much.
Several different
researchers have proven
psychological pain can
manifest as physical pain.
You think I have a conversion
disorder? You want me to see a shrink?
Brilliant idea sending Stacy away.
It's really done wonders for you.
Listen, none of this has
anything to do with Stacy.
Right. Giant coincidence that you've gone
completely off the rails since she left.
Inducing migraines,
worsening leg pains.
Oh, do you miss Stacy, too?
Brain biopsy shows
no white matter disease.
Cameron, you gonna tell Cuddy, or
has she already got you wired for sound?
I had to do what I
thought was right.
So, white is out.
It just leaves gray.
Neuronal ceroid lipofucinosis,
Heller Syndrome...
Any one of the mitochondrial
encephalopathies.
Am I in trouble?
You had to do what
you thought was right.
They call it "gray area" because
you never really know what's there.
We can't test for
any of those things.
So I'm not in trouble?
You can torture
yourself all you want.
What if everything we're
seeing is just smoke signals?
Okay. Who's sending them? Tumor.
If she has cancer
anywhere in her body,
she could also have
Paraneoplastic Syndrome,
which could be causing
antibodies to attack her brain.
Antibodies are stupid that way.
Paraneoplastic Syndrome's
awfully rare in a 15-year-old.
15-year-olds who look
like that are awfully rare.
It would explain the aggressive
behavior, the cataplexy,
the memory loss, even
the twitching. It's perfect.
What if it's not?
We could waste a week
searching for a tumor
that we don't
even know is there.
Then let's make
sure it is there.
There's no test for
Paraneoplastic Syndrome.
Sure there is.
The "squeeze the tube" test.
What did the biopsy tell
you? It wasn't definitive.
But the twitching should
stop right about now.
Oh, my God.
Could have just
been a coincidence.
Twitching does tend to
stop and start. Let's be sure.
The IVIG vacuums her blood, neutralizes
the stuff that's making her twitch.
It's actually kind of cool.
I wonder if I could make
you dance? Enough.
This is unbelievable.
You did it. You fixed her.
No.
All I did was prove
that she has cancer.
I need a favor.
I'm not in a giving mood.
It'll help us both.
I need a shot of
morphine in my spine.
If your leg hurts,
take your Vicodin.
It's not enough.
Get a syringe.
Morphine is
extreme, even for you.
Yeah. Write that on the insert.
Get one of your lackeys to do it.
I don't want them knowing...
That you're on the road
to becoming a junkie?
That I'm in this much pain.
I don't want them
questioning my judgment.
I can't ask Wilson, because
he figures it's all in my head.
Well, I agree with
him. I'm going home.
What about this?
What are you doing?
Is this in my head?
Because I could swear I
remember a thigh muscle being here.
I'll get a syringe.
It's gotta be cancer.
It's not cancer.
You seem to be back to
your old miserable self.
So I just randomly predicted
she'd respond to IVIG?
Her twitches are gone,
her memory's getting better.
What did you take?
The increased pain
was psychological.
No drug's gonna help.
If you think it will help, the drugs
will help. The power of the mind.
You're right.
The more I talk to you, the
more the pain floods back.
I knew the twins were
real. Chase owes me.
Did you check the
pancreas? Oh, come on.
You're just making up
organs now, aren't you?
We checked the pancreas.
Obviously, you've taken
something. Did you check the bones?
There are a lot
of bones, I think.
And none of them have cancer.
Ovaries? There's no mass.
If anything, they're undersized.
No leukemia, no Hodgkin's,
we checked everything.
Unless they've invented a
new organ, it's not cancer.
Differential diagnosis.
It's gotta be cancer.
There's gotta be
something we missed.
You've got to learn
to let go, Foreman.
Maybe the protein level
was some sort of anomaly.
It might just still be PTSD.
Just PTSD?
Yeah, Daddy's diddling
her. Nothing to worry about.
Okay, let me rephrase.
Maybe the protein level
was some sort of anomaly.
Oh, my God!
It might be PTSD!
If it was PTSD, the twitching
wouldn't have magically disappeared
when we started the IVIG.
Wrong.
What it wouldn't have done
was medically disappear.
Nothing to stop it from
magically disappearing.
She was watching me
start and stop the medicine.
You think she's faking?
Not consciously.
But if her subconscious is
trying to get away from it all,
cancer's gotta be a
lovely vacation spot.
Tell her you've got
to give her a fresh IV.
Don't tell her you're
starting her on saline.
See if the twitching comes back.
How long has the social
worker been in there?
Just went in. She was
in with the dad before.
You switched the girl's IV?
About a half an hour ago.
When's she gonna
start twitching?
If she's gonna start twitching.
Another few minutes.
We've got to wait for the
remaining IVIG to clear her system.
That was quick.
What's gonna happen?
What'd you think
was gonna happen?
The father had sex... Do you
have any medical evidence of that?
He admitted... He denies the
conversation ever took place.
But she... She denies it, too.
I'm sure you meant well.
You have to tell her the truth.
Nothing happened.
You don't have to be afraid
of him. They can protect you.
From what? Things are fine.
You think things
are fine. They're not.
He's my dad. He's abusing you.
He's not a bad person.
I seduced him.
You're the child.
He's the adult.
He has the responsibility...
I got him drunk.
I had to get him drunk.
I wanted to have sex with him.
You're sexually
attracted to your father?
No.
But by sleeping with him, now
he lets me do whatever I want.
I also slept with my photographer,
my financial manager and my tutor.
If I hadn't, I'd be getting C's
and posing for newspaper
ads back in Detroit.
Come on, we all
do it. No, we don't.
After your father slept with
you, you were traumatized.
My dad was last.
You've never taken a run
at your boss or professor
or somebody else you needed?
You're 15. You're smart.
You don't have... I
am not that smart.
I am that beautiful.
What's wrong with me?
Oh! George, get
your butt over here!
Help me. How'd you
get my pager number?
Please!
The problem is, if I
give you an epidural,
you won't be able to feel
when to push. You're not funny.
I'm pretty sure I am.
You just can't appreciate
it because you're in pain.
George, if you don't get
off your ass and help me...
Oh, shut up!
You've got yourself the
perfect man. A woman.
He's got more estrogen
coursing through his veins than...
Who did her vaginal exam? I did.
Did she have hair?
What are you getting at?
Right now I'm getting at whether
or not she had hair down there.
Not much. She's manipulative,
yet completely docile.
Everybody tells us that outburst
on the catwalk was out of character.
She's never had a period.
You're thinking
this is hormonal?
I'm thinking she's
the ultimate woman.
I need to schedule an MRI.
The twitching stopped.
Because we changed your
medicine back to the real stuff.
Stop talking.
You gave me fake medicine?
That's what I said, in the vain hope that
you wouldn't feel the need to also say it.
Stop talking.
Wilson already did an ultrasound.
He said her ovaries were undersized.
The ultrasound would be the way to
go if you were looking for ovarian cancer.
What are we looking for?
That.
Oh, my God.
It looks like a
tumor, doesn't it?
But those are... Yep.
We found a tumor.
She has cancer?
Technically, no.
So it's not cancer?
No, it's cancer,
but "he" has cancer
on "his" left testicle.
I don't have testicles.
She's not a guy.
His DNA says you're wrong.
Frogs and snails
and puppy dog tails.
You've got male
pseudohermaphroditism.
You see, we all
start out as girls
and then we're differentiated,
based on our genes.
The ovaries develop
into testes and drop.
But in about one in every
150,000 pregnancies,
the fetus with an XY chromosome
a boy, develops
into something else,
like you.
Your testes never descended,
because you're immune to testosterone.
You're pure estrogen.
Which is why you have
heightened female characteristics,
clear skin, great breasts.
The ultimate woman is a man.
Nature's cruel, huh?
This is obviously a
joke. This is impossible.
No. A joke would be
me calling you a homo.
You see the difference?
I'll schedule him for surgery.
No! You're wrong!
I'm a girl! Look at me!
How could you
say I'm not a girl?
You see, they're all
looking at me, I'm beautiful!
That anger. It's just
the cancer talking.
Put your clothes back on.
We're gonna cut your balls off.
Then you'll be fine.
How's the patient? Post-op.
They sent him/her
up for a psyche visit.
Calling her a "him/her"
isn't really helping.
The good news is, I don't think Dad's
gonna be sleeping with him/her again.
You see, now it's gross.
I need another shot.
When did the pain
start coming back?
A few hours ago.
About an hour after
you solved the case?
If I wanted to be psychoanalyzed,
I'd get Wilson to give me the shot.
Same dosage?
If you'd be more comfortable,
I might be able to deal with
a few less cc's of morphine.
It wasn't morphine.
What did you give me?
I told you I wanted...
It was saline.
I gave you a placebo.