Previously on ER:
- What's with the cross?
- My chaplain gave it to me.
You keeping up on
your Bible studies?
- I wasn't faking it.
- Yeah, I know.
- Take it off! Get it off me!
- Hey, hey, hey.
Weaver knew he had
problems before she hired him.
- Now we're paying for it.
- Well, Luka, it's your ER.
Have you any idea why
Michael went back to Iraq?
The boy's his father's son.
Soldiers gotta go
where they tell them to.
Why don't you explain why
he's not here with his wife?
The secretary of the Army would
like to express his deepest regret...
that your husband,
Captain Michael Gallant...
was killed in action
in Iraq on April 29th.
- So we can't even send anything, or...?
- Flowers? Donations?
There's gonna be a
memorial next week.
For today, Neela and the Gallants
wanna have a private graveside ceremony.
- Family only.
- And you.
Yeah, that's right. She needs
somebody to lean on right now.
- Plus, Mike and I were tight.
- Let her know we're with her.
And tell her to not even think
about coming back until she's ready.
All right. I should get out of here. Car's
picking me up. I need to be there by 9.
Dr. Weaver, that was Dr. Anspaugh's
office. He's waiting for you upstairs.
Dr. Weaver. WEAVER: Yep.
This is Mary Warner. She's
an EMT trainee from Mitchelson.
Hi. My program sent me over to
spend the day taking vitals or whatever.
- For credit.
- Of course.
Somebody needs to sign
this at the end of the shift...
to say that I was
here and did stuff.
- What would you like to do?
- Let her shadow.
- See how different nurses do the primary.
- That's what my instructor suggested.
Well, patients come in
through the triage desk here.
Waiting's out there, and ambulance runs
come in just outside those doors there.
- Right, I got it.
- How long you wanted to be an EMT?
Oh, not long, actually. I got
tired of retail. Christmas sucked.
Sam, this is Mary Warner,
she's studying to be an EMT.
Hey.
- I've got to irrigate a
full-body road rash...
on an unfortunate Vespa driver.
I got the mother of
all meth mouths here.
So? Can you let Mary
observe you for a while?
Haleh.
I'll come and get her
as soon as I'm free.
- Haleh.
- Bye.
- Yuck.
- Yep, that's the magic of meth.
Corrosive substances in the
drug eat away at the tooth enamel.
Plus, I have a feeling Mike here
hasn't been flossing. Have you, Mike?
It's not really a priority.
Dude, you gotta floss every day.
- Hey.
So how's she doing?
- I left messages, but haven't heard back.
- Amazingly well, actually.
Well, she's tougher
than she looks, huh?
Yeah.
I'll try calling her again.
Ray, I think she needs
some space, man.
- Yeah, but I just thought that...
- Look, she...
I just don't think
that you should, uh...
What?
Complicate it.
- You Dr. Pratt?
- Yeah, that's right. Where's Neela?
Dr. Rasgotra has asked that we
go on to the cemetery without her.
She said she's not
feeling up to it today.
Okay.
Hey. Bob Vila, look out.
- It's not finished yet.
- Looks pretty finished to me.
Well, either I've been sleeping for
days, or you're working really fast.
How's the insomnia?
I kept thinking about
Gallant and Clemente.
It's a lot.
I went with yellow.
Because we don't know
is it gonna be blue or pink.
What's it gonna be,
huh? Blue or pink? Hello.
Is it just me, or are
pandas kind of creepy?
Wow, they're terrifying.
Hey. Steady.
Hello.
Listen, I know we don't say it,
because I guess that's just how we are...
but I hope you know
how much I love this.
All of this.
But since we are on the cusp
of this hugely life-altering event...
and we haven't been as
specific as we could be about us...
- about our relationship...
- You're right, let's get married.
Donald, oh, I'm sorry I'm late.
I didn't realize we were having a
pre-meeting. I went to your office...
Have a seat.
I wanted us to talk prior to the session
with the Medical Executive Committee.
The fallout from Clemente...
may be more
significant than I thought.
- I've been hearing things.
- What kind of things?
This is a letter from an attorney
representing Mr. Fred Fong...
a patient Clemente
saw a few weeks back.
Yes, diabetic with a gangrenous
toe. I've reviewed the case.
Ended up needing an amputation.
A reasonable outcome for which
Vic was completely blameless.
The family sees an opportunity.
You know, can
we talk in private?
I'm sorry.
Hospital policy. I need this
conversation documented.
Dr. Clemente was cleared by the
Impaired Physicians' Committee.
He never once tested
positive for drugs.
I don't believe he
compromised patient care.
I'm not sure that that matters.
The state board posts a bad-doctor list
on their website, and Clemente's on it.
- Any idiot with a computer has access.
- Doesn't give them legal cause.
Let's let the lawyers determine that. In
the meantime, the board feels let down.
They expect their chief of staff to
exercise the utmost discretion in hiring.
I needed an Attending, Donald. I
hired the best doctor I could find.
Even when you knew his
history? What happened in Newark?
I'm tired of hearing about Newark.
That was a very complicated situation.
Very unclear. There were lots
of unsubstantiated allegations.
- You should have kept your eye on him.
- You know, I'm not down there, Donald.
I don't run the ER anymore.
Which leads me
to a second issue.
The board has concerns about Dr. Kovac's
ability to manage the department.
You're not serious.
Are you satisfied with
the job he's doing?
He's doing the best he
can with what he has.
Keep him on 100
percent. Six of Pavulon.
I gave him Norcuron.
Fine. Dopamine
to a systolic of 100.
- Did you call the ICU?
- Ten minutes ago.
Okay, fine. Let's find him a
monitored bed until we get a room.
I'll put him in 2.
Cold shoulder, huh?
Well, not exactly the
answer I was hoping to hear.
Well, not exactly the best
proposal I've ever heard.
How many have you heard?
Hey, hey, hey. Okay, so you
don't know what you want this to be.
I don't wanna get married for the
sake of getting married. I tried that.
- Don't we love each other?
- It's not about that. Of course we do.
Don't you think we should
stay together forever?
I don't know if anybody should, or can...
- Paging Dr. Lockhart.
I just... Let me get through one
humongous life change at a time, okay?
Luka, got a minute?
Yeah.
Sometimes it's easier if
you lump them all together.
- Hey.
- How's the hip?
- Good, thanks. Better all the time.
Looks like you'll be short
an Attending after all.
I have to attend an emergency
Med Exec Committee meeting.
Risk Management is coming to
advise us on the Clemente situation.
What situation? He's gone.
Well, there's potential litigation.
We're getting some heat about it.
We are getting some heat?
It's your department.
Kerry, he was your hire.
He was on staff before
I moved up to this job.
Yeah, I know that, I'm
the one who moved you up.
So, what, I should
have fired him sooner?
The warning signs were
there. You had the authority.
Am I gonna lose
my job over this?
Look, all I'm saying is,
if I weren't chief of staff...
I'm not so sure you'd
be department head.
So let's just get
through this, okay?
Neela.
You know, I'm not
used to getting stood up.
I'm not going, Greg.
It's gonna be fine, I promise.
Well, going means saying goodbye,
and saying goodbye means forgetting.
It doesn't have to.
I can't help it.
It's started already. I can't
remember his hands, his voice.
Can I come in?
I keep asking myself
why he went back.
It's like a hammer in my head.
He did what he wanted to do.
What he needed to do.
It's not a bad way to go.
He was 29 years old, Greg.
He was blown up by a bomb.
It's a tragedy, and believe
me, I'm not saying it isn't...
but Michael, he wanted to be a
part of something bigger than himself.
Now, two months ago, I
would have laughed at that.
But now...
Look, he put himself out there, and
sometimes that means taking risks...
and doing things that you could
never imagine yourself doing...
because you have
this crazy idea that...
you just might be able
to make a difference.
Nobody wants to forget Michael.
We all wanna remember him.
And that's exactly
what today is all about.
Smart, uh, efficient, um...
- Loyal friend.
- Something sexier.
- Sexier?
- Something about my charm.
Like a man whose
charm with women...
is matched only by his sensitivity
to his patients. Yes, action.
This is stupid. Forget it.
- What? Abs, this is it.
- Don't call me Abs.
I am out of here. You're not
gonna have Archie to kick around.
- Abs?
- Can't blame a guy for wanting memories.
You're not going to Kilimanjaro. You're
going to Ladokern Pharmaceuticals.
- Seven city blocks from here.
- Six and a half.
Besides, people don't make memory
videos unless they're getting married.
- I'm a sentimental guy.
- And they don't film them themselves...
so the person is held
hostage to say nice things.
Really? You didn't seem held hostage.
I expected better material out of you.
Well, you were feeding
me the lines, Fassbinder.
Oh, what was that? Some
kind of nasty Croatian word?
- Something about me and a goat?
- This is Timmy Jankowski.
Overindulged at the buffet
at his school's spring pageant.
Let me guess. Fruit salad.
You must be the funny guy.
School nurse brought him in.
As this is my last day, and seeing that I
am chief resident, I designate Lockhart.
- Excuse me?
- I'm out of here in 10 hours.
I call no kids for the duration. I'm
sick of getting bit, kicked and pissed on.
Guess you stopped
dating too, huh?
We got a 71-year-old male found
slumped over in a parked car. GCS, 224.
Okay, put him in Curtain 1. I'll try to
be right back. Take it easy, Timmy.
Easy? I'm a freaking strawberry.
- Stomach hurts pretty bad, huh?
- Kind of.
Hm. Well... Here.
Try pinching yourself.
- Here, let me do it.
- Ow! That hurts.
Well, you're not thinking about
your stomach now, are you?
When Mitch didn't show up
for the bus trip to Bloomington...
we knew something was wrong.
- They're part of the same church group.
- Mitch. Mitch, can you wake up for me?
We prayed and prayed, and
then we started seeing things.
- Everybody thought he was dead.
- But we found him.
- Our visions led us right to him.
- A half a mile from the church.
- Can you save him?
- We're gonna do our best.
Oh, thank you.
And, uh...
You should be very, very
proud, Mr. and Mrs. Morris.
Okay, cut. Mama Morris is dead,
so can we take that one more time?
- Holly says they need us in Exam 3.
- Holly?
You know, that other nurse.
Haleh? I gotta go.
The old lady in 3's still
waiting on her rectal.
No, no, no. Not on my last
day. No rectals, no geezers.
Any patients you're
willing to examine?
Yeah, hot chicks.
I got the vitals like you
asked, on the medium timer.
Mediastinum. Mediastinal mass.
Whatever. Had to pry her cell
phone off her ear to check her temp.
- Mary...
- She thinks I'm a bitch...
but this is a hospital,
we've got a job to do.
Did you write this? BP, 28/17?
- Did I do it wrong?
- 28/17 is practically dead...
not eating Jell-O or
chatting on your cell phone.
Sorry, I'm new to this.
Is that her? MARY: Yeah.
- She look dead to you?
- Not right now.
Before you take more, you need to
know what's normal and what's not.
And if you're not sure,
then get some help, okay?
- Okay.
- Let's see what we got in here.
- Hey, what do you have?
- Obtunded with bradycardia.
I need 0.5 of atropine, CBC,
Chem-7, ABG, tox screen...
and set up for
transcutaneous pacing.
- Okay, got it.
- No gag, I have to tube him.
- What happened?
- Eight-oh and a Mac 2.
He must have passed
out at the wheel.
Not from drinking.
He's not like that.
Atropine's in.
Have another dose
ready. I need suction.
- Is he taking any medications?
- Maybe.
- Maybe something for his pressure.
- Yes.
Right? Pressure. HELEN: Yeah.
I'm in.
Heart rate's down to 38.
Damn it, his IV blew.
We lost the pulse.
Start compressions,
he needs to be paced.
You know CPR, right?
- Uh, yeah, a little.
- Good, go.
So how did you
audition for this role?
I didn't. I wanted
to be the bad bunny.
I wanted to be the Cowardly Lion
once, but I had to play a Munchkin.
They cast you as a Munchkin?
It was before my growth spurt.
Okay, no tenderness,
guarding or rebound.
Think you could eat a
Popsicle, help settle things down?
- Sure.
- I'll get it. Let me guess. Strawberry?
Ah, and here comes our
trusty paramedic, Brian Dumar...
wheeling in another
needy patient.
Twenty-eight-year-old, blunt head
trauma, altered LOC, vitals stable.
Bitch-sucker. Rabid
dog, I'll send you to hell!
Nasty fight in detention.
Partner's behind me.
- Okay, Trauma 2. Ray will be right there.
- What?
- No prisoners, man. I called it, last day.
- I'll send you all to hell!
- You kiss your cellmate with that mouth?
- I'm right here, you dumb bastard!
That opened up a recent surgical
scar. BP, 124/78, pulse, 98.
- Your belly hurt?
- Hey, put me with him.
- Nice to see you.
- Recovering from an appendectomy.
Must have ripped open his stitches.
- Okay... Oh, yuck.
Yeah, that's not good.
Dr. Ray Barnett
will be right with you.
- How long do I have to keep this up?
- Epi infusion, 10 mics per minute.
He's very healthy, Mitch is.
- I ain't going anywhere!
- Even virile.
- Okay, tell me. ABBY:
Bradycardic arrest.
No response to atro,
no capture with pacing.
I'm behind you, you bastard!
- What are you doing?
- CPR.
You can't possibly hope to
perfuse the brain that way.
- Fuse the what?
- Okay, step back.
Step back.
- Who is she?
- Who are you?
That's Mary. She's an EMT trainee.
She's shadowing the nurses today.
Then you should be showing
her the right way to do things.
Okay, Mary, I'm Dr. Kovac.
I'm the Attending physician and
the ER chief, so let me train you a bit.
Hundred times a minute, and you
should really compress the chest.
There'll be a military
honor as requested.
I didn't request that.
Colonel and Mrs. Gallant
requested it, ma'am.
Sounds like something
he might want.
After the ceremony, we'll head
out to the reception in Lincoln Park.
Canapés will be served.
- Bed will be ready in half an hour.
- Sedation's off. He's trying to extubate.
Give him a few minutes, then
you can pull it and send him up.
- Hey, Luka, can I get a minute?
- Sure.
His heart's beating
well now. It looks good.
You hear, Mitch? You're okay.
- Probably took too many pills by accident.
- Oh, he gets confused sometimes.
Can we go now? Take him home?
No, probably not
for a couple of days.
Something the matter?
There's something
bad here, I can feel it.
Yeah. Heh-heh. I
feel that every day.
Is everything all
right with your baby?
It's fine.
Are you a believer, dear?
You must be very brave, then.
I could never have brought
a child into this world...
if I didn't have faith...
- In a higher power.
Amen.
I'm sorry about in there.
You're a senior nurse, I expect you
to know what's going on around you.
I want you to be
exact about meds.
I know, it's... I guess that that
girl is kind of dragging me down.
I'm sure you'll
whip her into shape.
My bad, I guess. He
sure is a gloomy Gus.
Needs to lighten
up a bit, doesn't he?
It's his department.
Hey, Sam, you got a minute?
I may have to tube this guy.
- I need you to draw up induction meds.
- Steve's here?
Yeah, he got in a little jail-yard
altercation, but he's okay.
Belly's benign. Looks
like superficial dehiscence.
Does he need anything?
Look, I'll get somebody else
to redress the wounds, okay?
I'll get you a CPR
dummy, okay? After this.
You can practice
compressions in the lounge.
I think I've had enough
CPR for one day.
GCS is 11, and
resps are shallow.
Sometimes, if you hit your
head, you can stop breathing.
- So then you do mouth-to-mouth?
- No.
We put a tube in his
trachea and breathe for him.
This is vec. It knocks him out
so we can do the intubation.
- 132/84.
- Good.
Pulse ox is up to 99.
Excellent. Let's lay off the
tube for now, he's doing okay.
Doc, how long I gotta wait
on Miss Congeniality here?
He needs to be
admitted for observation.
Jerk-off.
Come on, Hendricks,
we're missing lunch.
- Gumbo Thursday.
- Hey.
As long as they're here,
they're patients, not prisoners.
Sorry, but they're
always our prisoners.
Been a while since I seen that.
- What?
- Compassion.
Flank party.
Ready.
Ready, aim, fire.
Neela, it is too
dangerous over there.
It's too dangerous for me, but it's
okay for you? What a load of crap.
- Neela, I am a soldier, remember?
- You're also a husband, remember that?
Seems kind of silly now, but out
in the bay this morning, I was, uh...
I was thinking
about asking you out.
I was thinking of saying yes.
Ready, face.
You better come back.
You know that, don't you?
Yeah, I will.
You ready?
Goodbye, Michael.
- How am I doing?
- Your CT's normal.
But it looks like you'll
be spending the night.
Lucky me.
Yeah, well, you've got a
standard-issue jump suit...
an armed guard, and
a major head injury.
- You're not the luckiest guy in the world?
- Yeah. Could be worse, could be dead.
No arguing that.
Dead would be bad.
Hey, it's the other
guy who started it.
Is that so? RAFE: Yeah.
I've made mistakes, but
that guy's a wrong number.
I'd stay away from him.
Thanks for the advice. I'm gonna
go check on the guy in Sutures.
- Does he get a bandage on that?
- Just a little Neosporin. Oh...
- And we're gonna need some urine.
- I'll check his vitals.
You said every 30
minutes. It's been 35.
- I'm not peeing in front of everyone.
- Use the screen.
Hey. SAM: What's going on?
- I'm getting to be like a regular.
- Leave the nurse alone.
It's all right. We
know each other.
- What is that?
- It's called a moist-to-dry dressing.
We soak gauze in saline,
then pack it in the wound.
Ooh. Ooh.
- How'd you do this?
- Jerk tried to shiv me.
What, Bible group
got out of hand, huh?
He was trying to
snag my smokes, man.
These dudes will beef
it up over anything.
- Thought you were trying to turn around.
- I am, Sammy.
- I really am.
- Then you gotta stay out of trouble.
Hey, BP's 125 over...
Nice and easy, dumbass.
Pull the blinds, now.
- Are you out of your mind?
- Pull the blinds, bitch.
"Handsome. Sensitive.
Macho?"
- What is this macho?
- Thank you, Sveta, that's good.
- Dude, I slayed him.
- No, no, he's still moving. Look.
But I cut off his head.
Well, I got to the Oblivion Gate
long before you did anyway.
- Don't cheat, Jerry.
- I'm gonna move your old guy.
- The cops are coming.
- What for?
There was a missing-persons
report. I gotta follow it up.
- Who did the workup on migraine guy?
- Sam and Mary.
These vitals are completely
wrong. Where's Sam?
- In with prisoner number one.
- What?
Yeah, Steve and another guy came in.
I guess they had some sort of jail fight.
- Steve is here again?
- Mm-hm.
Here's how this is goes. You're gonna
walk us out like old Steve's going back.
This is it, Steve. You cross this
line, there's no stepping back.
They got me, Sam,
on all kinds of stuff.
You are such an idiot.
- I ain't getting out any time soon.
- That is what you deserve!
Hey, hey, kids. Can we
move this thing along?
If there's anything we haven't anticipated,
this is the time to mention it.
Hey, open up.
Um, just a second.
Come on.
- Hi.
- What's going on?
- Sit down.
- Come here.
Sit down, now.
Babe, tape him up.
No! No, don't shoot!
Luka!
Shut up, shut up. - Luka.
Stop!
- What was that?
- The crap you were gonna give Rafe.
Vec? You gave him vec?
Get me the ambu-mask.
- This thing?
- Yes.
That was vecuronium.
You were gonna give it
to Rafe. To knock him out.
- It paralyzes muscles, he's not breathing.
- Let's go, Sam.
He'll be paralyzed
for the next half hour.
Good.
His diaphragm
isn't working, okay?
- He's gonna asphyxiate.
- Not our problem.
Look, if you leave him here,
in five minutes, he'll be dead.
He needs to be
intubated, please.
You want a murder rap?
We're not killers, man.
Let me fix him up. I
swear, I promise you...
if you let me fix him up, I
will walk you right out of here.
Mary, go get the van.
- Curtis...
- Shut up, it's my call.
- We'll be right out.
- Hey.
Hi. Is the SonoSite in there?
- The ultrasound machine?
- Oh, I don't think so.
- Is something going on?
- They're about to do an intubation.
Who is? Kovac?
No. No, he went over to that
place where they do the head thingy.
- The head thingy? CT?
- The what?
CT? MARY: CT, yeah.
Oh, Exam 3. That's
where I saw it. Thanks.
Sitting Bull...
was facing terrible
odds against Custer.
He turned to his warriors and
said, "This is a good day to die."
That's how a
soldier has to think.
That's the kind of boy I raised.
Michael would want
you to have these.
To me, all they mean
is that he's dead.
- This is a hard time for all of us.
- How dare you.
How dare you stand
there and say that.
"A good day to die"?
I was explaining the
mindset of a warrior.
You could have kept him here.
- You could have saved him.
- Neela, sit down.
But instead, you made
him want to go back.
For what?
Because there was
something noble in it?
Why did you do that?
When it would have been just
as easy to convince him to stay...
for a much better reason:
Because we loved him.
Neela, come on. Let's
go for a walk, okay?
I can't see anything.
- Stick the damn thing in and let's go.
- It doesn't work like that.
- Luka, I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
- He can hear you?
He's paralyzed, but
he can hear and feel.
Come on, she's
waiting for us out there.
Come on, Sammy, we gotta go.
Steve, why did
you do this to me?
It was his idea, I swear.
Are we going together
or am I leaving you here?
One more try, okay?
- Enough. Grab her and let's go.
- Yeah.
- Put your hand...
- What?
Put your hand right here on his
Adam's apple. Yes, push on that.
Through the cords.
Okay. Okay.
Squeeze this bag. Squeeze
it just like that, okay?
- I swear to God, right now. Right now!
- No.
Come on.
Thank God. Thank
God. I'm so sorry... Ow!
- He still needs help breathing.
- Too bad for him.
- Hey, Sam.
- Hey, Morris, I'll help you in a second.
- Let me get Steve off.
- Hold it.
You have a missing
person. An old guy?
Mitch Keely? We
need to talk to him.
He was moved. Do
you know where he is?
No, I'm not sure. You might
wanna check in Sutures.
Sutures? Didn't you
just come from there?
Oh... Yeah.
You know what? Ask at the
front desk, they'll help you.
- Thanks.
- So back to the joint, huh?
- Yeah, I'm a quick healer.
- Where's your fight-club buddy?
They took him up to
the ward for observation.
Okay.
Well, nice to see you again.
Watch your back.
Let's go another way.
This way's fastest.
That's what you said.
But there's cops now.
Well, if we'd split right away,
we'd be on the Dan Ryan by now.
Hey, Steve, we
could just turn around.
We're only 30 seconds from
freedom. We are not pussing out now.
And no more smoke
signals from you. Got it?
Hey, Sam, you gotta
fill out the discharge.
Admin says we gotta be really
tight about prisoner paperwork.
Check in Sutures. I think
I might have left it in there.
Okay, Abigail?
Something's wrong.
- Something's wrong.
- Hey, sheriff, hold up.
Hey. Hey, bring it
back here a minute.
Come on!
Get in!
- What the hell happened?
- Get in!
Steve, just go! Stop! Just go!
Think about Alex. Steve, stop.
I already did.
- Alex!
- Get back!
Go!
Damn it.
If you're good to walk, move
out into the bay. The ER is closed.
Emergency, emergency. We
got shots fired by and at police.
I got officers down
at County General.
If you got someone hurt by you
or if you're hurt, give us a sign.
- We can move people.
- Vehicle heading north...
from the hospital on Franklin.
- You okay, honey?
- I think so.
- Is this okay?
- Please. Need a doc here.
Hey, buddy.
- Do you know what day it is? Neck.
- Axilla too.
Can we get a gurney
in here, please?
- Airway's okay.
- Pulse thready.
Page Surgery. You're
gonna be fine, all right?
Yeah, he's coming this way.
He's pretty bad. We'll take care of it.
Hey, find Kovac. Jerry's hurt.
- It's hard to breathe.
- He saved me.
- I almost got shot.
- Zadro, get a gurney.
Wow. Getting shot sucks.
Here. JERRY: Ow!
Is that better?
- Thanks, kid.
- Right, set up for a chest tube.
- O2, 100 percent nonrebreather.
- Radial pulse strong. You're good, Jerry.
- Jerry, man, what'd you do?
- I'm a big target.
Oh, tell Frank I can't cover
for him on Friday, okay?
- This is on you, man.
- Just shut up. Shut up.
- Keep driving.
- Where to?
Put some distance between us.
- We'll figure it out later.
- We need to figure...
Just shut the hell up.
You probably killed someone
back there, Steve. One of my friends.
I thought you said you
were turning yourself around.
I've been praying, Sam.
And asking God to
make me a better man.
And it took a while, but he
finally started talking back.
That's not God.
He said losing you
was where I went wrong.
Everything would be right in my
garden if I could only get my family back.
Did he tell you
to do it with guns?
Curtis. Steve Curtis.
He's down to 80 systolic.
The other one, I don't
know. There's a chart.
- Where's Sam? Have you talked to her?
- We haven't located your nurse yet.
We're still looking.
- I'll be right back.
- Lot of pressure here, pal.
Ah! Oh, man,
I'm not liking that.
You had to go and get shot. I was
three hours away from a clean getaway.
- I can't find it.
- Keep looking.
They taking him up to Surgery?
He arrested after the
thoracotomy. They're not optimistic.
- I can't do this.
- He's a big man. Go supraclavicular.
- Supraclavicular?
- Ray, sew this in for me.
The junction of the subclavian
and the IJ is a bigger target.
- Are you okay, Abby?
- Yeah, I'm just, um...
I'm all dizzy. I hit my head.
I'll prime the rapid infuser.
Enter at the clavisternomastoid
angle. And, bingo, we're in.
Ladokern Pharmaceuticals
is gonna be lucky to have you.
Ray, did Luka take
your cop up to the O.R.?
I haven't seen him. I
thought he was with you.
Is this something
I never get over?
No.
This is something you find a place
to put and let it make you stronger.
Then you go on living your life,
because that's all you can do.
That's the way he
would have wanted it.
I think there's something
going on at the hospital.
- Dropped his pressure.
- How you doing?
Time for you to say
something intended to be funny.
- Got to be bleeding in the belly.
- Belly is clear.
- Well, we're missing something.
- Units three and four going up.
- He needs a second chest tube.
- First one's in a good position.
- He had less than 500 cc's out.
- There's more in there.
- I don't see a hemothorax.
- They wouldn't let us down.
- What the hell happened?
- The O.K. Corral.
Oh, my God. Jerry.
- Any free fluid? RAY:
He may need a CT.
- It's not the belly.
- Morris.
Dr. Weaver, look at the film.
The right hemithorax is
slightly opaque. That's blood.
Don't see an air-fluid
level because he's flat.
- The first tube should've drained it.
- Not if it's kinked or clotted.
Oh. Oh...
- Okay. Over a liter in the chest.
- Where's another Thora-Seal?
- Next door, I think. ABBY:
All right. Be right back.