Good morning.
Hey.
Saw you posted a picture
at Wine Fest. How was it?
Great until I got drunk off a
flight of Pinots from Oregon.
Thought you didn't
care for Pinot.
Well, I don't, but Phillip...
Just thought I would try
something different.
Glad you had a good time.
Thanks.
Dr. Manning?
Yeah.
Treatment four.
Sixteen-year old female,
thirty-eight weeks pregnant.
Rear-ended
while she was driving.
Now, I cleared her C-spine
and she has labs brewing,
but I figured you could
check her cervix
before calling the OB.
Sure.
Great.
Lily? Hi, I'm Dr. Manning.
I understand you're 38 weeks.
Are you family?
I'm her father, yes.
Joseph Cooper.
And this is Edie Thompson.
I'm not family exactly.
She's, uh...
She's adopting my baby.
Great. All right, well,
let's take a look.
Thanks.
Baby looks healthy
and the placenta looks good.
All right, Lily,
if it's okay with you,
I'm going to ask
your dad and Edie
to step out of the room
while I check your cervix.
Okay.
We'll be right outside, honey.
Thank you.
All right, now you let me know
if anything's uncomfortable
or if you feel any pain, okay?
Mmm-hmm.
All right, if you could just
put your knees up
and then let them fall open.
Thank you.
All right, you ready?
You okay?
Everything okay?
Yeah, everything's fine.
I'm feeling that you're two
centimeters dilated
and seeing that you started
contractions.
What does that mean?
Oh, I think the car accident
caused you to start labor.
You've got to stop it.
I don't want to see the baby.
That's why I scheduled
a c-section.
I'm sorry, Lily,
but it doesn't work that way.
Um, you can't stop labor
once the baby is full term.
I just want to be
put to sleep and wake up
with it gone, okay?
I will call Labor and Delivery
and see what we can do, okay?
Now what's that
called again?
Turmeric latte
with macadamia nut milk.
Whatever happened
to just plain old coffee?
Okay, okay.
Now just a reminder.
According to our calendar,
next Wednesday we got that
appointment with a broker
to find you an apartment.
Danny, why are you talking
about something that's not
happening for a week?
Cece, this stuff is not gonna
take care of itself.
Yeah, but can't we just
visit with people?
We're visiting!
You know Dad likes to plan.
Yeah, I guess he never
read Be Here Now.
I'm here now.
Gwen, I want to be absolutely
clear on this, okay?
From what I am seeing,
this growth you keep
talking about is
virtually nonexistent.
I am confident we'll see
a marked increase
next quarter.
Next quarter?
That's what you said
last quarter.
Mr. Rhodes?
Dad? Dad, hey.
Hey, easy there. Easy.
Is everything all right?
I'm fine.
Just give us a minute,
will you? Thank you.
Okay.
Your pulse is racing
and you can't catch
your breath.
Incompetence makes my blood
boil. What can I say?
You having chest pains?
No.
Really?
Dad, there is clearly
something going on
with your heart.
We should get you seen
by a cardiologist.
Well, that's not gonna
happen today. I've got
too much on my plate.
Just let me take
you to the ED.
I'll check you out myself.
It'll only take a couple
of minutes, I promise.
Connor, please. Just stop it,
all right? I'm absolute...
Ooh.
Hey. So, good news.
Dr. Patchefsky called
and she can schedule you
for a c-section today,
if you still wanna do that.
So that means the baby's
coming today?
Mmm-hmm.
Oh, that's... That's
incredible. I... I have to
text Howard.
Are you sure you're okay,
sweetie? I know this is a lot.
I'm ready to get it
over with, Dad.
All right, well, we'll send
you upstairs as soon as a bed
becomes available, okay?
And where's Lily at?
Lily Cooper?
David, what are
you doing here?
Hi, Jessie told me.
Are you all right?
You need to leave.
It's okay, Dad.
I'm fine, but they say
the baby's coming out today.
It... It's happening now?
You better go, David.
That's right!
I'm ready to take care
of you and our baby.
You're telling me this now?
Yeah, you never
answer my calls.
All right, I get that
you're mad.
When you told me,
I'd just lost my job
and my mom was sick
and I freaked out.
But I got a good job
now, all right?
They're paying me
12 an hour at the...
At the tire and rim...
It's too late, David!
No, listen, listen, they're
giving me full-time hours.
That's enough!
You need to leave.
No, no. This isn't about me.
Maybe I should wait
in the lobby?
No, no. He's the one
who's leaving.
Hey, Maggie, call security?
Dad, stop! Please!
Don't touch me.
All right, I'm going to
need you to wait
in the lobby, okay?
But that... That's my baby!
Not anymore!
Security.
Wait, what does that mean?
What does that...
What does that mean? Lily?
I'm giving the baby up.
Did he talk you into this?
Hey, hey!
Hey, that's my kid!
You can't take... No, no!
You can't just take my kid.
Let's go, son.
Hey, hey!
I'm the father! I have a say!
Hey! Let go! Hey, no!
You can't take me from my kid!
That's my kid! Let go!
You can't do this!
David Novak?
Hi.
I'm Sharon Goodwin,
Director of Patient Services.
Why don't we have a seat?
I want to see Lily.
I understand that.
Hey, no, no, then tell this
rent-a-cop to back off.
I'm sorry but it's
hospital policy
to restrict access
only to those visitors
approved by our patients.
That's my baby she's having.
I don't have any rights?
According to
the adoption papers,
Lily is not certain
who the birth father is.
No, that's crazy.
All right, I'm... I'm the only
one she's ever been with.
All right, her dad is just
making her say that
so that he can give
this baby away.
How old are you, David?
Seventeen... And a half.
How did you and Lily meet?
How did we meet?
Well, I like to hear
those stories.
I saw her in...
In line at the cafeteria.
Oh, so you met at school.
Yeah, Marie Curie.
Archer Heights?
Well, let me...
Let me ask you,
is there anyone
that I can help you
with this situation?
A family member?
Maybe someone who can
speak to Lily's father?
No.
You know, technically,
I'm not supposed to do this,
but let me recommend a lawyer
for you, someone who
specializes in Family Law.
I just need to get to Lily
before my kid is born.
Can you... Can you help
me with that?
I'm sorry, David. I can't.
Hey, Maggie?
Yeah.
Can you see if you can
rustle up an EKG
and chest x-ray in two?
And have cardiology
come down to do a stat echo.
Sure thing.
Thank you.
You're examining your father?
Just a cursory
cardiac check-up.
Huh. A doctor shouldn't
be treating a close
family member,
especially one
with a fraught history.
Whatever you're doing, Ava,
I'm not interested.
What I'm doing is rising above
any personal animus
I might have to help
a colleague.
Well, this colleague
doesn't need your help.
Thank you.
All right. Take a deep breath.
And exhale.
Saw you with your little
friend out there. What were
you two talking about?
Well, there's some fluid
in your lungs which explains
the shortness of breath.
And I'm picking up
a heart murmur.
I know about the murmur.
My GP told me about that
a long time ago.
You know what?
Excuse me. I'm done.
I'm gonna get dressed.
Fine. I will get started
on your discharge.
Tell me if this hurts,
okay, Joshua?
Okay.
His temperature was 102,
which didn't seem crazy to me
because he was already
home sick from school,
you know?
But I called his mom and she
said just take him to the ER.
Where is my mom?
She's on her way, buddy.
Okay? Don't worry.
I'm gonna need to
draw a little blood
from you, Joshua,
in order to run some tests.
Would that be okay? Great.
I'm just gonna go find one
of our super nice nurses
to help us out.
I'll be right back.
And my car key
is in the diaper bag.
Okay? All right.
Thanks.
Are you sure you can't come
upstairs while he gets his
shots?
I mean, Vincent's so much
calmer with you.
I gotta work, Emily.
He'll be fine.
Hey, Ethan.
Hey.
April, got a patient.
Okay, bye.
Bye.
Sorry I'm late.
What? Just say it.
You know better than anyone
my sister is trouble,
and yet here you are
letting her
take over your life.
I am helping out
a young mother who also
happens to be your sister.
Dr. Choi? I gotta make a phone
call. Is it okay if I step
outside for a second?
Sure, we'll keep
an eye on Joshua.
That kid in seven's been
battling a persistent fever.
I need a CBC, CMP
and some cultures, please.
All right.
And the baby looks good,
so we're gonna take you up
and get you prepped
for the c-section.
Are you ready?
I guess.
It's going to be fine.
Hey, Maggie, will you page OB
and tell them we're
on our way up?
Copy that.
Thanks.
David.
Don't worry, I'm gonna
take care of everything.
What are you doing?
Whoa. David, put that down.
You think I'm gonna
let you come in here
and steal my kid?
Dad, Dad, Dad, no. Dad, stop!
Security, code silver!
Active threat in the ED!
Dad! Dad!
Oh, my God.
David, no. David.
Drop your weapon!
Oh, my God.
Dad!
David!
No, no, no, no...
Dad!
Stop! Stop!
No, drop it! Drop it! Now!
Frank, listen to the man.
Listen to him.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
I'm a doctor!
Let me just take a look.
Okay.
Don't move! Don't!
What's happening?
Was that a gun?
Shh. Stay quiet.
Just stay quiet.
Hey, hey, hey!
I said stop moving!
Dad!
Stop moving!
Dad, Dad, are you okay?
Please help my dad!
I'm a doctor. I can help.
Get... Get in there. Now.
This room here?
Yeah, yeah. Now, now.
Dad!
We need to help this man.
Daddy! Dad!
It wasn't my fault.
But you don't want him
to die, do you?
No. Help him, help him.
Okay.
Help him.
Lily?
Yeah. Yeah, yeah, okay.
Yeah, yeah. Okay.
Hey, hey, hey!
Hey! How do I lock the doors?
You need keys.
Get them!
Now! Now!
Easy, easy!
All right, lock
all the doors. Now!
Hey, they...
Hey, they can see me!
Hey, they can see
right through.
They're gonna shoot me!
All right.
Hey, you!
I have to cover the windows!
What do I use?
I don't know.
How about...
How about the sheets?
All right, you have
lots of those, right?
All right, do it. Now.
You... You help him.
Let's go.
Maggie, what's going on?
Hey, hey, kid. I need to get
this guy to a trauma room now.
Do you understand me?
Yeah, okay.
Maggie, I need
a backboard now.
Got it.
David, they're going
to need my help to lift him.
All right.
But right after, you're right
back where I can
see you, okay?
All right, keep
pressure on it.
I'll be right back.
Okay.
Come on, man.
All right, all right.
There we go.
Dad? Dad, are you okay?
Listen, I just want to get
my girlfriend and my baby
out of here.
I don't want to hurt
anybody else, but I will
if you get in my way.
Hey, you. Back where you were.
I got this.
How's he doing?
Not good, David.
He's bleeding
from inside his chest.
Well, it's his fault.
He grabbed the gun.
Breathe, breathe.
I don't care.
He needs to go
upstairs for surgery.
No. He stays here, all right?
He might not make it if you
don't let him go upstairs.
Okay, breathe, yeah.
You're a doctor.
Do something!
I need blood, plasma,
and platelets.
Now! Otherwise he dies.
Okay, what do I...
What do I do?
Pick up any one of those
phones and dial 911
and tell them who you are.
They'll find someone
for you to ask.
Now!
Okay.
He's got a pulmonary embolism.
So let East Mercy
know he's on a heparin drip
and monitor
his vitals closely.
Yes, Doctor.
Is this the last
of our emergency patients?
The last we could get out.
Miss Goodwin, the gunman
just called with a list
of supplies they need.
He's insisting
that you bring
the supplies in.
Me?
Yeah, he says you tried
to help him.
It seems he doesn't
trust anyone else.
You're completely dilated.
We have to deliver the baby.
No, I don't want
to push it out.
I know this isn't
how you wanted it to happen
but we cannot wait any longer.
Can't you just do
the c-section?
It's not safe to do it here.
I'm sorry, Lily,
but I need you
to deliver this baby.
Okay? I'll be right back.
Hey.
Hey, hey, whoa, whoa.
Hey, stay there.
What do you want?
Lily's about to deliver.
I just need you
to get me a precip pack.
It's for the delivery.
They're in the blue boxes
in the Pyxis.
Okay, just right over there.
You heard her.
You get it.
Go, now.
You get in there.
Go. Now, now.
Just breathe. It's okay.
You're okay, you're okay.
Just keep breathing.
You're doing great.
It's going to be okay,
Lily. I promise.
It's going to be okay.
You shot my dad.
Keep breathing, Lily.
It was an accident.
I swear... I swear it was.
But there's a doctor
looking at him...
There's a doctor looking
at him right now, all right?
And it... It's going to be
okay. I promise you.
He's going to be okay.
Dr. Manning is gonna need
another set of hands
to deliver your child.
Okay, yeah.
Help her, help her,
help her, help her, help her.
You've got this,
Lily. Keep breathing.
I just couldn't let him
take our baby like that, Lily.
I could... I couldn't do it.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Yeah, you're doing
great, Lily.
Just keep looking
at me, okay? Breathe.
Breathe with me, Lily.
We can raise
this kid together.
I know we can.
And I know that's
what you want too.
No. I just want my life
to go back to normal.
I wanna finish high school.
I wanna go to college.
No, no, no, no.
That's your dad
talking, all right?
And I'm gonna fix everything
as soon as we get out of here.
Hey.
Get back! Get back!
Hey, hey, get back!
You stay where
I can see you. All right?
You! You.
Get those cuffs. Now.
Don't move or I'll kill you.
Cuff him to that desk.
I want my mommy!
Take... Take care of that kid.
Baby, let's get you back
in the bed, come on!
Just get back
in the bed, okay?
Easy. Take it easy.
Take down these curtains!
I will shoot the next person
that tries anything!
Sharon, please.
Let me switch places with you.
I... I have a tremendous
amount of experience
dealing with people
in David's emotional state.
It's what I'm trained to do.
Oh, well, I appreciate
it, Daniel,
but I think we should follow
David's instructions.
Okay, this is everything
on the list.
All right,
thank you, Monique.
Okay, listen, people who are
as desperate as he is,
they need to know
that there's a possibility
of a happy ending.
Daniel, I'm going to be okay.
I really want you
to be careful, okay?
I know.
Be careful.
I will.
Miss Goodwin.
I need to show you something
before you go in.
Now, the gunman has
blanketed the windows
to obscure our view,
but there is a small gap
that gives James
here a clean shot.
Now go ahead, have a look.
That's the kill zone.
Uh, look, I'd like to
get this resolved
without anyone else...
Getting hurt.
I understand.
But that young man
has already shot two people.
You walk him into that spot
and no one else gets hurt.
All right?
Good luck in there.
Open it!
Get in!
Keys, keys, keys.
David.
David, what are you
doing with the gun?
Just help me. Okay?
He's that way.
Come on.
Sharon?
All right, hang one to one to
one on the rapid transfuser
and keep going.
Do not let his
blood pressure drop.
Got it.
Do you know how the other
patients are doing?
My father's in two.
He's got something going on
with his heart.
Earl got hit by a bullet.
Ethan said he was going
to be okay.
And April's got
a sick kid in seven.
Chest tube auto
transfuser's full.
All right, run it back to him.
Got it.
How's he doing?
His heart rate will come down,
thanks to the blood,
but he's still hemorrhaging
into his chest.
If we don't get him upstairs
soon, we're gonna lose him.
Okay.
David, Lily's father is not
going to last much longer
down here.
But the doctor said he needed
blood and they got him blood.
He needs surgery and
a full trauma team
if he's going to survive.
Just Lily's dad. No one else.
But I've got
a very sick little boy
down there
and... And a man
with a bad heart.
They need to go too.
No.
Just Lily's dad,
and then we'll see.
Okay. Okay.
Dr. Rhodes, get your patient
ready to move out of the ED.
We're going to wheel him out.
Whoever's back there, back up!
All right.
Wait!
Hey, hey, hey! Back up!
I swear to God, I'll kill her.
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
I swear to God!
Lower your weapons!
Step back! We need to move
this patient through!
Back up! Back up!
Lower your weapons!
Back up now! Now!
Move, move, move, move, move.
Okay, grab this. Move, move!
Move, move, move!
Close it!
Close it now! Now!
You better not try
anything else!
David, please.
Let me talk to the police
for you, try to figure
a way out of this.
No!
Hey, I need a doctor in here.
This boy is not responding
to his medication.
I can't get his fever down.
David, please, just uncuff me,
so I can check on him.
Do you think I'm stupid?
Deal with the kid yourself.
Nat, fetal heart tones just
flipped to the other side.
I just felt something shift.
Does that mean
the baby's coming out?
Let me see.
The baby just went transverse.
Wait, what does that mean?
The baby's turned sideways
in her uterus.
She can't deliver like that.
So what happens now?
We need to move her upstairs.
No, you do it here.
Well, then I need you
to get me something
out of the Pyxis.
A medication, Terbutaline.
I'll get it.
Just look at me.
Look at me.
Breathe.
Good.
Are you gonna turn the baby?
Water hasn't broken yet,
and the Terbutaline
should soften her uterus.
She's in labor.
We could cause a placental
abruption or a prolapse.
Well, he's not giving me
any other choice.
All right, breathe, breathe,
breathe... Hey, look at me.
Breathe. That's good.
106 over 66. Heart rate's 122.
All right, let's give 10 of
Lasix and 12.5 of metoprolol
on an IV drip.
All right.
What is it?
I don't know, Dad.
But something's not right.
This is your fault!
I should have never let you
convince me to come here
in the first place.
If...
Dad?
Hey! Hey, hey, hey, hey!
He's not breathing.
Start bagging.
No pulse. He's in V-tach.
I need the paddles!
Sharon, we need you in here!
He's in cardiac arrest!
We need the paddles.
Okay.
Charge to 200.
Charged.
Clear.
No pulse. Milligram of epi.
Epi's in.
All right, I've got a pulse.
He's back in sinus rhythm.
Dad, Dad? Can you hear me?
All right.
I want to do an echo.
We need to figure out
what's going on.
Got you.
Okay, okay.
Okay. Okay, okay.
All right.
Hang in there, Joshua. Okay?
Ethan, I still can't get this
fever under control.
His BP's in the tank.
He just seized.
Almost aspirated himself.
Sounds like he's
in septic shock.
He needs more volume
and pressors to get
his pressure up.
You're gonna need to do
a central line right away.
I've never done one.
It'll be okay.
I'll walk you through it.
Okay.
That man needs
to be moved upstairs.
He just had a heart attack.
No. No, no, no, no!
Not after what
happened last time!
If he dies, they're going to
hold you responsible.
I didn't do anything
to hurt him!
It'll be the same
as if you had.
Look, David, I know you didn't
want any of this to happen,
and it's not too late
to walk it back.
They were taking
your child away.
That's something anyone
can understand.
Please let these people go.
No, no! Because then
I go to prison
and then my kid
is just gone forever!
Lily? Lily?
She's hypotensive.
What's that?
Her blood pressure's dropping.
She must be bleeding
from somewhere.
We are losing the baby.
Fix it!
We need to do a c-section
now or you're going to
lose them both.
Well, if either of them die,
I'm gonna kill you.
Hey!
Fix it!
Now!
He's got a hole
in his heart between
the left and right atria.
He's in heart failure.
Can you repair it?
Not here.
I need to get him upstairs.
No, don't do that.
Don't let me die.
No, Dad. I won't, Dad.
Dr. Rhodes?
Lily needs your help.
I'm not leaving my father.
Connor, I think
her uterus ruptured.
She needs immediate surgery
before she and the baby
bleed to death.
I will do the surgery
if you agree to transfer
my father upstairs.
No, you fix him here.
I can't!
He needs an operating room
with a bypass machine!
Operate on Lily
or I will kill you
right here.
You want to kill
the only person
who can save her?
I will
transfer his father.
And I give you my word,
I will not let SWAT in.
Please, David,
Lily and the baby
are losing valuable time.
David.
Okay.
Go.
All right.
Bring whatever blood we have
to the hybrid OR.
Prep her belly, scrub in.
I'm gonna need your help.
Daniel, I'm... I'm bringing
another patient out.
But it's getting out of hand
in here and I need you
to keep the SWAT back.
What's the status
on the target?
I haven't been able to get
a clean shot yet.
Can you contact them?
TOC, TOC, Commander.
I want that Bearcat G3 prepped
and ready for dynamic entry.
Over?
Copy that.
Yeah?
Sorry, Captain.
Just out of curiosity,
what is a... A Bearcat? A G3?
That's an armored vehicle.
Kid's already unhinged.
We don't want to do anything
to make him think
he's got to shoot
his way out of there.
Miss Goodwin's doing
a pretty good job.
We already got
one hostage out,
bringing another.
Don't we want to give
her some more time?
That kid is a ticking
time bomb.
We cannot wait for him
to just go off.
Okay, I'm ready.
Insert the needle
at a 45 degree angle,
and then aim the needle
toward your index finger.
Josh's vein is right under
the clavicle.
Okay, I'm doing it.
Withdraw from the syringe
until you get blood.
There's no blood.
I'm just getting air.
It's okay.
Just pull back
ever so slightly.
Change your angle
and try again.
Okay. Okay, I got it.
Good. Now feed the wire in.
Okay, okay.
His sats are dropping.
April, you need to finish
the line quickly and then
insert a chest tube.
A chest tube? Ethan, no.
That air you got?
That was his lung collapsing.
He needs a chest tube
to breathe.
Daniel?
We're here, Sharon.
I've got a gun on me.
So if anyone charges through
when we open this door...
No one's gonna do that.
I promise you.
You can open the door.
He's my friend.
I trust him.
Give me the patient.
Sats are good. Ketamine's in.
Everybody ready?
Mmm-hmm.
Okay.
Her uterus ruptured.
Wait, what's happening?
I don't know.
The baby's floating
in the abdomen.
Need suction.
I'm in there.
There we go.
Mom's pressure is crashing.
O neg's running in.
All right, we're losing her.
Keep suction going. More laps.
More!
Don't let her die!
You hear me?
Okay.
Make an incision
next to his nipple,
about an inch and a half
over the top of the rib.
Okay.
Now take the big clamp.
Place it into the incision
and push until the clamp
pops into his chest.
It's not going.
This isn't working.
Push harder.
If I hit a lung
or the heart...
April, trust me.
Push harder.
I got a rush of air.
Sats are coming up.
Good job.
Okay.
What's happening
with the baby?
His color's coming back.
He's stable for now.
Guys, I need a little
help over here.
Wait, what about Lily?
She's lost a lot of blood.
What... What have we got left?
I'm hanging
my last two of FFP.
She's not stable.
All right, keep suctioning.
Yeah.
I can't see a thing.
All right, the rupture
extended into
the uterine artery.
All right, keep suction going.
She's bottoming out, Connor.
You said you could
stop the bleeding!
We had a deal, all right?
Your father for Lily!
All right, hold on. Hold on.
I think I got it.
Got it!
Give me an O prolene
on a needle.
Pressure's rising.
Bleeding's under control.
All right, let's finish
this and then we'll
close the uterus.
See? Lily's okay.
They stopped
the bleeding and...
And your baby's here.
You can still have
a meaningful life
with him, David.
Please put the gun down.
I promise to help
make sure this baby
stays a part of your life.
No.
I'm taking Lily and my baby
and we're getting out of here.
My baby?
It's a healthy boy.
Hey, Lily, we're gonna go
right now, all right?
That's not happening.
She can barely move
in her condition.
Stop talking.
We gotta go. Lily, we gotta go
right now. All right?
David, no.
No, listen, all we gotta do
is get to the neighborhood,
all right?
Because I know people
who'll help us get out.
I promise, it's gonna
be okay. All right?
No.
It's over, David. It's over.
If you change your mind,
when you do, call my mom.
She'll tell you to get in
contact with me and the baby.
David.
What are you doing?
Give me my son.
I can't do that, David.
Get back. Get back.
Everyone back
against the wall now.
Miss Goodwin, hand him over.
I said I'd help you, David,
and I meant that.
But I'm not giving
you this baby.
I'm not leaving here
without my son.
Sharon?
You don't have a choice.
No, you don't have a choice.
I will kill everyone
in this hospital
before I leave my son.
Then you're gonna
have to start with me.
Give me my son.
David! No!
David! David!
Stay... Stay with me, David.
Move, move, move, move!
Stay with me, David.
Target is down.
Target is down...
Stay with me.
David? Stay with me.
Weapons down!
Let's go! Clear the area!
Susie. Do you know
who did his surgery?
Yes, I believe
it was Dr. Bekker.
You did the surgery?
He had an atrial septal defect
the size of the Chicago Bean.
But fortunately, yes,
I was able to patch it.
I saved his life,
but I suppose
this is the closest
you can come to
saying thank you.
I'll be back later
to check on my patient.
Hello, Dr. Manning.
Hi. I'm glad to see you're
feeling better.
Just wanted to come in
and check and see
if you needed anything.
Hi. Lily Cooper?
Dr. Lang cleared the baby.
I'm having a hard time finding
the adoptive mom, though.
Edie Thompson, right?
I saw her leave
the hospital.
I don't think she'll
be coming back.
I'll call
the agency tomorrow.
Have them find
another couple. I'm sure
it won't be a problem.
Can you take him back
to the nursery until we get
this straightened out?
Hang on a second.
Lily, is there something
you want to say?
Would it be okay
if I hold him?
Honey.
Just for a little bit.
Of course.
Hi.
There you go.
Sweetie.
Dad?
Lily.
But he's mine, Dad.
What?
Will?
When everything first started,
you could've gotten out.
But you came back for me.
I know that.
Thank you.
Agent Lee?
Will, Dr. Manning.
Is the FBI involved?
No, this is a CPD matter.
I heard about what happened.
Are you two okay?
I was worried about you.
I'm all right, Ingrid. Thanks.
I should get going.
Good night.