Do you see them anywhere?
Why don't we go back to their
house, wait for them there?
Yeah, because they'll
probably answer the door
the 16th time I knock.
There they are.
Hi. I'm sorry I
followed you here.
I just really wish you could give
me a few minutes of your time.
I know you never agreed
to make it an open adoption,
but I just figured maybe
you never had a choice.
I mean, it's China, right?
What did he say?
He wants you to
leave them alone.
Please.
I just want 10 minutes.
Learn what you're like,
tell you about my life.
He said they have no daughter.
I am sorry you wasted a trip.
I know that's them.
How does that work?
How do I pray?
You make a wish
and lift the Buddha.
I wish they could understand
how badly I need this.
Now make the wish again.
If you cannot lift the Buddha
this time, your wish will be granted.
Are you okay?
Picked Cameron's pocket down
in the ER. Came up with a doozy.
Your mother called. Twice.
But she's still healthy. This
25-year-old woman, on the other hand...
Her messages
sounded kind of urgent.
Well, that's the way women sound
when their spouse of 50 years dies.
Your dad died? Are you...
Yep, fine. Our patient,
who's been known to take a
few drinks on non-occasions,
vomits blood and
collapses on a trip to China.
Chinese surgeons
cut out a foot of bowel,
but the pain is worse
now than it was before.
House, call your mom.
What are you, my mom?
We can continue this
differential in five minutes.
Are those bags under your
eyes? You were up all night.
You told her, didn't you?
I don't know what your daddy issues
are, but don't deflect them on me.
Told his wife he's been
getting some strange.
She kicked his adulterous
tuchus to the curb.
Seriously? You told her?
Yes, I told her,
but, no, she did not
kick me to the curb.
We stayed up late talking.
We're going to continue talking.
Much like House should be
doing with his mother right now.
Anybody read Chinese?
Otherwise, we have no idea
what these doctors did to her.
Kutner, you're sort of
Asian, right? Get it translated.
What about Meckel's
diverticulum?
If the surgeons didn't
remove the diverticulum,
it could cause pain, bleeding.
Too high up for a colonoscopy.
CT could miss it.
Ultrasound's fastest.
And since I'm the fastest
with the ultrasound...
House. Let me do the ultrasound.
You need to deal with
your dad and stop...
I'm not deflecting because
I'm avoiding something deep.
I'm deflecting because I'm
avoiding something shallow.
Seriously, I'm fine. I
didn't even like the man.
No Meckel's.
You there for the rice or
the re-education camps?
I was there to track down
my biological parents.
Like a salmon returning to
the stream where it was born.
Did you become whole again
or did you get eaten by bears?
They denied my existence.
Four parents and not one of them
taught you to cover your mouth.
My God, it looks like
they cut you in half.
Doctor, we're
her parents, I'm...
I'm just a technician.
Her doctors will be by later,
you can schmooze then.
Can you let them know that
we went by her apartment,
collected all her medications...
I'm a technician and a doctor.
You went through my apartment?
We found alcohol.
We thought you'd quit.
Did her drinking cause this? No.
Can you tell her it did?
Licorice root.
No, thanks, I'm good.
I threw it to you for a reason.
It's what the Chinese
doctors gave her.
It contains glycyrrhizin.
They were treating her for SARS?
Not very effectively. But
SARS explains the cough,
causes hypoperfusion, which
explains the ischemic bowel. It's perfect.
Lung involvement
isn't very severe.
Okay, well, so call it ARS.
Start her on ribavirin
and interferon.
I'm sorry about your father.
I'm not.
Are we done emoting now?
If there's anything
I can do, just...
You know, you're right. I don't
think I can sleep alone tonight.
Tell me that is liquid Vicodin.
We're giving IG
shots to everyone
who came in contact
with your patient.
Shockingly, none of the nurses
volunteered to administer yours.
It goes better in
a large muscle.
Drop your pants.
You know, I usually pay
tens of dollars to hear that.
The funeral's tomorrow.
My mom called you?
There is a 3:40
flight out of Newark.
If you leave now, you
can be in Lexington tonight.
Your mother wants
you to deliver a eulogy.
Eulogy, from the
Greek for "good word."
Now if she'd asked me to deliver
a bastardogy, I'd be happy to...
Then be a grownup.
Call your mother back
and tell her you're
sick with grief,
but you're too busy to be there.
She knows when I'm lying.
Then start writing.
I yanked my brother
and sister out of college?
Can you please tell
them I'm not dying?
You have SARS.
I'm wearing a mask.
It's a big deal. Cut
them some slack.
But I am going
to be okay, right?
That's what all
this stuff is for.
We're gonna need the
names and numbers
of everyone you
came in contact with
here and in China.
Flight numbers, dates.
That doctor that I coughed all
over, is he gonna be all right?
So far, he's fine.
It's back. This is where
the pain all started.
She's tachycardiac.
Get a crash cart in here!
What's going on?
I need to know what's
going on. That's my daughter.
Her liver's failing.
It's not SARS.
I am not doing
this because I care.
Cuddy drugged me. She...
My mom didn't call
Cuddy. She called you.
I knew you couldn't stay away.
I knew you loved me too much.
I'm doing this for your mom.
I'm not doing this at all.
If there was
something to be done,
I would have done it in
the year he spent dying.
You took my Vicodin?
I'm in pain.
One?
So the Vicodin is my leash.
One will take the edge off,
but it won't give
me enough relief
for an escape
back to Plainsboro.
Where's my phone?
It's the team, it's
their ring tone.
Forget it. The patient's
blood is on your hands.
House? You there?
I'm being held against
my will. Call the police.
Nicole had a clot
in the hepatic vein.
Chase sucked it
out, saved her liver.
No signs of a tumor or venous
malformations, nothing that could cause...
She's an addict. Drugs
and alcohol wouldn't...
She's a smoker.
Combine smoking with any
one of a dozen genetic disorders
and she's a clotting machine.
Multiple blood clots
would tie together
bowel ischemia,
lungs and the liver.
We need to pinpoint
which defect she has
so we can start her on
the right anti-coagulant.
Draw blood.
Let's find out which genetic
gift her genetic parents gave her.
Thanks for calling.
My ring tone for you is
Dancing Queen by Abba.
Nicole?
I need to pee. Pull
over at the next stop.
I'll just pee on the floor.
You bought used floor
mats? That is brilliant.
There's a rest
stop in five miles.
Cane. The
restroom's right there.
You can make it on your own.
I suppose I could
talk about the summer
he decided he
wasn't speaking to me.
Two months. Not one word.
Anything he wanted
to say, he typed up
and slipped under
my bedroom door.
You don't want to say anything,
don't say anything, but go.
Tell your mom
you're sad. For her.
Just by being
there I'd be lying.
She wants to think, for a moment,
that she had a happy family.
So give her a gift. Lie.
Give me my cane, I'll
go to the damn funeral.
I said I'd go to the
funeral. I didn't say when.
We have these two
categories, inside and outside.
Patients stay inside,
then, when they're better,
we let them go outside.
Thanks, but they don't
let you smoke inside.
So why don't you go back there
and give me five
minutes outside?
Make a fist.
Such a beautiful day, we thought
we'd do all our doctoring outside.
People stare at me any
time I'm out with my family.
It's like a puzzle. Which one
of these things doesn't belong?
Belonging is overrated.
I was adopted by a white
family when I was nine.
I like being different. The view's
better from the outside looking in.
Must be easier to be different
when you're a success.
Is that a problem?
This is why we prefer inside.
You actually keep a flashlight
that doesn't need
batteries in the trunk?
Next to the jacket,
emergency water,
nail clippers,
toothbrush, space blanket.
When things go
wrong, I like to be ready.
Will you please hold the
flashlight for a minute?
You know, those
aren't just my car keys.
My house keys are on there, too.
Amber gave me that key chain.
No, she didn't.
Not unless your pet
name for her was "Volvo."
A man who would lie about a
gift from his dead girlfriend...
Is probably responding to a
childish, pointless act of petulance.
The struggle to resist one's
captors is never pointless.
Well, I hate to break it to you,
Che, but simple delay won't work.
Your mother will hold
the funeral till we get there.
My father was a punctual
man, beholden to time.
Two minutes late for
dinner, you didn't eat.
My mother would never disrespect
him by starting the funeral late.
Yeah, you clearly have
no issues to work through.
Come on, forget the
keys. Call a locksmith.
We'll go inside and
play Guess that Smell
with the truckers
while we're waiting.
Join me on the dark side.
Dark side's done, House.
I'm delivering you to
your mother, and that's it.
I've moved on.
What do you think
House would send?
The Gentle Comfort arrangement
or the Warm Thoughts bouquet?
I mean, if he wasn't an ass.
Send one of those giant
cookies shaped like a coffin.
His mom would
believe it was from him.
I didn't tell you so you
could send anything.
Just wanted you
to know the extent
to which the man is
disconnected from the human race.
Took a six pack of
FFP to stop the oozing.
She's bleeding and clotting?
Plus schistocytes on
her smear means it's DIC,
which means she's got cancer.
She's young. It
could be leukemia.
Normal WBC
makes that less likely.
Belly pain points
toward a GI tumor.
House already did an ultrasound.
He wasn't looking for
a tumor. Go run a CT.
I don't buy it.
CT can find small intestinal
cancers that an ultrasound...
I don't buy House.
When my father died, I wound up
killing a patient. And I hated the man.
Whatever House says or doesn't
say, I'm sure the guy's a mess.
So he was a bastard.
He was still your father.
You're biologically programmed
to have feelings for him.
No, I'm not.
Feelings aren't rational.
I know you have
trouble with anything
that can't be
quantified and counted.
He's not my biological father.
I figured it out when I was 12.
Of course.
You're a brilliant,
socially-isolated 12-year-old,
and you create a
parallel universe
in which your life doesn't suck.
I looked at the facts.
First of all, he was deployed
on training exercises off Okinawa
during the time I
had to be conceived.
And since you're 150 years
old, air travel was impossible.
His second toe was
longer than his big toe.
Mine isn't.
This is sad. You don't believe
your mother screwed around.
I have a distinctive red
birthmark on my scalp
that matches a certain
friend of the family.
If you believed this story, you wouldn't
be telling me about his birthmarks,
you'd be telling me about the
genetic testing you had done.
And since you haven't mentioned
it, obviously, you didn't do it,
because you don't want to...
House, what are you doing?
Get your... Get off
the... There's a cop.
Uh-oh!
Nicole, lie still. This will
only take a few seconds.
One-millimeter cut
through upper abdomen.
She was adopted when the parents
thought they couldn't have kids.
Then they had three more.
She took the message
as, "Thanks for playing,
"but we have our
real children now."
And the real children probably
think they were accidents
while she was hand-picked.
Everybody's got
problems with their parents.
She's an addict.
Something went wrong.
And it has to be the
parents? Magnifying pancreas.
I'm not saying the
parents screwed up.
You're saying you like her, so you
don't want her faults to be her fault.
But they're someone's fault, and
the only other people you know are...
I think we may need
to call House again.
You lost track of your speed?
I think that was Hitler's
excuse, "Lost track of the Jews."
No one held him responsible.
I'm not playing, House.
You were protecting me.
Anybody in their right mind
would have ratted me out.
I'm just trying to
speed things along.
You are going to this funeral.
Make it fast. I don't want to
miss the anal cavity search.
Looks like a mass
in the pancreas.
Not to me. This is radio.
And I want a full play-by-play.
It's fluid-filled.
Could you get out
of the car, please, sir?
Officer, if you want to give
me a ticket, I totally understand.
Just get out of the car, sir.
Cyst? FOREMAN: Large cyst.
Something going on there?
Wilson's getting
arrested. How large?
SUV-sized or midrange-sedan?
Seriously? What did you do?
I'm obviously joking.
If Wilson was getting
handcuffed on the hood of his car,
would I be carrying
on a differential?
Diameter's at least
eight centimeters.
Is it in the tail or the head?
The head.
You, too, sir, out of the car.
We've got a construction site.
A steamroller is plowing...
Out, now.
No cane.
James Evan Wilson. There's a
warrant for your arrest in Louisiana.
What are the traits
of a steamroller?
Powerful. Maybe
pancreatic cancer.
Great idea. Except
the only symptom
it matches up with is
being steamroller-ish.
You don't think House
is onto something?
I think he thought
he had an idea.
I also think his metaphors are tough
enough to decipher after he's said them.
We need to be
focusing on the medicine.
No answer.
There's not going to be an
answer. They've been arrested.
He was joking.
He reacted to the
size and location.
That's what we should be
focusing on, not playing Madlibs
while our patient's exploding "noun"
destroys her life-sustaining "noun."
I'll try to get
Wilson on the line.
What if it's not how a steamroller
works, but what it does?
Clears things.
It's a waste of time.
I need that phone call.
I'm a doctor.
When someone tries to call
you three times, it's code for
"Pick up the damn phone
before someone dies."
I'm sure there's
other smart doctors.
You'd be surprised.
You told me you'd
taken care of this.
I did.
The first words
you ever said to me.
I took care of it.
You must have
screwed up somehow.
Sir? Not to hurry you, but
we need to be at a funeral in...
Nobody is going anywhere
or taking any phone calls
till I hear back from Louisiana.
It's a really old warrant.
Isn't there a statute of
limitations on this kind of thing?
It's suspended when
you flee the state.
I didn't flee the
state, I left the state,
because I don't
live in the state.
And the charges
were just so minor...
"Vandalism, destruction
of property, assault..."
There is a simple explanation.
There was a medical
convention in New Orleans.
You don't need to explain to me.
I was fresh out of med school.
I didn't know anybody
at the convention.
You heard the man, Wilson.
You don't have to explain.
I am not going to
sit here wasting time
just so you can avoid
your father's funeral.
He's my father.
I have the right to
avoid his funeral.
Not if your mother's
alive, you don't.
Okay. Explain.
Did House react to
the eight centimeters?
He whistled. It's huge.
Anyone would think so.
House doesn't whistle
because he's impressed.
Means he wasn't expecting it.
Means he changed
his mind at that point.
A single super-sized cyst
ruled out a diffuse process,
like scleroderma or lupus.
Rule out diffuse process,
you're stuck with single process,
affecting just the pancreas.
Gallstones or
pancreatic divisum.
Whatever he asked next
would have narrowed that down.
He asked about location.
Heads, it's gallstones.
Tails, it's divisum.
It's at the head.
She's got gallstones.
The steamroller means
potholes, means...
Relax. We got it.
You figured out
she's got gallstones?
I was at the hotel bar,
trying to unwind with a drink.
There was this guy
who kept playing
Billy Joel's Leave a Tender
Moment Alone on the jukebox.
Leave a Tender
Moment is a good song.
It's a great song.
He was out of line.
Not as good as Scenes
from an Italian Restaurant or...
So I asked the
man to stop. Politely.
Yeah, you yelled politely.
I was polite the
first couple of times.
But courtesy made no
impression on this ass.
So I threw a bottle
into the mirror,
which successfully
conveyed my message.
And smashed a
10-foot antique mirror.
And set an example for two other
patrons, who threw shot glasses...
I had nothing to
do with that fight.
The assault charge
was totally bogus.
And I paid for the mirror.
I think I have the picture.
I assume you're the guy
who was playing the song.
No, I was the guy
who bailed him out.
That's how we
met. I was in jail.
This guy was a total stranger
to you, and you bailed him out?
It was a boring convention.
I had to have
somebody to drink with.
And there's the foundation
of our entire friendship.
If you hadn't been bored one
weekend, it wouldn't even exist.
Hey, with 3,000 people
at that convention,
you were the one I thought
wasn't boring. That says something.
It also says something
that you lied to me
about getting the
charges dropped.
I got a lawyer, he cut a
deal. You didn't call the guy?
You have to show up at the
arraignment. Everybody knows that.
Everybody with your
misdemeanor experience.
You can go.
What?
He's a fugitive from justice.
That whole story was
lies. He stabbed a man.
Louisiana doesn't want
to pay to get you back.
Forget Louisiana. He
was driving recklessly
through your comatose village.
What, do they put lead
in the jelly donuts here?
Stop acting like such an ingrate
and go pay your
respects to your father.
CT confirmed gallstones.
Normally not dangerous, almost
everyone has them, but sometimes...
They kill you?
Yup. Unless I take them out.
We do it laparoscopically.
Um...
How long has her
urine been brown?
Kidneys were
fine this afternoon.
They're not now.
It's not the gallstones.
Well, of course
it's not gallstones.
Who thought it was gallstones?
You said "steamroller."
I also said "construction site."
Gallstones could
cause a pancreatic cyst.
Just turn around. The thing
is two hours over already,
and that's the third time
we've passed that colonial
with the cross
burning out front.
I'm not lost.
I'm not talking about
what caused the cyst.
I'm talking about
what the cyst caused.
Everything.
Cysts are symptoms,
not diagnoses.
Unless it's a multiple cyst with
connections to other organs.
Like a steamroller.
That's a long road
down to the kidneys.
How do we prove it?
Won't be visible on a scan,
Chase isn't gonna
go groping around
when she's got kidney failure.
Bubbles.
Is that your new stripper name?
Yes.
And also, we inject bubbles into
the cyst and follow where they drift.
If they end up in her other organs, we
know you're right, cut it out, she's fine.
Bubbles is right. Go echo.
I'm not lost.
Nicole, you gotta stay still.
I'm nervous.
You're not nervous.
It's the DTs, isn't it?
I haven't had a
drink since I got here.
Good heavens. We
haven't missed it after all.
It's like the end of
A Christmas Carol.
I'm so glad you're here.
It's a load off of my
mind just to see you.
Thank you, James.
Mom, how could
you delay the funeral?
Honey, your dad is dead.
He's not going to care.
Do you know what
you're going to say?
I don't know. Just
let the minister,
or one of his buddies
from the Corps...
You're talking.
I don't care that
you didn't like him.
He was your father
and he loved you.
The war is over, Greg.
Please do this for me.
Stop looking so worried.
I know he's gonna make me proud.
I'm sure you know
him better than I do.
Her liver's been compromised.
And the DTs will
cause her muscles
to continue to twitch,
even under sedation.
We need to paralyze
her to do this procedure.
I wanted to stop.
A phenobarbital coma
will not only allow us
to inject the cyst,
it'll treat the DTs.
When she wakes up,
she won't be in withdrawal.
We've seen her through
withdrawal before.
We've seen her
through everything.
We've been supportive,
we've been combative.
We've picked her up from
bars in the middle of the night,
we've let her spend
the night in jail.
I used to say it would be
okay, that I'd get it together.
I don't say that anymore.
Let's make you healthy.
Then we'll worry about
making you sober.
The Lord is my
shepherd, I shall not want.
I am not talking.
We were strangers. We shared
some geography 30 years ago.
Right. He had no
influence on you at all.
The father who was
compulsive about punctuality.
His issue, which I
deliberately made not my issue.
Thereby making it your issue.
Compulsively showing
up four hours late,
ignoring discipline,
ignoring rules...
Oh, God. He's here.
Who's here?
The one you're
pretending is your father?
Nice pick, he looks
like Sean Connery.
So, back when you were devising
this fantasy, did you tell your father?
"Dad, I refuse to
recognize your existence
"because I've chosen
James Bond as my dad?"
I used different words.
What?
Hearing your own
son hates you so much
he's replaced you in his mind?
That's gotta suck.
How did he take it?
I already told you.
He didn't speak to
me for a summer.
It means more to
me than I can say
to have all of you here today.
And now our son, Gregory,
would like to say a few words.
Greg?
There's a lot of
people here today,
including some from the Corps.
And I notice that
every one of them
is either my father's
rank or higher,
and that doesn't surprise me,
because if the test of a man is how
he treats those he has power over,
it was a test my father failed.
This man you're
eager to pay homage to,
he was incapable of admitting
any point of view but his own.
He punished failure, and he did
not accept anything less than...
He loved doing what he did.
He saw his work as some kind of
sacred calling,
more important than
any personal relationship.
Maybe if he'd been a better
father, I'd be a better son.
But I am what I am because
of him. For better or for worse.
And I just... I just wish...
Put it back.
Well, he's not gonna miss it.
I'm done enabling. You can't
even let them put him in the ground
without making it
serve your agenda.
You really wanna do
this in front of everybody?
You wanna punish me or them?
How can I still feel surprise?
You would take even this, a moment of
real human grief, and turn it into a farce.
Oh, cut the crap.
You enjoy what I do.
I never had to force you, you
like coming along for the ride.
Yes, that's why I'm
cheering you on now.
This is about you needing
to be prepared for the worst.
So you become an oncologist.
No surprises there, the
worst happens all the time.
But Amber, she was
young and healthy.
Her death came out of nowhere.
Don't bring Amber into this.
And you weren't ready.
That makes you
angry. The world sucks,
and you didn't have
time to brace yourself.
What happened out
there is your show.
You're scared to death of
losing anyone that matters,
so you dump the person
who matters the most to you.
I'm not scared to death,
I'm moving forward.
Because no one can take away
from you what you no longer have.
Your father's
death is about you.
Amber's death is about you.
I can't imagine why someone
wouldn't want to be your friend.
Admit it. You're angry and
you're scared of losing me.
I'm not angry, I'm
not scared. Admit it.
I'm not afraid. Admit it!
I've lost people. It
happens. Admit it. Admit it!
What are you, five?
Stop repeating...
Admit it. Admit it. Admit it.
Come on, admit it! Admit it!
Still not boring.
Did you know I was
going to do that?
Because I didn't know
I was going to do that.
I know you have
trouble losing people.
In New Orleans,
I saw you carrying
this express package
around the conference,
and you wouldn't let it go,
but you wouldn't open it,
so I peeked at
the return address.
Diamond, Fairbarren.
Divorce attorneys.
Your first wife had just
served you with papers.
Did you know that
when you bailed me out?
Were you doing
something nice for me?
What did I say
about being boring?
We owe your mom an apology.
Hello. It's House.
How'd the bubble test go?
The problem wasn't the cyst. It's
advanced dilated cardiomyopathy.
We did a three-dimensional echo,
showed a mass
in the left atrium.
Looks like an atrial myxoma.
But the ultrasound images are
a little grainy, so it's hard to tell.
House?
The images aren't grainy.
They sure look grainy.
I've seen pictures of
you where you looked tall.
It's an iron overload,
creates speckles on the
image, makes it look grainy.
Also makes her pancreas fail,
her blood clot, her intestines...
Atrial myxoma is more likely.
MRI for a better view.
Then call me back and
tell me you're embarrassed
because my eyesight
is better 500 miles away.
I need a phone number.
I'm a doctor in New Jersey,
treating one of your clients.
Young woman looking
for her biological parents.
You know, you could
just wait for the MRI
to have your
curiosity satisfied.
What person who is nothing
like me are you saying that to?
Did the parents look tan?
The disease she has is genetic,
which means they
should have it, too.
They don't look more
tan than anyone else.
Discolored teeth?
They're farmers. Their village
doesn't even have a dentist.
Right. Thanks.
But if it matters, I'm not
convinced they were her parents.
Why not?
Because they said
they had no daughter.
The man was adamant, and the
woman seemed confused and frightened.
Thank you.
Differential.
Say you're a middle-aged
Chinese woman.
Fine. Say it.
I'm a middle-aged Chinese woman.
Girl comes to you, says that
she's your long-lost daughter.
Why would you be frightened?
I'm frightened because she's a
threat, maybe she knows something.
She hasn't seen you
since she was an infant.
Maybe an inheritance issue.
They're peasants.
Her very presence
is a threat. She...
What year was she born?
'83.
She's not supposed to be alive.
China introduced the
One Child Policy in 1979.
Say they didn't want a girl.
They tried to kill her.
But maybe the baby doesn't die,
maybe the father
panics, or regrets it,
takes the baby to an orphanage,
maybe he doesn't tell his wife.
Who freaks out like she's
seen a ghost 25 years later
when the girl shows up.
But why does attempted
murder from 25 years ago
suddenly become
relevant to her health now?
Maybe they gave
her something toxic.
It would have to be fat soluble.
This is fun, isn't it?
Let me see the MRI.
We don't have one.
She started vomiting as
soon as we started the scan.
Then let her vomit through the
MRI. That's what nurses are for.
Her parents tried to kill her.
I don't know how, but I know it
caused her to get sick 25 years later
trying to lift a
Buddha. Explain.
I already had this conversation
with Wilson. Just go with it.
Poison?
Buddha wouldn't make it worse.
Maybe the weight
stressed her back, which...
Makes sense if she's never
lifted anything in her life.
She actually didn't get sick till
she tried lifting it that second time.
I'm guessing the weight changed.
Anyone have Taub's pager number?
What's up?
Maybe give him a call.
If he tosses that switch
on the MRI, she's dead.
X-ray her brain.
Pins.
Push them through the
soft fontanel of an infant,
you skewer the brain, and
the hair hides the entry wounds.
It's the perfect crime.
She's had them in
her all these years.
What changed at the temple?
Same thing that
changed in the MRI.
Shockingly, not all
religious leaders are honest.
I'm guessing these particular
monks are bilking the faithful
by pushing a magnet
up Buddha's butt.
There's another
one under the table
that'll repel or attract,
depending on how you shift it.
When she picked up that magnet,
it moved one of the pins deeper
into the sympathetic
nervous center of her brain.
This sent a signal
through the nerves
to the blood vessels
in her small intestines
that caused the symptoms in China
and in the giant magnet we call an MRI.
She's lucky.
We're all screwed up by our
parents, she's got documentation.
The pins will be removed
surgically, and she'll be fine.
We'll wake her from the
coma after the operation.
Is there any way
you could not tell her?
Please. She's fragile.
She desperately wanted to
know her biological parents.
For her to find out that
they wanted her dead,
I don't know what
that'll do to her.
She may not be as
fragile as you think.
We know our daughter.
See this pin here?
It's been pressing directly
on her addiction center.
It's not her fault, and it's
definitely not your fault.
She's not who you think she is.
I hear your patient's
going to be all right.
Is that why you're here? A
colleague checking up on a patient?
Something going on?
I'm celebrating.
My mom hated him, too.
Your DNA test showed
no match? That's incredible.
At the age of 12, you
actually figured out
your father wasn't
your birth father?
That's what you
wanted, wasn't it?
Why should it depress you?
It doesn't depress me.
It doesn't make any difference
at all. That's what depresses me.
Well, I guess nobody gets to
choose who their parents are.
I'm not even sure anymore we
get to choose who our friends are.
I spoke with Cuddy. She
hasn't filled my position yet.
If you're coming back just
because you're attracted
to the shine of my neediness,
I'd be okay with that.
I'm coming back
because you were right.
That strange, annoying
trip we just took
was the most fun I've
had since Amber died.
You hungry?
Wilson.
Yeah?
My dad's dead.
Yeah. My sympathies.