Previously on ER:
Be back to work next month.
- Ray Barnett. I don't think we've met.
- Katey.
- You two lived together?
- Oh, we were roommates.
Hope you had benefits.
You don't wanna have anything to
do with me, what about your brother?
- He'd like to know you, Greg.
- He just met me.
I mean, ain't we brothers?
Curtis Ames?
Left-sided paralysis
following an embolic stroke.
- But I thought the case had no merit.
- Guy wants his day in court.
It doesn't reflect on your
abilities as a physician.
Skiles has got them working.
And with Ben Wallace,
they're going to the playoffs.
I remember when the NBA
used to mean something.
Oscar Robertson,
yeah. Walt Frazier, yeah.
Now it's all a bunch of
gangsters with tattoos.
And cornrows.
And slam dunks.
Oh, my, hey, now.
- Healthy set of lungs on that one.
- If I was 20 years younger...
You'd still be her granddaddy.
- Is that Dr. Gregory Pratt?
- The one and only.
What are you doing down
here on the South Side?
I heard you bought a
condo on the Gold Coast.
You drive down here in
the Beemer or the Benz?
I walked from my apartment. How
long's your hand been shaking?
- Long as I can remember.
- Been to the doctor?
What for? Lou Sander's
wife was having headaches.
Twenty grand in tests so they
could tell her to take aspirin.
Lanny Cole checked in the
hospital for a stomachache.
Next day, he checked
out through the morgue.
So, what, nobody
here goes to the doctor?
- Not me.
- Well, you should.
That's right. Dr. Pratt needs
to make them car payments.
Ha-ha-ha.
Seriously, you need
your pressure checked.
- They do that at the drugstore.
- Your sugar, your prostate...
Oh!
I wouldn't let Halle Barry
stick a finger up my ass.
I sure as hell
ain't gonna let you.
I'll see you fools later.
Now, that is what
I'm talking about.
Ooh! MAN 2: Uh-huh.
Greg. Greg.
Chaz, what's up, man?
- What's up? It's been a while.
- Too long. What are you doing here?
I'm waiting for a
friend before class.
- Okay, where'd you wind up at school?
- UIC.
That's good. How's
it going over there?
It's going all right.
I'm running a little late.
Yeah, me too. I
gotta get out of here.
- We should kick it sometime.
- Definitely.
You know where I am. All right?
Cool. Good seeing you, man.
You too. Be safe.
You'll probably be home before
me, and Miriam has to leave at 6.
Okay, okay.
Joe, let's review P.E.A. Hm?
Treatable conditions
include hypovolemia...
tension pneumothorax,
cardiac tamponade, MI and...
And what's another
cause of P.E.A.?
Huh?
Reversible etiology of P.E.A.
- Massive pulmonary embolus.
- How could I forget?
- You'll do fine.
- I don't know, my brain is like...
Oh. Sorry.
Sorry. Sorry.
- I have to review this.
- Ten times?
I gave my deposition a year ago. It
looks really bad if I contradict myself.
Didn't do anything
wrong. Tell the truth...
- Okay.
- Sorry.
Who's that, huh?
Wanna go see who's
at the door? Hm?
Who's at the door? It's Miriam.
She's gonna take
you to the park.
Suppose if I can't remember
something, I can run it by the Attending.
But I just don't wanna bug them all
day like I'm a med student or something.
- You okay?
- Ah.
That guy is gonna be
so sympathetic to the jury.
But he doesn't have a
case. You're gonna be fine.
If I lose, they report me
to the national data bank.
It follows me wherever I
go for the rest of my career.
I could be turned down for a job, it
could cut back our income, it can...
- Want me to come to court?
- No, you got a shift.
Well, they've been doing fine
without me for the past couple months.
No, it's more important
for you to be at work.
Okay. Good luck.
- Thanks.
- Call me.
The plaintiff's attorney will provoke
you, try to get under your skin.
So you need to stay cool.
If you get defensive, the
jury will turn against you.
- Yeah.
- Keep it brief.
If you elaborate, they'll
think you're evasive.
Don't worry about getting the story
out. I'll ask follow-up questions later.
Right. I'll, uh,
meet you inside.
Mr. Ames, I'm sorry we're here.
I was hoping this
wouldn't have to go to trial.
I came in with a cough, and
you sent me out a cripple.
We need to pick a few
boarders from the night shift.
Diverticular abscess awaiting...
Hey, stranger. Welcome back.
Thanks.
I wanna see pictures.
Diverticular abscess
awaiting CT-guided drainage.
- A-fib patient...
- Hey, Abby.
This is embarrassing, but I
never got to wrap your baby gift.
- Oh, that's great.
- Ray.
- Thanks.
- A-fib with rapid ventricular response...
I disposed
Mr. Kerosene to Psych.
He drank kerosene?
More like a high colonic.
Hey, Abby. I'm Tony Gates.
Hi. Didn't you used to be...?
Paramedic. Now I'm an intern.
- Next week, he wants to be a cowboy.
- Astronaut.
I could use some help here.
I got half his tongue on ice.
Oh, man, how'd that happen?
- Wife bit it off.
- Why'd she do that?
She says he talks too much.
All right, come on,
let's put him in Curtain 2.
A liter of saline and a crit.
Ray, you're with me.
Abby, grab some charts,
and, Gates, you're with Abby.
Cunnilingus interruptus.
- They did a grand rounds on it last year.
- Abdominal fullness isn't too bad.
Congratulations on the
bambino. A boy, right?
Yup.
- Can you check a BP?
- Yeah.
Hey, Mr. Dolan,
how are you feeling?
Must be weird coming back, huh?
A little bit.
- Seventy palp.
- Pulsatile abdominal mass.
We better move him.
Sam, this guy is hypotensive.
What? His vitals
were normal at triage.
- Not anymore.
- Add a second line, four of O-neg.
- Labs?
- Dr. Gates?
CBC with platelets, Chem-7,
ProTime, type and cross four.
Good, but add a HemoCue,
EKG, and let's get Surgery on this.
What do you think,
abdominal aortic aneurysm?
- Classic presentation for triple A.
- You think it burst?
No, he'd be dead.
Probably just a steady leak.
You set up for ultrasound?
- Call Radiology for that.
- I'm talking about the ER ultrasound.
That's still out for repair.
- How are we...?
- Radiology brings one.
- How long?
- Depends on how busy they are.
Wow, great to be back.
Pressure's up to
90 with the saline.
All right, looks like he's okay.
I'll call for your ultrasound.
O-neg's here.
So, what's the big guy doing
today? Watching the baby?
No, he's in court.
Mr. Ames, what made
you go to the ER...
on February 13th, 2004?
Because I had a cough.
My boss, he brought me in.
I mean, I thought
it was nothing...
but he didn't want me working
until I got it checked out.
- How long is the wait?
- Don't talk, please.
How long until I see the doctor?
I don't know. Could be 12 hours.
Twelve hours?
Twelve is good.
We're not that busy.
It's okay, Curtis. I'll
get someone to cover.
No, no, I can work.
How about I just sign in
and I come back later tonight?
You could lose
your place in line.
So I just sit in the
waiting room for 12 hours?
That's how it
works. Be right back.
This seems kind of crazy. How
about I get checked tomorrow?
I need a note you're
not contagious.
I got insurance issues.
Don't give this job away.
I'm gonna be there tomorrow.
Dr. Kovac, when did
you first see Mr. Ames?
I was working at the Admit
desk when he signed in at triage.
How long until I see the doctor?
- It's hard to say.
If you're stable, it
could be up to 12 hours.
Hours?
We have a lot of
sick people here.
Let me just sign in and
I just come back tonight.
I'm sorry. We can't do that.
So I gotta wait in the
waiting room for 12 hours?
I'll be right back.
This is crazy. I can't do this.
Everything okay, Chuny?
Yeah, he'll settle down.
Do not give the job
away. I will be there.
A lot of patients get
angry about the wait.
Nurse Marquez was able to defuse
the situation before it escalated.
I'm in. You can do the next one.
- Sorry, I...
- Good breath sounds.
You haven't lost your touch.
- BP's 80.
- All right, I need the ultrasound.
They're doing a
rule-out ectopic.
- Where's Surgery?
- Their med student's right there.
Well, that's not doing us
any good. I paged them twice.
Listen, how did it go yesterday?
- How'd what go?
- Court. I heard you had to testify.
It was fine. A lot of questions
about procedure and policy.
But I don't think
they have a case.
Here come the cavalry.
Enlighten me.
Hypotensive pulsatile
abdominal mass.
Say no more. Redline to the O.R.
We're waiting on ultrasound.
- Wrong.
- We're not waiting on ultrasound?
Neela, what happens when we wait for
diagnostic tests on a ruptured triple A?
Attempts to
stabilize are fruitless.
Investigations delay therapy,
increase risk of exsanguination.
With a 90-percent mortality.
His crit's not so bad, 32.
Meaningless drivel.
- What if it's not triple A?
- Then something else.
Radiology's bringing
over the ultrasound now.
- He'd be dead.
- It'll be seconds.
Zip it, Sparky. Look,
we're admitting him.
- Sparky?
- Let's go.
Did you need me to keep bagging?
Sure, as long as you don't talk.
Oh, by the way, Abby
Lockhart. Lovely to meet you.
Shh.
When did you assume
responsibility for Mr. Ames' care?
The nurse was concerned
about his oxygen level...
so she asked me to see him.
Curtis Ames?
Hi, I'm Dr. Kovac.
What? What is that?
Uh, low oxygen.
Or just maybe
a dirty fingernail.
Wood stains. They
don't wash off so good.
What kind of work do you do?
Custom carpentry.
Doors, built-in bookshelves,
armoires, you name it.
My father had a wood
shop when I was a kid.
I used to play with the
shavings from the lathe.
I love the smell.
- How did it sound?
- Well, like pneumonia.
- You should be admitted to the hospital.
- Admitted?
Yeah, stay for a couple of days.
No, no, no. I start a
custom remodel today.
Your temp is 102, your
oxygen level is down to 90...
and your x-ray shows your right
middle lobe is full of infection.
Look, if you wanna get better, we
need to give you IV antibiotics, okay?
After he examined you,
then what happened?
He left me with a nurse
who couldn't start an IV.
Okay, this time, I get a flash.
Good. That's good, right?
But it won't thread. I'm sorry.
Keep pressure on this.
I know the drill.
Anyone ever tell you
you have bad veins?
How about just giving
me a shot in the butt?
The antibiotics are ordered IV.
Can I talk to my doctor?
He's with a trauma
patient right now.
How about after he's done?
It could be a while.
Here we go. Fourth
time's a charm.
And how long was it before
Dr. Kovac came to your bedside?
It was more than an hour.
Uh, I saw him
working on a computer.
He was talking to some nurses.
Then he had a bagel
with cream cheese.
I think it was poppy seed.
And how did that make you feel?
Objection, irrelevant.
On the contrary, Your Honor...
it goes to state of mind
and ability to make decisions.
Overruled. You may answer.
I felt alone.
Forgotten.
Like nobody there
cared about me.
I'm just saying,
he's a frail old man...
who deserves the benefit
of diagnostic confirmation.
The patient is now on the
surgical service, not the ER service.
Go downstairs, pull a
cockroach out of someone's ear.
Neela. NEELA:
He's not stable, Abby.
BP's 90 systolic.
Five minutes for an
ultrasound is not gonna kill him.
I picked up a sterile sleeve.
Why do you insist
on annoying me?
Only take a few minutes.
Ten blade. Want
these two out of my O.R.
- Shirley, call Security.
- All right, all right.
- Dab the bleeders.
- Nice working with you.
Bovie. Stand back.
- Irrigation saline.
- Code red.
Oh, my God!
Unplug the Bovie.
And turn off that oxygen
before the whole room goes up.
Dr. Kovac, when the
nurses couldn't start an IV...
what action did you take?
I knew I needed to place a
catheter into a deeper vein.
How are you doing?
I didn't know you
ordered acupuncture.
I'm Sonya Ames.
Hi, Luka Kovac.
Thanks for taking care of him.
Well, since we can't
get an IV in your arm...
I'd like to place a central
line under your collarbone.
That sounds pretty involved.
We need a route to
give IV antibiotics...
or we cannot treat the
pneumonia effectively.
I'll numb up your skin and guide
the catheter in at the top of your chest.
There are risks of bleeding,
infection, collapsed lung...
but all of those can be treated.
I gotta think about it.
Wait, no, he doesn't. He...
If you need some
time to consider...
He's just being stubborn. He
hasn't been to a doctor in 20 years.
I never get sick, baby.
You can barely catch your breath,
you've been coughing so much.
It's not that bad, really.
I just want him to get better.
We'll do whatever it takes, okay?
Well, if you want the procedure,
you need to sign this form.
Now, come on, baby,
I've gotta get back to work.
He didn't wanna be in the ER.
He didn't like doctors.
So I felt I needed to
treat him aggressively.
He said it was
the only way to go.
If he left, I was worried he'd get
worse and wouldn't come back.
He told me
complications were rare.
It was no big deal, that
he does these every day.
- His wife works, he's all alone.
- My opinion didn't matter.
If he took pills, he could've died
at home and no one would know.
He gave me and my wife no
other options, no other choices.
We were both
really, really scared.
- Can we grab you a sandwich?
- No, thanks.
Hey, Timmy, uh, is Abby around?
No, no, if she's in
surgery, then don't bother.
It's okay. I'll try later.
Thanks.
Tricuspid regurg.
Ah, the irony. A
bad heart valve.
Left him with right-sided
failure and a big pulsating liver.
- So the mass was his liver?
- Yep.
And the fire saved him
from unnecessary surgery.
A slightly scorched med student and
some burned drapes saved the guy's life.
Lucky guy. Had minor burns.
Excuse me.
Forget how to use that thing?
No, I just...
Didn't wanna be one
of those mothers...
who checks in with the
babysitter every hour.
My babysitter used to
tie me to my high chair.
I'm sure yours is much better.
After your first
dose of antibiotics...
how long were you in the ER?
A long time.
Over three days.
Three days? In the ER?
They said that there were no
other beds in the hospital, so...
Excuse me, I need
to use the bathroom.
- I'll let your nurse know.
- I don't think that I'll be able to...
- I said, I'll let your nurse know.
- It's kind of urgent, please. Plea...
So you stayed in
the hall all that time?
They put me in the back at night
so that I could try to get some sleep.
Louie partied a little too hard.
I'd say we're dealing with coke,
PCP and ETOH. Pulled out his line.
- You're gonna need hard restraints.
- I'll rip your head off, I swear.
They kept saying I'd get a
regular room after the first day...
but it never happened.
Nurse? Ahem.
Nurse, I, uh, never
got my breakfast.
You may be NPO.
What is that?
I have to look at your orders.
Where's, uh, Dr. Kovac?
He's not working today.
So who's my doctor, then?
I have to check.
Every 12 hours...
an oncoming Resident assumed
responsibility for Mr. Ames' care.
His progress was
discussed. He was improving.
So it was the nurses who
were watching him more closely?
Yes.
The state recommends an ER
patient-to-nurse ratio of 4-to-1.
Yet during Mr. Ames'
stay, the ratio was 8-to-1.
That's eight patients
for every nurse.
How is that possible?
Well, we can't control how
many patients come into the ER.
Dr. Kovac, you know that those
standards are in place for patient safety.
So on a day when the standards
were off by a factor of 100 percent...
did you discuss this with
a hospital administrator?
- No.
- With the director of Nursing?
- No, no, it's not uncommon...
- With a nurse manager?
Look, we're always
short-staffed.
Did you bring this deficiency
to anyone's attention...
or do anything to
address the situation?
It doesn't work like that.
Mariko Shimane, history of
Crohn's disease, vomited blood twice.
Systolic's 88.
Two liters of saline,
type and cross four.
Is there anyone
we can call, Mariko?
- Doctor Derezin.
- From Gastroenterology.
- How about a family member?
- Just me and my son.
- Where is he?
- Oregon.
Sophomore in college.
We can call him.
He'd wanna know.
I'm in the hospital a lot.
Your condition
is pretty serious.
That's what they always say.
Upper GI bleed?
Sure looks like it.
- Hello, Mariko.
- Sorry to bother you, Neil.
That's all right. Any
blood in your stool?
- Yeah.
- She didn't mention that.
- Red blood?
- Yeah.
Endoscopy here or in the GI lab?
Excuse us for a minute.
Dr. Pratt, dude on Line
2 says he's your brother.
Yeah, take a message.
And, Doc Lockhart, Big Daddy
called while you were upstairs.
- Thanks.
- I can't scope her.
Why not?
Crohn's can cause inflammation, erosion
into a vessel along the intestinal tract.
Twenty-five feet
of possibilities.
Not something I can reach.
She needs surgical exploration.
- I'll call the O.R.
- So, what's the good news?
We're gonna move
you to a different room.
It looks like you
need an operation.
Again?
Maybe it's time
to call your son?
He's got midterms, no.
On the afternoon of
his third hospital day...
Mr. Ames complained of
numbness in the left hand.
And what was your impression?
How long did it last?
About 10 minutes.
Okay, squeeze my hands.
Okay. Now spread
your fingers like this.
Don't let me close them.
Good.
Well, what do you
think happened?
It could be a number of things.
How's it feel now?
Back to normal?
Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah, I guess so.
The same on both sides?
It's kind of weird.
You probably compressed a nerve
while you were resting on your side.
I've slept on floors more
comfortable than this bed.
Here, let me take care of that.
Hi, Bed Control?
Yeah, this is Dr. Kovac.
Yeah, I need a med-surge
bed for my patient, please.
And when did the
numbness return?
It was about three hours later.
And was there something
different about this episode?
- Didn't have any feeling for half an hour.
- You're okay now?
It's worse. Went up higher.
Where is Dr. Kovac?
He checked. He
said you were okay.
I'm not okay. I
need to talk to him.
Not right now.
Why? Where is he?
He's taking care of a
patient with a heart attack.
Tell him to come and see me.
- When he's through.
- No, no, now.
Mr. Ames, there are
people in this ER...
who are much sicker and
need immediate attention.
Hey.
If he won't come to see
me, then I'm gonna go to him.
Get back in bed.
Something's wrong. I
need to talk to my doctor.
I need you on the
monitor. Frank, help me.
- Take it easy, fella.
- Take it easy?
You people have
ignored me for three days.
No one tells me what's going on.
Nobody gives a damn,
no one will talk to me.
- Mr. Ames, sit down.
- How am I supposed to take it easy?
I am not sitting down until my
doctor does what he's supposed to do.
I need some help here.
- Open your eyes, sir. FRANK:
Let's get a gurney over here.
Mr. Ames? Look at me.
Luka, he had a stroke.
Up-going toe.
- CT can take him now.
- Okay, we're on our way.
We recognized the stroke,
immediately moved him for monitoring...
and had him to CT
as soon as possible.
From what I remember
is, it was pretty chaotic.
- Why should this guy have a stroke?
- No idea.
Follow my finger, sir.
Sir, look over here. Over here.
Frank, I need a monitored bed.
There aren't any.
Okay, Trauma 2, then.
GSW just took it.
Let's move him to CT.
CT is backed up for a half-hour.
- Where can we put him?
I'll see what I can find.
- Chart, I need his chart.
- I'm looking for it.
- Where's the chart?
I never saw it.
- It's okay, take deep breaths.
- Where's Surgery?
Crenshaw called,
patient's not a candidate...
for anesthesia till
systolic's up to 80.
- All right, tank her up.
- Eight French cordis in femoral.
You know, I have another idea.
Oh, man.
Hey, has anyone
seen a Pocket Doppler?
- Uh, yeah, top drawer by the sink.
- All right.
What about an
intra-aortic balloon?
This girl in heart failure?
- No, it's a GI bleed.
- What?
Inflate the balloon
in the chest...
block off the blood
supply to the abdomen.
- No, you can't do that.
- Damn it.
Why not? That's a great idea.
She's not your
patient. Adiós, Gates.
Could be a
publishable case report.
A non-invasive way
to occlude the aorta.
It'll stop the bleeding.
Oh, crap, crap, crap.
What?
Pratt, can you come with me?
Four units of red cells, one
of FFP, a 10-pack of platelets.
We'll be right back.
Hey, hey, hey, what is this? Some
kind of post-partum power trip?
- Hey, the aortic balloon will work.
- It's an unproven therapy.
- You'd let her bleed to death?
- No, have the surgeons take her to O.R.
Doesn't look like that's gonna
happen. What's your problem?
It cuts off all circulation to the
bowel, liver, kidneys and legs.
Everything could die
from the chest down.
What are we doing in here?
You know, you used
to be such a cowboy.
- Why is this a big deal?
- I don't agree.
Gates thinks it'll work.
Gates is a knucklehead who'd defibrillate
with a car battery and jumper cables.
I am the Attending.
The buck stops here.
So if there's gonna
be a bad outcome...
let Surgery be to blame
for not showing up.
So you'd let her die?
No, I just don't wanna be the guy who
kills her with some crazy-ass therapy.
Oh, look, this is
her last chance.
She's pre-arrest.
If her pressure continues to drop
despite massive transfusions...
I would consider...
What are you doing?
I'm pumping. Sorry, my
boobs are about to explode.
When did your wife arrive?
Right after the CAT scan.
By then I could talk
again, you know.
Looks okay.
I still can't move
my arm and leg.
There's no mass, no
bleeding. That's... That's good.
Then, why did he have a stroke?
Probably a blood
clot in a brain artery.
But, uh, there is
something we can try.
What...? What should I do?
A medicine called TPA could
probably dissolve the clot.
You're saying that could work?
That I might...? I
can get better, right?
There is some chance of
recovery 30 percent of the time...
and, uh, full recovery
10 percent of the time.
We've gotta do something.
What about the side effects?
There's always side effects.
Well, there is a 10 percent
chance of, uh, bleeding in the brain...
causing more
disability and death.
Ten percent chance of recovery?
There's a 10 percent
chance of death?
What if we don't use the drug?
There can be some improvement,
uh, with time and physical therapy...
but probably not
a full recovery.
Ah...
Look, look.
I've been in this hospital...
long enough to know that
if something can go wrong...
it...
I don't want it.
And what do you recall...
of Mr. Ames' reaction to
your recommendation of TPA?
I brought in Dr. Saunders,
a neurologist...
to try to explain options
in an objective manner.
The statistics are averages for all
patients, even ones in their 70s and 80s.
Your risk of bleeding is
much less, given your age...
and the fact that it's been only 90
minutes since the onset of symptoms.
I don't know.
The TPA is your only
shot at complete recovery.
Forget it. I'm not taking it.
Settle down, baby.
Look, if it was me,
I'd take the TPA.
If it was you, you'd
be in intensive care...
with 10 doctors and nurses watching
your ass every second, day and night.
Curtis.
You wouldn't be getting
the runaround for three days.
Not sleeping, not
eating, pissing in a pan.
And now I am supposed to trust
you with a medicine that can kill me...
when all I've seen since I've
been here is total incompetence?
Mr. Ames, did you
refuse a therapy...
that had the potential
to reverse the stroke?
There were no guarantees.
Experts have agreed that TPA gave you
the only chance for a complete recovery.
And you didn't want it?
It was, uh, a lot more
complicated than that, really...
Did you refuse a medicine
that could have cured you?
I refused what they were pushing,
and you would have done the same thing.
So you did refuse the cure.
Systolic's only
50 after four units.
All right, hang
another two units.
Uh, I'm above the
diaphragm. Go ahead, inject.
I'm putting in 40 cc's of saline.
Let's hope this damn thing works.
Doc Lock, you got a call.
- Kind of busy right now.
- Balloon is up.
It's your babysitter.
They said it was important.
Pressure's up to 90.
All right, go
ahead. Go, take it.
We're out of the
woods. Mark the time.
Surgeons have one hour to get
her up and fix her or the game is over.
- Hello? SAM: They
should be here any minute.
- What's happening?
- We've got your bleeding controlled...
Is he hungry? Did
you try the stroller?
Thanks for joining us.
What's up with the fluoro? I
thought ER docs had x-ray vision.
Put the phone next to his ear.
Stopped a Crohn's patient from
intra-abdominal exsanguination.
Rather unconventional.
Dare I say, idiotic?
It worked. BP's 122/78.
ABBY If I go there will be trouble
Cross-clamp without
thoracotomy. It's cool.
What's not cool, her kidneys
will be dead in an hour.
- Go, clock's ticking.
- Abby?
It's his favorite song.
Puts him to sleep.
This indecision's bugging me
- Aren't you glad you don't work here?
- She's auditioning for American Idol.
If you don't want me set me free
- Hey, nice work, Abby.
- Thanks.
Exactly whom I'm supposed to be
Don't you know which
clothes even fit me
Upstairs, the neurologists
recognized a faint mid-systolic murmur.
What does that mean?
A murmur is from turbulent
blood flow through the heart.
So because of the murmur,
a cardiac echo was ordered...
showing patent foramen ovale.
Do you know what a patent
foramen ovale is, Dr. Kovac?
A small hole between the
upper chambers of the heart.
So that hole could have
allowed a blood clot...
from your subclavian catheter
to pass from the right side...
to the left side of the heart.
And then up to the brain?
It could happen, but
that's extremely rare.
I didn't ask you how
rare it was, Dr. Kovac.
I asked whether a patent
foramen provides a pathway...
for a clot to travel to the
brain and cause a stroke?
- Yes.
- So if you had heard the murmur...
if you had pulled the catheter
when numbness began...
is it possible that you could
have prevented Mr. Ames' stroke?
Objection. Calls
for speculation.
Sustained.
When the numbness began, did
you consider a cardiac source...
or did you ignore an important
warning sign of impending stroke?
I didn't ignore anything.
I considered what was
probable and acted accordingly.
After Mr. Ames
complained of numbness...
did you then appreciate
his heart murmur?
The ER is a noisy place. You
can't always hear subtle murmurs.
Dr. Kovac, I'm not asking you
about the noise level in your ER.
I'm asking, did
you, at any time...
in the three days that
you cared for Mr. Ames...
recognize his heart murmur?
At the time of Mr. Ames' numbness,
there were 47 patients in the ER...
82 in the waiting room.
I was taking care of a mother who
was the victim of domestic violence...
nearly beaten to death,
an 8-year-old hit by a car...
- Dr. Kovac.
- And a 53-year-old heart-attack victim.
There are always sicker patients in
the ER and it was reasonable to believe...
that Mr. Ames'
numbness could wait.
Order.
Only one can speak at a time.
Your Honor, I move to strike that
tirade be stricken as nonresponsive...
and I request the court
admonish the witness to answer.
Restate the question. And,
doctor, I'm instructing you to answer.
If you had heard the murmur...
is it possible you could
have prevented the stroke?
Objection.
Possibility is not the issue.
- Sustained.
Dr. Kovac, is it true that you
could have prevented the stroke?
- Well, doctor?
- Counselor, I'm warning you.
No need, I'm done
with this witness.
Scabies family went home...
and Lost Rectal Thermometer
went up to Surgery.
Gates needs you for an
extubation in Trauma 2.
- All right.
- I'm here till 7. Call if you get a break.
Any news from Kovac?
Not yet. CHAZ: Greg.
Hey.
- Am I too early?
- Yeah, just have a seat in triage.
- I'll be right back.
- All right.
It's Abby, right?
Yes. Oh, hi, sorry
about your arms.
It's okay. They fixed
me up pretty good.
Med school wants me to
make a chart for insurance.
Oh, it's no problem, I got it.
- Thank you, Ray.
- Thanks, Ray.
- I guess we can do it in Curtain 4.
- Great.
- Might need a little débridement.
- Go for it.
- So your shift almost over?
- Mm-hm.
They're giving me
two days off to heal.
- That's very generous of the surgeons.
- First free night in forever.
Have you been to Rednofive?
Uh, no.
They remodeled, and I hear the
DJ on Thursday nights is ridiculous.
You wanna check it out tonight?
Both emergency and
infectious-disease experts agree...
that Dr. Kovac gave
superior treatment...
and above and beyond
the standard of care.
The stroke was a
one-in-a-million complication...
that no one could have
either predicted or prevented.
And Dr. Kovac treats the patients
that no other doctor will treat.
His ER is the safety net for
millions with no health insurance.
Every day, he is out
there on the front lines...
providing the best
health care possible...
for the people who
need it the most.
If you find against Dr. Kovac...
what message do you send to
other health-care providers like him...
who make that daily struggle
their personal mission?
Dr. Kovac could have sent Mr. Ames
home with antibiotic pills, but he didn't.
He assumed that Mr. Ames was
unreliable, that he couldn't be trusted...
and so Dr. Kovac took
responsibility for his care.
And then he abandoned
that responsibility...
by subjecting Mr. Ames
to substandard conditions...
in an understaffed ER where that man
was shoved into a corner and neglected.
And the warning signs of a
major stroke were ignored...
resulted in a
devastating disability.
Before the stroke, Mr. Ames
was a skilled craftsman.
He supported a
wife and two children.
And now, with a paralyzed left arm, loss
of perception in his left visual field...
that livelihood has
been taken away.
Loss of income, loss of self-esteem,
has resulted in profound stress...
and led to a divorce and
separation from his children.
Mr. Ames now lives alone.
He's trying to get by on a
disability benefit of $1300 a month.
He cannot drive, he sees
his children one day a week...
and he is being
treated for depression.
Your award must fairly
compensate Mr. Ames...
for past and ongoing medical
care, for 25 years of lost wages...
and for the pain and
suffering that this man...
will experience every
day for the rest of his life.
And you wanna make sure that
this part rests against your rib cage...
not your armpits,
and then... Oop.
I'm okay. I'm okay.
- You sure those things are safe?
- Yeah, they just need an adjustment.
Or you can go to the
pharmacy and get a new pair.
Good idea.
Careful.
Should we sign you
in as a trauma patient?
I would say yes,
but my shift is over.
Call me if your spleen ruptures.
- Excuse me, hi.
- Hi.
- Is Dr. Pratt around?
- He's with a patient. Can I help you?
He told me he was
gonna be right back.
Will you let him
know Chaz is waiting?
Okay.
- Hey, Neela, you have a minute?
- I have 12 hours. I'm on all night.
- It's about Katey, your med student.
- Ray.
Hey, hey, she asked
me out, all right?
Residents are not allowed
to date their students.
Not my student. Never will be.
She's not doing an ER
elective, it's not against policy.
Well, then, why even ask?
Thanks. Appreciate your help.
I'm sorry, I gotta go.
- Tell Greg I'll call him.
- Okay.
- Hey, Mayday.
- Hello.
- What are you doing here?
- Small bowel obstruction.
Good times. So, uh, how's
the guy who went up in flames?
Minor partial burns to
the chest and abdomen.
You know, I hear
his aorta was just fine.
There's a lesson to be learned
here. Wise men say only fools rush in...
Oh, you missed
a guy called Chaz.
He left?
You were saying?
Hey, Chaz, Chaz, hold up, man.
Sorry about that. I got
caught up with a patient.
It's okay. I gotta go.
Now, come on, man.
Sounded like something serious.
- It's all good.
- Hey.
Things are just not
going so well at home.
Really?
When I wanna
study, it's too noisy.
When I wanna bring my
friends over, Dad won't let me.
I'm always late to class because
the commute takes forever.
What about the dorm?
Costs too much.
When you saw me earlier, I
was looking for apartments.
But they all kind of sucked.
Look, I know this is
gonna sound crazy...
but I was thinking, maybe I
could move into your place.
My place?
Yeah, your place. I
mean, it's close to campus.
I can get a part-time job
to help you with the rent.
I'm quiet. We'll probably
never even see each other.
You're serious?
Ah, Chaz, come on, man.
You know, I got my own style.
Oh, come on.
You say the word, and
I'm gonna clear out for you.
And if it doesn't work out,
I'll be gone real fast, man.
Never mind, it's a bad idea.
All right, look...
Let's try it for a month.
For real?
Yeah, I'll talk to your mom.
- Thank you.
- All right.
Thank you.
- I'm gonna holler at you.
- All right, man, take it easy.
- Hey. Ha-ha-ha.
- Yeah.
So, uh, how was
the first day back?
It was a piece of
cake. Like riding a bike.
Oh, yeah? You
miss your little man?
Yeah, but that's okay.
I'll bond with him again
when I feed him at 11...
and 2 and 5 a.m.
But you know what
was nice about today?
For 12 hours, I talked like
a grownup to grownups.
Well, except for when you
had to deal with the surgeons.
Yeah, at least they
don't spit up on you.
Much.
Good night.
Try to get some rest.
It's a nice idea.
How long do you
think they'll deliberate?
Shouldn't take more
than a day or two.
Ames' lawyer is
a publicity hound.
The local news is having
a field day trashing County.
It'd be good to get you in front of the
press as the doctor found not guilty.
Well, you are very optimistic.
People need to hear
our side of the story...
to reassure them that the
County health system works.
During that videotape, did you
see the looks on the jury's faces?
Doctors get sued for ignoring
and undertreating patients...
not for doing too much.
Plus, you did a
great job on the stand.
I don't think so.
I've been to at least
a hundred trials.
I can tell when a
jury likes the doctor.
He's just another greedy MD
getting rich by overtreating.
- What are you talking about?
- I've read about it.
The drug companies give kickbacks to
doctors who use their expensive drugs.
The judge instructed us
not to decide this case...
based on anything
we've heard outside.
They neglected this
guy for three days.
His pneumonia was improving.
That doctor used a hand
grenade to kill a mosquito.
To me, that's bad
medical judgment.
You're not a doctor.
We've got to decide this based
on the expert witness definition...
of the standard of care.
Well, when you're talking
about County General...
the term "standard
of care" is a joke.
That's right. Kovac
is part of the system.
And we all know
the system sucks.