All right, remember
what I told you.
Next time you're on the top
of the cheerleading pyramid...
Make sure
my boyfriend's ex
isn't at the bottom.
Mmm-hmm. Heard that.
All right, Simone here,
is gonna take great care
of you.
Sweet kid.
Yeah.
Hey, thanks for offering
to help today.
It's no problem.
Though, I confess
I may have had
an ulterior motive.
Oh?
Maggie's birthday,
it's in a couple weeks,
and I'm stumped
as far as gifts.
Mmm. So, what
are you considering?
Currently? Uh, thinking
a gold bracelet from Yurman.
Jewelry, huh?
That's a big statement.
That's the thing.
I'm not sure if we should
pick up where we left off,
or play it like
we're starting from scratch.
Hmm.
There's someone hit
on the corner.
Should we call it in?
I'll administer aid.
My chest!
Bitch shot me in my chest!
Hang on, we got you.
Gunshot wound,
right anterior lateral chest.
All right, we're gonna
roll him, okay?
Okay.
Bullet went
through and through.
All right.
Decreased breath sounds
on the right.
His lung's collapsed.
Give me a needle, Barry.
Got it.
Pulse is good.
Breath sound is improving.
Let's get him to Med.
I'll go get the ambo.
They're coming back.
Get down!
Are you guys all right?
Dispatch said
you were in a shootout.
What the hell
happened out there?
You're going to Baghdad.
Tried to help this guy,
banger circled back,
tried to finish the job.
Barry saved my life.
What?
19-year-old male was shot
in the right chest.
Needle decompressed
in the field,
still hypotensive.
Someone take
a look at Barry's leg.
He was hit.
Thanks, Barry.
Barry?
Sorry, it's not serious.
Um, Noah, Dr. Sexton,
meet us in Treatment Four.
On it.
Okay, let's transfer
on my count.
Ready. One, two, three.
Start on the groin line.
Are you sure you're okay?
Yeah, I'm fine.
Open a 36 French chest tube.
Hey, you still with me?
Damn it. Hold the tube.
All right, just a
tangential wound.
Nothing to do but dress it
and let it heal on its own.
Told you it wasn't
anything to worry about.
Okay, tough guy.
And why didn't you
ever tell me
you carry a gun?
Maggie?
Oh, hey, Alvin.
Mr. Vaughn,
I'm Detective Olinsky,
with the Chicago
Police Department.
Alvin, can this wait?
He's being treated.
It's okay.
Listen, we're gonna
need your weapon.
Of course, yes, sir.
It's locked in the
glove compartment of my rig.
Uh, it's now evidence.
Uh, you got
a concealed
carry permit?
Yeah.
There you go.
You always got a gun at work?
Uh, I've been carrying
for a couple years.
Necessary precaution.
And it's a good thing
he does.
He saved three lives today.
For real. Barry, you the man.
Big hemothorax.
Lots of blood.
Are you okay, Natalie?
Yeah.
Tube's in. Securing it now.
What's his pressure?
107 over 68,
heart rate of 121.
Three units of blood,
one unit of plasma in.
Okay.
Color is coming back.
He looks better.
Hey, Nat.
Yeah?
We'll take over.
Okay.
I'm so glad you're okay.
Yeah. Yeah.
Are you hurt anywhere?
Let me see.
No. No, I'm fine.
I just, um...
I hit my head when Barry
pushed me out of the way.
If he hadn't...
That bullet barely missed me.
Yeah, well,
thank god for Barry.
But you, what were
you thinking,
putting yourself
in the line of fire
like that?
I was thinking
that there was
a patient in need.
Dr. Manning, you feeling
well enough to answer
a few questions?
Yeah, of course.
Right this way.
Uh, is this
really necessary?
Like I said,
it's probably
indigestion.
First thing
they teach you
in med school,
always take
chest pain seriously.
That's what I get
for hooking up
with a heart surgeon.
Here, why don't you
pop into this room right here,
and I'll be in
as soon as I can.
Who'd you just plant
in my room?
She's a friend.
Uh, she woke up this morning
with tightness in her chest.
I'd like to get
an EKG and troponins.
What's your friend's name?
Margo.
Uh...
Does she have a last name?
Can you help me
out here, Bea?
Thank you.
It must be hard
remembering
all their names.
Now, I read
that Derek Jeter
used to send
his conquests home
with a gift basket,
but a full cardio workup
is much classier.
Jeter, huh? You...
You're a baseball fan?
No. It's too boring.
But, I love gossip.
So you're in from Missouri?
St. Louis. Here on business.
Well, we will get you
in and out of here
as quickly as possible.
That's what Dr. Rhodes
is renowned for around here,
quick in-and-outs.
I'm Dr. Bekker, by the way.
Your insurance card
has you listed
as a dependent of
Theodore J. Dimilio?
That would be my husband.
Would you like us
to contact him?
No, thank you.
Not just yet.
I'll make some copies
and be right back.
So, you're married?
Didn't wanna tell me?
If I had, would you have
come back to my hotel room?
No.
Maybe. I don't know.
That's why I didn't tell you.
Hey, there you are.
I thought you were
gonna come find me
as soon as you were
done with the police.
I just needed
some fresh air.
Well, I notified
the ped's on-call.
He's on his way in,
so you can go home.
What? Why?
I thought you should take
the rest of the day off.
Will, I'm fine.
Just, please don't do that.
Don't make
unilateral decisions
on my behalf, okay?
Excuse me!
Excuse me,
I need some help over here.
She's been screaming
blue murder
since Michigan City.
I pulled over
a couple of times,
so she could throw up.
And she says it hurts
too much to walk.
So, you think I had
a heart attack?
I'm afraid so, yeah.
Yeah, a mild one.
Yeah, it's hard to tell
exactly what's going on
from the EKG,
so I wanna get you
over to the cath lab,
so we can take
a closer look
at your vessels.
I'm not gonna catch
my flight home, am I?
No.
Dr. Rhodes.
I received a call from IR.
Said you required
a priority reschedule
for your patient,
Margo Dimilio?
Yes. Uh, her EKG
showed some PVC runs
and possible ST changes.
Ah.
I'm not sure you heard,
but her lab work came back.
They found traces
of cocaine in her urine.
What?
520 nanograms per milliliter.
I don't believe that's
what caused the distress.
Why not?
All right, you want
all the details? Sure.
Uh, we met
at a fundraiser,
at the Field Museum.
Uh, we were at
the roulette table.
We both liked the number 19.
She ends up inviting me
back to her hotel room,
where we...
Exerted ourselves
a couple of times.
I only offer that up,
because I believe
it was the exertion
that exacerbated the pain
that she was
already experiencing,
which is why I brought her in,
and why I believe
we need to take
a closer look
at her vessels.
Did you partake
in the cocaine?
No.
And I didn't know
that she was either.
I can take
a drug test
if you'd like.
That won't be necessary.
Carry on.
Thank you.
Let me know
if anything makes you
feel uncomfortable, okay?
Yes, ma'am.
All right, Mr. Cray...
Uh, Reverend Cray, actually.
Okay. Reverend,
how old is Lindsay?
Fourteen. Now, how long
is this gonna take?
And I'm only asking that,
because we gotta get down
to Cedar Rapids.
I'm preaching at
a revival meeting tomorrow.
Okay, we'll just figure out
what's going on here first,
and take it from there.
Have you ever felt pain
like this before?
Her last pregnancy,
she'd get sick like this,
but not with
all this blood, you know.
Last pregnancy?
Lindsay, what happened
with your last pregnancy?
Did you carry to term?
No, ma'am.
She had what they called
a spontaneous miscarriage.
That was four months ago.
Well, it doesn't look like
she's pregnant now.
However, I am seeing
some irregularities
in the lining of her uterus.
Perhaps something
that didn't move through
when she had her miscarriage.
All right, I'm gonna do
a pelvic exam now.
Are you all right with that?
You can come outside.
There's a waiting area.
We'll give your daughter
a little more privacy.
My daughter?
Lindsay's my wife.
This marriage is legal?
That guy and
a 14-year-old girl?
Her father gave his consent
and a judge signed off on it,
so yeah.
What about her mother?
Well, she died when
Lindsay was only three.
That man should be arrested.
Right, but on what charges?
Rape, coercion, whatever.
This girl is a kid.
She obviously had
no choice in the matter.
He barely lets her speak.
Can we call on the police?
Family services?
No, unfortunately,
we're required to respect
Michigan state law.
How's the girl doing?
She's undergoing a D&C
to get rid of any products
from her prior miscarriage.
Yeah, which the reverend
only okayed,
because he wants Lindsay
to be able to conceive
as soon as possible.
I realize
this is distasteful
for all of us,
but I implore
both of you
to do your best
not to let
your personal feelings
interfere with the care
of this patient or the law.
What am I supposed to do?
I'm not sure I can be
in the same room as that guy.
Then go home.
I'll deal with this.
You keep trying
to push me out the door.
Yes, I'm concerned about you.
I don't know why
you're being so stubborn.
I'm gonna go see
how the D&C is going.
Dr. Reese!
How did your rounds
at Cohn County Jail go?
Great. Actually,
the patient, Michael,
who tried to kill his brother
in a bout of manic psychosis,
we had a breakthrough
this morning.
He's no longer
on suicide watch.
Wow. Sounds like you're
really making some progress,
not just with your patients,
but, um...
with your own therapy as well.
I need to see
a psychiatrist, now!
Don't listen to my husband.
Ben, you're being ridiculous.
Sir, you need
to wait for triage.
Uh, it's okay, Leah.
Hi, I'm Dr. Charles.
How can I help you?
Listen, I need
to check myself
into the psych ward.
No, no, no,
he doesn't.
He's not crazy.
Ben, please.
People are listening.
Do you think I care?
I need to be committed,
for as long as it takes
to stop these thoughts.
Okay, I understand.
Um, how about if we step
into this room over here,
so we can discuss your...
No! No more talking!
I don't need to talk.
I need to be locked up.
Ben...
You send me back out of here,
then I'm going
to murder my wife.
Wait, so,
you're telling me
I need surgery?
Unfortunately, yes.
Uh, now, normally,
we would have
placed a stent,
but there's
too much curvature
in the vessel.
So, look, I recommend
doing the bypass
as soon as possible.
I can perform
the operation myself.
No, I need to get home.
This is all too much.
Margo...
I'm sure that there's
someone you can refer me to
in Saint Louis.
I'm very sorry,
but I can't let you leave.
What?
Your condition
is too unstable,
and we need to keep you
under observation
until the surgery.
I'm sorry, please, just...
Please.
What do they say?
You reap what you sow?
This must be
karmic retribution
for cheating on my husband.
Your coronary disease
didn't just develop overnight.
It's been building up
for a long time.
I've been cheating
on my husband
for a long time.
Dr. Rhodes?
Yeah.
I will let you know
as soon as an OR is open.
She's agreed to a CABG?
Mmm-hmm.
I'm confident we can do
a robotic assisted bypass.
It'll be less invasive.
Of course.
I'm having Dr. Bekker
perform the surgery.
What?
Uh, no, she is way
less experienced
with the robotics.
What happens
if something goes wrong?
Well, it won't.
And if it does?
Given the circumstances,
a lawyer could make
a compelling case
for negligence.
Dr. Latham, I...
There is too much
potential liability at stake
for both you and the hospital
to risk keeping you
on the case.
They're short
a trauma surgeon
in the ED.
I volunteered you.
Hi.
How are you feeling, Lindsay?
A little groggy still,
but I feel better.
Thank you, ma'am.
Is everything okay with her?
Well, that's what I came in
to discuss with you both.
Um...
the gynecologist found
a tumor growing
within the tissue
that would've
become the placenta.
Tumor?
Yes.
Um, she sent it to Pathology.
It is, I'm afraid,
malignant.
It's called
a choriocarcinoma.
I have cancer?
Thankfully, it's still
confined to your uterus.
That's what's called
Stage One.
Given that we caught it
relatively early,
these tumors generally
respond favorably
to chemotherapy.
And if that doesn't work,
what happens then?
Worst-case scenario,
we would need to consider
a hysterectomy.
But we are far, far
from even discussing that.
See? First,
she comes in here,
talks chemo.
Next, she's scheming
to remove your womb
altogether.
I can assure you,
there is no scheming going on.
Chemo can
lead to infertility.
Not necessarily.
Yes, there are
some risk factors,
but to do nothing at all
would be far, far riskier.
No thank you, then.
We will not be doing
any chemotherapy.
Sir...
I'm gonna ask you
to step out for a moment,
so that I can discuss this
with my patient, privately.
Why? She doesn't
want me to leave.
Go on, ask her.
He can stay.
Like I said, only thing
we need from you now, Doctor,
is to get Lindsay discharged.
Shortly after
my wife got pregnant,
I started having
these thoughts.
Okay, take your time.
It's all right.
No one here
is judging you.
Um, I'd imagine...
...killing her,
slashing her throat
with a knife,
to be specific.
I can't even be
around knives anymore.
Afraid of what I might do.
That must be terrifying.
Can I ask you,
was this pregnancy planned?
Yes... No.
We both wanted it.
I don't
have an escape fantasy.
I'm not jealous
of my unborn child.
It sounds like you've been
seeing some other therapists.
Two.
One wouldn't even be alone
in a room with me.
Thoughts only got
worse after that.
I'm really sorry
you had to go through hat.
You know,
sometimes when we over-focus
on fixing problems like this,
you know, not thinking
certain thoughts,
it tends just to
tighten their grip.
Like, if I tell you
not to think
of a brown bear,
you'd immediately picture it.
Look, I'm telling you,
I'm a real danger.
I need to be committed.
Grabbed your spare pants
from your ambo.
And, found you this.
Mmm.
Last one.
Nearly had to wrestle Doris
to the ground for it.
Thank you, babe.
Sit here
for a second,
would you?
Something I've been wanting
to say since this morning.
Me too.
But you go first.
Okay.
Getting back
together with you,
it is the happiest
I've been in a long time.
Now, I know you had
your reservations about...
Wait. Wait...
When that call
came through today...
I was so scared.
I admit
it's been hard for me
accepting you
back into my life,
but I realize now that
what we have is real.
Whatever happened in the past,
it doesn't matter.
I want a fresh start.
Continue this later?
Miguel Garcia,
55-year-old male.
Single GSW through
the left clavicle.
April, Dr. Choi,
you're going to Baghdad.
Copy.
Hypotensive and unresponsive.
Intubated in the field.
My finger's
in the bullet hole.
I move it and blood
will hit the ceiling.
Keep pressure on it.
All right.
All right, set on my count.
One, two, three.
There we go.
All right, it looks like
the distal subclavian artery
through the clavicle.
Let's take a look
very carefully.
Whoa! Okay, definitely
the subclavian.
All right. All right,
here's the plan,
April, give me
the biggest stitch needle
you can find, all right?
Got it!
Monique, you know where
we can find some zip ties?
Maintenance has them.
Go get 'em, quick.
Hey, Detective Olinsky?
Yeah?
Miguel Garcia, that victim
that we just brought in,
ShotSpotter pinpointed
the source of the gunfire
to the same time
and location
of your drive-by.
Got zip ties.
All right, good.
All right, we're gonna
jerry-rig something
to stop the bleeding.
Ethan, I've got one hand.
Get over here,
grab the needle driver.
Got it prepped right here.
Good.
All right.
Stick the needle through
the male end of the zip tie
and tie a knot.
April, hand me a scalpel.
Done. Here you go.
All right.
All right, needle is in.
Pull the stitch,
and feed the zip tie
around the clavicle
and the artery.
Zip tie is in.
All right, cinch it down.
Gently.
Mmm-hmm.
All right.
Okay, it's temporized.
How's the pressure?
Holding. Heart rate's down.
All right,
let's get him
up to the OR.
What did they say
his name was?
Miguel.
Don't go getting
ahead of yourself.
What if the bullet
is mine, Maggie?
What if it's not?
Look, if anyone can
get him through this,
it's Connor.
Let's just stay
in the moment
for now.
Dr. Charles...
You see
he's overreacting, right?
You're not
going to commit him?
I know it may be
very difficult
to understand,
but the thoughts
your husband
is experiencing
are very real to him.
Look, you don't know
my husband.
We've been together
since college.
He's a gentle soul.
But Ms. Samuels,
your husband's suffering.
Don't we wanna try
and help him get
some peace with all this?
Of course.
But if you commit him,
then what? I mean...
Our baby needs his father.
Can't you just, um...
give him some pills?
There must be
something you can do.
Dr. Charles,
can I speak
with you a moment?
Would you excuse us
for a second?
It seems to me
that Ben is suffering
from some sort of OCD.
Other than that, he has
no functional impairments.
We're not talking about
over-washing your hands here,
or checking the front door
every two minutes.
This is OCD Harm.
His thoughts
toward his wife are violent.
Judging from Ben's history,
there's no reason to think
he would act on it.
We don't know that.
I mean, what if we send him
out here today and he does?
Uh, I really think
that committing him
is our best option.
You know, put him
in an environment
where he feels safe
from his thoughts,
help him defuse them,
or, at the very least,
coexist with them.
What if the right move
isn't to make him feel
safe from his thoughts?
What if it's to make him
confront them directly?
You mean exposure therapy?
Dr. Reese, I know that's been
very helpful to you,
but in this case,
that approach would be
extremely risky,
and way too early.
Look, we need time
to fully evaluate
the patient, okay?
So, let's commit him
to the psych ward
and take it from there, okay?
Dr. Rhodes?
Not now.
Has to be now.
I'm ASA Ramirez,
state's attorney
investigating
today's shootout.
I'd appreciate if you could
retrieve the bullet,
so that we could
run ballistics.
My priority is
to save this man's life.
You'll get your bullet
if it's medically advisable.
Uh, I'm not sure I should be
talking to you alone.
Is that what he told you?
Listen, I'm not sure
how you feel about
being married,
but the one advantage
that it does give you
is that you are
considered, by law,
to be medically emancipated.
Emancipated?
It means you have
the right to make
your own medical decisions.
Does chemo really make it
so I can't have a baby?
No.
No, and Lindsay,
it's clearly your best
and safest bet
moving forward.
What are you doing?
Nothing. No, we...
I was just conferring
with my patient.
Lindsay, regardless of what
this man thinks or wants,
it is your body,
and your choice...
That has already
been decided.
So, what do you want?
Will you step outside
with me, please?
Step outside!
Sir, get your
hands off of me!
From the start,
you have been
willful and argumentative.
My patient has
the right to decide
how she wants
to treat her cancer.
The cancer is you.
You've been treating Lindsay
like she's a child,
not a woman.
She is a child! She's 14!
Just because you had
some judge sign off
on what's obviously...
Excuse me.
a case of abuse...
I need to talk to someone
who's in charge here.
...does not magically
decree her a woman!
And now you wanna
play games with her health?
You are a bully
and a predator!
I'm the charge nurse, sir.
How can I help you?
Yes, I want this bitch
removed from my wife's care.
All right, we've got
proximal and distal control
of the artery.
Need to remove
the bone fragments
before we can repair
the vessel.
Huh...
It looks like the bullet
is kissing the vein.
It's gotta come out.
...behavior is
what is outrageous.
This is why I never go
to city hospitals.
We will treat your wife...
I heard
he called you a bitch.
Not really what matters here.
Just got an earful
from the good reverend.
If he takes Lindsay
out of this hospital,
she will never get
the care that she needs.
Every patient is allowed
a second opinion.
But she'll die.
It's abuse, plain and simple.
She's right.
I admire your advocacy,
Dr. Manning,
but you're off the case.
Dr. Halstead will be primary
until the patient
can be discharged.
I swear I have a mind
to knock the hell out
of that sanctimonious...
Will, I do not
need my boyfriend
to defend my honor
right now, okay?
What I need is for... Ow.
Nat, are you all right?
Yeah, I just...
Natalie.
Natalie!
Nat...
So, you lost
consciousness as well?
Hmm.
Have you, uh, had
difficulty concentrating?
I don't know, maybe.
Have you been
more irritable
than usual?
Yes.
Sorry, it's true.
Look, I gotta
get out of here.
I have a patient
I need to go see.
Sorry, you don't get
to go back in the game,
Mitch Trubisky.
You have a concussion.
I'll need a head CT
to rule out any bleeds.
Uh, let me make a call
to Imaging.
Thanks, Sam.
I need to go talk to Lindsay
before she's discharged. Ow.
Natalie...
What?
Goodwin removed you
from her care.
You don't remember that?
She did?
Oh, no.
I really messed this up, Will.
No, you didn't.
Yes, I did.
She was asking me about chemo.
I was this close
to convincing her
to get treatment.
If I had just had
a little longer with her.
Well, maybe
it's not too late.
9 millimeter bullet?
It was my gun.
I shot him.
You can't blame yourself.
You did what anyone
in your position
would have done.
Mr. Vaughn?
Yes?
I need to ask you
a few questions.
How are you holding up?
Trying to keep it
together for him.
To be honest, Ethan,
I'm scared.
Even if the worst happens,
Barry's not criminally
responsible.
The shooting
was instigated
by someone else.
It was self-defense.
I know, but...
How is Barry supposed
to carry that burden?
It's inexcusable behavior.
No, you're absolutely right.
And again, I wanna apologize
for Dr. Manning's behavior.
It was entirely
unprofessional.
Right, and very aggressive.
It was pushy.
Yeah, well,
between you and me,
this is not the first time
we've had a problem with her.
She can get emotional.
Women, right?
I have to check up on
a patient in Orthopedics.
Let me... Monique,
help Reverend Cray here,
with discharge paperwork,
would you?
Patient's name
is Lindsay Cray.
Monique will take
great care of you.
Good luck
and God bless, Reverend.
I will be praying
for you and your wife.
Thank you.
You're very welcome.
Where's the reverend?
He's filling out
the paperwork needed
to take you out of here.
I can't keep you here
much longer.
I know you have some
big decisions to make,
but I won't be able to get you
the medical attention you need
unless you speak up right now.
My mother died
when she was 19.
She had ovarian cancer.
My great-grandmother, too.
Guess,
it's the family curse.
I'm sorry to hear that.
The lady doctor said
something earlier,
about a hysterectomy?
Dr. Manning, yes.
Now, that is only
if you get sicker.
With the right medicine,
you have a great chance
of beating this.
You can live a long life,
have a family someday.
Are those things
I'm supposed
to look forward to?
No, I want a hysterectomy.
A hysterectomy is really
not necessary at this point.
I don't care.
Some women have
their breasts removed
if they have the cancer gene
just so they don't
get it later, right?
But, you are so young.
All right,
hysterectomy is irreversible.
You will not be able
to become pregnant
and have children, ever.
You don't know my life.
You don't understand.
I don't want to bring
a kid into this world.
Dr. Manning said
it was my decision.
Mags, I just
talked to Connor.
They controlled the bleeding
and rebuilt the artery.
We have every reason
to believe Miguel
is gonna make it.
We've gotta tell Barry.
Barry?
Why is he in handcuffs?
The bystander made it
out of surgery.
Well, that's not the issue.
There's some kinda discrepancy
with his carry permit.
Permit? Come on, Detective.
Barry, what's going on?
I'm sorry, Maggie.
Have a seat, Ben.
Wait, have I been
committed already?
Shouldn't I be medicated
or in a straightjacket
or something?
So, the nurse is preparing
your admittance paperwork,
but in the meantime,
um, I would like
to talk to you
about something.
Talk about what?
I already told you,
I've done every type
of therapy in the book.
The thoughts won't go away.
I understand.
But what if I told you
that most of the thoughts
we have are just nonsense?
Just synapses
popping off in our heads,
and that we shouldn't
take them so seriously?
If you could, just,
do me a favor for a moment,
and close your eyes.
Now, I want you
to bring up the thought
that frightens you the most.
Tell me what you see.
It's okay.
You are in a safe space.
I see myself.
I'm holding a knife.
Okay, keep going.
I see my wife.
She's in the kitchen,
doing dishes.
I'm walking up behind her.
She doesn't know I'm there.
You're doing very well.
What's that?
I paged Dr. Charles.
Let me know
when he comes up here.
Kayla. I got your page.
Oh, here he is.
What's up?
It's Dr. Reese.
She's locked in
with a patient.
You've conquered
your fear of holding a knife,
a weapon.
Now, imagine
that I'm your wife.
I can't.
You can.
I trust you.
Do you see her?
Yes.
Here's your opportunity.
You can slit my throat,
right now.
No.
No, I don't want to.
I don't wanna do it.
No, you don't.
This whole time, you've been
beating yourself up
over your thoughts.
The fact that
you can't dismiss them
does not mean you're depraved.
It shows you have
a conscience.
Dr. Reese.
Outside, now.
Dr. Charles, I know I didn't
take your approach today...
You didn't take my approach?
You directly defied my orders,
and put yourself
and your patient
in real danger.
Ben isn't dangerous.
I think I just proved that.
The only thing you proved
to me is that you're reckless
and insubordinate.
And, I have half a mind
to suspend you, again.
The last few months,
you've been preaching to me
that I can either
see my patients
as a threat
or as an opportunity.
Was I afraid in there? Yes.
But my fear
no longer controls me.
I control it, and now,
Ben controls his, too.
You are missing the point!
I appreciate
that exposure therapy
has given you
a newfound sense
of confidence,
but it does not make you
all-knowing and invincible.
What you just did in there
was unbelievably stupid.
Sharon? You called for me?
Yeah.
Sit down with
me for a minute.
What is it? Do I need to get
Barry a lawyer? A bondsman?
I just spoke with my guy
at the State's
Attorney's office.
The discrepancy with
Barry's carry permit.
Yeah?
It turns out,
he changed his identity
at some point,
because of a juvenile record.
He didn't disclose it
on his permit.
That's why it wasn't
technically legal.
What do you mean
change his identity?
You mean, "Barry Vaughn"
isn't his real name?
Apparently not.
Why wouldn't he tell me?
He had a whole other life?
I'm sorry, Maggie.
The State's Attorney
is gonna file
a charge against him.
The whole time
we were together,
he was lying?
Every day?
Every day, Sharon?
What is going on here?
Lindsay has decided
to have a hysterectomy.
Over my dead body.
She's my wife.
I make the decisions.
Sir, please move.
You lay so much
as a finger on her,
and I will sue you
to kingdom come.
We have her consent.
You lied to me.
She can't make that kind of
decision for herself.
She was obviously coerced.
He forced you
to sign this,
didn't he?
No. It was my decision.
You have two seconds
to step aside, Mr. Cray,
or I will have you forcibly
removed from the premises.
You go through
with this, Lindsay,
and you will
be banished
by the church,
the community, everything.
You will be diminished
in the eyes of the Lord.
Do you understand?
Surgery went without a hitch.
Seems your personal life
keeps working in my favor.
Excuse me, Dr. Bekker?
I'm Teddy Dimilio.
I just wanted to thank you
for saving my wife's life.
It was actually
Dr. Rhodes here,
who made the diagnosis.
Well, both of you, then.
Yeah.
I don't know what
I would've done without her.
It was our pleasure.
Thank you.
Hey.
Someone told me
about a standoff
between you and Cray?
Yeah.
Were you able
to talk to Lindsay?
I was.
Is she gonna start chemo?
She's having a hysterectomy.
I tried to talk her
out of it, believe me,
but she was adamant.
It's a drastic step to take,
but I can see why she took it.
That girl will
finally have her say.
But she's just a kid, Nat.
She's tough.
Women are tough,
tougher than you think.
I guess I got a lot to learn
about this kinda stuff.
Trust me, you are way
further along than most.
Way, huh?
Mmm-hmm.
All right.
Thank you.
Impressive save today.
Yeah, thanks.
You headed somewhere?
No, just headed home.
It's been a long day.
Shame.
Waste of a nice tux.
I know a spot
over in the West Loop.
Makes the best
Old Fashioned's
in town.
Care to decompress
over a drink?
You're not married, are you?
No.
In that case, I'm more of
a Manhattan kinda guy,
but I might be able
to be persuaded.
Car is right here.
All right.