Picture this.
You've spent the past
five years of your residency
training to become a surgeon,
but those five years
suddenly don't matter.
The only thing that matters,
the only thing between you and
the rest of your career is a test
in a random hotel
in a random city
with a random examiner
asking you random questions.
Nervous? You should be.
We should be gone by now.
The flight's not for
three hours. You're fine.
I'd be fine if people
showed up on time.
No one is going to be late.
San Francisco is
a short flight away.
There's no reason
to be nervous, okay?
Not again.
I'm sorry.
It's just that my parents
called me this morning
to wish me luck,
and they told me that their
church is praying for me,
and what if I don't pass?
One in five people don't pass.
Kepner, stop. You're
a trauma surgeon.
We're soldiers.
We fight battles harder
than this test every single day,
and we win, okay?
So, dry your tears.
I want you to repeat after me.
I am a soldier. I'm a soldier.
No, no. I want to
hear you mean it.
Repeat. I am a soldier.
I am a soldier.
Now get on the bus. Okay.
Karev?
Now, have salmon for dinner.
And tell room service to
make sure it's not frozen.
You lose omega-3s
if it's frozen.
Avery, are you listening to me?
I'm trying not to.
All right, how are you on cash?
I figured you needed some.
Okay, don't overthink it.
They want standard
protocol, not cutting edge.
This is a test in proficiency,
and you're proficient
in your sleep.
So just make sure that
you get a lot of sleep.
You want me to be
relaxed, right? Exactly.
This isn't helping.
You're right. WOMAN: Bye!
Go! MAN: Bye.
Kick ass.
It's exciting, huh?
They started off
with so little promise,
I feel like I'm
witnessing a miracle.
Where the hell is Karev?
He'll be here. I
trained him right.
Okay.
Coming! Don't leave without me.
Miracle.
Where is Meredith Grey?
They called 10 minutes ago.
She started throwing up
right after I dropped her off.
She's really warm.
Maybe I should stay.
No, babies get sick. It sucks,
but it's the disgusting
circle of life.
We have trained too hard.
I have personally
put in hours of my life
that I will never get
back, so you are not failing
just because your mommy
hormones are all "code orange."
Go to the airport.
Pass your boards.
My baby is sick.
Lucky for her, her
father's a doctor.
Takes a village.
And Zola's village is
chock-full of doctors.
Okay? She will be fine.
Just go. Make me proud.
All right. Mama loves you, Zo.
You're my Zozo. I love you.
I'll be home soon. Yeah.
Hey, Torres, thank
you very much.
Do you mind looking
after her for a minute?
I gotta make some
calls. Yeah, no. No.
Sofia had that
bug last week, so...
I'm not getting
anywhere near that.
What happened
to "we're a village"?
It's a metaphor,
Shepherd. Good luck.
What's the deal with
Tommy's platelet count?
Did you know it dropped?
He's not your patient
anymore, remember?
His crit's been decreasing,
and his SATs are low.
We might want to...
We've been getting along
just fine without you
these past few weeks.
I don't need you butting in now.
Karev, outside.
Now.
Tommy's deteriorating.
What did his x-rays show?
Just... Shh.
Okay...
Look your examiner in
the eye, but don't stare.
And don't... And don't
rush your answers.
It's okay to take a second
to just compose yourself.
But don't... Don't
take too long.
Yeah, I got this.
Yeah, I hope you do.
What? I mean, I know you do.
Twenty-three
minutes late? Not okay!
Is it too late to request
a van without you on it?
I need you, Lex.
Hi. What?
I need you.
I'm doing a skin graft,
and I'm stuck with an
intern who thinks that
debriding the necrotic tissue is
the title of a Nine Inch Nails album.
Are you sure it's
not? It might be.
I'm not familiar
with their later work.
You're just sad because
Jackson is off to take his boards.
He and I work well together.
We understand each other.
Like you and I
used to, you know?
So I need you.
I can't. I am way behind
on all of this
research for Shepherd.
I was gonna pull an
all-nighter to finish, so...
All right.
Thought it would be fun,
working together again.
But if you're busy...
Mark, wait.
You should check out the
latest Nine Inch Nails album.
It is pretty...
Fresh.
Okay.
I said "fresh."
16-year-old male driver,
car versus streetlight.
Arrested once before
they freed him in the car
and once in the rig.
BP 80 systolic, tachycardic.
Contusions and lacerations
over chest and abdomen.
- Where's Altman?
- Abdomen is rigid,
so there's probably a
lot of blood in the belly.
It took over an
hour to get him out.
Kid arrested twice in the field.
Add an EKG to the trauma labs
and get x-ray in here, stat.
Right away. Oh, God. Ricky.
Excuse me.
What was he even
doing in his car?
He's supposed to be
at basketball practice.
Okay, is he allergic
to anything? No.
Does he have heart problems? No.
Probably driving too fast.
We swore that if he
got even one ticket,
we would take that
car away from him.
Hang a unit of O neg and
make sure the CT is ready.
Rick! What is happening?
Why are they doing...
Let's step out. Let's step
out. What's going on?
Oh! Sorry. Ow!
That's... Case Western Reserve.
Do you know Ted
Stevenson, head of trauma?
I do, yeah. He just
offered me a job.
I might be an attending there.
April Kepner, Seattle.
Kevin Banks. I'm the
guy whose job you took.
I was waiting to hear,
but I guess I just heard.
Thanks a lot.
He hates me.
How do you do that?
You've been here two minutes.
My examiner is gonna
hate me, too, instantly.
Don't psych yourself out.
One in five people
fail the boards.
Fine. Psych yourself out.
It's just a test. We've
all dealt with worse.
No one's bleeding
out on your table.
We will be fine.
Cristina.
What?
Zola has the stomach flu.
So? Kids get sick.
Derek's with her.
Zola has the stomach flu.
Oh, no. No, Mer,
you can't be sick.
You cannot be sick.
Okay.
You're just freaking out.
Just take deep breaths,
okay? Just take deep breaths.
So do you guys wanna go
register and then go get some lunch?
What just happened?
Stomach flu.
Zola has the stomach flu,
and you didn't say anything?
How could you? Are you
trying to sabotage us all?
It's not like it's
the black plague.
You are supposed
to be our friend.
April, calm down.
You stay right where
you are, Typhoid Mary.
Come on. Let's go register.
Mer, just sit.
And I'll get your
registration package.
Next in line.
Hey, Dr. Robbins, it's Alex.
Listen, I was thinking
about Tommy.
Have you tried
liquid ventilation?
It's just an idea. Let me know.
Dude, is that your mom?
Baby. Oh, no.
I know.
I know you don't want to see
your mother before the boards.
But they are wearing
this old girl out.
Got me examining
three sessions tomorrow,
and I might not see you,
so I had to say good luck.
Okay.
Thank you, Mom. Oh.
And I brought it.
Mmm-mmm. No, no,
that's fine. You don't...
It's in here somewhere.
That's fine. That's okay.
That's what you always say,
but you always want it
in the end. Okay, all right.
Mom, I'm good. I am.
I'm in room 809 when
you change your mind.
All right. All right. Excuse me.
Mommy bring you your binky?
It's my lucky pencil. She
brought my lucky pencil.
You know this is
an oral test, right?
Yes, I know, okay?
It's just, I used
it for my SATs,
and my MCATs,
and my intern exam.
So it's your binky.
It's...
Sort of like my binky, yeah.
Okay. Fill this out.
There must be, what, like
100 people in this room?
Okay, if Kepner is right,
20 of them are screwed.
I'm gonna puke. Relax.
You're not one of them.
No, on you.
So, it's his bowel? Again?
We won't know how bad it is
without opening him up.
Okay.
Morgan, we've already
removed part of his bowel.
There's a very good
chance he won't
make it through another surgery.
You've said that before.
A lot. We'll do it.
Do the surgery.
We can't wait for
you to prep an EVR.
All right. Well, why
don't you open him up,
and I'll get him prepped?
You're gonna fill him
full of blood thinners,
his organs will bleed out before
we get a chance to save them.
He needs damage control.
Opening his chest will cause
more damage in the long run
than we can control.
She's right. This gives him
his best options for recovery.
This sounds like a
good compromise.
Dr. Hunt, sir, no one's told us
what we're supposed
to be prepping for...
Laparotomy. EVR.
Both. Now that's a good plan.
Both.
Prep him head to toe.
All right then.
Okay, page me for the tib-fib
fracture when you're done.
Hey, where you going?
You want to be in the
OR with those two?
They hate each other.
They're professionals.
They'll be fine.
No, it's awful.
It's tense, and it's
cold, and it's dangerous.
It feels like defusing a bomb
in a haunted house
that's built on a minefield,
and there are bears everywhere,
and the bears have knives.
Now I have to be
in here with them
for the next eight hours.
You have to tame them, or
you will die. We will all die.
Their hate will
destroy the hospital,
and then the whole planet.
I am counting on you, Bailey.
We're all counting on you.
Godspeed.
Okay, 56-year-old presents
with pancreatic ductal obstruction
and dilated main
pancreatic duct.
Post-op procedure... Yes.
Dude, give it a rest.
If we don't know it by
now, we're screwed.
Besides, you've got your
magical pencil to see you through.
He's got a magic
pencil? Oh, say more.
His mommy brought it.
Wait. How magical
is this pencil?
And can it stop that?
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. This all just got
really, really real.
And man down.
Two men down. First Grey, now...
Meredith's not down. She's fine.
Shut up.
Dr. Robbins. Karev,
why do you keep calling me?
Well, you don't answer my texts.
I just want to know if you
got Tommy's x-rays back yet.
Yes, and your hunch was correct.
His necrotizing
enterocolitis has returned.
Is Morgan... Are you
gonna operate? Yeah.
In a few hours. We're
prepping him soon.
Listen, I will
text you when I...
Wait. Karev?
I gotta go.
Go where, to eat?
No, I gotta go back to Seattle.
What?
Hi.
Yeah, no, just...
Sorry, I was napping.
I'm just... I feel
a little tired is all.
How's Zola?
Her fever's down to
100. Stop worrying.
I can hear her screaming, Derek.
No, no, she's screaming, "Go,
mama. Kick butt on the boards."
Is she really feeling
better? Yeah, you hear that?
She stopped crying.
And now she's smiling
that cute little smile she does.
Oh, yeah. I love that smile.
You gonna be all right for
tomorrow? Tomorrow? Yeah.
I feel great. Listen,
I made some calls.
There is an opening at Mass.
General, and we could do this.
And Zola could grow up
with a Boston accent.
Whoa. I don't even know if I
want the job at the Brigham.
And I haven't passed
my test yet. You will.
Don't touch the buttons.
Zola, I'm talking to your...
Nice.
I don't take chances.
My kid just hung up on me.
Yeah, that'll happen again.
Where did you get
an IV and fluids?
I'm a doctor in a
hotel full of doctors.
Roll up your sleeve.
You're a nice person.
Don't get all misty.
I'm outta here in 60 seconds.
This room is like
a viral cesspool.
Ow! I take that back.
All right. Fluoro out.
Okay. Where were
we? Clamp, please.
I hope that was worth it.
Hey, just checking
in. Almost done?
Almost, but you
should ask Altman.
She usually disagrees with me.
I need to check the
final position of the graft,
so, yeah, I disagree with Hunt.
Okay, then. I don't
want to interrupt
the work that you're doing here,
fixing the problems
that we all want fixed,
that we all need fixed.
So, I'll be back.
You could stay.
There's room. Stay!
You mind if I join you?
No. Please.
I sent my idiot intern
to get me lunch.
I told him to get me
anything but lentil soup.
You know what he brought me?
Lentil soup.
The future of medicine.
I don't know. We're
not all hopeless.
I know. I'm spoiled with Avery.
He's quick, he's
thorough, he's funny.
Right, in a very dry
kind of way. Right?
What the hell
happened to you two?
Why'd you break up?
Great.
It's Dumbo, the flying idiot.
I left him treating a burn.
Now he's probably
the one on fire.
To be continued.
Okay.
Retract more here.
I need better visualization.
How can I help? What
the hell are you doing here?
Look, I can't just stay in that
hotel room and not do anything.
There's nothing for you to do.
Come on. I'm
here. I can scrub in.
No, there's nothing
that I can do, Alex.
Take a look yourself.
Almost the entire
bowel is necrotic.
There's nothing else to be done.
I'm closing.
We're falling apart.
Meredith's sick, and Alex...
What the hell was he thinking?
See, you gotta put all
that out of your head.
Okay? Concentrate
on your own game.
I'm a soldier.
What?
Nothing.
Hey, but we're
still standing, right?
Hell, yeah, we are. Yeah.
Me and you. Me and you.
Who is that?
Oh. That's the guy
who thinks I stole his job.
He hates me.
So what? He's a douche.
Oh. And here he comes.
Nah, dude, just don't.
Just sit down... No,
no, I want to apologize.
I was a tool this afternoon.
No hard feelings?
Sure, yeah. No problem.
No problem at all.
I'm sorry.
You have nothing
to be sorry for.
Best man wins and
all that stuff, right?
Or woman, whatever.
Yeah, he's had a few
beers. You know what?
And he got bad news
today, so we'll just...
All I'm saying is, obviously,
she can offer something
that I can't offer.
All right. Everybody's a
little wound up, all right?
So big day tomorrow, maybe
you should go sleep it off.
Are you the boyfriend?
You know, you should
watch out next year,
'cause Ted Stevenson
likes himself a redhead.
All right. Okay, Kevin.
I think you can leave.
Or maybe you found
that out already.
Is that how you got the job?
Oh!
Bitch!
Hey, look, you need...
Really? You want to go?
Yeah, bitch! I want to go!
April!
Stop! Yeah, you
want more of this?
'Cause I got more!
Shut your big mouth, all right?
Oh, yeah, it goes with
my big brain, dumbass!
What? That's why I
got your job next year!
April!
Enough!
Now if anyone is still
here in 30 seconds,
you're barred from
the test. Now get!
That was not our fault, okay?
These Case Western Reserve guys,
they started the whole...
What are you doing here?
What am I doing here?
We just came down here
to get something to eat...
No, I thought you
were here to prove
that the considerable
amount of money spent
training you wasn't wasted,
that the dreams you
had of becoming surgeons
won't vanish in a puff
of smoke tomorrow
when the examiner asks you a
question and you can't answer it
because instead of
getting a good night's sleep,
you were engaging
in a barroom brawl.
We should probably
go. We should go.
Good night, chief.
Okay, night, chief.
Oh, my God.
Good lord.
So you... You
didn't do anything?
You just closed him back up?
There was too much necrosis.
He's not going to survive.
So we'll keep the
pressors going,
keep him on TPN
until he's ready.
There's got to be
more that we can do.
Morgan...
We did it.
You did it. You did it all.
I'm sorry.
I really am.
All right. I am
almost finished here.
I think this boy is gonna
have to lose his spleen.
You see any way of salvaging it?
What... BP's crashing?
What... What happened?
There's a leak.
The graft is leaking.
Fluoro in.
I knew it.
What... What did you
know, that grafts leak?
It's common. It happens.
Fix it and then get out.
What do you think
that I am trying to do?
All right, the leak is
below the diaphragm.
I can try and
fix the graft by...
Here. The abdomen's already
open. We can try to fix it manually.
Fine. TEDDY: Try it.
Fluoro out.
I'm having trouble
visualizing with all this blood.
Hunt, a little help, please.
No, Altman can assist.
Altman? My head's
not in the game.
I shouldn't be here.
So, if you've got this,
I will leave you to it.
Catherine?
Richard?
You're an examiner?
Either that or I'm stalking you.
That's a win-win
if I ever heard it.
Give me a hug.
I didn't know you'd be here.
Every year.
Making the future of
medicine wet its pants.
What are you doing here?
Archie Katz, he came
down with the stomach flu,
and they asked me to sub in.
I figured I'd spend
the entire day
staring at sweaty,
anxious residents.
This is a real improvement.
I should hope so.
Coming.
No, don't open the door.
I don't want to
breathe your air.
I just want to know
if you need anything.
Oh, no. I'm okay.
Did you sleep?
No, it's worse
when I lie down or...
Whoa. Uh...
When I stand up, apparently.
Oh.
Do you think Zola's
gonna hate me?
Why?
Because moms should be
with their kids when they're sick.
All you want to do is lay on top
of your mom when you're sick.
My mother was never
around to lay on top of,
and now I'm not there
for Zola to lay on top of.
I was just wondering if you
think she's gonna hate me.
Owen slept with someone.
Yeah.
Did you know?
Does everyone know? No.
He thought you told me,
so he told me.
Anyway, that's how I know.
Okay.
He's a pig, and
you deserve better.
Are you still there?
Yeah, I'm still here.
Oh, my God. That was amazing.
You just punched a guy.
I punched a guy.
You were freakin'
crazy in there.
Jackson, we are gonna do this.
I can feel it.
I... This is our last
night as residents.
Let's hope.
No, stop that! You just
stop doubting yourself.
We freakin' kicked
that guy's ass in there.
We are gonna
kick this test's ass.
How come you're so
confident all of a sudden?
I'm a soldier.
Yeah, I still don't know
what that means, but...
Mmm. April.
Should I not have done that?
I...
If you want me to
stop, just say so,
and I'll stop.
I just... You're...
The way you're kissing
me right now, you just...
You're a virgin.
Yes, because my whole
life since I was a kid,
I had this idea of how my
life was supposed to be,
these rules that I was
supposed to follow,
but I'm not a kid.
I'm not the same person I was
when I started my residency.
I just punched a guy,
and it felt really good.
And if something
feels really, really good,
it can't be bad, right?
I...
Jackson, hey.
It's okay.
Really.
I'm just saying,
if Jackson doesn't
pass tomorrow,
I'm holding you
personally responsible.
Don't worry about Jackson.
He kept his head down.
He's in good shape.
And how about you?
How's Adele?
Okay, I think.
I haven't seen her in a while.
It confuses her more than
anything when I'm there.
How are you with that?
It... It's the right thing.
Actually...
She's happier.
At our age, you would think
we wouldn't have to
grow up anymore, huh?
Hey. How are we doing in here?
I am not the problem. He is.
He is completely
unwilling to collaborate.
He should've been
in here fixing that leak.
But, no.
He is just not willing
to even hear me.
It's obstructing patient care...
Really? You had eight hours.
Why is this on me?
Because she'll listen to you.
And because I organized
ladies night. It's your turn.
Jump in and save the day again.
I can't work with
him if he is gonna
fight me on every single thing.
Okay, he is not fighting you.
He disagreed with you
on a course of treatment.
That is something doctors do.
But you don't see
him as a doctor.
You only see him
as the man you blame
for the death of your husband.
And you know and I
know that was not his fault.
But he's accepted that blame
because he thinks it
makes you feel better.
He's not fighting you.
But you keep fighting him.
He lost you.
He lost his friend,
and now he's
probably losing his wife.
His world is falling apart.
So I hope blaming
him is helping you
'cause it sure
isn't helping him.
I've turned off his pressors,
so we won't be able to manage
his blood pressure anymore,
and his TPN and his fluids,
so he won't be getting
any more nutrition.
You okay?
I'm gonna turn off his ventilator
and remove his ET tube.
Do you need a minute?
His breathing will slow down,
and his heart will
eventually stop.
It may take minutes.
It may take hours.
This is the first time
I've ever really been
able to hold him...
Without the tubes and junk.
It's nice.
Stay.
Please.
Thank you, Doctor.
Hey.
We meet again.
Hey. Thanks.
By the way, it
wasn't me, was it?
What? That split you two up.
The fact that Avery and
I are working together,
the fact that you have
to see me all the time?
I don't... I don't make
you uncomfortable, do I?
No. No, no, no,
no. I... No, you don't.
Great, because this is nice.
Talking to you. I miss it.
I miss you.
I miss you, too.
And...
The reason that Jackson
and I broke up, it...
You know what? We
don't have to talk about that.
It's really... It's none of my
business, so forget I asked.
We can be friends who
don't talk about that stuff, ever.
Okay.
Oh...
But as your friend,
if you're not over him,
you should tell him,
because, seriously, you
guys are great together.
Thanks.
Don't stay too late.
And I look just to
the left of their head.
It freaks them out.
You are terrible.
Oh, come on, now.
You gonna try and tell me
you're all warm and maternal?
I am supportive
and I'm encouraging.
Mmm-hmm. I've watched
you with your students.
I know your moves.
Oh, do you now?
I certainly do. I don't know.
I may have a move or
two that you haven't seen.
Would you like
some... Some coffee?
No.
More... More dessert?
Yeah.
You tired?
Not in the least.
Would you like me
to get the check?
Honey, could you get
us the check, please?
Yes, ma'am.
Okay.
That was really
great. That was really...
Yeah. Yes. Yes. Yes, that was...
You were great.
I mean, are you...
Are you glad we did that?
Yeah.
So you're okay? Yeah, I'm fine.
I'm just tired.
Yeah.
You should get some sleep.
Yeah, I should get some sleep.
Here or... Yeah.
Yeah.
Or...
Or you could go.
Don't you have
to get your pencil?
It's the middle of the night.
Right. Yeah.
But you know what?
I could go if you want.
Yeah. You know what? I'll go.
You can get some sleep.
Okay.
You sure you're okay?
I'm great.
I'll see you tomorrow.
You can stay with me.
Alex, Jackson, and April
moved out. There's room.
I don't want to
come stay with you.
Is he moving out?
I don't know.
But you're not
together. You broke up.
No, we can't just...
Break up.
We're married. I know.
I mean, I think Derek used a
pretty good attorney for his divorce.
I don't want an attorney.
Okay.
Well... He cheated on you.
Yeah, this isn't you and Derek.
He didn't fall in love with her.
He screwed someone...
One time...
When he was drunk.
I mean, does that mean
my marriage is over?
What he did was wrong.
And if it were me...
Hey, if I screwed someone
once when I was drunk,
and I could, I know me...
If I did it...
I wouldn't want Owen
to leave me for that.
Everything isn't so perfectly
right or perfectly wrong.
Okay.
Say it.
You got married awfully fast.
Be on my side.
I am on your side.
But it, you know, it's
like you're defending him.
And I don't know how
we're supposed to feel.
Well, he's my husband.
This is a marriage.
Okay.
I want to leave him.
So that means I'm gone.
So you're gonna take
the job at Stanford?
Or Columbia.
Well, you'd be leaving me, too.
Well, you might
go to the Brigham.
Probably not.
Maybe.
Yeah, I... I'd leave you, too.
There are phones, you know?
You hate the phone.
I know I do.
But...
I don't have to like it.
Put your hand under the door.
What?
Just do it.
Oh, God.
He stopped breathing.
No. I'm not ready yet.
I don't... I don't...
Just please...
I'm not ready yet.
Oh, God.
Oh, my sweet Tommy.
Mommy loves you so much.
Oh, Mommy loves you so, so much.
How's Morgan doing?
She just lost her baby. How
do you think she's doing?
Okay, look, Karev...
Come on. It's been a long night.
Whatever you want
to nag me about,
just... Can't it
wait? No, it can't.
I need you as my
peds fellow next year.
I need you to pass your boards,
and you can't pass your
boards unless you take them.
Look, I need to stay
here with Morgan...
Morgan needs to get
by without you right now.
You were her baby's
doctor. That's all.
She's gonna be okay.
I will make sure she is.
The test is gonna
be in three hours.
I have never once seen you
give up on a patient, Karev.
Don't give up on this.
I'm never gonna
get there in time.
Try.
Are you up?
Uh-huh.
How are you feeling?
Worse.
Get up.
Seriously, Cristina,
I don't think I can.
Open the door.
Just go get ready. I'll be fine.
Open the door, Mer.
Easy.
Okay, now that's the
last time you throw up.
Mind over matter.
You can do this.
Okay?
Fine, Ma. You were right.
I always feel...
Sorry. I thought this
was my mom's room.
Uh... Uh...
No, no problem. I thought
you were room service.
No problem at all. Okay.
No.
Good luck, baby.
I...
Do you think he's traumatized?
For life.
Well, we did it.
We made it through the night.
You know why, Zola? 'Cause
we're survivors, me and you.
And your mom's
gonna pass the boards,
and hopefully you don't throw up
on me in the next
15 minutes, right?
Where have you been all night?
At the hospital. I was
finishing your neuro research.
Why is she in a
bumblebee costume?
She's thrown up on
all of her other clothes.
Mark said that...
That he misses me.
But I miss him, you know? I...
I really...
I really miss him.
You know, and he...
He thinks that I
still love Jackson,
but I try to tell
him that I don't.
I try to tell him
that I still love him...
But I open my mouth...
And nothing comes out.
And everything is terrible.
It's gonna be okay.
What?
Cristina texted,
and she's about to go in.
She's feeling good. And...
And she's ready.
I just thought
you'd want to know.
Kindergarten, high school...
College, med school...
Residency...
It all leads to this moment.
Good luck.
Diana Acardo. Here.
April?
Come on. You're not
even gonna look at me or...
No.
No, it's not you,
Jackson. It's...
It's Jesus.
I was a virgin
because I love Jesus.
And now Jesus hates me.
Some people can
crack under the pressure.
April Kepner.
Hi.
Others thrive.
Jackson Avery.
Here.
Oh. Sorry.
- Either way...
- Matthew Anderson.
There's nothing left to do.
No more studying...
Nice to meet you.
No more preparing.
Cristina...
Mind over matter.
Cristina Yang.
Pleasure to meet you.
Like it or not, the
moment has arrived.
Meredith Grey.
The only thing
left for you to do
is show up.
Alex Karev.