Previously on ER:
- About the other night...
- Stop.
It's over. I told Meg it's over.
Maybe for you, but any idiot could
see from the look on her face...
that it's not over for her.
Meg, Sarah, this is Neela.
So I called the Nursing Director
and I signed on for another month.
Huh. Well...
Enough meds for ninety
percent of your people.
You can fill this for
a month's supply.
While looking for
cans and bottles...
- I can't believe it's me up there.
- Yeah, well, you better get used to it.
I couldn't have done
it without my producer.
No, and it's too early to tell who
might've been responsible for the attack.
Obviously, we will do...
Ugh. I can't even look at her.
You don't think
she's a role model?
Not for me, but
she's impressive.
Yeah, if Shaquita needs a role
model, she can turn on Oprah.
What if she wants to
be secretary of state?
Well, then, she can look
up Madeleine Albright.
Come on, Henry. I'm
gonna get you dressed.
Here we go. Would
you mind getting that?
Sure. WEAVER: That's my boy.
Kerry Weaver's residence.
May I ask who's calling?
It's a news director.
From Miami.
Hello?
Are you crazy? What would I do
with two iPods and three Xboxes?
Fine, fine. Have your
fraud department call me.
What happened?
My credit card was
declined this morning.
It's time to dial back
on that escort service.
That's what you get
for being a big spender.
No, since I bought the
Beemer, I'm on a tight budget.
That explains the pants.
Hey, Sam, can you check
a sat on my bronchiolitic?
- No problem.
- Thanks.
Do you need any help?
Uh, actually, I need to move
some stuff to my new place...
and I hear you have a truck.
Yeah, I only help people
move if they promise to feed me.
We can work that out.
Hey, everybody. Over here. Whoa!
This is Sarah.
Hey, Sarah. SARAH: Hi.
- Cool hat.
- I like your necklace.
Thank you. My kid gave it to me.
He's about your age.
Hey.
She's shadowing me today.
You didn't clear that with me.
- I talked to Kovac and Weaver about it.
- But you didn't talk to me.
You must be that guy that's
always riding Uncle Tony.
- You know, like a bull in heat?
- Shh!
So, what else does
Uncle Tony say about me?
The rest I'm not allowed to say.
Make sure she signs
a confidentiality form.
And if she gets hurt,
she's your responsibility.
Understood, Uncle Tony?
Aye, aye, captain.
Kerry, this is huge.
You know how hard it is to
get your own morning show?
It's not my own show. I'd
just be the health reporter.
And get full-time, with
your own daily segment.
It's flattering,
but I'm a doctor.
Who just got demoted from a
hospital she worked at for over 10 years.
I love medicine. I've never
pictured myself doing anything else.
You'd still be able to do
that on your own show.
Will you stop saying that?
I'm not leaving Chicago,
I'm not leaving my friends...
and I'm not pulling
Henry out of his preschool.
You can find another preschool.
Yvonne Devilliere, 37,
tripped and fell on the sidewalk.
- My leg just gave out.
- Any LOC?
- Negative.
- I don't know what happened.
- I gotta take this.
- Forehead contusion and knee abrasion.
- Need to clear her neck, let's roll.
- This is hers.
- Do you know where you are?
- I know I'm not home.
Kerry, it's Miami.
You've got to consider it.
- When does the station want an answer?
- By tomorrow.
Better start thinking about it.
- I already have.
I'm not doing it.
C-spine X at Trauma 2. Let's go.
Kerry, we're talking "Miami"
Miami. South Beach, Miami.
C-spine's clear.
- Get-naked-at-the-Delano Miami.
- Take her off the board.
Is my sketchbook here?
Yeah, it's in the corner.
Ready?
Can't steal my 15 minutes
and then punt them away.
Not now, Morris.
- Are you an artist?
- A painter.
- Open your mouth, please.
- There we go.
No intraoral trauma
or dental fractures.
Glucose is 295.
- Do you have diabetes?
- My sugar's always high.
- I'm supposed to watch my diet.
- Are you on any medications?
Clindamycin for my foot.
Chronic infection at the
base of the second toe...
with some
surrounding cellulitis.
Does this hurt?
I've been limping for
a while, but I'm fine.
Okay, let's get a foot
series and culture the wound.
Okay.
Kerry. Kerry.
Listen, listen.
You could be the next
Judge Judy, Dr. Phil. No, Ellen.
- Go clear some patients, Morris.
- Well, come...
This is the big leagues, Weaver.
The majors, take your swing.
- Looks bad.
- Yeah.
Hurt her ankle during dance
class. Waiting on surgical consult.
- A surgical consult?
- Yeah.
Her fiancé fell on her.
You okay, honey?
Good luck.
- Hey.
- Remember Sarah?
- Hi, Sarah.
- She'll be shadowing me.
- Got your message.
You're gonna have fun.
Where does your belly hurt?
- All over.
That's good bowel sounds.
- FAST exam was negative.
- She doesn't look like a whore.
- Excuse me?
- Sarah.
- She just call me a...
- A whore. She called you a whore.
- Nobody called you a whore.
- Mom did.
- Sarah.
- Well, your mom's mistaken.
- You calling my mom a liar?
- You wanna go home?
Let's get a CT scan, shall we?
Hey, did you see my
infected G-tube in 3?
I'm about to go and check on
him. That tosser called me a whore.
- She seems so sweet.
- I've never been called a whore.
Did she say dirty
whore or filthy whore?
- Is there a difference?
- Depends on the whore.
Edgar Dixon, vomited blood,
passed out in the hardware store.
Pressure was 80 palp.
Type and cross
four. Call for O-neg.
Pulse is 105.
- Did you call my wife?
- Sir, be still.
It's Thursday. She's
at the hairdresser.
We called her, she's on her way.
- First bag is in.
HemoCue's 12.4.
Okay, forget the O-neg. Twenty
of IV famotidine, 10 of Reglan.
Another liter of saline, wide
open. Sir, have you had belly pain?
I felt nauseous today.
- Ever had an ulcer?
- No.
- Drink much alcohol?
- Not a drop.
- Belly's benign.
- Who's your doctor?
I don't really have one.
Are you on any medication?
Something from the
drugstore for arthritis.
- Ibuprofen? Naproxen?
- I don't know.
Some arthritis medications
can cause an ulcer.
- Is that serious?
- Keeps bleeding, could be.
- Hey, Sam.
- What's up?
- You have a guest.
- Go ahead.
Says she's family, drove
all the way from Dallas.
Oh, no. Thank you, Haleh.
Grandma?
Don't tell me we're out
of Compazine again.
Pharmacy's coming
to restock. Try Tigan.
Good idea.
Listen, I just heard
about your job offer.
No, don't worry, I'm
not moving to Miami.
- You're not considering it?
- No. I like it here.
We may have our occasional gunplay,
but at least we're helping people.
I don't need to tell you
January is budget month.
They're asking me
to make some cuts.
They want me to
lose an Attending.
Well, maybe we can
send Morris to Miami.
Morris' salary won't do it.
I need to cut at
least 200 grand.
Well, the only people who
make that much are you and...
You're kidding, right?
- Kerry, I have to cut costs somewhere.
- You're firing me?
- And since you have this opportunity...
- And this is how you tell me?
There is no good way.
It's unbelievable.
Kerry, you've been
doing this for a long time...
and I know it is
not for me to say...
but lately, it seems
like you've had enough.
- What?
- Most of the time...
you're out doing news.
Yeah, I do those
stories on my days off.
Excuse me, I need some Unasyn.
I'm sorry, my hands are tied.
- I was just trying to...
- To do what?
To do the right thing
or do the easy thing?
Kerry, I'm not happy about this.
You know what?
When they were gonna fire
you, I stepped up, I took the fall.
That's the only reason I
ended up back in the ER.
And that's the only
reason that you're still here.
Blood count's holding at 30, which
means you don't have ongoing loss.
We were in Atlantic City last
weekend and he started getting ill then.
I knew he should've
gone to the doctor.
Honey, you were right, I know.
Could have an ulcer or
a tear in the esophagus...
We're gonna admit you, have a
specialist look at you to make sure.
Do you wanna come and
fill out some paperwork?
I'll be right back, honey.
- I love you.
- I love you too, baby.
- This is the first you've heard of it?
- He just told me.
- Oh, I can't believe this.
- Just let it go, Haleh.
Let what go?
Your guy is firing Dr. Weaver.
Mrs. Dixon, I'll meet you
at that desk over there.
- Okay.
- He's what?
Budget cut.
I don't care if you
have a job offer.
You are the best
Attending in this place.
- What do you mean, another job offer?
- In Miami.
- Plain films on Yvonne's foot.
- Kerry.
- Oh, man.
- What's going on?
This is bad. I
gotta deal with this.
I know. I'll talk to him.
I looked at your x-ray...
and turns out, you have an infection in
the bones of your second and third toes.
Osteomyelitis, what else is new?
You knew about this?
I cut my foot.
The clindamycin's
supposed to clear it up.
Well, it isn't working...
and based on your increased
pain, it's getting worse.
So I give the antibiotics
a few more weeks.
Your diabetes has decreased
the blood supply to your toes...
so the antibiotics
aren't working.
What are you saying?
Surgery's your only
chance for a cure.
Surgery?
Partial amputation.
You want permission
to cut off my foot?
Not your whole
foot, but two toes.
No.
Look, if you don't do this, the
infection could spread and you could die.
I'll take my chances.
Mrs. Devilliere.
I am walking out
of here on both feet.
Hm.
Get out of my way.
They just kicked you out
of the retirement home?
Nobody cares about the elderly.
Did you get in a fight
with your boyfriend?
Which one?
It was a horticultural
infraction.
A what?
They didn't like my garden.
Why?
What were you planting?
The usual.
- Lavender, basil...
- Grandma.
Maybe a little cannabis.
- You were growing weed?
- It's medicinal.
You don't have glaucoma.
Guess why, sweetie.
I can't believe you.
You're 75 years old.
You're lucky they
didn't throw you in jail.
Then I could visit your mother.
She gets out next week.
- Identity theft. It's a victimless crime.
- No, it's not.
You're right.
Well, she married
this nice electrician.
Sweet Mexican guy, Pablo.
Well, maybe fifth
time's a charm.
Look, Sam, I know we
have drama, but we're family.
So how long are
you staying, Gracie?
Just till you throw me
out, not a bit longer.
Okay, Mr. Richmond, we'll see you
next week for your suture removal.
You're still here.
The bus is slow.
I thought maybe you were
having second thoughts.
I know this is a difficult
decision, but the surgery doesn't...
I'm tired of losing things.
I have lost my husband, my
house, the city where I grew up in.
Damn storm took it all.
You're from New Orleans.
You couldn't tell from my
bright smile and stunning glow?
Is that how you got injured?
Everybody begged us to leave...
but we thought it
would pass over...
like Ivan and all the
other ones before that.
When it finally hit...
my husband, Duane, and I went up
to the attic and broke through the roof.
A boat finally got us and
took us to the 610 overpass.
That's when I realized
my foot was cut.
Something in the flood
waters must've hit it.
It's surgery.
It's scary, but you don't
have to die from this.
Too many tough choices.
I'm afraid to make
the wrong decision.
Then let me help you
make the right one.
Will you trust me?
I guess I ain't got a choice.
You never said it was Weaver.
You have to fight for her.
- I did, but I have to make decisions.
- Why didn't you tell me?
- It's not your concern.
- That is like your mantra.
- What's that mean?
- Never mind.
She's one of the best
doctors on the floor.
I know that, but she's also
one of the most expensive.
Look, this is the job, and I
don't like it any more than you do.
Eighty-four-year-old
with shingles.
Stop it, you freak.
Lenny Rivers, got punched by
a passerby, fell on his tailbone.
- Okay?
- Analgesics, doughnut pillow, discharge.
Whoa, what about x-rays? I
gotta file for a disability claim.
You're not supposed to talk.
Go and order the films.
- Can I get a Percocet?
- Yeah, but you may need to be patient.
GI lab can take him at 4.
Okay, let's send
off a repeat CBC.
Ben, you got the Narcotics keys?
Oh, my bad, I meant to
leave them on the Admit desk.
The pressure's down to 70
systolic. Open up the saline.
Okay, put him in Trendelenberg.
Two units of packed
cells, and get Pratt here.
- He's gonna need a second line.
- Yeah, intubation tray.
- Dawn's from New Orleans too.
- What part?
Seventh ward by
the Florida Canal.
I used to work at
Charity. What about you?
Ninth, over near Jackson
Barracks. But I was born at Charity.
- You need to sign here too.
- You've been back?
I'm not ready.
Are you sure I need this?
Oh, yeah. The infection's deep into
the bone of the second and third toe.
Removing them is the
only way to prevent spread.
How long have you
been a surgeon?
Almost 15 years.
Dr. Dubenko's one of our best.
And how many
surgeries have you done?
Ten thousand.
What about toes? How many toes?
- I've done a lot of toes.
- He's good.
- You working all night?
- I beg your pardon?
- You seem a little tired.
- No, I'm fine.
I slept in my own bed last night.
You have nothing to worry about.
Can we have one of those
mirrors so I can watch my operation?
Oh, no, no. You're
gonna be fast asleep.
Dr. Weaver said I
didn't have to go under.
That's what Dr. Weaver said?
Just give us a sec.
Why would you tell her
she could be awake?
She barely agreed
to the surgery.
- Just give her an epidural.
- Anesthesia is better.
She's afraid of the dark.
She's a Katrina victim.
My heart goes out to her,
but epidural can drop her BP.
But general
anesthesia isn't risk-free.
- It's more efficient.
- Okay, cut the crap, Lucien.
You don't want her awake...
because you don't wanna
answer a bunch of questions.
I'll go up with her, I'll handle
her, she won't get in your way.
Okay.
Second unit is in.
Well, hang a third. Sats
are up to 90, call for a vent.
I already did. Somebody
get his wife here.
- Talk to me, Ray.
- Upper GI bleed, systolic of 60.
Second IV is in,
ready for blood.
- Has he had ulcers?
- We couldn't get a good history.
I know this guy. Was he here last week?
- No, first time to County.
Wait, how long has he been here?
- An hour and a half.
He's just getting a second IV?
- He was stable.
- No GI bleed is stable.
- Hematemesis only once, crit was...
The guy needed therapy. Why
wasn't an Attending involved?
- Abby and I both agreed...
- You're both Residents, Ray.
Get Abby in here now.
Call the blood bank, stay
ahead four units, and get FFP.
- I'll fire up the rapid infuser.
- You should've anticipated this.
- How long will the surgery take?
- About two hours.
Can you sign out marshmallow
girl so she can get out?
- Lucien, I'll be up in a minute.
- I know you will, Kerry.
Now, what's his problem?
Control freak. You okay?
- It's hard seeing folks from back home.
- Did your whole family come up?
- My aunt let eight of us move in.
- Eight? Wow, that must be hard.
Some moved back to make
sure their houses weren't seized.
The rest never wanna go back.
No, there's no
way that that's me.
Well, where did you
ship two iBooks to?
See, I don't even live there.
Is he still trying to work
out his credit problem?
Mine took years.
Come on. Go ahead, Gracie.
It says you're gonna
live a long time.
My family lives
well into their 90s.
Come on, look in there, and
tell me something I don't know.
- It says you're gonna be very wealthy.
- That's what I'm talking about.
Hey, Sam, Curtain 3 needs bilateral
leg ultrasounds to rule out DVT.
Okay. Come on, Gracie,
I'll put you in the break room.
Hey, Gracie. Am I
gonna have good luck?
We'll see.
Call me at 8.
I love that woman.
He's not even your
type, Grandma.
Well, you know what they say.
- Once you go black...
- Grandma.
You still living at
the same place?
We were living at this house
where I was working part-time...
but it wasn't really the
best environment for Alex...
so we just moved.
Is he still playing soccer?
Mm-hm. Indoor now. He's
the best left wing on the team.
How are his grades?
A's and B's. He's doing amazing.
Sweetie, that's great.
I'm proud of him.
Of both of you.
Thanks, Grandma.
That means a lot to me.
- How's my Xbox 360?
- What are you talking about?
Your little klepto of
a son is now a felon.
He stole my credit card number and
has been having stuff sent to your house.
- Are you kidding me?
- Do I look like the Last Comic Standing?
I bet you that necklace
you have on is mine too.
- Amp of epi is in.
- No, he needs volume, not epi.
Edgar?
What's wrong with
him? What's going on?
- Six units in so far.
- Getting harder to bag.
I just went to the cafeteria.
They said he was fine.
He's in pulmonary edema.
- What's going on? He was stable.
- Your husband doesn't have a doctor?
Not a regular one.
Is he gonna be okay?
- So, what, no past history, no meds?
- Renuvium, he's on Renuvium.
Mrs. Dixon called home.
Her son read the name.
Where would he
get Renuvium from?
At some church clinic
on the South Side.
- What church?
- First Mission Baptist on Calumet.
What, they got a doctor there?
Oh, I don't know.
I wasn't with him.
Oh, God.
Units 11 and 12 are running.
- And three of FFP.
- Run the platelets here.
- Try more volume?
- Maybe GI can scope him.
- Not without a pulse.
- What's our rhythm?
- Asystole.
Edgar, honey, please.
Please, be okay.
- Another four units, push another epi.
- He had five rounds of meds.
- Try an intra-aortic balloon?
- Too late.
Let's check a HemoCue,
PT/PTT, see where we are.
Pratt. Pratt, it's time to stop.
- No.
- No, don't you stop.
This is a reversible condition.
- Not anymore.
Forty-two minutes. We're
not gonna get him back.
You know she's right, okay?
Nobody's called it yet.
Please.
Please, keep going.
Time of death, 16:48.
No.
Oh, darling.
- I won't feel anything?
- Not with the spinal anesthetic.
Especially since
it's me who placed it.
Do you want a pulsed lavage?
Three liters, polymyxin
all in one bag, please.
I was in New Orleans once. I
became addicted to beignets.
Cafe Du Monde's
my favorite spot.
Where are you from? - London.
Really? I spent a
year in college there.
- Power setup?
- Micro E set with sagittal saw.
Grabbing to get rid
of the diseased bone.
Still plan to scrub in on
the robotic prostatectomy?
I certainly am, as
soon as we finish here.
You should check out
this new machine, Kerry.
Unbelievable.
Ensures perfect
nerve-sparing technology.
All for the low, low
price of 1.5 million.
The budget committee
approved that?
Yeah, they finally cut
us a break this year.
Culture tubes?
Aerobic and anaerobic, please.
Zosyn infusing.
Bovie?
Good.
Now, isolate the
neurovascular bundle.
What does that mean?
They're protecting
the nerves and arteries.
BP, 80 systolic.
- What's happening?
- One liter saline bolus...
- and get her head down. WEAVER:
Is this a reaction to the spinal?
Don't think so. BP
dropped after the antibiotic.
- Anaphylaxis?
- Could be an allergy to penicillin.
Sats are dropping, 88 percent.
What do we do?
I must've seen three or
400 patients at that church.
Didn't even remember the guy.
This is our fault.
Couldn't this have happened if he got
the drug through a regular prescription?
I don't know.
I have to go talk to her.
You're gonna tell her that
we're the ones from the church?
I'm not gonna bring you into it.
But I'll let her know I was
the one running the clinic.
Yvonne, we're gonna sedate you
and place a tube to help you breathe.
No, I'm not going under.
Etomidate's going in. - Honey.
You're not getting
enough oxygen.
When they left me on that
bridge, I woke up in the darkness.
Listen, Yvonne.
Sats only 81.
- What are you doing?
- Getting IV epinephrine.
- She's anaphylaxing. NEELA:
I can hear the wheezing here.
Ari can manage an airway.
No, her hypoxia's
worsening. She needs this.
Hard to bag.
We only ever give
IV epi for a full arrest.
Then you're about to
learn something new.
- Are you kidding me?
- Dr. Weaver, stop.
Pushing 2 cc's one to 10,000.
This should buy time to
do controlled intubation.
With all due respect,
this is my O.R.
I don't care. I lost my
job to pay for your robot.
I care about this patient.
Easier to bag. Heart
rate's coming down.
- Sats are up to 95. Go for it, Ari.
- Looks like the epi worked.
You just got very
lucky, Dr. Weaver.
None of this looks
like healthy tissue.
You're absolutely
right. It's into the tarsal.
So, what are we gonna do?
- She needs a BKA.
- No, wait, wait, wait.
You're not gonna
amputate below the knee.
Lucien, I promised her that
she wouldn't lose the foot.
The MRI was fine.
MRI was three weeks old.
- And it's progressed.
Prep for BKA. Let's
move the drapes.
No, can't you just take the
toes and give her six weeks...?
She's diabetic with vascular
disease, Kerry. She'd never heal.
Get me the Zimmer saw.
I love Italian food.
When I was in Venice,
they had this joint...
had the best fettuccini
you ever tasted.
Well, there's no
gnocchi like my gnocchi.
So maybe we can go to
the movies this Saturday.
There's a cool space movie, but it's
supposed to be good for adults too.
- See if I'm working.
- You're not. Just made the schedule.
Cool. Then it's a date.
Grandma?
Hi, Alex. Look at you.
So grown up. MORRIS: Hey.
Hey. Come here,
you little Artful Dodger.
- Alex, what the hell is going on?
- What?
- Did you steal from Dr. Morris?
- No. Why?
Where'd you get your Xbox from?
Well, um, Mr. Elliot
bought it for me.
Did he buy me this necklace too?
No, I bought you that necklace.
- Alex, you come here.
- What?
Now, don't give me
any attitude, Mr. Man.
If this was 20 years ago...
I could knock you back to China
and not have Social Services on me.
So I'm gonna ask you
one time and one time only.
Did you steal Dr. Morris'
credit card? Yes or no?
Gracie, just...
I, um... No, don't stammer.
Don't stutter and
look me in the eye.
Did you or did you not
steal his credit card?
I'm sorry, okay?
No, don't you say sorry to me.
You say sorry to Dr. Morris.
You know better.
I'm sorry, Dr. Morris, for
stealing your credit card.
Well, all right.
We'll figure it out.
You can start paying
me back in installments.
- Fine.
- Alex, why would you do that?
- Hey.
- No, you work, and I'll get him.
Hey, Nelson Wilcox, 39, vomiting and
abdominal pain, hypotensive after a liter.
Sam. We need you.
Morris, I don't even
know what to say.
What about my necklace?
- Vitals?
- 92/58, pulse is 97.
- I'm Dr. Kovac, where does it hurt?
- My stomach.
We were getting fitted for snowboard
boots. He started feeling queasy.
Get him on a monitor
and start a second line.
He's got pancreatitis
from gallstones.
He's supposed to have
surgery next month.
CBC, Chem-7, LFTs,
lipase and calcium.
He's been feeling good, so we
planned this trip to the Rockies.
Call my dad.
He turns 40 in February.
We got 15 people coming.
Don't forget a D-stick.
Check for hyperglycemia.
- But he's gonna be all right, isn't he?
- Systolic's down to 78.
All right, another
liter, wide open.
Hold on, lungs are wet.
- He's in failure or third spacing.
- Either way, he's hypotensive.
He needs volume. You
wanna try albumin, 25 percent?
- That won't work. ABBY:
I've seen Weaver do it.
- IV's blown and veins are crap.
- Sterile sixes and cordis to me.
Gonna throw in a subclavian.
He ate this huge plate
of waffles yesterday.
- I mean, I told him not to do it.
- Abdomen's tense.
I'll get the ultrasound
and call Surgery.
We don't know what
we're dealing with.
I think we have an idea.
If it's acute pancreatitis...
first-line management is
supportive care, not surgery.
They need to be involved.
- Got a flash.
- Sat's dropping, 82.
Mr. Wilcox?
You told her you
were the doctor?
And that I prescribed
the Renuvium.
And she's okay with that?
Well, she understands
it was a mistake...
and she's trying to
digest what's happened.
- You've gotta talk to Pastor Watkins.
- Oh, yeah. We're shutting it down.
- Yeah.
I can't leave my post. You have
to page Dr. Gates from the desk.
- Come on, there's 50 people there.
- I don't care...
It's okay. She's with me.
- What's he protecting, Fort Knox?
- I didn't know you were coming.
I was in the neighborhood.
Wanted to see how she was doing.
- You having fun, huh?
- Yeah, it's been great.
We treated this mime guy
and a lady who broke her ankle.
Cool, babe.
- So this is where you work, huh?
- Yeah, this is it.
You wanna see the
trauma rooms back there?
- Yeah.
- Come.
- Is your girlfriend there?
- Meg.
- Or is she out buying Ikea furniture?
- We're not gonna do this right now.
Oh, no. Now is the perfect time.
Let me show you the
break room so Tony...
No, Sarah.
- Tony has to clear a few things up.
- You're drunk.
You were gonna walk out
and move in with that little bitch?
- Meg.
- You're a liar.
Sarah, he's done
nothing but lie to us.
All he ever does is lie.
- Mom, don't.
Oh, speak of the bitch.
- Don't walk away from me!
- Meg.
- No, you need to hear this.
- No, I don't think I do.
Mom, stop it.
- I did everything for him.
- Meg.
- I straightened him out.
When he was a mess, when
he was just a useless vet.
I used my husband's insurance
money to put him through medical school.
You don't get to have
him, do you hear me?
- You don't get to take him from us.
- Meg!
- Where's Kovac?
- Trauma 2.
- Increase the peep.
- I can't, I'll give him a pneumo.
PVCs. Hundred of lido.
He's okay, isn't he?
I mean, he's okay.
His oxygen is low, and it's causing
his heart to beat in an abnormal rhythm.
Pulse ox, 78.
He's not dying, is he?
Luka, Surgery orders
some million-dollar toy...
- and I'm expensive? We need to talk.
- Not right now.
- V-tach.
- No pulse, starting compressions.
- Charging to 200.
- What do you got?
Acute pancreatitis,
hypotensive despite 6 liters.
What's happening?
- What's happening?
- Okay, clear.
Get back, get back.
Will somebody talk to me?
He's in cardiac arrest,
so you have to stand back.
- Is he bleeding from somewhere?
- His crit's stable.
- Has Surgery been here?
- They wanna observe in the ICU.
Get them back in,
18-gauge spinal needle...
connector tubing
and a manometer.
- We don't have time for that.
- What are you doing?
Checking for abdominal
compartment syndrome.
He's got arrhythmia.
Focus on the heart.
His BP sucks because the abdominal
pressure's crushing the vena cava.
Can't ventilate, because his
belly's compressing his lungs.
Okay, hold compressions.
Forty-two centimeters.
More than enough to
cause end-organ damage.
Okay, resume
compressions. Ten blade.
- Ma'am, what's your name?
- Marnie.
Your husband's pancreatitis is causing
swelling of all the abdominal organs.
- Another 50 of lido.
- Pushing it.
He doesn't need cardiac meds,
he needs to be decompressed.
Luka, you know I'm right.
Uh!
Pickup, sew set.
Retract the superficial layers.
- I'm doing CPR.
- He won't need it after this.
Back in sinus with a pulse.
Saline and sterile towels.
I still got a few
tricks up my sleeve.
I can't lose you, T.
This ain't just
the booze, is it?
You can't walk out on
us. We're your family.
Family?
What you did there, you
call that family? I work here.
You've been avoiding me.
What did you want me to do?
Move on.
You don't love me anymore.
Not the way you want me to.
- I'll change.
- You can't.
It's not about that.
You can't change.
You'd rather be
with that little bitch?
Back off. She has
nothing to do with this.
She has everything
to do with this.
All right.
I'll tell you one
last time, Meg.
I'm sorry, but it is over.
You don't care about Sarah?
Of course I do.
Well, I mean, do you not
wanna see her anymore?
I never said that, Meg.
Because...
that's what's gonna
happen if you do this.
You would hurt her
just to get back at me?
You're a damn liar.
You prick. Damn you.
- Prick!
- Knock it off.
Listen... You listen to me, Meg.
There's nothing you can do
to keep me away from Sarah.
Do you understand that?
Hey, it's cold out here.
You should come back in.
I hate her.
You don't mean that.
She's crazy. That's
why Tony's leaving.
No, he loves you.
You know that won't ever change.
Can I ask you a favor?
Sure.
Find somebody else.
- Sorry?
- He doesn't love you.
He's just having sex with you.
- Sarah...
- That's what he does.
But he always comes back to us.
When we opened you, we
learned that the infection had spread.
We had to do the amputation.
I should've never trusted you.
With the new prosthetic leg,
you'll have complete mobility.
Every time I make
a choice, it's wrong.
This was the right thing to do.
My husband and I
were on that bridge...
for 27 hours...
before a helicopter came
and took us to the Superdome.
And when the buses came,
there was only one seat.
I didn't wanna
go, but he insisted.
And I took that seat.
I left him there.
It was about a week later when I
found out he died in that stadium.
It's not your fault.
I know.
It's God's.
Why did he do
this, take it all away?
He didn't take it
all, you're still alive.
You're getting another chance.
For what? What
am I gonna do now?
You're gonna...
You're gonna accept this,
and you're gonna go on.
Go home, paint.
Find a way to use this gift to make
sure people never forget what happened.
They can't forget.
You won't let them.
All right, Dr. Pratt, arsenic
overdose has an ICU bed.
All right, call Hematology.
He'll need chelation.
Just the man I wanna see.
Did you work on a
Edgar Dixon today?
Yeah. Why? What's up?
- He was getting Renuvium illegally.
- Yeah, so I heard.
Apparently, First Mission
Baptist is dispensing meds...
without a pharmacy license.
- I'll need his medical records.
- Yeah, but the family's not gonna sue.
It's for the State Medical Board.
There's gonna be an investigation.
- Angela, how's it going?
- Okay, just following up a record of...
I meant you, your
daughter. How's Danielle?
Oh, she's better. Thanks, Luka.
For everything.
Hey, Dr. Kovac. Can I
talk to you for a minute?
Yeah.
In private?
- This is nice, Sammy.
- Thanks.
You remember when
we lived in that trailer?
You guys lived in a trailer?
- It was a mobile home.
- That's uppity for "trailer."
- Go unlock the door.
- Sure.
Where you from, Ben?
I'm from Georgia. Town
called Richmond Hill.
I had a boyfriend
once in Chatham.
He dumped me. I
swear it was for his sister.
My grandma has lots of stories
about her antics with men.
Oh, I'm not scaring you, am I?
You are one of the sanest guys
that Sam has ever been with.
We're just friends, Gracie.
Yeah, that's what
Angelina and Brad said.
Hey.
Do your homework, brush
your teeth and go to bed.
Tomorrow, we talk
about the new rules.
Go. ALEX: All right.
- Oh.
- I'm sorry.
You owe me dinner, right?
I'm so sorry, I forgot.
Okay, we finish unloading, and
then I will order us pizza, or we could...
I've got a better idea.
I'm glad we got past
the awkward part.
Yeah.
You need a pharmacy
license to dispense meds.
Your insurance covers
you only in the hospital.
I know. I was
trying to give back.
It's a felony,
Pratt. A man died.
- The hell was I thinking?
- I don't know.
This goes against
everything you've learned.
You okay, man?
I don't know what to do.
Were you the only one involved?
Yeah, yeah. It was just me.
Good. That's good.
I'll talk to Angela,
see what I can do.
Take a minute, okay?
All right. See you guys later.
Dr. Weaver, I need an
Attending order for Vanco.
Yeah, can you sign off
on my retinal detachment?
- Mm-hm.
- Okay. Thank you.
Kerry. Kerry, we need to talk.
- Oh, it's okay. I'm fine.
- No. Hey, I made a mistake.
What I said before... You
know how it is in this job.
I shouldn't give
in to the pressure.
I'm gonna find budget
cuts somewhere else.
There's no way we're losing you.
Thanks, but I resign.
- You what?
- I can't, I mean...
I've trained Residents, I've
saved lives, I even ran this place.
I loved it.
And I've probably gotten more
than I've given, but now it's time to go.
- Dr. Weaver, what are you saying?
- Kerry.
It's easy here.
It's comfortable, but that doesn't
mean it's the right thing to stay, sweetie.
Are you gonna go to Florida?
Yeah, I mean,
after Sandy died, I...
I thought I got over it. I
thought I moved on, but I...
I felt stuck, like
I'm treading water.
And it's taken a few years...
but now, I'm finally
ready to move forward.
So...
if you're ever in Miami, turn on
Channel 6, that's where you'll find me.
And if I'm not there, I'll be
on the beach with my son.
Kerry, wait.
Kerry. Kerry.
Please. Hey.
Luka, we're all right.
We're fine.