So he's a scalper.
He's a respiratory therapist.
But he's got a friend who
can get us good seats.
So it's either a sporting event
or a concert.
No more hints. Sporting event.
Were you one of those kids
who peeked at his presents?
Hi, guys. Hey.
Hey. You on swing?
Only an hour left.
Bringing your dog to work?
We're picking something up.
What's his name? Norman.
Hi, Norman. Don't let
him close to your leg.
John. What? Don't be ashamed.
He's a guy. I'm
getting him fixed.
Oh, God. What?
That car. What about it?
Read the license plate.
Huh. ABBY: "Man-o-med"?
Ha. That's Richard.
Ah. Who's Richard?
Randi, is there a guy named
Richard looking for me?
Your ex? Yes.
In the lounge,
talking with Dr. Kovac.
Call Security. Tell
them there's a BMW
illegally parked in
the ambulance bay.
She tried to quit three
times while we were together.
Got addicted to the gum.
What do you need, Richard?
You didn't return my calls.
When did you call?
Last night, this morning.
I haven't checked
my messages yet.
Excuse me. RICHARD:
Nice meeting you.
Yeah.
Look, it's your mom.
She's gone off the
reservation again.
She's holed up in a motel
outside of Muskogee, Oklahoma.
She called you? No.
Apparently, some guy that
she's been traveling with
prepaid the room
for a week, then split.
That was three weeks ago.
The manager of the
hotel got your old number,
which is my number,
and took it out of her bag.
What was he doing
going through her stuff?
Looking for money, I guess.
He says she's all spaced out.
She won't leave the room.
Is she answering the door?
Richard...
is she answering the door?
You should call this guy.
I'm sorry, Abby.
How did you fall?
Greased pigs. Heh-heh.
What? We were
chasing greased pigs.
Tau Beta Chi
against Gamma Psi Mu.
Is this a contest?
Oh, yeah. And thanks to Tasha,
Tau Beta kicked ass. Ha, ha, ha.
Been drinking already, huh?
It's Greek Week. Mm-hm.
Okay, we'll have to seal that
with some
calcium-hydroxide paste.
I'll be back. Mm-hm.
Abby?
What did the guy
say? She's there.
Um, he says she owes him $800.
Do you have that? Not really.
I do.
No, Luka.
Hey, I'll take care of it.
Don't give him a credit
card. We'll wire the money.
I told him I'd give it to
him when I got there.
When you got there?
I'm... I'm gonna take a redeye.
No, no, Abby. We'll
call the local hospital,
talk to a psychiatrist
and see if we can get
the police to bring her in.
I can't put my mother
in a lockup in Oklahoma.
You can fly down there
once she's medicated.
No, no, if I have to commit her,
it'll be easier to do it
from Chicago, trust me.
Why are you doing this?
Because my mother's sick.
I know. I saw her, and I saw
what she did to you last time.
Dr. Kovac, possible DKE
in 4. Accu-Chek is 400.
In... In a second.
I have to talk to
the supervisor,
see if I can switch my shift.
Abby, don't go out there.
It's my problem.
Damn it. You all right?
Oh, yeah. No problem.
Mark, I don't know why
you insist on baby-proofing
every drawer and cabinet.
The baby's not gonna
be crawling immediately.
There's a high likelihood that
he'll be advanced for his age.
Who was at the door?
UPS. More gifts.
Between the baby and the
wedding, they know me by name.
You didn't lift
anything, I hope.
No. It was light.
No lifting. I'm serious.
What are you doing?
Trying to get this
show on the road.
I hope you don't
have it on the floor.
I've been sitting
around for days.
I need to move.
Who's a good boy?
I had to pee, Haleh.
I didn't say anything.
You have nothing in coach?
Okay. Well,
what if I fly into...
To Oklahoma City?
Hi. Hi.
What did Richard want?
My mother has, uh, bottomed
out 40 miles outside of Tulsa.
And, of all people, the motel
owner had to call Richard.
Hey! Did you talk to her?
She... She's not
picking up the phone,
and she won't come
out of the room, so...
Hey, your dog!
John! Norman, drop that.
You brought him inside?
Yeah, we used the bathroom.
Is that gonna hurt him?
No. No worse than a chilidog.
No! No.
Good boy. Come on.
Did you get the
tickets? Yeah, all set.
So, uh, am I gonna
have to call you a cab,
or you gonna make it back?
I'll meet you outside.
What's wrong? I just
wanna change that bag.
Give me five minutes.
Or you can start running.
I'll wait. A dog has no business
in a hospital! Seeing Eye dog.
Well, how many people are
going to Oklahoma tonight? I...
No. Thank you.
You okay? I can't get a flight.
You trying direct to Tulsa?
I can't get anywhere close.
There's not even a connection
open. What are you doing?
I have a really
good travel agent.
She always finds
something somewhere.
Wanna fly out tonight?
Hi. Katie Witcher, please.
Open return? No, I
have to drive her back.
Why? Because she
can't handle flying.
You're gonna drive her all the
way back to Chicago by yourself?
Is Luka going with you?
Hey, Katie. It's John Carter.
Good. Yeah.
Any way that you could find me
two one-way tickets to Tulsa?
Tonight.
♪ A gathering of angels ♪
♪ Appeared above my head ♪
♪ They sang to me
This song of hope ♪
♪ And this is what they said ♪
Mark?
♪ They said, come sail away ♪
Mark! ♪ Come sail away ♪
♪ Come sail away with me ♪
♪ Come sail away ♪
Sorry, I didn't hear you.
I think it's time.
Will I have a black
eye? Probably.
Piggy-kick to the face.
Bet that's a new one, doc.
Ha, ha, ha, ha. It's
not funny, Kevin. Ow.
Sorry. Do you have a minute?
Yeah.
Your eye movement is intact.
But we'll have to take x-rays
to make sure
there's no fracture.
He could've cracked my face?
Probably not.
But maybe next time
you wrestle animals,
you should be sober.
Well, it wasn't my idea.
You're still the best-looking
piggy mud-wrestler I know.
Shut up, Kevin. Ha, ha, ha.
I'm taking an
11:40 flight to Tulsa.
Hold on, I checked.
There's a psychiatric facility
at Saint John's Medic...
Carter's coming with me.
What?
Her mom suffers
from bipolar disorder.
She's locked herself
in a motel room.
A motel room? Probably
in a major depression.
Well, why do you have
to go? He offered to help.
And I have to drive
her back here, so...
I offered to help.
No, you offered
to decide for me.
Abby, your mother
needs hospitalization,
not a road trip
with you and Carter.
Yeah, Luka. We're
doing it for the fun of it.
It's gonna be a blast.
It's a Bulls game.
You said you liked basketball.
I do. Then let's go.
Abby needs someone with her.
But why can't her boyfriend go?
Abby, it's... It's a mistake.
Are you gonna
lecture me on this? No.
Good. Because you
have no idea what it's like.
I grew up with this. And I... I
don't wanna be lectured on it.
I'm not lecturing.
I'm trying to help.
You're spending
the weekend with her.
And her depressed mother.
I will pay for the tickets...
It's not about the tickets.
Shut up! Don't
tell him to shut up!
Don't put yourself in the
position to get hurt again.
Well, you'd be the expert
at that, wouldn't you?
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. Go.
Rena. Okay, go.
I think I can make it.
Hospital policy. How
far are you dilated?
She wouldn't let me check.
You're the father,
not the doctor.
Ooh, I'll get it. You
get the elevator.
You having a baby?
Did your water break?
Why the sneakers?
I'll be on my feet. He's
worried about foot pain.
I've been through
this. I haven't.
Are you in labor?
You got cigars?
How far apart are
the contractions?
Three to five minutes.
For how long? Every hour.
Sounds like
you're getting there.
All right. Is it time?
We think so. Congratulations.
Don't be a hero.
Get the epidural.
We'll see.
She'll get it.
I'm so humiliated.
It was an honest mistake.
I've been through
the real thing.
I should know what
Braxton Hicks are.
Dr. Corday, you drop
that baby already?
Couple more hours. Or days.
I thought you were
having your baby.
I am. Just not right now.
They're sending us home.
This place ain't going anywhere.
Suppose I don't need
this chair anymore.
Relax. You'll need your energy.
♪ Trouble ♪
♪ Oh, trouble, set me free ♪
♪ I have seen your face ♪
♪ And it's too much,
too much For me ♪
Did you get any sleep
on the plane? No.
♪ Trouble ♪
♪ Oh, trouble, can't you see ♪
So why doesn't she like to fly?
♪ And there's
nothing Much left... ♪
What?
Your mom? Flying.
Uh...
Uh, one... Well, one day
she woke up and she decided
she wanted to take
us to Disneyland,
which sounded like a great idea.
We got to skip school,
and we all rushed
to the airport.
She didn't get on the plane? No.
When we were flying over
Nevada, the pilot came over the PA,
playing tour guide.
And...
she freaked out.
♪ Oh, trouble ♪
She was convinced we were
flying over a nuclear test site.
She tried to open the
emergency-exit door.
It took two flight attendants
and three passengers
to restrain her.
They tied her up right
there in the seat next to me,
and she screamed her head
off all the way to Los Angeles.
♪ Can't you see... ♪
Did you ever make
it to Disneyland?
No.
♪ I've seen ♪
♪ Your eyes ♪
♪ And I can see
Death's disguise ♪
♪ Hangin' on me ♪
♪ I... ♪
Thirty years,
and I still wonder.
Wonder what?
What brings her here?
He was an interstate trucker,
freelance by the
look of his rig.
He stayed one night,
prepaid the week, then left.
I figured he'd be
coming back for her.
She was ordering pizza
for a while, and then nothing.
Saw her by the candy
machine a few times,
tried to talk to her.
She didn't say nothing.
Well, should we, uh...?
We should knock first.
No. She don't answer.
Maggie?
Maggie, it's, uh...
It's John Carter.
We met in Chicago.
I have Abby with me.
Told you.
Thanks. We'll take it from here.
You're paying her bill,
right? Yeah, I'll take care of it.
Mom?
God.
Abby.
Do you have any clean clothes?
Mom?
Mom, you know where you are?
I'm in a motel. Where?
Where's the motel?
It's in Oklahoma.
Abby? Yeah?
How is she?
Oriented. No focal findings.
Can you run out to the car...
for me and grab my bag?
I brought some extra clothes.
Yeah, sure.
Raise your arms. No.
Yeah. No.
I need you to raise
your arms. Please?
No.
Hello?
Who's this?
Hey.
No, Abby's inside with her mom.
We're at the motel.
I don't know. I haven't
really seen her yet.
Abby's giving her a bath.
Ahem. Yeah, I will.
What?
You related to her?
I'm just gonna set
'em on the bed, okay?
Thank you.
And, uh, Luka called. He
said you can call him tonight.
Abby? ABBY: Yeah?
There's a diner about a
half mile down the road.
You want me to pick
up something to eat?
Uh...
Yeah. Some eggs maybe.
And some toast.
Sure.
Okay, I'll be right back.
You gonna be okay?
Abby?
Yeah.
Okay, lean your head back. No.
Come on. Come on.
There you go.
Okay.
I have to go to the bathroom.
Someone, please?
A nurse will help you.
When? Soon. You're late.
Four minutes. I needed a coffee.
You wouldn't be late if
Dr. Weaver was here.
That's true, but she's
not. Yep, it's showtime.
Will you take me
to the bathroom?
Get this guy a urinal.
Find a nurse. - Ow, my...
- What do we got?
- Frat boy. Roof to roof.
Didn't make it.
It's "fraternity."
You had a few? Stopped
counting yesterday.
Argh, I can't
walk on either leg.
Reed, you baby. Pete's
the one really messed up.
BP, 110/65.
Pulse, 120. Complains
of chest pain.
Man, you really ate it, bro.
I'm okay, man. I hit the trees.
Trauma panel, C-spine,
chest and pelvis.
- Fall from height?
- Maybe 20 feet.
Losers couldn't clear 6 feet.
It looks like you
had trouble too.
I was the only one that
made it. How'd he fall?
I jumped. Eww.
Come in.
No toast.
- Hope you like biscuits.
- Whatever.
Hi, Maggie.
John Carter, Abby's friend.
You don't have to clean up.
I gave the guy a little
extra money for the mess.
Abby, you don't
have to clean up.
I took care of it.
Hungry?
No. But she needs to eat, so...
Hey, Mom.
I need you to eat
some eggs now. No.
Yes. No.
Yep. Settle for one bite. No.
Come on. Oh, my God. No.
Come on. Just
one bite. Oh... Ugh!
Get that away. I don't want it.
Okay. We're ready to go then.
No. Yeah, we're leaving.
Let's go.
No, I wanna stay here. No,
we're leaving. Get the bags.
I'm staying here. No,
you're not staying here.
I'm staying. I'm taking
you back to Chicago.
I don't want to. Mom?
I don't wanna go back.
Mom, this one you're
not going to win.
Okay? So get up.
Get off the bed now!
Abby.
Okay, we'll carry you. No.
Yeah, we're gonna
carry you. Damn it.
Are you sure? I'm sure.
Get her into the car.
Why can't I stay here?
Why can't I just
stay here, please?
- Just let me stay here.
- Come on, Maggie.
Why can't I just stay? No. No.
I wanna stay here. Why
won't you let me stay?
Just let me stay here.
Damn it! Just let me stay!
Why won't you let me stay?
God.
Seat belt? No. Just go.
Let's get a post-procedure
film. You want a Foley?
Let's give this idiot a
tube in every orifice.
Can I please go to the bathroom?
Haleh, would you please
take this man to the bathroom?
In a minute.
Benton, right?
Peter Benton. Have
I seen you before?
Yes. What for?
I believe it was an
exploding condom.
Excuse me?
You filled a condom with
gas from a Bunsen burner,
and set it on fire.
Ah! Mr. Perry.
In my classroom. Uh-huh.
How are you? You
remember? Yes, yes.
I guess all that
detention time paid off.
Come. I'll take you
to the bathroom.
Thanks. I'm about
to have an accident.
You grew a few inches. Uh-huh.
So how have you been?
Good, until last
month. I had a stroke.
What from? Atrial fibrillation.
Left me with some left-sided
weakness, but I'm managing.
What are you doing here today?
I had my teeth
cleaned a few days ago,
and they won't stop bleeding.
Hm. What's your Coumadin
dosage? Five milligrams.
Any other bleeding?
From your...?
No, just my gums.
Did they draw your
blood? An hour ago.
I'll try to track down your labs
and see what
your prothrombin is.
Thank you, Peter.
I mean "Dr. Benton." Ah...
♪ Oh, very young, what
will you Leave us this time? ♪
♪ You're only
dancing On this Earth ♪
♪ For a short while ♪
♪ And though your dreams
may Toss and turn you now... ♪
I'm sorry.
♪ Like your daddy's best... ♪
I shouldn'ta let you come here.
You shouldn't have
to deal with this.
It's no problem.
Is this as bad as it gets?
Has it been worse?
It's always different.
Sort of.
Or maybe I'm different. Uh...
Your perspective
changes from 7 to...
To 20.
Although, it was
pretty bad the time
she locked herself in the
garage and turned on both cars.
She's been suicidal?
If you count attempted suicide.
How many times?
Seriously, two times.
♪ Will you carry the
words Of love with you? ♪
♪ Will you ride the great
White bird into heaven? ♪
♪ And though you
want To last forever ♪
♪ You know you never will ♪
You cut a tendon, Adam.
Broken bottle.
It was stupid. My fault.
Let me guess. Greek
Week. How'd you know?
Because you smell like
you've slept in a beer garden.
Actually, a car trunk, but...
Oh... Oh. Here.
So you were locked in a trunk?
Yeah.
It's a... It's a pledging
thing. Uh-huh.
And that's supposed to
make you feel like a man?
I don't know. It's tradition.
How did the bottle
break? I was, uh...
I was pounding it on
the trunk of the car.
I don't know why,
but I panicked in there.
It's called claustrophobia.
But I knew they'd come back.
They did last time.
You did this before?
Yeah, I'm pledging again.
I didn't make it
through last time.
Well, I guess you
really want this, huh?
It's a good house, and
th-they're good guys.
Don't you think you're
jumping the gun?
Hold on a sec.
I'll be right back.
You're ready to pop.
Shouldn't I be
the judge of that?
Is this time for real?
We should have been here
a few hours ago. We were.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
If we'd waited any longer, we
would have had a home birth.
Did you get any
sleep? Do I look rested?
Okay, good luck. Thanks.
A chef's salad
and a cup of pea soup for her.
No, just coffee. You...
You have to eat something.
No. Mom.
Pie.
Okay, fine. But could you bring
a glass of milk also, please?
Sure.
Well, it's about 30
more miles to Springfield.
And there's not much
after that until St. Louis.
Unless you wanna stay
in a town called Lebanon.
It sounds kinda dangerous.
So how'd you end up in
Oklahoma? Don't bother.
He can talk to me
if he wants. Fine.
How'd you end up in Oklahoma?
None of your business.
Oh!
What's that? Depakote.
No.
You can't make me, Abby.
I don't want to make you.
No, no, no. I want you
to do it on your own.
Thanks.
There you go.
Mmmmm.
I have to go to the bathroom.
No.
I can order for myself.
I can talk for myself.
I can pee for myself.
Just...
I'm not a child.
It's a bathroom.
What am I gonna do with myself?
Are you gonna follow
me in the stall? No.
Don't expect a thank-you.
Somebody had to come. We
needed to start her medication.
How long to reach
therapeutic levels?
Tomorrow night. It's
10 hours to Chicago.
I know. I-I'll take
her to my house.
I'll get her to Psych on Monday.
Are you working on Monday?
No, I'll switch shifts.
Well, what about Monday night?
Uh, Luka, I'm gonna have
to call you back. Why?
I'll call you back. Rena.
No, no. Wait. Because...
Wh-where'd she go?
You're misinterpreting this.
What? My mother.
I thought I locked that door.
I unlocked it.
Okay. I needed some air.
Okay. Okay.
See that family down there?
Right down there.
There's two little
boys over there.
They're fighting by the
pool. Do you see them?
And I think that must be
their parents over there,
having a cocktail.
I watch people
like that for hours.
People doing their marketing
and tying their shoes.
Just doing routine things
that probably
bore them to tears.
I think how lucky they are.
They have...
They have ordinary lives.
You could be like them.
No, I couldn't
ever be like them.
Yes, if you took your
medication. I tried.
I did everything
I could think of.
I got married. I had two kids.
I tried to fool everyone
that I was just like them.
God, why did you come, Abby?
Because you needed me.
There's no one here to save.
♪ Sunday, all the
lights Of London ♪
♪ Shining, sky is fading ♪
♪ Red to blue ♪
Do you want me to talk to her?
What would you say?
That I asked you to come with
me and help me with my mother.
You didn't ask me
to come with you.
Just get back and
send her some flowers.
I'm sure it'll be fine.
I don't think so. She's young.
If you get involved with a
teenager, expect drama.
We broke up.
You broke up?
She broke up. When?
Last night. Over a
basketball game?
Over you.
That's silly. What
does she think?
We're having an... An
illicit affair or something?
No.
Just that I have a crush on you.
It's not like the relationship
didn't have its obstacles.
Yeah, but I wouldn't want
you to break up because of me.
Face it. You're a home wrecker.
♪ Let go your heart ♪
♪ Let go your head ♪
Dr. Greene?
Hey, Malucci. Hey, I
got you your cigars.
Great. Congratulations.
Wow, she's a cute
one. Look at her.
You're gonna have to keep
the boys away from her.
What's her name? Ella.
Hiya, Ella, you're quite
the heifer, aren't you?
Can I hold her? No.
I just washed my hands.
Good for you, Dave.
Are you serious?
I'll see you later.
Why can't I hold her?
Go away, Dave.
Hey, you owe me 300
bucks for the cigars.
- What's the matter?
- My mother's coming.
She just left.
Yes. Well, she decided
she wants to come
help with her granddaughter.
We'll all get along famously.
Yeah, we'll see.
How did she do?
She was an angel.
She didn't even cry
with the heel stick.
Oh. Now she's gonna
give her mother a hard time.
Well, if you don't feed
her, I think she will.
I think she's hungry.
Well, the nurse said she'd
walk me through breast-feeding.
I don't think Ella knows that.
I suppose I can wing it.
Here we go. Oh, yeah. Oh.
Here you go. Oh,
it's okay. It's okay.
Just try and keep the
head above the tummy.
There you go.
Mark.
I don't know
whether I can do this.
Yes, you can. It
just takes patience.
No, I mean... I mean...
I know. I know what you mean.
You're gonna be great.
Can I help you?
Looks like you got a leak. What?
Yeah. Here's your problem.
You must have run over a nail.
But it just started hissing.
Yeah, I can patch that for you.
Fifteen dollars. You did that.
Just because I saw it
doesn't mean I did it.
- You put that nail in the tire.
- What's the problem?
He popped the tire. He
thinks I don't know about cars
'cause I'm a woman.
You want me to
fix it? Ten bucks.
Now his price is going down.
Fix it before we call the cops.
Five bucks?
Negotiating with me now?
Mom?
Mom.
What? What are you doing?
I'm hungry.
You're hungry? Yeah.
Okay. I'll go with
you. You all right?
Do you want something to eat?
No. What?
No. Here.
What's that? Egg salad.
It's disgusting. Not as
disgusting as Twinkies.
I don't want it. Uh,
and a veggie burrito.
You're getting a Slurpee.
And some Twinkies.
Anything else?
Yeah. A pack of
light cigarettes.
That's a nasty
habit. I know that.
You should take
better care of yourself.
$9.49.
Maybe I'm just being paranoid.
She was pretty close to traffic.
It's hard not to
overreact sometimes.
She seems better today.
She couldn't really be worse.
- All done.
All right. I'm gonna go
pay Paco his three bucks.
I'll bring the car around.
Coming.
You all set? Yeah.
How much longer to Chicago?
Two or three hours.
Abby, thank you for coming.
Good news. They haven't
given your room away.
Frank's calling a cab.
Right, Frank? Right.
Don't take any Coumadin tonight.
Take four milligrams tomorrow.
And I am going to
see you on Friday.
Thank you, Peter.
Ah, you're welcome.
I have to say I'm impressed
by your dispo skills.
I talked to his board and care.
They all refused to take him.
Oh, yeah? Well, I
promised to go by
and do his blood test.
Every other day? Mm-hm.
Since when does Peter
Benton give home care?
Yeah. Well, you know
what? I owe that guy.
He must have done something
for you to make house calls.
He was my junior high
science teacher. I did something.
I should have been expelled.
He gave me a month's detention.
Expelled? What did you
do? Blow the place up?
Almost. I had to prep the
experiments the night before.
And, just, you know, it changed
how I thought about things.
How I looked at school,
science, everything.
Did you ever tell him? No.
What was that for?
School, science, everything.
You did not. I did.
You did not. Why
would I make that up?
You got a perm?
Twice. Twice?
What?
It was junior high school.
That was the style.
I don't know what
planet you grew up on,
but I do not remember
perms on boys
ever being popular.
Yes, it was. Jenny
Butler liked it.
I'd like to see pictures of
it. I think I burned them all.
Twice.
So that means you thought
it looked good the first time.
As far as youthful
transgressions go,
I think it scores
pretty low on the scale.
If you say so.
♪ I don't know what
I'm Diving into ♪
♪ Just hanging by a moment... ♪
Is she still out?
Yeah.
Well, I think you'll be
all right by yourself.
I should be.
I really wanna thank
you again for doing this.
You didn't have to.
I'd never seen
Oklahoma before. No.
I mean it.
Well, I'll help you inside.
Okay, Mom. Uh, we're here.
Mom?
Wake up. We have to go inside.
Mom? Mom?
John!
What? She's not waking up.
Maggie? Maggie, can you hear me?
Maggie! Ah-ah. Ah.
Pupils are dilated. How much?
About nine millimeters.
Did she take something?
Sit her up. Did you
see her take something?
She's tachy. Oh, God.
Pulse is 130. God.
Don't see any head
injury. She took something.
Where'd she get it from?
Call the paramedics.
What are you doing?
We can be there
before they can get here.
Shut that door. Keep her
chin up. Keep her airway open.
Chuny, pull an intubation kit,
get a vent, NG and charcoal.
What size ET?
Seven and a half. She's little.
They're here. Okay.
And get her a unit bed!
Turn her head if she
vomits. She's cyanotic.
What's her Glasgow?
Negative 15, 2-2-4.
Got her? Yeah. Go.
Not anymore. She's
completely unresponsive.
Get a mask going at 10 liters.
Breaths are shallow, but
I think her airway's clear.
CBC, Chem-20, blood
and urine tox screens.
BP, 90/60.
QRS complexes look wide.
Get a 12-lead. NG tube.
Hold on.
No gag reflex.
One of Pavulon, 90 of sux.
- Look at this.
What? Diphenhydramine,
25 milligrams.
How many are
missing? All of them.
Twelve to a sheet. Three sheets.
Twenty-five times 36.
- That's 900 milligrams.
- Stand by with bicarb.
Hurry up, Carter.
Give me some cricoid pressure.
Charcoal after intubation.
Abby, you wanna be in
here? QRS complex is 0.16.
- Push the bicarb.
- Okay, I'm in.
Abby?
I'm okay.
19-year-old male. Passed
out from shots of tequila.
Wasn't breathing.
How long was he down?
Long time. They
thought he was sleeping.
And the writing?
Frat brothers did it.
Were trying to clean him.
Peter splinted him yesterday.
I can't get a pulse.
Nothing from the neck either.
Peter, was this your
patient? He's in V-tach.
- Charge the paddles.
- What happened?
Too much to drink.
Charged to 200.
Clear. PICKMAN: Clear.
How much? Uh, they
were having a contest.
Is someone coming in?
- They're all drunk.
Still V-tach.
Charge again. Amp
of epi. Come on.
Clear. PICKMAN: Clear.
No change. 100 of lidocaine.
Charge to 360. I'll
shock him again.
That doesn't work,
get him on the gurney.
He's young. We can get him back.
- Here we go. Clear.
Deteriorated to V-fib.
Let's get somebody
from that fraternity.
Find out what the hell happened.
Got more bicarb. Put
an amp in the next liter.
Charcoal is in. I
need vent settings.
Tidal volume, 600.
AC of 12 on 100 percent.
Pressure's down
to 80 after two liters.
Start dopamine at 10 mics.
Antihistamine overdose can
give you myocardial pump failure.
Did she have
sleeping pills with her?
I need another
Iomed for the drip.
Where did she get
them? Call X-ray.
Tell 'em we need
a portable chest.
She's hyper-reflexic.
Is the tox screen back?
She's seizing. Watch the tube.
Pulse ox is dropping.
Check the O-2.
We're bagging at 100 percent.
Hold on. Hold on.
Her finger probe fell off.
Help me keep her head steady.
- Hold on.
- Ativan's on board.
- Another four?
Give it a minute to work.
Still fib.
Pulse ox down to 72.
All right, um...
Push another epi. Shock again.
His friend is here.
Not you again.
Adam's pledging
Upsilon Psi Lambda.
I'm his big brother.
How much did you make him drink?
He drank on his own.
How much did you make him
drink? 35 tequila shots, maybe 40.
Clear.
Asystole.
All right, a
milligram of atropine.
And set up the
pacing pads. Come on.
Blood alcohol is
0.529. Tox screen:
negative for marijuana,
cocaine, opiates.
Adam wouldn't touch drugs.
Ready to pace.
Rate of a hundred.
Aren't you gonna
shock him again?
You can't shock a flat line.
You only shocked him once.
We've been shocking
him for 40 minutes.
No capture, no pulse.
Time of death, 2023. Here.
But you gotta help him.
His heart's been deprived
of oxygen too long.
He's gone.
Here.
Clean him up.
What? You and your friends.
You wrote this on him, right?
Yeah. But... But
it was just a joke.
I hope you got a
good laugh out of it.
We didn't know this
was gonna happen.
You're his big brother. You're
supposed to look out for him.
He drank voluntary... Shh-shh.
Just shut up, all right?
You get over there,
and you clean him up.
Hey, Maggie? Maggie,
can you squeeze my hand?
She's not waking up.
CT said they can take you.
She's got a unit bed? 2102.
You wanna call
Psych? No, no. Not yet.
She should be on a
hold. They can't talk to her.
Pressure's holding. You
wanna finish the Dilantin?
Yes. Have them check
her level in an hour.
I want her on a hold
when she wakes up.
She might not wake up.
Dr. Benton.
Hey.
What are you doing here?
Is this a bad time?
No. I, uh...
I just had to tell
a father in Iowa
that he lost his son.
So it is a bad time.
What can I do for you?
I wanted to let you know
I was accepted into med school.
Yeah, I know. I
know. Congratulations.
I wanna thank you for your help.
You deserved it.
It wouldn't have been an option
if you hadn't gone
out of your way.
Look, uh, don't
thank me. Just...
Just work your
ass off, all right?
They extubated her?
She woke up and
started fighting the vent.
Her vitals are normal.
Did you get a hold?
Legaspi saw her.
I thought I was watching
her every second.
That's not possible.
I shoulda listened to you.
She'll be okay.
She'll never be okay.