Previously on ER:
Did you work on a
Edgar Dixon today?
Yeah, yeah, yeah,
why? What's up?
First Mission Baptist is
dispensing meds without a license.
It's a felony,
Pratt. A man died.
- And thank you for the hot dog.
- It's my pleasure.
I'll catch you later, Joe.
- How long are you staying, Gracie?
- Just till you throw me out.
- Luka, this is...
- Eddie.
Eddie.
Nobody called you a whore.
- My mom did.
- Your mom's mistaken.
Find budget cuts somewhere
else. No way we're losing you.
Thanks, but I resigned.
This is Dr. Abby Lockhart.
I'm calling from County General, and
can you tell him I got his lab results?
And he needs to come in
and discuss them. Thanks.
Since when do you call
ER patients from home?
I was worried about this guy.
I wanna make sure he gets seen.
Isn't that more of a job for
his primary care physician?
He doesn't have one.
Well, no incentive to get one if
you're gonna make house calls.
I phoned his hotel to make
sure he comes in for follow-up.
- Hotel?
- Yes, he's from out of town.
- Who's this guy?
- It's Eddie Jackson, you met him.
What?
- Nothing.
- Well, why are you acting weird?
I just think it's a little strange,
the amount of personal attention...
you seem to be giving
some guy you met in a bar.
You didn't talk to her, did you?
I didn't see her.
I thought you were
gonna talk to her last night.
Yeah, but I got home so late...
and she was excited about how well
she did on her history presentation, so...
- Tony...
- I'm gonna do it, I'm gonna do it.
You've been saying
that for a week.
She needs to hear this from you.
She needs to know that it was your
idea. Otherwise, she'll never forgive me.
All right, I'll tell her.
Tonight, I promise.
Oh, man, would you
look at this board?
We got cough, cough and vomiting, itchy
feet, diarrhea, diarrhea and vomiting.
Hasn't been decent
trauma in my last three shifts.
People are too damn
careful these days.
Chopper's bringing in some
kind of snowmobile accident.
Called it.
- Is this the snowmobile?
- One of them.
Clarke Sutton, 13, lost
control and hit a fence.
It was an accident.
I was trying to turn.
- Where's Dennis?
- McKay's unloading the older brother.
This one got the worst of it.
His brother carried him
almost a mile to get help.
Can I be in the same
room with Dennis?
- It hurts to breathe.
- Try not to talk.
- Gates, grab the next one, I'll take this.
- I got this covered.
- I got this.
- This kid needs someone to treat him.
- That'd be me, I'll call if I need you.
- Knock it off.
- Okay, who gets this patient?
Me. Act like babies, then
that's how I'll treat you.
- Luka, sats are dropping.
- Okay, bag him.
Abby, run ahead and intubate.
- Way to go.
- It was your fault.
- Yeah, right.
- Yeah, I am right.
- Don't be an idiot.
- Ass for brains.
Edgar never liked to
talk about his troubles.
In fact, the only thing he
ever talked about was football.
So speaking about that,
ahem, I remember one Sunday...
Edgar looked troubled, and I said,
"Well, is there anything I can do for you?"
So he said, "No, no, Pastor,
you can't help my problem."
I said, "Well, maybe I can't,
but I know someone who can.
God will always listen."
Oh, amen.
Dr. Pratt.
Pastor, that was a nice service.
- Thank you.
- Very nice.
Amen.
Um, Mrs. Dixon, I just wanted to
pass on my condolences once again.
I just, uh, wanna let you know if
there's anything, anything I can do...
please don't hesitate
to call the hospital.
Thank you, Dr. Pratt.
Thank you.
Greg.
The medical board called me.
Yeah, I bet they did.
They said they're issuing a letter for
us to cease and desist our drug program.
That's not a surprise.
I told them to go to hell.
- You did what?
- They don't understand what we're doing.
Yeah, but I'm sure they
got a pretty clear idea now.
Look, I like what you're
doing, but it doesn't work.
People need a continuity of care.
Church clinic isn't open every day.
How many people do you think we've
helped since we started this program?
I'm sorry.
- We're not giving up on the program.
- You're headed for trouble.
My people have
nowhere else to turn to.
They're already in trouble.
I'm out.
- Sats drifting into the 70s.
- Clarke, stay with us.
- Want me to do that?
- No.
- You sure?
- Yes.
If you wanna help, you
can give me some cricoid.
- I got blood here, what do you want?
- Uh, CBC, LFTs, Chem-7...
- I'm in, bag him.
- UA and a blood gas.
You're probably
not gonna need that.
Decreased on the
left, pull back the ET.
- No, I stopped past the cords.
- It's obviously not, so pull it back.
I'm gonna call the blood bank.
Good idea.
Still decreased, sterile
6's and a chest tube tray.
Hold on, let's not jump the gun.
He's got a bruise and bad sats. Not
jumping the gun, it's a pneumothorax.
- I'll call for a portable chest?
- Let's see what we're dealing with.
Twenty percent of
pneumothoraxes are missed on x-ray.
- You taught me that.
- Nice to know you were listening.
We have time to wait for the
film before we start cutting.
What about the
sliding lung sign?
Okay, lungs are up, no
hemothorax or rib fractures.
What's happening?
Why isn't he sitting up?
They put a tube down
his throat to breathe.
Good bowel sounds.
He got the wind
knocked out of him.
- I had to carry him to the road.
- Good thing you did.
Crit's 38, pressure's
still good, 122/76.
Let me know if anything is sore.
He kept begging
me to let him drive.
- His father's gonna kill me.
- Wait, I thought you two were brothers.
He's my stepbrother.
My dad died when I was little,
my mom remarried in August.
He thinks I'm a screw-up.
This isn't gonna help.
Pretty much wrecked
the snowmobile... Ow!
Left lower quadrant, call Surgery.
- Not so fast.
- It's not a contusion, it's an abrasion.
- He's guarding.
Yeah.
- Do you have to keep doing that?
- Sorry.
He's hemodynamically
stable, his crit's good.
Get a CT of his belly. If it's normal,
we won't waste the surgeon's time.
Well, I'm gonna have to
disagree with your assessment.
- Okay.
- Let's run it by Kovac.
Let's not.
I decide when we
present to an Attending.
- No lung sliding.
- What the hell is lung sliding anyway?
Normally, there's lung
movement on ultrasound.
If it's not there, the lung
must be partially deflated.
Show off.
Okay, chest tube tray to Abby.
What? You don't wanna do it now?
I wanted to do it
15 minutes ago.
It looks like Abby was right, and Luka
confirmed the diagnosis radiographically.
Good work, team.
What do I have to do to
get someone to come here?
Dr. Gates from the ER.
That's with an E for emergency.
- You called for a consult?
- I dialed the Hot Surgeons chat line.
Which room?
No "Hey, how you doing?
You look sexy in that white suit"?
Hey, what's wrong?
Besides the fact the
last time I saw you...
the woman you live with assaulted
me and her daughter called me a whore?
I told you I was sorry.
And I don't live with her
anymore. Not for long anyway.
How's Sarah?
We're working through it.
No blood out, it's not the chest.
Xeroform and the Thora-Seal.
Could be cardiac contusion.
Get a 12-lead, hold off on
the blood till troponin's back.
- CT's ready. I'll take him up?
- I'll take him.
- You sure?
- Yeah, in case he crashes.
Well, that wasn't awkward.
Further proof workplace
romance, bad idea.
- Is that so?
- Uh, yeah.
Hey, look, the other night, you kind
of caught me off-guard with that kiss.
And I don't... I have a rule
against dating people at work.
- You do?
- Yeah.
It's kind of a new rule.
Oh, yeah.
But a solid rule.
That's cool, really.
This is Dennis' father, Gary.
Gary, this is Dr. Gates
and Dr. Rasgotra.
- Where's Clarke?
- Oh, upstairs for more x-rays.
Is this a social visit?
Tony asked for a consult.
I hope you're happy now.
I'm sorry. We were
being really careful.
You obviously weren't if
you put Clarke in the hospital.
I wanna see my son.
Where is he?
Lily, could you...?
- I can take you to him, sir.
- Thank you.
You better pray he's all right.
Uh, Neela, I'm sorry you
had to come down here.
He doesn't need a consult.
Well, I'm here now,
and I'm almost finished.
Can you explain to him why this patient
is not a good candidate for surgery?
I'm suggesting we
admit him for observation.
Why? His kidneys look good, liver
and spleen appear to be normal.
Did I miss something on the CT?
An occult injury could
take time to declare itself.
- He's right.
- No, he's not.
The surgeon concurs
with my assessment.
Hey, don't worry, boss, I'm not
one of those "I told you so" kids.
- Can I speak to you outside?
- Certainly.
Okay. Not you.
Sammy.
Hey, guys.
- Ben, hello.
- Hey, Gracie.
What's up, Alex? ALEX: Hey.
Alex is signing up for the
volunteen program today.
He's really excited about it.
I had to practically drag
him here by his ears.
Even if you volunteer for
a couple of hours a week...
it will still help on your
college applications.
- Maybe you'll even like it.
- Keep telling yourself that, Mom.
- When I was your age, I had two jobs.
- Yeah, doing what, milking the T. rex?
I worked on the Milfords'
farm before school, smartass.
And at night, I worked
in Addison's Bakery.
I can take Alex to
the volunteer center.
That's great, thank you, Ben.
Well, actually, I probably know
this hospital better than you do.
Great, then you can give me the tour.
I still can't find the gift shop, come on.
Ha-ha. So...
He gets cuter
every time I see him.
- Ben.
- I heard you.
You should be
going after that one.
It's a little tricky dating
someone you work with.
What's tricky about it?
- Having sex without getting caught?
- Gracie.
Look, honey, I know
what your life has been like.
Trust me, Sammy, I know.
All the women in our
family are the same.
Very fertile, allergic to chestnuts,
prone to bladder infections.
And we all have that damn gene
that predisposes us to bad boys.
Chestnuts?
Sammy, life is short.
You deserve to be happy.
You deserve a good man.
If you like this guy, go for it.
The least you can do
is give me an honest...
- and professional opinion.
- I did.
- You didn't.
- How would you know?
- You're not a surgeon.
- Neither are you.
Sorry, sorry, look...
No, I came down, I assessed
and made a professional call.
Your opinion isn't
professional, it's personal.
The only reason why you're siding with
Gates is because you're screwing him.
I can't believe
you just said that.
So it's true?
No. If it were, it's
none of your business.
- It has nothing to do with this case.
- It does if it's clouding your judgment.
Get an Attending
to weigh in on this.
- No.
Hey, somebody wanna tell me
what the hell's going on here?
Oh, so everything's
just all good now, huh?
Well, somebody better have
a good explanation. Ray?
Okay, a 13-year-old drove
a snowmobile into a fence.
Normal CT, stable crit and BP.
Gates wanted a Surgical
consult. I said we didn't need one.
- He decided to call Neela anyway.
- Better safe than sorry, right?
Wrong, it wasn't
your call to make.
Ray's above you.
Have a problem with your Resident
or with his judgment, call an Attending.
I wanted to present to Kovac.
- And I didn't.
He was busy with another trauma.
Now they've taken the
hospital's last surgical bed.
- That kid needs 24-hour observation.
- You can't give up the last surgical bed.
- I need to follow serial exams.
- Do it here.
- You're full.
- Send him home.
Have him come back for re-exam.
- Exactly.
- I'm trying to help you guys here.
- No.
Give up your last surgical
bed and we get stuck...
boarding a real surgical
train wreck here for days.
- Ray's patient, Ray's call.
- Fine, keep him here, less work for me.
- Thank you.
- Yeah, you better be right.
Thanks for the vote
of confidence, boss.
- Luka.
- Yeah?
Did you get to speak to Angela
Gilliam about Edgar Dixon?
- Who?
- The guy from the church clinic.
- Oh, yeah, she said she'd look into it.
- All right, I'm just a little concerned.
Someone called the medical
board, and they called the church.
- Okay, I'll talk to her again.
- All right, thanks.
- You looking for something?
- A patient.
Which one?
Hockey dad, Jim Singer,
30, hockey puck versus face.
It was a slap shot.
This is his son, Jimmy Jr.
- God, he spit out his teeth.
- Okay, uh, Jimmy.
We're gonna fix your dad
up, and you get to play Xbox.
Okay, Margo, you take Jimmy.
- How you doing, sir?
- I can't breathe.
A fractured jaw, multiple broken
teeth, pulse ox is down to 88.
Okay, he needs an airway.
Pratt, you want a piece of this?
Sure.
How come they didn't
bring Clarke back?
Probably moved him to another
bed to free up the Trauma Room.
And that could be a good sign.
Your stepfather
hasn't come by, huh?
No.
Why didn't you tell him you
weren't the one who was driving?
What's the point?
I don't know, maybe so that
he knows you didn't do this.
He'd still find a
way to blame me.
At least, now he can't
get mad at Clarke too.
You two are close?
Yeah, I guess.
First, it was kind of weird
having a little brother.
But he's cool.
His dad's really strict on him.
I'm afraid he thinks
that I'm a bad influence.
Sometimes let him do
things his father doesn't.
Like drive the snowmobile?
I'll find out how
he's doing, okay?
Thanks.
We're never gonna see the cords.
Let's bag him up and prep
the neck for a Seldinger crike.
What's the status on the
other kid, Clarke Sutton?
CT showed persistent pneumo.
Kovac put in a second tube, other
than that, he's good. Try Exam 3.
Thanks.
Dr. Pratt, I'd like you to stop by
my office at 4 today, if that's possible.
- Cricothyroid is right here.
- Yeah. Um...
- Did you to talk to
Dr. Kovac? ANGELA: Yes.
We need to have a quick sit-down with
the hospital lawyers about Edgar Dixon.
Guide wire.
I was at his funeral today.
I spoke to his wife. She's
not pressing charges.
Not the problem, the board is.
They're not happy Mr. Dixon was
getting his medications through his church.
Medications that
you distributed.
Yeah, but who got the
board involved in this?
I don't know. Four o'clock?
- Abby, here's your introducer.
- Greg.
- We got a hot MI five minutes out.
- Uh, Greg.
Yeah, all right. Uh...
Chest x-ray, call for a
vent, page Head and Neck.
And, uh, come find
me when you're done.
Do either of these
belong to you?
Hey, how'd it go?
Spectacular.
Sarcasm is a poor
substitute for wit.
- Do you know who said that, young man?
- Do I care?
Alex, don't be rude.
Say you're sorry.
- Just relax, okay?
- Hey, don't tell me to relax.
I think it's time we went home.
Okay, let's go.
March.
Hey.
So, uh, you finally get
things sorted out with Neela?
There's nothing
to sort out, man.
You sure? Because it looks like
you got some sorting out to do.
If you need my advice, all
you have to do is talk to...
Oh, no, no, no, I
don't need your advice.
I don't want your advice. I
took your advice, remember?
You know, "Give her some time,
Ray. Give her some space, Ray."
Yeah, I did that.
I gave her so much time and space,
she started seeing somebody else.
- Thank you for the advice, Pratt.
- What, so I...?
Stop acting like a baby.
Why are you even
here? Nobody invited you.
Hey, it's time you started
showing a little respect.
And you need to mind your
own damn business, bitch.
Don't you ever talk...
And don't you ever touch me.
- Hey.
You ever raise your hand to me or
your mother or any other woman...
I'll break every bone
in your sullen little body.
Grandma's got some game. - Ray.
Your snowmobile kid's
not looking too good.
The one you insisted
didn't need surgery?
Hey, I got this.
Thanks.
Yeah, okay.
Hey, look, um...
I'm sorry about Alex. You
know, he's not always like that.
- He's had a rough year.
- You don't need to apologize for him.
I just don't want you
to think that he's...
That he's what?
That he's a teenager?
Look, Sam, I was a
holy terror at his age.
My principal suspended me
from school one time for fighting.
So you know what I did?
- I slashed all the tires on his Corvette.
- Oh.
- That is a little delinquent.
- Yeah, I was a real piece of work.
My mom raised me by herself
too, Sam, so I know it's not easy.
We fought every single day
for probably 10 straight years.
And now we talk at least once
a week, and we're best friends.
And in time, I'm sure
you and Alex will be too.
Hey, have you seen Dr. Pratt?
- In the ambulance bay, waiting on a rig.
- Thanks.
I have a working girl with a
mandible dislocation. Tried everything.
Know any tricks?
No pun intended.
- Can this wait?
- No, I've paged Kovac and Pratt.
She's premedicated.
They're all tied up.
I've tried everything,
it won't budge.
- I gave a hundred of fent.
- Add some midazolam.
How'd you do this? Big yawn?
From what I gather, it was
an oral occupational injury...
- she got while performing a service.
- Oh.
Okay.
- Two milligrams in.
- Did you try it from behind?
Oh, you're talking to me?
Relocating the mandible?
Oh, no, that's a new one.
From the back, you've got
leverage for downward force...
and you could put
your weight into it.
- Makes sense.
- You also get a better grip.
Hey, Tony, got a visitor.
Sarah, what are you doing here?
I went up to your room.
I saw your boxes.
Why didn't you tell me?
Mmm.
I was going to.
You lied to me.
Sarah, this isn't a good
time. Go in the break room.
- Go with Sam, I'll be there in a few...
- You wanna leave, then leave.
- I don't care anymore.
- Sarah.
- You want me to get her?
- Go ahead, I got this.
You okay?
Sarah, wait.
Hey, stop and listen to me.
No, you can't tell me what
to do, you're not my dad.
Yes, but I'm your friend.
Friends don't leave.
Damn it, abdomen's
rigid with fever.
- Crit's stable, he's not bleeding.
- Could be a bowel perf with peritonitis.
Blood cultures and Zosyn 3.375.
- Should I get Gates?
- No, no, no, I need Surgery down here.
I already called them.
Okay, mix up dopamine.
Dennis? Dennis, can you hear me?
I need you to start fighting.
Your brother wants to talk to you.
Page Neela. Tell her
I need her here now.
Here you go.
"Thank you, Tony."
You're welcome, Sarah.
Hey, come on, you can't
be mad at me forever.
Why not?
Because of this.
- What are you doing?
- My sympathetic doctor face.
You look stupid.
No? You know what, you're
making me bring out the big guns.
When somebody's really sick,
and it's very fatal, I say to them:
"Mr. Smith, it's very fatal.
You're very sick, the tumor's
too big for your very tiny little head.
It's fatal, you're
not gonna live.
- Okay, stop.
- You're gonna die."
And then I give them
this face. Then I go:
Stop, stop it.
It's not funny.
- I'm mad at you.
- I know, I'm sorry.
I wanted to tell you.
Why do you have to go?
Because it's the right thing.
Is it because of Neela?
You called her?
Well, she was worried about you.
Come on, come on.
- What's happening?
- Free air under the diaphragm.
- Systolic's 90 after two liters.
- Throw in a subclavian, then to the O.R.
- He seemed okay. Where's his stepfather?
- I sent Dawn to find him.
- Thanks for coming.
- It's my job, Ray.
Cordis introducer.
Prime the infuser.
All right.
Hm.
You have a minute?
Yeah, why? What's up?
It was me, I called the medical
board about Edgar Dixon.
You?
Why the hell would you do that?
I heard he was getting his meds
from some doctor at a church.
- I thought it was an unlicensed crackpot.
- Oh, Abby.
- I'm really sorry.
- It's all right.
- I thought I was doing the right thing.
- You were, we both were.
Sometimes you do the right thing,
and you still get shafted, don't sweat it.
Hey, Greg, these detectives
would like to talk to you.
About what?
Your involvement with a
patient named Edgar Dixon.
- I called Angela, she's on her way down.
- All right, thanks.
Dr. Pratt, is there someplace
we could go talk in private?
Yeah, sure.
Right this way.
Yo, Abby, I've
been looking for you.
That patient you
were asking about?
- Phoned, he left a message.
- Thanks.
Let me guess, your
friend Eddie again?
- What, are you jealous?
- No, I just don't understand...
why you're giving this
guy so much attention.
He's a 60-year-old
man with lung disease.
I'm just trying to help him out.
Hi.
Hi, Kerry.
- Uh, we can talk about this later.
- Or not.
Is everything all right?
Yeah, just a disagreement
about a patient.
Mmm.
Gotcha.
I still can't believe
you're leaving.
Yeah, it feels a little weird.
Scary, but, uh, it's exciting.
I'm actually gonna
miss this place.
- You know, I...
- Listen, I just want...
- No, no.
- No, go ahead.
- No.
- You go.
Um...
I just wanna say that I think
that you've probably seen me...
at my best and, um, at my worst.
And even though we didn't
always see eye to eye...
you helped me go from a
nurse to a med student...
to a doctor.
To a mom.
- I'm the one who's supposed to be upset.
- I know, sorry. Heh.
You were always there
as a nurse and a doctor.
And most importantly, you've
always been here as my friend.
Do you think this happens to the
guys when one of them leaves?
I heard Carter bawled
like a baby when he left.
And I'll miss you.
Thank you.
Now, it's time for us to
take care of ourselves.
You can still hang
out with Tony.
It won't be the same.
No, but it will still be good.
You can go to Tony's place
when I get on your nerves.
Easy, I don't want
the kid living with me.
I can stay at your
place sometimes?
If it's okay with your mom.
I am gonna have a
swinging bachelor pad.
I'm talking big-screen TV over the Jacuzzi,
trampoline and a shark tank, the works.
Nothing stays the
same forever, Sarah.
That's part of growing up.
Besides, you won't care
about me in a few years anyway.
You'll run off and marry
that horndog character...
and have six kids
and eight cats.
We broke up.
- What?
- Yeah.
Oh. God, you know, I
really never liked that guy.
It was my fault.
He found out I
like Kevin Mclntyre.
Jezebel.
Better get going, kiddo.
Let Tony get back to work.
Hey, hey.
Baby girl.
His vitals have stabilized.
Get him up to O.R. 2.
- I'll call you when he's out of surgery.
- Okay, thanks.
Neela.
- Neela, I need to say something.
- No, you don't.
You did what you thought
was right, I respect that.
No, see, no, that's not it.
Well, what is it?
Uh...
This is probably wrong, I know.
It's the wrong place,
wrong time, but, uh...
- Why didn't somebody page me?
- We handled it.
What happened?
Seems that your patient
has a perforated viscus.
Really? Good thing we didn't
send him home, rock star.
Looks like he needed
observation after all.
It's not a small-bowel
perforation, okay, Tony?
- Has nothing to do with seatbelt sign.
- How'd you figure?
Small bowel doesn't seed the peritoneum
like this. Colonic, maybe diverticular.
Really? Interesting,
tell me more, doctor.
Where are they taking Dennis?
- To Surgery, if you really care.
- What's that supposed to mean?
- Sent a nurse to find you 30 minutes ago.
- I was with my son.
Yeah, this one needed you too.
No, you know, I'm sorry.
Uh, he needed a parent.
- I should've called his mother.
- Hey. You're out of line.
Neither of them would be here if
Dennis wasn't screwing around.
Dennis wasn't even
driving, Clarke was.
- That's not true.
- Yes, it is.
But did you bother to ask him? No,
you just blamed him from the get-go.
- Why didn't he say something?
- Would you have believed him?
He was trying to protect his
brother. That's what big brothers do.
- Dennis is older, should've known better.
- He's 15.
Do you know that he carried Clarke
almost a mile to the road to get help?
So instead of busting his balls,
maybe you should be thanking him.
He probably saved
your son's life.
You know, I don't
think I like your attitude.
I don't like the way
you treat your kid.
Where do you get off
talking to me like this?
Where's your supervisor?
You don't know a damn
thing about me or my family.
No, no, no, that's wrong.
Because I know that Dennis is a good
kid, and I know that you are an asshole.
If I were you, I'd start
to treat him a little better.
Couple of years, he's
gonna be bigger than you.
He's gonna remember
you treated him like crap.
And one day, he is
gonna kick your ass, okay?
You got a valid medical
license, Dr. Pratt?
Of course.
A pharmacist's license?
My license allows me
to write prescriptions.
Yeah, write, yeah, but
diverting controlled substances...
to a non-authorized
distributor, that's a felony.
I wasn't diverting anything,
I was treating patients.
- At this illegal clinic of yours?
- Illegal clinic?
All right, fellas, let's not
get carried away here, okay?
I was helping at a church
where most of the congregation...
- doesn't have health insurance.
- Like the man that you killed?
Isn't one of you supposed
to be the good cop?
Ray.
Look, Dr. Weaver, I just spent
the whole day with this great kid...
who saved his
little brother's life.
When his stepfather came and started
to belittle him in front of everyone...
He just remind me of
someone I used to know.
Yeah, I was just
coming to say goodbye.
Oh.
I may have done a great
disservice to the world of rock...
keeping you here, but you
could be a great doctor, Ray.
I kind of thought I was.
I'm kidding.
Sort of.
Wow. Um...
Thank you, Dr. Weaver.
Thank you for everything.
So, what do we do now?
Hug? Kiss?
Oh, right.
So, what's next, you guys
gonna beat me with a rubber hose?
- What the hell is going on?
- Dr. Pratt is under arrest.
- On what charges?
- Violating the Controlled Substance Act.
- You believe these jokers?
- Had to handcuff him?
- It's a felony charge.
- Come on, you can't do this.
Back off, doc, unless
you wanna go with him.
She's playing with the pets.
I'm looking for my camera, then
suddenly, we hear this god-awful scream.
And we see this billy goat
has Sammy by the pigtails.
Speak of the devil.
Gracie invited me for beers.
She did?
- Hi, Mr. Owens.
- Evening, Sam.
Don't worry, I'm not
staying for dinner.
- Thanks for the dessert, Gracie.
- Anytime, Bennet.
I baked a blueberry pie,
I'm making fish and chips.
- Night, Sam.
- Need a hand with anything, Mr. Owens?
No, I'm good, thanks.
I was just telling the boys...
about how the goat ate
your pigtails at the petting zoo.
Great. Where's Alex?
He's in his room, he's
doing his homework.
At least, he better be.
Nice shot.
Hey, what are you doing here?
Why didn't you come
back to the hospital?
How'd you find me?
Guy at your hotel
said you might be here.
In case you're interested, tests show
your lungs aren't expanding properly.
They've become fibrotic.
Guess I'll have to
switch to menthols.
You didn't have to come here.
Eight ball, corner pocket.
You're not getting enough
oxygen in your blood.
You're gonna need an echocardiogram
to check your cardiac function.
Better luck next time, chief.
You need to be
referred to a specialist.
No more doctor stuff.
Well, we need to find out
what's causing this, Eddie.
No, we don't. Abby, listen...
I don't understand why you got the tests
if you weren't going to follow through.
I don't care about
my damn lungs.
I didn't keep coming to
see you for health reasons.
Okay, well, then what?
Talk to me, what's going on?
Uh...
I've been taking care
of myself my whole life.
Usually, at the
expense of others.
I appreciate your concern...
but I don't deserve it.
You know what? I
shouldn't have come here.
- Abby.
- Look, just stay away from me, okay?
- Let me explain something.
- You don't have to, it's just a mistake.
- I know what you're feeling.
- I don't think you do.
I don't know what I'm feeling.
You're right, I didn't need to come
here, and I shouldn't have come.
Abby, I lied to you.
I didn't wanna scare you off.
My name isn't Jackson.
It's Wyczenski.
I'm your father.
Yeah, I talked to
Maggie a while back.
- Probably going on three years...
- No.
I caught up on you
and your brother, Eric.
No, no, no.
- Yeah, before she started screaming.
- This is not happening.
Yeah, it is.
She told me you're
working here in Chicago.
No, why are you doing this?
I wanted to see for myself.
- After 30 years?
- Yeah, I, uh...
I wanted to see what sort of
a person you grew up to be.
- Oh, God, I can't do this.
- Took me two years to work up the nerve.
One of the nurses
at the Triage desk.
She pointed you out to
me, and I got cold feet.
- Taxi!
- If you hadn't walked into the bar, I...
I probably would have left
without ever speaking to you.
But when I met you, I
wanted to know more, but I...
I didn't have the guts, because I
thought you'd tell me to go away.
Well, guess what, you were
right. Go away, go away.
No, Abby.
Abby, please.
No, and just leave
me alone, all right?
You don't get to
do this. It's not fair.
Hey, Kerry.
- Hey.
I didn't get a chance
to say goodbye to Pratt.
I'm on my way to bail him out.
Yeah, that's one of those parts of
the job they never tell you about.
Just one of the many parts
that I am not gonna miss.
Look, I never had
the chance to tell you...
Luka.
Luka, you know what? I'm
done talking about this, really.
I know, but, hey.
You... You hired me.
I still remember my first day.
An oxygen tank rocketed
through the ER, almost killed me.
Well, no one ever said this
was the safest place to work.
You... You changed my
life by giving me this job.
You may have even saved it.
I don't know where I'd be
if I hadn't found this place.
And you taught me a lot.
Thank you.
Come here, you big Croat.
You know what? Don't get up...
Don't get caught up
in the politics, all right?
A good hospital is about
people and medicine.
Thank you.
I'll see you around sometime.
Yeah.
Luka.
Take care of this place for me.
I will.
Can you hold it up? Right there.
You can't sweat me up in here.
- It's getting late, so I better get going.
- But we don't even work tomorrow.
Yeah, but I'm like Gracie,
and I need my beauty sleep.
Well, you could sleep
here tonight if you want.
I mean, it would save
you all that driving.
Yeah, but you have that rule
against workplace fraternization.
Yeah, it's actually more
of a guideline than a rule.
And it's, um...
Applies more to
doctors than to nurses.
- Hm. That's good to know.
- Mm-hm.
And Alex and Gracie
would be okay with this?
Mmm.
Come on.
Here's a two-bedroom on
Lake Shore with a concierge.
I always wanted to live in
a building with a concierge.
- You can't afford a place on Lake Shore.
- It's 3600 a month.
- Like I said.
- Eighteen hundred apiece.
What, are you gonna
split it with the concierge?
You make yourself laugh
there? You like that one?
You're a funny one?
Hold that thought.
Hello?
Hello? SARAH: Tony?
- Sarah?
- I think mom's really sick.
I can't wake her up.
- What, where are you?
- In the car.
Where? Where's the car?
I don't know where we are, Tony,
but you have to do something.
- I think she's dying.
- Sarah, Sarah.
Okay.
All right.
Here we go.
All right, one second,
I'll get you out.
One second.
Sorry, honey.
Okay, it's okay.
Here we go, we're home.
Hey, hey, just one
sec, okay? One second.
Here we go.
Come on, Luka, pick up.
Hey, it's me.
I'm home, I just
got Joe from Ellen's.
Listen, can you call me
as soon as you get this?
It's kind of a...
It's kind of urgent.
Thanks.
Okay, here we go.
I know, I'm sorry.
It's okay, here we go.
Yeah, I know.
Shh, shh, shh, shh.
Okay, okay.
You're okay.
Call your husband.
I just did, he's not picking up.
Call him again.