Hey, Dr. Weaver,
you better hurry up!
You're gonna miss
the party! What?
Ha, ha!
Hey, Dr. Weaver.
Cleo. You're off?
Uh, Dr. Kovac just gave me 15
to grab my dry-cleaning
before it closes.
We're slow, I take it?
We are now.
What's that music?
Looks like nail polish
to me. It's buffed, okay.
You got a manicure, Malik?
Hey, man, that's
what the ladies like.
First thing they check
out is your hands.
I check out the butt, myself.
You know what I'm sayin'?
Oh, that's a myth. I tested it.
Tested what?
It's so not worth explaining.
Kerry, happy Valentine's Day.
Isn't it a little loud?!
Sorry!
Hey, what are you doin'?
Oh. Hi, chief. You on?
All night. I see someone
went overboard with the hearts.
What's wrong with them? Nothing.
Want some pizza? No. Thanks.
Isn't...? Wait,
isn't Mark still on?
Oh, he left at 8. Double date.
I'm on till 9. Mighty fine.
We slowed down. No
one's waiting to be seen.
And I took over the board.
Okay. Everyone,
another five minutes
and then back
to work, all right?
I'm sorry, Mrs. Minear,
it was a mistake.
It won't... Yeah, I...
Well, I was expecting
some money, and it, uh...
I was... I was expecting a
check to clear, and it didn't.
I'm sorry, but I promise... Yes.
I promise I'll get it to you.
Thank you.
Teach me to check my messages.
Everything okay?
Uh, no. But I'm
sure it'll work out.
God, I'm beat.
Are you leaving?
Yeah. I've been on since
7. I gotta be back here at 7.
And I just wanna go
home and hug my girls.
Lose a patient today?
Yeah. Yeah.
Nice to have
someone to go home to.
♪ You feel the same way too ♪
Oh, no, girl, Alex
and I broke up.
What happened? I
thought he was The Man.
Yeah, so did my neighbor.
Ouch.
Luka, do have anybody
you need to hand off?
Oh, yeah, if you want.
Ankle films are back on Cupid.
A Singing Telegram,
slipped on some ice.
I need a doc in Radiology
to inject an IV contrast.
Patient named Rodriguez.
I think that's Carter's.
Okay, find Carter.
I need a bath.
Can I have a bath?
Let me look at your foot first.
Pablo, you're alive, huh?
Oh, yeah, I'm alive.
We haven't seen you in a year.
They put me on a bus.
Bus? What kind of a bus?
A green one.
A green bus?
Where did it take you?
Oh, I need a bath.
I think Pablo got deported.
It was very hot.
How'd he get back here?
That part's a little fuzzy.
I took a long time. I bet.
Welcome back, Pablo.
Yeah, welcome back.
Hey, Kerry. Happy
Valentine's Day...
Or night, I guess.
Yeah, you too.
You know where,
uh, Sobriki is? Who?
Paul Sobriki. I got
called down for a consult.
Yeah, I just got on.
Check the board.
Thanks.
So you must be Mr. Morris.
How'd you guess?
Is that my x-ray?
Yep.
Let's take a look.
Is the bone broken?
Hold on.
Eh. Gotta find another board.
I'll be right back.
Ah, Dr. Weaver, can you
talk to Toxicology for me?
What's the problem?
"Bare Butt Booty Oil"?
Kid drank it, but
he's not symptomatic
so they won't test
it. Sent it back.
No ingredient list.
Well, yeah. "Bare
Butt Booty Oil."
Okay, I'll talk to them.
Thanks.
Ohh!
♪ Sing us a song ♪
♪ You're the piano man ♪
♪ Sing us a song tonight ♪
♪ 'Cause we're all in
the mood For a melody ♪
♪ And you've got
us Feeling all right ♪
Is it just me or
are they dreadful?
♪ Now, John at the bar ♪
No, it's not just you.
♪ Is a friend of mine ♪
♪ He gives us our
drinks For free ♪
♪ And he's quick With a joke ♪
♪ And to light up your smoke ♪
♪ But there's someplace
That he'd rather be ♪
♪ He says ♪
♪ "Bill, this place
is killing me" ♪
♪ As the smile
escapes From his... ♪
- Surgery's on its way!
- Pulse is weak.
Spin a crit right away!
Watch it on the right!
No, I can't stay on the line!
This guy could still be here!
Just get 'em here! Every cop
in the city knows where we are.
John! John, can you hear me?
Airway looks clear.
John, open your eyes.
No response to command.
Glasgow coma-scale 7.
How long do you think
they were lying there?
Long enough to lose liters.
I can't believe
nobody saw anything.
Let's talk about it later.
One, two, three. Push
etomidate and sux now.
Stab wounds to the
left neck and chest.
Oh, man. Two more to the belly.
Right and left upper quadrants.
Number 8 ET tube. What's her BP?
Hold on. Pulse ox
is low. Eighty-two.
That's why I'm tubing her.
Get me a blood pressure!
Chest-tube tray.
No, start a central line.
BP is 90/50.
Four units of O-neg, hang
two on the rapid infuser.
Give me some cricoid pressure.
You okay, chief?
I got it.
Okay, start the
central line now.
Betadine and a sterile drape.
People are having parties
while these two were in
there bleeding to death.
Two stab wounds
to the left flank.
First one is at L-2, four
centimeters off the midline.
The second one is L-5
in the mid-scapular line.
Did he hit the spinal cord?
Depends on the angle.
BP is 70/50. Pulse, 120.
Squeeze in two liters.
Set me up for a subclavian.
Good breath sounds
bilaterally. Pulse ox, 93.
Should we intubate?
No. Ten liters by mask for now.
Send a trauma panel,
type and cross for four,
and get X-ray in
here for a chest.
And one shot IVP.
I was just talking to him.
Right here. The patient's gone.
Oh, boy. What's his name?
Paul. Paul Sobriki.
Who are you?
Carl DeRaad,
chief of psychiatry.
I was called to consult.
What's he look like?
I don't know. I
hadn't seen him yet.
I'll get his chart.
No, I'll get it.
No one else goes in
here. This is a crime scene.
Oh! Hey!
It's okay. He's a doctor.
Subclavian's in.
- First crit is 31.
Is he conscious?
Is he conscious?!
No, but he is responding
to fluid resuscitation.
It was some psych patient.
Got Lucy, too, pretty bad.
Roll him, let me see. Oh, man!
Pressure's up to 90 palp.
Why wasn't he in
restraints? I don't know.
- Where's the Foley?
- That's next.
Pulse ox is 83.
Give it a minute. 10 blade.
Dr. Weaver, the police
are sealing off Curtain 3.
They need to talk to anybody
who took care of
the patient right away.
Handle it, Randi.
God, look at this.
Look at this, chief!
Damn it. Damn it.
Tracheal laceration.
She needs a crike. No, a trach.
Get Benton in here.
Prep the neck, and
open a Melker kit.
Now. Let's go. Let's go.
Dr. Benton! Hold on.
Toes are down-going.
That means no spinal injury.
Hang the next two
units on the infuser.
Hold on. It's not set up.
Get it set up! I got it.
Probably got the
descending colon.
Peter, Dr. Weaver
needs you right now.
She has to trach Lucy.
Book an O.R. Get ready to send
Carter up. Where's the Foley?
I'm working on it. Betadine
prep. Sterile drapes.
Okay, clear the field of blood.
Hemostat!
Connie, where's the infuser kit?
It should be there.
They're not here!
Well, try the, um, top shelf.
What is it?
Uh, a knife.
Don't touch it. We got a weapon.
Any blood? Yeah, some.
It's from the lounge.
We were gonna
use it to cut the cake.
I-I have to go find some tubing.
Are you working on
one of the victims?
Yeah. I'm trying to.
Is he gonna make it?
I don't know.
Is he awake?
Got it!
Second unit is in.
- Got the tubing.
Pressure's up to 100 systolic.
Give a gram of cefotetan.
Right pupil is five
millimeters and reactive.
Left is... John? John!
John.
Deb? Look at me.
Do you know where you are?
My back.
You were stabbed. We've
got your pressure up.
Lucy?
I'm Officer Bernini.
Did you see the man...?
Do we need to do this now?
It's better if...
You'll have to wait! I'm sorry!
What?
Nothing. Looks like he
missed your spinal cord.
BP's 80 palp.
Is that Lucy?
Yes. She's alive.
Dr. Kovac.
What?
What is it?
Get Benton. He
needs to go up now!
Get ready to bag her.
Dr. Benton, we need you!
Hook up the Thora-Seal!
I've got breath
sounds. Dr. Benton!
Carter's got a bad renal lac.
Foley output is bright red.
What's her pulse ox? Down to 80.
Got another surgeon coming?
- Go!
Yeah, we're outside!
I'll be right there! Yup.
Dad, wait for us inside.
Register around the
front of the building.
I'm a surgeon! I have to see ID.
We don't have time for this!
And you have to
move the vehicle.
There!
Okay, go ahead.
Dad, I need you to move the van.
Where do I park it?
You're asking me?
I want you to stay awake, John.
You stay awake
until you get up there.
You want FFP? Yeah. Two units.
Come on, Carter, stay with me!
How is he? Stab wounds
with renal lacerations.
We're red-lining him to the O.R.
A patient did this? ABBY: Yeah.
What's his pressure?
I've got it, Elizabeth.
Kerry needs you. Go! Carter!
Carter, look at me. Come on.
Right in the eye.
Stay with me, man. Stay with me.
Xeroform and Elastoplast.
Belly's distended,
probably an
intra-abdominal bleed.
Why wasn't the guy sedated?
I don't know. Get Ultrasound.
W-was...? Was he on a hold?
Was there a sitter with him?
I never saw him! What?
Where are we?
Multiple stab wounds
to the left neck and chest,
right and left upper abdomen.
We did a chest tube, central
line and had to trach her.
How much blood loss?
400 in Thora-Seal.
Could've been another
2000 before we found her.
Yeah, it looks deep.
How long was the blade?
Pressure's down to 60.
She needs volume now.
Maybe not. Could be tamponade.
No, wait! Check the CVP.
Too late! Lost her pulse!
We're in P.E.A.
Starting compressions.
Neck veins are up.
We need to crack
her. Prep her chest.
Okay, amp of epi.
Sterile gloves, please.
You need better exposure.
Stab wound is near the midline.
Sternal saw. Now, Lily.
Go! Go! Go!
Ultrasound is ready.
In a minute. In a minute.
10 blade. Stand back.
Sats are down to 85.
Almost got it.
Okay.
Rib spreader.
Suction.
V-fib! Start internal
compressions.
You're right. There
is an effusion.
Metz.
- Prep internal paddles.
- Pericardium's open.
We've got a major
hemorrhage. More suction.
Looks like the proximal aorta.
Keep your finger on it.
I need a 4.0 prolene
on an RB-1 needle.
Belly's full of blood.
Probably got the spleen.
Gotta cross-clamp the aorta.
One thing at a time.
Autotransfuse
from the cell saver.
Charge the paddles to 15.
Cut! Cut! Cut!
Clear! NURSE: Clear.
We're still in V-Fib.
Another amp of epi.
Clear. NURSE: Clear.
Sinus tach. Check the pressure!
Get a portable monitor.
We're moving her
to the O.R. now.
Hang the other units.
Pulse ox is up to 92.
Pressure's 90
systolic. Let's go!
Whoa! Pulse ox cable!
Is she making urine?
Only 50 cc's in the Foley.
That's better than nothing.
Tell O.R. we have an open chest.
We'll need a laparotomy.
We're waiting on
the type-specific.
Have the blood
bank send it upstairs.
Putting her on bypass?
I don't know. Have a
perfusionist stand by.
Hold the elevator.
Malucci, don't bag so fast.
We don't want to
make her alkalotic.
Need anyone else?
I hope not.
Wait! And don't forget
the drug box. Go!
I can't believe this.
You think we got it in time?
She has a good chance.
Kerry?
You Dr. Weaver?
You're the one who
found them? Excuse me?
We got a problem with
the Medevac chopper.
Industrial trauma.
Try to divert.
I did but Lakepoint's
closed... Whatever.
Peter! I just heard.
What the hell happened?
I'm not sure.
Tammy, this is O-neg.
I asked for type-specific.
He is O-negative.
I'm gonna scrub in.
Hang in there, Dr. Carter.
How many units is that?
That's five, but, uh...
you shouldn't be counting.
It's bad, isn't it?
Well, we're having problems,
uh... keeping your crit up,
but, uh, I think that's
from the renal lac.
I'm gonna give you
Versed to relax you a little
before I intubate, okay?
It could be the aorta.
Or the vena cava or
mesenteric vessels.
Oh, God.
Carter, don't worry. I'm
gonna explore the abdomen.
I'm gonna check
out everything, okay?
I'm glad it's you.
Hey, I'm getting you
through this, man.
You hear me?
Carter?
Okay, ready to intubate.
Let's prep him for
a midline incision.
I want to be able to
cut in two minutes.
I mean it. You got it.
Had a laceration to
the proximal aorta.
What happened?
She tamponaded.
We had to crack her.
Peter, I got this.
Who's on anesthesia?
I got her. Go scrub.
Put her on the table supine
and keep her chest covered
with moist, sterile lap pads.
I don't understand.
You need a six-inch
butcher knife to cut a cake?
Hey, I didn't bring it.
They just told me
that's what we use.
Yes, and we just leave it out?
I didn't.
Was it at Admit
or in the lounge?
I don't know.
Somebody said lounge,
but I couldn't find it.
Amira, go upstairs
and get Security
to open up the personnel office.
I need emergency contact
numbers for Carter and Lucy.
Want me to look
through their files?
No, I want you to
bring them down. Go.
Okay, he presented
with a headache.
Who? Paul Sobriki.
Mark, please tell
me that you saw him.
Yeah, I saw him.
Lucy worked him
up, Carter supervised.
And who supervised him?
The LP came back negative.
If you wanted to leave early,
you could have at least rounded.
Kerry, I ran the
board with Dr. Kovac.
For how long? For 30 seconds?
He was up to speed. Hold on.
You didn't tell me
he was psychotic.
I didn't know he was
psychotic. Did he present to you?
No, I didn't see him.
I thought we were waiting
for his psych consults.
Unless his status changes.
Someone should say. I was
managing the whole board.
You were having a party!
Hold on. Kerry! Come on!
We both thought that Lucy
and Carter had it covered.
Well, they didn't. Excuse me.
We both know that
we use the Residents
to keep us informed.
You're blaming Carter, Mark?
No, I'm not blaming
anyone. Are you?
Excuse me. I have
Samantha Sobriki with me.
She's looking for her husband.
I got a message on my answering
machine from Lucy Knight.
She said to come down. That...
That Paul's okay, but she
didn't say what was wrong.
You'd better come with me.
That chopper's
landing right now.
What?
The Medevac from Whiting.
Kerry, you go and
change. I'll take it.
Right.
What happened?
Oh, good. You're
here. I need you. Okay?
The air squad's here.
Was there a bomb
scare or something?
I wish.
No, I don't believe you.
Where's Paul? I wanna see him.
He's not here.
Paul wouldn't hurt
anyone. He couldn't.
He needs help, Mrs. Sobriki.
There's been some
kind of mistake.
We believe he may
have schizophrenia.
What?
The first psychotic break
can happen in your 20s.
You're wrong, okay?
No, I... You're wrong.
More lap pads.
The kidney won't tamponade.
Didn't have time to get an IVP?
His crit was falling. I
didn't want to chance it.
Colon is lacerated, all right.
All right, 3.0 silk
on a GI needle.
Dr. Anspaugh, there's
blood welling in the hilum.
All right, all right, all right.
Isolate the renal
artery. Get a clamp on it.
He's hypotensive.
Heart rate's 120.
We gotta get this kidney
out before we lose him! Move!
Let me finish suturing his colon
before we do something drastic.
I'll dissect out the arteries
and tie them off. Move!
I said wait, Peter!
Why? He's lost too much blood.
His... His hilum is trashed.
He's getting shocky.
Pressure's 78 palp.
All right, pedicle
clamp. Come on.
We still have
time. No, we don't!
Peter, will you calm
down? And you listen to me!
Before there's no turning back,
let's check the source of
the bleeding once more.
Too many vessels injured.
Squeeze in another
unit. Let's be sure.
Too much bleeding. I
can't identify the source.
More suction.
Abdominal lap pads.
I'll pack off the liver.
BP's 105/70.
All right, angled Potts
now. What are you doing?
Pringle maneuver. Have
to cut this blood loss.
More suction, damn it!
The spleen's still bleeding.
Okay, give me a second.
BP's falling, 80/60.
Run another unit.
She's losing it as
fast as we give it.
Then do it quickly!
A and O times four.
BP, 132/82. Pulse, 110.
You sure there
wasn't a projectile?
A bolt? Some hardware?
No, just the oil.
Must've been a loose fitting.
Foreman said a small
stream at that pressure
will cut through you like a .22.
Mark? Hey, Dad.
What's going on? Hold on.
Okay, get a trauma panel,
type and cross for four
and an upright chest.
I'll be there in a minute.
A couple of our staff were hurt.
Oh, I heard that
part. Who's that?
I'm just covering.
Everything's a little off-balance.
Where's Elizabeth?
She's upstairs in Surgery.
Dr. Greene... Uh, sorry.
We've got an MVA coming in,
auto vs. pedestrian,
ETA five minutes.
Grab Chen or Malucci. And
Weaver should be around.
What do I do with her mother?
Uh... Just give me
a half-hour, okay?
I'll drive you guys home.
Are they gonna
be all right? Who?
Your friends.
I don't know, Dad.
You're acting like
you know he did it.
You don't know he did it.
You're right. We
don't know for sure.
But we still need to find him.
He's not at home. Nobody's
seen him at the diner.
Is there any other
place he might go
if he needed to feel safe?
So he was a little depressed.
It doesn't make him crazy.
Maybe not.
But at the moment,
we have to assume
he could be a great danger
to himself or other people.
It doesn't make any sense.
If he was that dangerous,
then why did they
leave him alone?
I understand.
This doesn't make
much sense to any of us.
But if Paul is in
trouble, he needs help.
And it's better if we
can find him now.
Sometimes he goes to the
roof when he wants to be alone.
The roof?
Of our apartment building.
He didn't do this.
Bleeding's under control.
If we can just keep it there.
Pean clamp.
Okay, watch the pancreas.
Hold on.
I'll enlarge the incision in
the posterior peritoneum.
Watch out for the
splenic flexure.
Got it. I'll clamp, you cut.
Mm-hm. Metz.
Bastard really sliced
the hell out of it.
It's senseless.
Why we have to cut up
this poor girl like this...
It's better than the
alternative, isn't it?
Let the renal artery
flush retrograde
before closing the defect.
There. Think we got it?
Well, there's only
one way to find out.
Release the clamp,
let the kidney perfuse.
Okay. Go ahead.
No bleeding.
Hilum's intact.
And the kidney is pinking up.
All right, we did it.
You were right. Thanks.
Well, he could've
lived without a kidney.
I just didn't want
to have to tell him.
Pressure's still down, 80/62.
We caught up on volume?
Almost.
Why is he still hypotensive?
There's some swelling
in the periaortic area.
There's a hematoma forming.
From the lumbar artery?
I hope so.
Hope so? It could paralyze him!
It's better than his aorta.
Dissect down to the artery.
Some kind of life to lead, huh?
Well, I hope this is not normal.
No. No, no. I don't think so.
You've got quite a
girl there in Elizabeth.
Heh. I wish I could
take the credit.
The boarding school raised her.
Oh?
I was teasing.
Oh.
Her... Her father passed on?
No. He was still
alive, the last I heard.
Oh. I'm sorry.
Oh, don't be. It
wasn't your fault.
Have you heard anything?
They're both still in the O.R.
Think we should go up there?
Nah. I'm sure they'll call
when everything's okay.
What have you got?
John Doe hit by a van running
across Michigan Avenue.
No head trauma, but
repeated questions.
I called a cab!
There's a cab waiting.
I think we got a
looney-toon. Why?
He was running around
naked in the freezing cold.
Get Weaver. Now.
You never want to
be doing this to me!
Sure it's him? Yeah, it's him!
What are you doing to me?
Trauma panel, C-spine,
chest and pelvis.
Is he combative? He's agitated.
I'm not taking any chances.
Okay, get the police
detective in here!
Diminished breath
sounds. Get X-ray.
Abdomen is soft, non-tender.
I won't... I won't talk! I
made promises to people!
Pupils equal and reactive.
Paul, do you know where you are?
Who told you my name?!
I don't even know you!
Paul, do you remember
what happened?
You can't trick me!
I don't know you!
Abrasions on the
feet. No deformity.
I'm not deformed!
Temperature's 95... No!
Get off of me now!
Leave me alone. Don't stick me.
You want some Haldol?
They wouldn't stop.
Dr. Weaver, do you
want some Haldol?
Dr. Weaver?
Two liters of warm saline
and five of Haldol, IV.
Where are you going?
Looks like fluid in
Morrison's pouch.
Can you take this patient?
You okay? He's the guy.
He's the psych patient.
He got hit by a car.
What is it? Can
you just take him?
Okay. We'll send him
to the O.R. Thank you.
BP 120/82 after a liter.
Probably some venous oozing.
Cleo, can you go up with him?
Who's our surgeon?
Whoever's free.
He needs a chest
tube and head CT.
Okay.
I don't want you to touch me!
Stop sticking me!
No hemotympanum.
Let me go!
Keep that mask on him!
Don't cut me! Don't cut me! No!
Hell of a way to spend
Valentine's Day, huh?
She's satting at 98
on 30 percent oxygen.
Well, can't ask for better
than that. Good work.
How's Carter?
Well, it took a while
to control the bleeding.
They salvaged his kidney.
Now they're working
on a colostomy.
Unbelievable. Yup.
Dr. Romano? County
supervisor's on the phone.
He just heard what happened.
Tell him I'm in surgery.
I just told him you got out.
Thank you.
Appreciate that.
I'll be right back.
Dr. Corday, she's waking up.
Lucy... Lucy, can you hear me?
Do you know what
happened to you?
There were several stab wounds.
One lacerated
your proximal aorta.
We had to perform a
thoracotomy after you arrested.
They gave you a trach
to maintain your airway.
And we brought you to the O.R.
Your liver was damaged,
but we were able to repair it.
However, we did have
to remove your spleen.
I'm sorry.
Lucy, you can't speak.
You can whisper
if I plug the trach.
Do you want to try that?
Okay.
Remember, only whisper.
Thank you.
Bring the proximal
colon to skin surface.
3-0 chromic.
You hanging in there,
Peter? You look a little ragged.
I'm fine.
Metz.
You know, all in all,
I think young Dr. Carter
here is very fortunate.
Well, that depends
on how you look at it.
Dr. Anspaugh, we
need a surgeon in O.R. 3.
What is it?
Some kind of penetrating
trauma. Something about oil.
Where's Dr. Corday?
Do you want me to page her?
We're busy here.
Why don't you go
take a look? I can finish.
I've come this far.
Patient stable? Yup.
Who's with the
patient? Dr. Finch.
Ask her to stay
until Corday shows.
They need me in the
O.R. I'll be back, Lucy.
Hold on. Her sat's down to 82.
What is it? Chest
pain? Sudden onset.
Put her up to 100 percent.
We need to go
for a spiral CT now.
PE?
Yes, Lucy, PE is a possibility.
What's going on?
Sudden onset chest
pain. Dropped her sats.
We're going to scan her
for a pulmonary embolism.
Bolus 5000 heparin. Start
a drip at 1000 an hour.
Whoa, whoa. Hold on. Hold on.
Keep going. Come here.
Wait till after the scan.
I don't want to thin her
blood if we don't have to.
I think she threw
a massive clot.
She's just had major surgery.
We don't want her to bleed out.
If she can survive
some post-op bleeding,
if it is PE and we
don't thin her blood,
she could throw another clot.
We'll have FFP standing by,
and we won't heparinize
for more than two hours.
I won't need that
long. Let's go.
Were you the one
working on my husband?
Your husband was hit by a car.
Collapsed lung, but we fixed it.
No head trauma.
And he's seeing
the psychiatrist now.
Can I see him?
You might want to wait a minute.
We gave him a drug
to calm him down.
No, I really need to see him.
There. Right pulmonary artery.
Yep. Get her in
Angiography for a filter.
I'll meet you there.
Get the room ready.
Chest and abdominal
dressings are soaked through.
Watch her BP, and
send her for a hematocrit.
Okay. There's
just a little oozing
from the incision.
That happens with heparin.
Your blood pressure's fine,
and there's no major hemorrhage.
Lucy, the CT shows a
pulmonary embolism.
Don't worry. We're
taking you to Angiography.
We'll put in a
Greenfield filter.
We'll reverse the heparin.
However, you might need
to have another transfusion.
Lucy, are you with me?
I'll get you through
this. All right?
All right.
Want anything?
Uh, just coffee.
Two coffees, please. KOVAC: Hey.
Hey. CHEN: Hi.
You didn't wanna go
home neither, huh?
Sit down.
We thought it was better
than waiting upstairs.
Pretty scary, huh?
Yeah, pretty scary.
I was complaining about my day.
BP's 112/78. Pulse, 102.
AC 14, tidal volume
600, 100 percent FI-O2.
Another two of Versed.
It's just to relax you a
bit during the procedure.
I... I want to be awake.
You want to stay awake?
Okay. Okay.
I'm going to numb the
inguinal area with lidocaine
and introduce a catheter
into the femoral vein.
I'll prep. Get gowned.
Spun crit is 32.
Good. Go.
I'll be right back, Lucy.
Don't worry, Ms. Knight. We
put far too much time and energy
into your training
to lose you now.
Greenfield filters are a snap.
I've done about 100 of 'em.
I'll talk you
through it if you like.
BP's down to 60. Pulse ox, 72.
Lucy! Lucy!
No carotid pulse.
Damn it. She's
throwing another clot.
Start chest compressions.
You, get in here and bag her!
Lizzie, I need you now!
Get me a staple remover!
Come on, come on, come on!
Throw some
betadine on the chest.
You're gonna open her?
She won't make it to O.R.
We need two more nurses.
What happened?
She's in PEA. Get wire cutters.
Wire cutters?
We wired the damn breastbone.
Dr. Corday's tied up.
What is she doing?
She went down to CT.
All right, can you take
it? Peter, I'm suturing.
Well, I've gotta
run the bowel again.
That man needs
an ex-lap. Now, go.
I'll page you if
anything changes.
Vitals?
BP's 125/85. Pulse, 92.
Crit? Forty-two.
That's normal. Okay,
prep for an ex-lap.
Cleo, stay here until
the surgeon comes.
You're not staying?
I'm still operating on Carter.
Start internal compressions
as soon as you can.
The right ventricle's dilated.
Side-biting clamp.
Come on, come on.
Do you want a fogarty?
Nope, just a yankauer.
Scalpel.
Try and suck out
whatever we can.
Suction.
Okay. All right,
that's the right side.
We've got a few clots here.
Good. Maybe she'll
get some oxygen.
Pressure's dropping.
He can't wait. Where are they?
Down to 80 palp.
Probably tore a
mesenteric artery.
Get Benton. Lost the pulse.
Starting compressions.
Betadine!
What are you doing?
Thoracotomy tray.
H-h-hold on. He... He
only needs a laparotomy.
I don't know how
to do that. Do you?
You can't operate up
here. Wait for the surgeon.
He can take over
when he gets here.
Somebody get me a scalpel!
And get Benton up here now!
- One more 4-0 prolene.
- Pulse ox?
Sixty-eight on 100 percent.
Still not oxygenating.
I don't know.
Removing side clamp.
- V-fib! Resuming compressions.
- Internal paddles.
Charge to 15.
Clear!
Still in V-fib.
Charge to 30. ROMANO:
Push an amp of epi.
Clear.
Nothing. Again.
Sat down to 62.
Charge again. A
hundred of lidocaine.
Clear.
No.
Again. Clear.
What the hell are you doing?
Saving his life. You
cracked his chest.
He needed a laparotomy.
Should've been here.
Should've called
me sooner. Gown.
Aorta's cross-clamped.
Pressure's coming up.
This was completely unnecessary.
What were you thinking?
A minute ago there
was no pressure.
Now there is. Sterile
gloves. I've got it.
He was about to arrest.
Step the hell back now!
10 blade.
Pulse is down to 90.
All right. Lap pad and
Bovie. Let's move, people.
Peter, I'm sorry
Carter's hurt...
Irrigate the chest with
three liters of warm saline.
Come on.
Clear!
Asystole. Push
an amp of atropine.
When was the last epi?
Four minutes ago.
Push another 7 mg now!
Clear!
Okay, that's it. We've
done everything we can.
Holding compressions.
Oh, damn it.
Son of a bitch.
No.
No, no.
Let's give a minute for
the last epi to circulate.
Charge to 30. Let's go.
Come on! Lizzie, let's go!
Robert...
Call it.
Time of death 2:56.
When can I go home?
I don't know.
I want to go home. I need...
I need to feed my dog.
Paul, we have
someone here to see you.
Paul. Sam.
Are you okay?
It's all right. I wanna go home.
Paul, what happened?
They took my clothes.
And they took my shoes.
DeRAAD: Who took
your clothes, Paul?
Them.
Who's them?
They had a... A blue cake.
DeRAAD: Is that
where you got the knife?
They were gonna open me.
Paul, where did
you get the knife?
They were gonna take my organs.
DeRAAD: What organs?
My internal organs!
Don't you understand? I
had to... I had to protect them!
Don't try to tell
me I don't know,
because I know.
They were trying to take them.
And I had... I had to stop them!
DeRAAD: Is he ready?
Yeah.
Do you want to
take him upstairs?
Can I...? Can I
please go home now?
I need to feed my dog.
I'll meet you in recovery.
Is Carter out of the O.R.?
Yeah, he's... He's
extubated in recovery.
Vitals are stable.
Peter... No, no,
no. Listen, um...
You were right.
I put you in a tough position.
You did what you had to do.
What's wrong?
There was a
complication with Lucy.
Not "Vanessa" Vanessa!
The one and only. Oh.
You know her?
Oh, I saw her when I
was in medical school.
She comes in with abdominal
pain. Carter orders a pelvic.
Tells Lucy the
patient would feel
more comfortable with a woman.
Oh, man!
Who...? Who's Vanessa?
Lucy's all official.
She's polite.
She gets her tray all in order,
puts on her gloves,
pulls back the curtain...
Carter's outside waiting.
Uh, waiting for
what? The scream.
I don't get it.
Carter sent her
in to do a pelvic
on a drag queen.
He did not!
Swear to God.
Terrible. How
could she not know?
Oh, you gotta
hand it to Vanessa.
He's got a better
figure than I do.
What is it?
Um, Lucy.
BENTON: Tell me
when the vibration stops.
What about the pancreas?
It's totally intact.
He just got the
descending colon.
How long will I have
the colostomy for?
About a month.
We'll do a take-down.
Now.
Good.
Sensation's intact.
You were lucky, Carter.
I know.
Thank you.
You're welcome. All right.
I'm gonna test
your motor strength.
Lift your leg.
How's Lucy doing?
Come on, man. Lift, lift.
That hurts. I know.
Now, don't let me
push it down, okay?
Hold it.
Mm-mm. Mm-mm.
Good, good.
Oh.
My back is killing me.
Yeah, I know.
Hematoma around
the lumbar plexus.
I'll give you some morphine.
I want you up and
walking in 12 hours, okay?
Lucy's dead, isn't she?
Oh, you're home.
Is everything all right?
No.
Do you want to tell me about it?
Not particularly.
I'll make breakfast.
We still need a pressure
transducer for Trauma 1.
Get two units of
O-neg down here.
We're out of Ancef.
Well, call the pharmacy.
Mark... I just heard.
How did this happen?
Can we, uh, talk about it later?
Yeah. Sure.
Something coming in?
Multi-victim trauma.
Assembly-line accident.
Told them we'll take
two majors, six minors.
ETA? They're rolling up.
I just realized we're short
a doc and a med student.
Hey, Abby, are you on? No.
We're short. Can you cover?
Uh... Sure.
Great. I need
someone to cover triage.
Forty-two-year-old male.
Crush injury, right arm.
Gave him morphine
and two liters in the field.
A little shocky, 90/60.
Neuro-circ intact?
No. Couldn't get a
radial or brachial pulse.
Multiple fractures.
Okay. Call Ortho and Vascular.
Type and cross for four.
Get him into Trauma 2.
I had to close her chest.
Thank you.
The nurses can do that.
I know.