Previously on ER:
Alex?
- Ma?
- He was driving some drunk girl's car.
She just died.
I let him go to the party.
Forget about the deposition. If the case
goes to court, I'll testify on your behalf.
Seen this guy?
That storage locker
in Indiana called again.
If you don't pay, they'll
sell your dad's stuff.
Hold CPR.
Get ready for
internal compressions.
You can't just show up at
my work and drop this off.
You wouldn't go to the storage
unit, so I brought it to you.
- I was gonna deal with it, eventually.
- What is this?
It's my dad's way of aggravating
me from the grave. This is my cousin.
- Simon Brenner.
- Johnny. Nice to meet you.
Look, I did you a favor. This
here? It's only the good stuff.
- I find that hard to believe.
- Well, have fun.
Oh, uh, and Aunt Ethel says,
"Thanks for the birthday card."
- I didn't send her a birthday card.
- Exactly. Bastard.
What am I supposed
to do with all this junk?
I'm sure there's a
logical explanation here.
Hey, Archie, Dr. Banfield's
looking for you.
- Great. She's gonna love this.
- Well, how about a peace offering?
Somehow I don't see her really
appreciating a cheese head.
Eager for a case?
Someone says abdominal
trauma, I come running.
Twenty-four-year old
female, EGA, 36 weeks.
Tripped during an immigration raid
at a tie factory down on North Orleans.
- Okay. Vitals? HARMS:
Stable, but contracting.
Q, 5 minutes.
- I'm Dr. Brenner. What's your name?
- Gloria.
- Uh, is there any bleeding?
- Uh-uh. BP's 124/81.
- It's okay. Where you going?
- It's a case for OB.
She still needs a
trauma assessment.
I'll give you my blessing,
but she's still an OB patient.
- I'm gonna page Coburn.
- Okay. Hang in there, Gloria.
Please, my baby.
Oh, Dr. Banfield.
I need to skedaddle
just a little early today...
to get in, uh, character
for the Christmas party.
Never met a costume
you didn't like, huh, Frank?
No, ma'am. Oh, and
your other half called.
Wanted to know what time
to be here for said party.
You're going to the party?
You say that like I don't
know how to have a good time.
- That's not at all what I meant.
- Anyone you want us to call?
My husband, but he
doesn't need to come.
- We got it. FRANK:
Here you go. Jock itch.
Oh, you sweet-talker, you.
Oh, hang on. You're
not seeing patients today.
I need you to do the
intern mid-year reviews.
- I'd rather do the jock itch.
- Too bad.
But, uh, Dr. Brenner
is great at paperwork.
Terrific penmanship.
Yoo-hoo. Dr. Morris.
- Hello, Mrs. Gaines.
- Hello.
I need refills for my cholesterol
and blood-pressure pills. And I also...
You know, I would love
to help you, Mrs. Gaines...
but I'm not seeing
patients today.
- Dr. Morris, you can go ahead and write...
- No, rules are rules.
However, Dr. Sanchez
here would love to help you.
Okay. My work here is done.
I brought you folks
some brownies.
- I made them myself.
- Awesome.
Frank, uh, did Psych come
down on my hair puller?
- Not yet. Don't eat at the desk.
- Ooh, I'm going.
- Right this way.
- Oh, thank you.
- Brownies?
- No, I'm good.
Dr. Gates, any word
on your homeless vet?
- No, I seem to have hit a dead end.
- All right.
Well, I'll put a call into a friend
of mine at Midnight Ministries...
- so maybe she'll know something.
- Thanks. I appreciate that.
- I gotta run upstairs for a minute.
- Okay.
- Sam coming in today?
- Should be.
Heard she wanted
to get back to work.
They're getting
ready to extubate Alex.
He's fighting the vent.
Sats are dropping.
- He's biting the tube.
- He wants off.
- He's agitated, Sam.
- Hang on. Hang on.
- Mm-mm. 40 milligrams propofol IV push.
- No, no, no. Please don't give up.
- Sorry, we can't extubate like this, Sam.
- He's right.
Well, he'll calm down.
Just give him a minute.
Restart the drip at 6
milligrams a minute.
Sedation's in.
Sorry, Sam, we'll see where
we are again tomorrow, okay?
Um, excuse me.
Is Dr. Morris working today?
Uh, yeah. He's somewhere.
Jerry?
What brings you to our neck of the woods?
I thought you were up in, uh... In Alaska.
Eh, I got tired of slinging
beers, so I moved back.
Hey, Archie. Look what the
world's largest cat dragged in.
- Jerry, my man.
- Hey.
- How you doing, brother?
- How are you?
- Good.
- Dr. Morris, do you realize...
there's a large storage unit in
the bay with your name on it?
I'm trying to get rid of it.
Burn it, donate it. I
want it out of here.
Sell everything.
You know, one man's
trash is another man's cash.
- And when do I have time for that?
- Uh, I'll do it.
- You will? Seriously? JERRY:
Yeah, I love a good fire sale.
Excellent. You know, I'll tell you
what, I will give you 10 percent...
Ten?
- Fifteen?
- It's cold outside.
Okay, fine. Fifty percent
of whatever you bring in.
You can't miss it. And paper
money only. None of this:
- "I want everything for a quarter" crap.
- You don't wanna look through it?
I made it this far without that junk,
no need to weigh myself down now.
Oh, welcome back.
How's Alex doing?
He's still sedated, you know.
We tried to extubate
him this morning, but...
- He'll be off the vent soon.
- You don't know that.
I thought he would
be talking by now...
but he was hypotensive
for so long, you know...
what if he has brain damage?
Or what if he just never
gets off the vent? It's...
Look, Sam, if you need
to take a little more time...
No, no. I really
should keep busy.
You know, I can't keep sitting
there staring at Alex's monitors.
Thank you for the offer.
Come on, let's get
some coffee first.
Chest is clear.
- How are you feeling, Gloria?
- Okay.
- Did you reach my husband?
- He's on his way.
He doesn't have to
come. I can call him later.
Cap refill's good. You know,
he's probably worried about you.
- How long have you two been together?
- We met at the aquarium.
I was 15. NEELA: Wow.
I can't imagine being married
to my high-school boyfriend.
- We were both new to America.
- How's the crit?
Stable at 39.
So everyone going
to the Christmas party?
Not a chance.
Yeah, but Surgery's hosting
it this year, you have to go.
Belly's benign. Archie
pinched my butt last year...
- and Frank nearly threw up on me.
- That sounds like fun.
Can't imagine why anyone
would wanna miss that.
- Fetal heart rate's at 145.
- You're not into the party?
A work party? At
work? Yeah, no thanks.
I got a hot date
with a stock broker.
So while you losers are
drinking virgin eggnog...
I'm going to be
sipping Veuve Clicquot.
- It's okay.
- Okay, they're three minutes apart now.
Breathe, Gloria, breathe. Okay?
- She's on mag?
- Yeah, but it's not doing much.
OB can take it from here.
She's clear surgically.
All right, Coburn's on her way.
This is Mrs. Ortiz' husband.
- Is the baby okay?
- We're just checking to make sure.
Do you know if it's a
girl or a boy, Mrs. Ortiz?
At my last ultrasound,
it was too soon to tell.
What are we looking at?
Something wrong?
- Is that a twin, maybe?
- I'm not sure.
Getting back to work will
probably be good for you.
- A little distraction. SAM:
Yeah, I could use the money.
Oh, excuse me.
Hey, excuse me, sir?
- Your kids need to be buckled up.
- Sorry, what?
- Your kids need to be wearing seat belts.
- Okay, lady, whatever you say.
Just saying it's better if the
kids had their seat belts on.
It's the law, it's common sense.
- Who the hell asked you?
- She's saying it'd be better...
- if the kids were buckled up.
- Screw off.
- Hey, watch it, all right?
- How are you gonna feel, huh?
If one of your kids comes
through that windshield...
and ends up in ER with
brains coming out of his skull.
- You're an idiot. It's idiots like you...
- Get out of the way.
That keep our hospital from shutting
down, so thank you very much.
- Idiot.
- Let it go. Let it go. Let it go.
How long do I have
to wait for my refills?
- Uh, check with Dr. Sanchez.
- I did.
He said something about
spiders and wandered away.
- If I see him, I will send him your way.
- Thank you.
Did you have that
necklace on earlier?
I got it from that
big man outside.
He wouldn't know a Hattie
Carnegie piece if it bit him in the ass.
I know, because I was a buyer
for Marshall Field for 40 years.
- Well, you wear it well.
- Thank you.
Oh, and you should know, the
original owner of that necklace?
- Mm-hm?
- She was a saint.
Frank, have you seen...
- the evaluation forms?
- Hello?
Let's see. Last time I
looked, they were right here.
Thank you.
Got myself a little something
from the Morris family estate.
- Let me guess, a nice broach?
- Hmm.
A baseball signed by
"Joltin'" Joe DiMaggio...
and some no-name Yankee.
Yeah, no, that was me.
"Archie Morris." My dad was
pissed. I couldn't sit down for a week.
Listen, um, that
was my friend, Ida.
- I... I need to find Dr. Sanchez.
- Okay, if I see him...
- you will be the first to know.
- No, no, no. No, this is really important.
- What do we have?
- Renee Webber-Stewart, 39.
She passed out at the mall.
All right, let's take
her to Exam 3.
- We were waiting for Santa.
- She has a 6-month-old, Lola.
Mom broke her fall, but
check on the baby too.
Belly's distended,
systolic's only 84 after a liter.
- My wife, Nicole.
- We'll call her for you, ma'am.
- I have the number.
- Could be vagal...
- but she's pretty out of it.
- Have Social Services watch the baby...
- until we can get a family member here.
- That's okay, I'll look after her.
Huh. Hi, you little reindeer.
It's okay. We're gonna get
you right back to Rudolph.
Oh, hi. Aren't you a cute baby?
- Oh, Frank? Frank. Still no Psych?
- I'll call again.
- Hey, I'm saving that for later.
- Okay, you still have one left.
I'm sorry. I'm hungry.
We're from Immigration. We're
looking for a patient, Gloria Ortiz.
Mom's 5 centimeters dilated
and maxed out on terb and mag.
- Can you tell if it's a boy or a girl?
- It's a boy.
- Ah, we're having a boy.
- Second IV is in.
We're having a boy.
Did you hear that?
A boy.
- That's great. NEELA: This
is what we were looking at.
- Thought it might be a multiple gestation.
- There's only one heartbeat.
- No, it's not a twin.
- Are you sure?
- What's wrong? COBURN:
All right. Mr. and Mrs. Ortiz.
The ultrasounds shows
your baby has a large mass...
involving the lower
face and neck.
- A mass? What does that mean?
- Does my baby have cancer?
The ultrasound doesn't
tell us if it's cancerous.
The most pressing
issue is the medications...
- aren't stopping your contractions.
- What are you saying?
We're gonna do everything
we can for your baby.
There are two Immigration
agents at the desk...
who wanna talk to your patient.
Well, we're kind
of busy here, Frank.
- They don't want to wait around.
- They're gonna have to.
What do we do now?
All right, your baby
needs to be delivered.
Is this Gloria Ortiz?
- We're doing an exam.
- What do you need?
- To take Mrs. Ortiz into custody.
- What for?
She's a fugitive alien.
She's being deported.
This yarn is so soft.
Yeah, my mom spent the
'70s obsessed with macramé.
Wall hangings,
tea cozies, vests.
- Vests?
- Mm-hm.
My first-grade class picture?
Rocking a blue macramé vest.
It's like no matter where
it is, it's staring at me.
Hey, come to the O.R.
Dr. Brenner's letting us
watch an EXIT procedure.
- What?
- It's when they section the mom...
to get an airway on the
baby before the delivery.
I mean, can you imagine?
- Hey, did you hear me?
- Oh, yeah. Airways. Airways, baby.
- Here.
- No. No.
Listen, have either of
you seen Dr. Sanchez?
Oh, he's over there.
Oh, oh, that's not one
of my brownies, is it?
Why, is it bad? I ate two.
- How are you feeling, dear?
- Hey, that's my Jell-O.
- You shouldn't be eating my food.
- It's okay, I'm a doctor.
Dr. Sanchez.
- What are you doing?
- Wiggling and jiggling.
Put that back.
Oh, doctor. Doctor, he's high as a kite.
The brownies have cannabis in them.
You gave pot
brownies to my staff?
Do you know how dangerous that is?
They could have mistreated a patient.
I know, it was a mistake. You
see, my friend, Ida, had cancer...
and I made special
brownies for her.
Now she's in remission, thank
the Lord, but she still likes them.
And I mixed up the batches.
You two are done for the day.
Drink some water, take a nap.
Whatever you do, do not drive
home until you're clean and sober.
Pick any three eight-track
tapes for the price of two.
Mr. Ortiz?
How's Gloria? Is she okay?
She's fine, but we're worried
the tumor on your son's neck...
could prevent him
from breathing normally.
- So fix it. Can you fix it?
- We're gonna do a Cesarean section...
so we can insert a breathing tube
while he's attached to the placenta.
I don't understand.
Well, that way, Gloria's body
can supply him with oxygen...
- until he can breathe on his own.
- Wait, she's having the baby today?
- We're prepping her for surgery.
- No. I can't. No, not like this.
- Well, we have to.
- Are they still there?
Did you know
Immigration was after her?
We're undocumented.
Two years ago, they scheduled her
for deportation, but she didn't show up.
I couldn't let her go.
- Our life is here.
- I'm so sorry. I have to get back.
- I'll call you when we're out of surgery.
- We're not bad people.
We never harmed anyone.
We only want to be happy.
- Frank gave this to me.
- Oh, that was my mom's.
That's your story,
huh? You want it back?
No, I'd break it.
When I was 9, I juggled
the holy-family set.
- Oh, yeah?
- Not sure what upset my mom more...
that I broke her Hummels or I
tossed around the baby Jesus.
The only time she
raised her voice at me.
Well, I don't juggle, so
I think this one's safe.
Dr. Banfield, this is
Nicole, Renee's partner.
- Hi. Is she okay?
- She's doing better.
- Can I see her?
- This way.
- Where's Lola?
- One of our nurses is babysitting.
I'll go get her.
Now, she's still a little
sedated from the CAT scan.
- What's wrong?
- We're not sure yet.
But we noticed the surgical
scar on her abdomen.
- Do you know what it's from?
- She had cancer of the small bowel...
but she's been in
remission for three years.
What does this have to
do with her passing out?
Her belly's distended
and we're concerned.
Oh, God.
Is that what you think?
That the cancer's back?
We'll know more when
we get the CT results.
This one's mine.
I got this when Alex and
I lived in Albuquerque.
He was just a baby then.
And this one's Haleh's. It
was a gift from her grandma.
And look, look. There's
Frank. That one's his, obviously.
It's pretty silly, huh?
Sam? We can take Lola
back to her mom now.
Bye-bye, little reindeer.
Bye.
- You okay?
- Nope, not even a little bit.
I remember this one Christmas,
Alex begged me for a skateboard.
And I gave it to him,
he was so excited.
- And then I made him wear a helmet.
- You were looking out for him.
You do everything you can
to keep them safe and then...
- he ends up on a ventilator.
- Sam.
He's been tubed for
almost a week. What's next?
He's gonna be on a
trach his whole life?
Let's not jump the gun. They're
gonna extubate tomorrow.
Yeah, I asked Dubenko if
they could try again tonight...
but he said they
only do it before noon.
Well, he's just
following the rules.
Why do you do that?
- What?
- Why do you always take the other side?
- I'm just trying to help.
- Yeah, well, then take my side.
All right, well, then
let's tell Dubenko...
that his rules are stupid, and
maybe he'll make an exception?
You never know.
- Cefazolin onboard.
- Uterine stapler.
Where did you get that?
- Surgical lounge.
- Low-V.
- Want some?
- Ew. No, thanks.
- Amnio infusion is underway.
- Okay, people, here we go.
Pulse, 118.
- Hey, you guys, look.
- Point-six fent.
Watch the head.
Fifty atropine,
30 of fentanyl IM.
Okay. Vecuronium's
in. Clock is ticking.
Get another zero and
a three-five. Let's go.
The scan shows some abnormal
tissue wrapped around part of the liver.
- The cancer's back?
- Most likely.
What's next?
We'll talk to a surgeon and
find out what the options are.
Run the scan by Dr. Dubenko.
- It was in the lymph nodes.
- Yeah.
We knew a recurrence was likely.
I convinced myself that
I was gonna be lucky.
That I could dodge the bullet.
Well, that's a great
attitude to have.
She doesn't understand the
concept of "The glass is half empty."
I finally met someone
that I couldn't live without...
and that's no time to give up.
A week before the surgery, we
flew to Boston and got married.
And we ran off like a
couple of teenagers.
That's quite a leap of faith.
It's not hard when you
have someone to hang onto.
What's gonna happen
once she's out of surgery?
She'll be detained
till they deport her.
What about her recovery?
Let's try a Miller one.
Detention facilities have doctors.
- Not good ones.
I can't get a good
view. Suction.
Can't we keep her
until the baby's DC'd?
We can't. Baby needs to
be in a NICU for three weeks.
- If people knew...
- Fetal heart rate's 138.
And by "people," you
mean the 10:00 news?
Couldn't hurt.
You put a magnifying glass
on our hospital like that...
public perception will be,
"Go to County, get deported."
The sat? MARISOL: 52.
Nothing we can do?
- We're doing it.
It's too distorted. Suction.
We got some uterine bleeding.
Switch with me,
Neela. Rigid bronch.
I can't get it.
You're taking too long.
- Systolic's 84.
Time's up. We gotta clamp,
whether you get the airway in or not.
Hold on. PERRY: 78.
If we don't handle this...
Mom is gonna bleed out
and we'll lose the baby too.
Damn it.
Okay, type specific and
0.25 methergine, now.
I have to cut the cord.
Not without an airway.
- No choice.
The baby's not getting oxygen...
We bail out now or
we lose them both.
How about a tracheotomy?
- Not yet.
Dr. Dubenko, a
39-year-old woman...
Find Anspaugh, we're busy here.
I want to make sure you...
- Find Anspaugh.
Got it. Sorry.
Lucien.
- We'll do the trach.
- Five minutes, that's all.
- Let's go, let's go.
- Okay, 15 blade and a 3-0 Shiley.
Nicole?
- What's the word from the surgeon?
- Uh, none yet.
How are you doing?
I was thinking, uh, what if...?
What if this is it?
Lola won't remember her.
You will.
And you'll make sure
your baby does too.
I feel like I might forget.
Just the little things.
How she burns the roof of
her mouth on pizza every time.
Or how she slaps my
arm when she laughs.
You won't forget those things.
You won't.
Jerry couldn't get
rid of this stuff?
- What do you want to do with it?
- Hey, thanks for the crock pot.
No problem. Uh, if it's the one with the
blue flowers on the side, it has a short.
Almost burnt the house down.
- Son of a bitch.
- What is it?
I made this in the third grade.
- Yeah, it's milk and cookies, for Santa.
- Okay.
Yeah. My teacher, Ms. Durbin,
said that wherever we are...
if we set this out,
Santa would find us.
That's sweet.
My dad didn't think so.
Yeah, he said Santa wasn't
stupid, he'd know it wasn't real.
- That was my dad.
- Yeah, but he kept it.
Yeah. Yes, he did.
Anatomy's so distorted. I
can't feel the tracheal rings.
- Focus.
- Crit's down to 26.
- I'm pulling the plug.
- Wait. Uh, guide wire?
- Systolic's only 68.
- Either you have it or you don't.
I'm in. DUBENKO:
Throw me the bag.
Twenty units of oxytocin
and start the drip.
Okay, we've got chest
rise. You can clamp.
Done.
Scissors.
Get the carboprost onboard.
Don't ever worry that you don't
do enough for your patients.
Right.
Lucien, can you stay? I need the hands.
- Yeah.
Uterine tone seems better.
- BP's coming up.
- Nice and clean.
Umbilical-line tray.
- Heart rate's over...
- Wow.
Good luck, Mr. Mosely.
Ha, ha. It's a little
late for that, isn't it?
- Sorry they couldn't extubate Alex today.
- Hopefully soon.
I'll keep my fingers crossed.
Copy, uh, the discharge
summary, will you?
I'll be right back.
Hey, Max?
Hey, Max.
Hey.
I've been looking for you, man.
- You all right?
- Yeah, I'm okay.
Jake has a hard time
when it's cold, though.
Well, come inside, warm
up a bit. Jake can come too.
Let's start with a cup of
coffee. You want some coffee?
Yeah. Yeah, coffee's good.
- This wasn't your average C-section.
- As long as she's stable...
- we have to take her into custody.
- She hasn't even seen her baby yet.
- I mean, give her a few days...
- Look, we don't like this either...
separating a mom from her kid.
- But we can't make an exception here.
- Well, why not?
- She should be able to spend...
- I'm sorry. We'll see you tomorrow.
I'll show you out.
- You got them to leave?
- They're coming back tomorrow.
They're gonna transfer
you to a detention facility.
- How's my baby?
- He's doing very well.
He's still on a ventilator, but
mostly breathing on his own.
- I should call my husband.
- I told him the surgery went well.
And that he'll be able to take
your baby home in a few weeks.
Immigration won't
get involved in custody.
A mother is supposed to
protect her child, keep him safe.
He's in good hands.
We're taking care of him.
I need to see him. I
need to see my baby.
- Dr. Dubenko?
- Uh, really swamped right now, Sam.
Yeah, I need you to try
to extubate Alex again.
- We will. Tomorrow.
- No, today. Please?
We already talked about this.
First thing in the morning, I promise.
I've been studying to
become a nurse anesthetist.
- There are some tricks we can use.
- Tricks?
Yeah. We can give an anxiolytic
before shutting off the propofol, right?
That may cut the agitation
we see during emergence.
Two Versed would be
calming and not too sedating.
- Okay.
- Okay, then we sit him up...
and we give him something
familiar to focus on.
It's the Blackhawks
game from last night.
Okay. Well, what
if it doesn't work?
No, it'll work. I'll talk him
through it, I'll stay there all night.
I will make sure he uses the
incentive spirometer. Whatever it takes.
He's so little.
We'll, uh, do an MRI...
to figure out exactly what we
need to do to remove the tumor.
Had you two picked names out?
For a boy we liked Pablo.
After my grandfather.
He was a strong man.
It's perfect.
How long will he be here?
Well, if all goes well,
only a few weeks.
We're pretty sure he won't
need chemotherapy or radiation.
All alone.
I'll come back.
- They took a risk staying here.
- So what?
It's still inhumane
to separate them.
Yeah, but there is nothing
that we can do, is there?
Not right now. It's not a
good time to rock the boat.
Why? Because you're at the
center of a malpractice suit?
Something like that, yeah.
I could have sworn that Neela
Rasgotra was a boat-rocker.
Like, a champion-grade,
professional one at that...
but I guess, I don't
know, I was... I was wrong.
- No, you're not wrong, but...
- What?
I just don't wanna take any
unnecessary chances with my career.
Ah!
Good things happen
when you take a chance.
You ready?
Okay, kiddo, we're gonna
take that tube out now, okay?
I know you can do this.
Try, try again, remember?
Like when we took the
training wheels off your bike.
The first time you fell off,
then you got right back on...
and you rode like the
wind. Remember that?
Okay. Balloon's down.
Just relax and take some deep
breaths, okay? Second time's the charm.
You wanna do the honors?
- Me?
- Yeah.
You know what you're doing.
Yeah, okay.
Are you ready? Here we go.
Come on.
Yankauer.
Give it a moment.
Alex?
Hey, Alex.
Hey, sweetie. How you feeling?
Did I...?
Did I miss Christmas?
No.
Hey.
Jake's in the break
room eating pot roast...
courtesy of our
clerk, Frank's, wife.
I'm not sure who's
happier, Jake or Frank.
Yeah. Thanks.
After I got back,
nothing went right.
Those people who used to care
were gone, or I scared them off.
The ones I thought I could rely on
from the Army said I wasn't their problem.
Then you came along, and I
figured you were more of the same.
But these, uh, past few days, I
heard you were looking for me.
- I saw the fliers.
- I was worried about you.
That means something, you know.
That makes a difference.
I don't... I don't wanna
die on the streets.
Oncology says if we do nothing,
she has a couple of months, tops.
The best thing we can do is
urge her to spend the time well.
She's has a 6-month-old child.
All the more reason for her
to enjoy the time she has left.
Look, if I take
her to the O.R...
there's a good chance I'll cut into
that thing and she'll bleed to death.
There's also a chance...
- you could debulk it and give her time.
- Slim chance.
Her and her partner
have had three years.
It that all the time they get?
You could give Renee time to
create memories with her daughter.
Christmas really brings out the
tenacity in you ER people, doesn't it?
Doesn't it?
Fine. Make her
NPO after midnight.
I'll try to get her on the
schedule for the morning.
Hey, I heard the good news.
- How you feeling?
- I'm all right.
You don't have to talk.
I brought you
some entertainment.
There's enough movies on here
to tide you over until you go home.
Thanks.
All right. I'm gonna run out and get
you that ice cream you've been craving.
- Rocky road?
- Cookie dough.
Ice cream for
dinner, huh, big shot?
Not bad.
Sarah wanted to be here, but
she's, uh, at her grandparents.
Although she did
send this tiny little card.
- How is she?
- She's good.
She said her arm
itches from the cast.
I thought I was
doing the right thing.
- I didn't...
- Oh, Alex, this wasn't your fault.
I should have never let you
and Sarah go out that night.
No, you were being cool.
Well, yeah...
that was the problem.
Here's your half.
- Three dollars and a Canadian quarter?
- Most of my customers were patients.
I mean, come on, I'm not gonna
charge some kid with the chickenpox...
for his first-ever
pair of rollerblades.
- There were rollerblades in there?
- Don't worry, I saved the best for last.
You know what
that is, don't you?
- A really old motorcycle?
- It's a 1966 Triumph.
Marlon Brando rode a
Triumph in The Wild One.
- Never saw it, don't care.
- Ah!
It's only the greatest rebel movie
ever with the awesomest bike.
You know what? If you
love it so much, keep it.
- What? No, I can't. I can't take this.
- Fix it up, sell it, whatever.
I don't get you.
All the great stuff in there, there
was nothing in there you wanted?
No, it's just...
It's just stuff.
Anyway, thanks for taking care of this.
I'm sure you had something better to do.
Actually, I didn't.
Since I moved back, work's
been tough to come by.
Oh, I'm sorry, man.
Anything I can do?
How can I get my old job back?
He fell asleep five minutes ago.
The extubation must
have worn him out.
Yeah.
- I'll put this in the freezer.
- All right.
He seems like
his old self again.
He wanted to remind you that
he wants a PS3 for Christmas.
- Lucien said he could be out in a week.
- Yeah.
We should have a party for
him when he comes home.
I forgot to tell you the other news.
Max showed up, can you believe that?
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah, I got him admitted...
and don't get mad, but I
said we could watch his dog...
- while he was in the hospital.
- Tony.
But you know what? Alex
always wanted a dog...
and I thought it'd be
cool, when he gets out...
- a dog will be there at the house...
- Tony, listen.
Um...
I'm gonna stay at
Chuny's for a while...
until, uh, I can find a
new place for me and Alex.
- You're moving out?
- It's just... It's just not working.
Sam, I know this has been
rough, but it'll get better.
We were doing fine before.
What, you just think things
can go back to normal?
I... I made a mistake.
- I shouldn't have let him go out.
- You keep saying that...
but it doesn't make
me feel better.
Well, I don't know what
else to tell you, Sam.
We can work past this.
I can't.
- So you're just gonna run away?
- I'm not running away.
I'm just telling you...
it's over.
- How's it look?
- Looks like locusts got to this.
- Oh, hey. How was the hot date?
- Oh, he was a douche.
You know, who
lies about their age?
First he was 34, then
he was 37, now he's 42.
Maybe he was afraid you
wouldn't date a 42-year-old.
Well, of course I wouldn't.
Besides, he was a stock broker, so
it's been a bad year for him anyway.
Bummer. Well, this has
been fun. I'm gonna get a drink.
I'm gonna get more food.
She hired you on the spot?
Yeah, she wanted a
Santa that wasn't stoned.
- Wow, you think you know someone.
- Ho, ho, ho, Dr. Banfield.
- And who might this young fellow be?
- Russell Banfield, the husband.
- Ho, ho, ho.
- This is Jerry. He's filling in for Frank.
- You can call me Kringle. Kris Kringle.
- Mr. Kringle.
And this is Dr. Morris.
So you must be the guy
that slept with my wife?
- What? Uh, no, no, no...
- I'm just kidding.
Nice to meet you.
- Jerry...? Uh, Santa?
- Yes?
- Listen, I need you to do me a favor.
- All right, now...
- Don't worry, it's a virgin.
I'll be ready for Renee's
surgery in the morning.
Hey. NEELA: Hey.
We got news on the Bertha
Mendenhall malpractice suit.
- What is it?
- Well, I don't know if I should tell you.
Why, is it bad? It's bad.
- Depends on whose side you were on.
- Just spill it.
Motion for summary judgment.
- The judge threw the case out.
- You're kidding.
Merry Christmas, Neela.
Gloria left?
Uh, yeah, looks that way.
And you're not upset?
People do crazy things
when they're desperate.
Eggnog?
Well, wait, uh, you're not
even the slightest bit worried?
She'll be okay. I'm starving.
- What's going on?
- Nothing.
It's nothing.
Wait, your patient leaves hours after
surgery and you're not concerned?
She needs to be
under a doctor's care.
It is possible that someone put
her in a cab to another hospital.
Good luck with everything.
So she's just gonna show
up and...? And ask for a bed?
And it's also possible that someone
wrote down a few instructions.
Neela Rasgotra,
rocking the boat.
Archie? Can you just
hold this? I'll be right back.
Hey, where are you going? Archie
Morris never leaves a party early.
In fact, more often than not,
he's the last man standing.
There's a first time
for everything, right?
Oh, come on. Who's
gonna pinch my butt later?
Frank? He's far too stoned.
- I'm not in the party mood, I guess.
- Well, we can change that.
You're like Happy Holly over here.
I should be asking if you're okay.
I'm just saying, there are
always things to celebrate.
Come with me.
Pretty amazing, huh?
Some days our job
really does matter.
Today I did paperwork and saw
my childhood parade around the ER.
Oh, yeah. Jerry gave me the Burl
Ives Christmas Favorites on reel-to-reel.
I kept acting
like I didn't care.
But, you know, I'd be lying if I
said there wasn't a part of me...
that hoped Jerry might
find something that would...
I don't know, help me
understand my dad.
Something more than
crock pots and cheese hats.
You know, I was thinking...
about us having a family.
Starting again.
That's a pretty
big leap of faith.
Not so hard when you
got someone to hold onto.