Previously on ER:
I never wanted to be around
this suffering. Who would?
- I'm glad I came here.
- I'm glad you came too.
I've been evaluated by the
committee. You know what?
I'm in the clear. You better
start showing me some respect.
- Getting sleep?
- I'm not doing this.
- What time you going home?
- I haven't been getting sleep.
And the thing is that I've been
really, really needing some.
I wish I didn't feel how I feel.
You're the best
friend I've ever had.
- Neela, I am a soldier, remember?
- You're also a husband, remember that?
One of the drivers got hit.
Corporal Milton,
can you hear me?
Okay. He's gonna be okay.
- I want you to hold pressure here.
- I just called the CASH.
- They're sending a chopper.
- That's not gonna work.
How far are we
from the aid station?
FOB Eagle is only about
four kilometers due north.
Okay, okay. On my count,
we'll lift him up onto the truck.
Keep pressure on his neck.
Shouldn't we wait
for the chopper?
He'll bleed out before
they get here. Let's go!
One, two, three.
I don't even think
he's breathing.
Just keep holding
pressure. You're doing good.
His pupils are
fixed and dilated, sir.
We can stop.
Thanks for trying, sir.
He just got engaged.
You got a girl back
home, captain?
Me? Yeah.
I'm married.
My wife, Neela, is a doctor...
Oh, my...
Oh, yes.
Shh, shh, shh.
Oh, yeah. Yeah.
Yeah.
Mothers eat their
own young in the wild...
and we think it's
part of nature, right?
But when women kill their children,
it's a crime, and we think they're crazy.
- What?
- It just makes you wonder, right?
Are the lions crazy too? Or are women
like Susan Smith and Andrea Yates...
just acting upon some
primitive impulse...
that's deep within our
genetic maternal make-up?
- Am I interrupting something?
- Just some girl talk.
Dennis Young,
34, assault victim.
Blunt trauma to head and face.
- Was he mugged?
Looked like a home-invasion
thing. They tuned him up good.
What's your name?
Airway's okay, decent
vitals, moves all extremities.
- Pupils are 5 millimeters. MORALES:
There were two kids with him.
Seventeen's bringing them. They
got worked over, one looks real bad.
Okay, Abby, Trauma 1.
Head, facial and C-spine
CT as soon as you can.
And send Sam out here to help...
- if you see her.
- Okay.
Get out of here.
She invited me in for a drink.
Door wasn't even closed...
- she was tearing my clothes off.
- Yeah, right.
To quote my man Rick James,
"The girl is a super freak."
She had sex toys I've never seen before.
Must have been German or something.
- One took two hands to operate.
- Morris.
Check it out. Oh,
yeah. I tapped that.
- What exactly am I looking at?
- It's Albright.
- Where?
- Right there.
I've seen more convincing
photos of Bigfoot.
But it was dark, I
couldn't use the flash.
Any chance he'll talk to us?
- I don't think so.
- Enlighten me.
- Open skull and facial fractures.
- We got nothing to go on.
- Nobody saw anything.
- Glascow coma scale?
Spontaneous eye opening.
- What's he trying to say?
- He's altered. Don't think he knows.
Withdraws from pain.
- For a total of?
- Twelve.
- We intubate at?
- GCS of nine.
- Excellent.
Blood in the belly?
We were focusing
on the primary survey.
If I wanted excuses,
I'd ask you directly.
Give me the SonoSite.
Any idea why CT scan on
your trampoline guy, Margolis...
- never got to the O.R.?
- I'll have a tech run them up.
- Dubenko wants you to bring them up.
- Hang a gram of Vancomycin.
- Is this about the oral contrast?
- No idea.
It increases the
risk of anesthesia.
If you want my opinion, I'd find
those results and haul my ass up there.
- After we stabilize the patient.
- No. Now.
- We got this. It's okay.
- Belly's clear.
Call me after the scan, Mo.
And have Neurosurg and
Head and Neck take a look.
Did she just call you Mo?
It's a nickname for Morris.
Or homo.
Hey, don't worry, okay?
That little vixen's
getting punished tonight.
Oh, yeah, she's
in store for a little:
Mo-Mo-Morris
How do you like it?
Oh, yeah, Morris
Hey, stranger.
- Welcome back, Dr. Pratt.
- Thanks.
Glad to see you
survived. How was it?
Well, hot, sweaty, fly-infested.
It was a little
overwhelming, to be honest.
- Did you save a lot of lives?
- I tried.
Three-year-old
Eddie, good pulses.
BP, 100/50. Decided to
stop breathing as we pulled in.
Can you open your eyes, Eddie?
- He's posturing.
He was awake on the scene,
this is all we can get out of him.
- Sam, you're with me.
- He's bradying down.
Probable head bleed.
Thirty mgs of mannitol, call CT,
let's get Neurosurg down here.
Sean, 10 years old, blunt
trauma, face and chest.
Tachy at 135, BP's good,
100 percent on room air.
How are you doing,
Sean? I'm Dr. Pratt.
I wanna stay with Eddie.
He's scared when
I'm not with him.
Don't worry, we'll have you in the
room right next to him. Come on, let's go.
- Damn it, the IV blew.
- Tube.
Who did this?
Ugh.
It must have been the same
guys who busted up the pops.
Looks like the work of meth
heads. What's this kid's story?
Three-year-old,
hypertensive and bradycardic.
Looks like traumatic
head injury.
Okay, I'm in. Bag
him at a rate of 40.
Pupils dilated, left
greater than right.
Step-offs, hematomas.
Could be head trauma.
All right.
Retinal hemorrhage.
Definitely head trauma. Call
Neurosurg and get mannitol onboard.
We've already done that, Vic.
Pulse hanging in the
60s. I still don't have a line.
Okay, throw me an IO needle.
- You don't wanna do that. Trust me.
- Oh, yeah, I do.
Betadine.
The IO drill is the greatest.
Wait till you see this.
- We don't have the pedes model.
- We do. We got it in last week.
I'm gonna show you
how to drive this baby.
- Vic, let me do it.
- No, I got it.
- Come on. I got it.
- I got it. Let me do it.
Vic, come on. Okay, I got it.
Okay, I'll talk you through it.
Tibial tuberosity.
One-finger-breadth medial.
One-finger-breadth
medial, that's what it is.
Are you listening to me?
- He's seizing.
- Two of Ativan.
- I can't. I don't have access.
- Hold on. Hold on.
There you go. That's it.
- Okay, now you do.
- Nice job.
- Get a head CT.
- What's wrong with you?
I'm trying to help
you, that's all.
You don't listen to a word anybody
says. You're all over the place.
Okay, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, I was...
I just didn't get a
lot of sleep last night.
Seizing stopped.
A hundred and fifty of Dilantin
and pack up for the scanner.
Outside.
- What?
- Now.
What?
- What are you on?
- I'm not on anything.
I just told you. All I ate was
a cup of coffee, that's all.
What? What, you
want a drug test?
You want a drug test
here, now? Go, grab a cup.
- Go ahead. Grab a cup.
- Okay, look.
Why don't you take 20 minutes
and get yourself together?
Because I repeated an order?
Come on, please.
What are you, my moms?
- Luka.
- Frank, not now.
Look, you're an Attending. I need
you to be on the ball. Vic, I'm serious.
Yeah, I'm serious too. You're
seriously starting to piss me off.
Because if you don't wanna work
with me, that's fine. I don't need you.
Vic. Vic... FRANK: Dr. Kovac.
What, Frank?
These gentlemen are
looking for Dr. Rasgotra.
One of them is a
Military Casualty Officer.
Sats are falling, 89.
Can't see the cords, too much
blood. Need a surgical airway.
- Crike tray.
- Slow your roll.
Open a central line
kit. Abby, grab a McGill.
- We're gonna do a retrograde intubation.
- Never seen that work.
You've never seen me do it,
junior. Today's your lucky day.
I'm gonna do a Seldinger technique.
I'm gonna wire up through the cricothyroid.
- It'd be faster to crike him.
- No, you'll get infection and bleeding.
Not to mention subglottic
stenosis and a big, ugly-ass scar.
Sats down to 84. Hypoxia's
not good for you either.
- Where's Neela?
- She got called up to Surgery.
We'll aspirate air, and
then pass the wire through.
There are soldiers
looking for her...
and one of them is a chaplain.
You need to find her.
Yeah, I'm trying to page her.
- Everything okay in here, Abby?
- Yeah, I think so.
We'd be doing better
if you stopped talking...
when I'm trying to show
them how to save his life.
- Listen, Vic...
- Look, I'm all over this.
I'm serious. Go
find Neela, please.
Okay, Abby, look. Look for
the wire in the oropharynx.
- I can't see it.
- You will, you will.
Come on, you son of a bitch.
Damn it.
Come on. MARQUEZ: Got it.
Hey, can you give
this CT to Dr. Dubenko?
I think he wants to see you.
I've been paged to ER. If you
can make sure he gets them.
He was very specific about
speaking with you in person.
Sats, 78, bradying down to 60.
I still can't see your
wire. Open up a crike tray.
- We don't need no crike tray.
- Vic.
Stop staring at me.
Focus on your patient.
Ray, give her more
suction. It's gotta be there.
Wait, wait, wait. I got it.
- All right.
Keep going, keep going.
Stop. It'll guide you
right through the cords.
- Okay. That's enough, Chuny. Thank you.
- Sure.
Hard to pass.
Wiggle it, mommy. Side
to side. Wiggle it, wiggle it.
Okay. I think I'm in.
All right, wire out and bag
him. Call for a portable chest.
- We all good here?
- We're doing great.
- Abby?
- Why you asking her?
I mean, I just told you
we're doing good, right?
I'll go find Neela.
Can you believe this?
It's ridiculous, huh?
What percentage of liver
injuries stop bleeding...
by the time surgical
exploration is performed?
- About half?
- How about 86 percent?
It's okay, you have time to
learn all that in five years.
What?
Seems like all my
complaining's finally paid off.
We've been funded for an
additional slot in a Surgical Residency.
- It's yours for the asking.
- Are you serious?
- Well, if you don't want it...
- No, I want it. I want it.
Sorry, it's the ER.
Ignore it, you're a surgeon.
We never answer the first page.
I'm kidding, go. Come
find me after your shift.
We'll grab a beer
at Ike's to celebrate.
Yeah, that would be great,
but the drinks are on me.
So I guess
congratulations are in order.
Yes, thank you.
Dr. Dubenko just told me.
I'm so excited, can't
wait to get started.
Yeah, it's gonna be fun.
Looking forward to
being your Attending.
Right. Wonderful.
Neela, Luka's looking for you.
Yeah, I got his page. Hey, guess
what. I got the Surgical Residency.
- Wow, that's great.
- You should really try to find Luka.
- Yeah, I will.
- Hold up. I need to talk to you.
- Hey, I got it.
- What?
The Surgical Residency.
That's good for you.
That's really great.
Well, try to contain
your enthusiasm.
- I need to tell you something.
- Yeah, Luka's paging me.
I know, and...
Because it's important.
So is my news, but
nobody seems to care.
- Neela, listen...
- It's not like I'm leaving the hospital.
I'm going into Surgery. I'd think you
people would like having me up there.
Abby, have you seen Luka?
There are two men
here to see you.
From the Army.
The Army?
We tried to find you.
- Doctor Rasgotra?
- Yes.
I'm Captain Evans,
this is Father Marris.
Is there someplace
more private we can talk?
Can you tell me why
you're here, please?
- I really think it would be better...
- Tell me.
Ma'am, the secretary of the
Army would like to express...
- his deepest regret...
- There must be some mistake.
That your husband, Captain
Gallant, was killed in action.
I'm sorry, you've
got it mixed up.
Michael is a doctor. He's
not a "soldier" soldier.
He was killed when his truck
was hit by a roadside bomb.
Again, the secretary extends
his deepest sympathies...
I'm sorry.
I'm working. I can't
do this right now.
Please tell Dr. Rasgotra that we're
here to help in any way possible.
Have his parents been notified?
No, but that's something
we can do if she would like.
What about Michael's...?
Her husband's remains?
It will take seven to 10 days for
the deceased to get here from Iraq.
Arrangements will be made to fly him
here to Chicago or wherever she decides.
Okay. I'll pass it on.
All pertinent information
is in the packet.
If she has any questions, she
can contact myself or Father Marris.
- Okay, thank you.
- Thank you.
- Hey, was it friendly fire?
- Sir?
How do we really know what
happened over there, huh?
Doesn't this whole war smell to
you a little bit of right-wing cronyism?
With the oil, and the multi-billion-dollar
rebuilding contracts, huh?
You know what real
psychological warfare is?
You coming in here, feeding us a
bunch of lies to placate the masses.
- Shut up.
- Tell me about the deficit.
Why do we have to go
there and kill everyone?
- For democracy?
- I need help with Mr. Engle's blood gas.
- Vic.
- Excuse me. Come on.
Sorry. RAY: I'm
gonna go find Neela.
Make sure she goes home.
Okay, he's doing better.
So why don't we lower
the FlO2 to 70 and then...
we'll grab a...
- Grab an ABG in 20, okay?
- You want me to look at your nose?
No, I'm fine. I'm
fine. Thank you.
I just wanna say I'm sorry.
I'm sorry about what
happened over there...
but those guys coming in here
like storm troopers and just...
It's like I'm a stigmata.
- Why don't you go crash in the lounge?
- I'm fine, I'm fine. I'm really fine.
You know there's no rest for the
wicked. You, Abby, should know that.
The intubation was
cool, though, wasn't it?
Gotta put that in your bag of
tricks. I'm telling you, you got...
Look, I gotta take care of this.
- Hey.
- Did you find Neela?
- Ray's looking for her.
You know, I came here today...
thinking about how nice
it is to be back, you know?
I figured I'd come back,
maybe save a few lives.
Maybe even bring somebody
back from the dead, you know?
I damned sure didn't
expect to lose a friend.
Yo, doc.
The 10-year-old won't say
anything, and we got nothing.
Did you find mom?
Yeah, she's been in
rehab since November.
Dad's out of it, and
baby's in a coma.
This kid's all we got.
Can you try talking to him?
Yeah.
- How we doing in here?
- Oh, kind of quiet.
Hey, man. You wanna see
something really, really cool?
That's your skeleton.
And, see, look right here. This is
where you broke your collarbone.
Looks like old rib fractures.
Do you remember
hurting your ribs?
No?
I know you're worried about
your dad and your little brother.
But we got the best
doctors helping them out.
So now we need you to help them
too, by telling us what happened.
You do wanna help Eddie, right?
Yeah? Well, then
you need to talk to me.
Eddie wanted to play
with my Bionicle guy...
and I took it away from him.
Then he started crying,
and he wouldn't stop.
So my dad started shaking him.
Did your dad hit you?
He punched me, then
threw me into a chair.
And what about your brother?
Eddie kept crying...
and he kept shaking him.
Telling him to shut
up using the F-word.
And then he grabbed Eddie's
head and slammed it against the wall.
Then Eddie was crying so
hard that he couldn't breathe.
So I got my baseball
bat and hit him.
You hit your dad?
I wanted him to
leave Eddie alone.
How many times did you hit him?
Until he stopped.
I was just talking to
him four days ago.
He was complaining
about the food...
and I was complaining about
how cold Abby's apartment is.
I honestly don't even remember
what else we were talking about.
I'm so sorry, Neela.
We all are.
You know, I was probably ordering
a latte or watching Celebrity Poker...
when he was being
blown up by a bomb.
Just like that, he's gone.
Listen, if you need anything...
- Or you want me to do anything...
- No, Ray, I don't.
I don't need you to do anything.
I just... I need to
go back to work.
No, Neela, look.
You need to go home,
take care of things.
- You need to take care of yourself.
- You know, I don't have a home.
I don't have a husband.
I don't have anything.
All I have is this
stupid hospital.
Just stay the hell away from me.
Are you hiding?
Is it that obvious?
I can't believe Michael's dead.
- You wanna go home? I'll cover for you.
- What about Neela?
Well, we can
take care of things.
Who? You and Clemente?
Weaver knew he had
problems before she hired him.
- Now we're paying for it.
- Well, Luka, it's your ER.
Let's go away someplace
where it's warm...
and where nobody
knows who we are.
- You mean like a vacation?
- No, not like a vacation...
a vacation. A real one.
Even if it's just for a couple
of days before the baby's born.
We could hang out by
a pool. Or the ocean.
I can dig a hole in the
sand for your big belly.
What is that? Some sort
of Croatian mating ritual?
- Mm-hm.
- What am I, a sea turtle?
Neela.
Neela?
- Hey. Hey, let someone take you home.
- I have patients to pass on.
We can take care of
that. You need to go home.
Why is everyone so damn
insistent that I go home?
I have things to do. I haven't
even told Michael's parents yet.
Well, the guys from the Army
said they could take care of that.
No. I have to do it.
Don't you think it'd be better to do it
from my apartment. Get some privacy?
Doubtless they're both at work.
I wanna tell them at the same
time when they're together tonight.
- Neela, go home, please.
- Abby, Dennis Young's crashing again.
I'll check in on you later.
- Hey, Neela, I just wanted...
- Don't.
Um...
The men from the Army
left a package for you.
Frank has it at the desk.
- Neela?
- You know what?
If it makes everyone
else happy, I'll go home.
- What's going on?
- He's bradying down.
Push the damn atropine.
- You sure he didn't have an epidural?
- No. Just diffuse brain edema.
- All right, a hundred grams of mannitol.
- We gave him mannitol.
Bilaterally blown pupils.
Check the ET tube. Maybe it came out.
- No, it's fine.
GCS, three.
His brain stem is failing.
There's not a whole lot
we could do about that.
- Heart rate's down to 30.
- I lost the pulse. It's P.E.A.
An amp of epi. Two angiocaths.
Maybe it's a tension pneumo.
- He's satting at 100 percent.
- Did he get Dilantin?
Fifty per kilo.
All right, Sam.
Start compressions.
Okay, Sam. You call those
compressions? Come on.
New AHA guidelines.
December issue circulation.
A hundred per minute, deeper and
faster. That's how you'll save a life.
Okay, I need to
perfuse his brain.
I need hypertonic
saline at 23.4 percent.
- We don't have that.
- Don't have that?
You don't have that? Hypertonic
saline reduces ICP when mannitol fails.
That paper last fall in The Lancet.
Or was it the New England Journal?
It was Neurosurgery.
That's right.
I knew it. The author was Weston or
Williams or something starting with W.
Wares, that's it.
That's it, Wares.
- Neurosurgery, 2004, October.
- Hold compressions.
Asystole.
- Okay, let's just call it, Vic.
- Call it?
Lockhart, I never
figured you for a quitter.
All right, he needs burr
holes. We gotta reduce the ICP.
He has an open skull fracture.
Burr holes are not gonna help.
Vic.
Okay, he should have
had an ICP monitor.
Everybody knows he
should've had an ICP monitor.
Time of death: 1420.
Oh, we could do
better than this.
We gotta do a
lot better than this.
- Do a lot better than that.
- Vic, I need to talk to you.
Yeah, and I need a cup of coffee.
Not the crap they serve here.
Not the effluence they
pass at the roach coach.
- I need a real cup of coffee.
- Vic, hey...
Ever been to this Italian place,
Marrinacio's on Randolph?
My God, best coffee this side of
Milan. They even make their own biscotti.
You walk through that door,
it smells... I'll treat everybody.
Everybody. I'm gonna treat everybody
to espresso and biscotti, okay?
Luka, 48-year-old
complaining of chest pain.
Exam 3. Is he on any medication?
Lipitor and aspirin.
- Should I go get Clemente?
- No, let him go.
Just pick me up as
soon as he comes back.
Okay, first-day labs,
12-lead, Lopressor and nitro.
Sir, don't worry, we'll
take good care of you.
One. PRATT: One.
- Following an accidental scalding.
- I'll be right in.
I guess his brother accidentally got his
head slammed against the wall today?
- Hey, what's going on?
- I got a kid with a busted collarbone.
He's got signs of old rib
and humerus fractures.
He's the lucky one. His little brother's
in the room next to him in a coma.
- Did you call Social Services?
- Yeah, they're coming.
You know, we got CTs, MRIs, PET
scans, Dopplers, 4-D ultrasounds...
and we still can't save one kid
from getting his brains beaten out.
That's right. Had
to kill his old man...
because there was nobody
else there to help him.
I guess that would be too
much to ask, wouldn't it?
It's much better that we
spend... What is it now?
6 billion dollars a month in a
war all the way across the world...
to kill off a few more of the other
kids who actually get to their teens.
Did you tell the police?
So they could arrest him?
Yeah, because that's the one thing
we do well in this country, isn't it?
We got prison down to a science.
Prison and war.
He and Dr. Gallant were friends.
This coffee is good. Italians
know what they're doing.
The French... What the hell is a
French press anyhow? Forget that, man.
- I know you.
- Oh, yeah?
- You're a killer.
- No, no. I'm not a killer.
Jerry Lee Lewis is the killer, and
you're the mayor of Munchkin City.
You kill them in the hospital.
You got blood on you.
Oh, damn. My nice, new shirt.
Right through the trauma gown.
- Yeah, I know what you do.
- Oh, man.
You cut them up
into little pieces.
- You gotta step off.
- Feed the surgical waste to the dogs.
- Stop the slaughter.
- Know how I got this?
Know how I got this?
Saving someone's life.
Because that's what I do. I save pieces
of crap like you, okay? You crazy son...
- Hey, watch where you're going, man.
- Hey.
What are you doing,
man? You trying to...?
Watch where you're going, man. I'm
a pedestrian, I have the right of way.
- You're not even looking.
- Want me to kick your ass?
Now you're gonna kick my
ass? Gonna get violent on me?
Gonna kick my ass.
Come on, kick my ass.
- Kick my ass up here.
- Hey.
- What the hell you doing?
You're gonna go violent
on me? Go ahead.
What the hell are you doing? Hey,
hey, hey. What are you, psycho?
- Psycho?
- Yes, psycho.
Psycho? You don't
know about psychosis.
I'm the freaking doctor.
I'll show you psychosis.
Oh! Oh! Oh!
- That's psychosis, okay?
- Hey, come on. What are you, on drugs?
Yeah, I'm high. I'm wasted.
I'm flipping. You
wanna dip my urine?
Is that what you wanna do? You wanna
dip my urine? Go ahead. Go ahead.
Oh! Oh!
Yeah, watch out, huh? Watch out.
I'm gonna get you all over the place.
Hi, Neela, it's Abby.
I was thinking about stopping
by tonight on my way to Luka's.
And we're gonna
get some takeout...
so if there's anything
special you wanna eat...
or if you need anything,
just give me a call.
You talk to her?
Tried. I think she
just wants to be alone.
She'll have a lot of time alone. Probably
best if she was around people now.
Yeah, well, like I said, I
tried, but it didn't seem to work.
Whoa, Abby.
Sam, Sam. SAM: Vic?
I got jumped. I was
going for a cup of coffee.
- They ambushed me.
- Forty-one-year-old male.
- Altered mental status.
- I'm not, you're altered.
There's no connection
with you on a human level.
He was wandering around in
traffic, combative, uncooperative.
You know why I'm uncooperative?
You tied me down, that's why.
What is this, Fascist Germany?
1984? What are we living in?
- Easy, Vic.
- Why is he in handcuffs?
He assaulted several motorists.
You know what it is? Xenophobia.
That's what it is. Keep us living in fear.
How about Trauma 1?
- Full.
- It's not H5N1.
- Take him to Exam 2.
- Pulse ox, 99 on two liters.
Pulse ox, 99? Ha.
On room air, mouth breather.
Get him away from me.
- He doesn't know what he's doing.
- Dextrostick, 102.
Sam, tell them I'm an Attending.
Tell them what a colossal
mistake they've made.
- Please, tell them.
- You cut your leg, Vic.
Yeah, but it's superficial.
I can feel the platelets
already gonna take care of it.
I can feel that. I can fix
that with a get-well sticker.
- Let us check it out.
- It'll only take a minute.
All right, all right. Okay,
okay. I get it. It's funny, guys.
The joke's on me. I get
it. Everybody's laughing.
Okay, now get it off me,
okay? Come on. Get it off.
- Four of Ativan.
- Take it off me! Take it off!
- Five of Haldol, IV push.
- Get it off me!
Abby, you can't give me Haldol.
You can't give me Haldol, Abby.
I'm not crazy. You understand?
- It's okay. It's okay.
- X-ray, come here, buddy.
Come here. These freaking
chicks are losing their mind.
- Come over here, help me, man.
- Get Luka.
What, are you gonna
amputate my leg?
Oh, that's it. Run to
Daddy, you little bitch.
Run to Daddy, little bitch.
Sam, don't you dare.
Don't you dare, Sam.
- Sam, don't you dare.
- Just try to relax.
Settle down, doc. Settle down.
See? He said I'm a
doc. You heard him.
I'm a doc... I'm a doctor,
not a freaking patient.
Abby. Abby, I'm your Attending.
You hear me? I'm your Attending.
- Do no harm, Abby. Do no harm, Abby.
- I know. I know.
I'm an Attending at...
Hey.
I thought it would be okay.
Do you mind?
Oh, sure.
- Sean, you want some more Jell-O?
- Can I?
Yeah, we got tubs of it downstairs.
I'll be back in a few minutes.
Eddie's gonna be
hungry when he wakes up.
You know, since
your mom's away...
you're gonna have to go
stay with a foster family.
Probably until she gets back.
The Fosters?
No, their name's not Foster.
That's what they do.
They take care of kids.
Eddie too?
No, Eddie's gonna have
to stay in the hospital.
Because he's still sick?
He's showing signs
of improvement though.
And we're gonna have him...
in a very special part of the
hospital that's just for kids...
and you can visit him there.
What about my dad?
His injuries were
very, very severe...
and, um...
the doctors, they
couldn't fix him.
He's dead?
Yeah. I'm afraid so.
- But I didn't mean to kill him.
- I know that.
But I'm gonna go to hell.
- What?
- For killing him.
God sends you to
hell if you kill someone.
Sean, I think that God
makes exceptions...
if you were trying to
save someone else.
Really?
Really.
- How is he?
- He settled down.
Okay, I'm gonna get out of here.
I'm gonna go to my
place, check on Neela.
- Call me. Let me know how she's doing.
- I will.
- What's with Clemente?
- Have to hear what Psych says.
Too bad, I was starting
to like the little guy.
- Clemente's labs. Tox screen's negative.
- Not so sure that's a good thing.
Come on, guys, let's
give Vic some privacy.
We still got a board to clear.
Back to work, everybody.
Do you need me to
sign off on anything?
No.
Everything okay with you?
Yeah. Why?
Well, sometimes it can
be a difficult transition...
coming back to this place.
Yeah, I'll be okay. I was
just a little rattled earlier...
because of the
whole Mike situation.
Well, it's good
to have you back.
Hey.
Thanks for making me go there.
Someday, maybe you
can tell me all about it.
Yeah, someday.
Neela?
- Hi.
- Hey.
I brought you some
dinner and some groceries.
Thanks.
Did you call Michael's family?
Hey, how about I
stay here tonight?
Um, I think I'd
like to be alone.
Really?
I could use a break
from Luka's snoring.
Michael used to snore
when he was drunk.
You know, I had to come
home and find a photograph...
because I couldn't
picture him in my head.
One day, I'm not even gonna be
able to remember what he looks like.
That's not true.
I'm gonna be fine.
Okay.
I'm sorry.
- I'm putting him on a 72-hour.
- What are you calling it?
Gravely disabled. He's
blaming it on insomnia.
Tox screen was clean.
There's no history of
schizophrenia or bipolar disorder.
But he's had prolonged
sleep deprivation...
and was recently the
victim of a violent crime...
so there's probably
some PTSD going on too.
- But we'll know better in a couple days.
- Yeah.
- Thanks.
Hey, Vic.
- What a day you had, huh?
- Yeah.
How are you feeling?
I'm pretty good, considering.
I just feel like such an ass for
flipping out in front of the kids.
I'm a passionate man. That's
what makes me a good doctor, right?
Right.
I just can't keep up my pace without
spinning off the road at some point.
I'm just sorry that it had
to happen on your watch.
No, that's okay. That's okay.
The important thing is
that you get some rest now.
Yeah. Yeah.
I'm gonna get some rest.
Oh, yeah.
I'm gonna get some
serious R and R.
- Catch up on my sleep or maybe do a...
- Let me, uh...
- Let me take you upstairs, okay?
- All right, sure.
- Okay?
- Yeah.
Personal escort
treatment. I like that.
Appreciate it,
Luka. I really do.
You helping me like this.
And don't be afraid to
come up any time to see me.
Especially if you need to run
something past somebody or...
I can still make a
diagnosis on the tough ones.
Take care of
yourself. Okay, Vic?
Yeah, be cool, man.
Yeah.
Get back to work.
Hey, it's me.
I'm getting the camera ready.
- Get out of here, you freak.
- I love you, Neela.
Get out of here.
You see what I gotta
deal with? You see that?
So hopefully you're
never gonna see this thing.
But if you are,
well, then, uh...
You know, something went wrong.
Well, maybe not wrong, but
certainly not according to plans.
I love you, Neela.
Marrying you was the
happiest day of my life.
You just... You make me strong.
Now, I know you didn't
want me to come back to Iraq.
And I guess if you're watching
this, you owe me a big "I told you so."
But I did what I had to do.
You're the most beautiful
and kind person that I know.
I just... I just want
you to be happy.
And just know that
I'll always be with you.
I want you to find somebody,
get married, have babies.
Of course, he won't
be as fine as me...
but I guess you'll just
have to live with that.
I love you, Neela.
Forever.