Morning.
Uh, do you want me
to make you some coffee?
No, I always get one
from the cart at work,
unless you're making
some for yourself.
Uh, no, actually,
the cart sounds good,
'cause I have no idea
how to use this thing.
Um, so...
You wanna go straight to work,
or do you need to stop by
at your place first or...
I think my fish will survive
till I get home tonight.
Though I could go
feed them now,
if you wanted to get
a drink tonight after work.
Yeah, sure. Uh, uh...
What?
Uh, I actually have
plans tonight.
Plans?
But I can cancel them.
Nope.
Keep your plans. It's fine.
Smooth.
Hey.
How was the night shift?
Only got puked on twice.
Then it was a good night.
Bye, guys. See you tomorrow.
Bye.
Night.
Have you contacted your
sister yet about meeting up?
Still working on it.
It might actually
be better for her
if I keep a little distance.
Better for her or for you?
You know what would
be good for me?
Is dinner with you tonight.
Are you gonna shower first?
Depends on who's paying.
Then it's definitely
on me.
Later.
Bye.
And now she's shivering
and, and throwing up,
and I don't know what to do.
Deb, what's going on?
Her homeless friend
is nine months pregnant
and has a fever.
She needs to come in.
But she won't, right?
No.
Would you come out
and help her, please?
Not when she's
this far along.
She needs to be monitored
and have emergency
measures nearby.
Dr. Choi...
Let me get some supplies.
Hey, wait. Hey...
You're just gonna go
treat a pregnant girl
on the streets?
I have met
some of these kids.
They're underage.
They know that
if they come in,
they'll get put in a system.
Yeah, but she's nine months.
She's gonna have to come in
eventually to have her baby.
But she needs
to be assessed now.
Nat, I could use your help.
Seriously?
Fine.
Thanks.
Text babysitter.
Cold pizza is
Owen's favorite breakfast.
There's some in the fridge.
Tell him I love him.
Send.
I'll send your message.
She's over here.
Come on. Come on.
I wrapped her up,
but she's still shivering.
Hey.
Laura, I'm Dr. Manning.
I'm gonna take
your temperature, okay?
Let me take a look.
103.
You most likely have
an infection.
It is very important
that we treat it
before you go into labor.
Okay, but my water broke,
what does that mean?
When did your water break?
Two days ago.
Dr. Reese...
How was your dinner
with your dad?
It was good.
Uh, I mean, I'm glad
we're talking again.
He's funny, smart.
You don't sound
entirely convinced.
Well, it's just kinda hard
to look past the last
20 years.
I know he wrote me
those letters, but...
There were other ways
to contact me if he wanted.
Makes me wonder.
Well, you know what,
I've always been
immensely impressed
with your instincts,
so no reason to stop
listening to them now.
Yeah, I guess so.
Courtney?
I've got Luke Wallis.
Cystic fibrosis.
No breath sounds on the right.
Tachycardic with
BP 122 over 66.
Satting at 86.
Oh, I know Luke.
How you doing, buddy?
Been better.
He was just watching TV,
and then suddenly,
he couldn't breathe.
Get a stat chest X-ray.
Make it a CT.
And get more information.
On my count, one, two, three.
There we go.
Has his lung function
been getting worse?
He's been in the ICU three
times in the last five months.
Dr. Rhodes
has him at the top
of the transplant list
for lungs, but
so far, it's nothing.
He's got a pneumothorax
on the right,
significant rales on the left.
Set me up for
a 16 French chest tube.
That's a little invasive.
We can use a pigtail catheter.
His lungs are too stiff.
He needs a tube.
Which will only cause
additional trauma.
It's bad, isn't it?
The collapsed lung means
that your lungs are so scarred
that they can't
hold together, so...
Yeah, buddy, it's bad.
Look, as soon as we get
your lung re-inflated,
I'm gonna sit down with you
and your mom and your dad,
and we're gonna talk about
what comes next, okay?
Chest tube, 16 French.
Lidocaine?
All right, buddy, you're
gonna feel a little pinch,
followed by
some pressure, okay?
There you go, buddy.
You're doing great, pal.
Mr. Thomas, I'm Dr. Halstead.
I heard you had
an incident at work today.
Yeah, I guess
I, uh, fell down.
The EMS report says
they found you unconscious.
How long you been
coughing up blood?
A few weeks.
Some wheezing and stridor.
What's his weight?
138.
Doc, I appreciate
your concern,
but I'd just as soon
go rest up at home.
Yeah, I don't blame ya,
but I fear if you go home,
you may have a far worse event
than whatever happened
this morning.
That's okay.
Well, you're too dehydrated
to walk out of here,
so why don't you let me
give you some fluids,
we'll run some tests,
and I promise
I'll be back soon?
All right.
Syncope, weight loss,
hemoptysis.
He's got cancer, right?
A lot of people
are more afraid
of getting the diagnosis
than the actual treatment.
Let's get a CBC
with diff, EKG,
chest X-ray, and CT.
And then we can try
and talk to him again.
So, um,
Robert Haywood is here
for a thoracic PET scan?
Uh, yeah, we're doing
a full cardiac workup.
You think you could add
a head study to that for me?
I just wanna make sure I'm not
missing anything on my end.
Sure, no problem.
Thank you.
Mmm-hmm.
Laura,
your membranes
ruptured prematurely,
allowing an infection
in your uterus.
The longer we go without
delivering this baby,
the greater the danger
you're both in.
So deliver it then.
We need to do it
at the hospital.
No, I told you,
I'm not going.
I understand that
you don't want to,
but this is a safety
issue, okay?
You need to think
about your baby.
I said no.
If there are complications,
if anything goes wrong...
It's okay, we'll do it here.
You're not seriously thinking
about inducing her
right here on the street?
Women deliver outside
the hospital all the time.
Yeah, and some of them die.
Listen, I don't like this
either, but you heard her.
She's gonna do this
with or without us.
And then what? A newborn
can't survive out here.
Nat, you don't have to
do this, but I'm staying.
I have good news.
They found a pair
of lungs in Kansas
that are a perfect match.
We're loading them
onto a plane now.
Oh, my God.
You hear that, Luke?
This is good news, buddy.
Uh, I am gonna have
a conversation
with Dr. Bekker,
and I'll be back in
just a few minutes, okay?
I'll start
the transplant protocol.
Hold on.
We have to put him on ECMO.
What?
He's satting in the 80s
and wearing down.
His respiratory muscles
are going to give out.
But ECMO could introduce
an infection.
It's a partial
contraindication to surgery.
And Kansas is
a two-hour flight.
We have to keep him oxygenated
till the lungs get here.
Those lungs only last
four hours.
If anything goes wrong
before they get here,
and he's stuck on ECMO,
we may not be able
to get him off.
He could die.
Then we make sure that
nothing goes wrong.
Thank you.
Mr. Thomas...
We found a large growth
in your larynx.
It's almost certainly cancer.
All right.
Now, the good news is,
we have an excellent
oncology department,
so I'd like to arrange for
a biopsy and a consultation,
so they can determine...
It's okay.
I'm not interested.
Mr. Thomas, the sooner
you begin treatment,
the better your chances
of survival.
You don't understand. I'm...
I'm ready to die.
I know it's a lot
of information,
and it can seem overwhelming,
but I...
I said no.
Can you tell me why you're
so resistant to treatment?
Because I've made it 56 years
without molesting a child,
and I can't stand it anymore.
I'm sorry?
I'm a pedophile...
And I wanna die.
Yeah?
Have you seen this yet?
A lawsuit?
An indigent man's claiming
an ambulance driver
passed him over to bring in
an insured patient instead.
Seems the extra wait time
cost this guy his leg.
Oh, that's terrible.
But isn't that the fault
of the ambulance company?
Apparently the ambulance
driver was following
our hospital's instructions.
Now that's ridiculous.
I never told anyone
to pass up uninsured patients.
No, but the claimant states
that an E.D. charge nurse
named Maggie Lockwood did.
Give me some time
to look into it.
Try to relax, all right?
Look at me.
Look at me, look at me.
Take a deep breath.
104. The antibiotics
aren't working.
We need a couple bags
of Flagyl.
Ethan...
I need more drugs?
Laura, what you need is to go
to the hospital, okay?
You're putting yourself and
your baby at unnecessary risk.
She can't. They'll put her
back into foster care.
I know it's not ideal,
but this isn't just about you.
Your baby's gonna need food
and a roof over its head.
Unless they keep 'em
out in the yard,
feed 'em whatever
the dogs don't want.
I'll talk to
the social worker,
make sure you find
a good home.
No one wants to adopt
a 16-year-old.
Even if you do get
a good home in foster care,
everyone keeps getting
passed along,
until you finally
end up some place
where they'd rather cash
a check from the state
than feed you.
Yeah, they're the ones
who keep you forever.
Nat, we really need
those antibiotics.
Okay, I'll be back
as soon as I can.
Yeah.
Okay, keep breathing,
keep breathing.
Okay? Keep breathing.
Just try to relax.
It's okay.
Dr. Rhodes?
What's wrong?
Luke's LFTs are rising.
What... What does that mean?
It indicates that he might be
in early liver failure.
Unfortunately,
if it progresses,
it could prevent him
from getting the lungs.
Prevent him?
Fortunately, we can still
get him off the ECMO,
while we try to
reverse this trend.
However, if we take him
off of ECMO now,
it decreases the odds
that he survives
until the lungs get here.
I don't understand.
Can't you agree on what to do?
It's not a black and white
situation.
Uh, you've been treating
him, Dr. Rhodes.
What should we do?
We should keep him
on the ECMO.
It's still our best chance
that he gets those lungs.
Okay.
Yes. That's what we'll do.
All right.
You're being completely
irresponsible.
That kid is going to die
if he doesn't get new lungs.
Only if your ECMO
doesn't kill him first.
He's a snowball
rolling down a hill,
and this is our last chance
to stop it.
So what are we doing
about Mr. Thomas?
Psych's in there right now.
As soon as they declare him
incompetent,
I'm gonna call Oncology
down here to get started.
Incompetent?
Who cares?
The man is a pedophile, okay?
If he wants to die,
why don't we just let him?
April, we're going
to stop him from dying,
because he's our patient
and because we can.
Did you put him
on a psych hold?
Uh, I'm not ready
to make that decision.
Why? He's suicidal.
He may want to die,
but he is lucid
and understands the
consequences of his choices.
He, he has
a treatable condition.
How lucid can he be if
he's not letting us treat it?
If he was depressed,
you'd put him on a psych hold
and try and treat
his depression.
You're not gonna do
the same for pedophilia?
I just don't know that much
about pedophilia.
Well, you better find out
fast, because he's dying.
"...Department charge nurse
Maggie Lockwood,
"especially providing
incentive."
I don't believe this.
All right, take it easy.
What do you know
about this patient?
I don't.
And I definitely never told
any ambulance driver
to make decisions based on
insurance coverage.
All right.
This driver, John Gates,
do you know him?
Yeah, he's a jerk.
Well, do me a favor,
page me when he comes in.
I wanna talk to him.
Sure.
If I don't kill him first.
I need a doctor in here.
Help him!
He's coagulopathic.
What does that mean?
The combination of
his poor liver function
and the anticoagulants
that we gave him
has disrupted
his ability to clot.
Hang a bag of heparin.
We thinned his blood
for the ECMO, we had to,
but his liver is failing
more quickly than we expected.
You did this,
so take him off that machine!
I am afraid that it is
too late for that.
Too late?
Heparin's running.
We're gonna try
and reverse the bleeding now.
Run the plasma now.
Hold on that.
Wait...
A transfusion is going to
increase his antibody count.
His PRA's already at 50.
If it hits 80,
we can't use those lungs.
You think I don't know that?
We don't have a choice.
We wouldn't be
in this situation
if you hadn't insisted on ECMO
in the first place.
You keep pointing out
problems.
What I need are solutions,
so if you don't have any,
just get out of my way, okay?
Hang the bags.
Dr. Halstead has a point.
Is this man, this pedophile,
really being rational?
Funny enough,
it sounds to me like he is.
So we just have to, uh,
stand by and watch him
kill himself?
Not treating your cancer
is not the same thing
as committing suicide.
I mean, it's his decision.
He's allowed to make it.
More to the point, I think
what he may be trying to do
is looking for a way to...
Escape his urges.
By dying.
Dr. Reese, have you ever seen
a pedophile's P.E.T. scan?
The prefrontal cortex
and the putamen,
they light up.
There's a very good chance
that pedophilia
could be genetically
hardwired into the brain.
There's nothing
he can do about it?
Well, yes and no.
I mean, the thinking is,
you can't change the hardware,
but the software
is another question,
and it sounds to me
like that's what Mr. Thomas
has been trying to do.
If you look at it
from his perspective,
the whole thing
seems quite rational.
Hey, what are you doing here
on your day off?
Don't ask.
Don't ask?
I'm not crazy about
what I'm doing,
and I will tell you
the whole thing later,
but right now, I just need
to get something and go.
I'll talk to you later.
Okay.
Hey!
Everyone out, please.
You stay.
John Gates,
this is Sharon Goodwin,
the Executive Director
of Patient Services.
You might stand up.
Did you speak
to anyone recently
regarding a lawsuit?
Yeah, lawyers asked me
some questions.
And what did you say?
I said you guys only wanted
patients with good insurance,
so I brought you
what you wanted.
And where exactly
did you get that idea?
Look around.
Excuse me?
The TV. The pizza?
Everyone knows
this room's just a ploy
to get us to bring in
paying customers.
Get out of here.
Sharon...
I never intended for him
to leave people on the street.
He's not the problem.
Dr. Bekker...
You disagree with Dr. Rhodes'
treatment, don't you?
It's a complicated situation.
Okay.
I know how hard it must be
watching him go through this.
It is.
And it has been for 12 years.
We tried everything,
modulator therapies,
clinical trials.
It's all we ever
thought about,
but nothing ever worked.
After a while, we just wanted
to let Luke be a kid,
while he still had the chance.
But now, I'm...
Maybe there was more
we could've done.
Did we just let
our little boy die?
There are no right answers
with cystic fibrosis.
It's relentless
and impervious to
whatever we throw at it.
But every decision
you made for your son,
you made out of love.
And I believe that whenever
you do something out of love,
it can never really be wrong.
Dr. Halstead!
Sats are down to 78.
Did you eat this morning?
He might be obstructed.
Laryngoscope on the gills.
Give him a sublingual nitro
and an amp of glucagon.
The food must've gotten
trapped by your tumor,
and it's starting
to block your airway.
I need to break it up.
Oh, please, don't.
What about his DNR?
I'm not tubing him,
I'm just clearing his airway.
Mr. Thomas, I am legally
obligated to do this.
It will only take a moment.
Forceps?
Almost there. Got it.
That's it, Mr. Thomas.
Take a few deep breaths...
Deep breaths.
God damn it.
Why won't you people
just let me die?
Well, I don't see any tumors
or signs of stroke.
Robert Haywood, is he one
of your prison patients?
Um, no. Why?
He's a criminal, right?
Not that I know of.
Decreased activity
in the lower frontal lobe,
significant reductions in
the orbital prefrontal cortex,
which is the regulator of
morality and aggression.
Oh, psychopath.
Well, in my opinion,
the best thing you can
do for this patient
is put a pillow
over his head.
How's he doing?
Not great.
His larynx is still
partially obstructed,
and now I need ENT to come
clear it out completely.
Are you putting him on a hold?
Dr. Charles believes
he is rational. We can't.
So that's that?
What, we just let him die?
Not necessarily.
Since he is rational,
maybe we can reason with him.
Fine, as soon
as he's cleaned up.
Why are you fighting
so hard for this guy?
Because it's not my job
to judge him.
I just got the call.
The lungs are ten minutes out.
His cardiac output is down,
urine, too.
He's in multi-organ failure.
BP's 90 over 50.
He's not going to be
stable enough for surgery.
This doesn't make any sense.
Cystic fibrosis is
a chronic disease.
This is all happening
too fast.
Only since you put him
on the ECMO.
These are symptoms
of under-perfusion.
It shouldn't happen on ECMO.
Unless the problem is
with the ECMO itself.
Let me see your readings.
The flow rate's too slow.
How long's it been at 2.6?
Couple hours.
Did you interrogate the line?
Yeah, it was clean.
You think it's
the oxygenator?
Let's find out.
His sats are gonna drop.
We gotta do this fast.
Turn the FiO2 up to 100.
Shut down ECMO.
What? You're turning it off?
I thought it was
keeping him alive.
Sats are down to 80.
We think there might be
a clot in the oxygenator.
It would impede
the blood flow enough
to cause his organs to fail.
75.
Set.
Got it.
It must've happened
when we hung the plasma.
ECMO back on.
Flow rate's at 4.
Sats are coming back up.
83...
85...
Is he gonna be okay?
He's getting oxygen
back to his organs.
The failure should be
reversible.
Oh, thank God.
Dr. Rhodes, Dr. Bekker,
the lungs are here.
All right, let's get him
upstairs. Come on.
You can still do
the transplant?
Yes.
Oh!
It's okay.
Come on!
All right, let's go.
You got this!
Good job, Laura. Good job.
You're doing great.
Nat, we've been
pushing for 30.
Come on.
Keep pushing, keep pushing.
I can't.
There you go.
You can do this,
you can do this, okay?
Push, push, push, push,
push, push, push, push...
Good job. There you go.
There you go.
All right,
keep pushing, Laura.
You're doing great.
Keep going.
Okay, I see the head.
Push, push, push, push...
Okay, here it comes.
Here it comes.
Is it out?
Nat...
What's wrong?
Shoulder dystocia.
The head is through
the birth canal,
but the shoulders are too big.
It's stuck.
Stuck?
What do you mean stuck?
Don't worry,
we're gonna get it out,
but we need to hurry.
Call an ambulance.
What? No, I'm not
calling an ambulance.
Call an ambulance.
What are you...
What are you doing?
No, no, what's going on?
You're okay.
What are you doing?
We're just gonna
pick your leg up.
You're gonna be fine.
What are those for?
An episiotomy.
I need to cut a wider hole
for the baby to come out.
I'm sorry,
but this is gonna hurt.
Can't you numb her?
Not with the head this close,
not out here.
I'll push harder.
I'll get it to come out!
Laura, we are past that
right now, okay?
I need you to just be strong
for your baby.
I can't. I can't...
Laura, I promise you
it will be worth it.
Now, are you ready? Yes?
Okay.
All right, you got it.
You got it.
You did it!
You did it. Great job, Laura.
It's a beautiful girl.
Hi.
Pulmonary artery is cut.
Left lung is free.
Yep.
Lungs are coming out.
Keep the heart elevated.
Okay.
All right.
Let's sew these new lungs in.
Dr. Bekker's gonna
take the lead.
Me?
Yes.
But he's your patient.
You are the better choice.
Why would you say that?
You've been fighting me
tooth and nail all day.
Your hands are smaller.
It'll be easier
for you to work
in the confined space.
I see.
And is that the only reason?
The size of my hands?
Also, you are
an excellent surgeon.
All right.
Stitch?
My apologies, Sharon.
This is my fault.
The pizza room was my idea.
No, Maggie, I was in
full support of it,
and never stopped
to think about what
we were encouraging.
How are you feeling?
Just let me go.
Mr. Thomas,
I can't begin to imagine
what your life is like.
But one thing I know is
that it can't get better
unless you let me help you.
Now, I've talked
to the oncologist...
Enough.
And we have a real chance
at getting you into remission.
Please, just take
a few minutes
to at least consider it.
Mr. Thomas,
can I ask you a question?
You have a job, right?
Coworkers, do you get along
with some of them?
Yeah. So?
How about interests?
Reading? Sports?
What's your point?
That you are not
just a pedophile.
There is more to you
than that.
And I understand
that you have been
challenged by your thoughts
your entire life,
but you have overcome them.
Maybe this cancer is
just another challenge,
something that you can
overcome as well,
so you can get back to
all of the parts of your life
that you do like.
Doctor, I have an itch...
Every second of every day.
To scratch it
would feel so good,
but I don't, ever.
Not scratching that itch
is the worst hell
that I can imagine,
and cancer is gonna
get me out of that hell.
It isn't another challenge...
Cancer is my reward.
So, Bob,
I know that we haven't
known each other
very long at all,
but from what I've observed
and our conversations,
it's my opinion
that you evident
some of the hallmark
characteristics
of something known as
Antisocial Personality
Disorder.
Huh. Interesting.
That could explain
a lot about my life.
I mean, divorces,
problems with colleagues.
Right, right.
Well, you should know
that it's very manageable.
I mean...
No, I've got things handled.
I'm okay.
Are you, though?
Because, very honestly,
from what I've seen,
that you aren't in fact
always the best judge
of your own self-interest.
What do you mean?
Well, you have
significant heart disease,
which, one way or the other,
is gonna require
serious long-term care.
Your plan is to have your
daughter provide that care,
a daughter whose father
has suddenly reappeared
in her life after 20 years.
I mean, she's gonna have
trust issues,
abandonment issues.
What I'm saying is
if you want this
to work out with Sarah,
it would be a really
good idea to discuss
this personality disorder.
And why would that help me?
Well, first of all, I think
she'd appreciate your candor.
She'd be comforted
by your honesty.
More importantly, it would
shed a huge amount of light
on her life,
on what transpired
between the two of you.
I think, ultimately,
she'd embrace your care,
she'd throw herself into it,
and that the time
you spend together
would just be much richer
for the both of you.
Or she could have
the opposite reaction.
Antisocial Personality
Disorder?
I mean, that's like saying
I'm a psychopath.
I mean, when people
hear that word,
they run in the opposite
direction.
Labels, semantics
can be toxic.
Whatever the case,
all I'm saying is that
I think it would be very much
in your best interest
to share this
with your daughter.
She's so happy.
All she does is smile.
Laura...
We need to take you
to the hospital.
You said I could stay here.
You could give birth
out here,
but it's not a safe place
to keep her.
It's too cold. She'll freeze.
But if we come in, we'll
have to go into foster care.
She's too good for that.
I won't let her.
Laura...
I'm sorry,
but we don't have a choice.
Take her without me.
What?
Babies with 16-year-old
mothers go into foster care.
But babies on their own...
Get adopted
into nice families.
Laura, this is your baby.
You'll never see her again.
I know.
You don't have to do this.
You're gonna
have a good life.
Hey, thought you'd wanna know
we're settling that case
out of court.
Yeah, I figured the hospital
wouldn't want the bad press.
We'll move on.
Hopefully, it's just
an isolated incident.
It should be.
It turns out the pizza room
was the source of the problem,
so I shut it down.
Wait, what?
I shut down the pizza room.
No. No, no, no, the board's
not gonna let you do that.
Why not? It was influencing
the decision-making
of ambulance crews.
And it's making this hospital
a lot of money.
The E.D. has shown
a 14% increase in revenue
since it opened.
Are you serious?
Sharon, the pizza room
stays open.
His obstruction must be
eroding into the mucosa.
Hang two units.
Vic, you're losing
too much blood.
I need to cauterize
the vessels.
No... You don't.
Hey, I'm sorry,
but I don't have a choice.
Yes... You do.
Hanging the blood.
Get me a cautery.
There's one in Trauma 3.
Okay.
It won't be long.
Time of death, 19:21.
Hey, hey.
How's it going, bud?
How's it feel?
Sore, but good.
Good.
Well, don't go anywhere, okay?
I'm gonna be back to check
on you in just a little bit.
I have to admit,
your way worked.
You got him
to the finish line.
I think we both know
that I couldn't have
done this without you.
Say, uh...
I canceled my plans.
Um, what do you say
we go get that drink?
No.
Last night was a mistake.
I was wrong about Laura.
I don't know if
I could've done
what she did.
Those kids surprise me, too.
I just hate the thought
of them out there,
having to take care
of themselves.
Yeah.
Oh, there's DCFS.
I got it.
Okay.
Hey, I am so sorry
about earlier.
Oh, that's okay.
It's just,
I had the most awful,
yet the most incredible day.
There is this girl
who lives at...
Hey, Nat, I'm not really
in the mood to talk right now.
Oh, okay.
Are you all right?
Yeah, it's just...
Don't ask.
Hey.
That patient...
I judged him.
I should've just
been his nurse.
Sometimes it's really
hard not to judge.
I've been there.
You mind if we, uh,
take a rain check
on dinner tonight?
Sure.
Hey, there.
Everything okay?
No.
No, I, uh, I just had
a long talk with my dad,
and it turns out he has
class III heart failure
from cardiomyopathy.
Oh, man.
Very sorry to hear that.
Yeah, you know, he said
he wasn't gonna tell me.
Said he was afraid.
Afraid?
That he just came back
into my life,
and now if he dies,
he doesn't know
what it might do to me.
Said he worries
he's giving me issues
with abandonment and trust.
Oh. Wow, he said that, huh?
Yeah, as sick as he is, he...
He didn't wanna tell me.
That is so... Selfless.
You were right.
Maybe I need to look at things
more from his perspective.
Dr. Reese, did your...
Did your father
tell you anything else?
No. Why?
I'm just curious, you know.
Nothing else?
No.
Ethan.
Hey.
Why are you here?
I just wanted to see
how you're doing.
Oh.
Maybe I should've called.
No, it's okay.
Your hair's longer.
Yeah.
Yours is...
Shorter.
Okay if I come in?
Yeah. Okay.