Excuse me.
Sorry.
Doug Ross. Leave a message.
Doug. Doug, it's Mark.
You there? Pick up.
Hello, hello.
You there?
Listen,
I left that sub-I paperwork
on the kitchen table,
and I need it.
Doug.
Shut up, man!
Oh, man!
Put this on your face.
He was here in the
emergency department.
They moved him up to Surgery.
You have one thing to do.
I've got 13 million.
Yeah, Dr. Weaver
wants those films now,
and she's not somebody
you want to mess with.
Hey, watch your mouth.
I hope you're not
Carol Hathaway.
Do I look like a nurse?
I'm very sorry, but...
if you could just wait
in the waiting room.
I don't have any information
about your son.
Hey, Wendy, can you come here
and help me with Mrs. Valdez?
They took her kid up to Surgery
about an hour ago.
Hey.
Hey, Jerry. What's going on?
Some serious gang-banging
in the wee hours.
Cops did a sweep
right under our carpet.
Trauma 1 or 2?
Take your pick.
Hey. That's your girl.
Miss Hathaway?
Yes?
Abraham Zimble,
the mobile notary.
Oh, yes, yes.
Thank you so much for coming.
Your escrow papers.
Oh, God, I have
to sign all of those?
By five o'clock,
or they won't give
you the house.
Okay, look, do you mind waiting?
$20 an hour, no problem.
Great. Okay.
BP's dropping
to 80/40,
pulse 150.
Cap refill is slowing down.
Resps 36, labored.
Need anything?
I don't suppose
you brought coffee.
Sorry.
Susan done with
that portable yet?
Doesn't look like it.
Call the O.R.
and let them do
the x-rays up there.
We've got this one. See
if Susan needs help...
Okay.
And tell her
to stop hogging that x-ray.
You're supposed to
stop hogging that x-ray.
She's all theirs.
They took him up to the O.R.
What's he got?
GSW to the face and abdomen.
Only it's a she, not a he.
Couldn't tell till we
cut open his shirt.
Abdomen's distended.
No bowel sounds.
I'll prep for a lavage.
You and Kerry the only ones on?
Carter and Benton
are in surgery.
Paged Ross, no answer,
and Mark's
on the train from Milwaukee.
Just us womenfolk.
What's up with that?
Oh, yeah.
Malik, see what's
keeping that O-neg,
would you?
Doug?
What are you doing here?
You didn't get my message?
What message?
I left the sub-I paperwork here
and Morgenstern
wants to review it today.
Look, why don't you
hurry up, get dressed,
and I'll ride in with you?
Why don't you just go? I
don't want to make you late.
No, no. I'm already late, so...
No, it's all right.
I'm gonna run some
errands and... It's okay.
Your beeper's going...
off.
Morning.
All right, look, it's
not what you think.
But it's what
I've seen, isn't it?
What the hell's that
supposed to mean?
I've overlooked a lot of
your behavior, Doug...
but now a medical student?
All right, Mark, look, wait...
There are rules, Doug.
You can't go breaking
them all the time
and expect me to do nothing...
Come on, Mark.
You don't get it, do you, Doug?
You could be out
on your butt for this,
and I could be too,
for not reporting you.
Mark, wait...
Okay, that's fine.
Whoa!
Hey, yo! Chill out!
I told you,
you're going to have to wait.
Don't make me say it again.
Have you seen Dr. Greene?
He's busy...
forever.
My name's Jeanie Boulet.
We haven't met.
I'm a new physician assistant.
I start my ER rotation today.
Oh, God, who died
and gave you their bad luck?
Well, you'll need one of these.
They're a lousy fit,
but it's all we've got.
Hey, next time,
you stay, I'll go to X-ray.
Sorry.
Hey, Jeanie.
You starting this morning?
Yeah.
Jerry, I need
those Benieto films
before the end
of the millennium.
They just came in.
This is Jeanie Boulet, a
new physician assistant.
Kerry Weaver, Chief Resident.
First day?
Yeah.
I think you'll find
it's a vaguely friendly crowd.
My first day was certainly
a bundle of open arms.
What do you think?
Uh, looks like a
comminuted fracture
of the distal femur
and a mid-shaft humerus...
Excuse me.
50% apposition
and 30 degrees of angulation.
You know your
way around an x-ray.
Good start.
I am a physical therapist.
I was a physical therapist.
All right, on my count.
One, two, three.
What have we got, Peter?
Peter?
Gunshot wound to
the posterior neck,
multiple facial abrasions,
scalp laceration.
BP's 90/60.
Pulse 92, resps 24.
Cap refill's poor.
All right, let's tube him.
I'll do it.
ET Tray's on the counter. 7.0.
This is Jeanie Boulet, Peter.
Physician assistant.
It's her first day,
and I know we all want
to make her feel welcome.
No guarding or
rebound tenderness.
Normal bowel sounds.
Let's find radiology.
What do we need for x-rays?
Cross-table and... Jeanie?
Cross-table C-spine,
chest and pelvis.
Get a gram of Ancef.
Good choice, Peter.
Everyone is so
on their toes today.
Film's back on Trujillo.
He's next door.
Except for Wendy.
Chest, stomach, back.
X-rays are in on Trujillo.
He's already gone up to the O.R.
This is Rico Figueroa.
If you could track
down his films,
we'd appreciate it.
Is he gonna live?
Yes.
Trying a little
rehabilitation there,
Chuny? Mark?
I gotta talk to you.
This is not the time or place.
Let's set up for a chest tube.
32 French.
Could you ask him to
squeeze my fingers?
Mark...
I said no, Doug. Get
the hell out of here.
Okay, Carter,
sixth intercostal space
at mid-axillary line,
then puncture the pleura.
We got a cop hurt,
pulling up to the
back door. How bad?
His hand.
Carol, why don't
you check it out?
Her son's up in the O.R.
She's been
hysterical all morning.
Okay, well, why
don't you put her
in the surgery waiting room?
And leave Randi
alone? She'll kill me.
Jerry!
Okay, okay.
Mrs. Valdez, Mrs. Valdez.
Is it calming down a bit?
Sort of.
Have you seen Mr. Zimble?
Who?
Mr. Zimble. Bald
guy, a lot of papers.
Oh, yeah, right.
He's in the cafeteria.
Have you seen Jerry?
He's upstairs.
I'm gonna kill him.
Whatever, but help
me with this first.
Grabarsky, what happened?
Dumb son of a bitch bit me.
Yeah, your stupid
dog bit me first.
That's what she's
supposed to do, idiot!
Now, where do you want him?
Nowhere near me.
You can piss off, culera.
What did you call me? Huh?
What did you call me?
Here, tough girl, hold the dog.
You. Now, lie down and shut up.
Grabarsky, I need
to look at your hand.
Hey! Hold on to Peggy for me.
I'd love to.
Page Bernstein for me, please.
Gee, I'd love to.
Al? Al, are you all right?
Yeah. Some moron bit me.
I'll take him.
Okay.
Okay, look out,
look out, look out.
Carter, you want to take him up?
Uh... I should probably
check in with Benton.
I'll do it.
Dr. Greene...
I need to talk to you.
Uh-huh. Uh, lounge
in 20 minutes?
So what's it look
like out there?
I think the worst is over.
Oh, never say the worst is over.
Oh, my God.
Mr. Zimble?
I went to get a doughnut
and the cashier was
picking him up off the floor.
Take him to Curtain
Area 3. I'll get Rico.
Mr. Zimble?
Passed out
right into his cream of wheat.
Who's Mr. Zimble?
My mobile notary.
What?
My escrow closes today.
I have to sign the papers by 5.
You bought a house?
Well, you know,
I got a great deal.
Mr. Zimble? Mr. Zimble?
I could never buy a house.
It's too scary.
It's not that bad.
You get over it.
Mr. Zimble?
I didn't know you'd
ever bought a house.
Oh, I haven't...
Oh, come on, Mark, shut
up and help save this guy.
Yes, thank you,
Carol. I think I will.
Mr. Zimble? There you go.
Come on. Hi.
Thank you.
Can I help with
anything in here?
We've managed so far.
Hey, Jeanie. How are you?
Fine, thanks.
Pulse ox falling. 82 on 50%.
Hang those two units.
I didn't realize you
were starting today.
Yeah, I finished.
BP?
91/50, pulse 112.
Must be great to be done
with all the classwork, huh?
Definitely.
You think you're
gonna miss rehab?
Carter! What the hell
are you yapping for?
I thought you wanted to help.
All right, then assess
the patient, all right?
Uh, penetrating trauma
to zone two of the neck,
can result
in tracheal compression...
secondary to hematoma formation
from subclavian or
internal carotid injury,
which is probably why
you're doing a bronchoscopy.
Anything else I can help with?
Yes, Mr. Carter.
We have used the
last blood gas kit.
It would be extremely helpful
if you would go and
make some more.
You mean...
actually go and make them up?
Syringe, label...
alcohol wipes,
little plastic bags.
Right.
Sorry. Sort of. Good morning.
Hi. What a day, huh?
Yeah.
Benton is in the foulest
mood I've ever seen,
which is saying quite a lot,
and Greene just yelled at Ross
right in the middle of a trauma
in front of everybody.
About what?
No clue.
Hey, you off tonight?
Yeah.
I've got two tickets
to Blues Traveler.
Good idea?
No, actually.
It would be great.
No, it won't.
I mean, I don't think...
I need to talk to you...
privately.
What?
Later.
Wait.
Wait, wait, wait. What?
Harper, wait a
minute. What is it?
Nothing.
No, it's something.
Yeah? So tell me.
Come on. What's going on?
Just tell me.
Harper, just...
I slept with Doug Ross...
last night.
Carter, let's go!
Hey.
Hey, yo, senoritas,
could I get a little medical
attention here please?
Hello? Hello?
What is his problem?
Peggy had a little snack.
You gonna let me go?
Hey, yo, senoritas.
Give him to Benton.
He just went up to Surgery.
You know, this is
brutality and neglect.
I think he's young
enough for a pediatrician,
don't you?
Ross is doing a
consult with Bernstein.
Jeanie?
It's about time.
Thank you so much.
I hate to bleed to death
all over your pretty floor.
Going to add another scar
to your collection there, Jorge.
I have to clean these
bites with peroxide.
It's going to hurt.
Ah! Stop it!
Come on, you're a big boy.
Ah!
Oh, my ear.
Nice work.
Thanks.
Just don't tell
my parole officer.
So, Joseph,
what kind of
bicycle do you have?
A mountain bike,
except now it's trashed.
He's not getting another
one, that's for sure.
Just flipped out
from under you, huh?
I hit a curb.
He was unconscious
for four or five minutes.
Yeah, Dr. Ross told me.
Touch my finger.
Now touch your nose.
Again.
Good.
Well, he seems in
pretty good shape,
Mrs. O'Connor.
I don't think you have
anything to worry about.
Dr. Ross?
I'll be right back.
The kid's fine.
No need to be admitted.
Five minutes ago, he
was still disoriented.
Well, he's alert
and oriented now.
Head CT's negative. He
could go squirrelly again.
He should have frequent
neuro checks for 24 hours.
His mother can wake him up.
Family situation
is questionable,
and Mr. O'Connor
just left them
his wife and child.
She's extremely distraught.
I don't know that
she would do it.
There is no medical
reason for this kid
to spend a full day in the ICU.
Send him home. End of consult.
Where's Randi?
She's on a break.
I bet it was assault
with a deadly weapon.
She's obviously good at it.
I bet she's good at murder too.
Murder?
They would never
have let her out,
would they?
My money is on grand theft auto.
Hmm?
Assault.
Theft.
Kidnapping.
Have you seen Dr. Benton?
Uh, he's with a patient in 2.
Oh, and Jerry,
with all the commotion today
you probably missed lunch.
You should just order
in a burger and fries
or something.
Eat here at the desk.
Jerry, 12-year-old
Joseph O'Connor
in, uh, uh... Curtain Area 2.
I want you to admit
him to Pedes ICU,
24-hour observation, please.
Sure.
The chest x-ray suggests
that you may have
an aortic aneurysm.
We need to do an arteriogram
to rule it out.
But I don't feel pain
in my chest anymore.
Well, that's because
you're medicated
but that could be deceiving.
How are you feeling, Mr. Lake?
Much better.
BP's 150/90. Heart rate's 96.
That's very good.
We'll keep you
on the Nipride drip
while we study your aortic arch.
What about the surgery
he's talking about?
This Dr. Vu...
Vucelich.
Do you know him?
No.
Dr. Lewis isn't on
the surgical team.
Dr. Vucelich
is an excellent
cardiovascular surgeon,
one of the best in the country.
He's doing very advanced work
on aortic aneurysms.
So he's the best one to help me?
Well, we're not even sure
that you're going
to need his help,
Mr. Lake.
Which is why I
called Dr. Vucelich.
For a second opinion.
Well, you'll be going to X-ray
in a few minutes
so it's premature
to discuss your condition
before we've seen
the films, okay?
Dr. Benton,
could I speak to
you for a minute?
Why are you stepping
in on my patient?
He's a medical case.
Could be surgical.
Ah, the chance to
cut is a chance to cure,
right?
We'll look at the arteriogram
and let Cardiology decide.
And Vucelich.
He's agreed to consult.
What are you doing?
Trying to use my patient
to get in on his research study?
He's doing clamp
and run surgeries
on aortic aneurysms.
Ah, so the big cheese
has you jumping through hoops
to find one, right?
I've never even met him.
Peter, Susan, is
there a problem?
No.
Good, then Peter,
if you don't mind,
I think I'm gonna
need a few stitches.
I'm on my way to Radiology.
I'll meet you in
the Suture Room.
Any time. It's just my ear.
How you doing?
I'm fine.
When you get a chance, uh...
I'm usually kind of
glad to avoid the, uh...
morning-after stuff.
Uh...
I'm sorry.
You don't need to apologize.
I was there too.
I know. If Mark hadn't,
you know, come in...
We would have already
had this kind of awkward,
kind of "Yikes,
what did we do?" conversation.
So, um...
I'll see you around, okay?
Okay.
Yeah. I'll see you around.
Maybe this job is too stressful.
Being a notary?
If it's causing
this heart attack.
You might have just fainted.
I don't know. This
business can be rough.
98% of my clients are
home buyers, like you.
So many papers to sign.
They never stop to read them.
I tell them to, but they don't.
It's so hard to watch.
They get nervous,
frightened, tense
thinking about the
mortgage every month
and the down payment
which just wiped out
their entire life savings.
Little beads of sweat break out,
their cheeks get flushed,
their fingers clammy.
My God, they know that at any
minute they could lose their job
or get disabled in some
horrifying industrial accident
and then within five years, bam.
There's that balloon payment,
and suddenly husbands and wives
are screaming at each other,
women are crying,
grown men throwing up.
Very stressful.
Could I have a glass of water?
You had Radiology
rush these up to
Dr. Vucelich, right?
Yeah.
Type III dissection
by the DeBakey classification.
Yeah, but, gosh,
that's only four
centimeters, right?
No signs of
pericardial tamponade.
The aortic valve is normal.
When you examined Mr. Lake,
did you appreciate
the murmur of
aortic insufficiency?
No.
Neither did I.
Looks like he doesn't
need surgery after all.
Oh, well. I'm sure Vucelich
won't mind coming
down anyway, will he?
I heard he's a pretty
easy-going guy.
It's still a good
time to meet him.
Don't forget your charts.
Dr. Vucelich, please.
Dr. Benton.
Hey. You want to talk?
I don't know, are you sure
this is the right
time and place?
Okay, fine. Forget it.
Mark, look, you
don't have to worry
about what you saw this morning.
You know what? I'm worried
about what I see every morning.
You fight with Kerry Weaver
over half your cases,
call in docs for
curbside consults,
fast-track patients.
What the hell are you doing?
The job. That's what I'm doing.
That's not what
Bernstein thinks.
Well, Bernstein
doesn't know squat
about working in the ER.
He knows about your cases.
Because you're telling him.
Oh, no. He reads the charts.
See, he's the
head of Pediatrics.
I didn't seduce her, Mark.
It doesn't matter
how it happened.
Harper's third year.
There are rules.
Stupid rule.
You know that. What
difference does it make?
You get caught breaking
them, you're out of here.
I get caught not reporting
them, I'm out of here.
Fine. You know what?
Report me. I don't care.
You don't care about anyone,
do you?
I didn't do this alone, Mark.
She's 21 years old.
What about Carter?
You care about him?
He and Harper are going out,
or didn't you know?
It's got nothing
to do with Carter.
No, it's all about
you, isn't it?
It's always all about you.
Thanks for dropping by, Peter.
I was going to go ahead
and have Jeanie do it,
but seeing as you're here,
why don't you just
talk her through it?
Do a local block of the auricle
by depositing a line
of one percent xylocain
in the sulcus behind the auricle
from the inferior
to the superior pole,
knocking out the
greater auricular
and lesser occipital nerve,
irrigate with normal saline,
close with interrupted
6-0 nylon suture,
dress with antibiotic ointment,
wound check, two days,
suture removal, four days
update the tetanus.
He's nothing if not thorough.
Gotta drop these
off at Radiology.
Okay. Great. Thanks.
Breaking and entering.
Give her more credit than that.
I think she took a hammer,
bashed in the windshield
of her boyfriend's car,
found a knife,
and carved him up.
Do we have to be that specific?
Hey, Carol, you
want to make a guess
as to why Randi was in jail?
Jerry, do you really think
you should be mocking
what must have been
a demoralizing, dehumanizing,
debilitating experience?
Excuse me.
Can someone direct
me to a Dr. Benton?
Yeah. Who are you?
I'm Carl Vucelich,
and I was supposed to consult
on a patient of his,
Harmon Lake.
Dr. Vucelich, I'm Susan Lewis,
and Harmon Lake
is actually my patient.
Excellent, Dr. Lewis.
Well, then, perhaps
you'll let me show you
what's on this film.
So...
well, you can see right here
that the aneurysm is
clearly four centimeters.
Which is borderline.
It should be treated medically.
Dr. Vucelich?
You're Benton?
Yes. I don't think we
had a chance to meet.
Why the hell did you
cancel my consult
on Harmon Lake?
Well, Dr. Lewis and I
took a look at the arteriogram.
And it showed the aneurysm
to be at four centimeters...
Yes?
Which is within the limits
when you manage medically.
I didn't want to
waste your time.
Third year resident?
Yes.
I think you'd better
push those limits
if you want to remain
invested in surgery.
Dr. Vucelich,
I'm still responsible
for Mr. Lake,
and I feel he should
be admitted to ICU
and started on oral
antihypertensives.
I talked to Mr. Lake,
and he agreed that surgery
was the better option,
which relieves you
of your responsibility.
Benton,
you're coming up.
It's time you learned something.
Should I come?
John Carter.
Fourth year Surgical sub-I.
He's my student.
Sure. Why not?
I like a crowd.
Well, here a croup,
there a croup.
Ross? You got it.
Let's get her started Ross!
On a vaponephrine nebulizer.
What the hell do
you think you're doing
admitting Joseph O'Connor
when I asked you not to?
I feel he needed observation.
I don't care what you feel.
He's not at risk
for intracranial hemorrhage.
Well, we'll know for sure
in 24 hours, won't we?
I sent them home.
You don't have
the right to do that!
I have every right! I am
the Chief of Pediatrics.
This is my patient,
and I will take responsibility
for him, Bernstein.
No, you won't,
and I will no longer
take responsibility for you.
You harass my clinic,
you harass my residents,
you deliberately defy my orders.
Now, your pediatric fellowship
is up as of December 31st.
Well, let this serve as notice
you will not be renewed.
You're out of here.
How long since we clamped him?
59 minutes.
I better hurry up here, boys.
Under an hour
and I've got a new record.
Now, Dr. Benton,
do you know why
we're in a hurry?
Prolonged lack of blood
supply to the spinal cord
can lead to paraplegia.
Is that where the
Lazerol comes in?
Mr. Carter,
you've been reading
my research study, huh?
On the 21-aminosteroids, yes.
Then you can tell Dr. Benton
all about it.
I, uh...
I'm sure Dr. Benton
already knows all about it.
Well, we could
always hear it again.
Repetition. Big
part of learning.
Release the distal Statinsky
and backfill the graft.
Mr. Carter?
Uh, Lazerol helps prevent
transverse myelopathy
from lack of oxygen
to the spinal cord,
as well as preventing edema
of the neuro tissue post-op.
Assuming the drug is effective.
Hopefully, that's
what my study will do,
isn't it?
We have perfusion.
Time?
Uh, 60 minutes, 28 seconds.
Damn.
How do you think
they come up with
these drug names?
Some guy walking
around New Jersey
going, "Prolixin,
Zoloft, Lazerol."
Come on. I came
up with that last one.
And a darn fine one it is, Carl.
Thank you.
Well, well, well.
Okay,
these two go up to Cardiology
and this one to Ortho.
No problem. Thank you.
Miss Hathaway?
Mr. Zimble.
How are you?
Miss Hathaway,
you should not
put this off forever.
I might have to leave.
I haven't been putting it off.
We've been pretty busy.
Perhaps you don't
really want this house.
Of course I want this house.
Oh, dear. You need some help?
Too late.
Here, let me get that.
Stay put, Junior.
I'll be right back.
Oh, God.
Me too.
I'll be right back.
I bet you're missing
rehab just about now.
Been missing it since
the first minute I got here.
There's extra
scrubs in the lounge.
It's okay.
I still got some stuff
in my locker upstairs.
Hey, Doug, you okay?
Yeah, I'm fine.
You want to talk?
Well, I'd love to,
but I got sniffles
and a cough in 7
and I got bed-wetting in 6.
You got a second?
Sorry. I'm on a break.
Can we at least talk about this?
Uh... yeah, okay, sure,
if you, uh... if you need to.
I'm sorry, John.
It was an exceptionally bad day,
and it just happened,
but it's not something
that's gonna happen again.
You don't owe me an explanation.
We've only been out a few
times. Never even kissed.
Once.
You know, you didn't
even have to tell me.
It's not that big of a deal.
John...
John, wait.
Do you remember
that little boy with
AIDS yesterday?
He was so small and helpless,
but I held him down,
listening to him cry,
squeezing out every
last ounce of life
he might have had.
It was the worst day of my life.
I didn't know where
to go with that.
Where I ended up...
Where I needed to be...
was with somebody who'd
been through that with me.
I hope you can understand that.
Picked her up at
the Delaney Mall.
Witnessed grand mal seizure
lasting about two minutes.
Any ID?
No, and couldn't
find anyone with her.
Normal saline IV TKO,
two of Narcan,
and an amp of glucose on board.
Move her on a count.
One, two, three.
Vitals are stable, BP 100/70,
pulse 110,
resps 18.
On our arrival she
was comatose, GCS 5.
I'm out of here. Carpe diem.
See you, Doris.
Let's get a CBC and Chem-7.
She has gingival hypertrophy.
Dilantin level?
Yeah. She's probably epileptic.
Babinski's downgoing.
Pupils equal, round, reactive,
corneal reflex normal.
DTR's one plus
equal bilaterally.
Small occipital contusion.
You want a CT?
No. Let's see how she responds.
Cross-table C-spine.
We should check with the police,
see if they've come up
with any identification.
I'll call
Child and Family
Services too, just in case.
Lydia, why don't you
clear out Curtain Area 2?
Put her in there.
Busy day.
Yeah, hi.
Peter. Peter!
I want you to know
that I didn't try to
come to County.
I applied to practically
every other hospital
in the county.
This is the only ER rotation
that was open.
Okay. Fine.
Peter, stop.
Are you going to be like this
the whole time I'm here?
Can we at least pretend
to be civil, professional?
Okay. Fine.
I've got some post-op
notes to check on.
You're cutting him
off, just like that?
It's hardly "just like that."
Neal's right, Mark.
We've been dealing
with this Ross situation
since last summer.
He's a little bit more
than a "situation."
Of course he... Not to me.
Neal...
Ross runs roughshod
all over that ER.
He takes over the
care of an outpatient,
never even shows
up to the Pedes Clinic
where I can at
least supervise him.
He's assigned to the ER, Neal.
Where, obviously, no
one is supervising him.
That's not true.
Pediatrics is not
going to pay for him
so much as one
day into the new year.
You guys deal with his behavior.
He's off my service.
He's a good doctor.
But he's a loose cannon.
I'm not sure I could handle
him any better than Neal.
He's a good doctor.
Look, I know this
is personal for you.
I know you two are friends.
I'll supervise him.
His fellowship runs
through December.
Gives him over a
month to find another job.
We need him in the ER.
We need a lot of
things in the ER, Mark,
but be realistic.
Have you looked at your budget?
I'm due in surgery.
Got M and M in 10 minutes.
This won't take that long.
Um...
what you saw this morning
was private.
No one should have seen it.
Believe me, I wish I hadn't.
But you did,
and I'm concerned
with what that means.
I know this is the '90s
and there are rules
in medicine now.
They exist to protect
a medical student
from feeling they have to comply
with the suggestions
of one of their supervisors.
This wasn't a suggestion.
It was a choice, as
much mine as his,
but I don't want
my career defined
by having gone to
bed with someone,
especially since
no one will care
about the reason.
You don't care about
the reason, do you?
No, I don't,
but my job demands
that I care about
the ramifications.
If this were to get out,
it would more than
likely be misinterpreted,
affect my recommendations,
possibly even my internship,
so I have no intention
of discussing this,
either now or in the future,
and I hope no one
else will, either.
Jerry, will you
scream at Radiology?
I've got to get
those films on...
Robert Potter Bradley,
10 years old, broken finger.
Thank you, Jerry.
There, there. You're okay.
Honey, just settle
back down. You're okay.
We're right here with you.
What happened?
She woke up
agitated, disoriented,
trying to boot the
side rails and...
doesn't seem to
like the IVs too much.
Can't say as I blame her.
Can't say as I do, either.
Who'd have thought we'd
ever agree on something?
Her labs just came back.
That's right, you're okay.
Just settle down.
We're gonna take care of you.
We're gonna take
care of you, honey.
We're gonna take care of you.
You're all right. Shh.
CBC and lytes are normal,
but her Dilantin
level's only five.
Sub-therapeutic.
An epileptic seizure
caused by her not
taking her medication.
All right, Chuny,
let's give her Dilantin,
seven mgs per kilogram
at 50 mgs a minute IV.
Coming up. Okay.
That's it. That's it.
You're okay.
You could have
gone into Pediatrics.
Thank you.
I don't want a nurse.
I'm not a nurse.
I want a doctor.
I work with doctors.
Now, move along.
You're a nurse?
I'm a physician's assistant.
Is that better than a nurse?
It's just different.
I don't want a nurse.
Mr. Stubey, I need
to examine you
and take your history.
Now, let's march. Come on.
Onward, Christian soldiers
Is everything okay?
Is he a doctor?
No, he's a nurse.
Thanks, Malik. I got him.
Onward, Christian soldiers
Marching as to war
With the cross of Jesus
Going on before
Onward, Christian soldiers
Marching as to war
This is Mr. Preston.
Gunshot wound to
the right shoulder.
Good distal pulses
and sensation in the arm.
BP 100/60, pulse 120,
resps 24.
And the wheelchair?
Frank Davelle, nasty scalp lac.
I thought this was a double MVA.
Malik, take Mr. Davelle
down to the Suture Room.
I think he can wait.
Harper, get in here.
Oh, damn...
All right, on three.
Here we go, people.
One, two, three.
How you doing
there, Mr. Preston?
Hell, he shot me.
I can't believe that
son of a bitch shot me.
Dr. Benton, shouldn't we order
a CBC, type and cross
four units packed cells?
Yes, Carter.
Cross-table C-spine,
chest, shoulder x-rays?
Yes, again.
Does it hurt anywhere else?
My neck.
I'm gonna sue his ass.
That's very American of you.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. What's that?
Your armpit.
Fresh dressing.
Thanks, Harper.
Can you feel this?
Yeah.
Squeeze my hand.
Carter, why don't you and Harper
go take care
of the bad guy next door?
I can handle that on my own.
Whatever.
Excuse me.
Harper, I need your help.
Will you help me log-roll him?
Doug?
Hey, Carol. What's going on?
Nice try,
but the film's upside-down.
Are you okay?
Well, generally, this
has not been a good day.
Specifically, this has
not been a good day.
Although I'll tell you,
it felt so good
yelling at Bernstein,
for about five minutes there
I felt completely liberated.
And now?
And now,
I've been here a few years.
It's the longest
commitment I've ever made
to anything or anybody.
Um...
so...
it's time to move on.
Carol, Shep's on the phone.
Speaking of moving on...
You call me if you
want to talk, okay?
Okay.
The pool is your
idea. You ask her.
She'd kill me.
I think Wendy should ask her.
Yeah. Now, she'd
never kill Wendy.
What?
What is wrong with all of you?
Can't put your mouth
where your money is, huh?
Hey, Randi,
what did you do time for?
Malicious mischief,
assault,
battery,
carrying a concealed weapon
and aggravated mayhem.
What?
No, Shep, I'm telling you.
No.
Carol, some guy
just crashed in 3.
Oh...
Defib. Set up for intubation.
Oh, my God!
I was examining Mrs. Kerns
when this guy went south.
Oh, I can't believe it.
It's my mobile notary.
Your what?
Notary.
She's buying a house.
He could see I
was putting it off.
Told me I shouldn't
wait forever.
Oh, don't beat yourself up.
I'm a big procrastinator myself.
God, maybe he knew
he was going to die.
He's not going to die. Give
him another amp of epi.
God, we were so
close. Two pages left.
I need a 10 cc syringe.
Get the paddles ready. 200.
Carol?
Carol!
These two.
Charging. 200.
I can't believe I just did that.
Neither can I. Clear.
It's a good thing I did.
Carter...
Carter, I've got to talk to you.
Now, look, I didn't know
about you and Harper, all right?
I'm sorry.
Hey, hey, hey.
Nobody meant...
nobody meant to
hurt you, Carter.
Nobody...
It happened
because she was hurt.
It was a mistake, Carter.
It was a mistake.
You understand that?
And if you were smart,
you little piece of...
if you were smart
you'll give her another chance
and you'll listen to her.
I have,
and now I'm having
to listen to you?
I'm really happy that you both
have made your peace with this
but I'm gonna need
a little more time,
if that's okay with everybody.
How's she doing?
Pretty well.
She's coming around.
Are you deaf?
Yeah.
Chuny, let's get these
restraints off now,
and call
for a sign language interpreter.
Do you know how to sign?
Poorly.
You're going to be okay.
Yes.
You had a seizure,
but you're fine...
fine now.
I want to call your family.
What's your name?
Hi, Janie.
I'm...
Kerry.
Okay.
If they're so itchy,
why don't you just shave?
What, are you kidding?
The fire department
finally let us grow this stuff.
I can't give in yet.
Okay,
we're almost
there, so don't look.
Well, I thought
the point of this
was for me to see this thing.
Okay, but don't
look. Don't look.
Step up. I can't look.
What? Step up.
All right, we're almost there.
Okay.
Okay, now look.
Isn't it incredible?
Yes, it is.
I mean, I know it needs work.
Yes, it does.
I thought I'd paint it.
Maybe gray with a green trim,
or yellow.
And I know there's no stairs,
because they're in the backyard,
but I figure I can just
nail those back on,
and also I can nail back on
the shutters.
You should see the
inside of this house.
Whoa. Oops. Sorry.
The bedroom is
the biggest bedroom
I have ever had
in my whole life,
which isn't saying
a lot, but still.
What?
You look very beautiful
when you're happy.
I am. I'm happy.
I'm happy.
Come on, let's go. Wait.
What? Listen, I don't
want you to worry
that I'm rushing
into anything here,
but this is your first house,
and I think that someone
should carry you
over the threshold.
Okay, no.
No, I knew that you would agree.
No, you know what? Shep! Shep!
Put me down! You're
gonna drop me.
What are you talking about?
I'm a fireman.
Oh, come on.
Shep, put me down.
They must have
changed the schedule.
I missed mine by five minutes.
So you didn't say anything
to Morgenstern?
No, I didn't.
Why are you doing this, Doug?
You're a good doctor.
Bernstein doesn't agree.
I looked at that kid's chart.
Joseph O'Connor.
No signs
of intracranial bleeding.
You knew
he didn't need to get admitted.
You were pushing Bernstein
the same way you've
been pushing me.
Why are you doing this, Doug?
I don't know.
You'll miss your train.