Do you feel the Spirit?
And in the 39th year of his
reign, Asa was diseased in his feet
until the disease was
exceedingly great,
yet he didn't seek
help from the Lord,
but from the physicians.
Now, there is nothing
wrong with seeing a doctor.
But can a doctor heal through the
power that Jesus gave his disciples?
Men of science can walk
through life with blindfolds,
never knowing that you or I
could not take a single step
if we were not uplifted by God.
Agnes,
thank you for letting me be an
instrument of God's love for you.
In faith,
all things are possible.
My friends, I want
you to let Agnes
feel the wave of faith in this church
here today, lifting her into God's hands.
Praise God!
You can do it. Come on, sister.
Praise Jesus!
Thanks be to God!
Thank you, Lord!
Is he all right? No!
My son!
Daddy, I think I need a doctor.
Didn't remember my DVD player?
Well, if you wanted it,
you shouldn't have left it
behind when you moved out.
I get it. It's a drag
watching porn on VHS.
I'll call you as soon
as I'm done with it.
That's if you ever
get a phone installed.
Oh, forget it. I'll come by and
get it myself. After work, Thursday?
Won't be home Thursday.
No problem. I still have a
key, I can let myself in and out.
I guess maybe I could
bring it in tomorrow.
After all, how many times can you hit
"pause" at the part where Lindsay Lohan
wins the spelling bee. What
is it about girls who can spell?
It's a math contest. What is
it about girls who can count?
It's poker night, isn't it?
You said weeks
ago that I could play.
Stop making excuses. Gotta go!
Building full of sick people. If I
hurry, maybe I can avoid them.
The abdominal series showed
no evidence of obstruction.
What did you have to eat?
Chicken sandwich. We
travel, lots of fast food.
Thank you, I barely felt it.
You're welcome.
God told me you were kind.
You talk to God?
God's presence often descends
on Boyd to help him guide others.
This been going on
long? Since he was 10.
God told me I would
meet a woman healer
who was harboring vengeful
thoughts about a man she works with.
That's God's job.
I'll keep that in mind.
His urine is dilute.
What does that mean?
Could mean that for some
reason his kidneys aren't purifying
the way they should, which would
let toxins accumulate in his body.
We'll run the blood work
and see what it tells us.
Thank you, I appreciate it.
God talks to him?
It's not psychosis.
He's just religious.
The only medical issue that showed
up on the blood work is low sodium.
No. You talk to
God, you're religious.
God talks to you,
you're psychotic.
A lot of people experience their
religion as something more than symbolic.
That doesn't mean...
God ever talk to you
when you were in the seminary?
No. God's loss, our gain.
He's either psychotic
or a scam artist.
He was actually
really impressive.
Well, yeah, with the burning
bush and all, it's quite the show.
He was intelligent, polite, dignified.
He's not a typical 15-year-old.
And he told Cameron God wants her to
stop being pissed at me over the article.
God knows you stole
Cameron's article?
He knows she's harboring
vengeful thoughts.
I'm over it.
Yeah, I could tell that from the Berlin
Wall of body language between you.
I'm shocked that he picked up on
it. Low sodium. Check for Addison's?
No pigmentation and
potassium levels were normal.
Cirrhosis? Liver feels fine,
transaminases are normal.
We should monitor his saline
intake to correct the low sodium.
No more than 1 meq
per liter, per hour.
Let's push the patient history,
see if there's any evidence of drugs
or other delusions. I'll take care of it.
You're gonna talk to a patient?
God talks to him.
It'd be arrogant of me to
assume that I'm better than God.
So, you're a faith healer?
Or is that a pejorative?
Do you prefer something like
"divine health management"?
Thought God might have
mentioned that I was coming.
I'm okay with faith
healer, Dr. House.
That's a nice one.
You didn't even go with,
"I see an H in a medical coat."
The nurses talk about you a
lot. Yeah, don't believe them.
I keep a sock in my pants.
Faith. That's another
word for ignorance, isn't it?
I never understood how people could
be so proud of believing in something
with no proof at all. Like
that's an achievement.
God's asking for our trust. You can't
love somebody and not trust them.
Trust has to be earned.
You can't trust someone
hiding in a closet.
You don't trust anyone.
You seem lucid. There's
no confusion, no lethargy.
What drugs have you been taking?
Nothing, some aspirin.
I get focused on
something, I forget to eat,
next thing you know, I've
got a hunger headache.
So, aspirin and
hospitals are okay.
That's an interesting attitude for
someone who's kept any number of people
from getting medical help.
Just because I believe in prayer
doesn't mean I don't
believe in germs and toxins.
That bottle's been opened before.
You refilled it at the water cooler.
Yes. How often do you do that?
Few times an hour. He
likes to stay hydrated.
You think germs
might have gotten in?
I think water might
have gotten in.
We can adjust your pain meds.
Again.
Suppose we increase
your oxycodone?
We both know the only
reason I'm talking lucidly now
is because I did not take
my full dose this morning.
You've done your best
and I have been a good soldier.
It's time we accept it's over.
What about the trip you
were talking about taking?
You've wanted to see Florence
since you were a teenager, right?
Yeah, go now all drugged up?
It's not exactly the trip
I'd been dreaming of.
Okay, but you're strong,
you're dealing with this
and there is the right combination of
pain meds out there. And we'll find it.
Don't give up on us.
And don't be startled by the
sound you're about to hear.
Excuse me,
I have a friend with
boundary issues.
Can this wait five minutes?
Is she dying?
Yeah.
Before the end of this consult?
They could build monuments
to your self-centeredness.
Patient, 15-year-old,
faith healer, hotline to God.
What are his symptoms?
He is not a saint.
He figures out what's
going on in people's lives
by watching,
listening, deducing.
And you're worried about
trademark infringement?
Then he passes on advice from
God so he can watch them jump.
It's a power trip.
Oh, and there the similarities
end. Why is he here?
I fear for the human race.
A teenager claims
to be the voice of God
and people with advanced
degrees are listening.
The majority of Americans believe in a
personal god. What are his symptoms?
Massive cramps, low sodium.
Turns out he's been drinking water
nonstop, God told him to purify his body.
Huge water intake
would cause low sodium.
Which would cause the
cramping. Yeah, I got it.
What, that's it? You solved it?
You just brought me out here to
rant because faith annoys you?
Mmm-hmm.
He's all better.
You know, I'd get it if people were
just looking for a way to fill the holes.
But they want the holes,
they wanna live in the holes
and they go nuts when someone
else pours dirt in their holes.
Climb out of your holes, people!
Go, tell it on the mountain
Over the hills and everywhere
That Jesus Christ is born
Go, tell it on the mountain
Over the hills and everywhere
That Jesus Christ is born
Boyd, are you all right?
Go, tell it on the mountain
Boyd.
Over the hills and...
Come on, let's go. Can
you tell me your name?
Do you know where you are? Boyd?
Boyd?
God doesn't want
you to be afraid.
He sent me here to heal you.
You think he hasn't heard your
prayers, but he heard them all,
even the ones you didn't say.
I'm sorry, Boyd, come on,
let's get you back to your room.
In faith, all things
are possible.
Let's go.
Lord, I call on you to relieve
the suffering of your daughter...
Grace? And make her whole again.
Hey, hey! What are
you doing? What is this?
He's just had a complex
partial seizure. He's disoriented.
He doesn't know what he's doing.
Well, get him back to his room, now.
You okay?
Are we certain he
even had a seizure?
Him singing and healing, he
does it all the time, doesn't he?
Isn't it interesting
that religious behavior is so close to
being crazy, we can't tell them apart.
The repetition, the lack of affect
and awareness. It was a seizure.
Infection? No fever.
Could be Wilson's or maybe
it's a glycogen storage disease.
Or a brain tumor.
Or tuberous sclerosis.
Hmm.
How to settle this?
We could ask our patient to ask
God or we could MRI his brain.
Which way do you wanna
go? 'Cause I'm open to all.
House! Yes.
Why the hell do you let an
unstable patient wander the hallways?
His leash broke.
The last thing a
terminal patient needs
is to hear somebody
taunt them with a cure.
She was freaked, she was angry.
And now she's not freaked
and angry and you are.
She says she's feeling better.
Maybe not singing and dancing,
but she's feeling just a little bit happy
for the first time in months.
A sudden drop in pain
could create euphoria.
Why don't you let
her have her vacation?
Oh, that's great. And
when vacation's over?
When she crash-lands
from all this denial?
She was dealing
with her illness.
Now her expectations are rising.
And you're not the one who has
to be there when all that false hope
gets yanked out from under her.
Don't you guys
have anything to do?
How long have you
been healing people?
You believe that's
what I'm doing?
I'd like to.
But you don't.
Why do you always do
things you don't want to do?
It's okay, I don't
expect a real answer.
God would probably want you
to take the stick out of your butt
and get over this.
If there is some higher
order running the universe,
it's probably so different from
anything our species can conceive,
there's no point in
even thinking about it.
But I doubt it gives a
damn about my butt.
So you believe God might
exist, but you don't think about it?
It's the most important
issue... I think penguins
might as well speculate
about nuclear physics.
Why are we having this
conversation? What? I'm curious.
You cannot tell someone they
are your colleague and not a friend,
and then casually
chat about the afterlife.
You actually keep score?
Your MRI results
aren't done yet.
Go back to your
room. No singing.
Well, you would get a point
for figuring why the low sodium.
What are my guy's points for?
Your trick about the spat between
Dr. Cameron and Dr. Foreman
apparently impressed someone.
And the second point?
Do you think it could be
because I healed Grace?
She's been back
to see me, I like her.
You like messing with people.
That's why you're here now.
Maybe you think that your batteries
are powered by God, maybe you don't.
Either way, you
enjoy what you do.
Yes, I like helping people.
I get a rush when I see the look
on their faces when they realize
their burdens are gone.
But you make sure you're in the next
state by the time the endorphins wear off
and the arthritis comes back.
That doesn't happen.
Oh, you do extensive
follow-up studies?
God told me.
You see, that's not
fair. We were having fun.
It's hard to keep sniping rationally
when you throw a bomb like that in there.
He spoke with me about you, too.
Forgive my enemies?
Never date a Taurus when
Mercury is in retrograde?
Yeah, I learned that
one myself, the hard way.
God says you look
for excuses to be alone.
See, that is exactly the kind
of brilliance that sounds deep,
but you could say it about any person
who doesn't pine for the social approval
of everyone he meets, which you
were cleverly able to deduce about me
by not being a moron.
Next time, tell God
to be more specific.
God wants you to invite
Dr. Wilson to your poker game.
Don't talk to my patient.
What are you talking about?
You get all huffy when my patient
stumbles into yours in the hallway,
but you got no qualms
about chatting my guy up.
This is fun, it's like Password.
Keep talking. I'll jump
in when I get a clue
what the hell
you're talking about.
God knows about my poker game.
You think I told him?
Either that or I start going
to church every Sunday.
That would mess with
my bowling league.
House, aside from yelling at
him to get back to his room,
I've never spoken
to your patient.
MRI shows an abnormal area.
Tuberous sclerosis.
It's the right neighborhood.
Accounts for all the symptoms.
All of them.
Leading cortical
tuber's identifiable.
We can do this surgically.
Tell our patient,
"Congratulations."
Soon his chats with God
will be a thing of the past.
Tie goes to the mortal.
Did you know the Catholic
Church keeps a doctor at Lourdes?
He hears the same
thing every day.
But, out of the thousands of cases of
people who have claimed to feel better,
the Catholic Church has only
recognized a handful as miracles.
But they do recognize a handful.
Well, they're a church.
It's what they do.
Look. For the past
couple of years,
the world's been
getting smaller.
Eight months, six months...
I watch a trailer for a movie
and I think, "Am I gonna be
here when that comes out?"
But maybe there is
still a horizon out there.
You know, maybe... Maybe I can
make plans for a year from now.
Two years.
I like the view.
The view is a lie,
and if you believe it,
you're going to crash so hard.
Let me take new
images of your liver.
You can't accept
that it could be true.
Well, if it is true, you
shouldn't be afraid of proving it.
Tuberous sclerosis
is a genetic disorder.
It causes small, benign tumors to
grow in various parts of the body.
In this case, the
brain. You said benign.
They probably are, but benign or
not, they're not in a good location.
We need to remove them.
You're talking brain surgery?
His symptoms are getting worse,
which means the tumors are growing.
Surgery will correct it all, the
chemical imbalance, the seizures,
the auditory hallucinations.
Hallucinations?
Without the surgery,
it's just gonna get worse.
Might even be fatal.
With the surgery, your son should
be a perfectly normal 15-year-old boy.
I'm not normal.
I need you to talk to my
patient. I'll get this one.
Why do I have the feeling
you're plotting world domination?
Moses is refusing
surgery. You have a gift.
People thank you for telling
them they're going to die.
If I can get him to agree to
surgery, I want in on the poker game.
You would let this kid die
just to get into a stupid game?
You'd let him die
just to keep me out?
Hi.
I'm Dr. Wilson.
I knew they'd send
somebody else.
That God has a big mouth. House.
Can I ask why you don't
want the tumors removed?
God put them there for a reason.
You think God needs a telephone
in your head to talk to you?
Isn't he everywhere? It's
not a long-distance call, is it?
This is the way God does
things, through natural law.
If he went around doing big
flashy miracles all the time,
nobody would need faith. How
come everyone else needs faith,
but you just get the guy
screaming his existence in your ear?
Your turn.
Do you think God
wants you to die?
This is the way that the Lord
often is with his chosen ones.
He gives the most trials to
those that he loves the most.
How sweet.
You abdicate your authority,
avoid those tricky parental issues,
like whether to let him drive
at 16. Just let him die at 15.
So, you believe your son is
a saint?
The way I understand it, one of
the hallmarks of a saint is humility.
Now, someone with true humility
would consider the possibility
that God hadn't chosen
him for that kind of honor.
Well, he'd consider
the possibility
that he just had an illness.
You have a gift
for manipulation.
I listen, I have an actual conversation
with people, which, shockingly,
does raise the odds
they'll be cooperative.
That's what I'm saying.
You read that kid and you
manipulated the hell out of him.
Bring pretzels.
I know that knock.
Use your key,
I'm not getting up.
Game's not till tomorrow
night and those aren't pretzels.
I took some images of
Grace Palmieri's cancer.
Yeah?
Her tumor's shrunk.
Don't tell my patient.
I want all the records
on miracle woman.
Every test, every
treatment she's ever had,
every question she's ever
answered in this hospital.
And anything sent from previous doctors.
Go back to neonatal if you have to.
Which part of "keep them away
from each other" confused you?
They're friends. She
thinks he saved her life.
Now we have obligingly offered
medical proof that his delusions are true.
They've withdrawn
permission for the surgery.
I put the lawyers on
it. Her tumor shrank?
I'm on it.
Tell Jesus that we need another 24
hours to normalize his sodium level.
He's already normalized.
Actually, tell Joseph.
Jesus will know you're lying.
And I want you and
Foreman and Cameron
to go over every line of
every file on that woman.
Isn't he the one we're
supposed to save?
The only way to save him is
to prove that she is still dying.
MRI machine checks out.
Maybe the radiologist mis-charted
which machine they used.
I checked both.
This is insane, we're
diagnosing a recovery.
What about six months ago?
Maybe there was a malfunction
in her "before" pictures,
some shadow that made the
tumor look bigger than it really was.
I'll go see what I can find out.
Maybe it's a delayed
effect from radiation.
Sometimes it could take a while.
She hasn't had radiation for six months.
Here. Nowhere. Her records...
There's about a dozen appliances
in every home that give off radiation.
Dosages that wouldn't hurt a hamster
if it was tied to the machine for a year.
If the machine's
operating properly.
Sometimes
remissions just happen.
You think House will
just shrug and say that
if one of us doesn't
check the home?
Kings on nines. MAN: Out.
Thank you.
Wilson. This is a dry cleaner,
tax accountant, guy from
the bus stop. This is Wilson.
How come he gets a name?
Seniority. Hello.
Find anything?
Do you have any idea how many
electrical devices give off radiation?
All of them. I'm going
to be here all night.
Everybody's a whiner.
Be a doer, not a me-tooer.
Raise.
I'm out.
She's got at least four
different types of pain pills here
and an LED device.
I'll raise your raise.
Keep looking.
Fold.
You were bluffing, he knew you were
bluffing. Your luck's changing tonight.
So, did they find anything?
Or are you gonna
have to accept the fact
that every now and
then remissions happen?
This call had better
be worth my time.
This is what happens when it's not
our patient. We don't know enough.
That's why you're there.
She's got a boyfriend...
Unless you think he's radioactive...
who could show up any minute.
The honor of working for you
is not worth a felony charge.
Give me a minute.
I'm saying the odds of you having
a straight flush are pretty low.
House?
I'll fold.
Fold. Fold.
I'm screwed, aren't I?
Nine bucks for a straight flush.
He's not coming home. Relax.
There's nothing in this universe
that can't be explained, eventually.
Take this game,
only two people knew
that you wanted in on it.
I didn't tell him...
I told you, I didn't tell
him. Why would you?
No, the only person he's been getting
all intimate and conversational with
is your cancer chick.
How would she know?
The subject of my
poker game isn't likely to
come up in the course
of a patient interview.
Well, that's the kind of
thing that you mention
to someone you're used to
sharing the details of your day with.
Don't.
Your rabbi. Guidance
counselor, parent.
She's not your mom, is she?
I'm seriously saying don't.
You've been having sex...
This is so not the place.
With our miracle woman.
Excuse me. May I talk to you?
Of course.
Boyd's getting dressed,
he's ready to check out.
He can't check out
without your permission.
His sodium level
still isn't normal.
I told him.
He said that God said
it was okay, he was fine.
Could you talk to him?
Tell them my name isn't Wilson.
Most people in your situation just
have their careers to worry about.
You've got that and
divine retribution.
Tell them.
Tell me how it happened, and
I'll tell them whatever you want.
She'd had a bad day, pain-wise.
Her ride didn't show
up to take her home.
So, you offered? Yeah.
She didn't have any groceries,
she was too sick to go out,
I figured I could afford
to take a half hour
and pick her up a few things...
Stay and make sure
she's okay. Yeah.
And never leave.
You told me you
got an apartment.
But you moved in with
her. You lied to me.
Tell them.
His name is not Wilson and
he's screwed up worse than I am.
Okay. Yes, I lied to you.
I'm sorry.
You know, half the doctors who specialize
in oncology turn into burned-out cases.
But you, you eat neediness.
Lucky for you.
Thanks for the game, guys. I
don't think I'll be coming back.
You're a functional vampire.
Sure, you're heroic,
useful to society,
but only because it feeds you.
There's nothing worth
stealing, so don't even look.
You don't just have a fetish for
needy people, you marry them!
Here we go. You mean it!
And then time passes, and suddenly
they're not so needy anymore.
Your fault.
You've been there
for them too much.
They're getting healthy,
independent and that's just ugly.
God, you must be pissed at God
right now, making her all happy.
Why are you doing this?
Because you're being stupid.
You know what you're risking
by sleeping with a patient.
Oh, that's crap.
You're not mad because
I'm risking my job.
You're not even mad
'cause I lied to you.
You're mad because I lied
to you and you couldn't tell.
Yeah. You got me nailed. Yeah.
That's why you didn't want
me in your poker game.
Because when it
comes to being in control,
Gregory House leaves our
faith-healer kid in the dust
and that's why religious
belief annoys you.
Because if the universe
operates by abstract rules,
you can learn them and
you can protect yourself.
If a supreme being exists, he
can squash you any time he wants.
He knows where I am.
I think it's yours.
Yeah.
I'll be right there.
Jesus is spiking a
fever. He's delusional.
Tuberous sclerosis
doesn't cause fever. I know.
I'll drive.
Pick any random guy off
the street, bring him in here,
examine him exhaustively, you will
find at least three things wrong with him.
This kid has tuberous
sclerosis, a mild case.
But his tumors are growing.
We assumed that the tumors were
growing, 'cause he's getting sicker.
But he could have grown old and
died and never known about them
if he hadn't come here.
We were looking for something, it's more
or less in the right part of the brain.
It's like we found someone standing
over a dead body holding a gun,
we arrested them,
didn't look any further.
Well, sometimes people really do
just stumble into a murder scene.
His fever's 103 and rising.
If we don't do anything, he's gonna be
chatting with God face to face real soon.
Fevers don't come from a
long-term underlying condition.
He's a garden-variety religious nut
who happens to have an infection.
It's lumbar puncture time.
No, no, God told me, no
more of man's medicine.
If we have faith in
him, he'll make me well.
It's just a test. Make me well.
We just want to find
out what's wrong.
God knows what's wrong,
God will take care of it.
He's delirious and he's a minor.
This is your decision and not his.
"The Kingdom of Heaven is
like a treasure hidden in a field,
"which when a man finds, he
hides, and for joy he goes and sells
"all he owns and
buys that field."
Buy all the land you want,
don't blow your brains out.
You're watching your son kill
himself. He's out of his mind with fever...
Dad! If your faith
is weak, I will fail.
I need you.
I'm sorry, you don't even
know what's wrong with him.
God knows the answer
and I would rather leave
it in his hands than yours.
Wilson.
I need you to do your thing.
You do know that I don't
actually have magical powers.
I have faith.
You're better off trying to slip
some antibiotics into a meal.
Which antibiotics? We don't
know what infection he's got.
Go as broad as
you can. Forget it.
Our best hope is
your silver tongue.
What if it's not an infection?
Were you not paying attention when I
was doing my murder scene metaphor?
What if the tuberous
sclerosis is guilty.
It had the gun in its hands,
it was standing over the...
Doesn't cause fever.
It causes everything else. What if
the fever's the innocent bystander?
The fever could have been set off
by something he picked up anywhere.
It could have been
a bug he got here.
Or a bug he gave here.
He gave it to your patient.
That's why her tumor shrank,
the virus went after the cancer first.
Are you saying a virus
attacked her tumor?
For 200 years, there've been reports
of wild viruses that target tumors.
Early 1900s, an Italian medical journal
wrote up a woman with cervical cancer
who was injected with
a weak strain of rabies.
I have no idea why they did
that, but her tumor shrank.
You think he gave her rabies?
One of the virus types most prone
to go after cancer cells is herpes.
Herpes encephalitis.
It would fit.
Seizure, low sodium,
even the blurred vision.
And it would
mean, if you're right,
Grace's cancer is coming back.
You're not gonna be
able to convince them.
They don't want any more
tests, they don't wanna...
They can't argue
with the mark of Cain.
I'm not going to change my mind.
No more tests. God knows the way.
Okay, let's start
with the shirt.
What are you doing?
I'm on a mission from God.
If you won't let me
undress you, then strip.
What's he doing?
What's going on?
That woman you helped?
You gave her a virus.
No, she's healed, I have a gift.
A gift is jewelry, socks.
What you have is
herpes encephalitis.
And the only way you
could've transmitted it
is by scratching one
of your own sores
and touching another person.
Herpes, that's something
you get from sex, right?
Either that or cold sores.
Your kid got it from the sex.
No, no. No sores.
No, my body's clean.
They examined me when I came in!
No sores. Herpes hides.
You have an
outbreak, it goes away,
it comes back, goes away. Strip!
Maybe you didn't have a sore when
you came in, but you've got one now.
Dad, I've never,
ever... Do you wonder
why a perfect child of God
should feel so desperate
to "purify his body" that he needed to
scarf down a dozen gallons of water a day?
Boyd, is he right?
Dad! No, he's crazy!
Help me! Dr. Wilson, help!
God said no medicine,
no procedures.
Taking off your clothes
doesn't count as either of those.
This one's your call.
Son...
Dad, you have to
have faith in me.
I have faith in the Lord.
You, I trust,
as much as you can
trust a teenage boy.
Take off your clothes.
Relax.
A few Hail Marys,
a little acyclovir,
you'll be picking up
angels again in no time.
Come in.
My father told me I
have to apologize to you.
You still hearing the voices?
You're lucky.
You go through life with a certainty
that what you're doing is right.
I know how comforting that is.
Good luck.
You're not gonna
give me my final point?
You knew it was me?
Who else?
You don't think God should
get a point knocked off?
The tumor shrank.
Because of a virus.
Do you know what the odds are?
She had to have the right type of cancer,
he had to have the right type of virus.
The exposure...
She won the lottery.
You say "won the
lottery," he says "miracle."
Yeah, the hand of God reached into
this kid's pants, made him have sex
so he could scratch a rash and
stick his fingers in some woman's face,
give her a few extra months.
Come on, he's just
another liar and manipulator.
Well, nobody's as
perfect as you are.
It is possible to believe in
something and still fail to live up to it.
So, how's your girlfriend?
She got a little extra
time out of this. Not a lot.
She didn't crash.
No. She says she's happier when she
believes in something bigger than she is.
She still believes.
Faith. She's going to Florence.
You moving out?
Yeah.
Moving back in with me?
I don't think
that's a great idea.
But we're okay?
House, you are
as God made you.