Don't worry.
You'll see, it'll be
like you never left.
Connor, last time
people from work saw me,
I was strapped to a gurney,
screaming about rats.
Look, they understand.
You were sick,
and now you're not.
Everything's gonna be fine.
And if you need me,
which you won't,
I'm on trauma service today,
so I will be in the ED,
okay?
Mmm-hmm.
But you have to tell me.
And violate the sacred oath?
It's not like you're
guarding the Holy Grail.
It's a holiday gift exchange.
That we call "Secret Santa"
because we're supposed
to keep it a secret.
Okay, so who is it?
Is it April?
I'm not gonna tell ya.
Fine, don't tell me,
but it's only a matter of time
before you crack.
Not a chance.
Mmm-hmm.
Can I grab you for a sec?
Something to show you.
Sure.
Oh, look who it is.
Hi.
Robin?
Welcome back.
There she is.
Hello, Robin.
You look great.
Doesn't she?
Wait till she snaps again.
She was cleared
to come back to work.
She's Dr. Charles's daughter.
They're gonna say no?
You, too.
See, I told you
it would all be fine.
Coffee at 11:00?
Yeah.
All right.
There you are.
You look great, honey.
I'd be a lot better
if everyone stopped
telling me that.
Help!
I need a doctor! Hurry!
We need some help over here!
Dr. Choi, with me.
Uh, he's having chest pain.
Sir, can you hear me?
Sir?
No pulse. Get on his chest!
Grab his arms.
All right, on my count.
Ready? One, two, three.
What's the matter with Santa?
It's all right, honey.
Let's get him to a room.
Uh, gurney.
We're on it.
He thought it was
just indigestion.
I told him we should
call an ambulance.
Is Santa going to die?
No, no, sweetie,
we're going to take
very good care of him.
Still no pulse.
We gotta move.
Let's get a
crash cart ready!
Massive MI. We hit him
with five rounds of epi.
There was no
bringing him back.
Poor man.
Name's Bill Cooper.
He's been Santa-in-residence
at Water Tower Place
for the past 25 years.
Saint Nick dying
in our waiting room?
Not a good look for us.
You let me know
the second his family arrives.
Yes, ma'am.
Incoming!
Monique, you're on deck.
Dr. Rhodes?
Pedro Suarez,
30-year-old male.
Fell 20 feet off his roof
stringing Christmas lights.
GCS of 8.
King airway in the field.
Initially hypotensive,
but responded to
a liter of fluids.
Please tell me
my son is gonna be okay.
Mr. Suarez, I promise you
we're gonna do
everything we can.
All right,
everybody on my count.
One, two, three.
Thank you.
Mmm-hmm.
Sats are 86 and falling fast.
I'm not getting
breath sounds on the left.
He's got a tension
pneumothorax.
Let's decompress him
and put a chest tube in.
Needle?
Straight up.
Sats and blood pressure
are coming up.
All right.
I'm gonna place the tube.
Scalpel.
Okay, come on.
That's not blood.
Nope.
That's...
That's fecal matter.
Fecal matter? How did
he get poop in his chest?
Vincent Kramer, went through
a stained-glass window.
Found him wandering
the streets.
Mr. Kramer,
can you tell me what happened?
They're coming for me,
the demons!
GCS, 13.
BP, 86 over palp.
Arterial bleed in his forearm.
Tourniquet applied
in the field,
but he's still bleeding.
Okay, let's transfer
on my count,
and watch out for
the glass, okay?
Ready? One, two, three.
Doris, let's take
a look at his arm.
Wait, did you see them?
The demons?
Try to stay calm, Mr. Kramer.
They're after me!
Heart rate, 134.
BP, 86/52.
That's hypotensive.
Bolus a liter of LR,
and give him two units
of uncrossmatched blood
on the rapid transfuser.
Yes, Doctor.
Ah!
Oh!
All right,
it severed his radial artery.
Give me a hemostat
and a silk tie.
We need to get control
and tie it off.
They're here.
Please believe me.
We got you, Mr. Kramer.
Just try to stay calm.
No, no, no.
Got it.
Bleeding's under control.
Can't you see them?
Blood pressure's
improving.
Oh! Demons, everywhere.
Help me.
We're going to, Mr. Kramer.
Let's get him
in soft restraints,
and we're gonna need
a psych consult.
Get away from me.
Okay, when did the fever
start, Mr. Rosenblatt?
Uh, I felt funny Sunday,
but that went away.
I definitely had
a fever Tuesday.
Okay.
Well, how specific
should I be?
Just answer
the question, Harold.
Tuesday.
Tuesday. Okay.
And don't forget
about the rash.
Oh... Oh.
Oh.
Okay, let's get
a chest X-ray,
CBC, blood cultures,
and start him on fluids.
He's jaundiced.
A liver panel and a CT scan
probably couldn't hurt.
Thank you, nurse. That's what
I was about to suggest.
Let, uh, Radiology know
that we're sending him up.
All right, Mr. Rosenblatt,
can you please put that on?
And you might wanna leave
any valuables you have
with your wife.
Wife?
She's my sister.
And housemate
who told you we should've
come in earlier.
Give it a rest, Sylvia.
Fine.
Next time,
I'll just let you die.
How does that work for you?
Anything is better than
listening to you.
Okay, um, we'll be back
to check on you guys
after that scan.
You wanted to see me?
Yes, uh, Daniel...
Uh, I'm afraid
I've got some bad news.
The man who shot you,
Jack Kellogg,
was killed in prison
this morning.
How?
All I know is that
he was murdered
by another inmate.
You predicted
something like this.
You didn't think he should go
to prison in the first place.
No, I didn't.
And you were upset
with Dr. Reese for testifying
for the prosecution.
And?
I just hope
you don't take this
out on her.
Do you really think
I'd do that?
I'm sorry,
but given how upset you were
that she testified,
I didn't know
how you would react.
I know this is difficult.
Why don't you just
take a few days off?
Oh, so not only
am I vindictive,
I'm emotionally unstable?
You know what,
I'd rather work.
But I sure do
appreciate the offer.
Daniel...
Come on...
Daniel.
Fever, rash, jaundiced skin.
I'm sure you noticed
his conjunctivitis.
I was getting there.
By any chance,
was the rash purple?
Yeah. Why?
Stohl had a patient
with the exact same symptoms
three days ago.
The cultures just came in.
Leptospirosis?
It's bacterial, right?
Yeah.
Stohl's guy went into DIC.
Disseminated intravascular
coagulation.
I know what it is.
Are we looking at an outbreak?
I'll page Robin Charles.
So, his colon's
in his chest?
Diaphragm ruptured
from the impact of the fall.
Stomach, spleen and colon
were ripped from
the abdominal wall,
and migrated
into the left chest.
I hate when that happens.
The OR is being prepped
for surgery right now.
You'll do the thoracotomy,
while I open his abdomen.
All right.
Oh, and just as a reminder,
uh, I am on
trauma service today,
and this is
a trauma surgery, so...
So you'll be attending
on the case,
and you're going to get
your kicks out of
calling the shots?
I'm delighted to assist you,
Dr. Rhodes.
I'm glad to hear that.
Shall we?
Okay.
Boss.
Dr. Charles?
Um... I, um...
I heard about Jack Kellogg.
I am so sorry.
It's exactly what you said
would happen.
Uh, he was a very
troubled man
who brought things
on himself.
Yes, but if he
had been remanded
to a psychiatric facility,
like you wanted, uh...
I... I just feel so awful.
Look, Dr. Reese,
if you're thinking
that in some way,
this might've been your fault,
it just wasn't.
He was a very
self-destructive guy,
and there's just no guarantee
the outcome would've been
any different,
no matter where he ended up.
Dr. Charles... Excuse me.
Um, you available
for a consult?
Yes, we are.
Name is Vincent Kramer,
homeless man.
Delusional, combative.
We have him in restraints.
I'm the only one
trying to help you.
Don't you see them?
The demons!
They're here.
No one is safe.
Why don't you listen?
Actually, Dr. Charles,
there's some patients
I need to check on upstairs.
That is why
they keep coming back.
Okay.
They won't stop.
They will find me.
They were looking for me.
The paramedics say he somehow
went through a window.
Oh...
No one is safe!
Poor fella.
Mr. Kramer?
I'm Dr. Charles.
I can't stop them.
Nobody can stop them.
They're gonna find me here.
Them?
The demons.
You know what,
I can understand how...
How demons would be
very frightening.
They're gonna
take me with them.
I'm not gonna
let that happen.
You're safe here.
Five of Olanzapine.
Yes, doctor.
Safe?
We're giving you something
that's gonna
calm you down a bit,
and you should be
feeling better pretty soon.
Better?
Yeah.
I'm just gonna
step out for a bit,
and when I come back,
you and I,
we're gonna start
to figure this out, all right?
Okay?
Gonna let the Olanzapine
mellow him out a bit,
and, uh, come back
and see if I can get
a better picture
of what's going on.
Yeah.
Uh, Leptospi-what?
Leptospirosis.
It's a bacterial infection.
We're starting you on
a broad spectrum antibiotic.
It's all that pork you eat.
Moo shu, bacon, it's treif.
Treif?
Not kosher.
Actually, the disease is
most commonly carried
by rodents, rats,
rat urine, specifically,
usually through water
that's been contaminated.
What the hell have you
been drinking, Harold?
Will you stop nagging
and let her finish?
There have been
a couple cases recently.
I need to ask you
some questions
to see if your case
is connected.
Okay, can you think
of anywhere
you have been recently
where you may have come
in contact with rats?
Uh, like an attic
or basement?
Anywhere you might've been
exposed to contaminated water?
Oh. You've been
swimming at the Y.
I told you to join the JCC.
She's talking to me, Sylvia.
Okay, we'll see if the Y has
reported a recent infestation.
Anything else
you can think of?
You sure it's not the pork?
I'm so sorry for your loss.
My sister would like to
move him to a funeral home.
How long do you need
to keep him here?
Normally, a day or two,
but I'll ask
the medical examiner
to release his body
this afternoon.
Oh, thank you, Ms. Goodwin.
Hey, Dr. Rhodes,
just wanted to let you know
Radiology's uploading
your patient's latest scans.
Thank you.
Hey, will you do me a favor?
If you see Robin,
will you tell her that
I got pulled into surgery?
I'm not gonna make
our coffee date.
Sure, but she's
probably busy, too.
Three cases of Leptospirosis.
Lepto?
Isn't that a rat disease?
Yeah, it can be.
Just what she needs today.
I was doing the laundry,
and the next thing I know,
I started cramping.
Are these contractions?
I'm only 22 weeks.
Okay, um, let's get a CBC
and UA with culture.
Is there anyone
we should call?
My husband's away
at a legal conference,
but he was having trouble
catching a flight
out of Buffalo.
Is everything okay
with my baby?
Let's take a look, okay?
All right,
there's the heartbeat.
Head circumference measuring
at about 178 millimeters.
Looks like a normal, healthy
22-week-old fetus to me.
Thank God.
All right,
so we'll run those tests
and go from there, okay?
And don't worry, Shannon,
we're gonna take really good
care of you and your baby.
Okay?
Thank you.
Harold? Harold?
We need to intubate.
20 of etomidate, 100 of sux.
Oh, my God.
Ms. Rosenblatt, it's okay.
Please, wait out here,
until we're finished.
Harold!
Get me an ET tube.
Harold...
I... I can't.
I can't get it in.
It's... It's too much
blood. Suction.
Sats are down to 76.
I still can't get it in.
Noah...
I'll get another doctor.
No!
He needs a surgical airway.
A crich? Really?
Splash prep on his neck.
Sterilizing.
Give me a knife.
I'm in. Bag him.
Heart rate's 140.
BP, 124/82.
You did it.
Of course I did it.
Shannon?
How are you feeling?
All better now.
I'm so sorry
I wasn't here sooner.
I canceled all my meetings,
got on the first flight out.
How's the baby?
Dr. Manning
was just explaining.
Hi, um...
Hi.
Well, I think
it's just a case of
Braxton Hicks contractions,
practice contractions.
Nothing to be concerned about.
However, I would like to
just run one more test,
just to ensure that
it's not pre-term labor.
If that's all clear,
then you should be good to go.
What a relief.
Man, is it me
or is it hot in here?
Mr. Kim, everything okay?
Throat's just a little dry.
Is there any way
I can get some water?
Definitely.
Your color is a bit off.
Have you had any fever,
headaches?
I'm probably just worn down
from the travel.
Well, how 'bout I give you
a quick look-see,
run a few tests?
But Shannon...
Oh, go ahead, honey.
You do look a little pale.
Oh, I'll have you
back in no time.
Honey, I won't be far.
Right this way.
Thanks.
First time dads.
Are you sure Robin was ready
to come back to work?
Let's get that tube out
before it contaminates
his chest.
I only ask because we had
an anti-NMDA patient
at Groote Schuur.
She had psychotic episodes
for a full year
after the tumor was removed.
Tubes out.
Staple the colon, before it
leaks any more stool.
Already on it.
Tough on you, huh?
Always wondering
if she'll flip out again?
I'm gonna pull the colon
back down into the abdomen.
You'll need to guide it
from the top.
Got it.
All right, colon is
repaired and reduced.
Dr. Bekker,
let's irrigate the chest
with 10 liters of saline.
Right away, Dr. Rhodes.
And open a 10-by-20
Gore-Tex patch
to reconstruct the diaphragm.
I will be back to put it in.
Where are you going?
It'll take you at least 30
minutes to clean out
the chest.
I'll be back then.
He's going to check
on his girlfriend.
I think I should get a manual
differential on his CBC.
And maybe
another chest X-ray.
Of course.
I know that.
Right.
And I'm sure you won't forget
about sputum cultures.
Will you stop it?
What?
I'm sick of you telling me
how to do my job.
I'm just trying to help.
Well, you're not.
I don't need
a big sister here.
I know what I'm doing.
Back off.
That's two cases
in the last week,
and you know of one
at East Mercy?
Have you found
a common vector?
Yeah. Are they
clustered geographically?
Okay, I'll need
charts on all of them,
and let me know
if any more turn up. Thanks.
Robin?
What happened?
Nothing. I'm fine.
What are you doing out here?
Uh, just my office...
I needed some air.
Robin, what's going on?
Connor...
What?
I heard them again.
Rats?
In my office, and...
Okay. Oh, honey.
Don't worry...
I'm gonna take
care of you, okay?
But you're not
seeing 'em now?
They're gone.
What do you think they want,
the demons?
To get inside me.
Oh.
That's what they do.
They get inside people,
make them do things.
They got inside of my friend.
I had to get away.
Yeah. And that's
when you hurt yourself?
Yes.
The window, I had...
I had to get through it.
How long have they
been after ya?
A long, long time.
Years.
Running all that time,
hiding, I mean,
it sounds exhausting.
You must be very tired.
Tired...
I am so tired.
Yeah.
You know, Vince,
I can provide you with
a place where you can rest.
Would you like that?
Clean bed, shower,
a place where
you can feel safe.
Yes, I would like that.
Okay.
Great.
So?
Hallucinations, paranoia,
hyper-religiosity.
This is definitely some kinda
delusional disorder.
Bipolar 1, maybe?
I'll wanna have him admitted,
you know, for a full
psychological evaluation.
Okay, I'll start working on
the transfer order.
Thanks.
Sure.
Uh, you said
you travel a lot,
so I thought of
West Nile Virus.
I ran a mosquito panel.
Good news is
you don't have West Nile.
Here's the thing,
you did test
inconclusive for Zika.
Really? Zika? How?
I'm wondering that myself.
I mean, there hasn't been
a case of Zika reported
north of the Mason-Dixon line.
Have you visited
anywhere else recently?
Maybe somewhere tropical?
There have been a few cases
reported in South Florida.
No, I haven't
been to Florida.
Okay, well...
Regardless, the first thing
we have to do is test Shannon.
Shannon? Why?
Well, since Zika can be
sexually transmitted,
Shannon could contract it,
leaving the fetus at risk
of developing microcephaly,
a devastating birth defect
where the baby's brain
doesn't form properly.
But we haven't
had sex in a week.
I've been out of town.
And you couldn't have
gotten Zika in Buffalo,
so you must've picked it up
before that.
It's important we test her.
I don't wanna scare her
needlessly.
Besides,
I'm feeling much better.
Probably just had
a touch of the flu.
Mr. Kim...
I really need to
get back to Shannon.
I'm sorry, am I...
Am I missing something here?
Okay. I wasn't in Buffalo.
I was in Aruba
with a lady friend.
Look, I'm not concerned
with your personal life.
I only care about my patient,
and in this situation,
we have to consider your wife.
No. She does not
find out about this.
I'm not risking my marriage
over an inconclusive test.
I don't think you understand.
Your baby's at risk.
Shannon needs to know.
Dr. Halstead...
They teach you about
doctor-patient confidentiality
in med school?
'Cause they definitely
covered it in law school.
I'm your patient, too, now,
and I'm telling you
to keep your mouth shut.
Why do I have to do an MRI?
We all know what is going on.
The MRI will allow us
to see the extent
of any lingering
inflammation.
This episode could end up
being a blessing.
It'll help us
adjust your meds.
And there's nothing
to worry about.
This is all part of
your recuperation process.
Which is endless.
I'll let the tech know
we're ready.
Thank you.
At least you don't have to
restrain me this time.
Maybe later tonight.
Hey, look, I have to
get back to the OR,
but I promise you,
I will not be very long.
We're starting another round
of antibiotics,
hoping he'll turn
a corner soon.
I hate seeing him like this.
Stubborn old fool.
But he's still
my baby brother.
He's lucky to have you.
I love him,
and I don't know
what I'd do without him.
But he hocks me a chainik.
This mishegas with Christmas.
Forgive me, but enough
with all the lights,
jingle bells, eggnog.
I'm sorry, I'm not following.
Harold's late wife,
Mary, lovely woman
but she was a gentile.
Catholic.
They celebrated Christmas.
He still does.
Maybe it's his way
of remembering her.
I suppose.
Seems kinda sweet.
Yeah...
I guess it is.
You were gone a while.
Everything okay?
Where are we?
Just coming around
the posterior medial.
You're just in time
for the hard part.
Good.
Every time the lung inflates,
the patch moves.
Do you have an angle on it?
No.
All right, then we need
to deflate his lung.
No. No way.
Sats are too low.
What if I use
a long Allis clamp
to get behind the lung
and hold the patch?
No, it's fine.
I've got it.
I've got room.
I can do it.
All right, go.
Clamp.
Patch is in place.
Stitch away.
No, I still can't reach
the crus of the diaphragm.
Can you give me
some more torque?
No, but I can finish
the stitches from here,
if you hold
the patch in place.
Okay, your call.
All right. Fine.
I can't get in
the last few stitches.
All right, Allis coming off.
All right, finish the run.
Look at you two, getting it
done like Jordan and Pippen.
Your scan was clean.
No residual edema or permanent
damage to your brain tissue.
Great, so I'm just
losing my mind?
Robin, this is good news.
It is?
If it would make you
feel better,
there are more tests
we can run,
an EEG, an autoimmune
antibody assay,
a lumbar puncture...
Ooh, a spinal tap.
Wow, that'll cheer me up.
Robin, we are going
to figure this out.
No, it's all pretty clear.
It's all in my head,
and there's nothing
that you or Connor
or anyone else can do.
Hey.
How's Shannon's husband?
Bruce Kim?
Turns out he wasn't
in Buffalo.
He was in Aruba
with another woman.
Tested inconclusive for Zika.
What?
Well, we have to test Shannon.
We can't,
not without violating
his confidentiality.
He refuses to tell her.
That's ridiculous.
I mean, if he was
HIV positive, we could
break confidentiality.
Doesn't Zika get
the same exemption?
No. Unfortunately,
Zika's so new,
there's no legal precedent.
But what if they have sex?
What if he infects the fetus?
I mean, you've seen babies
with microcephaly.
Natalie,
I have spent the last hour
trying to find
a way around HIPAA.
I've got nothing.
He'll come after the hospital,
and my license, incidentally.
So you're just giving up?
There's nothing we can do.
We can't justify
breaking the law
over an inconclusive
test result.
I know what you're thinking.
Don't do anything.
Desmond, talk to me.
Father Luke Novak,
parish priest
over at St. Emmelia.
Multiple stab wounds.
You're going to Trauma 1.
Ben, you're in.
GCS, 3.
Intubated in the field.
Heart rate, 137.
BP, 70 over palp.
Well, how did this happen?
Somebody broke
into the church.
The priest must've
confronted him.
All right,
let's transfer on my count.
One, two, three.
Go, go, go, go, go, go, go.
Call for two units.
Stephanie,
take over compressions.
Is that stained glass?
Did you get the guy
who did it?
Not yet.
I'm gonna get someone
to look at it, I promise you.
$16,000?
Sir...
What in God's name?
Sir, please,
lower your voice.
Excuse me, uh,
what seems to be the problem?
This.
Tell me how
I'm going to explain
a $16,000 bill to my sister,
who's already mourning
the death of her husband?
He died in the waiting room.
$16,000...
Yeah.
You're as bad as
the pharmaceutical companies,
profiting from our losses.
Mr. Williams, I promise you,
I will personally
look into this.
You're not gonna do
a damn thing.
$16,000.
I'd be mad, too.
So, we've got a mechanic,
a dry cleaner,
a retiree,
and now three other patients,
but they all live in
different parts of the city.
Well, they have to be
connected somehow.
Well, last Lepto outbreak
in Cook County
was five years ago,
a contaminated water
facility in Schaumburg.
And 10 years before that,
migrant workers picked it up
on a farm downstate,
so I've been thinking about
more than just water.
Maybe contaminated soil,
but this time of year,
there's not a lot
of gardening.
Hmm. Well, it is Christmas.
What about Christmas trees,
with everyone
bringing them home?
Yeah, I thought
about that as well,
but Harold
and Lydia Rosenblatt?
I mean, they're Jewish, right?
Would they get
a Christmas tree?
Harold may be Jewish,
but I know for a fact
he celebrates Christmas.
Huh...
Our job is to treat patients,
not to bankrupt them.
The man died
in the waiting room.
After which
you had him transferred
to a trauma room
and thoroughly examined.
Okay, "Position fee,
room charge, supplies,
"maintenance to clean
and sterilize the room."
These charges are
all legitimate.
His wife has suffered enough.
Can't we just
look the other way
on some of these things?
You know as well as I do,
the ED is
hemorrhaging money,
and you wanna
hand out freebies?
I'm just asking
to adjust the bill.
Ms. Goodwin...
What's the big deal?
His insurance will cover this.
And what if
he doesn't have insurance?
Then they'll cry poverty
and negotiate a lower bill.
That's how it's done.
At least we'll look
responsible.
Responsible?
Fiscally responsible.
Ms. Goodwin...
I'm looking out for you.
Get away from me!
No one is safe!
Kramer, you need
to come with us.
Listen to me,
the demons are here!
Detective, what are
you doing to my patient?
Dr. Charles,
you don't understand.
Why didn't you page me?
You said I'd be safe.
Dr. Charles,
let us do our job.
No, no, you give me a moment
and let me do mine.
Vince, nobody's gonna
hurt you.
I'm not gonna let 'em
hurt you, all right?
You can't stop them!
Call a code silver!
Get away from me!
Vince, look at me,
look at me.
You lied to me.
No, I didn't lie to you,
I promise.
There's been
a big misunderstanding.
Vince, look at me, look at me.
Right here. Nobody else.
Ignore everybody else.
Look at me.
What I need you to do,
I need you to lower
the paddles, okay,
so we can talk this out.
I promise you,
everything is gonna be okay.
All right?
So just slowly...
There you go.
Nice and easy.
Liar!
No!
No, don't!
Dr. Charles!
Dr. Charles, can you hear me?
Are you okay?
Whoa, whoa, whoa, easy.
Daniel, stop.
You were shocked.
Let me check your
heart rhythm, run an EKG.
I'm fine.
Don't be stubborn.
Dr. Charles,
you could've been killed.
Where are you taking him?
What are the charges?
Stop him. Can't you stop him?
No.
And the what the hell were you
thinking, risking your life?
It's a police matter.
How did it become
a police matter?
He's my patient.
Let me explain...
Look, what, that it's
a good idea to lock a man up
who's in serious need
of treatment?
Put him behind bars, blow any
chance we have of helping him?
Dr. Charles, please.
What did he do?
He broke a window.
He stabbed a priest.
What?
Father Novak died
in our trauma room.
He was covered in the same
stained glass as Vince.
You... You know why he did it?
Don't you?
It was because
of Jack Kellogg.
He couldn't save Jack Kellogg,
so he tried to
save this man.
I can't help but feel...
It's not your fault,
Dr. Reese.
The antibiotics are working,
Mr. Rosenblatt.
Your white blood cell
count has improved.
Now, we still have
a ways to go,
but things are looking good.
All because of
a Christmas tree.
Actually, it was
the Christmas tree lot.
The trees were cultivated
in infected soil.
Still, if you hadn't
brought that thing home...
Sylvia...
Could we take a night off?
Of course.
You need your rest.
Tomorrow, I'm gonna fix you
a fresh pot of split pea.
And if you're good,
I'll throw in a ham bone.
I'll be back
to check in on you later.
Okay, so Robin wants us
to update his chart
so she can send it
to the health lab.
You can do it.
You don't need my help.
Oh, really?
That's a change.
Okay, sometimes,
you need my help...
Oh, okay.
But...
You know what?
I need you, too.
Where's this coming from?
I've just been thinking.
Okay.
So, what do you say,
when we get to be their age,
we move in together.
Not on your life.
Okay. Thank you.
Let's go.
Oh, these flowers
are so beautiful.
Okay, let's go.
Thank you for everything,
Dr. Manning.
Bruce brought me these.
Aren't they pretty?
Mmm. Um, uh...
Um, before you go,
there's just one more thing.
What?
Since you're approaching
your delivery date,
I think it's really important
that you be cautious
with physical activity.
Um, try not to lift
anything heavy,
limit your stress, and, um...
Avoid sexual contact.
Why? None of the books say
anything about avoiding sex.
We're done here.
Uh, I'm sorry, I...
I think...
I think there's something
you should know.
Um, you...
Mr. Kim...
This is Dr. Ellen Hart,
Epidemic Intelligence
Service Officer for the CDC.
May I speak to you
in private, Mr. Kim?
No, you can't. My wife
and I are on our way out.
I'm sorry,
but federal law requires
that I speak to you
about your test.
What...
What's going on?
Uh, Dr. Hart
will fill you in.
Why don't we step
in here please?
What did you do?
I made some calls.
Since Zika's
a public health emergency,
the CDC has to investigate
all inconclusive test results.
I'm impressed.
Natalie, back there,
were you gonna...
Let's just say
it is a good thing
you showed up when you did.
So, are you keeping
anything from me?
Well, I haven't
been to Aruba,
if that's what
you're wondering.
Actually, there is one thing,
and this is just between us.
Goodwin.
I'm her secret Santa,
all right,
and I have no idea
what to get her.
I'm really glad
you shared that with me.
You know, she once told me
that the first thing she does
when she gets home
is take off her shoes.
So...
House slippers.
I'll help you pick 'em out.
Sharon, I mean,
what the hell?
You blackmailed the board?
All I did was explain that
it'd be very bad publicity
if it got out that
we gave Santa's widow
a bill for $16,000
one week before Christmas.
If it got out.
The board took that
as a threat.
What are they gonna do?
Well, they got no choice
but to forgive the charges.
Good.
No, it's not good,
They're not happy,
and believe me,
they would have no qualms
about replacing you
with someone who would
gladly bill Santa,
the Easter Bunny,
and the Tooth Fairy.
You need to watch your step.
I hear you, Peter.
Now, we were able to
remove all the stool contents
from his chest cavity
and repair his diaphragm.
It might be a little while
before he's back on a ladder,
but he should make
a full recovery.
Thank you for saving my son.
Uh, thank you both.
Of course.
We made a pretty
good team today.
We did.
Thank you, Doctor.
And sign this.
What do you say we go
have a drink and celebrate?
You wanna get a drink
with me? Seriously?
You know,
a little Don Corleone,
"Keep your friends close,
but your enemies closer."
Goodnight, Dr. Bekker.
Yeah, goodnight, Dr. Rhodes.
Dr. Charles?
Are you okay?
Yes. I'm okay.
Uh, I mean, with everything
that's happened.
I'm worried about you.
You know, that's funny,
because...
I've actually been
worried about you.
What? Why?
You know, this morning, when
they brought Mr. Kramer in,
I thought you seemed...
Anxious about treating him.
No. No, I told you,
I had patients to see.
Okay.
I, um...
I guess I just hope that...
That that's really the case.
Um, goodnight,
Dr. Charles.
Night.
Come in.
Hey.
So, uh...
Yeah, things got a little
out of hand today,
and, um...
You know, if the offer's still
good, I was thinking that...
Maybe I could use
a few days off.
The offer's still good.
Okay. Thank you.
You're welcome.
Don't stay away too long.
We need you here.
Tough day?
We billed $16,000
to a family of a man
who died in the waiting room.
I managed to quash it, but...
The system's broken, Daniel.
Well, don't know
anybody better
with a glue gun than you.
Well, enjoy your holidays.
You, too.
Why don't we take it easy
tonight, all right?
We'll get the fire going...
Let me just get my stuff.
All right.
Hey, sorry for the intrusion.
I had to get up
through your office.
Heating unit is on the fritz.
The heater?
Defective check valve.
Noise must've been
driving you crazy.
It's all fixed now.
Thank you.
It's good news.
Let's get out of here.
Yeah.
So, what did you
wanna show me?
In here.
Kiss me.
Shamrocks?
Uh, wasn't any mistletoe,
but I found a box of
St. Patty's decorations.
It'll do.
Merry Christmas.