♪ I'm so used to being broke
When the body's
exposed to rising temperatures,
it has the ability
to cool itself down.
We sweat,
our blood vessels dilate,
and our heart rate increases...
Mom! Why don't we have
air-conditioning?
Because
we live in Seattle.
Please go get dressed.
...and our body releases
as much excess heat as it can.
I thought Gen Z was all about
climate conservation.
Well, they're all about
speaking their minds
and spot-on hashtags.
Oh, and calling you "bestie"
as an insult.
Do you know what the temperature
is in Minnesota right now?
73 degrees.
No heat waves.
You're as bad as the kids.
Is it gonna be weird?
I can't do Minnesota
and be chief of
general surgery
the residency program.
Richard will
have to understand.
Well, I'm not talking
about Richard.
She's like my sister.
You're like my sister.
I just --
I don't want it to be weird.
Then stop making it weird.
But when the temperature starts
to inch above 100 degrees,
our bodies have to
work overtime...
I have back-to-back
craniotomies,
and then I have that video call
with Kai Bartley.
...leading to heat exhaustion.
I know --
I can't tell anyone.
73 degrees, Mer.
Maybe we just move to Minnesota
and become lake people.
Moving to Minnesota?
Great.
Not moving. Just might take
a few more trips there.
Got it.
Glad we discussed it.
Mm.
Uh, kiddie pool?
Yes, thank you.
Out back.
We become nauseated,
dizzy, and confused.
It's one of Link's lifelong
dreams to cure Parkinson's.
I know --
I can't tell anyone.
And we fight like hell to cool
down before it's too late.
♪ 1, 2, 3
Hey. I got the last window unit,
and I installed it myself.
Oh.
More burn pits?
Yeah, I found some
anecdotal accounts,
but no official documentation
about pulmonary fibrosis.
And Noah is still
not answering.
Well, he was pretty clear that
he didn't want treatment.
Yeah, I know.
I just...
I can't stop thinking about how
it could have been us, you know?
I know.
It's over 100 degrees
outside.
Did you not read
my e-mail?
I mean, not only is today
grand rounds,
but it is also
Silly Hat Day!
Bailey said that she wanted
better morale around here.
I said that
I agreed with her.
So she appointed me
Ambassador of Fun.
You?
Ambassador of Fun?
I'm fun!
♪♪
Whoa.
Teddy...
No. Okay.
Hey, Teddy, come on.
♪♪
See?
Fun.
Who do you
think it is?
Definitely someone big.
Maybe it's
Pier Cristoforo Giulianotti.
He pretty much invented
robotic surgery.
Hey, Dr. Wilson, do you know
who's doing our grand rounds?
Just because
I have to slum it
in the residents' lounge
with all of you
doesn't mean I can just give out
privileged information.
You don't know who it is,
do you?
I have important
work to do.
Did you know that
excessive heat
presents huge risks
in pregnant women?
Including Braxton-Hicks.
They announced who it is.
♪♪
You've got to
be kidding me.
Oh!
Mm!
Good morning.
Welcome back, Grey.
Hey!
Woman over P.A.:
Dr. Tracy Seip to Recovery.
How'd you know I was back?
I had a feeling.
Dr. Seip to Recovery.
I saw you getting out of
your car in the parking lot.
Oh.
You brought me coffee.
Hot coffee.
In triple-digit weather.
Iced coffee
isn't really coffee.
It's just
coffee-flavored water.
Not a fan of the heat,
I see.
There's more sheep
than people in Ireland,
so I like weather
that goes with hats and gloves
and scarves
and the like.
How's my friend Austin?
No idea,
to be honest.
Literally everything's
a secret on him.
Basically not even
allowed to ask.
I'm a few years
away from that,
but I'm definitely not
looking forward to it.
Well, enjoy your kids speaking
to you while you still can.
Well, they're really mad at me
right now
because they're adjusting
to the idea that
I may spend half the week
in Minnesota.
I'm adjusting to that idea,
as well.
Late!
None of us like it.
Late! Excuse me!
Late!
Cardio Tech Room 342.
Have you, uh,
told her yet?
No.
Webber?
No. And I don't like
this line of questioning.
Thank you
for the coffee.
Have a great day.
♪♪
It's locked.
Why would it be locked?
Welcome to grand rounds.
This is not your typical
grand rounds.
There's no lecture hall.
There are
no slide-show presentations.
This is grand rounds
on its feet.
What does that mean?
It means...
you'll be coming with me.
Nice to meet everyone.
I'm Dr. Addison Montgomery.
♪♪
And you must be the group
that's been
screwing up the program.
Uh...
Kidding.
♪♪
Oh, my.
Follow her, people!
Oh, my God.
Oh!
♪♪
Mm.
Ohh.
Dr. Robinson
to Nuclear Medicine.
Do I look like a batch
of raw cookie dough to you?
Why are you trying
to bake me alive?
Let these
automatic doors close.
Dr. Mahoney to the ER.
Chief?
Dr. Altman says that you put her
in charge of "fun"
and that
I have to wear this.
I'm starting to think
the heat may have influenced
my decision-making.
Dr. Eisenberg, 4673.
Hold still, please.
Dr. Lin,
how are you settling in?
Besides being told
to wear a hat to work
on a 100-degree day, just fine.
Thank you.
Ow! Ow! Ooh!
Dare I ask?
Second-degree burns to
the buttocks and upper thigh.
Needs debriding.
My buddy dared me to fry an egg
on the sidewalk
for our web channel,
NakedBroStuff.
And I fell on my butt.
Naked.
For more views.
And it worked, bro.
That egg got full-on fried.
Yeah, he also fried
through his epidermis.
Epic fail because of the burns
and the blisters,
but look at
how many likes we got.
We're gonna go viral.
Dude, check this out.
Some chick gets shot off
the back of a Jet Ski
and the water went
straight up her --
"Some chick?"
This will hurt a lot less
if you hold still
and stop referring to women
as baby birds.
Where are all of
the residents today?
There's been monumental progress
made in infertility,
but there is much
more work to be done.
With my background in obstetrics
and medical genetics...
And as one of
the foremost
neonatal surgeons
in the country.
...I will always endeavor
to find more options
for women who want
to become mothers.
Why isn't her grand rounds
for OB?
Damn it!
Save me a spot.
I'll be back.
Fix your face.
It's Addison Forbes Montgomery.
Apparently, she and Grey
have a "history."
And whatever happened,
I'm Team Grey.
I heard Dr. Grey cheated with
her husband, Dr. Shepherd.
You mean Dr. Grey's husband,
Derek Shepherd?
No. M-Maybe.
I'm confused.
Uh-huh.I heard he was married
to both of them.
Probably not
at the same time.
Would you guys shut up?
You.
Middle left.
Yeah, you.
What's your name?
Schmitt?
Is that a question?
No?
Schmitt, what are the vessels
found in the broad ligament?
Um, blood vessels
to the ovaries,
fallopian tubes,
and uterus?
Uterus --
not a question.
Correct.
Congratulations.
You're presenting.
Today's case is
a groundbreaking procedure
that has the potential
to change the game
for both fertility
and childbirth.
I will be performing
Grey-Sloan Memorial's
first surgical
uterine transplant.
Go ahead, Dr. Schmitt.
Oh, on my feet.
Okay.
Um...Tovah Freedman,
33 years old.
G-4, P-zero.
Had a complete hysterectomy
two years ago this January.
Secondary to
a placental abruption
in the second trimester.
Taking out the uterus was
unavoidable with the hemorrhage.
We couldn't save the baby,
but Tovah really wanted
to be a mother.
I was the youngest of five,
and, yet,
I was always the mom
when we played house.
And when I found out that
Jonathan was also one of five,
it was...
b'shert.
"Meant to be."
In Yiddish.
I had my first miscarriage
about six months
after we were married.
Then it was pretty much
one a year
until we made it to
the second trimester,
and I had the abruption
and lost the baby.
And then it got worse.
Jonathan was diagnosed
with malignant mesothelioma.
And before he did chemo,
we froze his sperm.
When Jonathan passed away,
I couldn't imagine
being a parent without him.
But then I heard about
Dr. Montgomery's clinical trial
and I realized that
I could be
the mom I was meant to be...
and maybe even bring
my and Jonathan's baby
into the world myself.
Tovah is the last patient
in my trial,
and her family's
here in Seattle,
so she has
a solid support system.
If all goes well,
I will have met my criteria
to publish my first round
of patient results,
which means
we're that much closer
to changing fertility
all over the world.
And one lucky resident
will be credited
when she publishes.
Oh!
Dr. Schmitt, you'll be scrubbing
in to assist me today.
Good. Dr. Schmitt,
start your pre-op.
Everyone else,
let's file out.
♪♪
Hi, hi,
uh, Dr. Montgomery.
Are you an OB resident?
Yes! Dr. Wilson.
Great!
Can you get me some coffee?
Black and sweet.
♪♪
Say it again.
Rashida,
a donor kidney has been found,
and it's on its way here
to Grey-Sloan for you.
Did y'all hear that?
Dr. Ndugu got it done.
Say hi, Dr. Ndugu!
Hey, followers!
Mm.
Mnh-mnh.
Forget it, y'all.
He's married.
Bye!
♪♪
Is this really happening?
It's really happening.
Ohh!
I can't believe this.
I want to thank the donor.
I want to thank their family.
You can thank them by getting
well and living your best life.
Who's doing the transplant?
I am still
confirming that.
But I'll be back soon,
alright?
♪♪
Hi.
Oh, you're back.
Yes.
Good, good. You know what?
I have so many ideas, you know?
Ideas?
Yeah, ideas, thoughts,
proposals.
You and I are gonna update
this teaching program together.
Okay. Well,
we should talk, because --
Oh, and not just
grand rounds.
I think we should bring in
visiting surgeons each week.
And, also,
we should start
video-recording
the surgeries again.
I mean,
it's the best way to learn.
They -- They can see
what went wrong
and how the team adapted.
Well, what do you think?
I...
It's a great idea.
♪♪
Come on. Come on.
-Hi. Hey, Dr. Grey.
-Hi, Dr. Grey.
-Welcome back, Dr. Grey.
-Missed you.
♪♪
Hunt.
My man.
Hey.
You are
a general surgeon.
Mm-hmm.
And you're skilled.
And you might be
head of trauma,
but don't you ever
think to yourself like,
"Man, it sure would be cool to
not just do trauma"?
You sound like a person
who's about to ask for a favor.
I need you to do
a kidney transplant.
Hmm.
Yeah, I know.
Webber's got grand rounds,
and -- and Grey's got a surgery.
And I-I definitely
can't ask Bailey.
Why not?
Well, because Bailey thought
there was no way
to get my patient on
the transplant list, and I...
came up with a way.
Would I be committing
some kind of a crime
if I did this favor?
No, no.
Definitely not.
But I will owe you one.
Okay.
Alright.
Thanks.
Thank you.
What do we have?
16-year-old female.
Hemodynamically normal.
Hydrostatic
pelvic injury.
Water plowed up and cut through
her entire pelvic region.
What? How?
She fell off a Jet Ski.
Or was blasted off.
Apparently,
it's all over the Internet.
No!
That video was for real?
Tovah, eyes on me.
Okay.
We have you, okay?
And the uterus?
It's being prepped
as we speak.
I hope it works.
I'm going to do
my absolute best.
And remember that whatever
happens is, um...
B'shert.
Mm-hmm?
I heard
there were sex parties.
Greys, Shepherds, Yangs --
all of 'em.
And they survived a plane crash
together.
What does that have to do
with Dr. Montgomery?
Pretty sure
she was on the plane.
She wasn't.
It was the Seattle Grace Six.
Or Five.
Definitely not Seven.
No --Groundbreaking surgery happening
below us right now, so shut up!
♪♪
Grand rounds on its feet
means that
you will be asked questions
during surgeries.
All of you.
So maybe you want to
put away the chips.
♪♪
You ready?
Ready.
Scalpel.
♪♪
Why is the uterine transplant
removed
after one or two healthy babies
are born?
♪♪
Okay, if I don't get an answer
in five seconds,
I'm clearing the gallery.
You want to limit
the immunosuppressive drugs
on the patient.
Okay, Dr. Schmitt,
is she right?
She is.
I swear, my 8-year-old listens
better than some of these guys.
You asked me
for an OR.
I didn't tell you
it wouldn't come with a price.
Now,
who can tell me where
the uterine arteries
are branched from?
Ooh, ooh!
♪♪
Hello, Lily.
I'm Dr. Hayes.
How are you feeling?
Oh.
Alright.
There we go.
I feel like that.
Mm-hmm.
Sorry.
Don't be.
I'm used to it.
I've developed reflexes
like a cat.
I'm seeing free fluid
in the abdomen.
Mm-hmm.
Pressure looks stable.
Lily, we need to get you
upstairs for a CT scan.
Are your parents here?
Lily!
Oh, my God.
I'm so sorry.
I-I didn't even realize
she slipped off the back.
Is she okay?
Hey, are you a friend?
Yeah.
I'm -- I'm -- I'm Micah.
Okay.
Micah, uh, we're going to
take care of her,
but Lily has had
the equivalent of a fire hose
blasted up
her undercarriage,
so we need to get ahold of
her parents right away.
I need you to call them
and tell them to
get down here right now.
No!
She hates them, like,
really hates them.
And, um...they don't know
she was meeting me IRL.
Understood. I still need you
to call them -- IRL.
No!
Lily, your parents are going to
be worried sick about you.
Not if they don't know.
You're 16 years old.
We have to call your parents.
Am I dying?
No.
Then I'm not calling them.
♪♪
What is the benefit of using
a deceased donor uterus
versus a live one?
The larger vessels
of the cadaver
can be used
for the anastomoses,
simplifying the procedure.
Is he allowed to answer?
No.
I've never done
one of these either.
Good dissection here.
Ready for the uterus.
♪♪
Oh, come on!
-Shh!
-You shush!
♪♪
Dr. Schmitt, can you point out
the uterine artery and vein?
♪♪
What the hell was that?
Noah,
this is Owen Hunt again.
I've left you a few messages.
Can you please call me back?
Thank you.
Well...crap.
You heard that, too,
right?
Air-conditioning system
is overworked.
A bit like the rest of us,
Chief, you know?
Ugh.
Jet Skis.
Basically just
motorcycles on water.
Nothing good
ever comes out of them.
Except fun.
Is it just me
or are all teenagers
losing their minds
right now?
Teenagers don't
have minds to lose.
Micah?
He's in the waiting room,
Lily.
Just try and hold still,
okay?
You know, I have OCD.
I don't like germs.
I don't like disorder.
This world is full
of both of them.
I wish I could
lock my kids in the house,
away from all of it.
But if you lock your kids up
too tight,
you run the risk of
locking up their minds.
Their wildly immature,
under-developed,
overly hormonal minds.
You know,
we've all been through a trauma
this past year and a half,
but the kids --
they don't even know
how to ask for help.
So they blast off
on Jet Skis
with "friends" they met
on the Internet.
She's got free air.
I suspect
her rectum is perforated.
Let's book her for an ex-lap
immediately.
♪♪
Optimum temperature
in the OR, Schmitt?
Between
68 and 75 degrees?
Correct. But it's really the
surgeon's personal preference.
Oh, good. Then can we prefer
that we turn it down in here?
66 degrees, please.
The AC is out.
The whole hospital is down.
I need to start
transferring surgeries.
Tseng, Ortiz, Chee,
you'll help.
How long will it take you
to close Tovah?
I'm halfway through
a complex
end-to-side vascular
anastomosis, Richard.
I can handle
a little heat.
The HVAC system controls
the air filtration
in the hospital.
You'll need to close her
as soon as possible
to prevent infection.
I'm not stopping
Tovah's transplant.
She's been waiting
months for this.
Then find a way
to double your speed.
Find me a set of hands
who's experienced in
microvascular anastomosis
of the abdomen.
Get me Meredith Grey.
Get all available staff to put
portable AC units and fans
in the ICU
and close any open window.
It's cooler in here
than it is out there.
For now.
What's going on?
The HVAC's out.
All surgeries are canceled
or postponed.
We need to divert trauma.
I have a kidney transplant.
It's already en route.
Tell them to call
the next person on the list.
Our patient is down to her last
access point for dialysis.
She's at severe risk
for bacteremia or sepsis.
I just got approval
from the transplant board
to list her with
medically urgent status.
I'm sorry, Winston.
There is a protocol
for when and if
the hospital HVAC blows out.
I just never thought
we'd have to use it.
Woman over P.A.:
Nurse Kruger to the OR.
She can't wait
for the next one.
She's getting sicker
every day
because I made the decision
not to put in a permanent port.
Why?
It's complicated.
But she needs this kidney.
She needs it,
and I need her to get it.
Okay.
Where are you going?
I'm gonna save your kidney.
♪♪
Dr. Grey.
Dr. Montgomery. Congratulations.
Uterine transplant.
Congratulations to you, too.
Abdominal-wall transplant.
Dr. Grey also assisted on
an abdominal-wall transplant
that included the penis.
Yes,
I read about that one, too.
She won
a Catherine Fox award,
performed several
ALPPS procedures,
and built mini-livers
in the lab.
Yes, Helm, we got it.
Thank you so much.
♪♪
Have you prepared
the external iliac on my side?
I have.
8-0 Prolene.
♪♪
Thank you.
Okay, so,
I closed us to trauma.
I diverted the rigs
to Seattle Pres.
Should we let the walk-ins know
about the situation?
What do you mean
"outsourced"?
You manage the facilities.
Uh --
Hello?
Apparently, our specialized
industrial HVAC company
is overwhelmed with calls
from all over the city.
You canceled
my double-knee replacement?
It's 87 degrees
in OR 3.
Well, it was hotter in Iraq.
Honestly, this is balmy.
Yes, I'm still holding.
I should go
check on Scout.
Oh,
I was just in the daycare.
Everyone's good.
They've got a snow-cone guy.
Hopped up on sugar,
but good.
I'm more worried about
the babies in the NICU.
Immunocompromised and unable
to regulate their temperature?
Yeah, should we consider
transferring them?
No ETA
for our HVAC team.
I could take a look.
Where is it?
The HVAC?
I'm good
at fixing things.
Oh, oh.
I-I can assist.
I just installed a window unit
this morning.
Wow. That's it?
Yep.
You're gonna do my surgery
on a Mack Truck?
It's not a truck.
Or it is,
but it's also
a fully operational OR.
It was designed for emergency
surgeries in the field.
It's incredible.
I gotta warn you guys --
it's chilly in here.
Do you guys have jackets?
Ooh!
Is he single?
Can I post live?
No and no.
Thanks for coming.
Hey...
But if
the fire chief asks,
I did not drive this here.
And if your wife asks,
same.
Are you serious?
The way I see it,
we're in a Grey-Sloan annex.
Let's go.
Okay.
♪♪
Oh, my God.
Shepherd.
Dr. Bartley, hey!
I am so sorry that
I missed our call earlier.
What happened?
I had a complication
in the OR,
and it took longer
than I expected.
Your head.
You hurt?
Oh, no.
I'm fine.
Just incredibly hot.
Uh, historic
Seattle heat wave.
Even the hospital is not
as cool as it should be.
Got it. I got the MRI scans
on the latest mice group.
And?
74% showed that the transplanted
cells are functional.
Oh, my God!
That's fantastic news.
Meh. I see it as a need for
26% improvement.
I want to start another group
next week.
Can you get up here by then, do
some trouble-shooting with me?
I would be thrilled.
Absolutely, yeah.
Thanks.
Close your eyes.
Um...
Okay.
You're in Lake Superior
in late fall,
right before
it freezes over.
No wetsuit, no sunshine.
It's the type of cold that
makes your fingers ache
and your eyelashes frost.
Your whole body chatters,
not just your teeth.
♪♪
Uh...are you trying to
guide-meditate me
into feeling cool?
Did it work?
I mean,
it didn't not work.
See you next week,
Shepherd.
♪♪
Doppler.
So, what's next,
Dr. Grey?
Uh, just finishing up
this last stitch here.
No,
I meant for you.
I will win the Fox award this
year for uterine transplants,
but what will earn you
second place?
To be honest, I could give you
a run for first
if I could get my logistics and
responsibilities here sorted.
Have to have
some difficult conversations.
Richard.
I'm not hearing a signal.
What do you mean?
I don't hear anything
on the Doppler.
Anastomosis looks perfect.
Damn it. There must be a clot
in the vessel.
Okay, we'll have to
reopen the anastomosis.
You just finished.
Well, it's all for nothing if
we don't get proper blood flow.
Let's re-open the anastomosis.
Now, Schmitt.
♪♪
This is...
not a window unit.
Nope.
NICU babies.
Let's give it a try,
then.
Yeah.
Uh...
Hey, I'm -- I'm -- I'm sorry
about you and Amelia.
Well, I'm sorry I didn't make it
to the wedding.
Oh, please.
It was impromptu.
I mean, 20 years in the making,
but impromptu.
Oh, my God!
What is it,
like, 120 up here?
You know, my body adjusted to
extreme heat in Iraq.
I'm not even sweating.
That sounds more like
dehydration.
♪♪
So, what's the plan?
Still coming up
with one.
♪♪
How about that?
Careful.
Oh.
Uh, lap pads for Lily
and my face.
Catheter.
I take it this isn't typical
summer weather in Seattle?
You didn't live here
last summer?
I don't remember seasons
during the pandemic.
What is it
about closing the ORs
that is so difficult
to understand?
This patient should have
been transferred!
And I chose
not to do that.
My patient, my call.
You're working with bowel.
The risk of infection --
Did not outweigh the need
for my patient to receive
immediate surgical care.
And the longer you stand there
arguing with me about it,
the longer it's gonna take
to get what you want,
which is no operating
in this OR.
Have anything else
to say about it?
Eh!
♪♪
Didn't think
that would work.
It works on my two teenage boys
every day.
3-0 Vicryl.
♪♪
♪ Caught in the morning low
Addison:
Okay, we've got good inflow.
Heparinized saline.
Won't the graft die
if this doesn't work?
Not if Dr. Montgomery can
dissolve or dislodge the clot.
♪♪
Still no flow.
We should use a Fogarty.
Fogarty Catheter.
♪ Pulled by the undertow
♪ An infinite map
with no directions ♪
Inflate the cuff slowly.
Pull back gently.
♪♪
Yes!
Well done, team!
You okay, Schmitt?
Who? Me?
I actually enjoy a shvitz.
"Sweat" in Yiddish.
Yeah, I know.
♪ ...away
Feels like old times --
you manning the anesthesia.
Don't get used to it.
Warren, I can't thank you
enough.
I'm just happy that
somebody's using this thing.
Well,
why'd it get benched?
There was an incident
with my, um --
with a junkie
with a gun.
And the department didn't love
that there was
a traveling target
for drug addicts
who were desperate enough
to hijack us for fentanyl.
Fair, but there must be
a solution.
Trust me, I pled my case,
but, you know, no dice.
Now it's just a very expensive
piece of machinery
that sits out back
of the firehouse,
waiting for the day when someone
will let me dust it off.
Hmm. Or some stubborn surgeon
asks you to borrow it.
And Grey-Sloan
paid for it, alright?
Grey-Sloan can decide
what to do with it.
Plus, you know,
no one ever
accused us of
being rule followers.
Well, I generally am
a rule follower,
unless the rules mean
my patient can't get
the kidney she deserves.
Wait, wait, wait. Is this
an illegal kidney transplant?
Okay, d-does my wife know
that I'm here?
No, but she's the one
who told me
to fight
the broken system.
By breaking the rules?
No.
Yeah, I didn't think so.
Anyway, no,
I didn't steal a kidney.
And even if we had,
it wouldn't matter now,
because there's urine
in the Foley.
Rashida now has
a functioning kidney.
♪ ...away
Come on!
Damn it!
Sorry.
I'm...hot...
and I just wanted to...
fix something.
I just wanted
to fix something!
Some things are harder to fix
than others.
I'm in love with her.
I'm in love with her
and I don't even think
she even thinks about me.
She's planning trips
without me.
She's -- She thinks
I'm old-fashioned.
She...
I mean,
I don't even know.
She thinks I'm trying
to control her
because I want some --
some commitment from her?
I mean, I don't get it.
I-I don't get it!
This is not what I wanted
for my kid.
This is -- This is --
This is what I had!
This is not
what I want for Scout.
I've been there.
For whatever it's worth,
I have been right where you are.
♪♪
I'm sorry.
I'm just really hot.
I made people put on hats.
For fun on
the hottest day of the year.
♪♪
Yeah,
you want to do fun today...
think cool.
♪♪
Zander, they're coming.
So, what happened?
Shh, shh, shh!
Did they have it out
in the OR?
No, but there
was tension.
There was definitely tension.
We can hear you.
Stairs.
Yes!
Go, go!
Oh.
I thought...
♪♪
...coming back here...
...to Seattle,
to Grey-Sloan,
that, uh, he'd be here,
that I would be able to feel
that he was still here...
♪♪
...in the city
that he loved,
with the people he loved,
but he isn't.
♪♪
And it's real.
He's not here.
And I'm really sorry
I'm doing this in front of you,
because you're the one who had
to actually go through it.
♪♪
Addison...
...he is here.
And he's in
his children.
And they are very real.
And I would love for you
to come and meet them.
♪♪
Meredith...
...you've never been one
to shy away from
fighting for
what you love.
So if you believe in
this next big thing,
fight for it.
♪♪
Richard will understand.
Grey made her cry,
and I'm here for it.
Okay, thank you.
Mm.
Congratulations.
So far, so good.
There's minimal output
from her drains.
Doppler studies
look good.
But the true success will be
when she gets pregnant
and, uh, we deliver
a healthy baby.
I'm sorry about
the HVAC.
It wasn't designed
to be pushed that hard.
The Earth wasn't designed
to push this hard.
And speaking of
pushing hard,
your residents are almost there,
Richard.
You made it sound
catastrophic.
Well, they aren't like
you and Derek back in New York.
I mean, I remember you two
were machines.
All this generation wants to do
is complain.
They're not complaining,
Richard.
They're standing up
for themselves.
They're not willing to be worked
to death by a system that,
frankly, should have been
considered inhumane.
I think that's progress.
Doctors are overworked.
You know, they're getting sick.
They're retiring early.
There's a reason for that.
You're saying
it's our fault?
I'm saying that
we can do better.
I'm saying...
there's always room
for improvement.
And, okay, yeah...
sometimes
they're a little whiny.
It's really good
to see you, Addie.
♪♪
It's good to see you, too,
Richard.
♪♪
She's not gonna die,
right?
No.
But she's got some
pretty serious injuries
and a long road
ahead of her.
So I need Lily's phone,
Micah.
I need to talk
to her parents.
Lily says
her parents don't know her.
They just want to
track her phone
and control
everything she does.
Okay.
But, on the other hand,
if she doesn't talk to them
and if she keeps secrets
from them,
how are they supposed
to know her?
How are they supposed to
feel safe?
even breathe?
She says all they do
is yell at her.
'Cause it's impossible.
Because you've loved them really
well all their damn lives,
and then, all of a sudden,
they turn 14
and they don't want to have
anything to do with you.
♪♪
And you can see
that they're hurting.
You can see their pain
and their fear, their panic.
And they used to talk to you
about everything
and cling to your leg.
Now they just slam doors
and stare at their phones
and tune you out.
And, yeah, it's --
it's really hard
being a teenager.
I remember it.
I remember how
my father used to shout.
I remember how I used to
hate him sometimes.
But do you know what,
Micah?
It's also really hard being
the parent of a teenager.
So if Lily's parents
have been controlling,
maybe they have a reason
to be scared.
♪♪
Alright, Micah,
Lily's gonna be crapping into
a bag for the next six months,
so unless you're gonna be
the one to help clean that up,
I suggest
you unlock her phone.
♪♪
Thank you.
There you are.
You saved
the grand rounds surgery.
The HVAC team
finally got here,
and the AC is on
in the ICU and the NICU.
The whole hospital
should be back soon.
Thank God.
Can we talk about
the residency program?
Yes! Ah!
And I hope I'm not
stepping on any toes,
but I really think the two of us
can revamp this whole thing.
Except it won't be
the two of us.
You're gonna take the job
in Minnesota.
Yes and no.
I was offered an opportunity
that I just cannot turn down.
Well, what is it?It's an opportunity
that I cannot turn down.
Oh, I see.
It is so good that
you can't even talk about it.
I'll split my time
between here and there.
And I'll stay on as
chief of general surgery,
but I do have to
give up the residents.
It would not
be fair to them.
And, quite honestly, Richard,
I think it's wrong
for anyone to have that job
but you.
Yeah, you're just saying that
to make me feel better.
So?
So I will be honored
to stay in the role.
I thank you.
Uh, Meredith,
uh, eventually,
you will tell me what it is,
right?
♪♪
Right?!
Her labs look incredible.
And she's got a full bag
of urine.
Did --
Did it work?
Do I have a kidney?
It did.
Everything looks great,
Rashida.
Ooh!
Thailand, get ready.
Yeah, you deserve to celebrate.
And so do you
with your doctor-wife.
And somewhere cool.
Well, unfortunately,
she's out of town.
But I did score an invite to the
coolest place in the hospital.
Um...hello.
Where?
Okay, it is definitely
cooler down here.
The morgue?
We got invited to the morgue?
Unh-unh. No.
I got invited.
You just followed me.
Hey!
Come on in!
Grab a snow cone,
cool off.
Wow! This is weird.
But fun, right?
Sure. Thanks.
I delivered two babies today
in 115-degree heat.
I mean,
it's not a competition,
but I did help out on
a successful uterine transplant.
"It's not a competition, but
I did help out on a" bleh-bleh!
Residents can feel like
they're being pulled
in a zillion directions.
You'll get in on
the next cool thing.
Are you seriously telling me
how it feels to be a resident?
I tell you how it feels
to be a resident.
Mm-hmm. Okay.
Oh, b-b-but if Dr. Montgomery
comes back
to deliver
Uterine Transplant's baby,
put a good word in for me
so I can get in on it?
Mm.
W--
Ambassador of Fun.
Yeah, nice job, Altman.
Creepy, but
nice.
People are dying
to get in here!
No.
They're not.
♪ I know there's gunna be
some brighter days ♪
For me,
the boiling point is more about
stuff bubbling up
from the bottom.
♪ I swear that love
will find you in your pain ♪
Oh, my God.
♪ I feel it in me
like the beating of life ♪
♪ In my veins Oh!
Oh!
♪ I know there's gunna be
some brighter days ♪
Oh, my God! I have been waiting
for this moment all day.
I was stuck over a brain when
the stupid AC went out.
I was over a uterus.
Oh.
Oh, good.
The air is back on just as
we're leaving for the day.
Typical of this place.
Oh!
So, where do you want
to go for dinner?
Your place.
Meredith invited me over.
She did?
Mm-hmm.
Is that weird?
Why would it be weird?
No reason.
Though I did hear that you guys
had a threesome one time.
I heard
it was a foursome.
Mm.
So...
♪ I feel it in me like the
beating of life in my veins ♪
It's about stuff you haven't
thought about in a while.
It's about stuff
that's been heating up
while you weren't even
paying attention.
♪ I know there's gunna be
some brighter days ♪
Hey. Listen,
I know you're scared.
No.
Noah...
Noah,
I know you're scared.
I know you're in pain.
But you should also know that
there are so many others
just like you who are also
scared and also in pain
because the military doesn't
want to take responsibility.
♪ Oh, if your walls
are crashing down ♪
The only way to help all of you
is to at least try to fight,
because
that is what we do.
We fight for what is right
for as long as we can.
And I will help you, Noah,
every step of the way.
♪ I know there's gunna be
some brighter days ♪
♪ I swear that love will
find you in your pain ♪
The question is...
...how well
can you contain things
before they boil over?
♪ I feel it in me like the
beating of life in my veins ♪
What do you need from me?
♪ I know there's gunna be
some brighter days ♪
I need to know everything
that you know --
what the V.A. said to you,
your story, and everyone else's.
♪ I know there's gunna be
some brighter days ♪
♪♪
♪ Oh-oh, oh-oh-oh-oh
Okay.
Come in.
♪ Oh-oh, oh-oh-oh-oh
The thing is, even if things
don't boil over completely,
they can still simmer.
♪ Oh-oh, oh-oh-oh-oh
We're here!
Come meet somebody,
guys.
Hi!
Hey. So, this is
Zola and Bailey.
And the youngest one
is Ellis.
She's upstairs,
in a mood.
She gets it from me.
♪ Oh-oh, oh-oh-oh-oh
Hi.
Hi.  Hello.
Were you
Daddy's friend?
I was, yes.
Uh, I'm, uh, I'm Addison.
But he --
he called me Addie.
And as long as you're careful
how you handle yourself...
Want some ice cream,
Addie?
I would.
I would love that.
♪ I know there's gunna be
some brighter days ♪
Oh, wow!
Look at this.
♪ I swear that love will
find you in your pain ♪
Is this rainbow sherbet?
Yeah, and guess what --
rainbow everywhere, too.
I mean, and a pizza.
And sprinkles.
Who doesn't like sprinkles?
I know, right?
Which topping
do you like the best?
Um...
Mini chips.
Yeah.
Oh!
Skittles?
Psych.
...you won't get burned.
You guys, guess what.
I'm falling more in love
with you every second.
Thank you.
Every stinkin' second.
♪ I know there's gunna be
some brighter days ♪
♪♪