If I learned anything
from growing up in a hospital,
it's that the standard of care
changes over the years.
Our meta-analysis
confirms the correlation
between the gut microbiome
and Alzheimer's.
Let's look at the data.
Wait. What is this?
I made some changes.
Because all these institutions
kept rejecting us.
So if we want
to win this grant,
I thought we need
more patient data.
Ellis broke the drawer!
- We just moved in.
- I didn't mean to!
It's okay.
I-I can fix it.
Uh, make sure
you triple proofread.
If Pitney is judging,
he points out every typo
passive-aggressively.
Did Nick tell you
he won the Blaisdell
Grant four years ago?
You did?
Yeah.
The judges are tough.
The competition's tougher.
You fire questions at each
other in the final round.
Alright. I am regretting
not studying on the plane.
A 373% increase
in Alzheimer's diagnosis
among
30 to 44-year-olds?
Yeah, we had
a 41-year-old patient.
University professor.
You should put it
in your presentation.
Your patients are fire
compared to these slides.
Not as fire as getting there
on time. We should go.
Oh. Yeah.
-Love you.
-Good luck.
Thank you.
If you had a cold
in the late 1800s,
your doctor would prescribe
heroin as a cough suppressant.
If you had schizophrenia
in the 1930s,
your doctor would perform
a lobotomy.
But despite the increase
in knowledge and research,
doctors still aren't perfect.
So now that
we're engaged...
Mm-hmm.
...the real question is...
DJ or cover band?
Cover bands
are so cheesy.
I was kind of hoping
that we would have
a really small wedding.
Small like...
50 guests?
No. Like, um...
you, me, the kids,
and...a witness.
We have to
invite my parents.
Oh.
What about Schmitt?
Don't you want him there?
No, it's not that.
I just --
I, you know, have already
done the huge wedding.
I just -- I don't want to
make it a big deal.
So you just want to go
down to the courthouse
and sign the paperwork?
I've done that, too.
Even today,
your doctor's not likely
to offer pain relief
for an I.U.D. placement,
even though it can be more
agonizing than a vasectomy.
We expect doctors
to not make mistakes.
But the history of medicine
is a history
of flawed judgment.
Don't open your eyes.
Nope.
And...
I present to you...
"Molly and Blue:
the greatest bites."
What is this?
Okay. Here we have the
third-date garlic sirloin
that led us to
our very first time...
You know what.
And the six-month anniversary
trip to San Francisco.
Crab cakes.
And the "I love you"
bacon fried rice.
And how did you have
the time to do all of this?
Well --
Here we go.
I thought
it'd be a fun way
for you to relive
a little of your past.
You know?
The tastes, smells.
You know, they're not
gonna make me remember.
Well, experimental surgery
might not, either,
but this is a lot less risky,
so why not try?
Let me guess.
Dave again?
Look. I turned down
his marriage proposal.
I mean, it's hard to
just cut someone out
of your life like that.
I'm late for pre-rounds.
You should go.
I never liked her.
Shouldn't we like
our therapist?
Who says I don't?
She clearly doesn't know
who we are.
Do we?
I mean, isn't -- isn't
that why we see her?
She told us to try an
unconventional marriage.
Because we told her
that sometimes
we are attracted
to other people,
so she's trying to
help us solve the issue.
Oh, so you want
an open marriage
and sleep with
other people?
I didn't say that!
You're not denying it.
Owen! Owen!
I am in love with you.
But if we continue
like this...
I don't want to lose you.
But we both feel
stifled and stuck.
"Stuck."
I want to change this,
but it doesn't feel like you do.
Oh, my grandma asked
where you were last night.
Well, she asked
about Linus,
but I'm pretty sure
that meant you.
Are they...
Us. A year ago. They're
here for interviews.
They look so rested.
We'll be in charge
of them soon.
Unless you're Adams.
No offense.
Oh, no.
No, no, no, no, no.
Wait.
You know someone?
Uh, the woman
in the purple sweater.
We might have
gone out last night
and I maybe might have
slept at her hotel.
What's she doing here?
We didn't talk details.
Who's the kid?
I don't know.
But he wasn't there
when she was doing
things to my neck --
Yes.
We've got prospective
interns visiting today.
And, yes,
that means that you --
You are about to be
second years, so act like it!
Stop standing around.
I want you to
take some initiative.
Make me look good.
Understand?
Where the hell is Kwan?
I'm here!
Here. I'm here.
Late. And sloppy.
You're on scut.
Yeah.
You'll be working
shoulder to shoulder
with the world's most
renowned surgeons attending.
Adams!
Melissa Walker, 52,
presented to the E.D.
three days ago
with abdominal pain,
nausea, fatigue.
Ultrasound
revealed gallstones.
She is now post-op
day two from a lap chole.
LFTs are all normal.
That's the video
I wanted to watch!
No, that one's dumb.
-Mom!
Okay. Jenina, can you take
them to get something to eat?
Oh. Wait.
Can we get something
from the gift shop, too?
Sure. Under $20.
Oh, oh, oh.
Are you in pain?
Mnh. I'm trying to
keep it in for my girls.
I mean, I know they may
look like they only care
about the phone.
Ever since I've been
in the hospital,
t-they're terrified that
they're gonna wake up
one day without me.
Ohh.
I-I understand.
Ohh. Okay.
I thought the surgery
was supposed to
take away the pain.
Yeah.
Uh, unfortunately,
it's probably inflammation
from the procedure,
but Dr. Adams will order
a CT just to make sure.
Okay?
Okay.
Hannah,
how are you doing?
Starving!
How long till we get
this show on the road?
Her INR is a bit high.
I'm sorry.
We should push
your hernia repair to
tomorrow just to be safe.
I'd like to see your labs
at a normal range.
Does that mean
I can eat?
I'll get you a menu.
Okay.
...was closely
linked to the discovery
of amyloid-beta oligomers
and plaques.
So with the correlation
to Alzheimer's confirmed,
our next steps
are how and why.
Our proposal
will significantly expand
our current data
on the microbiota
of the descendants of
people with Alzheimer's.
Is there a problem?
More of a question
about the veracity
of your research.
W-We have data
to support everything.
That's not our concern.
Another team presented
something similar
this morning,
except they're
several steps ahead.
That's impossible.
Who was that?
Where is he?
Grey! Shepherd!
Ohh!
This is a surprise.
Welcome to my lab...
where, uh, ahem, visits
are by appointment only.
Tuesday mornings
are good.
Oh. Meet my vassal,
Tommy.
I prefer protégé.
You're Tom and Tommy?
Well, my given name
is Vincenzo.
I needed something
I could remember.
I'm glad you're here.
I owe you a thank-you note,
and this saves me a stamp.
That abstract you published
was a gripping read.
Gripping enough to present
for a Blaisdell Grant?
Oh, no, no, no, no.
It was just a starting point.
You made it public,
so anyone could use it, right?
We weren't specifically
thinking about you, Tom.
And yet I'm the only one
who seems to have made
a groundbreaking
discovery.
Unless you've also
used antibiotics in mice
to trigger
a significant decrease
in Alzheimer's markers.
Hm? No? No.
Chins up.
Only one of us needs
to find a cure. Right?
Hm.
The girls are
at your brother's?!
He was in town.
Because Vegas
won't let him back.
The last time
he babysat,
he used a credit card
you gave him to --
Hi, Dr. Wilson.
Mr. and Mrs. Kotwani.
I expected to see you
two weeks ago.
So did we.
But this little guy
is as forgetful
about dates
as his father.
I apologized three times
for leaving them at home.
I've been eating dried dates
to induce labor naturally.
We've tried
acupuncture,
sex, long walks.
Passive aggression.
O-Okay, well, um, you
are 14 days overdue,
so we will need
to induce medically.
Can't those drugs
cause complications?
You've reached the point where
you can have complications
if you don't deliver.
I wish
we could keep trying.
Well, we need to
run some tests,
but maybe you'll go
into labor before that.
AJ Angstrum,
return to the admit desk.
Her name's Vivi.
We've been talking,
but when I get home,
I'm gonna ask her
to be my girlfriend.
Jules?
You two know
each other?
We met last night.
Oh.
Convenient.
I'm getting a vibe.
Like -- Like when
my homie Edgar
hooked up with
Elena Alvarez
and then he got
all weird around her.
How about we let
the doctors talk?
Great idea. Millin?
Yeah. Right.
Um. Carlos Navarro, 16.
History of
pectus excavatum.
Presents for the modified Nuss
procedure to raise the sternum.
No past
surgical history.
I'm gonna do a quick
exam, Carlos, alright?
Any, uh,
shortness of breath?
Mnh-mnh.
So...is Carlos
your...son?
I'm his patient
advocate.
Ah.
I work with foster
youth in Texas.
When my caseworker
finally approved my surgery,
Adriana called Dr. Beltran.
They used to
be married.
Yeah. Just not relevant
to your case.
-Ndugu, how are we looking?
-Asymptomatic.
His echo was normal.
Heart sounds great.
Great. That means
we can move forward.
Do you remember
how this works?
Uh, yeah.
You place a curved metal bar
under my rib cage
and then flip it over
to expand my chest.
And Vivi's not gonna be able
to resist me with my new pecs.
Well, right
on the first part.
Can't help you
on the second part.
Millin is gonna get you
prepped for surgery, okay?
Millin?
Yeah. Right. Right.
What she said.
See you soon.
These mice
have a family history
of beta-amyloid plaque.
Now, thanks to
your abstract, we know
that changes in the gut
microbiome can lead to --
Which of my students
knows the answer?
An inflammatory response
in the microglia?
Bingo! You're slow on the
buzzer today, Shepherd.
Not your student
anymore.
Of course, microglia are
crucial to the formation
of beta-amyloid plaques,
so I thought,
what if we use antibiotics
to change their microbiome?
To see if it led to
a reduction in plaque.
It did. By twofold.
Why do you even need
grant money?
You have
the Fox Foundation.
Oh, research funding
is like sex with me.
You can never
have enough.
And if I'd had breakfast, it'd
be coming back up right now.
Okay. Who wouldn't want
a Blaisdell Grant?
It's not just about
the money.
It's about prestige
and notice.
Then you parlay that
into speaking engagements,
a book deal, and...
And maybe you could
cure Alzheimer's.
Well, sure,
but when my work
changes the face
of medicine,
everybody wins.
Even you, Dr. Grey.
Oh. I see
you're keeping busy.
Does this mean
you're feeling better?
It means
I'm a procrastinator,
and Bianca's school play
is in a week.
Oh.
I hope I'm out of here
to see it.
Who's she playing?
A hot hors d'oeuvre. In
"Beauty and the Beast."
You know, I think
she's secretly hoping
the feather duster gets sick
so she can step in.
Mm-hmm.
Oh. Okay.
Your CT results were normal,
but we will give you
something for the pain.
But hopefully it will subside
as your body heals, okay?
Um, order repeat LFTs.
Now we're talkin'!
Two pieces
of banana cake!
Ooh! Y-You want one?
Uh, I wish.
I'm allergic to bananas.
Ever since menopause hit.
Yeah, well, allergies
can start at any time.
Did you develop any others
when you started menopause?
A few.
Some cheeses. Nuts.
Plus the standard symptoms.
Hot flashes, night sweats,
stomach pain.
But I guess that was
the gallbladder.
Well, I ordered
more pain meds.
We'll see if that
does the trick.
Dr. Isenberg, 4-6-7-3.
I read something
about amines
producing
excess serotonin
in people with
carcinoid syndrome.
Bananas, cheeses, nuts.
They're all high in amines.
Uh, you think my patient has
a one-in-a-million cancer?
S-Should she get
a PET scan?
If Bailey asked me to.
Anna's surgery
got pushed.
Do you mind if I do it?
Uh, knock yourself out.
If you're working
on my patients,
Mr. Follett needs
a rectal exam.
Hm. That's gonna
be all you.
Hey. where are
Carlos' pre-op labs?
I haven't put in
the order yet.
Ndugu had me
discharge Miles Aina.
Okay, well,
do you want to tell him
that you're delaying
his surgery or should I?
I will put
the order in A.S.A.P.
Hey. Thank you
for taking Carlos' case.
The favor means a lot.
You know I'm not
doing it for you.
Satellite Pharmacy, 2-1-2-7.
Can someone turn up
the heat in Carlos' room?
He says it's "cold as balls."
It's his words, not mine.
You didn't tell me
your ex worked here.
I didn't know
you worked here.
You didn't say that you were
in town for a patient.
You want
my whole life story?
Just be chill.
Monica's cool with it.
Cool or she doesn't know?
She knows.
Dr. Sarno,
call Oncology, 2-6-2-2.
Hey!
Hey.
I examined your patient with
pulmonary valve stenosis,
and she's cleared
for surgery.
Great.
Whoa!
Look at that rock!
Did you get engaged?
Yes.
Congratulations.
Link did great.
Is there a date?
Uh, no.
We're having a little,
um, debate
about the wedding.
Oh, well, if yours
doesn't kill your priest,
you're one up
on me and Owen.
Hm! Well, you guys don't
set the bar very high.
Okay. Ready for
your Pitoc-- Ohh!
You said
you locked the door!
I said
it didn't have a lock!
Sorry! We were
just trying to induce!
Aah!
Oh, God!
Oh! God!
Oh, God. Oh, God.
Oh, oh.
Is this the guy
who fell upstairs?
Unh! I think
I broke my ass! Ow!
He's got pain
near the tailbone
after falling off his wife
and the hospital bed.
They were trying
to induce labor.
Naturally.
She said she'd divorce me
if I didn't!
Anand, Dr. Hunt
is going to help you.
I'm going back
to Shruti.
She just went on
the Pitocin drip.
Okay, but this
really hurts. Aah!
On a scale of 1 to 10,
it's like a 47!
That is
oddly specific.
And not something you
should tell your wife
while she is in labor.
I'm needed upstairs.
Okay.
Dr. Mousa to the NICU.
Dr. Jennah Mousa to the NICU.
Ah! Hey. What do you know
about bananas and menopause?
Doesn't matter.
Nothing matters.
Whatever it is,
it can't be that bad.
My one night stand
is Beltran's ex-wife.
How did you manage that?
I saw a hot woman
in a bar.
She's here with
a patient from Texas.
So she'll be out of
here soon. Lay low.
I'm on Beltran's service.
And she knows.
Oh, it is that bad.
What do I do?
Get off the case.
He's got my resources,
and now he's going to
get my grant funding.
And so you're upset
he's using your work
to compete against you.
No. I'm upset
his research is good.
Yeah.
I mean, Tom Koracick
has been doing this
for five minutes,
and he's actually
moving the needle.
Yeah, that's what
money does.
And he wants
more of it.
But he doesn't care
about Alzheimer's.
He might as well
be researching
genetically modified
tomatoes.
Well, they are
actually studying those
to see if they fight cancer.
You know what I mean.
I do know what you mean.
I mean,
it's a game to him.
He's never had to search
for a grandmother
who's gone missing
or taken car keys
away from a dad
or look into the eyes
of a mother
who's alive
but not there.
Well, that's something
you have that he does not.
Passion.
I don't think the
Blaisdell Grant judges
care about passion.
You say Koracick's got
the advantage right now,
so all you can do is
make a case for yourself.
That's all you can do.
Might be your last shot.
-You paged?
-Yeah. Possible broken coccyx.
He has swelling and bruising
at the base of the spine.
I'm just ordering
the X-rays.
I didn't even
need a boy!
Anand's wife is being
induced upstairs.
Congratulations.
Whatever. Aah! I have
two teenage daughters.
Do you know how long
it's been since I've
changed a diaper? Aah!
They got a lot more
options now.
Ohh! My house has been
chaos for 17 years.
I've been counting the days
till an empty nest
since my youngest
started high school.
In my mind, Shruti and I
were spending next summer
in Cinque Terre, drinking
prosecco and eating pesto,
but Shruti suddenly
wanted a boy,
so now I've got
a broken ass. Aah!
I still don't see how
those things are related.
You don't want to.
I had my first interview
with an intern candidate.
Very impressive.
Oh no.
It's a strong group.
One of them interned at the
World Health Organization.
Dr. Bailey,
can I show you something?
Mm-hmm.
I overheard Melissa Walker
talking about
her symptoms.
They seem to be in line
with carcinoid syndrome,
so I took her for a PET scan
and sent some labs.
Uh, who asked you to
take her for a PET scan?
No one,
but I was taking in--
Dr. Griffith,
you're on my service.
You can't go running scans
on whatever patients
you want to
just because --
Melissa has a
neuroendocrine tumor.
1.5 centimeters on the
appendix. I'll be damned.
There's also a small
spot on the liver.
I thought her symptoms
were menopause.
Yeah, so did I.
Well, that makes sense.
The tumor is secreting hormones
into the bloodstream.
She needs an appy
and a liver biopsy.
Can Adams take over
your service?
Yeah, I suppose so.
Alright, then,
Griffith, book an O.R.
for you and whoever
you want to assist.
To assist...?
You. You found it.
You take it out.
Uh...solo surgery?
If you don't think
you're ready...
Oh, no, I'm r--
I can do it! Thank you!
Alright. See you
in the operating room.
Yeah. Hey.
Congratulations.
OT Morell to the 3rd-Floor
nurses' station.
Well, Carlos' pre-op labs
came back normal,
which, honestly, as the
intern on this case, you
should be telling me.
Dr. Beltran, I-I swear.
I had no idea.
If -- If you want me off the
case, I completely understand.
Talk me through
the Nuss procedure.
Now would be good.
Uh, get
thoracoscopic access
and perform cryoablation
on the intercostal nerves.
And then?
L-Lateral incisions
either side of the chest.
And then you pass the tunneling
bar under the sternum.
You're prepped.
You're with me.
Unless you want
off this case.
No, no, no.
I'll see you in the O.R.
Okay.
Oh!
I don't have time
to wait in lines.
Uh, hey, have you
ever read about
grid stimulations
to recall memories?
It's only ever been done
successfully on animal models.
Sounds cool.
Or risky and dangerous
and not proven to work,
yet Molly wants it.
I really need to eat
something before surgery.
You never held a retractor
on an empty stomach?
She's not holding
a retractor.
Bailey is letting me
take a lead on an appy.
Wait. You're getting
a solo surgery? I hate you!
Hm. You hate me
or you love me?
Because Bailey said
I could pick an intern
to go in with me.
Beltran's not gonna
release me from her service.
So she doesn't know
you slept with her ex.
- What?
So! It's an appy?
What about you? Technically,
she's your patient.
Um, I still have a bunch
of H&Ps to do for Webber,
but I know
you'll do great.
Well, it looks like
it's just you and me.
Fine. Let's go.
So...she's operating
on your patient?
Who'd you sleep with again?
Okay. You are
8 centimeters dilated.
And it's almost ready
to push.
Where is that
clumsy jerk?!
If you mean your husband,
he is waiting on a CT.
They want to scan
his pelvis and his spine
to make sure he doesn't
have an occult fracture.
This is your first, right?
Um, well,
my daughter's adopted,
but this is my first time
carrying.
When I told my husband
I was pregnant with our first,
he was so happy,
he cried.
This time, he barely
looked up from his phone
and said he'd get the crib
out of the garage.
Here. Let me make you
more comfortable, okay?
I know we've been through
this twice before,
but our son hasn't.
I want him to know
that he's special to us.
But now his dad is probably
gonna miss his birth!
I had to remind him about
that crib at least 10 times!
And -- Crap! I forgot to remind
him about the car seat!
Where's my phone?!
Oh. Uh...okay. Oh.
Here, here, here.
Shruti.
Did you install
the car seat?!
Oh, my God!
Are you in labor?!
What does it look like?!
So I did it!
I induced you!
My sex induced her.
The Pitocin
induced me.
Tell me that you remembered
to take the car seat
out of your trunk
and actually install it!
Okay.
Of course I did.
Take a breath.
You've got this.
I love you.
You're right. Thanks.
I forgot the car seat.
Take me to the parking lot.
You shouldn't ignore
a possible fracture.
Are you married?
Because my wife means
the world to me, and
I just want her to be happy,
so can you please
take me back to my car?!
Uh...
Identify the right colon.
Follow the taenia coli
along the cecum
to locate the appendix.
Use the grasper
to clutch the tip
and hold it up towards
the lower right abdomen.
Could you talk to Molly?
As a doctor?
I don't think she understands
that no one knows
how to precisely target
where lost memories are,
and her surgery is scheduled
with Shepherd in two days.
Okay.
You cannot do this.
Thank you.
How do we tell Molly?
No. I mean
you cannot do this.
I am about to perform
my first solo surgery.
It's just an appy.
It's my appy
from start to finish
for the first time.
Melissa has two
scared daughters.
If anything happens
to her, it is on me.
So be my assist
or get out.
Also, instead of talking to me
about Molly's surgery,
try talking to Molly.
Okay. Are we ready?
Scalpel.
Okay. We're ready
to start getting
thoracoscopic access.
Let's drop the lung.
I met Carlos
when he was 12,
and he had a crush
on Vivi back then.
Still hasn't realized
that she's been waiting
for h to make
the first move.
Okay. Are we ready?
SATs look good
with one lung ventilation.
Okay. Millin, get
the Veress needle.
Alright, so, because
the lung is down,
the heart may have moved
from where it normally --
Okay. Needle's in.
Oh. Damn it! He's bleeding.
Why is he bleeding?!
Because you may have
punctured his heart.
I did what?! We need
to page Dr. Ndugu!
Okay, Millin,
I need you to breathe.
Someone page
Dr. Ndugu right now!
Alright. You know what?
It's still loose. Here.
I'll hold it down.
You pull.
Why is this
always so hard?!
I think it's a test.
Survival of the fittest.
Yeah. Hey...
Have you ever done
anything you didn't want to
in order to
help your marriage?
Like what?
Also -- not married.
Really? I mean, something
kind of unconventional.
Did Jo talk to you?
Why would Jo talk to me?
Because we just
got engaged,
and I want a conventional
wedding, she doesn't.
Oh, this is --
this is about you.
Hm.
Oh. Uh, well, you know,
I'm always open to things.
You know? Relationships
are about give-and-take.
That's what I learned
from my parents.
Uh-huh.
So, uh, how long
they been married?
Not as long as they've
been divorced.
First marriage, everything was
"my way or the highway."
Uh, but now they let
a lot of things slide.
Their second marriage seems
to be going a lot better.
Well, take it from someone
who's on his third.
It's a lot of hard work.
Congratulations,
by the way.
I'm sure
you'll be very happy.
Alright.
What happened?
I screwed up and
I punctured his heart.
For all we know, I could have
torn a hole right through it.
Vitals are stable for now.
Where are you going? Get back
in here and help fix this.
Let me see
the size of the needle.
Okay. How does that
compare to a 16-gauge?
It's about the same.
And we use those to do
intracardiac injections.
So what's your
recommendation?
Uh, do a pericardial window
and then place a drain
so that it can heal itself?
Correct. We will
take care of this.
And then you can help
Dr. Beltran finish
the Nuss procedure.
If Dr. Beltran
still wants me --
If you ask me one more time
if I want you on this case,
I'm going to lose my mind.
Focus and stay in lockstep.
Are you ready?
Okay. Good.
Let's see what's going on.
So how's it going?
So far, so good.
I was just about to
check on Mrs. Balaban.
Oh, you can, uh --
You can wait a minute.
My first solo surgery
was monumental.
I called my friends,
my family.
If memory serves, I even
bought a new pair of shoes
for the occasion.
Now I can't tell you
if it was
a cholecystectomy
or a hernia repair.
First one's
always a big deal.
Then so is the second.
10th. 100th.
You got your whole career
ahead of you.
Don't beat yourself up
over one lost surgery.
Ah. First Endoloop is on.
Ready for the next one.
Not so scary, right?
Muscle memory
is a powerful thing.
I wouldn't know.
With that attitude,
you never will.
Here.
Thank you.
Now, now, go slow.
Ah.
Uh...
it's caught in the port.
I need a new one.
It's still slipping.
My hands are big enough.
D-Do you think you have
smaller hands than me?
No. Try again.
Going again.
You know this. You've seen
it done a million times.
Almost there.
Got it!
Scissors.
Separating the appendix
from the cecum.
Endopouch, please.
Yeah.
Let's get it to path.
Well done.
Yeah.
Melissa should be
recovered in time
to see her daughter's
school play.
Before we close,
we would like to acknowledge
the 55 million people living
with Alzheimer's disease.
We feel passionately about
this work because of them.
And a Blaisdell Grant
would not only
help us continue the next
phase of our research,
but you'd be contributing
significantly
to our relentless
pursuit of a cure.
We're happy to take
any questions.
I got --
Hi. Hi. Yeah.
Are you proposing
to test a hypothesis
you've already
confirmed?
No.
No? I have a --
C-Can I -- Yeah.
Uh, theatrics aside,
this sounds like the study
your abstract was based on.
That involved
175 patients.
We would recruit
thousands in order to
identify specific
bacterial strains.
Yeah. Like I said,
more of the same, so...
Can you talk
about the people
you'll enroll
in the study?
Ages, ethnicities,
geographic locations?
Softball game's
at the park, Marsh.
Look, if you want to
make this personal,
let me tell you
about Paul, hm?
John, George, and Ringo.
The Beatles?
Not Beatles. Mice.
I've also got
Jermaine, Tito, Jackie,
Marlon, and Michael.
We're taking Alzheimer's
research to a new level.
That's right. Um...
Theatrics aside,
what about
the female mice?
The -- Excuse me?
Alzheimer's affects twice as
many women as it does men.
So are you only
studying male mice?
Of course. You put a few
female mice in a cage,
and pretty soon you have
a whole social hierarchy.
The young ones are
taking care of the oldest,
and they experience
anxiety and stress,
sometimes resulting
in hair loss.
And their hormone cycles
create fluctuations in behavior
that can render the
whole experiment useless.
Your inexperience
in neurology research
is showing great.
Anyone in this
field of study knows, hm,
female mice are problematic...
Right?
So you're not studying
female mice
because their
reproductive systems
mess with your results?
You catch on quick.
That's pathetic.
And the most asinine excuse
for sexism I've ever heard.
No wonder no one's
ever cured Alzheimer's.
The men who have spent
decades trying to do it
have ignored the patients
who need it the most.
And what's worst of all
is no one in this room
seems interested
in changing any of it.
How can we let this happen
knowing it directly affects us?
Well, thank you all
for your time.
Dr. Binder to 3-West.
How's he doing?
Stable.
Post-op labs look good.
Oh. Hey.
Did it work?
It did.
Thanks to Dr. Beltran.
Thank you.
I'm gonna be able to go
to pool parties, the beach.
You can go with Vivi.
T-That's her name, right?
The girl you like?
Yeah, yeah, she's --
she's okay.
Uh, but now that
I've got this new body,
I should
play the field, right?
No. No.
When you find someone
you can't stop thinking about
and they make you feel things
you've never felt before
and you have a chance
to be with her,
you should call her.
Do you hear me?
Should I go after her?
Millin!
I'm sorry. I'm sorry
if that was out of line.
And I'm sorry that I punctured
that kid's heart.
And I'm sorry that
I didn't strap a patient
onto the O.R. table
properly.
Okay. I -- I'm not sure
about that last one,
but complications happen.
You're an intern.
You're gonna make mistakes.
Hell, I still do.
I slept with Adriana because
I'm going through a breakup.
I don't care.
I mean, I'm not thrilled,
but you know what?
Honestly, the less we talk
about it, the better.
But I am your attending
and I do care about
your surgical training.
And today,
when it mattered most,
you froze and you
got in your own way.
And I know this
because I've been there.
So no matter
how hard it is,
you cannot bring your
personal life into the O.R.
In particular, mine.
Okay?
Yeah. Yeah.
Are you ready
for a visitor?
We both are.
You want to hold him?
Yeah.
Congratulations.
Hey, buddy.
I'm your dad!
I broke my butt for you!
In about five years,
you'll find that hilarious.
I'm so glad we did this.
Hey. There's Mom.
So once we get the results
of your liver biopsy back,
we will work to ensure you have
the best treatment plan.
But your surgery
went beautifully.
I'm bored.
What did I tell you
about using that word?
You don't want to hear it.
Are we going home?
Your mom needs
a little more rest.
She can go home soon.
Can we sleep over?
Is that okay?
Um, if you want.
But you have to let your mom
get some rest.
Can you do that?
We promise.
-Alright.
-We'll send up some games
from the peds floor.
Thanks.
Well done.
You made me look good.
Dr. Bailey,
thank you.
Hm.
So?
How did surgery go?
Oh. It was okay.
It was...
I can't lie. It was the coolest
30 minutes of my...life.
You deserve it.
Jules and I are
gonna get a drink.
Do you want to come?
Uh, uh, n--
I still have to do hand-off
for next shift,
but, um, you should go.
Okay. See you later.
Yeah.
How's Shruti?
Doing better.
The dads are harder
than the moms.
I don't need a big wedding.
I don't need the band
or the slideshow
with photos
or a giant cake.
You're thinking
about cake.
I am.
Yeah.
But the point is...
I just want to
be married to you.
I don't care
about the rest.
I do.
I want the wedding.
I thought that
I didn't because, well,
I've already done it before,
but I've never done it
with you.
I want to.
Can't wait to marry you!
Truly unimaginable.
I think
I insulted Lucas.
He will be fine.
You flew solo
in the O.R. today.
You know, I think that
we should stop worrying
about relationships and
just focus on our careers,
which is why I have decided
swearing off sex for a while.
Yeah, I'm not doing that.
O...kay.
Okay.
That makes sense.
Someone told me that
I need to put my head down
and focus on work.
I'm off the clock.
I'm looking for a mentor.
I'll do your progress notes.
I'll do your rounds.
I will do anything
you want me to.
I'm asking you,
by the way.
Alright. Um...
Meet me for rounds
at 7:00 a.m.
Great.
Do you know who told her
to focus on work? Me.
And then she asks you
to be her mentor?
Well, I think she's
terrified of you, actually.
Well, I can live
with that.
Hey.
I -- I'm sorry.
I-I realized today
I'm not coming off
as supportive --
And I am.
I'm behind you 100% with
whatever treatment you choose.
And I think I'm just...
Well, I --
I'm scared.
I'm sorry, too.
Hey.
What's he doing here?
Beneath the
white coats and fancy titles,
medicine is just
humans treating humans.
I don't want us
to feel stuck.
And I think I didn't
want to admit it
because I had this idea
of what our lives should be,
and everything that therapist
said seems opposite to that,
which is...
Kind of terrifying.
Yeah.
Maybe it doesn't
have to be.
I'm willing to try
something new if you are.
Sometimes it just takes me
a minute to get there.
And...
It's a little weird
picturing you
flirting with
somebody else.
I am a terrible flirt.
You are.
Okay.
If we actually open this...
I don't want to
know any details.
Agreed.
And we check in
regularly.
And...
we stay safe.
And our marriage
comes first.
No serious relationships
or feelings.
Of course.
Are we really doing this?
The most brilliant surgeons
have made
questionable choices.
No one gets it right
all the time.
So, as a doctor,
what do you do?
There's only one choice --
find your team...
work shoulder to shoulder...
let them help you
when you falter.
Tom Koracick
won the grant.
Can't stop seeing
his smug face.
Who knew science was such
a male-dominated world,
even with rodents?
Ellis Grey knew.
She told me about it
her whole life.
Now I can't stop seeing
her gloating face.
What if Amelia and I did
Koracick's experiment
with female mice?
Mm. Okay.
Who will fund it?
I will.
I mean, I know we just
bought this house,
but I have some savings.
And I said this is
personal, and it is.
Mm-hmm.
What do you think?
Honestly, I think --
I think it's a great idea.
How do I become
an investor?
Well, I can't let you
do that
because we don't know
if it'll work.
Look, if I'm gonna
bet on anybody...
it's you.
Let them push you
to make you better.