Stand back.
What was his temp?
102.
Yeah, he's junky and wheezy
on both sides.
Zach's been coughing,
uh, gasping.
It's terrible.
Bibasilar infiltrates.
What does that mean?
Well, most likely, pneumonia.
April, let's start vancomycin,
40 milligrams per kilogram,
and we'll get him admitted
to the PICU.
Oh, God.
Don't worry.
We've got great pediatricians.
Yeah, you can
go up with him.
Dr. Charles,
why didn't you tell me
the truth about my father?
And... And what is that?
That he is a psychopath.
I looked at his chart.
You did, did ya?
Yes.
Before you looked at
your father's chart,
did you agree
to cosign his loan?
No.
You didn't?
Could that maybe be because,
somewhere, you already
knew what he was?
You could have told me.
Sarah, I couldn't tell you.
You know I couldn't.
Yeah, because
he locked you up
with doctor-patient
confidentiality.
He made it so you couldn't
interfere,
went to you
with a bogus complaint.
God, the premeditation,
the manipulation,
it's... He is disgusting.
Or he's just somebody
who is incapable of
empathetic feelings.
Sarah, look, I'm so sorry,
I can't imagine how difficult
this must be,
but I would just hope
that... That...
There might be something
positive in your knowing.
Positive?
Well, just the clarity.
The clarity of the revelation
that your father was
who he was
and he was born that way,
and that his leaving
had absolutely nothing
to do with you.
That's my consolation?
Dr. Charles,
after all of these years...
All these years,
my father finally
walks back into my life,
and it turns out...
He never loved me.
He can never love me.
ED?
Yeah.
Dr. Halstead, it's the PICU.
This is Dr. Halstead.
Yeah, that's right.
Zach Womack, four months old.
Really?
Hey, thank you.
That baby we just
sent up to the PICU...
He never made it there.
We got off the elevator,
a nurse met us,
and she said that Zach
needed some sort of test.
A scan.
She said he needed a scan.
She took him away
and she never
brought him back.
Did you follow up
with Radiology?
No scans were ordered.
And the nurse
they've described
doesn't match
anyone on my staff.
Has someone kidnapped
our baby?
We can't be sure
about that yet.
Oh, no.
No.
Call a Code Pink.
Tell Security to put
the hospital on lockdown.
The ED, including Trauma,
goes on bypass.
Until further notice,
no one comes in or out.
I promise you we're going
to find your baby.
Earl, the hospital's
going on lockdown.
Get to your post.
Yes, sir.
This is Cole.
Code Pink. Code Pink.
Copy that, Code Pink.
Get that patient in now.
Hospital's going on lockdown.
You're going to
Treatment Two.
Jill Fisher, 25 years old.
Her VW Bug got T-boned
by a pickup.
Seat belt sign
and chest wall abrasions.
Gonna need X-ray.
Help me!
I'm her mother.
We are, sweetheart.
BP, 100 over 70.
Heart rate, 96.
She's satting at 88%.
Is she gonna be okay?
We haven't examined her yet,
but we're gonna
take good care of her.
All right,
let's get her transferred
and onto the monitors.
One, two, and three.
Doris, 50 of fentanyl.
On it.
Is she gonna be okay?
Ma'am, please come with me.
I... I love you, honey.
Careful.
Multiple right
posterior rib fractures
and a pneumothorax.
She needs a chest tube.
20 of lidocaine.
Sats are 82 and falling.
All right, so hustle.
Ready for the tube.
She's at 90.
Sats are coming up.
Uh, we're gonna need
a repeat chest X-ray,
and let's order a CT c-spine,
abdomen and pelvis.
Code Pink. Code Pink.
Missing kid?
Yeah.
Probably the baby
Dr. Halstead sent to PICU.
Sorry, yes, I understand.
Step back.
Step back, ma'am.
We'll let you know
as soon as possible.
All right, people, the ED
is officially on bypass.
Lock it down.
Nothing comes in or out.
Keep your eyes open
for a woman,
probably in scrubs,
with an infant.
Doris, triage
the waiting room.
Let's clear out
any rooms we can.
And cycle in the patients
with the most immediate needs.
Got it.
Monique, I want an inventory
of our drugs, blood products,
all critical supplies.
We need to be ready to make do
with what we've got on hand.
Copy.
The cops should've
stopped you. We're on bypass.
We're not leaving.
This guy could die.
Earl, we're not gonna let
this man bleed to death.
Let him in. It's on me.
Come on, let's go. Dr. Choi?
Right here.
You're going to Baghdad.
Let's go, let's go, let's go!
Tim Vance, 30-year-old male.
Bar fight.
Took a long blade
to his left chest.
Heart rate, 120.
BP, 92 over 58.
He stabbed me
over a game of pool.
All right, save your breath.
Let's transfer.
On my count.
Ready, one, two, three.
All right,
no breath sounds on the left.
Hand me the ultrasound.
Code Pink...
The Code Pink could be
the baby I treated.
Man...
He's got a large
pericardial effusion.
Blood's pooling
around the heart.
BP's falling!
Tamponade's compressing
the heart.
He's bradying down.
Start bagging.
Page Dr. Rhodes.
He's not in the hospital.
Big CT event off campus.
They're not gonna let him in
'cause of the lockdown.
Get me another surgeon.
Dr. Latham's in surgery,
and the Trauma service is up
in the OR on another case.
Then splash prep his left
chest and hand me a knife.
I gotta open him up now.
Dr. Rhodes.
Morning.
You know my husband, Larry.
Larry, good to see you.
He's always dragging me
to these things.
I'm an introvert. I hate them.
I am completely
with you there.
Yes, well, there are
a lot of checkbooks here,
and their owners would like
to meet our rising star,
so please...
Go and schmooze.
Ah.
Dad.
Were your ears burning?
We were just talking
about you.
Oh, really?
Yeah.
I told Dr. Bekker
how your mother and I knew,
even when you were
just a little boy,
how you'd be a surgeon.
Do you remember when that dog
got ahold of your
Teddy Ruxpin?
He sewed that little thing
together.
You had a Teddy Ruxpin?
I wouldn't believe everything
my father tells you.
Oh, Connor's always
been uncomfortable
with anything that
smelled of praise.
That's funny,
I never noticed that.
I'm gonna go get
some breakfast.
Try the avocado toast.
We are having a trunk show
next week.
Loro Piana. I would love it
if you'd come as my guest.
I'd love to.
Ava...
Hospital's on lockdown.
Uh-huh. Uh-huh.
Dr. Reese,
Goodwin needs us upstairs
to consult on that Code Pink.
On the way.
Hey.
Code Pink. Code Pink.
All hospital personnel,
please report to
your designated stations.
It was a baby that I treated.
Oh, God.
Patient got in
just under the wire.
Both of you, please.
Good morning.
I'm Dr. Halstead.
This is Dr. Manning.
Hi.
Hello.
Mr. Taylor, I see you're
being treated for lymphoma.
That's right.
He's had multiple rounds
of chemo.
So, what brings you in today?
Woke up this morning,
could hardly breathe.
Our oncologist at East Mercy
said to come here
since it's closer.
Well, it's a good thing
that you did.
Uh, let's get a chest X-ray,
CBC, coags, and a d-dimer,
and also, call over to East
Mercy for his records, okay?
Thank you.
Just try to relax,
Mr. Taylor.
We're gonna run these tests
and sort this out.
Okay.
We'll be back shortly.
Thanks.
Let's hope he's just got
a little bug.
Yeah. Nat...
I can't stand this.
We gotta talk.
I know.
Come over tonight.
We reviewed
all the security cam footage.
No one left the hospital
with the infant.
So he and his abductor
are still on the premises?
We think so.
We would've gotten a ping
from the baby's
ID bracelet
if the abductor had tried
to exit with him.
Dr. Charles,
from your experience,
what kind of person
do you think we're
looking for?
In a majority of these cases,
the abductor is a woman
of child-bearing age,
who is either infertile
or has experienced fetal loss.
Um, they're distraught and
determined one way
or the other
to have a baby of their own.
Then maybe she's not likely
to hurt him.
Not if wanting a child
is what's driving her.
But what if that's
not what's driving her?
What if she's someone who
enjoys causing other's pain,
a person without a conscience?
I mean, it's possible,
and if someone like that
gets backed into a corner,
there's no telling
how she might react.
This person knew
where the PICU was.
Could very well
have been a patient here.
I think we should
compile a list of women
who have experienced
birth trauma here
in the last six months.
All right, and I think
it's a good idea for you
to assign a psychiatrist
to each search team,
help defuse any situation
where the baby may be at risk.
Let's get started.
Daniel...
We've got to find this baby.
Your patient has
a large mediastinal mass
with what looks like positive
nodes throughout his chest.
It's compressing his lungs
and all his major vessels.
That's why he's
so short of breath.
Okay, so, what's next?
Surgery?
Another round of chemo?
A tumor this large?
Even with chemotherapy,
it wouldn't shrink
to an operable size.
Then what?
Um, from his medical records,
it looks like he's had
a solid treatment history.
Unfortunately, we've reached
the limits of what we can do.
So that's it?
We're giving up?
No, there... There has to be
something else we can do.
Uh...
My advice?
The sooner you tell Mr. Taylor
and his wife the prognosis,
the better.
It'll give them a chance
to find some closure.
Hi.
I got your CT results.
In addition to your
rib injury,
you also have a compression
fracture of your L2.
That's a vertebrae
in your lower back.
Now, it's not serious.
Doesn't require surgery...
But because of the chest tube
and the fractures,
we wanna keep you in the
hospital for a couple of days.
Once we get you upstairs,
we'll start you on
a pain-management regimen
and fit you for a brace, okay?
Thank you, Dr. Sexton.
How much time do I have?
Hard to say.
A few weeks, maybe less.
Oh, my God.
I am so sorry.
We can have a hospice nurse
come in and talk to you.
A hospice?
I know.
But hospice will provide
your husband
with the best quality of life
in the time that remains.
I always said
I wanted to die at home.
Looks like I'll get my wish.
It'll be all right, Bev.
Call the kids,
have them come out.
How soon can we leave?
Unfortunately, the hospital
is under lockdown currently,
due to a security issue.
No one is allowed in or out.
But we can start
your discharge paperwork,
and as soon as
the lockdown is lifted,
you'll be able to go home.
Thank you.
It's okay.
Heart rate's down to 80.
All right...
I'm gonna release
the tamponade.
Give me some suction.
Numbers are
still in the tank.
Because he was stabbed
in the heart. He needs blood.
I don't care where he is,
get me Connor.
Just prepare
an innocuous press release,
and then let me know
the second we find that baby.
Dr. Rhodes.
Connor,
I need your help, buddy.
Yeah, okay. Ava.
Surgical suites one and three
aren't in use.
You check those,
we'll cover the rest.
Code Pink. Code Pink.
All hospital personnel,
please report to
your designated stations.
Clear.
So, your description
of our attacker
is someone possibly
without a conscience.
I'm just curious,
what led you to that?
There have been
a number of cases
of women murdering children,
Diane Downs, Susan Smith.
I don't really see
the comparison, though.
I mean, neither of those women
abducted a baby
from a hospital.
You're just speculating, too.
We don't know
who we're dealing with.
There's no guarantee
she's some bereft mother
who's lost a child.
For all we know,
she could be a...
A psychopath?
Dr. Charles, this has
nothing to do with my father.
And just because my opinion
is different from yours
doesn't make it biased.
All clear.
Will, I've been doing
research on Gary's cancer,
and I found a case
where a combination
of bleomycin, etoposide,
and cisplatin
rapidly shrank
germ cell tumors,
so I called
my oncologist friend,
who said it was anecdotal
but possible.
Anecdotal?
There haven't been
any studies,
and it's not approved
by the FDA.
So, you're proposing
we use these drugs off-label?
Will, the man is
terminally ill.
Yes... And I don't wanna
speed up that process,
or cause him
any unnecessary suffering.
Well, I think
it's worth the risk.
I'm sorry, I don't.
What happened to you?
You used to go to any length
to try and save someone.
Yeah,
and it never ended well.
I also have a larger
responsibility now.
Because you're an Attending?
That's right.
So I don't get a say?
I'm sorry, in this case, no.
What you're suggesting
is bad medicine.
Okay.
All right, give me
a view of the medial side
of the left ventricle.
Yeah, good.
Uh, now, Ethan, you're gonna
remove your finger,
and once you get
the stapler in place,
you're gonna close laterally
across the opening.
I can't get
the stapler in place.
It's a moving target.
Keep trying.
Got it. Staple's in.
Good.
No. No, wait,
this isn't working.
Every time I get a staple in,
it tears,
making the hole even bigger.
All right, here.
What are you doing?
I gotta get in there.
The hospital's on lockdown.
They won't let you in.
I have to try.
Help Ethan get him stabilized.
All right, Dr. Choi,
let's see if I can keep you
from killing this patient.
You understand
this is experimental?
I can't guarantee
it'll have any effect
on Mr. Taylor's cancer.
It might even be harmful.
We understand.
And do I have
your permission?
Yes.
Please. Go ahead.
Okay.
Sorry, folks, as soon as
the lockdown is lifted, you'll
all get to see a doctor.
So what? I'm just supposed
to wait here bleeding?
Got no choice, ma'am.
If you're worried,
Lakeshore Memorial's
only a mile away.
Sir, gotta stop you there.
Look, I am a doctor
on staff here, all right?
Sorry, can't let you in.
There is a man
in the emergency room
with a stab wound
in his heart.
Sorry.
If I don't get in there,
he's gonna die.
Not my call.
I wish I could let you in,
but it's not up to me.
Fine.
I will let you in,
as soon as the lockdown is...
Earl, I need to get in there.
Can you help me out?
Come with me.
Look, legally...
I found this tunnel
when we were reviewing
the hospital's emergency
evacuation plan.
Apparently, it was used
to ferry patients
and supplies
between buildings.
But once they put in
the over-street walkways,
it was decommissioned.
Here's your way in.
When you come to the fork,
stay to the right.
At the end of the tunnel,
you'll find a series of doors.
Take the first one
on the right.
That'll put you
inside the hospital.
All right, thanks, Earl.
Oh, and you...
You might need this.
Anyone asks,
it wasn't me who told you.
You got it.
How's she doing?
Um, sleeping.
Good. We're still waiting
for a room to open.
I'm transferring
another patient now,
but Jill's next in line.
Hopefully won't be
much longer.
Dr. Manning, can I see you?
Please excuse me.
You gave him those drugs?
Mmm-hmm.
I told you not to,
and you did it anyway.
His wife wanted
to give 'em a try.
You shouldn't have
even suggested it.
She deserved a choice.
You went behind my back.
I can't believe you did that.
You wouldn't listen to me.
I did listen to you.
I just hope you haven't put
a nail in this man's coffin.
Cole here.
We just got a ping
off the baby's ID bracelet.
She used an emergency exit
stairwell, East Wing.
Wait...
"Zachary Womack."
They were here.
She cut off his bracelet.
She knew the signal
would bring us here.
She's playing a game with us.
His IV.
He's not getting
his antibiotics anymore.
Ah, come on.
I still can't get it in.
Get me a closer look
at the hole.
Here's what I want you to do.
Get two Allis clamps...
Here.
I want you to clamp on
either side of the hole.
Ready.
Okay, April,
you're going to
take hold of the clamps
and lift the heart.
Okay.
As soon as she does,
Dr. Choi,
you'll remove your finger
and see if you can
get the staple in
while it's elevated.
Got it?
Copy.
Here we go.
One, two, three, lift.
It's in. It's working.
Well done.
Ava... Ava,
he's still bleeding.
Give me suction.
He's hypotensive!
Dr. Choi, I need you to snake
your hand around the heart.
What do you feel?
He's got a hole
in the backside.
The knife went
through and through.
Looks like you have
more work to do.
What's happening?
He's in v-fib.
No pulse.
Monique, start bagging.
Doris, get on his chest.
Charge to 150. Clear.
Still in v-fib.
Monique,
push one milligram of epi.
Doris, get back on his chest.
I got it.
Hold compressions.
Clear.
No pulse.
Monique, another milligram
of epi and atropine.
Natalie...
He's gone.
My Gary...
Time of death, 14:30.
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
Just don't even say it.
Nat...
Off-label meds.
Did I kill him?
The man was dying.
I shouldn't have done it.
Uh, yeah, sorry.
Help! There's something wrong
with my daughter.
What's happening?
Her vocal cords are
spasming, blocking airflow.
Help her!
This is Noah's patient.
Where is he?
He had to take
a patient upstairs.
Dr. Choi, we need
some help over here.
I'm a little busy!
Ay-yai-yai-yah.
We need to intubate.
Maggie...
Twenty of etomidate,
10 of sux.
Maggie...
We need a doctor.
Now.
Okay, sweetie.
It's too tight.
I can't get past
the vocal cords.
She's down to 87.
We need a doctor.
Oh, God.
I'll cric her.
Are you crazy?
You can't do that.
Doris, give me a scalpel.
You're not allowed.
It's gotta be a doctor.
Help her!
Give me the scalpel, Doris.
I'm in. Bag her.
Got it.
Sats are coming back up.
He's bradying down.
I can't reach it.
Keep trying.
Heart rate's dropping.
Where are we?
It's about time.
Hole backside of
his left ventricle.
Connor,
here's what's happening.
Whenever they elevate
the heart
to make the repair,
it cuts off his venous return.
Okay, get me
two bags of saline.
April, load up a 2-0 prolene
on a long needle driver.
How'd you get in here?
Long story.
On my count, I want you
to roll him onto his side.
One, two, three.
Up... And down.
All right, Ethan,
when I tell you,
I want you to remove
your finger,
and I'm gonna replace it
with mine.
Ready and go.
Okay, I'm gonna try
to access the hole
from this angle.
Careful,
he bradies down quickly.
All right, stitch is in.
That should temporize
the bleed long enough
to get him up to the OR.
Let's go.
Dr. Bekker, you are amazing.
Thank you.
Dr. Halstead,
Dr. Ray tells me
off-label meds were given
to that patient.
Bleomycin,
etoposide, and cisplatin.
For lymphoma?
I know.
But the patient died
within hours
after the drugs
were administered.
Adverse drug reaction.
We could get sued for this.
Where is Dr. Manning?
Ms. Goodwin, the chart,
it's not correct.
Dr. Manning didn't
prescribe the drugs.
It was me.
You?
I found some
anecdotal evidence
that supported the efficacy
of that cocktail.
Thought we had
nothing to lose.
Dr. Halstead, I had hoped
that you had outgrown
your recklessness.
Clearly, you haven't.
I'm referring this to
the disciplinary committee.
Hey, uh, my patient
in Treatment Two,
who cric'd her?
I did.
What?
You cric'd a patient?
She was in laryngospasm,
you weren't available,
and all my other doctors
were tied up.
A nurse cannot cric.
You should've waited
for a doctor.
She would've died.
And you could've killed her.
Noah...
What?
Maggie's been nursing since
before you started shaving.
So what?
It's against the rules.
She's seen a cric
done 1,000 times.
Okay.
Back off.
Please, we need a doctor.
She's waking up.
Jill? Honey? Can you hear me?
What's wrong with her eye?
She's got a left-sided
facial droop.
I think she might've
had a stroke.
All right, we need to get
her up for a head CT now.
Let's go.
Get ready to bag her.
On it.
One, two, three.
Hey...
You told Dr. Ray
that you prescribed
Gary's meds?
It's no big deal.
Yes, it is.
I own my mistakes, not you.
I feel terrible
that Gary might've died
because of those drugs,
but I am the one
responsible, okay?
You do not need to protect me.
I know that.
Do you?
Do you know that?
Natalie, you are
already miserable.
I didn't want you to have
to deal with all this.
Besides, I'm the Attending.
Ultimately,
it's my responsibility.
Oh, my... Come off it.
Would you have done the same
thing for Ethan or for Noah?
No, because they're men.
They can take care
of themselves.
But not me. I'm just
a helpless little girl.
I have some news.
Security compiled
a list of former patients
who fit the profile
of our abductor,
then cross-referenced them
against today's visitors log.
Turns out, we got a hit.
Joanna Harris.
Would you show them the tape,
please?
Couple of months ago,
Joanna Harris was
in the ED, pregnant.
She lost the baby.
Twenty-two weeks.
Very sad case.
So she impersonated
a healthcare worker
to get to the PICU.
It's entirely possible
that the trauma,
coupled with
the overwhelming fear
of never being able to
carry a baby to term,
uh, pushed her over the edge.
But she seems to have thought
things out pretty thoroughly.
I'd say her actions were
calculated, even predatory.
Well, given what we know
about the patient,
can you think of
where she might've gone?
Some place she could hide.
A supply closet or call room.
Security teams
covered all those.
According to the logs,
Ms. Harris took
our maternity tour last May.
Meaning?
Well, isn't that
when we were transitioning
between the old maternity wing
and the new one?
Yes.
She might know
the old maternity wing.
All right, let's go.
Clear.
Hi, Joanna.
I'm Dr. Charles.
Stay away.
You're not taking him.
Yeah, but the problem is
the baby is... Is very sick.
You can't have him.
He's mine.
And I'm sure you want
the best for him, right?
He needs medicine,
antibiotics,
or else he won't get better.
The fact is,
if the baby doesn't get
some treatment soon,
uh, there's a chance
he could die.
No.
None of us want that.
That's why we're here.
We need to get him
back to his room,
so he can get treated.
Will you let us help him?
I'm afraid.
There's nothing
to be afraid of.
We understand
why you did this.
No one is gonna punish you.
What about them?
They just wanna make sure
that the baby stays safe.
Nothing bad is gonna
happen to you, I promise.
Uh, well,
the important thing here
is that we need to get
some treatment for the baby
as soon as possible.
Give me the baby, Joanna.
I can't. I...
Oh, you can.
You can, trust me.
I'll protect you.
What? No.
Why? I gave you the baby.
You... You lied to me.
You lied to me.
Why did she lie to me?
Yes. Thank you.
Hey, everybody,
they found the baby.
Let's make sure
you check in with Admitting.
You will be seen
in order of need.
For those less seriously
ill or injured,
try to be patient.
We will get to you.
Go ahead, sir.
This way, yeah.
Patient suffered
an ischemic stroke.
Between the unsuccessful
attempt at intubation
and the time it took
to cric her,
the patient's airway was down
for over a minute,
starving the brain of oxygen.
Good thing you have
lawyers on retainer.
Thank you, Dr. Abrams.
I didn't have any choice.
All of our ED doctors
were tied up
because of the lockdown,
the patient was
in laryngospasm.
I couldn't get the tubes
past her cord.
At that point,
I had to cric her.
Any doctor would have
the same problem.
Yeah, except, Maggie...
They're doctors.
They're allowed to perform
these procedures.
Sharon, what would
you have done?
Exactly what you did,
but, unfortunately,
that's not going to help you.
Sharon, am I gonna lose
my job over this?
I hope not,
but until I can
figure something out...
I've got to suspend you,
Maggie.
Sharon...
I'm sorry.
The patient would've died.
I have no regrets.
I know what you're gonna say.
I should not have
lied to Joanna.
It was wrong.
She's just a desperate,
troubled woman,
not a psychopath.
I agree.
She's not, but am I?
Am I a psychopath?
What?
Look how easily
I lied to her,
how I coldly manipulated her.
In this context,
that's hardly an indication
of psychopathy.
Well, how about my life?
Would you say that I'm able
to form lasting relationships?
I mean,
I have no real friends,
no significant
romantic attachments.
I think I have emotions,
but maybe they aren't real.
Maybe they're just imitative.
You just told me
that you felt guilty
about lying to a patient,
which means that
you have a conscience,
you're not a psychopath.
Whatever you wanna call it,
I am my father's daughter.
Well... Well,
you're also my resident,
and I find you to be a...
A deeply compassionate person,
who's capable
of great empathy.
I just never would've
roped you into
this whole psychiatry thing
if I wasn't entirely
convinced of that.
See you tomorrow?
Thanks, man.
He should wake up
pretty soon.
Yeah.
Nice work today.
You, too.
Yeah.
Dr. Bekker...
Have you come to see me
or our patient?
How's he doing?
I think he's gonna make it.
It's a long day, huh?
Yeah.
I could go for a meal.
I'd, uh, check the cafeteria.
It's Tuesday.
It's meatloaf.
My favorite.
Good night.
Dr. Halstead.
I owe you an apology.
Gary Taylor's autopsy revealed
that he died from
cardiac failure,
not an adverse drug reaction
or metastatic cancer.
In fact, in the hours from
the time he was given
the drugs
until he died,
the mass actually shrank
one centimeter.
That off-label cocktail
of yours, it worked.
I let Ms. Goodwin know.
Congratulations.
Uh... Um, look, uh,
it wasn't my idea.
It was Dr. Manning's.
Okay, whatever.
We've been thinking
about launching
a Phase One
clinical trial to...
Excuse me.
Whoa, Nat, hold up...
You're gonna get
the credit you deserve.
I'll make sure of that.
You think that's
what's bothering me?
Look, I know I shouldn't
have taken the blame,
and I certainly don't
deserve the credit.
Will, stop.
Just stop.
My whole career,
from med school on,
I keep running into
the same problem,
men who either dismiss me
or patronize me,
who cannot see me as an equal.
Well, I see you as an equal.
No, you don't.
And it's not just today.
It keeps happening.
Natalie...
Look, I know you love me,
but in a way,
that's part of the problem.
You can only see me
as the woman you love,
the woman you need to protect
and take care of,
and in a way, that limits me.
It puts me in a kind of jail.
Look, I don't want that,
Natalie.
Let's talk about this.
We'll figure it out.
Maybe we can,
but right now,
I need a break, okay?
I love you...
But I need a break from us.
No, come on.