Shh.
How'd she do?
Up from 3:30 to 6.
Then she watched her feet at 7.
Lie down. Take a nap. Okay?
Are you leaving? Yeah.
Please don't go.
I have to.
I want you to stay.
So do I.
Can't you call in sick?
I wish I could. Just do it.
Mwah.
I'll leave the van.
What was that?
It's 8:00. They're demolishing
the old textile
building on State.
That'll wake you up.
Exactly our problem.
They blow up a manufacturing
plant to build a mall.
What's wrong with a mall?
Fifty cents.
All we do is buy and sell.
We don't produce nothing.
See? What do you do?
What? For a living?
I'm a doctor.
Okay. Bad example.
What are you talking about?
You're building the mall.
Not for long.
Mark Ainsley, 12 years old.
GSW through the upper left arm.
Neuro-circ still intact?
Complains of pain
and paresthesia.
Can you squeeze my hand?
It hurts. What happened?
Open fire in a
foster-care facility.
Foster care? Twelve down.
Can you feel this?
A little.
Think about a vascular study.
Got it.
Mark! Mark! Take that one. Go!
It's still in me. It hurts.
We're gonna help you out.
Entrance wound only.
Palpable in the
sub-Q. Got this, Dave?
As long as there's no
compartment syndrome.
I can't breathe.
Slow your breathing down.
Maria Fredrikkson, with
significant blood loss.
BP, 90/palp. Tachy at 120.
Any belly pain, ma'am?
No. My leg is cold.
Foot pulses are diminished.
Did they get him? Who?
The man with the gun.
I don't know. Did you see him?
We were hiding in a closet.
But he just shot
through the door.
Foot is pale.
Poor capillary refill.
Trauma 1, coming through!
Who's on for Trauma?
We're bringing everybody in!
Two more of saline,
order pre-op labs.
Doesn't she have
an ischemic leg?
Get through to Surgery first!
We have an
8-year-old girl in arrest.
Where was she hit?
Shot in the head. Intubated.
Bradyed down to 30,
then lost her pulse.
Pupils fixed and dilated.
P.E.A. Let's get her epi.
You just get here?
Nice way to start.
Well, I was gonna call in sick.
Dr. Weaver, gluteal
gunshot wound.
He needs a cystourethrogram.
Try a rigid sigmoidoscopy.
He should see a surgeon.
Yeah, get in line.
Where's Benton?
Charge to 60.
You getting a rhythm?
Degenerated into V-fib. Clear.
Another 120. Looks
like brain-stem failure.
Weaver, 104's on the
radio with the last one.
GSW to the chest.
Is he hypotensive? No change.
120 again. No.
Fine. Bring him in.
Is it the same gunman?
Yeah. He shot the
gardener on his way out.
Clear.
Surprised he had
any bullets left.
Push another .3 of epi.
Want to try mannitol?
Couldn't hurt. 30 grams.
Do you need an angiogram?
No, I don't think
so. No bruit or thrill.
Is that Helen?
Who? Helen. She's new.
Foster-mom bailed on her.
Uh, I don't know.
Clear!
Expanding hematoma.
No pulse deficit. They
catch the guy yet?
No. Dispatch doesn't
know anything.
He was mad at Mrs. Buckley.
What's that?
He was waving the
gun at Mrs. Buckley,
yelling, then shot her.
Did we get a Mrs. Buckley?
DOA.
Gram of cefazolin,
follow with neuro exam.
We've also got a GSW
to the lateral malleolus
in Exam 2 still waiting. Yep.
Portable x-ray and
a Doppler scope.
Make sure the bullet
didn't damage the bone.
Go ahead. I got this.
Let's get an AP lateral
to the left humerus.
Hey. Did you turn
it in? What's that?
Weaver said my
application was incomplete.
Missing my peer reference.
Right, yeah. I'll do that today.
It's due today.
Yeah. I'll do it. Okay, thanks.
I need you! Femoral
artery's pumping blood.
I can't control it
without my finger in.
Then get me surgeons.
I got three unstable patients
and a fourth coming in.
Anspaugh's gonna
take this one. I'll be back.
Dr. Weaver? Yeah.
Officer Napolitano.
I need someone to pull
out a bullet for the crime lab.
Which patient? Calf wound.
He's stable. We'll
get to him soon.
As long as we get evidence.
Just find the shooter.
We'll get him.
I was in the bathroom.
I heard a loud explosion.
It scared me for a second.
But then I remembered that they
were tearing down that building.
But then I heard all
this screaming, and...
BP, 132/78. Pulse, 96.
He was out front in the bushes.
Took us a while to find
him. We were inside.
Kerry, what happened?
Lunatic shot at a
foster-care facility.
Why? Who knows? Go.
Curtain 3. Go!
You were right to stay.
I should have gone to
help, done something.
No. You did the right thing.
I'll be right back.
Can I get a cigarette?
I need a cigarette.
Yeah. I'll see what I can do.
Kerry, I've got a
hypotensive social worker.
Probably just stress, but
you should check it out.
Okay. Thanks. Hello.
Mm-hm.
I read your letter.
Good. I was wondering.
Dr. Legaspi, Dr. Romano,
line three, for you.
Tell him I'll call him back.
She'll call you right back.
Anyway, um, I
appreciate the sentiment.
I'll give her the message.
"Sentiment"? Yeah.
He says for you to
get on the line now.
He needs to talk to
you about a transfer.
Frank, she's busy.
He should be too.
We could have as many
as eight GSWs going.
Nine. Carjack victim.
Okay. We're swamped with this.
Tell them to divert to Mercy.
Mercy said no ETAs 9 to 10.
Why do they bother calling?
Um, anyway, thank you,
um, but I don't think
that anything's changed.
Right. Okay.
Okay. I should get back.
Yeah.
Chuny, grab Cleo.
The kid she's with
isn't gonna make it.
Clear.
Asystole.
How long has she been down?
At least an hour
since the shooting.
Dr. Finch, can you take a
carjack victim rolling up?
Go ahead. This is a fatal wound.
What is it?
GSW to the abdomen.
Someone should have told
me that today was gun day.
Time of death, 9:12.
This the carjacking?
Yeah. Mr. Jeffries.
GSW to the left lateral abdomen.
You need to be careful.
He has AIDS.
How's his pressure?
140/82.
Okay, good. That's good.
What do you got?
Entrance wound
below the costal margin
and the anterior
axillary line. No exit.
Mr. Jeffries is HIV-positive.
I was getting out of the car.
He shot me anyway.
Frank, what's open? Nothing.
I got a GSW.
Don't make you special today.
Mark called in. Trauma 1.
That's fine. Let's go.
Let's set him up. Get
him a portable chest.
Hey! Roger?
Stay away from my wife! What?
You stay away from my wife!
She told me... She
told me everything.
You had your chance.
She's my wife now.
I don't know what you're...
I'll take care of
Carla. You stay away.
Frank, call Security!
Get him outta here!
Stay away!
I haven't touched
her! I'll kick your ass!
Nothing happened.
Chuny, get a trauma panel.
Type and cross for four.
He really nailed you.
Shut up and mind your business!
Is this the carjacking? Yes.
Sir, I'm sorry about that.
Sir? Sir, I'm
Officer Napolitano.
You told the officer your
assailant was Caucasian?
Yeah, that's right.
Did he wear a
yellow windbreaker?
Uh, yeah, you know.
How did you know that?
I think he might have
shot some people
at a foster-care facility.
Same guy? And... three.
Can you remember
your license plate?
No.
Pressure's down to 90.
Two liters saline, wide open.
But it's a black Acura
Legend, correct?
Ahh. What's wrong?
You'll have to do this
later. Check with DMV.
You might be bleeding
in your abdomen.
How do you know for sure?
Let's get an ultrasound in here.
It's a black Acura Legend?
What? Yeah.
We have to put a tube in
your chest to help you breathe.
Prep the chest.
You okay from here?
Got it. Lidocaine.
Pulse ox is 98.
You almost missed
your deadline. What?
I was eating breakfast
and saw your med school
reinstatement form
on your counter.
What did you do?
Ten blade.
You were lucky.
Lady in the registrar's office
has a daughter who is a nurse.
The registrar's office?
I told her you had a
bunch of night shifts,
and she slipped it
in with the others.
32 French. Wait.
You, uh... You handed it in?
Yeah. This morning.
Luka, why'd you do
that? It was due Monday.
I didn't want to turn it in.
I thought you forgot.
No. I changed my mind. Why?
Now they'll come after
me for summer tuition.
I can help you with the money.
I don't want help.
I just wanted to let it go.
Then why did you fill it out?
I'll get you some Xeroform.
Lesion by the shoulder.
The bullet passed mid-shaft.
This is much more proximal.
Mm. Look at the lateral.
It's in front of the bone.
Could be soft-tissue sarcoma.
Get a biopsy.
Is your kid stable?
Yeah. I just have to do an FNA.
Clear the room.
Next round coming in.
Two more gunshot wounds.
One chest, one neck.
Two more? It's not even 10:00.
It's the same guy again.
What?
CPD tracked a carjacked
Acura to a private residence.
Found a mother
and son shot inside.
Did they get the shooter?
Not yet. Do we have the ORs?
Cleaning two now.
Peter still needs to go up.
That leaves one.
And Anspaugh should
be finishing soon.
Psych nurses aren't trained
to handle ostomy care.
If they need ostomy care, he
can check his own damn bag.
We need you. Two
more GSWs rolling up.
In a minute.
Abby, let's go outside.
And when I call you,
you get on the phone!
She was helping with
the mass casualty.
We needed her down here.
I needed to clear
Recovery for the barrage
of gunshot wounds
you keep accepting!
I'm not taking responsibility
for post-op complications
in the psych ward!
Well, then we'll have
to find somebody
who's interested
in responsibility.
What is that supposed to mean?
DeRaad can finish your shift.
What? Nice knowing you.
GSW through the right
lateral neck. Airway's clear.
What's his pressure? 110/70.
Hi. What's your name?
Ted.
Ted, can you swallow for me?
Where's my mom?
Is all this his?
Dr. Greene?
No. His mom was
wrapped around him.
The bullet went through
her and hit his neck.
Mommy! Dr. Greene.
Get Dr. Weaver to scope him.
He may need an esophagram.
We're gonna take
you inside. Okay, Ted?
I think this is the lady
that brought in your
abused kid last week.
Simple gunshot wound
to the back. BP, 128/74.
Mrs. Shayatovich.
Where's Ted? Where's Ted?
He's gonna be okay.
There's a doctor with him.
Please, help him.
He was bleeding.
His neck was bleeding.
Who shot you, Mrs. Shayatovich?
Derek. I told the policeman
it was Derek Fossen.
Your neighbor. He
was looking for Ben.
I told him I didn't
know where he was.
He said if I was gonna
take his boy away from him,
he was gonna take mine from me.
Please, please help
him. He was bleeding.
We're gonna take care of him.
Let's get a HemoCue
and a pulse ox.
Roll her, roll her, roll her!
Oh, God! That looks
like about two liters.
May be an
aorta-esophageal fistula.
She's out. Okay, bag her.
I'll intubate her inside.
Get a thoracotomy tray
and all the O-negative we got.
Fossen. Derek
Fossen. F-O-S-S-E-N.
Looks like it was contained
until it blew through
the esophagus.
Do you have an address?
He lives next door to her.
Can't get a pressure.
Squeeze in two units of O-neg.
I'm in.
We put his son into
protective custody.
His name is Ben.
He should be somewhere
in the foster-care system.
Lost the pulse.
All right. Rib spreader.
Find the son. That's
who he's looking for.
Abby, get the infuser.
Pressure's up to
120 after two liters.
Do you need this? No.
Liver and spleen are intact.
So maybe I'm not bleeding.
No. You've got a slow
leak from a small vessel.
You're gonna need surgery.
I don't want surgery.
Look, we'll make
a midline incision,
find the bleeding
artery and then tie it off.
Doc, I'm already dying.
Your infection might
slow your recovery,
but it's routine surgery.
People live with HIV.
I know that. I've been fighting
this disease since 1986.
I responded to the AZT,
and the protease
inhibitors were a miracle.
They gave me
an extra five years.
But my T cells have
been dropping since July.
My viral load's gone
through the roof,
even with all these antivirals.
Mr. Jeffries, I, uh...
I need your consent.
No.
I had pneumocystis
three months ago.
If we don't operate, you'll die.
I am already dead, doc.
This may just allow me
to skip a very painful end.
Another Satinsky.
Unit number eight is up.
Heart's not filling.
Clamp the aorta.
Greene, the injury
is high and posterior.
Just trying to bring
you more light.
Oh, that'll help.
Can't you get your
finger in the hole?
If I could see it. More light.
Just call for FFP and platelets.
Forget it, forget it. I
can't close this defect.
Another amp of epi.
She'll go out of thoracic aorta
and exsanguinate in seconds.
Let's try bypass.
It's too late for that. Call it.
Time of death, 11:40.
0 for 2 and it's not even lunch.
We pull the sample
out with a needle.
And then we look
under a microscope.
You think it's cancer?
No, it could be scar
tissue. It could be a cyst.
Cancer's only one possibility.
My mom died of cancer.
How old was she?
35. I'm 12.
Okay, well, let's
see the biopsy first.
That way we can talk
about what we know,
as opposed to
what we don't know.
Do you have anybody
that you'd like me to call?
I'm in foster care.
Yeah, I know. Foster parents?
No. I'm between homes.
Right.
She make it? No.
Scary. This guy's on a rampage.
They didn't catch him yet?
I don't know.
They're gonna go to his house.
So much violence, huh?
Were you gonna tell me?
Tell you what?
I heard a rumor.
Oh, yeah? A good one?
Dr. Rosen called.
You know, from the emergency
department at Northwestern.
You took the message?
Yeah, he wanted to
set up an appointment.
Just looking at options.
Are you leaving?
I still have to make up three
months of my residency.
Well, after that?
I don't know.
I'm not even being
considered for Chief Resident.
I have to write this damn
peer review for Chen.
They're not even talking to
me about an Attending position.
Read the writing on the wall.
You talked to Weaver
about an Attending position?
No. Why not?
Because if she wanted me,
she would have
asked me about it.
Maybe she doesn't
think you're interested.
Maybe I'm not.
Carter, is your
cirrhosis patient
ready to go to the floor?
No. I have to do a
paracentesis first.
We need the bed. Got it.
What's the chest tube
output on the gardener?
300 cc's. He's third
in line for a tele.
You still angry at me?
I wasn't angry.
You seemed angry.
It's my fault. I should
have ripped it up.
I thought you wanted
to go back to school.
Maybe I do. Just not now.
What happened? Nothing.
You don't wanna be
a doctor anymore?
I don't know.
You don't know? I don't know.
It's $40,000 in tuition.
It's lost wages.
It's another six years
of me killing myself.
Then it's over, and you'll
be doing what you want.
Maybe I'm doing
what I want right now.
If that were true, you
would have never started.
Maybe I realized being
a nurse is good enough.
Is it not good enough for you?
No, no. It's fine.
Okay. You did great, Ted.
The bullet went through
a muscle in your neck.
But you're gonna be okay.
Can I see my mom now?
Uh, let me find out.
Do you know your
dad's work number?
No.
Okay. Do you know
where he works?
Abysco.
Abysco? Is that a company?
He makes binders.
He makes binders. All right.
You wanna draw some more?
Yeah. I'll be right back.
The mom didn't make it?
The proximal aorta was shredded.
I have to track down his father.
What do you wanna tell the boy?
I'll stall.
Dr. Greene?
This him?
Yeah. He has a record?
One arrest. Domestic dispute.
He hit his girlfriend.
He wasn't at his house?
I'll let you know when
we have him in custody.
What about his son?
We tracked down
the foster parents.
A patrol car's
picking him up now.
I think he's coming here. What?
Well, he was pissed
at the neighbor
for bringing him to the ER.
I mean, you took his
kid away from him, right?
Right.
Thanks, Frank.
I'll send in some extra units.
Mark, he couldn't come here.
He knows there's
too many cops around.
He hasn't displayed a lot
of sound judgment so far.
What is he shooting with?
Semiautomatic
pistol, 13-round clip.
He's been reloading.
Probably picked it up
at Kmart on the way.
It's not the guns.
People kill people.
Yeah, right. Only not as fast.
He would have
found another weapon.
Fourteen shots so far, Frank.
Six deaths.
You can't affect mass murder
with a Chinese throwing star.
Rescue 78 coming
in with an injured cop.
Motorist dragged
him for half a block.
See? There you go.
He hit him with a car.
That's assault with
a deadly weapon.
Frank, shut up! Shut up!
Free air under the diaphragm.
Must have nicked the bowel too.
His crit's down to 23.
I can't dilute him much further.
I checked his viral
load. It's over 50,000.
He'll die of an opportunistic
infection within a year.
Well, that doesn't mean we
should help him commit suicide.
He didn't shoot himself.
If we let him refuse
surgery, it's the same thing.
Get a court order then.
He'll be dead by the
time it's approved.
Then it's his choice.
All right.
I went over there.
She was upset. She was crying.
She came on to me.
I didn't do anything.
I didn't want to do anything.
Maybe she felt guilty
and she told Roger,
and she put a spin on it.
You wouldn't put a spin on it.
No. Then why didn't you tell me?
To avoid this. What?
You looking at
me like I did wrong.
I see. You didn't trust me,
and I'm supposed to trust you.
I didn't think it was
worth getting into.
Good. At least I
know where I stand.
Cleo, that's not what I
meant, and you know it.
Peter, his pressure's dropping.
Go.
Run in another liter of saline.
Any chest pain or dizziness? No.
Let's get two units
from the blood bank
and transfuse each over an hour.
No, no, no. I don't
want a blood transfusion.
Your hematocrit is
drifting dangerously low.
I understand.
No. Thank you.
What about your family?
I mean, if you don't care about
yourself, what about them?
I haven't spoken to my
mother in over 30 years.
I outlived the two people
that I loved in the world.
I've lived longer
than I expected.
Just let me go.
I'm ready.
Hi. Hi.
How are you feeling?
My neck hurts.
I'll ask one of the nurses to
come give you some medicine.
Can I see my mom?
Not yet. I'm trying
to reach your dad.
Can I stay with
her until you do?
I don't think so.
She's having an
operation right now.
Is she okay?
We're having a little trouble
trying to get the bleeding
stopped around her heart.
She was hurt bad.
I know.
You hungry? No.
Where's all this blood from?
Tore off part of his ear.
Give him more pain medicine.
Titrate 10 of morphine. Sir,
did you lose consciousness?
I don't think so.
You got him, Luka? Yeah.
Trauma panel, portable chest...
Get a good look? Not really.
Yellow windbreaker?
Yeah, Colby said he
saw blood on the collar.
Fossen did this? Just a minute.
Colby asked him to step out.
When he opened the door, the
guy smashed our unit and took off.
Colby's jacket must
have got snagged.
He was screaming.
He got dragged forever.
But he didn't stop.
Where did he get the
car? Probably boosted it.
Jeep Grand Cherokee, first
three license numbers G74?
That's all I got.
Maybe G79? You got him?
Shots at 823 Piedmont.
Jeep Grand Cherokee
parked at the corner.
License number G79-6L5.
Woman found down
inside. Oh, God. Here we go.
- Easy, easy. Is she dead?
- Called the paramedics.
We're all overworked, Robert.
You can't insinuate
you'll fire someone
every time you get frustrated.
I'm not. She's fired. Robert.
Cleaning out her locker
now. You can't do that.
I just did. This is
a county facility.
Employees cannot
be summarily fired.
Dr. Legaspi was already on
probation for that other matter.
And she was exonerated.
She's had a history of
violation of institutional policy.
Like what? What do you care?
She's a good doctor.
A good doctor who has
had 30 delinquent charts
awaiting discharge summaries.
And so does half the staff.
She used the
telephone watts line
for personal calls.
You gotta be kidding.
She yelled at a patient
in a public setting.
You're trying to
find a way to fire her.
Plenty of documentation
has been reviewed
by the disciplinary committee.
Dr. Weaver. Give me a minute.
Adele's been shot. What?
Adele. That maniac
shot her at her house.
The social worker?
Chest x-ray, T and L spine.
Let's set up an ultrasound.
Can you feel this? Yeah.
Miss, did you get a look
at the man who shot you?
Yeah, he... He looked familiar.
He said something about his son.
We put his son Ben into
protective custody last week.
Oh, my God.
Okay. Adele, can you feel this?
No.
Cord injury, 1.8
grams Solu-Medrol
over 15 minutes.
Hi, Adele. Hi.
She was shot mid-back.
She can't move her legs.
Was it a white male, late
30s, yellow windbreaker?
Uh, yeah. I... I think so.
Any pain in the belly?
BP, 92/65. Pulse, 110.
Adele, any pain in
your belly? Not really.
Could be a pneumothorax.
Lungs sound
good. Pulse ox is 99.
For an intra-abdominal bleed?
There's spinal shock.
How did he know
where I lived? What?
How did he know where I lived?
I only saw him at the hospital.
They can find anything
on the Internet. What?
Get someone over
to my house. What?
Send someone over
to my house now.
1211 Dupont Drive.
She's hypotensive. Dopamine?
Start her on five mics.
Come on, Elizabeth. Pick up.
Pick up.
Does this feel sharp? - Yes.
What's her crit? Working on it.
How about here? Yes.
Do you have voice mail
or a machine? Machine.
Would she hear a
message? I don't know.
How about here?
No.
Were you already home
or was he waiting for you?
He came in.
I was sitting at my
desk doing my bills.
Patellar reflexes are absent.
No one's answering the door.
You want 'em to search the house?
Yeah. They'd
have to force entry.
Search the house.
942, go ahead.
Still hypotensive.
Up her to 10 mics.
She needs volume.
I'm not in yet.
Adele, can you bend your knee?
I can't. I can't move
it. Look, I don't care.
We may have an
emergency laminectomy.
Fine. Check. Go.
Doc, they'll call it in
when they have it secured.
Am I paralyzed?
Hopefully, it's only temporary.
That's it. Give me a new kit.
Check for sacral sparing.
Come on, now. Now.
Set up the microscope.
We're coming up.
Maybe she went
out, went to the store.
Did you page her? What?
Did you page her? No.
I need you to page Dr. Corday.
I don't... I know
that. Page her.
Mr. Jeffries.
What's his HemoCue?
Down to five.
Barely responds
to painful stimuli.
Hang two units of blood.
He doesn't want that.
Where's the consent
form? On the cart.
You can't take him
without consent.
Well, he's unable
to give consent now.
I just need two
physicians' signatures
for emergency surgery.
No.
You'd have him die?
I'll respect his wishes.
Good, Adele.
The spinal injury is
incomplete. We can operate.
I need an emergency
signature. Not now.
- IJ's in. Get another chest.
- He's bleeding out.
Run the Solu-Medrol.
325 an hour.
Gunshot wound
to the belly. He's...
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Whatever. Whatever. Go.
Systolic's up to 100.
All right. Let's get him up.
Can you get a repeat CBC?
Whatever you want, Peter.
I've got my two signatures.
He made himself clear.
Look, he has advanced AIDS.
He probably has an
HIV encephalopathy.
No. He was alert and oriented.
You should have called Psych.
I did. They never showed up.
Laura called. They're
still... Ow! Damn it.
Oh, God. I'm sorry. Hold
on. Did you cut yourself?
I don't think so. The
glove just tore there.
Peter. Hold on. Hold on.
Let me get some
gauze pads. Come on.
Let me see it, all right?
Oh, God. BENTON:
Keep irrigating it.
- Where are the Zerowets?
- Bottom drawer.
Pharmacy? Yeah,
this is Dr. Benton.
I need you to pull
a PEP kit for me.
All right. And use two liters.
What? No, no, no, no. Look,
I'm on my way up there right now.
What about the patient?
Keep transfusing him.
Talk to Neuro? They're
doing a craniotomy.
Watch it, Peter.
I need help with a
thoracic decompression.
Adele, there's a piece of bone
in your 9th vertebrae, mid-back,
that's pressing on
your spinal cord.
That's why I can't move my legs?
Yes. But if they remove the
fragment, you may recover.
Doc, no one's at your house.
We did thorough sweep.
Check my garage?
Yeah, yeah. Nothing.
Call me if you find
her. Will I be paralyzed?
Not if I can help it. I
still need to talk to you.
Drop it, Kerry. It's over.
Is my van still there? What?
The garage. Was my
van there? Yeah. Yeah.
But you have two cars,
right? Hers is in the shop.
Does she take the baby out?
She's been going for
walks, usually around 3.
It's 1:05.
It depends on the
baby's schedule.
Can you keep a unit there
until she gets home? Yeah.
Nick. Yeah.
Nick, listen. WOMAN:
Shot in the head.
The guy was riding
in the back seat.
Cab driver on Roosevelt.
Roger that, 27.
Rescue's en route.
Okay, that'll be us.
Can you give it to Luka?
I have to go upstairs.
Think it's him?
Yeah, that's him.
Dr. Greene, I can't
reach this boy's father.
I think he's
figuring it out. Who?
The neck wound. His mother
died. You need to talk to him.
I'll be right there.
Carter, we got a GSW
to the head coming in.
I want you to prep Trauma 1.
Get some, uh, Dilantin,
mannitol and, uh, Decadron.
ETA? Check with dispatch.
Ewing seems pretty aggressive.
We'll need a chest
and abdominal CT
to rule out metastatic disease.
You sure? It's a
soft-tissue mass.
Extra-osseous Ewing. It's rare.
You might wanna write it up.
Thank you. Want me
to talk to the parents?
He doesn't have any parents.
Where is she? Where's my mom?
Where's this operation?
The bullet...
Uh...
She was shot in the back.
The bullet passed
through her heart.
She lost so much blood
that her heart stopped beating.
We opened up her chest
for an emergency surgery.
Gave her blood transfusions.
Best surgeon in
the hospital did it.
She wasn't in any pain.
She didn't suffer.
We worked on
her for a long time.
We couldn't stop the bleeding.
And we couldn't get
her heart to beat again.
Ted, your mother died.
I'm sorry.
Here. You need
to take these now.
Shouldn't we draw
baseline labs first?
No. Now. The sooner the better.
Peter, two units are in. I can't
get his pressure above 80.
All right. Hold on. He's
already drug-resistant.
You don't have a large
viral load. He does.
Cleo, listen to me.
The conversion rate with
meds is less than 3 in 1000.
Crit is 14.
If he's going, he has to go now.
Okay?
All right. Get
another two units.
I'll meet you at the elevator.
See if Infectious Disease needs
to modify the
post-exposure regimen.
I'm surprised my
code still works.
It's not gonna happen, Kim.
What isn't?
Th-they can't let
you go, not legally.
No. They always
intended to fire me.
They would have done it sooner,
but they needed a nice,
thick human-resource file first.
Which is completely bogus.
They'll never get away with it.
They already have.
Only if you let them.
It's not worth the effort.
I'm not interested
in working for a place
that doesn't want me here.
You have the right
to due process.
We... We can find
a-a civil-rights attorney.
We?
It's not right, Kim.
You know why they're firing you.
You have to fight it.
You have to fight this.
I'm supposed to fight?
You're hiding, but
I'm supposed to fight.
Well, I'm sorry. But
I don't wanna fight.
I just wanna move on.
So should you.
Hey, Chris and Hillary.
It's Mark Greene.
I'm looking for Elizabeth.
If you see her, could you
ask her to give me a call?
Thanks. Dr. Greene, we got him.
Where? He opened
fire in Lincoln Park.
Shot three people before being
shot by a civilian with a 9mm.
Is he still alive? So far.
- What's he had?
- Two of epi and atropine.
Is this the cabby?
Shot at the base of his
skull. Cleo, jump in on this?
High cervical injury.
Blew out his brains.
Cleo. Uh, uh, any
vitals in the field?
No, just brain matter.
Durcy, any witnesses?
No, but we think it
was Fossen. Well, why?
1211 Dupont was the last entry
on the driver's log at 1:14 p.m.
What? The house
you had searched.
Fossen must have been
on his way over there.
Cabby probably heard
his description on the radio.
Dr. Greene? Bang.
Fossen blew his brains out.
Dr. Greene? Don't worry, doc.
That means he never got there.
- Dr. Greene.
He's coming in.
Was that a record number of
gunshot wounds for one shift?
By the same guy? Absolutely.
He has a good chance.
Like you said,
you found it early.
It's more that he has to go
through it alone, you know?
As if having cancer as
a kid wasn't bad enough.
He could get passed
over for Chief Resident.
That's true. Or he could
get kicked out of med school
and be forced to
work as an ER nurse.
I was not kicked out. Really?
What would you call it?
Suspended for being a deadbeat.
Hmm.
Do you know he
offered to pay my tuition?
Who? Luka.
And I know he means well.
It's just frustrating
for me sometimes
'cause I have to explain
my every feeling to him.
And normally when you're
with someone for a while,
they get to know your moods.
But he doesn't do
that. You know what?
Stop it.
What?
Don't talk to me about Luka.
I'm not your girlfriend.
And I shouldn't really
even be here with you.
Why not?
Because I don't wanna wish
bad things for you and Luka.
And I don't wanna
sit on the sidelines
waiting for you two to break up.
And I don't wanna
be your friend.
It might be convenient for you,
but it's not doing much
for me. What are you...?
What are you talking about?
Where did you put him?
Where did you put my son?
How much O-neg you want?
- Four units.
You can't take me from
him! Quiet! So we can listen.
Two entrance wounds on
the right. One on the left.
Another two in the
belly. A total of five.
You. You did this.
Set up for bilateral chest
tubes and a central line.
Systolic's low at
80. I'll intubate.
This is your fault.
Ready for the chest tubes.
Now. Paralyze.
One of Pavulon, 100 of sux.
You stole my son.
You destroyed my family.
Ambu-bag.
He's my son!
What gives you the right to?
You can't take my son away.
It starts with one bad
cell that multiplies.
And then it grows
out of control.
You usually don't
know it's there
until the mass is big
enough that it causes pain.
We're very lucky
that we found it today.
So you're saying
I'm lucky I got shot?
In a way, yeah.
It's just gonna
take longer to die.
No. That's what I'm telling you.
We caught it early.
There's a good chance
you're not gonna die.
What...? What's a good chance?
70 percent.
You know what 70 percent is?
Yeah. It leaves 30.
Well, let's concentrate
on the 70, okay?
Dr. Carter, GSW's rolling in.
Okay. Be right there.
So, what happens to me now?
Now I'm gonna have a
cancer doctor, an oncologist,
come down and
take a look at you.
No. I mean, where do I live?
Oh.
I don't know. I'll find out.
When was your
last tetanus booster?
I don't know. Do
I need an x-ray?
No, it looks like just a
graze. Is that the guy?
Yes. Multiple GSWs to
the chest and abdomen.
At the range, they teach you
to shoot for the center mass.
It's not always fatal,
but it takes 'em down.
You shot him? I got
mugged last year.
Same park. I don't go
there now without protection.
He started shooting people.
Someone had to do something.
Yeah, we should
arm the whole city.
Hey, I stopped him. He
would have kept going.
You're lucky.
Lucky I was packing.
Carter, you free? Uh, sort of.
GSW to the right flank.
Vitals are stable, but
I need you to check
for gross hematuria.
Okay. I... I'll be right there.
I handed it in to her. What?
Your reference. Should
put you over the top. All fives.
Wow. Thanks. I had to lie.
- Now, Carter.
- Coming.
First two are in.
Another subclavian. Put
the next two on the infuser.
How's your chest tube output?
Couple hundred cc's.
Only 50 on my side.
Is he gonna make it?
Probably. Didn't hit
any vital structures.
After five shots?
Some guys get lucky.
Nineteen shot. Eight,
maybe nine dead.
He's lucky we
didn't take him down.
Dr. Greene,
Dr. Corday's on line four.
Could you get it for me?
Pressure's up to 85.
3-0 nylon. What's in the Foley?
Seventy cc's.
Dips are negative for heme.
Dr. Corday? Hold on.
Can you cut this? Elizabeth?
Mark, what's going
on? Where were you?
I was at the Farmer's Market.
There were police in the house
and the front door's
been kicked in.
I told them to. Why?
Uh, long story. Vaseline gauze.
You're not gonna tell
me what happened?
Nothing. It's just
a bit of a scare.
You're all right?
Yeah, I'm fine.
Uh, call you later?
I told the policeman to
stay with me till I called you.
Yeah. Yeah, he can go now.
You're not gonna tell
me what's going on?
Not right now.
Everything's okay.
Okay, then.
Will you be off at 7?
Yes. I will be there.
Okay.
I love you.
Me too.
Elastoplast.
Get ready for a portable chest.
Keep the dopamine at 10
mics. Neuro checks, 30 minutes,
and a CBC in an hour.
Any cord contusion?
No, extrinsic hematoma.
Did they find
Elizabeth? She's fine.
Ah, good. What
about her paralysis?
Ask me in 24 hours. What's this?
GSW to the renal parenchyma.
Marge, clear OR 2. We
got another customer.
I'll be right back.
Robert, I need to talk to you.
Yeah, sure.
Anything but Legaspi.
You're making a mistake. Look,
my main mistake was not
firing her three months ago
when I first found out.
Found out what? That
she is incompetent.
That's not what you were
gonna say. Oh, really?
In addition to your
diagnostic skills,
you're a mind reader.
It's because she's
gay. Of course it's not.
That would be wrong, or
at least politically incorrect.
She's a pain in the ass.
Like Maggie Doyle was?
Okay, let's stop right there.
And avoid your history
of discrimination?
If you don't rethink this,
there's a good chance
you'll be out of a job.
Dr. Legaspi has demonstrated
not only poor judgment,
but a reckless attitude
towards her patients
and a blatant
disregard for authority.
She's out. She's fired.
End of discussion.
If she goes, I go. What?
You heard me.
Are you giving me an
ultimatum? I swear to God, Robert.
I will walk out if
you don't back off!
I do not respond
well to ultimatums!
You had better choose
your battles very carefully.
You're the Chief of
Emergency Medicine,
not the county's
lesbian advocate.
That's where you're
wrong, because I am both.
I am the Chief of
Emergency Medicine,
and I am a lesbian.
And if you pursue
this matter any further,
I will take it to the County
Board of Supervisors,
the ACLU, the press
and anyone else who will listen.
So I suggest you choose
your battles very carefully.
BP's 100/60.
Going in the right direction.
Last HemoCue? 9.5.
You want me to bring him up?
Mark? What?
You want me to bring
him up? No, no. I got it.
They are sending
cross-matched blood to the OR.
Good. Could you bring a
copy of the chart back down
so I can write my note?
Sure.
He's gonna need
some more Pavulon.
Damn it. I forgot the drug box.
Be right back.
Whoa!