I just wanna say, I'm really
excited about the clinical trial.
I've been reading in The New
England Journal of Medicine...
Germs. Disease. Toxins.
Our bodies encounter dangers all
the time, just beneath the surface.
Hidden.
Whether you realize it or not, your
body is constantly protecting itself.
- I'd like to propose a toast...
- - Why is the sperm donor here?
- I thought tonight
was a family dinner.
- Dad.
To two extraordinary
women. May your lives
be overfilled with
love, happiness and joy.
To Callie and Arizona,
- the mothers of my child.
- Oh, for God's sake.
Oh, Daniel. Cheers.
- Cheers!
- Yes! There we go.
Do you ever go by anything
other than "Colonel," Colonel?
- The Colonel.
- Actually, um,
we forgot to say grace.
- Say what?
- We should say grace
before we eat.
Of course. Shame on us.
Fork down, The Colonel.
- Mom, you wanna lead?
- Bless us, oh Lord,
and these...
Every time you blink your eye,
you wash away thousands
of unwanted microbes.
Breathe in too much unwanted
pollen, and you sneeze.
- Amen.
OK, I'll go get her. Excuse me.
Arizona, we sat next to a charming
young man on the plane today,
and he said he was going with
his partner to march in a parade.
- For Pride.
- Yeah. Those are good.
The body knows when it's encountered
something that doesn't belong.
Oh! She couldn't
be cuter if she tried.
Mom, you haven't had
a chance to hold her yet.
The body detects the invader,
it releases its
white blood cells...
No, no. That's all right.
Thank you, though, I'm eating.
And it attacks.
This is Zola. She's six months
old, born with spina bifida.
Adorable African children.
Shameless ego stroking.
- Karev is a genius.
- He's single-handedly stealing
chief resident out from under all
of us. And we're helping him do it.
We can't exactly refuse
to treat little sick kids
- without making
ourselves look bad.
- He is a genius. Or...
That's what they say in Swahili.
Well, he only has a shot
because I've been benched.
The playing field has been
leveled. You're all welcome.
My Alzheimer's trial
kicks African orphan ass.
- It kicks all of your asses.
- You wanna keep
it down back there?
I'm trying to listen to what appears
to be the next chief resident talking.
Before we go, I wanna say thank
you to all of you for your participation.
It truly means
more than I can say.
Slow clap. They're giving
him the slow clap? Come on.
I'm not giving
him the slow clap.
OK, I want to personally
check the incision sites,
any weight fluctuations,
the patients' glucose levels.
When was the last time you
cleaned these cages, Avery?
A clean cage means a lower infection
rate which means FDA approval.
- Understood?
- Cages. I got it, sir.
Makena? Hi, I'm Dr. Shepherd.
Of course, you know Dr. Karev.
We're here to take
a look at Zola today.
Sometimes babies with spina bifida
can develop Chiari malformation.
It causes fluid build-up in the
brain. It can be pretty uncomfortable,
but sometimes, if you adjust
the patient's head position...
It helps relieve the pressure.
Let me see this.
Let me see this face.
We've had her at the orphanage
since she was two months old.
This is the first time she's stopped
crying since I can remember.
Let's just run an MRI
and check to see if she has
a Chiari malformation and hydrocephalus.
If it's positive, we're gonna have to do
a shunt to drain the fluid. It's
gonna postpone the spinal surgery,
- but I think
it's gonna be worth it.
- I think she likes you.
She can keep
that. I have plenty.
Sefu, I will be repairing your brother's
heart defect tomorrow while Dr. Sloan,
our head of plastics, he will
construct Kondo a new sternum.
He wants to know, if he dies, could
we wait to tell the family at home?
Our sister's birthday is tomorrow.
He doesn't want to ruin it.
We are gonna take really
good care of you. OK?
And you are not gonna
ruin your sister's birthday.
We have to look
at his chest, OK?
Wow.
- Sir...
- Get off me!
- I told you that I'm fine!
- Sir, please.
- I don't need any of your help!
- Sir, if you continue
to try to get out of bed, I'm
gonna have to restrain you.
- Ah!
- B52 cocktail. Ought to calm him down.
OK, listen. I need to get back
in the race for chief resident.
I need in on Teddy's
pentalogy of Cantrell patient.
This isn't funny anymore. She is still
shutting me out. Can't you talk to her?
I thought you were on Robbins'
service today. Isn't she on that case, too?
Yeah, but that just puts me like
inches away from some other resident
doing the most amazing
cardio procedure imaginable,
while I just stand
there and... suction.
- It's torture.
- You need to apologize.
Apologize for what?
For having better judgment than
Teddy? For saving Callie's life?
There is a wedding
tomorrow because of me.
Your apology could
use some work.
You asked me how to get back
in with Teddy. I'm telling you how.
Asha is ten years old, she
sustained internal injuries
six years ago from an explosive
device. She has multiple enterotomies.
There are some strictures
there and some ascites.
She has not healed properly.
This complicates things.
As does the fact that
she's HIV positive.
She's living with AIDS.
Hello.
April. Don't be scared.
I'm just gonna take your
blood pressure now, OK?
Oh, no, it's OK, it's OK.
Um, we're here to help.
- Help.
- Let's get her
on LR at maintenance
- and start broad
spectrum antibiotics.
- Understand?
- Help. Help.
- Dr. Kepner? Um...
The antibiotics and the LR.
Oh, right, sorry,
Dr. Hunt. Right away.
Dr. Kepner, perhaps
if you spent a little
more time just doing your job
and a little less time
learning the new languages,
your attendings wouldn't
have to repeat themselves.
Hold, please.
Dr. Altman, I would
like to apologize.
I am... sorry...
for going over your head
and putting you in a difficult
position during Callie's
surgery. I am sorry. I apologize.
Are you saying this
because you mean it,
or because you want
back on my service?
Does it really matter?
Yes. It matters.
- Here you go.
- Thank you.
I, uh, put together a schedule
to help with the next two days.
By the hour, military time.
Wow. Thank you, Colonel.
And I picked up a little
something for Sofia.
- Look at the little rosebuds!
- OK, Mom, baby clothes later.
Wedding rehearsal
now. I've got 20 minutes
before I have to get
back to the hospital.
- Dad, where's
the moment of silence?
- Time is tight, Arizona.
I could not find a place
in the ceremony for it.
We have to light a candle
for Timothy. It's two minutes.
- Timothy? Oh.
- Her brother.
- Dad?
- Sweetie, don't push it.
OK, so the table is the altar,
and the lamp is...?
- Father Brooks.
- Your priest?
Ahem. Minister. No, he's not Catholic,
but he practices at a very big church.
It's old and drafty. It's...
You'll like it. It's very churchy.
- I see.
- OK, Mrs. Torres,
you'll be over here
- in the front row.
- OK. And I know
where you want me.
Right back here to walk
my little girl down the aisle.
Sorry, sorry. Surgery ran
long, but I'm here. I made it.
- Where do you want me?
- That is not where you will be.
Is this your spot? Sorry.
Hey, Mark, why don't you
stand over here next to me?
At least one of my
fathers-in-law doesn't hate me.
You're Sofia's father. I love Sofia,
so I'm gonna at least try to like you.
But if you call me your
father-in-law again, I'll knock you out.
OK. So Arizona walks
down the aisle first...
There she goes.
All right, and then I go...
And then I hand
the bouquet to...
Mom, can I hand you the bouquet?
Actually, I... I need to use
the powder room. Excuse me.
Well, I'd like some bouquet
time, if you don't mind.
I haven't had enough
bouquet time today.
I mean, you'd think being on the
chief's research project would help
in the race for chief resident. You
might even think it'd make me a contender.
Only, I'm not saving little
kids or people with Alzheimer's.
- I am cleaning up mouse poop.
- Can you hand me that basin?
Wanna hear my conversation
with the chief every morning?
"Avery, how are the
mice?" "They're fine, chief.
They're running on their wheels,
they're eating their cheese."
If I worked at a pet store, I'd be
employee of the month by now,
but I'm a surgeon,
babysitting a bunch of mice.
Until you get FDA approval. I'm sure
you're gonna be working on humans
any day now. Now
grab me another plum.
Why are you peeling
these things apart, anyway?
I'm practicing.
Since my kid's skin has grown
directly onto the heart muscle,
I'm gonna be helping Teddy remove the
adhesions without puncturing the heart.
Hey, don't eat my adhesions!
Oh, gross!
OK, OK, look. I
need 20 good reasons
why I shouldn't let Cristina
back on my service today,
because I am ready to buckle.
I've got a really complicated case,
and I could use her skills today,
so 20 reasons. Right now. Please.
I don't have one reason. I think you
should put her back on your service.
No! That would be the
worst thing that I could do.
I mean, that won't
teach her a thing.
She went over your head in a
surgery. Yes, that was bad form,
but don't you think you're
being a little bit harsh?
Harsh? OK, first of all, she
went over my head to you.
And you enabled that behavior,
which you really shouldn't have done.
But more importantly is
Cristina is dangerous right now.
She got lucky. Callie
survived that procedure,
but it just as easily could
have been disastrous.
Cristina got lucky. She doesn't
see it that way. She thinks she's right.
She always thinks she's right,
and that is not being a good doctor.
- That is dangerous.
- Tell her that.
Instead of just shutting
her out, tell her that.
There's no telling Cristina Yang
anything. She has to learn it.
And, until then, I am
OK being the bad guy.
I can handle her being angry
at me. But do you really think
that she can handle something
like killing Callie Torres?
So, Zola doesn't have a Chiari malformation,
but she does have hydrocephalus.
OK. Let's book an
OR for the shunt.
Hey, what you got
for me? Any news?
Oh! I went over all
the screening tests,
but you need to start looking at
the next wave of patient charts.
- Next wave?
- For the Alzheimer's trial.
The first wave of
the trial is done,
now we're getting ready
to treat the next group.
Let me know when
the OR is booked.
Mer, what's going on?
Does he know what you did?
What did I do?
I saw you with the
clinical trial envelope.
You were hiding it under your lab coat.
If you messed with this trial somehow,
this could be bad for
you, like really bad.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Whatever you did, no matter how
minor, it invalidates the entire project.
- Alex.
- You could get
into real trouble, Mer.
It's illegal to mess
around with a blind trial.
I didn't do anything!
So shut up about it!
- Dr. Stark, can I talk to you?
- Well, it appears
you already are.
I have some concerns, about
Asha. She hasn't eaten a bite
- of food since she arrived.
- Start her on
parenteral nutrition.
I will, obviously. But more to the
point, the fact that she's not eating,
not speaking, she just
seems really scared...
You know, unless the next piece
of information from your mouth
relies on the words "lab results" or
"vitals" or "code blue," I don't care.
You promised!
You promised me that we could
work together, that it wouldn't be weird,
that you would treat me
like any other resident.
I assure you, I am treating you
exactly the way I treat other residents.
It's a 911 on Asha.
Asha, what's wrong?
- OK, what happened?
- Her blood pressure dropped
out, her pulse was thready.
Did somebody notify Hunt?
Help.
OK, get me four units of
packed cells, draw a new CBC,
coags, open up her
fluids. Kepner, get a gown.
I'm fine. I need a
central line kit right now.
- Kepner!
- I'm fine. I've got this.
- Two more days.
- Hm.
We can handle two more days.
And then they'll be gone and
our lives will go back to normal.
No more brunches,
no more praying.
No more my dad calling
himself The Colonel.
We just need to focus
on the big picture.
- Yeah.
- Which is...
you and I are getting married.
- We're getting married.
We couldn't stop the bleeding
so we rushed her here.
- Oh. What the hell?
- It looks like wax.
I have never seen
anything like this.
Nobody has, at least not in the
States. She has intestinal TB. Poor kid.
Adhesions everywhere. It's
hard to even know where to begin.
The perforation is pretty
high at the lesser curvature.
We should treat it like a normal perf,
right? Then start the anti-TB meds?
The less aggressive we are, the greater
chance we can avoid short gut syndrome.
Absolutely right, Kepner. Let's
start by ligating the bleeding vessel.
The trick is to go in very
slowly until you feel a little give,
- and then you should see some fluid.
- - Got it.
Very nice. You know, I wasn't
exactly pleased when you decided
- to bow out of the trial.
- Yeah, well...
But the work you're doing
with the kids, really impressive.
- Thank you.
- And you were
right about Meredith
being the right person for
the Alzheimer's trial all along.
I'm impressed. You
are remarkably calm
for a bride who's
getting married tomorrow.
You should see the schedule
that my dad put together.
I just show up where I belong
when I belong, it's perfect.
Everyone should
get married like this.
Who's that from? Hottie
Husband or Hottie Boyfriend?
It's from Andrew, who is not my
boyfriend. He's just my wedding date.
Uh-huh. And does your Hottie Wedding
Date know about Hottie Husband?
Well, there's nothing to know.
I mean, Andrew will be in town
for another week, and then
he's off to who knows where.
So I am just enjoying what he
has to offer while he's offering.
Appropriate urinary output.
Normal weight reading.
And... running on the wheel.
Patient H, you're looking great.
Very good.
Patient I, what can I say?
Appropriate urinary output.
I cannot believe I am talking
to mice like they are... Oh, no.
No, no, no. Mouse J? Mouse J!
OK, so just pretend my
hoodie's a gown. OK?
And... open your eyes.
What do you think? I had
it made to look like yours.
I... I can see that.
I have loved this picture
since I was a little girl
and I just wanted
to surprise you. I...
Do you like it?
OK, what, Mom?
- What don't you like?
- Nothing. It's...
It's lovely.
Lovely?
- That's... it?
- What else would
you like me to say?
Oh, I don't know, something.
I've been bending over backwards
since you first got here just
to make you feel comfortable.
I didn't ask you to
do anything for me.
I'm getting married
in a church for you!
Don't you dare imply there's anything
about a wedding to a woman or...
a baby out of
wedlock that's for me.
Wow... OK.
So, what bothers you more? My
bastard child or my lesbian fiancee?
You're a lawyer, Mom. You're out in
the world, you know other gay people.
Your secretary is gay.
I'm your daughter.
Do you know how
devastating it is
to raise a child
and to love a child
and know you won't
see that child in heaven?
Mom.
You are not a bride.
And I am not the
mother of a bride.
And this...
This isn't your wedding.
It isn't right. I'm sorry,
but I can't be here.
I just can't.
Sefu.
Didn't they get you a cot so you
could stay with your brother tonight?
I can't sleep.
Back home, I have
all these sisters.
But Kondo, he's my only brother.
And...
I don't want to lose him.
I know you don't. I know.
You have apparently stopped
answering your pages in order to what?
Join the kitchen staff? I
need those post-op reports.
Wet-to-dry dressing
applied in 1810,
vitals stable on your
Crohn's patient post-op.
You were exposed to HIV positive
blood. You've checked yourself for cuts.
I'm a doctor. We get exposed to things
all the time. I know proper protocol.
And this sticky yellow
mess here? This took priority
over reporting back
to me because...?
This sticky yellow
mess is nsima.
It's a maize porridge which
happens to be a staple
in most East African countries.
I found the recipe online.
I'm not sure why Asha
hasn't eaten in two days,
but I am sure that she's not used
to eating processed, American food.
I don't expect you to care, but
when she is ready to eat after surgery,
she's gonna be hungry. And
she's used to corn porridge.
So while I can't make her talk, I
can't do anything about the fact
that she is sick, that
she has advanced TB,
that she's a ten-year-old
living with AIDS, I can do this!
I can make my patient
something she might eat.
So, unless you have more insults
for me, Dr. Stark, I'm a little busy now,
making porridge.
I tried to reason with
her. She won't listen.
She's just sitting
downstairs in the car. I...
I don't know what to say,
sweetheart. I'm so sorry.
- Daddy, you need to go, OK?
- Go? I'm not leaving.
You have to go, OK?
Because if you don't,
I will start crying and then
that will make you feel bad
and then I will feel
worse, so you have to go.
OK.
Is there any milk over there?
Alex. Is there any more milk?
So you're not talking
to me now, is that it?
You told me to shut up, so I'm just
gonna sit here and read this cereal box
and practice keeping
my mouth shut.
I didn't change any
data or falsify any results.
Or switch a syringe so some sweet,
sad, old lady would get the drug
and not the placebo?
That's what I thought.
Nothing I did will
change any results.
It doesn't change the potential
effectiveness of the drug,
- it doesn't change anything.
- Except the life
of the guy who was supposed
to get the drug and now won't.
Look, the truth will come out.
And when the FDA investigates,
they'll invalidate Seattle
Grace as a research institution.
That blacklists you, Derek, every
fricking doctor in this hospital.
This is bigger than you. It messes
with me, it messes with everyone.
I'm a lot of things, but I'm not a
liar. I never thought you were either.
So, what are you
saying? You're gonna tell?
Morning.
I'm late for work.
OK.
All right.
Oh...
Oh, good. Can I
borrow something?
It can be anything, really. A
handkerchief, a tissue, cash?
I've got something old, new, blue.
I just need something borrowed.
- I just got a call
from Father Brooks.
- Mm-hm.
His wife got into an accident.
She's OK, but they're in the ER now.
He's not gonna make
it to the wedding.
You're kidding. Please
tell me you're kidding.
Do you know how hard it was to
find a minister willing to marry us?
He left me some numbers.
We can call for a replacement.
No, no. You know what? Don't
make any calls. Don't get anyone.
Just... forget it.
I'm not getting married.
Let's go.
Mouse J, here, took a
turn for the worse last night.
I did an X-ray.
It didn't show
anything, so I did a CT.
You did an X-ray
and a CT on a mouse?
If there's anything in
this CT, I can't make it out.
I couldn't either, which
is why I did an MRI.
You did a CT and an MRI? Avery, you
have $8,000 worth of scans right here
- for a rodent.
- Yes, sir, I understand that.
But if you just look at the MRI.
Just look. What do you see?
I see a little hernia. The portal
vein is not draining very well.
Which means the problem
isn't the way the device functions.
It's where the device functions.
We just need to put it closer to
the surface, just underneath the skin.
Let's get started.
Hi. You paged?
Zola, this is Meredith.
Meredith, this is Zola.
Can you hold her for
a minute? Come here.
- Sure.
- OK.
Zola, can you
smile for me? Yeah!
See, her facial movements are
intact. OK, look, over here. See that?
Watch how she's tracking me?
Over here. Neuro exam is good,
- even after the shunt.
- Great. Did something happen?
- Why did you page?
- I need to ask you
something, OK?
- Can you excuse us
for a minute?
- Yes, doctor.
I need you to be completely
honest with me, OK?
If Alex said something to you...
Let's adopt this baby.
- What? Are you serious?
- Yeah.
You know, I was
holding her yesterday...
and she was crying
and then she stopped.
And I've held a lot of babies,
I've fixed a lot of babies,
but I looked down at Zola,
I don't know what it was.
I just couldn't imagine her being with
any other parent or any other family.
We've been trying so
hard to start a family.
And she needs one.
Let's adopt her. I'm serious.
Let's adopt her.
You realize your
door is unlocked?
I could be anyone.
I could be a burglar
coming to burgle you.
Where's the baby?
Oh! I could be a babynapper
trying to babynap you.
I know why they sent you, and
it doesn't matter what you say,
the wedding is still off.
My mom's right. It's a joke.
It's not a wedding.
And it's not happening.
- Oh, Callie...
- I can't have a priest.
I no longer have a minister.
I'm not being given away by
my dad. The wedding isn't legal.
What's the point? This isn't a wedding.
It's not even in a church. It's nothing.
It's a couple of girls
playing dress-up.
It's not real.
- It's not real.
- OK. First of all,
you do not need
the law or a priest
or your mother to
make your wedding real.
And the church... The church
can be anywhere you want it to be.
In a field, on a mountain,
right here, in this room.
Anywhere. Because
where do you think God is?
- Mm...
- Come on! He's in you,
He's in me, just right
here, in the middle of us.
Your church just hasn't
caught up to God yet.
Your mother,
she hasn't caught up to God yet.
And, by the way, she
may not ever catch up.
But it's OK. It's OK.
If you are willing to stand
up in front of your friends
and family and God,
and commit yourself
to another human being,
to give of yourself in
that kind of partnership
for better or worse,
in sickness, in health...
Honey, that is a marriage.
That is real. And
that's all that matters.
Besides, girl, I got legally
married to a man in a church.
Look how well that turned out.
- You ready for me yet?
- Just about.
OK, Grey. Time to repair the
VSD through the diverticulum.
Can I have a little
suction here, please?
- Thank you.
- Uh-huh.
There's a small defect at
the neck of the diverticulum.
Grey, pull up on your
pickups so I can get in there.
- Hold the graft.
- Are you gonna use an 11 blade
- to make the incision?
- No, she's going in blind.
Five-0 suture.
I'm sewing in the graft.
Grey, would you like
to tie off when I finish?
Yes, yes.
We addressed all the
strictures and adhesions
without sacrificing much of the
intestines at all. Hell of a save.
So Dr. Hunt, I understand
you have been put in charge
of determining the
next chief resident?
With input from all of
the attendings, obviously.
In that case, I'd like to talk
to you about April Kepner.
I think, if you check my file, you'll
see that I rarely give formal feedback
about my residents. When I do,
it is almost exclusively negative.
That said, I'd very much like
to recommend April Kepner
for the chief resident position. She
goes above and beyond for her patients,
even when she isn't asked. Well,
especially when she isn't asked.
She sees the patient as a whole,
not just as a set of symptoms.
I tell you, that kind of
caring, that can't be taught.
So I think this hospital would be lucky
to have her as the next chief resident.
Hm. Thank you, Dr. Stark.
That's very good to hear.
- And are you sure
he's still breathing?
- I'm sure, yeah.
I couldn't have done this
without you today, Avery.
Any of this. I really appreciate
your dedication to these mice,
- to this project.
- Whisker twitch!
- His whisker twitched!
- OK...
- Come on.
- All right.
- Come on, yeah.
- We did it! He's back!
- Mouse J is back, baby!
Yeah. Excellent work.
Keep this up, you may be
getting your own slow clap.
Robbins!
Baby-sitter's here,
Sofia's asleep.
I look great, by
the way. Let's go.
Robbins, you OK?
When I came out to my brother,
he asked me if that meant
that I was gonna marry a chick.
And when I said yes,
he had this big smile,
and he said, "I'm gonna
dance so hard at your wedding."
My dreams are coming true.
Dreams I didn't
even know that I had.
But my brother's not here.
He's missing it.
And I know that I'm
late, I know it, I know it.
But why do you think that my dad
schedules every minute of every day?
If every minute is accounted for, then
there's no time to slow down and just...
I just... I need a minute
to miss my brother.
Look at this list. Blood
work. Financial statements.
A home study? I mean, fire
alarms? And this is all just to see
if the USCIS thinks that
we're suitable to adopt.
- If you don't want
to do this...
- No, I do.
- She could be our little girl.
- She will be.
Look, don't get overwhelmed, OK?
We're gonna take this list one
step at a time, one day at a time. OK?
In fact, look, I can see
something we could cross off today.
Look, right here.
I told you. I don't
wanna do that.
It's for the baby.
- OK. Are you ready?
- I am.
OK, then. Let's get married.
It's my own damn fault. Had
I minded my own business,
the wedding would be canceled and
I'd be home looking at TV by now. Hey.
You're gonna be fine.
You're doing great. Come on.
- OK.
- OK, right here. All right.
- You can let go of my hand now.
All right.
Hi.
They're ready.
- Don't trip,
don't trip, don't trip.
- You're not gonna trip.
You're right. I won't.
OK. Um...
Who gives this
bride to this bride?
That'd be me.
- Applicants Grey and Shepherd?
- That'd be us.
- Here you go.
- Need to see some ID.
OK, this seems to be
in order. I'll jump right in.
We are here today to
participate in a marital union.
To celebrate love and
happiness and loyalty
and, in my opinion,
a little bit of magic.
Acting in conformity to
the laws and regulations
- of the state of Washington...
- To bring together
two exceptional
and beautiful human beings.
Since it is your intention
to enter into marriage,
join hands and repeat after
me. "I, Derek Shepherd..."
- I, Derek Shepherd.
- I take you, Calliope Torres,
- to be my wife.
- For better or for worse.
In good times and bad.
I choose you to be the one
with whom I spend my life.
Do you have some token
you wish to exchange?
- No, we didn't
have time to get rings.
- OK, we'll skip that part.
I love you.
OK, you sign there
and you sign there.
By these acts and according to
the laws of the State of Washington...
OK, I hereby pronounce
you wife and wife.
- Congratulations.
- Well, thank you.
Next applicants, please.
First dance!
So, what happened with Teddy?
Did you talk to her?
So my date just called to say
she got stuck delivering a baby.
Literally. The baby
got stuck, halfway out.
I was wrong to doubt the
mice. Karev, watch your back.
Mouse J has just
made me a contender.
- Thank you, Mouse J.
- To Mouse J.
You're not the only
contenders, you know.
My sources tell me that
Kepner could be a dark horse.
No offense, Dr. Hunt, but I have you
scheduled for a Swenson procedure
on a two-year-old orphan tomorrow
morning. I'm sure you understand.
I'm just looking out for the kids
that I brought here. From Africa.
Any idea when they're cutting the
cake? I wanted to take a piece to Adele.
Oh, I have no idea, sir.
You know, it's funny
how things work out.
Karev's stepped up,
Jackson's starting to shine.
There's Kepner, Grey.
But, I always assumed that you'd be
the front-runner for chief resident, Yang,
but just goes to show,
can't count anyone out.
I'm gonna check on that cake.
- You want a real apology?
- Can't this wait
till work tomorrow,
- 'cause my date's
waiting for me.
- No, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry I'm such an exceptional
surgeon that it threatens you.
I'm sorry my surgical repair
saved Callie's life and yours didn't.
I'm sorry your ego is so fragile
that I had to stand on the sidelines
of a surgery I should have
been performing with you today,
but I have been standing on the
sidelines for the past three months,
basically ruining my
chances for chief resident.
You want sincerity? I
could not be more sincere.
And yet, you still don't get it.
- Hey.
- My glass is empty. Again.
- I, uh... I have
a proposition for you.
Mm! I like the sound of that.
I've been offered a position
at Landstuhl Medical Center.
In Germany? Wow.
Wow, that's, uh...
That's an amazing facility.
The position they
offered me is permanent.
- - So I accepted.
On one condition.
That they find an opening
for my incredibly talented
cardiothoracic
surgeon girlfriend.
- Andrew...
- I live a nomadic life,
and it's never
bothered me till now.
I wanna settle down, I wanna
start a life with someone.
And I'm hoping that
that someone is you.
Just when we think
we've figured things out,
the universe throws
us a curve ball.
All right, it's now time to clear
the dance floor and make way
for the father-daughter
dance, folks.
Oh, crap. I forgot to
take that off the schedule.
- I meant to. I'm sorry.
- No, no, no. Of course you should
get to dance with
your dad. It's OK.
I'll just sit this one out.
- OK.
- Go ahead.
No, you won't. I'm a
father. I can dance.
- Let's dance.
- - So we have to improvise.
Sh...
We really need to leave if we're
gonna even make an appearance.
Just one more minute.
- You said that 20 minutes ago.
- What's the difference?
Listen to her. Look at
her. Come on, listen to that.
We're not gonna make
the wedding, are we?
They'll understand. We'll
get them a really nice present.
Right? Look at you. Look at her.
Look at her!
We find happiness
in unexpected places.
- May I cut in?
- She's all yours.
We find our way back to the
things that matter the most.
I was driving to the airport
with your mother, and it hit me.
I've been looking forward to
dancing with you on your wedding day
since I first held you in my arms. So I
turned the car around and came back.
So here I am. To
have this dance.
With my daughter.
The universe is funny that way.
Sometimes, it just has a
way of making sure we wind up
exactly where we belong.