.
- We found a mass.
It's a cancer
of the soft tissue
called a synovial sarcoma.
Carmen and I
used to go together.
- You cheated on her.
- It's gonna be okay.
I can't--
- Terrell, Terrell, Terrell!
- I booked a flight
to Detroit tonight
to go finalize my divorce.
Wish me luck.
- Who's hitting you up
at this hour?
- It's your mom, actually.
- Dinner, then my place?
- Not tonight.
- Picking up a vibe
of not any night.
- Could I ask you
to take me home?
- Absolutely.
- Sorry, I didn't mean
to wake you up.
- Hey.
- Okay, I did, actually.
Here.
- Oh, thank you.
- You know, you really
didn't need to sleep over.
- Oh, well, I don't know
if this rings a bell,
but you were poisoned
with carfentanil yesterday.
Yeah, your sats could have
dipped overnight, so cheers.
- You made me wear
a pulse ox to bed.
I'm pretty the alarms
would have woken me up.
- Yeah, well, people have been
known to sleep through alarms.
- Oh. Okay.
- So what's on tap today?
Taking it easy, I hope.
- Yeah, I'm catching up
on some journal articles
that I agreed
to peer review ages ago,
and prepping my expert
testimony for a med mal case.
- Ah.
Hard being a luminary
in the field, huh?
- Well, stick with me,
maybe you'll find out.
♪
- Lonnie!
- Daniel.
Sorry, do we have
a session this morning?
- No, no, no, I'm just here
for a cleaning with Dr. Dennis,
you know, and my semi-annual
flossing lecture.
- Yeah. I know.
I see Dr. Dennis too,
so I am familiar.
Better get inside. It's cold.
- You know what, I'm actually
really glad I ran into you.
I've left a couple messages
on your answering service.
You know, I'd love
to get back on the schedule.
- Oh, God, I'm so sorry.
My assistant is out
on maternity leave,
and I've been struggling
to keep up.
- I totally get it.
Anyway, if you're doing
in-person again,
I mean, is my 5:30 Thursday--
is that still available?
- Um, right.
Well, here's the thing.
I'm cutting back on my hours
as I look towards retirement,
and I'm trying to lighten
my patient load, you know, so.
But I've already got
several excellent referrals
lined up for you.
- Wait, what?
- You know,
working with a new therapist
can be a really good thing.
Shake things up a bit.
- So you do think that--
that I've been--
I've been treading water?
- No, no, no, not at all.
Look, I have an 8:00.
I'm gonna email you
those referrals.
And you have my number.
You can call me
if you need anything.
♪
- Hey.
- Oh, I appreciate you
staying with him.
I always like somebody there
when he wakes up, you know?
- Oh, yeah, yeah, of course.
- Yeah.
- Get your errands done?
- Yeah. Yeah.
- Any word from Terrell?
- No.
- I'm really sorry, Carmen.
You don't deserve this.
- You really want to speak
on what I deserve from my man?
- Yeah. Yeah, you're right.
It's not my place.
- Yeah.
- Mom?
- Yes. Uh-huh?
- Can I have some water?
- Yeah, yeah, I'll be
right there, baby, okay?
I gotta--I should--I should--
- Of course.
- Okay, thank you, though.
All right.
Somebody's thirsty? Huh?
Here you go.
- Need some help over here!
- Thanks, Leah. We got it.
Doris?
- Uh, take Baghdad.
- All right, follow me.
We're going in here.
- What happened, bud?
- Right here.
- I looked over and I saw Pete
here was having, like,
some kind of, like, spasm?
He was jerking all around.
He was holding
his circular saw,
and he-he sliced his thigh.
- There you go, nice and easy.
All right, let's get a line.
Get 4 of morphine.
Also, draw a lab,
CBC and BMP to start, please.
- Normal breath sounds.
- Good.
- Do you have a history
of seizures?
♪
- You, uh, you mind stepping
out to the waiting area?
These rooms get crowded
pretty fast.
- Yeah, yeah.
No, no, no problem.
- We'll come by shortly
with an update.
- Sure. Thanks, doc.
- Yeah, you got it.
- Okay, go ahead, bud.
I was diagnosed with epilepsy
about three years ago.
Nobody at my work knows.
- Okay.
- Are you on any
anti-epileptic drugs?
- Yes, the generic stuff,
but the side effects
are a bitch.
Pardon my French,
but I just don't think
they're doing anything for me.
I keep having the seizures.
- Well, we definitely want
to figure out
why your meds aren't working.
But first, why don't we
get this leg cleaned out
and stitched up.
Sound like the right order?
- Yeah.
Can I get somebody tell
my buddy I'm gonna be awhile?
Tell him to get back
to the job site.
My boss will blow a gasket
he's down two guys all day.
- Yeah. Sure thing.
♪
.
- Hey.
- So, uh, how'd it go
within your ex?
- Oh, uh, yeah,
it went well, actually.
- Well, guess you were right.
Face-to-face was the way to go.
- Yeah. Definitely.
- It feels like we should mark
the occasion.
Let me take you to Molly's
for a drink tonight.
- Listen, last night,
things didn't go exactly
as I anticipated.
- Is that your wedding ring?
So you went to Grosse Pointe
to end your marriage,
and you came back
with your wedding ring on.
- Andrew and I
talked all night.
It was the most
honest conversation we've had.
He brought up the idea
of giving it one last try.
- Mm.
You think I'm being naive.
- I've just never seen
the whole
breakup-to-makeup thing work.
But hey, what do I know?
- Good point.
Serial monogamist, pushing 40.
- Ouch.
Okay, I'm still
several degrees south of 40,
thank you very much.
You know, good luck
with the long distance.
It's famously known to go well.
- Well, it may
only be temporary.
The chief of ED
at Andrews Hospital,
my old hospital,
is retiring next month.
Andrew wants to put me up
for the job.
- Wow.
When in the evening
did the job offer come up?
- It's not an offer.
He just wants to recommend me.
- Prospect of a job.
Did it happen before
or after you agreed to give
the marriage another go?
- Feels like you're suggesting
I was manipulated,
bought in some way.
- I'm not.
- Good.
- Going to Treatment 5.
What do we got?
- Emily Torres, 31-year-old
female, 37 weeks pregnant.
Spilled boiling water
on her abdomen
while removing a pot
from the stove.
- Please tell me the baby's
gonna be okay,
that I didn't hurt her.
- Honey, you didn't.
I googled it. This happens
more than you think.
- I'm not usually such a klutz.
You know, I've just been
in this fog lately,
and I got this cold
I can't shake.
- She is running a slight
fever, 100.5.
- Okay. On me.
One, two, three.
All right. Let's see.
Ooh.
Think I'm gonna have to agree
with Dr. Google on this one.
But I'll bring in
our resident burn expert
to take a look, okay?
Trini, can you see if Dr. Arch
is available, please?
- You got it.
- Okay.
Lean up a little bit
for me, okay?
- Careful.
Okay. Lungs are clear.
How long have you
had this cold?
- Couple of weeks, I think.
- Yeah, she woke up, like,
two weeks ago
with a sore throat.
- Hello, there. I'm Dr. Archer.
Let's see what we got.
Okay.
Okay, about 4% TBSA.
Superficial, partial thickness.
Wash and dress.
Okay.
All right,
you've got skin-level burns.
No associated
blunt force trauma.
Completely harmless
to the fetus.
- Oh, thank God.
- But your lymph nodes
are slightly swollen,
so I'd like to run some labs.
- Wait, you think this is
more than a cold?
- Oh, not necessarily,
but I'd like to do
a respiratory panel
and a strep test.
- Just covering our bases.
- Okay, sure.
- Whatever you need to do.
- First-time parents?
- I'm not sure.
- Hey, I'm not asking,
I'm telling you.
First-timers give off
a very distinct odor.
Fear.
- All right, I'll be back
in a bit, all right?
- Hey.
- So I reviewed
Pete's history.
- Okay.
- I think
his epilepsy diagnosis
was rushed at best,
negligent at worst.
He was never referred
to a specialist,
and no one ever confirmed it
with an MRI or an EEG.
- If he's not having
epileptic seizures,
then he shouldn't be
on anticonvulsants.
- No.
He needs to spend a few days
in a seizure monitoring unit.
Undergo far more extensive
testing.
- Yeah, I'll say.
Okay, I'll check in
with Med's SMU,
see if they have any room,
and we can flip
the idea to Pete?
- Yeah, that'd be great.
Thank you.
- Okay. Yeah. I'll see you.
- Yeah.
- All right.
- Hey, Dr. Marcel.
- Yeah.
- Can I borrow you
for a minute?
- Okay.
- So, uh,
you work closely
with Dr. Blake.
What's her deal?
- Her deal?
- Yeah. She seeing anyone?
- I think that's more
a question for her.
- Oh, come on.
It was Valentine's Day
last week.
She have any flowers
waiting in her office?
She mention having plans?
- What is this,
kind of hospital policy thing?
- No, it's--I guess
it's a vibe thing.
- A vibe thing?
- Yeah, I got a vibe.
- Okay.
- Maybe she's interested,
you know.
- I'm a little surprised,
because I always thought
you frowned
upon workplace relationships.
I mean, I clearly recall
you sending Dr. Manning
and I to HR.
- Yeah, I may have broadened
my thinking in the matter.
- Okay.
Oh, man. Shoot.
She-she did mention something.
- So she's seeing someone.
- I believe so.
- Okay.
- Yeah.
- All right, well,
never mind then.
All right.
- Okay.
- It's cool.
- Yeah, sorry.
- No. It's all right.
It's all good.
- Ah, look who decided
to show up today.
- I'm sorry I'm late.
- You know, the ED was
on the verge of collapse.
Oh, Maggie,
you actually look like
you're on the verge
of collapse.
What's wrong?
- I'm okay, and I tested
negative for COVID.
But I feel a little shaky.
Nauseated too.
Must have caught a 24-hour bug.
- Okay.
Well, let me check you out.
- No, no, no, no,
my shift is starting.
Good morning, Nancy.
- Nancy, mind staying on
as charge nurse for a bit?
- No problem.
- Looks like you're free.
Come on. Let's go.
- Dr. Halstead, CFD's here
with an elderly female
with Alzheimer's.
Suffered a fall
while home alone.
You're in Treatment 3.
- Show me the chart.
- Will do.
- Lorraine Hendrix, 75-year-old
female with Alzheimer's.
Fell down a short flight
of stairs.
Didn't report hitting her head,
and pain is confined
to the right wrist.
- Okay, who called 911?
- She did.
- Did I do something wrong?
My daughter was out
running an errand.
- No, you did the right thing,
Mrs. Hendrix.
It was good you called us.
Her chart says
she doesn't have children?
- Maybe she's confused.
She did give us the number
for her daughter.
- All right, we'll sort it out.
Okay, on my count.
Ready, one, two, three.
Thank you.
Okay, Mrs. Hendrix,
see if you can
follow the light
with just your eyes.
Try not to move
your head, okay?
Good.
- Oh, thank God.
I'm her daughter, Cindy.
- You are?
Sorry, there was confusion
because her chart--
- It says Lorraine
doesn't have kids.
Technically she's my stepmom,
but she's been in my life
since I was 13 years old.
She lives with me now.
- Good to know.
We'll make note.
- I feel terrible.
I just went
to the corner store.
I couldn't have been gone
more than ten minutes.
I've got an overnight shift
at the hospital.
- Oh yeah? Where do you work?
- St. Luke's. I'm a nurse.
Try to avoid the night shift,
but I couldn't get out of it
this month.
Lorraine doesn't like it
when I'm not there for bedtime.
That's why I went
to the market, actually,
to get her favorite cookies.
- Okay.
- I like to have them
on hand for the caregiver.
- Negotiation tactic?
- Exactly.
- Well, listen, I'd like to get
an X-ray of her wrist
to be safe,
but she's gonna be fine.
- Fine.
- Let's get an X-ray.
- You're gonna want
to look at this.
Emily Torres, pregnant woman.
It's her test results.
- What am I looking--oh, man.
- Yeah, syphilis.
If mom has it,
high risk of congenital
infection if not addressed.
- Right, if we don't treat it,
baby could be born
with severe impairments.
- Yeah.
- All right. I'll go tell them.
- Wait, wait, wait, wait, no,
no, no, no, no, no.
If you tell the husband,
then you also out the wife.
Right, you can't tell him that
she's contracted an STI
without her permission.
- Yeah, but I mean, he has
every right to know
about the health of his child.
He's the father.
Can't just shut him out.
- We'd like
to admit you to Med's
Seizure Monitoring Unit
for five to seven days
for continuous
video EEG monitoring.
- Yeah, no.
That's not happening.
I can't take a week off work.
- Well, maybe as short
a stay as possible.
- Sure. A couple hours?
- Well, no,
that's not enough time.
- Besides, there's no way
my crap insurance
is gonna cover that.
- Well, listen, we can help you
navigate the insurance side
of things.
- Look, I know you mean well.
But when I leave here,
it's not like--
you're not gonna be
coming over to help me fill out
the paperwork
and file the claims.
Okay, I've got three kids.
One of them, I just found out
this morning needs braces,
and my wife has MS,
she can't even work anymore.
Our roof is caving in,
and-and--
- I'm so sorry.
- Look, I'm not telling you
my sob story for pity, okay?
I'm just saying
so that you understand
that me missing a week--
- Hey, hey, hey! Pete, Pete!
2 of Ativan. Hey! Pete!
- Hold his legs.
- Pete!
- Put pressure on the joints.
.
- You know, in addition
to her privacy,
we also have to consider
Mrs. Torres' safety
and well-being.
Any red flag her husband might
become violent at the news?
- Not that I've witnessed.
And what about
Mr. Torres' well-being?
I mean, he needs
to be tested too.
- Well, syphilis diagnosis
requires reporting to IDPH,
and they will immediately
begin contact tracing,
and Mr. Torres
will be notified.
- Terrific. we're all
in agreement then, right?
Let's let the Health Department
inform Dad.
- No, listen, when you speak
to Mrs. Torres,
strongly encourage her
to share the information
with her husband.
Let's start there.
- Well, it strikes me it might
be wise to have somebody
from Senior Admin deliver
the news with Dr. Scott.
Uh, some member from Risk
Management should be present,
given the sensitivity,
don't you think?
- You know, someone like, uh,
the chief of the ED.
- I'm thinking higher,
you know,
Executive director
of patient services, maybe?
- Mm-hmm, and where will
you be, Dr. Archer?
- Well, three's really
kind of a crowd, yeah?
♪
- You notice the way his head
was moving back and forth
during the seizure,
and he was bicycling his legs?
- Yeah, and he didn't seem
to lose consciousness
at any point.
You thinking what I'm thinking?
- All suggestive of PNES.
- Yeah.
- Psychogenic
non-epileptic seizures
are commonly misdiagnosed
as epilepsy.
- Yeah, and stress
is a known factor,
and this poor guy's
got a lot going on.
- We've got to convince Pete
to admit himself
to a seizure monitoring unit.
I've looking into it
extensively.
It's really the only way
to get a definitive diagnosis.
- Yeah, well,
you heard the guy.
Unless his finances magically
change, he's not gonna budge.
He can't budge.
- I'm gonna talk
to Social Services.
You know, maybe he could apply
for worker's comp,
since the injury took place
while using
workplace machinery?
I mean, at least it would
alleviate some of his concerns
about missing a paycheck.
- Yeah, sure.
it's a long shot, though.
- It's all we got.
I'll see you in a bit.
- Dr. Halstead.
I'm sorry to bother you.
I work in an ED myself.
I know how backed up
things can get.
But we're still
waiting on radiology
to read my mom's X-ray.
- You know, do me a favor.
Hang tight,
and I will make sure
someone reads that X-ray
as soon as possible, okay?
- Fine.
- Hey, thank you
for your patience.
Dr. Charles.
Mind if I run something by you?
- What's up?
- I've got a patient who was
diagnosed a year ago
with Alzheimer's.
But she is now exhibiting
a surprising level of cognition
at this stage of the disease.
No problem
following directions.
She even had the wherewithal
to call 911 herself.
- You think maybe she was
diagnosed prematurely?
- So here's where
it gets strange.
I reviewed her scans
from a year ago.
MRI and PET scans show atrophy
to the hippocampus
as well as
abnormal accumulations
of amyloid plaques.
- Consistent with
Alzheimer's diagnosis.
- Exactly, but we both know
this isn't a disease
that gets better with time,
so unless this is some kind of
medical breakthrough, I mean--
- You mind coming upstairs?
I'm running
a little bit behind.
- Sure.
I don't want to jump the gun,
you know,
get Lorraine's
or her daughter's
hopes up prematurely.
- Look, why don't I stop by,
just have a, you know,
casual chat with Lorraine,
maybe do a little
under-the-radar
cognitive assessment?
- Yeah, that'd be great.
- All right.
I will be down shortly,
all right?
Give me, like, 15.
- You got it. Thank you.
♪
- Hi, Lonnie, it's Dan.
Look, I'm sorry
to use your cell,
but I just really wanted to
make sure you got this message.
I would very much like
to continue our conversation
that we started this morning,
so could you please call me
back when you get this message?
Thank you very much.
♪
- Your labs are back.
- It's not
a stomach bug, is it?
- No.
- All right, Vanessa.
Whatever it is.
- Maggie, you're pregnant.
- Wha--
♪
- I have syphilis?
What? No.
No, that-that has to be wrong.
I was screened for syphilis at
my first prenatal appointment.
- You were likely infected
after the first test
was performed.
- That's impossible.
I've only been
with my husband, I swear.
So--
You run your test again
because there's just--
there's no
possible explanation.
I can't believe he would...
But I'm carrying our child.
- Emily, do you need a minute?
- No. No.
I just need to know
what to do for my baby, so...
How do I treat this?
- Well, we are gonna start you
on penicillin immediately.
- Which typically resolves
the infection
in both mother and baby.
- And then what if it doesn't?
Then what?
What could it do to my baby?
- While, again, we have
every reason to believe
this won't be the case,
syphilis in pregnancy
can result in organ damage,
severe anemia, stillbirth--
- Emily!
Honey, what's wrong?
Is it the baby?
- What the hell
is wrong with you?
How could you do this to us?
- Mr. Torres, please, please,
step out of the room.
We can speak out there.
- Dr. Scott,
why don't you take him
to the consultation room?
- Yes, ma'am.
- Well, I caught the tail end.
Went about as well
as I expected.
♪
.
- Are you menstrual cycles
often irregular?
- Yeah, they are.
- Okay, and how many
prior pregnancies?
- Just one.
That's you, Vanessa.
- All right.
I think we have everything.
I'll reach out to Obstetrics
and see
if they can squeeze you in
for an ultrasound
at the end of the day.
- Okay. I'll let Ben know.
- Okay.
Wait, Maggie, I--
congratulations.
I'm so happy for you.
- Yeah. Thank you.
- I know it's a lot to take in.
Are you okay?
- Yeah, no, I'm good.
I just have to relieve Nancy.
- Okay, I'm stopping
the infusion, Pete.
Drugs should be
leaving your system.
- What drug?
- Should start coming down now.
Should be
coming down soon, Pete.
- What'd you give him?
- There you go.
- Why didn't tell me ahead
of time what you were doing?
- Not everyone is on board
with noceboes.
- yeah, because noceboes
are completely unethical
outside of clinical trials.
- I disagree.
- Really?
Okay, well, I don't know
how you justify
lying to a patient's face,
but please, go ahead.
- It's a diagnostic tool.
- Predicated on a lie.
You gave Pete saline, told him
it was medication
to induce a seizure.
- Which it did.
- So that makes it okay?
- Listen, this is not the route
I'd prefer to take.
- Oh, we agree on something.
- You got nowhere
with Social Services,
we had no options,
and now we can take Pete
off the anticonvulsants, right?
- Yeah?
Okay, by telling him what,
exactly?
- That no abnormal
brain activity
was recorded
during the seizure.
- The seizure you tricked him
into having.
- I think Pete will see
the bigger picture.
- Well, I guess we'll find out,
'cause if you don't
tell him the truth, I will.
- Hi there. I am Dr. Charles.
- Someone read my mom's X-ray?
- Yes.
And the good news
is that it's not broken.
So all we need to do
is get you a splint and--
- Ice and elevate. Yeah.
I know the drill.
Can I get her discharge papers?
- Of course.
I'll have the nurses bring them
in as soon as they're ready.
What are you reading?
- Oh.
- Oh, boy.
You know,
my favorite Neruda poem
is "The Book of Questions."
That last line,
"Is there anything
in the world sadder..."
- "Than a train standing
in the rain?"
- Yeah.
- I'm sorry, but who are you?
Did Dr. Halstead leave?
- No. No, he didn't.
- I'm Dr. Charles.
- Psychiatry.
Do you mind if we step outside
for a minute?
- Of course.
Nice to meet you, Lorraine.
- Nice to meet you too.
- I don't want my mom
undergoing any unnecessary
psychological testing.
- Of course.
- It just confuses
and upsets her.
- We wouldn't do that.
- Then what are you doing?
- Cynthia, hi.
Everything all right?
- I just, I don't know
why you handed
my mom's case off to Psych.
I just really want
to get her home again.
- We're doing our best
to make that happen.
Hey, you should know
I'm seeing a level of cognition
in Lorraine
that is very rare
at this stage of the disease.
So with your permission,
I'd like to get new scans
of her brain.
- No.
She's--I'm not putting her
in an MRI machine again.
She's extremely claustrophobic.
- You know, sedation can
really help with that.
- She's having a good day.
That's all.
You didn't see her last week,
when she could barely remember
how to bathe or dress herself.
I'm sorry.
- No, it's okay.
- Lorraine, she's lived
in fear of this disease
her entire life.
Her mom died of it.
Her mom's mom.
- I'm sorry to hear that.
- None of that made it
any easier
when Lorraine got
the diagnosis herself.
♪
- You have any allergies?
- No.
This will cure me?
- The shot will eradicate
the infection, yeah.
- How's Emily?
- She got a shot too.
Monitoring her and the baby,
and so far,
they're responding well.
- You must think I'm the
biggest piece of garbage
on the planet.
I would.
Just going over all the reasons
I cheated on her, man,
and they are so unbelievably
lame and cliche.
- All right, look, man,
you made a choice.
Made. It already happened.
You gotta live with it.
All this analyzing
and replaying things over
won't change it.
♪
It's just my opinion,
but your time would be
better served being there
for Emily and your baby.
In whatever way she'll allow.
- I can't stall them
much longer.
- Look, I put in a call
to this doctor
who diagnosed Lorraine
with Alzheimer's,
all right, Dr. Caleb Hunter.
- Good thinking. What'd he say?
- Not a whole lot
because he died five years ago.
- Before Lorraine
was even diagnosed.
- Yeah.
♪
.
- Maggie, hey,
I got you an appointment
with Dr. Patchefsky at 5:00.
Can Ben make it?
- He's on a field trip today
with the kids.
- I could go with you.
- No, it's not a big deal.
I'll be fine.
- Okay.
Maggie, are you not happy
about the news?
- No, I'm happy.
It's just that--
- Look, when I was going
through everything
a couple of months back,
you were there for me
in an unbelievable way,
and I just really want
to be here for you now.
- That's different.
- I don't think so.
Unless you don't feel
comfortable opening up to me.
- That's not it.
- Well, then, just let me help.
- I don't want to hurt you.
- Why would you?
- Because.
I'm excited. I'm overjoyed.
But I don't want you to feel
that
this baby is wanted
and that you weren't--
- Maggie, I'm not making
comparisons, I promise.
You work so hard to protect me
and my feelings
like a mom would,
but Maggie, you're my friend.
And I-I just hope
that I'm yours too.
♪
- Cindy, I just need to ask
your mom one more question,
if that's okay.
Lorraine, do you remember ever
being evaluated by a doctor?
- I told you
to leave her alone.
What's going on?
- Do you remember ever being
evaluated by a doctor
for Alzheimer's disease?
- Of course,
she doesn't remember.
She has Alzheimer's!
- Cindy, why don't
we step outside?
- Get the hell out of here.
- Get your hands
behind your back.
- What's happening?
- What the hell is this?
- you're under arrest for
felony forgery and bank fraud.
- I don't understand.
- I'm not saying anything
without a lawyer.
- Come on. Let's go.
What?
- Lorraine, we'd like
to take you for an MRI.
We don't believe
you have Alzheimer's.
♪
- There you go. Let it out.
Let it out.
She started having contractions
a few minutes ago,
and in that times she's become
hypotensive and tachycardic.
- A Jarisch-Herxheimer
reaction?
- What? Wait, what's that?
- A reaction to the penicillin
may be putting you into labor.
- No, no, no, no.
I can't--I can't
go into labor now.
The antibiotics need
more time to work.
- Okay, first things first,
can you put your heels together
for me and let your legs
lower, please?
- He's gonna check to see
how dilated you are.
- All right.
- Look at me. Look at me.
Look at me.
- Emily, you're about 9 1/2
centimeters dilated, all right?
So we're gonna take you up to
Labor and Delivery right now.
Go get a transport team
and a precip pack.
- No, no, no, please,
we have to wait.
What if the medicine--
what if my baby--
- Emily, look at me.
Look at me.
Waiting is not an option.
You're too far progressed.
Okay?
- I can't.
I can't do this alone.
- I'll go with you.
- Really? You'll stay with me?
- Yes. The whole time.
All right? Come on.
I need you to continue
to breathe, okay?
Here we go.
All right, keep breathing.
There you go. That's good.
Stay with it.
Stay with it, Emily.
There you go.
- Emily. Emily.
Hey, what's happening?
Where are they taking her?
- Emily's in labor.
- What?
Oh, my God. Can I be with her?
- Listen, I can ask her
if she wants you in the room.
- Um.
No. No, don't.
I don't want
to upset her right now.
- Listen, man, we are gonna
take good care of her.
Okay?
- Yeah.
- Hold up.
You think I'm faking this?
You think my seizures
aren't real?
- No, absolutely not.
Psychogenic
non-epileptic seizures
are not intentional or acted.
The symptoms are very real.
- He gave me medicine
to cause a seizure.
This isn't because
of something in my head.
- I actually gave you
saline, Pete.
- What?
- My aim was to expedite
a diagnosis,
and given the constraints
you described earlier,
I felt this was the only way.
- You're trying to say
you lied for my benefit?
- No, I'm trying to say that
if you had known
it was only saline,
it's unlikely it would have
provoked a stress response.
- Give me a supervisor.
Someone in charge. Now.
- Will do.
- Her MRI confirmed it.
Lorraine does not Alzheimer's.
- So get this.
Her scans apparently
are duplicates
of an Alzheimer's patient
from St. Luke's.
And as a registered nurse
at that hospital,
Cindy was able to just
swap them out and upload them.
- All the while draining
Lorraine's checking
and savings account, pension.
- Yeah, and according to Cindy,
Lorraine was something
of an evil stepmother
who convinced Cindy's dad
to cut her out of his will?
- Still, I mean, I've seen
some crazy stuff,
but convincing someone
they're losing their mind?
- Yeah, we can bet she played
off of Lorraine's terror
of eventually
developing the disease, right?
I mean,
given the family history?
You second-guess somebody
long enough,
eventually they start
to question
their perception of reality.
Anyway, good work today.
♪
- All right, let's take a peek.
- Okay.
- I'm gonna look at the wall.
And you tell me when you see
ten fingers and ten toes.
- Maggie, it's way too early
for fingers and toes.
- You know what I mean.
- Okay, I'll let you know
when to look.
- Oop, sorry.
- It's okay. Go ahead.
♪
What?
That's not a baby.
.
- Maggie, why don't you
get changed,
and then we can
discuss next steps.
- The mass. Is it malignant?
- It's not
an ectopic pregnancy.
But other than that,
it's way too soon to speculate.
We're going
to draw tumor markers,
get you scheduled for surgery,
and then we'll send
the tissue for pathology.
- Listen, there are--there are
several tumors, many benign,
that can cause
HCG levels to rise
and create a false positive
pregnancy test.
- That is exactly right,
Dr. Taylor.
Let's not get
ahead of ourselves.
- Okay.
- He refused to see
anyone at Med.
But let me refer him
to a neuropsychiatrist
I know at Northwestern.
He's an old friend of mine.
He'll take good care of him.
- Great.
- Appreciate it, Dean.
Hey, listen,
I want to apologize
to both you and Stevie.
I'm sorry.
- Thank you.
- No, no need.
I mean, I'm not saying
make deception your go-to,
but if it's confirmed that
his seizures were psychogenic,
then you saved the man time,
money,
unnecessary side effects.
- While completely
eroding his trust
in the medical system.
- Well, it's not
completely eroded.
He's getting a second opinion.
- There were better ways
to get there.
- Well, in my book, your only
sin was getting caught.
- Dean.
Listen, man,
I misspoke this morning.
- About what?
- Dr. Blake isn't seeing
anyone--to my knowledge.
- Oh. That's good to know.
May the best man win.
- We come bearing
very good news.
- She doesn't have syphilis?
- No.
We tested the placenta,
umbilical cord, blood.
All negative.
- I can't thank you enough.
If you hadn't been there--
- It was my pleasure.
You were incredibly brave.
- Uh, would you excuse me
for a minute?
- I couldn't hear
what you were all saying,
but I saw Emily smiling.
- It's all good.
Baby tested negative.
- I'm sorry.
God, I was so scared.
- It's okay.
You know, maybe with some time
and a little space,
you and Emily
can patch things up.
- Yeah. I hope so.
♪
- Hey, Will.
- Stevie, I'm sorry.
- Wow.
You're the second person
to apologize to me this hour.
What are you sorry for?
- This morning. I, um.
I wasn't trying to make you
second-guess yourself.
Actually, no, I was.
It's been nice, you know,
having my old rival back.
You keep me on my toes.
But, uh, you gotta do
what's right for you.
- Yeah, well,
it's not a done deal.
I'd be lying if I said I'm not
proceeding with caution.
But I can't just walk away
from my marriage.
- Well, I, uh,
I hope it all works out.
♪
- Hey. You okay?
- Hey, uh,
I just--you know, what I did,
back when I stepped--
- Oh, no, D, forget it.
Come on.
I was playing with you earlier.
We were kids.
It's water under the bridge.
- Uh, I appreciate that. I do.
But, uh...
It's impossible not
to think about what I missed.
What could have been had
I not ruined everything.
♪
- Thank you.
- Come in.
Lonnie.
- I got your message.
I actually had to check on
a patient up in the psych ward,
so thought I'd just drop by.
- Come on in. Have a seat.
- Oh, I really can't.
I have an early dinner.
So what's up?
- You know, honestly,
I was just a little thrown
by our conversation
this morning.
- Okay.
- Yeah, you know, I mean,
from my perspective,
we've had a long, successful
working relationship,
and I just, I deserve a little
bit more of an explanation
as to why
you're terminating me.
- Well, as I explained to you
this morning,
I really am cutting back
on my hours.
- Lonnie, come on.
I mean, after 20 years,
I don't make the cut?
I don't get
a little seniority here?
- Okay, fine.
There's also
a professional conflict.
- What kind of
professional conflict?
- I'd really like to just
leave it at that, if I could.
- Wait.
Did I--did I do something
to make you--
- No.
- To make you un--
Because if I've been
inappropriate in any way...
- You haven't.
- I sincerely apologize.
I've been working really hard
to re-educate myself, you know,
about appropriate language
in this day and age.
I don't always succeed.
- I have developed feelings
for you, Daniel.
You don't have to say anything.
I'd actually prefer you didn't.
But you wanted the truth.
So there. Now you have it.
- Come in.
- Hey.
- Hi.
- Fun day?
Ended with a bit
of excitement, though.
- Oh yeah?
- Yeah.
- Do tell.
- You just missed Dean Archer.
- Oh.
- He invited me to dinner.
- That was fast.
- Sorry?
- Uh, nothing.
What did you--what'd you say?
- I thanked him
for his kind invitation,
and I told him that
I don't dip my pen
in the company ink.
- Is that a hard and fast rule?
- Hmm.
- You ever make an exception?
- I don't know, I mean, I think
that would depend who's asking.
♪
- Ever make an exception?
- Hey, Mom. Oh, my God.
- Oh.
- Is this why
you ended things with me?
Because you were
screwing my mom?
- Hold on.
- Wait a second.
Ended things with you?
Did you go out
with my daughter?
- Okay. Oh, my God.
- What the hell just happened?
♪