Do you know who you are?
Do you know what's
happened to you?
Do you want to live this way?
There's a hole in
the pericardium.
That's the source
of all this blood?
No, that's what's
keeping him alive.
Well, hello.
All it takes is one person,
one patient, one moment,
to change your life forever.
Ross, I would like
to introduce you to
the black mamba.
It can change your
perspective, color your thinking...
Isn't that the IVC?
The single trickiest vessel
in the entire human body.
Delicate, unpredictable.
Hear that? The
gurgling? That's its song.
See that? Look how it twitches.
One wrong move, one
misstep, and this patient is dead.
You can't repair that
mamba without moving
with the mamba.
Some people say it's
impossible to repair.
One moment that forces you
to re-evaluate everything
you think you know.
Come on, mamba.
Let's dance.
You paged?
MVC victim.
Wanted you to take a
look at the C-spine X-rays.
Oh, damn. Poor guy.
I just nailed the mamba.
Do you know who you are?
The patient's C3 and 4 are
obliterated. His spinal cord is severed.
There's no way
I can repair that.
Do you know what's
happened to you?
But we just fixed his heart.
Against all odds.
'Cause I'm awesome.
Yeah, well, even so,
he's lost all motor function
from the neck down.
The man's paralyzed.
Do you want to live this way?
Wait, what?
Unfortunately, the impact of the
crash severed his spinal cord at C3,
which is quite
high in the neck...
Yeah, no, I'm a nurse.
I know what C3 is.
So you're saying...
He's paralyzed?
Yes.
I am so sorry.
But his brain function is good,
and I was able to
fully repair his heart.
Is his diaphragm working?
Can he breathe on his own?
No, he's currently
on a ventilator.
There are options from here,
once he's had time to recover,
surgery to fuse his
spine so he can sit up.
We can insert a permanent trach.
These are all options
we can discuss...
Will he ever breathe
on his own again?
No. He will not.
Okay,
I need you to wake
him up right now.
You can do that, right?
Elise, your husband just
underwent major surgery.
I know, and now I'm
asking you to wake him up.
And I need you to ask him if
he wants you to remove the vent.
Well, the vent is breathing for
him. It's what's keeping him alive.
I was gonna
surprise him tonight.
As an early anniversary
gift, I got us playoff tickets.
I mean, nosebleed seats,
but we kind of love it up there.
It's like, pretzels and
hot dogs for dinner.
I mean, it's fun.
The last thing I thought
when I woke up this morning
was I'd lose Jason.
I understand what I'm asking.
Believe me, I don't
want to lose him.
But...
I know him. I know
everything about him.
I understand how he
thinks. I get his humor.
I could predict what he's
gonna order in a restaurant.
And I just... I don't
think he would want this.
I know it.
I think he would rather die
than live one more minute
hooked up to a machine.
It's your husband's
right to decline treatment,
if that's what he wants.
It'll take some time
to fully wean him
off the sedation,
but I'll let you know
when he starts to wake.
Thank you.
I think she really means it.
And that bugs you?
No. I mean, maybe. I don't know.
It's just... I don't know.
It's not like I want to get
married tomorrow, but never?
But you're with her.
If you love her, who cares if
she's not the marrying kind?
I wasn't. ALEX:
Yeah, but then you did.
Right, but some people don't.
So, what, we just keep
doing what we're doing
for the next 20
years, and that's it?
But if you're together,
what does it matter?
Hey!
Hey.
Didn't see you there.
You okay?
Yep.
Jason?
My name is Dr. Yang.
I know you must be
very confused right now,
but I need to ask you
some questions, okay?
There's a tube down your
throat, so you can't speak,
but you should be
able to nod "yes" or "no."
Think you can do that for me?
That's great. Okay.
Let's get started.
Do you know who you are?
Do you know where you are?
Do you know what
has happened to you?
You were in a car accident.
Your vehicle was hit from behind,
and you flipped over
into oncoming traffic.
You're in a hospital right now.
Do you know who this is?
Your spine was
crushed in the accident,
and you are paralyzed
from the neck down.
You're currently breathing
with the help of a ventilator.
That's the tube in your mouth.
Now, I understand
it might be your wish
for me to remove the vent?
I want to make sure you
understand what this means.
The ventilator is
breathing for you.
That means, once it's removed,
you will not be able
to breathe on your own.
Now, if you can't breathe,
you will die.
It might take a few
hours, probably less.
Do you understand this?
Oh, God.
Do you still want me
to remove the vent?
I love you.
And I want you to know,
whatever you decide,
I'll support you.
I'll be by your side,
no matter what.
I'm sorry, but I have
to ask one more time.
Jason,
would you like me
to remove the vent?
Do you know who you are?
Do you know what's
happened to you?
Do you want to live this way?
Oh! God!
Hey, you.
What are we doing?
What the hell are we doing?
I'm waiting for an elevator?
I just spent my day
saving the life of a man
who's now choosing to die,
and all I keep thinking is...
You and I are
throwing so much away.
We should be together.
You're the love of
my life, and it is stupid,
just stupid for us
to keep pretending.
I love you.
I want to be with
you for real, forever.
It's as simple as that.
That's it. We've christened
every room in this house.
Yeah.
And it's a pretty big
house. Mmm-hmm.
I thought I wasn't gonna
make it through the guest room.
Yeah, but you rallied at
the end. Mmm-hmm, I did.
You know, the house feels big
for just two of us. Don't you think?
Ah! He is gorgeous.
No. Oh.
Okay. Um...
This one.
I agreed to a dog,
not a horse.
That's a mid-size dog.
No, that is huge. You
know what a big dog makes?
What? Big poop.
That thing could crap
my entire body weight in a day.
That is a beautiful
image. Thank you.
That one.
What? That's the one.
No, no.
That is not even a dog.
That is a rodent,
and it looks mean.
We want this thing in here.
Can someone get it out?
Conduit, please.
Fresh off the printer.
Kid's tiny for 12 months.
He'll grow when
his heart's sending
a little more blood
around the system.
The first couple kids
we put conduits in,
you can already see the
difference in only a year.
So, I have an emergency surgery.
I'm gonna be in the OR
for the next nine hours.
Okay. Mrs. Rodriguez!
Oh, no. This is gonna
take me at least three hours.
Well, Mrs. Rodriguez
is not gonna make it.
Is she a cardio patient?
I could have somebody
page you a consult.
Mrs. Rodriguez will last until
I finish here, and then I'll go.
Ross, you'll close for me?
Yeah. Are you sure?
Well, this is why I said we
should keep the damn dog
in the kitchen when we're gone.
I am not locking the
dog in the kitchen.
Well, then you can clean up the
puddle on the rug when you get home.
I'll leave it for you!
You got a dog?
Yes.
Thing's gonna be dead in a week.
Wait. You named your
dog Mrs. Rodriguez?
When you meet
him, you'll understand.
Meet him soon, before he dies.
What? I'm a physician!
It's not like I'm gonna have
trouble keeping an animal alive.
Uh-huh. Do you have
5-0 prolene, please?
What? You think I
can't keep a dog alive?
Whatever. Don't worry about it.
He's perfectly healthy.
Alex, it's not funny.
I can't believe you're gonna
dress the dog in my son's sweater.
Mrs. Rodriguez gets cold.
He doesn't have the constitution
for all this damp and rain.
He gets the shakes.
What?
You like the dog!
He's an unusual dog.
It's not like I'm becoming
someone who likes dogs.
He just happens to
relate to people like I do.
Uh-huh.
It's true. I mean, he
doesn't want to talk
about his feelings
or the future.
If I walk him and feed
him on a regular schedule,
he'll curl up next
to me on the couch,
and if I don't, he'll
bite my ankles.
It's a set of behaviors
that makes sense to me.
You like the dog.
The dog gets you.
You're alike. That's how
I talk about my children.
You have a baby. A dog baby. Oh!
Mrs. Rodriguez!
I'm sorry.
I know how painful it is.
I've been through it myself,
but it's been over two
years since the injury,
and at some point, you just
have to say enough is enough.
What? No. You
have no idea where...
Look, your hand needs
more time, all right?
Just give your hand rest,
throw yourself into the rehab.
I've done the rehab!
It's been two years!
It's done, okay? I'm
good enough to operate.
I mean, what is this? Is
this about Mr. Willenstein?
That was a routine...
The decision has been made.
You can keep your
administrative duties,
but you are not
cleared to operate.
You're not going back in the OR.
Any other business
before we adjourn?
Actually, yes, there is.
You had to bring
it up to the board!
Yeah. It was time.
It absolutely was not time.
We didn't make the decision yet.
Well, clearly, I'm
wrong, 'cause we did.
I just wasn't part of it.
Listen,
it is the job of a lifetime.
Running the entire military
trauma division with Teddy,
it's what's next for me,
Cristina. I can feel it.
Yeah, in Germany!
We have a house!
I have my trial!
We are good here,
Owen. We're happy.
We can't just leave everything.
Just listen to me
for one second...
No. No. You want to know what?
You're not backing me into this.
Come on. Nobody
backs you into anything.
Believe me. I've tried.
So, you want me to
dump my whole trial,
just when I'm starting to get...
That is not what
I'm... Please stop.
Stop acting like you're some
hit-and-run victim.
I can't have
another conversation
where the idea that my career
or, in fact, any of my wishes
might come first
is presented as some
crime against humanity!
Oh, what?
So, now we're back
where we started?
I never give you anything,
so the terms under
which we're together
are that your dreams die?
Can you quiet the damn dog?
You know what? You quiet the
damn dog. You wanted the dog.
Not that dog! He doesn't
even like me. He only likes you.
Because you make stupid
decisions! And he knows it!
I'm not moving to Germany!
So, that's it?
Conversation's over?
Uh-huh.
Of course it is.
I don't know why
I ever entertained the
idea for one second
that we might ever do
anything that I'd want.
Shh!
Coming through! Dr. Yang!
Whatever it is, it can wait.
My shift is over,
and I am going home.
Come on. Patient
11... Jasper O'Neil.
He's back for his
annual checkup.
Apparently, he's
learning to play hockey.
You handle it. Send him my best.
But if my conduit gets smashed
because they let their kid
get body-checked on the ice,
I'm killing them! Will do.
Oh! Hi!
Hey! Who'd have thunk it?
You and me, we're belly buddies.
No, we're not.
Breathe. It's okay.
You're almost there.
All you have to do is push.
No. No can do.
We are almost there. He's
gonna have to stay in there.
I've got a cozy womb.
He'll be happier.
It'll be better for everyone.
Oh, my God! Oh, God! Oh, God!
Wait a second. You have
to wait a second. No, I can't.
You have to wait one second.
Oh, God. This is a
mistake. It's a mistake!
I Can't! I can't! What?
This is a mistake, Mer!
Everyone says that.
Here we go. We
need one more push.
Okay, now!
Push! Push! Push!
Great!
I screwed up, Mer.
Mer, I screwed up.
I really screwed up.
Shh.
I can't...
Oh...
Hello.
Oh. Go back to
sleep. I got this.
Okay.
It's okay.
You're being so good.
Yeah. He's fine. He's fine.
This is all my fault. You
know, I was at the park,
and I looked away for a
second when Ross texted me.
I was standing right there.
Listen, it's okay.
These things happen.
And have you met our son?
He lunges headfirst
into everything.
It's a wonder this
never happened sooner.
Well, we can't go
back to that park.
They need, like, sand or
some of that soft turf stuff.
I mean, who puts concrete
steps by a play space?
It's completely irresponsible.
It is a superficial cut.
He's gonna be fine.
I'm already late for my meeting.
I can't just stick
him in daycare.
Slow down. Slow down, okay?
Now, we're gonna
figure this out.
And, by the way, daycare
has very capable teachers.
Oh, please. I am capable.
So, your text said, "Make
sure the phase 3 patients go."
Go to the bathroom? Go away?
Sorry. I didn't
realize. Is he okay?
Yes. No.
Do you want me to reschedule
the phase 3 patient meetings today,
maybe try to squeeze
them in next week, or...
No, just...
Ross, will you take them?
You understand the procedure.
You know what to do. Just...
You know, I want you to
take over phase 3 from here.
What? Are you sure?
Yes. Can you do this for
me? Just do this for me, okay?
Of course, if that's
what you want.
I can't believe
Bailey's already seven.
Please tell me he has
outgrown that whole
"I fiddle with my
junk 24/7" phase,
'cause I have to practically
duct-tape Theo's pants
onto his body.
Of all the conversations that
you and I have had about boys,
I didn't expect
this one to be it.
Feel any kicks yet?
No, not really.
Nauseous? Just tired.
Every day, I go to
work and do my job.
Then I come home
and do that job.
I'm so tired.
It's like I'm
sleepwalking all the time.
Well, you're well into
your second trimester now,
so that'll start getting better.
It's not the pregnancy.
Cristina...
Look how happy he is.
You're not dressed?
We need to get going.
The Harper Avery Awards await.
Are you nervous? Are you okay?
Do you need a minute?
No.
Maybe.
Okay. But just a minute.
And then nerves of steel.
Right?
Right.
Okay.
The surgical mind needs
to be constantly inspired,
always asking the
toughest questions.
The Harper Avery Award
is a celebration of that,
of the kind of mind I
saw in tonight's recipient,
even when he was just an intern.
Ladies and gentlemen, I
am honored to present to you
this year's Harper
Avery Award recipient
to Dr. Shane Ross.
Thank you. Thank you.
First and foremost, I'd
like to thank Dr. Yang.
I wouldn't be here
without your guidance,
encouragement, and support.
All it takes is one
person, one patient
to change your life forever.
When I first met Jasper
O'Neil, he was 12 months old,
and we didn't think
he'd make it to 13.
He's here with us tonight.
Jasper, would you
stand up, please?
Cristina. Cristina.
Do you know who you are?
Do you know what's
happened to you?
Do you want to live this way?
I love you.
And I want you to know
that whatever you decide,
I'll support you.
I'll be by your side...
No matter what.
I'm sorry, but I have
to ask one more time.
Jason,
would you like me
to remove the vent?
Ah!
Son of a...
Hey, you.
I just spent my day
saving the life of a man
who could've chosen
to die but didn't.
I repaired a heart that
was impossible to repair.
I achieved the impossible
today, and it feels good.
No. More.
It feels incredible.
What are you doing right now?
Waiting for the elevator.
Yeah. We're gonna
have to take the stairs,
'cause I just finished my
shift, and I feel like celebrating.
Tonight...
Naked. With you.
Oh. I could be into that.
Are you
sure you're okay with this?
Oh, yeah, yeah. I'm very sure.
No, no.
No, not... Not this.
Us being
just us.
I know.
And I'm good.
I am.
You said you were
okay. You told me...
You told me that... I thought
I was, okay? But I'm not.
What does that...
I just need my films.
Not right this second, though.
Listen, all I am asking
is that we just reopen
this conversation.
There is nothing
left to talk about.
Owen, I was clear
about this. I was so clear.
I can't give you more than
what I am already giving,
and if now you need more...
Yes, I think I do! I think I do!
Well, then get it
somewhere else.
Oh.
Okay, I will.
It's over.
No, this time, Owen
and I are really over.
I mean, we can't keep falling
back into the same pattern.
It's just...
Mer? You awake?
Yeah. You and
Owen are over again.
I'm totally listening. Continue.
Well, see? That's the point...
It can't continue the way it is.
It's not good, it's not healthy.
Your heart's healthy enough now
that you'd be an
excellent candidate
for the type of
research they're doing.
Mmm-hmm.
Could it hurt him?
No. It is a surgery.
I would implant an array of
wireless sensors into his skull
that would transmit
electrical activity.
But none of our subjects
ever complained of pain.
It's a chance to help us, to
help revolutionize treatment
for people like yourself. Hmm?
What do you think, hon?
It'll help "people like me."
It won't help me?
Honey, wouldn't it be
nice to have a place to go
instead of sitting
around the house all day?
It's something, Jason.
It's something we can do.
Please?
I don't care.
Fine.
Thank you, Dr. Yang,
for thinking of us.
Oh, no, actually, it
was Chief Hunt's idea.
He told us about Jason.
Oh, well, thank you, Dr. Hunt.
It's gonna be great for him.
Well, good luck.
What?
That was a really nice
thing you did for them.
Well,
I'm a really nice guy,
or so I've been told.
I would never ask you for that.
You're not asking.
I am telling you.
Well...
I don't believe you.
Cristina, people change.
I mean, you're not the same
person that you were when we met.
I can change, too.
Really?
People who want kids
don't just stop wanting them.
Don't give up things for me.
Hey, I'm not.
I haven't.
I'm not giving up anything.
Good.
Good. Good.
Yeah, slowly but surely.
Just focus on your balance.
How does it feel,
Jase, to walk again?
It's pretty good.
Yeah, I think he
needs to concentrate.
It's amazing, in
just a few years.
Unbelievable.
Is Dr. Yang busy? I would
love for her to see this.
Let me check, okay?
Jason, are you all right?
Jason!
Get a crash cart!
Jason?
I need you.
Yes.
No. I can't.
These abstracts were
supposed to go out an hour ago.
You know what? Okay.
On-call room, but fast?
No, no, it's not...
It's Jason Castor.
He just had an
accident in the BCI lab.
He has rhabdo, renal failure.
Grey is putting a shunt in him,
but his wife's asking for you.
Jason Castor, your
patient, the quadriplegic?
We put him into
Derek and Callie's trial.
His wife is...
Right, right, right. Yes.
Does he need a heart consult?
No, no. She's just scared,
and she trusts you...
You know, Owen,
I have to finish this.
I've got seven prints going.
Where's Ross?
Ross can't do this.
I'm one step away from
funding for animal trials.
Owen, he's not my
patient anymore.
If the guy's heart is fine,
I don't have time to hold
someone's hand right now.
You know what? You
saved her husband's life.
You were the first
doctor she met.
She likes you, she trusts you,
and now she's waiting for you.
About a million heart
patients are waiting for me, too.
Right.
You can't let people down.
Hey.
Thanks.
Was it because of the suit?
No. His kidneys failed, and
that caused him to pass out.
But the surgery is going well,
and then we'll get
him on dialysis.
This is just a complication
of Jason's condition.
It's all just complications.
And he should be able to
continue with the study, so...
He won't.
Yeah, this will be his excuse,
and he'll never forgive
me for making him do it.
What? You didn't
make him do this.
He told me once,
we were fighting,
and he told me that
when we woke him
to ask him if he wanted to live,
he only said yes because
he was looking at me,
that if it had been up to him,
if I wasn't there,
he would have said no.
So all this is because of me.
I mean, he's miserable
every day because of me.
And I'm not a wife anymore.
I'm a nursemaid and
a cook and an orderly,
and I never go
home from that work.
I am that work. That's
all I am anymore.
I wanted to have a child.
And I will never,
ever have a child.
I'm sorry.
I'm being selfish and horrible.
No, you're not. No,
no, no. Not at all.
Not at all. I
totally understand.
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
No. It's okay.
Get on out!
Okay, now, that is
a healthy heart sip
that's both delicious
and nutritious.
Thank you very much for that.
Next up, I'm going
to debunk the top five
biggest health myths for you
folks, coming up right after this.
She better include my
suggestion on too much calcium
increasing your
risk of heart disease.
People pop those
pills like candy.
I haven't seen you in two days.
Yeah, I took a couple
extra night shifts.
I went by the
trailer this morning.
Yeah, I just crashed
in the on-call room.
Is something going on?
I need more, Cristina. You know?
I just can't keep...
I just need more, you know.
More from you, more from us.
- Another, please?
- You got it!
Okay, let's just
get out of here.
Nope.
Let's go home.
Just sleep this off,
and let's talk about it
in the morning, can we...
We don't have a home, Cristina.
I have a trailer, and you
have a room at Karev's house.
It's not...
Another, please.
Right up!
There you go. Thank you.
There's too many.
The kids outnumber the adults.
Should've thought of that
before we adopted again.
I mean, what if there's a
mutiny? Derek and I will lose.
Well, not until the
third one can walk.
So, you broke up again?
Same thing, over and over.
You know what else is the same?
This.
You and I laying in this bed,
talking about you and Owen.
Why do you keep
doing this to yourself?
I need help.
Mer, you have to help me.
Don't let me go back to him,
for his good and mine.
Please help me.
Of course. Of
course I'll help you.
What do you mean? It's been six
months since my last procedure!
Your hand's still not healed!
You need more PT and
more time in the skills lab.
You are not
stepping into that OR,
not today, maybe not ever!
All right, first of all, you
need to lower your voice.
Okay, so what,
nobody can yell at you?
Why's that? Why is that?
Because you're an Avery?
That has nothing to do
with any of this, and you...
Some pampered little rich
boy who was gifted a hospital,
so he thinks that it's okay to
go ahead and endanger patients,
'cause he's too damn proud to
admit that he can't operate anymore!
Dr. Hunt!
Do you know how many infants
are born without a
pulmonary artery?
Cristina, I'm so sorry.
But there is a
surgery to correct it.
It's called unifocalization,
which I was doing with a robot.
But now Shane is finishing it
because you paged me
"911" like a million times.
So whatever it
is, it better be...
It's Owen.
He wanted to work a shift.
I didn't feel comfortable.
He only agreed to get
in a bed if I paged you.
You came.
Give us a minute.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
Oh, God, you stink.
You tried to start a shift?
Are you insane? You
could've hurt someone.
Yeah. Yeah. I love you.
This has got to
stop. I love you.
I love you. I love you,
and I see you every day,
and I can't have you.
So how am I supposed
to keep doing this,
keep working here,
when every time I turn around,
I see your face?
Owen...
Owen, Owen, Owen, Owen...
I love you. Please. Please.
Please marry me. Just marry me.
Owen... Why can't
you just marry me?
Please, I'm begging
you. I'm begging.
I am begging you.
I mean, we should
never have called it quits.
We should never have called
it quits when we did. Please.
Please marry me.
Well, there's no
sign of him yet,
but there's still
plenty of time,
so there's no reason to panic.
I'm not panicked. Okay.
Can you get my belt? Sure.
You look beautiful.
Thanks.
He is late. How could
he be late to this?
I'll go look for him again.
Okay, we've got a
full house, people.
Page anyone who's available.
10-Year-old female,
thrown from a vehicle,
multiple blunt injuries
and hypotensive.
Hey, you, assess her, then
rush her up to radiology,
get a CT with contrast.
Then page me as
soon as... Excuse me.
Contrast, like the iodine dye?
I'm allergic to that. Do you
think my daughter could be, too?
We'll run a test and check.
Not a problem. Excuse me.
What've you got?
Do you want me
to call him again?
No.
Do you have to take
that? 'Cause you can go.
It's not like you haven't been
through this with me before.
It's a general page,
for whoever's on call.
I'm not even on call.
I'm not going anywhere.
What happened?
She was seizing,
severe allergic reaction.
I was passing by and
saw this intern freaking out.
I've given her a .3 EPI.
Well, did anyone order contrast?
Was she tested for allergies?
I got paged. What's going on?
We need to get her
to the OR immediately.
Let's start her on
Benadryl and steroids, stat!
Is this your patient? Yes.
Why didn't you screen her
for any contrast allergies?
I did. It's not here.
I mean, there's no
record of any tests.
I ordered it. You did?
Yes! Yes. You sure? You did?
I ordered the damn test!
Didn't I?
Cutting it a little
close, don't you think?
Hi. Sorry I'm late. I know.
I got held up, and
there was traffic and...
Anyway, sorry. I'm here now.
You look incredible.
Thank you.
Well, shall we do this?
Let's.
This is unacceptable.
Things like this keep happening,
and this time there
was a kid involved.
And I'm not looking the
other way any longer.
He's unreliable, a
danger to his patients.
I mean...
Did you smell his breath?
Yeah, well, let's just wait
for the breathalyzer results.
No. We need to convene
an emergency board meeting.
Right now, Derek. Right now.
She's a pioneer, an inspiration,
a mentor, and, I'm proud to say,
my friend for over 15 years.
Please welcome,
for an unprecedented
fourth consecutive year,
tonight's Harper
Avery Award recipient,
Dr. Cristina Yang.
I came as soon as I could.
You know he's just
sitting out there waiting?
April, you run the
trauma department.
You work with him more
closely than anybody else.
Do you trust Owen
Hunt to treat patients?
He is my mentor,
and he trained me.
We value your opinion,
April. That's why you're here.
Just be honest.
Do you trust the man?
No, I don't.
I move to terminate him,
effective immediately.
If there's one thing I've
learned over the years,
it's that it only takes one
person, one patient, one moment,
to change your life forever.
To change your perspective,
color your thinking,
to force you to re-evaluate
everything you think you know.
To make you ask yourself
the toughest questions.
Do you know who you are?
Do you understand what
has happened to you?
Do you want to live this way?
I'm sorry, but I have
to ask one more time.
Jason,
would you like me
to remove the vent?
Okay.
Hey, watch your hand.
Thanks.
No problem.
Hey, Cristina.
Hey. You got a sec?
I could use a set of
eyes on my patient.
Yeah. Just give me one...
Never mind. What do you got?