Meredith:
Despite its complexity,
the human brain can only focus
on about one thing at a time.
How about we share the pâté?
Teddy, I thought we said
no screens.
I'm sorry. It is my last
CABG patient,
and the nurses
needed an order for a bolus.
Maybe use an intern.
Tell them to call... Beckman!
Well, she is my patient.
Hunt.
Oh!
- Altman. - How are you?
- Hi.
David, hi. Of course, you
remember my incredible wife, Cass.
We met at that boring
dinner last year. Right.
That might have been the last time
we had a sit-down dinner together.
It might be.
Oh, there's a trauma coming.
Oh, yeah. Multiple victims.
Including this dinner.
Um. Hey, wait.
Listen, why don't you two stay?
At least somebody
can have fun. Oh...
Please, take my seat.
Um...
Why not? Sure. Yeah.
Of course. Please.
What?
I'm sorry.
Meredith: Mono-tasking
reduces distraction,
sharpens attention,
and allows us
to operate at peak performance.
Meredith: But surgical residents
don't have that luxury.
One thing? Try 30.
Luna's fever's still 100,
but thankfully,
Scout has taken some Pedialyte,
so that's something.
Maybe I should call
and tell him I can't make it in.
You think I can't handle
two sick kids?
You're on call. Go.
I thought I was charging
my computer.
Yeah, my phone was at 2%.
So you couldn't have used
one of the other 50 chargers
we have in the house?
Next time, I'll ignore
the vomiting kid to go find one.
Can you move your bag?
I'm trying to clean.
Meredith: They order labs,
dictate notes, take vitals,
check drains,
make split second-decisions
while on the move.
It's chaos.
Fresh from the warmer.
Chloe, how are you feeling?
Like I got chemo today.
Hopefully you'll feel
a little better
after a night's sleep.
Thank you.
Yeah.
I brought one for you, too.
Thanks.
I'm not sure who's more tired,
her or me.
You have been working a lot.
Yeah, well, making up
for the time I took off.
Thanks for that, too.
I'll swing by in a bit.
And you had better
be sleeping. Mm-hmm.
She's quality.
Shut up.
Meredith:
But a brain can adapt
and thrive in just
about anything, even chaos.
Hey. I thought you were
on trauma tonight.
I am, but I've been playing
chess with Ophelia,
and it was my turn,
so I came to check in.
Her leg looks good. Yeah.
Her parents are on their way.
I heard it's pretty backed up, but
hopefully she gets moved into rehab tonight.
Yeah, she told me
at least five times.
I said I'd come by and
see her again before she goes.
She's very excited. Hey,
speaking of excitement,
I heard you got the research
position with Wilkinson. Congrats.
Oh, I, um, I haven't
officially accepted yet.
That's smart.
Take your time deciding.
You think that I shouldn't take
it? You told me about it.
No, no,
it's a great opportunity.
It just... It doesn't guarantee
a peds fellowship.
So I don't want you
to feel resentful
if you spend a year in Texas
and it doesn't work out.
Um...
It's Webber.
Um, if you were me,
would you take it?
Yeah.
But I really love Tex-Mex.
Hey.
I heard you're going home.
Yeah, yeah,
I hit my 80 hours this week,
so Bailey tagged me out.
I'm just gonna crash
in an on-call room.
E.R. consults... drunk guy
with an arm lac,
drunk guy with a head lac,
and drunk guy just drunk.
You can pick first.
Have fun.
Mm-hmm.
I'll catch you
in the morning, yeah?
Yeah. Love you.
Did that just happen?
It's on replay in my head.
Was I hearing things,
or were you listening to
the "Final Fantasy" theme
yesterday?
Good ear. Yes.
I love how the instrumentation
gives the franchise
that bright, regal feel.
How we doing, maestro?
Oh, teaching Dr. Millin
the joy of orchestration.
Can you keep a beat,
Dr. Ndugu? Of course.
I'm a heart surgeon.
How's he doing? Uh,
hemodynamically normal,
except for the past hour.
He's a little bit tachycardic,
in the low hundreds.
Chest tube put out 50 CCs
overnight.
I did walk to a chair today,
but I can also use a new lung.
Well, how about
I go get you one?
Don't play with me, now.
I'm going right now
to procure it.
Dr. Millin will take care
of you until I get back.
Let's, uh, see how his heart
rate does on a 500 CC bolus.
And call me if you need me. You
got the whole floor tonight, okay?
Rest up. Okay?
I'll be back.
Am I in trouble?
We know about the peds
research position in Texas.
They called to get a letter
of good standing.
Oh.
Um, I was going to tell you.
Well, actually, we're glad
they gave us a heads-up.
We'd like to extend
an offer, as well.
General surgery attending.
I mean, you'd have to
finish your residency,
but we wanted
to let you know now
while you're making
this decision. Okay.
Most attendings start
at this salary,
but there's room to negotiate.
Mm-hmm.
Uh, plus, there's seed money
for research,
a signing bonus, healthy
student loan repayment.
I, uh, I... I really
wasn't expecting this.
Um...
I'm not sure what to say.
Think about it.
Uh, better yet,
let's try it out.
You're on my service tonight
but as the attending.
Yeah? Okay. Let's go.
Oh, hey. My last surgery
pushed until tomorrow.
How's Scout?
Still sick.
He threw up on his bed.
Oh, poor thing. He
seemed better when I left.
I meant Jo.
I'm going to go pick him up.
That'd be great. Yeah.
Okay.
Oh, but don't tell Jo
I said that.
She's trying to do it all.
Okay. Yeah.
Woman: Doctors Luke to the E.R.
Doctors Tommy and Martha Luke.
What if I say it again but give
him more time to say it back?
Uh, I don't think lack of time
is the problem.
Is it going to be weird now?
Well, you told him you loved him
at work and he left you hanging.
Yes is my answer.
I hate everything.
Except Adams.
Kwan, Griffith,
finish up and let's go.
Multiple traumas arriving.
Uh, you go ahead first.
I'll catch up.
Okay.
Love you.
Woman: Dr. Laura to the NICU.
To the NICU.
Looks like someone
promoted themselves.
Webber and Bailey offered me
an attending position.
What?
That's amazing.
Did they say anything about me?
Well, it was an early offer
because they know about Texas.
I'm just doing a trial run
tonight.
Where do I apply for a crappy
research job that I can leverage?
Well, it's clinical research.
I'd be with peds patients.
And how does James feel
about you chasing
your peds dreams in Texas?
I'm not sure.
He got paged to a code
after I told him,
and that was the last time
we talked.
I-I-I don't even know what
I'm going to do yet.
Well, you got two job offers
and a boyfriend.
You get zero sympathy.
Blue: Trauma's here.
Monica: Schmitt!
Schmitt! Oh, he's with me.
Official business.
Navy scrubs. Kind of bold.
Isn't it?
Should I go change?
Scaffolding collapsed
at a concert venue.
17-year-old female, GCS 15,
unstable pelvis.
Binder was placed at the scene.
Vitals are stable.
Given four milligrams
of morphine en route.
I'm Dr. Beltran.
Can you tell me your name?
Joni. But where's Vaughn?
He was onstage.
We'll find him for you.
He's your friend?
My boyfriend.
And incredibly talented.
Let's get her to trauma three.
Okay, Schmitt,
whatever's in this rig,
we're following your lead.
Alright, let's go.
If you're giving
away promotions,
can I be a fifth-year?
What do you think?
19-year-old male.
Penetrating abdominal injury
after a fall from
a two-story scaffolding.
GCS 15.
Systolic in the low 100s.
Received two liters of fluid.
Well, that's going to be tricky.
Trauma one.
Get him inside.
Let's go.
Oh...
I don't know what I want.
Thank goodness no one's asking.
Do you know what panisse is?
It comes with the lamb.
No, um, I don't. Do you
want me to look it up?
No.
If it was any good,
they'd probably be more upfront
about it on the menu.
Honestly, I think the best meal
I've ever had is when
Owen and I shared a can of
refried beans on flatbread.
During the Great Depression?
We served in the Army.
It turns out, everything tastes
better after military rations.
You were in the military?
Yeah, that's where we met. Wow.
You just look so poised
and put together
in your boss-lady heels.
Who knew?
Thanks. I would prefer
a t-shirt and combat boots,
and I would take a burger
over this menu any day.
Do you want to ditch this place
and go somewhere
that serves fries
instead of pomme frites?
Yes. Please.
Oh, great.
Wonderful.
Okay,
just take a little... No?
No.
Just a little sip?
Good job, good job, good.
"Great job.
You did so"...
Hey.
Oh, wow, I thought that you
had a late surgery. Mommy!
Um, wait, did Link tell you
to come rescue me?
Uh, I was gonna ask
how everybody is doing,
but I think I got it.
I'm fine. Hey, sweetie.
I'm sorry you're sick.
I'm just gonna take you home.
Ooh! Hey,
do you have his lovey?
I'm just gonna take him home.
Despite what Link may have
told you, I'm not incompetent.
Uh, no. He... Uh,
he never said that you were.
You know, I just want to
take care of my sick kid.
Everything is under control.
I've got it. I'm fine.
Okay.
Well, I think
we're just gonna go.
Ooh!
Or maybe we will change first.
Luna:
I'm coming, sweetie.
Mama!
I'll run him a bath.
Joni, I'm Dr. Lincoln.
Have you seen Vaughn?
W-Where is he?
Vaughn is?
Boyfriend. Trauma one.
He's got a pink stripe
in his hair.
Ice-cold eyes.
The skull pinky ring
that I gave him.
He was performing
at the concert. Clear.
No pneumothorax or fractures
in the chest X-ray.
What instrument
does Vaughn play?
Ugh! Air.
She's on morphine.
Try and hold still.
No, he plays air guitar.
Tonight was
the regional championship.
She's got a bad pelvic fracture.
The scaffolding
from the performance
fell right
into the crowd.
He was supposed
to make it to the finals.
He could have taken Scissor's
title. No, he would have.
Yeah, I'm sure he's great
at... air.
FAST was negative.
Systolics are stable at 110.
All right, let's get her to
CT. Parents are on their way.
Oh! Uh, they're... they're not
the biggest fans of Vaughn.
Could you maybe not mention
that he's here?
Patient privacy laws.
We couldn't if we wanted to.
Griffith, would you put in
the trauma scan orders,
meet us in CT?
Owen:
What have we got?
Ah, this is Vaughn,
19-year-old male.
Thoracoabdominal impalement.
Systolics in the low hundreds.
Responding to fluids.
Pleasure to meet you, sir. Try
not to move. Save your energy.
Help get another IV.
Give 20 of fentanyl.
We need to type and cross
and hang two units of O-neg.
Schmitt's running point
on this one.
Copy that.
Where'd you need me?
Put in the orders for CT.
If we can stabilize him more,
we might be able to run him
through the scanner
on the way to the O.R.
Can somebody get a message
to my girlfriend, Joni?
Try not to talk. Frankly,
It's a miracle you can even...
Uh, his pressure's tanking.
Owen: There's blood
in the Foley catheter.
Change of plans. We need to
get him to the O.R. now.
Am I good?
Uh-huh.
Alright, let's go.
We got here as fast as we could.
Where is she?
Can we see our Joni?
She's on her way to radiology,
but I will let her know
you're here.
Thank you so much.
My roommate's here.
Vaughn Bishop...
rad riffer, sick hair.
Gish?
Mr. and Mrs. F!
Dude, crazy night, right?
All those people in the crowd,
and Vaughn falls and...
bloosh... crushes Joni.
I mean, coincidence
or true love?
How about true stupidity?
I'm going to strangle that kid.
Let's not invoke violence
in the emergency room.
It was my idea for him
to climb the scaffold.
I built them so
he could shred off the rafters.
If you're going to be cheesed
at anyone, it should be me.
I don't get it.
She's a smart kid.
Where did we go wrong?
Sir, look.
No, this is gonna live
on the Internet forever.
Everyone will know
she's the girl
who got crushed by
an idiot guitar mime.
All due respect, air musician.
Why don't I show you both
to the family waiting area?
And... Gish?
I got this guy.
Right this way.
I'll show you where the other
air musicians are waiting,
uh, Mister...
Gish.
Just Gish. Like Slash.
Yeah.
Yep, that makes sense.
Woman: Dr. Stephanie Russell to
cardiology. Dr. Russell to cardiology.
You're supposed to be sleeping.
Well, in a dumb moment
of exhaustion,
I gave Mr. Donovan in 2114
my cellphone number,
and he texted me "911"
times in a row.
What did he want?
A hot dog.
He called it a hot dog sandwich.
Also, um, every time
I close my eyes,
I see the worst possible
outcomes for Chloe.
She's here.
She's getting the best care.
And you being sleep deprived
won't change anything.
Also, isn't Mr. Donovan
on a liquids-only diet?
Woman: Rapid
response, second floor, ICU.
Rapid response,
second floor, ICU.
Rapid response, second floor...
Mr. Riley, are you okay?
You tell me.
Uh, the pump isn't working.
There's low flow in the circuit.
We need a new pump ASAP.
Karen: On it.
We need to switch over to
the emergency hand crank,
or he'll code.
Okay.
Cannula flow.
Am I... Am I dying?
Just some
technical difficulties.
That's all.
Do your best to stay calm.
Karen:
Dr. Millin, I'm sorry.
Best-case scenario on
a new pump is a couple of hours.
The ECLS coordinator
accidentally left with the keys
to the supply closet.
What?
Ugh! Dr. Ndugu's triple A
patient is tachy.
Yeah, and his quadruple bypass
next door
has blood in the pleurovac.
Wait, you're both leaving?
Go.
I can take over you.
You don't... You're supposed...
You need help. Chloe's down the hall.
I've got this.
Go.
So, I have to reconstruct
this guy's entire face,
which is barely a face
after busting through
the back windshield.
Insert seatbelt PSA here.
Exactly.
I get home, and I just
want to crawl into my bed...
Mm-hmm.
And David has taken apart
our kids' marble run,
and my son is freaking out,
so now I have to reconstruct
that, too.
Of course you do.
And he wonders
why I'm not in the mood.
Well, we're scheduling sex,
and it's going about
as well as you could imagine.
I'm sorry. That was just
way more information
than you needed to know.
No. You're fine.
We're not at work. You have to
get it out somewhere.
Isn't that what therapy is for?
Sure.
Listen, a few years back,
David and I went through
a really rough patch.
We couldn't talk
without arguing.
The spark was gone.
I didn't know if we were
going to make it.
So what did you do?
We opened our marriage.
Opened as in...?
Yeah, we date
and sleep with other people.
Oh!
Mm-hmm.
I mean, with boundaries,
of course.
And it's not for everyone,
but it worked wonders for us.
But you're a trauma surgeon at
Seattle Presbyterian with two kids.
How do you find the time?
Hot single tennis pro.
You have time for tennis?
I do.
Do you want another round?
Yes, please.
Excuse me.
Can we have another?
He's changed and bathed.
And I'm just going to
let him sleep for half an hour
before I take him,
if that's okay.
Yeah, sure.
Also, thank you
for your clothes.
Hey.
You can tell me
where to shove it,
but, I mean,
give yourself some grace.
It's impossible to do it all
on a good day,
let alone
when there's a sick kid.
You know what?
Forget the half-hour.
Clearly, you do not
want company. That's fine.
I'm going to grab him.
It's not you.
When Luna woke up sick
this morning,
she started crying,
and she asked for Jessica,
her daycare teacher.
Yeah.
That sucks.
I'm at the hospital
working 80 hours a week,
and I don't have time to make
the... the cute lunches
or, um...
take her to, you know,
story time at the library
or do any of the good things
that parents are supposed to do.
All I ever do is...
feed her and clothe her
and bathe her.
Well, if it helps,
we don't even have the robust,
explicit memories
until about 7 years old.
I just...
I really wanted to give her
the mother that I never had,
and instead, she's
at daycare all day
developing a secure attachment
to Jessica.
And this is all
while I have just one kid.
What's going to happen
when I have two more?
You and Link...?
Oh, my God.
Do you want me?
No, I've got it.
Clamp.
Schmitt, you want to
ask Kwan what he sees?
I can just answer you.
Or wait to be asked.
Kwan, what do you see?
Um, perforated small bowel.
Right.
Kidney seems involved.
Maybe a small liver lac.
There's probably more.
How do you want to handle that?
Let's pack first,
then go quadrant by quadrant.
We'll save the scaffold
for last.
Dr. Hunt,
you can pull it out slowly.
And the rest of us will attack
any problems as we go.
Alright.
You heard the man.
Owen: Let's get packing.
I know it's basic,
falling for the musician.
He is not a musician.
My parents say I'm making
a fool of myself,
but they're just jealous.
I'm kissing my boyfriend
onstage at his concerts,
and they don't even
hold hands anymore.
They're probably just worried.
They don't want you
to have regrets.
He's Van Vaughn Bishop.
What would I regret?
Haven't a clue.
Type three pelvic fracture
with active extrapolation
of the contrast.
Yeah.
She's bleeding.
We should embolize
before you repair it.
Does anyone know about Vaughn?
I'm sorry I keep asking
about him. I just love him.
I love him so much, I'm even
willing to put up with Gish.
What's gish?
You don't want to know.
How's it going?
Took me a while
to find the right speed,
but now I'm in a groove
and he's stable.
Well, I can take over for you.
You can go be with Chloe.
I want to stay.
Gives my mind something useful
to focus on.
Plus, you've done
so much for me.
I'd like to do something
for you.
Oh, I-I wanted to help you.
You don't owe me anything.
I know.
Uh, the pump is on its way.
I'm going to go do my rounds,
and I'll be back by the time
it gets here.
Are you sure you're good?
I'm single-handedly
keeping this guy alive.
What's better than that?
I'm almost done with
the small bowel.
Almost out of the abdomen. It's
going to take weeks of recovery.
Should have climbed
air scaffolding.
Okay, this isn't
the time for judgment.
Would you go to an air guitar
concert, Dr. Bailey?
I don't do crowds,
unless it's Beyoncé.
Alright, last serosal tear
is repaired.
We can run the bowel again
at the end.
You can continue
pulling out the pipe.
Okay, here we go.
There we go.
Bailey: Okay,
he's hemorrhaging.
Looks like the rod went through
the kidney and his blood supply.
Alright, I need suction.
Lap pads. Kidney's shot.
Owen: Well, luckily, he can
survive with only one.
Schmitt, do you want
to do the honors?
Well, what if the other kidney
ever gets damaged?
What, do you want
to try and salvage it?
If we did,
he'd be open for longer.
If we can't save it, we'd be risking
him becoming unstable for nothing.
You can resect it or salvage it,
but you don't have
much longer to debate it.
Schmitt.
Do you or Dr. Hunt
want to step in?
I want to salvage it.
Are you sure?
Is he sure?
Isn't the hilum injured?
We can repair the renal artery
and then do a renorrhaphy.
And you think that'll work?
I don't know, but ..
It's the plan.
I'm still an attending, right?
You're damn right you are.
Alright.
We're saving a kidney.
6-Oh prolene.
Beats the hell out of research.
What's that?
Well, it was going to be
the best grilled cheese sandwich
you ever had, but I couldn't
find cheese,
so it's toast.
Thank you.
You're a mom and a resident.
That is two impossible things
at the same time.
I know it's going to be hard
in the beginning and the middle,
but I really want
that big family.
And I want it for Luna,
too, for all of us.
I'm just... I'm so worried
that I'm gonna mess it up.
Maybe I already have.
You haven't messed anything up.
Where's Link in all of this?
Can you lean on him more?
We haven't been
in the best place lately.
When he and I were together,
I would be lying if I said
that the years of friendship
between the two of you
didn't bother me.
But I think it was Link
who was lying all along,
to himself.
I think, underneath it all,
he always wanted you.
He proposed to you
with three rings.
I had to listen for months about
how he was so in love with you.
Maybe.
Or maybe he was trying
to force us into something
because he was scared to leave.
I'm going to check on Scout.
You eat the toast.
You think there are
air guitar teachers?
Why? You want lessons?
Fluoro.
I'm just wondering
how you get good at it.
A lot of hours
in front of the bathroom mirror,
which, honestly,
is really where it belongs.
I don't know,
I think it's sweet.
I mean, they know what they
want, and they're not holding back,
no matter how bonkers it is.
Alright, another bleeder down.
Griffith, go for the next one.
Now, advance
until you see the extrav.
Good.
Now flip the guide wire.
And advance again.
Good.
Deploying the coil.
Ah, you make it look easy.
Been practicing.
It shows.
Go for the next bleeder.
Okay. Thank you. Well,
the new pump is working. Ah!
I can't believe
you cranked that for so long.
I'm used to it.
Grandma Servino had
an old-fashioned butter churn.
His stats are dropping.
But the O2 on the ECMO
circuit's maxed out.
Call a rapid response.
We need to intubate.
Woman: Rapid response,
second floor, ICU.
Rapid response, second floor,
ICU. Okay, I know it's a little scary,
but this will help you
to breathe.
Rapid response, second
floor, ICU. Okay. Oxygen.
Rapid response,
second floor, ICU.
All right,
we need X-ray in here.
1, 2. Okay.
Careful. He only
has one lung. Yeah.
Okay. Can you get the
ambu ready? Mm-hmm.
I can see the cords.
I... I'm in.
We need to confirm placement.
I think we're okay.
His pressures are dropping.
Karen: I don't understand.
The pump's on,
but the flows keep cutting out.
Get us a visual of the chest.
I'm calling Dr. Ndugu.
Come on, answer, answer.
Winston: Millin, tell me
he's still alive.
He's still alive.
But we had to intubate him.
I think he's going to code.
There's not enough blood
moving through the ECMO machine.
Is that Yasuda?
She's helping me.
Pressures are plummeting.
Alright. X-ray's up.
Okay. Damn it.
His heart's herniating
into the right chest cavity
where his lung used to be.
So what do we do?
Alright. You'll need to...
to... to pump air, okay?
What?
Dr. Ndugu?
I hate the night shift!
It's fine. We're fine.
He said to pump air
into the chest. Right?
Chest tube.
Right.
Okay, I have the
syringe. Uh-huh.
Don't go anywhere. Maybe
you should wait for an attending.
Everyone's operating.
If we wait, he dies.
She's going to need
a new image after every pump.
Okay.
Did it move?
Uh, maybe a little.
Go again.
It moved! It moved!
Pump again! Okay.
Pressure's coming up.
He's stabilizing.
Oh, my God.
We did it!
Yeah.
It's insane.
I know!
I get more emails
from my kids' school
than everyone else in my life
put together.
And Don't get me started
on the parent portals.
Oh, no, I lost my password.
I mean, who needs a portal
when you have all those emails?
This is crazy.
Mm!
I haven't had this much fun
in a long time.
Oh!
Me neither.
When Owen got paged, my first
inclination was to go home
and put on a pair of
sweatpants. I'm glad you stayed.
Oh, me too. You know what?
At first, I felt like
maybe Owen and I needed
a break from the kids.
But maybe I just needed
a break from Owen.
Mm-hmm.
Mm. Whoa. Um...
Oh.
Sorry. I misread.
Yeah. No.
I mean, your marriage
might be open,
but me and Owen,
it's... it's... we...
It's closed.
It's very closed.
Understood.
Again, I'm... I'm sorry.
Yeah.
Let's forget it ever happened.
Mm, you know what?
It's late,
so I think I'm just, um...
I'm just gonna get
a ride home. Sure.
Hi! Were you in surgery?
Hey!
No, I just like to wear the hat.
Okay.
How'd it go?
I saved a man's kidney.
How's your night?
I spent it talking to
an adult leukemia patient.
The one that you were
going to see five hours ago?
Yeah. She was working
through some stuff.
Didn't want to leave.
So, have you thought
any more about Texas?
Actually...
I'm thinking there might be
more for me here.
Really?
Webber offered me
an attending position.
Oh, congratulations!
Also, there is this guy.
Oh, a guy?
Mm-hmm.
Okay.
He's very nice.
I like nice guys.
So as the pain meds wear off,
there's going to be
bad days and good days.
Stick with the P.T.
It helps.
And maybe skip the
air guitar concerts for a while.
Hey, you hear that?
Doctor's orders.
Will you order the labs
for the morning
and finish the
post-op now? Okay.
Get some rest, okay?
Oh.
Could you answer it for me?
Of course.
Hey, babe.
Are you okay?
I'm good.
I was worried about you.
I dreamed about you
during surgery.
Can't dream under anesthesia.
Aw, that's so sweet.
Dude, what are you
doing? It's mood music.
Vaughn: I wish I could play it
for you right now.
Oh, my God. Let's
give them some privacy.
I taught her that riff.
Oh, I bet you did.
Yeah, you did.
Winston:
Meet you in the O.R.
Good work, Millin.
I'd say 9 times out of 10,
that man would have died
tonight.
Scrub in. You can do
the bronchial anastomosis.
Really?
After what you did tonight,
you deserve it.
Actually, there's... there's
something I should tell you.
Uh, when Mr. Riley...
Did I miss her?
You're in luck...
Transfer took forever,
so they're just packing up.
Okay. Hey.
Dr. Schmitt! I'm leaving.
Well, I'm glad you didn't
before I could say goodbye.
We couldn't have left.
She's been talking about you
the whole night.
I have something for you.
We can't thank you enough
for taking care of our daughter.
Of course.
Here.
That's you fixing my leg
on the helicopter,
so you always remember.
I love it. Thank you.
Hey, I-I wish I had something
to give you.
It's okay.
I'll never forget you.
Thank you so much.
Thank you, Doctor.
I heard I might
find you in here.
Mika: And I heard I'm here
because of you.
You didn't have to give up
this surgery for me.
You said you were trying
to catch up on your case logs.
And you deserve it.
I'm gonna go home.
I miss you.
I miss us.
I mean, I don't even know
if we were an us.
But that thing we started,
it made me feel...
You shook me up.
In a good way. In a way
I didn't even know I needed.
And as much as I like your face,
it is pretty impossible to read,
so I'm gonna shut up now.
Really wish
you hadn't scrubbed in yet.
You want your surgery back?
No.
I really want to kiss you.
Right now, for a very long time.
But, um...
Rain check?
Hell yeah.
Mika: Thank you.
Schmitt, I heard you were
quite a hero last night.
Dr. Webber's
patting himself on the back
for offering you
the attending position.
It was both our idea.
And it was an excellent one.
I remember walking down
these halls as a sub-I with you,
dreaming that I might be
an attending here one day.
You've come a long way
since then.
Thanks to both of you.
I think I would really like
being a general attending here.
But my love is peds.
I love the highs and the lows
and the goofy things they say,
and that when I save a kid,
I'm... I'm not just
saving a life.
I'm saving a lifetime.
And if I've learned
anything from the two of you,
it's to be passionate
about your work.
So...
I accepted the research position
in Texas.
Then I guess the only thing
left to say is...
congratulations.
Go make us proud.
How's Luna?
Did you get some sleep?
She's better.
She's still down.
Good.
I know this isn't
what you wanted.
What?
I don't want to force you
into something.
It's never going to be
just us again.
It's going to be chaos, and I...
I don't know.
What if you leave me?
W-Why would you say that?
Everyone else has.
I don't want to do this alone.
That's what you think of me?
You... You're gonna put me
in the same group as all
the other people in your life
that have been so awful to you?
Well, it's never been
just us, Jo.
And the fact that you think
I would back out
just because we have two more?
Meredith: Scientists call
the conscious thought
needed to complete
everyday tasks
"working memory."
Oh, I'm sorry.
Did I wake you?
I should get up.
How was dinner?
Oh, we ditched the restaurant
and went to the bar next door.
Get this...
Cass Beckman kissed me.
What?
Yeah, she'd had
a-a couple glasses of wine...
I mean, we both had a couple.
Wait, so you both...
You were both drunk? Did you...
Did you kiss her back?
No. She just...
She got the wrong idea, huh?
How?
Yeah, how?
Do you think
that I provoked this?
I don't know, Teddy.
Two minutes ago, I was asleep,
and now you're telling me
that some women kissed you?
You know what?
I have to go do rounds.
Owen, I...
That memory is always there,
always busy, getting you
through the chaos of life
one task at a time.
Morning.
Is it time to go home?
This bed's really comfy.
How was the chair?
Irrelevant.
I wound up working.
Mm, I'm sorry.
Actually, I had
a pretty great night.
Let's go home.
In some ways,
that's all life really is,
all the things we do
strung together.
Molly: Hi. You've reached
Molly's voicemail.
Please leave a message.
Meredith:
This patient. This diagnosis.
Morning.
This night. This moment.
How'd you sleep?
Oh, great.
Some alarm kept going off...
I'm normally self-assured,
very poised.
I'm on fire
when I'm in the O.R.
But when I'm around you,
my entire brain scrambles,
and sometimes I just...
say things.
You were tired and busy.
It happens.
But I do love you, Lucas Adams.
I love you.
It's okay i-if it's too soon.
You don't have to say it back.
But that's how I feel.
Crap. I'm late for rounds.
Oh, uh...
I love you, too.
This connection.
This family. This friendship.
The best part
about the night shift
is having breakfast
like it's dinner.
Let's get fries at Joe's.
Oh, actually, I have to round
before I go home.
Oh, sorry.
Yeah.
What are you doing here?
Uh, waiting for you.
I have to tell you something.
I took the job in Texas.
Hey, no, no, no, no.
Don't cry. Don't cry.
It's okay. We...
We will text all the time.
And we can FaceTime
and watch our trashy TV shows.
And... And you'll visit,
and I-I'll take you for Tex-Mex,
assuming that I like it.
Hey, hey.
Damn it, Levi.
Do you know what I said
to... to Bailey and Webber
in my residency interview?
That I-I wasn't here
to make friends.
I was like
a reality TV contestant.
I was... I was focused
and cutthroat.
And then I met you.
You're my best friend.
Hey, we... we will always
be besties.
You do not
need to be sad. I...
I know, dummy, I know.
These are happy tears.
So you're not mad?
Of course not.
You're following your dream,
or whatever.
Okay, that's such a relief,
'cause I was... I was
very nervous to tell you.
Seriously?
Yeah.
Well, I'm easy.
Think about how hard
it'll be to tell James.
And somewhere in all of that,
sleep and wake up.
Sleep and wake up.
Can we stop for doughnuts?
I want powdered sugar.
Like, actually just the sugar.
Is that weird?
Or a waffle.
Maybe we should get
real breakfast.
That's healthier, right?
Mimi?
Mimi.
Sleep and...
Mika!
Mika: Wake up.
Subsync johnhallgeir