When we get sick,
our bodies launch a coordinated defense.
It's called the immune response.
They scheduled my hearing.
And...?
"The medical commission will
gladly expedite your process
and give you the date of..."
That's in three months!
Okay, well, that's...
that's not that bad.
I'll have to go
to the Department of Corrections
to get a day off
to see if I'm still a doctor.
You should go
dressed like this when you go.
It's good, right?!
It's an impressive fashion statement.
It's my disguise.
Once a germ's detected...
Have a nice day.
- Oh, look out for needles.
- Thanks. Yeah.
...a team of white blood cells,
proteins, and chemicals
swarm to mount an attack.
You a doctor?
For the moment.
I was wondering if maybe
you could take a look at this.
Time to go, people.
Steam burn from an iron.
I work at a dry cleaner's.
They told me to run it under cold water,
but it blistered.
They should've sent you to the doctor.
Is it bad?
Well, it's definitely infected.
It needs debridement and antibiotics.
So, are you gonna give me
that stuff or what?
These cells catch up
to the invaders and latch on,
destroying them in their wake.
People, let's go!
Or at least that's
what they're supposed to do.
Mm-hmm.
Okay, I, uh... I don't know
what the special occasion is,
but, uh, I want it noted
I do not miss the green smoothies.
The occasion is that I have no joy.
My best surgeons work elsewhere,
and Catherine gave away my job.
Oh, but you still have a job.
Mm, I have a job,
but then a man, a man who I can't stand,
has another job,
and he has a title above my job.
Where's my joy, Ben?
Let me tell you something
about the woman I married.
She don't let anything stop her.
No surgery, no intern,
and certainly no man.
Now, you go back in there,
and you take your joy back.
The body's ability to come back
depends on what you have to fight with...
...and how strong you are.
You don't have to go back
to work if you're not ready.
Mm, it's time.
It's time for me to go back
and let everyone stare at me
like I'm some rare, delicate bird
that might shed all my feathers
and fly naked through
the hospital at any moment.
I would definitely like to see that.
You know, you can always
come work for me.
Nobody knows who you are
or what happened.
You could run your own fellowship,
be your own boss, keep all your feathers.
My therapist, Michelle,
says it's important
that I try to return
to the life I left, you know,
revisit my routine without
changing things up too much.
You just don't want to work at Pac-North.
Mm.
Is it appropriate for me
to tell Link in a text?
So I can avoid having to
look him in the eye while I say,
"Hey, remember how careful we were?
Not careful enough, Daddy!"
You kept medical textbooks here?
I like to study.
It was a sex thing, wasn't it?
Look, you're a decent person,
and Link is a decent person.
He deserves a face-to-face.
Is it poor form for me
to steal all the toilet paper
since I'm the one who always bought it?
Mm, I already stole two protein bars.
Ew, yikes.
"Yikes"? What, "Yikes"?
Nothing.
I... Jackson posted a sunset photo
from his balcony last night.
Oh, let me see it.
"#Freedom"?
I said, "Ew."
Dr. Emma Griggs, report...
Hey. Hey.
First day back, right?
Yeah. Morning, Tom.
Oh, shoot.
Is this weird for you?
We've all shared the same,
mm, how should I say it?
- You shouldn't.
- Pastimes?
Lady friends?
- You have poo on your collar.
- What? Where?
Made you look.
Oh, you are such a stand-up guy.
Leaving Teddy all alone
in a motel with a new baby.
What are you still doing here, Tom? Hmm?
Don't you have a job back in Baltimore,
or did you lose that, too?
That's a funny way to talk to your boss.
What, Teddy didn't tell you?
Tell me what?
Oh, since your friends went rogue,
Catherine made me God of this place.
So, practice kneeling.
Maybe throw in a few prayers.
Hmm.
Oh. Oh, no.
After me.
Synced & corrected by -robtor-
www.addic7ed.com
Nice of you all to finally show up.
We're gonna do things differently today.
Keep up or get out of my sight.
55-year-old male, presents with
weakness of the hips
after walking short distances
and erectile dysfunction.
Who do you think's gonna have to
clean the window after this?
Whoever asked that question.
Now, someone tell me what to do first.
Check distal pulses, ABIs.
And if needed, proceed with CT Angio.
Who is he? Who are you?
He's Koracick's protégé.
Fifth year from Hopkins.
We are rounding, not talking.
Now, physical exam revealed
non-palpable femoral pulses,
low ABIs, and the angio shows
near-complete blockage of
blood flow in the distal aorta.
- Diagnosis?
- Leriche syndrome.
Leriche syndrome.
Little late, Qadri.
They're three years ahead of us.
See, uh, you all have been sulking around
for the last month
since I made changes
to the attending staff.
But Alex Karev and Meredith Grey
are my creations.
I made them the surgeons they are.
And I will make new ones.
So, do you want to be
the new Grey and Karev,
or do you want to keep making excuses?
- I want to be Grey.
- Karev!
Grey and Karev would have been
studying the case by now.
Go.
Ah!
I want it noted that I would never
send a message through Instagram
because I am mature.
Very mature.
But if I did, it would be "#Happier,"
"#INoLongerHaveToPlaySmall-
ToThreatenMenAndTheir- ThreatenedEgoes."
Mine would be "#JokesOnMe."
I just told Link
I didn't want
to fast-track our relationship.
- You're sure
- I have to tell him?
Whoa!
You're right.
I know. I have to.
- Go, go, go, go!
- Aah!
The hits just keep coming.
I'll page Hunt.
Sir? Sir? Lay still.
Dr. Richie to Peds.
Dr. Nancy Richie, report to Peds.
Hey, happy first day!
Is it?
You hired me as general
surgery residency director.
I've met only two residents.
Where are the rest of them?
There are only two in the entire program.
Huh? And none of the attendings
want to put those two residents
on their service.
What was the word
they used to describe them?
Oh, right. "Incompetent."
And would you like to know
what the residents said?
I feel like you're gonna tell me.
They are so overworked with scut
they don't have time
to hone their mediocre skills.
All right, isn't this why I hired you?
I need a class of more than
two residents, Karev!
I need a skills lab for them,
a core curriculum, visiting professors.
- Chief Karev?
- You know what...
There's an inspector upstairs
who says the helipad elevator
isn't up to code.
Did you know this hospital
was ranked number one?
- What decade?
- This one.
It's number one in mortality rates,
physician burn-out,
patient dissatisfaction,
and malpractice claims.
A bunch of suits
gave me a big pile of money,
and you said I could turn it around.
This was your idea. So help.
You said I'd have an office!
Sir? Sir, I'm Dr. Hunt.
Do you have any pain in your neck?
A little, but more in my chest.
It's fine. I'm okay.
C-collar's secured.
Okay.
The scooter... Is it totaled?
I'm gonna say yes.
Ohh, I stole my girlfriend's
credit card for the rental.
Well, she bought it now.
- We ready to move?
- Yeah.
On "three." One, two, three.
Let's go.
Don't embarrass me.
Um, W-Wade Foltz,
suffers from Leriche syndrome.
Due to a build-up of plaque
in his arteries,
he no longer has sufficient
blood flow to his legs
and his, um...
Gentleman parts?
Sure.
History includes a pack-a-day
smoker for 25 years,
elevated BP for 10,
and adhesions from a sigmoid resection
due to repeated bouts of diverticulitis.
Hmm.
How long have you been symptomatic?
Well, I went to my, uh, doctor
about a Viagra prescription
about nine months ago.
Schmitt? Something you'd like to share?
Um...
patient emergency.
Then what are you still doing here?
DeLuca?
Right. Uh, today we'll
be doing a surgery called
an axillary bi-femoral-bypass.
We will essentially be creating a tunnel
from your armpit
down to your groin with a graft,
which will then redirect
blood flow to all of those,
uh, poorly perfused areas.
Okay, trauma one's free.
- Be right there.
- Yeah.
I heard about the parking lot.
- Everyone okay?
- Uh, we are fine.
He is hemodynamically stable
with no neurological deficits.
Hey, how's freedom?
- You enjoying it?
- What's that?
- Oh, no.
- The sexy firefighter.
She's freedom, right?
Freedom from having to live with someone
who intellectually challenges you?
A surgeon dating a firefighter.
You get to feel superior all the time.
Nice.
It wasn't. That was the point.
- Hey.
- Ah.
Maggie, I should...
- Yeah.
- If you or Owen need me, just page.
Go.
Dr. Wendy Bliss to
Oncology. Dr. Wendy Bliss to Oncology.
Let's call X-ray.
Hi.
Hey!
Uh, uh, could we go somewhere private?
Uh, not that kind of private.
Oh. Oh! Bad private?
No. No. I just...
You-met-someone-else kind of private?
Pregnant, actually.
I know! It's absurd!
But it's also true.
Uh, judging from my last period,
I'm thinking eight weeks or so.
And, um, I'm not asking you for anything.
I just want to avoid
any kind of secret-keeping
or hand-wringing.
Uh, also, I don't have
the best track record with pregnancy,
which is a story
I should probably tell you.
Um...
Head trauma coming in. I gotta go.
Can... Can we finish this later?
Okay.
Dr. Bailey! Chief! Hi. Hi.
Karev?
I didn't know you were coming back today.
I didn't know
if you were coming back at all.
Thank you,
for all of your help last month.
I was in bad shape, but I am better now.
I'm rested,
and I'm seeing someone
on a regular basis and...
I mean I didn't know if you were
coming back to Grey-Sloan.
I thought you might join
the other Dr. Karev
in his new... endeavor.
Oh, well, he did offer me
my own fellowship,
- with no oversight, but, um...
- Did he?
Well, as it happens,
my plate is fuller than ever
with all the groundbreaking
things we do here.
So, um, I will need to take
a step back from the fellowship,
and give you more free rein
to pursue and develop
as you see fit.
Does that sound appealing?
Um...
I-I...
Take the day. Think about it.
Let me know.
Uh, I-I'm sorry.
How... How... How do you know Meredith?
Community work crew.
She said to come here,
ask for Dr. Webber.
He would get a CT of my head.
Uh, what's wrong with your head?
I was running really fast,
away from these people,
because they thought that
I had stolen someone's car.
- But I...
- Uh, you know, n-never mind.
Uh, uh, hang tight.
Dr. Brown to Imaging.
I need a pen.
Uh, where are the CT orders?
- Uh, CT's out.
- What do you mean, "out"?
Broken, I guess.
Well, shouldn't we close to trauma, then?
What?
Should we close to trauma?
Look, I asked an hour ago,
but, uh, rigs keep showing up
with some more patients.
- Oh, man.
- Do we have pens?!
- Any pens that work?!
- Oh, my God.
Hey, are you Dr. Webber?
Um, can I help you?
I'm friends with Meredith Grey.
Dear God.
So, what you want
to do is go to Pac-North.
You want to see either
Alex Karev or Richard Webber.
Tell them you're a friend
of Meredith Grey's
and you want to get
an ultrasound on that leg.
- Okay.
You got my stuff?
Lidocaine, gauze, uh,
scalpels, bandages, saline.
Am I gonna get arrested?
I feel like I'm gonna get arrested.
- For what?
- I just stole from the hospital.
I own the hospital. That's my stuff.
You just brought me my stuff.
Go set it up.
- Who's next?
- Hey!
So, not only are you not
picking up trash,
but these "patients" aren't, either.
Who are you?
I don't want to answer.
This isn't a walk-in clinic, Grey!
Get back to work.
Come on, let's go, guys.
People, let's go!
Get back to work!
How long have you had
that lump on your neck?
I noticed it while you were swallowing.
It's a nodule. It's oval-shaped.
I could take a look at it
for you if you want.
Or I could get back to work.
Who can tell me the most difficult part
of an ax-bi-fem bypass?
Subcutaneously tunneling the graft?
Wrong.
Your prize... rectals for the week.
Next incorrect answer gets
to empty bed pans in the ICU.
Helm?
Uh, is it anastomosing the graft
to the axillary artery?
Congratulations.
And that is why you see
vascular instruments
and PTFE grafts in front of you.
Dr. Bailey.
D... What?
Dr. Grey uses Dacron grafts.
And I don't. Is there a question?
I didn't think so.
For the rest of you, studies have shown
that one synthetic material
is not superior to another
in this procedure.
Now, the first person
to complete perfect anastomoses
gets to do it in the OR.
You just confirmed
that it was the hardest part
of the surgery.
Then if I were you, I'd start practicing.
Joy.
Well, Reid, it looks like
you've gotten away
with a few fractures near your sternum.
You are extremely lucky.
I mean, so is she.
You're the one who hit me.
- Hit you?
- I could have died.
You were the one who ran him over?
I-I was sitting still.
You were the one who recklessly
scootered into my car,
like a squirrel with a death wish.
Okay. No pulse.
- What the hell happened?
- Ultrasound. He was just stable.
Show me the films. And did you do an EKG?
No, I just saw rib fractures.
Okay. Let me see that.
Okay, cardiac tamponade.
Let's get a chest rig.
We need to open him up right away.
Link.
I am being treated like a commodity.
Like, I-I came back expecting
rare-bird looks,
and instead, I am being offered
total creative control over my fellowship
by two different hospitals.
I mean, this doesn't make any sense.
Link? Hey. Are you okay?
Pregnant.
Amelia's pregnant.
From me.
Whoa.
Okay.
Have you two decided what you want to do?
We didn't get that far.
She, uh... She got paged to a case.
I guess she's got
some bad history with pregnancy,
so maybe she wants to keep it?
Turn your head.
I noticed it at my dad's birthday dinner,
which was about a few months ago.
It hurt to cough.
My primary care physician looked at it.
You need to see an ENT.
That's exactly what she said.
But insurance took two weeks
to authorize a specialist.
And when I called,
the soonest they could fit me in
was November.
Okay, well, I know someone
who can see you right now.
The crew has two hours left in the day.
You have two hours left.
Who's gonna know if we leave?
I could lose my job!
Cancer, Robin.
This could be cancer.
Yep.
O-Okay. L-Let's go.
Schmitt, you're driving.
On my bike?
This is why I don't have
a resident today?
- Bailey's holding boot camp?
- Mm-hmm.
Uh, without Grey, Karev, and Webber,
the pressure is on
to improve the caliber
of the surgical department.
Sounds like a lot of work.
I prefer not firing people.
Also, I don't trust bottom
feeders to touch patients.
That's why I don't teach.
- Hmm.
- It's a teaching hospital.
Oh. ER. Good. This is boring.
What does that man have over your mother?
Probably just saving her life.
Hmm.
Done!
Done! So done!
All right, Helm will do
the anastomosis this afternoon.
- What?
- I am so Meredith Grey.
Dr. DeLuca, you'll still join us
in the surgery.
Prep the patient and transport to OR 1.
The patient has a fever...
Okay. ...no abdominal pain,
the labs are normal, and a negative CT.
Yet you paged me, a surgeon.
Who should I page?
Anyone but me.
Mer, my ER's over capacity.
You need to send your street
clinic to a different hospital.
- Hey.
Everything okay? How's your day?
Uh, it's weird, for a couple reasons.
Um, Bailey made me
the same offer you did...
complete control over my fellowship.
Did you ask her to do that?
Is that, like, another pity offer?
What? No way.
Bailey hates me right now.
- Look, nobody's giving you any...
- Excuse me.
Hi.
Uh, you need to wait in the chairs.
Look, Jo, if you don't want
to do the fellowship,
um, I will make you full general
surgery attending right now.
The only pity that needs to be shown
is you coming here to help me.
I'm really sorry to bother you again,
but the guy sitting next to me...
I think he's dead.
I gotta call you back.
Damn it!
Why is a rib fracture in a trauma room?
And furthermore,
why is a rib fracture filleted?
Turns out the rib hit the heart.
Suture. We need
to temporize the bleeding.
We still don't have good pressure.
Just give it a second.
- V-Fib.
- Paddles.
Simms, come to trauma two.
See someone save a life without
turning him into a sauté.
This guy can't die.
I could be charged with manslaughter
or vehicular homicide.
Clear!
You didn't hit him. He hit you.
I can't go to jail right now.
Mer's already on the verge,
and if I'm in jail and she's in jail,
then Amelia has the kids
and she cannot handle that right now.
What's wrong with Amelia?
Uh, nothing.
Charge to 20.
Clear.
So, he was just half dead in the ER?
Mm-hmm.
Left gastric artery's compromised.
There's a small area of necrosis here.
Karev, careful.
You're using too much traction.
If I go any slower, the entire
stomach won't be viable.
And if you perforate it,
he'll be more septic and die.
Do you want me to get someone
else in here?
Because I'd be happy to tag out
and get you another assist.
With one of your subpar
residents? No, thank you.
My subpar residents?
I'm only here because you told
me to come get this job.
I know this, Karev.
That doesn't mean I want to work here.
You told me to hire you.
I was 15 minutes late
for work this morning,
and I'm never late.
I find it to be an indicator of laziness.
But I got into my car this morning,
and I drove to Grey-Sloan
because for the past 35 years,
that's where I've driven every day.
I spent more of my life in that
building than in my own home.
It's where I was called "Dr. Webber"
for the very first time.
I figured one day I would just
drop dead in OR 2,
and the thought of that made me happy.
So, no, Karev, I don't want to work here.
I want to work at my hospital!
That is no longer an option.
I started chemo when I was 10,
then radiation,
then more chemo, and so on.
I spent my entire childhood
getting poked and prodded
and listening to my parents fight.
Link, that's not gonna
happen to your kid.
Your cancer wasn't even genetic.
It was random, which is...
I swear to God it's worse.
There's no way to prepare.
I mean, forget cancer.
What sane person turns on
the news and thinks,
"Oh, great, the...
the polar ice caps are melting.
The planet is on fire,
and all of humanity is whining
on Twitter while doing exactly
nothing to prevent any of it.
So, yeah, yeah, I should bring
a baby into this world"?
Sometimes I forget how dark
your dark streak is.
It's her choice, so, uh
If she wants to have this kid,
do I say any of this?
It's her body, her choice, yes.
But you're a person, too.
You get to weigh in.
It's Amelia.
Wait, Link.
You're an excellent friend.
And if it comes down to it,
you will be an excellent dad.
Jo, if people are treating you
like a commodity,
it's because you are.
Don't get fired, don't get
fired, don't get fired.
Why are we in the parking lot?
It's a long story.
But don't you work here?
She used to work here.
It was a whole thing. Very dramatic.
Why do I think this must be related
to why you're on my work crew?
It's not unrelated.
Can you hold still, please?
Are you trying to lose your
medical license or what?
So, Robin, this is Dr. Avery,
- the ENT specialist I told you about.
- Yeah.
Hey, so, Robin has an enlarging
mass in her neck.
Ultrasound is showing
some concerning features.
You think you could do a biopsy for me?
- Now?
- It'll take you 20 minutes.
I have surgeries scheduled.
She's got an appointment in two
months with Clark at County.
- Clark's an idiot.
- Right.
Please.
I'll see if I can move some stuff around.
Will you not practice medicine
in the damn parking lot?
Bailey's gonna see you.
Okay. All right, let's start heparin,
and then let's prepare for anastomoses.
Angled DeBakey, please.
I'll obtain proximal and distal control
before performing the arteriotomy.
All right, now, remember,
the artery is fragile, okay?
- So don't be too...
- Aggressive.
- Right.
- I know.
If anyone's gonna operate
from the sidelines,
DeLuca, it'll be me.
- Dr. Bailey!
- Yes?
I beat her. I beat her time.
Should have beaten her by more
than one second, DeLuca.
Helm, let's get to it.
Oh, God.
How many times have we shocked him?
18 and multiple rounds of meds.
Come on. Come on.
Another 50 joules.
Clear.
If I wasn't blaming myself for this,
I would have called it by now,
wouldn't I?
You would and you should.
Not only is he dead,
but you've charred his heart.
- Give it up.
- Oh, God.
Let me try, Pierce.
Let's charge to 50, okay?
And... clear!
You know, if you two get off on this,
take a set of paddles down to the morgue,
but at least free up my trauma
room. You hear me, Hunt?
Charge again, and, clear.
- We got a rhythm!
- Ohh!
Let's push epi, and let's get
him up to the OR now!
Aah!
Oh!
Aaaah!
- Oh!
- Crap.
No, no, no, no.
No. Mnh!
That son of a bitch tried to kill me!
Tom, you should really sit down.
I physically can't!
I had no idea you were behind me, Tom,
and the paddles were still charged.
I was just trying
to resuscitate the patient.
You hit him with 50 joules
of electricity.
What the hell is wrong with you?
Simms, go find him a bed
and page urology.
Page Catherine Fox.
I'm not letting incompetence touch me.
No, no, no, no, no, no.
Aah.
Also, 25 disposable scalpels,
12 bulk packages of bandages,
a lot of 4x4s, bags of saline.
Why are you telling me all this?
I'm a Gryffindor. I'm brave.
I'm scared all the time,
but I am brave and sometimes stupid.
So, when Dr. Grey called, I went.
I just do not want to lose
my license or go to jail.
So, when Chief Bailey asks me
why I took those supplies,
I'm hoping maybe you could say
you asked me for them.
Fine.
Here's a sample.
Fine? Really?
Meredith Grey's a good friend
and the best doctor I know.
I'm not scared of getting in
a little bit of trouble
if that means she's helping someone.
Also a Gryffindor.
I named him Christopher.
I, uh, donated his organs,
and it was the hardest thing
I've ever gone through.
So, the thought of being
pregnant again, um,
the idea of reliving it, it just, um...
it was always paralyzing.
That is why I am militant
about birth control.
I mean, I've honestly
been on it for so long
I barely get a period anymore,
which is why
it took me a while to notice... this.
And I've had a long time to process it,
to grieve him.
But... even though I, uh...
I'm in a privileged situation now, I'm...
with my sobriety and with my career,
and even though I could
give a kid a good life,
I just don't think that's
a reason to have a child.
And, um...
And even though the odds of
what happened with Christopher
ever happening again
are like a million to one,
I...
I just...
I know I wouldn't survive it.
So, um...
Sorry.
And, uh, I know it's my body,
but, uh, you are free to have feelings.
Um...
I've spent the day trying to
wrap my head around this, um,
imagining worst-case scenarios
if we actually went through with this,
a-and I've got about a million of them.
Cancer, uh, global warming,
gun violence,
antibiotic resistant superbugs.
But, um, talking to you now,
looking at you,
listening to you, and hearing
what you have survived, I...
What I know I don't want
is for anything to hurt you.
That feels real to me.
That feels tangible.
And everything that scares me
suddenly feels irrelevant.
So... if you want to have this kid,
I-I will suck up my fears and
I'll be a dad because
Well, I mean, let's be honest.
Kids love me.
And, um, if you don't want it,
I-I, um... I'll drive you
to the appointment.
I will be there for you
in every way I possibly can.
That's what I know.
That's ... That's my feelings.
Damn it, Link!
And... done.
Ready to tie.
Awesome.
Time to remove the first clamp.
And flush the graft.
The graft is...
...good.
Mm-hmm.
Air's out.
Now for the second one.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
- Why... Why's he bleeding?
Where's it from?
Uh, seems to be coming
from your suture line.
Suction. What?!
There's so much blood.
Do something. Fix it.
Why aren't you fixing it?!
Can you fix it?!
I don't know. Can I?
Oh, God. Ohh.
DeLuca.
He's bleeding out too fast, Bailey.
So, what do you do?
Aah...
Clamps.
I'll get proximal and distal control.
All right. Ahh.
All right, coming around.
6-0 Prolene. Right now. Come on.
- Thyroid cancer?
- Papillary thyroid cancer.
It's the most common
and the most treatable.
You'll need surgery,
possible iodine treatments,
but all of it's perfectly doable.
If it wasn't for you,
I'd still be waiting
two months to get checked.
And that's if I could
afford the time off.
If I miss work, I don't get paid.
And if I don't get paid, I can't pay rent
or I can't pay for my asthma medication.
Insurance doesn't cover
the cost of the inhaler?
They'll cover one per month.
I shell out $500 a month
if I need another one,
which I'm guessing may be cheap
compared to what it costs
to treat cancer.
We'll make sure you're given
options to consider.
Yeah.
Bankruptcy or death.
Dr. Grey? Are you back?
Is she back?
I'm visiting a friend, Helm.
Walk, Helm.
So, we were able to repair
the hole in his heart,
but it'll be a long road to recovery.
He steals my credit cards.
He lives in my apartment
and eats my food.
Why do I stay with him?
Because at one point, things were good.
He made you laugh.
You were attracted to him.
And maybe a quiet part
inside of you raised a red flag
here or there, but you ignored it because
dating in today's world is miserable.
It's digital and terrifying,
and, let's be honest,
the pickings are slim for an
educated, independent woman.
So you stayed.
But, Tara, the longer you stay,
the harder it will be to leave.
And maybe you think
that he will leave first,
but if he does that,
then you'll just feel like
a victim, which I think is worse
than just ripping off
the Band-Aid yourself.
Thanks.
Hey. Our guy's stable.
His wife's on the way.
Well, it's nice that one
thing went right today.
Yeah.
Hey, Dr. Webber.
I-I didn't want to work here, either.
You know, at Grey-Sloan,
I inherited a-a legacy.
Bailey's legacy, your legacy.
You know, I mean, every choice I made,
I heard your voice in my head...
"Don't settle. Do better."
At Grey-Sloan,
failing was our last option.
But here, failure's the culture.
But we can change that.
I mean, dying in an OR
at Grey-Sloan is one plan,
but maybe there is a better plan
for you here.
A new legacy.
Help me turn this place around.
Help me do the impossible.
H-Help me prove Bailey wrong.
Yeah.
Oh, I, uh... I almost forgot.
I had to pull some strings with
maintenance, but, uh, ta-da!
Your office.
Karev! Do better!
You're wrong, you know?
Excuse me?
What you said about Vic.
She's really smart, Maggie,
and she's brave.
And you're right.
She is different from me.
I don't think that's a bad thing.
I'm sorry for what I said.
Even so, "#Freedom"
is a little aggressive.
I wasn't being consciously spiteful.
Unconsciously, then?
You hear that, Wade?
It's the sound of blood
flowing through your body.
- That's good.
- That's right.
Monitor proximal
and distal pulses every hour.
Really? That's it?
Nothing else to say?
What? Oh, you want praise?
Um, good work, Dr. DeLuca.
You did your job.
You let someone who wasn't ready
do the most critical part of his surgery.
I should have been doing that
anastomosis from the beginning.
But instead, you sidelined me
because of my relationship
with Meredith Grey.
Excuse me?
I aced that skills lab, Bailey.
My suture technique
was far more advanced...
Helm needed the practice!
She needed the adrenaline
and the fear because all of that
is what makes you a surgeon!
And don't you dare question my methods!
This is not personal, DeLuca!
Unless you make it personal.
If I were you, I'd start
thinking about my career
and let go of certain... loyalties.
Dr. Lawson, extension 2290.
Dr. Bailey? Hi, um, can you talk?
Is now a bad time?
I no longer have good times. What?
I've taken the day,
and I've made my decision.
I want to be a general surgery attending.
I don't recall giving you that option.
Did Tom Koracick...
No one did.
Well, no one here did.
So, you're going to Pac-North?
That's up to you.
They've made me a tempting offer.
Your husband.
Their chief.
They believe that I'm ready.
I've trained under the best,
and most of whom
no longer work here.
I know how this place works.
I know how you work.
And I'm ready.
I would be an asset to any hospital.
The question is... do you want
that hospital to be yours?
Let's go to my office.
Yes.
Uh, hey. I wanted to apologize for the...
I'm sorry, Tom, for the incident.
- Incident?
- Yeah.
You deep-fried my nads.
It was an unfortunate accident, Tom,
and I am very sorry, so...
Actually, champ, I'm gonna need
you to step back a few feet.
500 feet, if we're gonna be
sticklers about it.
- Court orders.
- What?
I've obtained an emergency
restraining order against you,
Hunt, due to acute emotional
and physical distress.
- Restraining order?
- If you need any clarification,
feel free to reach out
to my attorney, Ron Brickman.
He can answer any questions you have.
He's a good friend, hell
of a tennis player, actually.
Tom, we work together.
Shut the door on your way out, would you?
Ohh.
Ahh.
...which is just a long-winded
way of saying thank you
for the offer,
but I'm afraid I have to pass.
Wait. You took my offer
to Bailey to get a better one?
It didn't feel that calculated
in the moment, but basically.
I feel used.
I know! I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
But it's the smart choice.
The facility's better.
The tech is cutting-edge.
Higher-profile patients.
Look, you're making it sound like
I'm the chief of a burger joint.
Someone died in your waiting room.
Nobody died.
Webber and I got to him in time.
He's fine.
Okay, you're basically making
my argument for me.
All right, just make sure
you get a parking spot.
Bailey's really tight with them,
so demand one.
She gave me yours.
After we've been sick or hurt,
our bodies remember.
So, he had them in... His nuts?!
- Look, it's only funny because he's okay.
- Yep!
We learn from the past
and develop tools to help us cope.
Basically, the more we go
through something,
the better we can handle it
if it happens again.
- Hi!
- Hey.
Now, I heard a rumor you were
at the hospital today.
I, uh, stumbled across
a patient at work crew.
I actually have stumbled across
a lot of patients at work crew.
I know I got fired
for trying to help a kid
who fell through the cracks.
And as much as I try to keep
my head down and lay low
and just get through my hours,
I keep coming across people
who can't get the help they need
because of the same crap.
They keep falling
through the same cracks.
Okay, look, before you decide to
do whatever it is you're doing,
okay, jail sucks. It's not fun.
You're not gonna be able to see
your kids or pee in private.
The water tastes like feet.
Should I go on?
Okay, I'm not planning on going to jail.
But what I'm planning to do
is write about what I'm seeing.
You want to publish?
I do.
You're about to face the medical board.
I know.
Didn't the lawyer say to lay low?
Yes, but I-I-I don't think
I'm capable of that.
What?
Nothing. Nothing.
You're just very, very sexy
when you're about to burn
your whole life down.
You know that?
Our bodies are prepared to bounce back.
Or so we think.
Did I... say the wrong thing?
I had made up my mind.
Because I was scared.
Of what happened with
Christopher, and, um...
...of doing this alone.
And a million little things.
I was scared.
And then you said things.
That made you less scared?
Less scared and a little bit in love.
It's probably just the hormones.
Probably.
- Please don't say it back.
- Okay.
You and I...
We'd make an amazing kid.
And now I kinda want to meet that kid.
Well...
I kinda do, too.
Sometimes an unknown
throws the whole thing off.