Previously on ER:
A glass of a wine and a hot
bath at the end of the day help.
Sounds good to me.
The water bill,
because I need to...
You live with someone.
- We love you.
- Meg, I can't do this anymore.
There's a little girl.
Curtis Ames was
a patient of mine.
He followed my wife
and child to the park.
Help me protect my family.
My mom used to put it in a trash
bag with chicken broth and Crisco.
Grill it on the barbecue,
you'll never go back.
I read that brining
keeps the juices in.
Did you take the giblets
out of the marinade?
Take what out of what?
- C-spine is clear.
- We should try to pull off the gravy.
All right, I'm gonna take this collar
off. Let us know if anything hurts, okay?
Fried turkey is a religious experience.
- Gross.
You'd rather cook
it in a trash bag?
Americans, so sentimental
about their holidays.
This from the guy that celebrates
Croatian independence...
Croatian State Day, and something
called Patriotic Gratitude Day.
- Oh, no.
- What?
I have 10 minutes left in my shift
and the transport pager goes off.
- I'll go.
- No, you can't, you're an intern.
The dispatcher wants to
say "Happy Thanksgiving"?
Yeah, right. I'm
sure that's what it is.
- Jane? Jane.
- Abby.
- You carry the transport pager overnight?
- Uh, yeah.
Well, it just went off, and I was
thinking maybe you could just take it.
- Mm, no.
- No?
Why not? Five more minutes, it
would have been your call anyway.
- Sorry, it just doesn't work that way.
- What way?
If the pager goes off during
your shift, you have to go.
Yeah, but I wanna spend
Thanksgiving with my kid.
It's like that story with
the guy hunting dinosaurs.
He strays off path, steps on a butterfly
and the future's ever so different.
- What?
- It's bad karma to mess...
with the universal
order of things.
- Your ace unicycle man, he can go.
- Ray.
- Yeah?
- Take this, I'll owe you.
- I'd love to.
- Great.
I can't. Pratt thinks I'm
losing too much ER time.
- He banned me from transports.
- I just like having you near me.
Surprise. You get me
instead of Morris tonight.
He begged me to switch so he
could spend time with his kids.
- What's your excuse?
- Henry went to Orlando...
with his grandparents.
I might as well come in.
I love working Thanksgiving.
Everybody's at home...
eating and watching
football. Even the freaks.
Ah, the great American tradition
of sanctioned gluttony. No, thanks.
I'm not trying to block the run. I'm
just asking, does garden-variety MI...
really need a doc on board?
Miss Lulu Davis, age 12, vomiting
and abdominal pain times two hours.
- Hi, I'm Dr. Figler.
- Lulu, we'll take care of you. I got this.
- I got here first.
- I'm good with kids.
- Are you saying I'm not?
- No. Wait a minute. Hold on a second.
Lulu, you okay?
Oops.
- Cranberries.
- Sorry, Jane. Karma sucks.
The book says three hours at
450. And don't forget to baste.
How often?
I don't know. Q-30 minutes?
I'll probably be home
to mash the potatoes.
- Okay, what do I do with the pumpkin?
- Oh, I forgot about the pie.
- Dr. Kovac. You got a minute?
- Yeah. Just a second.
I thought pumpkins
were for Halloween.
Screw the pie. I never really
liked pumpkins, anyway.
- Sure you don't wanna order Chinese?
- No.
But baste. Remember to baste.
- Hey.
- I went to see Curtis Ames yesterday.
He didn't know
about any kid's toy.
Did he admit to following
them to the park?
He didn't know what
I was talking about.
Look, the guy's had a pretty
tough time. He's barely getting by.
Okay, I realize that, but that's no
excuse for messing with my family.
If you want my opinion...
he's too busy trying to feed and
clothe himself to mess with anyone, doc.
Right.
- You get airsick?
- No.
Claustrophobic?
Maybe you should just
tell me about the patient?
Eighty-eight-year-old
female, anterior MI.
I can't tell you how many
docs freak out at altitude.
I work in an ER. It's
pretty hard to freak me out.
You do okay with heights,
honey? Loud noises?
Yeah, but mice make me
jump on a chair and say "eek."
Danny, meet Dr. Lockhart.
Hi. DANNY: Sit.
Don't stand. Don't
disembark till we tell you to.
Keep your headset and
your seatbelt on at all times.
If you need to speak to us...
slide this switch this way
to activate the intercom.
Do not press that button.
That transmits over the radio.
This baby is tight.
- Excuse me?
- First night out...
after two months of upgrades.
Satellite phone, GPS, new hoist.
All the cool toys.
- I'm Jasper, this is Evan.
- Hey.
What'd you say your name was?
- Abby.
Come fly with me
Let's float down to Peru
In llama land there's
a one-man band
And he'll toot his flute for you
Come fly with me, Abby
Let's take off in the blue
When I press, when I let go?
- About the same.
- I see.
- I'm thirsty.
- Too bad. You're NPO.
- What's that?
- Nil per os, nothing by mouth.
Food or liquids exacerbate or complicate
an obstruction, volvulus or inflammation.
Not to mention increase
aspiration risk during intubation...
should you go to
the O.R. tonight.
Um, I'm sorry I threw up on you.
Oh. I don't mind the fact I had to
shower to get the chunks out of my hair.
I just don't know how I'm gonna
survive a whole shift dressed like this.
I'm gonna order a few tests,
see what's going on in there.
I mean, bunnies, puppy dogs.
I'm, like, breaking out in hives.
Jane, why don't you
let me take it from here?
- Your parents are on their way, right?
- Yeah. Definitely.
I think it's hip. I think it's fetishy. I
think you totally pull this look off.
Shut up, Gates.
Hey, Sam, I need a
CBC on a little girl in 2.
And order up an extra red top if you
can, just in case the blood bank needs it.
- Got it.
- Hey, Alex.
Don't you have anything better to do
than hang out with us on Thanksgiving?
If he stayed home, he'd
play video games all night.
I figured I'd bring him in,
make him do community service.
Hey, that's cool, man.
Handing out cookies to
sick people? That's cool.
Could be worse. You could
be one of those sick people.
Four pages in the last 20 minutes?
What's the crisis, Dr. Gates?
Oh, no crisis, just an
incarcerated hernia...
a gluteal abscess, road
rash that needs skin grafting...
embedded drill bit, rule-out
appy on a 12-year-old girl.
- You're making this up.
- I wish I were.
You sure it's not an
excuse to keep me here?
Please. I would never dream
of wasting your time like that.
But really, must you
look so hot all the time?
I mean, even with that ridiculous hat,
I can't concentrate. I can't even talk.
You know, enough of this
harassment. I have work to do.
Are you the team from County?
Yeah. Watch it.
Hi, I'm Dr. Lockhart.
Mom was fine. Cooked a 20-pound
turkey, carved it, then she collapsed.
- We thought she was kidding.
- But then we couldn't wake her up.
- Must have been scary.
- Get the history later. Stay here.
We need to examine your mother.
- Okay.
Excuse me, I'm looking
for Elizabeth Timmons?
Thank heavens. This way.
You didn't say about
her being intubated.
They never tell the whole story.
- Vitals?
- Tachy to 124, sat 92.
- You got a BP?
- Last one was 74 over 38 on dopa.
- Great. What about a EKG?
- Here, Dr. Russo. Thanks for coming.
- Lockhart.
- Place gets backed up...
- when we have a patient like this.
- Sats 82.
She's tombstoning.
- Thrombolytics?
- I gave it. No response.
Okay, a reality check here? Does
this family know how sick she is?
- They know she's having a heart attack.
- She's not breathing...
her blood pressure sucks and
she's not perfusing her brain enough?
- We can't move her. She's unstable.
- The family wants her out.
- She won't make the trip.
- You don't know that.
If she survives the helicopter, she will
die before the family makes it to County.
- What's your point?
- Well...
She's 88 years old. She's
not coming back from this.
Don't you think dying
here with her loved ones...
is better than dying alone
in the ICU at County?
Listen, doctor, our
job is to scoop and run.
The longer we stay and jaw about it,
the more unstable this lady's gonna get.
Know what? Just give me five minutes.
I'm gonna make sure they understand.
Fifty-two years,
rain or shine...
he drives me around the lake on
a tandem bike after Thanksgiving.
- Isn't that sweet? RAY:
You're blind, Mr. Hunter.
Maybe you should let her drive.
That wouldn't work.
I can't carry a tune.
Oh, he drives, I
sing. It's tradition.
Radiology. Call me
when the films get back.
- You got it.
- Ray, help. Need order for sumatriptan.
- Migraines?
- I get one every Thanksgiving.
- It's the stuffing.
- Okay, 20 milligrams, intranasally.
Then why do you eat it?
Because it's amazing. Mom
makes it with bacon and almonds.
Lands me in the hospital
every Thanksgiving.
It's worth it.
Be right back
with your medicine.
Holidays weird me out. The
special foods, little rituals.
- It's not my thing.
- Yeah.
When I was a kid, Thanksgiving was
an excuse to stay home and watch TV.
I always figured when I grew
up and had kids of my own...
I'd do the whole family
thing, a big banquet, but...
well, here we are. Me and
Alex, hanging out in the hospital.
Didn't your parents
demand you come home?
No. My mom's in Trinidad
with a new boyfriend.
And my dad's never even heard
of a home-cooked meal, so...
Ah, well, at least you got something
hot waiting for you at home.
What?
Missing your cell
phone, perhaps?
What? Yeah. How did you...?
Hematology needed you,
so we called your cell phone...
and you will never
guess who answered.
Surgical med
student Katey Alvaro.
- Oh, well, we were studying.
- Right. I mean, well, she couldn't talk.
She was baking you
something. A little treat.
- Any chance you could be wrong?
- Well, yes.
- But based on my experience...
- Well, which is it?
You tell us she won't survive the
trip, now you say you might be wrong.
I know this is hard. I
just think it's important...
- Time's up. Let's go.
- All right, just wait.
Find the clerk, sign the consent,
we'll be at County in 45 minutes.
- But she just said that we should...
- It's your mom's only chance.
Okay, uh.
Take her.
- She's gonna die.
- Uh-huh.
I'm doing my best to
facilitate a good death.
- It's not your job.
- Not your call.
Here's how it works. The
referring hospital refers...
the accepting hospital
accepts. We're the delivery men.
- Delivery people.
- You're denying the responsibility...
- that comes with your job.
- I'm not the one who's in denial.
Good death? No such thing. If
you think you can make this...
a good experience for that family
you're more arrogant than I thought.
Mom, if you can hear me,
we'll see you in Chicago, okay?
In a few weeks, you're
gonna be a great-grandmother.
Everyone, stay back.
God bless you, Dr. Lockhart.
Systolic's holding above 80.
- Yeah, on 20 mics of dopamine.
- Still counts.
All right. You know, maybe
you were right, maybe she...
Don't say it. Don't say it.
Nothing more painful than
to listen to a lady eat crow.
- I'm not eating crow.
- Which reminds me, I am starving.
- Good idea.
- Turkey, cranberry sauce.
Wife even baked the bread.
- We got a patient here.
- She's fine.
You know, I feel
sorry for your old man.
What's that supposed to mean?
- It's just the turbulence.
- I don't think so.
Charge the defibrillator. Now.
Febrile to 101, vomiting
and mild rebound.
- How long this been going on, sweetie?
- It started during the salad.
Salad for Thanksgiving?
Your family's weird.
- Yeah, tell me about it.
- White count?
Pending.
Are those chocolate chip?
- Uh, no.
- Could I have one anyway?
Um, yeah, sure.
- You know, this holiday's a lie.
- Really?
Yeah. The only thing the Pilgrims
shared with the Indians were measles.
- Okay.
- I'm Lulu. Thanks for the cookie.
Yeah.
Hey, you can't eat
that, honey. You're NPO.
Oh, yeah. Nil per os.
It's Thanksgiving
and I can't even eat.
What did I tell you about asking doctors
or nurses before giving away cookies?
Labs are back.
- Our white count's 14. Let's get a CT.
- I'll call the scanner.
All right. We talked to
your mom on the phone.
She gave us permission to give you
a very special x-ray on your tummy.
She didn't want to talk to me?
No, but she said to make
sure we treat you like a VIP.
I'm sure she'll be here soon.
Oh, that's okay.
Alex can wait with me.
Right, Alex?
Yeah.
Clear.
- Still V-fib.
- Damn it.
- She's 88 years old.
- I tried to make that point an hour ago.
- We're committed now.
- Lido's in.
- Another mg of epi.
- She had five rounds.
Yeah, well, let's make it six.
- We never should have brought her up.
- Darling, it's the job.
Spare me the platitudes, okay?
Go again. Go.
Clear.
Nothing.
If the scar shows above my
bikini, I'm suing your asses.
- Need some help here.
- We're in a hospital. Grow up.
- Don't tell me what to do, grandma.
- Grandma? You bubble-headed bitch.
Let's settle down, all
right? What happened?
- She pushed me into the display.
- I fell.
These three were fighting over
a bag at Bovards' midnight sale.
- Come on, let's go.
- Midnight? It's not even 8:00.
The name's just
tradition. It starts at 4 now.
Bendi brioche, 80 percent off.
- Normally, $1800.
- They only did a limited run.
During the scuffle, Mandy
fell into the Nativity display.
- I was pushed.
- Nativity display? It's Thanksgiving.
Yeah, that's when the
Christmas decorations go up.
Impaled by a fiberglass
Star of Bethlehem.
Jane, call Surgery.
With all that's happened,
I can't keep this now.
Oh, that's so sweet, honey.
Give it back, evil
grandma whore.
Wow.
This is really sad.
Hello?
Hi. I was just calling to say it's
still probably gonna be a while.
You okay?
Abby?
Abby? You there?
Don't worry, we're taking
good care of your girl.
Are you listening?
Who's that?
You guys are assholes.
- Abby?
- Luka, I'll call you when we land.
Hang up the phone.
- You didn't say goodbye.
- Hang up the phone.
Sorry about that. I accidentally
mixed up my channels.
What are we, in
fifth grade here?
Air Medic 6, Dispatch.
- Air Medic 6.
- We have a report of a vehicle...
over the side of Highway
16 at Neosha Ravine.
Are you available?
- Why aren't you answering her?
- We're about to time out.
Pilots are only allowed to
fly for a max of 12 hours.
I've been up for almost 11.
Air Medic 6?
So you're just gonna ignore her?
Don't worry.
Another unit will get it.
Yeah, but we're
not far from Neosha.
Tell her where we are.
Don't look to Daddy
for permission.
Just do your job and
tell her where we are.
Dispatch, Air Medic 6, we're
at Highway 12 and county line.
Are we the closest unit?
Air Medic 6, that's affirmative.
Then put us on the call.
Air Medic 6, you're
assigned to the incident.
Who is this?
Abby Lockhart. I'm the doctor
onboard, and we're responding.
Darling, it's the job.
No free air, no fluid. Looks like
the star missed the peritoneum.
The Thanksgiving sales, the
parades, the blockbuster movies.
Those are to prime you for bald-faced
commercialism of the holiday season.
Syringe?
Lidocaine, 1 percent.
Your wounds are
superficial. You got lucky.
Yeah, right.
By the time I get back to the sale, all
they'll have are bad colors and big sizes.
You were impaled while fighting over
a vessel for credit cards and lipstick.
Doesn't that sort of kind of
feel like a sign? Wake up.
Ow.
A gram of Ancef, 3-0
silk, and irrigation tray.
Jane, stay and
assist the doctor.
We should be close.
She said vehicle, not bus.
Cheap trick.
How are we supposed
to get down there?
She's alive.
Hang on. WOMAN: Hang on.
- I don't know how to help.
- We're coming to help.
Let go. Let go. We got you.
Well, you stay put,
I'll get her. Don't worry.
Hold on. Hold on.
Stay right there. Hold
on to her. Don't move her.
If you're taking that long to find
a pulse, it's not worth looking.
Don't waste time
with resuscitations.
- Help the people you can help.
- I know how to triage, thanks.
Oh! That bus is unstable.
Keep triaging until
the cavalry gets here.
Help. My arm.
- It won't stop.
- All right.
- I'm telling you, it won't stop.
- Okay, let me see. Let me see.
Okay, sit down. Sit down.
Keep pressure on this and
keep your arm up, okay?
Hell, we're all gonna
freeze to death out here.
We're gonna get you out
of the cold soon, okay?
- How?
- Help! Please, somebody!
Over here!
- Stay like that. Stay like that.
- Wait! Wait!
- Wait! Are more people coming?
- I don't know what to do.
Please, his foot is
pointing the wrong way.
Okay.
- Can you tell me what your name is?
- Matt.
Hi, Matt. I'm
Abby, I'm a doctor.
- Hey, doc.
- No, no, no. Don't move. Don't move.
Could you hold his head? Make
sure he doesn't move his neck.
I can't feel my leg.
Oh, my God.
Can you move your feet at all?
- No.
Okay. HAYLEY: Don't.
I'm gonna find something
to splint your leg with.
Okay. MILO: Help!
Somebody! Somebody help!
Please. Help!
Close your eyes. But stay awake.
Somebody's coming. Mom? Mom?
All right, don't move. I'm
gonna come back there.
Mom, she's here now.
It's gonna be all right.
Hello?
- Are you hurt too?
- No, it's just my mom. Please.
- Hang on. MILO: You
gotta get her to help.
Milo?
- Okay. MILO: Oh,
please, get her out.
I'm Abby. I'm a doctor.
Can you tell me your name?
Melanie. ABBY: Okay.
Melanie, can you move at all?
She's stuck.
- Oh, God.
- All right.
Okay. We're gonna get
you out of here, all right?
Okay. MILO: Come on, let's go.
Are you ready? One, two, three.
Is that all my blood?
I don't know.
I don't know where
that blood's coming from.
Come on, fix her. ABBY: Okay.
I can't, uh...
I can't move you now.
Okay, I understand.
Okay.
- You should take Milo out.
- No, I won't go.
Shh. Baby, go with the doctor.
- No!
People are coming
with special equipment.
- They're gonna help us.
- And I'll wait here with her.
- Milo, I love you.
- This is gonna help you with the pain.
But I need you to be a
brave boy now, okay?
Please, just get
him off this bus.
No! MELANIE: Go
with the doctor, baby.
- Milo.
- You can be a good helper.
No!
No. ABBY: Come on.
Please, just make
sure he's okay.
- Mom.
- Let's go now. Come on.
- No.
- Let's go. Watch your head.
See? I told you
it wouldn't hurt.
That's my mom. She
won't stop calling me.
You're lucky.
My foster mother only keeps me
for the money she gets from the state.
When I started barfing at dinner,
she loaded me into the ambulance...
then went back to her ham.
So she's not coming.
- That boy is smitten.
- Boys are easy.
You know, Meg and Sarah
are out of town tonight.
- The liver looks good.
- Which means I have the place to myself.
And why are you telling me this?
Because Meg and I, it's over.
I thought you weren't together.
Well, we weren't. But now, we're
not even not together anymore.
That's fat stranding
a cecal phlegmon.
- She needs O.R.
- I'm gonna call Crenshaw.
Sit down.
I have a very important
job for you, okay?
I don't want my mom to be alone.
I want you to take that flashlight
and point it wherever I'm working.
Someone's gonna help her, right?
The fire department's
gonna be here soon.
- And they'll get her off the bus?
- Yeah.
Promise?
All right. Don't move, okay?
Just shine that light at me.
Up.
Four dead, nine criticals,
14 minor injuries, 11 delayed.
The driver had a passenger
manifest and the numbers all match up.
Good job, good job. All
the criticals are off-site?
Does this include the
woman on the bus?
No one's going back on
that bus until it's stabilized.
How long is that gonna take?
The anchors aren't
holding. It could be hours.
- She can't make it that long.
- There's nothing we can do.
We are not gonna
endanger our guys.
- Calm down.
- Hey, nobody's getting back on that bus.
But she promised. She
said you guys would go back.
- Oh, yeah? What else you tell him?
- Why don't you back off?
No! WRIGHT: Hey. Hey.
No! WRIGHT: Out of the way.
Milo, you... Hey.
WRIGHT: Get that...
Hey! Hey! MILO: No!
- No!
- Milo.
Milo, you cannot get
on that bus right now.
- You said they would get her.
- I know.
- You said they would.
- Okay.
- You said they'd try.
- I know. It's gonna be okay.
Lockhart. Give him
to me. Pass him down.
No. No!
Where the hell's those
guys? Go ahead, pick it.
Lockhart!
Melanie?
Melanie? Can you hear me?
Milo, is he...?
All right. All right,
everything's gonna be okay.
- This is not okay.
- Everything's gonna be all right.
Hey, I need an IV and
a liter of NS in here.
His dad's in Milwaukee.
- Would you please tell him...?
- Okay, Melanie.
Melanie, listen to me.
Help is on the way, all right?
Milo likes it if you
break up his toast...
- and scramble them in his eggs.
- Okay.
He'll only let you
comb his hair...
- if he's wearing his Ronaldinho jersey.
- Yeah.
Oh, damn it.
Ah, ah, ah. No, no, no. Melanie.
Stay with me. Melanie,
come on, stay with me.
Melanie, tell me some more
about Milo. What does Milo like?
He likes to sleep with an
inchworm named Charlie.
- Okay, that's good. What else?
- You trying to get us all killed?
I am trying to keep her alive.
- You are out of your mind.
- Well, what are you doing here?
I thought you might need this.
Hi, Katey, it's me. Uh, I
think you have my cell phone?
I wanna come by later and
pick it up, if that's okay. Call me.
Marsupialized the
abscess on your shooter...
sent the "implanted"
chip up to Pathology...
convinced Captain Kangaroo
to stop eating erasers and, uh...
what's the deal
with the new nurse?
What, you mean, Jane? - Yeah.
- What about her?
- Nothing, you know? Just wondering.
- You like her.
- Quiet, you silly infant.
What about Radiology? Yeah,
Alex loves the fluoroscope.
- I went there. Nobody's seen him.
- Okay, can you check MRI?
- The tech lets him man the controls.
- Sam, I got work to do.
Jasmine Chastek, 17, fell down
a couple of steps, positive LOC.
- Hey, I'm Dr. Barnett.
- What happened?
We were doing hits of nitrous
from whipped-cream cans.
- She went overboard and passed out.
- Okay, this should clean up just fine.
Uh, I have to go find Alex.
Teenagers are such idiots.
Push harder.
It's stuck.
Come on.
Good job.
- Okay, I got her. MAN
2: Come on, come on.
There she is.
Let's go. Let's go.
Gotta go.
- Can I have a cookie?
- Yeah, but they really suck.
Oh, yeah? Eh.
- Listen, your mom's looking for you.
- Oh, man. Now I'm in trouble.
No, she'll understand.
No, I mean, everything
I do makes her angry.
Well, sometimes you have
to go the extra mile for a girl.
She'll get it. Trust me.
Lulu's in recovery.
She's doing fine.
Good.
- Go get her.
- Yeah.
Getting a critical victim from the
crash. I've gotta meet the helicopter.
All right.
Don't you need to be
in the ER or something?
- My shift ended hours ago.
- What are you still doing here?
Waiting for you, dummy.
Tony, it's gonna be a while, I've
gotta get a sign-out, then I've...
All right, here's the deal. You're
going home with me tonight.
Why is that the deal?
Because there's
nobody at my house...
it's Thanksgiving...
and I really, really
wanna make you dinner.
Okay, chocolate cherry.
- Amazing, right?
- Mmm. Wow.
- Looks great to me.
- Hey, Greg.
- Hey, I'm Dr. Greg Pratt.
- Oh, nice to meet you. Courtney Brown.
- Courtney is my producer at Channel 5.
- Oh.
I might be able to hang out here if I
can get my neighbor to let the dog out.
- I'll give her a call.
- Great.
- Who is that?
- I just told you who she was.
Come on, now. Hook a brother up.
You know what? Your gaydar is
terrible, even for a straight man.
Oh.
Yeah, well, you have excellent
taste in women, Dr. Weaver.
Of course I do.
Hey, uh...
- can I ask you something personal?
- Maybe.
All right. How, um...?
No, no.
When did you know you were gay?
Are you coming out to me, Greg?
No, no, no. I came home and I
found my brother with another guy.
Really?
Yeah. He says he's just
experimenting, that it's only a phase.
And what do you think?
I don't know.
Can a straight guy go
through a gay phase?
I think it's more
likely that he's gay.
Hey, and he's telling you
what he thinks you wanna hear.
Okay, but for today, right...
he's taking some hot girl
to the family Thanksgiving.
- If he was gay, why is he doing that?
- I don't know your brother.
I mean, I don't know
what's going on in his head.
But I do know that
when I was that age...
I brought a lot of boys
home to meet my parents.
- You did?
- Hell, yeah.
I mean, I was 30 before
I faced up to being gay...
but my life got a
lot better once I did.
- Hey, Abby.
- Hey.
Your transport go okay?
Um, yes.
Be grateful you got
to skip this freak show.
It's been a real
madhouse around here.
Just got lucky, I guess.
Hey, Lockhart.
Hurry up and sign this
before I get called out again.
Bye.
And thanks.
You're pretty tough for a girl.
Go to hell.
- Hi.
Was afraid you
weren't gonna show.
Sorry, Crenshaw
made me do an I and D.
Come on in. I
hope you're hungry.
Couldn't do the
turkey. Made tacos.
Homemade salsa, I got these tortillas
from a Salvadorian market on Fulton.
- You ever been there?
- I don't think so.
Some wine.
You okay?
- Uh, yeah.
- Here's some more wine.
- Wanna take your jacket off?
- Uh, yeah.
You sure you're cool? If you don't like
Mexican, say the word and, you know.
I'm fine. Really. It's just I haven't been
in a situation like this for a long time.
- I know.
- It feels weird standing here...
knowing what we're about to do.
What? Have dinner?
Tony, I wanna be here. I do.
I mean, I've
thought about it a lot.
Not creepy a lot, but it's
definitely been on my mind...
and I wouldn't want you to be
worried that I don't really wanna...
I'm not worried.
We can take it as
slow as you want.
Slow? What's slow?
Hey, stranger. RAY: Hey.
Well, thank you. And
what are you doing here?
- Working.
- Oof, surgeons are such bastards.
Making med students come in
on Thanksgiving? That is really low.
No, actually, it's the bastards in
the ER who scheduled me for this.
- What?
- I'm starting an ER rotation.
Tonight.
Now, see, you said
you were never gonna...
Radiology fell through at the
last minute. I got reassigned.
- Don't freak out. I'm not stalking you.
- I can't evaluate you.
- We'll work it out.
- I can't have these...
- Okay.
Hey, Abby, what took you so
long? You were out all night?
Well, you know, sometimes
these things can take hours.
Sure you just weren't having
sundaes with the team?
Last run I did, we burned off
the whole shift at the Plush Horse.
Good for you, Ray.
Well, well, well,
look who's back.
She got to soar over Chicago...
while we dealt with
maggots and colostomy bags.
I guess I must've done
something good in a past life.
You look wiped. Transports do
that to you if you're not used to it.
- Want me to get you a coffee?
- No.
Right now, I really
just wanna go home.
No, stay. We just got here.
I missed you guys.
I know. We had no
water or toilet paper.
We looked...
Oh, my God.
Meg, Sarah, this is Neela.
How many times do I have to tell
you? When you leave the glass...
directly on the wood,
it leaves a stain.
- You hungry?
- Yeah, I'm starving.
Let me get my stuff. Then we can
pick up something at the chicken place.
Okay.
- What do you got?
- I have a cupcake over here.
Sam, Alex, happy Thanksgiving.
There's some food over
there. Help yourselves.
Wow. Thanks, Luka.
- Tofurky anyone?
- Uh, no.
- I'll try it.
- Are you really a vegan?
Surgeons just shouldn't be
carnivores. It's a known fact.
- Woman, what the hell is that?
- Looks like milk Jell-O.
Mmm. No, coconut
flan, and it is killer.
Oh, hey, Dr. Weaver,
do you remember me?
- Katey Alvaro.
- Hi, Katey. How are you?
I'm good. I started my ER
rotation about an hour ago.
Oh. Yeah, well, I hope Ray's
giving you the lay of the land.
Oh, yeah, he is. Definitely.
All right. How do you stay
so skinny and eat so much?
Look who's talking,
little Skinny Minnie.
Well, it seems like
good genes to me.
You wanna come over and watch some
football with me and Kerry tomorrow?
Damn, you're lucky.
- I can't believe you made all this.
- Well, maybe I cheated a little.
If anything happens to me,
remember Joe likes strawberries...
- but raspberries give him hives, right?
- What are you talking about?
If you put the fan on in the
bathroom, he doesn't cry in the tub?
I know that.
And it's mandatory he
be exposed to everything...
Stevie Wonder
recorded in the '70s?
Dr. Lockhart. That trauma you
choppered in did well in the O.R.
Oh, great. That's great.
Yeah, it required over 12 units, but
she's holding her own in Recovery.
Thanks.
Are you okay? How
did that transport go?
I didn't know you
got skills like this, doc.
Hey, I have my kid here.
Be quiet with that kind of talk.
Hey, it's Thanksgiving.
I'll tell you tomorrow.
All right, let's give
a toast to Dr. Kovac.
Or Chef Kovac, as he
wants to be called now.
Hear, hear. Thanks.
- Cheers, guys.
Happy Thanksgiving.