♪ Ohhh ohhh ohhh ♪
♪ the way
you move your hips ♪
♪ when you're strutting
down the street ♪
Sam's blocking me
from joining the practice.
Sam is not blocking you.
Oh, please.
Violet doesn't care right now
if you give the partnership
to Godzilla,
Addison would say it to my face,
and since I'm paying
what you owe,
you'd be a fool to block me.
That leaves Sam.
Everybody's really busy,
Charlotte.
We just haven't had time
to discuss it.
You're my man on the inside.
Work your magic.
Want to play
python in the forest?
I'm gonna stand up
very slowly now.
Would you let go?
You really want me to?
No, Charlotte. Come on.
I'm really late.
Mm.
I want this, Cooper.
I want to join the practice.
♪ ...enough, and, baby,
yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
I have to go.
You feel sick now,
but you get on the stand
and just look straight
at the prosecutor--
only at him.
That's what I did, okay?
Violet, you don't
have to do this
if you don't want to.
No, I do, I do.
I want to.
Okay.
Violet Turner.
Hey.
Sorry I'm late.
Please raise your right hand.
Do you solemnly swear
to tell the truth,
the whole truth
and nothing but the truth?
Dr. Turner...
It's customary to say "I do."
I can't do this.
I...
I can't do it.
- Any word on the trial?
- No, not yet.
But Violet's on the stand
all day.
Oh, uh, I heard back
from Stan Parsons.
Ooh, and?
He is happy where he is.
Ugh! Stan really would've
fit in well here.
We could use
another ortho guy.
Yeah, well, we could use
any doctor at this point.
Look, what if--
just keep an open mind here--
what if we just...
Went with Charlotte?
You cannot seriously think
that she would fit in here.
She's skilled, she's connected,
she's a specialty we don't have.
Hey. Wh--
what happened?
Why are you back?
Wh--
she refused to testify.
Oh. Well, did you try
to talk to her about it?
I tried.
Well, she needs support,
Cooper. It's hard.
I know it's hard
and I am supporting her,
but she won't talk to me
about it.
She won't talk to me, either,
and she won't talk to Pete,
so looks like it's your turn.
Well, if she won't talk
to them,
she's not gonna talk to me.
What the hell
are you doing here?
No, they told us that
you'd left the practice.
- They--they promised us that you'd left the practice.
- Okay.
You people lied to us!
Shh.
Zoe, you have this all wrong.
I do not work here anymore.
You screw up
our implantations,
and then you force us to carry
each other's babies--
Zoe, please, just...
I'm sorry. Just sit.
I have high blood pressure.
That's why you're here?
No.
No, the appointment's for me.
Our obstetrician--
thinks there might be
something wrong with the baby.
- Okay, which one?
- Mine.
Sorry. The--the baby
that I'm carrying, her son.
It gets a little confusing
sometimes.
Dr. Carey said that we needed
a consult--surgical--
and the only one
he'd recommend was you.
Okay, uh, Amelia,
while you're here,
we'll go ahead and get
your blood pressure checked.
Zoe, why don't you
come on back?
Okay.
Okay. Hmm.
I'm sorry that I blew up.
I-I thought I was okay
with everything,
but it--it's been hard.
My pregnancy,
Amelia's pregnancy,
and then seeing Naomi again,
I just...
Something is wrong, isn't it?
Give me a second.
Dr. Carey deflected
all my questions.
I won't do that.
Oh, my god.
What is it?
It's a teratoma.
It's a kind of tumor.
Sometimes when the stem cells
differentiate
into cartilage, bone or flesh,
they end up
where they don't belong.
And in this case,
the tumor is large enough,
that it's taking over
the baby's blood supply.
What I'd like to do
is operate,
try to separate the tumor
from the fetus.
And will that fix it?
Well, it's not that simple.
Sometimes it works.
Sometimes it doesn't work.
But without surgery,
the baby will die.
Well, this is Amelia's
last embryo, so i--
I have to tell you
that if I do the surgery,
I'll need to perforate
the uterus.
Sometimes that can affect your
ability to carry another child.
I know it's an awful choice.
You'll want to talk it over
with your husband, with Amelia.
Uh, no. Martin left.
He never liked it--the having
each other's baby thing.
And he--he didn't understand
the bond between Amelia and I.
It's--it's like...
Both babies
belong to both of us.
I can't do it.
Martin will come back,
and we--we've always wanted
a big family.
I just can't.
Well, then I'd recommend
terminating the pregnancy.
My god.
What will that do to Amelia?
And i--if we do nothing,
it's gonna die in the womb?
Yes.
Then I think
I should let it
and get Amelia further along.
I... I can't have her think
that I just gave up.
I think that it's better
for her to think
that it's an act of god,
whenever it happens.
Zoe, this is Amelia's baby.
She has the right to know.
It's in my body,
and I'm your patient.
You can't tell her
without my permission.
Zoe--
you can't tell her.
You look like
somebody shredded you.
Did you talk to Violet again?
No, no. I just, uh...
Remind me never, ever
to go upstairs again.
No, I didn't talk to Violet.
I-I didn't know
what to say to her.
You--you gonna have
another run at her?
Nope. I'm done.
I tried. I pushed.
I... had no effect on her.
So if she wants to let
Katie walk...
Pete, Katie is not gonna
walk away from this.
No, but the defense
will line up experts
who will say she was crazy.
Yeah, well, wasn't she?
Not guilty by reason
of insanity is not guilty,
and Katie is guilty.
Six months in a nut farm,
some meds, a little therapy--
after what she did?
That's unacceptable.
You don't know
how long it's gonna be.
I mean, she--she--she could
be in there for years.
I got on the stand
and told them about the wound,
the blood,
the baby gone,
thinking Violet was dead.
But unless Violet tells the jury
what it was like,
unless they hear it
from her--
but if--if Violet is gonna be
too traumatized...
Then she'll just
keep being stuck.
She'll never be Violet.
And I'll still have a son
whose mother can't bring herself
to care about him.
She's missing everything...
The little sound he makes
when he smiles...
The way his eyes try to take in
the whole world at once.
It's just gonna take time,
Pete.
Well, she can have
as much as she wants.
I'm done.
Cooper put you up to this?
No. We're all concerned
for you, Violet.
Why does it matter
if I testify or not?
Why should I have to sit there
and relive it?
Why am I the only person who can
make sure Katie gets punished?
Well, it's not about Katie.
This is about you.
That's right. It's about me.
So sitting there for eight,
ten hours a day on the stand
with Katie staring at me?
That would be like living
through it all over again.
Aren't you doing that anyway?
And don't shrinks always say
it's good to--to talk?
Well, what do shrinks know?
I know facing her
will be hard.
Being on the same planet
with her is hard.
All right. Well, we could
all chip in and get her
one of those guest trips
to the space station, one-way.
We could probably get a discount
if it's one-way, right?
Dr. Turner, there's someone
here to see you.
Who is it?
A Mr. Kent. He says to
tell you he's Katie's father.
Okay, uh,
could you give us
a second, please?
All right, Violet.
Violet... if you had
a patient in this situation,
would you tell your patient
to face it or to run away?
All right,
you see that chair?
I'm gonna be sitting in it.
If you need help,
you look at me, you blink,
and I'll come riding
to the rescue, okay?
You... you can still blink,
can't you?
Can you...
Okay.
When Dr. Wilder testified...
What he found--
to hear...
It's horrifying.
I-I can't apologize
to you enough. Just...
You helped her.
Well... if that were true,
we wouldn't be sitting here.
No. No, she couldn't
stop talking about you,
how you just knew.
You knew
that all she wanted
was to have her baby
and...
Be not sick anymore.
She told me I was
going to be so proud of her.
She said, "you'll see, dad.
I'm gonna be just like mom."
If that jury
sends her to prison,
she'll disappear.
This illness
will eat her alive.
Why are you here?
Katie wants to see you.
She wants to talk to you.
She says you're
the only person who understands.
Violet talked to you?
Yeah, I guess
she was just ready.
Yeah, but to you?
Look, do you want to hear
what she had to say or not?
She doesn't want to testify
because she's terrified
of facing Katie.
That's the revelation?
We were interrupted.
Katie's father showed up.
Why? What did he want?
I don't know.
But when he left, she went
and hid in the ladies room.
You got a minute?
Uh, yeah.
Just, uh, in one minute.
I was talking to Sam.
Oh, we're just in the middle
of a--
it'll only take a second.
I am a damn fine doctor with
an established patient base,
and as I made clear, I have
great ideas for expanding it.
I have the cash to buy in. I'm
chief of staff at St. ambrose,
so I can steer you so many heart
surgeries, you'll beg for mercy.
Why are you stalling?
Because I just don't think
you're--
you're the right fit here.
You know,
we're--we're all friends,
we--we respect each other,
we get along.
Uh-huh.
I guess that would be why
Naomi and Pete couldn't
get outta here fast enough.
We need someone who is
great with patients,
someone who's great with staff,
someone's who calm--
oh, you want Naomi.
Okay, I-I don't want
to be mean,
but I just don't like you.
Oh.
Well, good grief.
What does that have to do
with anything?
Excuse me.
I need to talk to you
about Amelia and Zoe.
Okay.
This place is
a kindergarten.
If somebody's offering you
something you need,
don't you just grab at it
instead of whining about
your delicate feelings?
What on god's green earth
do feelings have to do
with anything?
It's good for you
or it isn't. Oh!
You agree with me?
Sure.
Something needs doing,
you just do it.
Otherwise, what good are you?
It's Amelia's baby.
Ethically, it doesn't matter.
It's in Zoe's body.
Zoe's my patient.
I can't breach confidentiality.
I hate this. I hate that
this baby is sick.
I hate that Zoe won't let me
even try to fix it...
That I'm lying to Amelia,
that Naomi's
caught up in this again.
We're all caught up in it.
If this baby dies,
then the settlement
goes out the window.
It's based on these two women
bringing these babies to term
and then switching.
If that can't happen, then we're
facing a malpractice suit.
So, no. Lying to Amelia
will only make it worse.
I know that. I tried to get
Zoe to change her mind.
Look, Naomi knows them--
don't even think it.
You saw how hostile Zoe is.
Do not bring Naomi in.
I just meant to ask her--
if litigation starts again,
they smell that
Naomi's been involved--
they'll go after her first.
They'll go after her first.
So nobody knows what
Katie's father said to Violet
except Violet,
and she's not talking,
except to Sam,
and not about that.
I didn't get a babysitter
to talk about Violet.
All right, what do you
want to talk about?
Anything but that.
Uh, well, we could talk about,
uh, Charlotte, my benefactor.
You upset
because she paid your way?
No. I love being emasculated.
Okay, no Violet talk
and no Charlotte talk.
You want to bet on the game?
If you lose,
do I collect from Charlotte?
If you could've
seen her face.
Who knew Charlotte
had feelings?
Cooper.
Thanks. That helps a lot.
You can't tell
your friend's girlfriend
that you don't like her.
I know, I tried...
I tried to dodge her,
but she backed me into a corner
and kept on telling me
all the reasons why
we should hire her and--
we should hire her.
You don't actually
like her?
I like her check.
I like that hiring her
would make Cooper happy.
I like that we would be moving
forward in at least one area.
And I like her specialty.
It could be good for business.
Look, we have a problem.
She is our solution.
Ugh.
All right, fine.
Let's just get it over with.
Addie?
Uh, hey, up here.
Oh, I'm interrupting.
Mnh-mnh.
Mnh-mnh. I was
just leaving, really.
Uh, Amelia came to see me
this afternoon.
I was surprised, too, given
what happened this morning,
but, um, she thinks there's
something wrong with the baby,
and she thinks that you and Zoe
are lying to her about it.
Okay, look, I know
I'm supposed to be out of this,
but she--she looks like
she's about ready to explode.
So... is she right?
Are you lying to her?
There is a problem.
That we can't
tell you about.
Okay. How serious is it?
Nai.
Can it be corrected?
Is it--
oh, this is ridiculous.
We're playing 20 questions.
They were Naomi's patients,
all right?
Like it or not,
we are all in this together.
We either all sink
or we all swim.
It's a sacrococcygeal teratoma,
and it's on the baby
that Zoe's carrying.
Well, can't--can't that
be operated on?
I'd like to try,
but Zoe said no.
Well, that can't be
the end of it.
Well, look, I know you don't
want me involved--
not a good beginning
of a sentence.
Amelia came to me,
and I have to do something.
I mean, Zoe's mad,
but she was my patient,
and I do know her.
So get me into a room with her
and maybe I can get her
to change her mind.
You--you guys
have to let me try.
Thank you for coming.
I'm on my meds.
I'm myself.
I've heard that.
So you wanted to see me?
I...
How are you?
Oh, d-Dr. Turner,
I am...
I'm--I'm so sorry.
Please... tell me you know it
wasn't me who did that to you.
Please tell me you know that.
Why?
So that I'll know
you understand
that I'm not a monster.
That's why you wanted
to see me?
That... and I want you
to testify.
When Dr. Wilder
was on the stand,
the jury looked at me
like I am a monster.
And you think my testimony
would counteract that?
I think if you testify,
the jurors will know--
they will know
that I was crazy that night.
And you'll avoid prison.
I won't get help in prison.
I'll slip.
I'll be crazy again.
I-I don't ever want
to be crazy again.
I'm scared.
I'm scared of that...
That person--
that person who did that.
It's...
It's not about
avoiding punishment.
It's just...
I need--i need help.
I need someone on my side.
You--you--you--you--
you gutted me like a pig.
You ripped
my baby out of my body.
You left me there
to bleed to death,
and now I should be
on your side?
I should care
about how sorry you are?
I should give a damn
about what happens to you?
You made my life hell.
You made me crazy.
And now you want
a free pass from me?
Please, Dr. Turner.
Please!
Dr. Turner, please!
Thank you
for agreeing to see me.
I know how angry you are,
and, uh, how much you blame me,
and rightfully so--
I don't want your apologies.
Dr. Montgomery said
that you had something
that you needed to say to me,
so why don't you just say it?
Amelia came to see me.
You told Amelia?
No, I told you I wouldn't.
Amelia came to me. She knows
you're hiding something.
She knows that there is
something wrong with the baby.
So now you want to atone
by talking me into something
that I don't want to do?
Zoe, listen,
when all this happened,
I did not want to talk you
into keeping the baby.
All I wanted was for you
to see things from all sides.
It was not about me.
This was so you could feel
as okay with what
was going to happen
as you possibly could
given what we did to you--
given what I did to you,
what I did to you.
I wasn't the one
who changed your mind.
It was Amelia
and it was you,
knowing that it was
the best thing
given the circumstances.
If the situation were
the other way around,
wouldn't you want
to know, Zoe?
Don't you see?
It is the other way around.
This is my baby, too.
They're both mine.
They're both hers.
If I tell her now--
tell her that I am going to
end this pregnancy--
it will be bad for her--
her blood pressure.
She's already at risk
for eclampsia.
I may lose both babies.
We'll lose both.
Or I could do the surgery,
at least try.
Okay, if you're gonna choose
not to have the surgery,
then you're gonna have to let
Addison end the pregnancy.
If you ever want to be pregnant
again, it is the safest choice.
And that means...
Telling Amelia.
Okay, I'll tell her.
But you have to explain to her
why the surgery can't be done.
You cannot put that on me.
About Charlotte...
She was in a bitch of a mood
when I got home last night.
Cooper, I'm sorry.
I don't want your apology.
Just make a decision
one way or another.
Is she in or is she out?
Come on.
We did. Yeah, we called her
this morning.
She... she didn't tell you?
Uh, no. I left early for rounds.
What is it, yes or no?
She's moving in to Pete's
old office right now.
You coulda called me.
Congratulations.
I wanted to surprise ya.
Uh, just anywhere
except for that one.
It goes on the desk.
Wow.
This is, uh,
this is gonna be great.
Wait till you see what I got
going on in here.
Um, is this what I think
it is?
Yes.
What is this for?
I mean, why is it here?
New job, new specialty.
Porn shop?
Sexual dysfunction.
You're a urologist.
That and now more. Look.
I hired a web designer.
You'll be able to click on
a condition, get information.
You can do
an e-mail consultation,
you can order stuff, you can
make an appointment to come in.
This didn't happen
since last night, right?
You been thinking about
this one for a while?
Yes.
You didn't think
to mention this to me?
It just slipped your mind?
It's a work in progress.
And what do you call it? What,
is it, like, uh, genitology?
Can't-function-ology?
Sexology.
Is that what it's gonna say
on your business card--
Dr. Charlotte king,
sexologist?
Kinda sounds a little bit like
a hooker or a dominatrix.
You did not just call me
a hooker.
No, I said it sounds
a little bit like a hooker.
For god sakes, Cooper.
This is a legitimate
medical specialty.
Really, this?
How old are you?
Some people
have trouble with sex.
They need a doctor's help.
I emphasize "doctor."
You know what?
Um, let's table this.
Violet Turner.
All right, pick a fist.
Come on. Pick a fist.
Oh, good. Yes. See? That means
you have to answer one question.
You still don't want
to talk to me?
No, it's--it's not that.
I'm just afraid
you're gonna pressure me
into doing something
I don't want to do.
Yeah, but Sam--
you talked to Sam.
No pressure.
I will not pressure you.
Promise.
Okay.
What's the question?
Why... did Katie's father
come in to see you?
To tell me that
Katie wants to see me.
And did he really think
you were gonna go?
I did go.
I thought that...
If I could face her--
just us--
then I could face her
in the court.
Why didn't you tell me?
I would've gone with you.
How'd it go?
I wanted to rip her lungs out,
but the deputy was there.
Well, that's probably
a good thing... for Katie.
She wants to me testify.
She wants me to say
that she's crazy.
And... what do you want?
Well, Dr. Turner thinks
she needs help.
But Violet wants her dead.
You can have conflicting
emotions about a person.
I speak from experience.
Yeah, but only one of us
can testify.
What should I do?
Well, I think Dr. Turner's
the best psychiatrist I know.
But I want
what's best for Violet.
The teratoma depletes
the baby's blood supply,
and the fetus can't develop
or thrive.
And the baby dies?
Amelia, I wanted to tell you.
I was--
and is--
is there anything that we can do
except for the surgery?
I wish there were.
If I thought
that there was a way--
no, I understand. I do.
Okay.
I do.
Amelia.
Uh-huh.
Are you okay?
I'm okay.
I'm just--I'm a little
light-headed, I think.
I'm gonna go ahead and take
your blood pressure now, okay?
Okay.
When we--when we first found out
we had the wrong babies,
I was afraid.
I was afraid that you wouldn't
try to make it work.
Thank you for trying.
So what do we do now?
I think termination
is best.
I want to be there.
I--I'm sorry.
No.
I-I know--i know
this must be hard for you
if you--if you feel--if you feel
anything like the...
Like the way that i--
that I feel...
Amelia.
Her pulse is weak and thready.
Get 4 liters of oxygen going.
It's all right.
It's all right...
I'm gonna get an I.V. Pack.
You just breathe.
Okay, okay.
Okay, just breathe.
Okay? Breathe.
All right, lean back.
Lean back. Slow breaths.
I'm okay.
Is the baby okay?
Yes.
You just had a transient rise
in blood pressure.
It slowed your heart down,
but you're okay now.
Oh, thank god.
I am such a mess.
You just need to avoid stress
and rest so it doesn't
get any worse.
Mm.
And I am going to call
your regular ob-gyn
and see about adjusting
your medication.
I wanted to be stronger
for her.
You are, Amelia.
Is she still here?
Of course she is.
I'll go get her.
How is Amelia
and the baby?
Amelia's gotta be careful,
but they're both
going to be fine.
Good. That's good.
I changed my mind.
I want to have the surgery.
I-I-I want you to try,
as soon as you can.
Zoe--
no, I know.
I know what I said.
But she is putting her health
at risk for my baby.
She's doing it for me.
I need to do it for her.
♪♪♪
Did Violet decide whether
or not she's gonna testify?
Oh, I think she will. I just
don't know what she's gonna say.
I think that she should--
ah...
I--
ix-nay on the iolet-vay.
Ix--
I've backed off.
Will she? Won't she?
It's not my concern.
If you want to try
to change her mind--
oh, not me. Katie.
Katie wants her to testify,
tell the jury
that she was crazy.
Is Violet
actually considering--
Can we talk about
something else?
Yeah, Charlotte,
uh, is going into sexology.
How crazy is that?
I don't think
it's crazy at all.
She didn't tell you?
What, you knew?
Of course we knew.
She didn't tell you?
No.
Dude, you gotta work on
your communication skills.
I think so.
Besides, I think she'll
be good at sexology.
I think so.
I mean, I'm assuming--
that is exactly the problem.
It's a medical specialty.
Come on.
That is so not the point.
You said you wanted her
in the practice.
As a doctor, Sam. As--
excuse me. May I have
another one of these, please?
Hey, listen. Uh, uh, uh,
it's Brad.
If your girlfriend told you
that she was gonna be
a sexologist,
would you be okay
with that?
♪ 'cause I don't seem to ♪
♪ recognize
this look on your face ♪
♪ I don't seem to ♪
Mm. Where have you been?
I had a party.
A gin party?
Yep.
With Brad the bartender.
Hmm. Did you kill anybody
on your way home?
I'm a responsible adult.
I took a cab.
You know, I decided it's a good
thing that you're a sexologist.
Really?
Yeah, it's gonna be like
a peep show for me at work.
You can put on
your little leather Teddy,
and I can watch
through the window while you do
what you do
the way that you do it,
because you're really good
at it,
and you really should be putting
your skills to good use.
Just please wear a condom.
You get nasty mean
when you're drunk.
I'm not drunk. I'm clear.
And I'm happy for you.
I'm just--I'm confused--
how do I introduce you now?
Because there's no page on this
in Emily post.
I mean, how about this? "This is
my girlfriend Charlotte.
Do you need help
with your erection?"
You know
this is my bed, right?
That I paid for!
Oh, yeah.
Take it all, Charlotte.
Leave me nothing but shame
and mortification.
♪♪♪
The mass is almost as big
as he is.
You've done it before.
Yeah, but usually when I go in,
I'm trying to save one baby.
In this case, I feel like
I'm trying to save two,
and one's not even
in the room.
Look, if I lose the baby--
then you will have done
everything you possibly could,
which is what we wanted.
We wanted to try everything.
If this doesn't work,
it won't be good for you.
Don't put that on yourself.
Just go.
It's not your mistake
that got us here.
You know what she's gonna do?
Mnh-mnh. Hey.
Hey.
I'm glad you're here.
All rise.
Should it be taking
this long?
Addison will come and get us
just as soon as there is news.
God, I hate waiting.
I felt this way every time
we finished another implantation
and I came in
for a pregnancy test.
Just panic. Sheer panic.
Amelia, I am so sorry for what
I've put you both through.
Oh, I didn't mean to bring up
something that's--
no, no, no, please, please.
Don't--don't try and make me
feel better for what I've done.
It was hard at first,
for all of us.
But Zoe and I...
It's crazy after the way
it happened,
but... I'm closer to her
than I've ever been
to anybody before.
You did that, too.
Well--
Addison.
Zoe's fine,
but I couldn't save the baby.
I'm so sorry.
I did everything I could.
I do.
Are you comfortable,
doctor?
Are you kidding?
I appreciate
you coming back.
I know this is hard on you,
so I'm gonna get right to it.
Can you tell us what happened
on the night in question?
The defendant rang my door,
and when I answered it,
she jabbed me with a syringe.
Do you know what was in it?
No. I remained conscious,
but I couldn't move.
And then she told me what she
was going to do to me.
And what did she say
that was?
That she was going to cut
my baby out of my body.
And she did.
Will you tell her
it's gonna be okay?
She doesn't believe me.
You're gonna
get through this, Zoe.
I just feel like
I failed you.
I feel like I lost my baby.
It is not your fault.
Listen, all of this,
it just happened.
Okay? Come here.
Michael is still here.
Your baby is fine.
He's in here kicking.
And we're a family,
so it's gonna be okay.
We can do this together.
You'll see.
Zoe.
My god, are you okay?
The baby?
You come back now?
Amelia--
no, this isn't right.
Now that the baby's gone?
No, Amelia, it's okay.
He left you.
No, I called him.
I wanted him to come.
Martin.
Baby.
I'm so sorry you had to
go through this all alone.
I wasn't alone.
I don't know
what else to say.
I'm sorry.
I'm back.
I'm sorry that I didn't
call you sooner.
No.
Oh, my god.
Amelia. Amelia.
I am so sorry.
I'm just the surrogate.
No, no. You're much more
than that.
I thought I was.
Her husband's back.
That's--that's good, right?
But I-I gotta go.
No, Amelia.
They can have other children.
Amelia.
They can have other kids.
Lots of kids.
Amelia,
he is not your baby.
You cannot just leave
and keep him.
Yes, I can.
He's not yours.
He's all I have left.
The last thing I remember
was her walking out of the door
with the baby.
Nothing more?
Just blood.
I remember the blood...
Spreading out...
All around me.
Thank you, Dr. Turner.
You and Dr. Wilder were
treating the defendant,
is that right?
Yes.
And you felt it was safe for her
to stop taking her medications?
She refused to take them.
She was afraid
that they would harm the baby
that she was carrying.
Did you understand
that she had an illness
that required medication?
I understood that she could
benefit from medication.
Did she understand
that she would benefit--
objection. Speculation.
Your honor, the witness
is not just a victim.
She was the defendant's
psychiatrist.
She's an expert
in mental aberrations.
I'll allow it.
Were you aware that without
proper medication,
your patient would likely
lapse into a delusional state?
L-Likely is not quite
the right word.
All right.
Do you think it was possible
for her to become delusional?
Your honor, counsel is trying
to blame the victim
for not being clairvoyant.
I'll rephrase.
Dr. Turner,
in your expert opinion,
on the night in question,
was the defendant delusional?
Yes.
Yes, she was.
Dr. Turner.
I hate what you did to me.
So do I.
So why?
Because you were right.
It wasn't you that night.
If I had said
you were just...
Evil...
It would be like denying
everything I do.
More than anyone,
I'm supposed to understand
that you weren't you.
And I do understand.
Because I'm not me either.
I hope you get better.
I hope you get better, too.
Perfect.
You give her our baby,
she walks away,
and there's nothing we can do.
God knows what she's
gonna do to him.
She's not gonna hurt
the baby, Martin.
She stole our baby.
How can you be this calm?
Calm? I just lost a baby.
And we're gonna find her
and we're gonna get it back.
Martin, I wasn't talking
about that baby.
I was talking about the one
I was carrying.
Her baby.
Hers. Mine. I-I know it's
hard for you to understand,
but when a child grows inside
you, you feel like it's yours.
You're defending her?
I'm understanding her.
Martin--
what? What are you
gonna say now?
Because you know
the settlement's out the window.
This was never about that,
Martin, for either of us.
Martin--
what? That's our baby.
And we'll get him back.
We will.
She's a good person, Martin.
She'll look at him, and she'll
know the right thing to do.
How can you excuse her?
You rush in here
after months of being away,
and you're just happy
that I'm okay.
But Amelia was there for me
through the hardest thing
that I have ever done.
She tried to make me feel better
when her baby died.
Martin, you're my husband,
and I love you, and I am
so glad that you're back,
but she is my friend, okay?
And I know--
I know that that is gonna
mean something to her.
Just watched Violet testify.
She did great.
Calm, focused--
she just said what happened,
that hell that happened
to her.
And then she told the jury
that Katie was not
mentally responsible.
I don't think
I coulda done that.
I'm sorry.
I love you, Charlotte.
I am too much woman
for you.
I have more money.
I picked a specialty
that makes you nervous.
I bought your way
into the practice.
I'm strong and I am comfortable
with being strong
and I like that I'm strong.
And if that is
too much woman for you,
if that makes
your junk feel tiny,
I'm not gonna
make myself smaller.
I'm not gonna put myself
in a box
so that you feel
like a big man.
I am a big woman, and you either
get used to it or you get out.
I'll get used to it. I will.
I will get used to it.
You are hot.
Strong women are hot.
It's hot.
I mean it, Cooper.
I am not--mm.
♪♪♪
I've given you space
and time.
I've been raising our son
by myself.
♪ As I sit here in the cold,
and it's a story... ♪
I quit my job
to make things easier.
I did all these things
so that you would have time
to get over what happened,
so you could move past it.
Today you had a chance--
you had a chance to make
a huge step past it
and make Katie pay for what
she did to you, and you,
uh, what--what--i mean,
what, what was that?
Did you want me to lie?
She's always
going to be dangerous.
She's gonna make someone else
believe that she's fine,
and there's a chance
she could do this again.
That is an unacceptable risk.
After what she did to you,
you--you help her?
I didn't do it for her, Pete.
I did it for me.
What she did to you
was unspeakable.
And she needs to pay
for what she did.
She needs to--
she needs to pay for it.
Oh, my god. Oh, my god.
I've been so in my head,
I-I didn't realize...
What?
That it...
That it happened to you, too.
What Katie did to me
happened to you, too.
I'm not the only victim.
You're the victim, too.
Oh, my god. I'm sorry, Pete.
I'm so sorry. She...
She took something from you.
She took me from you.
I'm so sorry.
Don't be sorry.
Just...
Come back.
♪ When you leave it
in the past ♪
Come back to me.
♪ ...that I won't be waking
almost every single night ♪
Come back to me.
♪ ...with deep regret
locked in this endless fight ♪
You have to
come back to me, okay?
♪ I am falling
faster to the ground ♪
Just come back.
♪ With my arms securely bound ♪
♪ and I am waiting
for existence ♪
♪ to hold me by the hand ♪
I don't think I could be
that forgiving.
I couldn't either,
but good for Violet.
It's gotta be
a positive step.
♪ Make me understand
that I am free ♪
You think she'll get back
to normal?
I hope so.
Yeah.
But it won't be
the old normal.
Yeah, what is?
Nothing lately.
♪ Make me understand
that I am free ♪
Which raises the question...
Charlotte king... really?
What can I say?
You're hard to replace.
♪♪♪
She has some interesting
sex toys.
♪ As it tackles
with my breath ♪
♪ and I can see this is
no playground fight ♪
♪ it's a battle to the death ♪
♪ and I am choking
on the concrete ♪
Excuse me.
So, uh,
I just wanted to apologize
for, uh... saying
that I didn't like you.
That's an apology?
You sorry you don't like me
or are you sorry you said it?
No, uh, it's...
Cooper likes you,
and, yeah, I just...
I wish that...
I'm--I'm sorry.
I'm--i'm--
I'm making this worse.
You know what, Sam? I don't
need everybody to like me.
But I'm here.
You on board with that?
♪ Make me understand
that I am free ♪
Welcome to the practice...
Dr. King.
♪ Make me understand
that I am free ♪
♪ make me understand ♪