Help me.
Please, please.
Oh, God, oh, God, it hurts.
B.P.'S 70/50.
Pulse down to 45.
Help me. Help me.
Pupils are sluggish.
Ophthalmoscope?
She's out.
Respiratory arrest.
Give me E.T. Tube, 7.0.
I'll take that.
Mrs. Horne?
Kathleen, can you hear me?
All right, let's give her
500cc normal saline.
Here we go.
It's in. Let's bag her.
Hyperventilate.
Let's blow off the CO2.
All right, Doug, let
me give you a hand.
36-year-old female
fell off a ladder.
B.P., 70/50. Pulse is 45.
Possible bleeding in the brain.
G.C.S., 6. Hematomas
of the left lower quadrant.
Got lacerations of the upper-right
quadrant and her left thigh,
contusions on her back.
She fell off the ladder
and got this banged up?
What'd she do, bounce?
I see papilledema.
All right, she's in
trouble. Decorticate.
Get a head C.T.
Let's lavage first.
Her abdomen's rigid.
Terry, call the O.R.
Get a neurosurgeon
down here now.
Can I have a
peritoneal lavage kit?
Betadine in the cut, please.
I'm not getting any
sound down here.
Hey.
Hey, guys, come over here.
Come on.
My mom's going
to be okay, right?
We hope so.
Is your dad coming?
Yeah. I tried to call him.
What happened to your hand?
I hurt it when my
mom fell off the ladder.
Well, we've got to
get you cleaned up.
Come on.
Belly's full of blood. Spleen.
See who's on for Neuro.
You look awful, Carter.
I'm exhausted.
Good morning, Carter.
Morning.
You shooting for high honors
on your E.R. presentation?
I was up all night.
It's really hard
putting surgical
procedures down on paper.
Can I have Dr. Benton's
charts, please?
His patients have
already been checked.
Deb. Been here an hour.
All right, well, I'll
go get their labs.
Deb sent them.
Breakfast orders?
Gone to the kitchen.
Oh, John, boy, am I you're here.
Jerry, thank you.
I've done a census
of all six-month-olds
with fever in the past year.
I want to develop a
protocol. Can you help?
You checked
Dr. Benton's patients.
Now don't be upset.
You've been here awhile.
Everybody likes you.
I want to make a
good impression.
Carter, the girl in Two,
could you stitch her up for me?
Sure.
Um...
Let's go.
This isn't a Sunday
stroll, people. Come on.
Mrs. Horne's chart.
She's been here three
times in the last six months.
Mm-hmm. She broke her
arm falling down the stairs
but no bruises.
Orbital fracture
walking into a door.
Okay.
Hi, Mandy. I'm Dr. Ross.
Dr. Carter, would you
let me finish up here?
I'm just about to bandage it up.
Let me do this.
Yeah, okay.
Okay. Thank you.
Sure.
Hi.
Is my mom going to be okay?
Well, we don't know yet.
Hey. What's your name, buddy?
David.
Listen, David,
come over here for a second.
Okay, you guys, look.
Your mom got hurt
pretty bad today
and it could be a while
before she comes home.
How long?
Well, we don't know yet.
Want to tell me who's
been hitting your mom
for the last six months?
Mandy?
Mom can't take a whole
lot more of this. David?
Is there somebody else
staying at the house?
See, if we know,
we can get your mom some help.
We can find a safe
place for you to stay.
Things will get
better for all of you.
I promise that.
No?
All right.
Okay, well, I'll be back
when I know more about your mom.
It was Mandy.
Shut up, David.
Shut up!
Hey, hey...
'Cause you didn't
like her dress!
Shut up or I'll kill you!
You really did it
this time! It's not true!
I didn't. He's lying.
She hit her with my bat.
She hits her all the time.
I didn't! She fell off
the lad... She fell down!
When can my mom go home?
Captioning sponsored
by WARNER BROS.
Pregnant patient in Two.
Suicide attempt's coming in.
Okay, thanks.
Rachel, Rachel Greene.
Oh, really? That's great.
Could you tell her
that her dad called
and that he'll talk
to her later? Thanks.
Rachel's on a field
trip to an aquarium.
I wish I was on a field trip.
Gunshot, hunting accident.
He's waiting for discharge.
So discharge him.
Oh, we decided
I'm not incompetent?
Nobody said you
were incompetent.
But I am the only one
who has to bring
my charts to the chief.
What time is your review
board with Kayson today?
3:00. Please don't
come to offer support.
God knows what you'd say.
Does that happen?
She's just a kid.
She hit her mother
with a baseball bat?
Well, we see three or
four of them a month.
Doug, broken leg, Exam Four.
A nice diversion.
Well, I-I-I just
can't believe it.
Well, you will get used to it.
Uh, well... Send Mrs.
Neely up to the O.R.
Oh, Dr. Benton, she wants her
surgery explained to her again.
Well, I've explained it
twice. That's enough.
Well, I could try.
Yeah, I'm taking a course
on relating to
patients as people.
It's called "The Whole Patient."
Just don't let it
interfere with your work.
He didn't mean that...
did he?
I didn't throw him that hard.
I just showed him
a takedown move.
I must have done the
same move a hundred times.
This hurt, Zack?
Yeah, it hurts a little.
I bet it hurts a lot.
I broke my arm when
I was nine years old.
Haleh, two migs
of morphine, I.V.
Does this hurt?
No.
13 years of teaching Phys. Ed.,
this never happened to me.
Mr. Allman, it's a
broken leg. Relax.
Posterior tibial pulse is weak.
All right, Zack, push down
on my hand like a gas pedal.
Mm-hmm. Okay, wiggle your toes.
Femur films?
Mm-hmm, yeah. A.P. and lateral.
All right, Zack, we're going to
get you up, get you some X rays
and see what's going on.
Is it gonna hurt more?
Well, it's gonna
hurt a little bit,
but think of the fun
you're gonna have
getting everybody
to sign your cast.
Here you go.
Look, she's been throwing up.
Maybe you should induce labor.
That's a little
extreme right now.
Mrs. Chang, have you
had any cramps, bleeding?
It's just her stomach.
You could have a condition
called preeclampsia.
Your blood pressure's
a little elevated.
But we'll know a lot more
when we get your tests back.
Maybe the baby's in trouble.
I mean, why not induce?
It's only two weeks away.
We're going to take
care of your wife.
Why don't you try to stay calm?
Who's on for ortho?
Taglieri.
Who else is available?
What about Dr. Nelson?
He's still up there, isn't he?
Tell Dr. Nelson
ten-year-old, broken femur.
I need somebody
a few days a week.
Haleh: Your mom's
gotten worse, huh?
You know anybody?
A woman on Eight.
Part-time in Physical
Therapy. Jeanie Boulet.
You'll like her as much
as you like anyone.
Haleh, Can you
get a blood workup
on that pregnant woman in Two?
I don't think so. The lab's
completely shut down.
What? Just kidding.
Mark, suicide attempt.
Harris, Fran, 32.
Looks like an O.D.
She wrote a note. They found
an empty bottle of imipramine.
Vitals?
B.P. 50, Palp. Pulse 120.
I started calling at 7:00.
I should have
gotten there sooner.
Get her on the bed.
On my count.
One, two, three.
Point eight narcan.
Haleh, get a glucose.
Dialysis or hemoprofusion?
Not with tricyclics.
We got to pump her stomach.
Let's get an Ewald
tube and a charcoal.
Draw a tox screen
and a ruds.
Was she on other
antidepressants?
I don't know.
She kept saying she
wasn't that depressed.
Ma'am, maybe you should
take your baby outside.
It's not mine. It's hers.
Take him outside.
Somebody help her, please.
See the bottle of pills,
get the shrink's name.
Find out what else she was on.
Ewald tube.
Capillary refill is poor.
Three liters saline.
Lavage till clear.
B.P. Falling. 40 Palp.
Sinus tach, 140.
Seizures, Mark.
Aw, crap.
Valium.
Ten milligrams, I.V. Push.
Dilantin, one gram
at 50 migs a minute.
Tachycardic.
Give her an amp
of bicarb, I.V. push
and then put two
amps into that liter.
Looks like torsade.
Magnesium sulfate, two grams.
Pulse ox is falling
here. Come on.
I.V.'s infiltrated.
Slow down.
Happened in gym class.
Wrestling.
Okay. I won't need
you for the exam.
No problem.
And, Doug? Mm-hmm.
Listen, I'm the
attending on call.
When I'm on, you call
me, not somebody else.
It's not personal,
it's professional.
Got that clear?
Yes, John, that's clear.
Hey, Tiger, how you doing?
Ma'am, would you
like to sit down?
No, I should stay.
When she wakes up,
she'll want to see her baby.
Miss Eiger, we can't get
in touch with her therapist.
Is there anything else
she might have taken?
I should call Carl, Fran's
boyfriend. He should be here.
Was she taking any
other prescriptions?
How could she do this?
I mean, she was happy.
She'd gone back to school.
Everything was fine.
If you'd just let me...
No, I'll take care of him.
It's okay. It's okay.
Okay. Yeah.
Was she taking any other drugs?
I should call Carl.
Where... Do you have a phone?
Where's the phone?
Hey, kiddo.
Pulse ox is 60.
This isn't working.
Still P.E.A.
No pulse.
High-dose epi, seven milligrams.
Another mig of atropine.
Get another I.V. line here.
She's really cyanotic.
I'm done.
25 minutes at least.
I don't hear a thing.
She's in asystole.
You had to take tricyclics, huh?
Why the hell didn't
you take painkillers?
Abnormal doll's eyes.
Pupils fixed and dilated.
Brain stem's shot.
She's gone.
It's okay, buddy.
You'll be okay.
This big mass around the bone
may represent an osteosarcoma.
I can't believe I did this.
Well, turns out to
be a good thing.
What the hell is good?
He broke my nephew's leg.
Oh, Ted, please,
come on, don't swear.
Because it happened,
we found out about
Zack's condition sooner
than we might have.
Wait a minute. What condition?
We won't know for
sure till we get a biopsy.
A biopsy?!
What is this, cancer?
It would explain why
his leg broke so easily.
My husband died of liver cancer.
Is Zack going to die?
We really don't know.
I think it's much too
early to worry about that.
Would you like
me to talk to Zack?
No. We'll tell him.
I'll talk to him, all right?
Doctor, you have
to induce labor.
Your wife's tests are normal.
The nausea was probably
caused by something she ate.
She... she had a
drink from the herbalist.
I mean, I tried to
call her gynecologist,
but he was out of town.
Your gynecologist
is an herbalist?
No, no, no. I... She...
The New Year is coming.
It's the year of the pig,
and right now it's
the year of the dog.
And... I can't believe
I'm saying this.
People, they think sometimes
that the babies born in the
year of the pig will be lazy.
I mean, we don't believe that.
I mean, we sort of believe it.
I mean, my... my ma...
my mother believes it
and her mother
believes it, but...
So, you used herbs
to induce because
you didn't want
your baby to be born
in the year of the pig.
You want it to be born
in the year of the dog.
I know it sounds crazy, but
yes, we want you to induce...
Mr. Chang, this is an emergency
room, not an auto body shop.
We don't do procedures
just because you want them.
Dr. Greene? Yeah.
Hi. I'm Dr. Noble.
Hi. How are you?
These Mr. And Mrs. Chang?
I was just about
to discharge them.
I'm checking them in.
I'm covering for Dr. Whitbread.
They left a message,
they wanted labor induced.
Some religious thing?
Oh, thank God.
She's not due for ten days.
Hey, we induce so
people can go on vacation.
We do it at Christmas
for the tax break.
What's the big deal?
Have a very happy
year of the dog.
Gently.
Let the water do the work.
I'm not a housekeeper,
Dr. Benton.
I'm a therapist.
Yes, I know. Look, we just need
someone to take her for walks
and look after her two or
three times a week, that's all.
Stroke victims
need a lot of care.
Now, I'm sure you
love your mother,
but you should be
thinking nursing home.
Slowly, Mr. Fayid.
You're in there for an
hour no matter what.
Will you at least consider it?
Can you afford me
on a resident's salary?
I'll, uh... I'll find the money.
Well, I have nursing
classes Mondays and Fridays.
I'm working Saturdays here.
I could do a middle of the week
starting a week from Tuesday.
We'll try it for a while;
we'll see how it works.
Okay, okay. I,
uh... I appreciate it.
It's not a favor; I get paid.
All right. That's cool.
Mark, crispy critters coming in.
Guy tried to rescue
a kid from a fire.
Okay.
Come on, Tag, you promised.
I can't help it. Staff
meeting at 6:00.
We get the room at 7:30,
and I don't want to be late.
Carol. I've been dreaming
about this romantic weekend
with room service... without
my mother and your dog.
I'll try to move
the meeting, okay?
Okay.
Gurney coming in! Move over!
Kane, William. Entered a
burning building to save a kid.
Vital's normal, resp: 30.
Kid's coming right behind him.
My throat... it's burning.
Put him in Trauma One.
Right.
Potter, Nancy, 14.
Burns on her leg, chest
abrasion, hit by a falling beam.
B.P. 90/50. Pulse 90.
All right, Connie, we're
going to need blood gases,
cross-table C spine, H-and-H
type and cross with four units.
Give me O-negative
in the meantime.
All right, on my count.
I can't breathe!
Get that. Ready? Yes.
One, two, three.
There you go.
I can't breathe.
All right, let's
get that mask on.
Start a gram of Ancef.
Connie, call the
Burn Unit. Okay.
Throat's fine.
Pupils normal.
How long were you
in the fire, Mr. Kane?
A couple minutes.
A lot of smoke.
Pulse ox is only 80.
Respiratory's high at 36.
Is the little girl okay?
Come on, lie back on there.
Sounds like fluid in here.
Let's get him on a
mask, 15 liters of O2
and a chest film quick.
Right, I'll go check.
No distal pulses.
B.P.'S falling 70/50.
Open the I.V.s wide.
Looks like a bone fragment.
We've got an open
tib-fib fracture here.
All right, we're going to need
Vascular and Orthopedics.
Let's get her up to O.R. now.
Watch her arm.
All right, here we go.
Coming through!
Here we go.
O.R.'s been notified.
Hold that elevator, please!
Carter... there's
this guy outside.
Can you go and
take a look at him?
What, can't
somebody bring him in?
I don't think that's
going to work.
Yeah. Come on, John, let's go.
Hey, Jerry, I really
need a cigarette.
Do you know where
Lydia keeps her stash?
I didn't know you
smoked. I don't.
Uncle Ed.
Uh... how long has
he been... sleeping?
Since breakfast, I guess.
I don't know quite
how to tell you this,
but your Uncle Ed is dead.
My God.
I thought he was
awful quiet back there.
Jackie, Jackie, I said I
was going to be there.
Yeah, Michigan and Wacker.
All right, I won't be late.
Oh, my Lord.
That's dead.
We can take him
through to Denver.
Leave him with his son.
Please move, please move.
You can't do that...
It's against the law.
Why? He's our uncle.
Medical examiner's
got to come and get him.
His people are in Denver.
We're sure as hell
not burying him here.
Carter, throw a sheet over him.
S3 and s4 gallop.
Add nitro 50 milligrams...
William?
Willy. Everybody calls me Willy.
How's your breathing? Okay?
How's the little girl?
Her name is Nancy.
She's going to be fine.
Fire department said that you
inhaled some toxic chemicals.
Your lungs are badly damaged.
It's not the... only reason.
C.F.
You have cystic fibrosis?
Is there anyone
you want me to call?
Your wife or your family?
Dad.
Doug, get a pulmonary consult.
Mm-hmm.
Haleh, do you know
Dr. Lubin's extension?
4230.
Lungs going, huh?
Yeah. Yeah.
Billy, go to the third floor
and get us some gauze.
Six gross of gloves and no 4x4s.
Oh, thanks.
It must be hard for you.
The overdose this morning.
The girl with the kid.
I didn't have a kid.
Haleh, I really try not to
think about it too much.
Can I ask...
Did you leave a note?
No.
I couldn't figure
out what to say.
And when did your pain start?
This morning.
Mm-hmm. Is it
constant or intermittent?
Both. What?
I think she means
it comes and goes.
Yeah. Mm-hmm.
Is it sharp or dull?
Sharp.
Uh, uh... Ask her if
she's had the pain before.
Oh, oh, right. Have
you had this pain before?
The pain is in my stomach.
It hurts like hell.
I mean, what
else can I tell you?
Ask about meds.
Oh. Uh, d-d-do you
take any medications?
Yeah. Norvasc and Tenormin
for my blood pressure,
Allopurinol, Colchicine,
sometimes Indocin for the gout,
Zoloft for depression,
Antivert for vertigo...
Wait a minute.
What did you eat today?
Some granola.
Oh, a couple of poppy
seed bagels, some cheese...
a nice lamb chop.
Um, excuse us a second.
Yeah.
I'll bet you anything it was
the poppy seeds or the granola.
We'd better find Dr. Benton.
I questioned Dr. Lewis about
every conceivable symptom.
Is that the case, Dr. Lewis?
I don't think so. No,
Dr. Kayson was in a hurry.
Dr. Kayson, the
patient, Mr. Vennerbeck,
died under our care.
You say you asked
about every symptom.
Including back pain?
Dr. Lewis should
have mentioned it.
You didn't tell him about
the back pain, Dr. Lewis?
It was on the chart.
Well, you should have
called it to my attention.
Please let's try to stay civil.
Are you sure you gave
her your full attention?
No, I don't think that's
the problem here.
But you did sign the chart.
David, I already told you,
I didn't have all the
relevant information.
Aren't you supposed to
obtain the information?
Oh, come on. We
know what this is about.
We all depend on the residents
to do their job.
Dr. Kayson,
attendings are here to
help residents do their job.
Dr. Lewis,
the... back pain
was ascribed to
a previous injury.
How would you assess
that information now?
I think I'd consider
it more carefully.
A possible sign
of unstable angina.
Well, we all make
those judgments
and we learn from them.
Ladies, gentlemen,
Dr. Lewis, Dr. Kayson.
How you doing, buddy?
They going to fix my leg now?
They'll do a couple
of things first.
Can I talk to you
quickly, please?
You haven't told him.
We were gonna, but...
We discussed it, and we think...
we think he's just
too young to hear it.
We have to do a biopsy
now, do you understand?
He doesn't need to
know, so just do it, okay?
Mrs. Mika, we won't go through
with this unless he knows.
I won't do that to him.
Sweetie...
Zack...
Sweetie, I... I've got
to tell you something.
I'm going to let
the doctor tell you.
I...
Zack, you may have
a form of... of cancer.
You know what cancer is?
Yeah. My dad had
cancer, and he died.
Am I going to die, too?
We don't think so,
but you're gonna have
to go through some tests,
and that's gonna hurt a little,
and then you're gonna
have to take some medication
and that's gonna make you
feel really sick.
Am I always going to be sick?
No. I think when it's all over,
you're going to be okay.
Well, what kind of tests?
Okay, well, we're gonna
put a needle in your
leg today, a little one.
Are you going to do it?
No.
Will you come with me?
Sure.
So... so let's go
do it then, okay?
Okay, kiddo.
Let's do it.
49-year-old woman presented
with acute stomach pain.
Leukocytosis with a high B.U.N.
Recent diet includes
both seeds and nuts.
Diagnosis: likely
diverticulitis.
Possible surgical candidate.
Okay, so what made
you ask about her diet?
Actually, it was Deb's idea.
Oh, yeah? Yeah.
Well, the next time
Deb has an idea,
let her present it.
Uh... um...
How did you come up with that?
Well, I have a
photographic memory.
It's kind of embarrassing,
but I saw on a page of the
pocket manual in my head:
Stomach pains plus seeds
or nuts could be diverticulitis.
That's right.
You could have
inflammation in the colon.
If it doesn't get
better in the next
couple of hours, you
might have to have surgery.
Dr. Chen will come
back and check on you.
Great!
You holding up?
Uh-huh.
What happens now?
Well, Dr. Taglieri's
going to mark a
spot on your leg.
This won't hurt.
It's just a pen.
This is going to
feel a little cool
while the nurse cleans it.
Ready for the local?
It's going to sting a little.
It's a small needle
with some stuff in it
that's going to dull the pain.
You okay?
Mm-hmm.
Here's the needle gun.
Ah, this is the thing I
told you about... the gun.
Dr. Taglieri is going to
take a little piece of the tumor
out of your leg with it.
You're going to feel
it when it goes in.
Okay? You ready?
I'm ready.
That's all she wrote.
That wasn't so bad, was it?
Never got shot before.
You're going to do okay.
Look, this woman
does this for a living.
Are you crazy? I've spent
weeks looking at nursing homes.
Yeah, Well, she's
my mother, too,
and you don't make
these decisions without me.
Why do you keep like this?
I mean, this could
be the solution
that we've been looking for.
You're looking for.
I know the solution.
Okay. So, she goes
to a nursing home,
and you get the house
that we grew up in, right?
Oh, please, honey,
don't give me that
sentimental crap.
You wouldn't get
this house burn...
Hey, don't answer that.
I came all the way
across town to see you.
Jackie, I don't want
to see Ma end up
in some warehouse for old folks.
Look, look, Jackie.
This woman will come
three times a week.
I'll look after her
two times a week.
No, you won't, Peter.
You never have before.
And tell me something:
Just how do you plan on
paying this physical therapist first?
Look, if-if it's three
days, I can swing it.
Three days?!
God, Peter, when
are you gonna accept
that Mommy needs full-time care?
Okay. So how are you supposed
to pay for a nursing home, huh?
Her savings.
That's perfect.
You get the house,
you get to spend every penny
that she and Pop
ever saved, right?
Except what she gave
you for med school.
Jackie, don't even go there,
'cause I'm up to my
ass in debt, all right?
And in a couple of years,
you'll make more money
than Walt and I will ever see.
I tell you what, Peter.
Take the damn
house, okay? Take it.
You can even have
your old room back.
We'll clear out of
there tomorrow.
Then you can bathe
her and feed her
and keep her from
taking her clothes off
in front of the damn neighbors.
Look, Jackie, we'll work it out.
Peter!
Peter.
Hold on.
Yeah. This is Benton.
He did what? Okay, okay, okay.
Look, tell him I'm sorry
and I'm on my way.
I'll be right there, okay?
Yeah, yeah, I'm
leaving right now.
Look, Jackie, we can...
I couldn't move the meeting.
You're kidding.
No. But it'll be short.
Anyway, we can still
get out of here 8:00.
I hope so, or I'll be
feeling very... unromantic.
Well, if I'm not
here, just page me.
If you're not here,
I'm going to come up to
that meeting stark naked
and drag you out.
I'll see you at 8:00, okay?
I'll see you.
How was your review?
Fine, thank you.
I see you two are
still having a love fest.
I tried to stop them.
Doug? Yeah?
Kid's been beaten up.
Look at him. There's
blood all over the street.
They hit him and
they wouldn't stop.
They just kept hitting him,
and the cops wouldn't
even come, you know.
Hey, buddy.
You're pretty banged up.
What's your name?
Terry.
All right, Terry.
Does this hurt?
No.
I don't know why the
cops wouldn't come.
How about this?
No.
You okay, man?
Does this hurt?
Uh-uh.
Nothing looks broken.
I'm just taking
your temperature.
We should've gone
away someplace...
How old are you, Terry?
Eighteen.
Temp: 102. Resp: 24.
You got a fever, Terry.
You been sick?
No. I... I got a cough.
His lungs are clear.
He's tachycardic.
Let's get a C.B.C., Lytes,
A.B.G and a chest film.
Terry, this is Haleh.
She's going to clean you up,
give you some bandages
and get some X rays.
Okay? Can I talk to you?
Are you his girlfriend?
No. I'm just his friend.
We need to call his family.
Do you... do you
know their number?
They live, uh,
someplace in Georgia...
or someplace.
They threw him out
or he... he run away.
I don't know.
He's my best friend.
Is he going to be okay?
Where does Terry live?
We don't live no place.
We used to have this
place on the West Side.
It got torn down, though.
How old is Terry?
You heard him. He's 18.
How old is he?
Fifteen.
He's got to say he's older,
or the cops will pick him up.
Okay.
Fine.
Could you just take
care of him... sir?
Sure. Sure.
Hey, bad day?
Pediatrics is fine when
the kids are healthy.
How was the, uh...
review board thing?
They crucified Kayson.
I hate to admit it,
but I loved watching him squirm.
So you going to give
Mark a break now?
Does he deserve one?
Can you people help me?
Could you see the nurse
back there at the desk?
Yeah, he deserves...
I know, but...
Um, I've been
waiting 40 minutes.
Yeah, I know, uh,
we're very busy.
Okay.
Okay. Sir. Sir!
Come here!
What is that?
Well, what does it look like?
The kids next door were
playing cowboys and Indians.
How did you get here?
I took the bus.
Do you want to just...
Yeah, if you would...
I'll get it.
Mm-hmm.
The doctor said he
had five or six years left.
He's not going
to make it, is he?
His lungs are
filling with fluid.
We'll suction them out,
but they will fill
back up again.
Eventually, we're going to
have to put him on a respirator.
He never had kids.
Said it wouldn't be fair.
He wouldn't be around
long enough for them.
Five, six years,
that's a lot of time.
New blood gases.
Not good.
PO2 is 50, PCO2, 60.
They brought the little
girl down from the fire.
Her mother says she
wants to talk to him.
Thanks.
The versed has him under.
He may not be able to hear her.
It's okay?
Sure.
What's his name?
Willy.
His name's Willy.
Willy, my name's Nancy.
Nancy Potter.
You saved me from the fire.
Can you hear her, son?
Thank you, Willy.
Thank you for getting me.
Good afternoon,
to you, Dr. Benton.
I don't want to talk about it.
I didn't ask.
You know, for the first time,
I've missed grand rounds.
What the hell do I
tell Morgenstern?
You had something
more important to do.
Yeah, right.
You know, in pediatrics,
you guys got it made.
You all go into
private practice.
But surgeons, we
all want to be chief.
If I have another day like this,
I don't have a prayer.
There are more
important things in life
than being chief.
Yeah, right. Like what?
This morning,
I had a little girl
who beat up her mom,
and her mom is dead.
Another kid with osteosarcoma.
He's probably
going to lose his leg.
Another one with
cystic fibrosis.
It is the middle of winter,
my apartment is freezing,
and the woman that I vaguely
thought might stay with me
has said that I'm
not the kind of guy
that women marry.
So I'm going to
shoot some hoops.
Yes!
Oh! Hey, you want
to share the court?
Play you one-on-one.
I'm Doug.
Jake.
Nickel a point.
A dime. To 21.
Okay, dump that.
Let's go, right now.
My mom works at the hospital.
Diane Leeds. You know her?
Nope.
Up!
Lucky shot.
What's your mom do?
She's on the seventh floor.
I'm waiting for her
to get off work.
Oh! Very fancy.
Strains it.
Nice.
I'm going to the Bulls tonight.
Yeah? Who's your
favorite player?
B.J. Armstrong.
Yeah, mine, too. You know why?
'Cause he's short
just like I was.
You're good for a short guy.
Well, thank you.
Jacob!
Damn it!
Jacob.
Hi, Mom.
Hi, kiddo. I'm sorry I'm late.
You got a killer player there.
Yeah, he's a pretty tough guy.
Much longer, I'll be paying
his allowance for the week.
I wish you would.
With video games
alone, I could go broke.
Are you ready?
I'm Doug Ross, in
Pediatrics in the E.R.
Oh. Diane Leeds,
Risk Management.
Yeah, we spoke
on the phone once.
Dr. Ross... Doug.
Before you try any harder,
Cindy Sadwick is a
very good friend of mine.
Mm-hmm. How is Cindy?
Well, she can't say your name
without adding a few words I
wouldn't want my son to hear.
Button up, babe.
Well, tell her I said hello.
Right.
I owe you a dime.
Well, you'll win it back
from me next time, okay?
Have fun at the game.
Ah! Rescue 61,
M.I. on the way in.
53-Year-old male,
drunk out of his gourd
at Shaw's Crab House.
A drunken coronary.
Can you talk
Mark into taking it?
Uh-uh. He quit.
He's now the house
doctor at Field's.
Um, department meeting.
Benton's in surgery, and
Mintzer went home sick.
Wish I could go home sick.
Susan, we got a chest pain here!
Trauma Two. Trauma Two's open.
What do you got?
Patient complained of
mid-sternal chest pain.
Diaphoretic, vomited twice.
Sublingual nitro,
two migs morphine.
Says he's a doctor.
Sir, are you...?
Oh, my God.
Dr. Kayson.
Dr. Lewis.
In Two.
This is aspirin,
Dr. Kayson. Can you chew?
Yeah. Well, start chewing.
B.P., 150/100.
O2, 15 liters.
Dr. Kayson, I know
how you feel about T.P.A.
Do you want it?
I don't know.
They're prepping in the
cath lab for angioplasty.
The choice is yours
but make it now.
Run a 12-lead.
Where the hell is Steinman?
He's in surgery.
Cardiology will be here
as soon as they can.
Tachy, 120. Resp, 24.
Where is blood results?
What's the E.K.G. say?
"S.T. elevation in
the inferior leads."
I'm going to die.
You are not going to die.
B.P.'S crashing, bradycardic.
He's in cariogenic shock.
Okay, E.T. Tube, 7.0.
Whole respiratory down.
Open up the IV.
Bolus one milligram
atropine I.V.
It's falling, Susan.
60/35.
Start a dopamine drip.
Tube's in.
Bag him.
All right. He may
need a pacemaker.
Yeah. Let's get
him upstairs now.
Haleh, call cardiology.
Tell them he's stable.
He needs angioplasty.
And see if anyone's
gotten a hold of his wife.
Coming through!
Oh, man.
Come on, guys. Let's go.
What is this... a convention?
Is that a joke?
No.
Hey, Terry.
How you feeling?
Better.
I want to talk to you
about your condition.
You've heard of P.C.P.
Pneumocystis pneumonia.
AIDS, huh?
We need to confirm
the diagnosis,
but if it's P.C.P., then yes,
you probably have AIDS.
Angie, don't cry.
Don't cry, please.
Come on. Hey...
Listen, hey...
Would you get my...
my, uh, coat and stuff?
Please?
Come on. Come on.
You still working
the streets, Terry?
Playing it safe?
Look, they don't want
you using rubbers.
It's not what they
pay for, you know.
All right, we're going to
check you in, do an HIV test
and treat the pneumonia.
Thanks anyway, but no thanks.
I just want to get out of here.
Terry, if you have
sex with people,
you're going to
infect them, too.
I got to feed myself, right?
Some of my friends, too.
Terry, you are sick, and
you're going to get sicker.
Check yourself in.
We can stop the
pneumonia, and we'll put you
on a program for AZT.
Hey, man. I'm okay.
Terry, listen to me.
You are not going to
get healthier on the street.
Can you go home?
Is there anybody
that'll take you in?
They threw me out.
They won't be
taking me back now.
I want you to use these condoms.
I'll get you a medicine
called Bactrim.
I want you to take
that every day.
Only time I took medicine
every day was in jail.
Please try.
And use the condoms.
Terry, use the condoms.
Here's some
numbers for a shelter
and an AIDS treatment center.
Keep this.
You're going to need it, okay?
All right.
Thanks.
Your wife's on the way.
Dr. Steinman's coming
to take you to the cath lab.
Nod if that's what you want.
Do you want T.P.A.?
Hi, Jack. You look great.
We're going to blow
your arteries out.
Dr. Steinman, he wants T.P.A.
Jack, I looked at your
echo; you need angioplasty.
Jack, you're scared.
Remember we did
a couple hundred
of these last year.
And when this is over,
you'd better stop smoking
and start jogging.
Let's move him.
You can't do that. What?
He's my patient.
He doesn't want
angioplasty; he wants T.P.A.
Dr... Lewis, this
man's under sedation.
He's in no condition
to make a decision.
No.
Stop this adolescent behavior
and get the hell out of my way.
If you take him out of here,
I'll see you at a
review committee,
and they will fry
your ass so fast,
to keep your license.
Please order the T.P.A.
Get it in here now.
Wow.
That was really dull.
I guess I'll have
to try it again.
Maybe we should use that stuff
you got in New
Orleans last year.
Really?
You still have some of that
edible massage oil left?
It gave you a rash.
We could try a different flavor.
Where's my bag?
My bag? You know,
that little gladstone bag.
What?
You had it.
You're joking.
No, I'm not.
Where is it?
I brought the bags downstairs.
I stopped to get you.
Yeah?
Oh...
I'll never be able
to go to work again.
Where did you leave it?
Admissions.
Under the desk.
Mm-hmm.
Doug, you sleeping?
I wish.
How many kids am I
going to see this year?
Based on last year...
3,000, give or take.
Hmm.
Feel like I saw them all today.
Baby with croup.
God love the croup.
At least it's
something I can fix.
You okay?
Yep.
I'm coming.