This is a teaching hospital.
I'm not a therapist.
I'm here to make her
into a doctor.
Our job is to nurture,
not to cull the herd.
Said he'd been assaulted
by a masked assailant.
He did this.
I've been advocating for you
ever since you got here.
And you know what?
I'm done.
How are things at home?
Honestly,
it's a little strained.
The job is to be there
for your patient
throughout their care.
It's a hard rotation for anyone,
but it's the burden we bear.
Yeah, me too.
I don't want to be sad anymore.
So I just want to be clear.
You're saying you don't think
- there's any way that...
- Goodbye, Daniel.
Everything OK?
She just got herself transferred
to another hospital.
A little extreme,
don't you think?
Wow, I'm sorry you two
couldn't work it out.
Don't know what to tell you,
you know?
She still thinks
that Ripley attacked Pawel,
and it infuriates her
that I don't.
You miss her?
Been a little quiet
around the house
since she moved out.
Not gonna lie.
- Do I have to worry about you?
- No.
You've got to get ready
to address your troops.
I'm ready, I ...
don't know if
they're ready to hear it.
- Good luck.
- Yeah.
Hey, you up for
a celebratory beer?
Oh, yeah.
What are you celebrating?
I'm done with chemo.
I've got a good feeling
about this PET scan.
Hopefully, I can start
helping Lynne with the baby.
Well, I'm digging
this new attitude,
but a beer and chemo is not a...
not a great combo.
Maybe it's the perfect combo.
Hey -
you hear anything more
about our other situation
with, uh, Pawel?
It's been quiet.
You see?
What'd I tell you?
Cops don't care about
small time stuff.
- See you.
- Yeah.
Excuse me.
Uh, you were
a no-show last night
at Crockett's goodbye party.
He's sleeping it off on
a plane to Boston about now.
Yeah, sorry.
I, uh, got held up here.
- What's going on?
- Oh, you haven't heard?
Ms. Goodman's about to make
a very big announcement
to the entire ED.
Well, that can't be good.
Maybe we'll get a new hot tub
in the staff lounge.
Did it just get colder in here?
We're on a break.
Like a Ross and Rachel break
or a Brad and Angelina break?
I don't know,
but I'm not gonna let it
ruin my good mood.
Have either of you
seen the Brick?
- No.
- No, I haven't.
It's just so strange.
The night nurse normally
leaves it at my desk, and...
- So everyone's here?
- Yeah.
Good morning, everyone.
I know that you've all heard
that Jackson Monroe Hospital
is closing its doors next week.
Gaffney will absorb
the overflow.
Daily patient numbers
will double.
We need to rethink
how this ED operates.
So changes are on the horizon,
and I just ask for your patience
as we navigate
this thing together.
And thank you in advance.
Dr. Archer, we should talk.
Dr. Archer?
Trauma 2 needs you.
Uh, let's talk later, OK?
Uh, don't be concerned
about the ED.
I'm ready for whatever's coming.
Excuse me.
Hi.
- Can I have that?
- Yeah.
Thank you.
Oh, my God.
The commuter ship was struck
by a smaller vessel.
Water flooded the hull,
and it capsized within minutes.
Rescue operations are underway.
That's right.
A mass casualty incident
is en route for Gaffney ASAP.
70 or 80 victims,
nearly half critical.
Most of them are coming to us.
Full MCI protocol.
Yes.
What's the ETA
for the first arrival?
Two minutes out.
Trauma suites have been cleared?
Treatment rooms too.
Have you locked down
the walk-in entrance?
Done, the ambulance bay's
the only point of entry
into the ED.
Chaos control.
Trigger the all hazards
disaster plan.
Every on-call doctor,
nurse, and otherwise
hightails it in here ASAP.
- All hands on deck.
- Look at you.
That's why I keep
my RN license active
for emergencies like this.
Take intake and triage.
- It's all set up.
- Got it.
Thank you.
Thought it was gonna be
a quiet morning.
That's when
the universe gets you.
Coming in behind you!
Paramedics say she was impaled
by deck railing
in a small explosion.
Please!
Please save my baby girl.
All right, baby's 39 weeks.
Let's make mom comfortable.
- 20 of Etomidate, 80 of roc...
- Kelsey, I'm Dr. Asher.
We're gonna give you something
to help you go to sleep, OK?
Can someone find my husband?
Was he on the ship
with you, Kelsey?
Yeah.
Finn Gallicano.
What does he look like?
Etomidate and roc going in.
Thin, dark hair,
lots of tattoos.
- Black.
- We're gonna find him.
Is my baby gonna be OK?
She's in good hands.
Do you have a name for her yet?
It's Darby.
Darby.
OK.
I'll let you know
when I track down the husband.
She's under.
Intubating now.
All right, carry on.
OK, baby's in distress.
Fetal heart tones are slow.
The metal shard is
penetrating the placenta.
The baby's unharmed,
but the placenta is abrupting.
We need to deliver right now.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Chest X-ray first.
- Mike?
- You got her?
X-ray.
All right,
ET placement confirmed.
Look, see?
Free air.
Yeah, but no free fluid.
She likely perforated her bowel.
Who knows what else.
Mom could bleed to death
all over the table.
How do you repair the damage
if the baby is on the way?
The only option that we have...
Remove the debris and deliver
the baby at the same time.
Pretty risky.
What other choice do we have?
Oh, we can't take any
overflow from Jackson Monroe.
She's not overflow.
She's a patient of mine
who needs an MRI.
Well, your hospital
has its own MRI.
The hospital sold
all of its radiology machines
because of the closure,
so I was hoping that...
No, it's not gonna happen.
Look around.
We're underwater,
and more are coming.
I get that, OK?
But just because this kid
wasn't on that ship
does not mean
she isn't in danger.
Look, Maggie?
You're a capable, intelligent
woman with a big heart.
I can tell.
Well, thank you for
really seeing me, Dr. Frost.
I'm sure you can
figure this out if you try.
Does this usually work?
Does what usually work?
The charm assault and the
smile and the puppy dog eyes.
Uh, yeah, it does,
most of the time.
- OK.
- This is Zoey.
- Hello, sweetie.
- Hello.
How are...
are you?
Where are her parents?
She's been in the system since
she was four years old
when her mom abandoned her.
She's never met her dad.
I'm sorry to hear that,
but who gave you permission
to bring her here now?
Her DCFS rep.
I have the paperwork.
Zoey's been in and out
of my ED the past couple
weeks with headaches, and today,
she got roughed up
by some older kids
because of her speech issues.
My hospital wants
to discharge her
without any further assessment.
OK, I'll call upstairs
and see if we can get her in.
You're an angel.
And you're trouble.
You know, it becomes endearing
once you get to know me.
It becomes less annoying
when you get to...
I'll just quit while I'm ahead.
Yep.
Nice to meet you, Maggie.
Hey, Ellis.
How you doing?
Where's, um...
where's Mom and Dad?
- Fighting, I think.
- You know what?
Sometimes my parents would fight
when they were worried about me.
So I don't know.
I mean, a lot of stuff
happened today.
You got hurt.
I think your parents are
a little worried about you,
right?
And your leg.
- My leg hurts.
- Huh.
Let me take a quick look, OK?
OK.
Um, you know what?
I think it's time
for Dr. Johnson
to check up on you anyway, so
I'm gonna go find him, OK?
Be right back.
OK, just try to stay off the leg
as much as possible
for the next few weeks.
Dr. Ripley?
Hey, Rosado.
How's it looking out there?
Still a lot of people
missing inside that ship,
but I want to give you
a heads up.
About what?
- The Pawel Wapniarski case.
- OK.
A witness just came forward
who puts you at the scene.
Claims he saw you at the bar
where Wapniarski was beaten
moments after it happened.
Look, I appreciate the heads up,
but I got nothing to hide.
I'd get a lawyer.
An arrest is not
out of the question.
Dr. Ripley,
Code Blue, Trauma 2.
He's unresponsive.
One moment, he was fine,
the next moment, not.
Mr. Harley?
Mr. Harley, can you hear me?
Heart rate 140.
Pulse ox 92.
Respiratory rate 30.
Blood pressure 78 over 40.
Abdomen's distended.
He's in hemorrhagic shock
and bleeding into the abdomen.
Could be a splenic laceration.
Page Archer.
Surgery's slammed.
Hybrid OR is the only
available option.
OK, he needs blood.
Let's give him two by two.
Hang a liter of LR on
a pressure bag while we wait.
- Let's move.
- OK.
Ellis's leg
has a tissue infection
called necrotizing fasciitis.
The bacteria's point of entry
was the cut he sustained
during the accident,
and then it quickly
spread through the fascia.
So this is like
a flesh-eating bacteria?
What it also is
is a scary name for
an often
very treatable condition.
I... I'm sorry.
I don't understand.
Was the bacteria in the water?
Maybe, or it was on the object
that he scraped his leg against,
but that is just a guess.
And it's spreading so quickly.
Jeanine, Ellis is gonna be OK.
Good news,
we caught it fast, so,
- you know, we got options.
- Right.
I'd recommend antibiotics
and debridement.
We remove all the dead tissue,
irrigate the wound,
and then we leave it open
for a couple of days,
- clear out the infection.
- Surgery?
What about his hemophilia?
It's totally manageable
with meds.
My son almost bled out
an hour ago.
Now you want to fillet his leg?
No way!
What are the other options?
W... uh, well, we could
try stronger antibiotics.
Great.
Let's do that.
OK, but that's...
that's a risk.
His infection's too severe
for antibiotics alone.
You just said
that we caught it early.
To save his life, not his leg.
If the antibiotics fail, I mean,
amputation's gonna be
the only option.
We can't gamble his leg.
Let's do the surgery on Ellis.
Enough.
Tell them what you did, Seth.
- Jeanine, please don't.
- What?
What's the matter?
You don't want to talk
about it now?
We were below deck
when the ship capsized.
Water was rushing in
faster than we could swim.
Ellis was trapped
in a tangle of chairs
pressed against a wall,
and he was screaming to us
- for help.
- Please stop.
I turn around and Seth is gone.
So even though we almost
drowned several times over,
I pulled Ellis out alone.
- You don't understand...
- I understand perfectly, Seth.
You abandoned us.
You were gonna let our son die
to save yourself.
So, no, you don't get a vote.
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry...
Stay the hell away from us.
No surgery, period.
- Ready?
- Ready.
On three.
One, two, three.
Ah, trigger the MTP.
- OK.
- Bolus. Start pressors.
We're in trouble.
Baby's blue.
Let's go.
She's apneic.
- Where's the neonatologist?
- Yes, doctor?
OK, I'll resuscitate.
Let's go.
Starting CPR.
We've got to get
her heart rate up.
Come on.
Show me how strong you are,
baby girl.
- Come on.
- V-fib.
Ah, damn it.
We need to shock.
Paddles.
Charge to 120.
Clear.
Still in V-fib.
There you are!
All right.
Again, 200 this time.
Clear!
Ah, Mom's back.
OK.
Strange timing.
It's almost like
she heard her baby cry.
Or it's the electrical current.
Can I help, Ms. Howard?
No matter how tight
I make the tourniquet,
the bleeding won't stop.
Well, it's hard to compress
a blood vessel at the elbow,
so just slide the tourniquet
above the elbow,
and then tighten it.
There you go.
This job is a lot of things,
but boring isn't one of them.
Want to know a secret?
I miss the hell out of it.
Not the suffering, mind you,
but being able to help
in an immediate way?
That adrenaline is a drug.
Don't let anyone
tell you different.
Why'd you stop?
Being a clinical nurse, I mean.
I realized there are other
ways of being of service.
So I went back to school,
got my MBA.
Administration
was a natural fit.
So it's a trade-off.
Yeah, like most things
in life, Ms. Howard.
Dr. Archer?
Huh?
I have a second wave
of ship accident victims
coming in, but I'm out of space.
Bypass them to Jackson Monroe.
Is that really necessary?
We're getting slammed, huh?
Soon we'll hit
a tipping point where
we will be unable to maintain
a proper level of care.
So why don't we pivot?
Find empty ICU beds
and move the beds to...
- what's that room?
- The consultation room?
That is a tremendous
waste of space.
Your first day here and you...
you know everything, right?
Diverting patients
could cost red tag victims
precious time that they
can't afford to lose.
That also falls below
a proper level of care.
You're military.
Army.
Well, I guess that counts.
You?
Navy.
OK.
This is fun,
but I need a decision.
Yeah, what she said.
Isaac?
Talk to me.
Late 20s adult female.
Critical.
Heart rate 133.
BP 94 over 59.
Intubated at the scene.
Frontal scalp wound, bleeding
controlled with dressing.
We've got an 18-gauge IV
on the left AC.
Her name is Wendy.
I'm her wife.
Please just help her.
Let's go to
the consultation room.
Dr. Lenox,
the room is not prepped.
Walk and chew gum
at the same time.
Dr. Hudgins, you're with me.
Get ready to rotate.
Let's go.
Let's flip this.
Put the bed here.
You OK?
Dr. Hudgins, you OK?
Yeah, I'll be fine.
Dr. Uh, Frost, I presume?
Dr. Abrams,
pleasure to meet you.
Uh, I imagine so.
- Can we talk in private?
- Yeah.
Be right back.
So I reviewed
the MRI brain imaging,
and you're right.
Your patient has
a large 6-by-4-centimeter
glioma tumor
in her Broca's area.
Well, that explains the
sudden onset of speech issues.
Yes, that's why
I said you were right.
I can say it again if you like.
No, I'm good.
So, um, what happens now?
I get the kid on my table
ASAP so I can remove the tumor
before it does any more damage,
but there are some
significant risks.
What kind of risks?
Well, there's a chance
that you could completely
lose your ability to speak.
How... for...
For how long?
Permanently.
And if I don't...
don't do the surgery?
Well, pediatric brain tumors
are tricky to predict.
Your speech difficulties
might keep getting worse,
or they might stay
the same for a while.
But the tumor will likely
continue to grow and eventually
start to affect other functions
of the brain, like strength.
And by that time,
it'll be harder to remove,
and it might even progress
to Stage 4 brain cancer.
And by then,
I'm afraid it'll be too late.
Will you do the surgery?
I wish I could, but I...
I'm not a brain surgeon.
Not smart enough?
Wow.
That...
That was a good one.
Look, Dr. Abrams is the best
neurosurgeon in the country.
I mean, just ask him.
He'll tell you himself.
Look, Zoey,
I want you in the world.
OK, it's a better world
with you in it.
You're scared.
I get that.
But if you can embrace
that fear and move through it,
you will be shocked
how much stronger
you are on the other side.
So what do you say?
Y... you talk too much.
Well, guess what?
So will you,
very, very soon.
We got this, right?
We got this?
Yeah, come on.
We got it.
- Hey, Dale.
- Hey.
John Does are
in the back corner there.
OK.
Thanks.
Damn it.
OK, looks like
we're about done here.
Bleeding's stopped.
Spleen's in the bucket.
Let's close.
Oh, what the hell is this?
He's seizing again,
just like he did on his ship.
Whoa, ah!
Ah, damn it,
I lacerated the liver.
Heart rate increasing to 180.
Don't your paralytics
prevent seizures?
Yes, this shouldn't
be happening.
He's eating through
the paralytic.
I'll recheck my train of fours.
Get these seizures
under control.
I can't repair his liver
if he's bucking
like a damn bronco.
I've started an Ativan drip
to break the seizure,
and I'll re-bolus
so we can get out of here.
Now what?
Pressure dropping, 90 over 40.
He's bleeding
all over the place.
Where the hell's his O-Neg?
He's not gonna make it
without it.
I'll get it myself.
At a certain point,
I think if Dr. Ripley's
- not here and I am...
- What's holding up my O-Neg?
My patient's circling the drain.
We've got a situation,
Dr. Ripley.
The MCI depleted
our supply of O-Neg.
These are the last five units.
And my patient
won't survive without it.
Yeah, neither will mine.
- You must be Dr. Lenox.
- Correct.
Run down your patients
for me, please.
28-year-old female,
severe head trauma.
GCS is 6.
Intubated with
right flank stab wound.
She's in hemorrhagic shock.
Probably
a retroperitoneal bleed.
43-year-old male,
chest and abdominal trauma.
Grade 5 splenic laceration.
Possible late onset of epilepsy.
But didn't he cause
the whole accident?
No moral judgments.
We favor the patient
who has a better chance
for a positive outcome, period.
Prognosis for recovery?
If he makes it
through surgery, excellent.
He's bleeding out
in the OR as we speak?
We removed the spleen.
We're working on
a small liver lac now.
We just need blood.
My patient is only 28.
She's younger and stronger.
But her GCS was only 6, right?
Does she have a bleed?
- Was she anoxic?
- We don't know yet.
- No CT.
- Mm-hmm.
She needs the blood
and surgery first.
And what are the chances
of all that working out?
Or is your only argument
that my 43-year-old patient
- is too old?
- All right, that's enough.
The blood goes to Dr. Ripley.
Thank you.
I'm sorry, Dr. Lenox.
I would have made the same call.
Protocol demands it.
Hannah?
Hannah.
- Hey.
Baby and mom
are both doing great.
I heard.
That's wonderful.
Um...
What's going on?
I have some sad news.
I found Kelsey's husband
in the morgue.
Finn showed up
about five minutes ago.
He was at another hospital.
Are you OK?
Yeah, uh,
guess I didn't realize
how much I needed
good news today.
Me too.
Jeanine, there you are.
Oh, no, Ellis is fine.
I just wanted to
let you know that the, um...
the antibiotics are going in,
and fingers crossed.
Did my husband send you
to convince me
to let Ellis have surgery?
No, I have not discussed the...
the surgery with your husband.
But you do think
I said no to spite him.
I absolutely do not.
I don't think you'd ever do
anything to hurt your child.
I mean, come on.
You saved his life today.
Enough said.
I mean, look,
you've had an unimaginably
horrible day today.
I... I mean...
I don't know why
Seth did what he did.
That's Ellis's father, his hero.
He was our world.
I don't want to sound
for a second
like I'm trying to minimize
what he did or didn't do,
but human behavior, I mean,
it's just endlessly mysterious.
And my sense,
for what it's worth,
is that he was just as shocked
by what he did today
as you were.
I keep replaying it in my head.
I was holding Ellis's hand
with all the strength
that I have because
I knew if I let it go,
the water would suck him
right under.
And for two minutes, I felt the
terror of losing him forever.
And I will never forget
the way he looked at me.
I'm supposed to protect him,
and I was failing.
I was so tired.
But I just kept thinking,
"Do not let go of his hand.
Do not let go of his hand."
So maybe letting Ellis
have the surgery
would be letting go of his hand?
Yes.
Am I making a mistake,
Dr. Charles?
You know, that's not
really for me to say.
But I think if it were me,
I would just want to make sure
that this decision,
whatever it might be,
wasn't being driven
by my own fear
when it's my child
who might be suffering
the consequences, right?
Still in V-tach.
No pulse.
Dr. Hudgins?
Dr. Hudgins!
120.
Clear.
Oh, Dr. Hudgins,
it's worse now.
V-fib.
Dr. Hudgins.
Dr. Hudgins!
Zach!
Come back here!
- Maggie?
- Yes?
We need a doctor in here now!
I'll get someone.
200.
Clear.
You brought him back?
I'm certified in critical care.
It's been a while.
Where's Dr. Hudgins?
This is his patient.
He walked.
He abandoned his patient
and walked out on you?
I'm afraid he did.
No, no, no, no, no!
Wendy!
Oh, I am so sorry.
Are you OK?
That was a close one!
Yep.
- That was weird.
- People are weird.
How's Zoey's surgery going?
Oh, just got
an update from the OR.
Abrams should be done
within the hour.
Good.
All right, that's good.
You really care about her.
Yeah, I do.
What are you gonna do
when Jackson Monroe
- closes next week?
- I don't know.
Beg someone to let me
finish my residency?
You know what?
Maybe I'll find
a sugar mama and retire.
Yeah.
I can spend my days
drinking Pabst
and my savings getting
bleacher seats to Cubs games.
Well, as a White Sox fan,
I can't support that.
You like disappointment.
OK.
I'm learning so much about you.
Admit it.
I am more endearing
once you get to know me.
Uh-uh.
Just slightly less annoying.
- Mm, OK.
- Yeah.
Hey, that was a compliment,
whether you know it or not.
Dr. Johnson says
Ellis will be fine,
but the parents, not so much?
Mm, they got a lot of stuff
to work through.
Do you think they've got
a shot at staying together?
I don't know.
Sometimes you know, you, uh,
hit a point of no return.
How are you holding up?
Oh, you trying to get all up
in my business, Ms. Goodwin?
All up in your business.
I learned from the master.
So stop deflecting.
Breakups suck.
What are you gonna do?
I hear it helps
to talk to your shrink.
Today's tragic events
recall another sad day
in Chicago history when
the SS "Eastland" capsized
109 years ago...
You almost died
on the table today.
What?
You had a near fatal seizure,
which should not
have been possible with
the paralytics given
at the start of your surgery.
It didn't make sense
until we tested
your blood
for common seizure meds
and found Dilantin.
How long have you known
you had epilepsy?
How long?
Six years.
You should not have been
behind the wheel of that ship.
Not today, not ever.
If I told the company
about my diagnosis,
I'd have lost my job.
My family depends on me.
You had a responsibility
to disclose your condition.
And I was responsible.
I did everything
I could to manage it.
I took the medication,
changed my diet,
I exercised, I avoided alcohol,
and it worked for years...
Until today.
I thought
if anyone ever found out,
I'd just get fired,
and that'd be the end of it.
Never thought
I might hurt anyone else.
It was just one little lie.
One little lie.
Yeah.
Hey, Zoey.
You made it.
Hey, sweetie.
How are you feeling?
Hey, it's OK.
Just take a deep breath
and try again, all right?
No rush.
Did my surgery go OK?
Um...
You rocked it, Zoey,
just like we knew you would.
Dr. Hudgins?
I know you just met me,
but I'm not usually like this.
I'm so sorry.
What happened in there?
The day, it just got to me.
You're a resident.
I'm sure you've seen your
fair share of unpleasantness.
Not like today.
So much blood.
I froze up,
and I knew the patient
would be better off
if I wasn't there.
That's a normal human reaction.
But a doctor can't afford
to be normal.
We take an oath
to be more than that
so our patients
can have faith in us.
I know. I'm sorry.
You don't belong here,
and I don't think
there's any reason
for you to come back here
tomorrow.
What?
You're fired, Zach.
- Hey.
I was just coming down
to see you.
I hear congratulations
are in order.
You found me.
Sully called me that day
to tell me that he and his boys
had followed Pawel
to a bar in Lincoln Park.
He told me that they were about
to give him a proper beatdown
on my behalf,
and he was offering me
a chance to get my licks in.
I tried to talk him out of it,
but no one talks Sully
out of anything
once his mind is made up.
So I rushed over there
to try and stop it.
I was too late.
I found Pawel lying unconscious
in the alley,
just as Sully and his boys
were walking away.
He assured me that Pawel
couldn't ID any of them
because they all were
wearing face masks.
Why are you telling me this now?
'Cause you don't always
get a chance to apologize
to the people you hurt.
I shut you out, and I let
that jeopardize what we had,
and what we had was really good.
And for that, I'm sorry.
You fired Dr. Hudgins?
I made a judgment call.
You made a jud...
listen, you just got here.
You don't have the right
to make a judgment call.
You have no knowledge of
the way this place operates
or the chain of command.
He walked away from a patient.
I'm aware of that,
and I do not condone that,
but you should have
consulted with me first.
I didn't see the need.
Goodwin signed off
on Zach's termination.
Chain of command.
Are you worried I'm here
because Goodwin's
lost confidence in your
ability to lead alone?
What I'm worried about
is your effect on morale
and making snap judgments
without consulting me.
I've run this ED just fine
before you came here.
Dr. Archer, your department
nearly came apart today.
No plan for overflow,
misuses of space,
blood shortages,
and a doctor who walked away
and nearly cost a patient
their life.
I wouldn't call
any of that just fine.
We were in the middle
of a mass casualty incident.
And in a few short days,
Jackson Monroe will close
and nearly double the patients
will come through those doors.
Today could become every day.
I'm here for a reason,
and it's not to keep
the status quo.