♪
- ♪ Head under
- Oh, whoa.
God, sorry. Sorry.
- No, no, no.
I was just gonna
brush my teeth.
- Yeah, me too.
- No, it's okay.
You can go ahead.
No, really, go.
- Okay, just wait here.
- ♪ I try to breath
but it comes slow ♪
- It's all yours.
- Are you sure 'cause...
- Yeah, yeah, no, I insist.
- ♪ So I make do with
what I know ♪
Toothpaste.
- ♪ I lament
in the pouring rain ♪
♪ I'd rather
wash away my pain ♪
♪ Can't spare the time
to entertain ♪
♪ Afraid of loss,
afraid of change ♪
♪ So I keep lying,
lying to myself ♪
♪
♪ Tell myself
I don't need help ♪
- Excuse me.
I'm looking for the owner.
- ♪ Lie myself
right into hell ♪
♪ Oh, I keep lying,
lying to myself ♪
♪ The moon is laughing
at me now ♪
- Hello.
Um...Oh.
- Are you the guy
with the Jeep?
- No, yeah, sorry.
I'm looking
for Horace Reynolds.
- And you are?
- I'm Floyd.
♪
- ♪ My brother told me
- Okay, this is where
he sent the last check,
but it's old.
I bought this place from
your pops, like, ten years ago.
- Thank you.
No, this is great.
Thanks.
- Hey, look, I heard
he got really sick.
Don't know
if he ever recovered.
I'm sorry.
♪
- ♪ I'm afraid
I'm too late for this ♪
♪ So I keep lying, lying
- You like it?
- Oh, my...
Martin Eugene McIntyre,
I love it.
- Great,
I was walking down 8th Avenue,
I saw it in a window,
and it reminded me of the one
you had on the night we met.
- Oh, the one that I spilled
beer all over, you mean?
- Uh, tequila.
- Right.
God, I was so neurotic.
What are you still doing here?
- I see all the work
you're putting in.
All the little things.
The coffee you make me,
your work with Dr. Rieger.
- Mm.
- You're trying to fix it.
Us.
- Yeah.
- I think we're getting back
to where we started.
♪
- Thank you.
- Yeah.
♪
- I am but hours away
from catching that
magical red-eye to Heathrow.
- Magical is not quite
the word I would use,
but I'll take it.
- Had a few hours,
thought I'd call
and help out
with the wedding planning.
- Oh, you do know
what to say to a lady.
- You know, our romance
has just been
so fly by the seat
of our pants.
I thought the our wedding
should be the opposite,
you know?
Thought out, considerate.
- I completely agree.
How do you feel about castles?
- Castles.
I love castles.
Is this a random question?
- No.
My parents got married
in a registrar's office
in Leicestershire.
No dress, no ring.
It was like they
bumped into each other
just queuing for driver's
permits and thought,
"Well, we're here.
We might as well."
- Yeah, so what
are you thinking?
- I'm thinking the Hereford
Court Estate and Gardens.
It is this beautiful
15th century castle
nestled in 500 acres
of Herefordshire countryside.
Mina and I are
going to go see it today.
- Sold,
sounds so over the top,
it might just match
how much I love you.
- I love you too.
- Can't wait to grow old
and gray with you.
- I can't wait
to grow old with you.
Gray?
Mm-mm, not so much.
- That's a lot of gray.
- Max?
Babe?
- Hey, sorry.
I'm just doing math.
I'm gonna call you right back.
Hey, what's happening?
- The elder care facility
on Roosevelt Island shut down,
and we're absorbing
all their residents.
- All?
Can we handle
that many intakes?
- Every other city
and medical director said no.
- And New Amsterdam said yes?
- We don't have
a medical director.
- Keys, phone.
Oh, no, Mina.
♪
Mm-mm.
Don't do it.
Stop that.
Don't, Helen.
Just put the phone away.
♪
No, put it...
okay, well, you're just gonna
disappoint yourself,
then you're gonna
ruin it and...
Mom, hi.
What are you doing today?
♪
- We should go on diversion.
- No.
- We're out of beds.
- I've got a plan.
- Just found three more
wandering the halls.
- I said I've got a plan, okay?
This is an ED.
They don't all need to be here.
- I'm going to Hawaii.
- We treat and we transfer.
- So how many
did they dump on us?
- Us?
Aren't you supposed to be
on a plane right now?
Unless you want to be
the new medical director.
- I'm just a concerned citizen
who's offering to help.
- Okay, well, in that case,
welcome to "The Best Exotic
Marigold Hotel" in my ED.
- Yo, you paged?
- Yes, yes, I did.
Okay, so you see these five
elderly patients over here?
They are all candidates
for surgical procedures,
and last time I checked,
you were still the chair
of surgery.
So get to cutting, bub.
- Well, now, hang on.
- Put me in, coach.
I'm ready to play.
- Nice sweater.
- Thank you, yeah.
- I don't care.
I don't care.
So I need you to take
these people up to your floor.
They're all depressed.
- And you know that how?
- They live in a nursing home.
- I'm going to Hawaii.
- Just find them a new home.
Can't you just be
the interim medical director?
- I already told Karen no,
but the search committee's
gonna find you someone amazing.
It just won't be me.
- Well, as long
as we're all pitching in.
Mr. Wallace.
- Hmm.
- Mr. Wallace,
meet Dr. Goodwin.
- How can I help?
- How the hell should I know?
You're the doctor.
You tell me.
- The patients in these files
were all denied surgery
at other hospitals
solely because of their age.
Guess what?
That's ageism.
Plain and simple.
Now, that might fly at other
hospitals, but not mine.
These patients
want these surgeries,
they need these surgeries,
and we're
gonna make it happen.
Now, I will be performing
Mr. Lewis' osteotomy.
- Wait, all these surgeries
are happening today?
- After being placed
on hold for months and,
in some cases,
years... just imagine
that this is your father
or your grandmother.
Hell, I have to fight tooth
and nail to get my mother
the care she needs,
and I know the system.
These patients
have waited long enough.
Any questions or concerns?
- You are the boss.
- I just wedged Mr. Jackson
into bay 27.
- I thought Lottie Carlson
was 27.
- She was surprisingly
fine with it.
Okay, so come on.
What are we at?
What are the numbers?
- We've placed 17 patients.
- Well, that's pretty good.
- We have 46 to go.
God, I take that back.
- Excuse me.
- I asked
for hot tea with lemon.
- Yes, we're gonna get
right on that.
If you could just
get back to your...
- Does this feel hot to you?
- Uh...I would call it tepid.
- Yes.
- Mrs. Lew, please.
- I'm just an old lady
with a sore throat.
I'm begging for help.
- All right, okay.
I'm gonna take a look.
Come on.
Okay.
Open your mouth.
♪
- It's strep throat, right?
Oh, God.
Lottie and Patricia
got it last week,
and Reuben's got it now.
Rhonda, Sheila,
it's really going around.
♪
- Mrs. Lew has gonorrhea.
- Didn't see that coming.
- Okay, shut the doors and
divert all level one traumas.
Well, your wish came true.
We have a gonorrhea outbreak.
- To be clear,
that wasn't my wish.
- And there is that.
After a month or so,
Mr. Lewis will be back
with his bridge club.
No pain, no pills.
- I'm sure
he'll appreciate that.
I would at 87.
- Listen, it's why we do
what we do, right?
And to think, some surgeon said
that he's too old.
- Sorry, Dr. Reynolds.
- Yes.
- If we're done, OR 4 needs
three units of O-pos.
- All right, no problem.
They can have it.
We're good.
Suction.
- Dr. Reynolds.
- Yeah, over here.
- OR 3 needs
a spare set of hands.
- Aren't there
any available scrub nurses?
- There were, but there seems
to be some sort of problem.
- Any available surgeon
to OR 2.
Any available surgeon to OR 2.
- Excuse me
while I check on it.
♪
- Watch it.
- Sorry.
- Any available surgeon
to OR 2, 3, and 6.
Repeat, we need a surgeon
in OR 2, 3, and 6.
Any available surgeon, stat.
♪
- As you can see,
our attention to detail
at Hereford Court
is unparalleled.
Of course,
you and your wedding party
would have full use
of the grounds.
A lovely chamber quartet,
five-course tasting menu,
livery service for arrivals.
- What's a livery service?
- For those arriving
on horseback.
- Oh, dear God.
Mum.
Mum, this is important to me,
which is why
I invited you, but...
- What?
So I can't ask questions?
- We've left the castle
exquisitely unchanged.
Some things really do
stand the test of time.
- You ask me, people
getting married in castles
are over-compensating
for something.
- Fiona, tell me.
Does the estate have a dungeon?
- Yes, it does,
but unfortunately
it's off-limits to guests.
- Oh, that is unfortunate.
♪
- Yo, fill me in.
- I resected a pancreatic tumor
with an extension
into the liver.
- And what's the problem?
- I can't close the liver
because I can't get
the bleeding under control.
And every stitch
is pulling through
because the tissue
is too friable,
which is probably the reason
Ms. James' surgery was denied
in the first place.
- We'll see about that.
All right, I'm tagging in.
Suture.
- Okay, Vic,
you want to tell me
what medications
you're taking lately?
- Hand me my bag.
Thank you.
- No problem.
- Now, let me see here.
Dr. Lockhard prescribes
amlodipine besylate
for my hypertension.
Dr. Lee gives me levothyroxine
for my hypothyroidism.
Dr. Wheeler gives me
omeprazole for my reflux.
And Dr. Brennan gives me
some simvastatin
for my high cholesterol.
- You got a whole pharmacy
in there.
- Listen, here's
what I'm thinking.
- I'm also taking prednisone
on Mondays,
azathioprine
every other Tuesday,
diclofenac sodium as needed,
and tramadol.
Am I pronouncing that right?
- Yeah.
- Oh, I'm so sorry.
- Oh, that's okay.
- That's okay.
- Oh.
- Okay, it's all right.
And you have
rheumatoid arthritis.
- Yeah, it's miserable.
Nothing makes my hands
stop swelling.
Oh, and there's adalimumab
on Fridays.
Let me see what else.
- Hi, I'll be right back.
Yes, hi.
- Nurse Gene from
South Point Nursing Center.
- Oh, am I glad to see you.
Oh, my God.
We are bursting
at the seams here.
- We got the transport outside.
I'll get them all resettled
and get the paperwork
sent back, okay?
- Please, thank you
to your team from me, okay?
- You just did.
- Did I tell you I'm flying
to Hawaii tomorrow
for a long vacation?
- Oh, now, are you going to
the Big Island, Mrs. Boulton?
- Yes, I am.
- Yes, she is.
- It's supposed to be
beautiful this time of year.
- Oh, good
with this population, huh?
- Oh, now,
hey, these are my guys.
- Got Big Wally here.
Big Walt.
- Hey, now.
- Yeah.
Hold on a second.
- You got him?
You okay?
You all right?
Need a sec?
- Just my asthma.
- Your asthma.
No, no, no.
Asthma doesn't look like this.
You know, Gene, I think
you're having a panic attack.
Come, now, come in my office.
It's okay.
Take a second.
Come on.
- All right,
well, the good news is,
is that gonorrhea can
be treated with one shot.
So we just have to talk to them
and figure out
who needs it, okay?
♪
- Ms. Forsheim,
we need to talk to you
about your sexual activity.
- Where do you get off
asking a question like that?
- And are you sexually active?
- I wouldn't call it active.
I mostly just lay there,
and I'm happy
with a little kissing
and touching.
If it happens, it happens.
- I haven't had sex
in 30 years,
unless you count oral.
- How about sexual partners?
- I had only been
with one other man
before my Jerry passed,
but life goes on, yeah?
- And why should I tell you
what goes on
when the lights go out?
- And do you use protection?
- From who?
- Condom?
Where would I get a condom?
- Oh, I don't do condoms.
At my age,
I got enough problems
getting this boat in the water.
- Well, maybe you'd be
more comfortable
if we all just played
shuffleboard till we died.
- We're just trying to help.
- By embarrassing people?
- No, that's not...
- I haven't had sex in years.
You should be ashamed
of yourselves.
♪
This interview is over.
- Dr. Wilder,
BP 78 over 42, dropping.
- Drop to 3-0 vicryl.
- No, no, no.
I already tried that.
- Well, what if I do
a purse string suture?
- Another unit
of blood coming in.
- Yeah, what I'm thinking
is I take this tissue here,
and I pull it together
with that suture.
And then you can come in
and cauterize the edges.
Yeah?
- Let's do it.
- Dr. Reynolds.
- Yes.
- So sorry.
You're needed in OR 3.
I'm kind of busy right now.
- I know, but it's
Dr. Nottingham's patient,
Mrs. Bennett.
She's in trouble.
- What kind of trouble?
- I think you better see
for yourself.
- Go, I've got it.
- Oh, God.
I mean, all these patients.
I mean, they all needed
these surgeries, right?
- Dr. Reynolds.
♪
- I'll let you and your mother
take in the bridal suite,
and I'll pop right back
with contracts and champagne.
- She's gonna pop back
with champagne, Mum.
You really ought to cheer up.
- You'll need it,
what this is gonna cost you.
- Do you know what,
I am curious,
if you were just gonna be
miserable the whole time,
then why did you want to come?
- I didn't want to.
You asked me.
- Because I thought,
mistakenly,
that for once, you just
might want to see me happy.
- Happy?
Where do you think the money
that built this place
came from?
The backs of your ancestors,
that's where.
Sugar plantations.
Colonial slavery.
When that woman tells the story
of the lord and lady
who built this place...
I'm sorry, but I don't
hear timeless love.
I hear something
very different,
and of all people,
why couldn't you?
- I thought that...
- You thought you deserved
a fairy tale in a castle
with that man and his daughter.
If it's a fairy tale you want,
it's a fairy tale you'll get.
♪
- Okay, Vic, I think
I have got some great news.
I think I got a way to cut
that suitcase of pills in half.
- Really?
- Yeah.
Thing is, you've been seen
by a whole host of doctors,
each one treating you
for a different ailment,
and nobody is communicating
with each other.
But now, unfortunately for you,
you're stuck with me,
and I think I've got a way
to streamline that regiment.
That means no more
bags of pills,
no more dozens of doctors.
- And will my hands
finally stop swelling up?
- Well, no,
that will still unfortunately
be a side effect.
- We... have you got
one of those smartphones?
- Sure.
- Look up Carnegie Hall
December 12, 1973.
- Okay.
♪
- This is you?
- It was.
I haven't played
for over a decade,
ever since
the arthritis got bad.
- Vic, you're amazing.
You ever been in love?
I'm about to get married.
Oh.
Playing was the love
of my life.
I still dream
about it every night.
My fingertips
touching the ivory,
teasing out the melody.
And every doctor I go to,
they just see me
as some old guy
with symptoms
that need to be treated.
And I always ask them,
can they help
my hands stop swelling?
Every time,
and nobody ever listens.
Not even you, Dr. Goodwin.
♪
- I got to get back out there.
I got my residents.
- No, no, no, no,
they're with a nurse,
and, my friend,
they're not the ones
dealing with
a pressing medical issue.
- Oh, come on.
Let's not get melodramatic.
- Talking to the wrong guy,
I'm afraid.
All right, sit.
What happens if you have one
of these panic attacks
when you're physically
supporting one of them, huh?
Or while you're driving?
- So what, this is
some kind of a stress thing?
- I don't know.
Is it?
- So now I'm
in a therapy session.
- No, Gene,
I'm not your therapist.
Genuinely, I'm just a concerned
medical professional
chatting with another one.
That's it, I promise.
- Okay, you're good.
You got me.
My wife and I
have been fighting.
- Okay, what about?
- Chores, kids, money,
you name it.
We run the whole jukebox.
- She says I'm not showing up
like I should.
- All right,
well, do you think you are?
All right, never mind.
What do you do to feel good?
You know, how do you find
relief from these feelings?
- Well, that one's easy.
My job.
- Tell me.
- I mean, I love it.
A lot of nurses
won't work elder care.
Too depressing, underpaid,
but I went to geriatrics
straight out of nursing school.
Some of the folks I work with,
their families don't visit.
They're totally alone,
but they got me.
I get to help them smile.
I keep them fed,
bathed, and clean.
I... yeah, yeah, the hours suck,
but every day I see
how much it means to them.
And whether they know it
or not,
it means even more to me.
- That's nice.
No, that's good.
I just... I think I know
what you need to do
to get rid
of these panic attacks.
- What's that?
- You need to quit your job.
♪
- That was mortifying.
In Pakistan, we don't
ask elders such things.
- Right,
and that's the problem.
I mean, no one's
talking about it,
no one's asking about it,
and everyone's got VD.
It's like I'm
back in high school.
- What high school
did you go to?
- I need back up!
I need back up!
- Okay, what do we got?
- She's crashing.
Unresponsive,
respiratory rate 40.
- All right,
she's gasping for air.
Lungs clear?
- Yes.
- Allergic reaction?
- No and no pneumonia.
- All right.
All right, there's an abscess,
and it's blocking off
her airway.
- We need
to get her into surgery.
- No time.
Suction.
♪
What?
- It's gonorrhea.
- She said she hadn't
had sex in years.
- Well, she lied.
- What do we got?
- Carotid endarterectomy.
Can you sew in
the distal anastomosis?
- Okay, clamp this, needle.
How much time?
- Two and half minutes
to finish
or risking permanent
brain damage.
- You're just now telling me?
Suction.
Come on, come on.
- CTA shows stenosis
in the Circle of Willis.
- That explains why
there's no retrograde filling.
- You see why the small window.
- I do.
Why didn't you push back?
- Excuse me?
- If this surgery
was a mistake,
why didn't you tell me?
- You're chair.
You're the boss.
♪
- Time.
- 1 minute, 45 left.
- Come on.
Almost there.
Okay, there.
Got blood flow.
What now?
- Dr. Flores' patient
is crashing.
- You got this?
- Do I have a choice?
♪
- All right, Vic,
now I've really got great news.
- Where have I heard
that before?
- That's fair, but I found you
a steroid injection.
It's gonna increase mobility
in your fingers.
- So the swelling will stop?
- Yes, but at a cost.
The steroid's gonna interact
with other medications
that you're on,
creating more side effects,
which may not be
entirely pleasant.
- But will I be able
to play again?
- Yes.
♪
- Oh.
- We need to talk about your
sexual activity, Ms. Forsheim.
- There's nothing
to talk about.
Just give me the medicine.
- Right, so it doesn't bother
you that you nearly died
because you refused to admit
that you were having sex.
This is how venereal diseases
kill people.
- Please.
Look, it's all very well and
good for young people like you
to talk about your sex lives
to anyone who'll listen,
but where I come from,
women who had sex
out of wedlock were called
all sorts of nasty things.
And now we get laughed at
even at the care home.
- They knew you were having sex
at the care home?
- Of course they knew.
They think it's a hoot.
♪
I don't need to be
anybody's punchline.
Not at my age.
- Sandy, look,
no one is asking you
to go public
with your sex life.
But if you are having sex,
then you do need to face up
to the medical realities.
- You mean well, I can tell,
but I'd rather just
not be intimate again
than talk about it
with strangers.
♪
- I can't quit my job.
- No, you can.
You don't want to.
- Were you listening?
- Yeah.
- My job is my calling.
I work long hours
because people need me.
- No, people need a nurse.
- They need a nurse
who gives a crap.
Doctors like you think
every nurse is the same.
You have no idea.
- All right, answer me this.
How many residents
do you see on a shift?
Just ballpark it.
Give me a number.
20.
- What was that number
five years ago?
- Eight.
Look, man, everyone
is dealing with this.
We're in the middle
of a national nursing shortage.
- No, we're not.
Incorrect.
There are more trained nurses
in this country right now
than ever before.
Institutions aren't hiring them
because they know
that short-staffing nurses is
a great way to make more money.
That's it.
I've been trying
to hire for months.
HCC is blocking me
left, right, and center
because they know,
you screw over a doctor,
they leave.
Screw over a patient, they die.
You screw over nurses,
they're gonna stay on the job
because for them,
it's not a job,
it's a calling.
This profession that you love
does not love you back.
- That doesn't change the fact
that right now
there are five patients
downstairs waiting for my help.
I've gotta go.
- You're doing it again.
You're denying
what you know to be true
because you think
someone needs your help.
What about you?
When does somebody help you?
When does Gene get help?
♪
Gene, Gene, wait, hey, hey.
You're not
wearing scrubs today.
Why is that?
Today was my day off.
♪
- Yeah.
- Come on, let's go home.
- Helen, listen.
And I mean this.
I'm sorry if I got in the way.
When you were a girl,
your cousins would
play princess.
The big fairy tale wedding,
you know?
Imagining castles and princes.
- I remember.
- Mm.
Remember what you were doing?
You'd be off in the corner
dissecting your poor dolls.
- They needed those surgeries.
- Well, I knew
you felt left out.
I know you wanted those things.
At least you wanted
to want those things.
If you want
to have your wedding here,
then have your wedding here.
♪
Okay?
Because you deserve everything.
♪
- I don't want
to have my wedding here.
♪
I don't know if I want
a wedding at all.
♪
- Coming through.
- Increase the joules.
Going again.
Clear.
- What happened?
- Still pulses v-tach.
I got nothing.
I got nothing, Dr. Bloom.
Time of death, 1:52.
I was just with him.
He was fine.
- Max.
- I changed his meds.
- He had a brain aneurysm.
No change in meds
could've done this.
It was just his time.
♪
Hold, hold.
- We got to hurry.
- Almost done
with the first suture.
- Okay, resuming compressions.
- Okay, suture's holding.
Going again.
One, two, hold.
- I'm sorry
I put you through this.
- Don't apologize to me,
apologize to Ms. Keller
if she makes it through this.
- Dr. Reynolds.
- Not now.
- But OR...
- You heard me.
Whose ever patient is crashing,
I can't help them.
- It's yours.
- You close to bypass?
Tell me you got it.
Come on, come on.
- Handle your business.
I've got this, go.
♪
- Watch out.
Heads up.
♪
- Bleeding's under control.
Plate is in place.
- If you're ready to close,
Dr. Reynolds,
we'd be happy to assist.
- What about your patients?
- They're stable.
- Okay.
"I recently had
a hip replacement.
Can I still have safe sex?"
The answer is, yes, you can.
Some positions
are gonna be better
and feel better than others,
but that's gonna be different
for everyone, so...
Tough crowd.
Okay.
"Is there any reason
to still use condoms?"
Look, growing up,
I always used condoms
because public messaging
drilled it into me
that if I didn't,
I was gonna get pregnant.
Now, if today has
taught us nothing else,
it has taught us that safe sex
does not mean
just not getting pregnant.
And it's definitely not
just for kids.
Okay, any questions that are
not about how weird
that just sounded?
♪
Come on, guys.
I would've thought
with the wealth of...
- Excuse me.
- Oh, yeah.
- If we run out of lube,
is olive oil safe to use?
- Medically speaking
and in moderation, yes.
But if you like your sheets,
I don't recommend it.
Yeah.
- How do you ask your partner
to put on a condom
without killing the mood?
- Don't ask.
Do it for him.
And it does not have
to be with your hands.
♪
- What do you say if...
if you like foreplay best?
- I would say get in line
behind Dr. Shinwari.
Sorry.
♪
- When I got the new residents
through the door,
my supervisor said I'd have
to pull doubles all weekend
to set them up.
But...
I don't have the energy.
I'm trying, but...
- I know you are.
- I'm just out of gas.
I haven't seen my kids
in weeks, man.
They're asleep
by the time I get home,
and I'm out the door
before they're up.
I just...
someone's got to do this work.
- You know that somebody will.
There will always be work,
and when you're spent,
it's on to the next,
and on to the next,
and on to the next.
- What am I supposed to do?
- It will never stop
unless you make it stop.
- This is what I love.
- I know.
♪
- It's what I...
- I know.
I'm so sorry.
♪
- How are the others?
- Just came to.
- Stable.
- Ms. James is looking forward
to her weekly Zumba class.
- Good.
Listen, I need to apologize
to all of you.
Today I made the wrong call,
and I forced you
to go along with it.
- Oh, come on.
We'd follow you into fire.
You know that.
- Mm.
- But I don't want you
to follow me into the fire.
I don't want
to be the kind of boss
where folks are afraid
to speak their mind.
- You sure about that?
- Hey, if you see risks
that I don't, tell me.
Disagree with me.
It helps me to know
when I'm walking
down the wrong path.
In fact, it helps me
to know when I'm right.
Yeah.
- Mm.
- Today you were right.
- No, listen,
you don't have to.
- None of us, I mean,
literally none of us
wanted to do these surgeries
because the outcomes
were not in our favor.
But you know whose favor
they were in?
Them, our patients.
You knew that.
You fought for that.
That is why you are the boss.
♪
- Well, look
at this gorgeous man.
I didn't hear you come home.
The sweater looks great.
- Yeah, I'm not gonna
wear this anymore.
- Okay, what's going on?
- You were right.
I have been trying
to fix everything.
I've been feverishly trying
to make up
for all of my shortcomings
in this marriage.
And I realized today,
wearing this...
sweater,
that I had been doing that
since the night that we met,
been wounding myself
so that you can save me,
Martin.
Because that
is how you love me.
Iggy.
- No, no, no.
I am not the problem.
You are.
♪
- Excuse me, are you the super?
Only when nothing needs fixing.
- Hey, maybe...
maybe you can help me?
I'm looking for someone
who lived here years ago.
Horace Reynolds.
- I don't give out
information on tenants.
Building policy.
- Well, this is
a family matter.
- Nobody by that name has
lived here since I been around.
Good luck.
- Thank you.
♪
- Hey, Courtney.
I found Dad.
♪
- No, never in my life
have I been asked so many
questions about flavored lube.
- I just wish I'm having
that much sex when I'm 80.
- I just hope I'm having
that much sex when I'm 40.
- Thank you for calling me out,
by the way.
- Yeah, sorry.
I did get
a little carried away,
but it is true though.
- Not always.
♪
- Leyla, this is a bad idea.
- I know.
- It is.
- You're right.
♪
- So...
- Hey, how was the castle?
- Max, I don't know
how to tell you this.
- Tell me what?
- I don't want to get married
in a castle.
♪
I don't know
if I want any of it.
♪
- Kind of thinking
the same thing.
♪
- You are?
- I don't think
I'm getting on that plane.
♪
And I know this is unexpected,
and unplanned,
and everything we said
we weren't gonna do,
but I've been waiting
my whole life for you.
♪
And if this is it,
if this is our time, then...
then I don't want
to wait another minute
'cause in a minute,
it could be gone.
♪
I'm not coming back to London.
'Cause you're coming home.
- I am?
- Let's get married tomorrow
in New York.
- Max.
- Wait, wait, wait.
Just think about it.
Okay, what do you need
for a wedding?
You need two people in love.
You need a couple people,
a couple friends to witness it,
and a super cute flower girl
who just happens
to be my daughter.
Our daughter.
Max.
Is that a yes?
Yes.
- Can you say that
again please?
Yes.
Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes.
♪