Did you catch her?
Oh, yes. I caught her.
But once she starts
writing, she can't stop.
Heaven forbid.
I should have jammed that
pen into her carotid artery.
Mm. I think they double
the fine once you draw blood.
You need a building
with guest parking.
Take my spot.
I don't want your spot.
Damn!
What?
No milk.
Want some of mine?
A grown man, you put
an empty milk carton
back into the refrigerator.
It's not empty.
Now it's empty.
Not that it chills anything
cooler than room
temperature anyway.
It's just a parking ticket.
It's not just the ticket.
It's that had to go
chasing down there
half-dressed with my hair wet.
I said I'd go. But
you didn't, did you?
You didn't give me a chance.
You weren't fast enough!
I'll pay the ticket. Okay?
Calm down.
I paid the other ones.
What?
Let's just say it
wasn't your first ticket.
You stole parking
tickets off my windshield?
Just two. And paid
without telling me?
Well, I was trying
to avoid... this.
Well, that's it then. I'm
not staying here anymore.
Here we go.
Every faucet leaks.
Your toilet actually rocks.
I kinda like that.
There are creatures
scurrying in the walls.
Do you know what scurries
about in walls, Mark?
Bunnies?
Do you wanna take the
El train, or shall we drive?
Hey, is this the AA meeting?
How'd you guess?
I'm Brant. What's your
name? Hi, I'm John.
Ah, thanks, John. Welcome.
To believe a power
greater than ourselves
could restore us to sanity.
Step Three: Made a
decision to turn our will...
It's a lot of coffee.
This is backup.
First time? Here? Yeah.
It's a good group.
A searching and fearless
moral inventory of ourselves.
Step Five: Admitted
to God, to ourselves,
and to another human being
the exact nature of our wrongs.
Step Six: Were entirely
ready to have God
remove all of these
defects of character.
Step Seven: Humbly asked
him to remove our shortcomings.
Step Eight: Made a list of all
persons whom we have harmed
and became willing to
make amends to them all.
Step Nine: Made direct amends
to such people wherever possible
except when to do so
would harm them or others.
Doc, can you take this
guy? He is driving me crazy.
Same here. Oh, no.
Shunt's clotted.
He missed his
dialysis appointment.
Mr. Fletcher, only
one day late, huh?
You? No, not you. You know him?
Yeah, he's one of our favorites.
Hey, Cleo? Can you, uh,
take Mr. Fletcher, please?
I see you called 911 again.
They're faster
than the El train.
My arm stopped buzzing.
No thrill, no bruit.
Talk English.
Mark, ready?
In a second.
Raise your right foot.
I can't.
I don't want to
keep him waiting.
I'll be right there.
Okay.
Have you started
teaching rounds?
No. The residents
are waiting in ICU.
All right, I'll be there.
And you need to schedule
the Surgical Service meeting.
Tomorrow. You have a mastectomy.
Well, whenever.
Dr. Benton.
Hey, Carter. What
are you doing here?
I have a meeting.
Oh, right. Hi, Shirley.
Hi, Dr. Carter.
I need you to sign off
on last month's O.R.
expenditure report.
I've never done that.
You do now. I take care of it.
You just sign it.
Suit yourself. I need it by 4.
It's good to see you, Carter.
Important Attending stuff?
Oh, yeah, well. Congratulations.
Thanks. Ah, man, you look good.
Well, couldn't look much worse
than the last time you saw me.
He's gotten big.
Yeah.
Hi, Reece.
Hey.
Well, hey, you're in a hurry.
Yeah. Um, I'll see
you later, all right?
I don't know. Maybe. We'll see.
Ah, good luck, Carter.
When does he wanna start?
As soon as possible.
I don't think
that's a good idea.
62-year-old female,
slurred speech,
also weak grip
in her right hand.
Any history of stroke?
Yes. A lacunar infarct.
She got much worse this morning.
He's eager to get back to work.
So we just throw
him in the deep end?
No. Of course not.
We'll start him on half-shifts,
limited responsibilities.
In the same place
where he started using.
Mark, he's doing the
program every day.
Good. Make him take
time. He can afford it.
Okay. We'll
monitor his progress,
and if he gets into
trouble, we'll just cut back.
If he gets into
trouble, it's too late.
Please, somebody!
What is it? I'm
having contractions!
Are you pregnant? Only 22 weeks.
Come here. Try to relax, okay?
Here, you're gonna sit down.
Sit here. Wait one second, okay?
Dr. Chen, I need you
over here. No, now.
How did you get here?
Taxi. I was shopping downtown.
What is it? She's
having contractions.
How far along are you?
Twenty-two weeks.
Oh, that's too early.
You're probably
having what are called
Braxton Hicks contractions.
They're coming
every three minutes.
Get a gurney,
clear a trauma room,
start an IV and call OB. Okay.
What's your name? Regina.
Okay, Regina, don't push.
Whatever you do,
don't push. Okay?
How much?
Four, almost 5.
No, that can't be right.
I was 4 centimeters
two hours ago.
You're doing fine.
Can Dr. Coburn take a look?
She was called in
to do a C-section.
How long will that take?
We have plenty of time.
Why don't we roll
you back on your side
and get you more comfortable.
Abby, they need
someone downstairs.
Where?
ER. They have a preterm labor.
Get a resident.
Simons and Perry are delivering.
Lift your leg. Where's Dana?
She's on break. Not
back for another five.
You're not leaving, are you?
It sounded urgent.
Do you know where you are?
Let the doctor
check you out first.
What did she say?
She wants to go home.
Pulse ox is 92.
She's in A-fib.
It probably triggered
the new stroke.
Do you provide 24-hour care?
Yes.
Does she have any family?
No. Not that she's
in contact with.
Connie, call Psych.
Psych?
After this stoke, she
might not be competent
to make her own
medical decisions.
Preterm labor? Next door.
EKG, Chem-7, UA, culture
urine, blood and sputum.
Your husband's on his way, okay?
Okay. How far along?
Twenty-two weeks.
Let's hope it's a couple more.
Stop it. Please, stop it!
Where's the resident?
You got me instead.
Membranes are intact,
but she's fully effaced
and dilated to 6 centimeters.
Can you stop it?
What's...? What's
her name? Regina.
Regina, did you
have any ultrasounds
during your pregnancy?
About a month ago.
My doctor said
everything was okay.
Who's your doctor?
He's in Indianapolis.
Why is this happening?
Sometimes women go into
preterm labor for no apparent reason.
I shouldn't have come. I
should have stayed home.
This is not your
fault. This happens.
Giving you medicine
to stop contractions.
Your membranes haven't
ruptured yet, which is a good sign.
We're giving you something to
help your baby's lungs mature.
Oh, no! I feel pressure.
Strong contraction.
She's leaking amniotic fluid.
Make them stop. It's too early.
Two grams of amp.
Get a baby warmer in here.
No! It's too early!
Random urine tests.
Yes.
And I get to pay
for them too, I see.
Is that a problem?
No.
In addition to the
state meetings
we'll require 90
NA or AA meetings
during the first 90 days.
That's not a problem.
I'm going anyway.
Good. Good.
And the three of us
will meet once a week
just to, you know, check in.
Make sure you're
handling the stress.
Okay.
I came prepared.
The naltrexone
binds to your opiate...
I know what it does.
It protects you. It blocks
the euphoric effects.
It protects all of us.
You need to, uh, begin today
if you wanna begin
work next week.
You want me to
take it in front of you?
Yeah, we'll periodically
monitor your regimen.
How much?
Fifty milligrams a day.
Sorry. That was, um...
It's okay.
It's gonna be
difficult at first.
So we'll work it out.
All right. So we'll put you on
the schedule for next week.
Tuesday. Start out very light.
No trauma.
Whatever you say.
Kerry, I gotta go. Yeah.
See you next week,
Carter. Welcome back.
Thank you.
Thank you both.
Sure thing.
Baby's cephalic. Normal anatomy.
Progressed to 8.
Oh, God, please stop it.
Father's here.
Regina, wh...? What happened?
I was at the mall.
It started hurting.
I... I didn't know what to do.
Is she in labor? Yes.
My water broke.
Her OB confirms previous
ultrasounds put her at 21 weeks.
That's way too soon, right?
She's got rales.
Pulmonary edema.
No more terbutaline.
What...? What's wrong?
The medication we're giving you
is causing your
lungs to fill with fluid.
I don't care. Stop
the contractions.
I can't have this baby.
Okay, I'll try 50
mgs of indomethacin.
If the baby's born
now, can it survive?
Joseph, it's coming!
The baby's crowning.
Regina, you're gonna
deliver this baby.
No! No!
Yes. There's nothing
else we can do.
What have we got?
Preemie. Under 22 weeks.
Okay. Regina, go ahead and push.
No! No!
You okay there, Dr. Chen? Mm-hm.
The head's out. Whoa.
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
It's a boy. Is he breathing?
Yes, he's breathing.
Can someone...? Can
someone please help me?
You okay?
Dilute it in 1000 cc's,
100 drops per minute.
I don't hear
anything. Is he alive?
Yes.
Let's get a weight.
He's so little.
BP, 100/60.
Okay. Let's give
the mom 40 of Lasix.
Take her temp.
Please save him.
Please save my baby.
You're doing charts?
Yeah, I needed to catch up.
Um... Look, I-I'm
really sorry about, um...
With the baby.
It's all right.
Our reactions can
surprise us sometimes.
But you need to go back in
there and manage your patient.
Um... I can't.
Jing-Mei, you should know
you're being considered
for chief resident next year.
People need to be able to
look to you for leadership.
I'm pregnant.
I... I didn't know what to do,
and then eight weeks
became 12, and 12 became 20.
So you're... You're
20 weeks pregnant?
Twenty-two.
You know, that baby
was the size of mine.
Oh, sweetie...
Why did you wait
so long to tell me?
My parents are gonna kill me.
You should go home. No.
Go home. I'll cover
the rest of your shift.
We'll work out your
schedule tomorrow.
Okay.
Good.
Oh. Not fair. Not
in the workplace.
I found a soft spot.
I'm going to exploit it.
I'll exploit you. Mm-hm.
You know I will. Bring it on.
Time and place.
Clotted-off fistula
needs a new shunt.
Renal failure?
Missed his dialysis.
Mr. Fletcher? Who else?
Give him to somebody else.
I got stuck with him.
Last time, the man
yelled in my stethoscope.
And he grabbed
my ass. Suck it up.
Uh-uh. Come on. Be a man.
That's not right.
Oh, you're crying?
You guys got a baby?
Twenty-two-week preemie.
Still breathing?
For now. Oh, man.
What took you so long?
I need to take a dump.
It's good to see you
too, Mr. Fletcher.
Is he hypothermic? Yeah.
Okay. Order another lamp.
It's on its way down.
What's his pulse?
Down to 90.
This is some heated saline
to keep him warm
while you hold him.
Did your husband leave?
He went to call a priest.
We wanna baptize our baby.
Well, there's a priest
on call with the hospital,
unless you had
someone specific in mind.
No, we're just in
town for a few days.
My doctor said I could travel
during my second trimester.
Well, Regina, this probably
would have happened
whether you were
traveling or not.
We tried for, um,
almost two years to get
pregnant and finally gave up.
And then suddenly, I was.
Look at him. He's hanging on.
I counted 10 little
fingers and 10 little toes.
He looks perfect.
He's just a little small.
Even if your baby
was a few weeks older
and somehow
managed to survive...
I know that that's what you say
because that's what you've seen,
but maybe he's
meant to be a miracle.
Sometimes you have
to help a miracle along.
And sometimes
you have to let go.
What took so long?
They had eight of us
in a holding pattern.
Are we still in Trauma 1?
Yeah, sure.
How bad is it?
I'm not sure I should
discuss this with you.
Why?
I can't share
medical information
with anyone but a family member.
Glenda and I are family.
I thought you were her nurse.
No, I'm, uh...
We're partners.
Oh. Right.
We should sit down.
Hey.
You're safe. I've had my coffee.
Good. How about a date tonight?
Sure. As long as
it's at my place.
I was thinking
the going-out kind.
We're going out Friday.
Yeah, I moved up a reservation.
What reservation?
It's a surprise.
Look, Mark, I'm fine.
I just had an
episode this morning.
I know. I know. I'm used to 'em.
Six o'clock. Trust me.
You'll like the place.
By the way, your patient has
an abscess around L4 and L5.
Who? Patterson.
I was in Radiology
when they flagged his film.
Suddenly bored? What?
Poaching my patients?
There can be some improvement
in the first 24
hours after a stroke.
But in Glenda's case, I'm afraid
there's too much brain damage.
So she'll never recover.
Maybe slightly.
Dr. Kovac?
Her sats are dropping to 86.
Glenda? Yes.
What does that mean?
She's not getting enough oxygen.
Eight ET tube, 10 cc syringe.
BP's 110/90. Pulse is 110.
Put her on a 100%
non-rebreather.
This your patient?
Large CVA with
dense hemiparesis.
Chest x-ray shows an
aspiration pneumonia.
Ma'am, we may have to
put a tube down your throat
to help you breathe.
Do you know where you are?
Psych note says
she's not competent.
I think she's just confused.
Does she have an
advance directive?
What do you mean?
Like a "Do Not
Resuscitate" order.
I don't think she'd wanna
be put on a ventilator.
Suction. I'll put
in an oral airway.
Are you a family member?
No, she's her...
They're together.
Do you have power of attorney?
No, I guess I should,
but we didn't do that.
Sats are climbing.
Okay, let's keep her
on 50 liters by mask.
She's okay? For now.
But if the pneumonia progresses
we'll have to intubate her
unless a family
member directs us not to.
Or a spouse?
One recognized by law.
Can you do it by phone?
Yes.
Yes, if you can verify
an out-of-town relative.
She has a brother in Houston.
I've never seen one so small.
You can practically
hold it in one hand.
I delivered a 700-gram
baby in med school.
Had a brain-bleed.
I don't even wanna look.
Randi, can you page
the chaplain on call?
I did. The baby's
father already asked.
He's gonna be a few hours.
Well, we don't have a few hours.
He needs to get here.
Well, he's helping talk down
a jumper from a bridge. I...
Okay. Then start
calling parishes
till you can find someone
who can get over here.
You want me to
cold-call priests?
Yes. Now, please.
Okay.
No, I just need the
coags. Dr. Benton?
I don't care what the computer
says, I'm trying to pre-op him.
Is this about Mr. Fletcher?
Tell you what, when they're
ready, page me, all right?
Thank you.
Maureen Conway,
Financial Services.
We can't admit Mr. Fletcher.
Why not? He's got Medicare.
Which he sold to a bankrupt HMO.
Come on, that's not his fault.
True. But in nine months,
Mr. Fletcher has run up
over $200,000 in avoidable
unrecouped charges.
He needs a new dialysis shunt.
Dr. Romano left strict orders
not to admit these patients.
Now, you can stabilize in
the ER, and then transfer.
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Wait a minute.
Do you have an M.D.
behind your name? No.
Yet you're gonna try to tell
me how to treat my patients?
I've got a pheochromocytoma,
53-year-old male.
How do you suggest I treat him?
Do whatever you think
is medically necessary.
But we won't admit Mr. Fletcher.
Now, if you have any concerns,
take them up with Dr. Romano.
We took Regina
to get cleaned up.
Believe it or not,
a shower can help.
She did everything right.
She read that damn
Expecting book every day.
Well, it's important that
she knows it's not her fault.
What happened? Did he die?
No, uh, you wait here.
Did they find something
that might help him?
Someone from
Neonatology has to examine
every premature baby
born in the hospital.
They might do something?
Wait here, please.
Note how the thinness
of the fetal tissue
makes thermal
regulation impossible.
The eyes remain closed...
What are you doing?
We heard you had
a micro-preemie.
It's not show-and-tell.
No, it's a teaching hospital.
As you can see, the heart,
limbs and palate are fully formed.
With a transparent skin,
we might even be able
to see the heart beating.
Okay, p... Uh, put him down.
Excuse me?
Put him down.
He is not a science experiment.
No, he isn't. But I need
to examine for anomalies.
You should have called.
Well, you examined him.
Now go. When I'm finished.
The father is standing outside
thinking that you
are saving his baby.
How long would you
like to torture him?
Are there any questions?
No? Good.
Transfer him to the fifth floor.
No.
You can't keep him down here.
I'm not sending those
parents upstairs with the moms.
Fine. The NICU then.
No, he's staying here,
with his mother and father,
so they can have some privacy.
In the ER? Yes.
Is there anything you can do?
Um, no. I'm sorry.
He's too young.
Can you get Mr. Morgan a
chair so he can sit next to his son?
Sure.
I know this is difficult.
Don't be afraid to touch him.
He's not suffering, is he?
No.
We gotta clear the room.
Multiple MVAs coming up.
Find someplace else.
This is a Trauma Room.
I don't care. This
room's off-limits.
Titrate the phentolamine
to M.A.P. 120.
Don't worry, Mr. Robertson,
you are in good hands.
Dr. Romano. Hello, Peter.
I heard you were
hoarding a pheo down here.
An Attending for a
week and already
you're stealing the
fascinomas, huh?
Uh, you can have him.
Ha. I wasn't asking
your permission.
We have a problem
with a dialysis patient.
Why do you say "we"?
Financial Services
won't let me admit him.
Don't let those geeks
push you around, Peter.
Show a little backbone
before you come crying to me.
They're blocking
him on your orders.
Oh. That's different.
Let's take a look.
I've cleared him for surgery. I
can have him out in 24 hours.
Mm-hm.
Twenty-eight admissions
for renal failure?
He frequently misses dialysis.
Yeah, apparently.
Well, street him.
I am done carrying
these parasites.
That's an EMTALA violation.
No. He's had an exam,
and he's not emergent.
How do you know? You
haven't looked at him.
Okay, Peter. Let's take a look.
Where is he? Curtain Two.
Too late, Lizzie, I
already grabbed the pheo.
What? Nothing.
Listen, have you seen Mark?
He has a spinal
abscess patient for me.
He said something
about Radiology.
Hi, Mr. Fletcher.
I'm Dr. Romano.
How are you feeling today?
Like crap.
I'm sorry to hear
that. Can I take a look?
You're the seventh
person to take a look.
What am I, a freak show? Mm.
Why did you miss your dialysis?
I was busy.
Uh-huh. Doing what?
None of your business.
Mm. More important
things to do, I imagine, huh?
I don't like you.
I didn't like you the time
you sliced my foot open,
and I don't like you now.
Oh, I'm hurt, Mr. Fletcher.
Uh-huh.
What about my pain pill?
I need my damn pain pill!
The nurse is gonna
bring it, Mr. Fletcher.
She's too slow. I
need a new nurse.
Put him on a bus to Milwaukee.
He's fluid-overloaded.
This guy knows exactly
what's gonna happen
if he misses his dialysis,
and he still blows it off.
He's not gonna stop
abusing the system
until we draw the line.
What's this? This
is for his bus ticket.
Pfft. You serious?
Absolutely.
New state, new Medicaid,
and a whole new set
of doctors to piss off.
He lives in Chicago.
Cry me a river.
Oh, man...
Please call back immediately.
Thank you. Machine.
Do you have a
pager number, or...?
No.
A next-door neighbor?
Another relative?
No.
Well, her breathing
has stabilized for now.
How long have you been together?
Twenty-seven years.
Kerry?
Could you excuse
us for a moment?
Sure.
What are you doing?
She talked to her
brother twice in 10 years.
Yes, and she didn't grant
her partner power of attorney.
I'm trying to find a legal
way to fulfill her wishes.
Twenty-seven years. That
should count for something.
The woman has a
reasonable chance of survival.
But what kind of life?
Intubation is an
appropriate step
unless she has an
advanced directive.
The only person who can
change that is the next of kin.
She is the next of kin.
They lived their lives together.
We should treat
them like a couple.
I agree. The law doesn't.
If her sats drop below 80
before her brother
calls back, tube her.
No.
What?
If you want to
manage it this way,
then you should manage it.
Okay. Fine.
Give me the chart.
Thank you. I just...
I need a picture.
I understand.
Should we use the
name? You don't want to?
No, I think we should.
There's only one boy's
name that we could agree on.
What's that?
Julian.
It's a nice name.
Yeah.
How much longer?
I don't know.
It could be a few minutes.
It could be a few hours.
Let's take him outside.
What?
We'll take him to
a lake or a park.
If he's gonna die, I don't
want him to die in here.
We have to wait for the priest.
Is he coming?
I'll check again.
Abby.
Excuse me. I'll be right back.
I paged you three times.
We had a 22-week birth
here. The baby's alive.
You had a patient
upstairs who needed you.
Did she deliver?
Yes, she delivered.
Shoulder dystocia.
Is the baby okay?
Well, apart from a broken
clavicle, he'll be fine.
She was really scared,
and she was asking for you.
Look, if you wanna take
shifts as an OB nurse,
I need you to work
as an OB nurse.
You cannot let these women
grow dependent on you,
and then just walk out on
them when you got an excuse.
I was not looking for an excuse,
I was taking care of
this woman and her baby.
There are other people
down here who can do that.
Your job is upstairs.
Janet, I'm sorry.
It was my call.
I asked Abby to stay.
These parents are
completely distraught.
There's nothing we can do,
but they need support,
and Abby's been with
them since the birth.
Just don't ignore
my page. I'm sorry.
Thank you.
No. You're doing the hard part.
Is he still breathing?
Agonally.
Let me know when
you need to pronounce.
Okay.
Last time I got heated
blankets and an extra pillow.
Phew.
What's open, Shirley?
Depends on what you have.
Revision of an AV
graft, left forearm.
Patient named Fletcher?
How did you know?
Dr. Romano warned me
you'd try to bring him up.
Yeah, well, it's my call.
Just, uh, give me a room.
I'm sorry, Dr. Benton. I can't.
I'll be in and out in
less than an hour.
He actually said he'd fire me.
Okay. Okay, well, please hurry.
Thank you.
That was the priest.
He finally talked that
woman down from a ledge.
He's gonna get over
here and baptize this baby.
How long has it been?
Almost five hours. Wow.
He's really hanging on.
Maybe the mother's right.
Maybe he is a miracle.
In 10, 15 years, we
might be able to help.
You know, they wanted to try.
We could intubate
him, just in case.
Abby... I know.
It's his time on Earth,
and all you can do is
make it a good time.
I think he stopped breathing.
Here we go.
That's not a respirator?
No. It provides positive
pressure to her lungs
so she doesn't have to
work so hard to breathe.
Her father died of lung cancer.
I remember Glenda
and her brother
fighting outside the ICU.
Danny couldn't let go,
and Glenda couldn't watch
her father suffer like that.
You know, all those tubes.
After her first stroke,
Glenda made me promise
to never let her die like that.
We'll do everything we
can to reach her brother.
He doesn't know her like I do.
I love her.
I don't wanna lose her,
but I know what she wants.
His breathing just
slowed down for a second,
and then it just... It stopped.
Please, if you
could do anything.
Is there a heartbeat?
No.
You wanna call it?
Oh, God.
Abby?
Yeah.
Is that it?
The time of death is...
Wait! His chest moved.
Is he...? Is he still alive?
Got a heartbeat.
Yes. Ye... But your sister
has an aspiration pneumonia.
If we put her on a ventilator,
she may never come off it.
Possibly. Possibly, but she
suffered a massive stroke
from which she
probably will not recover.
Mr. Walton, I cannot
give you percentages.
Extremely unlikely.
We understand
your sister's wishes
are not to be kept
alive by artificial means.
Judy. Would you
like to talk to her?
Yes, if we don't
intubate her, she will die,
but the chances of a mean...
The chances of a
meaningful recovery are ex...
I understand.
Yes. Goodbye.
Hey, you. Malatucci.
Come here. Malucci.
Whatever. Look, wave you
seen the OIG officer down here?
Who?
Deputy inspector general.
Regulates our
Medicare compliance.
I heard she was snooping around.
Short, battle-ax, humorless?
That's her. Curtain Two.
Thank you.
Dr. Benton told you
you needed surgery?
He brought me upstairs.
Why didn't he operate?
Nurse wouldn't let him in.
He tried to tell me they
didn't have a room ready,
but I could tell
she kicked him out.
Okay, Mr. Fletcher,
we're ready for you. Sandy.
Hello, Robert.
What an unexpected, uh, visit.
Actually, I'm investigating a
possible EMTALA violation.
Really, what patient?
Mr. Fletcher.
Some sort of spot audit?
No, we got a call that you
were trying to bounce him.
From whom? Anonymous.
Well, fortunately anonymous
does not always equal reliable.
I was just coming to take
Mr. Fletcher up to surgery.
The O.R.'s ready, Peter.
Is that true, Dr. Benton?
I'm sure Dr. Romano's
found a room.
This is a consent
form, Mr. Fletcher.
I'll explain it to
you on the way up.
Yeah, I know the drill.
Robert, tell me you
don't have policy
to redirect all non-paying
Medicare HMO patients.
How could we? We're
a county hospital.
Oh, good. I'm glad to hear that.
Always a pleasure, Sandy.
I'm sure.
As long as I'm here,
I think you should
know I will be auditing
all of your patient transfers
from the last month.
Audit away. No skeletons here.
I hope so.
Dr. Romano, I felt I had to...
Not a word, Peter.
Not a single word.
You're not gonna
leave a scar, are you?
The hack that first put
this in left a big scar.
Shut up.
I'd have had exposure
and direct visualization
without beaming a
gigavolt of radiation
into the poor man's spine.
A gigavolt?
You know what I mean.
And I could have
completely evacuated
all the infected tissue.
These guys are
going in half-blind.
Fine. Whatever.
Next spinal abscess
is all yours, I promise.
Where is this place, anyway?
You'll see.
These are houses, Mark.
Uh-huh.
Oh.
Oh, Mark!
It's beautiful!
See, I have some taste.
Can you afford it?
I've been living cheap.
Besides, I'm gonna
have a roommate.
That's awfully
presumptuous of you.
I could take out an ad.
You will not! I love it!
Check out the refrigerator.
It's nice and cold.
Look at this deck!
I knew you'd love that.
When can we move in?
When can you pack?
It has an icemaker.
These floors are gorgeous!
Check it out. What?
The icemaker.
It's lovely.
You have... You have to open it.
It has a special ice feature.
What? Does the ice come
in different-shaped cubes
or something?
Oh, my God. Oh, Mark...
I'm a little nervous. So, uh...
Uh, let me... Let me say it.
Elizabeth, I love you.
I was hoping you'd give
me the joy and honor
of being your husband.
Oh.
Is that a yes?
Yes.
All alone, I
Didn't like the feeling
Sat and cried...
Do you believe in God,
the Father Almighty,
creator of heaven and Earth?
I do.
Do you believe in Jesus
Christ, his only son,
who was born of the Virgin Mary
suffered and died,
but rose and now sits
at the Father's right hand?
I do.
Do you believe
in the Holy Spirit,
the Lord, the giver of life?
...Came into this world
All alone, I will
Someday die...
Regina and Joseph,
is it your will that Julian
should be baptized
in the faith of the church
which we have professed?
Yes.
I'm sorry.
I will see you in the
light Of a thousand suns
I baptize you in the
name of the Father
and the Son and
the Holy Spirit. Amen.
I will know you when I
come As we all will come
Through the doors
We all engraved...
Hi. Could I get a coffee with
cream, no sugar, to go, please?
Sure.
Hey.
Hi. You back already?
No, not for another week.
What, are you just hanging out?
I have a diversion meeting at 9.
You look much better.
Thank you.
Hey, I like your hair.
Some nice scrubs.
You picking up
some extra shifts?
No. I was suspended.
Oh?
Didn't kill anybody,
did you? No.
I wanted to.
My ex-husband was
supposed to pay my tuition.
He didn't pay it, so...
Ouch.
I'm on the bench for a while,
but it certainly didn't
seem like that today.
Oh, thank you.
Hey, I got that. It's okay.
Hey, it's a cup of coffee.
Sit down.
It's the least I can do after
acting like a complete jerk.
When?
Three months ago.
You know, you might
have saved my life.
If you hadn't stopped
me when you did,
I could be dead now.
I'm working on my steps here.
You're up to nine already?
Well, more or less.
I forgive you.
Do you mind?
Sorry.
I really have to quit again.
Thank you.
Keep it.
Long day?
Yeah.
Twenty-two-week-old
preemie survived nine hours.
I just finished the death kit.
Wow. Yeah.
I don't know why I do this.
Sometimes I think I should
just go be an accountant,
or something.
That's an option.
If I could balance a checkbook.
What about you?
A lot of waiting.
A lot of meetings.
Yeah, you get
kinda meeting-ed out.
Aren't you gonna ask?
What?
What I was doing
there this morning?
You only go for one reason.
I figured I'd keep
going and eventually
you'd stand up and share.
It's not that interesting.
I'm a drunk.
How long have you been sober?
Almost five years.
So you could sponsor somebody.
Yeah, I guess.
Have you? No.
'Cause I'm, uh, supposed
to find a sponsor.
Don't look at me. No?
No, I'm barely holding my
own life together right now.
Trust me.
'Cause it would be great to
have somebody at the hospital.
And since you did sorta start
me on my road to recovery...
And men and women aren't
supposed to sponsor each other.
It's... Don't worry about it.
Thanks.
Come on.
You're not gonna make
me ask a stranger, are you?
I mean, the only person I met at
the meeting was the coffee guy.
Okay. Okay.
I will work the steps with you,
until you find a
permanent sponsor.
Fair enough.
I'll start by setting
a good example.
Besides, I don't
think cigarettes
are gonna do it for me tonight.
No? No.
I'm getting a hot fudge sundae.
Mm.
Would you like one?
Mm-mm. I got enough vices.
No. I think part of
the rules should be
that you have to
splurge with me.
Is that how it works?
All alone, I will
Someday die
Solid stone is just
Sand and water, baby
Sand and water
And a million years gone by