Why are you sad?
I'm not sad.
Is there another reason to get
drunk at 10:00 in the morning?
Shut up.
It's fun to drink with
someone who is fun.
Lea is fun. You're not fun.
Shut up.
No.
If I have something
to say, I will say it.
Well, if I have someone to
shut up, then I'll shut them up.
If I have something to...
Okay, I do not
like to be touched.
Just shut up.
I am a surgeon...
You've had sex with each other?
Yes.
And you're planning
on doing so again?
- Yes.
- Good news.
Because neither of you
are in a subservient
position to the other...
Well, sometimes.
You work together and
you're sleeping together.
You don't see any
way that can go wrong?
Nothing for your
employer to worry about?
I'm going to interview
each of you separately
to ensure that the
relationship is consensual.
Zack Cordell, 31,
loss of consciousness,
laceration with a closed head
injury, possible brain contusion.
GCS score?
Nine. Dr. Murphy thinks it
might be an epidural hematoma.
Dr. Murphy?
Yeah, he's with...
Where'd he go?
Shaun?
Come in. Tell us what
you saw, what you did.
I can't.
I'm not a doctor here.
You're still a doctor, Shaun.
We need to know what happened.
I found him like that.
I want a stat head CT. Get
me a CBC and a tox screen.
It might be an
epidural hematoma.
We heard.
- Let's get a bolt ICP monitor ready.
- I'm on it.
Dr. Lim, how was your meeting?
I confirmed the lack of
inducement or pressure.
I assume you did likewise?
We are approved.
For what?
At last
My love has come along
My lonely days are over
And life...
I farted, I peed, I pooped.
Everything's working as
well as I can possibly hope.
We just need to know there are
no post-surgical complications.
You're not wearing
a wedding ring.
I'm not married.
Well, gays can get married.
They have children. You
need to have children.
I'll tell you what's
more interesting
than a non-married
woman not wearing a ring.
Dr. Park here wears a wedding
ring even though he's not married.
I'm divorced, but
we're trying to reconcile.
Well, good for you. Kids?
A son. BP looks good.
How often do you see
them? Dinners, I hope.
I mean, dinners
are really important.
They live in Phoenix.
Oh, no. No, no, no, no, no.
JP drain site looks good
with no bilious output.
Do you have any other symptoms?
I've got a bit of a stomach ache
because of those
nasty veggie slushies
Dr. Mitzger has me on.
Does this look inflamed?
I don't think she's ready to go.
What? Why not?
We need to order an
abdominal ultrasound.
Make sure you don't have a
deep post-surgical abscess.
Hopefully, just one
more day with us, Ida.
I am concerned about how
you dealt with Dr. Murphy.
Have you known
anyone else with ASD?
Not well. Have you?
When you give people
responsibility they can't handle,
the results can be devastating.
Well, every time Dr. Murphy's
been given responsibility,
he's risen to the...
He's never been
given responsibility.
He's been given things to do,
but always with
someone right behind him.
I'm the first one to
really challenge him.
And he failed.
Are you okay?
Yes.
When something bad
happens, we have to remember
we're not defined
by any one thing.
You're not just a doctor, Shaun.
You're a good
friend, a good person.
There are so many
things you can do.
What do you want?
I want to be a surgeon.
What else?
What else do you want?
I want what everybody wants.
I want...
I want my life to matter.
I wanna have fun. I...
I wanna fall in love.
I think I'd be a good father.
I think you will be, too.
But I don't know
how to fall in love.
- Good morning, Claire.
- Good morning.
Here are some chocolates.
They're not really chocolates.
Here is a stapler which
represents flowers.
Thank you. These
flowers are beautiful.
You have nice hair.
Thank you, Shaun.
I like your shirt.
It's old.
I was wondering
if you would like
to...
Say the words.
There could be other people
there. That would be distracting,
there could be noises
that would be distracting.
She could misunderstand
my question.
- You can't let that...
- She could say no.
Shaun, come here.
She will.
You don't know.
Someone will.
Shaun, you're
gonna fall in love,
and you're gonna
have your heart broken.
And you're gonna
fall in love again.
lose your job again.
- No.
- Yeah.
This is life, you know that.
You've been hurt,
and you've survived.
You've gotten stronger, better.
Not better.
It's not better.
Zack's tests are ready.
Large iced, extra shot?
Oh, no, no extra shot for me.
Today, I'm already kind of up.
Having a good day?
Uh... Yeah, a real doozy.
As of today, I'm
officially cancer-free.
- That's fantastic.
- Thank you.
I'm so happy for you.
You just got
yourself a free coffee.
Thank you. I got
you something, too.
A Model J.
Just like the one that
we never got to see
at that car show
we never made it to.
Wow.
Put up the hood,
check out the engine.
Oh, okay.
You're right, we're
too old to just have fun.
I wanna commit.
"Commit"?
I meant commit
to a relationship,
not to, like, pledging our
never-ending love before God.
In sickness and in health,
that's what you wanted.
I have just been through
the seven levels of hell.
I am ready to
embrace life, to be bold.
This is definitely bold.
It's also... It's also stupid.
I made it a part of
our wedding vows.
Marty and I pledged
we would never be apart for
more than five days at a time.
And we never were, until
he died two years ago.
I made my daughter
put it in her vows.
Junie lives in Napa.
Three children,
two boys and a girl.
You're still young.
You should give your
son a brother and sister.
Everything looks great.
I think we can send you home.
Good. Junie's driving in
with her youngest. Oh...
I can't feel my fingers.
Other than the
contusions, no hematoma.
I wish you were back in path.
I don't wish I was back in path.
CBC is normal, tox
screen is basically clear.
No drugs, trace
amounts of alcohol.
Maybe he tripped
and hit his head.
No. His gait was erratic,
and so was his behavior,
both highly suggestive
of intoxication.
I thought you found
him unconscious.
What happened?
Did he do something to
you? Say something to you?
Shaun, you never lie. Why
would you lie about this?
If Zack wasn't intoxicated,
then he has a neurological issue.
You need to run an
EEG and a CT angiogram.
I have to go.
It could be Guillain-Barré,
maybe peripheral neuropathy.
I think we should perform an
EMG and a nerve conduction study.
- And what do you wanna do?
- Send her home.
I think she's making it up.
Her symptoms are very mild,
very typical post-op reactions,
except the one that
suddenly appeared
as soon as we told
her she could go home.
She's just lonely,
looking for attention.
She can be lonely and sick.
According to the
MRI, she's just lonely.
It's no fun releasing a patient,
only to find them in the
morgue 24 hours later.
Re-check her history,
run whatever tests you need,
rule out everything you can.
Thank you. And congratulations.
You and Dr. Lim. It's
an excellent match.
I have a sample
I'd like you to test.
Shaun, you don't work here
anymore. How do you have a patient?
It's Claire's patient.
There's no patient name on it.
What are this
patient's symptoms?
He's coughing blood.
I'll expedite the test.
We'll get the data analyzed by a
neurologist as soon as possible.
And when it comes back okay,
we could have you discharged
by the end of the day.
You said, "when."
You think I'm making this
up? Wasting your time?
- No, I don't...
- Yes. I do.
- You're right.
- You're faking?
No. Not entirely.
I can feel my fingers,
but they're tingling.
Because you're 87, Ida. These
are just symptoms of old age.
Junie had leukemia.
Months of chemo, and she
just got sicker and weaker.
Three days before
her ninth birthday,
two oncologists said there
was nothing more they could do.
Told us that she would never
make it through the night.
They said it was pointless.
"Oh, and it's so cruel..."
But it wasn't their
little girl who was dying.
The next morning...
Junie was still alive.
And the morning after that,
she opened her eyes, and...
All the people said,
"Oh, it's a miracle!"
But it wasn't a miracle.
Junie is alive with
three beautiful children
only because I refused to let
those doctors tell me what to do.
And now that I'm old,
they give me even less credit.
We'll let you know
the test results.
WBC and PT are elevated,
and hemoglobins are a little low.
It could be pneumonia, DIC...
It's trauma-induced,
so more likely...
Trauma?
Then coagulopathy is
possible, making bleeding worse.
You need to get the patient on
phytonadione as soon as possible.
I'm writing a script.
You'll tell your patient
how important this is, right?
Good news, Ida.
Normal electrical
activity at rest,
normal action potentials
with contraction.
Thank you. I'm sorry I
wasted your time here.
You don't have to
listen to your doctors,
but you do have to
be honest with them.
Park, bile.
They're treating you
for rhabdomyolysis.
That makes sense.
- Why are you here?
- I am a doctor.
Why are you sad?
I'm sad and angry and...
Confused, and I don't know.
I wasn't supposed
to be at the bar.
I was supposed to
be at a job interview.
Dr. Glassman got me a job
interview, but I don't want a new job.
And people tell me
that I have to move on,
but why can't I just be sad?
And angry and...
It's not rhabdo.
You need immediate treatment.
What?
Wait, for what?
For what? For what?
Trampoline...
Hey.
Dr. Murphy?
I need help in here!
Left hemothorax and
grade-two splenic laceration
resulting from a rib fracture.
Inserted a chest tube
to reduce the blood
pooling in the pleural cavity.
Any idea what caused the trauma?
Zack Cordell beat him up.
The patient he brought
in? Shaun told you?
Not explicitly, but...
He was acting strange
from the minute they came in.
Well, Shaun acting
strange isn't strange.
Excuse me.
Dr. Murphy saved
another person today.
Encountering an emergency
is not a job qualification.
And how can you trust a doctor
who doesn't have the sense
to tell someone he was
injured before passing out?
It's no longer a
request, Jackson.
Am I only allowed to do my
job when you agree with me?
You knew someone on the
spectrum. What happened to them?
They died.
But if either of us
are making decisions
based on our personal experiences,
we're making the wrong decisions.
You paid a lot of
money for my judgment.
Too much, I'm starting to think.
Well, that was the point.
I didn't need the money, I
needed the commitment.
You went out on a limb for me.
You fire me now, you look
like a fool in front of the board.
It's not the clips. Ida needs
to be opened up again.
That's too bad.
But there's one
other test I'd like to try.
I'm starting to feel
some pain in my left side.
It's important for a doctor
to use all their senses.
Tastes like a bit of kale,
seven delicious vegetables.
Good news is you don't have a
potentially fatal bile duct issue.
Bad news is we know you've
been dumping your veggie slushie
into your drain to make
us think you were sick.
You'll be discharged
this afternoon.
- You asked to see me?
- Yeah, for the last two hours.
I'm sorry, I've been
dealing with Dr. Murphy.
Seems someone beat
him up, quite severely.
Yeah, that shouldn't
have happened.
But before he passed out, he said
he knew what was wrong with me.
Well, we all know
what's wrong with you.
You're an ass with a
head trauma and rhabdo.
No, he said you're wrong.
He kind of spaced
out, all distracted,
and then he said that I don't
have that, and that I need treatment.
Distracted, how?
Like, he was looking around,
trying to find something
in the air, I don't know.
And then it looked
like he found it.
What exactly did he say?
"Trampoline"? And?
That's it.
You know Shaun,
it could be a reference to
something he read somewhere.
It could be a metaphor.
Could be the guy misheard.
It could be delirium.
Shaun had a systolic
pressure of 70.
He may have been hallucinating.
He may have just been wrong.
He's hypotensive.
O2 sats are dropping.
- He's crashing.
- Bag him.
Bolus five units of
vasopressin and start a drip.
"Trampoline" from the Spanish word
"trampolino," meaning springboard,
from the Italian root
"trampoli," meaning stilts.
Maybe Shaun was talking about
an excessive growth
disorder like acromegaly.
But instead of just saying
the name of the disorder,
he used the English translation
of the Spanish
derivative of the Italian?
Maybe we should
just wake him up.
His respiratory
status is too fragile.
We have a very sick patient.
If Shaun can save his life...
We have two very sick patients.
And if there's a 1% chance
that waking Shaun will risk
his life, I say we don't do it.
We shouldn't need Shaun.
We can figure
this out ourselves.
What do we know?
Low BP, nausea and dizziness,
erratic gait and behavior.
Adrenal insufficiency could
explain his gait and BP.
We'd be seeing
hyperpigmentation. Botulism?
There'd be descending paralysis.
If anything, he has ascending.
Lyme disease?
Explains fatigue and dizziness,
and, if advanced,
impaired muscle movement.
And an arrhythmia
could be lowering his BP.
But none of this
sounds like "trampoline."
Let's get him started on
100 milligrams of doxycycline.
- Do you need...
- Shh!
Sorry. Sorry.
You were on duty when
Dr. Murphy passed out, right?
I was first one in.
Is this where he was standing?
I think he was
closer to the patient.
Hmm...
What about the blinds?
Were they like that?
Please, I need to know
what Shaun's experience was
when he was standing here.
Also, could I get a step stool?
- Sure.
- Thanks.
Why can't you get
him his job back?
I mean, you were the president
for, like, a hundred years.
I'm gonna fight for him,
but I'm only one vote.
We all get smacked around.
We gotta learn to take the hits.
Lick our wounds and move on.
He likes you, you know.
Yeah, I like him, too.
He likes you more.
When he gets rejected,
I'm glad it's coming from
somebody who cares about him.
We need an OR stat!
Hey, Shaun.
It's me, Auntie Em.
What are you doing in my room?
No, Shaun, we're
in the hospital.
You were pretty bad
earlier, but now you're...
Zack. Zack has
the wrong diagnosis.
- No, no, no. Shaun, I know.
- No, no...
It's fine. It's actually fine.
He'll die unless he's
treated immediately.
- No, he needs...
- "Trampoline."
Zack had an aortic arch aneurysm
with signs of impending rupture,
the evidence of which was
a pulsatile mass in his neck.
That and his erratic
gait and behavior
are explained by the fact
that he had tertiary syphilis,
also known as...
Treponema.
Zack misheard you.
But we were able to repair the
aneurysm, and he is stable now.
Okay.
All right.
Lie down, Dorothy, and
get some rest, all right?
We finally got her history.
Those doctors who said Junie
wouldn't survive the night...
They were right.
Three days before her
ninth birthday, Junie died.
Ida never had any grandchildren.
What about her husband?
He did pass away two years ago,
but he and Ida separated
after their daughter's death.
It doesn't change
anything medically.
I'm sorry.
You know what $300,000
can get you in Tempe?
How are you doing?
I have an O2 sat of 97%
and urine output of 200 CCs
an hour, so I'm doing well.
I just got off the phone with
Dr. Turner at San Jose General.
You missed a job interview.
I like being a surgeon here.
But you're not anymore.
And we can't change that.
Shaun, both of us...
We need to face reality.
My brother Steve said
that whenever people
want you to do something
they think is wrong,
they say it's "reality."
Yesterday, Dr. Shaun Murphy
did something that was different.
And it wasn't because
he showed mercy
to someone who had been
cruel and violent to him,
although that's extraordinary.
What was different
is that yesterday,
Dr. Shaun Murphy made
Dr. Claire Browne a better doctor.
Why? Because Dr. Claire
Browne looked at a problem
through Dr. Murphy's
eyes, and she saved a life.
And that's extraordinary.
Dr. Han,
Dr. Murphy may not
communicate like you do,
he may not
communicate like I do.
But make no mistake,
he does communicate.
And he inspires.
Well, welcome back to
the board, Dr. Glassman.
I've heard of your insights and
passion, and I'm grateful to witness it.
Thank you.
But I didn't fire Dr. Murphy
because he doesn't inspire.
I fired him because he was
irrational, unprofessional.
He couldn't calm down.
He couldn't control himself.
I stand by that decision.
And if Dr. Glassman insists
on putting this to a vote,
the issue isn't whether
Dr. Murphy should be working here.
The issue is whether I should.
Whether I control my staff.
Because I can't
work here if I don't.
Okay.
I don't think there's anything
else on the agenda, so...
Steve was right.
And Dr. Glassman is right.
You're gonna propose his motion?
Dr. Andrews, I don't think
you have the votes to carry it.
I agree. But I don't
need the votes.
Just as you have the power
to fire someone under
your supervision, so do I.
You're gonna fire me
to save Dr. Murphy?
He's not ready to move on.
Neither am I.
Did you hear about Han?
Can't imagine Andrews
will survive the fallout.
They're gonna need
a new chief of surgery.
What if either of us
is offered the job?
One of us bossing the other around?
I don't think that would fly with HR.
Someone would have to
resign or we'd have to break up.
Or we could turn it down.
I think things are great.
And they've been great
for, what, four weeks now?
Just over a month.
It'd be crazy to pass on a chance
at being a department head.
Are you that crazy?
No. Are you?
No.
Good. I talked to
Andrews' assistant.
Aoki should be calling you
with the offer any minute.
You'd better answer.
Hello.
Miss Aoki, it's good
to hear from you.
Hi, Shaun.
I got my job back.
That's great.
I have a question for you.
Yes. I don't mean yes.
I also don't mean no.
Just, what is the question?
Do I look nice?
Yes, Shaun, you look very nice.
I know myself.
I know what I want,
and I know what I love.
You don't love me.
You barely know me.
I think I do. I
think I know you.
And sure, we can go
out on another date,
and then another date after
that, and more dates after that.
But life is short
and getting shorter,
and I wanna spend whatever
time I have left with you.
When we're together,
it feels like we're speeding
down the PCH in a Duesenberg,
12 cylinders with 400
CCs and turbo boosts,
and a picnic basket in
the back with baguettes
and Gruyère and prosciutto
and Châteauneuf-du-Pape.
And you're sitting next to me,
wind in your hair
and you're laughing.
That laugh.
And the sun and the ocean.
And it just feels like
we can go. Forever.
Debbie Wexler,
will you marry me?
Yes.
You have nice hair.
I know, fabulous. I was just...
Here are flowers and chocolates.
Real ones.
I was wondering if
you would like to...
Eat dinner?
Are you asking me out?
Yes.
On a date?
I would love to.