When you get sick, it starts
out with a single bacterium.
One lone, nasty intruder.
Pretty soon, the
intruder duplicates.
Becomes two.
Then those two become four...
and those four become eight.
Then, before your body knows it,
it's under attack.
- You can't put that in there.
- They told us to grab a cubby.
Yeah, I know, it's just...
We keep it empty for a reason.
Can you take your stuff out? There's
empty ones over there you can use.
I don't think so.
I said take it out!
Great. I get the
crazy one next to me.
You wanna fight? 'Cause I will.
I will fight you! You're tiny. I
could take you down in seconds.
- Come on.
- Stop!
It's an invasion.
The question for a doctor is
once the invaders have landed,
once they've taken
over your body...
They took George's cubby.
How the hell do
you get rid of them?
They're locusts. Comfortable
locusts feeding on our surgeries.
That's rude. There should be a
couple of days where they act like guests
before they put their
feet up on the coffee table.
And what's with the orange scrubs?
Ours aren't good enough for them?
We ran out. They're
on back order.
Randall from the supply company
says they'll be here in a week.
That's what you learn
when you lie here all day.
Why order new ones? We can
give these to our replacements.
We're not gonna be
replaced by anybody.
- If I have to become a coroner.
- No one is becoming a coroner.
- Cristina, tell him.
- Tell him what? They're here.
- It's over.
- Hey, we are not
some stupid hosts.
They can't invade us. They can't
attach themselves to our faces,
and while we're eating
spaghetti, explode out of our chests
and skitter across the
floor. This is our ship.
This is our ship.
Excuse me, are you quoting
a Sigourney Weaver movie?
Shut up.
That's what happens when you
live here. You watch a lot of TV.
We own this hospital. We
were born in this hospital.
And we will hold this hospital
with our last gasping breath.
I really don't wanna be a
coroner. I don't like dead people.
Go out there and go get
surgeries before they take them.
Go! And I want a full
report by the end of the day!
And what is wrong with you?
- I don't know
what I'm fighting for.
- Surgeries, Cristina!
Surgeries. There will be a
cardio god here again one day.
And when there is, you don't
want to be out of practice. Now, go!
This the overflow
from Mercy West?
Their ER closed
for good last night.
- Everyone's coming here.
- A perk from the merger.
- Our new attending.
- First day back?
- Yeah.
- You picked a good one. Nice and quiet.
- Not a lot going on.
- Yeah.
- Thank you.
- Coming through!
Where do you want us?
- At this point,
anywhere is good.
- At Mercy West, we do zones.
When it's super busy, we
give everyone a zone, a space.
Nurses put a person in,
you know it's your patient.
- Helps get to them quicker.
- This is an ER,
not a schoolyard.
- We're not playing four square.
- I like it.
- What?
- Good idea. Let's try. Your name?
Jackson Avery.
Dr. Avery, Dr. Hunt.
It's all yours. Zone away.
Let's go.
- Chief?
- What do you need, Karev?
I know you have cuts to
make at the resident level.
I just want you to keep in mind
that Izzie's not 100 percent back yet.
I mean, she's
recovering. Look, she...
- She just... She needs this.
- I have a hospital to run,
Karev.
I have two hospitals to run.
- Hey, that wasn't cool.
- What?
In the locker room. My friend
should've left that cubby empty. I'm sorry.
- She's obviously not, so...
- It's the first day of school.
Everyone's on edge. I'll probably
kill someone before the day's through.
I'm Charles, by the
way. Charles Percy.
Might be kind of hard for
you not to talk to me all day.
It can be done.
I once didn't talk to my family for a
car ride across the whole country.
Ten days, 15 states, not a peep.
I just read books,
pretended I was a hostage.
- Izzie Stevens.
- Nice to meet you,
Izzie Stevens.
Hey, do you happen to know the
key code to the research library?
I was here last
night, it was closed.
It took me two years
to get that code.
I need every
advantage I can get.
Did the gentleman from the
waiting room ever find you?
- What?
- It's the gentleman
- who could possibly
be your father.
- What?
Daddy.
Calliope.
What? What are you doing here?
- I came to see you.
- Why?
Calliope, we used to talk.
Every Sunday, we used
to talk. I'd wait for your call.
And you'd tell me everything.
All about your crazy adventures.
Even when you were
in trouble, you'd still call.
And we worked it out.
We'd always work it out.
Hmm?
Daddy.
I'm sorry. I'm... I'm
sorry things got so...
But the fact that you came.
Daddy, is that Father Kevin?
Hello, Calliope.
Are you...
two here to...?
- You think
you can pray away the gay.
- We can just sit and talk.
- Oh, no. You can't
pray away the gay.
- Calliope Iphegenia Torres!
You can't pray away the gay!
The man flew 3,000 miles to
make me straight. With a priest!
I'm lucky they didn't march
into the ER swinging incense,
- all hepped up for exorcism.
- Are you done?
Am I...? No!
He came to disinfect you.
You don't find that abhorrent?
- I do, but...
- There's no but.
You're gonna tell me you
get where he's coming from?
- Maybe you should
try and talk to him.
- I have nothing to say!
If he wants to throw away
our relationship after 30 years,
- that's his decision.
- He hasn't done anything.
You're the one who
changed the game.
You didn't expect understanding
when you came out to your parents?
I never had boyfriends. Ever.
I had a poster of Cindy Crawford,
and I wasn't just looking at her mole.
It wasn't news to my mom when I
brought somebody home named Joanne.
But you... you dated men
your whole life. You loved men.
You even married one. Want to
talk about 30 years of a relationship?
He's been consistent
for 30 years.
All of a sudden,
you're a whole new girl.
So cut him some slack. Sit
down and have a conversation.
Give him room to
be a little shocked.
- I hate you.
- 'Cause I'm right
and I'm awesome.
Thanks for being my tour guide
through this first-day madness.
We both got
assigned zone five, so.
I know, it's not like
you had any choice.
Still, you're a peach
to pretend otherwise.
- Being the new kid is...
- A little scary, I know.
You were here when that psycho
intern cabal was marching around
chopping out each other's organs.
Now, that must've been scary.
- Hi! I'm Dr. Kepner. Oh, handcuffs.
- I'm not an axe murderer.
I just broke into
someone's house.
The dude came after me with a
golf club, beat the crap out of me.
You don't need the
cop, I can barely move.
- Roll him.
- We'll keep the cop.
He's got multiple contusions
and ecchymosis over his back.
He's gonna need lumbar
and thoracic films. Down.
OK. By the way, it was
one organ. An appendix.
It wasn't a psycho cabal.
Oh! Good to know.
- Hey, Sarah.
- Dr. Stevens.
I have to go. The
doctors are here.
My sister and her daughters want you
all to promise them it's a good kidney.
- It's a good kidney!
- There. All right?
Bye.
Uh, Sarah Fremont, age
27. End-stage renal disease,
on dialysis for three
years waiting for a kidney.
- Down to her last access site.
- Polite way of saying
they've run out of
places to stick needles.
Ms. Fremont has a
subclavian catheter for access.
- Why is this not ideal?
- It's difficult to obtain
sufficient blood flow through...
Oh... You guys raise hands.
Frank Nusbaum, 42, multiple
mostly superficial stab wounds,
vital signs stable. His
buddy's got a lacerated palm.
- Got it.
- I'm not his buddy!
He touched my
little girl! My baby!
She's not a baby, she's 19 years
old! Ain't a scrap of baby left, Don!
One, two, three.
OK, we got a bleeder here!
Draw up some lidocaine and
get me a lac tray with 3-0 silk.
- Need any help?
- This is gonna pinch.
He came at me with a
knife! Tried to cut off...
Come on, I was gesturing!
You ran into the knife!
You're an idiot and a pervert!
She used to baby-sit your brats.
- Can't believe
I let her in your house!
- I love her, Don.
- I love her and she loves me.
- I'm gonna kill him!
- Easy! All right?
- Let him die! It's what he deserves!
- Shut him up!
- There's nothing...?
There. That's how we
do it on our side of town.
Nice try. This is my
zone. He's my patient.
Yet I'm the one actually helping him.
How long have you had stomach pains?
A few days now. They
keep getting worse.
My dad fell a couple of months
ago. Had a stable hip fracture.
- This is my patient.
- Not anymore.
Fine. Good luck doing
an H&P without a chart.
- I'll just add this
to the chart later.
- If you can find it.
This is the nurses' lounge. It is
literally always someone's birthday.
If you're nice to the
nurses, you will get cake.
- The lab.
- How's the IL-2 going,
Dr. S? Good?
- Good.
- IL-2, huh?
- Are you feeling...?
- Stable for now.
And you don't want
anyone to know
because they'll be
blown away by the fact
that you're back at work and
only be able to think of you
as some sort of
awesome superwoman.
- Which, clearly, you are.
- You know what?
The fake flattery?
It's kind of gross.
You wanna know something
deeply personal about me?
See that girl? Her name's Reed.
I have the biggest crush in the world on
her and she doesn't even know I'm alive.
She calls me Charlie.
Nobody named
Charlie ever got the girl.
Charlie Brown, Charlie Manson.
I'm not trying to minimize your
cancer, but this really sucks for me.
- You like her?
- I love her.
- 4381.
- What's that?
The code to the
research library.
"While performance
has been evaluated,
the largest considerations
have been budgetary."
This is the speech we want
you to use when you're firing staff.
These exact
words. Don't deviate.
I'm not using your
speech to fire people.
And I don't need an HR
chaperone. Thank you for your time.
Chief, are you familiar
with Megan Nowlan?
Yes. She was an intern.
Married to Steve Mostow.
I fired her. I know
how to fire people.
I don't like it, but I know
how to do it. And I do it well.
You used an e-mail to fire her.
And now she's suing the
hospital for wrongful termination.
Claims she was fired
because she was pregnant.
So... this is the
speech. Don't deviate.
T&L spine films show
a burst fracture at T12.
You see evidence of instability
because vertebral height loss
is greater than 50 percent, which
implies both ALL and PLL are disrupted.
What's that mean?
I got a broken back?
I'll still be able
to walk, right?
You will still be able to walk,
burgle, have a full life.
- Ideas?
- Decompression via corpectomy
and reconstruction with
strut graft and instrumentation.
Wow! I might be
out of my league.
She has a photographic memory.
- We're all out of that league.
- I was thinking you could do
transpedicle screws
with a posterior approach.
Hmm...
It seemed like a good idea,
but, you know, maybe not.
Let's go with the
pedicle screws.
OK. Get him in pre-op. Let me
know when his test results come back.
I'm on it.
Frank! Oh, my God!
- Honey, are you OK?
- I'll be fine, sweetheart.
- Get off of her, you perv!
- Daddy!
- I will kill you,
you son of a bitch!
- Security!
- Nice work!
- Thanks.
I got it from here.
A tackle like that, you
had to play football.
- I played a little in college.
- Safety?
- And wide receiver, yeah.
- Offense and defense. Impressive.
Can you bring
that guy over later?
I want to thank him.
He saved my life.
No, I saved your
life. I'm still saving it.
- You paged?
- Yes, I ran a CT on your guy
with the tummy ache. Turns
out he has an adrenal mass.
Thought you might
want to see the scans.
I was waiting till I got
lab results to order a CT.
Hmm-hmm.
- You stole my lab results?
- And look,
I get a surgery
for all my trouble.
Excuse me, Dr. Karev? My dad and I
have some more questions. He's still upset.
I'll be there in a
minute. Thanks.
I'll take those.
You gonna fight back at some
point, or just let her bury you?
She's not burying me. She's new.
She's just finding her footing.
She found her footing
on the back of your neck.
- Why do you care?
- I don't know. I like you.
No, I like that.
Stop.
Find her open window.
Everyone has one.
A weak spot. Undefended.
An open window or a
key hidden in a fake rock.
- That's how I do it.
- Yeah, you're a criminal
and I'm not.
It's not a crime to do to
her what she's doing to you.
- Which is what, exactly?
- Making you look like an idiot.
Hey.
- Have you talked
to any of them?
- Who?
- The Mercy Westers.
- Yeah.
- And?
- And I love you.
Not that. I need to know
what's going on out there.
How's Cristina doing? She was
cardio-deprived and depressed.
Are you and Cristina in
a dark and twisty place?
- Are you having
the dark and twisties?
- We are.
- Both of you are dark
and twisty.
- I told you we are.
OK.
Uh, excuse me,
Dr. Hunt, you paged me?
Your patient was having neurologic
symptoms, you didn't notice?
- Well, I...
- Lucky for you,
Dr. Adamson did,
and correctly diagnosed carotid
stenosis. Book an OR for the afternoon.
What about the surgery
for his adrenal tumor?
Your dad has a 90 percent
blockage in his right carotid artery.
We need to operate
first. That's a lot to digest.
But Dr. Adamson here
will keep you informed.
With all due respect, Dr. Hunt,
Mr. Goldman's my patient.
- I found the tumor.
- When I operate on the tumor,
you can scrub in. In the
meantime, help Dr. Adamson
- prep the patient for the CEA.
- Sir...
Whatever she needs, Karev.
Neurologic symptoms? You
didn't put that in the chart.
Oh, I didn't? Hmm...
All right, fine. I get it.
I sprang this on you.
It's a lot to take in.
And... you feel like you don't have
much experience with gay people.
Uncle Berto hasn't been
single for 60 years for no reason.
- Calliope...
- It's still an adjustment.
That said, you should've
adjusted by now.
You're supposed to
love me, no matter what.
That's... what a parent does.
I love you with all my heart.
But with all that's
going on with you now...
Look, I'm scared for
you. It's an abomination.
- It's an eternity in hell.
- Let's not start with words
like hell.
That's why you flew 3,000 miles?
To tell me I was going to hell?
- I thought you came here
to apologize.
- I can't apologize, Calliope!
I don't understand what
happened or where I went wrong!
- Where you went wrong?
- OK. Leviticus:
"Thou shalt not lie with a
man as one lies with a female.
- It is an abomination."
- Don't quote the Bible at me.
"The outcry of Sodom and Gomorrah
is great and their sin is grave."
- This is not what we...
- Jesus: "A new commandment
that I give
- unto you that
you love one another."
- Romans: "The law is..."
Jesus: "He who is without
sin cast the first stone."
- So you admit it's a sin.
- "Blessed are the merciful,
for they shall obtain mercy."
Jesus: "Blessed are the pure in heart,
for they shall see God." Jesus:
"Blessed are those who have been
persecuted for righteousness' sake
for theirs is the Kingdom of Heaven."
Jesus is my savior, Daddy, not you!
And Jesus would be
ashamed of you for judging me!
He would be ashamed of you
for turning your back on me!
He would be ashamed!
With this kind of injury, there
is a chance you could end up
- with severe weakness
in your legs.
- That's OK.
I carry the stuff out with
my arms, not my legs.
- This is serious, Billy.
- You're gonna fix me up fine.
Listen, I've got
a present for you.
- You stole her notebook?
- Keep it down.
You want my cop all
over this? Don't you get it?
- This is her open window.
- I don't want her open window.
"You're not just a good
doctor, you're a great doctor.
You are the future of medicine.
Only you can keep you down."
And my favorite: "No one
can tell it's plastic surgery."
Oh, my God.
I think it's the nose, but it could
be the boobs. What do you think?
- Give it back to her! Stop reading!
- Future of medicine alert!
You haven't seen my
notebook anywhere, have you?
Small, red. I was
holding it all morning.
- I'm not sure.
- So much for
that photographic memory.
Good luck finding it.
This blows.
- Getting your ass kicked?
- Shut up.
I hear yours got a
standing ovation in the ER.
The one who saved the whole
ER from the maniac with a hammer?
OK. He didn't save anyone.
He did some stupid ninja
leap and tripped a guy.
I used actual medicine to
stop a person from dying.
Mine has a notebook
that she takes notes in,
notes of a very personal
nature, and I stole it.
- You what?
- Give it.
No! No, I am not
sinking to their level.
They are vindictive
and they are aggressive
and they're not team players,
and if we are not careful,
that spirit is going
to infect our hospital.
- We have to fight it.
- Which is why you
stole her notebook?
- And read it.
- She's not a very nice person.
- Hey.
- Score! You rock.
- No. That's not for you.
- Who's it for?
- Charles.
- Your Mercy West guy?
They're handing us our asses on a
plate and you're serving him coffee?
Charles is kind of awesome,
and if you could get past
your egos, you'd
realize you can't write off
all the Mercy West residents
just 'cause you feel threatened.
- We don't feel threatened.
- No.
We feel pretty threatened.
- Dudes, they're not here.
- Hallelujah.
They're not eating.
They're working.
Oh, my God! They
don't eat lunch!
- What's going on?
- Pulsatile mass over
the stab wound.
- What are we looking at?
- Can't be sure without Angio,
- but it's a pseudoaneurysm.
- Right. Keep pressure on.
Get him to Angio. If it's
positive, you scrub in.
- Thank you, sir.
- That's my patient.
He was here and you weren't.
- Dr. Hunt!
- What?
- Cristina, what?
- Doesn't matter
that it's my patient
or my surgery. You're prioritizing
based on some random code,
some stupid rule you
have to not favor me.
It's one surgery!
Forget it.
The woman does whatever I ask.
I want something, she gets it
for me. The research library?
Anytime you wanna go in,
it's closed, just say the word.
- She gave me the code.
- You're kidding.
She can't do enough for me. It's
like I have my own surgical bitch.
It didn't go well, huh?
At least now I can
move on with my life.
Stop entertaining any thoughts of
getting back together with my family.
I don't need a father.
I don't.
Not one who won't accept me.
His vital signs are
fine. BP looks good.
I hurt... The neck...
- Blood...
- What?
In... head... place... 12.
- What's happening here?
- I'm not sure.
We're gonna have
to hold off on the OR.
- Pathetic.
- He just said a bunch
of weird crap.
He has expressive
aphasia, means Broca's area.
The left side of the brain. You
said the right side was blocked.
- Five percent have Broca's on right.
- - Wanna take that chance?
What if it's brain
met from the tumor?
Because you diagnosed
the tumor, it's a met.
- I've seen this before! Have you?
- Enough!
Your behavior has
been disgusting.
All you've done all day is take pleasure
in how the other one got it wrong,
how they screwed it up.
This is my father.
My father!
And you are
supposed to be healers.
That's what your
job is supposed to be.
To heal people.
We're gonna run some
more tests, ma'am.
We're very sorry.
Thank you.
- Can I talk to you
for a minute?
- Go away.
I picked up the labs. If you want,
I can take care of the dialysis.
I've got this. I don't need
a surgical bitch, thanks.
Izzie, it wasn't personal.
That stuff, it just...
comes with the job. I'd expect
you to do the same thing to me.
Outside of work, you can be friends.
But inside, it's a different story.
- It was at Mercy West.
- Isn't how it is here.
Here, we don't just think about
ourselves. We support one another.
We have each
other's backs. We...
We throw ourselves in front of buses
to save the lives of complete strangers!
But you will never measure
up to the people we've lost!
Let's do 140 base
sodium, 37 base bicarb
and zero K bath with an
ultrafiltration of 3.5 liters.
That, I suppose, makes
everything quite all right.
This?
Cristina?
Cristina!
- Cristina, talk to me.
- No.
Cristina!
What happened?
Here.
Talk to me. Tell
me what happened.
Nothing.
Nothing is happening to me!
I don't know what I'm doing.
I'm, like, chasing after
surgeries I don't care about.
Do you know how long it's been
since I've held a heart in my hand?
Since I felt that... that joy?
That rush?
I miss Burke!
I miss him all day!
I miss...
It's not the relationship
or the sex. I miss...
Every day when he
was here, I held hearts.
And I got picked not
because of favoritism,
but because it was
just... It was right!
And I learned. I learned.
And I felt seen.
And now, you know
what? I don't know what.
I spent this
entire day fighting.
And I don't wanna do it anymore.
Come over here.
I have a method all my own.
If you notice, the coat came
first, then the tie, then the shirt.
Now, according to Hoyle, after
that, the pants should be next.
There's where I'm different.
- Where are we
with Billy Sheehan?
- Ready. I helped put him under.
- Prepped and positioned.
- We said I was handling that.
We did. I wanted everything
ready for Dr. Shepherd.
Your first day and you're
making my life easier.
Yeah. Dr. Kepner, she's
not just a good doctor.
She's a great doctor. In fact,
she's the future of medicine.
Only you can keep
yourself down, right?
By the way, I can tell.
Dr. Shepherd, I
just need a moment.
Look at this. Acute on
chronic subdural hematoma.
- That's not mets.
- It's a brain bleed.
Which explains aphasia
and the numbness.
Would explain
everything. I'll tell Neuro.
No, nice try. I'll tell Neuro.
I'm the one that said
it was a brain issue.
The only reason why you
knew that was I got the ball rolling
- by diagnosing
carotid stenosis.
- Give it a rest.
Didn't you hear what
Goldman's daughter said?
Sorry.
- I'll stop if you stop.
- I've stopped. You can have it.
Talk to Arizona Robbins.
She's head of Neuro.
She's not really
head of Neuro, is she?
- What happened?
- Push another two of Ativan!
- Get me new chemistries
and an EKG!
- Get the crash cart now!
Start ventilating her!
Torsades? You gave her
torsades? What did you do?!
I didn't do anything!
You were with her last.
- Page Bailey.
- I already did.
Clear! Clear!
I don't know you well
enough to talk about her.
We're not gonna do that.
Most people think I was named
for the state, but it's not true.
I was named for a battleship.
The USS Arizona.
My grandfather was
serving on the Arizona
when the Japanese
bombed Pearl Harbor,
and he saved 19 men
before he drowned.
Everything my father
did his whole life
was about honoring
that sacrifice.
I was raised to be a
good man in a storm.
Raised to love my country,
love my family and
protect the things I love.
When my father,
Colonel Daniel Robbins of
the United States Marine Corps,
heard that I was a lesbian, he
said he only had one question.
I was prepared for, "How fast can
you get the hell out of my house?"
But instead...
it was, "Are you still
who I raised you to be?"
My father believes in country
the way that you believe in God.
And my father's not
a man who bends,
but he bent for me
because I'm his daughter.
I'm a good man in a storm.
I love your daughter. And
I protect the things I love.
Not that I need to.
She doesn't need it.
She's strong and
caring and honorable.
And she's who
you raised her to be.
- She's alive. Barely.
- She still gonna get
the kidney?
I'm asking the
questions right now.
Dr. Percy here tells me you
were in charge of Sarah's dialysis.
- Is that true?
- Yes.
He also says that you
were pretty upset with him.
I don't see what that
has to do with anything.
It has to do with the
fact that your mental state
may have clouded your judgment,
may have made you a
less competent doctor,
may have led you to read the
labs wrong or not read them at all.
Otherwise, why would you
tell the tech to give Sarah
a zero K bath
when her potassium
this morning was 3.4?
You sucked all the
potassium out of that woman.
You stopped her heart.
She's alive, but she's
not getting her kidney.
After three years of waiting,
somebody else will
be getting her kidney.
And if we don't find her another
one in the next three days,
she's going to be dead.
And you will have killed her.
Surgery went pretty well,
Mr. Sheehan. Good bone alignment.
Then I'll be back to my old
self? I'll be able to get around?
Get around, yes. To where
you were, no. Probably not.
Probably about 70 percent. Which
is good, considering your injuries.
I guess that means I only
steal 70 percent as much stuff.
Billy...
See this?
I noticed this afternoon there
were splotches all over the page.
They're tears. She was
crying when she wrote this stuff.
She's scared.
And these stupid little sayings,
they make her feel better.
This is her comfort. We
stole her comfort from her.
You and me, we're
taking things from people
and leaving them at 70 percent.
You promised.
You promised my nieces
I was getting this kidney.
I'm sorry. I am...
so, so sorry.
But I'm going to make this right.
I'm going to get you another kidney.
It's my sister.
What do I tell her?
I'm sorry.
It must be hard, being the
new people, being the invaders.
But that's no excuse
for you being...
I don't like you.
But what I did, that
was over the line.
I'm sorry. I thought
you wanted to see me.
This is Missy Grant
from Human Resources.
You're kidding me.
You're firing me?
- Stevens...
- You can't!
You can't fire me for having
cancer! That's five kinds of illegal!
This is not about the cancer.
It's about the kidney patient?
I made a mistake. I...
- Doctors make mistakes
every day.
- Yes, but...
You let me back
after I cut an LVAD!
That was a different
era. Times have changed.
Dr. Shepherd and Dr. Hunt
had concerns about your
stamina and emotional stability.
- And Dr. Karev has questions...
- Alex? Alex said something
to you?
Dr. Webber.
In the wake of the
merger with Mercy West,
the needs of the
hospital have changed.
While performance is evaluated,
the largest considerations
are budgetary.
There was simply
no room on the staff.
Please don't do this to me.
Please don't take
this away from me.
I don't have
anything left. Please...
What do you do when
the infection hits you?
- Calliope.
- When it takes over?
I can't do this anymore.
You'll, you know, see me in hell.
Listen to me, please.
I have to catch you.
- What?
- Your whole life...
You've always been
on a bridge, Calliope,
ever since you
were a little girl.
And you don't just walk on it,
either, you climb on the railing.
You're ready to leap.
And when you do,
when that happens,
I have to be there.
I have to catch you.
- You don't have
to catch me, Dad.
- Yes, I do.
That's my job.
If this works out
between you and Arizona,
is there a chance,
maybe, you'd...
give your mother a wedding?
If Arizona wanted to spend
the rest of her life with me?
Yeah, I'll put on a big white
dress and dance down the aisle.
How about grandkids?
Yes, I would imagine...
when the time
came, there'd be kids.
- Does she make you happy?
- Yes, Dad.
She makes me very happy.
I love you. You know that?
She's not a vegetarian, is she? I
don't know how much more I can take.
She's not a vegetarian.
I feel very old.
Do you do what you're supposed
to and take your medicine?
Or do you learn to
live with the thing,
and hope someday it goes away?
Tell me everything.
Did you beat them?
Did you kick their asses?
Come on, I want a full report.
Everything that happened.
Izzie left me.
She wrote a note
and she left me. I...
I don't know if
she's coming back.
What do you mean she
left? Where did she go?
Go hug him.
- What?
- Go hug him.
Or do you just give up entirely,
and let it kill you?