Dr. Ryan to Pediatrics.
There he is. Hey.
Right on time.
Reporting for duty.
I half expected I'd have to
physically drag you out of your office.
Have you met the group?
Uh... No actually, uh...
Come. Don't be shy.
Morning everyone. Morning.
Hey. This is Max.
It's his first day.
Why are you in scrubs?
Oh, I'm a doctor. Mmm. Where?
Here. WILLOW: Nice.
I wish I could do
chemo at Whole Foods,
but we're not even
allowed to use our phones.
Mmm-hmm. Uh, Max,
this is Mr. Kiggens.
"Big Mike." Yeah, clearly.
That's Willow. Smart,
bringing your own food.
No one delivers here. Really?
And Millie. Don't
be scared, Max.
We don't bite.
Uh, no, thank
you, but I'm not...
I'm not scared. Okay.
Hey, you know, why don't you
join us? We need a fourth for euchre.
You know what, I would love to,
but I actually got the, uh, to-go chemo.
It's fewer calories, so...
Max, it's three hours.
You can't stay put
for three hours?
Yeah, no, I would, but
you know me and sitting.
It's just not a good...
Have a good game.
Good luck out there.
You know, a doctor with an IV
pole is gonna frighten patients.
That's a good point.
Why don't we just, uh, do this.
There we go.
Meet Earl, my new sidekick.
Oh, yeah, that's much better.
Right? A smiling bag of poison.
Yep, going full chemo.
Please don't say that. Got it.
I know that at some
point I'm gonna be useless.
Thanks for not disagreeing.
Well, we both
know what's coming.
And, uh, after what happened in Cold Spring,
I can't just let the hospital fall apart.
I mean, I need to find someone
who can, you know, take over
when I'm, uh... When I can't...
Will you be my deputy
medical director?
Sorry, I don't know why that
sounded like I was asking you to prom.
I'm flattered, of course.
My friend Earl, here, doesn't
think you look flattered.
I've already cut back on
my public appearances.
If I cut back any more, we're
gonna start to lose funding.
Okay, yeah.
Well, think about it.
Otherwise I'm gonna have to
give my friend Earl, here, a sad face.
Uh, was that our medical director
attached to an IV of cis-platinum?
Don't ask.
Why are you here?
Uh, tough one.
Uh, because this is a
hospital and I'm a doctor.
You said that you were
gonna take some time off.
Well, that was before.
I mean, Max needs
my help, clearly.
Sweetheart, this is important.
You need to take
care of yourself.
And I am going to, okay.
I'm just gonna do it
without leaving the hospital.
I flushed all my
pills this morning.
You know I'm going cold turkey?
Yes, it is gonna
suck for a while,
but it's what I need to
do. And not just for me.
For Max.
Oh.
Ooh, triage. Gotta run.
Damn it, Andy.
Triage said an acute
coronary syndrome in here.
I did not use those words
'cause I don't know them,
but it had to sound serious
or they would have given
me to one of your residents.
Yeah, well, you nearly
gave me an acute coronary.
Did you do something
new with your hair?
All right, Andy,
what's the story?
My knee's been swelling up.
I can't move it without...
Patel, let's, uh, let's
drain Andy's knee.
Hey, take your time, LB.
Clean sheets.
Tony, I know it's difficult
to talk about the attack but
you should.
I was painting up in Mohonk.
Lots of light.
My dad came with
me, so I was annoyed.
I'd wanted to go solo.
But it's good he was there,
'cause when I moved my
easel near the tree line, I...
I saw this shape.
Okay. Tell me more about that.
It was daytime.
They're nocturnal, right?
Yeah.
It shouldn't have been there.
But I saw it, and it just...
it just stared at me.
Mmm.
And then it started running
right at me
and then I turned
and ran, and I'm fast.
I used to run track, but
I didn't make it two feet.
Before it... Before...
So...
before this most recent
attack, you hadn't seen the wolf
in over a month, correct?
Uh...
Yeah.
Hey, Tony, is the, um...
is the wolf here right now?
Okay, all right. Here's
what we're gonna do.
I am gonna go get your dad,
and we are going to talk next steps.
Okay?
Right. Okay.
Oh, my God, this is Rohan.
I mean, I thought it might be because
he has the same... but I didn't wanna...
okay, I'm done.
Hi. Hi. Oh, it's so
nice to meet you.
Your dad talks about
you all the time. He does?
Okay, thank you.
Thank you, Ella.
Now he's blushing,
so this is a disaster.
I'm gonna go, but I
hope I see you again.
You talk about me?
Uh, yes. I wanted to get you a
gift, and Ella was helping me.
What kind of gift?
We've not decided,
but I didn't want to get you
something which meant something
other than what I
wanted it to mean.
Oh, that's...
that's thoughtful.
There is something...
Yes, tell me.
I told you about the songs
I'm writing? Mmm-hmm.
Well, I'd love to make a demo,
and to do that, I
need to rent a studio.
I was wondering if
you could, you know...
Give you money?
I don't think it's a good idea.
Okay. Okay. Baby steps, right?
LB. How's that knee doing?
It's better. Oh.
So why are you still here?
I meant better than bad,
which is still, you
know, not good.
All right, Andy. Why don't you
tell me what's really going on?
My shelter voucher
doesn't start till Saturday,
so I got four
days on the street.
So I thought...
We're a hospital, okay?
You don't warrant
an overnight stay. Yet.
Just do some more digging.
There's gotta be something else wrong
with me. I'm a very unhealthy person.
You paged?
Uh, yeah.
Yeah, is, uh, now a bad time?
For both of you?
Oh, yeah. What do you got?
You said you wanted to know the
next time a frequent flyer came in.
Yeah, frequent flyers
mean we're not doing our job.
Oh, well, then you're in luck.
Meet the Amelia
Earhart of frequent flyers,
Andy Keener.
How can I help?
Looking good, Dr. Reynolds.
Just hold it there.
Fantastic.
That's perfect. Thanks, Chris.
That was great.
This is going to come
together seamlessly.
I thought Fred Niemens usually
does the, uh, medical articles?
My editor thought the personal angle
would be better for The Face of Diversity.
Is that the angle?
I figured we'd start
with a profile on you
and then talk about how you've
put together your department.
Okay. For your
profile, I was thinking
it's a "rags to riches" story.
I already know the layout.
Just below the headline, there'll
be these two pictures of you
where you are now
right next to this.
I wanna know the details of what
led to the mug shot, so we can...
This interview is over.
Wait.
Um, sorry, I didn't mean...
Your chemo bag is
making people nervous.
Yeah, sorry, just one more hour.
And by "people," I mean me.
Did you know that Andy Keener has
been in this hospital over 100 times?
He's a frequent flyer.
If my math is correct,
and I'm pretty sure that it is,
Andy Keener has cost New
Amsterdam $1.4 million this year.
And we haven't done
a thing to help him.
Andy Keener has rung up over $1
million in charges here at New Amsterdam.
That is enough for
50,000 prenatal visits,
two liver transplants, or,
you know, one NBA contract.
How do we lower this
number right there?
Don't look at me.
Well, he's had over 30 visits
and three surgeries for a foot ulcer.
He walks around all day. He
can't keep his foot elevated.
Look, bandages fall off,
antibiotic creams get lost.
Okay, Bloom. ED's number one on
the hospital encounters hit parade.
My ED is open 24/7,
so if he wants to get out
of the rain, or snow, or
sun, or get a hot meal, then...
Got it. Neurology. 10 EEGs and
18 head CT scans this year alone.
All indicated and necessary.
Andy falls, and gets beaten
up, and has a withdrawal seizure.
EMTs bring him in and we
give him the same evaluation
we would give to anyone else.
Yeah, Helen, you can't tell me that
all these biopsies were necessary.
Well, if we don't have
a patient's family history
then all concerns have
to be taken seriously.
Psychiatry, help me out. There's
gotta be a way to save a dollar.
Just one dollar.
Uh, no. No can do, Doc. Andy
suffers from PTSD and depression.
An abusive childhood will do that to
you. Not to mention, he is an alcoholic.
Multiple detox stays.
Okay, so what
everyone is telling me
is that not only was there no
way to avoid spending $1.4 million
on Andy Keener this year,
but apparently there's no way
to avoid spending another $1.4
million on Andy Keener next year?
Yes? Yes, I was
hoping to meet Earl.
Is Earl here? Is
he coming later?
Not here, okay.
Hey, Max, hold up. You
got a fix for Andy Keener?
No, apparently I missed the Solve-America's-Homeless-
Epidemic class in med school.
Fair enough. All right, so, uh,
look, a reporter from The New
England Cardiothoracic Journal
dug up some dirt on me.
Some dirt that... That
could embarrass the hospital.
Define "dirt."
Ten years ago I was
arrested and, um,
she wants to print my mug shot.
Every time I think
this is dead and buried
it just keeps popping
back up in my life,
and I never wanted to be a
burden to you or this hospital.
You're not.
You wanna tell me what happened?
Do I have to?
Well, if I knew the story,
would I trust you less?
No.
Would it make me think
less of you as a surgeon?
No.
Then I don't need to know,
and neither does anybody else.
I just don't want anyone
to think less of me.
Patients, colleagues...
They won't.
Let's go full chemo
on this. "Full chemo"?
Let's get legal to bring
down the hammer.
I wanna keep him overnight
for observation. The, um...
The delusions are back, full-on.
I'm, uh...
I'm so sorry, Hector.
This last attack, he was
screaming.
Clawing at his throat.
He thought he was dying.
My little boy.
How's he supposed
to live like this?
I mean, what's he
gonna do when I'm gone?
I've been reading about,
uh, "deep brain stimulation"?
Deep brain stimulation is not
designed for psychological issues.
It's for, um... It's
for Parkinson's.
It's people with
physical ailments.
But there's trials
happening right now.
Yes, Hector.
A handful of patients with
delusional disorders have tried it, but,
you know, the side
effects are not...
we're not talking scars, here.
The kind, funny, artistic son
that you know and love right now?
It can change
Tony's personality.
Ativan,
Paxil, Klonopin,
Cognitive Behavioral Therapy.
Hypnosis, ECT.
Electricity shooting
through my cariño's brain.
That hasn't changed him?
'Cause it has.
We can try a
compassionate-use trial.
But, Hector, you gotta know that if
you send your son in for this surgery,
you may not recognize
the person that you get back.
Do you understand?
If helping him means
losing some of him,
parts of him I love,
I'll pay the price.
Hey, there. You okay?
No.
Got a migraine,
among other things.
Did we... Did we page you?
No. No, I just got
you some ginger tea.
Okay.
Why?
Because ginger is a miracle
cure-all for the whole system.
Wait, are you monitoring me?
No.
I'm just checking up on you.
Oh, I'm sorry, I
thought I was an adult.
I didn't realize I
needed a babysitter.
Lauren... You know
what, don't, okay?
I am leaving now,
'cause, you know,
I've got an ED to run.
Born a son
Feel the pull from inside of you
The world's behind
Oh, hey.
Hey.
Ella, right? Yeah.
Are you... Are you
waiting for your dad?
Oh, no.
Just taking advantage
of the free Wi-Fi.
Have a seat. Thanks.
What are you writing?
Nothing.
Oh, no, come on. We've known
each other a whole two minutes now.
I'm a songwriter.
Go ahead, take your best shot.
Oh, I should have known your dad
would raise the sensitive, artistic type.
Back then he didn't
do much raising.
Right, sorry.
Uh, he's just been
so generous with me.
I didn't mean to... "Generous"?
How?
Oh, my God, he totally
saved my dog's life.
My dad's still a human
neurologist, right?
Yep.
But, uh, he paid for
my dog's surgery.
He did? Yeah.
Gave me $2,000.
I didn't even have to ask.
Wow.
Bloom?
We've been trying to help Andy
Keener entirely the wrong way.
Are you screaming
right now, or is it just me?
I figured out what to give him.
Andy? ANDY: G.
Um...
We have done you
a great disservice.
You guys have the
best service in New York.
Every time you've
come to this hospital,
we have focused on treating
a whole host of symptoms.
I'd give you five stars on
Yelp if I had a computer.
That ends today. Scrips?
The, uh, fatigue, stress, heart
arrhythmia, malnutrition, you name it,
each of these
symptoms is the result of
you not having a stable
living environment.
This cure will fix all of that.
Mr. Keener...
I am prescribing you a home.
Morning.
Max in yet? Haven't seen him.
Day two can hit you
like a ton of bricks.
He might still be in bed. Okay.
Well, if you do see him...
I made it, I'm here. Sorry.
I made it. Call off the dogs.
How do you feel?
Oh, like a million bucks
that was shoved dollar by dollar
through an industrial shredder
and then set on
fire with a blowtorch.
Your feet, huh?
Points for Big Mike.
Swollen and sore. Thank you.
You should borrow some
Crocs from the nurses' stash.
They're super ugly but
they do make a difference.
And then you should...
You should sit down.
You should join us for euchre.
We could still use a fourth.
Appreciate the generous offer, Millie,
but this hospital never sleeps, so...
Back at it. I'm
going mobile again.
Max.
They know what they're
talking about. You should listen.
Well, Willow was
right. They are ugly,
but, man, I feel like
I'm walking on clouds.
Mmm. And Earl is
shaping up... I know, right?
To be far creepier than any
plastic bag has a right to be.
Now, that's just
mean, all right?
Maybe he could use a hat.
I, um...
I want you to know that I've
truly considered your offer...
Great.
And I...
I can't be your deputy, Max. Oh.
I'm barely maintaining the
commitments I already have,
and as you know I'm knee-deep
in oocyte cryopreservation.
When the time comes to
move forward with implantation...
I understand, I do.
What about Bloom?
Bloom? Yeah, she's reliable.
She's great under pressure.
Let me get back to you. Okay.
The wheels on the
bus go round and round
Round and round, round and round
So he really has to
be awake for this?
Yeah, yeah. It reduces the
risk of damaging critical areas
that control speech
and other skills.
And we can't have him draw,
so singing is the next best thing.
Go round and round
Round and round, round and round
Very good, Tony. Keep going.
Advancing the wire.
The wheels on
the bus go round...
And...
Pull back.
Round
Round and round All through
Let's keep going.
You know, you've raised
an amazing young man.
For his 13th birthday, he
begged me to take him to the Uffizi.
What kind of kid begs
to go to the Uffizi?
But I took him,
and he marched straight
up to The Birth of Venus.
Studied every detail.
And he knew what he
wanted to be when he grew up.
But then the wolf appeared
and never left.
And all that potential...
I just I hope the wolf goes away
so he can be that man again.
Max.
You must really enjoy
putting me through this,
because that is the only
explanation I can come up with.
Probably, but, uh, what
are we talking about?
Just explain to me
why I got a phone call
from a landlord on First Avenue
asking me if Andy
Keener has any pets.
Oh, that. I can explain that.
Yeah, I sure hope you can.
Yeah, uh, since I've only
been here at New Amsterdam
for a few weeks, the landlord
wouldn't let me co-sign his lease.
So, I, um, put your name down.
Did you? Yeah.
And who is Andy Keener, and
why are we renting
an apartment for him?
Uh, Andy is a,
um, frequent flyer.
His homelessness has cost this
hospital over $1 million this year alone,
and many of those costs will go away if
Andy simply has a full-time place to stay.
I mean, renting this man an apartment is
actually gonna save this hospital money.
So you suddenly decided
to care about money.
Well, I care about money
when it's only going to one patient
when it should be
going to thousands.
Right, so let's say I let
you do this, hypothetically.
Okay. And we rent this
apartment for a year.
Right. And then Andy
gets back on his feet
and he pays for
it himself, right?
No, we would be
paying for it for a while.
How long is "a while"?
Just, you know, forever.
Oh, Max. No, look,
I'm already solving one enormous
fiscal problem for this hospital.
I can't also solve...
This is socialism.
This is exactly what's wrong
with our whole health care system.
You're right. Somebody
really should fix it.
So this guy abuses the system
and he gets a free apartment.
What about all the other guys
who are working their asses off?
You think this is fair to
them? It's not fair to them,
but it's smart business for us.
We're talking about saving
over $1 million a year.
That's $1 million
that could be spent
on those very people who
are working their asses off.
Who do deserve more.
Andy better not have any pets.
Hey. Oh, no tea today?
No tea.
Just, uh... I'm sorry.
You were right. I was hovering.
But that's not because
I don't trust you.
I want to help you.
I obviously have no
idea how to do that.
Oh, that's all right.
I know your people like to
think that tea fixes everything.
Wow. That was
pretty good, right?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
That's a horrible accent.
So, look, I'm sorry too.
I shouldn't have
been so defensive.
Just, it was a lot rougher
than I thought it was gonna be.
You seem better today. Yeah.
Yeah, I, uh...
I got a lot of sleep.
Uh, okay, I gotta go to work.
Do you maybe want to grab
some dinner after work today?
Yeah. Yeah, sure.
Just, uh, meet me back
here when you're done.
Yeah. Okay.
I heard.
I'm sorry.
Yeah, thanks.
Max wants me to go "full chemo"
on this reporter.
I don't know what that means,
exactly, but here
are a few options.
Okay.
Step one, we pull the interview.
If she wants to write about a
10-year-old arrest, she can go right ahead,
but she can expect a
defamation suit to follow.
No doubt she indemnified the
publisher when she was hired,
so when we threaten to sue her
for libel and demand damages,
the onus will be on her.
Not on The New England
Cardiothoracic Journal.
And that's just step one?
Do you want to go
"full chemo" or not?
I can make it so this Penny
Atwater can't find a job
at The New England
Journal of Trout Fishing.
Damn, you're good.
It's just so typical.
It's like if you're
African-American
and you're exemplary,
they're always
looking for a catch.
I just want my nephew
to know that you can be exemplary
without a catch, you know?
As your legal representation,
I can make this all go away.
But as your girlfriend,
I think you should
own your story.
Not in spite of your nephew.
Because of your nephew.
He should know the truth.
All of it.
Well,
here we are.
It's safe to come
all the way in.
Well, will you look at that?
Stove works. Good to know.
I haven't made
myself a cup of coffee
in decades.
Look, Andy, uh, I know
this place isn't much but...
No.
It's an awful lot, Dr. Goodwin.
When do I need
to be out of here?
No, uh, this isn't temporary.
Andy, this place is yours
as long as you want it.
Just no pets.
Other than that,
you make the rules.
All of this is mine?
Welcome home, Andy.
Floyd?
You wanna begin?
Yeah.
It was, uh...
It was 2008.
Election night.
And we're having this big party
out in Connecticut where I
was interning at a hospital.
And, uh,
it was electric.
I remember I never felt so,
uh, empowered, you know?
So present.
So American.
I felt invincible and
I was on my way home
back to my apartment,
and I remember I rolled the windows
down so that I could feel that cool breeze.
And the empty road.
And then
flashing red lights.
Siren.
I was getting pulled over.
And I checked the speedometer,
only three miles over the speed limit.
Officer asked me to step out.
Still had on my scrubs.
Showed him my hospital
badge but he didn't like my tone.
And I begged him.
I begged him to
just give me a ticket.
Nope.
There I was, face-down
on my own hood
with my arms cuffed
behind my back
on a night that started
out at my dream internship
celebrating this newfound
hope for America.
Ended with me in a holding
cell, stripped of my dignity.
Waiting for my sister to catch the
next train up, so she could bail me out.
Not even a Morehouse
College license plate
or a Yale Med School
bumper sticker could save me.
No, a mug shot,
that you found,
as a lifelong souvenir.
You know, I was ashamed
of that night for a long time.
That's why I...
That's why I buried it.
You know, that's why I
tried to forget all about it.
I mean, the fact that you
were so eager to shoehorn it
into an article that purports
to celebrate a black doctor,
I mean...
That says very little about me.
I'm a good surgeon.
Period.
That's your story.
What are you doing here?
Can't I just stop by to say hi?
Any time. All the time.
Would you like to go for dinner?
There's a nice Indian
restaurant down the street.
The food tastes exactly
like your mother's cooking.
Actually, I have
plans with Ella.
Ella?
Turns out we have
the same taste in music.
Weird, right?
Where are you going?
We're gonna go
see this band play.
The bassist is a friend of mine.
We used to jam together a lot.
He was gonna help
me with the demo.
Okay.
Anyway,
thanks for introducing us.
You paged? BLOOM: I did.
What happened?
Uh, he says he fell off a
ladder and hit his head.
Make that 1.5 million.
Hey.
Hey, uh, so can we please go
somewhere not healthy, for once?
I mean, I actually
think I hate salad.
Uh, Dr. Bloom?
Can I ask you to take a quick
look at a patient in Bay 4?
So close.
Okay, um, I'm
gonna be right back.
Your job is to Google dive bars.
I want a giant,
disgusting burger.
Ew.
Lauren.
Lauren!
You're not real.
Buddy, you need a hand?
You know what?
That'd be awesome, thanks.
All right, thanks, man.
You should really go see a
doctor, man. That's a good idea.
Max.
Where are you? 33rd and Park.
I don't think I can make it.
Stay there, I'm coming to you.
I don't understand.
Well, it's, um... It's
an agricultural co-op.
It's not a hospital.
No, it's not.
What kind of medicine
do they practice there?
None.
They don't practice
medicine there.
That's the point.
You're suggesting I... I
send my son away without me
to a farm?
To a place where they
claim the way to fix him
is to pretend
that he's not sick?
You know, Hector, one of the keys to
avoiding relapse in delusional disorders
is environment.
Plain and simple. And
Tony's current environment,
it's not helping. You know?
You mean me?
And me.
And this hospital.
That...
That boy is the
pride of my life.
I know.
He needs his father.
Someone who will... loves him.
Who will run
through walls for him.
No, no, no.
Listen, listen, listen.
You're trying to fix him.
We're all trying to fix him.
And on a very deep,
profound level, Tony feels that.
He knows it, and it's
making him worse.
This place will
accept him as he is.
You're telling me
to stop trying to
make him better?
To not be his father?
You told me
that to help Tony,
you'd be willing to
risk losing some of him.
This is how you do that.
Andy?
You gonna take
away my apartment?
No.
I don't know what to do.
I guess I just like it here.
Think we're the only ones.
You are always welcome here
when you're sick.
And when you're not sick,
we have a lot of people
that we have to take care of,
and that's just the
way it has to be.
I'll... I'll leave.
No problem.
Excuse me?
Sorry, does anyone know
how to get to the ICU?
Oh, dude, you can't get to
the 12th floor from this building.
You gotta take the
elevator to the 3rd floor,
then take the
breezeway to Harriman.
Then you take the second
set of elevators to 12.
Then you walk to
the end of the hall.
Thanks, man. You're a lifesaver.
Andy...
Do you know how to get
to the Oncology Ward?
Of course, I've had many the
nonexistent tumor examined there.
How would you like to start
paying off that apartment?
How?
By spending a little more
time at New Amsterdam.
Hey, champ.
You got time to
rap for a minute?
I got something to tell you.
And I'm hoping you
can still be proud of me.
All inside our
Amsterdam she hides
Watery-eyed
I... I can draw there?
You can draw and paint
and just be you.
If you want, Tony.
If it'll make you
happy, I'll let you go.
Oh, silhouette
She's growing tall and fine
She's got my back
She'll follow me
down every street
No matter what my crime
Lauren.
Done enough good for one day?
Think I'm gonna puke.
We paid enough for those chairs.
I think that our medical director
deserves to try them out sometime.
I don't want
everyone to see me so
weak.
You know?
It's why I can't
let Georgia come.
Why I can't sit in that chair.
Everybody's gonna see me.
The answer's yes, Max.
I'll be your deputy.
But you... Go.
Be weak.
Sit.
I won't watch.
Millie.
Glaciers are moving.
Children are being born.
Can you shuffle any faster?
I... I think I just went from a
stage three to a stage four.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Room for a fourth?
Yeah, always. Unfortunately.
Loving your slipper game, dude.
Oh, yeah, thanks.
I'm, uh, feeling
pretty good about it.
Those are pretty sharp yourself.
Okay, so, uh, these are mine,
I take it. Whose are those?
Those are Stevie's.
Our old fourth.
We always deal him in.
Hmm.
You know how to
play euchre, Max?
Uh...
I'll catch on.