Sorry, Dr. Andrews, I had a patient
with some post-op arm pain.
- How can I help you?
- What's happened to all the nurses?
Hello. My name is Dr. Shaun Murphy,
surgical resident, year three.
I will be assisted by Dr. Claire Browne
on today's open appendectomy.
I will not be putting on my sterile gloves
myself, as I am lead surgeon.
Nurse Fletch, can you adjust
the overhead light?
- How many degrees, Dr. Murphy?
- Yes, I should be more specific.
A 35-degree angle.
Nurse Hawks,
please hand me the 10 blade.
Straight clamp, please, Nurse Fletch.
Hello, Dr. Andrews. I'm going to try
to pretend you're not here.
You have not pretended to scrub in
and may not be here
when here is there,
there being OR Two later today.
You don't need a full surgical team
to rehearse.
Some of the staff needs
to get back to their stations.
No, they can stay here.
Chief Lim has assigned me
my second first surgery.
And she assigned them all to me,
and told me to rehearse with all of them
unless and until there's an emergency
on their floor.
Dr. Browne, please hand me the Bovie.
Dr. Browne had a dental appointment.
I'm doing my best to be annoyingly
caring and empathetic in her stead.
There's the baby...
and there's the mass...
way too close together.
A biopsy is out of the question.
The best course is to go in
and remove the entire mass.
Will that be dangerous for the baby?
The odds of your daughter
being harmed are very low.
And what about recovery time?
How long?
Normal recovery's about three weeks.
We're opening a specialty toy store.
I need to be up and about in a week.
- Tell them, Andre.
- Sustainable natural toys.
Good for the kids,
good for the world.
I don't really wanna leave Andre
to fight the crowds alone.
A week is not realistic.
Too much stress after the surgery
could put the pregnancy at risk.
It's okay.
Andre worries.
Thought it was too much
to start a business and a family
all before our first anniversary.
Business and family are easy.
If I'd known it was business
and family and cancer, I...
might have waited on one of them.
Let's just worry about the surgery
right now.
Dr. Lim.
Just came from Dr. Murphy's
improv class.
Don't remember Browne getting a full
team rehearsal before her first surgery.
Our residents are not homogeneous.
Each one requires different attention
and training.
I agree. And for Shaun,
that means less training wheels
and more scabbed knees.
Trust me, his knees will get scabbed.
I'm trying to prevent a decapitation.
- If he's not ready...
- Why don't you follow your own advice?
You think this is the wrong option,
stop telling me.
Let me fail and learn.
But be sure to apologize
when you realize I was right.
The appendix can be removed
in various ways,
including suture ligation,
purse-stringing
and inversion appendectomy.
I will be using
the suture ligation technique.
Dr. Browne,
place a clamp just proximal
to the distal ligature
on the appendix.
How's it going with Carly?
Divide sharply and cauterize
the exposed mucosa.
Isn't dating life wonderful?
Everything you hoped it would be?
Okay.
Please refrain from asking
non-surgical questions, Morgan.
I need to concentrate on the next
step in my OR management.
And I need to be Claire.
Any chance she's not concerned
about your personal well-being
and inquire repeatedly?
Things are going well, Dr. Browne.
We make out a lot.
Let's close the peritoneal cavity.
Did you guys have lots of fun
on your last day off?
I went to the museum.
Nurse Hawks, please check
the patient's vitals.
Everything looks normal.
You went alone?
I called Carly at her house to see if
she wanted to play Chinese checkers.
Close the external oblique fascia
with a continuous 2-0 Vicryl stitch.
Although, they're not really Chinese,
it's actually a game of German origin
called "Sternhalma."
It's very fun.
I will use 4-0 Monocryl subcuticular
interrupted sutures for skin closure.
However, Carly said she could not
hang out because she was busy.
If the wound was contaminated,
we could leave in a Penrose drain
and remove it two to three days later,
but it is not.
She had friends over. I could
hear laughing in the background.
Dr. Browne, approximate
all split muscle layers.
That's odd.
Nothing is odd.
We just have two more steps and...
No, that whatever she was doing,
she didn't invite you.
Why?
She isn't treating you
like a boyfriend.
You don't exclude your significant other
from a get-together.
Not true.
It could've been a family thing.
Or she thinks it's too early
to introduce you to friends.
It's also possible that there was
no get-together at all.
I mean, maybe you just heard
the television.
Maybe she just doesn't see you
as her boyfriend.
Has she ever called
you her boyfriend?
We have practiced enough.
You had a dental appointment
this morning.
The reason you're late.
So brush extra well
and don't forget to floss.
Thanks.
Don't take this the wrong way,
but when did you get so slutty?
I'm not.
Thank you for covering, now...
This smells like it's been dipped
in Drakkar cologne.
Do you really care what I wear
or what I do?
I care when you're late. About the
extra work I do covering for you.
I was an hour late, how much
extra work could that be?
One hour's worth.
You can thank me by taking
two hours off my hands.
Thank you.
Hey, Shaun.
Hello.
Waiting for Carly?
I want to know why she did not
invite me to her get-together.
Might have a better chance of finding out
if you were physically closer.
Maybe later.
This prescription should help him
feel a little bit better.
And if I may suggest,
don't store the chocolate laxatives
in the candy drawer.
- Hi.
- Hey.
I was wondering
if you could get away for lunch.
Yeah. Let me see if I can move
some things around. Come on in.
All right.
I got fired.
- What?
- Mm-hm.
- What happened?
- I was giving away free coffee.
We work in a hospital
and I hear a lot of sad stories.
And sometimes, when they're really sad,
I like to give that person a free coffee
and it makes them smile.
And yes, okay, I know
it's against policy.
But you'd think my asshat boss
would give me more than two warnings
- before giving me the ax.
- Okay.
What do you want me to do?
Beat him up?
I want you to come home for lunch
and I wanna bitch about my ex-boss
and I want someone there to...
listen.
Okay.
Use a tenaculum to grasp the
lesion to create countertraction.
I'm gonna separate the mass
from the underlying myometrium.
Damn it. Let's get suction.
The mass has surrounded
the uterine arteries.
We can't remove the mass
without killing the baby.
Dr. Reznick, if you were lead,
how would you proceed?
We're already in, so...
I'd biopsy the mass for testing.
Then perform an embolization
of the arteries feeding the tumor.
Very good. Dr. Park, what does that do?
It should allow us
to control the bleeding
so we can leave the baby
in place for two months.
That'll give the baby time
to become viable outside the womb.
At that point, we go back in,
safely take out the baby and the mass.
Sounds like the right call to me.
We'll be performing an embolization
of the arteries feeding the tumor.
- I'll inform Chief Lim.
- Not necessary.
It's protocol to run all decisions
about complex procedures
by the chief of surgery.
There's only one clear path,
which means there is no decision.
In my office, please.
I didn't think you'd mind.
We always complained about Andrews
and his red tape.
I hoped our relationship is better
than whatever you had with Andrews.
It is. But you're busy,
- you don't need...
- You know how this makes me look?
You know how this makes me look?
This job was on your to-do list.
The lab must have made a mistake.
I'll deal with it.
We might have a bigger issue
than you lying about the blood test.
I'm not lying.
Like I said, this is a bigger issue.
Shaun is distracted.
- Well, why would he be...
- Because you were at the dentist.
Nurse Hawks asked questions.
Carly didn't invite Shaun to something,
and now he's worried
they're not boyfriend and girlfriend.
- So did you talk to him?
- No, that's what you do.
Think I put it on your list,
"Be kind and care," so I don't have to.
- Okay, I'll talk to him.
- Talk to Carly first.
Do it when you drop off the blood vials
and pretend it's the second time.
This is good, you were wasted there.
I was happy there.
I love that hospital.
I love... I love the staff
and the patients. It just...
It felt like home.
Here's a thought.
What if I come work with you?
I saw your waiting room,
you need the help.
- We have an office manager.
- She doesn't manage. She's never there.
I was a nurse.
I could schedule your appointments,
I could triage the walk-ins.
It's like a win-win.
I don't think we have the budget
for new employees.
Aaron, that's horse crap.
You're the president.
What's the real reason?
I... I think couples...
that are apart now and then,
it's a good thing.
Couples together 24/7?
I don't want to get to the point
where we come home
and we run to opposite
sides of the house.
Okay, it was just a thought.
Just gonna...
keep looking.
Hi, Carly.
Replacement vials.
For some reason the bloodwork
for Shaun's case was never processed.
- That doesn't sound right.
- Why is not important.
But if you could put a rush on them.
If the tests get delayed any longer,
Shaun's surgery
could get rescheduled.
There's no record of bloodwork
dropped off for Shaun.
If his surgery gets rescheduled, Shaun
will lose the team he's practiced with.
It might throw him.
Shaun doesn't get thrown by
anything medical.
Shaun is already thrown.
He has it in his head that you dissed him,
that maybe there's a problem.
And now he seems distracted, upset.
I wondered if you could speak with him,
let him know everything's okay.
I'll make sure to put a rush
on the blood tests.
Thank you.
My wife says
that the earth is a womb,
and when you garden, you
become part of its birthing process.
Not that I mind sharing hobbies
with her, it keeps us close.
And I don't mind the dirt in my eyes.
Just could do with a little less
of the talking.
I feel you.
You don't by any chance possess
the power of flight?
- What?
- You have a wing in your eye.
- I'm sorry?
- Just hold still.
Ow.
Congratulations. Your womb
just gave birth to a bee.
Ew.
Triplets, in fact.
Dr.. Glassman,
I need to compartmentalize.
Hi, Shaun.
Nurse Hawks says girlfriends invite
their boyfriends to get-togethers.
That means it's possible Carly
did not invite me
because I am not her boyfriend.
But we make out
and she wants to hold my hand
and she lets me touch her breasts.
Those are things you do
with a boyfriend.
Now all I think about is Carly.
Even when I'm supposed to be doing
my job. I do not like it.
I tried to talk to her, but I can't.
- You can't talk to her?
- I can't.
I need to compartmentalize.
Well, Shaun, you're very good
at compartmentalizing.
Were you wearing your white lab coat
when you tried to talk to her?
No, I was in my surgical scrubs.
Okay. See, we all struggle to...
To separate our work life
with our personal life, right?
That's why we wear uniforms.
It tells us, it tells the world:
"This is what I have to focus on right now,
I can't worry about anything else."
- That makes sense.
- Good.
So when Carly's wearing
her white lab coat,
she's just a co-worker,
not a girl you happen to be seeing
at the moment.
When you're wearing your lab coat,
you say to yourself,
"I'm a doctor, damn it.
I'm not gonna worry
about everything else."
Say to yourself, "I'm a doctor,
romance doesn't matter."
I'm a doctor,
romance doesn't matter.
I am a doctor,
Um, you're wearing a white lab coat.
Wanna be a doctor
and get the other bees out?
You make a fair point.
- Looking for Murphy?
- Yep.
- Blood test being expedited?
- Yes.
Did you own your mistake
or blame some innocent clerk?
How did it feel? Is it eating at you?
You mean, how do I live one moment
behaving how you do constantly?
At least I'm consistent, even when
I'm going through my own issues.
Shaun?
- Why aren't you wearing your white coat?
- I am a civilian.
Medicine doesn't matter.
You're not leaving.
Your surgery is in six hours.
Did you speak to Carly?
I need to talk to Carly.
Shaun, why did we practice
this morning?
Because...
- I'm not good at communication.
- Exactly.
But with practice, you can do it.
Talk to me.
Tell me the problem,
tell me how you feel.
Okay.
I have to talk to Carly.
Shaun, stop.
You don't have to talk to Carly.
Everything is fine, I talked to her
and it was just
all a misunderstanding.
Why did she not invite me over
to meet her friends?
There were no friends.
Uh, the laughing you heard,
it must have been a podcast
she was listening to.
I need to get my lab coat.
Told you you're better
at this than I am.
Though you could have
jumped in earlier.
We were able to do a biopsy
and the mass is non-malignant.
We've stabilized it, but it does
still need to be removed.
- When?
- Two months.
By then the baby
will be viable outside the...
I don't feel well.
My vision's getting blurry.
- Your blood pressure's tanking.
- What?
- Doctor, what's happening to her?
- Page Dr. Melendez.
Hello. My name is Dr. Shaun Murphy,
surgical resident, year three.
I will be assisted by Dr. Claire Browne
on today's open appendectomy.
I will not be putting on
my number seven sterile gloves myself
as I am lead surgeon.
Nurse Fletch...
can you adjust the overhead light?
Adjust to a 35-degree angle.
Nurse Hawks,
please hand me the ten blade.
The arterial embolization
was rejected above the bladder.
The mass is seeping blood,
and we have to go in again
or she'll slowly bleed to death.
We deliver the baby early, have an
incubator and ventilator in the OR.
Even with maximal NICU support,
the baby's chance of survival
is around 15 to 20 percent.
Maybe we were wrong the first time.
Maybe we can leave the child
and work around her.
We can suction resect
this friable lesion
and control the bleeding better
with the argon beam coagulator.
Very easy to go too far,
cause a uterine rupture.
If we don't screw up, the baby gets to stay
in the womb and grow to term.
- Nice.
- I'll go book an OR.
Wait.
One more thing we need to do.
It's a good plan,
but the safest course of action
is to deliver prematurely
and remove the mass.
By "deliver prematurely,"
you mean terminate the pregnancy.
Not necessarily. But yes.
To save her life.
If I place internal
iliac artery balloon catheters,
I can control most bleeding as it happens.
Most?
I've performed surgeries
a lot more complicated
- under more difficult circumstances.
- When you had no other option.
You have a choice, a safer choice,
the mother's life takes precedence.
That's our policy.
Are we sure it's hers?
Okay. Go make your case.
Thank you.
Neil.
Thank you for getting my approval.
It's your job.
I will now use electrocautery
to incise through both
the fascia and muscles.
Can I please get a measurement
on the patient's pulse,
blood pressure and temperature?
Pulse is at 65.
Pressure 118 over 82
and temp is normal at 98.6 degrees.
Thank you for hearing and responding.
The appendix can be removed
in various ways.
I will be using
the suture ligation technique.
Dr. Browne, can you identify the
ascending colon and its taenia coli?
- I see it.
- Thank you.
Please free
the appendix-mesoappendix complex
from its adjacent tissue.
Babcock clamps.
We must have nicked an ileocolic
branch of the SMA.
Get suction on it, Dr. Browne.
Nurse Fletch, please use lap sponges
to stem the bleed.
- If she hemorrhages, she could die?
- That is a possibility.
But if you're successful,
then I complete my pregnancy.
No, it's too risky.
If Dr. Melendez says he can do it...
Do the other surgery, the one where
you take the baby out and save Patty.
I'm the one carrying the baby.
I'm the one going through the surgery.
- It's not your choice.
- I didn't want this baby.
Sorry, I...
We can have another child
some other time.
But I can't replace you.
I don't want another baby.
I want the one that's been giving me
morning sickness for the last
23 weeks.
I want the one
who's been giving me heartburn,
constipation and insomnia.
That's the baby that I wanna hold.
And I couldn't live with the guilt...
if I killed our baby
to save my own life.
Performing a suture ligation
with two interrupted 2-0 Vicryl sutures.
Dr. Browne, cauterize
the exposed mucosa.
I may owe Dr. Lim an apology.
- Continue.
- Yes.
We still need to copiously irrigate
the wound with normal saline,
grasp the peritoneum
with two straight clamps,
and close it up
with a continuous 3-0 Vicryl stitch.
Irrigating.
Straight clamp, please, Nurse...
Straight clamp, please, Nurse Hawks.
You are handing them
to me incorrectly.
I'm sorry?
You are handing them
to me incorrectly.
This is how I always do it.
You do it wrong.
- Shaun.
- I don't know how else to do it.
You can do it the right way.
- What's the right way?
- The efficient way.
- Efficient?
- Yes.
There is historical precedence...
to my preference.
- Please just take the clamp.
- I can't.
Of course you can.
Take the damn clamp.
You need to leave.
Nurse Hawks...
you need to leave the OR.
Leave now.
Dr. Reznick, please cauterize
those bleeders with the argon coagulator.
I nicked an artery.
She's hemorrhaging.
Hang four units on the rapid infuser.
Give me a vascular clamp.
The surgery was successful,
the patient's vital signs are stable...
You can't solve
your interpersonal problems
- by making people go away.
- There was a bleed.
You threw the nurse out
because of a bleed?
Yes.
Because we nicked the ileocolic
branch of the SMA,
Nurse Fletch was attending
to the lap sponges,
so Nurse Hawks had to hand me the
straight clamp and she did it wrong.
And she refused to do it right.
Did you tell her how to?
I wanted my straight clamp
handed to me at a 45-degree angle.
So I do not have to bend my wrist
to go from handoff
to the surgical field.
Did you explain all of that to her?
I told her to do it the efficient way.
I want you to apologize
to Nurse Hawks.
No, no.
Why would I apologize
because she did not do it right?
Because you didn't either.
When you're lead surgeon,
you're in charge.
Which means if anything goes wrong,
it's your fault.
Do you understand?
You've gotta make this right.
Okay.
You could have stepped in
and kept this situation from escalating.
You have your way
of dealing with Shaun.
And so do I.
We need better control.
Clamp off the common iliac.
There's too much blood to see in here.
We have to take the baby out.
Page the on-call neonatologist.
They're gonna have a 23-week-old girl
coming their way very soon.
Second time in as many days
you've dropped by unexpectedly.
Starting to think you like me.
- I got a job offer.
- Well, there you go, that was quick.
- Let's go celebrate.
- I'm not gonna take the offer.
I wanna work here with you.
We've already talked about that.
You talked, I listened.
Now it's my turn to talk.
We got married to be here
for each other,
even when the other one didn't know
they need it.
You're so busy with your patients
you don't see that the clinic
is starting to suffer.
Right now it's
double-booked appointments.
Next, it could be
the wrong medication prescribed.
- I'd never let that happen.
- I'm a good partner.
I'm good at home, on the weekends.
I could be equally as good here
in this office.
Okay, if it doesn't work out, I'll quit.
Or you can fire me.
No harm, no foul.
Nothing is ever as simple
as "no harm, no foul."
Got a resume?
Well, I was...
hoping...
to avoid that.
I read a study that said
sharing a cup of coffee with colleagues
promotes professionalism.
My cup is empty because I do not like
the way coffee makes me feel.
I've had a long day.
Can I just enjoy my lunch?
Chief Lim asked me
to apologize to you.
Okay.
The earliest known drawing
of a pivoting surgical instrument
dates back to 1500 BC on a tomb
at Thebes, Egypt.
This does not sound like
the beginning of an apology.
I want to explain why I prefer
the straight clamp handed to me
at a 45-degree angle.
Putting it in historical
context will help.
You need to stop.
In the ninth century, Albucasis,
known as the father of surgery...
- You need to go away.
- No, I need you to understand,
because if you see why I'm right,
you will see there is no reason
for me to apologize.
- She's gone into unstable V-tach.
- We're gonna need the defibrillator.
Charging.
Clear.
- Continue compressions.
- One milligram of epinephrine.
- She's gone into V-fib. Shock again.
- Charging. Clear.
I'm gonna crack her chest.
I'm gonna do an open-heart massage.
Heart's exposed.
Starting the massage.
Internal cardiac paddles.
Charging.
Clear.
Again.
Charge. Clear.
Charge.
Clear.
Open the uterus and get the baby.
All you had to do
was say you're sorry.
I tried to explain
why the straight clamp...
I don't hear the word "sorry."
I don't hear any taking of responsibility.
You said I had to make this right.
An apology seemed to be
just one possible way...
Shaun, she filed a complaint.
- No. No.
- Yes.
You have a problem with communication.
- But I am...
- I'm going to make this clear.
You screwed up.
- No. No.
- Yes. Yeah, you were wrong.
You are wrong. You screwed up.
This incident will
be noted in your file.
And if this, or anything like this,
happens again,
that will be the end
of your residency.
Now, what do you have to say?
You're sorry?
I failed.
I'm sorry.
Good.
Now go say those words
to Nurse Hawks...
and mean them.
I spoke to Carly.
You're a terrible fairy godmother.
You swoop in,
enchant the hero with a lie
and you carry on
like you made his world better.
Shaun was about to talk to Carly.
That's what he needed to do.
I think Carly's pissed at him.
Fine, then she's pissed at him.
They deal with it.
Shaun's problem is communication.
You made it worse.
Shaun needed to get his head straight
before his first solo surgery.
That is what I did.
I fixed the problem.
You buried the problem.
Which seems to be your general
approach to life right now.
Hey, Shaun.
Hello.
We need to talk.
You're mad at me.
Yes.
Because whenever you have a problem,
I hear it from Glassman,
or Claire, or Morgan.
Anyone but you.
I'm sorry.
Good.
Shaun, stop!
This is the problem. You have to tell me
what's bothering you.
Why did you not invite me
to your get-together last Sunday?
I had some old friends over.
We were gonna drink
and play a little poker.
My friends are snarky.
They tease and play practical jokes
on each other,
and I knew that you wouldn't like that
and that it would get weird,
so I decided not to invite you.
That's it...
the whole story.
My father...
always sent me to my room...
when he would play poker
with his friends.
They were loud...
and they would tease me.
They said I talked funny.
Is that what your friends
were going to say?
- No, Shaun. Of course not.
- Then what were they going to do?
Nothing, I guess.
It's just...
Sometimes, when you bring the guy
that you're dating into the mix,
that relationship changes.
It can be a disaster.
Was it a disaster...
every time you brought a date
to meet your friends?
- No, some fit right in.
- Then how did you know...
How did you know
it would be a disaster with me?
I didn't.
I made an assumption...
and I shouldn't have done that.
I'm sorry too.
Can you forgive me?
I wasn't a great girlfriend.
"Girlfriend"?
- You're my girlfriend?
- Yeah.
- Does that mean I'm your boyfriend?
- You are.
Oh. I forgive you.
- Can I kiss you?
- Okay.
- I'm glad we talked.
- Me too.
I'll introduce you
to my friends next week.
No, thank you. I would not like
to meet your friends.
- Okay.