Hi, Mark.
Hi, Susan.
Excuse me?
What?
You just called me Susan.
No, I didn't.
Yeah, you did.
I guess she's on your mind, huh?
Not necessarily.
I wish you guys would just
hurry up and get married.
What?!
You're perfect for each other.
I mean, you almost
went on vacation together
You knew about that?
Mark, everybody knew about that.
What I don't get is
why you backed out.
She didn't want me to go.
Mark, she wanted you to go.
She did?
Oh, yeah.
Nobody told me.
Look, just do us all
a favor; ask her out.
We need some fresh
gossip around here.
Oh, man, do I need some sleep.
You? At least you
get off in 11 hours.
I've got 18 to go.
Where's Benton?
He still in the E.R.?
No. He's where he's been
most of the last six days.
Still with that baby, huh?
I'm telling you, the
man is obsessed.
Damn it, Epson, I told
you to keep an eye on him.
That's what I told the nurses.
We must find him.
I'll find him.
He's probably in the cafeteria.
Well, he better not have eaten.
Oh, hey, you guys, listen...
Have you seen a male patient
about, uh, this tall;
kind of peculiar?
Sorry. Lost one, huh?
Yeah, great case. Guy's
got a tumor in his throat
the size of a golf ball.
He needs an esophagectomy.
Anspaugh brought in
some hotshot from Japan.
We're all set to go;
the patient goes AWOL.
Tough break.
Listen, you guys help
me find him, I'll get you in
on the surgery.
Well, we'll keep our eyes open.
Great, thanks, dudes.
Listen, he's got a sweet tooth
so check the vending machines.
Yeah, right.
You know, last shift
he left me three
lines to change.
I had to pick up his labs.
Did you have breakfast yet?
I'm starving.
You paged me?
Yeah. Her abdomen's distended.
Crit's down to 30.
She's hemorrhaging.
We need to take her
off the anticoagulants...
That means taking
her off the machine.
Can she live off it?
I doubt she'll last a day
but there's no other choice.
Well, then maybe we should
get her back up to the O.R.
Her platelets are too low.
Then we've got to
transfuse her. We just did.
Look, Dr. Keaton, I mean,
we've got to try something.
We can't just...
At this point
the best thing to do is nothing.
I also think, that
for the time being
you should be more of an
observer than an active participant.
You mean on this case?
On all the cases.
You know, Dr. Keaton...
I'd do anything
to undo what I did
but I can't.
This isn't a punishment, Peter
but you have a tendency
to act without thinking.
If you want to grow as a surgeon
you've got to learn
more patience.
Hear ye, hear ye,
who wants taffy?
Ah, homemade, perchance?
Saltwater. Pulled it myself.
Don't mind if I do.
Excuse me.
Do you have change
for the candy machine?
Um... let me see...
Yeah.
Quarters okay?
Yes.
Uh, excuse me, Cuz.
You owe me a buck.
I-I don't have one.
Then you're SOL.
Jerry, Connie's sick.
We gotta call in a float.
Yeah, I already did.
Well, call them back.
I want to approve
whoever they send.
Why?
Could someone call security?!
There is a man urinating
in the phone booth.
That's why.
Did anyone hear me?
Yes, Rhonda, we heard you.
You don't need
security, you need a mop
and the mop is in the corner.
I don't mop.
Way to go, Jer.
How was I supposed to know?
I wonder how long
we can sit here
before anyone
notices we're missing.
We'll never know.
You just jinxed it.
What do you mean?
Oh...
That's what I mean.
It's Benton.
It couldn't happen to a nicer...
What's that?
It's the E.R..
You want to trade?
No. No way.
Oh. John, hi.
Hi, Dr. Keaton.
I got that review article
you dropped off for me
on congenital hernias.
Yeah, I, I heard
you were doing one
and I didn't know whether
or not you read it, or...
Well, actually,
I helped edit it.
Oh. Well, then...
but it was very sweet of you.
See you.
Something going on
I should know about?
Please...
And when was your
last bowel movement?
Uh, well, technically...
That would have been
Monday afternoon.
Monday afternoon...
Which is a little
unusual for me.
I'm generally a morning person.
Morning person...
And then, uh,
sometimes in the evening
I pass a little gas.
Gas in the evening...
We don't take lengthy
histories in the E.R.
I believe in being thorough.
Well, when your patient is in
for an extended stay on the ward
that may be appropriate
but down here, we keep
our notes short and sweet.
That's not the way I do things.
The longer it takes
the longer the patient
waits in distress.
Well, that's all right.
We were having
a nice little chat.
Anything else?
Now, where were we?
Gas in the evenings.
Oh... yes.
We'll need some
saline, four-oh nylon
and a suture setup.
Coming up.
I know the squirrels
look cute, Arthur
but, uh, I wouldn't
try petting one again.
He was trying to eat it.
Oh.
You all right,
Wendy? It's not me.
Oh, he's choking!
His airway's blocked.
Oh, my God.
It's my taffy!
We'll Heimlich him.
It was meant for the staff!
He's dying, Wendy! You
want to give me a hand?
One, two, three!
Oh! God!
Jesus, there's still a
lot more down there.
How much taffy did you make?
Two pounds.
Get a Magill and
hook up the suction.
Arthur, go back to
the waiting room.
What's a patient in a
surgical gown doing
down here, anyway?
Call upstairs.
I think we might've just
found Dale's AWOL patient.
Just lay back, sir.
Where do you want him?
All right. What's this?
13-year-old. Full arrest.
Took two bullets
to chest and belly.
How long has he been down?
Been working on him for 15.
Any signs of life? Negative.
Let's transfer him over.
Give me four units O-negative.
On my count. One, two, three.
Here's one entry.
I got the other one.
What happened?
Some gang thing.
He's a banger. Look at the tats.
Flatline.
How long was he down
before you got there?
About five, ten minutes.
Anybody give him CPR?
No, they were just
standing around.
So he was down
for... 20 minutes?
At least.
Pupils are fixed and dilated.
This kid is dead, very dead.
You calling it?
Yeah.
Time of Death: 8:26.
This the GSW?
He's been down for 20
minutes. He's not coming back.
You giving up on him?
He had no sign
of life in the field.
Lydia, start bagging him.
Thoracotomy tray.
Peter, I called it.
Gant, let's get a
cutdown on the ankles.
Hold on. Hold on.
Let's get some
blood into him now.
This kid's been
down for 20 minutes.
We can bring him back.
His brain is mush.
All right, ten blade...
His parents don't
want him ripped open.
I'm sure they want us
to do the most we can.
Lydia, go get Mark. Go get Mark!
Get the O-neg on
the rapid infuser.
Rib spreader. Let's go, Chuny.
God... it's like rubber.
It's all in the cornstarch.
Scissors.
Yeah.
I think it is coming loose.
Carter, what are you
doing to my patient?
He swallowed
two pounds of taffy.
Saltwater.
There it is.
Shame on you, Mr. Percy.
You know better than
to eat before surgery.
I'm sorry.
No harm done. Nothing
can get past that tumor.
We need to move.
All right, let's take him up.
Hey, Dale, remember me?
Oh, yeah. John.
I'd ask you to join us,
but we're a little crowded.
Well, I think we can make room.
After all, Carter
saved your keister.
Did you consent Mr. Percy?
I did.
All that's left to do is an
art line and he's ready to go.
Carter, you do the line
and Edson, you prep the OR.
Dr. Okida likes the temperature
to be precisely 67 degrees.
Precisely.
Have you got the O-neg running?
Two lines, wide open.
What's the story?
The kid was down
20 minutes. I called it.
Peter is now playing God.
The kid was out in the cold.
Peter already started,
might as well let him finish.
He's dead, Mark.
Maybe.
This was my patient.
I assessed him as unsalvageable.
And you should
support my assessment.
He's not just your
patient, Doug.
Gant, get over here.
Put your finger in the hole.
High dose epi.
Behind you.
All right, start
internal massage.
Like this?
Just keep squeezing.
Anything?
Still flatline.
Whoa, it jumped.
He's got a rhythm.
That's the epi, not his heart.
That's more than the epi.
All right. You brought him back.
Great. His heart's
back. His head's dead.
You don't know that.
All right. Call the O.R.
Tell them we're on our way up.
Okay. Here we go, people.
Let's move.
Thanks, Haleh.
Here we go.
Hello, Dr. Lewis.
What's the matter, E-Ray?
I just don't feel like myself.
You have a fever?
No, but I had an MRI
yesterday on my shoulder...
An old Conga injury...
And ever since, I just feel off.
Could it be radiation sickness?
MRI's aren't radioactive.
They just scramble
your electrons a bit.
Forever?
No, just for a few seconds.
That's odd.
What?
My watch stopped.
Oh, my God.
What?
My watch stopped last night
right after the MRI.
And the toaster.
What toaster?
My toaster.
It shorted out this morning.
I've had that
toaster for ten years.
So?
Could the MRI have
rearranged my molecules
causing me to radiate
some sort of bizarre
electronic interference?
No.
Follow the light with your eyes.
What light?
That's funny.
What have we got, Peter?
13-year-old, GSW to the
abdomen and pulmonary artery.
We clamped him in the
E.R. and got his heart back.
Downtime?
15 minutes.
Well, actually closer to 20,
but he was out in the cold
so we may be able
to save his brain.
You giving odds?
Dr. Greene and I both felt
we should keep trying.
This could take all day but,
in for a penny, in for a pound.
He's bleeding from
the belly wound.
I'd go for a midline incision.
I thought I was just
supposed to observe.
In this case, I'll
make an exception.
It's all yours.
All right... all right.
Mark a 9:35 start time.
Oh, Mark. Got a ten-foot fall.
Yeah? Where from?
A tree, taking
pictures in Grant Park.
Dizzy? Nauseous?
Dizzy, yes. Nauseous, no.
What were you taking
pictures of? The birds.
Turn. Haven't most
of them gone south?
Ah, not the ones
I'm interested in.
Well, seems okay to me.
Why don't you take
her to curtain area two
and I'll be there in a minute.
Susan.
Hi.
You want to go out tonight?
Yeah, sure. I'd love to
but, um, I can't.
I have something planned.
So you can't.
I guess not.
Maybe some other time.
Sure.
Uh...
We need to talk.
Dr. Lewis?
Dr. Morgenstern's on the line.
I'll call you tonight.
Okay, Mr. Percy.
We need...
Mr. Percy?
Who's there?
It's Dr. Carter.
I take it you have some
reservations about the surgery.
Do you have change
for the candy machine?
You can't eat with that
tumor in your throat.
Eloise put a Hershey bar
in the blender and I drank it.
Do you know you're about to
have a very serious operation?
There's no blender
here. I asked.
Has someone come in to
go over the risks with you?
Another time...
she blended up a Snickers.
Mm-hmm.
The trouble was...
the nougat got
caught in the straw.
You ever have a Zagnut?
I love Zagnut.
They're my favorite.
Mine, too.
Mr. Percy?
Do you want to
have this operation?
Can I just have change
for the candy machine?
Is it ready?
Not quite.
What are you doing?
Mixing an enema.
White and brown, I call it.
Milk and molasses.
Did a doctor order this?
After 22 years, I know
when somebody needs an enema.
When somebody needs an enema,
we give them one in a
box and send them home.
We don't spend half an
hour mixing up a recipe.
I do.
Not anymore you don't.
I'll take over from here.
Go change the beds in Exam Four.
You can't do that.
Sure I can. I'm
the charge nurse,
which means I'm in charge.
But I don't want a new nurse.
Well, you're in luck
'cause the chart here
says you can go home.
Where are your clothes?
Well, uh...
Hello.
Your CT is fine.
I don't see any birds in here.
I'll let you in on a secret.
I'm more than
just a bird watcher.
Really?
I'm a comparative anthropologist
doing a field study
on the mating rituals
of man and bird.
Oh, sounds like
interesting work.
It is.
For instance, you take
those two over there.
Notice the occasional
lateral body contact
initiated by her, then
reciprocated by him.
Yeah?
Identical to the courtship
dance of the sharp-tailed grouse.
Really?
Oh, yeah... oh, yeah.
Check out those two at the desk.
Do you see how
he puffs his chest
and strokes his goatee? Yeah.
Same as the
slender-billed shearwater.
Oh, look... at... that.
What?
Her frontal neck presentation.
What's that mean?
In the nuthatch,
it's an invitation to love.
Oh, she is shameless.
Why?
You see how she strokes
her throat with her finger?
Yeah, what does that mean?
The corresponding behavior
in the spoonbill would be
to bend over and
shake her tail feathers
in his face.
I need some moist lap
pads to pack off the liver.
Thank you.
Bad news for the gallbladder.
The bullet tore through
the common duct.
2-0 Prolene.
What's your plan, Peter?
Pack and stitch off the liver,
put in three or
four Jackson Pratts
and move on to the gallbladder.
Sounds good.
I'd love to stay and watch,
but I've got a cystic hygroma.
Shirley, is Dr. Maxwell
available to supervise?
He's resecting a valve,
but Dr. Breedlove is around.
Breedlove? I thought he died.
I just saw him in the hall.
Breedlove would be perfect.
Track him down,
would you, Shirley?
3-0 on a needle. Let's move!
Jerry, did my blood
test come back?
Not yet.
Damn.
What?
The computer just went down.
Why don't you have
a seat right there.
Here's your aftercare
your prescription
and your enema.
The instructions are inside.
I know all about them.
Someone from the home's
going to be picking you up.
They should be
here in a few minutes.
I'll believe that when I see it.
Mark, what are you doing?
You see what I see?
Susan's talking to
Morgenstern. So what?
He's stroking himself,
puffing out his chest
just like a slender-billed
something or other.
She's giving him
full-frontal neck.
I pulled a couple of
strings and they're
on their way.
What are you talking about?
You'd know if you
were a nuthatch.
Mark, are you okay?
She turned me down.
Susan?
Now I know why.
Oh God, she's stroking her neck.
So?
So why doesn't
she just bend over
and shake her tail
feathers right in his face?
Did you consent Mr. Percy?
Yeah. Why?
He couldn't reiterate
the risks to me.
All he wants to do is
talk about chocolate.
He's just in denial.
Candy's his way of coping.
No, no. We're talking about
doing a high-risk procedure
on a guy that can't
carry a conversation.
He signed the consent.
He's not qualified to
make treatment decisions.
I disagree.
Let's get a shrink down
here and see what he says.
You want to delay
Anspaugh's surgery
with Dr. Okida because
you aren't comfortable
with a patient's mental status?
I'll get a Stat Psych consult.
If he agrees with me,
then I'll tell Anspaugh.
What happened?
Doug was trying
to explain things
and the guy just went postal.
It's a damn scratch on his
finger, for crying out loud!
It's a serious infection.
Look, who are
you to tell me what
to do with my son?! I am
his doctor and he's going
to be treated or I'll
have to call the cops.
Doug, what's this about?
The young man. He has an
infected human bite on his finger.
His father won't let me
put him on IV antibiotics.
It's a free country and
we want to go home.
Come on.
Hold on a second.
Can I see the x-ray?
The infection
could be in the joint.
Uh, let me see you guys outside.
We'll be right with you.
He could lose his finger.
There's no sign
of osteomyelitis.
It could develop if he
doesn't get it treated.
It took his dad two
days to bring him in.
I doubt he's going
to bring him back.
I agree, an IV course
is the best way to go
but I don't think we
should call the police
if he can be treated
with oral antibiotics.
Fine. You do what you want.
Your psych consult come down?
Still waiting.
Well, time's up.
Mr. Percy, do you
want to go through
with this surgery or not?
Can I have change
for the candy machine?
Art line in?
It's in.
Let's take him, Oki.
Okey-dokey.
Dr. Anspaugh, I
think you should know
Mr. Percy seems more interested
in talking about candy
than having surgery.
Don't you worry, Mr. Percy.
You can have all
the candy you want
just as soon as we get
that tumor out of the way.
You coming, John?
I'm due for my break.
Oh, we don't take
scheduled breaks.
When it gets slow, we
rotate out for ten minutes.
It's in the contract.
Is a little flexibility
too much to ask?
Nurse!
Whose patient is she?
Oh, she's not.
She was discharged
to a nursing home.
Her nursing home
ain't going to take her.
She just had an accident.
What kind of an accident?
The loose, runny kind
that makes a
puddle on the floor.
Nurse. Oh, nurse.
I believe the mop is over there.
More oh-chromic
on a liver needle.
Cut.
Box!
You Benton?
Uh-huh.
Stan Breedlove. Where are we?
Just finished the pneumonectomy.
Almost done with the liver.
Got a gallbladder to go.
Take wider bites
and don't tie so tight.
Okay.
More three-oh Vicryl.
Good stuff, Vicryl.
Closest thing to catgut.
Surgeons still use that?
Not these days.
It's a shame.
Nothing ties like catgut.
Ah! We got a bleeder.
Is it new?
Sure is.
Where is it coming from?
Aorta.
Okay, more suction.
Whoa!
Got a pumper!
Damn. Blew a clot.
Put your finger on it.
Statinsky!
Okay. Come on.
I got it.
Clamps here. Clamp?
Still falling.
Debride the hole and sew it
with some three-oh Prolene.
Vascular needle now.
Damn it!
Internal paddles.
Let's move. All right...
Charging. 20.
Clear.
Still in fib.
Charging 30. Clear.
No change.
Charging 40. Clear.
Got him back.
Still at it, huh?
Yeah. A lot of work to
save an organ donor.
Wait. Lost it.
Charging 40. Clear.
Charging. Clear.
Fifty!
Susan and Morgenstern?
I don't believe it.
The more I think about it,
the more sense it makes.
She's been preoccupied
lately; distracted, avoiding me.
You know, now
that I think about it
I did see Morgenstern and her
having lunch the other day.
See? I waited too long, huh?
Missed my chance. Blew it.
I can't believe that
we got him back.
Yeah. Kid's got good protoplasm.
Set him up for an apnea test
see if he's got any brain left.
Think he's got a chance?
Well, he's made it this far.
Dr. Benton, the boy's mother.
Do you want to talk to her?
Not yet.
I want to assess his
brain function first.
I'll go talk to her.
All right.
Uh... don't get her hopes up.
How's the Herlihy baby?
Still alive last time I checked.
Ow! My foot!
Sal Urbanski.
Playing football in the street
went man-for-man with a Buick.
Right foot ripped
off at the ankle.
He's shocky; lost
a liter at the scene.
Where's the foot?
Wrapped up between his legs.
Why's he holding a football?
Says it's his lucky ball.
How lucky can it be?
At least he didn't fumble.
All right. Let's
get six units O-neg
CBC, type and cross.
All right. On my count.
One, two, three.
Let's get this foot on ice.
I got it.
Someone call vascular
and page the
reimplantation team.
Aye, aye.
All right. Stand by with
morphine, four migs.
This pressure
dressing isn't working.
I need a thigh cuff.
Oh, thank you.
You see that Oki's freeing
up the esophagus posteriorly
with his fingers.
Dale, you're in a position
to displace it laterally.
I can free it up
anteriorly from here.
You stick to suction, Carter.
I can feel it coming loose.
Suction.
You falling asleep.
As Oki cuts along
the sternocleidomastoid
down towards the carotid sheath
what's he got to
watch out for, Carter?
Not to nick any arteries?
Dale?
The, uh, Vagus nerve
which runs through the sheath.
Very good.
Dale is smart.
Are those little bubbles
on the lung normal?
Bubbles?
What bubbles?
Those ones right there
where Dale just
moved the esophagus.
Oh...
You poke hole in pleura.
I didn't feel it tear.
Congratulations, Edson.
You've just given
Mr. Percy a pneumothorax.
I'm in a good position
to put in a chest tube.
Yes, put tube in now.
Dale, want to hold
that for me, please?
Scalpel.
Chest tube, 32-French.
Scissors.
Got it.
That was a nice catch, Carter.
Hey! Where's my suction?
Oh, I'm sorry.
All right. Give me
the football, sir.
Don't lose it.
It's signed by Ditka.
Don't worry I'm going to
put it in with your clothes.
BP's down to 60.
Let's get another line going.
Start the rapid infuser.
Hey, there, sports fans.
Someone call for a
vascular surgeon?
Ah, it's about time.
Don't get fresh
with me, little lassie.
BP's down to 40.
Ice is here.
Put it on the foot.
Uh-oh.
I'm in trouble here.
What? You can't find a vein?
No. Itchy in my mouche.
Your moustache?
Would you be so kind?
Left side, near my nose.
Yeah. Ah, that's it.
That's my spot.
Ah...
You want me to help you?
No, no, no. Susan's got it.
Uh! Here we go. I'm in.
Okay. Hook it up.
Okay. Let's get him upstairs.
The reimplantation team awaits.
Have we got the foot?
Right here.
I'll see you later? Yeah.
Dr. Benton.
The boy's mother wanted to watch
and said I'd have
to come ask you.
All right.
Tell her to come in.
This is Mrs. Dorsett.
I'm Dr. Benton.
I took your son
off the ventilator
a minute ago
to test if his brain
will trigger him to breathe.
I don't understand.
Well, if we see your
son take a breath
then that means
his brain function is intact.
If there's no attempt
to breathe, then...
well, that's a sign
of brain death.
PCO2 is 60.
That's high enough
to make him breathe.
How long will it take?
We'll know in ten seconds.
Come on.
I'm sorry.
You wanted to see me?
Yes, I did.
How many shifts you
work a week, Mark?
Four?
Usually.
As long as we don't
work the same four,
we'll get along great.
Is this about that kid's finger?
It's about your inability
to respect my decisions.
Professional differences
happen, Doug.
You can't take it personally.
It's entirely personal, Mark.
You've been on
a moral high horse
ever since I came
in with that OD.
Yeah, well, what do you
expect when you drag
your dirty laundry
through the door?
But it's not personal, right?
Who are you kidding?
Mrs. Urbanski, your
husband's up in surgery.
The surgeons are going
to try and reattach his foot.
But is he all right?
Well, he lost some
blood. We transfused him.
I think he's going to be fine.
Here's his stuff.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
He seemed very concerned
about his Mike Ditka football.
He loves the Bears.
Yeah, well, I'm going
to try and find someone
to bring you up to
the surgical floor.
Okay?
Wendy.
Can you bring Mrs.
Urbanski up to surgery for me?
Sure.
Thank you.
How we doing?
Ready when you are.
Let's bring on the foot.
What the hell..?
Mrs. Urbanski, what is it?!
Oh, God!
Oh, my God!
Oh, I'm so...
Oh, my God.
In and out, under two hours.
Oki's amazing.
I really appreciate
you inviting me along.
I'm glad we did.
Otherwise we might not
have seen that pneumothorax.
I have two hours
until my flight.
Want to eat?
If you're buying.
Why don't you join us, Carter?
Edson,
monitor Mr. Percy in recovery.
It was an honest
mistake, a mix-up.
It was the most incompetent,
horrifying thing I've ever seen.
And because you
didn't ice the foot
they can't reattach it.
Please, don't write me up.
Are you kidding?
If anyone deserves to
be written up, it's you.
All right. Go ahead.
Do their dirty work for them.
That's just what they want.
Whose dirty work?
Hospital Administration.
I'm nine months away from
getting my maximum pension
and they're trying
to force me out.
That's why they keep
floating me down here
where I don't know
what I'm doing.
You're right. You don't
know what you're doing.
They want to get
rid of people like me
and replace them with
cheaper, less experienced aides.
If they know the difference
between a football and a foot
I'll take them.
I am not going to let you
put me through the humiliation
of a review board,
not after 22 years.
Watch me.
Don't bother.
I quit.
Dr. Keaton said
her oxygen level's
as low as it can go.
It's only a matter of time.
Thank you for everything
you've done for Megan.
So, what happened to that float?
She quit, thank God.
She told me the Hospital
Admin was trying to make her quit
before her pension maxed out.
That's why they were
floating her down here.
Yeah. She gave me the same line.
It's a bunch of bull.
They're floating me to Neuro.
What?
Starting tomorrow
the hospital's floating me
to Neuro three times a week.
When's your pension max out?
In a year.
So, maybe it was personal.
Go ahead. Say it.
I'm a sanctimonious,
judgmental, self-righteous
sexually frustrated little man.
Well, you're not little.
Thank you.
I'd hate to think that
my personal pique
could color my
professional decisions
but it happens and it
probably happened today.
Now look, you don't
need to beat me up
about making a
mess out of my life.
I like to do that myself.
Well, it may not be
the healthiest approach.
Yeah.
Hey, you know,
I'm seeing a shrink.
Oh, well that's a good step.
Yeah.
Man or a woman?
A woman.
Don't worry.
She's 62 years old.
Oh. Freudian?
Yeah.
Sorry. I couldn't resist.
I hate you, you know that.
I know.
When the Whippoorwill calls
Whippoorwill calls
And evening is nigh
Evening is nigh
I hurry to my
My
Blue
Heaven
Heaven, Heaven
You see a smilin' face,
a fireplace, a cozy room
Chica-boom, chica-boom
A little nest that's nestled
where the roses bloom
Chica-boom, chica-boom
Just Molly and me
And baby makes three
We're happy in my
My
Blue
Heaven
Heaven, heaven
Take it, Oki.
Chica-boom, chica-boom.
Rough day, huh?
You knew it would
be, didn't you?
I had an idea.
Well, I guess I did exactly
what you said... you know.
Rushed ahead; didn't think.
Did you actually believe
you could save that boy?
I never worked so hard
or performed more
surgery than I did today.
I took that vent off...
I absolutely thought
that kid would breathe.
You check on the Herlihy baby?
A couple hours ago.
I, uh...
I can't face those parents.
You should check
on her before you go.
I'm telling you, Wendy,
the guy walks in the room
and every vending
machine goes kaput.
I don't believe it.
Ready? I got the keys.
Are we really going
through with this?
Yes, Wendy, I'm desperate.
You guys are nuts.
MRIs do not cause
negative force fields.
I think we better
take the stairs.
...blue heaven.
Dale, my hale and hearty friend.
Today was a blast.
Not bad.
Too bad Mr. Percy stroked out.
What did you say?
Didn't you hear?
No.
I went to check
on him in recovery
couldn't even talk.
You're kidding.
Nope. Nothing left to do
but turn him and water him.
Shame you backed off
on that psych consult.
Could have saved
his life such as it was.
Too bad you didn't
have the balls.
You smug son of a bitch!
What the hell
is going on here?
John and I were just discussing
the finer points of
informed consent.
What is wrong
with you guys?
She and Morgenstern
are going out.
I can live with that.
But what bothers me is
that she didn't tell me about it.
Well, if I was going
out with Morgenstern
I wouldn't tell anybody.
Susan and I are supposed
to be friends, right?
I mean, how did this happen?
How serious is it?
Why don't you ask her?
What, oh, you want me to just go
to her apartment, knock on the door
and say, "So, what's up
with you and Morgenstern?"
That'd be one way.
That's not my style.
Mark, you might want to
think about changing your style.
Okay, E. Ray, what's
that key sequence?
Control A-Q-R, and
then push the pound key.
Okay.
Hurry up! I hear someone coming!
Well, close the door.
Okay. Here goes.
Control... A... Q... R... pound.
Good job, Jerry.
Don't leave me in too long.
15 Seconds should be
enough to reverse my polarity.
This radiology tech
stuff isn't so hard.
I can feel the difference.
I'm me again.
Turn it off.
Uh, okay. What's
the sequence for that?
Isn't there a switch?
Which one?
There should be
like a kill switch.
A big red button?
Uh, what about this?
Oh, my God!
Jerry, what are you doing?
Uh, I don't know.
What are you doing, Jerry?
I don't know, I don't know.
Pull the plug.
Pull the plug!
Oh, my God!
Medicine is supposed
to be a noble profession
not a motorcycle club.
Why were you fighting?
I was... it was
stupid, Dr. Keaton.
Abby. I'm listening.
There was a patient
scheduled for a
high-risk surgery
clearly non compos mentis...
Mm-hmm.
And I knew I should have called
a psych consult
down to clear him
but... I didn't.
I was too afraid
of... I don't know
pissing off the
surgeons to speak up.
What happened?
He stroked out.
He should never
have had the surgery
and I knew it.
Well, at least you care
about your patients.
A lot of surgeons don't.
They don't?
Mm-mm.
Dr. Keaton...
Abby.
Abby...
Who is it?
It's Mark.
I just called you.
Are you alone?
Yeah, yeah.
So, uh...
I'll make this easy.
I know about you
and Morgenstern.
You do?
Yeah.
So, how long you
been seeing each other?
You mean as...?
In going out?
Yeah.
Mark, we're not.
You're not?
No.
Are you sure?
Yes.
So, are you seeing anybody?
Maybe we should sit down.
Morgenstern has been helping
me get my transcripts together.
Transcripts?
I'm leaving my residency.
You're quitting?
Transferring.
Where?
Phoenix.
When I was there
visiting Chloe and Suzy
I just got this feeling
like this is where I'm
supposed to be right now
and...
I don't have anything here
in Chicago really, and...
I mean...
I-I know what you mean.
And after I've decided,
I just feel happy
for the first time
in a long time.
Like I'm finally
moving on with my life.
That's great.
God...
So, you're sure?
Yeah. I am.
I don't... I don't
know what to say.
I know.
I'm going to miss you.
I am going to miss you, too.
Kit...
is the pulse ox monitor right?
Yes, it is.
What did you do?
Nothing.
About an hour ago, she
just started getting better.
It's a miracle.