What time?
4:30.
Why so late?
Make-up test in social studies.
Did you invite
Shelby for Saturday?
No.
Do you want me to call
her? Yeah, that'd be great.
You calling a 12-year-old
girl for a sleepover.
It'll be fine. Make you a deal.
I'll call a friend when
you call a friend.
It's your birthday.
Do what you want.
Thank you. Bye.
Bye.
What did you forget? Nothing.
Then why'd you come back?
'Cause I live here.
Come on, Samantha, you're
gonna be late for school.
What are you talking
about? It's 4:30.
Are you okay?
Tired, I guess.
What's wrong?
I don't know.
Right.
That's all I need to know.
You're late! Okay, bye.
37-year-old male with
recurring blackouts.
Tell him to switch from tequila
to bourbon. Worked for me.
The three doctors he's already seen
already ruled out drugs and alcohol.
Then it's epilepsy.
Tell him to buy a
hockey helmet and...
EEG's clean, so is the CT.
Relax. Just because you got
approved by an adoption agency
doesn't mean you'll get
approved by the birth mother.
You're a single mom.
That puts you somewhere below
couples acquitted in day care scandals.
You're welcome, Dr. House.
It is an interesting case.
What time are you
seeing the mom?
Are you having
your guy follow me?
I just trashed your
social value as a mother,
and all I got was
a little sarcasm.
It means you don't feel
the need to defend yourself,
which means you're not
worried about getting a kid,
which means you've
already got one.
We're meeting at 11:00.
She's due to deliver a
baby girl in two weeks.
Well, I'm sure the mom will be thrilled
to hand her crack baby off to a doctor.
She's not a crack baby.
No, mother's perfectly healthy.
She just had to give
up the baby in order
to continue her work
on the human genome.
She confessed to
some past meth use.
What they don't confess to is
almost always more interesting.
This is a mistake.
Because a kid you don't know may
have some problems you don't know about
that she may have
passed on to a kid...
Because you're a
control-seeking narcissist,
which is fine, good
even, in some jobs,
but you're not equipped to handle a
real kid, never mind a factory second.
Where are you meeting her?
In a little place
called, "Follow me,
"and your urologist will be
buying himself a new yacht."
They explained the
returns policy, right?
It's worse than video games.
I'm not changing my mind.
Could be
post-concussion syndrome.
Not without a pre-concussion.
Pick a number.
For what?
Cuddy pool. She got the nod.
Little tweaker's
due in fourteen days.
That's great news. I think.
It's good news.
The great news is she insisted that
she's not gonna change her mind,
which means she's actually
thought about changing her mind,
which means she's not
sure she's ready to be a mom,
which means she's
not ready to be a mom,
gonna change her mind.
The only question is when.
$100 buy-in, less than seven
means the next seven days.
But she's been dying
for a kid for three years.
No way she's gonna back out now.
Not one of the options.
Mini strokes can cause
blackouts and memory loss.
Nine hours is a lot of time
to be out for a mini stroke.
And there'd be residual
damage on the CT.
The guy works at home
as a consumer product tester.
He could've been exposed to a toxin
that caused short-term memory loss.
Wouldn't show up on imaging.
A cavernous sinus thrombosis could
cause absence seizures and memory loss.
I'll take seven to fourteen.
We have a player.
You just said it was great news.
Now you want to bet against her?
It's only great news if she
wants it to be great news.
House knows her
better than any of us.
I'd rather use a pseudonym.
Good thinking.
I say she's gonna
meet the mom and bolt.
I'm going for the early fold.
Check his home for toxins,
and his sinuses for thrombosises.
Maybe he OD'd on caffeine.
Apparently he didn't drink
the coffee, just smelled it.
Wow.
Did they just move here?
Six years ago.
This is no way to raise a kid.
He's a single dad. I'm
sure he's doing his best.
Which is why single
people shouldn't have kids.
You got a problem with
what Cuddy's doing?
You think single
mothers can't...
I think the traditional
family is a fraud.
Even married moms
are single moms.
Daddy just pays some bills and
reads just enough bedtime stories
to not kill himself
out of guilt.
My dad was great.
After my mom died, he...
He might be the exception.
On the other hand, you
are fairly screwed up.
No booze, no meds, no drugs.
And no view.
The building's half empty. He'd rather
a view of the turnpike than the park.
Park views are
probably 50% more.
You're surprised the guy's a
pragmatist after looking at this place?
The guy's not a
pragmatist, he's a flagellant.
Mmm.
Looks like mold.
Mom would have cleaned better.
Exposure to certain types of mold
can cause short-term memory loss.
We're testing both of you.
I feel fine.
I'm sure you are. We're
just being cautious.
So, where do you guys go,
other than home and school?
Nowhere. Dad works at
home, and I go to school.
What about sports,
friends, travel?
Like I said, Dad works at
home, and I go to school.
Must be hard not having
your mom around, huh?
I was only four when
the accident happened.
Still, I'm sure you both
miss her sometimes.
Not really.
You're strong.
No, I just don't get
what the big deal about
death is, you know?
Yeah.
How is she?
Physically, she's fine.
Mentally, she's weird.
I'm sure she's just freaked
out about her dad. Mr. Harmon?
Mr. Harmon?
Where are you going?
I have an appointment.
I have to go.
We haven't finished
with your treatment,
and we're still waiting
on some test results.
I have an appointment.
I'm sorry, you're gonna
have to reschedule.
I really have to go.
Mr. Harmon, do you
know where you are?
Why are you trying to stop me?
Look at his eyes.
Is he having a seizure?
His pupils are responsive.
I think he's asleep.
He was just asleep. It
means no memory loss.
And sleepwalking doesn't kill,
unless he walks out a window.
Sleepwalking's not a
diagnosis, it's a symptom.
As long as we can't
figure out why...
Stress-induced insomnia.
Lots of people sleepwalk.
Not in the middle of the day before
they've even put their head on a pillow.
Could be some
sort of narcolepsy.
Which is caused by...
There's usually
a genetic history.
Or?
If you know the answer,
can you tell us the answer?
I don't know the answer.
Which brings us back to "Or?"
Some sort of
environmental trigger.
Which means? It's a toxin.
So we are?
Being led down an annoying path.
I honestly don't know where this
is going. Just following the clues.
We're right back
where we started.
The mold we found doesn't
cause these symptoms,
and there's nothing
else at his home.
And? And you're obnoxious.
He never goes anywhere else.
Which we know because?
Because he says so.
Because his daughter says so.
Because they have no reason to lie.
Which proves he never
goes anywhere else
when
he's...
Conscious.
Oh, my God, you're right.
He said he had an appointment.
Next time, let him keep it.
Send him home, see
where his dreams take him.
Becca?
Dr. Cuddy?
Lisa. Nice to meet you.
Oh! You want one? No, thanks.
I can't stop eating them. I
guess it's, like, a craving.
I must have, like,
a dozen a day.
And this is decaf.
How have you been feeling?
Uh... You know,
tired, fat, nervous.
Is there anything
you want to ask me?
Yeah, actually, I just
have one question.
What are you going to call her?
I'm not sure.
It's all been rather
sudden, you know?
I like Joy.
But as I said, I haven't
really decided yet.
Well, is there anything
you want to ask me?
It's okay.
The agency website is
filled with prospective parents.
There are their photos,
their biographies.
There're so many
wonderful people out there.
Wonderful couples.
Why did I choose a single mom?
My grandmother was married for 37 years
to a man that treated her like garbage,
and my mom would've stayed
married to my loser dad that long,
but he dumped her.
You know, I never understood how you could
fall for the same crap as your mother.
Then I met Tony.
When I read your bio, a
doctor, a head of a hospital.
When I saw your picture...
I don't want her
raised by a loser.
How long have you had that rash?
I don't know, a few days.
Have you had any joint pain?
Yeah, I'm pregnant.
All my joints hurt.
They shouldn't all hurt.
Have you been using?
Not in seven months.
Not since I found
out I was pregnant.
That needs to be checked out.
You sure you
don't want children?
You know, just because we're
stuck here, and I'm lying down,
doesn't mean we
need to get deep.
You're afraid you'll make the same
mistake you made with your wife?
Get caught taking some
other kid to a ball game?
I like my life as it is.
Alpha waves increasing.
Any change in demeanor?
No, nothing. He just got up.
Maybe it's a result of a
blood pressure change.
Delta waves. Out of nowhere.
He's now asleep.
Brain's supposed to
turn off motor function.
If the brain was doing what it was
supposed to be doing, we wouldn't be here.
He's leaving. Come on.
She's 38 weeks. You
think it's Fifth disease?
What's that? It's
a viral infection.
It can infect the fetus.
Usually in the first 20
weeks of pregnancy,
and in women who have
trouble with their immune system.
History of drug use could have
compromised her immune system.
I told you I haven't used
anything in seven months.
It does look more
like a heat rash to me.
Yes, well, maybe we want to
look at the actual blood tests.
Of course.
Does she work for you? Yeah.
Everybody here works for you?
When this happens for real,
are you okay to deliver here?
Yeah, sure. Good.
Blood work's normal.
Test it again.
Tested it twice.
I'll get you some topical
cream for that rash.
I'm admitting her.
There's nothing wrong with her.
There are dozens of other
things this rash could indicate.
I want a full fetal workup.
You're losing it. That's what
happens when you have kids.
Ceaseless crying and
nagging leads to irrational fears.
It's impressive that you didn't wait
for the actual crying and nagging.
She had a lace-patterned rash,
joint pain and a history of drug abuse.
You would've done
exactly the same thing.
And I'd be an excellent father.
Hey, what are you doing?
Baby barf.
Maternity ward was
handing out free samples.
Well played, sir.
You leave me no
choice but to change.
My clothes, not my mind.
That's exactly my point.
It's not gonna be me and a cup.
It's gonna be eight times a day.
If you can't handle wearing that
stain, you can't handle a baby.
Why do you even care?
It's not like I'm ever
gonna ask you to baby-sit.
I'm a humanitarian.
We should stop him.
The whole point was to...
Let him plow into some
innocent bystander?
His legs are working. Obviously
his eyes are working, too.
His reaction time
could be slower.
He's stopping.
Yeah, I see.
He's having sleep sex.
Maybe.
Pull up to her. I know.
What'd that guy want?
Piss off.
Go after him.
She's not a hooker.
How do you know?
Do you want me to
describe the clues,
or do you want to stop him before he
finishes off the drugs he just bought?
Apparently, Rip's a coke fiend.
So, Sleeping Beauty has
a jones for Snow White.
Coke explains the narcolepsy,
narcolepsy explains
the sleepwalking.
But it doesn't explain the rip
in the space-time continuum.
Coke leads to sleepwalking,
which leads to coke,
which leads to sleepwalking.
What caused the
first sleepwalking?
The coke he took while
he was wide awake.
He says he didn't.
Wouldn't be the first time
somebody lied about drug use.
He has no reason to lie.
He knows he's sick,
his job doesn't drug test,
no relationship, his
daughter wouldn't find out.
Maybe he just forgot.
Forgot he did cocaine? You're
going with forgot over lying?
It fits. Cocaine explains the narcolepsy,
narcolepsy explains the sleepwalking.
Whatever's in the cocaine other than
the cocaine explains the memory loss.
Dealers cut that stuff
with all kinds of garbage.
Great. We'll start him on immediate
treatment for "all kinds of garbage."
You can narrow
it down in the lab.
Not without a sample.
So get a sample.
You want us to score
cocaine from a drug dealer?
It's exciting.
It's a felony.
It's necessary.
There she is. Amniotic
fluid looks good.
Good fetal movement,
heart's beating nicely.
What?
It looks like
pulmonary hypoplasia.
What's that?
The baby's lungs
are underdeveloped.
She won't be able to
breathe on her own.
She might die? I don't know.
If she was born today,
she'd be in trouble,
but we're not going
to let that happen.
We'll put you on
magnesium to prevent labor,
and steroids to grow the lungs.
It's a good thing
Dr. Cuddy brought you in.
How do you know what
a drug dealer looks like?
I'm not doing drugs, if
that's what you're asking.
I just noticed that she had cash in
her hand. Obviously came from him.
Obviously didn't have enough
time to perform any other services.
I didn't notice
her holding any...
Mmm. There she is.
We're not cops.
Cops aren't allowed
to say that, right?
Yeah, they can say it.
Oh!
But if you were a cop, you'd
know that. What do you want?
I'd like to buy some
cocaine, please.
Definitely not a cop.
Thank you.
Wait.
It's good. Glad you like
it, Pablo. Now can we go?
No. You gave us the wrong stuff.
What are you talking
about? You got my best.
I know. I don't want the good,
"get the new customer hooked" stuff.
I want the stepped-on, "keep the old
customer coming back for more" stuff.
Are you crazy, bitch?
No, I'm just a bitch who
knows what she wants.
Looks like this kid thing is
really working out for you.
All of the shopping,
none of the stretch marks.
Not a good time.
Right. Kid's getting worse.
Blessing in disguise,
although completely predictable.
If you take in strays, don't
be surprised by the worms.
I'm still wearing the sweater.
I didn't say you weren't stubborn,
I said you weren't maternal.
Thank you. Go away.
You're getting
crankier. Baby's sick.
Sorry I'm not
finding the fun in that.
Is it really worth it? Just for
the pursuit of unconditional love?
Only you could see
that as a bad thing.
It's a fake thing.
There's no unconditional
love, it's just unconditional need.
Don't make this child a
victim of your biological clock.
Victim?
You think she's
better off staying...
Yes.
'Cause at least she knows
she's not qualified for the job.
Let me guess. I'm gonna tell
her not to play ball in the house,
but she's not gonna listen. No.
Actually, I was going for she sneaks
her boyfriend in while you're sleeping,
and he wants to
do it on the desk,
and at first she says no, but
she has issues with self-esteem...
You know you're
gonna pay for that.
I'm paying for it right
now with wisdom.
Get out.
We found lactose. The coke
was cut with milk powder.
Makes it nutritious.
Not much of a toxin.
It is if he's allergic to milk.
He's not. There's
milk in his fridge.
How does he like his coffee?
I don't know. What does that...
What type of cereal's
in the cabinet?
Cocoa something. Why?
What does it matter?
He likes his coffee
black. Milk's for the kid.
How can you be sure?
Because if he drank the milk, he'd
know that he's lactose intolerant.
Ask him, then treat
him for allergic reaction.
If he gets better, we
all get to go home early.
Steroids make you
more prone to infection.
You'll have to stay here for the next
two weeks, so we can monitor you.
The baby's lungs, is
that because of the meth?
Could be.
You must hate me.
If you had done everything right in
your life, I wouldn't be getting a baby.
You're not scared?
I am scared.
You got, like,
this perfect life.
Not yet.
What's that?
Heart rate's climbing.
What's wrong with her?
It's not the baby, it's you.
I need two units
of O-negative, stat!
The mother had a Stage Two
placental abruption, she's losing blood.
So, deliver the baby.
Lungs are 10 weeks premature.
So, deliver now, risk the baby.
Deliver later, risk the mom.
It's not your baby
yet, it's not your call.
She'll do whatever
I tell her to do.
Self-worth issues...
That's genetic, you know.
You should deliver now.
Right.
Are you serious?
You're not? You just told me...
The wrong answer.
You can give the mom more blood.
You can't give the
fetus more lungs.
The lungs might work.
It's the right
decision, medically.
And yet, you're here.
To get your opinion,
not to get jerked around.
See, this is what's
screwed up here.
You're not sure that
this is the right call,
but you are sure that this
is what you want to tell her.
And that scares you because
your motives aren't medical.
Some part of you
doesn't want this baby,
and that part wants
to tell her to kill it.
This is an impossible situation.
I'm advising her to
take the safest route.
Right.
Doesn't explain why you
changed your sweater.
I need your advice.
It's not cancer.
Wow! Can you remove
spleens with your mind, too?
You're here to talk about
Cuddy. The file is a pretext.
Why the hell haven't you
come to talk to me about Cuddy?
I've been doing all
sorts of insane stuff.
If she can't handle your
insanity, she can't handle a baby.
That's exactly my point.
No, it isn't.
You're feeling threatened because
she's going on to high school
and leaving you behind
to repeat the 8th grade.
She's sleeping with her math
teacher to get her diploma.
Adoption is cheating? Are
they giving her a fake kid?
That's the problem.
She gets to have a
relationship with a kid,
but she can't handle
one with an adult.
So she's gonna kill it.
That does seem cleaner.
I've seen the file. She's
making a judgment call.
Decisions are never
made in a vacuum.
Just like your decision
to make her miserable.
You're doing this because
we no longer have inkwells,
and Cuddy doesn't have pigtails.
Why do you think I did that?
How you doing?
Not sure.
Been keeping an eye
on the clock, like you said.
I don't think I lost any time.
The machinery agrees with you. That means
your problems were caused by the coke.
Can't believe I did coke.
You were asleep.
I chose to do coke.
In your sleep. You
weren't responsible.
Something inside
me wanted to do it.
Something inside of me
didn't think it was wrong.
It's like a dream.
We all do stuff in our dreams
we wouldn't do when we're awake.
I don't.
What's that?
Did I fall asleep
and hurt myself?
I don't see any cuts.
'Cause there aren't any.
I think
you're sweating blood.
The guy is bleeding out of his
pores. What does that tell us?
Other than you don't want to play
basketball against him, and he's dying.
That neither cocaine or
allergies are the answer.
It's gotta be systemic.
Hemorrhagic virus maybe?
You think it's Ebola?
His white blood cell count would be
through the roof. It's not an infection.
DIC?
Coags are normal.
It's cancer. Leukemia
explains everything.
- No fever.
- The bleeding.
No weight loss. - The rash.
No Headaches. The fatigue.
Leukemia would be
obvious from the CBC.
Leukemia has false
negatives all the time.
So, we have four reasons for
leukemia, four reasons against.
You only need one against.
Yeah, if we had one reason for anything
else. Go do a bone marrow biopsy.
What would you do?
I think...
I think you should wait.
But if I wait, I could die.
There would be more
danger for you, but...
Is this your
opinion as a doctor,
as a mother?
It's my medical opinion.
It's my personal
opinion. I don't...
I don't wanna wait.
It might only be one week.
We will keep you on plasma.
This is not my baby.
I already sacrificed nine
months for this stupid mistake.
I don't wanna
sacrifice any more.
Becca, you asked my opinion
because you wanted to do the right thing.
You are giving up this baby because
you don't want to make the mistakes
your mom made, her mom made.
You have a chance to break this
cycle, to do something great for this baby.
No.
I need you to hold still.
Wait.
You been testing any
tanning creams or sprays?
No.
It's not a tan. Means
it's not leukemia.
Chem panel confirms
kidney failure, end stage.
Got him on dialysis?
BP's too low.
Too bad. Would have been nice to
have more than an hour to solve this thing.
Haemachromatosis?
He have tiny testes?
No. Scleroderma.
His skin's darker, not lighter.
As much fun as 20
Questions tends to be,
he's blowing blood
out of every orifice.
You think it just
might be vascular?
Vasculitis?
If I said it might be vitas gerular,
would you have said Vitas Gerulaitis?
Test him for vasculitis.
Angio and blood.
Even if we're right, he's going
to need a kidney transplant.
Test the daughter. She's 12.
Small kidney? It just
means he won't pee as much.
Great for road trips.
I meant she's a minor,
and Daddy has a conflict, so
we're gonna need Cuddy's sign-off.
So get it.
She's kind of busy.
Clamp.
Suction.
Entering the abdominal cavity.
There's the head.
Got a minute?
Get out of here.
Who's that? CHASE:
Dr. Gregory House.
He's the one you'll be suing
when you develop sepsis.
Well, why is he here?
Better question
is, why is she here?
You're an administrator,
administrate.
My patient's daughter
needs a guardian ad litem.
That's it. HOUSE:
Tests are inconclusive,
but either way, he's gonna
need... House, get out!
This doesn't need you, I do.
Head's out.
Later.
Later's too late.
And there she is.
Come on, cry.
There we go.
Come on.
Come on. Joy, cry!
Cry, Joy.
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
That's a sound we like to hear.
Apgar's 9 out of 10.
You hear that?
You just got your first A.
She's yours now.
Mazel tov.
Now it's time to say
those magic words you'll
be telling her for
the rest of her life,
"Mommy's gotta go to work."
Have the risks of the transplant
procedure been explained to you?
Damn it! I was hoping you
weren't going to ask her that.
Of course she knows. Can
you just sign the paperwork?
Dr. House explained to you that all
surgeries carry risks? You could die.
And if you don't
do it, Daddy will die.
Stop pressuring her.
Sorry. Daddy's
perfectly healthy.
But we want you to give
him the kidney anyway,
'cause it'd be cool
if he had three.
Shut up.
Do you understand the
risks of living with one kidney?
Yeah.
And you still want to
proceed with the transplant?
Yeah.
Okay. Go ahead.
No.
I'm saying you can proceed.
And I'm saying I can't.
Whatever he has, she has, too.
She's sleepwalking.
If we don't give him a new
kidney, he's dead in a week.
We have to transplant.
When your remote
has a dead battery,
you don't replace it with
another dead battery.
Whatever's killing
the dad's kidneys
is going to kill the kid's, too.
It is possible the sleep
issues aren't medically related.
Maybe they're both insomniacs
due to the turnpike noise,
maybe they both drink
too much coffee, maybe...
House is right.
How do you know?
Because the daughter
is sweating blood.
But if they have the same thing, it
means there has to be a common cause,
which means it has to be
a toxin, infection or genetic.
And since we've ruled
out infections and toxins...
It narrows it down to any one
of a dozen genetic disorders,
each of which takes
more than a week to run.
Call Foreman, get to work.
Cuddy is positively aglow.
What's your theory, she's only
acting happy to make you miserable?
I need a genetic disease.
I'm sure you're carrying a few.
Symptoms are kidney
failure, bleeding and insomnia.
You paid off the pool?
Technically, anyone who
didn't enter is a winner.
It's not over yet.
Everyone's happy until they
unwrap that pretty present
and find they got a wall
clock in the shape of Africa.
Adoption's a cheat, remember?
There's no real pregnancy, so
there's no stranded dopamine receptors,
so there's no
post-partum depression.
Cuddy will be the happiest
new mother you've ever seen.
I've just given you
the answer, haven't I?
And now you're going to walk
out of here without saying a word.
Nope.
Good news. I know what you have,
and you're both gonna be fine.
What? Are you serious?
Yes, and no.
So you do know what they have?
Yeah.
But they aren't
going to be fine.
No idea. They might be.
Why the hell would
you say they were?
To make them happy.
For two seconds?
Technically, to see
if they can be happy.
I should have seen a grin, a
twinkle, a sigh of relief, something.
They're sick, they're tired.
They're anhedonic.
Incapable of
experiencing pleasure.
Something's bushwhacked
their dopamine receptors.
They're depressed.
Mom's dead, Dad's dying.
You should know that being
bummed isn't necessarily a pathology.
Being bummed doesn't
explain their lack of friends,
or their indifference
to each other.
Why their place had no
music, no view, no decor.
But if you can't feel pleasure,
what's with the cocaine?
Really? Is that why you do
drugs? 'Cause you're happy?
Most people do them
'cause they wanna be happy.
His subconscious
craved it, needed it.
The most common cause of
anhedonia is schizophrenia.
Sure, in white folk.
They're black?
They're liars.
What's your name?
Jerry Harmon.
Your real name. Hosarian?
Herzog? H'Ali-Baba?
Hammoud.
Jamal Hammoud.
Changed it when we
invaded Iraq, the first time.
How did you know?
You and your daughter have
Familial Mediterranean Fever.
It's a genetic disease contracted
by people of Mediterranean descent.
Sephardic Jews,
Armenians, Arabs.
Causes anhedonia, seizures,
kidney failure, even lactose intolerance.
Symptoms are set
off by age and stress.
Kid couldn't get happy, but she
could get stressed by Daddy dying.
You don't know
if we'll get better?
Treatment tends to be hit and miss,
once you reach the sweating blood stage.
Start them on
colchicine and melphalan.
His kidneys are fried.
If he doesn't have FMF,
the colchicine will kill him.
Boy, I sure hope I'm right.
Mr. Harmon?
Mr. Harmon, I need
you to open your eyes.
Feeling better?
How's Samantha?
Healthy enough to
toss you a kidney.
Dad? Sammy.
Baby's doing great.
I can't imagine how
hard this must be for you.
I was stupid and selfish.
You were scared.
Yeah. But you
wouldn't have been.
That's not true.
Well, I mean, you
would have been scared,
but you would have done
the right thing anyway.
And I wanna be like that.
I don't wanna be a loser.
You're not a loser.
When I saw you hold her,
and the look on your face,
it was the most beautiful
thing I've ever seen.
And that's when I realized
I can't...
Becca.
My life, it's always been about
pain and anger and disappointment,
never about love.
And that's when I realized,
you know, it could be.
And I can't give that away.
Becca, don't do this.
What you're feeling is natural,
but you're filled with
hormones and emotion and fear.
And you just can't make a
huge decision like this right now,
you have to give it some time.
I'm so sorry.
It's a decision that
changes everything.
Changes the rest of your life.
I hope so.
It's really not the
greatest time for gloating.
There's more than
one baby in the sea.
The world is full of teenage
boys riding bareback.
No.
I'm done. I can't go
through that again.
You're quitting?
Just like you quit IVF?
Yeah. Just like that.
There, you just did it again.
It's too bad.
You would have
made a great mother.
You son of a bitch.
When I was getting a baby,
you told me I'd suck as a mother.
Now that I've lost it, you tell
me I'd be great as a mother.
Why do you need
to negate everything?
I don't know.
Good night.