Ahh!
Help! I need a corpsman.
Game over.
Don't I get a rematch?
Sorry, shift starts
in 20 minutes.
How 'bout a kiss though?
I will take it.
Dr. Choi! You there?
Dr. Choi!
Our neighbor, Trent,
has been stabbed.
I need you.
Show me.
Bitch! Crazy bitch!
Trent...
Call 911!
Oh, God, Ethan.
You know I'm a doctor.
I'ma take care of you.
She stabbed me!
Our crazy neighbor.
Get her!
April, wait.
April!
Oh, my arm!
Help!
Gonna need a second ambo!
Evil...
Trent Gardner is an evil man.
Help is on the way, ma'am.
Ow, my arm.
Where else
are you hurt?
Ow!
Mags, where do you want us?
You're going to Baghdad.
Naima, talk to me.
Forty something female,
GCS, 15.
Fell down a flight of stairs.
Head lac, possible
left wrist fracture.
Tried to board and collar,
but too agitated.
He's a monster.
She's a suspect
in a stabbing.
Dr. Halstead,
Treatment Four.
On it.
I opened the door,
and he was right there.
He wants to kill me.
Who wants to kill you?
Trent.
Watch her arm.
Ready?
Stand by!
One, two, three...
50 of fentanyl
for the pain.
Let's get an AP lateral
X-ray of that arm.
Ma'am, did you hit your head?
Oh, God.
There you go.
Do you know where you are?
He's been trying
to kill me for weeks.
Ma'am, do you know
where you are?
I had no choice.
I had to protect myself.
Argh!
April, let's give Trent
50 of fentanyl.
She's crazy.
Single stab wound
to the epigastrium.
No evisceration
from what I can see.
I need X-rays,
chest and abdomen,
and let's echo the heart.
I didn't do anything, man.
I tried to give her
her mail.
What?
Brittany,
her mail got
mixed up with mine.
Echo's negative.
No pericardial effusion.
Belly's also negative.
Knocked on her door.
And she attacked me.
Everyone stand back.
I know, it sucks.
Ow.
Gonna need a CT,
head and C-spine.
Oh, my God.
Stand back.
Yeah, ulnar styloid fracture.
Mags, need a hematoma
block to reduce.
You got it.
He puts gas
in my air vent.
I can smell it.
We're gonna
take good care
of you, all right?
No, no.
Nothing is safe.
I'm not safe.
I had to stop him.
I had to.
Ow!
This our victim?
Yes.
You up to giving
me a statement?
Crazy bitch stabbed me
for no reason.
Page Trauma for
a surgical evaluation.
Trent, we're gonna see
how best to proceed, okay?
You can talk while we wait.
Oh, God!
Detective Jay Halstead,
Chicago PD.
Why don't you start
with what happened?
Dr. Charles.
Allow me to introduce you
to Dr. Robert Haywood.
Doctor.
Not medical.
Astrophysics, actually.
Oh, way beyond me.
Dr. Haywood is a visiting
professor at Northwestern.
He was at MIT,
and his cardiologist
in Boston
referred him here.
Uh, please, Bob.
Bob asked specifically
to see you.
Well, I've read
your papers.
I'm particularly impressed
with psychodynamic
therapeutic applications
in acute medical
environments.
Oh, dear, a masochist.
Yeah. Uh, I'm gonna
leave you two to talk.
Here's that. Sir.
Thank you.
Of course.
Thank you, Doc.
Yep.
So, chronic cardiomyopathy,
from chronic ischemia.
Class-3 heart failure.
Wow, I'm sorry.
My energy is low.
When I lecture,
if I stand too long,
my legs swell.
I can't get an erection,
not that anyone's
clamoring for one.
And I'm on 11 different meds,
as you can see.
And I expect
in the next six months,
I'll be in the ICU
with an inotropic drip,
waiting for a transplant.
Yeah, well, unfortunately,
that is a possibility.
Yeah, so,
it isn't unreasonable
I get a little anxious?
I'd be surprised
if you weren't.
Well, last thing I wanna do
is add to your drug regimen,
but, you know,
we should have
that conversation.
In the meantime, I'm happy
to prescribe you
a mild sedative,
tide you over.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Oh, by the way,
I think you might
know my daughter.
She's a psych resident here,
Sarah Reese.
You're Sarah's father?
Yeah.
Has she mentioned me to ya?
Well, only in passing,
but, um...
We've been estranged
for many years.
I didn't write or call.
That was a mistake.
I should've
at least written.
But, I didn't
wanna interfere
with Sarah's relationship
with her mother.
It was an extremely
bitter divorce.
But, I see my coming
to Chicago as...
Serendipity,
a chance to reconnect
with my daughter.
Sure. I certainly
understand that.
Since you've seen me
professionally, I assume
everything I've told you
is confidential.
I'd prefer
if Sarah didn't know
about my condition,
my need to see
a psychiatrist.
Of course, you have
nothing to worry about.
I will zap this prescription
into the hospital pharmacy,
and I will get back to you
with a referral.
In the meantime,
it's lovely to meet you.
I'm a great admirer
of your daughter.
Thanks.
Dr. Sexton.
Paramedics called ahead
with a STEMI alert.
Mr. Murphy got aspirin
and morphine on the ride.
Just started an esmolol drip.
EKG.
Yeah.
Big ST elevations
in the lateral anterior leads.
X-ray?
Uh, normal.
Except for some mild
pulmonary congestion.
Time is muscle,
Dr. Sexton, so?
We get him to
the cath lab for a stent.
Now.
All right, Mr. Murphy,
you're having a heart attack,
but we're gonna take care
of you, okay?
Open up that blocked artery.
Can't believe it.
What's up?
I just got this
from my father.
He's relocated to Chicago.
He wants to get together.
Wow.
Yeah, the nerve.
I mean, I've gotten, like,
two birthday cards
in 20 years.
He totally disappeared
from my life,
and now he thinks he can
just leave me a note
and I'll come running
to see him.
Well, I can
certainly understand
why that would
make you angry.
Right.
What would you do?
Well, I mean,
that's not...
That's not
for me to say.
But...
But what?
Well, I mean, I think,
when a family member,
you know,
somebody important
in your life is...
Wants to seek resolution,
that's never
a bad thing, is it?
So, you think
I should see him?
I didn't say that.
I just...
I think it's
a personal decision.
Well, that still
sounds like a "Yes."
Mmm, I'm not going to.
Hey, Doc, I got a patient
in Four, Brittany Coleman.
Stabbed her neighbor.
Cops have her under guard.
Seems pretty nutty.
Wanna take a look?
"Pretty nutty,"
is that a...
Is that
a clinical term?
She's had fentanyl,
but no sedation.
I'll be right there.
Dr. Bekker,
what do we got?
Meet Mr. Murphy.
Some genius in the E.D.
sent him to the cath lab
with a STEMI.
Take a look at his aorta.
Damn, it's blue.
Aortic dissection?
That's what
I'm afraid of.
Where's that echo, Marty?
Coming up now.
Yep. Type-A proximal
aortic dissection.
This guy's in big trouble.
Diagnosis should've
been made an hour ago.
Heart's been ischemic
for too long.
He's gonna need
a bentall procedure
to repair.
Hope your dance card's free.
I can't go it alone.
You're in luck.
Put him into deep
hypothermic arrest.
Let's take us down
to 18 degrees.
Put the cooling wrap
on his head.
Let's see if we can't
save this guy's life.
Somehow, at night,
he gets in my apartment,
and he moves
my things around.
Okay.
He poisoned my food,
my water.
Is he alive?
Where is he?
He is alive.
Oh, my God.
.5 of Ativan,
please, Maggie.
Well, don't let him near me!
Oh, we won't. We will not.
What is she doing?
She's just giving you
something to make you
a little bit calmer.
Thank you, Maggie.
You know, he...
He started by killing the pets
in my neighborhood.
Brittany, I can
promise you this,
you're safe here.
You have nothing
to worry about.
What I'd like you to do
is try and get a little rest,
and then I'm gonna
come back later,
and we can talk
some more, okay?
I'll see you in a bit.
Head case?
Well, Ms. Coleman
certainly appears
paranoid and delusional,
but I'd like to know
what's driving it.
What are the labs saying?
Tox screen
is negative,
but she is malnourished
and extremely dehydrated.
She definitely has
some kidney damage.
Yeah, that's
not surprising.
I mean, she hasn't been
drinking water or eating.
She thinks Mr. Gardner's
trying to poison her.
Says she acted
in self-defense.
Yeah, but how
can we believe her?
You just more or less said
she's crazy, right?
Can't have it
both ways.
Well, Jay, he's saying
we don't know yet.
Yeah, I mean, just because
you're paranoid
doesn't mean
they're not after you.
All right, well, in any case,
I wanna get her statement
and get a tech down here
to take her prints
to match 'em to the knife.
Get a much clearer
picture for you
if we let her
calm down a bit.
I'm sorry, guys.
She admitted
to stabbing someone,
so it doesn't matter
if you certify her or not,
compos mentis,
she's a suspect.
Fair enough.
All right,
lead the way.
Okay.
Hey, Mags?
Mmm-hmm?
You know Barry's
court appearance
is today.
And you're
telling me this why?
Well, I just thought,
maybe you'd wanna go.
I don't.
Look, Maggie,
I understand,
but still I...
Nat, he had
plenty of chances
to tell me the truth,
but he didn't.
I get it,
but the only reason
why you know
the truth now,
is because
he used a gun
to save my life.
Infant with
a bad cough in Two.
Go. Please go.
Okay.
Ms. Campos?
Hi, I'm Dr. Manning.
Why don't you tell me
about your little girl,
Abby?
About a week ago,
she came down
with a cold,
and it kept getting worse,
and now she has
this really bad cough.
And it sounds
so strange.
Is that normal?
My sister, Wendy.
Hi.
Um, I'm gonna take
a listen to her chest,
but you can hold her
while I do that, okay?
Of course.
Temperature's 101.2
Thank you.
Hey, it's okay.
It's all right.
Okay, so, that sound
that you're hearing,
it's what we call
stridor cough.
Uh, it could be
caused by croup,
but more likely pertussis,
whooping cough.
I'm pretty sure that's
what we're looking at here.
Abby already had
her first DTaP shot.
She's not due for
the second one.
Unfortunately,
she doesn't have
full immunity yet.
Oh, God.
Is it, uh, really serious?
It can be,
but Abby doesn't seem
to be doing too badly.
I'd like to start her
on antibiotics,
give her some Tylenol
for her fever,
and run some labs
just to confirm.
Let's get a babygram,
a CBC, BMP,
and do a nasal swab
for cultures and a PCR.
Right.
Thank you.
Is there anyone
you'd like us
to contact?
My husband's
out of town
on business.
I'll give him a call.
All right, just hang tight
a little while longer.
I'll be back to check soon.
Thank you.
Yeah.
So, I saw this patient.
Guy is taking big doses
of acetaminophen
for back pain, right?
Then he gets a cold,
and starts taking
an over-the-counter
cold medication,
also with acetaminophen.
He comes in with...
Liver damage.
Yeah, people don't read
the labels.
What's up?
My dad is trying
to get in touch with me.
Oh, really?
Finally.
I mean,
that's a good thing, right?
No... It isn't.
My, uh...
I wrote my Mom about it,
and, uh,
this is what she said.
"Stay away from him.
He'll only hurt you."
Hmm. That's rough.
My mom is a mess.
Yeah, she hates my Dad.
I never should've written her.
Oh, hey, my patient,
Joe Murphy,
how'd his stent go?
Uh...
Any word?
Give me a sec.
Oh, he didn't get a stent.
He went straight
to the O.R.
But why?
Well, he didn't have
a heart attack.
What do you mean?
He didn't have
a heart attack.
Aortic dissection?
Mmm-hmm.
Okay, I'm...
No, no, no.
I'ma head up to surgery.
Text me if you need me,
okay?
Okay.
Dr. Rhodes, how's he looking?
Your patient, Doctor?
Yeah.
Brilliant.
Repairs to the heart
are complete.
Let's wean him off pump.
Cutting to two liters.
All right.
He's tolerating it.
Take him off pump.
Off pump.
Damn it,
right heart failure.
Yeah, heart's ballooning.
Echo confirms.
Mean arterial pressure's
down to 30. He's crashing.
Put him back on pump.
I'm on it.
He had all the symptoms
of a heart attack.
Marty, where are we at
with drugs?
He's maxed out on everything.
Dopamine, dobutamine,
milrinone.
All right, let's add epi.
Up inhaled nitric to 20.
And two amps of bicarb.
He's severely malperfused.
You're gonna kill his organs.
I'm aware, Dr. Rhodes.
Is this why
you brought me in?
So I could share
in your disaster?
April?
Heart rate's 110.
Oh, I don't feel good.
Let's get another
blood pressure.
Why is this happening?
Started out a normal day.
Oh, God, how did
I end up here?
Nobody expects
to wind up here,
but I promise
we'll take
good care of you.
BP's 108 over 76.
Wait...
Knife must've
nicked his stomach.
Didn't show up
on the scan.
Trent, I'm sorry,
but we have to
get you to surgery.
Let the O.R. know
we're sending him up
for an emergency laparoscopy.
Dr. Manning, this is
my husband, Aaron,
our son.
Ben, say hello to Dr. Manning.
Hi.
You know, it's
a little tight in there.
Would you guys
mind waiting
out in the lobby?
Sure.
You'll let me know
how Abby's doing?
Yeah.
Come on, buddy.
I know.
Hi.
She sounds worse.
All right,
let me take a listen.
Hi.
All right.
Maybe the antibiotics
aren't working.
They just need
some more time.
Let's start her
on the nebulizer.
What's that?
It's gonna open up her lungs,
make her more comfortable
until the antibiotics
start to work.
Go ahead.
Okay.
Are you ready?
Thank you.
So, I'm gonna have you
hold this right here,
just like that.
Okay.
Yeah?
That's perfect.
All right, you let us know
if you need anything, okay?
Thank you.
Yeah. Thanks.
The first microsecond
of the Big Bang,
the inflationary epic
of the universe,
when it went from
the size of an atom
to the size of a marble,
lasted 10 undecillions
of a second.
That's 10
to the negative 36th.
That's just slightly longer
than the attention span
of the average
college student.
So, we can get
a few of the "hows"
of the universe.
As to the "whys," well,
that's a question for Siri.
See you all next week.
Sarah.
How do you even know
what I look like?
Look, you have every right
to be angry with me.
What do you want?
Just another chance.
Just... Wait.
Dr. Charles,
this is Ms. Sutton,
a friend of your patient's,
Ms. Coleman.
Alana.
Nice to meet you, Alana.
I was hoping
I could see Brittany.
Would it be all right?
Do you mind if I ask you
a few questions first?
Oh, of course.
You're a psychiatrist.
Yes.
Um, so, how do you
know Brittany?
I'm a very close friend.
Uh-huh, so then,
you know why she's here?
Yeah, I heard.
It's terrible.
I mean,
what would make her
do such a thing?
Well, that's what
we're trying to figure out.
You know, have you
noticed anything unusual
in her behavior recently?
She has seemed
a little more nervous,
and I do know that she's had
problems with her neighbor.
He's a very unpleasant man.
Could he have
threatened her?
Well, the police
are investigating all that.
Good.
By the way,
did she mention anything
about a check for me?
Sorry?
I'm thinking
it might not be
a good time to bring
it up with her.
I mean, it's not important.
Can I see her now?
Yes, um, I think
that she might find
your presence reassuring.
Thank God you're here.
You poor dear.
Poor dear.
Help! We need
a doctor! Help!
She's having
some kind of fit.
She's seizing.
Get me some suction.
Got it.
Ativan?
.05 mgs per kilogram IV.
Right.
Oh, my baby.
Oh, my God.
Oxygen.
I can't stand
to see her like this.
Isn't there anything else
you can do for her?
Lauren, we are
doing everything
that we can for her, okay?
We'll be back to check
on her again soon.
Dr. Manning?
Yes?
A couple of weeks ago,
we visited my sister
and the baby,
and my son, Ben,
he, um, he had
a little bit of a cold.
But that couldn't
cause this, right?
The whooping cough?
No, not if it was
just a cold.
Okay.
A mild case of whooping cough
can present as a cold,
but I'm assuming that
your son is vaccinated?
Wendy?
He isn't.
Then, yes.
Your sister's baby
could've caught this
from your son.
Oh, my God.
Has your son had any
of his childhood inoculations?
No, my husband
doesn't believe in it.
Not this guy?
Excuse me? Can I talk to you?
Yeah.
So, your wife tells me
that Ben hasn't had
any of his childhood
vaccinations.
Oh, God, here we go.
Really? You had to tell her?
You know how these
people think, honey.
Yeah, I had to tell her.
If you notice, Doctor,
our son is doing just fine.
Yeah, maybe he's just fine,
but your niece is in there
with whooping cough,
most likely
because of him,
because of you.
You don't know that.
That baby is
suffering horribly.
She could die.
Aaron!
Look, I'm sorry,
but I have to do
what I think is right.
I have to protect my son.
Oh, you think
you're protecting him?
Do you have any idea
how dangerous an E.D. is
for a child without immunity?
Do not assume
that there aren't
more idiots
like you out there.
Excuse me?
And who knows
what these kids might have.
Measles, mumps, polio?
Get your son out of here.
I'm serious.
Get your son
out of here, now!
Ben, come on, let's go.
Dad...
Now, come on.
Let's go.
I'm staying with Lauren.
Wendy?
And, honey,
go with your dad, okay?
I'll be home
as soon as I can.
Okay.
Mean arterial
pressure is 53,
58, 65.
It's coming up.
Bypass.
Now.
We're still giving
blood products?
No.
How about meds?
He's still on
maximal support,
but his urine output
has improved.
Profusion's improving.
I think he's stable enough
to decannulate.
I agree.
He's looking good.
Great.
No thanks to you.
Let's just close him up.
Trent, we understand
the surgery went well.
We'll get you up
to your own room,
as soon as
a bed opens up.
Thank you.
What's she doing here?
The woman
who attacked you,
she was injured.
But don't worry,
she's under guard.
No, no, not her,
the other one.
I think she's a friend.
Keep her away from me.
Keep her away.
Dr. Charles,
I went to see my Dad.
What made you
change your mind?
I don't know.
Maybe, because my mother
told me to stay away from him.
Ah.
But it's not just about
me being rebellious.
All these years,
I've wondered who he is,
why he left.
You always tell me
there are two sides
to a story.
I wanted to hear my dad's.
Makes sense.
Oh, and just so you know,
my dad said he did write me.
Really? He said that?
Yeah, yeah.
My mom must've thrown
the letters away.
Huh.
He's not really the monster
she made him out to be.
He's a professor
of astrophysics.
He's brilliant,
his students love him.
He's, um, taking me
to dinner tonight,
at the Faculty Club.
Maggie, what's the, uh...
The new extension
for the pharmacy again?
4482.
This is Dr. Charles.
I sent in a prescription
this morning,
for a Robert Haywood.
Lorazepam.
He pick that up yet?
He didn't?
You sure?
Okay, thank you.
Dr. Charles, my patient,
Mr. Gardner,
you know,
he was more upset
seeing the friend
of the woman
who stabbed him.
The friend?
Alana?
Yeah.
He says she filed
a crazy lawsuit
against him
to get possession
of his apartment.
It cost him
thousands of dollars
to get it dismissed.
He says
he often sees her
outside our building,
staring up at his place.
Somehow, she's
got it in her head
that his apartment
belongs to her.
Poison! Get it away!
Ma'am, you need to
get back on the bed, now.
I got this.
And he poisoned me!
I told you! I told you!
Calm down.
He's trying... I told you.
He has poison.
Brittany.
.5 of Ativan.
Look at me.
I'm not gonna
let anyone hurt you.
I told you.
He's trying to kill me.
I'm not safe. He...
No.
No, I can't...
So, tell me again
how you figured out
that your neighbor
was poisoning you.
Well, you can't taste it.
It's just a little bit,
but it builds up
in your body
and it kills you.
And...
Alana saw him do it.
Oh, Alana saw him?
Yeah.
Uh-huh.
She knows what he's up to.
I got it.
You two are, uh...
You're very close,
aren't you?
Oh, yes.
How long have
you known her for?
I don't know,
a couple of years.
We met at the farmer's market.
Ah.
I don't know
what I would do
without her.
Alana looks after me.
You know, if she lived...
Next to me,
instead of that man,
I would be safe.
She wants to be close,
so she can protect me.
Hey there.
How's Brittany?
Better.
Thank God.
When will she be able
to come home?
I'm not so sure
that she will.
I mean, not
right away anyway.
She's gonna definitely
need more therapy,
and, well, frankly,
there's a
very good chance
she gets arrested.
Arrested?
Yeah.
That's terrible.
Who's gonna drive me
to exercise class?
Excuse me?
I don't have a car.
Brittany drives me.
Very nice of her.
Did you say something
before, about a check?
Did I?
Yeah.
Oh, well,
Brittany is helping me
with this month's rent.
Oh.
I'm not very good with money.
She really is such a...
A kind, agreeable person,
isn't she?
Mmm-hmm.
Chauffeuring you around
and giving you money.
She lends me money.
Of course.
I'm a very good
friend to her.
There is no doubt
in my mind.
You know, um,
I should have
some news
for you very soon.
Why don't we find you
a warmer place to wait?
Okay.
BP's stable.
Let's start titrating
down the epinephrine.
Nice job.
How could I
have missed that?
I did a chest X-ray
and an EKG...
Neither of which showed
the aortic dissection.
Look, every indication
was that the guy was
having a heart attack.
What if I had just done
a bedside echo?
Why?
Look, you thought
your priority was
to get him
to the cath lab.
But that was wrong.
Look, we're all taught
to see things a certain way,
and most of the time,
that works, just...
Not all the time.
It is a very,
very hard thing
to see past
our assumptions.
Believe me,
I'm still learning.
Code blue.
Oh, my God.
She's cyanotic.
She needs more oxygen.
Oh, no.
Sats at 88,
86... 80.
We need to intubate.
Intubate? A tube?
Yes, I'm sorry.
.14 of atropine,
2 of etomidate, 14 of sux.
What are you doing?
Is she gonna make it?
I'm in.
Take over bagging, Monique.
Did it work?
Heart rate's back up to 110.
Sats at 98. She's stable.
It's all my fault.
It's all
my fault that she's sick.
What are you
talking about?
I am so sorry!
I'm so sorry.
What?
Ben. We thought
he just had a cold.
What?
We never gave him his shots.
Shots? You mean,
Ben had whooping cough?
It seems likely.
He never had his shots,
and you let him near Abby?
I didn't know.
How could you?
I am so sorry.
You did this
to my baby! Get out!
Get out!
I think we're dealing
with a case of folie  deux.
And that is...
A shared delusion.
Heads up, guys,
I got an arrest warrant
for Brittany Coleman,
attempted murder.
Gonna transfer her
to the psych ward
at Cook County.
Before you do that,
there's somebody
I'd like you to meet.
Two minutes.
Alana.
This is Detective Halstead.
I thought it would be
very important
for him to get
your perspective
on how this all unfolded.
How do you do?
Uh, maybe we should talk
somewhere more private?
Oh, all right.
Great.
So, how can I help?
So, I understand
that you were the one
who warned Ms. Coleman
about her neighbor, right?
That he was
poisoning her food,
putting gas
through the vents.
And he's a child molester.
Did you know that?
I haven't seen
any indication
of a criminal record.
Huh. Now, what about
Mr. Gardner's apartment?
What do you mean?
Well, that you think
it should be yours.
Who told you that?
We're just trying
to understand
all the different factors
that might've prompted
Brittany to attack
her neighbor, that's all.
I hope you don't
think that...
I don't know
what he has been telling you,
or how he has twisted things,
but I have only wanted
to protect Brittany.
Here's the thing,
you could look at this case
and come to
a different conclusion.
That maybe you didn't really
care that much about Brittany,
and you just wanted her
to kill her neighbor,
so that you could
have his apartment.
He's out of his mind.
You keep lying,
and something really bad
might happen to you.
Ma'am, was that a threat?
No, of course not.
You sure know how to
bring out the best in people.
Yeah, it's a gift.
So the way I see it,
Alana is who we refer to
as the inducer.
So, is Brittany insane?
I think she's malleable,
impressionable,
maybe a little paranoid,
but without Alana's influence,
she would let go
of the delusion
and probably
even be remorseful
for what she did.
Was Alana making
the whole thing up,
or did she really think
Trent was evil?
Well, evil in the sense
that he was standing
in her way.
And she did all that
for an apartment?
I would diagnose Alana
as a psychopath.
I mean, they get off
on playing those kinda games.
I'm sorry, guys,
I still got to
arrest Brittany.
But Jay, is she really
the criminal here?
We might be able to charge
Alana with accountability,
bur for now, I got
a signed complaint
from the victim.
Here you go.
Thank you.
Hey.
That guy who didn't
immunize his kid,
did I hear you
call him an idiot?
That was a very
Will Halstead moment.
I just... I can't stand it.
No matter how much science
we give people,
no matter how much proof,
they just go on believing
what they wanna believe.
I mean, the guy who started
this whole anti-vac thing
has been completely
discredited.
So, what is wrong
with people?
Why do they keep clinging
to this myth?
Mass hysteria.
Yeah, and that baby
pays the price.
See ya.
All right.
I had my arraignment today.
I know.
I pleaded guilty.
Sentencing's next week.
I wanna explain, Maggie.
I was barely 17.
Barry, I've heard
a lot of stories today.
I'm really not up to
hearing another one.
I got busted
for aggravated battery.
Juvie records are sealed,
but state agencies
still have access.
I never would've gotten a job.
So, I changed my name.
I thought...
That's not the point.
All the time
we were together,
you never told me.
I'm trying...
I don't know who you are.
I don't know. Just...
Hi.
So, good news.
Abby's latest labs
show her white count
has come down,
and I am also very encouraged
by her latest chest X-ray.
Really?
Yeah.
So, I'd like to do
what we call
a spontaneous breathing trial.
I'll see if she can
breathe on her own
without the ventilator.
Okay.
Go ahead and turn it down.
She's breathing.
Sats are holding.
Respiratory rate
and tidal volumes are good.
Hmm, I think she's turned
the corner.
Oh, thank God.
Monique?
Oh, my baby.
Have you seen my sister?
Do you know
if she's still here?
She is.
Dr. Haywood.
Dr. Charles.
I'm taking Sarah
out to dinner.
So she said.
I was there
when she got
your note.
I played dumb.
Thank you.
She told me
about your ex-wife.
Uh, kinda disturbing
that she destroyed
all your letters.
Uh, yeah, it was a, uh...
Nasty divorce.
I know all about those.
Listen, your prescription
is waiting for you
in the pharmacy.
Great.
Anytime you're ready.
Thank you.
You know, frankly,
just talking to you
this morning
made me feel
a whole lot better.
Well, good.
Just so I know,
did you decide to share
your condition with Sarah?
No, not yet.
I don't wanna make her think
I might need
something from her.
Well, like what?
Uh, well...
You know, honestly,
I don't have many friends,
no other family.
My ex-wives refuse
to even talk to me.
You might say
I've burned all my bridges.
Right.
When your health starts
to deteriorate,
who are you gonna turn to
to take care of ya?
Well, it's natural, isn't it?
Daughter taking care
of her father?
Plus, I admit,
I'm not very good
with money,
so I could use Sarah's help
in that department.
Uh, everything I tell you
is confidential.
Of course. Of course.
Good.
A-ha! Here she is.
You met my dad.
Yes, I did.
Ready?
Yes.
Good night, Dr. Charles.
Nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you too.
You were throwing in
some beautiful stitches
back there.
Fast.
No, you moved right with me.
Spot-on with the graft.
Yeah.
So, which of your
myriad girlfriends
gets Dr. Rhodes tonight?
Yeah, no.
Tonight, it is just
me and Jimmy Fallon.
I've gotta... I gotta
pace myself, you know?
You're a real mystery.
You used to be
such a one-woman guy.
Yeah, well,
that didn't work out
particularly well, did it?
Ah.
Aortic dissection.
Very often fatal.
Mazel tov to you both.
Thank you.
I emailed you a case,
conjoined twins.
We plan to separate them
in about a month.
It's going to be a long
and difficult procedure,
involving several departments.
I am putting together
our team.
I look forward to it.
Actually, I haven't decided
which of my fellows
I'm going to include,
but I wanted everyone
to be au courant.
Sure.
You know,
we often say "mazel tov"
as an offer
of congratulations,
but it literally means
"good luck."
It sounds like
he's only going
to bring on one of us.
Yeah.
You shouldn't have invited me
into the aortic dissection.
You could've grabbed
all the glory for yourself.
Gotten a leg up.
That's what I get
for hedging my bet.
Yeah, it's better
to go all-in.