They found this guy in Maine
who had been living completely
alone in the woods for 30 years.
They called him
the last true hermit.
Thirty years without the
warmth of human touch,
without conversation.
The hermit felt more lonely
when he was out in the world...
Alex! Alex!
Than he ever felt in
the woods by himself.
Surrounded by people
but drowning in solitude.
That kind of loneliness
can swallow you whole.
Hi. I texted you.
Yeah, I saw that. I was busy.
Well, Cristina would've
responded. That's not how it works.
Not if she was doing
what I was doing.
You pause. That's the rule.
What? If the text is urgent,
Cristina would say
to Owen, "Pause,"
and I would say
to Derek, "Pause,"
then we'd text each other back.
In the middle of sex?
If the text is urgent.
The fact you are
checking your text
while you're doing
it is already sad.
We have a special ringtone.
Hey, you want a special ringtone?
No. Wait, this pause thing...
Like, your legs are in the air
and you're screaming and...
Pause. No, I don't
pause. Jo doesn't pause.
She fast-forwards, she rewinds,
but she doesn't pause.
Okay, that's gross.
Do you wanna scrub
in on my IVC sarcoma?
Is it a kid? No.
Then no. Why?
Because I want some company.
Get a resident.
I have a resident.
I want a grownup.
Bye.
Cristina would've scrubbed
in. You're no good at this...
Bailey!
You wanna scrub in
on my IVC sarcoma?
Well, you don't need me for
that. Don't you have a resident?
Residents are boring.
All they wanna do is learn.
Come on. It's gonna be good.
It's all over the
liver, hepatic vein.
It's gonna be bloody and gross.
Does look like fun.
Page me when you're
ready. See you in the OR.
Adrian Nelson, 51.
Presents with abdominal pain.
Scans show a leiomyosarcoma
behind the liver, including the IVC.
What's the surgical plan?
Laparotomy to
isolate the vessel,
resect the tumor, and
then replace with a graft.
It's a pretty straightforward
procedure, Adrian.
I don't foresee any problems.
Could I ask you to...
It's silly. Never mind.
What is it?
She wants you to
swear on the book.
The Odyssey.
It's the first book I
ever sold to Adrian.
The day we met.
Michael's a rare book vendor.
Our hands touched
when I was ringing her up,
and it was such a high.
It was electric.
We were both too
shy to ask for a date.
So I wrote my
number on a bookmark.
I saw it as soon as I got
home, and then I called.
We've been together ever since.
This book, it's
our wedding ring.
Could you swear on the book,
Dr. Grey, that you'll do your best?
It would mean so much.
Dr. Wilson, too.
Sure. I swear.
So Dr. Wilson will prep
you, and I'll see you up there.
They're adorable.
They're weirdos.
Okay, you're gonna
feel a little bit of pressure.
And this will tell
us conclusively
if the osteogenesis
imperfecta is type II or III?
Yes. It's probably
type III though, right?
I mean, so far there's been
no indication of fetal distress.
We'll know soon enough.
It'll be okay. OI type
III, it's hard, sure.
I mean, there's surgeries and
challenges, but we're surgeons.
We can handle challenges, right?
Mmm-hmm. I mean, we'll...
We'll still be able to give our
baby a wonderful life. Right?
Many type III babies
live very, very happy lives.
Shouldn't Dr. Herman
be doing this?
It's a very routine procedure.
Dr. Herman is the big gun.
We only fire the big gun
when we need the big gun.
I'm the little gun. So
let the little gun work.
Thank you so much. I know
that took up a lot of your time.
I just wanna get
all of the views
with the thinnest
cross sections I can get.
And I find that adorable.
You really think you can
pull off your plan, huh?
I've got all your
past medical records.
Once I get a firm grasp
on the roads your other
surgeons took to get to "no,"
I can cut away a
clear path to "yes."
By the time I'm done with your
tumor, I'm gonna be able to tell you
what street this
bastard grew up on
and where it lost its virginity.
Hmm! Well, you
certainly are confident.
Thank you. Or delusional.
One of the two.
It's hard to tell.
They look so similar.
So I think we need to
talk about what we'll decide
if it turns out the
baby's type II.
I already told you, he won't be.
Yeah, I know that's what
you believe. So do I, obviously.
But if he is type II,
then it's so terrible...
I know. And fatal usually.
All right? And before
that, it's even worse.
I know all of this. I just... I
don't wanna talk about it.
But we should talk about
it. We need to talk about it.
Why? Why can't we
just wait until tomorrow?
Because we should have
a plan. What do you mean?
Okay, what do you wanna do?
That's what I'm saying.
I think we should decide.
No, no. I'm asking
what you want.
I want for us to figure
this out together.
I don't think that's true.
I think that you already know
what you would wanna do.
So... What?
Just... Yeah, just
say it out loud.
Don't... Right now.
What do you wanna do?
If our baby is type II, I...
I think we should terminate.
And I don't care whether
our baby is type II or type III.
Either way, I wanna keep him.
April!
I told you I didn't
wanna talk about this.
Look at all these adhesions.
Yeah, there's no way
to see 'em coming.
Sneaky little bastards
won't show up on the scan.
And there's more of
them posteriorly, too.
I need some more exposure.
You're thinking of
extending the incision?
I have to. I can't see
what's up in there.
This tumor just keeps coming.
And all the landmarks are obscured.
I'm lost in here. It's
like going in blind.
Hey! Would you bring
those scans closer, please?
Yes, Doctor.
See, the tumor should be
in the suprahepatic IVC only.
That can't be right.
It doesn't show any
further local invasion.
Show me the coronal view?
What's the tumor doing
all the way over there?
That's what I want to know.
- How old are these scans?
- They're only two weeks old.
And they're completely outdated.
I mean, this thing
is growing too fast.
Nothing is where
it's supposed to be.
Tumor has extended
to the IVC tributaries.
Yeah, these scans are useless.
I can't see what I'm doing.
Oh, God. It's also spreading
through the diaphragm. Suction.
I can't even see where...
Neither can I.
Don't touch that. It's tearing.
The tumor's extended all
the way up between the lungs.
Someone page cardio! It's all
the way up into the pericardium.
Get the suction out. Don't
touch it. Don't do anything.
Okay, page cardio, 911!
We gotta get out.
Everybody out. Hands off.
What are we doing?
What's going on?
Can someone say
something? What are we doing?
It's spread from her major
blood vessels to her liver,
diaphragm, pericardium,
and maybe even her heart.
How can one tumor
grow this big this fast?
It is everywhere.
It's a monster.
So what do we do?
I have no idea.
Michael, I'm afraid Adrian's
tumor has grown considerably
and it's now reaching
around her heart.
So Dr. Pierce is here.
Her heart?
It's entangled through
the vein that stretches up
from her liver to her heart.
And it's growing more
rapidly than anticipated.
So we need to take
her for more MRIs
so we can see how
extensive the tumor's growth is.
Now there's all of you.
Three doctors.
Three is a lot.
Look, Odysseus didn't
return to Ithaca all by himself.
He needed a lot of help,
right, from the Phaeacians?
Well, we're the Phaeacians.
You want all the
Phaeacians you can get.
We are going to
figure this tumor out.
Oh!
Mmm! So light. And
it's last year's model.
We're weeks away
from unveiling one
that will weigh 30% less.
Wow. Very impressive.
Your project is impressive.
Robotic limbs for
injured vets? Sexy as hell.
And we at CyberSystems are
dying to climb into bed with you.
Well, that's very flattering.
Good. I want it to be.
I'll leave you this folder so
you can go over the materials.
I'll be in Seattle another day,
so, please, call me
if you need anything.
Thank you. Thank
you for coming in.
So what do you think?
I think you should
definitely go for it. Really?
'Cause I was not that
impressed with these transducers.
What? No. No,
those things are crap.
I'm talking about her.
Her vibes? You
didn't feel her vibes?
Major vibage for Major Hunt.
You read that totally wrong.
Oh, please.
"Your project's sexy as hell.
"Ooh! Ooh, let's
climb into bed."
I was actually uncomfortable.
Stop it!
There you are.
Where have you been?
I was performing a
CVS on April Kepner.
We're just waiting for the
results. God, I hate waiting.
In peds, it's so much easier.
You know, the
parents are right there.
And you talk to them, and
then their kid is right there,
so they can hold them
close and hope for the best.
The cat's on the roof.
With this, there's
no kid to hold.
The problem
feels so theoretical.
You know, there's
no cat, there's no roof.
There's just two scared
parents feeling totally helpless.
And you've had
the results rushed?
Yeah. I should get
them in, like, 24 hours.
Then there's nothing more to
do about it today, which is good.
I have been working miracles.
I have found us the
most incredible surgeries,
all for the next few weeks.
Look, a TTTS in a 19-weeker,
a 21-week TRAP
sequence that needs an RFA,
a unilateral pulmonary agenesis.
And that is just the beginning.
The beginning of what?
Your crash course.
I have hunted down
the most screwed up,
medically compromised
fetuses that I could find,
and I'm bringing them
all here to this hospital
for you to learn and us to save.
And you'll get to
fix them all? We will.
Start reading.
You can thank me later.
And then, and this sounds
crazy, I know, so don't even...
I'll build in a distribution of a
radioactive seed during surgery,
keeping Dr. Herman's tumor
bed free of recurring cells.
I thought you were
gonna use a laser.
I am. I already did.
We're way past that.
Try and keep up.
I'm sorry, Shepherd, but
this is a great opportunity
for them to learn.
I know. It's fine.
The laser is for ablating
cells off the optic nerve.
It's a massive butterfly glioma.
Well, it's not just massive.
I mean, it's magnificent.
No, no, no. I mean that
won't a laser take months?
Again, before
that, I'll be using
the ultrasonic surgical aspirator
to mush and flush the cells,
then the sexy laser
and the... Yeah.
I'm sorry. I'm just lost.
You were just talking
about laser ablation.
So is that confined
to the optic chiasm
or will that extend...
Guys, step back.
Look at the whole big,
beautiful, shapely thing.
Every part of this tumor's
body will respond differently.
You will need a
multitude of approaches.
You will have to be gentle with
one part and rough with the other.
That is the only way
she will respond. Get it?
I don't see tumors
the way she does.
Didn't five surgeons say any
one of these approaches would
likely kill the patient?
Six.
But none of them tried it all at
the same time. It should work.
Maybe we should start over
again from the beginning.
Okay.
I will begin with a
bifrontal approach.
Is that the right
atrium? I can't tell.
Everything looks like mush.
Look at this angle right here.
Is that invading
the right atrium?
I think that's a
motion artifact.
Crap. MIRANDA:
Adrian's back in her room.
Stable for now.
How we doing here?
Has the Cyclops revealed
himself? The Cyclops?
Well, the patient's a
fan of The Odyssey,
so I'm calling the
tumor the Cyclops
'cause it's a big, ugly monster.
And I feel like I'm working with
one eye because I can see it,
but I can't get a sense
of the whole thing.
Every view is incomplete.
Okay, what if we get a new
set of scans, with contrast,
this time with 3-D
reconstruction?
Well, the woman's
lying open in her bed.
We don't have time
for a lot of trial and error.
I just wanna
reach in and grab it.
Well, we could go in with
these, but, yeah, I can't see.
If I could just hold it in my
hand so that I could see it...
Holy crap. What?
She's having an idea.
I already had it last
year, and it's brilliant.
We are going to print
it. The whole tumor.
I tried it with the portal
veins, but it's not working.
But with this, we don't
need it to function.
She's got a functioning tumor.
We just need to be able to see it,
- so we know how to kill it.
- Know your enemy.
Is this gonna work? It'll work.
Oh, 2% left to upload.
This is how we beat this thing.
This is how we
get visualization.
We are going to have a
tangible, anatomically correct
3-D model of this exact tumor, and
correlate to the adjacent organs...
Done! Loaded!
In 10 hours.
The longest documented
surviving type II case that I could find
lived for all of 18 months.
In an ICU his entire life,
hooked up to feeding
tubes and a ventilator.
That's not a life.
That's not a life I
want for my son.
Neither do I. I...
Okay. So then how can you...
Because we don't
know what will happen.
We don't even know if he's
type II. Okay, but what if he is?
Any amount of time
that he survives,
any amount of
time that he lives...
Will be with us,
in our arms. Yes.
Knowing that he's
loved and wanted.
Baby, his bones can
break if you touch him.
His bones can break if
we're changing his diaper.
We're doctors. We can handle it.
If anyone can handle it, we can.
I'm not saying we can't handle
it. I'm asking if we should.
Yeah, we're doctors.
Maybe we are better equipped to
make an educated decision here.
And maybe we were
given this baby for a reason.
April.
You called your mom.
Yeah. People need
their mom in a crisis.
No, not everybody does.
I came as soon as I
got your call, sweetie.
It's okay. Everything's
gonna be okay.
I'm here.
Are you working today?
No. Then let's get out of here.
You could use a
change of scenery.
That's actually a
really good idea.
We should take the day,
go somewhere nice,
maybe drive to the ocean.
Let's go to church.
You'll find comfort there.
Yeah, go ahead.
Let's go pray.
She is doing fine.
Those chairs
will kill your back.
You should go home
and get some rest.
I can't.
I can't go home alone
when she's like this.
Thought I'd just stay and read.
Okay. That's fine.
But I can't read either.
Can't concentrate.
It's odd. I've never
had that problem.
I think it's because I
don't know where she is.
I always know where she is.
She's right here.
It's just as if she's asleep
in the bed next to you.
Not really.
Because she might not wake up.
I feel like...
Like she's sailed away and I
don't know if she's coming back.
That's the feeling, you know?
Michael, we are working
very hard to solve this.
I know.
I know. I just...
I just want her to come back.
I do, too.
This HLHS case seems impossible.
This mother's pregnant
for the third time,
and each baby was stillborn.
Well, this one will be, too.
22q11 deletion?
She should adopt.
Now this one, however...
Tracheal balloon occlusion
for CDH? Card that puppy.
How do you do this without... I
mean, these stories are awful.
They're patients, Robbins.
The more you find, the more
you learn, the more we save.
It's as simple as that.
Your work is making
these three categories,
possible, impossible, maybe.
Any other approach
is a waste of our time.
Ah!
Oh, wow.
Holy crap. It's fate!
Look! It's your sexy tech
rep! Your sexy tech rep!
She's not my sexy anything.
Not yet, but she could be.
I came out tonight with
you to unwind, not to...
And she's a tech rep.
That's a conflict of interest.
Not if we don't buy
her transducers. Mmm.
They're junk, anyway.
Come on! You gotta
get back in the saddle.
And she's got a nice saddle.
Oh, yeah.
What? Whoa, what are you doing?
Okay, so listen, I'm not
really great at this kind of thing,
so I'm just gonna blurt it out.
I think that you were interested in
more than just our program today.
Oh, you picked up on that?
I was right!
I knew it! Okay. So
this should be easy.
Owen is a little bit shy,
but he's a great guy.
And the feeling's mutual.
So...
So what do you say?
I would say that there's
something about him
that doesn't quite
feel like he's my type.
What? No! He's...
He's very attractive.
He's nice. He's funny.
People like funny, right? I mean,
come on. Give him a chance.
What about him isn't your type?
He has a penis.
Oh!
Oh...
Oh.
Wait. No. You were...
You were flirty. I was.
But not with him.
Oh.
Um...
Wow.
I am wildly saddened by my
intense lack of game right now.
I can't believe I
didn't see that coming.
There was a time
when I would've been all,
"That's right. I know it's me."
But right now, I'm just like...
Uh...
'Cause you looking
at me like that...
You are gorgeous, by the way.
Do people just tell you that all the
time? Because you are gorgeous.
No, I'm not.
Am I? No. Am I?
No. Wait. No, no. Wait, wait.
Stop. Stop, stop, stop, stop.
Not into women? No,
no, no. I am, totally.
Women. Men. People, really.
I'm just, I'm just, I'm just...
I'm just not really
shopping right now.
I'm divorced.
And it was recent
and painful and brutal.
Brutal, actually.
Well, if you wanna
forget for just a little while,
I fly out tomorrow.
Doesn't have to be
anything more than one night.
I would love...
I would love to love
that. I'm just not ready.
I'm so sorry.
Uh...
Hi, guys. Hi.
You're here late. Well,
we're on a timeline.
I was taking a look
at Dr. Wall's notes,
and I found some
contradictory information.
He was the second opinion?
Wall is where?
Case Western.
Uh, he was third.
He's radiation.
Right. Just getting
my dates straight.
What are all these?
Cases. Fetuses.
Each card represents a fetus that
I'm gonna teach Robbins how to fix.
That I estimate we can
get to in the time I have.
And those? These?
No. These are the
ones that I could save,
if I had time.
You should just think of
them as babies who will die
if it turns out that you're full of
crap and can't take out my tumor.
Oh.
No pressure. Oh, no. Pressure.
We're on a timeline here, right?
Try being me.
Okay.
Dr. Meadows, labor and delivery.
Oh, good! You're home!
Just in time for dinner.
Smells good.
How was church?
The choir was there,
practicing for their
service tomorrow night.
Really beautiful.
We should all go to it.
I don't think we'll know what
we'll be up for tomorrow, Karen.
Because of the test results?
April told me about
the test, and I told her
there's really no point in
even getting those results.
Excuse me? God gives
what he wants to give.
No test is going to change that.
And April's already
so upset, so stressed.
It's not good for the baby.
Just focus on loving
that sweet little baby.
That's all that matters.
No, that's definitely
not all that matters.
I know, it's hard to
understand sometimes
how His plan will unfold.
Yeah, but I'm not worried
about His plan, am I?
I'm worried about our plan.
He never gives us
more than we can handle.
Getting the results,
being informed about
our baby's condition,
that's how we handle it.
I called our pastor at home.
April spoke to him at
length. He was very helpful.
April.
Me. Let me help you.
Whatever happens, we
will shoulder the burden
when it is placed upon us.
We will. You and I.
We'll shoulder the burden.
She's just trying to help.
Is she, though?
Really? Is she helping?
Don't snap at her.
Don't talk to her in
that tone. What tone?
I'm not talking using a
tone. I'm trying to understand.
You're trying to
talk my little girl
into doing something she
knows in her heart and soul
she does not want to do.
I'm not trying to talk
her into anything.
I'm supporting her in trying to
make the best choice possible
for our baby, for
her, for our family.
This is between April
and her God. Okay.
And if you think
she is going to agree
to abort her child... Our child!
You are... Get that
straight. It's our child.
Stop it! Stop it!
None of this is helping!
You are not helping,
neither of you.
I am standing here,
listening to you tell me
that God only gives
me one choice,
and you telling me that I
should forgo God's choice.
And the truth is, I
don't know anything
expect that I am scared
and sad and I'm alone.
You're both just standing there,
yelling at each other and talking at me,
but I am alone,
and it is terrifying!
And the louder you get,
the more terrified I become,
so I just need you
both to just shut up!
Can you... Can you do that?
Can you please, can you
please both just shut up?
What are you guys
still doing here?
We're solving a
tumor by 3-D printing it.
Yeah.
What are you still doing here?
Also solving a tumor.
Maybe you should
3-D print your tumor.
Visibility is not my problem.
I can see my tumor in
all its problematic glory,
and it's giving me
the middle finger
in front of Richard Webber
and a bunch of residents.
Where are the kids?
Upstairs.
Daycare. Nightcare.
Whatever care.
It's open 24 hours.
You know that's only for
surgeons on call, right?
Bailey, don't judge
me. Derek lives in DC.
No, I'm saying if they ask you,
make up something
about being on call.
When I had my genome
lab, I was on call twice a week.
You all realize that
printing this thing
is gonna take, like,
five more hours?
Seven-ish. Seven
hours and 20 minutes.
Seven and a half.
I'm just saying you could go
home, sleep, and then come back.
Someone has to stay in
case the printer crashes.
Plus, I don't mind. I like the
sound. It's kinda soothing.
It feels weird to sleep alone.
I'm not used to it.
I don't know why.
He used to go away all the time,
but this time, he's...
He's gone, and I know he's gone.
And the bed feels lonely.
It's like I don't know
how to sleep alone.
You don't.
I mean, before three months
ago, any time I called your house
or came over or
Skyped or whatever,
Cristina was there.
There's no way you ever slept
alone. I mean, you had Derek.
And if you didn't have
Derek, you had Cristina.
I'm guessing if it
came down to it,
you were, like, the middle spoon
in the middle of a very
weird spooning situation.
I've never met a less alone
person than you used...
Used to be.
I have to learn to sleep alone.
Ben snores. And he
sometimes talks in his sleep.
And he's hot.
Like a furnace.
Like flames shootin' out of him.
He's lucky I love him.
And he's a resident
and hardly home at night.
Or he'd be dead.
I miss sleeping with
a man in my bed.
You know, facing
away from each other,
barely touching expect for just
the arm thrown over your waist.
When I'd wake up at
night, terrified of me,
I liked knowing he was there
and I wasn't by myself.
I cannot sleep with
someone lying next to me.
Literally cannot.
My one serious guy, Dean.
Dean just loved to
spoon and snuggle,
and I would just lie there,
staring up silently,
counting the seconds
until he would fall asleep
and I could sneak off
to sleep on the sofa.
And then I'd sneak back into bed
before he woke
up in the morning.
Yeah, people think that's a
cute story. It's not a cute story.
That sofa was hard as
a rock. I was exhausted.
Dean is a really sweet guy.
He's tall and kind.
Civil rights lawyer.
He's funny.
So when he proposed,
I explained to him
about the sleeping.
I said,
"Maybe you could sleep
in a room down the hall."
I wanted to sleep alone.
And what happened?
He is now married to someone
who loves to spoon and snuggle.
And I sleep like a
baby every night.
I might be too
good at being alone.
Maybe I could print a Derek.
Just for sleeping.
Hey, move your butts.
Hello again, Cyclops.
It is crazy cool amazing.
It could not be more amazing.
Okay, hit me. What's next?
I think we can
divide the diaphragm
to resect the pericardial
component of the tumor.
But carefully.
We'll need to dissect
two to three centimeters
proximal to the IVC
first to control flow.
Yep, and then we can clamp
and create the
veno-venous bypass flap.
You sure you don't
wanna do a sternotomy?
Now you have something to
say? Where were you yesterday?
You should've showed me
this. Karev, what's your point?
Well, I would do
McGinn's technique
to access the chest
with less invasiveness
to avoid diaphragmatic
hernia postradiation.
He's got a point.
Back to the beginning.
Okay, so feel this, right here.
Okay, that's what, like five
centimeters superior to the renal vein?
Okay, but stop.
Close your eyes
and just feel. Okay.
Because all we have to
go on is muscle memory.
It's two fingerbreadths
from the confluence
of the hepatic veins.
And then we anastomose
the bifurcated graft.
Bailey?
Write that up.
You're their board bitch.
You're jealous,
aren't you? No. A little.
Wilson! Oh, yeah. On it.
Okay, my finger is in
the foramen of Winslow.
Bailey, can you feel me?
Yeah, I'm right behind you.
I can feel the edge
of the lesser omentum.
I think that gives me enough
space to control the porta hepatis.
Yes. Yes. I can
palpate a good window.
Good. That works.
No. All right, what next?
There is no next. The
wound VAC has frank blood.
She's bleeding. We have
to get her up to the OR.
You need an extra set
of hands? Yes. Wilson's.
Take that white board. Bring it
up where everyone can see it.
We haven't even gotten to the
retroperitoneal dissection yet.
We will when we get up there.
We'll figure it out as we go.
You are coming with me.
I'm into the retrohepatic
area. More suction.
Okay, then you're
on to step two.
Step two, access
the pericardial IVC.
Bailey, a little
more retraction?
Okay, I'm at the pericardium.
It branches two centimeters
in either direction,
so you're close.
Damn it. Adhesions here, too.
There's too much blood. Suction!
I need to do a partial
resection of the liver,
but I just can't see to do it.
Same problem up here. Can I
get some more suction, please?
Should we control
the hepatic veins
and resect part of the liver?
- I'm trying.
I think that's the only way.
But without visibility, I might
hit a major vessel. Pierce?
I can't see the field.
Yeah, I can't see anything.
Crap. They're drowning.
I'm not sure the
model's gonna help them.
It's not telling them any
more than the scans did.
And they still can't
see enough to...
The model is how they'll see
without adhesions
and bleeding in the way.
How the pieces
relate to her anatomy.
It's the big picture.
Oh, my God.
I get it.
You're welcome.
How's it coming?
You know, by millimeters.
Your notebook-wielding
minions got bored
and ditched me
for another tumor.
I thought you might need this.
Are you keeping tabs on
me? Is that what's happening?
No. Why would you say that?
Because you might
be worried about me,
and that I have decided I can
do something that cannot be done
just so that I can prove that I am
okay and that I deserve to be here.
That I'm overreaching. Should
I be keeping tabs on you?
I mean, you saw the look on
those residents' faces yesterday.
They think that
I am certifiable.
And why shouldn't they?
Why should I think
that I can do this?
Why shouldn't I think that
I'm gonna kill this woman
and all those little babies with
her? You are not doing that. No.
Nobody thinks that this can
work. No one understands it.
You were talking way
over those residents' heads.
And you think so fast,
it made my eyes spin.
But you have a plan.
And just because you're the
only one that can see the endgame
doesn't mean that you're wrong.
It just means it's lonely.
And scary.
You'd be a fool if
you weren't scared.
I'm-a leave you be.
Oh, don't. Then I'll be
alone with this thing.
What you were
talking about yesterday,
the whole big, beautiful body?
I think I get it. I think.
So you do the fluoroscein
first. Tell me why.
So you can keep an
eye on the pituitary stalk
even though you're
nowhere near it.
Because?
Because you want to appreciate
the whole thing at once.
Right? Yes.
Thank you.
You can go now.
Oh, there. Got it.
Just ligated the hepatic
veins. What's next?
Okay, you just controlled the
lower end of the tumor, so...
That's as far as you
got. That's the last step.
Okay, so next we...
Dissect around the diaphragm.
Finish my dissection retroperitoneally.
Uh, that's two ways to go.
Her heart can't
handle all the clamping.
Whatever we do,
we have to do it now.
You mean cut blind?
No. Wait. Jo, bring
the Cyclops over here.
On it. MEREDITH:
Bring it over here,
hold it up, turn it slowly.
Okay, so we're gonna anastomose
the graft to the lower end.
And then I'll start from
the upper end, yeah.
Okay. Find me.
I am at the diaphragm.
6-Prolene and graft stat.
I'm on top of the
right hepatic vein.
This is where
we cut, right here.
That's my finger.
Oh. Okay. No, it's...
Got it. Here. It extends 10
centimeters off where the veins meet.
Right? This is it.
This is it, right here.
This is where
we cut, right here.
How much do you
trust that thing?
I'll let you know
in a second. Metz.
No excess bleeding.
Not any more than before.
Your dissection was flawless.
Then she's comin' out.
Okay, Cyclops, show
me that ugly face.
Ugh! So gross and
so freaking cool!
Oh! Got some bleeders!
Beautiful bleeders, right
where we can see them.
She was really pretty.
The woman.
At the bar.
With the nice transducers.
I'm not ready.
You gotta start sometime.
Owen, the last woman
that I kissed in that bar,
I ended up marrying.
Maybe just take the
next one home then.
Right? Shut up.
Hey, you're not ready either.
You know, I can't
even imagine it.
It's sex, sure.
You know, I've gone out and
had one-night stands before but...
I don't know. I can't...
Something real?
I pulled that icicle
out of her chest, Callie.
I bathed her when she
couldn't bathe herself.
I can't imagine belonging
to anyone like that again.
Have we used up all our happy?
You ever afraid of that,
that this is all there is now?
It's like I had a certain
amount of happy
that was supposed
to last my whole life,
and I've used it all up.
Do you think that's true?
God, I hope not. Hmm.
The last true hermit was found
and dragged out of
hiding and into the world.
Most might find
his existence sad,
but the hermit knew
something we didn't.
Mmm! Pause!
No!
Oh! Steph's rocking
neuro with girl Shepherd.
She got assigned
her crazy tumor! Yeah!
Who taught you "pause"?
Oh, um... Grey told me about
it when we were scrubbing out.
Great rule.
Now, unpause.
He knew that when
it comes down to it,
even when you're with someone,
or in the noisy rush of people,
it's just you.
The one you can count on
and lean on
and depend on.
It has to be you.
Hi. Hey.
Is something wrong?
No.
Just... What are you doing?
Nothing. Nothing. You?
I'm just lying in
bed with my tumor.
Aw...
You brought it
home. Can I see it?
Mmm-hmm.
And once you figure that
out, that's when being alone...
Well, it's no 3-D husband,
but it's something.
It'll do for now.
Oh, my God. I have to...
becomes a choice.
Um, it'll be a minute.
Okay.
What?
This is a big guns
conversation, isn't it?
Yes.
April, Jackson, we
have your test results.