Luka! What is that,
Croatian for "lucky"?
No. Luke.
You sure? Yeah.
Huh. What's the matter,
buddy? You're dragging.
I worked four shifts
in last three days.
We are 200 charts
behind in coding.
And I haven't done
one QA in the last week.
Come on, man. Pull
yourself together.
Prove your mettle, and I'll
anoint you temporary chief.
Or not. Anyway, listen.
There was a hole
in the schedule,
so I slugged you
into the midnight shift.
Tonight? Or tomorrow morning.
Depends on your view.
Nah, come on.
I'm not doing this.
Luka, Luka, Luka, listen to me.
This is important,
because no truer words
have ever been spoken.
The last four letters in
"American" are "I can."
All right, let me
put it another way.
Cover this, and I'll owe
you. Don't, and you're fired.
When is Kerry coming back?
Who says she is?
Randi, can you tell Mark
I'm running across the street...
Will you get me a doughnut?
Sixteen-year-old driver,
single vehicle MVA,
crashed into a guardrail.
Cleo, need help? I've got it.
Do you know where
they took the car?
It was still there. They'll
take it somewhere?
We'll find out. BP
is 130/85. Pulse 110.
No LOC. Complains
of abdominal pain.
Do you have neck pain? No.
Okay, I'm going to take this
off. But don't move your head.
I've only had my
license two weeks.
This is the first time
he let me drive it.
Any pain here? No.
Okay, look at me. I'm okay.
Now look at the nurse.
Can I use the phone?
Soon as the doctor's done.
Neck is clear. Okay,
roll away from me.
And we're gonna get you
off this board. All right?
Pulse ox 99 on 2 liters.
Okay. Did the airbag deploy?
It's a '65 Mustang.
It doesn't have an
airbag, just a seat belt.
No shoulder strap?
No. He's gonna kill me.
Okay. I'm sure your father
is more concerned about
you than he is his car.
You don't know my father.
Chest is clear.
Does this hurt? No.
Here? Aah!
I-I... I think the belt
caught me there.
It's a good thing
you were wearing it.
Okay. CBC, chem
panel, UA chest x-ray,
abdominal CT with contrast,
and let's get a
surgical consult.
Hit the brakes. I-I
can't believe this.
Insurance will pay for it.
It's a classic.
They just can't fix it.
Sure they can.
Eli, look at me.
We call them
accidents for a reason.
Now, you might
think this is a big deal,
but it's gonna be okay.
Really.
Can I get some extra napkins
and more water, please?
Morning, ladies.
No offense, but
you look like hell.
Yeah. If you haven't noticed,
we're short in Attending.
Yeah, it's been pretty quiet.
For you maybe.
Come on, Kate. You
gotta finish, honey.
So you got them
into daycare, huh?
Yeah. They usually
don't take 'em this early.
I had to talk them into it.
Yeah. They're just
advanced for their age.
I couldn't afford
a nanny anymore.
Sweetie? Please?
Please? A couple bites.
I don't blame her.
What? What is that?
It's rice cereal. She likes it.
Yeah, I can see.
Well, she's just mad
because I fed Tess first.
Uh-huh. Come on,
Kate, we're gonna be late.
Sweetie, please. Here,
let me try. Let me try.
Good luck. I swear this one's
gonna get me gray hair.
Yeah, just wait till
she's 14. Oh, yeah.
Oh, how gorgeous. Oh, thank you.
Girls? Yeah.
Oh. They look like angels.
Yeah. Looks can be deceiving.
I don't believe
that. No, I don't.
Now, look. You don't
give your mommy
and daddy any trouble, do you?
Beautiful family.
Yes, it is. - Quit it.
Aidan, now, please.
He pushed me. MOTHER:
Wyatt, stop. Wyatt!
Wait. Hold on a sec. Are
these all your children?
Yes. No wonder you collapsed.
BP's a little low at
95/70, tachy at 120.
Wyatt, come here now.
There's a candy bar
stuck. I think I can get it.
I said, come here. Hey,
Zadro, you babysitting?
LOC in a grocery store.
Couldn't leave
them in the produce.
Here, try this. Hey.
Say thank you, Wyatt. Thanks.
You're welcome.
Where are we going?
Exam 2. Abrasion
to the right temple.
I think I hit my head on
a shelf. Mommy, mommy.
Have you ever
fainted before? No.
I was feeling a little dizzy,
but I think I'm just tired.
She vomited in the rig and
complains of double vision.
Mouth and lips are dry.
Is that bad? Ah, It's
probably just dehydration.
Whoops. Ha-ha, ha. I
think his diaper's leaking.
I'm sorry. He pulls
at it sometimes.
Look, Mom, I got two.
You have to share.
No, these are mine.
Share it with your brother.
Dr. Greene, your dad's
nurse is on the phone.
Okay. You got this? I think so.
Here. You wanna get down? Yeah.
I thought Tech Support
was gonna fix this.
I paged them twice. They're
waiting on the software guy.
Which line? Two.
Mrs. Fredriksson?
I can't get my labs.
Usually Dr. Weaver
calls and yells at them.
Look, don't worry what
he says. You work for me.
Mark, do you know where
the extra T-sheets are?
There is no abdominal pain
and no shortness of breath.
I don't know. It's
Kerry's system.
How long is this
suspension going to last?
Look... Uh, look, just, uh,
grab a general adult form. Okay.
Uh-uh. Listen, I understand
all that, of course.
No one is questioning
your qualifications.
He is? All right, let
me speak to him.
Someone called for
a surgical consult?
Dr. Finch, Trauma Two.
Well, tell him I
wanna speak to him.
All right, well, tell him
that I said to knock it off.
I'm... I'm sorry,
Mrs. Fredriksson.
Just bear with me, okay?
Uh... Uh, I'll be home tonight,
and we'll straighten
this all out.
Okay. Thank you.
Is everything all
right? Yeah, it's fine.
We're out of the
general forms too.
Okay, well, go back
to the old charts.
There should be a
stack in the lounge.
Um, do we have a
forwarding address for Lucy?
She got something here? Yeah,
the National Resident
Matching Program.
Oh, God. They forgot
to pull her application.
Yeah, so this means
some hospital thinks
that she's working
for them next year.
Somebody should call them.
Should we send it to her mom?
I don't know.
Well, what should I do with it?
I'll take care of it.
Carter, are you sure? I...
No, no, I got it.
All right.
- He's so cute.
- I can do that.
Really, you don't have to.
It's not a problem.
I feel a lot better already.
Ian, put that down.
Come here, please.
I said, come here.
Wow. Four kids under
8. That's very ambitious.
Five. The baby's
home with the neighbor.
I asked you to
please stop, didn't I?
Wyatt, stop that.
You're probably just exhausted.
But we're still
gonna do a head CT.
Wyatt, that's enough. Please?
And I'm giving you some saline.
What's a CT?
A CAT scan. It's a
picture of your brain.
Good news. A volunteer
down in Pedes ward
agreed to watch
the kids down there.
I don't wanna be any trouble.
Oh, it's no trouble.
You kids wanna go play? Yeah!
No. OLIGARIO:
We've got Nintendo.
Do you have "Super Smash Bros."?
Oh, I don't know. They
got something with a gorilla.
Come on, sweetheart.
Wyatt, hold Emily's hand.
Help me, help me. Okay.
Ian, follow your
brother. Bye-bye.
Okay, guitar. Guitar.
I need the guitar. Mommy.
- Thank you.
- You're lucky.
We're gonna have a
lot of fun. Bye, baby.
Okay, here you go.
Ah. Let's go.
How do you do it?
One day at a time.
Good bowel sounds. Any nausea?
No.
There's no guarding or rebound.
There was rebounding before.
Eli, what happened?
I had an accident. With the car?
I lost control. Sorry.
How fast were you going?
I don't know! I didn't think...
It's okay. Don't worry about it.
The car is bad,
Dad. It's no big deal.
Mr. Emerson, I'm Dr. Finch.
What's wrong with him?
We may need to perform
exploratory surgery
to rule out any internal injury.
Oh, God.
That's probably not necessary.
You don't know?
We'll need to observe
him for a while.
Let's keep him NPO and
check his CBC every six hours.
Sure. You have a minute?
Yep.
I'll do whatever it takes to
replace it, Dad. I promise.
I don't care about the car.
I can get another car.
He has a lap belt injury.
That doesn't mean
he needs surgery.
Let's wait on the CT.
CT is only 20 percent sensitive
for small bowel perforation.
You should explore
him either way.
He has no peritoneal
signs. He did.
Well, not that I appreciated.
You asked for a surgical
opinion. I've given you one.
Let me know what
the CT shows, okay?
The ICON is positive.
She's pregnant.
The woman with all the kids?
Yeah. Her quant beta
puts her at eight weeks.
Albumin is low, and
there's ketones in her urine.
No time to eat, I guess.
I take it this wasn't a
planned pregnancy.
Who knows? Maybe
she wants a softball team.
She already go to CT?
Five minutes ago.
All right. Call Radiology
and let them know,
and then talk to
her about her diet.
Um, Carol, do we have any
Materna vitamins down here?
Try the drug lockup. Thank you.
Mark, can you sign
a purchase order
for central-line
kits? We're low.
Sure. Where? Right there.
Now sign out three cases,
and put two and initial.
It's this game I
play with Kerry.
I-I need two, so
I ask for three.
So every time...
Don't ask, Mark.
She gets to manage,
I get what I need.
Okay. Whatever it takes.
Thanks. Maybe
I'll have you sign off
on some crash carts too.
Bring it on. I'm easy.
Hey, Carol.
Patient with pyelonephritis.
Can you give a dose of Levaquin?
Sure.
Did the girls settle in? Yeah.
They seem to like it?
Well, I don't know.
They're babies.
Yeah. I'd worry about the staff.
You know, "The Hathaway
twins hit daycare."
Ross.
Their last name is Ross.
Right. Yeah.
Sorry.
No. Don't worry about it.
They're fine. They'll be fine.
Good. Good.
And, uh, run in a
lit... Liter of saline.
Okay.
Mr. Simpson? SIMPSON: Yes.
I'm Dr. Kovac.
You experience some chest pain?
Oh, it's not really pain. It
just feels tight, you know?
How long does it last?
A few seconds.
I tell you, I think I'm
having anxiety attacks.
I can't breathe, my heart
starts pounding, I get sweaty.
Do you have a history
of heart disease? No.
What brings it on?
My wife. I'm going
through a bad divorce.
Oh. I see.
Does the pain move
anywhere else?
Doc, I got aches
and pains all over.
I swear, she gets
up every morning
thinking how she can
screw with me that day.
Okay. Let's get a 12-lead EKG...
and draw cardiac labs.
You married, doc?
No.
Stay that way.
It's not enough
she bankrupts me,
and she uses my son against me,
she's putting me
in an early grave.
We'll see what we
can do about that, huh?
Yeah. Heh.
Yeah.
There.
Looks like a good heartbeat.
By the time I get one to sleep,
another one's hungry
or needs changing, or...
somebody's into
something he shouldn't be.
Do you have any help?
My husband works a lot of hours.
You should see our grocery bill.
Well... you're
gonna have to start
taking better care of yourself.
You're seriously malnourished.
You're gonna have
to start eating more
and taking prenatal vitamins.
I got you a starter pack.
Did you know you were pregnant?
How long have you known?
I don't know.
Have you told your husband?
No.
And you were fasting?
No. No.
I just don't have time to eat.
You weren't, uh...
starving yourself, trying to
induce a miscarriage, were you?
We both wanted a
big family. I just thought
I'd get a break before
we tried again, that's all.
Well, your body's always
gonna protect the fetus first.
But you're putting
your own health at risk.
You could develop heart
problems or kidney trouble.
Were you trying to
terminate this pregnancy?
Well, there are
safer ways to do that.
Have you considered an abortion?
I can't have another
baby right now. I just can't.
Another Webril.
Poor guy slips in the
bathtub, breaks his neck.
This woman falls
down an entire flight
of concrete steps
and cracks her wrist.
One of the benefits of
alcohol consumption.
I could do with a
margarita myself.
Between the pregnancy
and breastfeeding,
I don't remember the
last time I had a drink.
It's not the "no alcohol,"
it's the "no caffeine"
that I couldn't deal with.
Thanks, Mark.
Three-inch roll.
I'm thinking of weaning them.
It's been six
months. I don't know
how much longer I can deal.
I can't believe that
you've lasted this long.
So you don't think I'm
being a terrible mother?
If you planned on
being the perfect parent,
you might as well fail now...
while they can't remember.
Another three-inch.
You okay?
They deserve a father, Mark.
Doug's been seeing them.
He asked me to
move to Seattle again.
And, uh... I think
he's serious this time.
What did you tell him?
Do you have a second?
Go ahead. I got this.
Okay.
What's up?
She was starving herself,
hoping she'd miscarry.
"Supermom"? Yeah.
I may have talked her
into having an abortion.
She didn't ask for one?
Well, she's scared.
Come here.
She doesn't want
her husband to know.
Apparently he's
very controlling.
You need to refer
her to the GYN Clinic.
Well, I offered to
arrange things for her upstairs.
Uh, today.
What's the rush?
Well, this might be
her only opportunity.
Can't get out of the house?
She's got five kids under 8.
She needed somebody
to make it happen for her.
Meaning, she might not
be in an emotional state
to make her own decision?
No, she made it. She
just needed a push.
And you pushed her?
I don't know.
Did you give her her options?
Yeah. But adoption's not gonna
work because of the husband.
If she has another kid, it's
gonna push her over the edge.
If she's gone to this much
trouble to avoid an abortion,
there's a part of her
that has a problem with it.
Or her husband does.
Can GYN even do it?
I don't know. I
haven't asked them.
All right. Talk to them. It
might not even be possible.
Thank you.
Be careful, Abby.
Make sure.
Your surgical consult is here.
And who might that be? Mm.
How about a clue?
Um... Dr. Romano?
Okay. See?
Oh. Whatever.
Need a doctor to
take a look? Hm?
Don't worry about me.
I'm getting some Lasix.
Lap belt injury, huh?
Yeah, CT is clear.
But he's guarding.
Y-you know. Just, um,
discussing a patient.
I could use a good
discussion myself.
Maybe I should
go see the patient.
Good idea. Good idea.
Eli. Mr. Emerson.
This is Dr. Benton.
He's a surgeon.
Hey, how are you? Hey.
How's your belly, Eli?
Same. A little sore.
Okay. Does this hurt?
Only when you press real hard.
Any back pain? No.
His white count is up.
So was the other surgeon wrong?
What other surgeon?
Dr. Corday.
Could you give us a
second? We'll be right back.
So Elizabeth already saw him?
Sorry. I didn't get
a chance to tell you.
She didn't think an
ex-lap was warranted.
I disagreed... wanted
a second opinion.
Well, his belly
is fairly benign.
Uh, there's no
back or flank pain.
He could have a leak in
his bowel and not look sick.
He doesn't have a fever.
Delaying diagnosis and repair
can raise mortality
from 5 to 65 percent.
Okay. Okay, okay.
I'll do an ex-lap, okay?
Thank you, Peter.
One, two, three.
Oh, God!
Watch my back, would you?
How far did you fall, Mr. Fazio?
I don't know. Six, eight feet.
Coworkers said about four.
Four, my ass!
I felt something pop.
I think I blew out a disk.
Complains of leg
weakness, brief LOC.
I passed out.
Everything went black.
BP's 110/70. Pulse 81.
Is that bad? That's normal.
Why don't you press on
my hands with your feet.
Oh, jeez!
That hurt?
Yeah! What do you think?
Does your employer cover
on-the-job injury, Mr. Fazio?
Huh. He better. Okay.
I'm gonna press
down on your head.
Tell me if it increases
the pain in your back.
Here we go.
Oh, oh, oh, oh. Stop, stop.
Pain is MU.
What's that?
We're gonna check
it all out, Mr. Fazio.
Better get a CBC, Chem-7
and a lumbar-spine series.
What exactly is MU?
Made-up.
You think he's faking? Oh, yeah.
Hey.
So is it anxiety attacks?
I can't say for sure.
But your cardiac
enzymes are normal.
And I'm not seeing
any irregularities on the EKG.
Yeah.
Well, I didn't think
it was my heart.
You might just
be overly stressed.
Ha! I could've told you
that without the test.
I still need to monitor
you for another, uh,
six to eight hours.
But you said
everything was okay.
Damage to the
heart doesn't always
show up in the
blood work right away.
The way you came in,
I just wanna make sure.
Uh-huh. Heh.
I just got myself all worked up.
You see, she's, uh...
She's driving me crazy.
I-I-I never wanted a divorce.
Oh, hell... Mr. Simpson.
Mr. Simpson. I'm sorry.
E-every t-time. J-j-just...
It just hits me. And I-I...
I don't know what I'm doing.
I'm sorry.
No, don't worry. It's okay.
Every day...
Every day it's
another damn letter
or a phone call from her lawyer.
More threats, more demands.
I don't know what I did wrong.
I love my son.
I loved her. I still do.
I understand.
I'm sorry.
It's not your problem.
Maybe I can get a
clinical psychologist
to come down and
talk to you, huh?
Clinical psychologist?
That worse than
the ordinary kind?
Hi.
I checked on your kids.
They're having a great time.
They're gonna need to eat
soon. They're eating now.
It's a great thing about kids,
they don't complain
about hospital food.
Um... Are you sure
this is what you want?
No, it's not what I want. Heh.
It's what I need.
Okay, um... well, I
worked it out with GYN.
There's a doctor who
can squeeze you in,
but if it's gonna be
today, it has to be now.
You better take me up there
before I change my mind.
Yeah. Well... the thing is...
I would hate for you to
change your mind later on.
No, I know.
I meant... Forget it.
No, tell me.
I feel like such a hypocrite.
I know that this is so wrong.
I just keep telling myself
I'm doing this for my family.
Well, maybe you better
take some more time
and think about it.
My husband is a good man,
but he would never
understand this.
It would be better
if he doesn't know.
Let's just get it
over with, okay?
Okay.
Thank you.
This isn't easy to do alone.
He's had steroids. Another hour
of continuous nebs should do it.
Dr. Greene, It's that
nurse again. Now what?
Uh, apparently your
father's making racial slurs.
She's Swedish.
Well, maybe he
called her a meatball.
Well, tell her I'm on my way.
I'll be there in
about half an hour.
Okay, Exam 4, I put
the shoulder back in.
You need to check
the post-reduction films.
Does he have an orthopedist?
Give it to the Ortho Clinic.
Are you leaving?
I've been on since 5:30.
Can you take the new
altered mental status, Exam 6?
Yeah, sure. Thanks.
Can you pull the
old records on that?
You got a critical
value from the lab.
White count's 150,000.
Looks like leukemia.
What patient? Fazio.
The workers' comp guy?
What did he present with?
Guy fell off a ladder.
Just look at that, 95
percent blasts. Ninety.
Get a Hem/Onc consult.
Has anyone seen Carol?
She's upstairs. Again?
She's on break. She
was just up there.
Who are you, the hall monitor?
No. I'm a Resident whose
patient needs an NG tube, okay?
Well, do it yourself. You
gonna let this go on, boss?
Give her a break. I don't
think the chief would.
Well, talk to me after you've
raised two children on your own.
That was her choice.
Why should I suffer?
Quit whining. I'll put
down your damn tube.
Thank you.
Hey, where's my MVA?
Cleo's patient? Yes.
Think Benton took
him up to the O.R.
Benton? Yeah.
Hey. How you feeling?
Something's wrong.
My back's going through spasms.
Well, your x-ray didn't
show any fractured vertebrae.
Well, that doesn't
mean I don't have pain.
I'm sure that you do.
You know, doc, I
can't work like this.
I don't think you're gonna
be going back to work.
Yeah? For how long?
You have acute
myelogenous leukemia.
Leukemia? Wha...?
You mean like the cancer?
Yes. And it can cause bone pain.
Oh. Come on.
Get out of here! I fell
off a freakin' ladder.
We picked it up
on your blood work.
Hematology's coming down.
They're gonna want to... Whoa.
Admit you today and start chemo.
Wait a second. Wait a second.
I'm sorry. John,
we need you now.
Hey, I'll be right
back. Wait, doc!
I'll be right back.
Push 0.2 epi. We may
need an airway. What is it?
Ten-year-old girl in
anaphylactic shock.
Found on a school field
trip. No response to albuterol.
Allergic reaction?
Bracelet says peanuts.
Gave Benadryl, but
pressure's dropping.
Draw up 75 of
ketamine, 75 of sux.
Pulse ox is 82.
Can't wait. Rapid induction.
Number 70 T-tube?
No, I've got it.
BP's 60 palp.
Come on, Deb. Let's go.
Hold on.
You want cricoid pressure? Mm.
Mm. Cords are swollen.
I can't pass the tube.
Let's set up for
fiber-optic intubation.
Fifty milligrams of Solu-Medrol.
Repeat the epi in five.
Okay, Deb, out of
the way. I've got it.
You've done one? Two.
Keep gentle tension
between your hands.
I know. I'm feeding it in.
There's the epiglottis.
Ahem. What are
you doing? Come on.
Keep advancing. I
can't see the cords.
Pulse ox down to 78.
All right, pull out. Bag her.
No, no. I just need
to... I said, get out now.
What are you doing?
I'm gonna take over.
I said, get back!
John!
Up to 82.
All right. Let's go again.
Thank you for being
so understanding.
I'm sure he'll be better
tomorrow. Couldn't be worse.
Is she gone?
Yeah, okay? She's gone.
We'll be lucky if
she comes back.
Speak for yourself.
Dad, we need her.
Someone has to
be here if I can't.
That wouldn't be necessary
if I went to that hospice.
Yeah, well, Dad, you'd just be
surrounded by strangers.
They don't get much
stranger than Nurse von Bülow.
And look at... And
look at this room.
It's like a... A damn hospital.
How much is all this costing?
Don't worry about it.
And wh... What the hell is that?
It's a portable toilet.
You got me a...? A
Johnny-on-the-spot?
It's just for
convenience. I should...
I am not taking a...
A dump in your
living room, Mark.
God. I am not an invalid!
I can still make it to
the damn bathroom!
Okay, Dad. Sit down. Sit
down. Come on, sit down.
Sit down here.
Sit down and relax.
This is exactly... Exactly
what I didn't want happening.
You don't have to use it, Dad.
Relax. Take deep
breaths. I won't use it.
I'll get your albuterol, okay?
I'll take it back, all right?
Okay.
Here you go. Just
take a few puffs.
Nice and easy. Calm down.
Where is he? Blue suit.
Uh, Mr. Parker?
Hi. I'm Abby Lockhart.
Hi. You're the one
taking care of my wife?
Yes. She was a little
dehydrated and tired. Heh.
They said she had to be
brought in by an ambulance.
Standard protocol when
the paramedics are called
and a patient has
lost consciousness.
Oh, God. No, it's okay.
She has a small abrasion, but
mostly, she just needs to rest.
She overdoes it.
I tell her she takes
on way too much.
You might want to think about
getting her some help at home.
Yeah. Well, where is she?
Can I see her?
When she gets back. She
went upstairs for some tests.
What kind of tests?
She was anemic,
so we had to check out her
heart and so some blood work.
Why don't I take you
to see your children.
Yeah. Okay.
But I thought you said
she only needs rest.
She does. And should.
But we're just being thorough.
Okay, I should
really be with her.
Well, that might be difficult.
What's all this about, Peter?
I've got an ex-lap.
Were you planning on calling me?
I didn't know I needed
your permission.
Did your friend
bother to tell you
that I'd examined
this patient first?
Dr. Finch fully advised me
of your surgical opinion.
I bet she did.
And I made my own
clinical assessment.
That boy is completely
asymptomatic
except for a small
bruise on his belly.
His white count rose to 18,000.
Well, then, she
should've called me.
Mm. Well, maybe she thought
you already made up your mind.
I was observing him.
Now, Dr. Finch may not
be as comfortable with me
as she obviously is with you,
but had she disclosed
the elevated white count,
I might have changed my mind.
Maybe.
Stop scrubbing, Peter.
What? You heard me.
I said stop scrubbing.
I'm operating on that boy.
No, you're not. I am.
Elizabeth, come
on, I'm ready to start.
Mm. Sorry to have
wasted your time.
But as associate
chief of surgery,
it's my prerogative
to schedule cases.
Especially ones I've seen first.
You mean you're
pulling rank on me?
Absolutely.
Dr. Carter? Yeah.
Dan Shine, Hematology.
You sent me a patient named
Fazio for a bone marrow biopsy.
How did it go? His bone
marrow is perfectly normal.
Not this guy. He
had 95 percent blasts.
Somebody else has blasts.
This guy's got a normal
white count. What?
I had the lab cross-check.
They mixed up the
medical records.
Do you have a patient
down here named Simpson?
Uh, Randi, can
you find Dr. Kovac?
Just a second.
No, now!
Did you talk to Fazio? Yeah.
Uh, you might want to go up.
I had to stick him
with a corkscrew.
Then when I told him the
diagnosis might be a mistake,
he wasn't going to be dying
next month, he threatened to sue.
Oh, I'm sure that he did.
Excuse me?
They took my wife upstairs.
I just wanted to
see if she was back.
The last name's Parker.
Uh, Gynecology Clinic.
Wait. Gynecology Clinic?
I... I thought she was anemic.
I'm sorry. I didn't
take care of her.
If you want to have a seat,
you can wait right over there.
Call me after you talk
to the real guy. Yeah.
Excuse me. W-what's your name?
Abby. Abby, yeah.
It says "GYN" by my
wife's name. Is that right?
Mr. Parker, why
don't you have a seat,
and I'll check on her.
Is there something wrong
you're not telling me?
No, she's fine.
Then why is she in Gynecology?
Is she pregnant?
You should just wait
until she gets back.
Look, I don't want
to wait anymore!
I want you to tell me
what's wrong with my wife.
Uh, I can't. Why?
Sir. Medical information
has to remain private.
This is my wife.
What can't I know?
Uh, Mr. Parker...
She's not having
an abortion, is she?
Is she?
I can't say.
What floor is Gynecology on?
What floor is Gynecology
on?! Ninth floor.
You needed me, Carter?
Yeah.
Sure it's not another mistake?
No. We double-checked.
How long?
It's hard for me to say.
Ballpark. Best guess.
With a successful
bone-marrow transplant,
there is a...
60 percent survival
rate at five years.
Without one?
Chemotherapy alone?
About half of that.
But we'll do everything we can
to find you a match.
They'll type your entire family:
brothers, sisters...
I don't have any
brothers or sisters.
Are your parents living?
Have an uncle.
That's good.
And there's your son.
He's only 8. Yeah.
Probably the best chance.
Should call my wife. Hm.
Yeah.
You called for a
surgical consult?
Yeah. Nine-year-old with
right-sided abdominal pain.
I think it's a hot appy.
You didn't bring them
to the O.R. yourself?
Temp's 101.
I just closed Eli
Emerson's belly.
I thought Peter was go...
No, he was my consult,
my responsibility.
Fortunately, there
was no perforation.
That's a relief.
Pity I had to cut him open.
Better to know
than regret it later.
Yes.
Well, I know you have
special access to Peter,
but in the future
I'd appreciate it
if you'd come to me if you have
a problem with one of my calls.
Obviously you agreed with
him or you wouldn't have
performed the surgery.
A simple "Yes,
Elizabeth," will do.
Do you want this appy or not?
Which room? Four.
Hey. What's going on, Pablo?
Oh. They took all my stuff.
The city swept his street.
Cleaned everything out.
Yeah? And when was
your last drink, Pablo?
Push me down. I tried to
climb up on this dumpster,
and they pushed me down.
Right. And, uh, how much
have you had to drink?
They took my
pillows, my blanket.
I had a tarp for when
it rain, you know?
Right. And have you been eating?
I have no money. Oh, let's
get a banana bag going.
CBC, chem panel
and blood alcohol.
Did you hit your
head, Pablo? What?
I said, did you hit your head?
Pablo, hold still. Ah.
No, let me go.
Hold still, Pablo.
No!
All right. Soft restraints!
It's okay. It's okay.
Call Security.
It was an accident.
Pablo, hold still.
What is that? Leave me alone.
Haldol. What? No!
Let me go!
Carter, what are you doing? Aah!
No. Carter!
What's the matter with you?!
He's violent. It
was an accident.
This is Pablo. They
don't come any gentler.
Are you gonna help
me, Carol? No! I'm not!
All right, fine. Why don't you
call me when he calms down.
Hey, you got any
four-by-fours in here?
Uh, let me check.
Xeroform, Adaptic...
If not in here, they're
in the suture room.
Hold on, Carter, I'm
still looking. Here we go.
What's going on with you?
What, you mean Pablo?
I mean your
overreaction to Pablo.
Or am I now overreacting
to your overreacting?
Ah, I was just
trying to be careful.
Maybe it was a bad call.
Are you okay?
Yeah, I think so.
I know what it's like
to have life change
up on you, you know?
I mean, a year ago I
was living with Doug.
Now I'm living alone
with two babies. Go figure.
Yeah.
It takes a while
to deal with it.
To get used to it.
I think you still
need to get used to it.
Lucy matched.
Oh, God. Where?
Here. Got a spot in Psych.
Go figure.
There's always gonna
be something, Carter.
Well, what are you gonna do.
Go back to work.
She's not really Swedish. What?
Mrs. Fredriksson.
She's married to a
Swede, but she's Dutch.
So you did actually talk to her.
No, Mark, I didn't
do the talking.
She yapped and
yapped and yapped and...
finally, about halfway through
watching Rosie O'Donnell,
I told her to stick her
damn thumb in her dike
and shut the hell up.
You didn't. Sure, I did.
You told her to stick her
damn thumb in her dike?
And she got what I
meant. And... And it worked.
Not another word.
What is this? Meatloaf.
It's the only recipe of
Mom's I can ever remember.
Where's the egg?
What egg?
Your mother used to cook it
with a hardboiled
egg in the middle.
Then you'd get a
sliver with each slice.
I... I didn't remember that.
I never much liked
the egg anyway.
I always ate around it.
Okay.
Work was pretty decent today.
That's good.
So anything happen here?
Like what?
I don't know.
Maybe you and Mrs.
Fredriksson did something.
What the hell would we
do, Mark? Play Parcheesi?
Dad, forget it. Okay?
Ahem. I was just, uh,
trying to make conversation.
Yeah, okay.
Whatever.
Your mother used to
serve this with peas, I think.
Not... Not with string beans.
Yeah. Guess so.
Hey, Abby. Hey.
How's she doing?
Pretty well. She's
gonna be okay.
That's good.
I do want to apologize to you.
I let my emotions get
the best of me downstairs.
Of course.
Lynn let herself
get a little run-down.
She just got depressed.
I guess I didn't see it.
Well, it's easy
for that to happen.
She's resting now.
So I'm gonna go
check on my kids again.
Sure.
Hi. How are you doing? I'm okay.
I saw your husband
out in the hall.
Oh. He was pretty
upset, but he's better now.
He forgave me.
He forgave you?
We all make mistakes sometimes.
And... And what you did today,
that was a mistake?
He didn't call it that. Just
a moment of weakness.
Well, what do you think?
And he talked to the doctor,
and I'm going to be fine.
We'll be able to try again soon.
For another baby?
Ken's a wonderful father.
We both love kids.
We've always
wanted a big family.
Kids are great.
Why don't you try and
get some rest, okay?
Thanks.
Look at Kate in the
little hat. She's so cute.
Isn't that Tess?
Nope, Kate. Tess is
the one eating the hat.
Hey, Luka. You off? Uh... no.
Heading out to meet the
trauma coming in. You?
After I pick up the
girls. Look at this.
Isn't that adorable?
Yeah. Very beautiful.
See you. Bye.
Has anyone seen Benton?
He's on call. I
think he crashed.
Oh, God. I just realized.
Dr. Kovac... What?
He had two children.
It was two, wasn't it?
Yeah.
Hey.
Where are the girls?
I'm on my way up
to get them now. Mm.
How much longer you on?
If Romano has his
way, probably forever.
Listen, Luka, I just realized,
looking at those
pictures... I'd, um...
I've never seen any
pictures of your children.
You want to see one now?
Yeah. That'd be great.
Yeah.
Jasna. That was
her birthday party.
She was 4.
She's beautiful.
So is your wife.
Yeah, she was.
Can I see one of your son?
Nah, I don't have any.
You don't have any on you,
or you don't have any at all?
No, I'm lucky to have this one.
No, to see Marco I just...
have to close my
eyes, and he's there.
Um... Usually with
chocolate ice cream
on his face and hands.
I'm sorry.
No, no. No. Thank
you for asking.
Oh. Here I go. Back to work.
See you tomorrow. Bye.
Bye.
What is it?
It's me.
Cleo.
What's wrong? Nothing.
Lie down. Lie down.
I thought you were going home.
Maybe later.
This is okay for now. Hm.
Dr. John. I thought
the dog got in.
No, it's just me, Corrine.
Couldn't sleep? No.
You want me to make
something to eat?
No, no, no, no.
I'm fine, thanks.
Okay.
Good night. Good night.
Mark!
Dad?
Yeah. Just a second.
What's wrong, Dad? I
told you this damn stuff
would get in the way!
Ow. What happened?
Ow. I was trying to
get to the bathroom.
I got tangled up in these
wires and the tubes.
Damn!
I'm sorry. I should've
moved this stuff.
I should be able to get up
and go to the
bathroom by myself.
It's my fault, Dad.
I should've left the lamp on.
I tried. But I got
tangled up in...
Oh.
It's no big deal, Dad.
Oh. My pajamas are soaked.
Well, don't worry. We'll
get you a fresh pair.
I haven't wet the
bed since I was 5!
All right, Dad. Just
sit down here, okay?
I'm gonna put the
shower on, let it warm up.
You shouldn't have
to do this, Mark.
Think how many
times you did this for me
when I was little.
Well, I'm a grown man.
Whoa, whoa. Wait,
wait, wait, wait.
This isn't right, Mark.
It... It just isn't right.
I know, Dad.
I know.
All right.
Let's just rest for a minute.