Voltaire said
that the art of medicine
is amusing the patient while
nature cures the disease.
So according to one
of the greatest.
French philosophers
of all time,
surgeons aren't
really helpers.
♪ Black tears on my shirt ♪
We're more like circus clowns.
Sorry. Just...
♪ Black tears on my freckles ♪
I know.
♪ I been stung by this hurt ♪
But suck it up,
because I need your help.
♪ I been stung by
the stinging nettle ♪
♪ Someone call, someone call,
some-one call ♪
But help comes in many forms.
I stopped pulling
on my fingers.
Or... ♪ I don't know
who I am at all ♪
No, a-at least now
I notice when I'm doing it.
And I've been doing
the exercises you showed me.
♪ Someone call, someone call,
some-one call ♪
I'm really noticing
a change.
Don't try to rush it. ♪ I
don't know who I am at all ♪
Takes time for the meds
to balance out.
Right. But...
♪ Black hole in my heart ♪
Well, for instance, uh,
you have a little bit of, um...
♪ Black hole in my favorite
sweater ♪ ...I think,
maybe yogurt
on your, uh, chin.
I've wanted to mention it
this whole time,
but I didn't, so...
♪ Someone call, someone call,
some-one call ♪
I think
we're making progress.
And something tells me
Voltaire never held an aorta
while a patient's
entire blood volume
pulsated between his fingers.
I'd say we are.
♪ Someone call, someone call,
some-one call ♪
You beat up the bar
with a baseball bat?
♪ I don't know who I am at all
♪ Not exactly sober behavior.
No.
Legendary,
but definitely not sober.
♪ Hey, hey, hey ♪
And, um, my wife has...
♪ Can anyone hear
what I'm saying? ♪
She's been diagnosed with
something frightening.
Oh, man.
And you were with Ollie, right?
Yeah.
So you need a sponsor?
If you'd be willing.
♪ Does anyone hear
what I'm saying? ♪
How you doin' with
prayer and meditation?
Uh... I'm not. ♪ Someone call,
someone call, some-one call ♪
Well, how 'bout
we start there?
Call me tomorrow.
♪ I don't know
who I am at all ♪
♪♪
♪ Someone call, someone call,
some-one call ♪
♪ I don't know
who I am at all ♪
Oh! Dr. Bailey.
Just the person
I was looking for.
Uh, do you live here now,
or do you fly back
from Germany
on a weekly basis,
and if so, why?
Oh.
Well, um...
I mean,
as it turns out...
I am pregnant.
With Owen's baby.
And Owen and Amelia Shepherd
are back together again,
and Amelia's sisters
have issues with me.
Rightfully so.
It... It's not undramatic.
It's not undramatic to
the point of it being comical.
And... And, still,
Dr. Bailey,
I need a job.
I really need a job.
I-I-I need to be occupied
with work,
and I... I need it badly.
Oh, I'm so sorry.
Um, y-you're gonna
have to say
all of that again
to Alex Karev.
♪♪
You're on the board?
Yeah. I-I'm sorry.
I want to be there when...
No, no, I have
a dozen little kids
coming to my house
in a few hours.
You said you would help.
I don't know anything
about superheroes.
Well, you tell Bailey that
Uncle Alex is saving lives,
that he actually
is a superhero.
Yeah, right.
That'll definitely work.
Ooh, Dr. Karev,
can I walk with you?
Um, yeah, what,
do you live here?
Well, it's...
It's complicated.
Catherine!
You're back.
How are you feeling?
How am I feeling?
Why don't you tell me?
Since you seem to be
so good
at telling everybody
everything.
Catherine, I...
Save it.
You're fired from my team,
Dr. Grey.
And if you value your job
at this hospital,
I suggest you stay
out of my sight
until my fury passes.
♪♪
- Hey.
You look nice.
Thanks.
Cece's funeral.
Yes. How'd that go?
It was awful.
And beautiful.
A lot of her single clients
were there.
There will probably be
a lot of hookups tonight.
Fitting.
Yeah.
How are you doing?
Did you talk to your mom?
Uh, yeah.
Yeah, I mean, we all
had dinner last night,
and we all have a surgery
together today, so...
You're doing a surgery?
Catherine's doing a surgery?
A pelvic exenteration that
spares the uterus, to be exact.
And the patient's
ready for us.
- Mm.
- All right.
Dr. Berjeron to the ICU.
Morning, Grey.
There's a trauma
coming in.
Yeah, that's why
I'm here.
That's how
you wait for a trauma?
How'm I supposed to wait?
I don't know.
Maybe a little less casually.
So...
Like, uh...
Yeah.
Hey, where's the rig?
It's not here yet.
See?
Jo knows how to wait
for a trauma.
No point in stressing out
until you have to.
I don't believe in that.
You don't believe in that?
Mnh-mnh.
And now
I stand up straight.
- Hey.
You look awful.
Thanks.
No, I mean, you should
go home if you're sick.
Uh. Pit's full of people who
look a lot worse than I do.
Yeah, flu season.
Yeah.
You're in scrubs?
I have to audition
for Pierce,
which is only
slightly enraging.
Did you know that Alex Karev
is interim chief?
I mean, time is so weird.
So, you're gonna work here?
And I find out
after the fact.
That's par
for the course.
Whoa, whoa,
wait a minute.
Where is this coming from?
You said that you wanted
to figure it out,
and that's what
I'm trying to do.
Yeah, me, too, but there's
a lot to figure out.
And this whole situation
is a mess.
Okay, let me remind you
that the reason
I upended my entire life
was for you
so that you could be part
of our baby's life.
Listen, Teddy,
you came to Seattle
the day
after Karev's wedding,
before me and Amelia
had even really
gotten back together.
You seemed pretty
back together to me.
Right, right,
and you took one look,
and you decided that
you had the whole picture.
Maybe if you'd
just talked to me,
been a little more
up front with me...
Your teenager
answered your door!
Maybe you would've saved
a lot of people a lot of pain,
but, no, you waited
five whole weeks to...
Wait, are you try...
A-Are you saying that somehow
it's my fault that you and
Amelia are back together again?
I'm just saying
it's a crap situation,
which is worse
than it would have been
had you been
a little more up front.
Had some
excellent nicknames,
but "Crap Situation"
might be my new favorite.
♪♪
Amelia.
Hey, Amelia, I'm sorry.
♪♪
Hey.
So...
I need a job.
And Karev said that
I should talk to you.
♪♪
Captioning provided by
ABC Studios and ABC, Inc.
And brought to you by Ford.
Going further, so you can.
Her abdomen's distended. She may
have some internal bleeding.
Let's get an ultrasound.
Let's hang some LR
and a unit of O-neg.
She fell from
a hotel balcony?
Three floors up.
Apparently the railing broke.
Pelvis feels stable, but I want to
see an X-ray. Yes, Dr. Lincoln.
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God!
Natasha, I'm right here.
I'm right here.
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God. Is she...
Is she
on any medications?
Has she had
any previous surgeries?
Um... uh, she... she gets
migraines sometimes, and...
And she has a scar from...
She had her appendix out.
Is... Is she... I'm...
We're getting married
tomorrow.
She didn't want me to see her
until she walked down the aisle,
and I...
She got her own hotel room.
Hey, hey, hey.
What's your name, buddy?
Garrett... Boland.
Garrett. Okay, well, the best
thing you can do to help Natasha
is to let the people
in this room
do what we know
how to do, okay?
Okay, okay.
Oh, God.
Let me show you
where to wait.
And I thought my wedding day
was a mess.
I'm sorry
I said that, Amelia.
We were fighting, and
it just... It happens.
Couples fight.
Oh, come on.
We're not a couple.
Who's not a couple?
Owen and Teddy Altman.
Only they are.
The baby really sells it.
Oh, there's a baby?
Do you mind?
You know, I do, actually.
We're busy.
Way too busy
to catch whatever it is
you're losing a fight against,
so... you can go.
Amelia, please.
Owen, he's right.
We're going up against
one of the nastiest tumors
I've ever seen.
We need to focus.
Altman's the tall
blonde, right?
I am trying to focus.
Uma Paxton, 25, here for
total pelvic exenteration
with flap reconstruction
for a recurrent vaginal tumor.
Not total, Dr. Helm.
We are preserving
the uterus.
Oh.
Wow, that's possible?
It is now.
Because I developed
the technique.
My first doctors blasted me
with chemo and radiation,
but it came back,
so they said I had to remove
most of my insides,
but Dr. Fox
found a silver lining.
- Dr. Webber?
- I'll make an incision
into your abdomen
and remove your rectum
to create a colostomy
while Dr. Fox
removes your bladder
and creates a urostomy.
And then
I will remove the tumor
and everything
but your uterus.
I'll lead on
your vaginal reconstruction.
We'll cover any defects with
skin and fat from your belly.
So...
not complicated.
Man, I didn't think
that I ever wanted kids
until I found out that I might
not be able to have any,
so thank you, Dr. Fox.
Uma, we've talked
about this before,
but now that
the day has come,
I really have to ask again.
This surgery's long,
it's complex,
and it's very personal.
Are you sure you're all right
with other doctors
watching from the gallery?
You're a pioneer,
and this could help save
more women like me.
So teach away.
All right, guys.
Let's do this.
I'm gonna
be right back, all right?
It's like
a plague in here.
Bronchitis, pneumonia,
some gastroenteritis.
Whoa, you okay?
Ohh. What do we got?
Right. Uh, Grey and Link
are in Trauma 2
with a woman
who fell from a balcony,
and almost everyone else
is flu-like symptoms.
Including you, I guess.
Look, if you want
to grab some rest,
I can page you
if anything's urgent.
- Incoming!
- Uh... Ohh.
- Sorry! Sorry! Sorry!
- I'm gonna muscle through.
Could you, uh,
prep an IV, uh,
bag of LR
and 4 milligrams of Zofran?
Yeah. You got it.
Thanks.
So, we have our
interdepartmental meetings,
M&Ms, lung tumor boards,
and such
in the conference room.
Oh, good,
you still do it there.
I-I moved it
from the lecture hall
to get a more open
and honest exchange.
"A more open
and honest exchange."
You don't say.
Well, it's just that my sister's
kinda wrecked right now
because you failed to have
an open and honest exchange.
I told them.
You told them too late.
Are we gonna be able to
work together, Dr. Pierce?
I've heard nothing but excellent
things about your work,
Dr. Altman,
and any minute now,
I will shove aside
my personal contempt
in favor of
professional courtesy.
Dr. Huser
to Labor and Delivery.
On 3... 1, 2, 3.
What do we got?
Patient collapsed
at a convenience store.
Last BP 110 over 50,
pulse 82.
Ma'am, did you
lose consciousness?
Uh, no,
I don't think so.
Hey, guys,
what did you see?
She was like,
"Ow, my stomach."
Then she was like,
"Ow, my face."
Nice, guys. Real nice.
Ma'am, do you have
any other symptoms
uh, dizziness or headache?
Uh, yeah, headache because
Gabe just told me today
that his project
is due tomorrow...
- Quit touching me!
- You touched me first!
And I have the flu,
and I hate children,
- so life is punishing me.
- No! Let me go!
So if I could just get
something for my stomach
and some sedatives for the children...
Let me go!
- We'll be good to go.
- Hey, watch out.
Hey, guys, guys,
knock it off.
Should we call
their parents?
- I am their parents...
- It's your fault!
Ever since
my sister died,
and clearly,
I'm crushing it... Ow!
Abdomen's a little tender.
Uh, Schmitt, do you want
to see if CT's open?
Whoa, CT?
No, no, I'm fine.
I just have the flu,
and I already took antibiotics
I had left over
from last year, so...
Bad idea?
Unprescribed?
Yes.
Listen, I know
that you're stressed,
and maybe it is
just the flu, but...
Claire, if it isn't,
you're really gonna wish
that you'd stayed, okay?
Are you okay?
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, I'm fine.
He sounds like me.
Free fluid in the pelvis
and abdomen.
X-rays are up.
Post-ops are done, Link.
What'd I miss?
You tell me.
She's got
a windswept pelvis.
"Windswept"?
It's a combo platter.
We got AP compression
on one side,
lateral compression
on the other.
You see the widened
SI joint here
and the sacral fracture
there?
Okay, well, I'd love
to get her up to the O.R.
for a neuro check.
And we can do an intra-op CT
when we get there.
100%. Let's do it.
Well, wait, aren't we gonna
stabilize her pelvis first?
Of course.
Nah.
"Nah"? She's got
a pelvic fracture.
You're not gonna at least
put a binder on her?
Nope.
We'll see you up there.
♪♪
All right.
She's hypotensive.
We got to move, people.
She's all prepped
for her ex-lap.
Okay, so what
made you think
that Link and I
would be a good match?
Okay, listen,
before I met Alex,
Link was the very best person
that I knew,
and Alex would say the
same thing about you, so...
Oh, come on.
Link's a great guy.
And Labradors
are great dogs.
They're always
happy to see you,
they're super cute,
and they're full of energy.
Okay, listen.
He is not a Labrador.
You just have to
get to know him.
Who's ready to put
a pelvis back together, huh?
I am.
I am ready.
Did you jog up here?
Ran up the stairs. Gets the
blood flowing, you know?
We got to save this lady.
She's getting married.
We have to save them all,
even the sad and lonely ones.
Is there another Dr. Grey
you thought I should ask out?
Okay, just relax
and try not to move, okay?
I haven't relaxed
in two years.
My mother used to say, "I hope
you have children someday",
and they're as awful to you
as you were to me."
And I'd say,
"Joke's on you, lady.
I'm never having kids."
And then Cynthia died,
and now I have
her two human tornadoes.
They're loud,
and they're smelly,
and they think
fart jokes are hilarious,
and they never stop eating.
I love them,
but they are disgusting.
I think I owe my mom
an apology.
Yeah, me too.
Whoa.
Her transverse colon is...
Is huge.
Toxic megacolon
with peritoneal signs.
We're gonna need to
get her to the O.R.
before her bowel perfs,
okay?
I was hoping,
if we start medially,
we could remove the tumor
en bloc.
Ah...
It's not working.
I know. Just...
Let's try coming
from the inferior side.
Maybe if you approach it
superiorly...
I am.
Yeah,
it's still not working.
You know,
I can see that, Shepherd.
That's why
we're practicing.
And at this rate,
we will be ready
in, what...
Five years?
Don't take your baby daddy drama
out on our tumor baby.
We can do this.
Consult in the O.R.
I'll be right back.
Wh-What... You're...
You're leaving?
Do me a favor and come back
with a little positivity!
It's quite a crowd.
Quite a surgery.
It sounds really complicated.
I hope it goes well.
Well, if you thought you might
be performing your last surgery,
wouldn't you want to
go out with a bang?
Catherine told you?
This morning.
She's symptomatic.
She's in pain.
This is not
a simple surgery.
I mean, do you think
this is a good idea?
I think
she's Catherine Fox.
I think...
she's gonna
make her mark here.
And I think she has
a stellar team by her side.
They're ready.
♪♪
Full house.
10 blade.
♪♪
No bleed,
no indications for surgery.
Possibly an anoxic
brain injury,
so I'll monitor her closely
in post-op.
Thank you,
Shepherd.
Basin.
Spleen is out.
Bleeding in the left-upper
quadrant is controlled,
but it must be coming
from somewhere.
- How many units have we gone through?
- Eleven.
I'm gonna clamp
the internal iliac,
try to slow the bleeding.
Mmhmm.
Parker,
just so you're clear,
we would have gone through
fewer units
had we stabilized her
in the E.R.
Yes, Dr. Gray.
- Retraction here, Nico.
- Got it.
A pelvic binder
tamponades the bleeding...
It's a very simple
standard of care.
- Yes, ma'am.
- More retraction.
How did you even
become a doctor
with this sort of "everything'll
work itself out" attitude?
I became a doctor
the way everyone does, Grey.
I worked my ass off,
I went to med school...
He became a doctor
because he got cancer...
Jo, that's not
your story to tell.
Sorry. But he's...
He's not a lightweight,
and he's not an idiot.
Thank you.
Got it.
What? Where?
Check this out, Parker.
You want to make sure
you pack below the pelvic brim.
That's where
you're gonna run into
a lot of the
nasty vascular variants
like the crown of death.
I had a hunch
when I saw the X-ray,
and I typically do use
a pelvic binder,
but in this case,
it could've caused
the internally rotated side
to be crushed inward,
causing
even further damage.
And you couldn't have
just said that in the E.R.?
I guess I could've, but
I didn't realize part of my job
was convincing you
I belonged here.
I thought
I just had the flu
and the antibiotics
would knock it out.
No, no.
The antibiotics wiped out
the good bacteria
in your intestine,
which caused
severe inflammation
that made you pass out.
But we caught it
just in time.
Just in time?
Like, before it killed me?
Oh, God. I-I...
I-I can't die.
Those boys
can't lose another parent.
Eli just got to the point
where he's not
crying at night.
They... They need me.
They need...
Okay, the bowel
seems to have ruptured.
Let's, uh, get her
intubated and prepped.
She's moving too much.
Okay, let's push
100 of propofol with 100 of sux.
- Already on it.
- Good.
What?
I-I... Oops.
Oh, my God.
Oh, God, did you...
I'm so sorry.
Okay, everybody, stop!
Listen to me.
The propofol and sux had just
been accidentally injected
into my IV, which means
I have about 30 seconds
until I will be paralyzed.
So let's page the chief.
DeLuca,
start the surgery, stat.
Uh, I'm gonna need somebody
to put a tube in me,
because once I am down,
I'm gonna lose my airway,
and if I can't breathe,
then I will die.
I'd also appreciate it
if somebody could help me
by breaking my fa...
- Patient's intubated.
- Okay, Schmitt, look at me.
Don't rock
the laryngoscope, okay?
10 blade.
♪♪
Now, drive the tube
in between his vocal chords.
Dr. Hunt, you may experience
some discomfort now.
Schmitt, he can't hear you.
I've never done this.
That doesn't mean
you can't, all right?
Now, Bovie.
♪♪
I did it.
I did it!
Okay, do not
stop bagging, okay?
Get him upstairs,
hook him up to some fluids.
Now. Come on.
Let's go.
She's in a coma?
It's a
medically induced coma.
The sedation
will keep her calm
and allow her body to heal.
But...
she will wake up?
Natasha lost
a lot of blood,
and her body underwent
severe stress.
We don't always know
how a patient's
gonna recover from that.
So she won't wake up.
We can't know for sure.
We will continue to monitor her
and support her
and do everything we can.
I don't know what to do.
You can hold her hand.
You can speak to her.
She may be able
to hear you.
She was gonna wear
a blue dress...
for our wedding.
She's not
a traditionalist, and...
she's not a kid.
We waited forever
to meet each other.
It was just
this one tradition...
Sleeping apart.
We thought it would
bring us good luck.
I don't want
to do life without you
now that I know
what it's like with you.
Wake up...
♪♪
And marry me.
Please.
What's wrong?
I'm just glad
that you're alive,
glad that we're alive.
Me too.
I have a surgery. You okay? Yeah.
Hey, thanks
for marrying me.
You're welcome.
I know, Shepherd. I know.
I've run every one
of those scenarios!
I am just trying
to be realistic.
Well, maybe if you'd stop
running off to consults...
That has nothing to do
with the fact
that we are staring down
the impossible here.
Where is
the Amelia Shepherd
that looked at Nicole Herman's
inoperable brain tumor
and said, "Yes, I can,
and I should"?
That was Brain Tumor Amelia.
Non-Brain Tumor Amelia
is a reasonable surgeon
who asks
reasonable questions.
I... And she is currently
speaking in the third person,
so, you know...
This is what
we are dealing with.
We have to visualize this.
Well, that would be lovely,
but it's not an option.
Yes, it is.
Okay, you guys were
talking really loud,
so I'm not gonna apologize
for eavesdropping
despite your angry faces.
Jo...
No, th-there is a way
to 3-D visualize
a tumor like that.
It's brand-new,
and they're about to do
the first launch of it
at UCSD.
- It's called the ORBEYE.
- Oh.
Can I just see your...
That's... Yeah, that's fine.
G-Go ahead.
Who is she?
She's a surgical
fellow studying future medicine.
That's not a thing.
Uh, am I dreaming,
'cause she, uh,
just walked in
with a miracle,
and she looks like a...
mermaid.
It's still
a giant tumor, Tom.
- Just let me have this.
- Okay.
♪♪
What?
I want him to be on fluids,
and check his vitals
every 15 minutes.
I don't want to miss any bumps
in Dr. Hunt's numbers.
- Of course, Doctor.
- What the hell happened?
He said that
he had the flu.
I mean, I told him to go home,
but what is it?
Is it pneumonia? A P.E.?
What happened to him?!
He was injected with a paralytic
by mistake in surgery.
Oh.
Um...
That's, uh...
I'm watching him.
I promise, I'll make sure
he comes through.
Respectfully,
I'm not going anywhere.
Hey.
What?
No one has ever started
a sentence to me
with the word
"respectfully."
Dr. Ryan to Oncology.
Yeah, no. I get it.
Thank you. Thanks.
Everything okay?
No.
I have a bunch of 5-year-olds
on their way to my house
for a birthday party,
and Hulk just canceled.
The Hulk.
What?
It's "The Hulk,"
not "Hulk."
Whatever.
I could help.
Seriously?
After the day we just had,
I could use a party.
For 5-year-olds?
I was a Cub Scout.
I make a mean s'more.
But, I mean, if you don't
need the help...
No, wait.
I'll take the help.
Something wrong?
Tissue's too friable.
Can I help?
You can stop talking
so I can hear myself think.
She's incredible.
Hmm, if by "incredible,"
you mean she possesses
an absurd level
of stubbornness,
then, yeah,
she is incredible.
♪ Be yourself ♪
She's only out-stubborned
by the other two people
operating with her.
♪ Be nothing less ♪
♪ Make your choice ♪ I'm, um, trying to
be better about expressing my feelings.
♪ And let it rest ♪
I never asked you to.
♪ When you're looking for
a meaning ♪ Jackson did.
Now he's sharing nothing
about his feelings with me
or with Catherine.
♪ When you're lost
in the haze ♪
Neither is Richard,
and who knows what's going on
in Catherine's head?
♪ In yourself is the healing ♪
They are stubborn.
♪ Be the choices you've made ♪
My mother did the same thing.
She hid her cancer from me,
tried to protect me,
and all I can think of is
how much time we lost.
♪ How you going to know
what you're looking for? ♪
And they could have that time
if they just talked.
So you want them to
hug it all out right now
over an open abdomen?
I'm saying you can
waste a lot of time
waiting for
the right moment.
That storm's gonna come
when it comes.
♪ And I'm scared to love ♪
How can you
just accept that?
♪ You're scared to love ♪
I'm trying to be better
about not trying to control
the things I can't.
♪ Here we are, here we are ♪
♪ Just a little life
on a spinning rock ♪
- ♪ And you're scared to love ♪
- Wipes.
♪ I'm scared to love ♪
Hemostat, quickly.
♪♪
Mom, if you're in pain,
I can take over. It's fine.
Yes, Jackson, I'm in pain.
I'm in pain because,
when this woman wakes up,
she will not have
a uterus.
The radiation
has fried her tissues.
It's falling apart
in my hands.
No matter
how many times I try,
I cannot safely
separate the uterus
without compromising
the blood supply.
It's literally disintegrating
right before my eyes.
Her body's been through
too much.
You can't fix that.
Neither can I.
Okay.
No one can fix this.
♪ Scared to love,
scared to love ♪
I'm taking out the uterus.
Bovie.
♪ Oh ♪
♪ Scared to love,
scared to love ♪
Ready?
♪ Scared to love ♪
Close her up.
♪♪
- Hunt was given paralytics?
- Yes, but it was a mistake,
and we got him intubated
and off to a room.
And I've also isolated
the area of perforation
and washed her out.
All right. Right.
Since it's toxic megacolon,
you're gonna have to... Perform a
subtotal colectomy with an ileostomy.
I did that, too.
All right, so,
what's left?
I...
I don't know.
You don't know.
It's my first time, okay?
Can you just tell me
what to do next?
You don't know because
there's nothing left.
You did it.
You stepped up.
All right, well, don't get
too swelled up about it.
But great work.
Good job.
Close.
♪♪
Okay, all right.
Breathe, breathe.
There you go.
All right. All right.
Okay. Breathe.
Welcome back, Dr. Hunt.
Ugh.
Dr. DeLuca finished
Claire's surgery.
They did the subtotal colectomy,
and she's in recovery now.
Oh, great. Thank you.
And thank you
for not dying.
Okay, we're done.
Thank you, Doctor...
Schmitt, but everybody
calls me...
You know what? No.
Just Dr. Schmitt.
Ohh.
How you feeling?
Ugh, like I got hit
with a brick.
How was your first day
with Pierce?
Yeah, well...
She is Amelia's sister,
so...
All right,
you know what? Um...
Listen.
I didn't do anything
to Amelia.
I didn't... I didn't set out
to hurt anyone,
and I know that I'm...
I'm not perfect,
and I have made
plenty of mistakes here,
but you showed up
in Germany,
and then you came back here,
and you did what you did,
so please just stop making
everything my fault.
Landstuhl
was my perfect job.
I was in charge,
I was respected,
and they've not yet
filled that position,
and in Germany,
the maternity leave is...
Is really generous.
You... You... Are you saying
you want to go back?
I'm saying I'm having a hard
time wanting to stay here
and answer to a 20-something
who hates me.
I'm saying I don't understand
why I'm the only one
who has to sacrifice anything
so that our kid has two parents.
I mean...
You could move
to Germany.
They've got a great
paternity leave there, too.
Stay here.
Work in Trauma.
I don't want
to work for you, Owen.
- Are you even listening to me?
- No, no.
I'm saying...
run the department.
I'll work for you.
I mean,
you're more than qualified,
and we still have a position
that we haven't filled,
and... and you're right.
Teddy...
you sacrificed a lot
to come here,
and now...
now it is my turn.
Are you giving me
your job?
Teddy...
You're
giving me a lot more.
♪ Who will keep
my fire burning? ♪
♪♪
♪ Keep my heart yearning? ♪
♪ Who will keep
my fire burning? ♪
♪♪
♪ Keep my wheels turning? ♪
♪ One, two, three,
wait a second for me ♪
♪ And tell me,
where's my man? ♪
♪ Who will set my soul
on fire? ♪
♪ And feed my desire? ♪
Uh, hi.
I saved
Dr. Hunt's life today.
♪ Who will knock at my door? ♪
I wasn't Glasses.
♪ And make me beg for more? ♪
I wasn't bumbly.
I didn't drop anything.
♪ One, two, three, wait a second for me
♪ I... felt like a different person.
♪ Tell me, where's my man? ♪
♪ Who will keep my fire burning?
♪ I think it's you.
I think you're
rubbing off on me.
♪ Keep my heart yearning? ♪ Or, uh, you
know, something that sounds less dirty.
♪ Who will keep my fire burning? ♪ I
think this has always been you, and...
you just didn't know it.
♪ Keep my wheels turning? ♪
♪ One, two, three,
wait a second for me ♪
♪ Tell me, where's my man? ♪
You saved my life.
Thank you for doing this.
You really don't
have to keep saying that.
I'm happy to help.
You seemed kind of...
stressed.
Thought you didn't believe
in stress.
I believe it exists.
I just don't believe
in letting it run your life.
I mean, spending your childhood
in a hospital,
losing half the friends
you made there
to a cancer you survived,
watching your parents
split up
because they could barely
afford your treatments...
made me kind of picky
about what I let get to me.
Dude!
Look at this place!
We did this in, like,
a half an hour.
And I was an ass
to you all day.
I literally did nothing
to deserve this.
True.
But... I think I kind of
like the chase.
Because women just
throw themselves at you?
That's not a phrase I would ever use.
Ready or not,
here we are!
- Hello!
- Happy birthday, Bailey!
All right!
What do you think?
Come on, you guys!
Hey!
Presents go
right over there.
Wait.
Are you Thor?
I am.
So cool!
Now, which one of you kids
stole my hammer?
Aah!
♪♪
I completed the ostomies,
and Jackson closed
with a flap.
Uma's in recovery.
How is she doing?
Stable.
Now, look, Mom, I know
you're
-  frustrated, okay?
- Frustrated?
I'm livid.
You questioned my ability
to complete that surgery.
You inferred that
I am somehow not capable...
You had a massive tumor
on your spine,
and you didn't say anything about it.
You didn't even tell me
you had cancer.
I wasn't ready
to bring anyone else into it.
Except you did.
You told Maggie.
I did not tell Maggie.
I told Meredith.
Right. That's different.
Tom Koracick.
I see.
Just the important people.
- I told people who could help.
- Wow.
Good Lord,
that's offensive.
Do you have any idea what that sounds like?
Richard, please.
How am I supposed to
depend on you
when you're hanging out in bars,
swinging baseball bats?
No, no, now, that's not his business...
Wait, what?
And that's not what
we're talking about.
You all are acting like
such big old babies.
This is my problem!
Oh, the hell it is.
No more than my first wife's
Alzheimer's was her problem.
This is all our problems, Catherine.
No, no.
You do not want to go in there.
Sorry. Wait. Can we go back?
There's a... a big storm in there.
What happened at the bar?
A big, big storm. They were giving
people shots for their AA chips.
Are you serious?
That's disgusting.
Amen.
Stop it. Stop it.
Stop it!
Now, I was not wrong
not to tell you.
You were...
This is what you always do.
It's exactly
what you always do...
Now, you try to control
everyone and everything
that you're around.
And look what happens
when I don't.
I'm gone for two days,
and my husband
has an arrest record.
I'm married to a felon.
Mom, he just said they
were trying to give shots
to people with AA chips.
I would've smashed
the damn place up myself.
Thank you.
Uh, I mean, that...
That's... that's still, uh,
no... no excuse for my behavior.
I mean, I realize
that now, but...
We can handle bad news,
all right?
We're surgeons.
And we're your family.
We deserve the truth.
You two both know if
I had told you any sooner
you would've
driven me crazy,
ordering every test
under the sun.
At least Thomas...
Don't... Don't say
that man's name again.
Richard, honestly,
your jealousy
is your least attractive
quality.
And lying doesn't look very good
on you, either, Catherine.
No, you don't get
to say that to me.
You don't get
to talk to me like that!
Not now, not with all
that I'm going through!
Mom, you're seriously
gonna play...
Play the cancer card?
You're damn skippy.
And I'll be irrational,
and I'll make bad decisions,
and I can play
the cancer card all I want,
because I'm the one
with the damn cancer!
And talking to both of you
makes it true.
♪♪
Hey. Hey.
But, luckily, Dr. DeLuca
was here to take over for me.
Wow. I wish I could've seen that.
Mm.
Are you okay?
We're sorry.
For what?
You don't have to
be sorry.
Today was
a really scary day.
And I'm gonna need both of you
to help me for a little while.
You can start
by going into my wallet,
getting some money,
getting yourself some pizza.
Aunt Claire is starving,
so save me some.
Yes, ma'am.
Okay.
- You can't eat, Claire.
- Shh.
It makes them
feel better to help.
Ohh, I can't believe
I almost died.
Well, you were
in good hands.
Thank you
for saving my life.
You're very welcome.
And you.
♪ Take it in ♪
Thank you
for making me stay.
♪ While you can ♪
Yeah.
♪ On the edge of it all ♪
♪♪
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh ♪
♪ I feel it coming ♪
♪ Hold your breath ♪
♪ Don't let go ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh ♪
♪ I feel it coming ♪
♪ Hold your breath ♪
Hey. Hey.
Honestly, Owen,
I'm... I'm too tired.
I gave Teddy my job.
Okay.
Yeah.
'Cause I want her to stay.
I want her here.
I want the baby here.
Clearly.
It's the truth, Amelia,
and I have to be able
to tell you the truth.
I have to be able
to make mistakes,
because there is
no clear path here.
The only thing
I know for sure
is that I am having
a baby with Teddy
and that I have a very real
family with you,
and I don't want to do
any of it without you.
I miss you.
I miss us.
♪ On the edge of it all ♪
♪ Take it in ♪
I don't need time.
♪ While you can ♪
I need you.
♪ On the edge ♪
♪ Of it all ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh ♪
What took you so long?
I was paralyzed.
- Seriously...
- No, literally.
What? Yeah, it was weird.
It was...
Are you...
Yeah.
♪ I feel it coming ♪
It was, like...
What?
Cheat Day.
Mm...
You're about, what,
16 weeks, right?
Do you work
for a carnival?
Every other week.
Want a ticket?
I'm Tom.
I'm sorry.
I can't hear you over
the smell of those fries.
Oh, here.
Here. Do your worst.
I have feet on my hands.
I'm not gonna feed you
unless I have to.
- I don't even know you.
- Well, that's on you.
I tried
to introduce myself.
Teddy Altman.
New Chief of Trauma.
I know.
Tom Koracick,
world-renowned neurosurgeon.
Oh.
We good?
Better.
Hmm.
You really want one,
don't you?
I really do.
Yeah.
Here.
Mmm!
Help comes in many forms.
Mm-hmm.
All right.
A kidney, a kind gesture,
a friend to light your way.
♪♪
Still...
too often we insist
on doing it ourselves.
♪ You're angry, but you
don't know how to be that yet ♪
What's he doing?
Trying to touch
his eyeball.
Why?
Because I want to look
as different as I feel.
♪♪
♪ Resistance
seems impossible... ♪
Ugh.
Do you want me to do it?
Yes, please.
♪ ...from down this low ♪
We're afraid of looking weak,
of not being tough.
♪ And surely no one else
can feel like this ♪
Truth is,
we're all capable
of walking through the world
by ourselves.
I take it back.
What? I don't blame you
for being stressed.
Three kids is no joke.
And you run a department,
win awards.
I'm shocked you're not
more stressed.
Well, trust me...
I'm having a glass of wine
with Thor,
and all I'm doing is
thinking about
how much stuff
I have to do tomorrow.
♪ Sound and pulse
and volume ♪
What?
You like me.
I don't dislike you.
Which is an improvement
from this morning, right?
I won't be offended
if you have to check that.
I'm gonna give myself
a moment.
♪ This is so damn simple,
yeah ♪
♪ It's so damn simple ♪
I have figured out
why you run so much, though.
You eat more junk food
than any surgeon I've ever met.
One perk of being
a cancer kid...
I get to eat
whatever I want,
and no one
can tell me no.
♪ This is so damn simple ♪
- Yes!
- But most of the time,
life is better with company.
♪♪