- Previously on The Resident..
- Oh, my God. It's Bradley.
I love you, too.
And I do think it'll
be different this tim.
I hear you have a
wedding coming up.
- You studying up
to do a Bollywood dance?
- I have two left feet.
Well, maybe I can
help. I was a dancer.
Dr. Benedict at Atlanta
General told me all about you.
Said you were the best
student he ever had.
- You know Abe?
- Who's this douche?
Head of the hottest new medical
device company in the country.
Also the most eligible bachelor.
We all know you're the
most eligible bachelor.
Dr. Bell is meeting
my boss, Gordon Page.
I've done some reading on
your vagus nerve stimulator.
- Is it everything I hear?
- More.
It exceeded all
our expectations.
We're gonna help so many people.
If you can't land
Gordon, I will.
Rare high-altitude potatoes.
Glacier water.
Quadruple-filtrated through...
uncut diamonds.
Cheers.
Best one yet.
Well, have I convinced you?
No, you didn't need to.
I did my homework.
Your new VNS
device is top-rated.
All the QuoVadis
products are solid.
Why'd I buy all this vodka?
Because you want more. You
want exclusivity in my hospital.
Smart man.
So, what do you need
to make all QuoVadis devices
Chastain's standard of care?
It's not what I need. It's
what Chastain needs.
Something to impact
our bottom line.
A discount. Deep discount.
40%.
Whew.
I never give more than ten.
And that's a hell
of a profit margin.
- Before you mark up
the patients.
- 30.
20. Final offer.
And that's only because
you can hold your liquor.
Chastain can get that number
from any of the established
device manufacturers.
Why should I go with
you, aside from the vodka?
Because, as QuoVadis's
newest opinion leader,
you can speak at conferences,
like the one in Cabo next week.
You fly on the company jet.
Five-star hotel. Gourmet meals.
Abundant downtime to hit the
beach with a margarita in hand.
Of course, there's a small
speaking fee and stipend.
It's not much, but
we can offer you 200.
Thousand.
Uh...
That and a 25% discount,
and you have a deal.
♪ ♪
- Voilà.
- Mmm, doughnuts.
- I'm starving.
- Have one.
You're the best.
- Mmm. Chocolate. Good?
- Mmm. Mm-hmm.
Morning. Fresh from the oven.
- Very kind of you.
- Mm-hmm.
- You made those?
- Someone else's oven.
QuoVadis is just
the delivery system.
No, thanks.
He doesn't do carbs.
I don't do bribes.
I heard you're
helpful in the OR,
but I'm not a fan of sales
reps inside the hospital.
Seems like a
conflict of interest.
- No offense.
- None taken.
You know what,
I'll take another one.
We don't make enough
to turn down free food.
I should've gone into finance.
And quit medicine?
Speaking of which, Bradley's
coming in for a heart valve.
Headlines: used to be
one of us, took a nosedive
through a skylight,
left the halls of healing.
Be nice. He's still one of us.
Oh, no, he's not.
Now he's a Muggle.
Hundreds of thousands
in med school debt,
- down the drain.
- Yeah, and he'll be
paying it off for decades.
Pravesh, they need you in VIP.
They don't page you
when they need me.
Looks like they do.
Hey, uh, do you
remember the Barnetts?
First-year intern,
pediatric rotation.
Two adopted kids with
medical needs, right?
Yes, and, apparently, you
made quite the impression.
The oldest boy hurt his wrist.
He's asking for the cool
doctor with the tattoos.
- Ha!
- Our peds resident
isn't here yet,
- so...
- I'm on it.
Don't do that.
In this new Mario game,
- I just like...
- Hey, Jasper!
- Henry.
- Hi.
Look at you, all grown
up. You driving yet?
Good to see you, Dr. Hawkins.
If that's still your name?
Yeah, I was an intern.
I was trying out some nicknames.
Yeah, it wasn't good.
Right, Hammer?
Hammer?
Anyway, here we are again.
Who knew our stairs
could be so dangerous?
Can you give me a little wiggle?
Elbow pit, dude.
Did he get his flu shot?
For sure. But
every kindergartner
has a cold right now. The
school is a phlegm factory.
We have been
seeing so many kids.
Is Henry's hand broken?
Can he still pitch
his game today?
Maybe not today,
but sometime soon.
Are you a righty or a southpaw?
Absence seizures.
He's had them since infancy?
Yeah, but they've
always been mild.
And we have them under control.
Is that why you fell, Henry?
It wasn't a seizure.
I just tripped.
I was reading to Jasper
when we heard the crash.
Okay, he probably
just needs a med adjustment.
It happens as kids grow.
We'll call for a neuro workup.
Keep icing his wrist.
Get an X-ray, too.
- Mm-hmm.
- Cool?
- Cool.
All right. Come here.
All right. All right.
Wash your hands.
He never takes that off. Ever.
'Cause it's awesome.
He loves this hat.
It inspired his police
birthday party this Saturday.
Right, dude?
I'm gonna try to move his
pediatrician visit up to today.
No, no reason for
an extra doctor's visit.
We'll check him out here.
We'll be back.
Hey. It's okay.
You're worried
about the little brother.
Yeah, Jasper had it rough
when he was fighting leukemia.
Chemo, radiation.
He had pneumonia twice.
Poor kid has been in
the hospital all the time.
How long has he
been in remission?
His last bone marrow
transplant went well.
Been clear for two years.
Now he's got a low-grade
fever and a cough.
Saw a yellow bruise on him,
and his nodes are swollen.
- Who's his pediatric oncologist?
- Dr. Richards. Retired in June.
Buzzkirk took her patients.
I know. I don't like him either.
Hi, I'm Dr. Pravesh.
Conrad can't even
answer his own pages now?
Bradley, you're my VIP patient?
VIP. That's me!
- How you doing?
- Never better, man.
You know, besides needing
a whole new heart valve.
But who cares,
right? I'm back here.
I get to see all my pals from
before leaving the rat race.
The rat race. Is that
what we're calling it now?
Well, in medical
marketing, we do, for sure.
Yeah, I got really
lucky with a major firm.
Signing bonus took care
of all my med school debt.
- You're kidding.
- Nope.
Boom. Debt-free and
pulling in mid-six figs.
Seriously, man. But
it's not just that, dude.
- I've never been happier,
honestly.
- That's great.
- You found something you love.
- I did.
So, how are wedding plans going?
Good. Never better.
Uh-oh. I know that look.
That's the look you used to get
when Conrad would pimp you.
You look really stressed, man.
Just normal wedding stress.
Dumb stuff that Priya
and I have to decide.
And we're not always
on the same page.
Uh-huh. Is everything
okay with you two?
It's crazy. You know,
this wedding just feels like
this endless
pile of to-do lists.
- Mm-hmm.
- Plus, I'm always here.
Mm. And here is not
exactly a walk in the park.
- Right.
- Look, I remember how it is.
Definitely no signing bonuses.
Right? Just sleep deprivation.
Hey, man. What
else is goin' on, man?
You were supposed
to be here an hour ago.
Rounds start at 6:00 a.m.
I had patients before you.
How many of them have a
tumor the size of a persimmon
- on their spine?
- I looked at your scans.
Your tumor has shrunk
to the size of an apricot.
Never cared for apricots.
It's good news. It
means we can schedule
the surgery to remove the
tumor for tomorrow morning.
Any questions?
You gonna shave my head?
It's spine surgery.
Why would we do that?
Roger down the block
had his appendix out.
Came home with a Mohawk.
I'm confident that had
nothing to do with his operation.
What do you know about Roger?
Or hair? You barely have hair.
Where's Dr. Voss?
More suction,
- right here.
- There's so much blood.
I said suction.
♪ ♪
♪ You got to let me go ♪
Uh, should we page Vascular?
No. When you
reduced the clavicle,
a clot got dislodged, and
now it's bleeding like stink.
These are
ortho problems. We
are ortho surgeons,
so we fix them.
♪ Ready for war, I
got my armor gear ♪
♪ Carry your sword
'cause the time is near ♪
♪ What a thrill, always
seems to amaze me ♪
♪ In the forest with the
youth and they're raving ♪
♪ Dancing nonstop
till the break of dawn ♪
♪ Sheriffs come around,
probably best to run ♪
♪ Fire in my eyes,
can't catch me now. ♪
Shall I page Pre-Op
to bring the pat...
♪ Don't judge me,
you only live once ♪
♪ Homies in the back,
so we got to live it up ♪
♪ Party in the lake,
everybody get in now ♪
♪ Get in now, get in now,
get in now, get in now ♪
Ah. There.
The source of the bleed.
- Huh.
- Here. Put pressure here.
- Okay.
- No, here.
- Oh.
- Bulldog clamp, six-oh Prolene.
♪ Run wild ♪
♪ I'm on a mission ♪
There.
Easy to control the bleed
once you recognize the source.
That...
was so cool.
Agreed. Mayo.
♪ Running miles and running
and I'm loving all the bruises ♪
♪ Running miles
and running wild ♪
♪ I'm chugging
like I'm fueling ♪
♪ Houston, tell 'em
that I'm coming up ♪
♪ Let me go. ♪
What the hell is that?
This is not my valve.
Who put this valve here?
Cancel the surgery.
I'm booking your
spa day in Cabo.
Question: did you want
the couples massage or...?
You're not going alone, are you?
Ooh, couples massage.
Sounds delightful.
But perhaps it can wait.
A word, Dr. Bell?
Of course. Tilly, hold my calls.
I'm speaking at a
conference in Cabo.
I'd love a top woman
orthopod to introduce me.
Let's talk about a
screw, shall we?
A screw?
Does this look like
a 6.5 millimeter,
nine-grooved cancellous
bone screw to you?
Well, it shouldn't,
because it's 6.3 millimeters
with eight grooves.
Care to explain
why it showed up in the
middle of my clavicle surgery?
They accomplish the same thing.
The AorMed valve
is a thing of glory.
Sleek leaflets.
Perfectly aligned suture ring.
- She drives like a dream.
- Let me guess.
Changes in your OR?
An intruder. An
alien heart valve.
- It's a top-of-the-line...
- That's not the point.
You don't get to make
surprise, unilateral decisions
that affect our patients.
No ceremony. No discussion.
- No notice, even.
- You two can't agree
on anything.
Suddenly you're
on the same team?
A bomb just exploded in my body.
Jasper Barnett's labs.
White blood count over 150,000.
Low platelets,
blasts everywhere.
- Liver's starting to go, too.
- Henry came in
with a broken wrist,
but we thought Jasper
- was in remission.
- And now he's not.
He already has a rare phenotype.
It's known to be resistant.
And when a kid
comes back like this...
I'll give him a month.
Maybe two, tops. Only
reasonable thing now
is palliative treatment.
Anything else
at this point would do
more harm than good.
Let's hope Mom sees it that
way. They hardly ever do.
What if it had been
caught earlier?
Wouldn't have mattered.
His initial treatment was
aggressive and thorough,
and it was his best
chance at a cure.
They kept the cancer at
bay as long as possible.
Now it's back with a vengeance.
Guess I'll go spill the beans.
- Best to get it over with.
- Let me handle it.
They know me.
- I had them
on my intern rotation.
- Hey,
if you want to take the worst
part of the job, it's all yours.
How does someone like
that guy end up in pediatrics?
The same way HODAD
ended up in the OR.
You okay?
How do you tell a
mother her child is dying?
Found it.
Let's see.
So, look, this is way
before I broke my pelvis.
I told you I started early.
You're incredible.
Do you miss dancing?
No. I got my hip
replacement, got my life back,
and now when I sell devices,
I help other people
do the same thing.
I love it.
So, I showed you mine.
You show me yours.
What?
- The health monitor app
you're working on.
- Oh. Uh...
we're still making some
tweaks in the program.
If we could monitor
elderly patients from afar
with more accuracy...
You could see their
overall medical report
instead of relying on
day-of examination results.
Exactly.
And it's working, but
now we have to install
the device and pair it
with something wearable.
Wearables are huge
in the aging market.
So show me it.
All right.
Diagnosis:
a previously unbeknownst
cyst beneath the ulna.
It ruptured with such
power, such force
that it fractured
the strong bone.
You found that on the
Internet. A bomb in your body.
Oh, there was an
explosion. I created it.
It was undeniably godlike.
Right.
Let's get you in
a splint, shall we?
I'll order X-rays
to confirm you can be
treated nonoperatively.
So, my diagnosis
was correct, huh?
Your Web surfing was correct.
Let's talk
about our mutual
problem, shall we?
The craven king
in the high tower.
There are half a
dozen other devices
Bell is swapping
out for QuoVadis,
including one I need for a
spinal resection tomorrow.
That's where that man
makes my ego look nonexistent.
Not possible. But it's useless
to try and overrule him.
At least for doctors.
Say more.
Well, if patients were unhappy
with administration
making medical decisions,
- Bell might listen.
- He'd have to.
The power of
persuasion. I like it.
- Yes, but can you use it?
- Me?
Oh, I'm damn near a master.
I'm gonna get you so much!
Did you get Jasper's
results back?
We'll go over everything
in the conference room.
You want to wait for
your husband to get here?
Uh, not happening.
It got tough. He bailed.
His loss. Let's do this.
I knew it.
Inside, I knew it.
If I had gotten Jasper
in here earlier...
We'd still be right here.
This isn't your fault at all.
You need to hear that.
There has to be something.
I will find him another
bone marrow donor.
Even if we found one right
away, he's not healthy enough
to go through the prep regimen.
Then when can he
start chemo again?
- We just have to get
even more aggressive.
- Zoey...
Jasper can't be cured.
And if we tried anyway,
the treatments are painful.
I will connect you
with an oncologist
so you can discuss it, but...
he would suffer.
I read about alternative
treatments in Mexico.
- We can go.
- Zoey...
No.
I will do whatever
you want to do.
This is your decision.
But my job is to
tell you the truth,
which is Jasper can't beat this.
You can't stop that.
You can't change that.
None of us can.
But what you can do...
is you can focus on the
quality of life he has left.
You can be with him every step.
And you can be there for Henry.
He's gonna need you.
I knew you couldn't resist
putting your hands
on my heart again.
That is a stretch.
Actually, Dr. Okafor misses
standing shoulder to shoulder
with a surgical
giant on the reg.
Little housekeeping
matter. Sign this.
It's a form saying that you
insist on the AorMed valve.
The website said QuoVadis is
the new protocol here at Chastain.
Which is why I need you
to insist on using the valve
that your brilliant
surgeon believes is best.
You want me to use those devices
to kick administration
in the cojones?
- Mm, maybe not quite that.
- But aren't they new
for a reason?
- Because they're better?
- Well, it should work that way.
But the FDA approves new devices
that have literally
never been tested
inside a human. Not
only do we not know
if they're better, we
don't know if they're safe.
Okay, and what exactly do
you like about the AorMed?
Do you really want
to have a conversation
on the finer points
of a heart valve?
Bradley used to be
a surgical resident.
At this hospital.
Great. I guess that's
better than a trip...
Triple-board-certified
master of the scalpel?
Okay, well, I still work
in the medical field,
so I definitely have
- an understanding of what... Nobody
cares about your understanding!
I am the surgeon.
You are the patient.
I am the one who
knows what's best,
and you are the one who
takes a medically induced nap
in an OR with your life
in the hands of people
who are far more experienced,
more educated and more awake.
- I don't believe it.
- Unfortunately, it's true.
Medical devices are far
less regulated than pharma.
Thousands are
recalled every year
for harming the patients
they were supposed to help.
Which is why I
prefer older devices
that have a proven
safety record.
The hospital wouldn't
put something inside me
that would hurt me.
Doctors want the devices
that work best for patients.
Our administration chooses
the device manufacturer
that gives them the
greatest profit margin.
Now, I caution you not
to let them decide for you.
But ultimately it's your choice,
and I will support
whatever you decide.
Sign the damn thing.
What was that?
That was his charm offensive.
I think maybe you're trying
to tell your boss to buzz off.
But I support it.
You make the call.
Oh, I am so loving my
career change in this moment.
Poor you. I can't believe
you have to work with that guy.
Listen to me.
Good surgeons are
often arrogant jerks.
But Dr. Austin has the most
skilled hands I have ever seen.
You want happy chitchat
and fake empathy,
or you want your heart
fixed without complications?
I want the best surgeon
using the latest innovation.
Well, you can't have
both at Chastain.
Our surgeons want proof
that whatever the latest
innovation is, it works.
Got your page.
How can I help you?
Austin's X-rays.
It's a non-displaced fracture
through a benign cyst.
- He's cleared for surgery.
- Oh, good. He's one of our best.
Although he's no Kit Voss.
Thank you, Dr. Bell.
Randolph.
One of my patients is requesting
I implant a VertGuard device
instead of the QuoVadis one
for her spinal tumor resection.
I'm gonna need my
device back in this hospital
by tomorrow morning.
I made that decision
as a CEO and a surgeon.
QuoVadis is a trusted
brand with proven outcomes.
If you want me to talk
to your patient myself...
Over my dead body.
You've got some
tension in your neck.
I can see it from
here, Randolph.
I am not trying to
cause you stress. Truly.
Wow.
Well, that-that was...
that was effective.
How about a peace offering?
Your office in an hour?
That should be interesting.
Clear your schedule.
Hey, buddy.
Can I hang for a minute?
If you're looking for
Mom, she's in with Jasper.
Nope, just checking on you.
Do you know what I want
to be when I grow up?
A baseball player?
Not anymore.
Now I want to be a scientist
or doctor or something.
Find a cure for cancer
that could save Jasper.
You are a great brother.
Do you know that?
Is that for Jasper?
His birthday's this weekend.
He loves police stuff so much.
We were gonna have a party
where he dressed up like a cop.
That's all he's
been talking about.
It sucks, 'cause now
we have to be here.
I think we might be able
to do something about that.
Really?
I think I can pull that off...
with a little help.
Think you can help me?
Mmm, yeah.
Perfect.
Okay, unfortunately, Make-A-Wish
couldn't do anything official
for a couple of weeks.
But they did give me...
You ready for this?
These guys.
- Oh...
- Right?
Not the hat.
Jasper has his own.
Good call. Okay, you
ready for this, though?
Ta-da!
- Oh-ho!
- A police car!
Awesome, right?
No, seriously, junior year,
- Decatur Community Playhouse.
- You played Macbeth?
I understudied.
We found everything on the list.
Band-Aids, ketchup, hair spray.
Oh, and these.
So...
You just found real handcuffs?
Yeah.
Hmm.
You know your part, right?
You bet I know my part.
It's almost showtime.
Uh, Dr. Voss says I
should send you straight in.
Uh... excellent.
Uh, no disturbances
for the next hour.
Let's make that two.
Who are you?
I'm Ken.
What kind of pressure
do you prefer, Doctor?
Uh...
- Oh!
- Oh! I got 18.
- You won.
- I won by one point.
You did.
I work undercover on the force.
The police station called.
There's a criminal on the loose.
Oh, no. A criminal?
His name is The Germ.
Things could get tough.
I need a partner.
Here.
I was gonna give this
to you for your birthday.
I can help you.
Yeah? Okay.
I got your squad car.
All right, let's solve a crime!
- All right, where to?
- I don't know,
but security caught
The Germ on camera
- sneakin' around.
- Uh-oh.
How do we find him?
The Germ has made a move!
Detective Okafor!
Talk to us.
He's stolen all of the bandages,
- except... one.
- Oh...
There's a red fingerprint on it.
You think it's blood?
That's ketchup.
Hmm.
Good catch, eagle eye.
Where would The Germ
have gotten into ketchup?
Oh, the cafeteria!
All right.
Looks like we're going there.
Ready?
Let's do this!
Come on, let's go.
Let's go.
You see any clues?
Mm-mmm.
I see a handprint.
Hey, mister, we're
looking for The Germ.
It's Bob, okay?
I haven't seen him,
but if you want food,
you're out of luck,
okay, because someone,
they stole all
the sterile gloves.
I see one!
Jasper, look.
Another one, and another one.
We have to follow them!
- Move it, guys! Go!
- Let's go!
I think we're getting close.
Keep your eyes peeled, guys.
- The Germ!
- He's really here!
Stop bothering
me! I'm a super bug.
- How do we stop him?
- We got to use what's here.
You can't fight me.
Like, maybe this?
If you push these buttons
right here, you will stop him
with an electric shock.
You got this.
Stop it right now, Germ!
Okay, Germ,
Are you gonna give back
those bandages and gloves?
Never!
I'm MRSA the super bug.
Okay...
stop him.
You, you little
shrimp, I'll crush you.
Bring it. What are those?
What are those things?
Get away from me with those.
I'm trapped!
- Don't come any closer!
- Yeah, you are!
Ow! Ow! Ow. Ow.
You're arrested!
- Get up, kiddo.
- Don't make me go back!
It's so dark in there.
We got him now.
Get him out of here!
♪ ♪
Is this damn hospital
gonna kill me?
Penny, tell me what's happening.
I don't know! I woke
up, the bed was wet.
I couldn't get up.
Incontinence, lack of sensation.
- Can you feel this?
- No.
- How about here?
- Nothing below my waist.
Am I paralyzed?
My guess is cauda
equina syndrome.
The tumor must be compressing
the nerves of your spinal cord.
- Oh, my God, oh, my God.
- Penny, Penny,
your surgery just
moved up to now, okay?
Book an OR.
If we don't get her
in there right away,
she's never gonna walk again.
All right, fast and focused.
Pull the mayo closer.
Ten-blade, full retractor set.
- Where's Okafor?
- On the way, Dr. Voss.
Damn it.
That's the QuoVadis device.
It's the only one they
had left in supplies.
- Do you want me to call out
for something else?
- There's no time for that.
Looks like I have to put
a device into her spine
that I already
convinced her not to use.
Dr. Austin. I don't
know if you remember,
but we've met before.
You're a horseman of
the apocalypse. I know.
I wanted to speak with you
about one of your patients.
- I don't do device reps. Sorry.
- Well, this device rep is
trying to tell you that Bradley
Jenkins wants a new surgeon.
Who does he want?
Archibald Simon.
I'm better than
Archie. Significantly so.
That's what everyone says,
but Bradley has his heart set
on QuoVadis, and
you won't use it.
I've installed over 600 valves
from 12 different companies.
I've tried what's out
there, and every single time
- I go back to the AorMed.
- Do what you want.
I know QuoVadis
devices are gold.
I'm just trying
to do you a solid.
Right. Sure you are.
Look, this doesn't affect
me one way or the other.
Either Dr. Simon puts in
the QuoVadis device here,
or Bradley says he'll transfer
to Abe Benedict
at Atlanta General.
- Dr. Benedict?
- Mm-hmm.
I was his star resident. He
raised me on the AorMed.
Well, now he uses QuoVadis,
and he's willing to
poach your patients.
- Austin.
- Good evening, sir.
What's that?
A mere flesh wound.
I'll survive.
Well, good to see
you, as always.
- How'd you find me?
- Well, it's 7:30,
constitutional jog
at the alma mater,
rain or shine.
I know. I'm a creature of habit.
Which is why I was surprised
to hear that you've moved away
from the heart device
you've used for years.
Why the QuoVadis valve?
Uh, well, the truth is,
valves are very similar.
Then why the switch?
- The penicillin coating.
- Really?
I thought that was
much ado about nothing.
- You've found
it really makes a difference?
- Reduced the rate
of postoperative
endocarditis by half.
- You're certain?
- AJ, you know better than anyone
it'd have to take
a great product
to get me to change my ways.
All right, well,
dinner next month,
- per the youzh?
- Wouldn't miss it.
- All right.
- Good to see ya.
They're bringing
in a cot for you.
Thank you... both,
for everything.
You kidding me? It was
fun. Who knew Jasper was
such a good little detective?
I caught The Germ, Henry.
You were awesome.
Okay, Freddie Freeman, bedtime.
All right, good night, guys.
Good night, Officer Jasper.
I'm not gonna grow
up to be a police officer.
What do you want to be now?
I'm not gonna grow up.
I saw my mom crying.
I know what that means.
Can you do something for me?
Name it.
Take care of my brother.
He fell down the stairs.
It was maybe one of
those things he gets.
An absence seizure?
Can you fix him?
I can try.
My mom needs him.
Promise.
Yes.
♪ Ta-da! ♪
Ooh.
You and Conrad were great today.
If you ever decide
to leave medicine,
you have a backup career.
As police officers?
I don't think we really
play by the rules.
No, I was thinking as
children theatre actors.
Oh.
How are you doing?
Heartbroken.
That family...
Jasper. It's okay.
- Oh, talk to me.
- Unresponsive, bradycardiac.
- Cheyne-Stokes breathing.
- You have do something.
- Pupils are fixed and dilated.
- Epi and atropine's maxed out.
Intracerebral hemorrhage.
- He's herniating.
- I know.
What are... What's
happening? Save him!
Zoey...
Listen to me.
Jasper has a brain bleed.
Okay, so stop it.
We can't.
No one can. His blood is...
His blood... it can't clot.
- No. No.
- This is the end.
No.
I don't want his last moments
to be torture, and neither do you.
He needs you, both of you.
I'm here, Jasper.
I'm right here.
Zoey, do not miss this moment.
Tell him you're here.
Yeah.
Tell him you love him.
Just tell him it's okay.
- Tell him it's okay.
- It's okay.
Tell him it's okay.
Baby.
It's Mommy and Henry.
We love you... so much.
♪ ♪
Left arm...
Retract the myocardium
while I finish snipping.
There.
- Ready for valve placement.
- Pickups.
When you grab the
valve, it helps to...
Saleswoman, I've been
grabbing valves since...
Well, I was gonna say
since before you went to
med school, but you didn't
go to med school. You
went to business school.
Wharton? U Penn?
This damn valve is too big.
No, I think you're
holding it upside down,
which is, I believe, what
Julian was trying to tell you.
Speak up, then.
Put the valve on the mayo stand.
You see that white tick mark?
Clamp it there
when you pick it up.
Now it's positioned
for proper placement.
Easy-peasy.
Oh.
A perfect fit.
Start suturing,
Dr. Okafor, please.
Six-oh Prolene to me.
For the record, I went
to dance conservatory.
- Juilliard.
- Oh.
An artist. That's why
you're good in the OR.
Boo-hoo.
How was that massage?
Helped with the neck
tension, but for the record,
I prefer a female
massage therapist.
It's not so fun to
expect one thing
and be surprised
by another, is it?
The QuoVadis devices
are good for the hospital
because they're
good for the patients.
Your case yesterday
had a perfect outcome.
- Yes, but that's not the point.
- What, pray tell, is the point?
You're a gifted surgeon.
In your OR, did you want
an agenda shoved down
your throat from an ivory tower?
Kit, just see the big
picture, They're innovators.
There's opportunity
here for you, as well.
- QuoVadis can...
- Let me be clear.
Perks, bonuses, trips
to Cabo as payola... no.
I'll never be a shill
for a device company,
even a reputable one.
It's not in the best interest of
my patients. And Randolph,
I have a high
enough opinion of you
to believe you
wouldn't do it, either.
I've gone over
the surgical report.
The heart valve was
installed perfectly.
Blood flow and
oxygen levels are good.
- You have a new lease on life.
- And no more excuses.
You are officially included
in the Bollywood dance
- at my wedding.
- No. You do not
want that. I have three
left feet. I'm serious.
Listen, if Julian can make me
look coordinated,
she can teach anyone.
Devon is an exceptional student,
and we have a final
rehearsal coming up.
I can catch you up in no time.
Mina,
- dance with us, too?
- Uh, just try and stop me.
Now, I have to remove
the surgical drain
and the patient needs to rest.
- Okay, take care.
- Thank you.
- Mm.
- Sorry.
- See you later, man.
Thanks for everything.
So... those two?
- He's engaged.
- And she is gorgeous.
So is Devon's fiancée, Priya.
Mina, has having a boyfriend
turned you into a romantic?
I have always been a romantic.
And I've romantically learned
to mind my own business.
Okay. So you trust Julian?
Not at all.
I trust Devon.
♪ The black above ♪
♪ Is dense with stars ♪
♪ Can anybody ♪
♪ Hear me? ♪
♪ Can you hear ♪
♪ My heartbeat ♪
♪ My heartbeat? ♪
Mmm, mmm, mmm.
Nice watch.
You're right.
- Those stipends are generous.
- Yeah, well,
it pays to be a QuoVadis
Opinion Leader.
Now, Dr. Benedict...
let's discuss Cabo details.
Mmm.
Captioned by Media
Access Group at WGB