- You're gonna be okay,
I promise.
- I'm gonna hold you to that.
- Those lungs are shot.
- We're gonna find him a donor.
- Imagine the liability...
- If we declared this man dead
and taken his organs.
- Dr. Ahmad, you're suspended
pending an investigation.
- I appreciate
how much you've helped us.
- See ya around, Mags.
- Loren is a catch, Maggie.
Make your move.
- Mr. Brenner, your liver is
going off to a father of three
in Milwaukee.
Pancreas to a librarian
in Indianapolis.
Kidneys to a social worker
in Cleveland
and to a new mom in Detroit.
But first, your heart is off
to a college student
in St. Louis.
Thank you for these gifts.
Okay, let's move on
to the lungs.
- We got you covered.
Doris, Dr. Johnson is about to
transport a heart to St. Louis,
and he just lost
his flight nurse.
He needs a replacement ASAP.
- Mm.
Sorry, Mags, I get airsick.
- The ED is not too busy,
so I'm gonna go.
Just giving you the brick.
- Well, all right.
I'm in charge.
- Easy. I'm coming back.
Hey.
So you're flying off
with Loren, literally.
Today the day you're gonna
let him know you're interested?
- It's work, Hannah.
- Absolutely.
- You asked for a nurse?
- Really?
You're filling in?
- Mm-hmm.
- I thought you would have sent
Trini or Nancy.
- They're busy.
- Works for me.
- Europe.
- Uh, Navy station,
Rota, Spain.
- Asia.
- Naval hospital, Okinawa.
- Obviously, the U.S.
- Uh, Pearl Harbor,
Coronado, and Portsmouth.
- And yet you chose
to settle in Chicago?
- I like the unpredictability.
You're not gonna get
a near-freezing day in May
at those other places.
- I'll buy that,
but Honolulu, come on.
- Nah.
Hold on, hold on.
- Hey, hey, hey.
Watch out. You okay?
- Yeah, I think so.
The lady walked out in front
of me, and I totally lost it.
- All right,
I'm a doctor, all right?
Did you hit your head?
- No, my arm. I landed on it.
It's kind of tingly.
- All right, let's see here.
Let's see here.
Make a fist.
Extend and contract the elbow.
All right,
nothing's jumping out.
Yeah,
you didn't break anything.
Still tingly?
- No, it's gone.
Just an ego bruise now.
- Yeah, okay.
All right, you know what?
Arm starts swelling up,
just put some ice on it.
You'll be all right.
- Will do.
- All right.
- Thanks.
- Oof.
- Superman.
- Oh, it's just a--
just a bruised arm.
It's not a challenging case.
- Yeah, still,
you fixed him up.
You got him going.
You know, addiction medicine,
every case,
it's a deep dive into genetics,
life experience, environment.
Sometimes I wish
I could fix my patients
just as quickly as you did.
- I'm pretty sure
my patients feel
the less time with me,
the better.
- Come on.
You're a good guy, Dean.
- Let's keep that
between us, okay?
- Oh, I think that's Ashland.
And that's the apartment
I lived in
during nursing school.
- It's an entirely
different city from up here.
Every day is a walk down
memory lane.
That corner office
has got nothing on this.
- Oh, Dr. Marcel.
- Hey, Ms. Goodwin.
- Good morning.
Listen, I wanted you
to hear this from me.
I just met with
the emergency medicine
program director
as well as the board,
and Dr. Ahmad has been let go.
- That's too bad.
I'm sorry for Zola.
Well, thank you
for letting me know.
- Sure.
Mrs. Miller?
- There's a rumor
going around the ICU
that there's an organ donor
in the hospital.
- Yes.
Unfortunately, the lungs
were not a match to Carson.
Kendall, he's at the very top
of the transplant list.
The next pair of lungs
that match will be his.
- If they come in time.
Clots formed again in
the ECMO circuit last night.
They're forming
more frequently too.
- Yeah, I read that
in his chart.
- Dr. Marcel, I am trying
so hard to stay hopeful,
but you were concerned that
Carson wouldn't survive a week
on ECMO without lungs.
It's been over three.
- Yeah, well,
we've come this far.
Gotta keep the faith.
- Name's Perry Eastman.
He's 22 and flying high
on something.
Paramedics picked him up
a few blocks from CCU.
He's a college student.
- All right, thanks.
- On my count.
One, two, three.
- All right, Perry, if you're
able to take any of this in,
I'm Dr. Archer.
You're in the ED
of Chicago Med.
What the hell is this, bark?
- When we got there, he was
going toe-to-toe with a tree.
- I'm guessing the tree won.
- We were able to coax him
into the ambo,
gave him two of Versed
for medical control
to calm him down a bit.
He's all yours.
- Gee, lucky us.
All right, Perry, looks like
you only busted a few fingers.
All things considered, I'd say
that's a pretty good outcome.
Let's get ice on these hands
and an X-ray
and also the usual
from the OD menu.
- Chest X-ray, EKG, CBC, BMP,
pan CT, and a urine tox.
- Have security
check his clothes,
make sure he doesn't have
any more drugs on him.
- Yeah, you got it.
Dr. Archer, um, I have
a situation with my patient.
- Why are you whispering?
- Well, it's not
exactly with my patient.
She just has a sinus infection.
- Oh, Zach, get to the point.
- Right.
It's my patient's husband.
Look.
- Under his jacket.
You see it?
His name is Greg Sanders.
- Is he a cop?
- No, an accountant.
- Wow, that's a problem.
- What's going on?
Thought you said Florence
only had a sinus infection.
- It is.
This isn't medical.
- I got this, Dr. Hutchins.
Mr. and Mrs. Sanders,
I'm Dr. Archer.
I'm chief of the ED.
First, Mrs. Sanders,
I'm sorry
you're not feeling well.
Second, Mr. Sanders,
your firearm is poking out
from under your jacket.
- Oh.
- Outside of law enforcement,
firearms are not permitted
in the hospital.
- I have a
concealed carry license.
- Permit or not, it's a felony
to have a weapon
in the hospital,
so either
you stash it in your car
or leave the premises with it.
Otherwise, security is
gonna have to get involved.
- I'll keep it covered.
Problem is solved.
- Not on my end.
- Honey, it shouldn't be
that much longer.
Why don't you just
wait for me outside?
- That sounds like
a great idea.
- Yeah, fine. Okay, yeah.
Just, you know,
if you need me, call me.
- Dr. Hutchins, how about
you walk Mr. Sanders out?
- I'm sorry.
- It's--
- Greg was mugged
a few months ago,
and the thief
pulled his wedding ring
right off of his finger,
so now he feels like
he needs the gun
to protect himself and me.
I don't like it, but I get it.
- I understand.
- My patient's been waiting
almost two years on a heart.
Thank you. Day zero.
- Second birthday.
Wow, that was powerful.
- Yeah, it hits deep.
- We'll never meet
that patient,
but we'll always know
that we helped save her life.
- Mm-hmm.
All right, let's go home.
- Yeah.
- Ripley called in sick.
Flu's going around.
Is that what it is?
- How should I know?
- I figured you might,
that's all.
- Dr. Asher,
you have a patient in three.
Mallory Bates--
fatigue, nausea,
diarrhea, and a low fever.
- Okay, I'll take a look
at her chart and be right in.
- Yeah.
- Anyway, regarding Ripley,
chicken soup may help,
you know, if you talk to him.
- Talk to me.
- June Bishop, 28,
suicide attempt.
Witnesses saw her jump
from her fourth-floor balcony.
BP 90 over palp.
Heart rate 118.
Intubated in the ambo
with no drugs.
Peri-arrest
the whole ride here.
No movement at all.
- Okay.
All right, here we go, folks.
Nice and easy.
On my count, okay?
Ready? One, two, three.
Start a unit
of whole blood, please.
Breath sounds bilateral.
Compound fracture,
left humerus.
No rock in this pelvis.
No deformity of the legs.
Pinching the feet.
No response to pain.
Sternal rub.
Again, no response.
Mike, let's get X-rays,
chest and pelvis.
Okay, I got a massive
head trauma and blood loss.
Brain's exposed.
I think some of it's missing.
- Chest X-ray up.
- Okay, multiple
left rib fractures,
large pulmonary contusion,
left side.
- Pelvis X-ray up.
- All right, pelvis is normal.
Might be the only thing
that is, though.
All right, guys,
let's roll to the CT.
- My wife? Where's my wife?
June--June Bishop. June?
Is that June? June? June?
- Sir? Sir!
- Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
I'm right here, baby.
It's gonna be all right, okay?
I love you.
- Sir, please. I'm so sorry.
We gotta get through.
Dr. Charles, please.
You gotta let us
get through, okay?
- Sir, sir.
I'm Dr. Charles.
Now they're gonna take
the best possible care of her,
but we've gotta let them
do their job, all right?
- Okay.
- So I want you to come down
here with me, all right?
- I was at work,
and my neighbor called,
and he said that
he saw June jump.
I just don't get it.
Why? Why would she do this?
I don't--I don't understand.
- You notice any, I don't know,
changes in her mood recently
that were unusual?
- No, I don't think so.
And we just got married,
you know?
We bought a condo.
Um, she likes her job.
You know,
she's close with her family.
She's got a lot of friends.
- In her day-to-day life,
no changes there, either?
- Um, I don't--
I don't really know.
The last few weeks, I've been
kind of absent, you know?
Um, work's been crazy.
I've been pretty much
living at the office.
What if--what if
that was the problem, me?
- No.
- No, neglecting June,
being a bad husband.
- No.
- What if--what if
I'm the reason this happened?
- Nathan.
- Oh, my God, this--
this is my fault, isn't it?
- Nathan, it's not
your fault, all right?
The reasons that people
take their own lives,
it's just very complex
and mysterious,
and it's rarely just one thing
or one person.
- No, June--
June wanted to talk last night,
but I had another long day.
You know, I was exhausted.
She was reaching out for help,
and I ignored her.
And now--now she--
- Mr. Bishop?
- No, no, please.
- Mr. Bishop,
your wife suffered
a catastrophic head injury.
Trauma to her brain
is extensive,
and all we can offer at
this time is supportive care.
She's now on a ventilator
in the ICU.
The nurse can take you
to see her.
- I'm so terribly sorry,
Mr. Bishop.
I really am.
- This is gonna be brutal.
- Hey, Dan,
June's chart shows that she--
she was seeing
a doctor here at Med,
Valerie Clark, psychiatrist.
- Oh.
- Ooh.
- Does that hurt, Mallory?
- No, no, it's just tender.
My whole body feels tender
and exhausted,
probably from trying
to shake this fever.
- How long
has this been going on?
- A week or so.
I thought I was pregnant,
but the home test was negative.
Thank God.
I just moved to Chicago
and started a new job.
That is all I can handle
right now.
- I can understand that.
You take care of you,
and the rest will follow.
- You're the nicest doctor
I've had so far.
- So far?
- I went to urgent care.
They said it was a cold.
When I started feeling worse,
I went to East Mercy.
They thought
it might be the flu.
- Hmm. Well, it's possible.
The flu is
going around right now.
- I don't know.
I had the flu in January,
but this feels different.
I told that to the resident
at East Mercy.
He ordered some labs,
but then he disappeared.
I felt so crappy.
I just went home.
Never got my results.
- Well, that's okay,
because you're here now,
and we will start over.
- You know, flying a helicopter
is a balancing act.
The three main controls have
to work together as one.
It's all about synergy.
- That sounds like the ED.
- Well, you gotta think
just as fast, that's for sure.
- Oh, really?
Oh, what was that?
- Collecting some moisture.
Look, I'm gonna drop us down
to about a thousand feet,
see if we can't
duck under this weather.
Loren, what's going on?
- Yeah, we're losing lift.
Ice is forming
on the rotor blades.
- Ice? But it's May.
- Yeah, well,
it's winter at 3,000 feet.
Okay, Maggie,
I need you to hold on tight.
I'm gonna take us down
really fast,
try to get us
below this icing level.
- Oh, my God.
- We're dropping
through 500 feet,
and the ice on the rotor
isn't melting.
Okay, Maggie, I need you
to brace yourself.
I'm gonna take us down.
It's gonna be a hard landing.
- Oh!
- Hey, Maggie, you hurt?
- Just shook up.
But I'm not injured.
- That's good.
- You okay?
- Yeah, I'm good. I'm good.
- Mr. Bishop?
Hi, my name is Sharon Goodwin.
I'm with patient services.
I'm so very sorry
for your loss.
And unfortunately,
there's no good time
to bring this up,
but would you be open
to speaking
with a representative
from Organ Donors of America?
- I figured someone was gonna
come and ask me that.
And I believe
in organ donation.
I think it's a wonderful thing.
But no, I do not wanna talk
with them
because June
is going to wake up.
You know,
the first time that we
held hands was in the winter.
It was freezing cold.
But she was so warm.
She still is.
So I have to believe
that she's still in there.
So however long it takes,
I will sit here
holding June's hand
until she wakes up
so I can apologize
and we can talk.
- I will leave you alone
with your wife.
- He said no.
- Perhaps you can speak
with him later.
- No, I don't think so.
June's blood group
indicates that she's
a possible organ donor
to my other patient, Carson,
but we all know
what happened to Zola.
In cases like these,
it's easy to overstep,
and I don't wanna
influence Mr. Bishop
into making a decision
he's clearly not ready to make.
- Hey, everybody.
Everybody,
just gather around please.
I've got news to share.
Uh, just learned
that Loren and Maggie
hit some weather
during their flight,
and their helicopter went down.
It is not a crash.
It is just a--a hard landing.
- What does that mean?
Are they okay?
- They seem to be fine.
Uh, the area they went down in
is remote.
Loren is in contact with 911
and the helicopter company,
and they're working out a plan.
Loren is an army guy,
so Maggie is in good hands.
All right, let's--
let's get back to it.
- The urine tox came back
on your patient, Perry--
cocaine and PCP.
- Cocaine and PCP?
That's a jolt.
Explains him trying
to beat up a tree.
- Security went through
his clothes,
didn't find any more drugs.
- Okay, has ortho checked out
his busted fingers?
- They said soon.
- Okay, that means a few hours.
Do me a favor, uh,
get those pamphlets
on drug treatment,
meet me in there, all right?
- I got it.
- Ah, damn it. Trini!
Damn it. Perry bolted.
His clothes are still here,
so he can't be far.
Look at this.
You believe this?
Secret compartment in his shoe.
Security missed it.
- Emergency stash.
- If it's cocaine
laced with PCP,
then he's wired as hell.
All right, get security
to start looking for him,
tell them to check
the bathrooms.
- You're gonna fight me?
- Get back!
- Scratch that.
Tell them to get to ambo bay.
- Yeah.
- Get back!
Get back! Get back!
- You're gonna fight me?
You're gonna fight me?
You wanna fight me?
- Get back!
- I'm gonna fight you.
- Perry, stop.
Perry, stop. Perry.
- I'm gonna kick your ass.
- I'm warning you, get back!
Get back!
- Mr. Sanders?
- Huh?
- Bilateral breath sounds.
- BP 112/72.
Heart rate 118.
- Two holes, left deltoid,
close together,
through and through.
Two holes, upper left arm,
another through and through.
Single hole, upper left
quadrant of the belly.
Uh, need to roll him, please.
Yeah. No exit wound.
Mike, need images,
chest and torso.
- X-ray.
- No bullet. Torso?
- X-ray up.
- Retained bullet,
left abdomen.
All right, that means surgery.
Coming to the hybrid OR.
Rails up.
Trini, I need six of blood
and six of plasma waiting
for me when we get there.
Let's go.
- Well, she's grounded.
One of the main rotor blades
is cracked.
The company
will have to figure out
how they wanna recover it.
Meanwhile, volunteer search
and rescue is coming for us,
but we're in
the middle of nowhere,
so it's gonna be a few hours.
- Yeah, there could be
worse places to wait, right?
Yeah.
- Loren, are you okay?
- Yeah, cyclic jammed me
in the chest
when we hit the ground.
I think it might have
broken a rib.
- Oh.
Oh.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Okay.
There you go.
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa.
Your pulse is thready.
Okay, why don't you lie down?
There you go.
Okay, I'll go get
the trauma bag.
- Yeah. Oh.
- Give me your arm.
There you go.
Tell me what you're feeling.
- It's tough to breathe.
My chest is really tight.
- BP 94 over palp.
- That's too low.
What do you hear?
- No air moving
on the left side.
Tension pneumothorax?
- Touch the skin.
It looks bad, doesn't it?
- I've seen worse.
- Is it crackly?
- No crackles.
- Probably not
a tension pneumothorax.
- Hemo pneumo.
You're bleeding
into your chest.
- Pressure's collapsing.
Okay, look, you're gonna
have to decompress me.
- Seriously?
There's no chest tube kit.
There's only a Cordis kit here.
- It'll have to do.
- Okay, okay, okay.
- I'm sorry, Dan,
it's just shocking.
June Bishop jumped
from her balcony?
- This morning.
- I'm absolutely stunned.
I'd only recently
started seeing her.
I didn't detect
any suicidal tendencies.
- Yeah, I'm having
a little trouble with it
myself, you know?
Just the lack of
warning signs, you know,
the no note, and the overtly
public nature of the act.
I mean, female suicides tend
to be more private, right?
And this is just anything but.
Do you mind me asking what
you she was seeing you for?
- Insomnia.
It was a recurring issue
that had been at bay
and recently came back.
- Huh.
- She works from home,
so she'd been
taking naps during the day,
but her sleep cycle
has really been suffering.
- Insomnia can be tricky.
Any idea why maybe
it resurfaced now?
- We only had two sessions.
I hadn't yet landed on a cause.
I recommended that
she get a sleep study.
She emailed me and said
that she'd had it done
and that she would bring the
results to our next session.
- As you might imagine,
her husband, Nathan,
is just an absolute mess,
but he didn't mention to me
this morning that his wife
had been seeing a psychiatrist,
and it makes me wonder,
maybe he didn't know.
- He didn't.
She was planning to tell him
after the sleep study.
With everything that Nathan
was dealing with at work,
June really wanted to make sure
that she was working
on a solution before
she dropped her baggage
in his lap.
- Huh.
- Hey, how is your patient,
Mr. Eastman?
- He's stable. And Greg?
- The detectives are getting
his version of events,
but the video
and witness statements
point to him acting
in self-defense.
- It looked
that way to me too.
- Well, legally, I don't
expect charges to be filed,
but emotionally,
he's shattered.
- Well, he found out
what it feels like
to actually shoot someone.
- Okay, Mallory,
I'm seeing your stomach
is a bit distended,
and I'm seeing
some dilated loops of bowel.
- Which means?
- Right now, it's hard to say.
The bowel can be really
reactive to inflammation.
So it could be gastroenteritis
or an obstruction
or maybe even an ileus.
That's when your intestinal
muscles don't contract
the way that they need to.
And the next step
is an NG tube.
It'll go in through your nose,
down into your stomach.
- In my nose?
- I know.
It doesn't sound pleasant,
and it's not,
but it will ease your nausea,
and you'll feel better.
- Well,
that's worth it, I guess.
- Okay, well, after the tube,
I'd like to get a CT
so we can take a better look
at your abdomen.
- Tubes?
Scans?
I was hoping
all I needed was an antacid.
- I'm sorry.
- Wait.
You're OB,
but I'm not pregnant.
Am I getting passed off
to another doctor?
- That is how it works.
But, you know, I--
I know what it's like to need
someone in your corner,
so I'm not gonna
disappear on you.
Okay, Mallory?
- Yeah?
- Hey, Daniel.
I just got a call from the ICU.
June Bishop's nurse
says that Nathan
refuses to let go of her hand.
It's interfering with her care.
And I'll tell you,
I sat with him for a bit,
and he's clinging
to false hope.
I'm--I'm worried about him.
- Yeah, you and me both.
- What's all of this?
- Everything that we know
about June Bishop.
It's, um, you know, her charts,
uh, it's session notes
from Dr. Clark,
you know, her shrink
that I was telling you about,
the sleep study that
she ordered a couple weeks ago.
- What are you looking for?
- Look, we know that
she stepped off that balcony,
right?
But suicide?
I mean, just not quite
making sense to me yet.
So I'm just looking
for some other reason
that makes a little more sense
for Nathan
to wrap his head around
so he can start to process.
- I'll let you get back to it.
- Thank you.
- Lidocaine going in, but
I think it's still gonna hurt.
- Yeah, if it's pain
or death, I'll deal.
- Okay.
One...
Two...
Okay, okay, okay.
All right, through the muscle.
- And I'm in. Oh.
Okay, okay.
- You're doing great, Maggie.
- Hang in there, Loren.
You're doing great.
Tube is in.
Okay.
Diluters coming out.
- Ah.
- Okay. Okay.
- Nice job.
Now we can both breathe
a little easier, huh?
- Yeah.
You're losing a lot
of blood, Loren.
- The helo carries two units.
- That's it?
- It'll be enough.
- Yeah, yeah.
- And then you got shot,
three times to be exact--
shoulder, arm, and belly.
- Man, I don't remember
any of it.
I went out
to a party last night,
and I ended up here.
Sounds like you fixed me up
real good, though.
Saved my life, even.
Thank you.
- So, Perry, you're gonna
be here in recovery
for a couple hours,
ICU for a few days,
and then the hospital floor,
and then eventually
outpatient care.
- You'll still be my doc, yeah?
- Technically.
But now you've been admitted
to trauma service.
There'll be other residents and
attendings taking care of you.
- Okay.
I guess this is goodbye, then.
Thanks again.
- Yeah.
- I understand,
but I've got a nurse
that just placed a chest tube.
Well, how long until
your search and rescue team
gets there?
Okay, okay. Thanks.
- Wait, Maggie placed
a chest tube?
Dean said everyone was fine.
- Well, it seems Dr. Johnson
was more injured
than he let on.
Maggie got him stabilized,
but now they're running low
on oxygen and blood.
The SAR team is moving
as fast as it can.
Doris, give Dr. Archer
the update
and share the info
with the rest of the ED.
- It's gonna be dark soon.
That's gonna slow
the SAR team down.
- Yeah.
- The CT results for
your patient, Mallory.
- Thank you, Trini.
- Listen, uh, when I get
more info, I'll find you.
- Okay, thank you.
- So what did the scan show?
- There's an obstruction
in your right heavy pelvis,
a mass.
- A mass?
Is--is that, like, a tumor?
Cancer?
- I can't say for certain,
but that is a concern.
- It was a stomachache,
that was all,
and now I have an IV
and a tube in my nose
and possibly cancer?
I wanna go home.
- I'm sorry, Mallory.
Because of your fever,
the distended stomach,
dilated bowel,
whatever this mass is,
we need to get it out
immediately.
- You mean, like, today?
- I mean, like, right now.
- Um, is he--
- He's gonna be okay.
- I keep playing it over
and over again in my head.
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
Please, will you tell him?
- And when I walk home
from work at night,
sometimes it can be scary.
- Mm-hmm.
Thought of getting a gun?
- Yeah.
- So what do you think now?
- This is a scan
of June's brain
when she's asleep, all right?
You'll notice that these areas,
right, this one
controls movement,
sight, speech.
Those are all active.
But this area up here,
the prefrontal cortex,
not active.
- Okay, what does that mean?
- Well, the prefrontal cortex,
it's our--
it's responsible for--
for awareness, right?
It's our--
it's our decision maker.
- So you're saying that Jean
could walk, talk and see,
but had no idea
what was going on?
- Yeah.
- So then what was she doing?
- I think that your wife
was a sleepwalker.
- Sleepwalker?
- People have been known to,
you know, leave the house,
go for a drive, cook a meal.
And they've been known
to injure themselves,
you know, falling down
a flight of stairs
or even jumping out a window.
- I mean, there's been times
that I'd wake up
in the middle of the night,
and June would be, you know,
on the couch with the TV on.
One time, though,
she was at the table,
and there was food out.
And I just assumed that she
dozed off after having a snack.
Do you think
she was sleepwalking?
- I think
it's very likely, yeah.
- Wait, two weeks ago,
she stayed with her sister
up in Bucktown
for a few nights,
but she was actually
getting the sleep study done.
Why didn't she tell me
about any of this?
- I think that she was probably
just trying to be considerate,
you know, given what you
were going through at work.
I think that she
didn't wanna burden you
with it until
she had a better idea
of what she was dealing with.
- Do you think that's
what she wanted to talk
with me about last night?
- I think it's possible, yeah.
But listen, Nathan, even if
you had had that conversation,
last night, all June had was
the results of the sleep study
in terms of raw data, right?
She had not had
a clinical interpretation yet.
So if she didn't know
about sleepwalking,
how could you?
- How'd he take it?
- You know, he--
uh, he listened.
So fingers crossed.
- Your pulse is still thready.
It's worse than before.
Oxygen tank is almost empty,
and...
catheter,
it's still draining blood.
We're gonna need more.
- We're out?
- Yeah.
I wish I could, um,
recycle your blood.
- You can't.
Where's the SAR team?
They should be here by now.
- I'm really cold.
- You're getting cold?
Okay.
Let me warm you up. Okay.
There you go.
- Maggie, I messed up.
- No, you didn't.
There was ice on the rotor.
You didn't do anything wrong.
- No, I--I messed up with you.
The moment I met you,
I was like, "Damn."
But you were married.
And now you're not.
And I kept waiting for this
right moment
to ask you out, and...
Maggie, I--
I shouldn't have waited.
Yeah.
- Loren?
Loren?
- Dr. Loren Johnson.
This is a search and rescue.
- We're here! We're here!
They're here.
- Have you been following the
data on early onset cancers?
- It's on the rise
for people in their 30s,
especially in women.
You caught this one early,
though.
- I hope so.
- Lots of adhesions
in the pelvis.
This is odd.
- Right lower quadrant's
really socked in.
Looks to be all cecum.
- Peeling the small bowel
off the ab wall.
Whoa, suction.
- Is that pus?
- Yeah.
Hannah, there's
no mass in here.
What you saw on the CT was a
big clump of infected schmutz.
- Okay, well,
where's it coming from?
- That's a good question.
Sponge stick.
Give me this.
There we go.
Appendix is disintegrated
into mush, totally ruptured.
Well, ironically,
this is a pleasant surprise.
- Yeah, it means Mallory
doesn't have cancer.
- No, just an odd presentation
of a perforated appendicitis.
And urgent care thought
this was a cold?
- And East Mercy
thought it was the flu.
All that pus, Mallory easily
could have become septic.
- It's a good thing
you didn't pass her off.
By the time
a resident from medicine
would have seen her,
run it by their attending,
it've been too late.
Nice job.
All right, irrigation.
- Hey.
- Treatment seven.
- Doris, I'm good.
I'm out of the danger zone.
- Yeah, well, you're still
getting a full workup.
Zack, Trini, you're up.
- Chest tube out
of a Cordis kit? Nice.
- Nursing 101.
- Yeah, right.
- I'm just happy
that Loren's doing okay.
- Humble in
the face of victory,
that classic hero behavior.
- Oh, it's the ICU.
Nathan Bishop
wants to speak to me.
Look, Maggie, I gotta go.
But you had us
worried for a bit.
- Happy ending.
- Yes.
- An emergency landing
in the boonies?
Are you kidding me?
- And that wasn't even the most
unexpected part of the day.
- Oh, my.
- Girl, I'll call you later.
- Okay. Okay.
Doris, the Mariano's
around the corner,
how's their chicken soup?
- Mmm, so worth it.
- No, no, I get it.
I appreciate you trying.
All right.
Hey.
- Hey.
- Still no luck
in finding Carson the lungs.
- You don't need luck anymore.
Mr. Bishop's asked to speak
to Organ Donors of America
about June.
And this time, I think you
should join the conversation.
- Can you page me
when Mallory wakes up?
- You're back.
- I'm back.
And I was thinking
maybe I could stick around
through your recovery.
- Yeah, thanks.
I'd like that.
- And also,
there's another doctor
I was hoping you might want
on the team with me.
It's Dr. Collins,
addiction medicine.
- Perry...
beating up trees,
emergency stashes,
and secret compartments,
getting shot?
Where you are right now,
this doesn't seem
like a party, man.
This seems like a problem.
- Yeah.
I've tried to stop using
a few times.
I just keep slipping, man.
- I know.
So is that a yes, then?
You'll meet her?
- Yeah.
- Good.
- Hey, Perry.
- Okay, suture line is intact.
No leaks.
Nice and pink.
Good blood flow.
I like it.
Carson, my man,
you got new lungs.
They came from
a special young woman.
Her name is June.