Good morning, sunshine.
Hey.
Look like you could use
an aspirin.
What time did you make it home
from Molly's last night?
I didn't.
Oh.
Walk of shame?
I mean, I've been there.
Dr. Rhodes, I need you.
I'm not on Trauma
today, Maggie.
Not a Trauma.
Robert Haywood,
Dr. Reese's dad,
CFD just arrived
with a STEMI alert.
Yeah.
Courtney,
you're going to T 2.
Robert Haywood,
58-year-old male
with known history of
heart failure, CAD, and...
Ischemic cardiomyopathy.
Yeah, he's my patient.
Heart rate, 95.
BP, 88 over 44.
New onset angina unrelieved
with nitro and aspirin
in the field.
EKG shows ST elevations.
It feels like
someone's squeezing.
I know, Bob,
you're having a heart attack.
Just try to stay calm, okay?
All right, everybody,
on my count.
One, two, three.
There we go.
Maggie, you paged.
It's your dad.
The ambo just brought him in.
What?
Irregular heartbeat.
He's in a-fib.
Four of morphine,
esmolol drip, and an aspirin.
Rapid ventricular rate, 210.
He's in SVT and hypotensive.
We need to cardiovert.
Give me the paddles.
All right, five of valium.
Charge to 75 joules.
Charged.
Sync and clear.
Back to sinus rhythm.
Rate, 88.
All right, Maggie,
call the cath lab.
Tell 'em we're on our way up.
I got you.
Ready?
Wait.
All right. Let's go.
Come on, Sarah,
you can ride up with us.
Sarah?
We stented your right
coronary artery,
and we placed a balloon pump.
Now, your ejection fraction
is low,
so I'm afraid
that you're gonna
have to stay in the ICU...
Until a heart
becomes available.
Mmm-hmm.
It's just as I predicted.
Though, I'll admit, I didn't
expect to end up here so soon.
You are at the highest status
on the transplant list.
But only for 30 days.
If I don't get
a heart by then...
Ah, we'll... We'll cross
that bridge when we get there?
Took the words
right out of my mouth, Bob.
I'll see you soon, all right?
All right.
Oh, Dr. Rhodes,
do you know if, uh,
Sarah's here today?
Uh, I'm not sure about that,
but I can check on it for you.
Hey. I heard about your dad.
I'm sorry.
If you need to talk or...
I don't.
But thanks.
Dr. Sexton, heads up.
This is Henry Lee.
How are you doing, Mr. Lee?
You're going
to Treatment 2.
Congestive heart failure
and metastatic stage four
non-small cell lung cancer.
Stopped chemo last month.
All right, Mr. Lee.
Hey, Henry.
There's my girl.
You two know each other?
Old friends.
Henry used to come into
the ED once a month
for his heart meds.
Been missing you
around here, man.
Okay, where does it hurt,
Mr. Lee?
Faster to tell you
where it doesn't hurt.
Give five of morphine IV.
Bibasilar crackles.
Add 20 of Lasix
and order a chest X-ray.
Henry has a history of
malignant pleural effusions.
Every time
they drain my lungs,
suckers just fill
right back up.
Okay, well, we can put in
a drainage tube.
No, no, no more procedures.
No needles, no tubes.
I'm done with all that.
Yes, sir.
Henry's cancer's everywhere.
Hey, does he have any family?
Not that I know of.
His wife is deceased.
I'm pretty sure
he lives alone.
Okay, well,
we'll have to transfer him
to a hospice facility.
I'm sorry, April.
Choi, Halstead,
walk with me.
CFD's inbound
with two teenage boys
burned in a house fire,
one of which is
Carter Singleton the Third.
Singleton?
Yes, as in
the soon-to-be-constructed
Singleton Center
for Diagnostic Radiology.
Huge donors,
and Goodwin's godson, so...
VIP.
Yeah.
You're going to
Treatment 6. Desmond?
Sixteen-year-old male,
22% second-degree burns.
BP, 120 over 82.
Heart rate, 110.
A friend's right behind.
Bo? Where's Bo?
Bo Williams, 17 years old.
85% third degree burns.
Couldn't get a BP,
but palpable
radial pulse of 112.
Kid's a real hero.
When we got there,
he was giving his buddy
CPR on the lawn.
Okay, gently,
one, two, three.
A hundred of fentanyl
for the pain.
Yes, Doctor.
Thank you, Desmond.
Yep.
All right, lungs are clear.
Where'd you learn to do CPR?
Boy Scouts.
Carter, I'm here.
Is Bo gonna be okay?
He's with Dr. Choi,
one of the best.
He's taking
very good care of him.
Groin line's in.
I'm having trouble
bagging him.
His chest is cooked.
He needs a chest escharotomy.
Scalpel?
You're gonna do it here?
No choice.
His chest can't expand.
Gotta release
the skin tension.
Ms. Goodwin?
Oh, my God, Carter!
Lydia, careful.
Sharon, is he gonna be okay?
Carter suffered
second-degree burns.
They're gonna be painful
to the touch for a while.
Dr. Halstead,
Lydia and Maurice Singleton.
Son, uh, how...
How did this happen?
Is Bo all right?
Were you with Bo?
That boy is nothing
but trouble.
That's not true, Mom.
You know you are not allowed
to go over to his house.
Lydia, just lighten up
a little bit, please.
Uh, Maria, wash the burns
with soap and water,
apply Silvadene cream,
and I'll be back
to help dress him.
Thank you, Dr. Halstead.
Here, please.
That kid's in
pretty bad shape.
Have you notified
his parents?
They were visiting some
friends over in Lake Geneva.
Driving back now.
That's terrible news
to come home to.
Yeah.
All right.
Hey.
So, sidelined for
the conjoined twins surgery,
and now you're doing
procedures before
your morning coffee?
I like the fight in you.
I'm a glutton for punishment.
Latham made his choice clear.
You know, it's not over
until the first incision.
Start playing nice, maybe
you'll be holding the scalpel.
Are you all of a sudden
rooting for my success?
Not at all,
I just hate
winning by default.
Bruce Hammond, 34.
Blunt trauma to the chest
following a high-speed
car accident.
Negative echo,
but a small left hemothorax
and a sternal fracture.
CT's negative
for aortic injury.
Yes, but Radiology read
that there might be
a small pericardial effusion.
Since he's got a hemothorax,
let's put a chest tube in
and see what comes out,
and if he needs surgery,
we can do a high left
thoracotomy.
Hold on.
Is that a blush of contrast
over the right atrium?
If there's a hole
in his heart, he needs
a median sternotomy.
Good eye, Dr. Bekker.
If it is a blush,
we can't afford to ignore it.
I don't know, opening him up
is highly aggressive,
and we don't know
whether the contrast
is inside or outside
of his heart.
If the majority is
in favor of sternotomy...
I'll follow.
Excellent.
Dr. Bekker, you'll lead.
Dr. Rhodes, you'll assist.
Mmm-hmm.
Oh, don't look so pained.
I think you just earned
yourself some good will.
When did Emma's pain start?
About an hour ago,
halfway through ballet class.
I wasn't sure
if I should bring her in,
but her mom would have my head
if something happened to her.
I was worried that
it might be appendicitis.
No, appendicitis would be
pain on her right side,
but I would like to get
an ultrasound.
You know, when I was young,
I wanted to take ballet,
but unfortunately,
I was born with two left feet,
so I went with violin instead.
Well, I don't
really like dance,
but my mommy did ballet
when she was young,
so she makes me go.
Oh.
Right now, I'm gonna
put this on your stomach,
so I can see
what's inside, okay?
All right.
Monique,
can you increase the depth?
I can't see
her uterus and ovaries.
It's already all the way up,
Dr. Manning.
All right,
let's start a line.
Give her one milligram
of morphine for the pain.
And let me know as soon
as her mom gets here.
I'd like to speak with her.
Is Emma gonna be okay?
Yes, but it's a good thing
that you brought her in.
All right, Emma,
I'm gonna be back soon, okay?
Okay.
Thank you.
Hey, Dr. Charles,
you got a sec?
I've got a case
I'd like to run by you.
What you got?
My patient, Emma, nine,
she presented with abdominal
pain on the left side,
so I did a quick bedside scan
to check her ovaries.
It's actually
testicular torsion.
Testicular torsion?
Yes.
The ultrasound showed an
absence of uterus and ovaries,
but she has
undescended testes.
Huh.
Nothing about this
in her chart?
No, I doubt the family
has any idea.
Okay. Page
Pediatric Urology.
We need to get
a plan together.
Okay, thank you.
I suspect Emma has
17-beta HSD3 deficiency.
It's caused by
a genetic mutation.
Emma's testes aren't
able to carry out
the final step of
testosterone synthesis.
So, just to be clear,
genetically, she's male?
She almost certainly has
XY chromosomes, yes.
As far as the testicular
torsion, what's required?
We need to untwist the testis
and then fixate it
via orchiopexy.
So we'll be able
to save the testicle?
With surgery, yes,
otherwise, it'll die from
lack of blood flow
in six, maybe
eight hours tops.
Okay, thank you, Dr. Rios.
We'll share the news
with her mother
and get surgical consent.
This news could
change Emma's
whole sense of identity.
It is a lot for this family
to process.
You know, my experience
in situations like this
is that the children are often
surprisingly open-minded
and resilient.
What's the story?
Well, Carter said that
Bo was cooking up BHL.
Uh, butane hash oil.
You blast marijuana
with enough butane,
and you get pure THC.
Lengths kids will go to
to get high these days.
Exactly.
Uh, Carter said he heard
screams from the other room,
so he ran in, he tried
to pat out the flames on Bo.
Then his sweatshirt
caught fire,
but he dropped and rolled.
Guessing from Bo's burns,
he didn't do the same.
Yeah, Carter said
Bo panicked and ran.
Can I talk to him?
He's nonresponsive
and on a ventilator,
but I'll let you know.
Hey, Will.
Dr. Frisch.
I think after last night,
you can call me Maia.
Lunch? I'm buying.
Uh, pretty slammed today.
Another time.
I take it you and Nat
are on the outs still?
As far as I know.
Careful.
She'll come around.
Mr. Lee, this stage
in your life can bring
a lot of painful emotions
and memories up.
I can help to talk about
what you're feeling,
any concerns you're having,
fears, regrets.
Henry, what is it?
What's wrong?
Where's my shirt?
My boy...
Jackson.
You have a son?
When he was little,
he was my shadow...
But as he got older,
we started butting heads.
Didn't care too much
for all my rules.
Rough neighborhood
where we lived.
Sounds like you were
just trying to protect him.
But maybe I was
too hard on him.
His mom passed
about 10 years ago.
After the funeral,
we had words.
Said some ugly things
to each other.
Haven't spoken since.
Do you have his phone number?
Any idea where he lives?
Last I heard,
he was up in Wilmette...
Or maybe Skokie?
Can't remember.
Should've reached out sooner.
It's not too late.
We'll find him.
We will do our best, Mr. Lee.
Don't you think
you're overpromising?
How do you know we'll be
able to track this guy down?
I'm not letting
Henry die alone.
Ruptured atrial appendage.
Median sternotomy
was the right call.
Ah, it was a coin toss.
Could've gone the other way.
Still, pulling
someone through
that kind of blunt trauma,
it's impressive.
You should write it up.
I know I said play nice,
but don't go soft on me.
That's no fun.
Hold on...
There are only
244 instruments here.
There are supposed to be 245.
Dr. Rhodes, stop closing.
Everyone search your areas.
Check your trays,
the drape pockets,
look in the basins,
everywhere.
It has to be here somewhere.
Somebody talk
to me, anybody!
We counted
three times already.
Instrument's in the chest.
Get a tech in here
to get a chest X-ray,
and page Dr. Latham now!
I don't understand.
How could her doctors
have missed this for so long?
Why don't we go
somewhere more private?
Your daughter is in
excellent hands, trust me.
Here, right this way.
So, because Emma's genitals
are typically female,
there was no reason to suspect
that she had the condition.
If the testicular torsion
hadn't caused
Emma's pain today,
it's very likely she
wouldn't have been diagnosed
until she reached puberty.
What happens during puberty?
When Emma turns 12 or 13,
uh, the testes will start
to make testosterone.
She may develop
typically male attributes.
Um, body and facial hair,
an Adam's apple,
her voice may deepen.
What?
No, that can't happen.
You have to take them out.
The only thing that is
medically necessary right now
is to alleviate Emma's pain
by untwisting the testis.
But Emma would have to have
another surgery
down the line, right?
I mean, she'd have to
have them taken out.
She's a girl.
Children with
Emma's condition
often identify as male
after puberty.
No, that's not...
That's not gonna happen.
I want you to take them out.
To perform an irreversible
procedure of this nature,
we would need to inform Emma
and get her assent.
Her assent?
She's nine.
She won't understand,
and even if she does,
it'll traumatize her.
We fully appreciate
how completely overwhelming
this is right now.
Really, we do.
But the truth is that
the evolving thinking
among medical ethicists
is that children should be
afforded gender autonomy,
regardless of their age.
You know what, I just wanna
be with my daughter right now.
Of course.
What the hell is that?
No idea.
Not an instrument I recognize.
But it is a foreign body,
and we can't pinpoint
where it is.
It could be in the pleural
cavity, the pericardium.
We're going to have to
reopen the sternotomy.
Clearly.
How could a careless oversight
like this occur?
We use the same instruments,
the same routine
every single time.
How could both of you miss it?
Is the patient's skin
fully closed?
No. A few staples away.
If the skin isn't closed,
then the incident
isn't a sentinel event.
Going back in won't be
considered a second operation.
You both narrowly escaped an
investigation by the hospital
and a report to IDPH.
I want you in my office
as soon as you retrieve
the foreign body,
and I wanna know
who's responsible.
Don't beat yourself up.
It's only your second strike.
You know this could
just as easily be
your instrument, right?
Lucky it's an easy fix.
You better not have
been smoking with Bo.
I wasn't, Mom.
I told you already.
Bo almost ended up
in juvie last year,
but the judge agreed
to give him another shot.
Now, you would've thought he
would've learned his lesson...
Mom, just shut up, okay?
Whoa, whoa, whoa...
Excuse me?
Don't talk to your mother
like that. What is with you?
What's going on?
Sats are dropping.
What's wrong with Bo?
Take him off the vent
and start bagging.
He's bradying down.
Heart rate's 30.
Milligram of epi.
No pulse. PEA.
Another milligram of Epi.
No.
No! No! No!
Son...
Bo, please!
Carter...
Carter... Carter...
No, just go save him, please!
Sweetie...
Please, Bo, come on, man!
Bo!
Carter...
Bo, come on, man!
That poor family.
Yeah.
It's strange.
Bo's parents said
he'd been doing so well.
They'd been regularly
drug-testing him.
He'd been clean for months.
Guess he just
fell off the wagon.
Did you get
a tox screen on Bo?
No, why?
Do me a favor and get one.
I'm gonna get one on Carter.
Jackson Lee.
No? Okay.
All right, thank you, bye.
Hey, any news?
Not yet.
I think I found
his LinkedIn profile, though.
Just trying to track down
a phone number
or an e-mail address.
I have a friend
over at the DMV.
Send me what you have
on Jackson.
I'll see what he can do.
Thanks, Maggie.
Yeah.
Need some help in here.
Okay.
Sats down to 90.
CO2's at 65 on the ABG.
Okay, Mr. Lee, you have DNI
and DNR orders on your chart.
Now, I need to
confirm that you do not
want us to intubate you
or perform CPR
should your heart stop.
Okay. Then we're gonna
make you feel comfortable.
Start a morphine drip
and give four of Ativan.
Okay.
No holes in the right pleura.
Or the left.
It must be in the pericardium.
Give me more suction.
Instrument's not there.
It's in the heart.
We're going to have
to reopen the atriotomy.
That's going to require
putting him back on bypass.
You're increasing his risk of
air embolism and stroke.
We're aware, Marty,
but we don't have a choice.
Your quick fix just got
a lot more complicated.
Hi.
You feeling better, Emma?
My mommy says
I'll need an operation.
Yes, that's what my friend,
Dr. Charles, and I
came to talk to you about.
Hi, Emma.
So, you remember
when I took a picture
of your belly earlier?
Well, it showed me that you
have something inside of you.
Something that only boys
have, honey, not girls.
That part inside of you,
it may cause you
to change a little
on the outside in a few years.
It'll make you
look like a boy.
Ms. Paulson, would you mind
giving us a moment to explain?
Please?
So, Emma...
Most people
who look like girls
on the outside
feel like girls on the inside,
but sometimes,
a person who looks like
a girl on the outside
feels like a boy
on the inside,
and you know what...
Okay, stop, stop, you...
You're just confusing her.
Of course Emma
feels like a girl.
Sweetie,
the part inside of you,
it's what's hurting you
right now,
so Mommy wants
the doctors to take it out
so that you'll be safe.
Mrs. Paulson...
Wait, will it hurt?
No, not at all, sweetie.
You'll be asleep
the whole time.
And when you wake up,
we can get chocolate sundaes.
So it's okay
if they take them out?
Mmm-hmm.
Ms. Paulson, can we speak
to you outside for a moment?
Okay, you heard her.
You have her assent.
Take them out.
It was not
an informed decision.
Well, Emma's nine years old.
She didn't understand
half of what you were saying.
Again, regardless of her age,
it's very important
that we at least try and
explain the situation to Emma,
so we can give her a chance
to tell us how she feels.
I... I know how she feels.
I know my child, and I won't
let you manipulate her.
We were not trying
to manipulate her.
Why don't we take a beat,
let Dr. Manning and I
put our heads together,
and see if we can come up
with a course of action
that everybody's
comfortable with, okay?
I take it
things didn't go well.
Emma's mom coerced her into
having her testes removed.
Yeah, we gotta get
Goodwin involved
to see if we can convene
an emergency ethics panel.
We have three hours tops
until the testicle dies.
We better move fast.
Given the placement and
orientation of the handprints
on Carter's back,
there's no way
they're his own.
Okay? So?
So Carter told
my brother, Jay,
that he tried to slap out
the flames on Bo.
I haven't said
anything to Jay.
So, you think Carter
may have started the fire
and is blaming Bo?
Carter tested positive
for THC.
Bo was clean.
Thank you, Dr. Halstead.
What you up to?
I'm trying to write a budget
for this research
grant application,
but Excel formulas hate me.
Well, I don't know
if you know this,
but I am kinda a math whiz.
I am, I can take a stab at it,
if you wanna go see your dad.
I don't.
I don't want
to talk about him,
and I don't wanna see him.
Okay?
Yeah.
Noah...
I know you Sextons
are as thick as thieves,
but not every family's
like that.
April?
Your son is coming, Henry.
Jackson's coming.
Thank you.
My angel.
Metzenbaum
and DeBakey Forceps.
Reopening the atriotomy now.
I'll need better
visualization. Suction.
A-ha. There it is.
Stuck in the ostia
of the pulmonary vein.
What is it?
It's the tip of
a suction catheter.
You were the only one
on suction.
Then hold on.
Cardiac suction catheters
don't have detachable tips.
At one point, Dr. Bekker
had to suction
an area herself.
I handed her a catheter
from a trauma tray.
I think it's yours.
Well, we're going to need
to take it out, aren't we?
Stone forceps.
Forceps.
Got it.
BP is dropping.
The vessel tore.
He's bleeding out.
Quick,
get me some 5-0 Prolene
and a long needle driver.
Careful you don't
ligate the vein.
If you narrow it,
he could lose
part of his lung.
Why don't you stop
backseat driving
and help me save his life?
You okay?
Yes.
No.
My patient's mom
is trying to force
an invasive surgery on her.
Unless the ethics committee
intervenes,
I don't think
I'm gonna be
able to stop it.
I mean, I know I shouldn't
be unloading on you.
I'm... I know we're...
I'm sorry.
No, it's okay.
Case sounds tough.
Sorry, Nat.
But I know
you'll figure it out.
Yeah.
You look exhausted.
Are you okay?
Uh, yeah.
Had a tough time
sleeping last night.
Anyway, good luck.
Finished repairing
the pulmonary vein laceration.
BP any better, Marty?
Talk to me.
Vitals are stable.
Dr. Rhodes,
close the atriotomy,
take the patient off bypass,
and staple him up.
Uh, wait a second,
you're the lead here.
You have to decide
how you want him closed.
Wires or plates and screws
for the sternum?
Don't you remember
how we closed him last time?
Do it again.
I don't know who the hell
you think you are,
but that stunt
you just pulled,
leaving me there
to clean up your mess?
I'm sorry.
Come on, Ava,
you don't have to worry
about your reputation, okay?
This isn't some reflection
of your surgical skill.
This is just... It...
It's human error.
It could happen to anybody.
You really think
it's my reputation
I'm worried about?
Bruce... Bruce
almost died today,
because of my stupid mistake.
He didn't...
Hey, listen to me.
Ava, he didn't.
He didn't, okay?
He's in recovery
because of what you did.
Oh...
What if he has deficits?
I could never forgive myself.
Involuntary manslaughter's
a class 3 felony.
Carries a potential
jail sentence.
It certainly doesn't
help matters
if Carter lied
during his statement.
Why are we discussing charges
when we should be
talking to the police?
I'm sorry...
But whatever
the consequences are,
Carter needs to face them.
You're right.
Thank you, gentlemen,
for filling us in.
We'll handle it from here.
Look, Sharon...
CFD and CPD will conduct
their own very thorough
investigation,
and it is in the hospital's
best interest
and frankly yours
to not put yourself
in the middle.
But I am
in the middle, Peter.
Carter's my godson.
I've known this boy
since he was in diapers.
He's not some
master manipulator.
If he lied,
it's because he was scared.
Beside the fact that the
Singletons are your friends,
they are also major donors
to this hospital,
and there is a multimillion-
dollar relationship
at stake here.
So if the kid is gonna
get in trouble,
please, let PD be
the bad guys.
Any word from
the ethics committee?
No way.
No way they're gonna
allow this.
Because, technically,
they have both Judy
and Emma's consent,
and because testicular torsion
is a medical emergency,
the hospital feels
obligated to act.
But the assent was coerced.
Yeah, but coercion's
very difficult to prove,
and the truth is that in
the majority of these cases,
the courts do side
with the parents.
The board's worried
about a negligence suit.
What?
Oh, no. Oh.
Help. Someone, help.
Uh, what... What's...
what's wrong with her?
The testicle
must be more ischemic.
Not getting enough blood flow.
We can't wait any longer.
Prep this patient
for surgery now.
Mommy, I'm scared.
I don't want them to hurt me.
No, no, no, honey,
they won't hurt you,
I promise.
Judy, I know you love
your daughter,
and I know you're afraid of
what the future might hold,
but Emma trusts you,
she counts on you.
I just...
I don't want anything
to happen to my little girl.
She's all that I have.
You're not gonna lose her.
No matter what gender
Emma identifies with,
she's still gonna be
your child,
the same kid who loves
chocolate sundaes
and hates ballet.
She told you?
That's the exciting part.
Having our kids show us
who they are
in their own time.
Mommy?
Don't take them out.
Are you sure?
Yes, I'm sure.
Hey, Maggie,
any word from Henry's son?
I thought he was just
driving down from Wilmette.
His phone keeps on
going to voicemail.
Maybe he changed his mind
about coming.
How can he let
his father die alone?
We don't know
the whole story, April,
what went on between them.
Some things are hard
to get over.
I never should have
gotten Henry's hopes up.
I have to tell him.
I'll go with you.
Henry?
Henry...
Jackson...
Son...
Henry, I'm sorry...
I'm here.
I'm right here.
You came?
Yeah.
My boy.
The evidence is substantial,
and it's in
Carter's best interest
to come clean to the police
on his own.
A jury will look
favorably on that.
A jury?
Oh, God. No.
Sharon, I am begging you,
please do not say anything.
Lydia...
This will not bring Bo back,
and it will ruin
Carter's life.
Grace?
I had to talk to you.
When we got here,
Dr. Choi told us
what, uh, Carter did.
Grace, I...
He said when the paramedics
found the boys,
that Carter
was performing CPR on Bo.
I'm so sorry, Lydia.
I'm so sorry that Bo got
Carter into this mess.
I'm so sorry.
Hey, Will...
Thank you for earlier.
I didn't do anything.
Well, that's the point.
You just listened.
I appreciate it.
All right.
Well, I'm always here to lend
an ear any time you need.
How 'bout tonight?
Oysters at Shaw's?
Sure.
Okay.
Hey.
You know the last time
we were in a hospital room
together?
The day you were born.
You were there?
Mmm-hmm, yeah.
I was holding you
when you opened your eyes
for the first time.
You know, they say
it takes about a week
for a newborn
to focus on objects,
but I swear,
you looked right at me.
And that was it.
I was hooked.
You know, Carter,
you're my godson.
I only want
what's best for you.
And if there's anything else
you need to tell
the police, baby,
now is the time.
You...
You're gonna carry
this day with you
for the rest of your life,
and holding a secret
on top of that...
It'll be too much, baby.
It'll break you, Carter.
It'll break you.
Yes, he's hanging in.
Yeah, I'll...
Let... Let...
Let me call you back,
Miles, thanks, bye.
What is he doing here?
Carter asked to speak with
Detective Halstead again.
What did you say to him?
I'm sorry, Lydia.
You're sorry?
That was the right thing
to do, Ms. Goodwin.
Yeah, I think
that's debatable.
When the Singletons
pull their funding,
which I imagine
they're going to do,
you're gonna have to
answer to the board.
I'm prepared to do that.
Noah...
What you did in there...
You think I was wrong
for letting him think
his son was there.
No. No, I don't.
I think it was really kind.
I'm sorry I snapped
at you earlier.
No, you don't... You don't
have to apologize. That's...
No, I do. I do.
You were just being a friend.
When I said I didn't
wanna see my dad,
the truth is I don't want
to want to see him.
Does that make sense?
Um...
It's okay.
It doesn't make sense
to me either.
Night, Noah.
Night.
How's the patient?
Just waking up.
But his vitals are stable and
he's neurologically intact.
Ah.
I suppose you know
what I'm going to ask next.
It was my instrument,
Dr. Latham.
I take full responsibility.
No, it was my instrument.
My fault.
That's not true.
Yes, it is.
Ah.
My rabbi used to say,
"You are smart, smart, smart,
"but, eh, not so smart."
You both are my most
promising fellows,
but now I am no longer certain
that either of you
should be my second for
the conjoined twins surgery.
I'll be watching you both
very closely going forward.
You didn't have to do that.
I know.
I can take my lumps.
Never said you couldn't.
I guess we're both
in the doghouse now.
Plenty of room for two.
Don't worry,
you get used to it.
Builds character.
Here you are, sir.
Oh, hey.
I ordered us half a dozen
of Henderson Bay oysters.
What do you want to drink?
Uh, excuse me...
Wait, Nat...
If there's any chance
we're moving forward here,
there's something
I gotta tell you.
What is it?
Last night after work,
I grabbed a drink.
I met someone at the bar.
It was nothing.
It was just high school stuff.
High school stuff?
It didn't go beyond kissing.
Well, not much.
And I... I thought of you.
I put the brakes on.
I actually fell asleep
on her couch.
Were you thinking of me
when you went home with her?
Nat, you've been so distant
the past two weeks,
I didn't know if things
would turn around
between us...
You know, when I asked
for a break,
it was never about
wanting anyone else.
I don't want anyone else.
It meant nothing, I swear.
Nat, I'm...