- Previously
on "New Amsterdam"...
Half our karaoke party
is missing.
Elizabeth.
Mia.
- Now Trevor.
♪
- Casey.
- Ronnie,
pull the car over now.
- Why is it just
those four missing?
- It's not just four.
♪
Helen!
Helen.
Hey, hey, Helen! Helen!
Helen!
Helen.
Hey, Helen.
Talk to me.
Helen, hey!
Helen, please.
♪
Hey, help!
I found her on the floor.
It's, uh, shallow breathing.
A weak pulse.
♪
Get me a finger-stick
blood sugar stat.
- Pupils equal round reactive.
- DTR's intact bilaterally.
♪
- Hi, this is Dr. Bloom
from New Amsterdam Hospital.
I'm trying to track down
a veteran in your system.
Uh, Ronnie Cooper.
- Hi, this is Trevor.
You know what to do.
- Hi, Trevor, it's me.
Would you please call me
as soon as you get this?
I'm, uh,
I'm getting worried over here.
Okay, thank you.
Bye-bye.
- This is her bike.
Mia! Mia!
♪
All right, let's fan out.
She's out here somewhere.
♪
Uh, hello?
- Ronnie?
Ronnie Cooper, where are you?
Do you need help?
What a night.
- Is Casey with you?
- Casey?
I don't--
♪
Who is this?
- Dr. Lauren Bloom.
You were with my friend
Casey Acosta last night
and now we can't find him.
Is he--is he with you?
- Uh, no, ma'am.
We, uh...we kinda
got into it last night.
And, uh,
we almost got into an accident
and he just bounced.
Who is this again?
- Dr. Lauren Bloom
from New Amsterdam Hospital.
- Uh, yeah.
I did--I did see Casey
last night.
We, uh, we went for a drive.
- A drive where?
- Well, uh--
- What's wrong?
- Casey's missing.
I'm going out to find him.
- Out,
like out of the hospital?
Then I'm going with you.
- Okay, is there any landmarks?
Tell me where
you last were there.
- Mia! Mia!
♪
Hey, I got her.
I got her.
Damn it.
- Trauma?
- Not that I can see,
but she's hypothermic
and we gotta get her
out of here now.
♪
- Oh, my God!
- Oh.
Make sure
we're the only ones here.
- Uh, Karen, come look at this.
- Oh, my God.
- Ah-ah, just lie there.
Don't move.
I'm calling an ambulance.
- The apartment's all clear.
- Thank you.
♪
Helen.
- M--Max.
- Hey, easy.
Easy, tiger.
It hurts...
everywhere.
What happened?
- We found Thanatophol
in your blood.
Happened last night at the bar.
- My drink was spiked?
- Not just yours.
It happened to Wilder,
Trevor, Mia, Casey.
- Oh, my God.
- We're getting the word out
to everybody, but right now
you're my priority,
which means
getting you fluids and rest.
- Oh, I'd rest a lot easier
if my leg wasn't killing me.
- Which one?
The left one.
♪
That bad?
- We got more of her labs back.
Her D-dimer's high.
- So's your protein.
You're at 12 grams
per deciliter.
- What's--what's
my platelet count?
- Uh, you're down to 25,000.
- I am ripe for severe DIC.
- You could have clots
everywhere.
You need a body scan now.
Walsh, let's move.
Doing great, babe.
You're almost done.
- How's it look?
♪
Max?
Max, what do you see?
Please just--just tell me.
- Uh, you have multiple clots.
In multiple arteries.
♪
Where are they?
- Renal.
And hepatic.
- Two surgeries,
that's not too bad.
- And gastric.
♪
And ovarian.
And uterine.
♪
- So that's three more.
Including a hysterectomy.
♪
- Yeah.
- Hello?
- Trevor, hi.
Oh, my God.
- Hey, boss.
Got your messages.
- Yeah.
Yeah.
Uh, where are you?
- Baptist Hospital.
I swear to you
I'm not cheating on you, mate.
It's where
the paramedics took me.
- So I'm sure you know by now
that you were drugged
last night.
- Yeah.
- Wasn't just you though.
A bunch of us got dosed
unfortunately.
- Damn.
The last thing I recall
I was on the train home.
Good Samaritans found me
passed out like a real derro.
They called 911 and I'm here.
- And are you hurt?
Are you okay?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
I'm fine.
I promise.
Thank you for checking up
on me.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
No, of course.
I've been, you know,
I've been really worried.
Uh, mind has been racing.
Can I ask, um...
one thing?
Uh.
- Yeah?
- This is gonna sound stupid.
I have a little bit
of the old brain fog myself
from the uh, you know...
Did, uh...
did anything happen last night?
- Happen?
♪
- Yeah, happen.
You know,
anything less than professional
between you and I?
♪
- Sounds like you got it worse
than me, mate.
Nothing happened.
- Nothing?
- Some rocking karaoke,
lovely late-night
conversation.
That was it.
We parted ways.
- And, uh, that's it?
- That's it.
- Oh, well, that's good.
- Yes.
- That's good.
That's, uh, great.
I mean, all, you know,
all druggings aside.
- Yes.
- Okay, well, you rest up
and feel better.
And, uh, just let me know
when they release you, okay?
- Right-o.
- Okay.
Bye.
- Bye.
Hey, babe.
What are you--
♪
- Sameera has
her parent-teacher conference
tonight.
- Yeah. Yes, of course.
Yeah, yeah, I, um.
Yeah, I didn't forget.
I just--it's been a crazy day.
♪
I, uh...
- Core temp's 79.
- Here, grab the far end
of this warming blanket.
Hook her up
to a Level 1 rapid infuser.
She'll need Amp, Gent,
and Dranova.
- Not Dranova.
Chart says she's allergic.
Severe flushing.
- Well, make it Vancomycin.
Watch it.
♪
All right, she's okay.
All right, look, everyone,
we're gonna have
to be very careful, all right?
Just one bump could stop
her heart.
And we won't be able to restart
it until she's warmed up.
Okay?
- I'm not having
a hysterectomy.
- Your uterus could rupture.
- Yes, I know.
I know
that the clots are a problem
and that I have to do something
about them.
But I wanna try something
less invasive.
I'm gonna try
and break them up,
so can you put me on a regimen
of Platazel?
- Platazel could lead
to uncontrollable bleeding.
- As a hematologist,
I am aware of the risk.
- Yeah, and this seems like
an unnecessary one.
And surgery would mitigate
a lot of these issues.
- Yeah, and it will
permanently change my body
in dozens of ways.
I'm on your side.
- I know.
A hysterectomy.
That's gonna permanently
change my future.
It's gonna change
my personality.
And I can't help but think
of the fact
that hysterectomies,
they've been overperformed
for decades
on people who look like me.
♪
'Cause if we're talking
about risks,
well, that's feeling
pretty risky to me.
And none of that
is gonna be mitigated.
- I hear you.
I do, but we're talking
about your case.
Your body had
an extreme reaction
to the Thanatophol,
and you wanna add Platazel,
which is long-acting.
And if it doesn't work,
then we're gonna have
to rush you
into an even riskier surgery.
- Max, please.
- And I don't wanna do that.
- Please don't be my doctor.
Be my partner.
♪
- That should do it.
- Thanatophol. Oh, my God.
What is that?
It's like a roofie on steroids.
- Someone really wanted
to knock you all on your asses.
- Or kill us.
- Who would do this?
I'm calling the police.
You rest.
- I'm gonna order a CT scan
of your head.
Be right back.
♪
- Yes.
That's right, officer.
Thank you.
♪
Elizabeth?
- You think he's near here?
- This is where his idiot
friend said he left him.
Casey!
Okay, uh, let's just look
for any sign of him.
His wallet is like old,
and brown, and crappy,
and his phone is like
from 2017.
- Lauren, we'll find him, okay?
♪
- Yeah, okay.
So talk to me.
What's going on with your visa?
- You don't wanna know.
- Of course I do.
♪
- There was a glitch
in my paperwork.
And I never got any
of the notices
because I was living in my car.
And in the middle of all that,
my case officer changed.
♪
Bottom line, my refugee status
is being revoked.
And if I don't fight it,
I'll be sent back to Pakistan.
- You need to contact
Legal Aid immediately
and tell them.
- I did.
They're backed up for years.
- Pro bono programs?
- Same.
With the new laws,
I'm not the only one
this is happening to.
- Leyla, you need a lawyer.
♪
- I know.
I know, I know, but just...
♪
- How much do you need?
- $10,000.
Just for the retainer.
♪
And then
another $10,000 a month.
♪
I hate to ask you.
I don't know who else.
♪
Is that his UMI ID?
Lauren!
- Casey!
Casey, Casey.
Oh, God.
- Oh, my God.
- Oh, God.
Oh, God.
- Okay, it looks like
the screwdriver sealed up
the wound, thank God.
- Pulse is thready.
Feeling like 45 beats a minute.
- Okay, that's something.
Casey?
Casey, can you hear me?
- No, no. Just get away.
- No, no, no, no!
Damn it, damn it!
Oh, my God.
He's bleeding out.
- I need a suture.
Anything.
Anything to seal up the wound.
Okay.
I need you to stay still,
buddy.
Okay?
- Okay.
- You find anything?
- Not yet!
- What the hell happened
to you?
Mugged.
- Okay, you know
there are easier ways
to get a day off, right?
- Found something.
- Good.
- Cardboard.
Egg crate foam, and...
- A caulking gun?
- It works on tiles.
What the hell?
- Here goes nothing.
Okay.
Releasing in one, two, three.
♪
Okay.
- Okay, I just need
to get in that hole.
♪
Got it.
- Well, the bleeding's stopped.
- For now.
Call 911.
- Okay.
- You're gonna be okay.
- Come on.
Stay with me, buddy.
Come on.
♪
- Mr. Higbee says, "If you're
not early, you're late."
- Oh, Mr. Higbee sounds like
a real stickler.
- We'll make it in time, hon.
Don't worry.
- Hey, nothing happened.
Okay?
- Uh, our daughter is ten feet
in front of us.
- I know.
I'm just saying that whatever
you think you overheard
back there, it was not
what it sounded like, okay?
- No?
- No, no, no.
- 'Cause it sounded like
you hired Trevor,
the guy who hit on you
during his interview,
the guy we both agreed
you shouldn't hire.
- Okay, yeah.
That--that part is exactly
what it sounded like.
But the rest of it--
- Stop. Just stop.
- Honey, please--
- No, no, I am not gonna have
a conversation with you
about your infidelity
out on the street between here
and PS 144, so just park it.
If not for me,
then for our daughter.
- Hurry up, you slowpokes.
- Hey, coming, hon.
♪
- Hey.
We should talk.
- Yeah.
Uh.
Whew.
Where to begin?
- I don't know.
I just found out.
I've been spinning and I--
- Look, since the baby's mine,
then I think it's only right
that you and I raise the child
together.
Claude can take the job
in Denver
and, you know,
we can stay together.
- Floyd...
I'm not leaving Claude.
Right.
- I mean...
is there any way
the three of us
could raise the baby together?
- And what, I move to Denver?
Would we go to church together?
Thanksgivings?
That does sound--
- Yeah, crazy.
- Yeah.
I mean,
Claude and I could
raise the baby without--
- No, no, mm-mm.
Definitely not.
- Yeah, I didn't think so.
I just, you know,
I had to--
- Any other options?
- I mean, I could, um...
I could terminate
the pregnancy.
Then there would be nothing
tying us together.
♪
- Do you want that?
- No.
♪
This baby is a miracle.
- Then where do we go
from here?
♪
- So I just spoke to Dr. Malvo,
who told me
that the clot busting
is working.
- Yeah.
You don't seem, uh, elated.
- It's just
this isn't quite how I imagined
our first ultrasound
as a couple.
- Yeah.
Totally thought
it would be your gallbladder.
Look, I know
that we haven't discussed this,
and I don't mean
to just spring it on you--
- I wanna have a baby with you.
- I mean, who even knows
if it's possible.
Frozen eggs.
Your cancer.
- Let's not go there right now.
- My--
- Let's just live
in the possibility.
♪
Luna would love it.
Big sister, are you kidding?
- And we already have like
a million baby clothes.
- Yeah, and a crib.
Got that.
- The baby practically
pays for itself.
- Yeah, and this baby would be
a little mini-you,
so, you know,
freaking adorable.
♪
I had a whole plan.
I had a whole plan
to propose to you.
♪
- Excuse me?
- Mm-hmm.
Nice reservations
at this fancy restaurant
and a walk through
New York City
in the moonlight
and everything.
You know, I even got a ring.
♪
- Max?
- But--
Screw it.
♪
Maybe this place
is as good as any.
♪
Will you make me
the happiest man
in this whole ICU?
♪
Will you marry me?
Yes.
Yes, yes, yes.
Oh, my God.
Wait, you--you got a ring?
- Yeah, I got a ring.
I got a ring.
It's nice.
Should I get it?
- Yeah.
- I should?
I should go get it, okay.
- Yeah, yeah.
- Yeah, yeah, okay.
I'm gonna get it.
I'm getting the ring.
Yeah.
♪
- Okay, so somehow
this is now my fault?
- I'm not--no, I didn't.
I'm not saying that.
- Okay, and look, surprise.
- Say that.
- He has once again steered
the fight away
from the real issue at hand.
- The real issue?
- Yeah.
- No, the real issue,
as I see it,
is that you have
a ton of hot gay friends
and I have never once--
- What?
- Insinuated that you might be
sleeping with one of them.
But that's exactly
where you went with me.
That's the first place
your mind went.
- My friends' hotness
isn't a secret.
You and I talk about
how guys look all the time.
- Yes.
- Yet this guy has been
in your life for months,
yet you've never mentioned him
once.
- Because...
it wasn't important.
- And yet you go out with him
one night and the next morning
you're worried something
might've happened
between the two of you.
- Because--
- The roofies didn't put you
in that situation.
You did that all on your own.
- How can you--
- And that's infidelity, Iggy.
Emotional infidelity.
- Stop using that word.
I--it's banter.
It's banter, Martin.
Over coffee.
That's the extent
of our relationship.
All right?
I don't even know
the guy's last name.
Does it bring me pleasure
that this handsome guy
flirts with me?
Yeah, sure, I'm a human being.
But it's harmless.
- But it isn't harmless!
♪
- Lower your voice.
You're gonna scare the kids.
Jesus.
- You've been different
these past few weeks.
I've noticed it.
The kids have noticed it.
- No.
- You've been happier.
And I just assumed
it was you getting back
in the saddle again.
Finding joy
in this amazing life
that we've built together.
♪
I even thought...
maybe it was me.
♪
No, but the thing
that's been bringing you
all this joy
these past few weeks
is flirting with another man
at work
and then lying about it.
♪
- Martin.
That's...
Come on.
♪
- If you still think
that's nothing,
you're not just lying to me.
Excuse me.
Someone's gotta start dinner.
♪
- You're gonna be okay.
Don't do that.
You know why
you're gonna be okay?
Because I wore
a freaking taco hat for you
and that can't be
the last humiliating thing
that you make me do, okay?
- It makes me really happy
to see you and Leyla together.
- Yeah, I mean,
she's talking to me again.
Voluntarily, so...
yeah,
I feel pretty good about it.
- Wow.
If I die, you're gonna feel
really bad about lying to me.
- You are not gonna die.
My BP is 87/40.
I've lost one
and a half units of blood
and the only thing
that's keeping me
from completely
bleeding out is...
Plumber's caulk.
If I was some random patient
that got wheeled into your ED,
I don't think you'd be so sure
about how this is gonna go.
♪
Is that right?
Just level with me here.
♪
- Leyla's immigration status
is in trouble
and she has asked me for money.
- Mm-hmm.
- Like a lot.
- The good news
is you have a lot of it.
- If I give it to her,
then she'll get to stay.
But then our entire
relationship is transactional
and eventually,
she's gonna resent me for it.
- And if you don't?
- Well, then she's gonna have
to leave the country.
And I'm never gonna see her
again.
- Guess money doesn't solve
every problem.
- That would appear
to be the case.
- How many?
- Four times.
Clear.
- Four, five, six, seven.
- Okay, we're going again.
- Eight.
- Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Her body temp's 92.
Still too cold.
Look, her heart
is not going to restart
until we get her
to a normal body temp.
- That's what we've been doing.
- Well, we need fast acting.
- Five, six, seven.
- Let's get the 12 point ready.
- Give her 10ccs of Dranova.
IV push.
- Wait. No, wait.
No, no.
It--she's allergic to Dranova.
- An allergic reaction
will raise her body temp.
- Yeah, or it'll kill her.
- So will arguing with me.
Just do it.
♪
Your call, chief.
- Six, seven, eight, nine.
♪
- Hey.
Doc from last night,
what can I get you?
- Why?
- Why what?
♪
Hey!
Lady, what the hell?
- Look, look, look.
I don't know
what you're saying,
but you gotta get out of here.
Hey.
Stop! Stop!
- What?
Sto--
- Why?
- Okay, you wanna know why?
- Yeah.
♪
- You doctors.
Everybody says you're heroes.
You're no hero, okay?
I got COVID, and it was nothing
but a bad cold.
But you doctors,
you exaggerated everything.
You scared people.
You shut down businesses.
I was outta work for 18 months!
Because of you.
- You didn't lose your job,
did you?
You know what it's like to owe
a year of back rent, huh?
Huh?
- Elizabeth?
- Yeah. Yeah, I did it. I
drugged you
and I hope you suffer
the same way I suffered!
- Stop right there.
Stop right there.
Back off.
- He did it!
He...
- Elizabeth?
Elizabeth!
Elizabeth.
- Call an ambulance.
- Give me a tidal volume 700,
respiratory rate 12.
- Lyn, what happened?
- And five PEEP.
One of the clots broke free
and is lodged in her lung.
We need to do an embolectomy
now or she's going to die.
All right, it's working.
Body temp's at 95.3.
- She's in full anaphylactic
shock, Dr. Reynolds.
We need to reverse
the allergic reaction now.
- She's not warm enough for us
to shock her heart yet.
- Her airways are closing.
Here, I'm reversing it.
- No, she's at 96.7, all right?
She's getting there, Walsh.
All right, she's getting there.
- O sats are tanking.
- 98.
- This is killing her.
- Come on.
Come on, Mia.
- 99.
- Now!
Paddles.
Clear.
♪
I'm going again.
Clear.
♪
Got a pulse.
EpiPen.
Give her the EpiPen!
What are you waiting on?
♪
Airways clearing.
- O2 sats are rising.
She's gonna make it.
How 'bout you?
- Caulk?
- Yeah, seemed better than
a hammer and nails.
Jeez,
no one in this department
got a sense of humor?
- And looks like
the carotid artery's intact.
- That's a relief.
♪
- I'm so sorry.
I swear I'm not trying to take
advantage of your feelings or--
- I would never think
that about you.
♪
Things between us
are complicated.
Over.
♪
But I'm in awe of you.
Starting out in a new country.
Never backing down.
Even when faced with obstacles
that would probably break me.
♪
I love you.
And not just in the way that
I know that I need to get over.
♪
I love you as a person.
And I wanna do whatever I can
to help you be that person.
♪
I'll give you whatever money
you need.
♪
Thank you, Lauren.
Thank you so much.
Thank you.
- Advancing
the embolectomy catheter
through the subclavian artery.
♪
Headed for the right atrium.
- Oxygenation's falling.
You gotta get the clot
out of her lungs.
- And smoothly through
the tricuspid valve.
- Careful, careful.
You're touching the wall
of the right ventricle.
- I'm pulling back.
- No, push through.
The only way to get
to that clot is to push through
the heart.
- If I advance any further,
she could have
a cardiac arrest.
- If you don't
get that clot out,
she's not gonna make it.
If her heart stops,
I'll restart it.
- You'll only have
a few seconds.
♪
- I know. I'm ready.
I'm not gonna lose her.
- Advancing catheter.
♪
- It's all right.
Just a few irregular beats.
You got it.
♪
- Made it.
I'm at the clot.
Activating embolectomy.
Okay, got it.
- Oxygenation is stabilizing.
That's...
that's great, Lyn.
- Now comes the hard part.
The catheter's gotta go out
the way it came.
Ready?
- Yeah.
- Out of the lung.
Approaching the heart.
And through the pulmonic valve.
- V-fib arrest.
♪
Normal pulse.
Good rhythm.
- And the catheter?
- It's out.
That was close.
- She made it.
She's gonna be okay.
- Thank you, Lyn.
♪
- Mm.
Hi.
- Hi.
Surgeon says
you're gonna be fine.
Be out of here in no time.
- But, uh, going back
and confronting the bartender
all by yourself...
is not one of your best ideas.
- When did everything change?
- What?
- Do you remember
the--the parades?
- Celebrating
healthcare workers.
Spontaneous applause throughout
the city every night.
- And now.
The hospital is full
of unvaccinated people
who hate us.
♪
We've become the enemy.
- For trying.
- For trying to help.
- I know.
♪
- I used to wear my scrubs
home from work.
♪
Now before I walk home,
I put on regular clothes.
I don't want people to know
that I'm a doctor.
- Because...
♪
- Because I'm afraid
that I will be attacked.
♪
- How can I...
- How can I--can I have hope
in a world like this?
- I'm sorry, kid.
But you're the hope.
It's just you.
That's all you got.
♪
- I heard
you saved Helen's life.
- I heard you saved Mia's.
You know, my, uh...
dad wasn't around much.
My mom raised me and...
Believe me,
she's a force, but...
somehow it was my dad
who made me who I am
through his absence.
You know?
And because of that,
I so want to be a father.
A good father.
I mean, it's shaped...
everything I am.
Everything I've done.
So there's no way I could
abandon my own child.
But if that child
had you and Claude...
I wouldn't be abandoning
that child at all.
♪
'Cause they would have
a wonderful mother.
♪
And a wonderful father.
And be raised in a home
filled with joy and love.
♪
- Floyd, are you saying--
- I just ask
that when the time is right...
♪
I get to tell our child
who I am.
♪
I get to be in their life.
'Cause I just--
I just want them to know
that we were united in love.
♪
Trying to make something
bigger and better
than our parents did.
♪
It didn't work out for us.
But look what did work.
A little miracle.
♪
Just like you said.
- ♪ And the sleep is faster
than the daylight ♪
♪ And the daylight's faster
than the night ♪
♪ Every time I go towards
my pillow and close my eyes ♪
♪ That's the way
I say goodnight ♪
♪ And your feet move faster
than the moonlight ♪
♪ And the moonlight takes
another night ♪
♪ As the cool night breathes
♪ And forms a ribbon
towards my eyes ♪
♪ As the last frontier
casts away ♪
♪ These things of the night
♪
♪ All the things we tried
to make right ♪
♪ Should we stay
or should we go? ♪
♪
♪ Drifting in a sea
of gray glass ♪
♪ Am I asleep
or am I woke now? ♪
♪ Can you show me how
to breathe in the night? ♪
♪ So we can breathe alight
There she is.
♪
Hey.
They got the clots.
♪
They got all of them.
Now that that is out
of the way,
I, um...
I got you this.
♪
I had it made just for you.
- ♪ So let's take that back
- Mm.
- ♪ Sleep
- Hm.
- What?
Hm.
- What is it?
S-s-s-speak.
C-c-c-can't...
C-c-c...
C-c-can't...
♪
Hey.
- It's okay.
It's okay, it's okay.
Hey!
♪