Previously on "ER."
‐ What happened?
‐ Her husband freaked out.
'Called 9‐1‐1,
but wouldn't let us in.'
She was bleeding
all over the place.
All this time
I'm worrying about HIV
and I get hepatitis "C"?
My wife,
is she dead?
‐ Kerry, can you get Mark?
‐ Sure, I can do that.
And security.
I'm going to resign.
You want him to go?
I love him
like a brother
but I can't do this anymore.
It's too hard.
I can't rem‐remember a time
when I didn't love him.
You're not coming
with me, are you?
I tell you, you got to love
this night shift.
‐ No, you don't.
‐ How's your ride‐along?
It has been wild. First,
we had these two old guys
swimming naked in the lake,
nearly froze their, uh..
Okay, thank you,
we get it.
We got this crazy lady
out in the rig.
‐ Oh, yeah?
‐ Yeah. Bring your coat.
Tried to eat the lovebirds
at the Delaware Hotel.
You're right.
She's crazy.
Acutely psychotic.
She's combative.
She locked herself in.
We'll try a little Haldol
before we call for
the bolt cutters.
One, two, three.
Ah, what does she think
she's some kind of hawk?
Hawks attack with their claws,
Jerry, not their teeth.
‐ Why is she staring at me.
‐ Maybe she likes you.
You're threatening her
with your gaze.
‐ Look away. Look away.
‐ I‐I'm looking away. Fine.
'...and you're looking
at it right now'
'on Nicole's lovely wrist.
It's a winner.'
'It's a knockout.
It really is.'
'It's a bracelet
that is memorable.'
'It's a bracelet you'll want
to wear every single day.'
'It's wide, it's bold,
it's beautiful'
'and you know what else?
It's reversible.'
'How hard would it be for you to
flip that over for me, Nicole?'
'Watch the other side.
Gorgeous.'
'Matte gold
on the other side.'
'This beautiful, soft,
satiny matte gold finish'
'on the other side
and, then, a high‐polished'
'glam look
on the front side..'
What do you mean, you want me
to wait for Jerry?
I mean, he likes
this kind of stuff.
What stuff?
These strange dudes
in the middle of the night.
They're called patients,
Malik, and I'm not waiting.
‐ Mr. Kornberg, hi.
‐ Hi.
‐ I'm, uh, Dr. Weaver.
‐ Nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you.
Here you go.
He twisted his
knee wrestling.
Huh, at 3:00
in the morning?
No, in last night's match.
Wasn't so bad
till I got up to pee.
Then it really
started hurting.
Okay, let's take a look.
How'd you do it,
flying dropkick?
Jackknife power bomb.
I thought you guys
never really got hurt.
‐ What's that supposed to mean?
‐ Malik..
Now, come on, man, everybody
know pro wrestling's fake.
‐ Who are you calling fake?
‐ Malik, I think that's enough.
You, man,
it's all rehearsed.
You and your boys
are a bunch of fakes.
Is that right, yeah?
I'll show you fake.
‐ Hey, man!
Hey, hey, hey,
hey, hey, hey!
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
Mr. Kornberg, I said
put him down right now!
Call security!
I need some help here.
'Malik, are you alright?'
I got you good.
Oh, man.
I wish Jerry
could've seen this.
Sorry.
Now, he really wanted
to do that.
Sit down.
‐ What happened to her son?
‐ He and his wife just left.
They said they'd only
be a few minutes.
Well, they picked a great time.
Mrs. Fong, don't worry.
You're fine.
We're taking you back
to your room now, okay?
Is everything alright?
Yes, everything's fine.
Did my mother
have another seizure?
She doesn't remember we
told her we were leaving.
She's fine. She just got
back from her head CT.
If you don't mind, it would
be best if you stay close.
I don't speak Chinese
and it's difficult
to find an interpreter
at 4:30 in the morning.
‐ We needed to get the po chai.
‐ The po chai what?
To settle her stomach.
Oh, I don't think she
should take that right now.
It's only herbs
that make her feel better.
If you don't mind,
I would rather wait
until all the test
results come back
before giving
her anything.
'How's she doing?'
Haldol's kicked in
and maintenance is here
to cut open the cage. Psych
should be down in a few minutes.
Yo, John, got to go.
Okay. Hey, we're sorry
to dump her on you.
Hey, that's our job.
Carter, you wouldn't be stealing
those supplies, would you?
‐ Of course not.
‐ Thank you, Yosh.
Didn't think so.
Malik..
Ah, Dr. Weaver.
Yeah, about Mr. Kornberg..
Yeah, look, I asked him first.
He could've said no.
Look, a patient comes in
with a bad knee
and you want him
to do tricks?
Yeah, but that's
what these guys do.
And Kornberg's a major
contender. He's the man.
Okay, everybody,
let's break it up.
Hey, uh, let me
get one for my mom.
‐ Okay.
‐ 'Here we go. One more.'
'Jerry.'
Uh, okay, everybody,
that's it for now.
‐ No, that's it, period.
‐ You're looking good, man.
Hey, you ready
to take on the hybrid?
‐ Oh, yeah.
‐ Malik..
...I think I can handle this
on my own, thank you.
Sure.
Mr. Kornberg, I'm sorry
about all this attention.
That's okay.
I'm used to it.
Okay, you have some bleeding
inside the knee.
So, I'm going to numb it
and tap the joint.
That should decrease
some of the pain.
I've had that
done before.
Oh, this isn't
your first injury?
You name it,
I broke it.
That sounds like
a rough sport.
Living on the road
200 nights a year
and getting mobbed by
40,000 screaming fans..
...that's what's rough.
Oh, I've only surfed by
on cable, but it..
You know, it seems like
a profession for showoffs.
You don't...you don't like
the celebrity, huh?
Well, just give them
what they want.
What would you
rather do?
You'd laugh
if I told you.
I will try not to.
I'd like to move
to Montana..
Lots of land,
peace and quiet.
Oh, really?
You'd raise cattle?
Nah, I'd like to have
a farm...grow sugar beets.
‐ Really.
‐ Go ahead and laugh.
I'm‐I'm not going
to laugh.
That's okay. I do.
Okay..
There.
Does that feel better?
‐ Oh, yeah.
‐ Good.
'You going to wake Maloney?'
Not at this hour.
He only gets up
for admissions
and code blues.
Want me to
talk to them?
No, I can do it.
Um, Mr. and Mrs. Fong, I'm
afraid I have some bad news.
Emily, why don't you go inside
and keep your
grandmother company?
‐ In a minute.
‐ It'd be better if you..
It's okay, dad.
Yes, Miss Knight?
Uh, your mother has
a tumor in her lung
and it has spread
to her brain.
That's what caused
the seizures.
It's cancer at a
very advanced stage.
Oh, my God!
I know this news is
difficult to take in.
We've known about
the cancer for a year.
‐ Why didn't you tell me?
‐ You were away, at school.
You couldn't call?
Uh, maybe if you take some time
to discuss this..
We did not want
to upset you.
Well, this is worse,
not even knowing.
Why don't I let you talk
about this and I will come back
and review the results
with your mother, okay?
That won't be necessary.
My mother does not know
about the cancer.
'You haven't told her?'
We're not going
to tell her.
She should be seeing
an oncologist
and getting treatment.
I don't understand
why you're doing this.
This news
will only depress her.
'She will die sooner
for knowing.'
Radiation therapy can
improve the quality
of her life and
stop the seizures
but she has
to be informed.
We are not telling her
and we do not want
you to tell her.
You're right,
Miss Knight.
You do not understand.
Can't talk to them
when they're like this.
‐ Like what?
‐ Traditional.
I guess that's
the polite word.
What's her prognosis?
It's a stage‐four cancer.
What does that mean?
She probably has a few months.
Wish they told me.
I could've spent
more time with her.
You said something
about treatment.
'Well, she could have
radiation therapy'
'and maybe chemo,
but I don't know'
how we'd treat her
if we can't tell her.
They think if she hears
about the cancer
she'll lose
her will to live.
And what do you think?
You think she'd want to know?
I think she's a tough lady.
She'd want to fight this.
'Malik, what do you got?'
Mr. Kingsley started
vomiting at 2:00 a. m.
I ate the steak
tartare at Fletcher's.
Never again.
‐ Steak what?
‐ Raw beef, raw egg yolk.
Start him on five of Compazine,
a liter of saline.
Is that who I
think it is?
‐ What, you know Kornberg, man?
‐ Know him?
He's the best
since Freddie Blassie.
Wait a minute.
Freddie, who?
He used to bite the hell out
of his opponents' foreheads..
...in the '60s.
Oh, you're too young.
Jerry, I thought I told you
to leave
Mr. Kornberg alone.
‐ It's okay.
‐ No, it's not.
You know, I'm taking him
up to radiology.
Well, what happened
to transport?
They were backed up, so I
thought I'd lend them a hand.
Hey, dude, remember that one
pay‐per‐view when Jericho
messed up your shoulder and you
went down for a two count?
Yeah.
Yeah, but you had to come back
with the jackhammer
slide slam, right?
‐ That's right.
‐ Kornberg's the bomb.
Jerry..
Okay, okay, come on, dude.
Malik..
Hey, how come you never
wrestled tag‐team, man?
You and Stinger
would be unbeatable.
'He's got that corner drop
that's like..'
I called the floor.
Bed'll be ready at 7:00.
Okay, thanks.
Mrs. Fong,
who do you want
to make decisions
about your health?
She says to talk
to my father.
I don't know maybe
we shouldn't do this.
If there is any news about
your condition, good or bad
who do you want
us to talk to?
She says a year ago
my father told her
she had tuberculosis.
They must've told her that
instead of telling her
she had cancer.
Cancer?
'Repeat‐‐'
Unit 47 requesting police backup
3800 block of Drexel.
Sons of bitches, they threatened
to burn down my building!
Settle down, Mr. Leonelli.
Hold that to your head.
Yeah and we still might.
It's the only way we keep warm.
Why don't you have
a seat up here?
Why didn't you call the cops?
Because they'd haul
his ass off to jail.
Landlords can't pull that kinda
crap and get away with it.
Shut up, Felonia! You haven't
paid your rent in two months.
‐ C'mon. Take the other side.
‐ I got it.
You still can't turn
the heat up, man.
My grandmother's upstairs
freezing to death.
‐ Get a job, you dumb ass.
‐ You're the dumb ass.
Hey, back off!
Let's get him out of here.
‐ They could have killed me.
‐ I mean, look at this.
Turn the heat on, man.
Pay your rent,
I'll turn it on.
Hey, hey!
Throw your beer bottles
at me now.
Take it easy, everybody.
This isn't helping anything.
Get back!
‐ Dwight, you okay?
‐ Yeah, I got blood in my eyes.
Get the hell out of here.
They're a bunch of animals.
Is Lars trying
to be a diplomat?
'Just back up a step.
Son of a bitch!'
Get me out of here.
‐ When did it start, Lily?
‐ About two minutes ago.
'Somebody help her.'
‐ I've got more Ativan.
‐ Push another two.
‐ Lucy, protect the air wave.
‐ Do something, please.
‐ Dilantin's onboard.
‐ Load it with a gram.
You did this.
You upset her.
What's he talking
about, Lucy?
You told her about the cancer.
She said you did.
'And look what it's done.'
‐ 'How's the pulse ox?'
‐ 96.
We asked you not to,
but you wouldn't listen.
This is your fault.
All your fault.
'Out of the way!'
Dispatch from RA‐47,
still waiting for police backup.
Give me the keys.
Let's get out of here.
‐ Now you're talking.
‐ Lars okay?
I don't know.
Yeah, he's alright. He's just
having trouble getting through.
They don't want him,
they want you.
‐ How do you work the PA?
‐ Bottom button.
Everybody stand away
from the vehicle.
'We're coming through.'
Step back from the vehicle.
Stand back!
We're coming through.
Get off the car!
'Everybody, please stand back.'
Get away from the rig.
Coming through, nice and easy.
'Stop! Stop!'
'What was that?'
I don't know.
I think we ran over something.
‐ It must've been the curb.
‐ Look out the back.
Give me some room.
There's a guy down.
Lars is with him.
‐ Oh, God! Did I run him over?
‐ I don't know.
‐ We got to stop.
‐ No way. We gotta go.
‐ Go, Carter, go.
‐ We got to pick him up.
They'll finish this guy
off first. Drive, Carter!
Oh, God.
'This is unit 47 requesting
second paramedic unit
3800 block of Drexel.
A man is down.
Ambulance versus pedestrian.
Oh, God.
‐ Morning!
‐ Hey, Mark.
Another headache?
Same as yesterday.
Mmm. Did it ever go away?
In the afternoon.
Like I said yesterday,
you should let me do a CT.
I don't need
a head CT, Mark.
Well, at least let me
do a neuro exam.
Mark, you have to stop
thinking like a doctor.
We both know what's
causing these headaches.
How's your insomnia?
It's gone.
Did you talk to him?
No. We both thought
it was better
not calling for
a while, you know?
Give it some time.
You know, you don't need
me to tell you this
but it's okay for
you to miss him.
Hell, I miss him.
I know. I'm okay,
though, you know?
I‐I actually like
coming to work.
Really? Now I am worried
about you.
Move over.
These guys saved my ass. They
really did. It was a great job.
If you'd turned on the heat,
we wouldn't have had to.
'Dr. Carter.'
He's got no neuro deficits.
‐ Just that head lac.
‐ What happened?
Mr. Leonelli decided to
instigate a little civil unrest.
Your typical "angry mob"
kind of thing.
They started it, not me.
Dispatch, can you tell me
what unit was sent
to 38th and Drexel?
They still on‐scene?
What's their ETA?
‐ Here. You should change that.
‐ Oh, thanks.
Okay, follow my finger with
your eyes. Here we go. Good.
This time's going to teach
them a lesson, isn't it?
The lesson, Mr. Leonelli, is you
need to figure out a better way
of dealing with
your tenants.
Carter, outside.
What do you know
about my business?
They don't pay their rent.
They leave the place a mess!
So turning off the heat.
That's the way to solve that?
Carter, I said
outside, now.
There seems to be a problem
with this patient.
‐ He'll be fine.
‐ Well, then.
the problem's with you.
So why don't you go
cool off and I'll
finish him up? Go on.
‐ Will she wake up?
‐ It's hard to say.
And if she does will there
be permanent damage?
After a prolonged
seizure there could be
some confusion
or memory loss.
She could have
had a stroke.
Uh, I want to talk
to a more senior physician.
I'm not happy
with her care.
'Everything was done
properly, Mr. Fong.'
A medicine attending will
see her when she's upstairs
and we'll check back
in a while.
'It was a championship
tag team match.'
This giant of a guy
twirls him around
then suddenly he stops..
...picks him up,
threw him down..
I took Mr. Leonelli
to X‐ray.
He'll be there
for a while.
Eh, thanks.
Thanks, Yosh.
Good morning.
Always a pleasure
to welcome the day shift.
Hey, Jerry,
what's with the boxes?
They're for pedes.
Well, why aren't they
in the pedes room?
Well, they're addressed to
Dr. Ross, so I'm not sure
if I'm supposed to keep them
or forward 'em
or send them
somewhere else.
Jerry, we're still
seeing kids just like
we did before
we had a pedes attending.
Come on, Jerry.
Help me with the boxes.
So, Kerry, how was
the graveyard shift?
Well, it was
fairly typical.
Just a few "strange dudes"
as Malik would say‐‐
Including Dr. Carter.
Oh, I thought he was
on a ride‐along.
He was.
Dr. Carter, we were
talking about you.
‐ Did you settle down?
‐ Yeah.
Well, Mr. Leonelli's
back in X‐ray
if you want to tell him
that you're sorry..
I got a bigger problem.
We got an MVA coming in.
Ambulance versus pedestrian,
and we were the ambulance.
Just, uh, set them
down here?
Yeah.
Anywhere's fine.
‐ Thanks, Jer.
‐ Sure.
Avery Campbell, 17,
crushed pelvis.
BP, 70 at the scene,
up to 80 with two liters.
‐ Lars, are you okay?
‐ Yeah. I'm fine.
They weren't mad at me.
‐ This guy needs an airway.
‐ Okay.
One of pavulon,
two of versed, 100 of sux.
Number eight ET tube.
CBC, type and cross
for eight.
Chem 20. Let's get
a portable chest.
AP pelvis in prep
for a central line.
BP 75 palp,
pulse ox 88.
‐ Two units of O‐neg.
‐ What do we got?
'Ambulance ran over
this guy's pelvis.'
Hope you weren't
driving, Doris.
No. It was me.
And you're not
supposed to drive.
I know that. Are you in?
'Yeah, I'm in.
Bag him.'
Where were the paramedics?
I got trapped outside
in the crowd.
How's the airway?
Good breath sounds.
What about Zadro?
He was bleeding. Couldn't see.
‐ Blood at the meatus.
‐ Damn it!
'Could have torn his urethra.'
I'll prep for
a retrograde urethrogram.
I'll need a supraumbilical
peritoneal lavage.
‐ Why didn't you call the cops?
‐ We did.
Why didn't you
wait for them?
Can we talk
about this later. Come on.
Will you hook this up
to the rapid infuser?
I need betadine
sterile gloves and a Foley.
Come on!
‐ Hey, Jeanie.
‐ Good morning.
‐ Getting settled back in?
‐ Yeah. I'm doing okay.
Any side effects
from the interferon?
‐ No.
‐ Good.
You know, maybe you should do
fast track today..
'sore throats,
sprained ankles. Easy stuff.'
I think I'll stick
with triage and paperwork.
Okay. Uh, Jeanie..
...Al called here
last night.
‐ Did you speak to him?
‐ Yeah.
He was upset about
the message that you left him.
‐ He couldn't reach you, so..
‐ Yeah.
Well, thanks, Kerry,
but I can handle this.
I know. It's just that
he sounded concerned.
Right. Well, I've had
every conversation with Al
I'll ever need to have.
I find out on top
of everything else
that he's given me
hepatitis "C"
so there's really nothing
else to talk about.
I got to cover
a meeting for Romano
but do you want
to grab a bite to eat later?
No, thanks. I'm having
lunch with a friend.
Okay. Sure.
Got a ruptured bladder
and an open book fracture.
‐ Lavage is negative.
‐ Pressure's up to 95.
Let's get him
to angio.
‐ Good work, Carter.
‐ Not out of the woods yet.
I'll track down
urology and ortho
let them know
what's going on.
His dad's outside.
Wants to talk to someone.
I should do that.
I don't think
that's a good idea.
Well, I was there.
Oh, right, I did it.
Exactly.
Still, it's
my responsibility.
Alright, but remember, you're
this kid's doctor first. Okay?
Only talk to the father
about his medical condition.
Oh, Carter, I want you
and Zadro and Audia to find me
and fill me in on exactly
what happened, okay.
That way, I can defend
your actions to the police
the hospital administration,
fire department
and the media, if necessary.
Does that make sense?
Mr. Campbell?
‐ My God. Is he alright?
‐ I'm Dr. Carter.
Mr. Campbell, Avery's
got a broken pelvis
and some
internal bleeding.
Does that mean
you have to operate?
No. Not
necessarily.
A radiologist will
use a catheter
to stop the bleeding
in his pelvic arteries.
'Hey, Avery..'
Um, how long
does that take?
About an hour or so.
They said an ambulance
ran him over. Is that right?
Uh, uh,
I believe so.
Yeah, but I mean, how could
that happen, huh?
As I say,
we'll know more about
his condition
in about an hour.
Sorry, I don't
mean to bug you but
I sure as hell am
going to bug somebody
because somebody here's going
to have to pay for that.
Thank you very much,
doctor, okay.
Looks good, Debbie.
Any pain?
It's been
kind of throbbing.
I had a lot
of trouble sleeping.
That shouldn't
last for long.
Will it be gone
by tonight?
I mean, a lot of trouble.
We'll give
you something.
Jeanie, let's write her
for a few vicodin
and I'll see you
in the office in two days.
‐ Do I keep the splint on?
‐ Yeah.
You have to
let the tendon heal.
Uh, where's my
prescription pad?
‐ Did you drop it?
‐ I hate when this happens.
Carol, how's your headache?
‐ Oh, not bad.
‐ Yeah? Still there?
Mark, you have to stop treating
me like I have a brain tumor.
Okay. Okay.
Jerry, who is that
big guy over there
in curtain area two?
He looks familiar.
Yeah, no kidding he looks
familiar. It's Kornberg.
Oh, right, that's
who it is.
I hate to be such a girl,
but who's Kornberg?
Used to be a defensive end
for the Denver Broncos.
If anybody needs me,
I'm in the suture room.
Obviously, Dr. Greene
is not a wrestling fan.
What?
Jerry, would you hand me
a pen, please?
‐ Sure.
‐ Thank you.
Pharmacy's on
the second floor.
‐ Here you go.
‐ Thank you.
So, uh, did you get my message
about Saturday night?
Yeah. I've been
meaning to call.
I'm afraid
I can't make it.
Really? I have reservations
at Charlie Trotter's.
That sounds great,
but I can't.
Let's do it Sunday,
if that's better.
Actually, you know, Graham,
I need to tell you something.
I feel really
awkward because
I should have
been more up front..
...from the get
go, but, uh..
...I'm seeing
someone else.
Oh.
‐ Right.
‐ I'm sorry.
I'll see you
around, then.
Yeah.
'Hello. Can we help you?'
Does this thing even work?
‐ Yeah. Used to.
‐ Jerry, what did you do?
I didn't do anything. It's
the alarm inside the bathroom.
‐ Hello.
‐ Which bathroom?
‐ Trauma hallway.
‐ Intercom doesn't seem to work.
Oh, my God. I sent Mr. Kingsley
in there for a stool sample.
‐ Have you seen Mr. Kingsley?
‐ He wasn't feeling so well.
It's probably just
a false alarm, right?
Mr. Kingsley!
Mr. Kingsley,
are you alright?
Let me see.
‐ It's definitely locked.
‐ Where's the key?
‐ What? I'm supposed to have it?
‐ Call security!
He may have vaso‐vagalled
and passed out.
‐ He could have had an MI.
‐ Might be dead.
Jerry!
Mr. Kingsley!
We need to get this door
open right now.
Excuse me.
Stand back.
'Mr. Kornberg'
Mr. Kingsley?
Lydia, get a gurney!
‐ Dude, that was awesome.
‐ Mr. Kornberg, are you alright?
Yeah.
‐ Make it two gurneys.
‐ Right.
Man, all the good stuff
happens on the night shift.
Hm. This photo's
going to be framed
and put up
on the mantelpiece.
The unbeatable tag team
of Markovic and Kornberg.
‐ Excuse me.
‐ Oh, I don't think so, Jer.
What are you talking about?
I could have been a contender.
I'm the transport,
county jail.
I'm looking for
Dr. Mark Greene.
I've got an inmate
he's treated before.
‐ Mobilaje Ekabo.
‐ Mobalage.
Hasn't been eating or drinking.
I need to get him checked out.
He's dehydrated. We need
to get him on IV fluids.
Randi, get Mark Greene.
Hey, Carter, is this the kid?
How's he doing?
Yeah. No, he's..hang
one second.
Mr. Leonelli?
I just want
to apologize.
I think in all
the excitement earlier
I got a little heated
and I didn't mean
to take it out on you.
Kid, I got thicker
skin than that.
It'll be a hell of
a sorry day when I let some
sweet faced, do‐gooder
baby doc get to me.
Right. So you're
feeling better?
Feeling great.
Going to have a nice, big
scar to show the judge
when I take these freeloading
bastards to court.
‐ 'How's Avery doing?'
‐ Taking him up to the OR.
But he's doing much better.
They embolized the bleeders
and his pressure's
up to 120.
‐ What about his spine?
‐ No lumbar fractures.
He started moving his legs
in radiology.
‐ So he's going to make it?
‐ Oh, yeah.
He'll be up and around
in a couple of months.
‐ Thank God. Excellent.
‐ Nice work, Carter.
We needed a good
outcome on this one.
Dr. Greene?
Carol is looking for you.
Alright.
Why did you
even try that?
When you're my size,
it's kind of expected.
You like signing
autographs, huh?
Yeah. Don't hurt
anybody's feelings.
Keep everyone happy.
Even if it doesn't
make you happy?
Never thought
about it.
Growing up,
I was the big guy.
Coaches wanted me to play
football and wrestle.
Friends asked me
to help them move.
I can't tell you how many times
I played Santa Claus.
So, you do.
‐ Has he said anything?
‐ Nothing.
Sheriff said
he hasn't spoken
since his first
day in jail.
‐ Can you undo that, please?
‐ 'Sure.'
'Hi, Mobalage.'
How you doing?
Listen, you're dehydrated
and we need your permission
to give you intravenous fluids.
Do you have
any objections?
Has anyone filled you
in on Kubby?
She's upstairs
in the intensive care unit.
The surgery went well,
but she's in a coma.
However, there's
a very good chance
that she'll wake up.
You're gonna feel
a little needle stick now.
'I've seen how much you
love your wife, Mobalage.'
I know you didn't
intend to hurt her.
'I believe that your response
was out of your control.'
All we want to do
is help you.
Do you understand?
'My father didn't
want me to get you.'
'My grandmother woke up,
but she's very confused.'
The fact that she's
conscious is a good sign.
she doesn't even remember
coming to the hospital.
Well, there's been
some memory loss.
Tell her she had a seizure.
I want another doctor.
Mr. Fong..
...I'm just trying
to help your mother.
All I'm asking you to do
is to tell her
that she had a seizure.
She wants to know why.
What you've experienced
is fairly common
so you don't need
to worry.
You had a seizure because
you have a condition
called epilepsy..
...but you're
going to be fine.
Thank you, doctor.
ER.
Jeanie, you got a call
on line three. Some pharmacy.
‐ Okay.
‐ Hi.
Thanks. Hi.
How can it be
this cold in March?
Yeah.
I've got a phone call.
Oh, that's okay. I'm just
doing a report on a DUI
I brought in earlier.
I'll catch you later.
‐ Okay.
‐ Alright.
This is Jeanie Boulet.
Yeah, it was a prescription
for, uh, Debbie Anderson.
She was in here earlier
with a hand laceration.
No. It's for
four tablets, not 40.
Can you fax it over?
Okay. Just send her back here.
We'll take care of it.
Thank you.
Randi, let me know
when a fax comes in
from Blue Hills Pharmacy.
Elizabeth, I was just about
to try calling you.
‐ About Kubby Ekabo?
‐ How'd you know?
I heard her
husband came in.
She's had some
spontaneous eye opening.
‐ That is a good sign.
‐ Yep. How's he doing?
Let's just say
I don't feel so bad
having insomnia
and headaches.
You're having
headaches?
You know, I thought of another
reason you'd be having those.
‐ Mark's trying to cure me.
‐ Carbon monoxide poisoning.
‐ You have an old house?
‐ Yes, she does.
‐ Maybe a faulty furnace.
‐ Not venting the exhaust.
‐ You wake up with them?
‐ Yes, she does.
Could be that, then.
We...we should get
a carboxyhemoglobin.
‐ Who's on for trauma?
‐ I am.
‐ If you need me.
‐ 12‐year‐old, ten‐foot fall.
‐ Five minutes out.
‐ I'm going to need you.
Excuse me? Sir?
Excuse me.
I, I'm going to have
to ask you
to leave
Mr. Kornberg alone.
I am Mr. Kornberg.
‐ Senior.
‐ Hey, doc, this is my dad.
‐ How do you do?
And his biggest fan.
Thank you, doctor for taking
wonderful care of my boy
except we'll want his trainer
to look at that hand.
Dad, really, I'm fine.
You know, I'm so sorry
about what happened.
Nonsense.
My son performed a mitzvah.
Uh, an act of virtue.
You wouldn't believe what a
publicist can do with that.
Uh, by the way, do you
have, uh, a children's ward?
'Yes. Upstairs.'
Good. We're going.
‐ Excuse me?
‐ Visit the sick kids.
No. I'm sorry, he needs,
he needs to rest.
He can't shake hands with
a few unfortunate children?
Bring a little joy
into their lives?
For millions,
my son is a hero.
Marci Canchola. Fell from
a second story balcony
right onto a wrought iron fence.
Fire department cut it away.
She's got good vitals,
but no room to intubate.
Okay, everybody,
let's do this nice and gentle.
Ready, and go.
I need suction.
Don't worry, Marci, we're going
to take good care of you.
Parents are on the way,
in hysterics.
Okay, I need
a full trauma panel.
Type and cross for four.
I can't get
a laryngoscope in here.
There's no room for a crike.
Get a fiber optic scope
and a number six ET tube.
‐ Pulse ox is 92.
‐ Oxygen up to 15 liters.
BP's 100 palp.
Pulse 120.
Okay.
High on the suction.
Pulse ox down to 87.
Hurry up, Mark.
Uh, I can't see.
No, I can't see a thing.
There's too much blood.
I'll be right back.
Prep the neck.
I need suction.
I can't see the cords.
'Pulse ox is still falling.'
'BP's down to 70 palp.'
I've got a pediatric needle
crike kit. Doug ordered them.
‐ Bar's in the way.
‐ Try and get the needle in.
'She's throwing PVCs.
Pulse ox is 85.'
Aspirate air. Make sure
you're in the trachea.
Now it's just the Seldinger
technique with a guide wire.
Okay.
‐ Tube, please?
‐ Right here.
Get ready to bag her.
Okay..
...that's pretty nifty.
‐ Good breath sounds.
‐ Pulse ox is up to 89.
Dr. Corday,
they need you in the sicu.
Okay, we can take it
from here.
Okay.
Good thing those supplies
came in today, huh?
Yeah. Looks like Doug
just saved another kid.
Actually, Carol,
I'd say you did.
You want me
to arrest her?
Well, she forged
the prescription.
Changed "four" to "40,"
F‐O‐U‐R‐T‐Y.
That's fraud,
violation of DEA laws.
Okay, okay. If I arrest her
you're gonna have to come down
to the station
and file a report..
...spend two days in court
waiting to testify..
...then watch the judge
throw the case out of court
because it's probably
a first offense.
‐ Great. Arrest her.
‐ My advice?
Write a new
script for five pills.
She can't change
that to "50"
she's happy, and you
can have lunch with me.
I can't have
lunch with you.
‐ Then dinner.
‐ I can't.
You're not going to take
this out on me, are you?
No, Reggie. It's just..
..you know, I need
to tell you something.
I haven't been
completely honest with you.
No time like the present.
I'm seeing someone else.
I thought we had
something going here.
I know, and I'm sorry.
It's just...it just
isn't going to work out.
I need to get back
to work.
Can we at least talk
about this later?
I don't think so.
I'm going to call you.
'County, this is Zadro
of rescue 47.'
'My partner's been shot.'
47, what are the vital signs?
'I can't get them.
It's bad. He's unconscious.'
Hey, Zadro, this is Carter.
What happened?
'We got ambushed.
They shot Lars.'
Shot him? Shot him where?
Where are his wounds?
'I can't tell.
There's blood everywhere.'
Alright, well,
just get here, get here.
Lungs sound good.
Hi, Kubby.
How you feeling?
Dr. Greene.
Where is my husband?
Kubby, you were stabbed
and you've been in a coma.
I don't think Mobalage
intended to hurt you.
He wasn't himself.
Oh, God!
Mobalage.
That is not true.
I think your husband
suffers from what's known
as post‐traumatic stress.
No. He did not hurt me.
What do you mean?
I wan...I wanted to die.
I was so ashamed..
...I, I took the knife..
...I did this.
Oh, God.
Give me a C‐collar.
Looks like head,
neck, chest.
‐ I got a faint pulse.
‐ 'Ready with the backboard.'
Hang on. Hang on.
Okay, slide it in.
'How's his airway?'
Shallow arrest.
Get ready to bag, Connie.
‐ Okay, let's move!
‐ Alright, very careful.
Chest tube's in. Let's go with
the thoraseal.
‐ What's his pressure?
‐ 80 palp.
‐ What about the thoraseal?
‐ Wait a second.
I've got the subclavian.
Let's hang the type specific.
Set up another
central line on the left.
‐ I've already got one.
‐ We should have two.
‐ One is enough.
‐ What if it infiltrates?
It's not going to happen.
Even if it does we've got two
large‐bore antecubitals.
‐ Are you alright?
‐ How's he doing?
I'll take it
from here, Carter.
Getting ready
to go to the OR.
Came around the corner,
there they were
just waiting for us.
‐ Was Lars driving?
‐ I don't know.
It went down so fast, I couldn't
even tell what was happening.
Dwight, was Lars driving?
‐ Yeah.
‐ They were shooting for me.
I was driving last night.
They wanted me.
Mr. Kornberg..
...You were looking for me?
I just wanted to say thank you.
We're going to be leaving now
as soon as my dad gets
done with that photographer.
'Oh, photos from
the pediatrics ward, huh?'
Yeah. Nurses handed
out these balloons.
Little boy
insisted I have his.
You can't get away
from it, can you?
The kids all seem
to know who I am.
Their faces light up.
Plus, it makes
my dad proud.
You know
how parents can be.
‐ Thanks again, doc.
‐ Okay.
‐ Take care.
‐ You're welcome.
'I want to go in.'
'Let us do our work.
We'll explore the chest'
'stop the bleeding
then call the neurosurgeon..'
Let me know
what's going on.
I'm gonna be with him the whole
time. but you better stay here.
‐ Carter, what are you doing?
‐ Scrubbing in.
Aren't you
on duty in the ER?
No. I worked last night.
That was the ride‐along
with this fella, right?
That's right.
Carter, I don't think
there's enough room.
What do you mean?
We've got general surgery,
neurosurgery and thoracic
all working together.
I'll scrub out if I have to.
'We appreciate
your concern, doctor'
but it might be best
if you watch from
the observation gallery.
Feeling better?
The fluids should help.
I talked to Kubby.
'She woke up, and she's doing
much better.'
She also told me
that you didn't hurt her.
When the paramedics
showed up..
...the flashing lights
and the sirens..
...the pounding
on the door..
...they must
have scared you.
Yes.
Is that why you ran away?
Why didn't you
tell the police?
'Why did you say
it was your fault?'
It was my fault,
what happened to her.
When I left Nigeria
the soldiers came,
and they raped her..
...because of me.
I had left her alone.
When she told me..
...I couldn't
look at her.
I couldn't talk to her.
She was alone again,
and that's when she took the..
...she took the knife.
She needed me..
...but I had left her.
She needs you now.
I need more suction.
2‐0 vicryl.
Okay. He's oozing
all over the place.
Shirley, give me some FFP
and platelets, now!
Hey, what's going
on in there?
What are they doing?
I'm going
to the blood bank.
Are they using
the cell saver?
‐ Yes.
‐ Have they called neurosurgery?
I don't know, Carter.
I need to get blood.
Should we set up for bypass?
Not necessary.
'There are no
intercardiac injuries.'
Vascular clamp.
Have you called
neurosurgery yet?
We will, Carter.
We will.
Yeah, hi. I need neurosurgery
to OR three, please.
OR Three.
'We took her statement.'
'DA agreed to drop
the charges.'
‐ I wish it was all good news.
‐ What's up?
Immigration service
contacted the department.
It turns out Mr. Ekabo
came into the country
on a forged visa.
‐ What does that mean?
‐ He's an illegal.
Don't tell me you'll
take him back to jail.
No, but the INS will start
a deportation hearing.
To send him
back to Nigeria?
That's the way it works.
Hey, are you
from neurosurgery?
No. Radiology.
I got the CTs
I'll take these.
Uh, films show bullet fragments
in the right parietal lobe.
Neck wound‐‐ shattered c4.
Thank you, Dr. Carter.
I didn't know whether
you'd be able to read them.
‐ Neurosurgery wants the films.
‐ What did they say?
They said they were
called in too soon.
V‐fib. Starting
internal compressions.
Give me the paddles.
Let's move. Charge to 15.
Come on people, let's move.
Heart's empty.
He needs volume.
Okay, here we go. Clear!
Okay. Let's go again.
Charge to 30.
'Clear.'
'Okay. Charge again.
Clear.'
‐ Hey, Jeanie.
‐ Hey.
What are you doing?
Just checking out
some old charts.
Looking for
anything specific?
Yeah. I talked
to Al today.
He tested negative
for hepatitis "C."
he even faxed me
his results.
Which means I probably got it
from a patient.
We're all so worried;
me working here with HIV‐‐
the chance of me
infecting someone.
Never even thought
about a patient infecting me.
But it could have happened
to any one of us, right?
Yeah.
Hey, Jeanie,
do you want to..
...want to go get a cup
of coffee, or something?
No, thanks.
I'm going to stay here.
Okay.
‐ I'll see you tomorrow.
‐ Okay, Kerry.
'Carol?'
What are you doing?
Oh, unloading these boxes.
Doug ordered a lot
of supplies.
Have you spoken
with him?
Thought about it
a lot last night.
I ended up calling
the home shopping network
and ordered myself
a pair of fleece booties.
So, uh, did Mark manage
to strap you down..
...get a blood gas?
Finally talked me into it.
It's easier doing that
than listening to him.
My carbon monoxide level
was normal.
Oh, well. It was
a good guess.
Mark's just trying
to be a friend in that
endearing‐slightly‐inept‐male
kind of way.
I know.
I'm a week late.
You're what?
At first, I thought
it was just stress.
But it's not.
I'm pregnant.
Yeah.
That was a..
...it was a good effort.
Yeah.
Thank you, everyone.
Carter, let's go.
I'm just going to
stay for a second.