Book you for 9:00 o'clock?
Uh-huh.
Take the day off. All right.
So, what did you do?
You figured out I was in
jail, but you don't know why?
I've been busy.
Excessive prescribing.
Not that busy.
I know that you pled down
to excessive prescribing.
My question was,
"What did you do?"
Thirty-six-year-old, non-smoking,
junior high science teacher
started coughing blood in
the middle of homeroom.
Uh...
House says he's gonna be
out for the next three days.
Sweet. If I go
straight to the airport,
I can make Cabo for last call.
He also said to call
him if we find a case.
Which we didn't. MARTHA:
What do you call this?
It could be a case, it could be
nothing. Sadly, we'll just never know.
He's coughing blood.
A lot of people are.
Right now I have
to get to Vernon
while there's still
enough powder to ski on.
This is where a lesser man would
make a "black guy skiing" joke.
You owe me a body shot.
Make it fast, I'm driving.
I don't want to
end up in jail, like
a person should who used
their phone illegally while driving.
Thirty-six-year-old male
with hemoptysis, headaches,
chills and chest
pain. Where are you?
On my way to the Greater Schenectady
Chili Cook-Off and Spud Gun Competition.
That's your honeymoon?
Nope. Dominika went
to A.C. with her boyfriend.
ER ruled out bronchitis,
pneumonia and lung cancer.
So, diagnosis
boring. It's epistaxis.
It's a nose bleed. Blood runs into
his lungs, he coughs it back out.
The flu explains the
rest of the symptoms.
Going once,
going twice...
Toxic exposure to ammonia or
sulphites can traumatize the lungs,
cause neuralgias or fevers.
Fits better because of
his radiating chest pain.
Sold to Masters.
Do a home search for toxins.
Draw cultures for bacteria and fungi.
You're married?
You were gone so long.
Green card.
Thanks for not saying anything.
I just need some time to...
I didn't do it for you. Some
puzzles are just too good to share.
This is my exit.
Chili?
Hate chili.
Love spud guns.
You get nose bleeds?
Yeah. Yeah.
You think that's where
the blood came from?
I don't just
think it, I hope it.
When was the last
time it happened?
At the quarterfinals.
I coach volleyball,
and during warm-ups, I got hit
in the nose a few months ago.
You coach volleyball
in a gym? Yes.
With showers? Yes.
Clean showers?
Not particularly.
Blood you were
coughing out wasn't blood.
Dirty gym washroom
means Serratia infection.
Your lungs are
full of red bacteria.
You're right. It was
an interesting case.
You start him on Levaquin, I'll
start looking for my good flip-flops.
I think that might be blood.
What's this really
all about, House,
as convincing as I find your deep
devotion to vegetable trajectory?
First of all, it's a tuber.
And you're just jealous
because your potato-related plans
are more of the
serving-up-fries variety.
You did time,
means your license is suspended,
which means your leave of
absence is definitely indefinite.
What exactly are
you going back to?
I'd only have to serve up fries
until the medical board hearing.
I stand corrected.
You obviously have a
rich, full life waiting for you.
I'll slow down the car
and you can roll out.
I don't even have
a change of clothes.
Damn.
If only I had planned for that.
Okay, here's what I got.
One, you were in
jail for six months,
but you were gone about a year.
Which means that when you
left, you hadn't been arrested.
Two, you enjoy being
known as a number.
You don't want people to know the real
you 'cause you think the real you is weak.
You were running
a bleeding heart medical
consulting business for illegals
or some other
sympathetic underclass.
No.
Overclass? This interrogation
thing is getting annoying.
Studies have shown that
un-annoying interrogations,
50% less effective.
Why are you so determined
to bring me to this competition?
Why don't you bring Wilson?
Wilson thinks it's stupid.
I think it's stupid!
Junior year of high
school, you placed fourth
in the West Virginia
All-County Science Fair.
Your project, clean combustion.
Yeah. I also wore a training
bra. Things have changed.
Not that much.
I've been going to this
contest for four years.
And for four years,
I've come second
to a pissant named Harold Lam.
This is serious?
Second!
Okay.
I can help you.
But, I'm going to need to make
a personal stop along the way.
What kind of stop?
Personal. Did I
not mention that?
You gonna tell me
where you were last night?
I ran into a friend.
We had 50 bucks on the Bulls. I
had to eat a large pizza by myself.
You missed me.
Not as much as I missed my $50.
Where'd you meet
her? At the hospital.
If it's Masters, just lie to me.
It's the new CNA
in the third floor.
The redhead? She's hot.
Yeah, and I'm seeing
her again tomorrow night.
I don't know how you do it.
Is it the cute, harmless vibe,
the self-deprecating humor,
or just straight-up roofies?
If you're interested,
I do seminars.
No electric. No gas,
either. It's cold in here.
The good thing is, I found a guy who
makes you look like a good roommate.
Maybe hoarding's a symptom.
Could be caused by brain
injury, or early onset Alzheimer's.
Most likely that
it's psychological.
As to what's making
him cough blood,
dealer's choice.
Declutter Your Home.
The Hoarder's Handbook.
He's hoarding books on hoarding.
Ugh.
He doesn't have running water.
How does this guy live,
let alone make it to work every
day, and teach a bunch of kids?
Fridge is on. He's hooked it
up to a neighbor or something.
Cat.
I might have to throw up.
He'll wanna keep that, too.
Aspergillosis.
Explains the coughing blood,
and if he's formed
small aspergillomas,
it could explain the
headache and chest pain.
I'll be in the car.
Okay. Turn right.
You were writing bogus
prescriptions for medical marijuana.
Please say no because you have to
be an idiot to actually screw that up.
No.
I mean, I was, but
I didn't get caught.
I have to admit, you have one of
the best game faces I've ever seen.
Also one of the
best game bodies.
Pull over.
Just a second.
Didn't know you were
a Jehovah's Witness.
Yeah, the weak lost faith when Christ
didn't return in '75, but I still believe.
So you're really not gonna
tell me what just happened.
I don't know about
you, but I'm starving.
You broke into my home?
We slowly pushed into your home.
So, what did you find?
A compost heap in your fridge.
We think you have aspergillosis.
It's treatable
with anti-fungals.
You do remarkably well
for living like you live.
I use bottled water
and flashlights.
Just like camping.
Fun.
We're also gonna
need a psych consult.
I'm not a hoarder.
Just a major slob.
You save ear wax.
You know, I'm actually kind of
hurt that you don't know what I did.
I'm not worth bribing a court
official or hacking into police records?
What's the fun in that?
You could've at least hired
Cuddy's weird boyfriend.
Lucas? Mmm-hmm.
You don't know?
What, is he dead or something?
No.
Actually, until a couple of weeks
ago, I was Cuddy's weird boyfriend.
You're gonna have to
do a lot better than that.
Are you okay?
Yeah, I'm fine.
It's not a big deal.
I killed a man.
Psych eval gave us nothing.
So our patient is just an average
Joe with a 2-foot pile of used Q-tips?
Whatever he is, he
doesn't have aspergillosis.
Pain's intensified and
now he needs oxygen.
There's gotta be all kinds
of toxins in that place.
Exposure issues
don't make sense.
He's been here a full day,
he'd be getting better, not worse.
Unless exposure was
keeping him from getting worse.
Gas was off at his place.
How does he stay warm?
Portable heater? Or
portable gas heater,
which emits carbon monoxide...
Which is a vasodilator.
The low-grade exposure was
actually improving his lung capacity.
We bring him
here, he gets worse.
If we're right, don't need House
and we still get two days off.
Still have to prove it.
Someone's gotta go back
into that place and test for CO.
Chase and I can go.
It's only fair.
Fairness is important.
You're awfully quiet.
Sorry. It's just how I get around
people who've recently killed a man.
It wasn't...
You know, I've had
a pretty rough year.
Do you think maybe we could
just give this whole thing a rest?
You killed a man!
You pled out to drugs.
Hit and run, under
the influence.
The guy you kneed in the groin
was your date who
dropped a dime on you.
I'm asking you to let it go.
Yeah, I really wish I was the
kind of person who could do that.
Ruby, right?
Yeah.
Hey, how are you liking PPTH?
It's great. Everyone's
so friendly.
Yeah. Especially Dr. Taub.
Don't worry. I'm not gonna bust your
chops. I just wanna know one thing.
How did he get you
to go out with him?
Why? Is there something...
No, no, no. He's great.
You know, I'm just
asking because...
Well, he's...
Um...
You know what? Never
mind. It's none of my business.
You guys have fun tonight.
I'm not seeing him tonight.
We had plans but, he canceled.
This thing's got no fuel valve.
Means you can't
regulate the input.
What is this? A
barbeque lighter?
Your gun sucks.
We should treat this
like an archeological dig.
Grid the site, excavate,
catalog, analyze.
You like it here?
What, you don't think
this is fascinating?
Not nearly as fascinating as the
fact that you think it's fascinating.
But this guy kept everything
he ever came into contact with.
An interactive life history.
It's an indiscriminate
pile of rubbish.
Mmm.
For the most part,
so are our lives.
There's no carbon monoxide.
A bit of a blow to Foreman's
exposure hypothesis.
And my plan to get
out of here quickly.
Maybe we don't just figure out
the "what," we figure out the "why."
Then, maybe...
From the size and
the undigested seeds,
I'm guessing this
came from a raccoon.
If you're thinking Q fever,
it fits.
So, why are you still looking?
Well, we only found one thing.
And it fits perfectly.
Yeah, but that
doesn't mean it's...
Chase?
You missed
something at his place.
His wife.
Nina.
I didn't know where you were.
I'm so sorry. I
couldn't get home.
You okay?
We think you both have Q fever.
We found raccoon feces
in the kitchen cupboard.
We're gonna start
you on doxycycline.
Why wouldn't you
tell us you're married?
Fewer people who know
about it, the easier it is.
When can I go back?
She gets anxious when
she's away from her things.
She's the hoarder.
He just lives there.
On purpose?
She's my wife.
How do they not
have half-inch drill bits?
By the way, Harold's
probably gonna hit on you.
Everything I have, he
wants. Just turn him down flat.
Unless... Yes.
Let's stop shopping. I'll just do
him and get him to throw the contest.
I'm not suggest...
Would you do that?
How is this thing judged?
Hang time, distance
and accuracy.
Okay, how about this?
You met a guy in a club, you
brought him home, he ODed.
So, the guy now
writhing on his front porch
was the dealer who
sold you the faulty goods.
Categories weighted the same?
Yup.
Screw accuracy, we're gonna
double distance and hang time.
Beat Harold on points.
We need raw power.
Where's the fertilizer?
By all means, Kaczynski.
Hi.
You and Taub sharing phones now?
He's seeing the
redhead on the third floor.
Please tell me you're not talking
about the hot, new CNA with the dimples.
She confirmed it.
What she didn't confirm was
her date tonight. He bailed on her.
He's standing her up. He must
have something better going on.
Better than sex
with a 22-year-old?
Who's RT-92?
Presumably a 21-year-old.
Whoever it is, Taub's meeting
him at my place at 8:00,
which is usually
when I go to the gym.
Guess you'll be
missing spin class.
Okay, contestants. Field
is now open for practice.
You've got one hour. Have fun.
Schedule 80 PVC is
pressure-rated for 220 psi.
Fuel valve 300. We
can easily push it to 250.
Have your friend, Harold,
peeing in his pants.
Damn.
Be cool.
Harold.
House.
You look good.
I like that jacket on you.
Thanks.
You filled out a little.
Who's the babe?
She's the boot in your ass.
Perhaps you've heard of famed
Russian physicist, Olga Petrovich.
Olga Petrovich is 72-years-old.
And her granddaughter
works in a little
place called JPL.
I did an internship
there last summer.
She killed a man.
I'm guessing she didn't
do it with a spud gun.
Just a bad combustion valve.
Shut up.
On my sofa.
Oh!
Hey.
You remember my wife?
Hi, Eric.
Hey.
RT-92.
I hope you like rhubarb.
We're celebrating.
We're going rogue.
We rip out the combustion
valve, replace it with this,
so there's enough pressure to
blow out at maximum velocity.
Turning the spud
into spudnik.
What do we use for discs?
Here's a hint. I
actually hate rhubarb.
Pie tins.
You're a genius.
You know that I'm a doctor?
Any interest I have in the
human body is purely clinical.
Yeah, that line never
works for me, either.
That line always works for you.
So what did you do?
No more guessing?
I need to know.
I could make some phone calls,
see if we can speed up
your medical board hearing.
In the meantime,
no one can stop me
from hiring an assistant.
You were right this morning.
I met a guy at a coffee shop,
we went back to my place,
and he ODed.
Damn.
Could've saved
myself a job offer.
We both acted like idiots.
And I ended up doing time.
Guess he did more.
When we first moved into the
house, we had people over all the time.
And then she just
started collecting things.
I figured it was a hobby.
Piles turned into art projects,
and art projects turned
into what you saw.
So why do you stay?
To everyone else,
the world is full of junk.
Meaningless,
ugly, broken things.
But to Nina,
every shape,
every color, texture, smell,
they all tell a story.
They're all worth treasuring.
I wouldn't wish what
she has on anyone,
but every now and
then, I get a glimpse
of what she sees,
and it helps.
Your lungs are
clearing up nicely.
Respiratory rate's
normal, temp's normal.
Looks like you're gonna be fine.
Is she okay?
Something's wrong
with her heart.
The husband is fine, the wife
is worse. She had a heart attack.
Her heart attack could
be from a complication.
Q fever would've caused congestive
heart failure, not myocardial infarction.
So she had Q fever and something
else that causes heart attack?
And the hoarding. Now that
the wife is the only patient,
hoard is back on the board.
Or we were wrong about Q fever.
I don't buy that it's
just a coincidence.
It's not a coincidence.
Diagnosis X caused the hoarding,
which caused the Q fever
when the raccoons came
to spend spring
break at her house.
Now all we have
to do is solve for X.
I remember somebody saying
that hoarding could be a symptom.
We should do an MRI.
Hydrogen sulphide.
It's given off by
eggs and rotting food,
long-term exposure could
cause the pulmonary issues,
headaches... CHASE:
And the heart attack.
Hydrogen sulphide
is also a vasodilator.
Which my crack team
never tested the place for,
whereas half my crack team
never tested the place for people.
So we should go
back. Check it out.
Might be safer to just assume
we're right and start treatment.
Go with God. And
some air freshener.
You know, maybe Taub was right,
so I'm gonna stay here with him
and help him with the MRI.
Shine up your spuds, folks.
We're gonna start shooting for
hang time in just a few minutes.
Okay, wind's coming
from the south-east.
So we're gonna have to
aim five degrees to the left.
We're gonna break
14 seconds. I can feel it.
When I was 10 or 11, my dad
used to take us to this county fair,
and there was this kid.
What?
Who's "us"?
My mom and me.
Your mom, who had
advanced-stage Huntington's.
You have a sibling, which
you've never mentioned.
Why did you slip up now?
Not everything means something.
We're gonna be up soon. I
wanna check the pressure.
You don't wake up in the middle of
the night to cry over a dead stranger.
You don't confess to killing a
man and then hide the details
unless the details reveal more
about you than the crime itself.
You pled down to drugs,
you've got a horrible
genetic disease
and a sibling who's
suddenly on your mind.
You euthanized your brother.
And the guy back at
the house was the doctor
who wouldn't help
you cover it up.
Guy back at the house,
he's my cellmate's boyfriend.
He cheated on her
when she was inside.
But I was right about
everything else?
Congratulations.
You're mad.
No.
Actually, I'm impressed.
Messing around on a 22-year-old
hottie with your wife, on my sofa.
You're a full-throttle
head case.
I was doing you a
solid with the sofa.
Rachel wanted
to do it in your bed.
You've got the memory foam top.
Let's make this really simple.
If I own it, I don't
want you doing it on it.
You might wanna get
rid of your kitchen table.
Look, I'm sorry.
But it was worth it.
Yeah, I bet.
You get to mess with her
physically and emotionally.
I still care about her.
Not enough to let her
move on with her life.
And while we're talking
about your bad ideas,
MRI is clean.
There has to be some kind of
inciting psychological incident.
This is perfect for you.
You get all the human
interaction you crave
without any actual
human interaction.
She was a cheerleader. Hah.
You know, when you're interested
in something and nobody else is,
the polite thing is
to keep it to yourself.
Popular, beautiful, gregarious.
Hydrogen sulphide is about two parts
per billion, the size of a healthy fart.
I'll be back for you in July.
He couldn't do it himself.
He was...
The disease had
progressed too far.
He was flailing,
he didn't have any
control over his own body.
He'd pretty much lost
control of his mind, too,
but every once in a while, he
would have a few seconds of lucidity.
He turned to me, and he said,
"It's time."
I hooked up the IV,
I used gloves. I knew
they'd get me on the drugs,
but they couldn't prove
who pushed the plunger.
I put in the needle, and he just
got quiet.
And it was over.
And I was alone.
And one day, I
will be that sick,
and there will be no
one there when it's time.
I didn't expect
compassion from you.
I would've taken commiseration.
Hell, I would've
taken revulsion.
Any emotional engagement at all.
It's no wonder Cuddy
broke up with you.
Folks, Chad Mochrie just won
first place in the Chili Cook-Off.
Congratulations, Chad, that
cocoa powder really did it.
Dumped in a field in
Schenectady. Ouch!
You mind if I make a move?
I know she's out of my league,
but she's at a spud gun
contest with a soon to be
five-time runner-up,
so she's probably got
some self-esteem issues.
You wouldn't.
So?
Warning.
They gave you a warning?
Well, it turns out
our friend, Harold,
felt up the Sheriff's daughter
last night at the potato mash mixer,
so Sheriff's feeling
kind of ambivalent.
You always get
your way, don't you?
Not always.
Today would have been
our one-year anniversary.
Hmm.
Which is an incredibly
arbitrary thing to celebrate.
If you want to get to
the bottom of something,
you literally have to
dig down to the bottom.
So, stratigraphically,
the oldest stuff I found
was in the bedroom,
and the oldest stuff in the
bedroom was in the closet.
And at the bottom
of the closet...
Tell me about this.
We have a new
symptom, infertility.
They wanted kids
but couldn't have them.
She started collecting
things to fill the void.
We should run a full
hormone blood panel.
Hey, Harriet the Spy,
before you get
too full of yourself,
you might want to
go back to Bio 101.
It takes two to not tango.
Hubby could be shooting blanks.
So, either it's a new symptom
that will help us save her life,
or it's a complete
waste of time.
Figure out which is fried,
the bacon or the eggs.
I'll start the hormone work-up.
There's another option.
House, who's that? Radio.
Sounded a lot like Thirteen.
It's a Thirteen tribute band,
with their new song, I Got A
Better Theory Than Masters.
She said they never had kids.
Oh, my God.
Where the hell have you been?
I think we've all got something
a little more important
to worry about than...
No, we don't. She's
been missing for a year.
And you can ask her all about it
when she comes in on Monday.
Monday? This Monday?
Can I talk?
She said they never had kids,
and you all jumped to infertility.
You never considered
the other option.
And the bitch is back.
We think you have
Ehlers-Danlos syndrome.
It would explain the symptoms.
It also causes miscarriages.
Is that something you
think you might have?
Were you pregnant?
Three times.
The miscarriages
trigger the hoarding.
Hoarding eventually
made you sick, too.
Can you cure her?
We can treat the physical
symptoms as they arise,
make her life a lot better,
but the hoarding,
we're the wrong kind of doctors.
You lied to me?
For nine years?
I was so afraid of losing you.
What have I ever done
to make you afraid of that?
I need to get some air.
I've been selfish.
I need to let you move on.
I think we should
stop seeing each other.
No.
I just want you to be...
The last time you
got all noble on me,
we ended up dividing our dishes.
This time, I want to
make the decision.
You don't feel weird about this?
Of course I feel
weird about this.
It's confusing, and messy,
and dirty, dumb.
But we spent our whole lives trying
to do everything right, and it sucked.
Wasn't all bad.
It sucked, Chris.
And this,
whatever it is,
it's fun.
So,
I'm not taking advantage of you?
The fun is fading.
You know,
there's something
seriously wrong with us.
I know.
Home sweet home.
You owe me 87 bucks for gas.
I'll kill you.
When the time comes,
if you want me to.
I'd do it now if you like.
Yeah. I've got a
baseball bat in the back.
I'll see you Monday.