♪ Ohhh ohhh ohhh ♪
♪♪♪
♪ it's been a long time ♪
Henry laughs when I sneeze.
He thinks it's hilarious.
He's starting to develop
a personality.
And I started thinking,
you know,
how I'm responsible for
the person he grows up to be,
whether he's gonna be empathetic
or brave or...
Thoughtful.
And then I remember how
so many of these things
might already be decided,
inscribed on his d.N.A.
You think nature
trumps nurture?
♪♪♪
I'm coming.
Hey, buddy.
I missed you.
How was he?
He was great.
How are you?
I'm great.
Wow. Two greats.
Hey, do you think the nanny
would stay late tonight?
Uh, probably. What for?
So you can go to dinner
with me.
Is that
your alternative therapy?
Yes.
No.
Come on.
What are you afraid of?
I--you are not
taking this seriously.
I take dinner
very seriously.
Our problem is not
a lack of date nights.
Our problem is that we need to
learn how to communicate again.
"Again" being
the operative word here.
We don't need a referee
to help us get our mojo back.
What if we just try to...
Enjoy each other's company
and laugh
and remember that
we love each other?
Can't that be a way
that we become us again?
Come on.
I am even willing...
To go to that Thai restaurant
that you love.
You hate that.
And yet,
I'm offering to go.
That should
tell you something.
I'll think about it.
I'll pick you up
at 7:00.
♪♪♪
No, i--it's just that
keisha can't get here early,
and I couldn't get in touch
with the backup nanny.
And I thought since your company
brought me both of them,
that you might...
Okay. Well, do you have any
other nannies that are...
Really amazing
and super trustworthy
that can get here right now,
like, in the next ten minutes?
I mean, clearly,
you don't have them
stacked up in the closet
like robots.
I get that.
But I just thought...
No, thank you. Okay.
I'll figure it out.
Thank you. Bye.
Everything okay?
No, not really.
It's my first day
back at work.
I got paged to the E.R.,
my nanny's not here,
and I tried Violet,
but she's got an early patient.
You know what?
Forget the walk.
I'm gonna take a shower.
Yeah.
Mm. I gotta try Cooper.
All right. Just...
Give him to me.
Really?
Yeah, I'll take him.
Are you sure, Sam?
It's fine. It's fine.
Oh, Sam. Thank you.
Thank you. Thank you.
Stop. Hi, buddy boy.
Oh, go with Sam, Henry.
His bottle's in the fridge,
his blanket's in the dryer...
I got it. I got it.
And the nanny will be here
in an hour, tops.
I got it. I got it.
All right? Okay.
Bye, Henry. Bye.
Say bye-bye to mama.
Bye-bye, Henry.
Say see you later.
Yeah, she has a way
of doing that, doesn't she,
getting you
to agree to do things
you don't really want to do?
You gotta watch out
for that.
Come on, let's go watch
some movies.
♪ phinedroids and ferbots ♪
♪ phinedroids and ferbots,
phinedroids and ferbots ♪
Hey, mase,
it's getting late.
You should probably
get ready for school.
♪ And we're stomping
our feet ♪
Mason.
I heard you.
And yet,
you're not moving.
There's, like, ten minutes
left of the show.
I'm not
gonna ask you again.
Mason,
it's time to get dressed.
I just told him that.
Right now.
♪ Phinedroids and ferbots ♪
You suck.
What did you say to me?
Did you hear that?
Sure did.
I'd probably
say something about it
if only I were actually
his parent.
♪♪♪
♪ phinedroids ♪
Reina reyes,
26-year-old female.
Primip at 35 weeks.
Complaining of nausea
and vomiting.
Okay, get her
on a fetal monitor.
My baby--is he coming?
One, two, three.
Aah.
Are you having contractions,
Mrs. Reyes?
- I-I don't know.
- Any bleeding?
It hurts.
Did your water break?
Mnh-mnh.
Any pain when you urinate,
fevers, chills, back pain?
No.
Let's get a metabolic panel,
c.b.c., u.A.
This baby needs to come.
Okay, you're not
having contractions.
You're not in labor,
Mrs. Reyes.
Are you sure?
Yes, I am. Have you
eaten anything recently?
Um...
I-I-I don't remember.
Mrs. Reyes, if you want us
to help you and your baby,
you're gonna have to
tell us the truth.
Did you eat anything?
Did you take anything?
They told me if I drink it,
the baby comes.
I keep drinking
and trying more.
What did you drink?
Tia carina cocoa.
It's a folk medicine.
It's a chocolate tablet
you dissolve in hot milk.
It's probably loaded
with ergotamines.
Causes smooth muscle
contractions that mimic labor.
In large doses,
causes this.
Mrs. Reyes, we're gonna
have you drink some charcoal
to help absorb the toxins.
We're gonna keep you
on I.V. Fluids,
and in a few hours,
you should feel better.
Can I ask, though,
why did you drink it?
They're deporting me.
But I want
my baby to stay here.
I want my baby
to have a life.
She tried to self-induce?
Yeah. If her baby's born here,
he's a citizen.
That way, if she's deported,
he can stay.
Stay, but be put
in the system.
She figures,
she'll leave him somewhere
he'll have a shot
at a better life,
and that's worth it.
I just got off the phone
with immigration.
They issued a removal order
for reina reyes,
but she never showed up
on her deportation date.
So they want to put her
on a plane
back to El Salvador tomorrow.
Well, she's not gonna
deliver by then.
We could induce.
Pete, she's only 35 weeks.
And it's not
medically indicated.
Mothers schedule deliveries
for all kinds of reasons.
I worked with an o.B.
Who would induce
if it threatened
his Saturday tee time.
We are talking about a baby
that could have another month
inside the womb.
There's a 90% survival rate
at 35 weeks.
And there's
a 10% mortality rate.
And even if the baby
does make it,
we're talking about time
in the Incubator,
surfactants to help
lung growth.
It's a very tough road.
Yeah, but, Addison,
we're talking about a baby
born in this hospital
with us taking care of him.
And you weigh that against
reina taking him to a place
where it's gonna be tough
to find clean water--
believe me, I'm not arguing
against birth mothers
putting their babies
in a position
to have a better life.
That's why I have Henry.
It's just--it's not right
that we're discussing
delivering a baby prematurely
so that he doesn't
live in poverty.
It's an awful choice.
It is, but, Addison,
I worked in El Salvador,
and I'm telling you,
in rural areas,
there is minimal access
to health care.
The infant mortality rate
is triple ours.
Which is a tragedy,
but there's not a lot
we can do about that here.
We're in the business
of making sick people better
and delivering babies for women
who are ready to give birth.
Now right now, reina doesn't
fit in either box.
So either
we discharge her--
- or deliver the baby right now.
- Despite the fact that
it's clearly
not what's best for the baby?
Isn't that reina's call?
Hi.
Good to see you.
Hey, Dr. Cooper.
Hey.
Mel.
So melody has been miserable
all week.
First it was her throat,
then she stopped eating,
now her ears hurt.
Okay, that's a lot
of symptoms.
And we tried
the over-the-counter stuff,
but nothing worked.
She just seems
to be getting worse.
All right.
Well, Mel,
let's check you out.
All right, I'll, uh,
I'll wait here.
I don't need you
to come in with me, mom.
I'm not a baby.
You know what, Pam?
Why don't I check out Mel,
and if we do need you,
we'll come get you?
How are you feeling?
Tired.
Huge.
Well, your weight gain
is right where it should be
for the third trimester.
Any problems,
any g.I. Or g.U. Complaints?
No,
everything feels normal...
Which just seems cruel.
Should I...
Is there anything
I should be doing
to help my baby reach
the optimal birth weight...
For the transplants?
Well, you're doing it.
You're resting.
You're eating right.
If you keep taking care
of yourself,
this, uh, this baby will be
able to help a lot of others.
And when it's time for me
to deliver?
Well, my hope is that you'll
deliver naturally at term,
but sometimes women
carrying anencephalic babies
don't always get
the signal from their bodies
to go into labor.
If that happens,
I'll induce,
once the baby is born,
I'll--
I'll have you sign
the consent forms,
and then the transplant team
will take over.
Everybody at the practice
is looking at me now, you know?
Like they're afraid to
say anything to the crazy lady
who's carrying a baby
with no brain to term.
I'm sure they all want
to support you.
Maybe if you let them know
what the plan is, that...
No.
I just...
I can't handle talking about
this with anyone but you.
Okay?
Okay.
Hey.
Thank you for watching Henry.
I-I really appreciate it.
Yeah, no problem.
Was he fussy?
No, it was fine.
Did he do that thing
where he stretches
and he looks like
a relaxed old man?
You know, honestly,
I didn't notice.
You did... offer
to watch him, Sam.
Yeah.
Well, you shouldn't have if it
was just gonna piss you off.
Sorry for the inconvenience.
You know your parents are just
looking out for you, right?
By following me
everywhere I go?
That's what parents
are supposed to do.
All right.
Your ears look good.
Your glands are okay.
Open your mouth
and say "ahh."
Ahh.
You're 10 years old.
That means they got, like,
eight more years to hassle you.
All right, no fever,
no swelling, no redness.
If I didn't know better,
I would think maybe
somebody wants
to ditch school today.
You got a big test
or something?
Hey.
You've been coming to me
since you were 2 years old.
You know you can
tell me anything.
They won't listen to me,
Dr. Freedman.
I keep telling them,
but they don't believe me.
What don't they believe?
Hey.
I can't help you unless you
tell me what's going on.
I'm a boy.
Of course melody's parents
won't listen.
Who wants to hear that?
Look, parenting ain't easy,
all right? That's the job.
It's--it's how you handle it
that's the issue.
Well, denying melody's feelings
isn't the answer.
I mean, she says she's always
known she was a boy.
Even as a toddler,
she felt like
she was trapped
in a girl's body.
She used to line up to--
to go to the boys' bathroom.
She wanted to play
on the boys' sports teams.
Well, isn't that just
being a tomboy?
- Could be g.I.D.
- She's 10.
You can't diagnose gender
identity disorder in a kid.
Her prefrontal cortex
isn't fully developed.
Well, that doesn't mean
she doesn't know how she feels.
No, but it might mean she
doesn't really understand it.
Look, when Maya was 8, she said
she wanted to be a fireman.
She grew out of it.
And melody probably will, too.
As soon as she hits puberty,
the hormones will kick in,
she'll start to develop,
and she'll want to be
around boys.
She won't want to be one.
Well, it's a little bit
more complicated than that.
Kids with g.I.D. Experience
a disconnect between
their sex, which is anatomy,
and their gender,
which is emotions, behaviors,
and everything else.
And the longer they're forced
to live with the wrong gender,
the more damage is done.
And the sooner they can
integrate their external body
with their internal image
of themselves,
the better they do.
You're talking about melody
dressing up like a boy?
For a start.
Well, it's one thing if they
allow her to do that at home,
but once she steps foot
in school,
I mean, she's gonna
open herself up to ridicule,
possibly bullying--
okay, so we're saying
she's screwed either way?
I mean,
she lives like a boy
and she risks getting
the crap kicked out of her
at school every day,
or she lives like a girl
and has to face
the angst and depression of
being caught in the wrong body?
Well, it's--
it's not just depression.
I mean, kids with true g.I.D.
Often hurt themselves.
They cut themselves,
they do drugs,
suicide rate is five times
the national average.
Okay, well, that means...
You have to talk to her
and make a diagnosis.
And if it is g.I.D.,
we need to explain it
to the parents.
Well, that's assuming
they'll listen.
Well,
I just can't help thinking
that while I am obsessing over
whether or not my nanny
can work longer hours,
this mother is trying
to keep her kid alive.
You have
rich white lady guilt.
Yes. No.
I--come on, Violet.
I have a mixed-race baby.
I adopted him from a woman
with limited options.
It's not like I don't get it.
I know.
But it's hard.
You have $10,000 worth of
baby clothes in Henry's closet,
and you have no way to help this
woman who's actually desperate.
Yes.
And you're
not comfortable inducing?
I don't know.
It's not ideal, but I mean,
then neither is bringing
the baby back to El Salvador.
And when did Charlotte say
immigration is coming?
Uh, the next 24 hours.
Oh, I'm so sorry.
Yeah.
Well, you can always take
Pete's strategy
and do nothing until
it blows up in your face.
What blew up in your face?
Nothing. Nothing yet.
No, he just wants to, uh,
do the whole,
you know,
"put down the baggage thing,"
and, uh, I am wary.
Okay, what exactly does that
mean, put down the baggage?
It means he wants to go
to dinner instead of therapy.
Are the two
mutually exclusive?
To him they are.
I--look, I...
I don't feel like
I can say no.
I don't even want to say no,
I just--i want us to work,
and I don't think that we can
get there on our own anymore
but...
But maybe I can use the dinner
to convince him to...
Go back to therapy.
Hey, any chance you could pick
up Mason after school today?
Sure.
I have this, uh, patient--
melody, 10-year-old girl
who thinks
she's a little boy.
Violet and I are gonna go over
and talk to the parents.
I cannot imagine
dealing with that as a parent.
Yeah, well, I wouldn't know
about that.
Oh, come on, Charlotte.
I apologized for saying that.
No, you've been talking to me
like you've apologized.
You've been saying
the things people say
after they've apologized.
But the actual apology,
I never heard that.
God, please don't do this.
My son
is barely talking to me.
He doesn't listen
to a word I say.
He only responds to you.
I'm a little pissed off.
There's only child
in our family, Cooper.
So grow up
and get over it.
I'm worried about Amelia.
She's not seeing me
for prenatal care.
I don't even know if she's
getting any medical attention--
I've got it covered.
Oh, so you're her o.B.?
I've got it covered,
Addison.
That's it?
You're not gonna tell me
how she's doing physically,
emotionally--
I am not discussing this
with you.
Okay, look, I respect that.
I do. I do.
I mean, Amelia's made it
very clear
that she doesn't want my help,
but I just--i love her,
and I-I want her to know
that if she needs me--
if you want to tell Amelia
something, tell her yourself.
I'm not getting
in the middle of it.
¿Usted ha visitado
a Santa Ana?
Hace muchos anos.
Hey.
How are you feeling?
Fine. But I'm running
out of time.
Reina was just telling me about
the village where she's from.
I helped set up a clinic
in that area years ago.
I know this clinic,
but it's just a building now.
When I was little,
the doctors left,
and it was hard for us
to get any medicines.
Wait. What?
I spent a year down there.
We made so much progress.
But the crime
and the poverty
and the hurricanes--
you could not
do anything about that.
No one can.
If I could make a life
for my baby at home,
I would not have come here.
But I can't.
No, I know, reina,
and I can't imagine how hard
this is for you, truly.
But I do need you to understand
the risks your baby would face
if you had him now.
I do. I promise you.
But I want you
to understand the risk
if I don't have him now.
Hey.
You all right?
Ooh. I am trying so hard
not to be angry right now.
Uh-oh. Addison?
Huh. Who else?
What now?
She drops by this morning,
asks me if I can
look after Henry.
Really?
Yeah, man.
I mean, she didn't
"ask me" ask me,
but, you know,
the nanny was late,
she couldn't find
anybody else to cover.
What am I supposed
to say, no?
It's just like
when you were together.
Y--
that's not funny, man.
I mean, I shouldn't even
be an option, right?
I'm the ex.
That Henry is
a cute little baby, though.
And we circle back.
You know what? You're right.
She wanted that baby.
She should handle him
on her own.
Hey... stop trying
to be the bad guy.
It's not really you.
Hey.
Reina really put us
on the spot earlier, huh?
Yeah, well, I get it.
You know, she's a mother
advocating for her child.
Oh, it's so frustrating.
You know, we opened a clinic
near where reina lived
in Santa Ana.
We staffed it,
we trained people,
and in a region that's
that deprived,
even the slightest changes
make a huge difference.
You know, a little access
to preventative care
and medicine, it's...
I know.
I left there thinking that
the problem was solved.
Is there any chance that
reina would want to stay here,
fight the deportation,
try to make a life?
I asked her that.
She said she tried.
She traveled all the way
up through Mexico,
she snuck across the border,
immediately applied
for asylum,
but she lost her hearing
and her appeal.
So she's out of options.
What if we sponsor her,
and do whatever it takes,
get her a job?
That's not really the way
the process works.
I just... I don't know.
If I induce her, then i'm
gonna feel responsible for
a woman leaving her baby.
This is not on you,
Addison.
Physically,
melody is fine.
She has no infections.
Her blood work came back
totally normal.
But emotionally,
I am a little concerned,
which is why I asked Dr. Turner
to join us.
We may have noticed
some things about your daughter
that might be
a little concerning
or hard to understand--
what are you talking about?
We understand her just fine.
Well, melody feels like
she's a boy
trapped in a girl's body.
Not that again.
No, melody's
always loved make-believe.
From the time she was little,
she would always do these plays
where she was the cowboy,
the cowgirl, the horse.
She'd dress up,
do different voices.
I'm not sure
if this is make-believe.
Sh-she may have something
called g.I.D.--
gender identity disorder.
Or she's just confused,
going through a stage.
Maybe. Maybe.
I-I won't really know until I
have a chance to speak with her
and to do that,
I need your permission.
Well, if she does have
this g.I.D...
Is there anything
you can do to cure it?
Well, that wouldn't really
be our approach to this.
Therapy would be more about
helping melody adjust
to her new reality.
And in addition to therapy,
there are hormone-blocking drugs
that could
stave off puberty for her
so that she would have some time
to deal with these issues.
Well, Dr. Freedman, that--
This is a joke, right?
You want us to stop
our daughter from growing up
because she told you
some ridiculous story
about being a boy?
I know this is a lot
to take in.
I won't listen
to any more of this.
You have to leave
right now.
And stay the hell away
from our daughter.
♪♪♪
♪ days in our lives ♪
♪ you know ♪
A man who has lived
and worked all over the world
has eaten
practically everything,
and yet, cannot stand
the one thing I always crave.
Yeah, well,
you work in a Thai village
and eat nothing
but massaman curry for a month
and see if you still like it.
Remember, we came here
every other day
the first few weeks
we were together?
How could I forget?
Why did you do that?
Because I...
Got to be with you.
It was worth it.
Why are you doing it now?
♪♪♪
Are you wooing me?
Well, I really didn't get
to finish doing that
that first time around,
did I?
Uh, yeah, right.
Well, let's see, um, sex...
Mm-hmm.
Baby, horrific attack...
Prolonged absence due to
emotional devastation,
and then, you know,
marriage.
Maybe that's our problem.
Or it's just our way.
You know, I'm glad
we're doing this. I am.
I-I heard what you said
in therapy, and i--and I get it.
We should have fun.
But you have to understand,
we still have work to do.
♪♪♪
Right?
♪ Oh, the other day ♪
♪ they lost it
in their heads ♪
I missed this.
Me, too.
I miss you.
I miss us.
♪ And I tracked
and kept receipts ♪
♪ for the day they turn
the bastards on their head ♪
Hey, your shoelace
is untied there, buddy.
It's fine.
It's not fine. You're gonna--
you're gonna trip.
You're gonna hurt yourself.
Mason, hey.
Cooper.
I understand that you're upset
your mom is gone,
I know you're struggling
with a lot of feelings,
but that doesn't mean
you don't have to listen to me.
I'm your father, and when I
tell you to do something,
I expect you to listen.
Just leave me alone.
Mason.
Let him go.
He's such a little jerk.
No, he is in pain,
and he's taking it out on you.
Okay, Charlotte, please don't
lecture me about children, okay?
I've been dealing with them
my entire career.
Other people's children,
ten minutes at a time,
when they need your help.
This is your kid.
It's different.
And now you're the expert?
I know that sometimes kids
can be a royal pain in the ass
and it's the job of the parent
to love them anyway.
You're not gonna fix Mason.
All you can do is give him
some structure and be patient,
no matter how hard
that is for you.
How's it going?
Fine.
Are you okay?
What's wrong?
Nothing.
I'm fine.
Hey, Pete.
Where were you last night?
You cut out early.
Dinner.
Business or pleasure?
Uh, Violet.
Oh, so, uh, you two
are doing all right?
I think we're better
than all right.
I think maybe
we're back.
Who's back?
Pete and Violet.
What?
How'd that happen?
Last night we went out
and just...
Look, there's a time to talk
and there's a time to...
Not talk.
Enough said.
Yeah, but this is Violet,
though. She's all about talk.
Sometimes.
All right, look, i'm--I'm not
rooting against you,
and I hope that you get
everything out of this
that you want,
but in my experience,
you know, you can use sex
to get back,
but once you're there, you end
up having the same problems
you left behind
the first time.
You're just bitter
'cause you wound up
watching Addison's baby.
What? Really?
I had no choice.
Look,
you two are big boys,
you can make
your own decisions, but me,
I never go back
to the same well twice.
Immigration came
to the hospital for her?
They have a removal order
and want to take her right now.
Said they have
their own medical facility
and can handle everything.
Charlotte--
I am repeating not agreeing.
Addison, you know the official
position of this hospital
is that you can't induce
a woman early
without medical indication.
I know. I know.
What's your position?
I think that no matter
what our lawyers,
or those agents,
or anyone else says,
you are her doctor.
Reina, I'm going to break
your water.
And then I'm gonna put you
on an oxytocin I.V.
That will start your labor.
It may take a couple of hours,
but by the end of the day,
your son will be born.
You ready?
I'm ready.
He kicked.
My baby, he, um, he kicked
like any other baby,
like a normal baby.
Uh, maybe--maybe we should
do some more tests
or, uh,
a second ultrasound?
Why don't you, uh,
why don't you have a seat?
Don't look at me like that.
I know what I felt.
My baby...
Oh, my god.
I am a crazy person.
I'm a neurosurgeon.
I know what is going on.
It just felt so real.
It is real.
Your baby is real.
I've been focusing so hard
on the end goal,
I just--i haven't...
Stopped to think about
what it would be like...
What it would feel like when he
started moving inside me.
Do you feel that?
Yes.
I do.
That's my son.
How did she get here?
She took the bus.
And her parents?
They think she's at school.
We need to call them.
I know.
What if we waited a little while
before we called 'em?
Cooper.
It would give you a chance
to be with Mel alone,
make a real diagnosis.
I need
her parents' permission.
Well, you're not gonna
get it, Violet.
I mean, you were there.
They won't believe us
or her.
Well, talking to melody
behind their backs
is only gonna address
half the problem,
and it might make things more
difficult for melody at home.
Well, it's better
than nothing.
Melody is not Mason.
What is that
supposed to mean?
I think you are frustrated
that you can't help Mason
with his grieving,
and so you're pushing too hard
to save melody.
Come on.
Hormone-blocking drugs?
It's a real option.
It's way down the line,
Cooper,
and it's not
the first thing you say
to two terrified parents
who are afraid to admit
that their daughter--
okay, I get that, Violet,
but these people
have turned their backs
on their daughter,
and the more they ignore
how she feels,
the more
she's gonna withdraw.
We need to do something.
My mom and dad were fighting
about me last night.
He said he wanted to know about
the pills that could help me.
But she wouldn't listen.
Then she started yelling.
So if I take the pills,
will I become a boy?
Well, it's not
that simple, Mel.
The drugs won't turn you
into anything.
But they will stop you
from maturing into a woman
until you decide
who you are.
I know who I am.
I-I know you think you do,
but sometimes,
things can be confusing.
I'm not confused.
During the day,
I have to be a girl.
But at night,
when I close my eyes
and I dream...
I'm a boy...
Doing boy things.
And then when I wake up,
for a second, I'm still a boy.
But then my mom comes in
and lays out clothes
for the day.
It's usually a dress
or glittery shoes.
It's always the same.
I refuse to wear it,
she gets mad,
and we fight,
and I lose TV.
She doesn't understand
how it makes me feel.
How does it make you feel?
Wearing girl clothes,
acting like a girl
at school...
I hate it.
It's like...
I'm pretending all the time
and I can't stop.
No one will let me.
It's okay to cry,
melody.
Even boys cry sometimes.
I'm sorry.
Are we interrupting?
Uh, could you just
give us a second?
What's wrong with you?
Nothing.
My mom died.
I'm a boy
and nobody believes me.
You want to come play?
Hey.
Do you have a second?
I have a delivery.
Can it wait?
Oh, yeah, yeah.
It's nothing really.
I just... yeah, it's--
it's nothing.
All right. Out with it.
Uh, I think Pete and I,
we did a bad thing.
A bad thing like?
We had sex.
Ooh,
that's an interesting way
of convincing him
to go back to therapy.
No, I know, but, you know,
maybe it's a start.
A start toward?
Trying to fix things
Pete's way.
Acting from what I feel
instead of what I think.
Can you do that?
I can try.
Should you do that?
Maybe not.
I did say it was a bad thing,
didn't I?
Oh.
It's so much easier
telling other people
what to do
with their lives.
She's dilated,
plus-2 station.
I just need a big push.
I'm trying.
You're doing great.
Just bear down.
Come on.
Okay, I've got the head.
Almost there.
Is he here?
He's here.
Is he okay?
Is everything okay?
He's fine.
He's a healthy,
beautiful boy.
He's amazing.
You want to hold him?
For as long as I can.
Te quiero, cielito.
Everything okay?
Great.
The immigration guy
is still hanging around?
You don't feel like she's ready
to be moved yet, do you?
Not today.
I'll let him know.
Thank you.
I'm gonna give you two
some time.
Thank you so much,
Dr. Montgomery.
Reina, are you sure
you want to leave him here?
I mean--
at home, I have no one.
My parents are dead,
and my brother, he left home
a long time ago.
And the baby's father is...
He disappeared.
If I could go back...
I love my baby, but...
I would do my life
differently.
But that is not possible,
so... for me,
no looking back.
Hey.
Yes!
Does melody know
you called her parents?
I couldn't bring myself
to tell her.
Cooper.
I didn't want to risk
her running away again.
No! So close.
Okay, showtime.
A second chance.
Fine.
We're here
to see Dr. Freedman.
Hi.
Where is she?
She's, uh, playing.
She's okay?
She's fine. She's fine.
Good, because she and I
are gonna have a little talk.
Y-You know, you cannot
berate your daughter into
changing her mind.
The only thing you can do
is support her
and help her navigate
these feelings.
She's just a child.
Who feels that she's
trapped in the wrong body.
And I know that sounds
crazy to you,
but I have spoken to her,
and she--well, she came
to us for help, and i--
and I couldn't
not talk to her.
I just--i just couldn't.
But the important thing is,
now I believe that--
that she's not confused
and that
she's not imagining this.
Well, what are we
supposed to do?
Don't encourage them
Michael.
Well, what if they're right?
We need to help her.
I don't have to listen
to this anymore.
Where is she?
She's in here.
Mel.
Melody,
we're going home.
But I-I-I don't want to.
I don't care
what you want.
Don't yell at her.
Uh, mase.
Who is this?
- Th-this is my son.
- And he's right.
Nothing's gonna be solved
by yelling.
Dad, do something.
Come on!
Pam, Pam, Pam.
Ow!
I understand that you're angry
and frustrated and scared.
Melody is not happy, and you
don't know how to help her.
But we do.
We can help, okay?
We don't have to listen
to you.
No, you have to listen
to melody.
Your job is to protect her
and love her and help her,
no matter what.
But first...
You have to try
to understand her.
Don't you tell me
how to raise my daughter.
You're hurting me!
Pam.
This is my little girl.
Do you hear me?
She's my little girl!
Don't cry, mommy.
You don't
have to do this alone.
We can help you two understand
what's going on with melody
and--and help her transition
to be the person
that she is inside.
She's right.
Violet, oh, I have
an amazing idea.
A-Act-actually, i--
no, no, no. Remember that place
in carmel that you love
with the cabins?
Let's drive up there
with Lucas this weekend.
Just the three of us.
We would love it--
Pete, no, no, Pete, Pete--
we could spend
some time together--
no, we're--
we're not gonna do that.
I mean, what we've been
trying to do here,
this whole
"put down the baggage
and have fun and be us again,"
it's--
it's--it's seductive
and I can't say
I haven't...
I haven't loved it.
But going forward,
it's not gonna be enough.
You know, having sex
and talking about starting over,
it's just not gonna be--
it's not gonna fix
whatever's fundamentally
wrong with our relationship.
Violet, why do we have to
keep looking back?
Can't we just deal with
the now?
Because we don't even know
what happened... Pete.
We--we have to go back
and figure that out.
And we had just started
to scratch the surface
and...
You need to do the work.
We...
We need to do the work.
I thought you understood.
I do. I do understand.
And if you were to tell me that
you wanted to leave your baby
because you weren't emotionally
prepared to raise him,
I would be the first one
saying that you're doing
the right thing,
but you do want to raise him.
And even though I admire
your willingness
to sacrifice so that
he has a better chance
at life than you had,
I just--i feel like
there has to be
a better way.
There is no other way.
What--what if you
went back temporarily,
and then you reapplied for--
it would take years
if it ever happened.
What if I went with you?
What? Pete.
I--I've spent time there.
I know my way around.
I could help you and the baby
get settled, make a life.
It would...
How could you do that?
You have a family
and your life is here.
Well, there's no other way,
is there?
Hi.
Hey.
What's going on?
Um, i'm...
I'm gonna leave
for a while.
What?
Wh-where are you going?
El Salvador. There's a clinic
there I used to work--
what the hell
are you talking about?
I want to fix it.
I-I feel like--
you should feel like you have
something to fix right here--
us, our marriage.
I'm standing
right in front of you, Pete.
Your son is sleeping
right upstairs.
You can't just run away.
Please.
Please do not do this.
Hey, hey, Amelia.
Look, I know you hate me,
but... this isn't the end
of the road for us.
We're family and we always
will be. I just...
I just need you to know,
I think...
You're amazing.
You're stronger
than I could ever be.
I don't know how
you're getting through this.
And I'm here for you
for whatever you need,
even if what you need
is someone to hate.
Dr. Montgomery,
we need you right away.
What happened?
I came in to take reina
and the baby back to the room,
but they were gone.
We searched the whole ward,
but...
If she cut off the tags
or tried to take him out,
the alarms would've sounded,
and there's nothing.
Well, she's not stealing.
It's her baby.
But she shouldn't be
leaving yet, should she?
She's the mother.
It's her choice.
Doctor, quint's map.
How did you
come by it, lad?
Why he gave it to me, sir,
when he sent me for help.
He said that we'd share.
Share what?
You don't know?
Pirate treasure, man.
It's gold.
Hey, fellas.
Hey.
Hi.
You want to join us?
It's okay.
You two look comfortable.
Come on. Come watch.
Well, all right then.
Master Roland,
you're a trump, young Hawkins.
Mark my words,
you will share.
I really am sorry.
I know.
Hey, guys.
Sorry I'm a little late.
Hope I didn't miss bath time.
Keisha?
Henry?
Hello.
You guys upstairs?
Are you up there?
Keisha?
Keisha.
♪ what ♪
♪ you are ♪
Oh.
♪ Up above ♪
Hi, sweetie.
♪ The world so... ♪
Hey.
There we go.
Mama's here.
Hey.
There's mama.
Hi, little one.
Yeah.
Your nanny cut out early,
so...
Ahh.
You need to find
better child care.
Thank you.
Yeah.
♪ all the way home ♪
♪ I will follow love ♪
♪ All the way home ♪
Do you have
those consent forms?
Yes.
♪ Though it breaks my back ♪
♪ and leaves me all alone ♪
♪ I ♪
Can I sign them now?
You don't have to do that yet.
♪ Though it breaks my back ♪
I want to sign them now.
♪ All alone ♪
♪ I will follow love ♪
♪ all the way home ♪
♪ though ♪
♪ I'm sad you've gone away ♪
♪ I hear love ♪
♪ it goes by different names ♪
If you change your mind,
if you want to... just hold him
for whatever time he has
and forget the rest,
you can do that.
♪ And it put me in my grave ♪
You can wait
until he's born to decide.
♪ ...follow love ♪
I can't wait.
Once he's born...
♪ Think of all the friends
that you have known ♪
I'm worried
I won't be strong enough.
♪ Every blade of grass ♪
♪ every face
that kissed you back ♪
♪ all the sunsets ♪
♪ and pouring rain ♪
♪ every joy and holy pain ♪
♪ every kiss and bloody stain ♪
♪ are the proof
that we have lived ♪
♪ And every flash of light
you've seen ♪
♪ every color every dream ♪
I'm a scientist.
I know there are
more than 20,000 genes
in the human genome.
Everything from hair color
to the likelihood of getting
certain kinds of cancers,
the genes that are responsible
for the development of
your brain--
they're all in there.
But I know...
Nurture beats nature.
Because Henry looks at me
with love.
I'm his mom,
and he knows it.
And no protein code in his brain
told him to think that.
♪ Will follow you ♪
♪ all the way home ♪