♪ Ohhh ohhh ohhh ♪
♪ I need all my money ♪
♪ I want all my cash ♪
♪ and I can be your man ♪
♪ she said I was
her cousin ♪
♪ ...was her man ♪
♪♪♪
♪ yeah, see all I want is ♪
Hello.
That guy is lookin' at you.
You wanna try talkin' to him?
Sure.
Should I lead with, "hey,
one day I could be in a diaper.
Want to go out"?
Or maybe I should go with
the crazy facial ticks,
the tremors...
The dementia.
♪ She got to learn ♪
♪ I ain't going nowhere
for your concern, girl ♪
Watching my mother die
of huntington's,
I can tell you...
♪ I'll die without you,
girl, I'll die without you ♪
No one wants to be
a part of it.
But you don't even know
you have the gene.
And I prefer it that way.
But you're living like
you already have the disease.
Just take the test.
Know for sure.
♪ You got a body that would
kill, keep dancing ♪
♪ girl, I'll die without you ♪
♪ black girl, put your Booty on
the floor, don't stop now ♪
Good morning.
♪ Keep dancing ♪
♪ girl, I'll die without you ♪
African flame lilies.
Gabriel.
They're the national flower
of Zimbabwe.
I had to go through six
importers to get them here.
I-I know what they are.
What are you doing here?
The newspaper said you were
in the capital--Harare--
donating an m.R.I.,
courtesy of what's his face.
W-William white.
You're doing a good job
handing out his money.
I'm g-gonna ask you again.
What are you doing here?
I gave you time to mourn.
How magnanimous of you.
Oh, come on, Naomi.
We were good together.
I missed you.
Last time I saw you,
you yelled at me
and you just rolled off.
Rolled? Really, Nai?
Th-that's not what I meant.
He's gone, and I'm back,
so let the wooing begin.
Hey, Sam.
Who's the new girl?
Oh, hey.
It's only been
a few days, Coop, but...
It seemed longer?
Yeah. I-I hit a wall
with the captain and Archer.
Oh, well, that makes sense.
Ooh, I can see that.
I-I know it wasn't easy
for you guys, either,
but so you know, I, uh...
I appreciate it.
Hey, hey, hey.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Do you want--
Ignore this.
Ever since bizzy died,
this has just been happening.
So I'm fine. Ignore me.
Hey, you are never
gonna guess who...
Addison.
I'm fine.
I-I'm sorry. Are you okay?
No, it's, uh, transient tears.
Who--who showed up?
Spill.
Um... okay. Fife.
Hey. How's he doing?
He's exactly the same.
Snarky,
aggressive, self-involved?
Pretty much.
Oh, he's not that bad.
Yeah, I didn't realize
how much I missed him.
Well, he certainly caught you
in the right mood.
Sorry. The bitchiness,
it comes with the tears.
I can't control it.
Addison, if you--if you want
to talk about Archer, i--
no, I want to talk
about fife.
So did it stir up
some old feelings for you?
I don't know. It's, you know,
too early to tell.
I don't know.
You know, maybe.
Hey, lady.
Welcome back.
Mm. Thank you.
I was just about
to call you.
I have a patient who came
to the hospital looking for you.
Fancy.
They wanted you, too.
What's the issue?
Frank and isobelle's baby has
hypoplastic left heart syndrome.
Dr. Montgomery,
your in utero surgeries
have been well-publicized.
Well, unfortunately, due to
the severity of this case,
your baby's heart
isn't strong enough
to pump blood through her body,
so no surgery--
in utero or otherwise--
will help.
And we understand, she'll die
within a day of her birth.
We won't get to be parents
to her,
but there is a way that we can
keep more than just her memory.
We've done I.V.F. Three times.
Miscarried twice.
She was our last embryo,
and I have
no more eggs left.
But our baby,
she has hundreds already.
But eggs don't mature
until adolescence.
Actually, we've done
quite a bit of research,
and, um, if an ovary
is treated with hormones,
it can speed up
the maturation process.
I'm sorry. I'm not sure
what you're asking.
We're asking you
to remove our baby's ovary
and fertilize her eggs
with donor sperm.
I want another chance
at motherhood.
- Hmm.
- Hot?
Whew.
Do you think
they're too hot?
Oh, how could you be
too hot?
My publisher said the jacket
photo is really important.
People see the author,
and it gives them a sense
of what they're gonna get
if they buy the book.
Well, I'd buy pretty much
anything from this woman.
I'm serious.
So am I.
Hey, tonight, um, maybe
you could wear this dress?
Oh, my god.
And I could pretend that I was
a fan at the book signing
and the bookstore was closing.
Hmm?
Okay... first of all,
that's not my dress.
What?
Second of all, it would take
a stylist and an hour
to get my hair
to look that way again.
Oh. Mm.
These don't even
look like me.
They got you all worked up.
Mm-hmm.
You know what? I think you like
the fake, glammed-up me
better than the real thing.
Oh, come on, Violet.
Stop it.
You know what? These--
these are no good.
And you're no good.
Get out. Get out.
I'm--i-i--you got--
no, I cannot possibly get in
trouble for thinking that you--
you know what? Get out.
Get out.
If you like them so much...
Take them with you.
Okay. Thank you.
Wait. What?
They want to use their baby
as an egg farm.
Severe hypoplastic left heart
syndrome is a death sentence.
Well, yes. We're all gonna die
eventually, but I doubt
that means that you're prepared
to donate an organ today.
Stop. You're not seriously
discussing this?
Charlotte, you can't let that
happen at St. ambrose.
Why not?
Look, if it's publicity
you're after and--and you think
this is gonna translate
into funds,
then I can have the foundation
give the hospital money.
Would it achieve notoriety
for the hospital? Absolutely.
Would we be effectively
performing a miracle? Yes.
And most importantly,
we could be altering
assisted reproductive
technology forever.
That's why I want to do it.
But it is morally wrong.
Not everyone
shares your compass.
But you know that.
Addison, if there's something
personal that you want--
okay, could we just stay
on topic for a second?
You are going
way off the rails here.
Cooper.
In utero surgery can rupture
the mother's uterus, right?
It could.
Which she would need
if she wants to--
carry her baby's baby.
I was gonna say have another
baby, but, you know, yuck.
What if we wait
till the baby's born?
So that a baby that's gonna live
maybe a day
can spend that day enduring
painful abdominal surgery?
The cards are dealt.
I'm just suggesting
we create something good
out of a nasty situation.
We shouldn't do this.
Addison, you shouldn't do this.
Hey, long night?
I was out
with my friend Michelle.
I finally convinced her
to take
the huntington's d.N.A. Test.
Is she seeing Violet
or Sheldon?
Neither.
I told her to come in,
we'd just do the test,
find out one way or another.
There's a 50% chance she'll find
out she's gonna die, Amelia.
She needs counseling
before that test.
She's strong.
She'll be fine.
This is why doctor's
shouldn't treat their friends.
I'm doing this
because I'm her friend.
I'm thinking I want to
check out Naples.
It's time for another stamp
on my passport.
Ooh, Italian men.
Spicy. When you gonna go?
If I'm negative,
I'll go in the fall.
If I'm positive,
it's all over, right?
No, if you're positive,
you'll have 10 years, 20,
maybe more.
I know how it works--
early onset, late onset,
every complication.
There's all sorts of ifs,
but one thing is for sure.
From the day my mother was
diagnosed, it was a nightmare
that got worse and worse
until the day that she died.
And that was a relief.
And I...
I don't want to wait
for the horror show to start.
What does that mean?
If I'm positive,
I'm gonna kill myself.
All right.
I know that--
I think that--
oh...
You first.
Things are a little tense...
After, uh...
Our night on the deck.
It was--it was...
Just felt comfortable...
Mm-hmm.
And, uh, familiar,
and we were just nostalgic.
And that's okay.
Don't patronize me, Naomi.
I--
okay?
I'm not chasing after you.
I just want to know
if you think it was
something more
than nostalgia.
Or are you still
thinking about Archer?
Uh, no, Sam. No.
So you mean to tell me
that you didn't feel anything
when we were out there
all alone...
Aren't you two
supposed to be divorced?
Goo-goo eyes,
hushed tones...
It's good to see you,
Gabriel.
You don't mean that.
No, I don't.
Did she tell you about
the African lilies?
I thought they were impactful.
Speaking of which--
she's allergic. Okay.
Well, I've got patients.
I'm sure you two have a lot
of... catching up to do.
Have dinner with me
tonight?
I-I can't.
Lunch?
No, i--there's no time.
I will sit here and continue
to propose meals,
Espresso, crudités,
whatever it takes--
until you say yes.
I'm very patient.
I already told you. I like
that first set of pictures.
Come on, Cooper.
Help me. Which one?
See, I know
how this turns out.
I say,
"the blue one looks nice,"
and you say,
"just nice not great?"
And then I say, "no. You look
great in everything you wear."
And then you say,
"you don't really sound like
you mean that." So I say,
"no, it's not that. I just
like the other one better."
And then we get to the part
where you say,
"you think I look fat in this,
don't you?"
And then I'm sleeping
on the couch.
You do realize
that I'm not Charlotte?
If you asked for help, I would
at least take it seriously.
This is important to me.
Please.
Okay. The blue one.
Ooh, you think so?
Hey, Sheldon.
Do you have a minute?
Don't pick the blue one.
Uh...
I'm slammed.
We just need a minute.
- We?
- Please.
Dr. Montgomery, we are
desperate to be a family.
Giving birth, uh,
is not the only way.
Have you two
discussed adoption?
I need to be a mother
to a child
that came from inside of me,
a child that is a part of us.
It may be irrational,
but--
I understand that you want
to have a baby.
Frank and I have
been together 20 years.
And at first, we were young.
You know,
we wanted to do things,
and then our careers--
you get off the fast track,
you lose your place.
Finally, we were ready,
and after spending
every dime we had on I.V.F.,
two miscarriages
in the second trimester.
But when this baby
finally made it to 24 weeks,
we--we thought...
We--we thought
it would be okay.
But it's not,
because our baby will be lucky
to get a full day of life.
So either god really hates us,
or she made it this far
for a reason.
You know, women think
that they can have it all.
They can just wait and decide
when the time is right,
but we're wrong.
Okay.
You'll do it?
I can't guarantee
that it'll work.
It's never been done before.
And I won't risk your life
or risk perforating your uterus,
so I will do the surgery,
but after your baby's born,
not before.
Thank you.
You okay?
Michelle's test results.
I'm sorry.
I pushed her...
To find out, and now...
She's gonna kill herself,
Pete.
She's going to be devastated,
but--
no, she has already decided.
People say things. They--
Michelle knows
what is coming.
She saw what it did
to her mother.
I mean, she has seen
the clumsiness,
then it gets hard to swallow,
your muscles go rigid,
the seizures and dementia--
I mean, I don't blame her,
but I have
been through this before--
losing somebody close to me
way too soon.
And maybe it is selfish--
it's not selfish.
You care about her.
But as good a friend as you are,
it's not enough anymore.
You need
to get her some help. Now.
No, I am serious.
Where'd you go?
I got a giant Grant
from the only place
that has more money
than you now.
The government.
Oh.
Mm-hmm.
Impressive.
No, what's impressive is,
I left my big, fancy office
at the n.I.H.
With lots of cute
little doctors fawning over me
to come back and get you.
To get me?
Come on, Naomi.
We have great chemistry.
You can't argue with science.
I'm... very fond of you.
But, uh...
This just isn't
the right time.
Please don't tell me
I'm competing with a dead man.
With William? No.
No, I just...
Um... my life has
certain complications right now.
Oh.
Oh? What "oh"?
That's code for "Sam."
No.
Naomi, you can
talk to me, about anything,
even Sam.
If you want to woo me,
discussing my ex-husband
i-is not the way to do it.
Okay?
You gonna do something?
I don't know.
Well, I want a banana.
You know, it's customary
for the boyfriend to offer
comfort in this situation.
Well, my comfort
isn't always... comforting.
Well, sometimes you just
have to plow through it.
Mm.
And sometimes
you just need to avoid.
Thank you.
Oh, keep it. Really.
Oh.
Okay.
You know, i'm--I'm okay,
you know.
I mean, it's not like
we were close or anything.
Well, sometimes
that makes it harder
than when
the relationship was good
and there were
no unresolved issues,
nothing left unsaid.
But it's not like anything's
even setting this off.
I am crying
because we're out of sweetener.
I mean, it's--it's like
my tear ducts
are acting on their own.
I just...
I just want it to be over.
Grief has its own timeline.
Wait, wait, wait.
What does that mean?
You can't get off
till the ride stops.
Even in college, you had
a killer poker face.
Michelle--
you know, the day
my mother was diagnosed
was the worst day of my life,
but today--
today could actually top it.
Okay.
I'm ready.
You're negative.
What?
You don't have it.
You're not gonna get
huntington's disease.
Oh, my god.
Oh, my god!
You lied to her
about the test results?
Pete, I told you.
She said she would kill herself,
and she was serious.
And I told you that when you
have a suicidal patient,
you refer them to a therapist.
You don't lie.
No, you do
when it is in the best interest
of your patient.
You're letting your friendship
get in the way
of your medical training.
You're just
trying to justify this.
You were right.
You are being selfish.
One day--maybe sooner,
maybe later--
but one day she is gonna die
a shell of who she is.
But right now, Michelle is
healthy and happy,
and she can stay that way
for ten years, even more.
So as her doctor
and as her friend,
I need to protect her from pain
for as long as I can,
because neither of us
wants to give up yet,
not while she can still
go out dancing and travel
and tell jokes
that are so stupid
that they pull me out of
the blackest places I go.
As long as there is no treatment
for huntington's disease,
the best medicine
that I can offer her
is to tell her that
she won't get it at all.
What are you gonna tell Michelle
when she wakes up with symptoms?
I'm gonna ask...
Did you enjoy
the time you had?
And hope to god she says yes.
Hey. Oh, cookies.
Oh, my god.
These are good.
They're crunchy,
but the chocolate's still soft.
I know.
I'm keeping 'em over there
'cause I already had three.
Better be
from a grateful patient
and not some secret boyfriend.
"We're forever thankful for your
help. Frank and isobelle."
No.
Addison's gonna wait until
after the baby's born--
that's worse, Charlotte!
It's a baby!
With a life--
a tragically short one,
but that is a life.
How are we not
on the same side here?
Because you're
ignoring the fact
that this could help make
another longer life.
I can't believe
you'd be a part of this.
So my publisher
needed these, like, yesterday.
Do any of these work?
Well, you look great.
Really?
Mm-hmm.
You kidding?
You look trustworthy, smart.
Yes, definitely.
Trustworthy and smart.
Cooper?
Yeah, they're good.
What's with the book?
It's a psych textbook.
I can see that,
but how often do you sit
at the edge of your desk
with it
in your hand like that?
Well, the photographer
thought this staging
would make me look
more... respectable.
What, you don't like it?
No.
It's just, you look like
you're about
two seconds away
from hurling it at a patient.
Well, you do look
a bit intense.
Which is not necessarily
a bad thing. Is it?
I'd buy a book
written by this woman,
in fact, I'd even pay
hardcover price.
But if you're asking...
This isn't you, Violet.
You're not some uptight, stodgy
therapist who looks like this.
You're open and welcoming.
You sit on your couch
all curled up drinking tea,
making people
feel like they know you.
I mean, that's who you are.
It's a good thing.
It's--it's why
your patients love you.
Hey.
Do you have a minute?
Oh, isobelle's water
just broke.
I was just on my way to
the hospital to check on her.
Addison, you're really
gonna do this?
You're gonna harvest
that baby's eggs?
That baby's gonna die.
At least this way,
isobelle and frank--
no, no,
just forget about them.
They are blinded by their
desire to become parents--
a desire which they clearly
do not understand.
Who does understand it?
It's some
psycho-biological impulse
that's hardwired into us.
Well, it's also
a responsibility.
That they seem
fully prepared to accept.
I mean, Nai, where--
where is this coming from?
You've devoted your whole life
to helping women
who can't conceive
on their own conceive.
No, this is different.
It's experimental.
No, this is Nazi Germany
and--and tuskegee
all rolled into one.
We are scientists
trying to progress.
They want a baby. We might
be able to give them one.
By allowing them to treat
the baby that they have now
like it's already dead?
Addison, you can't do this.
I want to.
But--o-okay. For whom?
Addison...
You're grieving your mother,
and you desperately
want a baby,
and if you can help them,
maybe it means
that down the road,
you might get one, too.
I know you're not questioning
my judgment.
Maybe I am.
You've been questioning mine.
There are lines
that we shouldn't cross.
Unless our teenage daughter
becomes pregnant.
Oh, wow.
When did I stop knowing you?
Do you have a minute?
Do I have a choice?
Um...
I'm--I'm not
a romantic person.
Here it comes.
I'm a--
I'm a practical person.
I'm the person
who looks around
and sees what needs
to be accomplished,
and then gets it done.
When William was dying,
I-I fed him,
and I cleaned him,
and I did what I had to do.
When my marriage to Sam
was over,
I was the one who took care
of all the details
so that we could both
just move on.
You carry
a lot of responsibility.
And Addison--
you know, I...
I have loved her
like a sister,
and I have forgiven her
all her flaws
because I-I know--
I know that she is doing
the best that she can.
Again, a heavy burden.
And it feels heavy. God.
Mm.
Why is it then
that when--when I was--
when I was traveling the world
and--and doing all of
the foundation business
and solving serious problems,
i-i...
I felt so light?
Because the problems
you were solving
weren't your own.
Yeah.
Fife says
he's in love with me.
Well, how do you feel
about that?
Well, you know, he makes me
laugh, and that feels good.
Recently,
Sam and I had a...
A moment,
and, uh, I don't know.
No. You know what? No.
I-I do not want
to revisit the past.
I just--
so, uh, what do you want?
I don't know. I want simple.
I-I want to go
and build hospitals in India.
I want to vaccinate
African children.
Is that all?
So go build and vaccinate
and--and--and just...
Go.
Ow! Mm.
It's okay, isobelle.
It hurts. Is it supposed
to hurt that much?
Unfortunately, yes.
Keep breathing.
Try to stay calm.
Oh, oh, oh.
The baby's cord
is prolapsed.
The baby's in distress.
We need to do a c-section.
Oh, help her!
Please help our baby.
Okay, okay.
You're okay. You're okay.
Oh! Ow!
...every time.
I do n--
what?
As a recovering addict,
you know... honesty
is always the best choice.
This from a man
who tried to convince me
a patient could see when she
was actually still blind?
So Pete told me about
your friend. I'm so sorry.
Thank you.
But you shouldn't
have lied to her.
She's living her life.
I'm helping her.
You're deceiving her,
and--and she's living
someone else's life.
Of course you would
take his side.
No, i'm--I'm taking
your friend's side.
She's--she's gonna need people
that she can--that she can trust
down the line
when she becomes symptomatic.
I hope
she can still trust you.
If I tell her the truth,
she will take her own life.
Well...
Show her a reason to live
and bring her in here
where she can get the therapy
she really needs.
Can I help you?
Naomi can't move forward
while you're still holding on.
Or she's just not
that into you.
You had her and you let her go.
That was your mistake.
Now you need to do
the right thing for her.
You mean for you.
I mean for all of us.
You are an arrogant bastard.
Why don't you go back
to where you came from?
I intend to, with Naomi.
Is she okay?
I mean, I know that she's...
But is she okay?
She is resting.
Have you thought about
a name?
When can you do
the surgery?
W-Wouldn't you like
to meet her first?
Just remove her ovaries.
You said you would do it.
We need you to do it now.
Hey.
You can't tell, you know?
She looks just like
all the other preemies.
I wonder what she would've
grown up to be.
Cooper, don't.
Don't go there.
How can you not?
I have to take her now.
Okay.
Here we go.
Where are the parents?
They don't want to meet her.
Oh, they're cowards.
They're worse.
It's their right.
What about her rights?
What about her life?
She won't last the day.
So what?
We're all gonna die.
We have no idea when.
And they just...
They say they want
to be parents,
but parenting is more than
onesies and bassinets.
It's a lifelong commitment,
no matter how long or short
that life is.
Cooper.
They don't deserve her.
Okay. All right.
Sheldon.
Hey.
Just the man
I've been looking for.
Oh, sorry. I'm busy.
It'll just take a sec.
I said no, Charlotte.
I am sorry,
but I am tired of being
the sounding board
for all the women
around here.
I can't solve everyone's
problems, nor do I want to.
I have a life of my own.
Listen, I'm a man
and a therapist.
I like to believe that
that makes me sensitive.
But do I care
what dress you wear?
I mean, I've become the guy
who's not your boyfriend,
who gets treated like
a boyfriend when it comes to
the annoying things
that boyfriends don't want
to deal with, but they have to
because if they don't,
they don't get any sex,
but still... I just--
please just keep
your problems to yourself,
or at least
just away from me.
I am resigning
as the not-boyfriend boyfriend.
Well, I'm sorry
to hear that.
Pass it on.
I will.
I-I guess I'll get
your check another time.
Fund-raiser for
the pediatric oncology unit.
You pledged $1,000.
You need to step up.
With your women.
Mine's not complaining.
You both have amazing women
in your lives,
you get all the perks,
but you need to be there
for the neuroses
and the insecurities
and the existential crises
that plague them.
I-I don't want to pick out
Violet's photo shoot wardrobe.
And--and Addison is grieving
and Naomi is--
Naomi's not one of ours.
What?
I-I can't be
the not-boyfriend boyfriend.
Just--not anymore.
It sounds to me like you just
need to be a boyfriend.
Look, I live with Violet's
neuroses every day
and every night.
And Sam gets
more than his share--
Whew.
This is not about us.
What he's trying to say is,
you need to find
a woman of your own.
But since, according to you,
I have two, I'm the expert,
and I say, join a monastery.
I'm sorry.
Okay.
Guess what I just did.
New sundress for Naples.
And--new hat.
Wanna come?
Michelle...
I lied.
About the test.
You have the huntington's gene.
But y-you said...
I know. I'm sorry.
You lied to me?
I was just afraid. You said
you'd kill yourself, and...
Don't, because if you hug me
right now,
you're doing it
because you're sad for me,
but you can't be sad for me
before I'm sad for me,
and I can't be sad for me,
because...
I'm too scared to be sad.
I am so scared.
Michelle--
I never
want to see you again.
What are you doing?
This is your baby.
Maybe not the one you hoped for,
but... she's still yours.
No, please. Please don't--
don't do this.
You said you were desperate
to be parents. Are you?
Don't you get it?
If--if we don't--
we loved every baby
that didn't come to be.
We named the first two--
David and Rebecca.
But now... We...
If--if we meet her,
we'll bond.
You want to be parents,
right?
Not for a day.
You want to be parents?
Here's your chance.
If we do this,
we're gonna have to grieve.
You'll have to grieve anyway.
There's nothing you can do
about that.
At least this way
you'll know that...
You did the one thing
you could.
Oh.
♪ ...lifting off,
leaving the world behind ♪
♪ I take a window seat ♪
♪ so all I see is sky ♪
We're not doing
the procedure, are we?
Oh, baby.
♪ Tell me I'm not up here ♪
♪ all alone ♪
♪ did I just leave
so you would come to me? ♪
♪ Did I make you up
just so I could... ♪
No.
We're not doing this.
Just give me one minute.
One minute, and then
you never have to see me
or hear from me again,
I promise!
♪ Before a dream ♪
♪ why do I ♪
♪ why do I have ♪
♪ to leave to see? ♪
I didn't expect my father
to die.
He was gonna live forever
'cause that's what dads do.
And then one day he went to work
and he got shot.
Are you trying to make me
feel better?
Because you're not.
What I'm saying...
Life is hard.
There's no way to predict
what's gonna happen.
Someone could back out
of their driveway tomorrow
and mow me down,
and I will be dead before you.
I mean, right now
is all anybody has.
Right this minute.
And, yes,
this diagnosis
is unspeakably cruel...
And living with it will be
a daily struggle,
but as long as the good days
outnumber the bad,
you gotta live those days.
I mean, why would you give up
rocky road ice cream
before you have to...
Or swimming in the ocean,
or... driving?
I mean, god, driving with
the top down on a sunny day--
I mean, that has gotta be
worth living for.
♪♪♪
It is.
Right now, when you say it,
it is.
But when you're not here
cheering me on...
How am I
gonna make it through this?
♪♪♪
Well, first off,
I am your friend,
and I will be here
cheering you on
until you take
your last breath.
But you can also...
You need to talk to someone
who can help.
I work
with amazing therapists.
And then...
When the day comes
that your life
really is not worth living
anymore...
When it is worse than even
rocky road can fix...
♪ Did I make you up
just so I could believe ♪
♪ a hopeless notion ♪
Then I will kill you myself.
♪ Why do I ♪
♪ why do I have ♪
♪ to leave to see? ♪
♪ Did I just leave
so you would come to me? ♪
So this isn't crazy?
No, I think it's brave
and, you know,
honest and real.
Look, you didn't shy away from
the tough parts of your story
because you knew it was
the only way to help people
who don't have your strength,
so...
Make yourself vulnerable.
Okay.
Let's do it.
Ready?
♪ To leave to see ♪
♪ Leave to see ♪
We have a child
and a grandchild.
Well, that's not it.
Well--or maybe it's all of it,
but we both know that
it's more than just nostalgia.
Yeah,
but, Sam, we can't keep
just returning to the well
that is us
when things go bad.
It's... it's gotta change.
Fife?
He's the, uh, the change
you're looking for?
Because he basically
just challenged me to a duel.
Yeah. Apparently,
he's under the impression
that I'm the only thing
that's keeping you two apart,
which makes me think you're not
being totally honest about us.
But there is no us, Sam.
Despite what happened,
there's...
Anything you guys
want to tell me?
Not everything's about you,
Addison.
Did something happen
between you two?
You know what? Your boyfriend
was my husband for 17 years.
He married me, I had his child,
so unless you ever hit
those milestones,
my relationship with Sam
will always trump yours.
What's going on with you,
Naomi?
You know,
here's what's going on--
Maya and Olivia,
they are my life.
That's why I came back here,
but... here isn't good for me.
Here is just fraught
with manipulation
and cheating and...
Sam, you basically offered
to kill a man for Charlotte,
and--and Pete lied
about a patient's blindness,
and, god, a pregnant junkie
came to St. ambrose,
and instead of helping her,
we bought her baby.
I mean, what...
That's not us, is it?
I mean, I'm not perfect.
I'm not saying
that I'm perfect. I'm not.
But since when do we
do things like that?
Just coming back here,
I'm just not sure anymore...
How far is too far
for everyone?
I'm sorry. I just...
Nothing feels right
here anymore.
I wish it did,
but it just doesn't.
I can't...
I just can't be here.
Come with me, then.
Oh.
I was over you.
Over you, back at the n.I.H.
Doing the kind of work I love,
and they were happy
to have me back,
excited about the cutting-edge
research I was doing for them.
They threw money at me--
research grants, post-docs,
unlimited lab resources.
It was a dream job,
and I had it all.
I had everything.
Almost everything.
I quit my job.
I walked out on them.
Sold my place
and everything I own,
and I came out here
to be with you.
You're my past, Gabriel.
You're all my past.
♪ So like your ♪
♪ father in the face ♪
♪ and blood ♪
♪ terrified ♪
♪ and cold ♪
I'm fine.
Cooper.
I said I'm fine.
I think what I think,
Coop.
But I never
want to hurt you.
♪ For you ♪
♪ ooh ♪
♪ ooh, ooh, ooh ♪
♪ ooh, ooh ♪
♪ You hide your ♪
♪ Filthy hands
from all of us ♪
I know you told everybody
not to mention the tears,
but really, I mean,
it freaks me out.
♪♪♪
Well, now i'm...
I actually am crying
because...
My mother killed herself.
♪ Still you run ♪
Well, that...
Does not freak me out.
♪ ...to be changed from ♪
There were so many times...
That I had wished
she'd just...
Disappear.
And now
I would give anything...
For one more conversation,
just one more chance
to talk to her.
♪♪♪
What would you say to her?
♪ ...a silver ring ♪
There's nothing trashy
about twirling the Baton.
What?
When I was 10...
The uniforms were cute
and the batons were sparkly,
and what the hell
did it matter anyway?
But bizzy said no.
Actually, she said,
"over my dead body."
♪ From you ♪
So...
Should I get you a Baton?
♪ And the tomb ♪
Hey.
♪ Ah ♪
♪ like water rushing over us ♪
Hey.
♪ The tide
pulls from the moon ♪
♪ the tide