The Greek myths loved to talk
about the perils of hubris,
the dangers of believing
you can outrun
the will of the gods.
How is she
still out there?
It's already 100 degrees.
She just barely left
that chair in six weeks.
Grief doesn't care that it's
the hottest spring on record.
One of us
needs to go out there.
She can't be late
on her first day back.
Or pass out from heatstroke.
Not it.
How long has she been
- out there?
- Too long.
I wish there were something
we could do for her.
Yeah, bring her sister back
from the dead.
- I'm being serious.
- I am, too.
I knew it. Just not ready.
Ready for what?
As surgeons, we need hubris
just to get through the day.
Come on, losers.
Let's ride.
We have to believe
we can fix people,
even with the odds stacked
against us.
Okay.♪ Life goes on and on
Oh, sorry.
Uh, Nora,
- what are you doing here?
- Hi.
I was going to text you.
I have a follow-up with Teddy.
Well, had.
I just heard it was canceled,
and now my car won't start.
And I've been on hold with
the tow company for 20 minutes.
Oh, well,
if they're as busy as we are,
you going to wait a while.
You should get out
- of this heat.
- No kidding.
My 10-year-old baked cookies
on the hood of my car yesterday.
- Didn't we do that once?
- Yeah, on your porch.
And then the dough sat
there for an hour,
doing nothing,
and then your dog ate them.
That's right.
I should get back in here.
It's like your Bat-Signal.
Are you calling me
a superhero?
You did save my life.
Technically,
that was Teddy.
Anyway, there... there's
a cooling center in the clinic,
so you're more than welcome
to wait there... Okay.
...and, uh, yeah,
good luck with your car.
- Thank you.
- Yeah.
Humility makes you good,
but ego makes you great.
I got the two
last iced coffees on Earth,
and one is for you.
I have this amazing case.
Some might call it
impossible,
which is where I'm focusing
my energy right now,
but there is
a cardiothoracic component,
and I thought, who better
to do it with than, uh...
Thanks again
for last night.
Call me.
Thank you.
Sorry about that.
Hm. I'm sorry
about your coffee.
If that means flying
a little too close to the sun,
well, that's a risk
we're willing to take.
Yasuda.
How are you feeling?
Any pain?
A little, not much.
Okay.
You still taking meds?
Just NSAIDs.
And PT? Benching 180.
Kidding.
I have the upper-body strength
of a jellyfish.
Listen, it can be hard
coming back to a place
where something traumatic
happened,
so just be patient
with yourself.
Thanks,
but what I need is routine.
I'm... I'm ready
to get back to work.
Okay, then,
welcome back.
We have expected high of 108.
That means a full E.R.,
lots of heat-related illness,
especially amongst
the most vulnerable populations.
Fortunately, we have
some extra local doctors
who have agreed
to help us out.
Please show them
a warm welcome.
We have cool IV fluids,
misters,
and inflatable ice baths.
Use them.
Cold immersion is
the fastest way
to lower internal body
temperatures.
All elective surgeries
have been canceled
until further notice.
Looks like your surgery
- just went up in flames.
- Be on the lookout for any
of the following symptoms...
cramping, nausea, vomiting,
dizziness, headaches.
Take care of yourselves,
hydrate,
and we will get through this.
Let's get back to work.
I know that you've been on
since yesterday,
but you need
to take a break.
- I'm good for now.
- Okay.
Guess I should find
my patient.
Come on. I'll introduce you
- before she has to leave.
- Okay.
Hey, Chief, uh,
I'm on your service,
and I'm ready to be
the best surgical wingman
- you've ever seen.
- I'm glad you're here,
but no scrubbing in today.
Today, I need
first-responder Ben Warren.
You'll be managing overflow.
You want me on admin?
What I need today is someone
who is good in a crisis.
I want you to communicate
with the command center
and update me as needed.
Can't imagine having
- to give birth in this heat.
- Yeah.
Or, you know, ever.
Turns out extreme heat
can cause preterm labor,
so that's fun.
- You know what's more fun?
- What?
The guy can't fix
our AC today.
Then call a different guy.
I've tried like 10 guys.
They're all slammed.
The kids can't sleep
in 90-degree heat.
I can't sleep
Fortunately,
we don't have to.
We could get a hotel
for the night,
or I could find us a house
to rent.
Damn it.
Can you just figure it out?
Jackie, Sky.
This is Dr. Winston Ndugu,
our chief
of cardiothoracic surgery.
He has agreed to work
on Jackie's case with me.
- Oh, my God, you're the guy.
- Jackie.
- You ghosted my mom.
- Oh, no.
I recognize you
from the profile on the app.
My mom showed it to me
in case she went missing.
Hello again.
If you want another doctor,
I can...
No, no, I have bigger things
to worry about
than a guy
I went out with once.
As long as you're excellent
at your job, I'm good.
Okay,
Jackie Williams, 18,
recently diagnosed
with Marfan syndrome,
a connective tissue disorder
that weakens blood vessels.
She has three brain aneurysms
as well as an aortic aneurysm.
I got a full ride
to Georgia Tech for basketball.
A week later,
I get this diagnosis.
And they're telling us
that they have to push
Jackie's surgery?
The hospital needs to
dedicate all resources
to the heat dome.
Her father died of a ruptured
brain aneurysm at 27.
Now we know it was
probably Marfan, too.
We'd really like
to get this taken care of.
We should sneak her
into CT just to take a look.
Thank you, Dr. Ndugu.
Least I can do.
No crap.
I thought you
were seeing Beltran.
I'm seeing a few people.
Clearly.
I'm really glad
that you're back.
If you need anything... Don't. I'm good. Really.
- Let's go.
- You're with me.
Carl Halcomb, 52,
was operating a crane
when it collapsed
on the apartment building.
Temp in the field
was 109.
Fluid and cooling measures
initiated en route.
Temp currently at 106,
and he's still altered.
Alright, we need to get
his temperature down fast.
My nephew... shaggy hair...
is he...?
He was on the phone.
- I tried to yell.
- We've got him.
David Holcomb.
20-year-old male.
Crush injuries to
the abdomen and right upper.
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
- whoa, whoa, whoa.
- Go, go, go, go, go.
He's burning up.
Let's get a gurney out here.
Get everybody inside,
and page for more hands.
Oh, Lord help us.
I'm guessing shooting guard.
That's a position
in basketball.
She thinks she's funny.
No. She's right.
Um, huge Storm fan.
Sue Bird's my idol.
Excuse me. Blue.
Dr. Kwan.
We'll meet you in CT. Yeah.
Hi.
What are you doing here?
I heard about
the heat dome,
and I hopped on a plane
to come help.
That was a lie. I'm sorry.
I don't know why I said that.
Is everything okay?
Dave proposed.
He, um, proposed,
and I immediately came here.
Like, ever since that day
that you kissed me,
I just haven't been able
to get you out of my head,
and I don't know what to do,
so I just thought...
I don't know what I thought,
but I had to see you.
I...
This is not a good time.
Can we...
No, you're busy.
I don't want to keep you.
Sky. Jackie's on her way
to CT now.
Thanks.
Uh, my divorce was
more amicable than most,
but, still,
it's been rough,
so I-I've been trying
to get back out there,
and I'm just not ready
for anything serious right now.
That's what I should've
told you after our date.
For the record,
I never used the term "ghosting"
with my daughter.
Either way, I messed up.
I'm sorry.
Dating as a single mom,
it isn't exactly
a pleasure cruise,
but none of that matters now.
Since Jackie's symptoms
started,
all my energy
is going to making sure
that she gets the best care.
Well, you've come
to the right place.
Jackie's my whole world.
You can ghost me.
That's fine.
But you do not mess around
with my girl.
I wouldn't dream of it.
Okay,
nephew's in trauma one.
- How's he doing?
- Temp's 105,
Heart rate's rising, and
Adams got the last ice bath.
- Sorry.
- My nephew...
please say he's okay.
- Did I kill him?
- We'll try to find out.
He's delirious.
We have to cool him
down quickly
or he'd risk
permanent organ damage.
I need a body bag and ice
right now.
The E.R.'s out
of body bags.
Do you want me to...
go to the morgue?
No. I want you to run
- to the morgue.
- Okay.
- I can go by myself.
- I want to help.
Sir? Sir?
Uh, Adams,
give me an intubation tray.
He's got
an unstable humerus.
There's free fluid
in the abdomen.
I heard you might need
some help in here.
I brought some visitors.
Dr. Walters, Nurse Constantine,
and Dr. Beckman.
I thought
Dr. Beckman was... A man?
That'd be my husband.
I'm just helping out
for the day.
Dr. Hunt,
wondered if I'd see you.
What happened here?
Uh, poor kid
wasn't paying attention.
Crane fell on him.
That's a hell
of a wake-up call.
We should get him to C.T.
before...
BP's tanking.
Guess we'll go straight
into surgery.
Who's going to help me
find an O.R.?
What? No bossy women
in your lives?
- Come on.
- Deal with the arm later.
Let's go.
My patient's
got a temperature of 105.
Oh, yeah? Well, mine's
104 and pregnant.
You know, pregnancy
doesn't automatically
trump everything else.
Well, I trump you,
so I should get
the rest of the ice.
No, no, no, no, no, no.
That's my ice.
Oh. There's a machine
in the attendings' lounge.
- Try there.
- Empty.
The cafeteria, then?
ICU? Dermatology?
Okay, I will be
the adult and order some.
Thank you.
Oh, you know what?
There's a convenience store
over on Pine.
You should probably just...
faster to go.
Why are you bossing me
around?
Because I'm dealing
with overflow for Chief,
we barely have enough orderlies,
and, well, you know,
we need ice.
Load as much as you can
in your car
and just hurry back.
I didn't drive today.
Okay, we'll take my car.
It's nice in here.
Quiet. Peaceful.
Which one do you think
was Chloe's?
I don't know.
I bet she was happy here.
She always liked
cold weather.
Mika?
Come on. We keep this guy
waiting any longer,
we'll kill him, too.
How's Molly?
Adams swore me to secrecy.
Molly is... deciding if she
wants to marry her boyfriend.
Do you still have feelings
for her?
Too much has happened.
It would be impossible
to make it work now.
Maybe it wouldn't be
as hard as you think.
How much longer
do I have to be in here?
I'm supposed to be in Georgia
right now,
starting team workouts,
but instead I'm sitting
in this giant tube
with blood bombs in my brain.
Well, maybe when
this is all done,
you could look into
a low-contact sport.
Basketball's the only thing
I've ever loved,
so I'm not letting
it go that easy.
After all this is over,
I'm going to find a way to play.
Good luck convincing
a pro team
to take that kind of risk
on you.
Scans are up.
Let's see
what we've got.
Okay. The aortic root aneurysm
definitely needs surgery ASAP.
Okay,
this is the brain CTA.
Right, there's two on the MCA.
There's one aneurysm on the ACA.
Damn it. See this one
in the posterior circulation?
That is on the basilar artery.
- That's new.
- And big.
Mm-hmm. Yeah,
that's Godzilla on steroids.
We need to embolize
that immediately.
Do you do it
endovascularly?
If we can get
the right angle.
If not,
we'll have to convert to open.
And I'm going to need
you to put her on bypass.
Uh, no, it'd be too much
stress on the heart.
It could cause
the aortic aneurysm to rupture.
I mean, this could rupture
at any second.
If that explodes,
she's brain-dead.
So what do we tell the mom?
We tell her I will go in
endovascularly,
and we pray that
I don't have to open her up.
I don't understand.
I thought that
all surgeries were postponed.
Well, her case is now
considered emergent.
You said that
the brain aneurysm could wait.
This new one is larger
than the others.
And in a more
concerning location.
Does that mean
that it's harder to fix?
Mom, don't freak out.
I was going to need
this anyway,
and she's the only doctor
who actually said yes.
Are you sure you
can still do this?
This aneurysm is difficult,
but it's the same game, and I've
been playing for a long time.
I know how to do this.
Do we have to decide
right now?
I'd like to proceed
sooner than later.
You should take a minute
- to think about it.
- Kwan.
I know my word might not hold
a lot of weight right now,
but Jackie does need
this surgery,
and you want Dr. Shepherd
to do it.
I promise.
It's my only shot.
Then I guess
you better take it.
We should clear the air.
I'm sorry?
I am sorry for what happened
with Teddy.
We should get in there.
Look, what happened was
not my finest moment.
I don't typically go around
kissing other people's wives.
We were just having
a good time,
and it was
a misunderstanding.
And it was
my misunderstanding.
You know,
no apology necessary.
I trust my wife.
She told me it was nothing,
and I believe her.
We're good.
Okay. Hm.
Wait. What would you
have done just now
if Teddy hadn't told me
about the kiss?
Crawled under a rock
and died.
- Chief. Chief.
- Seattle Pres's generator failed
and a semi-truck blew a tire
and caused a 15-car pileup
on the 5.
That means
more incoming traumas
and staff caught
in traffic.
So, uh,
it's not a great time
to tell you
that the ICU is full, huh?
I have 700 problems.
I need you to bring me
the solutions.
Okay, we can send overflow
to the PACU,
and I can put out
another request to nurses
to come in
on their day off.
Great.
- Make that happen.
- Alright.
Oh, uh, also,
the ice delivery is delayed.
Already sent someone
to get more.
Thank you.
Yeah, this is Altman.
Hey, you got any ice?
Yeah, it's in the back
if there's any left.
Ooh. Yum.
What? I haven't had
any breakfast yet.
What? We drove across
the Sahara for this?
We got to go somewhere else.
This is not going to...
Open the register...
now.
Get down. Get down.
- Oh, my God.
- I said open it.
Okay, um... Hurry up.
Okay, okay.
Just please don't hurt me.
You know what's worse than
burning or freezing to death?
Burning and freezing
to death.
Please stop.
Uh, core temp is coming down.
Slowly.
Millin, we have, uh,
incoming traumas.
Go give Altman a hand.
Okay.
Um, BP is falling.
Are those ST elevations?
He just went into v-fib.
Ah, he's having
a heart attack.
Okay, Yasuda,
get a crash cart.
Yas... Uh, anyone?
Crash cart? Now.
He's... He's dying.
That is what the crash cart
is for.
Okay, Carl, stay with us.
Give me the pads.
Okay.
Okay. Right,
we're going to charge to 150.
Clear.
It's not working.
You're losing him.
You're letting him die.
Okay, charge again
to 200.
Okay, clear.
Dr. Bailey, he's dying.
Hey, don't you think
I know that?
Go again. Clear.
- He's dying.
- Damn.
Aren't you supposed
to be a doctor?
He is dying.
You are letting him die.
You just can't let him die
like that.
You can't just let him die.
You have to save her.
Save her.
Just please save her.
Just... Just...
Just save her. Please.
You have to save her.
Please. Just take me.
Dr. Bailey,
just take me.
Just take me.
Going again.
Clear.
Got him back.
Chief, ICU is full.
PACU is full.
I think it's time
we considered moving
intubated patients
into the E.R.
We don't have the staff
to manage that.
With the outage, a few towers
have been knocked out,
and I can't get through
to anyone.
I need to talk to you
- about Yasuda.
- Okay.
We're kind of in
the middle of something.
She wants to work, but
she's not even close to ready.
- I have to bench her.
- Okay.
Offer her extra time off.
She has been through
so much.
She shouldn't come back
until she feels ready.
- Agreed. Thank you.
- Yep.
Chief, I've got
critical patients and
no place to put them.
Alright, we are going to
have to divert traumas.
You want to send
patients away?
No, but we don't have
the resources.
I know you only
want to talk about solutions,
but this is
a big problem.
Those hospitals
you want to divert to?
Seattle Press has been
experiencing power
outages all day.
Tukwila Hospital's
entire IT system is down.
I have been a first responder
with nowhere to take patients.
We can't close down.
Altman.
Wait, you're breaking up.
Wait. Don't do anything
until I get there.
I don't see any other options
right now. Do you?
So are we diverting
or not?
We're staying open.
I'll figure it out.
Okay, well, do it fast
before I have to start putting
patients in stairwells.
Open the drawer.
What's your name?
- Gladys.
- Gladys, listen to me.
I need everything that's in
that drawer right now,
- Gladys, okay?
- Okay, okay, okay.
Nothing's going through.
Okay. Uh...
There's got to be
another door.
Stay here.
No. No. No.
Oh, God.
That... That's everything.
I-I-I promise.
I-I-I swear.
Hey, look,
what about these, huh?
I need you to do exactly what
I say exactly when I say it.
Got it?
Hey. Get over here
where I can see you.
Both of you. Now.
Behind there with her.
Put your phones on the counter.
Put them on the table.
Alright, nobody moves
unless you want to die.
Got it?
Last anterior aneurysm
has been coiled.
Moving on
to the beast.
What are the chances
of Jackie developing
more aneurysms later on?
Well, the Marfan syndrome
does predispose her,
but that does
not necessarily mean...
Doesn't it, though?
I mean, we can fix these,
but the underlying problem
will always be there.
Can we hold
on the negativity
while I am inside
Jackie's brain?
Of course. Sorry.
Wow. This is not good.
You see how
there's no neck to it?
Looks worse than
on the scan.
If we go any further,
I'm going to rupture it,
and she's going to lose
a lot more than basketball.
We are going to have to put
her on bypass and open her up.
Specimen coming your way.
Liver and stomach look good.
How's the small bowel?
Think we're ready to close.
Oh-looped PDS.
Is there any ETA
on when I can set this arm?
Uh, we're closing now.
Dr. Beckman, what do you think
of Grey-Sloan so far?
State-of-the-art O.R.s
and dark roast
in the attendings' lounge.
If you tried to poach me,
I wouldn't be mad about it.
Are you looking
for a new job?
Aren't we always looking to
upgrade some part of our lives?
You didn't consider applying
for a position in the past?
Oh, I did.
Head of the department
never called.
We haven't had
many openings lately,
but, by all means,
e-mail me your résumé.
That'd be fantastic.
Blood's coming
from somewhere.
Damn it. We need
to open again. Scissors.
Page me when you need me.
Hey.
That's where she died.
Chloe?
My parents let me name her.
Did they run out of ideas
for the eighth girl?
I already had
two younger sisters,
and I was not excited
about a third.
They figured I'd be more into
her if I had a bigger stake.
- Did it work?
- Too well.
I love all my sisters.
But Chloe...
she was my heart.
And now I've lost it.
I've grieved my mom
every day of my life,
and I never met her.
I can't imagine
how you're feeling.
Will I ever feel
normal again?
I think this is
your normal now.
And every day you'll get
a little more comfortable
with it.
♪ Of holding tighter
♪ Of losing control
♪ Could I let it go?
Cream, no sugar. Right?
You remembered.
Yeah.
♪ Slow fading
♪ Short breath
Jackie's first basketball.
Once she outgrew it,
I started using it
as a stress ball.
She was just a baby
when her father died.
In the blink of an eye,
the love of my life
was just gone,
and I had this little girl
to take care of.
And I didn't think
that I could do it,
but she gave me
the strength.
Every smile, every giggle,
every... every milestone.
She kept me going.
I don't know
what I would do if...
She's going to be okay, right?
We can't make guarantees,
but...
Hey.
So the good news is I got
all but one of the aneurysms.
Okay, um, uh,
what's the bad news?
There's been a change
of plans.
We are going to have to
open Jackie up
to get the last aneurysm.
What does that mean?
Well, I will open
Jackie's skull
after Dr. Ndugu puts her
on bypass.
We will cool her down
to stop her heart
and cut off blood flow
to her brain,
which will make it safe
to clip the aneurysm.
You're stopping her heart?
I know it sounds scary,
but Dr. Ndugu will be there
to make sure
that her heart is okay.
I couldn't go any further
without risking a rupture.
This is our best shot.
Okay, just...
just save my baby.
Okay.
Save my baby,
What the hell happened?
We knew this was
a possibility.
Hey,
I got your text.
What's going on?
Are you okay?
I just want to feel normal.
Please.
Help me feel normal.
♪ Addiction to ambition
♪ Addiction to addiction
♪ Addiction to selfishness
♪ Addiction to condition
♪ Addiction to addiction
♪ Release
Gladys,
do I look stupid to you?
$47 on a busy day?
I-I just work here.
Where's the rest
of the money?
Hey, look, you want money?
Yeah? Yeah?
How about we give you
what's in our wallets?
I got, uh...
- 12 bucks.
- Um...
12 bucks?
Where's the safe,
Gladys?
Where is it?
Gladys, look at me.
Where's the safe,
Gladys?
I-It's, um, in the back.
Okay. Let's go.
Okay.
And you two,
you follow her.
And don't try
anything stupid.
Well, that was...
Yeah.
My whole body's vibrating.
You're welcome.
Mm, Dr. Bailey's
probably looking for us.
I need a minute.
Oh, it's not you.
I know.
Aw.
Just, every room in this
hospital, I-I see her face.
- Every room.
- Okay, come here.
- I see her face.
- Come here. Come here.
It's okay.
It's going to be okay.
We'll figure it out
together.
- Yeah.
- Yeah. I promise.
No wonder no one wanted
this case.
One wrong move, and
we literally blow up her life.
Or we could save it.
As Jackie cools
to 16 degrees Celsius,
the heart will stop,
and Dr. Ndugu will shut off
the pump.
And then I will have 45 minutes
to clip that aneurysm
before she's at risk
for permanent brain damage.
- Is that enough time?
- It's going to have to be.
But what if we don't access
the right angle?
No more questions.
I...
As I work, I need comp...
complete...
No distractions.
I need complete concentration.
Dr. Shepherd.
You said it yourself.
This is an impossible case.
That was before you saw
the fourth aneurysm.
No one will fault you
if you can't do this.
I have been Sky and Jackie,
desperately searching
for a shred of hope.
My dad, my brother.
I have seen loss.
I thought
there was a chance
that I could keep Skye
from losing Jackie, but...
but what if there's no...
what if I can't give her that?
It's too late for that.
You've come too far now, okay?
You have to
see it through.
Can you do this?
Because I think you can.
Okay, let's do it.
Okay. Okay.
Okay.
Scissors. Mesenteric bleeding
has stopped.
Good catch, everyone.
It was all Dr. Beckman.
It was a team effort.
And this was a lot of fun.
We should all have dinner
again sometime.
Too soon?
I think
we're ready to close.
Dr. Beckman,
you do the honors.
Go ahead.
I'm right behind you.
Somebody paid ortho.
I've dissected down as far as
I can without risking rupture.
Are we ready
for circulatory arrest?
Internal body temperature
is at 16 degrees.
Perfusionist is ready
to stop the pump.
Just say the word.
Start the clock.
♪ Oh, and we know
Bipolar.
Dr. Bailey,
do you have a minute?
Yasuda.
I was just going
to look for you.
Come find me after, okay?
You should know
that I got Carl back.
He just got a stent placed,
and he's recovering.
I am so sorry
that I freaked out, okay?
- It will not happen again.
- Oh, yes, it will.
My mom died
three years ago,
and I still lose my cool
sometimes.
I thought that work
would distract me.
I leapt into work
after I lost my mom.
I... I needed a purpose
to help me make sense
of her death.
Turns out,
death doesn't make any sense.
If I could do it again,
I would stay home.
I would rest
until I was ready to come back
because I wanted to work,
not because I-I needed work
to save me.
♪ Wherever I go
I don't want to be here.
Take more time, okay?
Go be with your family.
Grieve. Okay?
We'll... We'll be here
when you're ready to come back.
I don't think
I can come back.
♪ Rolling in my mind
Rest can do wonders.
Okay?
Y-You'll... You'll feel
differently in a few weeks.
I want to believe that,
but I-I know myself.
I am either all in
or I am all...
I need to find
a way forward.
I-I can't do that if everything
around... me reminds me of her.
I'm sorry to hear that,
but you know yourself best.
You know, great surgeons
have great respect
for how fragile life is.
And when
you are ready...
...this will
make you better,
stronger.
I know it.
I really, really hope
you're right.
Stay right there.
Gladys, what the hell
is taking so long?
- I've never opened this before.
- I don't know how.
Figure it out unless
you want me to use this.
My grandfather owned
a convenience store.
Did he ever tell you
what to do
if you're robbed
at gunpoint?
He died
before I was born.
I'm sorry.
How'd he die?
Robbed at gunpoint.
Yeah, my Uncle Derek
and Aunt Amelia...
uh, Dr. Shepherd...
were there.
Maybe we don't talk.
Are you okay?
I think I'm bleeding.
What? Where?
I'm pregnant.
Almost done.
Just have to deploy the clip.
- One minute.
- I can see that
but I have to finish this
if we don't want her
stroking out on the table.
Kwan, retract here.
50 seconds.
Almost there.
40 seconds.
Got it.
Alright.
Let's restart the pump.
That was... Impossible.
Ticktock, Gladys.
I'm starting to lose
- my patience.
I'm trying.
Wait.
- Where are you going?
- We have to get you
out of here.
Hey. Sit down.
Sit down.
Hey, hey,
she's pregnant.
Congratulations.
Okay, look... look,
if you let us go,
we'll walk out of here
like nothing happened.
I'm not going anywhere
until I get my money.
What, are you digging a tunnel
back there, Gladys?
- Hurry up.
- Safe won't open.
- God. Well, try again.
- I'm trying.
Sit down!
I'm not going to tell you again.
- Alright.
- Sit down.
Come on, Gladys.
- Oh, God.
- God!
Miss Williams?
- How is she?
- We got the last aneurysm.
We're warming her up
to restart her heart.
Thank you so much.
Everyone was so scared
to take Jackie's case.
Everyone except
Dr. Shepherd.
Thank God she did.
We'll have more updates
for you soon.
Thank you.
I haven't been able to get you
out of my head, either.
I've wanted this
for so long.
We'll get you an ice bath
to lower your temperature
as soon as possible.
Hey, have you seen Wilson
anywhere?
No. I got to go
pick up the kids.
But if you see her,
- have her call me.
- Yeah.
Warren, I told you to divert
all incoming an hour ago.
I-I know it looks chaotic,
but I have a plan.
No one has a plan
with a heat dome.
That is why I asked you
to close to trauma
so that we could focus on the
patients that we already have.
People will die
waiting on rigs.
Says the firefighter.
Think like a surgeon.
You told me to be
a first responder today.
We are closed to trauma,
effective immediately.
Nurse Milstien to the O.R.
Nurse Callie Milstien
to the O.R.
So you take the heels off
and eat residents for lunch?
Do you ever feel like
no one listens to you?
I work in
a male-dominated specialty.
Sometimes I think
they hear me
- the... third time I say it.
- I mean,
did you see the E.R.?
I don't know what
- I'm going to do.
- Yeah,
you are pretty screwed.
How can I help?
- Can you stay?
- Yeah, I can stay.
Hey. I'm just, uh...
I'm heading up to the ICU.
Can you... Actually, uh,
I'm going to take that break.
Call me if you need anything.
Every surgery
is an act of hubris.
You open a body knowing
you can make it better.
37 degrees Celsius,
and her heart hasn't
restarted yet.
Why hasn't it restarted?
V-fib.
We need to shock it.
Charge to 100.
Clear.
Alright,
let's charge to 200.
Clear.
It should be working.
Why isn't it working?
Again.
I said again.
Clear.
♪ Trust we lose
♪ Reach for hands
♪ To pull me through
On our best days, surgeons
decide our patients' fate.
Hey, how did your talk
with Bailey go?
What are you doing?
Mika.
Mika,
please don't do this.
Please.
Let's just talk about this.
♪ On the inside of my skin
I'm so sorry.
♪ Ohhhh
♪ Oh, ohhhhh
♪ Waters rise but can't erase
It can make you feel
invincible,
like you can do no wrong.
Hey.
Still no tow truck?
Eight people ahead of me.
I'm going to be here
till winter.
- I'm sorry.
- Me, too.
You know who's not, though?
My kids.
I told my ex
I can't get them today,
and he booked a fancy lake house
for the weekend.
So I either go
and get them tomorrow
and ruin their vacation,
or I don't see them
for a few days.
He's always the hero,
and I'm just...
...crying in public,
which, apparently, I do now.
Come on. I'll give you
a ride back to your hotel.
- Don't you have to work?
- If they need me,
they can, you know,
send out the Bat-Signal.
♪ Ohhhh
♪ Oh, ohhhh
What did you say
to Mika?
♪ Forgiveness
I told her
to make the best decision
for herself
and her family.
And now she's leaving
for good.
She needs our support.
Support?
You let her go like
she meant nothing to you.
But inevitably,
our hubris catches up with us.
In those awful moments,
we're left with nothing
but the wreckage
of our shattered egos.
When are you do?
It's okay.
You can tell me.
When are you do?
- Leave them alone.
- Hey, whoa, whoa, whoa.
What do you think
you're going to do with that?
Put that down, Gladys.
- Put it down.
- Mnh-mnh.
Put it... Hey, sit down.
Don't move, Gladys.
Don't move.
Oh, my God.
Aah!
And we're in total free fall.