Now, who can tell me the
steps of a partial laryngectomy?
In group settings, men are 75%
more likely to speak up than women,
and when a woman does
speak up, it's statistically probable
her male counterparts
will either interrupt her
or speak over her.
It's not because they're rude.
Cross.
It's science.
The female voice is
scientifically proven
to be more difficult for
a male brain to register.
What does this mean?
It means in this world, where
men are bigger, stronger, faster,
if you're not ready to
fight, the silence will kill you.
Let's move!
This is killing me. We have
not moved in 10 minutes.
I swear that bumblebee has
passed this car twice already.
It passed us, it
circled the earth,
and then came back
around to pass us again.
Yeah, because we left
late because you overslept.
Not fun when you're driving
and someone makes you late.
If you want to stay up all night
screwing around with some dude,
I don't care, till you
spend all morning
complaining about it in my car.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
We share a wall.
So move out!
Nobody told you you could
crash in Amelia's room, anyway!
Okay, that's not
Amelia's room anymore.
What is that? Two fire trucks?
And three ambulances.
That's got to be like a
four or five-car pileup.
Fifty bucks says
a big rig's involved.
Hey. Hey! That's
not a good idea.
Let's go, Karev.
Screw it.
Keps, I could use
another set of hands here!
I'm on it!
We've been paging
you for half an hour.
I've been a little busy.
Let's get him in the field.
We got a 45-year-old male with a
head lac, positive LOC on the scene.
Also has abdominal contusion.
I'd like to say it's not
as bad as it looks, but...
Major pileup, multiple wounds.
A big rig flipped. Bigger mess.
Do you think he has
intra-abdominal injuries?
Well, there's one
way to find out.
All right, let's get her inside.
I got this. Go.
A bony deformity in
the temporal region.
Five cm head lac.
Abdomen's clear.
Palpable pulses in
all four extremities.
We've got mild
pupillary asymmetry.
We need to get a head CT.
Let's page neuro. Mmm-hmm.
Starting to regret taking
that tour of the city today.
No rain. Thought
it was a good idea.
I got more than I bargained for.
Yeah, hey, this is
Dr. Warren here.
Well, you did hit your
head pretty good, Lou.
But we're gonna
get you fixed up.
Wasn't my most
graceful landing, either.
Yeah, sure. I'll hold.
Pushing 150 of fentanyl.
This should help with the pain.
You know they had
a wall at Pike's Market
covered in people's chewing gum?
I do, in fact, know that,
Lou. I grew up here.
Mmm. BENJAMIN: Thanks.
Where's neuro?
Paged. No response.
Well, then go get them.
Any pain here, Lou?
Just a little sore. Little sore?
He's lost his pulse!
All right, cover your ears. Why?
That's why.
I want an hourly neuro
checks on bed six,
sign off on beds four and eight.
Bed seven. What?
Bed seven. We don't
have a patient in bed eight.
Right. So busy in here,
who can remember?
We're being paged to...
Trauma One. Dr. Grey.
And Trauma Three. Dr. Hunt.
Uh, both urgent, not critical.
Do you want Hunt first or Grey?
Dr. Grey told me
to come find you.
Really? Meredith
actually asked for me,
or did she just want
neuro in general?
I don't remember.
Yeah, you do.
Have Grey give us a page if
her patient becomes critical.
Where's Hunt?
Trauma Three, right?
Three.
We'll be there in
less than 10 minutes.
Dr. Warren, some
help over here, please.
Coming through!
I need O2 tanks over
here for transport.
We're out here
visiting my sister.
She and my kids
are on a girls' day out,
so I decided to go
see the Space Needle.
Now I'm seeing
all kinds of needles.
Yeah, it's corny.
I know. I'm sorry.
My daughters tell me I
make the worst jokes.
How many kids do you have?
Uh, two. They're 10 and six.
Aw, sweet. They are smart, man.
They're smarter than I...
Whoa! Okay. What
are we looking at?
Um...
Come on, speak up!
Tonic-clonic seizure.
That's right. Let's roll him.
One, two, three.
Okay, what do we do now?
- We wait for it to pass.
It's going on too long.
We need 10 of lorazepam.
It's locked in pharma. Go, now.
It's okay, Lou. I got you.
Ooh, that was a big one.
Okay.
All right.
Oh, he's gonna need a
new gown and fresh sheets.
Oh, I hate it when they do
that. Could you get an orderly?
Do you mind? Okay.
Be right back. Okay.
Hey, there's no rush,
but if you do see neuro,
get them up here, please.
Mmm-hmm.
Okay, Lou.
Lou?
Lou.
You need to lay down.
You shouldn't be up.
Lou.
Let's get back on the bed, Lou.
Coming through!
I need that chest X-ray!
V-fib, charge to 300.
Charged.
All right. All right, ready?
Clear!
Come on. Come on,
come on, come on.
All right. Clear!
Come on.
Okay. I'm calling it.
Time of death, 11:42.
Crap.
I really thought we had him.
Yeah, me, too.
I need some help in here now!
Trauma panel. Send
blood for a crossmatch.
Belly is soft. APRIL:
Bruising on the left chest.
Decreased breath
sounds on the left.
Art line is going in.
Pulse ox is down to 88.
For a trauma series.
Hook up those monitors.
You'll need a wide bore IV.
Get ortho here to add
some left arm and leg films.
Has anyone told the chief?
Okay, do not page her.
This is one patient. We
can do this one, okay?
She has to handle
everything else.
The guy who did this, he
was stable, non-aggressive.
He wasn't a threat.
I left for, like, five
minutes, and this happens.
He was postictal. Hyper-aggression
can occur after a seizure.
Temporary fugue state.
He won't even remember it.
- Where is he now?
- Restrained,
and being treated
right next door.
Vein's collapsed.
I can't get in.
Put in a central line.
I got it. RICHARD: Oh, okay.
Obvious dislocation
of the left elbow.
We got some left knee swelling.
Rib fractures on the left
with palpable crepitus.
Get ortho here. Have a
liter of bringers on standby.
Get a blood gas from the art line.
- We need a wide bore IV.
No obvious flail.
You're doing just
fine, okay? Just fine.
Damn it. Send for a
trauma panel and a cross.
Somebody get Jackson
in here, right now!
Grey. NURSE: I'm on it.
Grey, we're gonna shoot
a quick X-ray, all right?
No JVD. Hi. I'm here.
I'm here.
One, two, three, easy.
Easy, easy, easy,
easy. Okay. Easy.
All right, okay.
All right, everybody back.
Okay. All right,
ready? On three.
One, two, three.
All right, easy.
- No, no, no, no, no.
- Meredith, it's okay.
It's okay, it's okay.
It's okay. It's okay.
We're here. What have we...
Possible concussion,
head contusions,
multiple blunt-force blows
to the head and neck.
It's... It's Grey. I'm
sorry. I thought you knew.
Dr. Shepherd?
Dr. Shepherd.
Dr. Shepherd!
Here's the films.
Pressure's 90 over 60.
Okay, she's got 30% pneumo.
No obvious effusion.
She needs a chest tube.
I need a 36 tube, Betadine,
and six and a half gloves.
Set up the Pleur-evac.
Just got labs. Crit is stable.
Oh, good. Draw blood
gas from the A-line.
What is this? What
the hell happened?
She was attacked by a patient.
The neck is bruised and swollen.
She needs an airway evaluation.
All right, I'm on it, I'm on it.
No, uh, bony deformity.
Positive Battle's sign.
Okay, Meredith, we're gonna
have to put in a chest tube, all right?
Your lung is collapsing.
And this is gonna burn.
I'm injecting the lido.
You can't work on your family.
Everybody in this
damn room is her family.
It's fine. OWEN: Here we go.
- Breathe, Mer. Breathe, breathe.
- Chest tube is in.
Okay, easy, easy,
easy, easy, easy.
Okay, let's hook
up the Pleur-evac.
Pulse ox is coming
back up. Eighty-eight, 90.
No evidence of traumatic brain
injury. No, no, no focal deficits.
Uh, except, uh, uh, Dr. Grey, I
need you to move your fingers for me.
Or your toes.
Come on. Just come
on. Wiggle something.
She responded to the painful
stimulus. It doesn't make sense.
Pulse ox is dropping again.
Unless...
The chest tube
has a small air leak.
No, she has mild
sub-Q emphysema.
We need to secure
this airway and tube her.
Got it. Guys.
Guys, I don't think
she can hear us.
What? OWEN: What?
Are you sure? No. Mer.
I can see evidence
of barotrauma,
possibly from the blows.
I think Karev might be right.
I don't think she can
hear anything we're saying.
Her jaw is locked. Suction!
Suction. Can we take a look?
All right. Let me see.
Yeah, yeah, easy, easy.
Yeah, we've got a dislocation
here, possible fracture.
There's no way we're
getting a tube in there.
You have to get a tube in.
You have to preserve her airway.
- Or we have to trach her.
- No, no, no, um...
All right, wait a second.
If I can reduce the dislocation,
we can probably get her mouth
open just enough to intubate.
It's gonna hurt
like hell, though.
Okay. Hang tight. Okay.
I'm sorry. Here. Okay, Mer.
Okay, we're gonna have
to pop your jaw open, okay?
I'm sorry. I know.
But we have to do it.
And we're gonna do this on
the count of three, you guys.
Ready? One, two...
Mer.
Hi.
See you in there.
You want to see.
Hey.
What's wrong? What can I do?
Hey. It's okay.
I'm here.
Just get it out, get it all out.
The tears, all the...
You know, you've
got a lot of snot.
I'm serious, I'm for real.
I mean, you might
have a serious condition.
Come on, woman.
Blow your damn nose.
Hang on.
Mer.
Can you hear me?
Mmm.
You can hear me? Mmm-hmm.
You can hear me?
Mmm-hmm.
Oh, my God!
Oh!
It is important that you
continue the voice rest, okay?
Your tracheal injury
is not fully healed,
and your latest audiometry shows
that the hearing
in your right ear
has almost completely returned.
On your left, you're looking
at about 55%, which is good.
It's only been a few weeks, you
know, so I'm not concerned about it.
It's gonna come
back, Meredith, okay?
I want you to continue to...
Mmm.
I want you to continue
to move your fingers
while in the cast,
and you will remain
non-weight-bearing
on your leg until
we take the cast off.
Yeah, well, there's a little
swelling in that left leg.
Uh, it's probably local edema,
but I've ordered a
Doppler, just to be safe.
Anything else? No.
Mmm.
"Lou?" What's... Who's Lou?
The patient who
attacked Meredith.
I've been calling
him something else.
Now, look, we don't have
to go into that right now.
She wants to know. Tell her.
Okay.
Lou suffered a severe epidural
hematoma in the accident.
It's what caused the seizure.
We think he was in a postictal
state when he attacked.
After a few minutes, he woke up
and had no idea
what he had done.
He had surgery
and was discharged.
Uh, he's doing fine.
Mmm.
Lou has reached out.
He has made a couple
of requests to see you.
Mmm-hmm.
I think he would
just like to apologize.
It's okay.
- She's kicking us out. Let's go.
- Mmm. Mmm-hmm.
Go ahead.
Apologize? Are you serious?
Of course I'm serious.
Yeah, I don't see why.
Because the last time that woman
got hurt working for this hospital,
she purchased this hospital.
That is why.
And what do you think will
happen if she sees him again?
- Nothing good.
- Exactly.
Mmm.
Good, good.
All right. Try and
lift your leg for me.
Good, good. Decent mobility.
I don't know.
Well, we're done,
and it's all good, so...
Thanks.
Uh...
He has been working a lot of
night shifts, and she's been...
They haven't been talking,
I don't think, or hanging or
anything, uh, from what I can tell.
So, anyway.
Let's do this again.
Follow the pen.
Okay, this isn't
exactly the right shade,
but it's doing a pretty good
job of covering the bruising.
All right.
So...
Don't try and get up, okay?
Just let them come to you.
And smile.
But try not to open your mouth
because it's still pretty swollen in there
and the wires, the metal
wires, they're a little scary.
You ready? Okay, all right.
Hey, hey, hey!
Look who's here, guys!
Your mommy is so excited
to see you! Come here.
Come on in. Go
ahead. Go tell her.
Tell her what we
talked about, okay?
I don't want to.
Oh, come on, Zola.
You ask me every day,
"When can we go see Mommy?"
Look. She's right over there.
Go give her a big hug!
No!
No, no, no!
Zozo, come see Mommy.
I want to go.
Come on.
Zozo, come see Mommy, honey.
Zo. Come on! Come on.
Zozo! Come see Mommy, honey!
Come on, honey!
Come on, Zo!
Come on, honey. Please.
Let's go talk to her. You
know... You know what?
Let's just, um... Let's
do this later. Come on.
It's... Let's do this later.
It's not... It's not okay.
Come on, come on,
come on, come on.
Let's do this later.
We're gonna do it later, okay?
We're gonna do it later. Okay.
Okay, does anybody want
anything yummy from the cafeteria?
All right.
Okay, Zola!
Dr. Robbins wanted...
Dr. Grey. Okay, okay.
I can't breathe!
Okay, you're okay.
Hang on, hang on. Deep breath.
Deep breath. I need
you to breathe for me.
Breathe for me,
Dr. Grey. Breathe.
Stay still. Stay still.
I'm gonna get you
some air. Just stay still.
I'm gonna open you up, okay?
Okay. I'm opening you
up. Stay still. Please.
Okay.
Hold on.
All right. Good.
Hey, what the
hell are you doing?
She was having a panic
attack. She couldn't breathe.
Do you not realize how
delicate the jaw actually is?
Dr. Avery, she...
You could jeopardize
the entire healing process here.
She couldn't
breathe! Look at her!
She's been stuck in this
room in that bed for weeks!
She can't move! She can't talk!
But I'm her surgeon now, right?
You can't come in here
and just take out her wires.
She is my patient!
I know what I am doing!
You can rewire her
jaw tomorrow morning,
but right now she needed some
air, so I got her some damn air!
I brought you
something to eat...
Drink.
I know. I'm sorry.
Good morning!
Oh, come on. Or not.
How's the pain today?
And the discomfort?
Well, her energy's up.
- All right.
I'm sorry. I have all of five
minutes to update you on the miracle
that I've been working
on your service this week,
but it seems like a bad time.
Uh, I'm gonna check
in and update you later.
Maybe we all
could check in later.
Yeah.
I'm just gonna
leave that.
Oh, what happened?
What was that?
Everything okay in there?
Nurse's station.
Yeah, okay. I got it.
You don't want to
look at me. I get it.
Do you think that I
want to be out there
hanging out outside your door
like some pathetic little
rat looking for scraps?
Do you think that
feels good for me?
I...
I have been out there trying to
figure out how to make amends.
As if that would matter to you.
I know I'm a mess,
who talks too much
and feels too much,
and I know that it
drives you crazy.
But that is the one way I
know how to stay sober.
And every time
I try to suck it up
and shut up and just
be cold and normal,
I end up drunk.
Or on pills or at a funeral.
Do you know what it felt like
to walk into that trauma room
and see you on that
table and think to myself,
"Great. I did it again. Here
comes another funeral."
You know what?
Forget it. I...
I don't even know
why I came in here.
Hello.
Cross, let's get
Dr. Grey a wheelchair.
I understand you saw Amelia.
Hey, look, look. I know you're
not in the mood for a lecture.
But... Are you finished?
She came to see you
the night after the attack.
She was drunk.
She was upset
because you called
her for a consult that day,
the day of the attack.
And she had a choice
between coming to you
and going to another trauma,
and she went to the other trauma
because she was mad at you.
Forgiveness is a
powerful thing, Meredith.
Not only to make the
other person feel good,
but to heal you.
You need to forgive
her, Meredith.
Forgive her for not being Derek.
For being the wrong Shepherd,
just enough to remind
you of what's missing,
but not enough
to bring him back.
That's not her fault.
You need to forgive her.
You don't have to like her.
You don't have to love her.
But forgive her, okay?
So you can forgive Blake
for being in that room
when a wrong decision
cost you your husband.
To forgive Derek
for dying too soon.
To forgive yourself
for hating him
for dying too soon.
Let it go, Meredith.
And forgive.
Sun feels good on
the face, doesn't it?
What the hell is the
point of counseling, then,
if you're just gonna suddenly,
without even talking about it...
Oh, come on. All
we do is talk, April.
So, what? You just, you
just serve me papers?
Just like that? Just no
warning. No, no any...
Do you have any idea what
a slap in the face this is?
Are you kidding me?
You ready?
Hi, Dr. Grey.
Lou.
Um...
Thank you for meeting me.
This is my wife, Joanne.
My daughter, Kylie.
I told you about her, the
youngest, really smart.
And that's my Anne.
Um...
Um, have a seat, girls.
Uh, you got kids?
Right.
Forgot you can't talk, the...
The jaw.
Um...
I wanted to...
I didn't know what I was doing.
What I did to you...
I didn't know.
I would never...
I would never hurt a woman.
And I...
I just want you...
I just want you to
know that I'm sorry.
Truly sorry.
It's my 30-day chip.
I'm sober.
And I'm starting back
at work on Monday, so...
I'm trying.
I know you are.
You...
You can talk. That, um...
That's great. They,
uh, took the wires off?
Yeah, this morning.
I'm just not ready
to forgive you yet.
I'm not
exactly ready, either.
See you later.
Hmm.
Mer.
Let's go.
Do you want anything? You
know, like a sandwich or a...
I don't know, a blanket?
All right, all right.
I'm good. I'm good.
Sit down, sit down.
I just spent six weeks in
a bed, unable to speak.
When that happens,
you see things.
There's a lot of things that
people don't say to each other
that they should just say.
So I need you to hear
me when I say this.
I know I've needed
you a lot lately.
But I also know, and I
have known for a long time,
that Jo loves you.
"Post-it on the wall" loves you.
Don't ignore that.
You can have more
than one person.
I used to think you
couldn't, but now I know.
I mean, turns out I have
a whole damn village.
So, you don't have
to worry about me.
Go be with Jo.
I'll be fine. I'm okay.
Don't let fear keep you quiet.
"And the moon gave
everything a magical glow
"as if they were dancing
on the Milky Way."
Mommy. Mommy... Yes?
You have a voice.
So use it.
Speak up.
Raise your hands.
Shout your answers.
Make yourself heard.
Whatever it takes,
just find your voice.
And when you do,
fill the damn silence.