Previously on ER.
It'd be remiss if
I didn't offer up my services.
Yeah, burns seem
to be well healed.
Wanna tell me how it happened?
We put the patient first
and that's what
we're supposed to do.
Anytime you want to prescribe
schedule two narcotics
we want to co‐sign the order.
You should agree
for something called, uh, PCA.
Hook Ricky up to an IV.
That would deliver pain
medication to him at home.
They need you to sign off
on the Dilaudid.
Yeah, I can't sign off on that,
he's not on our service.
Hey.
Doug..
Hi.
‐ What time is it, huh?
‐ It's almost 6.
It's very strong.
How's Ricky?
He's still alive.
‐ How's Joi?
‐ She's not so good.
It's amazing he made
it through the night.
I've got to get to work.
What time's your shift?
Seven.
I'll see you there.
‐ Bye.
Doug..
Hmm?
Thanks.
For what?
For staying last night.
Hey.
I love this time
of night, just before dawn.
So quiet, peaceful.
When they're babies,
it's the best time.
You complain about it but..
...it's when you're
closest to them.
Singing to them
in the dark and nursing.
Did you get any sleep?
I must have.
I closed my eyes for
a moment and he was laughing.
He was getting up
to go to school.
He was kidding me
about how much I worry.
He always used to do that.
Try to cheer me up,
make me laugh.
Oh, God.
‐ When was his last booster?
‐ About an hour ago.
They won't give me any more.
Mommy..
Go back to sleep, sweetheart.
I'm thirsty.
I'll get you a drink
of water, okay?
It's okay, buddy.
I'll take care of you.
'Dr. Ross?'
I increased the Dilaudid.
It's going to make it more
difficult for him to breathe.
I..
I don't know h..
...how much more
of this I can take.
Would you please..
...help us?
Please.
I..
...I can't watch
him suffer anymore.
He's suffered enough.
No more.
'Our recent spring‐like
temperatures'
'will be a thing of the past'
'by early afternoon..'
Ah, man, I'm supposed to be
going ice fishing tonight.
Ice fishing?
Al and I are supposed to be
driving up to Wisconsin to ski.
Skiing in Wisconsin?
That's an oxymoron, isn't it?
No, cross‐country.
You should try it.
‐ It's great exercise.
‐ Uh, you're the moron.
Sitting on lake Michigan
in the middle of winter
with your little pole.
"Oxymoron."
It's a figure of speech
in which opposite
or contradictory
terms or ideas
are combined.
I know what it means,
I just think you're a fool
for freezing your butt
off out on a lake.
Who gave him that damn
"Improve Your Vocabulary"
calendar in the first place?
I did.
Broadens his horizons.
What's today's word, Jerry?
Uh, today's word..
...is..
"Ratio...cination."
Oh, yeah, that's
going to come in handy
in daily conversation.
Uh, has anyone seen Carol?
It's ratiocination.
And it's to reckon, to reason
especially to reason
using formal logic.
Jesuit High School.
Hathaway's in sutures.
'You're kidding, Rocket Romano?'
Yeah, it's only temporary
until your committee
finds a permanent
department head.
‐ Why Romano?
‐ What? What about Romano?
Anspaugh's made him
acting chief.
Of emergency
medicine?
Hey, I'm not happy
about it either.
He's an egotistical,
arrogant, mean‐spirited
sexist little
bullet‐head.
Good morning, doctors.
News of my recent appointment
precedes me, I take it?
What, no popping
of champagne?
No, uh, ticker tape?
Excuse me.
I have a patient.
Looking forward to working
together again, Maggie.
I took the
liberty of reassigning
a few
minor tasks.
Greene, you'll handle
chart review
resident and medical
student supervision
time card scheduling
and any patient complaints.
Dr. Weaver.
Joint commission
report is due.
And I'd like
a weekly census
divided into surgery,
pedes and medicine.
I'd also like a daily list of
consults and their outcomes.
You'll sit on
the budget committee
and handle all billing questions
and insurance approvals.
What do you do?
I supervise you.
Delegation...one
of the eight hallmarks
of effective leadership,
or didn't you read that book?
Well, if you need me,
I'll be in surgery.
Oh, um..
Bullet‐head.
I'm offended.
Aren't you, Dr. Greene?
Deeply, deeply wounded
by your callous
and uncaring remark.
In fact, I‐I might have
to start an investigation
and interview others
who might have been hurt
by your vicious
invective in the past.
This is going to be fun.
Doug.
Just get his coat
and sweater off.
‐ I'll be right in.
‐ Okay.
That two year old eats nothing
but French fries and pizza.
The mom doesn't understand
why he's constipated.
So how was Ricky
when you left?
Alive.
I better get going,
I'm behind already.
‐ Lunch?
‐ Sure.
You sure look beautiful.
How do you do that
without any sleep?
Good genes.
You look like hell.
‐ It's a chick flick.
‐ It's romantic.
Isn't it, like,
four hours long?
Yeah, but the special
effects are great.
Kate Winslet
gets naked.
Oh, well,
that's encouraging.
‐ What you got?
‐ Fender bender. Tender abdomen.
You ever seen
"Titanic", Carter?
‐ Nope. Chick flick.
‐ That's what I said.
Lucy just rented it,
wants me to watch it with her.
Leonardo DiCaprio,
hoopskirts and tragic love
is kind of my idea
of hell on earth.
You guys are
Neanderthals.
Whatever happened to
the sensitive 90's male?
The ones who love romantic
dinners and candlelight.
They're all gay,
aren't they, Carter?
Every last one.
Listen, I don't want to ruin
the movie for you, Dale,
but in the end, the ship sinks.
I hate you both.
Nice package, huh?
So you two
getting serious?
She is.
Um...have you two..
Consummated?
I couldn't discuss it if I had.
I wouldn't want to
damage Lucy's reputation.
Tell you this
much, though..
...thongs.
Don't take my word for it.
When the lighting's right,
you can see through her scrubs.
E...S..
Make it a little rounder.
Yeah. E.
Reese.
‐ That's hard.
‐ You'll get the hang of it.
How long will it take?
Oh, it depends on
how much you practice.
You're learning
a new language.
Reese is already
getting it.
Oh, he's a kid.
It's easier.
He wants
to communicate.
Yeah.
That's it for today.
‐ Um...how often should we..?
‐ You and me?
Oh, I would recommend
three times a week.
150 bucks a week?
There's good
video available
but, I think
one on one is better.
Mr. Ekabo, how are you?
Fine.
How did it go
at the urologist?
Did you see the doctor?
Yeah, everything's good.
Say, if you have any
questions about a procedure
or what the doctor's telling you
I'd be happy
to answer them.
Huh, no questions, no.
You didn't go
see the urologist
did you, Mr. Ekabo?
'Why not?'
I've not told my wife
about my needing a doctor.
She will be frightened.
Would you like me
to explain it to her?
You will do that?
I'd be happy to.
Dr. Greene..
we've got an eight‐year‐old
coming in, full arrest.
‐ 'How long?'
‐ Coming up now.
Uh, bring your wife around.
'We'll talk.'
Then we can go ahead and, uh..
...set up that
urologist appointment.
Okay?
Where's that bad‐ass snow
we're supposed to be getting?
‐ It's summertime out here.
‐ You know what they say..
"It's the calm
before the storm."
Eight year old male found
unresponsive in bed at home.
Asystole, began CPR
in the field.
‐ Joi?
‐ What do we got?
Uh, end stage ALD.
He's Doug's patient.
‐ How long has he been down?
‐ Don't know.
We scooped him up
15 minutes ago.
He wasn't expected to
make it through the night.
His mother wanted
him to die at home.
Joi, why did you
call the paramedics?
‐ 'I didn't.'
‐ Mrs. Abbott.
Do you want us to use
extraordinary measures
to keep your son alive?
‐ No, I don't.
‐ But I do.
'Who are you?'
Ricky's father.
Sir, your son is
at the end stages
of a painful
terminal illness.
Extending his life is only
going to prolong his agony.
Doctor, please don't
let him die.
Intubation kit.
‐ Her leg isn't broken..
‐ Doug, I need you.
They're much tougher
than you think.
Yeah?
Ricky Abbott's back
and his father
is insisting we try
and resuscitate him.
His father?
Carol, what meds
is he on?
‐ Car...where's Carol?
‐ She left to go get Doug.
'He's on Dilaudid for the pain.'
Two milligrams of Narcan.
Chuny, why don't you take
Mr. And Mrs. Abbott to chairs.
What's going on?
Mr. Abbott asked us to try
to resuscitate his son.
‐ Still flat line.
‐ Atropine and two of epi.
He shouldn't have made
it through the night.
‐ Who the hell are you?
‐ I'm Dr. Ross.
Look, he was in my care..
Son of a bitch!
'Get him out of here.'
Get him out of here!
Get your hands off me.
Still flat line.
Oh, please.
Please.
Sorry, Mr. Abbott.
Time of death, 9:42.
You're actually going
to need a couple of sutures.
Want me to get
plastics down here?
You can do it.
So, what the hell
was that all about?
I have no idea, I didn't
even know there was a father.
Is he going
to be okay?
Couple of stitches to
add to his rugged charm.
How's Mike Tyson?
He went to make a phone call.
Took the little girl with him.
Did Joi ever mention there was
a father in the picture?
She told me
they were separated.
You went down
like a brick.
Cheap shot. The guy
caught me off‐balance.
I didn't realize
you had such a glass jaw.
Child support,
my med school loans..
Man, I don't know how
I'm going to shake it.
'And how much do you
have to pay in school loans?'
Uh, over 120 grand.
'Oh, that's barbaric!'
'Oh, well, yeah,
payment's $700 a month.'
'That's a quarter
of my take‐home pay.'
Money woes, Peter?
Every resident's
chief complaint.
You know, I'll never understand
this country's insistence
on forcing its
highly trained residents
to live
in abject poverty.
'And slave labor.'
Only way the public
health system can afford
to provide care for all
the, uh, freeloaders.
By freeloaders,
you mean people without
educational
opportunities, job training
children and the infirm.
Yeah, like I said.
Freeloaders.
You're a despicable human being.
Do you know that?
So, having trouble
making ends meet?
Things are a little
tight right now.
Why don't you do what I did?
Apply to a locum tenens program.
A "locum" what?
Tenens. Filling in
for vacationing surgeons
in rural hospitals
in, uh, Minnesota
the Dakotas
on your vacation time.
These places don't have
enough staff to cover
when somebody's out and they
pay you a bundle to step in.
‐ Oh, yeah? What's a bundle?
‐ I don't know.
Eight, ten grand
for a couple weeks.
Where's the big storm?
Should be any minute now.
They're closing
all those schools at lunch.
Recommending people leave early.
They really emphasized
that last point..
...the importance
of people leaving early
so they can
get home safely.
No, Jerry.
‐ The national weather service‐‐
‐ I said no, Jerry.
Spoke with Anspaugh
this morning.
He said it might be months
before we get a new chief.
Months with Romano?
Did we do
something heinous
in a past life
to deserve this?
There's Viking
in my family.
Maybe I raped
and pillaged Northern Europe.
Pillaged? Cool.
You must've looked great
in one of those big horned hats.
Maybe you
should consider
reapplying for
the chief's job.
Once foolish,
twice stupid.
Don might entertain
renewed interest.
I spoke to him about
you this morning.
Really?
Oh, God, I don't know
if I could go through
all that again.
Can I at least tell him
that you seemed interested?
How about intrigued?
Excuse me, I'm looking
for Mr. Abbott.
‐ Who?
‐ Richard Abbott.
His son Ricky died
here this morning.
‐ Um..
‐ Hi, I'm Dr. Greene.
I was with Mr. Abbott earlier
but I haven't seen him around.
I'm Dan Sullivan,
I work with Richard
down at the state
attorney's office.
He's asked us to open
an investigation
into the circumstances
surrounding his son's death.
Have the police arrived yet?
‐ Hey.
‐ How are you?
I'm fine.
I'm sorry Richard hit you.
We've been...separated
since Michael died.
I called him yesterday
to tell him that Ricky..
That, that he should
probably try to come see him.
He was at a...a conference
in Houston so I left a message
and when he arrived
this morning..
...and saw that Ricky was gone,
he kind of lost it.
He just wasn't ready.
Joi.
It's time for you
to let the nurses
finish up with Ricky.
‐ You made arrangements for him?
‐ Oh, um..
I‐I think I'll go
to the same funeral home
that took care
of Michael.
I'll call them.
Give me the number, I'll call.
Thanks.
Doug, got a moment?
Yeah.
What's up?
The police are here.
Mr. Abbott is accusing
you of murdering his son.
She was hit in the face
while kickboxing.
Not kickboxing. Tae‐bo class.
It's like aerobics,
but only better.
Hey, I heard about that.
It's supposed to be
good for losing weight.
‐ Yeah, I lost 16 pounds.
‐ 16 pounds, wow.
I had everybody in the
class spread out enough
but this new guy shows up
and she got kicked.
Did you lose
consciousness?
No, but I was pretty dizzy.
How long did it take
you to lose the weight?
Just melted off.
Hope this won't keep me
from getting back to class.
Fundus is sharp.
No papilledema.
‐ Want to palpate the orbit?
‐ No, that's okay.
‐ Is it expensive?
‐ Not too bad.
It's worth it.
You feel this?
Mm, yes.
Any numbness?
‐ No.
‐ Do you have early classes?
I usually have
to be here by 7.
Any visual changes?
Shapes, things
out of focus?
I teach a 5:30 class, if you
buy 20, you get five free.
‐ No kidding?
‐ Anybody know where a phone is?
Yeah, there's a pay phone
right over there.
No step off. I'm concerned
about your blurred vision.
So let's get
some facial films
and a visual acuity.
Lucy, if you think
you can tear yourself away
from fitness bargain hunting
for five minutes, stitch her up.
Your wish is my command,
Dr. Carter.
Irrigate and suture.
Hey, I don't usually get
a lunch break, so I end up
eating out of the
vending machines
and it's hard
to keep the pounds off.
First Lidocaine to numb the area
and then you'll feel
a little bit of wetness
as I irrigate the wound.
Dr. Carter.
Yeah.
Uh, the cut's pretty deep.
Should I do a few
subcutaneous first?
Yeah, absolutely.
Well, I'll check back
with you in a little bit.
Was he staring at my ass?
Hmph.
Coroner's coming over to get
the body and do an autopsy.
Roger Julian's coming
down from genetics.
He's hopping mad,
says Ricky was on his service.
Wants to know where the hell
the mother got Dilaudid
and a PCA machine.
The boy was dying.
You promised Kerry and I that
you wouldn't
prescribe any more‐‐
‐ He was in excruciating pain.
‐ You promised us yesterday!
‐ The mother was begging me.
‐ Where'd you get the machine?
Genetics didn't prescribe it.
I know we didn't.
I got it from Carol's clinic.
Come here.
Carol's clinic
doesn't have PCA's.
She called in a favor.
Got it from one
of her suppliers.
The police are on their way
to Joi Abbott's house right now.
They have a warrant
to impound the PCA.
Are they going to find
anything out of the ordinary?
Like what?
Like the machine
set to administer
enough Dilaudid
to kill ten grown men?
I don't know.
What'd you mean,
you don't know? You set it.
This boy was suffering, Mark.
He had end‐stage ALD.
In agony. The mother was
watching this child die.
Did you help him along?
I gave the mother
the entry code.
I showed her how
to change the dosage.
Now, I don't know what she did
afterwards. I went to work.
And you would have
done the exact same thing
if you were there.
Anspaugh's coming down
with Romano and Julian.
Doug prescribed the PCA
machine and the Dilaudid
through Carol's clinic.
What? When?
Right after he told us
he wouldn't.
Uh!
We're going to have
to tell Anspaugh
about Doug violating
the pain study protocol
and our covering it up.
I mean they're going
to scrutinize
everything he's
prescribed, Mark.
They're going to interview the
mother, it's bound to come out.
What the hell's wrong with you?
I mean, we trusted you
and you immediately choose
'to betray that trust.'
I'm done defending you, Doug.
Defending me? You've been trying
to nail me for years.
'I don't nail colleagues.'
'You want to destroy
your own career? That's fine.'
But you stay the hell
away from mine.
Have you called an attorney?
I don't need an attorney.
It was the right thing
to do, Mark.
Ricky had a degenerative
genetic disorder.
His brother died of the same
disease several years ago.
I have a 16 year old.
I don't know what I'd do
under similar circumstances.
Look, I know
Mr. Abbott is upset
but his son died.
There's nothing Dr. Ross
or any other physician
could do about it.
This, um, PCA machine..
It delivers um...pain
medication to the patient?
A steady dose
through an IV.
Well, can the, uh, patient,
or the patient's parent
program the machine
to increase the dosage
if the patient
is still in pain?
No. They can give
a booster every hour
but, um, they need
a key or a code
to change the dosage.
That way they can't
screw it up.
Well, that's what
I thought, so
I was surprised when
Mrs. Abbott, uh
told her husband Dr. Ross
had given her the code.
And showed her how
to change the dosage
before he left.
Why do you think
he would do that?
You two took it
upon yourselves
'to cover up a serious breach'
of a federally funded program?
We thought it was in
the hospital's best interest
'to keep the incident
from becoming public.'
Well, it's gonna
go public now.
And in connection with
a high‐profile euthanasia case.
Where the hell
did Ross get a PCA?
‐ 'From the clinic.'
‐ God, what a fiasco.
What about Ross?
Take him out back
and shoot him.
We'll convene a meeting
of the disciplinary committee
immediately and begin
an investigation.
You can begin that process
but don't conclude it
until we know whether or not
the father's going to sue.
Ross keeps working?
Listen, you can have him
dispense aspirin if you want to.
I don't care. But don't take
any further action.
What about Hathaway's clinic?
Close it.
Alright, public relations will
handle all the press inquiries
and Dr. Romano and I
will talk to the staff
and make sure they cooperate
with the police fully.
That's it.
Kerry, Mark.
I don't know what to say.
When the dust settles,
I will personally
chair an investigation
into this matter
and the appropriate disciplinary
action will be taken.
And on a more personal note..
I don't think I've ever
been more disappointed
in two people in my life.
Kerry, sorry this..
I think I just beat it in, the
roads are getting really slick.
Took me forever
to navigate the Kennedy.
Traffic was backed
up...for miles.
What's the matter,
somebody die?
Somebody we know?
Dr. Ross lost
that ALD Kid.
The police are in trauma two.
The boy's father accused Doug
of giving him an overdose.
‐ Called the cops.
‐ Oh, my God.
Yeah. Coroners took the body.
Police are interviewing
everybody.
‐ Where's Doug?
‐ In the pedes room, I think.
Chuny, have you seen
the, uh, labs on that
drunk with the head lac?
No, but he managed
to throw up on me again.
Third scrub's up today.
Yeah, we should wire
a bucket to his head
like one of those
feedbags for horses.
Yeah, right. Hey, any,
uh, word on Doug Ross?
Uh, police are still
interviewing Dr. Greene.
Have you seen Lucy?
Dr. Edson keeps coming
down here looking for her.
Yeah, last time I saw her
she was working on the..
Hey, where's my, uh, kick boxer?
Dr. Weaver moved
her into exam two
when that rule‐out
MI came in.
Lucy was still working
on her about ten minutes ago.
‐ Suturing?
‐ Yep.
Well, that should've
taken like, two minutes.
‐ I haven't seen her come out.
‐ 'One.'
‐ Two, three, four..
‐ My heart's really pumping.
Five, six, seven, eight, and..
‐ 'Oh, man.'
‐ 'Dr. Carter.'
Are you okay?
Don't move, don't move.
Chuny, uh, backboard
and a hard collar.
Well, I don't see
any other blood.
Nice kick.
‐ 'Damn.'
‐ What happened, ma'am?
‐ I kicked him in the chest.
‐ Why?
I was practicing
my tae‐bo.
Now we're going
to roll him..
..back under there...one..
'Okay, great.
Roll back.'
'On my count,
one, two, three.'
‐ So it's good, huh?
‐ Oh, it's terrific.
I'm definitely going.
Maybe I'll come with you.
Hey, Doug, I just heard.
‐ You okay?
‐ Yeah.
Didn't anyone explain Ricky's
medical condition to them?
And they're still
pursuing it?
Apparently so.
I don't believe this.
Well, can I do
anything for you?
Do you need anything?
You know, you're the first
person to ask me that all day.
No, I'm fine, thanks.
I'm supposed to
work fast track
but I can get
someone to cover.
Could stay here,
help you out.
Well, not much to do.
Weaver pulled me away
from seeing patients.
Told me to sit here
and catch up on paperwork.
For how long?
Uh, from the tone of her voice,
I'd guess maybe forever.
What did Mark say?
They're closing ranks,
covering their asses.
Dr. Ross, you have
a couple of minutes?
Sure.
I'm going to grab some coffee.
You set?
Yeah, I'm fine.
I'm down the hall in 117.
‐ Meet you there in five?
‐ Okay.
Dr. Greene?
I'm sorry.
Is this not
a good time?
No, it's fine.
Come on in.
Do you remember
my wife, Kubby?
Sure. Hi.
Did you two have
an opportunity
to talk about this?
His back, it is worse?
His back is
better now.
I suggested that
he see a urologist
for his other problem.
It's possible that, uh,
he may need surgery.
Surgery?
If this is uncomfortable
for you to have
this discussion
about these issues
in front of me
I can leave for
a few minutes.
No, please.
Uh, stay.
‐ How you doing?
‐ Hey. Hi.
'Have a seat, doctor.'
'Are you sure you don't
want some coffee?'
‐ I got an extra one.
‐ No, I'm fine.
Well, I guess I'll
have to drink it myself.
Can't get enough
of this stuff.
‐ Who's that?
‐ That's Detective Brannigan.
He's part of the uh,
felony review team.
We investigate all
uh, first‐degree murder cases.
I'm not trying
to hang you out to dry
or ruin your career.
But, um..
If you showed Mrs. Abbott
how to alter the PCA
to deliver a, uh...
a fatal dose of Dilaudid
you can be held accountable
for Ricky Abbott's death.
Now, Miss Hathaway said
that Ricky was getting, uh
80 mics of Dilaudid an hour
through the PCA.
Mics is, uh, micrograms?
And that Ricky's mother,
could give him a, uh
a booster of an additional
120 every two hours.
That's right.
But she was
uncertain as to, uh
how much Dilaudid you originally
placed in the machine.
It was empty when,
uh, Detective Brannigan
examined it a few minutes ago.
Mr. Sullivan.
I've dedicated my life
to pediatric medicine.
I've cared for dozens
of dying kids.
Kids in agony, pain..
...you and I
can't even imagine.
Ricky Abbott was going to die.
Not in a month.
Or a week, or a day.
In hours,
and nothing I did
or‐or could have done
was going to change that.
His mother had already watched
one son die from the disease
and she was sitting there
watching her second son
dying a horrible
death from something
that she passed on to him.
Sometimes it's impossible
to save a kid's life
and the only thing
we can do..
...is save them
from suffering.
Leave them with
a little dignity.
In the end,
that's all they have.
Tell me, were...
you relieving the, uh..
...the child's suffering
or...were you
relieving your own?
'If you were so certain
you were doing the right thing'
'why didn't you administer
the, uh, lethal dose yourself?'
'You're the doctor.'
You could have stayed,
you could have made sure
there were no complications.
'That he really did
die with dignity.'
'But you left.'
You knew that
killing that child was wrong.
That's why you...
you snuck out of the house
before dawn, isn't it?
'You didn't want
to be there, did you?'
to be there..'
...because you knew..
...killing Ricky Abbott
was wrong.
I don't see a broken rib.
Maybe a hairline fracture.
Uh, I feel like an elephant
sat on my chest.
Well, just stay seated, okay?
‐ Don't get up.
‐ Oh.
How did you get that cut
on your forehead?
I think I hit it
with the chart.
You've taken
martial arts before.
Karate when I was
like, seven.
‐ Ouch.
‐ Oh, come on.
It can't hurt that bad.
It's tiny.
‐ It doesn't even need a stitch.
‐ Ouch!
Baby.
There.
Better?
Much.
I'm a doctor,
you're a student.
Mm‐hmm.
So we shouldn't
be doing this.
Mm‐hmm.
Storm's finally here.
Romano closed my clinic.
Why?
Because I helped you
get the PCA.
Well, Ricky was dying.
I was there.
I know he was dying.
I didn't know you were
gonna help his mother.
Use a piece of
my equipment to administer
a lethal dose of Dilaudid.
I didn't want to
get you involved.
Oh...but Doug,
I was involved.
'I mean..'
Were you planning
on telling me...
..any of this, ever?
I don't know, you know.
Hadn't decided.
What about you promising Mark
'never to prescribe narcotics?'
I mean, had you
decided on sharing
that information with me?
I did what I thought was right.
Damn the consequences or whoever
else gets hurt, right?
I was willing to live
with the consequences.
Mark and Kerry are facing
disciplinary action.
'My clinic has been closed.'
'Which means
hundreds of patients'
'have no place else to go.'
The police..
...are questioning
the entire ER Staff.
'Your actions carry
consequences, Doug.'
It's not just about you.
Do you even give a damn?
Hey, hey don't do that.
Don't walk away.
Why not?
You don't need anybody else.
You are a country unto yourself.
'You know, you just
make decisions.'
'Ruin people's lives.'
Narcissism elevated
to a high art.
‐ 'Carol, Carol.'
‐ What?
I'm sorry.
That's what
you always say, Doug.
'Some of the roadways are nearly
impassable as you can see from'
'this video we've taken end
of the last half hour.'
'Both the airports, Midway
and O'Hare, are closed..'
I'll never get home now.
‐ Somebody beep me?
‐ I did.
Where you been?
I'm getting buried down here.
Upstairs with legal.
We are stacked up.
When Romano closed
Carol's clinic
all her cases got
dumped onto our service.
And most of them are still
waiting out in chairs.
Jerry, stop watching TV
and get your tail over here.
How long will the police
gonna keep trauma two tied up?
‐ I don't know.
‐ I'll find out.
Why does Carter have so many
old cases up on the board?
Oh, he got kicked
in the chest.
Lucy's working on him
down in six.
Could this day
get any worse?
Connie, go tell the clinic
patients we're sorry
but we're not going
to them today
so they might
as well go home.
Chuny, go see
how Carter's doing.
If he can't work today,
we'll have to call
in the jeopardy resident
to help out.
‐ You got it.
‐ Damn it, Jerry.
Stop watching that TV
or I'm gonna run over there
and rip it off the wall
with my bare hands
'and beat you
to death with it!'
‐ 'Wait, wait.'
‐ 'But I almost got it .'
'No, I mean really wait.'
'Um...yeah.'
This isn't right.
‐ We can't be doing this.
‐ Why not?
Well, because
there are rules.
What, you mean, you think
we could get in trouble?
Not "we."
Me.
'Dr. Carter, you in there?'
You, uh...you locked
that door, right?
Yeah. Absolutely.
Both of them?
Dr. Carter, you okay?
‐ 'Just a second.'
‐ What are you doing?
You locked the door in her face.
She knows somebody's in here.
How you feeling?
Much better,
thank you.
Lucy?
Oh, he didn't
need any stitches.
‐ That's good.
‐ I'm going back to work.
You're inside out.
Your sweater, you've got
it on inside out.
When did it
stop snowing?
A few minutes ago.
We don't look much
like dangerous felons.
Speak for yourself.
I'm so sorry
about all this.
You okay?
Are you?
I've had better days.
Yeah.
You know, when..
...when Michael died
I cried for days.
I felt that...
that I'd died, too.
'That I'd..'
...never...feel love
or joy again.
And then..
...Ricky came and read to me.
'He'd sit on the end
of the bed and'
tell me these stupid jokes
'that he'd heard
in second grade'
'and...he'd smile.'
God...I..
I wish you'd seen him like that.
Joi.
You still have your daughter.
Yeah.
I guess I should go back inside.
See if my ex‐husband's ready
to let me talk to her again.
Thank you, Dr. Ross.
For everything.
Yeah.
The 92 year old dislocated ankle
in exam one has been reduced.
Lydia, give her a Vicodin and
tell her to stay off her skates.
92 years old
and she's still skates.
You got something
on your neck.
‐ Where?
‐ Right there.
‐ Looks like somebody bit you.
‐ Yeah.
I think I might
have hit something
when I fell down.
You bit me.
What? No, I didn't.
Oh! Guess I must
have gotten carried away.
Hm‐mmm!
Now, that's what
I'm talking about. Mmm!
Roxanne called, twice.
‐ So?
So what, Jerry?
So, Lucy.
Yeah. Come on, man.
Everybody knows.
I heard it from the cashier
in the cafeteria.
Sheri from radiology‐‐
I'm not having
this conversation.
Can somebody answer
the MICN, please?
Nothing happened.
Mark, I got
to talk to you.
I got patients.
Listen.
I'm going to go to Anspaugh,
I'm gonna tell him
that I coerced you
and Kerry to go along
with me on this
drug protocol thing.
Coerced? How?
Tell him that I‐I begged you
not to report it.
That I promised that
I would do it myself.
And that's the only reason
that you didn't report it.
I think there's been
enough lying, Doug.
Why don't we all just stick
to the truth for once?
I'm, I'm trying to help.
I don't want your help.
I made decisions
of my own free will
and I'm ready to
stand behind them.
So, you don't believe me.
I don't know
what to believe.
You lie to me.
Undermine my authority
every chance you get.
Bend the rules
to fit your needs.
I'll bet, that's how we do it.
I'll just lie my way out of it
I'm just trying
to do you a favor.
'Hey, Mark.'
Don't do me anymore
favors, alright, Doug?
I'll be lucky if I survive the
ones you've already done for me.
‐ Mark.
‐ What?
We got a school bus
flipped over by a snowplow.
Kids are trapped, firemen
need a doctor on the scene.
‐ Where?
‐ Downtown somewhere.
Couple of the kids may even die
before we can get them out.
I wanted to go, but Weaver
thought it should be you.
Unit 62 is waiting
for you in the bay.
‐ How many?
‐ Fifteen.
Nine are still trapped,
this snowplow blade
intruded right into the bus.
Where the hell
do you think you're going?
‐ You need a pediatrician.
‐ You are off the service.
I'm coming.
The hell you are.
Ready to go, doc?
Yeah. Let's do it.
‐ Get back inside.
‐ Coming with you.
‐ You got kids dying out there.
‐ Oh, well.
Maybe you'll think
about that next time.
Hey, Doug,
where you going?
Driving myself.
‐ I'm going with you.
‐ You don't have a coat.
I'll get one.
Just wait... wait for me!
We got five out.
We got the jaws working
the forward section
but we got three kids trapped
inside under the plow blade.
Lot of blood,
I was afraid they'd
bleed out before
we could get them out.
I got a crane coming
to try lift that snowplow off.
The driver tried to stop,
but it's pure ice.
Plow hit him dead on.
We're going in through
the side window.
Climb down to reach them.
Doc, it's pretty bad in there.
Watch your step.
‐ Skipper?
‐ 'Yeah?'
We're going to need O‐neg,
lots of it, okay?
‐ And get some propane heaters.
‐ 'You got it.'
Let's blow up
some heat in here
before these kids
freeze to death.
Hey, turn this up.
I love this song.
"Earth, Wind And Fire?"
My dad used
to love them.
'Cause you were dating me.
Junior high.
♪ Yeah ♪
So you never asked me
if I did it.
I hope you did.
'Wouldn't want to suffer the way
that little boy suffered.'
I thought about that a lot.
♪ And my love
won't disappear ♪
You know, Jeanie,
you never talk about your HIV.
Nope.
♪ My dear ♪
♪ Can't find a reason to ♪
Doug.
'Hold on.'
'Doug!'