Home run!
Open wide,
Glass-wipe!
This one's comin' at ya!
Hey, Jerry!
You haven't
driven anyone home
since junior prom!
Ha-ha!
Whoo! You tell him, Glassy!
Whoo! Whoo!
Lea,
what are you doing here?
Is Shaun all right?
He's fine.
Basically.
"Basically"?
Well, he's been
trying to reach you.
You missed
your tux fitting.
Are you here
to take my measurements?
Shaun is really
struggling right now.
He's been calling you.
Struggling? Really?
You came all the way
out here to Montana
because he's struggling?
Wasn't he struggling over the...
the billboard thing, right?
Turns out, he didn't
need me at all, did he?
So you figure he's
never going to need you?
What are you gonna do?
Run away? Stay here?
I'm not running away.
I'm hitting .394,
batting cleanup
for the Devil Dogs.
Why?
Yo, Doc!
We're just headed
to the Stick & Steak.
You and your friend
coming with?
My friend was just leaving,
but I'll be right there.
Shaun's fine.
You're fine.
I am fine.
I'll call him tonight.
Go home.
Lea is on
a business trip.
She's gone until Sunday,
which means I can
spend the weekend
reviewing the latest
case reports.
I can't allow that.
Morgan's on call
this weekend.
You and I are going out...
pizza and a movie.
Two de facto bachelors
looking for trouble.
I don't like loud movies.
Or trouble.
We'll pick a quiet one.
Or olives, mushrooms,
or anchovies.
But other than that,
that sounds like
a lot of fun.
Unstable level one trauma.
25-year-old male,
fell 30 feet
from scaffolding.
...open.
Massive head trauma,
multiple fractures.
BP is 50 over palp.
You go.
Bilateral tib-fib injuries.
Femur fracture
of the right thigh.
Belly is distended,
tense, and bruised.
He has internal bleeding.
He's lost 40%
of his blood volume.
Apply pressure
to the open wound.
He's O-neg.
We need six units
and a rapid infuser, stat.
There's too much blood
in his abdomen to see.
We need a portable CT
before...
He's in respiratory failure.
Crash intubation tray!
Hi.
Playing helps with
attention, working memory,
and processing speed.
Mm.
I can make the clinic
profitable.
A woman in
my barre-cardio class
is the health insurance
manager for a media company.
They're looking for another
health provider.
Could mean
3,000 insured clients
if we win the contract.
Give me her name
and I'll get it done.
I'd like to close the deal.
And then, I would like
full control of the clinic
and its budget.
Holding onto
your leverage.
Smart.
Let's see
what you can do.
Severe brain contusions.
Multiple rib fractures.
Blood in the right
pleural space.
He has a massive
hemoperitoneum.
Grade five liver lac.
Spleen is pulverized.
Lumbar spine fractured.
Right kidney's
unsalvageable.
Pressure's falling,
and he's maxed out
on vasopressors.
Try T.X.A.
Is he an organ donor?
I don't know,
but it's not relevant,
because I am not
going to let him die.
Attention on the concourse,
this is your final
boarding call.
Dr. Park?
Park: Hi, Val.
Hi.
We've got a patient in the ER
who's severely injured,
and he's O-negative.
And the heart?
Seems to be healthy.
The patient is an adult,
but not a big guy.
Oh.
Do you think
it'll fit Ollie?
I think so.
But I need you
to bring him in
for another CT to be sure.
W-we're just about to leave
for Ollie's Make-A-Wish trip.
We've got
a cardiology team
and a very accommodating
paleontologist.
And other hearts
have fallen through.
This trip won't
happen again.
Not with the amount
of time he has left.
Should we get on
this plane, or not?
Bring him in.
Okay.
We managed to slow
your son's bleeding,
but Brandon has a lot
of internal injuries,
so we won't know
the full extent
until we look inside.
Do you have any questions?
No.
You've been very clear.
We're ready to move him
to the operating room,
so I'll find you
when I know more.
Can I talk to my son?
Before the surgery.
I'm sorry, uh,
he's been unconscious
since his fall.
I-I promise, I will
take you to see him
as soon as he's
out of surgery.
After vision
and hearing exams,
I'll do a full
occupational health screen.
And I would do that for
every one of your employees.
Hmm.
Rest your chin
here, please.
Cucumber water
is a nice touch, too.
Never had
this test before.
You don't wear glasses.
Most places wouldn't
bother with this test.
Hmm.
Do you see a dot anywhere?
Yep, right in the middle.
Where's the dot now?
Nowhere.
Nothing in
the upper left corner?
No.
How about now?
Upper right?
No.
Okay.
It seems like
you have deficits
in your peripheral
visual fields.
According to this test,
you're going blind.
It's an optic nerve tumor.
A craniotomy could
get rid of it all,
but it'd stop the blood supply
to the optic nerves,
and she'd still go blind.
An endoscopic
endonasal approach
would avoid those
blood vessels.
She'd keep around
60% of her vision.
I need to do
better than 60%.
Is this about the client,
or the big fat contract
she might bring
to your clinic?
Glassman's basically gone.
I see a vacuum.
I want to fill it.
I thought you wanted
to be a doctor.
Last week, you told me
I shouldn't expect you
to become more ambitious.
The reverse is also true.
This could clear
the tumor
proton beam radiotherapy
with a synchrotron accelerator.
It's experimental.
Never been done on
an optic nerve tumor.
Got to go.
That's the last piece
of this kidney.
Hemoglobin's 6.
I don't like his BP,
either.
I can't fix this liver lac
without risking a major bleed.
We're almost out
of O-neg.
Isolate
the vascular pedicle.
O-O-Okay.
You know, his dad's in
the waiting room.
Think there might be
some unresolved issues.
Well, if we can
get Brandon through this,
maybe they'll
make amends.
My dad and I set aside
a lot of our issues
after his
cancer diagnosis.
Maybe my dad will get cancer
and we can bond.
You know,
other than one letter,
I haven't heard from him
in five years.
What did it say?
Don't know.
Never opened it.
Oh! We need more
suction and laps.
Where's it coming from?
There.
His vena cava ruptured.
Clamp it and pack
all four quadrants.
Crickets are
high in protein.
Marcus,
my needs are simple.
You gotta smell good.
Oh.
You gotta know
I love my work,
and I'm not gonna
apologize for it.
And you absolutely gotta be up
for trying new things.
Noted.
So, how is your newest thing
coming along?
Our hospital.
A few problems
in radiology.
We're spending too much
in the pharmacy.
And how well
do you know John Colson?
Head of Pediatrics?
Good doctor, good administrator.
Why?
He won't sign his Ethicure
employment agreement.
Don't know if I can
afford to lose him,
and I don't know if I can
afford to keep him
for what he's asking.
You signed your Ethicure
contract without any pushback.
What sold you?
I'm up for trying
new things.
How do I get
one of those hats
in my size?
Dr. Park!
I knew you'd find me
a new heart.
Uh, let's not get
ahead of ourselves.
But first,
how do we get ready
for a dunk
in the giant donut?
With a little donut?
Jelly?
You rock.
When are you gonna stop
stalking me?
When you agree
to come back to San Jose.
It's his patient
satisfaction scores.
How bad?
Is his job at risk?
Well, no.
Okay.
Because I omitted some
of his negative reviews
to bring his scores up.
You did what?
Sorry.
There's no way
this was Shaun's idea.
No.
He... He didn't even
want me to talk to Salen.
Did he agree to this?
Does he even know about it?
No.
So, instead of telling him,
you decided to come see me?
When did you get so unethical
and condescending?
You're infantilizing him.
These scores,
the way Salen
runs the hospital,
this could really hurt him.
Hurting him any more than
you're hurting him right now?
I kn... I know.
I...
So, what do you
want me to do?
You want me to go back
to San Jose
and co-sign your crap?
This isn't about me.
It is.
It's about Shaun.
It's about you.
It's your fiance.
Your responsibility.
Your mess.
Go home.
And clean this up.
No leaks.
The graft is holding
and the bleeding is stopped.
We still have to deal
with his brain edema.
How's his intracranial
pressure?
31.
It's even higher than it was
before we started surgery.
Run an EEG.
Slow waves.
Burst suppression pattern.
Minimal activity.
He's in a coma.
Brandon is in a coma.
We're trying to relieve
the pressure on his skull
to try to help
his brain recover.
And how long will that take
for it to recover?
It's... It's
hard to say.
Um...
What's more likely,
given the extent of his injuries
is that it won't.
And he will progress
to brain death.
I thought about
calling him this week.
So we could
work through some stuff.
Yeah, those are...
...tough calls to make.
We haven't talked
in about two years.
Since he dropped out
of Annapolis.
Instead,
he was gonna be a
drummer.
Your dad must be
very proud of you.
Uh...
He wanted a rabbi.
A st-straight rabbi.
I failed at both,
so he disowned me.
I really need to talk
to my son again.
We're trying everything we can
to make that happen.
Knock, knock.
Did you see the proposal
I sent you about Nira's treatment?
Yes.
Very ambitious.
And also quite expensive.
If the proton beam
radiotherapy is successful,
we'd save 100%
of Nira's vision.
We'd definitely win
the company's contract.
Reasonable
medical decision.
Bad business decision.
The cost of the equipment
and treatment
is several hundred
thousand dollars more
than the value
of that contract.
You have a perfectly
acceptable treatment
that's FDA approved,
covered by her insurance,
and saves her life
while preserving 60%
of her vision.
I'm fairly certain
that's all you need
to secure the contract.
Our client deserves to know
all of her options.
You're her doctor.
Do what you think
is right.
But our deal only stands
if you make
the clinic profitable.
It's gonna fit like
a heart-shaped glove.
Let's see how much excess fluid
you're lugging around, Ollie.
Well? No salt
and no soda all week.
And did you know
the brontosaurus had
a 300-pound heart?
Imagine what that
sounds like.
Probably like
"ka-boom, ka-boom!"
Check this out.
It's my new lucky charm.
It's a triceratops toe.
It's, uh, 65 million...
...years old.
Is your chest
hurting, Ollie?
I need a nurse
and the ECMO team, stat!
Oh, this doctor
in Boston used
an external drain
to lower pressure
in the brain.
Never mind.
The patient died.
Well, maybe we can try
to relax brain pressure
with a hemicraniectomy.
He wouldn't survive
that surgery either.
Made any progress
with your patient?
Not yet.
H-Have you discussed
organ donation with his family?
No.
In his fragile state,
his organs won't last long.
Shaun, this is a tragedy
no matter how it ends.
You are breaking
the rules.
My patient is getting weaker
by the minute.
Stop.
An organ recipient's doctor
is not allowed
to communicate with
a potential donor's doctor.
I am talking to you
as a friend.
You can't save everyone.
If your patient is gone,
let me save mine.
Go away, or I will
report you to UNOS,
and you'll lose your
transplant privileges.
Hey, Shaun.
You're late.
Yeah, the plane
was late and cramped
and devoid of refreshments,
and I'm starving.
You ready to get
some pancakes?
I need to fix
my neurophysiology test.
Okay, well, uh, great.
Can we do it
while we eat?
No.
I answered this one
correctly.
Check my work.
I understand that it's not...
not a perfect score, but...
Check my work, please.
Check it.
Question 5.
Okay, okay.
Yeah.
It should be A, but, uh,
it could also be C.
But the internal
carotid arteries branch.
It is worded
a little strangely.
I would have
gotten it wrong, too.
Yes, Professor Fontaine
is wrong.
You need to tell him that.
I'm not gonna
tell a professor
to rewrite
his test question.
But he is wrong about
how blood flows
into the supratentorial brain!
So what, Shaun?
It's just a test,
and I'm starving!
You go eat.
I'm going to see
my professor.
Shaun.
The internal
carotid arteries.
I don't see any issues
in that area.
You wouldn't, if there is
a very small dissection
hidden by all the swelling
and other damage.
Stents could
increase circulation
to his supratentorial brain,
which might wake him up!
Nira?
I found a surgery.
It's not only going
to remove the tumor
from behind your eyes,
it will also be able to save...
...60% of your vision.
Oh, thank you.
There it is...
a tiny tear in the carotid.
Good catch, Dr. Murphy.
But there's a clot.
The stent could
expand the clot,
which could kill him.
Not if we
break up the clot
with therapeutic heparin.
We'd be risking major bleeds
in all his organs.
If we don't give him heparin,
he will end up brain dead.
During my residency,
we had a woman die
on the table.
Healthy organs,
no contact info.
No one was saved that day
because we didn't know
if she was a donor.
I thought we weren't
supposed to consider
organ recipients
when treating patients.
We're not.
Right up until the point where
what we're doing is futile.
It is not futile.
This has a 1% chance
of helping Brandon.
Start the heparin drip.
I'm sorry, Val.
My boy spent his entire life
in hospitals.
Getting poked and tested
and promised things
that never came.
And all I wanted
was to give him
just one perfect day.
Just one.
Here's your hot mocha.
Dr. Colson.
Glad I ran into you.
Let me get this.
I got a favor to ask you.
My usual.
In that case,
I'm having a muffin.
You know, my friend Joanne,
she flew in from Seattle.
You got a minute to
chat with her,
give her the lay
of the land?
She's sitting
right over there.
She's interviewing
for your job.
She's a great
pediatrician.
I'm not sure what you heard,
but I'm not going anywhere.
Wait...
Uh, thank you.
I... Oh, I'm sorry.
I heard that
you were moving on.
No, just renegotiating.
I thought...
I have to go.
Thanks for the muffin.
Excuse me.
Is this seat taken?
Your patient is in
multi-organ failure.
Yes, w-we are treating him
with plasma and platelets
to increase...
He has clots forming
on his heart valves,
which means his heart
is no longer an option
for my patient.
Okay, you are not
supposed to look at
my patient's
medical records.
It is a violation
of policy.
I wanted to see if his heart
was still an option.
Your Hail Mary surgery
didn't save your patient,
and it just killed mine.
Professor Fontaine said
my answer is wrong.
I'm sorry
to hear that, Shaun.
I'm going to talk
to the dean.
You need to come with me.
You're gonna go over the head
of your professor?
That might cost you more
than two percentage points.
He is wrong.
Well, he might be.
Then, why...
I got you something, Shaun.
Pick one.
Mm, I don't care
about these things.
Okay, I'll pick one
for you.
I don't do embroidery.
You can learn.
It's good practice
for your sutures.
Sometimes bad things
happen, okay?
Sometimes even
unfair things happen.
You know that
better than anyone.
And sometimes
you gotta let them go
and focus on the next thing,
the next challenge.
Are you not coming with me
to see the dean?
No.
You said you would
always be there for me,
to help me.
I am.
Go if you need to go.
I'll still be right here.
We need to talk
to Brandon's father!
I think we can save
Brandon's heart.
We can use
an embroidery technique.
In the 1900s, Alexis Carrel
perfected vascular suturing
using embroidery.
If we treat his valves
like blood vessels,
we might be able
to repair them.
You can save my son?
N-N-No.
We can only save
his heart.
For d-donation.
It's time to let go.
My son is not dead.
Only because of what
we're doing to him,
but he will be very soon.
It is futile.
No.
I nee... I-I need to talk
to my son again.
I-I need to tell him...
...s-so much. I...
I understand.
It's too late.
No, it's not.
Not for that.
Talk to him.
Say goodbye.
If something needs to be said,
it should be said.
Here you go.
Everything's so blurry.
That will improve.
But the tumor was
more complicated
than the imaging showed.
We were only able to preserve
50% of your vision.
I'm so sorry, Nira.
Don't apologize.
You saved my life.
I would be blind or dead
if you hadn't found
that tumor. It's...
I should run some
vision tests on you now.
I will go
get those prepped.
Remember when I bought you
that ham radio?
Whenever I was
stationed overseas,
we would send each other
messages in Morse code.
You picked that up
so quickly...
But...
Then,
you sent me
that message saying
that you wanted to be
a rock star.
And I, um...
I shot it down.
Everything you wanted changed.
I didn't understand it.
I...
I didn't know
how to help you.
I had a path laid out,
and you didn't want
to follow it.
I thought you were
rejecting me, s...
And now I know,
you were just becoming
your own man.
Goodbye, Brandon.
I love you, son.
♪ There's a longing
inside of my chest ♪
♪ For what could have been ♪
♪ The weight is heavy,
♪ Tell the sender
That I'm ready
♪ To see you
♪ I know I'll see you
on the other side
♪ The other side
♪ Holding on now
to memories
♪ That won't let go of me
♪ Reminding me
that you're gone
♪ And I'm the one
that can't breathe
♪ I can't breathe
♪ I know I'll see you
on the other side
♪ The other side ♪
Can I?
No, thank you.
People have always
tried to accommodate
for Shaun's differences.
Compensate,
overcompensate...
I don't need
another lecture.
I was one of those people.
Mm.
It took me forever to get
to where you started.
Right, it's so easy for me.
It is.
You always treated Shaun
like a person
instead of a problem.
You always saw Shaun.
Why did you stop
doing that?
You left.
So, what?
So you panicked?
Yeah.
Maybe.
I don't...
I don't know.
It's...
We're getting married,
and he's not always easy,
and I'm pretty much
always a screw-up.
And...
It's just...
It's too much.
No, it isn't.
B-But you've always been there
to back me up.
You don't
need me anymore.
You're kind
and you're patient.
You're resilient
as all get-out.
You're the right person
for Shaun.
Shaun's the right person
for you.
If you can just trust that,
you will have
the most perfect,
imperfect marriage.
I kind of feel like
hugging you right now.
Hey.
You don't need me.
There's something
I want you to hear.
Ka-boom!
Sounds like
a 300-pounder.
No, no, no.
This is
your lucky charm.
Yes, yes, yes.
I don't need it anymore.
You wanted to see me?
Make yourself at home.
This is
Dr. Glassman's office.
You've earned it.
I found a very
interesting documentary
about the science
of storm clouds.
We should watch that
tomorrow night.
I'd like that.
I'll bring the pizza.
No olives, no mushrooms,
no anchovies, right?
Right.
Because they don't
taste good.
Is this payback?
No, a gift.
Worms have more protein
than crickets.
Then I'll take another.
I feel like celebrating.
Colson suddenly lost interest
in playing hardball
and signed his
employment agreement.
Hmm.
I assume you had
something to do with it?
Glad I could help.
You smell good.
You coming?
I came to give you this.
It's where
Brandon's organs went.
A secretary who's
a single mom of three
got his kidney.
A truck driver
with a vision problem
got his corneas.
A teenager with
a rare autoimmune disorder
got his ligaments.
And a young boy
got Brandon's heart.
He loves dinosaurs.
Brandon helped
all these people?
There are 63 people
on that list.
♪ Don't
♪ Don't lose faith
♪ I know it can be
so hard some days
♪ Go
♪ Hide your face
♪ But when you're ready
Come back to your place
♪ Here, right by me
♪ Take all the time you need
♪ And when you feel
you can't be found
♪ Caught up
in the mess-around
♪ When the walls
are crashing down
♪ I'll be your solid ground
♪ When you think
you've lost the light♪
♪ Stuck in a starless night
♪ Lift your eyes
and watch the sky
♪ I'll be your satellite ♪
Here you go.
It's perfect.
It was a good exercise
for suturing.
Would you like
to get some pancakes?
Yes, I would like
some pancakes now.
♪ When the walls
are crashing down
♪ I'll be your solid ground
♪ When you think you've
Lost the light ♪
♪ Stuck in a starless night ♪
♪ Lift your eyes
and watch the sky ♪
♪ I'll be your satellite ♪
Hi,
you haven't reached
Aaron Glassman,
so I'll call you back
sometime.