Hey, Greg.
Hey, Dr. Greene. Busy day, huh?
Yeah. Sorry I'm late.
Can we, uh, skip the
gown? I got a shift.
Oh, sure, yeah. Let's go.
You know they say we're
gonna hit zero tonight.
Even with the snow?
Thought my heating bill
was bad last month. Hm.
Feel any side effects?
Just the usual fatigue.
Well, in eight days
this will all be a memory.
Believe me, I've been counting.
Okay, hold on, because we're
off by about a millimeter or so.
Take your time. I don't
want anything to get zapped
that doesn't have to be.
There we go. I'm
gonna lock you in now.
Here we go. You okay? Yeah.
About three minutes. Right.
What do we got?
58-year-old male.
Collapsed at a birthday
party. Intubated in the field.
Whoa. That's a clown.
He aspirated a balloon in
front of a dozen 6-year-olds.
Good air entry. BP's 105/70.
Carter, will you
help Abby with this?
Why can't you do it?
I... I just can't.
What, Dave, you
afraid of clowns?
Maybe he had a bad circus
experience. How long he down?
Three to five minutes.
Found him in respiratory arrest.
Hook him up to a vent.
EKG, CBC, lytes,
cardiac enzymes.
Dr. Carter... will you
talk to this woman?
And a chest film. I wanna
check tube placement.
What's up? I've
got a dirty needle.
I want a clean...
We don't do that.
Like I said. A doctor
here gave this to me.
He said if I come back
today, I can have...
There's a number to
call. There's a van...
I don't want to call the
van. I want a clean needle.
I'm sorry. I cannot
help you. Dr. Carter?
He said I wouldn't have to wait.
Some girl called. Said she
can't make it tonight. Flu.
Some girl? That's...
You didn't get her name?
You got more than
one date? Oh, great.
Big date? Had potential.
So ask someone else.
No, it's this charity
event. It'll be boring.
Nobody will want to go.
Why? Ask someone
in the ER. Like who?
I don't know. Chuny?
You, uh, wanna go?
Not me. I've got plans.
Don't even look at me.
Dr. Carter?
Hey, sorry about that. I
got, uh, pulled away there.
You were gonna give
me something for...
Mary, can you give Jeff
here some viscous lidocaine?
They haven't taken my blood yet.
No? Someone will be in there.
Do you think it's
something serious?
Probably not. But, uh,
with two weeks of fever,
we should check
out a few things.
How we doing in here?
Some spontaneous
movement, but he's still out.
Glasgow Coma Scale is 1-1-4.
So, what are you doing tonight?
I've got an appointment
with my couch.
Pulse ox, 98 on 50 percent.
Well, I hate to come
between you and your couch,
but how does dinner and dancing
at the history museum sound?
Dancing at the museum?
Pressure's down to
90/60. Run in 500 of saline.
Yeah, it's, um...
It's a benefit for an
after-school program.
Ah. Charity date.
How's the EKG
coming? Almost done.
Yeah, my grandparents,
um, host this annual event,
and I have to go.
But I would...
think of it as a favor...
Do I owe you a favor?
Ha. At the very
least, it's a free meal.
Tombstones on
the anterior leads.
Let's push 6000 of
heparin. Call the Cath Lab.
BP's only 70 systolic.
Would you get Dr. Weaver?
Start dopamine at 10
mics per kilo per minute.
I'll put him in Tredelenburg.
Dr. Weaver. This
clown is crashing.
So, what do you, uh,
think about tonight?
I think it's the
least I could do.
No one should be
alone after killing a clown.
You killed the clown? No.
Didn't save him.
Enough flu on the board?
'Tis the season.
Guy in Curtain
3 fell off a ladder.
Oh, yeah? How far?
Taking down Christmas
lights. Fell from the top rung.
That's what you get
for procrastinating.
I'll take it.
There he is. This is
my doctor. Hi, Janice.
They wouldn't give me a needle.
Haleh, take it and
give her a clean needle.
You serious? We
I&D'd the abscess
on her forearm
yesterday. I got that.
This will keep it from
happening again.
Thank you, Dr. Greene.
Come back tomorrow
for a wound check.
I'll try.
You're, uh, not
gonna fill out a chart?
Nope. No prescription?
Waste of time.
I can get behind that.
Excuse me.
I'm looking for Dr. Kovac.
I know you. You're...
You're the bishop, right?
Right.
Where's that hat
you were wearing?
I left that one at home
today. Oh. I really liked it.
Me too. There he is.
Hello again.
Bishop... are you all right?
Oh, yeah. Sure. I was just
finishing up my visitations.
Do you have a moment?
I don't see a cane.
No, you don't.
Have any more pain?
Not from the fall.
Your arthritis is
still a problem?
I was wondering if I could get
another prescription for
some prednisone to keep going.
Did you follow up
with your doctor?
No, I keep having to
change the appointment.
That should be
the priority. I know.
Unfortunately, he
doesn't work on Saturdays.
What's his name?
Don Frost at St. Mary's.
I should call him. Ha.
You'll only get his service.
And frankly, just between
us, I'd rather not get him going.
I so much as sneeze,
and he wants to poke
and prod every inch of me.
I'd have to do some tests
before prescribing
anything more.
What kind of tests?
Blood, urine... check
your sugar level.
My sugar's a little high.
I have a touch of diabetes.
But I control it with diet.
Okay. Let's take a look.
Ah.
Ah. Ah. Ah.
Mm. Looks good.
Strep throat, right?
No fever, no swollen glands.
I had the exact
thing last year. Strep.
You have a cold, Mr. Ramirez.
Antibiotics, 10 days. Right?
No white spots on your
tonsils. Antibiotics won't help.
Well, last year I took
'em, they cleared right up.
It would have cleared up anyway.
Come on, doc. I've been
waiting three hours here.
Plenty of fluids
and get some rest.
Can you just give
me the prescription?
Dr. Greene, we need you.
You don't have strep throat.
I'll take them just in case.
85-year-old woman,
collapsed at her nursing home.
You got a pulse? No.
Found her in V-fib. Intubated,
shocked five times,
two rounds of drugs.
How long you been
at it? 20 minutes.
She's pretty blue. Okay,
everybody, nice and easy.
On my count. One, two, three...
Any medical history?
Emphysema. She's on home oxygen.
Asystole on the monitor.
When was the last
epi? Five minutes ago.
Push another amp.
What? She didn't respond
to 20 minutes of
ACLS in the field.
She doesn't have a chance.
I know. The family
wanted us to bring her in.
Why? So we could flog
her for another hour?
You want dopamine? Nope.
I'm sorry, Dr. Greene.
She should have
died in her own bed.
Abby, hold compressions.
Asystole.
Time of death: 1409.
Family's in Chairs.
Don't worry about it.
Hey. Hey.
Everything okay?
We just lost a patient.
Sorry.
That singer you like is
playing at the hotel tonight.
Really? Ten o'clock.
I told Carter I'd go
somewhere with him tonight.
Oh. Okay.
It's a fundraiser thing.
His date stood him up.
It's not a problem.
I have a pile of
journals to read.
Well, I'm sorry. I wouldn't
have said yes if I knew...
Labs are back on the bishop.
Blood sugar's high.
Go. Have fun. Okay.
Draw five units. Take
a look at his ANA.
Do you have his
BUN and creatinine?
Renal insufficiency.
Hey, Jeff.
You okay?
Just nervous.
Sit. I got your blood test back.
Okay. Bad news is you
have mononucleosis.
Good news is, if you rest up,
you'll bounce back
in a couple weeks.
Mono. Yeah. But
you'll be all right.
How is my blood count?
Uh... white cells were
a little elevated, but...
that's consistent with mono.
What about my CD4 count?
Are you HIV-positive?
'Cause we only
do that if you are.
I think I need an HIV test.
Have you ever
been tested before?
Five months ago I was
negative. That's good.
But, uh, since then
I've been exposed.
You've had unprotected sex?
With an infected partner.
You know how unsafe that is?
I guess I just get caught up.
Gotta put a stop to that, Jeff.
My sugar that bad?
Three hundred forty-eight.
Maybe I should go
back on the glipizide.
Right now you need insulin.
There was also...
protein in your urine.
So I ordered an, um, ANA.
That's a test for a
disease called lupus.
I know.
I take Plaquenil.
200 milligrams a day.
You lied to me?
Ha. I wanted to avoid a debate.
I may have harmed you
by giving you those steroids.
The steroids help me.
I can move around, make visits,
do my work.
Without them...
I'm stuck in bed.
The steroids raise
your blood sugar so high
that the diabetes
destroys your body.
I need to continue my ministry.
You understand?
Anyway...
thank you for your time.
I need to do a
complete physical exam.
Ah. No, I'm sorry. I got
a lot on my plate today.
I have to make sure I didn't
harm you with my treatment.
You owe me that much.
And what is it you
think I owe you?
Bishop...
lupus is very serious.
It can attack your kidneys,
lungs, your heart.
I know what it does, Dr. Kovac.
I even know I'm
gonna die from it.
Did I wake you?
No, I was just resting my eyes.
So how's the heart?
EKG looks good.
That's what we like to hear.
Do you want me to call
someone to come be with you?
No. I called the
archdiocese just in case.
What church do you belong to?
I don't.
Haven't found one you
liked? Haven't looked.
How long have you
been in Chicago?
I don't go to church anymore.
Really? Why's that?
I don't remember.
You married? No.
Haven't found one you liked?
Something like that, yeah.
Dr. Kovac, we've got a kid
with bad congestive heart failure.
The nurse will be in.
What's the pulse ox? 81.
Sixteen year old. Collapsed
at a basketball game.
Watching or playing? Watching.
What's his name? Nick.
Hi, Nick. I'm Dr. Kovac.
Whoa.
Have you had
heart surgery, Nick?
Transplant.
How long ago? Six years.
Okay, someone call
his parents. On their way.
BP, 115/72.
Lungs are full of fluid.
He's in pulmonary edema.
Sublingual nitroglycerin
and start a drip.
Open your mouth,
Nick. This will help.
Okay. Titrate up
to 10 of morphine.
I need a 12-lead, blood gas,
portable chest and 40 of Lasix.
Pulse ox down to 78.
Notify the transplant team,
and order a PICU bed.
They want to give
me a new heart?
Yes.
I don't want another transplant.
Malucci, what do
you got in Exam 4?
Uh, lady with bronchitis.
Sending her out
with amoxicillin.
Bronchitis? Productive
cough, myalgias, arthralgias.
Sounds like the flu. She's
pretty high-maintenance.
She wants antibiotics.
Antibiotics are not indicated.
I told her that, but
she still wants them.
You need to educate her
about antibiotic resistance.
Do I have to? Gotta
break the cycle.
It's easier to just
write a prescription.
If you feed the bears,
they'll come back for more.
Food poisoning gets
another liter of saline.
Check a post-reduction
shoulder on this one.
This is a patient who's
waiting on an... HIV test.
Okay. Malucci can take it.
This last one's pretty
delicate. He's high-risk...
Malucci can be delicate.
Thank you, chief.
No, really...
Dave, this one's
gonna require some tact.
You got it.
He's a patient with
mono, he's gay,
he refuses to use condoms.
Think you can talk to him?
Without being insensitive?
Sure. I'll wrap it all
up in a nice big bow.
Tsk.
Carter... a construction worker
had a pane of glass
dropped on him.
Can you help with the
suturing? Actually, I'm off.
I gotta go.
Oh, yeah, the fundraising. Yeah.
Yeah, you know, it's more
like a family obligation.
It's nothing really exciting.
What's the charity?
After-school
enrichment programs.
Enrichment?
Yeah. It's, you
know, extra education.
Arts, music, that kind of thing.
Actually, Abby's saving me
from getting heat
from my grandparents.
They kind of insist
I bring somebody.
I hope it's successful.
Thank you.
Oh. See you.
Hey, Jeff. I'm Dr. Malucci.
Dr. Carter went off duty.
You, uh... You
have his lab results?
I'd like to talk to
Jeff about that.
Would you excuse us?
Uh, actually, I'd like to stay.
I'm Sean, Jeff's partner.
Is that okay with
you, Jeff? Yeah.
Okay, well, it's all good, man.
Your HIV antibody test
came back negative.
Really? Yeah. You got lucky.
But now you need to avoid
risky behavior and, uh...
and... And keep
yourself healthy.
Yeah.
Mm. Am I missing
something here, guys?
I'm HIV-positive.
Oh.
Jeff and I are together.
Through everything.
Right.
So, what?
Are you...
trying to contract HIV?
You a bug chaser, Jeff?
We don't call it that.
Really? Then what
do you call it? Suicide?
HIV is treatable
with medication.
Doesn't mean you
should try and catch it.
Look... we both know
that his HIV antibody
could be negative
for six weeks after exposure.
So you can't really tell us
that he's definitely
negative, can you?
Uh, no.
We'd have to take
a direct measure
of his viral load.
Okay. Mm, let's do that.
That's gonna take some time.
We'll wait. Yeah, we'll wait.
Okay.
Flat T-waves in
the lateral leads.
Okay. Repeat 12-lead in an hour.
Something wrong?
You have some
non-specific EKG changes.
Yeah, and there is a
friction rub around your heart.
I'm creaky all over.
Have you had chest pain?
Occasionally. I'm used
to it. How about today?
This morning. For how long?
I don't know, half an hour?
You may have fluid
around the heart.
You could be at
risk for a heart attack.
I feel fine.
We need to get a cardiac
echo and admit you.
No.
I have to observe your
heart for at least six hours.
I'll stay six hours, but I
don't want to be checked in.
I'd rather observe
you in the Cardiac Unit.
I don't want my life
to end in a hospital.
You're not gonna die
today. I will not be admitted.
Are you Nick's
doctor? Yes. Dr. Kovac.
There's no doctor
with him, just a nurse.
Well, Nick is stable right now.
He was in heart failure?
Yes, uh, he's responding
to aggressive therapy.
He has pulmonary edema.
The same thing happened
after his second transplant.
He's had two?
One when he was 4, then
again when he was 10,
and now he's on
the list for a third.
They did angioplasty last
year, but he's still so weak.
Has Nick ever told you he
doesn't want a new heart?
He says that when
he's depressed.
He takes 15 medications a day.
He's still so sick.
A lot for a 16-year-old
to go through. Mm.
Can you call UNOS? He
should go to a higher status.
I was waiting to talk to you
to see if that's
what you wanted.
Of course we do.
Okay.
Dr. Greene, my flu patient
wants to see someone higher up.
What's the problem?
She wants antibiotics.
Says she gets them every
year. Refuses to leave
until she gets a prescription.
Where is she?
Right there. Curtain 1.
Hello. My name's Dr. Greene.
Sara Dell. I've been
sick for three days.
Fever, runny nose... Feel
like my head's in a vise.
Mrs. Dell, antibiotics
don't help the flu.
They always help mine.
I can assure you they don't.
You're not giving them
to me 'cause I'm poor.
If we give antibiotics
to the millions of people
who don't need them,
a resistance builds,
which eventually
makes the drugs useless
to the people who do.
And 'cause I don't
have insurance.
That's persecution.
You think so? I know so.
You know what? Follow me.
Well, where are we going?
Come on, follow
me. Pay attention.
Excuse me.
My name is Dr. Greene.
I'd like to see a show of hands
of people who
have a sore throat.
Right here. Yeah, man.
Cough?
Muscle aches, fever?
You all have the flu.
People who have the flu
will not be receiving
antibiotics today.
So consider that
while you decide
whether you want to wait or not.
What are you doing?
Clearing the board.
Isn't that an EMTALA violation?
I didn't discharge anyone.
Hey, Greene. Tell me you are not
giving free needles to junkies.
On a case-by-case
basis. No, no, no.
On no basis. It's illegal.
Not if there's a public-health
emergency, which there is.
How much of your
brain did they cut out?
This does not put extra
needles on the street.
I don't care. We
are not gonna have
junkies parading
in and out of here.
So you're not interested in
cutting back on HIV and...?
And? What? Sounds like...?
Hep...
Hep...? Hep...
Hep? Heparin? Heptathlon?
Hepatitis. Tough one.
Tell you what. You want
to start a needle exchange,
do it from your house.
♪ Forgetting all I'm lacking ♪
♪ Completely incomplete ♪
♪ I'll take your invitation ♪
Hi. You're wearing a tuxedo.
You didn't say it
was formal. I didn't?
No. Oh.
Yeah, it's formal.
Heh. You tricked me.
Doesn't matter.
You look terrific.
Well, yeah, we don't
match though. I mean, I c...
I can go change.
I don't even know
if I own a dress.
Wanna go buy one?
No. Can you just...?
Just wait one minute.
You mad at me? Yes.
Did you get a haircut? Yeah.
Who are my parents talking to?
Dr. Corday. She's a surgeon.
I told you I didn't
want surgery.
You were in a lot of
pain when you said that.
I still meant it.
You won't survive
without the transplant.
I was hoping to
make it to my prom.
But if I can't...
I can't.
With a new heart, you will.
Do you know what it's like
to have your chest split open?
No.
I can barely walk to
class, I get so tired.
I take pills every two hours.
And I look like a freak
from the side effects.
It's not worth it.
He's at the top of the
list? Yes. Status 1-A.
It's just a matter of
waiting for a heart
with a tissue match.
We waited a month
on Status 1A last time.
Now that he's older,
there are more possibilities.
Excuse me, uh,
Mr. and Mrs. Stevens,
but Nick doesn't
want a new heart.
We explained that to you.
He's thought it out.
He has good reasons.
I think you should
listen to them.
He's 16.
And he is tired
of living like this.
Well, I'm not giving up
on him because he's tired.
I'm... only telling you
what Nick told me.
I understand. When do
we move him to the unit?
Shouldn't be too long.
Kerry...
we have a little
personnel problem.
Well, you do. Mark Greene.
Mark. He's walking
around with attitude,
handing out needles,
blanking out on words.
Yeah, it's swelling from
the chemotherapy wafers.
We... Really?
He has a mild
expressive aphasia.
It's temporary. I don't like it.
Well, I don't think
he likes it either.
You noticed any
personality changes?
He got very
confrontational with me.
You're used to confrontation.
We're not talking about me.
Isn't that your
favorite subject?
Just straighten him out.
Who's this with
you at the beach?
Eric. My brother.
You know, I never
got the whole concept
behind dried flowers.
I mean, they're dead.
They're dead as
soon as you cut 'em.
Yeah, but... they look nice.
Dead ones look nice too.
Right. Right, no. I
was just wondering.
Wondering what? Wondering, um...
Why not just buy the, uh...
fresh flowers?
Because there's something sad
and dark about the dried ones.
Oh, yeah? You like
sad and dark? Yeah.
Okay.
Just give those a couple days.
Wow. You found something.
That looks nice.
It's a bridesmaid's dress.
Oh. It... It... It works on you.
You're lying.
No, honestly. Nobody
would know that.
Looks like it was,
um... made for you.
Okay. Now I know
you're lying. Let's just go.
Carter. What?
What is this?
Oh, come on. What do
you want, to take the El?
You're not gonna take
me to the airport and say,
"By the way, this
party's in Paris"?
No. We stay in
Chicago, I promise.
He needs bandages,
update his tetanus,
and order a six-pack of Keflex.
You lost your cap.
I decided to wear
my scar with pride.
It adds character.
Well, it scared a little kid.
Called me Humpty Dumpty.
Well, Humpty...
how do you feel about
an evening service?
What service? The wedding.
Coordinator
double-booked the afternoon,
and they want to
push us back to 5:00.
That would push
the reception back.
Yes. I've already
spoken with the caterer.
He says he can do it,
but we can't use
the patio for cocktails.
What's wrong with the patio?
April, the evening.
Be really chilly.
Well, ask him to
move out the, uh,
um... you know, uh...
Space heaters.
So it's all right with
you? Yeah, sure.
Okay then.
Mark...
you're getting better.
The aphasia's fading.
I'm glad you think so.
No, it is.
In a couple of weeks,
this will all be gone.
I don't think I can count on
you for an unbiased opinion.
No, you can't. I am biased.
I'm also right.
Dr. Corday? Nick
Stevens just arrested.
Whose patient? Kovac.
I'll grab him.
Oh, God. What's the rhythm?
Still V-tach.
Charge to 300.
Nick. Come on, Nick.
Excuse me, sir. You'll
have to stand back.
Okay, I need to intubate.
100 of lidocaine. Stand
by with amiodarone.
Charged and ready. Clear. Clear.
- Still no change. MRS.
- Please save him.
360.
I need some cricoid pressure.
I'm in.
Rebolus 50 of
lidocaine in five. Clear!
Clear.
Got a rhythm.
There's a weak radial
pulse. Mix up the dobutamine.
Open your eyes, Nick.
Come on, Nick. Wake up for me.
Good breath sounds bilaterally.
Unresponsive to
painful stimulation.
He wasn't down long.
He should wake up.
Maybe.
You get the three
separate light settings.
That's an essential amenity.
So I talked to Luka. Me too.
Didn't seem to
mind about tonight.
No.
He doesn't get jealous.
Ever.
All the, uh, years
I've lived here,
I've never been to the... The...
Natural History Museum? Mm-hm.
Oh, that's criminal.
They've got dinosaurs, cavemen.
Dinosaurs and
dancing...? It's great.
Yeah. My grandparents
like spectacle.
It's not gonna be that
big of a deal though.
A few people.
You are so dead.
It's kind of a scene.
Kind of? I told you.
They like spectacle.
Did you grow up going
to these kind of things?
Yes. This is par for the course.
If you hate it, we can
leave in a half an hour.
I won't hate it.
Can we duck around
this photographer?
Can we? Yep.
Give me a smile.
Hey, Jeff.
Where's Sean?
Uh, he went to move the car.
Well, I don't want to
wait to tell you the news.
Your viral test is back.
No virus detected.
So I'm really HIV-negative.
Definitely negative.
You and...
You and Sean are close, huh?
Been together almost a year.
That's nice. Yeah.
But nothing's
worth dying for, is it?
I'm not dying.
No. You're safe right now.
But you have to
protect yourself.
I'm gonna get it
sooner or later.
Not if you practice safe sex.
I don't want to treat Sean
like he's contaminated.
If we use a condom,
that's how he feels.
HIV can kill you, Jeff.
I know a lot of
people living with it.
I've seen a lot of people
who'd rather be living without it.
Look. Look...
How old are you,
man? Twenty-three.
Because you got 50...
60 years ahead of you.
I love him.
Well, if he loves you, he
should want you to stay healthy.
He thinks that
this is the only way
that we can really be intimate.
That's easy for him to
say. He's got the virus.
I don't have anybody else.
You have yourself.
Whoa.
Those are the
bouncers. I know them.
Oh, yeah?
Bark is much
worse than their bite.
I can see how they
keep people in line.
John. There you
are. Hi, Grandpa.
Finally. Someone I
really wanted to talk to.
Not so loud.
Is this your friend
from the auction?
No, no. She had the flu.
And you are...? Abby Lockhart.
Jonathan Truman Carter Sr.
Delighted. We don't get to see
too many of Johnny's friends.
You got lucky tonight.
You're very good
to get dressed up
and come out on
such a cold night.
I'd much rather stay at
home... in a bathrobe.
Don't let Gamma
hear you say that.
Oh, she knows me by now.
I'd love to meet her.
Yeah, where is she?
Talking to the
keynote speaker...
Go on.
Shall we? Nice to meet you.
Have a good time.
Friend from the auction?
Last family event I was
at the daughter of the host,
she, um...
Never mind. No,
come on. Tell me.
You ever take dance classes? Ah.
No. Have you?
Mm-hm. Yeah. Actually,
I have a few moves.
I'm sure you do.
Care to give it a whirl?
Mm, I don't know. Come on.
Just follow me.
I'm not sure that
I can. I got you.
I feel like I'm back at my
spring formal in high school.
I went with this guy Seth.
But really I had a
crush on this guy Tim.
I'm feeling for Seth. When
he went to the bathroom,
Tim asked me if I wanted to
go outside and
smoke a cigarette.
And, um...
we never went back inside. Mm.
That's cruel. I know.
Is that when you
started smoking?
I guess so.
See, it's all Tim
Stillman's fault.
Right. Ha-ha.
I didn't forget you.
Your...
CPK's normal.
I watched you work
on that boy. Yeah.
You'll be going
for your echo soon.
It was remarkable.
You brought him back to life.
Yes.
It won't do much good
if he doesn't have the surgery.
Can't find him a heart?
He doesn't want one.
But he's so young.
There are bound to be
medical advancements.
He's gotta fight.
One could say the
same to you, bishop.
I am fighting. Are you?
You say you should
prolong his life...
but you want to
hasten your death?
I'm not looking forward
to dying, Dr. Kovac.
But I also don't want to
be enfeebled or bedridden.
I only wish I was
as brave as he is.
I think you've been
more than brave.
Have I?
I wanted to set
a good example...
serve my parish...
do God's work...
as long as I was able,
and then... go to glory...
with a modicum of grace.
But there are times...
when I'm alone in prayer
or... trying to get to sleep...
when it just overwhelms me.
I should never feel
the way I do sometimes.
How's that?
Frightened.
You got the phone
number, right? Yeah.
You should call tomorrow and
make an appointment, you know?
I'll see.
Anyway... Anyway... thanks.
Yeah.
Uh, Jeff?
You gonna protect
yourself from now on?
Maybe.
Probably not.
Big plans tonight, Malucci?
Uh, no. No. Just
getting out of here.
Go ahead, 104.
We're at the home
of a 65-year-old male.
Collapsed in the bathroom.
Found him in V-fib.
Haleh, can I... take the mike?
Defibrillated times four.
Gave epi and lidocaine.
Now in asystole.
He's gone.
This is Dr. Greene.
What's the downtime?
Been here 15 minutes.
Probably down
another 10 before that.
Any medical history?
Two MI's. Status,
post-bypass surgery.
The last doctor's
appointment? Hold on.
If he's seen a PMD
in the last month,
they can sign the
death certificate.
Save us the trouble.
Saw his cardiologist
nine days ago.
Still in asystole? For
the last five minutes.
That's it. Stop CPR. What?
I'm pronouncing him.
Time of death, 2118.
Can you do that? Yeah. You can.
Let the family know
that everything was done
under physician guidance,
but he did not respond.
You want us to transport?
No, have them
contact a funeral home.
This is County General,
clear with Rescue 104.
I don't know why
that was necessary.
What's the point in going
through the motions?
I'm looking for Dr. Kovac.
I'm Dr. Frost, Bishop
Stewart's personal physician.
See? You were great.
I had a good partner.
If we get really motivated,
we could enter a contest.
That might be too
much of a good thing.
Thank you.
Oh, no. What?
Hello, Abby.
What are you doing here?
I'm here with a friend...
John Carter.
Hi.
How you doing? That's Richard.
So what are you doing
at a charity event?
Oh, I'm here with Alexis. Who?
She went to get us drinks.
She old enough to drink?
Rich, who's this?
This is Abby.
Oh. Hi. Hi.
We should probably...
Where've I seen that dress?
You haven't. I swear.
No, I-I really don't
think you've ever seen it.
My sister's wedding.
You were a bridesmaid.
Always the gentleman,
Richard. Thank you.
Rich, let's go sit down.
Okay. Nice meeting you.
Bye.
Am I awake or was
that just a nightmare?
Last week I gave him IV
Solu-Medrol and put him on
high-dose steroids
for his arthritis.
Last week? Yeah,
this is his second time here.
He has diabetes.
Steroids put him in the
ICU last year with DKA.
I didn't know that.
Which is why you should have
contacted his primary physician.
I was going to, but...
What's his sugar?
348. Oh, great work, doctor.
You're destroying his vision,
his kidneys, his circulation.
Now that I know
about his diabetes,
I'm checking for
end-organ damage.
I've been treating Bishop
Stewart for 15 years.
He doesn't need
another physician.
Well, maybe you
should tell him that,
because he came to me.
Underneath that robe, he's
just a man like everyone else.
A man facing death.
And right now he's drug-seeking.
He just wants to
feel right again.
Well, that's not possible.
Where is he?
Okay, 104. See
you at the back door.
This is County Base. Clear.
What's going on? 104's
bringing in a full arrest.
I just talked to that guy.
Called en route. Cardiac arrest.
I already pronounced him.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
We gave him two
of atropine en route.
What's your
problem? We did this.
The family freaked. They want...
Do not unload the patient.
We have to. We're here.
He's been dead for an hour.
Family wanted a doctor.
They're right there.
Mark. Kerry, he's not
supposed to be here.
Stop CPR. No.
Resume compressions.
I said stop. This is the
guy who died at home.
Keep going, Cleo. Set up
Trauma 2 for a full arrest.
He's dead. When the
paramedics bring a patient,
we have to care for him.
Chuny, wanna put a
shroud on the bed. Shroud?
Yeah, he's dead.
Might save some time.
Mark.
Not gonna get him back, Kerry.
We still try. Are you
running this or am I?
Fine. What's his
rhythm? Still asystole.
What do you think?
Another amp of epi?
Might get him back?
Pupils fixed and dilated.
Hold compressions.
Dr. Finch, would you concur
that the rhythm is asystole?
Yes.
Code is over.
Take out the tubes
and clean the body.
That's the family.
I hope this helped them.
I'll go talk to them.
So typical of him to cry poor
and then show up
at this fancy party.
And did you think
she was even pretty?
I don't think I'll answer that.
I don't see it. I
think this is silly.
It's a blue BMW. What
if they took her car?
What do you think
she would drive?
A Lexus?
Ha. Get it? "Alexis"?
No... I mean...
Say we find it. What
are you gonna do, key it?
No. Maybe I'll
just slash the tires.
I think that would be overkill.
Oh. Stop! Stop!
Wait. There it is.
Do you have a pen? Yeah, why?
I'm just letting the
air out of the tires.
How many tires? Two's fair.
One's fair. Fine. Pen, please.
Uh-oh.
Now what do we do?
I think we have to run.
He's awake?
Yeah. And oriented.
Passed mental-status
exam with flying colors.
Where are you taking him?
He's got no neuro deficits.
He'll go to the ICU
and be extubated.
And the heart? I'm
gonna recommend surgery
to the transplant committee.
Dr. Romano?
Nick has requested
not to have the surgery.
Well, he's a minor. His
parents make that call.
You're gonna make him
do it, knowing how he feels?
Dr. Kovac, he's a teenager.
What do they know about life?
He'll thank us for
this in a few years.
Mark.
I'm off, Kerry. We
have to talk about this.
And what might "this" be?
The way you've been
acting. A-abrupt, cavalier...
Realistic?
Are you ready to
be back? Yes, I am.
Mark, you are still
reaching for words.
I'm fine.
What happens in a code
if you need a cardiac drug,
and you can't think of the
name? That won't happen.
I am asking you to
take some time off.
I'm telling you no.
Dr. Frost is arranging for you
to have more tests on Monday.
Did he dress you down?
He was, uh...
pretty mad, yeah.
He's very possessive
about my care.
You were on his turf.
Well, as I told him,
your EKGs and cardiac
enzymes are normal.
Thank you, Dr. Kovac.
For the treatment.
And for listening.
You're welcome.
I, uh... I saw they
took the boy away.
Is he gonna get
the operation then?
Yeah.
I'm sorry. Me too.
You think he should
have been able to choose
how he wanted to live?
I think so.
Well, I wanna work.
Do you still want the steroids?
I need to work.
Poor guy doesn't even have AAA.
So he has to pay for this.
Maybe Alexis will chip in.
She looks about ready
to call a cab to me.
I'd say we've successfully
ruined their evening.
Mission accomplished.
Now I feel kind of bad. Why?
Because I kind of
ruined our night too.
Ruined, how?
Besides the vandalism?
Yeah.
And that we're
freezing to death? Yeah.
You never even saw
your grandmother?
Oh, she knows I was
there. That's enough.
Okay, then, I guess nothing.
I had an okay time.
Me too.
Yeah. This is Kerry
Weaver at County.
I need information about
evaluating a physician
who's possibly
cognitively... impaired.
Could we speak first
thing Monday morning?
Thanks.