Move the C-arm.
Stay with me.
So this is how it's gonna be?
All day long, you've been
talking down to me.
I should have
given you credit.
I was very impressed
with the way you nearly
killed our patient.
We are running low
on a number of key supplies.
No, no, no, no.
Stop, stop.
I need that dye.
We can't have one patient
depleting our supplies.
So call another hospital.
We're all in the same boat.
Dr. Cuevas and I have
a strong hunch
that David is developing
schizoaffective disorder.
No! My boy isn't crazy.
Stay away from us.
How is that boy supposed
to get any help?
It is a real pleasure
to finally meet you,
Dr. Hawthorne.
My colleague at Med,
David Kwan,
he sings
your praises highly.
Oh, I'm not the doctor.
I'm her assistant,
Katherine.
Okay.
Sign and date
these forms, please.
Just wherever you see
a highlight.
While you're finishing up
with that,
I'll go over our policies
and procedures.
Everything you discuss
with Dr. Hawthorne
is confidential,
except in the event
she feels
you're a danger to yourself.
You know what,
Katherine?
I'm actually a practicing
psychiatrist myself,
so, I mean, if you'd like,
you can skip that part.
I totally get it,
but Dr. Hawthorne,
who you'll meet next week,
requires we go through
the policies together.
If the doctor feels
that you're a danger
to yourself or others,
she's required to report...
You know what,
Katherine?
I appreciate you're just
trying to do your job.
But, um, maybe you could
tell Dr. Hawthorne
to give me a call
when she has a chance
to meet me herself
in person, okay?
Um, you know what?
On second thought,
maybe, um, tell her
not to bother.
Yeah.
It's been a long time
since you had to hunt
for a therapist.
Want me to shoot
you some names?
I got a small stockpile
of referrals.
I gotta be honest, Sharon,
after these
last two experiences,
my interest in the process
might be waning.
I mean, this morning
in particular
actually had me questioning
the state of psychiatry.
Well, that assembly-line
mentality is plaguing much
of medicine these days,
not just psychiatry,
but don't worry,
you'll find your person.
See you later.
No coffee?
Oh, no.
I don't have any time.
We're implementing a new
drug shortage protocol,
so I'll be in the ED
all morning walking
the staff
through the new guidelines.
You couldn't get
the enforcer,
otherwise known
as Maggie Lockwood, on that?
She's in Paris.
She and Ben never took
their honeymoon, and she was
gonna lose her vacation days.
Wow.
Yeah.
Well, still, not a great time
to be short-staffed,
though, right?
There's never a good time.
Yep, you got that right.
See you later.
Get these off me!
David Sullivan,
17-year-old male.
We've met.
David, it's me,
Dr. Archer.
Do you remember me?
I can't stay here.
They're gonna find me.
I have to keep moving.
I can't stay in one place!
It's okay, honey.
You're safe.
He ran naked into the street.
Dad managed to grab him
before he got hit by a car.
No visible injuries that
I can see. Gave him 0.5
of lorazepam en route.
Hello, again, Mrs. Sullivan.
Is your husband all right?
He's fine, yeah.
He's just a bit shaken up.
He drove behind us,
should be here any minute.
Doris, would you...
Page psych. I'm on it.
Okay, finish my sentences
for me, why don't you?
Okay, David, we're gonna
loosen your restraints now
and move you to the bed.
I need you to stay still.
Keep your hands
by your side, all right?
Okay, ready, everybody?
On my count,
one, two, three.
Good. Okay.
Very good, okay.
No, no, no, no, no!
It's all right.
David, please.
Just let the doctor
look at you, okay, honey?
They came
inside the light.
They're trying to steal
my DNA so they
can clone me.
Okay, so what do you think
could have triggered this?
We were at a stoplight,
and David became fixated
on this billboard.
It was just
some random man
selling car insurance.
He's not random.
He works for them.
There's a whole network.
I don't know.
He started taking
his clothes off
and telling us
that they were bugged
with recording devices.
And then right when
the light turned green,
he bolted.
He ran across four lanes
of oncoming traffic.
There was...
There was a pickup truck
that was coming right at him.
And he...
Eric.
Sir, are you all right?
Oh, my God, Eric!
All right,
let's get him
to the ground.
Eric! Eric!
Come on.
What's going on
with him?
It was meant for me.
They're gonna kill us all!
It's okay, honey.
Mom, we gotta
get out of here now.
Let's get a gurney
over here!
It's okay.
Come on!
Oh, my God.
No, no, no! No, no!
Your husband's
CT angiogram showed
an aortic dissection.
That's essentially a tear
in the wall of his aorta.
So Eric didn't have
a heart attack?
Well, a dissection
can often mimic
heart attacks
in presentation.
This particular tear
is very close to his heart,
which is why we need
to get him to surgery
as soon as possible
in order to repair it.
Open heart surgery?
Mm. Yes.
Dr. Morris, one of our
cardiothoracic surgeons,
will be performing
the operation.
He's on his way here now.
Oh, okay, can I see Eric
before he goes under?
Yes, of course.
Once we get him to pre-op,
I'll have a nurse
come get you.
How about
we go somewhere
and chat for a bit?
Thank you. Okay.
I don't understand.
Why would David
think that this man on
a billboard was after him?
It's what we call
a delusion of persecution.
Yeah, one becomes convinced
that some individual,
you know,
or group is conspiring
to harm them
or the people
that they love.
And these delusions,
that's something that
you see with schizophrenia?
It is, yeah.
I know Eric and I
weren't exactly receptive
the last time we all spoke.
We completely understand.
It's a lot to take in.
I just thought
that David was
going through
some kind of phase,
growing pains, you know?
But in these last couple
of days, it's like he's...
He's lost all touch
with reality.
It's just like,
I feel him slipping away.
Mrs. Sullivan,
I promise you,
David is still there.
Yeah, and with treatment,
these episodes will become
less severe
and less frequent.
And with proper management,
they can even go away.
What do you mean, medication?
That's a crucial
component, yeah.
David thinks people
are trying to poison him.
How am I going
to convince him
to take pills?
There are actually
injectable versions
of many antipsychotics.
Though we don't
generally start there.
Those are
usually held in reserve
for non-compliant patients.
Of course. I'm just saying,
if he refuses or becomes
non-cooperative,
they're an option.
Right.
But we'll cross that bridge
if and when we get there.
In the long run,
it's just much better
if we can get David on board
with taking medication.
Okay.
Ms. Martin, I'm Doctor...
Liza.
Sorry, you were
saying?
I'm Dr. Choi.
I understand you haven't
been feeling well.
Yeah, I can't keep
anything down.
And you're
12 weeks along.
Uh, that's just
an estimate.
I only just recently
found out I was pregnant.
I haven't gotten around
to see a doctor just yet.
Well, in that case,
we'll go ahead
and run an ultrasound.
Doris, will you mind
grabbing Dr. Asher?
Sure thing.
Thanks.
So when did the vomiting
and diarrhea start?
Just last night.
And you haven't taken
any medication?
No, nothing.
I don't want
to take anything
while I'm pregnant.
Well, you know there are
some nausea medications
that are safe for pregnancy.
Still, I just...
I would rather not.
Um...
I'll be fine. I just really
came in here to make sure
the baby's okay.
Understood.
Mind if I press
on your belly?
I just want to see
if anything feels tender.
No, no, no. No, no, no.
I don't want her.
You'll have to get me
another doctor.
Dr. Asher?
Hannah Asher, right?
Yeah. She's an
excellent physician.
She's an addict.
You get me another doctor,
or I'm leaving.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Okay, okay, okay.
Just hold on a moment.
Hey, Hannah, sorry,
I jumped the gun, actually.
We're all good.
Oh, okay.
Well, in that case,
I'm grabbing breakfast
if anybody's looking for me.
Dr. Tanaka-Reed,
hold up a minute.
Can you have them
update that for me?
Thank you.
Look, I...
I wanted
to clear the air.
The other day,
I may have come off
a little condescending.
I appreciate
the acknowledgment,
Dr. Marcel.
Of course,
and if there's anything
you'd like to say...
No, don't think so.
We're all good.
What, you didn't
have time to grab him
flowers from the gift shop?
I mean, I expect
the other docs to go soft
on the residents.
I thought you had grit.
Well, no man's
an island, right?
You know, island life's
really not so bad.
Maybe you just don't
have the stomach for it.
Dr. Marcel, you've got
a trauma incoming.
Well, thanks for
that pep talk, coach.
Anytime.
What do we got?
Marcus Walker,
50-year-old male,
fall from standing.
Gave him a 500-liter
bolus en route.
Pressure's hanging
around 100, systolic.
Heart rate's 120.
Yeah, I've never seen him
in this much pain.
It hasn't let up since
he hit the pavement.
This is his sister, Janet.
Did you witness
the fall, Janet?
He lost his balance
stepping off the sidewalk.
It didn't look that bad,
but then he couldn't get up.
Okay, we'll give him
something for the pain.
We just got to find
the source of it first.
Any medications
we should know about?
Dialysis.
Oh, and he takes ramipril
for his blood pressure.
Okay, here we go, guys.
Nice and easy
on my count, okay?
One, two, three.
I'm sorry, Marcus.
I'm right here, Marcus.
I'm right here.
Janet, let's give the doctor
some room to work, okay?
We're gonna take care
of him, Janet,
we got this.
Let's hang
a unit of whole blood.
Pressure it in, Ron.
Hey, Marcus,
put your arms
by your side for me.
There you go, bud.
Deep breaths.
Okay, lungs are clear.
He's still shocking.
Yeah.
He's bleeding
from somewhere.
Let's fast him, Dr. Taylor.
Belly's negative.
Really?
Yeah.
All right,
let's get him on his side.
Uh, Herbert,
come over, please.
All right, here we go.
Nice and easy, all right?
One, two, three.
There you go.
You're doing great.
You're doing great, Marcus.
What is it?
Oh.
An abscess.
Looks like it.
Pus under pressure.
It's gotta be the source
of the pain.
All right, let's drain it.
Scalpel.
Hematoma.
Yep. Hold pressure
and pack it in.
You got it?
Yeah.
Okay.
Got it.
All right, give me
another unit of
whole blood.
Start DDAVP and a unit
of platelets, stat.
Come on, let's move, folks.
Ms. Arya, hello again.
Indrani, please.
Indrani. I got the results
back on your culture.
Unfortunately,
you tested positive for
an infection called MRSA.
From an ingrown toenail?
MRSA is really hard
to treat, isn't it?
While it is resistant
to many antibiotics,
luckily, there are a couple
that still work for it.
How long do I have to be
on antibiotics?
About seven
to 10 days.
Oh.
See, I told you
you wouldn't have to
cancel your trip.
Oh, yeah?
Where are you headed?
Well, I'm going
to Scotland in a few weeks
to hike the West Highland Way.
It's a 96-mile trail through
the Scottish Highlands.
Ninety-six miles?
I've been training
for the last year.
I may be pushing 60,
but I don't feel it.
Let's start with vancomycin.
No, I can't take vancomycin.
I'm allergic.
Uh-huh.
I see that.
I had a terrible reaction
when I was a kid.
My throat closed up.
Then we will
steer clear. Nancy?
Linezolid? On it.
Mm-hmm.
We'll get you in tip-top
shape for Scotland, Indrani.
I've been wanting
to do this a long time.
Um, Dr. Halstead, the pharmacy
won't release the medication.
What?
Is there a problem?
No, just probably
a system glitch.
Sit tight,
and I'll be right back.
Look, per the new protocol,
you're gonna
have to go through
Infectious Disease first,
and they're going to want
to try incising and draining
the infected tissue
before they approve
giving linezolid.
Incising and draining?
So source control.
That is not gonna
cut it, Ms. Goodwin.
She needs linezolid.
I mean, can't we
just say that, uh,
you know, Infectious Disease
already signed off?
No, we cannot,
Dr. Halstead.
Linezolid is
on the restricted list due
to extremely low inventory.
There's a region-wide
shortage.
And we are dealing
with a systemic
MRSA infection.
You're looking at the patient
in front of you.
But the Oversight Committee
designed the guidelines
to ration these drugs
to the most severe cases.
I have seen early
source control work wonders.
Give it a shot.
Dr. Marcel.
Yeah? Uh-huh.
I got Marcus's CAT scans.
Two very severe
lumbar burst fractures.
All from a spill
on the sidewalk?
Take a look.
Oof. Renal disease
definitely sped up
his bone loss.
He's gonna need spinal
stabilization surgery.
Yeah, agreed. Only option
to get him walking again.
Given his comorbidities,
without it, he's just gonna
circle the drain.
All right, let's, uh...
Let's go talk
to Neurosurgery.
And David, this voice
that you're hearing,
is it male or female?
I don't know.
It's more like it
has its own language,
its own way
of communicating.
And then my brain
translates the messages
so I can understand them.
Mm-hmm.
Are you getting
any messages right now?
That you're writing down
everything I say because
you work for them.
You're one of their spies,
aren't you?
No, I'm not a spy.
Then give me
your notebook.
I'm not gonna give you
my notebook, David.
Give it to me.
David, I need you
to listen to me.
I'm a doctor.
I'm writing things down
so I can better understand
what's going...
Get out of here!
Out, now!
David, David,
how about Dr. Cuevas puts her
notebook away for now.
Would that
make you feel better?
And I notice you've been
checking out this vent.
There's a camera in there.
Huh.
They're always
watching me.
There isn't a camera
in there, David.
Yeah, I'm pretty sure
that there isn't,
but, you know, we're...
We're happy to cover it up
if it'll make you
more comfortable.
Okay, good.
So why don't I go see
what I can scrounge up.
And I have
another couple of patients
I need to check in on,
but in the meantime,
is there anything else
I can get you?
Can I have a Coke?
Absolutely.
Okay, so back in a bit.
And Dr. Cuevas,
can I just get
a quick word, please?
So with patients
experiencing paranoia,
I've found that
it's probably not
the best idea to push back
too hard on their version
of events, you know,
especially at the outset.
There's actually
evidence-based research
suggesting the opposite,
that you shouldn't reinforce
a patient's delusion.
Instead, you should try
to explain to them
why they're experiencing
things differently.
I hear you,
except that that's
pretty much impossible
if you haven't
first established trust.
But very glad to hear
that you are keeping up
on the literature. Way to go.
Oh, got Choi
as your advisor.
Luck really isn't
on your side.
Why?
He's been
really cool with me.
Yeah, well, I wouldn't
get too comfortable.
Word is,
he's a real hard-ass.
Got his
last resident fired.
Olga, what are you
doing down here?
I was gonna ask you
the same thing.
I assumed you were
out today.
Why's that?
Oh, well, Dr. Choi
asked me to ultrasound
his pregnant patient.
I don't understand.
Why would he ask you?
I cover the ED.
So do you have a question
about my qualifications
or something?
Of course not, Hannah.
Then why would you
ask another obstetrician
to do an ultrasound
in the ED when I'm here?
Obviously, you don't
trust me.
It's not that. I...
The patient
requested another doctor.
She... She knew
about your past.
What? How?
Uh... Does she
know me personally?
She didn't volunteer
that information,
so I didn't press it.
Fine.
Forget it.
Hannah.
I'm just so sick
of this following me
everywhere I go.
No matter how much
progress I make,
everyone's still judging me
for who I used to be.
Nope. Medically,
it's just too risky.
Chronic hypertension,
end-stage renal disease,
the list goes on and on
with this patient.
The real kicker
is that platelet count.
I'm not touching anyone whose
platelet count's below 100k.
Listen, we know that
he's not an ideal
candidate.
Oh, wait,
I almost forgot.
You guys also hacked
his back open in the ED,
making a posterior
approach impossible.
Should I go on?
Look, I can give you
great anterior exposure.
All you have to do
is stabilize his spine.
I'll take care
of everything else.
Oh, you'd be assisting me
on this one?
Wow, way to save your
strongest argument for last.
Maybe you're just worried
about your stats, Sam.
Send him up
to Interventional Radiology.
Have them inject cement
into his fractures.
That'll at least
get him sitting up.
But that won't
get him walking.
And lack of movement
is dangerous in
Marcus's condition.
He can...
He can develop pressure sores,
blood clots, pneumonia.
All preferable to him
bleeding out on my table.
We just need to get
his platelet count up.
Yeah, it's the only way
to get Marcus
healthy enough for surgery
and Abrams on board.
All right, I'll, uh...
I'll order a couple
of units of platelets,
all right?
Patty, any updates
on your husband?
Oh, he just went
into surgery.
Dr. Archer said
it will be a while
before there's any updates.
Okay, well,
he's in very good hands.
You can trust me on that.
David, got that Coke
you asked for and
some stuff for the vent.
Do you think you might
be up for chatting a bit?
You all right, pal?
Trini gave him something
just to calm him down.
Oh.
Okay, back in a second.
What did you give him?
Six of risperidone.
What?
Who the hell
ordered that?
I did.
He became
extremely agitated
and was resisting
restraints.
Lorazepam worked
this morning.
You didn't see
how upset he was.
Haldol, then.
He was going
to tear out his IV.
His mom was freaking out,
begging me to do...
Well, you cannot let
a family member
pressure you into making
a rushed treatment call.
It wasn't rushed.
It was necessary.
And besides, the meds
will clear his system
by tomorrow morning
at the latest.
At which point,
we'll be back
at square one with David,
if we're lucky, all right?
Any trust established,
down the drain.
How about this,
in the future,
maybe at least page me
before administering
a very high dose
of antipsychotics
to a patient
we're still evaluating?
With all due respect,
Dr. Charles,
I am not a trainee.
And six milligrams
is well within
the standard of care, I...
Standard of care,
whatever that is,
is not some
blanket template
you follow
without any regard
for the person
in front of you
you're supposed
to be helping!
Hey, Janet.
I just want to let you know,
the nurse will be by soon
to start Marcus's
platelet transfusion, okay?
I know it's been
a rough day.
More like a rough year.
Lost my husband
in January.
I'm so sorry.
Marcus came out
from California
for the funeral
and just never went home,
moved in with me.
You must really
get on.
Never had a choice
in the matter.
We're twins, actually.
Marcus was born
45 seconds before me,
but you'd think he was
years older, the way he acts.
Seeing him here like this,
so fragile...
It's really hard.
I want you to know that
we're gonna do everything
we can for Marcus, I promise.
Okay.
What is it?
I was just looking back
in Marcus's history.
His platelets
have always been low.
Oh. Do you think
this is chronic?
Some kind of undiagnosed
blood disorder, or...
ITP would be my guess.
Oh, man.
And if that's the case,
a transfusion
is not gonna do much.
I mean,
his body would just
keep chewing up
any new platelets
we give him.
Well, unless...
Unless what?
Um, forget it, actually.
I thought I had something.
But let's just hope
the transfusion moves
the needle a little, okay?
Podiatry incised
and drained the toe.
They had to cut
the nail out.
I'm not a doctor,
but it looks like
it's getting worse to me.
Don't worry. I'm on it.
We're gonna get you
the medicine you need.
Dr. Halstead,
can I speak
with you outside?
What's wrong?
Uh, just give us
a moment.
We're now completely
out of linezolid.
You've gotta be
kidding me.
I knew it.
I knew source control
wasn't gonna cut it.
How soon are we expecting
to get it back in stock?
Tomorrow morning,
at the earliest.
Order vancomycin.
She's allergic.
I know, all right,
but I've got an idea.
Hey, Liza.
So got your labs back,
and they look good.
Your white blood count
is slightly elevated,
but that's pretty common
in pregnancy.
I think we're just looking
at a stomach bug.
Makes sense.
I can go home, then?
Yeah, Dr. Patchefsky
sent down a list of
OB-GYN referrals,
as well as some
genetic testing counselors.
We'll just add those
to your discharge.
Genetic testing?
I thought she said
the baby looked healthy
on the ultrasound.
Genetic testing
for hereditary conditions
is completely optional.
But the baby's
healthy, right?
Yeah.
Hey, listen, if...
Liza, my dear.
I have your
discharge paperwork.
I'm not sure
I'm following you.
You want to give me a drug
I told you almost killed me?
And we'll do everything
we can to mitigate
the chances
of another adverse reaction.
How, exactly?
Through a process
called desensitizing.
We'll pre-medicate you
with steroids
and antihistamines
and then administer
the vancomycin via
a slow IV drip.
And can you promise me
that my throat won't
close up again?
I can't promise that, no.
But if you do go
into anaphylaxis,
we'll have epinephrine
at the ready.
Worst-case scenario,
we might need to intubate,
but that would
only be temporary.
Intubate me? No, no.
I'll go to another hospital.
Well, we've
called everywhere.
The earliest anyone
has linezolid is tomorrow.
So I'll wait.
As you're seeing,
MRSA moves fast.
I am afraid if we wait
until tomorrow, it will have
already spread to the bone.
You could lose
your leg, Indrani.
Give me the vancomycin.
Okay.
Marcus' platelet count rose
from 50,000 to 105,000.
Can you believe it?
That's great.
It's fantastic.
He must not have ITP
after all.
Do me a favor.
Show Abrams
these updated labs.
I think he'll be
more receptive
if you deliver them solo.
How could he possibly
refuse to operate now?
It's Abrams.
I'll get him on board.
Dr. Choi?
We've got a problem.
Liza?
I thought she had left.
I came in to turn over
the room, and I found her
passed out.
Let's get her back in the bed
and up on the monitors. Ready?
One, two, three.
All right. All right.
Liza? Liza,
can you hear me?
All right, let's restart
her IV and get a Foley in her.
Grab OB.
Patchefsky, right?
No, no, no. No time.
Grab Asher.
Okay.
She's hypotensive. BP 85/43.
Maybe she vasovagaled?
Her white count
was more significant
than I thought.
Liza.
You know her?
Yeah, Doris filled me in.
How long had she
been experiencing symptoms
when she came in?
Less than 24 hours.
And that's self-reported
from the patient?
Yeah, why?
Bolus a liter
of normal saline.
Hannah, we've been
giving her fluids.
Could this be sepsis?
We could start a broad
spectrum antibiotic.
Let's just see what
this does first.
I don't think
we're looking at sepsis.
I think she's hypovolemic
from massive volume depletion.
I suspect she's been
sick a lot longer
than she reported.
BP's starting
to come up.
Hey.
Appreciate you
stepping up to the plate
on this one, Sam.
His platelets sure turned
around fast, didn't they?
Marcus is a fighter.
All right,
this is my show.
Once we get to the spine,
you follow my lead,
understood?
Fair enough.
Mia,
start my playlist.
All right, after you.
Scalpel.
Where are we at?
I gave 125
of the methylprednisolone
and 50 of diphenhydramine.
All right, we're ready
to start the vancomycin.
Now, we're gonna
take it slowly, gradually
increase the dose over time.
Are you ready?
As I'll ever be.
Something doesn't
feel right.
Okay.
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God. My throat...
I can't swallow.
Okay, we got you.
Nancy, 0.3 of epi.
I can't...
It takes time to work.
Just stay calm.
Keep your eyes on me.
Another 0.3 of epi
and another 50
of diphenhydramine.
Mask.
There you go.
Get ready to intubate.
Just a precaution.
I think it's working.
Slow, deep breaths.
In through the nose,
out through the mouth.
That's it.
So how long
have you actually been sick?
This is day six.
Ever since I stopped using.
Did you know
that these symptoms
are a result of withdrawal?
I figured.
Dr. Asher, if I outed you
to your colleagues...
No.
No, you didn't.
Everyone here knows
that I'm in recovery.
And you don't have
to call me Dr. Asher.
It does feel kind of weird
calling you by your last name.
I won't tell anyone
in group.
Thank you.
I don't even know
if the drugs have cleared
my system yet.
I couldn't risk you
running a drug test on me,
given everything
you know about me.
I just... I don't want
anyone taking
my baby away.
Well, I commend you
for quitting, Liza.
Going cold turkey
is really hard.
There are some medications
like Suboxone and methadone
that can help curb
the cravings.
Those are opiates, right?
Yes.
But when you're
medically supervised,
you are allowed to be
on them while
you're pregnant.
The risk to the fetus
is minimal...
No.
If there are any risks,
then no.
I probably shot up,
like, a half dozen times
during my first trimester.
And still, by some miracle,
the baby seems to be okay.
I can't do anything
to jeopardize that.
I won't.
Come in.
I was going to check
with Mrs. Sullivan
to see if she would agree
to David spending
a couple of nights
in the psych ward.
I figure we can
talk to him more,
begin to find the correct
medication and dosage.
Well, that sounds good,
Dr. Cuevas. Thank you.
Oh, and his father
is out of surgery.
No complications.
Well, good stuff.
I'm glad to hear that, too.
I should have spoken
to you first before
medicating David.
Look, you know
it was a chaotic situation,
and I understand that you felt
the need to act swiftly. I do.
I probably did jump
to medication too quickly,
if I'm being honest.
I know I rely heavily
on the literature
and the standard of care,
but I just don't always feel
like I can trust
my own instincts.
I mean,
it took me years, years.
And still,
I have my days when...
You know?
But this,
I can promise you,
you will get there.
You will. There's not a...
Not a shred
of doubt in my mind.
Trust me on that.
Hey, Janet.
Marcus did great.
I can't thank you both enough.
No need. He's got
a long road ahead,
but with physical therapy,
I'm confident he'll be back
on his feet.
Can...
Can I see him?
Of course.
I'll take you to recovery.
Now, he's just waking up,
so he might be
a bit groggy, okay?
This way.
Dr. Abrams,
I heard the good news.
I really appreciate...
Yeah, you two ever pull
a stunt like that again,
I won't keep it to myself.
I'll go straight to Goodwin.
Excuse me?
I don't appreciate
being conned into surgery
under false pretenses.
Wait.
I'm sorry, Dr. Abrams.
What are you talking about?
My antenna went up
when Marcus's platelets
corrected so quickly.
So I had the lab run
an anti-platelet
antibody test
while we were in surgery.
You might be interested
in the results.
Marcus has ITP.
Mm-hmm.
But this doesn't
make any sense.
If Marcus has ITP,
the transfusion
shouldn't have worked.
Correct.
Unless someone gave him
a little assistance.
You gave
Marcus steroids,
didn't you?
And that's why
his platelet count went up.
I know steroids
can be controversial
in the surgical settings...
To put it lightly.
You put him
at greater risk
of post-op infection.
Vanessa, believe me
when I tell you,
this was our only play.
Our only play?
I was left in the dark.
Look, I didn't want you
catching any heat
if things went south, okay?
I have more cover
as an attending.
I was trying
to protect you.
I do not need
your protection.
I need your respect.
Vanessa, of course
I respect you.
It does not feel
that way right now.
Looking much better, Indrani.
Some techs
will be back soon
to move you upstairs.
We're gonna keep you on IV
vancomycin for a few days
and then switch you over
to the oral version.
Dr. Halstead,
I can't thank you enough.
I'm just sorry we had
to put you through all that.
Oh, it was worth it,
believe me.
That's where
I'm going to be next month.
I'm adding it
to my bucket list.
Would you excuse me
for a moment?
Of course.
Ms. Goodwin.
Stop by my office
before you leave tonight.
I'd like a word.
Will do.
Dr. Choi,
uh, this is for you.
I saw you were staying on
for the night shift,
so I figured you might
need a caffeine boost.
Oh, and these
are also for you.
It's my CV, in-progress
research papers,
and all my case logs to date.
For our first advisor
meeting tomorrow.
Ah, well, you are
really prepared, Zach.
Will you excuse me?
Yeah, of course.
See you tomorrow.
Hey.
Liza agreed to be admitted
overnight for observation.
Good.
She's in withdrawal,
I take it.
Don't worry,
I won't say anything.
I appreciate that, Ethan.
And while I suspect
that the drugs have
already cleared her system,
she's terrified someone
might report her.
The last thing
she needs is to be
penalized for seeking care.
Look, you were
absolutely right,
by the way,
to bring in
Dr. Patchefsky.
I never should have
given you flack for that.
Look, I know how frustrating
it is to always feel like
you're being held
to some former version
of yourself.
But on the flip side,
because of who you were
and what you went through,
you were able
to connect to Liza
in a way no one else could.
Yeah.
I guess that's true.
Maybe it's not always
such a bad thing, having
your reputation precede you.
Great work today, Sam.
Good night, Dr. Taylor.
Ooh, ouch.
Why, I see
you've got yourself
quite the fan club.
You know, maybe I was
wrong about you.
You might be cut out
for island life after all.
So, let me
get this straight.
You gave the patient
an antibiotic you knew
she was allergic to...
Only after I advised her
of the potential risks
and with her full consent.
Which, trust me,
wouldn't hold up in court
if this thing
had gone sideways.
Well, Ms. Goodwin,
it wasn't my first choice.
I understand the new protocols
got off to a bit of a rocky
start today, but...
They're not working.
I have no doubt
they were designed
with the best
of intentions,
but as your boots
on the ground, I have to
give it to you straight.
Let me give it
to you straight.
These supply chain issues
are not gonna resolve
anytime soon,
and not for
lack of trying
on my part.
So, as imperfect as these
new protocols may be,
we need
some sort of semblance
of order in the ED.
I can't have it turning
into the Wild West!
Honestly, Ms. Goodwin,
I think we're already there.