She's a love bug.
Have you ever had the
starring role in a play?
A solo in a recital?
She's gonna take her first
steps any minute. I can feel it.
All eyes on you.
Okay, so I am gonna
give you the giraffe,
and maybe she'll walk to you.
Well, she's not
gonna do it on cue.
She's gonna surprise us, right?
You gonna surprise
us? Here you go.
Waiting for you to do
what they came to see.
No! Hi. Yeah, Daddy.
She's gonna take her first
steps while she's in day care,
and then I'm gonna kill
myself. No, she won't.
You're not gonna
do that, right, Zo?
Zo, come to Daddy.
Come to Daddy.
Come on. Come get
the giraffe. Come on.
You're just the cutest
kid on the entire planet.
Why is that? She's perfect.
Okay.
Feeling the incredible
pressure to perform.
There was a time when they
used to call operating rooms
an operating theater.
It still feels like one.
Scores of people get
ready for the show.
The sets are arranged.
There are costumes,
masks,
props.
Everything has to be rehearsed,
choreographed,
all leading to the moment
when the curtain goes up.
You know what they
say about Carnegie Hall?
There's only one
way to get there.
Practice, practice, practice
until it is perfect, people.
This is a long, complex
procedure with many parts.
Therefore many
opportunities for error.
So we're gonna
go over this again.
Team leaders,
let's get in place.
All right, green team,
over here, please.
Let's go, red. We've
offered this family
every pro bono dollar,
every surgical hand, every
resource this hospital has.
So I'm asking you for every
resource that you have.
Be sharp, be
present, be focused.
Dr. Robbins has been
caring for these children
since the day they were born.
They will each get
a new life today.
Our actions will decide
what kind of lives they will be.
Let's begin.
I thought I had Dr. Knox.
You know what I love
about you? The warmth.
You were doing
the conjoined twins.
Well, now Knox is
doing the conjoined twins.
Uh-huh. Uh, we're
not talking about it.
Of course we're
talking about it.
It is a crazy idea
that I am not talking
about, because it's crazy.
It's not crazy. We'd
sleep in one bed,
we would have breakfast
at the same table,
we'd have one electric
bill instead of two.
Oh, that's why you want
me to move in with you?
So we could save
on the electric?
Yeah, it's the
responsible thing to do.
For the planet.
I am not moving in with you.
Look, we've been
together, what, two weeks?
Two weeks and nine
months, before the pause.
And I want to hit play
again, right where we left off.
I don't want to start
at the beginning.
Because it's good
for the planet?
And I have a better TV.
Look, come on, now. Admit
it. You want to live with me.
You love me.
I want
Knox back.
Flaps are inset and viable.
We are looking at,
at least, 18 hours,
so come and go if you need to.
Hydrate, eat,
but be here at least 30
minutes before your procedures.
All right. Next up,
general surgery.
First we need to
establish each baby's
blood supply to
the shared colon.
Then we separate the colon,
making the first incision...
I will make the first incision.
We'll separate the colon.
Okay, and now I'm checking
the displaced kidneys...
To make sure they're
intact and functioning.
That's implied.
I don't care. Say it.
Checking the
kidneys to make sure
they're intact and functioning.
Man, she's wound up tight.
Thought you were off work today.
I won't see another one
of these in my lifetime.
Okay, you need to tie that...
You're doing the flip,
right, Karev? With Robbins?
Mmm-hmm.
The flip's a critical
part. You ready?
Yes, sir. ARIZONA:
You forgot to cauterize.
You want this baby to bleed out?
- Do I...
No, I... ARIZONA:
Yeah, I should think not.
Look, I know this
procedure's her baby,
but she keeps
nitpicking everybody,
she'll destroy their confidence.
Don't let her do that to you.
No, sir.
Good, because if this flip goes
wrong, she's gonna blame you.
It'll go on your record, and
they have boards coming up.
It's not gonna look good.
Did you check the pelvis?
Glad it's not me.
Okay, it's time to flip them.
Karev, you're up.
Ready?
Yeah.
And why is the
flip so important?
It just gets very tricky.
They have open incisions,
so they have to stay sterile,
and we have to make sure that
they stay intubated and monitored.
Okay. And we also have to keep
all their IVs and wires
from getting tangled
and intertwined in the process.
You know...
Imagine changing the battery
of your car while
speeding down the freeway.
Except it's not a
car or a battery.
I mean, they're your babies.
So... It's a bad
analogy. I'm sorry.
No, that's the first thing you've
said that I've totally understood.
But if the flip goes wrong,
then everything after that is...
Is hosed.
The doctors have planned
and rehearsed this for weeks.
I mean, they've got it down.
Karev, you rushed it. You're
like two steps ahead of me.
No, you over me. Yours
over mine, everything's fine.
Mine over yours,
babies in the morgue.
That's how it works. That's
your mnemonic device?
Great. Now Brandi's
wounds are exposed,
and little Andi's gone without
oxygen for a whole minute.
Okay, can we start over?
No, there's no time.
Let's just finish this practice
and try the flip again. Next.
Neuro. CALLIE: Ortho.
Okay, we will access and
separate the conjoined spinal canal.
Separate the bony
elements of the spine.
Well, that was a train wreck.
You nearly killed both dolls.
I have it. I know it.
If only freakin' Robbins
would trust me to do it.
- Doll killer.
- Meredith Grey.
Hey, come with me.
OR two, right away.
Okay, I am gonna tell you
something about my personal life.
Really? Okay,
my personal life is
none of your business.
The fact that I know things
about your personal life
is one of the great
sadnesses of my existence.
Sorry about that.
And the fact that
you're going to know
about mine is
exponentially worse,
but I don't see how
we get around it.
Okay.
We're about to
operate with Dr. Warren.
He and I are involved.
Everybody knows that.
Can you not pretend?
Oh. Oh, you and Dr. Warren? Wow!
He is going to try and discuss
personal matters in the OR today,
and I don't want
that to happen. Okay.
Okay, so I'm going
to teach you a lot.
And you are gonna
ask questions a lot.
And if he gets a personal
word in edgewise,
I want you to forget which is
the business end of a scalpel
real quick, and ask for help.
Okay, but let me
get this straight.
You pulled me out of a
once-in-a-lifetime surgery
to be a buffer between
you and your boyfriend?
Now don't you use that
kind of language with me.
Spinal separation complete.
I have to go. Teddy.
It's been two weeks now. You
need a break, and she does, too.
I got to go.
Okay, I am now prepared
to separate them completely.
Wait. Hold on. What
about complications?
I mean, what if there's
a double hemivertebra
or a tethered cord?
We will cross that bridge
when we come to it.
We're done here. I'm sorry.
What if we're standing
on that bridge right now?
Dr. Robbins, I said...
No, no, no. We haven't
even separated them yet.
We haven't gone through
the post-separation surgeries.
Dr. Robbins, stop.
There's so much...
We're done practicing.
We have practiced our
parts not only here in this OR,
but in the shower,
on your drive to work.
We're ready.
We know what to do.
Now we just have to do it.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I present to you Andi
and Brandi Edwards.
Let's give them
new lives, shall we?
It's show time.
Raising the skin
flap. Avery, you there?
One step ahead of
you. You want to race?
No, no, no. No racing.
That was fun last night.
Did you and Mer have a good
time? I know Julia had a good time.
Yeah, we did. You got enough
length there for coverage?
Yeah, I'm dissecting from
the base to the midline.
Did Mer say
anything about Julia?
She liked her.
Jackson, slow down.
And Zola liked Julia, too?
Yes, she did.
Everybody liked Julia.
Anybody else here meet Julia?
Did you like her? Show
of hands if you liked her.
You did? You did?
I'll update the parents.
Hunt, they're clearly racing.
No racing. We're not racing.
We have been
rehearsing this for months,
and now they're gonna
jeopardize the patient...
Robbins, you take care of your
team, I'll look at the big picture.
Done. I win.
And by that, we mean
ready for the colon resection.
Cafeteria? Race you there.
General surgery teams, let's go.
Is that enough lap pads?
A little more is not gonna
hurt. They'll help mobilize it.
How's Zola doing?
Oh, she's great, thanks.
She's about a minute
away from walking.
That's great.
And she's in the
day care downstairs?
She is, yeah.
She really likes it.
Must be nice, having the
whole family in the building.
Yeah. It's a win-win.
You love Dr. Shepherd,
and he loves you,
and you see each other at work,
and then you see
each other at home.
Just more of a good thing.
Dr. Bailey, is that
the spleen right there?
That is the spleen.
So are we gonna take
out the whole thing?
We will. We will
take it right out.
So how many suture ligatures
do you think we'll need to do
for the splenic vessels?
Oh, could be two,
could be three.
I'll see if two does it, but I
may have to throw in a third.
This is good stuff. I'm glad I
skipped the conjoined twins.
There's beauty in the basics.
There's beauty in sharing a
bowl of cereal with a woman that...
I can't remember
how to do a stick tie.
No shame in that.
There's no stupid questions.
You sure about that?
Dr. Altman.
Dr. Yang. You paged me?
I didn't realize Cristina was...
Do you want me to
step aside so she can...
No. But you paged her.
It's no problem,
really. I don't mind.
I can go peek in on the
progress of the conjoined twins...
Stay put, Kepner.
Yang. From the beginning?
Yes.
Vitals were stable after
receiving L.R. and packed cells.
The bronch was already
placed when I entered the OR,
so I proceeded with the laser
endoscopy using the CO2 laser.
Step-by-step.
I had good visualization of
the tumor almost immediately.
About 80% of the tumor
had been vaporized
when the bleeding began.
He had clots, which
were blocking my scope.
I passed a brush through
the scope to clear the field.
However, Henry's
hemorrhaging was so severe...
Suction, Kepner.
Kepner, suction.
Yang?
Henry's hemorrhaging
was so severe
that the brush did
not solve the problem.
SATs dropped to 88. Blood
was coming out of the ET tube.
At that point, Dr. Webber exercised
his judgment and stepped in.
We cracked his chest and
tried to get to the source.
Henry became bradycardic,
so we pushed atropine.
Then I realized the tumor had
eroded through the pulmonary artery.
He flatlined.
We did ACLS protocol
and got sinus brady.
We pushed high-dose
epi. He flatlined again.
We did more compressions.
We continued in this manner
until Dr. Webber and I both agreed
that since he already lost
more than half his blood volume,
his heart could not restart.
We called time
of death, 8:52 p.m.
Again.
When I entered the OR,
Henry's vitals had been stable.
He had received
L.R. and packed cells.
The bronch was already placed so
I proceeded with
the laser endoscopy.
And then, thanks to the
unhealthy level of comfort she felt
working for her husband,
she took some liberties
with the clinical trial,
and now neither of their
careers will ever be the same.
You know, I would
love to go back
to dividing the
gastrocolic ligament,
but I'm not sure I
remember how to...
Figure it out. Look,
all I'm saying is,
it'd be nice to maintain
some boundaries,
so a person's life doesn't fall
to pieces, like Dr. Grey's here.
For the record, my life
is pretty great right now.
You hush. No one's
interested in your life.
Dr. Grey. Please ask
me about a spleen.
Who's the last person you see
before you fall asleep at night?
Or a pancreas. I've got
a very good view of it.
It's tan and lobulated...
Answer the question.
Last person you see before
you fall asleep at night.
Derek Shepherd.
Must be nice. All I'm saying.
Zero silk.
Thank God.
They're separating
the colon right now,
making sure that they each
have good blood supply.
Have they done
the flip thing yet?
That's next.
Um, I got to get out to here.
Is there a bar around here?
Um... Yeah. Across the street.
He's not a total drunk, if
that's what you're thinking.
He has a job.
It's a good one, with benefits.
Seriously, Gretchen, I wasn't...
No, I know what
you were thinking.
It's what everybody thinks.
That we accidentally
got pregnant
and now we're stuck with
these kids we can't take care of.
You're probably
placing bets in the OR
of how long we'll stay together,
or whose mother is gonna
end up raising the girls.
Well, you can tell everyone
in that room that they're wrong.
We love each other and
we wanted these babies.
We're staying together, and we
will do whatever we need to do
to make sure that they're okay.
Including accepting
the hospital's charity,
even if I have to sit
around with judgy doctors.
I wasn't judging you.
Really. I just...
I was thinking how lucky you are
to be with somebody
that you love.
Looks like Andi has the bulk
of the blood supply to the colon.
So we'll give her
all the colon then?
And leave Brandi with an
ileostomy? I don't think so.
I'll do an ileoproctostomy.
Maybe they should just
share, so we don't have to...
No. We'll do it my way.
Check the function of the
blood supply to the kidney.
Flip's coming up,
and I don't want
a repeat of this
morning's rehearsal.
That's what I want
to talk to you about.
I'm a little nervous about it.
We practiced that flip
before, and it turned out great.
And today... Robbins
doesn't trust anybody today.
Get to your point, Karev.
I just don't want
to screw this up.
We got to be the perfect team.
And you're not comfortable
doing it with her?
She's making
everybody uncomfortable.
I get it. You don't need
to say another word.
Who wants to replace
Karev on the flip?
No, that's not what I meant.
I'll do it, sir.
You sure you can do this?
Disconnect and
cap Subclavian IVs,
anesthesiologist
holds the ET tube,
designated circulators and
the techs hold the monitors.
Yours over mine, babies...
Don't. Don't.
Why aren't you doing the flip?
Webber snaked it from me.
Webber? But he hasn't practiced.
You've been practicing
this for two weeks.
Yeah, tell him that.
I told the parents
that you've practiced.
I told them that you
had this thing down cold.
Okay, one, two, three.
Easy, easy, easy.
I hope he drops her.
How's he gonna like it when
one twin's pushing her sister
in a wheelchair the
rest of their lives?
I'm just pissed at Webber.
You're just a monster.
And we're done.
All right!
Good. Okay.
Nice work.
Well done. All right!
He flatlined again.
Then Dr. Webber and I decided
that without any blood left to circulate,
his heart would not restart, so
we called time of death at 8:52 p.m.
Tell me about the tumor.
The tumor had eroded
through the pulmonary artery.
Okay.
How do you know? Know what?
When you say that the tumor
eroded into the pulmonary artery...
how do you know? There
was a hole in the artery.
Did you actually see the artery?
I felt it. You just
blindly felt it?
It wasn't a blind feel.
I knew what I was doing.
I traced it with my fingers.
Uh-huh.
It was the posterior
segmental artery. I'm sure of it.
How can you be sure?
You never got a visual.
I followed the
tracheal bifurcation.
It came directly off the
main pulmonary artery.
Okay, Kepner, let's get a few
of these lymph nodes for biopsy
and then get ready to close.
I didn't call it
without being sure.
From the top, Yang.
Um...
His vitals were stable
after receiving fluids.
He was under anesthesia,
and the bronch was placed
when I entered the OR.
So I proceeded with the laser
endoscopy using the CO2 laser.
Dr. Bailey, op notes done.
Do you mind if I
run out for a minute
until the next patient's ready?
He's gonna be here
30 minutes from now.
I know. I can get out and
make it back in that time.
You're going to try
and get a sandwich
then I'm going to get the
sad story 40 minutes from now
about how long the
line was in the cafeteria.
He's a nice man. You could
do without me for half an hour.
Dr. Grey.
He won't bite.
For God's sake.
You can run, but you can't hide.
Look, what we have is good.
Now why on Earth do you
want to rush it and complicate it
and quite possibly destroy it?
Because we're not kids anymore.
Because my life
is happening now.
Not 10 years from now or five
or a respectable 14
months, but right now.
And I want to share it, every
day, every morning, every evening,
and if that's not what you want,
then I guess we're just
not right for each other.
Now, look, we just got
back together two weeks ago.
I can't...
Well, I guess I
just got my answer.
Hey... It's been two weeks.
Excuse me. Excuse me. Excuse me.
Okay. Look at this face.
Seriously, look at this face.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, super-cute.
They're in the spinal cord now.
Bailey spent the last two hours
telling me how
crappy my life is,
but look at this face.
Oh, Zola, look.
There's your daddy.
He's about to repair
a myelomeningocele.
Can you say myelomeningocele?
What an ass. Hey, language.
Baby here.
He pretends he's
all gentle and sad
with the Alzie wife at home,
dispensing Zen wisdom
from his half-century
of being a surgeon.
Well, guess what?
Yoda down there,
biggest shark of them all.
The guy is dangerous and mean.
I think what Teddy's
doing is mean.
It's fine.
No, it's horrible.
It's horrible and...
You know what else is horrible?
Having a dead husband.
No, you know what?
You don't know,
okay? It's not right.
Teddy's OR, it's like...
It's like a morgue.
Well, Altman's husband died on
Yang's table. Payback's a bitch.
Oh, will you just
shut up? It's fine.
I can handle it.
Well, it has been two weeks
of this. It must be getting to you.
No more than it did
yesterday or the day before that
or the day before
that. It's fine.
I can handle it.
Damn it. Spinal dermoid cyst.
It's all tangled up
in the spinal root.
Yeah, there's a lot of scarring in
there. I don't see a clean approach.
Well, no, you
have to take it out,
because the cyst could
become malignant.
Yes, we're aware. Thank you.
Maybe if I can come in
from an angle like this,
but then we risk the
contents spilling out...
Which could cause
a chemical meningitis.
Dr. Robbins, we've got this.
Okay, what if we stretch
the nerve root here?
Well, that might
paralyze Brandi.
Yes, Brandi might
end up paralyzed.
Yeah, no one understands
that better than we do,
which is why we will be
making this decision, okay?
Us. Not you.
Us. You all right with that?
Just make sure that...
Yes, I'm okay with that.
No more talking from
anyone in this OR.
We need complete
silence from now on.
Hey.
I was in the shop downstairs,
and I figured, you know,
now there's gonna
be two of them,
they're gonna need
their own clothes.
So I figured Brandi
could be the punk first
and then we could
make them switch
and see which one
wears them better.
I love you.
I love you, too.
Oh!
Uh, they're about to
separate the girls, which is so
cool. It...
Okay, we're ready
for the final cut.
All right. Separation complete.
No, no, no. Not yet, not yet.
We still need to check
on the motor function.
Let's do
2 milliamps of stimulation
on Andi first, please.
All right.
All right. Let's try Brandi now.
2 milliamps of stimulation.
Let's go up to 3
milliamps, please.
Come on, Brandi. Just give
us some kind of movement.
Anything.
All right. Let's go to 4
milliamps of stimulation.
Hey, there you go.
Great work, everyone.
One step at a time,
by the numbers,
like we practiced.
Let's move.
Okay, count of three. One,
two, three. Gently. Nicely done.
We've still got a hell
of a long way to go.
I'll be checking in on you both.
How's it going in here, Sloan?
The flap is well-vascularized,
has good cap refill,
and is covering
the defect perfectly.
I nailed it.
Did Avery nail his?
What's going on, Avery? You
should've finished your flap by now.
Yet I haven't even started.
Why don't you give me
a call when you're ready?
Her kidney's
completely necrotic.
V-tach.
Okay, push 30
milligrams of calcium.
She's already showing
signs of renal failure.
Her kidney was fine earlier.
Maybe something
caused an arterial spasm
while we were checking the
function of the blood supply.
I don't know, but at this point,
I don't think it's salvageable.
She hasn't had any urine
output since she's been in this OR.
How did it happen?
Sometimes
complications can arise.
I didn't even want this.
I mean, you people, you
doctors talked us into this.
You promised us
that you could do this.
So what are you
saying, Dr. Grey?
She's saying that our
perfectly healthy daughter
started the day
sharing three kidneys
and now she only has one,
which isn't even working.
Which basically
means she has none.
That's what she's telling you.
Can they fix it?
Is Brandi gonna be okay?
We don't know yet. We're
just gonna have to wait and see.
17-year-old male with
multiple GSW to the chest.
We're bringing him
straight from the ER,
so we don't have a
lot of time, people.
Get him on the table.
Dr. Yang, are you
scrubbing in this time?
No. No.
All right, on my
count. One, two, three.
Let's move, Kepner.
Yang.
Vitals were stable after
receiving L.R. and packed cells.
The bronch was already placed
when I entered into the OR.
So I proceeded with
the laser endoscopy.
How was your lunch, Dr. Grey?
Oh, it was fine.
Actually, no line at all.
I was able to get my sandwich,
find my daughter,
see my husband,
go watch the
groundbreaking surgery
that's going on right next door,
and still get back in
time to do my work.
Sounds like you
have it all, Dr. Grey.
I do, actually. I have it all.
I've heard enough
about the lunch.
I don't see anymore perforations.
I'm gonna start closing.
I'd say we should grab
a drink and celebrate,
but I know you don't have
room in your life for joy.
Is it a crime that I like to focus
when I'm in the workplace?
If so, my apologies.
I focus. I focus like a laser.
That's why I don't
make mistakes.
That's why my
patients survive surgery.
That's why I'm not
sloppy or careless...
We're missing a sponge.
Or inconsistent, like
many of my colleagues are.
Frankly, like most
of my students are.
When you and
Chatty Cathy over here
we're discussing
the magic of lunch,
I was focused
enough for both of us.
Dr. Bailey. What?
We're missing a sponge.
Well, count again.
We did. Three times. We've
looked everywhere except...
Except where?
Inside the patient.
Did you clear out the clots?
Yeah. OWEN: Were
there any adhesions?
No, the vessels are clear,
and yet the kidney is dead.
What if we tried a bypass graft?
A kidney transplant.
We've got the perfectly
matched donor right next door.
They used to share all
three of those kidneys.
There'd be no need
for immunosuppressants
because they're identical twins.
They'd be saving each other.
Okay, Karev. It's your
idea. Make it happen.
The parents wanted to see
her before she went up to PICU.
She looks so weird.
Where's her sister?
I cannot look at her
without her sister.
Honey, Brandi's gonna
be fine. She'll be here, too.
They're both gonna be fine.
We need Andi back in the OR.
What's wrong?
We're gonna do a kidney
transplant. Brandi's kidney failed.
It's straining her other
organs, including her heart.
No, you can't. EVANS:
It's okay. Let them take her.
I can't lose them both.
Please. No. You can't.
Please. I cannot lose
them both. Please. No.
How much longer?
You need me to scrub in?
Almost there.
Well, can you be almost
there a little faster?
There. Got it.
Thank you.
Open the frigging door. Okay.
Kidney looks healthy.
Are you ready?
Yeah. Go ahead and scrub in.
Vitals were stable after
receiving L.R. and packed cells.
The bronchoscope was already
in place when I entered the OR,
so I started with
the laser endoscopy.
I had good visualization of
the tumor almost immediately.
Tell me about the tumor.
It was highly vascularized
and had eroded through
the pulmonary artery.
How do you know? I felt it.
What did you feel? A hole
in the pulmonary artery.
Are you sure that it was
the pulmonary artery?
Yes. Or did you
just blindly feel it?
I knew what I was
doing and what I felt.
You had your hand on
it? I had my hand on it...
and traced the anatomy.
Are you 100% sure?
She said she's sure!
Enough! It's enough! This is
enough! You can't keep doing this.
You can't...
He's gone.
Dr. Altman, I'm
sorry, but he's gone,
and this is not
gonna bring him back,
so please just stop.
Please.
Are you all right, Dr. Kepner,
or do you need time
to gather yourself?
No...
No.
Okay, then.
I am 100% sure.
All right.
Henry flatlined.
We did compressions, pushed epi,
got a sinus brady,
pushed high-dose epi.
He flatlined again. We
did more compressions.
We continued in this manner
until both Dr. Webber and I
decided that his
heart would not start.
We called time of
death at 8:52 p.m.
You have every reason to
be pissed with me, Karev.
I played you.
I wanted in on that surgery,
and I looked for the weakest link,
and it was you.
That's all right.
Next time, I'll know better.
It's not all right.
That was your moment,
and I took it away from you.
What I did today was
sad. It was pathetic.
An old man acting out of fear.
You get to a point
in your career...
Hell, in your life,
when you realize you got
more yesterdays than tomorrows.
And that realization
is hard on a man.
But when you get a chance
to get in on something like that,
you fight like a tiger,
all because you
think it'll give you
just a little more
time in the game.
I don't think you have
to worry about that.
You kidding?
A year from now,
maybe two if I'm lucky,
they'll stick me in
an office in a part of
the hospital
nobody ever goes to.
They'll appoint me to
some do-nothing board
that makes up rules
nobody pays attention to.
They'll let me do a
couple of appys a week,
so I can still call
myself a surgeon.
You reach a certain
age, that's what happens.
It's the order of things.
I can't think of anything
more humiliating.
Can you?
No.
Hey, you want to scrub
in on the transplant?
Robbins just needs one of us.
Go ahead.
Really?
Go on, or I'm gonna
change my mind.
I don't know...
Thanks, Karev.
36, 37, 38, 39... Nope.
The X-rays are here.
Look, keep looking.
Dr. Bailey, we have to close.
He's been under too long.
You have boards coming up.
Is this really what you
want on your record?
Well, don't just stand
there like a whipped puppy.
Check under the liver again.
It's not under the liver.
Excuse me?
It's not in the patient.
Dr. Grey, I thought I taught
you the simple, reliable rules,
like when you don't
find the problem
on your first look, check again.
Double-check,
triple-check if you have to.
We don't throw our hands up in
my OR when a man's life is at stake.
Dr. Bailey, the sponge is
on the bottom of your shoe.
On the...
Focus, like a laser.
Why aren't we getting any urine?
There's a kink in the
vessels. Papaverine, please.
Hey, why are you
doing this and not Karev?
He was the one who
suggested the transplant.
I picked Karev's pocket.
You what?
Twice in one day, Karev?
Honest to God.
It was like taking
candy from a baby.
No, that's not right.
It's not fair to the baby.
It was easier than
taking candy from a baby.
At least the baby
puts up a bit of a fight.
Removing clamp.
Yes! We got it! We have urine.
The kidney's working!
We did it.
Good job.
Dr. Webber exercised his
judgment and stepped in.
So we cracked his chest and
tried to tamponade the bleeding
and get to the source.
He became bradycardic,
so we pushed atropine.
I then realized he had lost
so much blood, because...
The tumor had eroded
through the pulmonary artery.
Right. That's when he flatlined.
We did compressions...
Pushed epi, got a sinus brady...
Push high-dose epi...
Which is when
he flatlined again.
Yes.
And you and Dr. Webber agreed
that he had lost too much blood.
Yes.
And didn't have
enough left to circulate,
so his heart would not restart.
Yes.
So you called time of death.
8:52 p.m. 8:52 p.m.
I'm sorry.
Oh, you don't apologize.
You hear me? You
don't blame yourself.
You did every single thing
that I would have done.
You were me in that OR.
You were good
and you did it right.
He just...
He just died.
I had a husband and a
baby and I was a surgeon.
I had it all.
And then it all turned bad.
So I got divorced.
And then I got back
on my feet, I found you,
and then there was a shooting.
So now I am finally back on my
feet, again, and I have you again.
I just don't want it to blow up.
Okay. You're scared.
See, all right,
and now I am, too.
Why can't we be scared
in the same house?
Well, don't act like
it's not complicated.
It's not complicated. We
just take it one step at a time.
Put a toothbrush
in my house today.
Tomorrow, maybe a
couple pairs of socks.
Then a suitcase
on the weekend...
I have a child. I can't
just move in with you.
Wait. You have a child?
Whoa! When did that happen?
Stop. You are not a funny man.
I met him. Rick, right?
It was a mistake to even
enter into this conversation.
T. rex versus
Megalosaurus, who wins?
Well, I have no idea.
You know who does?
I do, and so does Tuck.
Megalosaurus is
a tenth of the size.
T. rex eats Megalo every time.
But T. rex versus
Pteranodon, though...
Ben... Pteranodon can fly.
That's an easy win. Unless
you think that's a forfeit.
Yeah, I can do this all
day, and so can Tuck.
You're bored already, and
we've been at it 30 seconds.
I like Tuck.
I like hanging out with Tuck. I
like dinosaurs and Transformers
and I like you.
I want the whole package.
I know you don't
come without Tuck.
I know that.
I know who you are.
So that's it?
Nothing?
My toothbrush is in my locker.
One step at a time.
Ooh!
Sorry, guys.
Ha-ha! So that went well today.
Hmm. You were a monster.
No, no, no. I was amped up.
Okay.
Yeah. I think people
found me helpful.
Oh! Mmm-hmm. Okay.
Okay. Anyways.
I'm gonna go check on the
twins, then I'm gonna head home.
Hey, could you put the
humidifier on in Sofia's room?
She seemed a little
congested this morning.
Yeah... Yeah, but don't
give her anything for it.
I don't think we're
there yet. All right.
Oh, and give her
the pink blanket
that your friend Terry gave us.
She likes that. No,
no, she doesn't...
Yes, she does.
And don't put it
on her directly,
'cause she'll just fling it off.
Lay it down on top of
the sheet, fuzzy side up.
Excuse me. This is
important. Are you getting this?
Fuzzy side up, not down. Up.
Not down, up. Not
down, up. Fine, fine, fine!
My way. My way.
Fine, fine. Fine. Fine.
I was a monster.
Hey, Mike.
Hey.
Mind if I get started?
No, no, no, go ahead,
Mike. We were just leaving.
Hey, I'll come see
the babies with you.
Seriously, though, I'm
putting the humidifier on.
If only life was just
a dress rehearsal.
And we had time for do-overs.
That's something, isn't
it, Karev? What a surgery.
This is a teaching
hospital, okay?
You were the chief for 20 years.
You're supposed to be
teaching your residents.
Not stealing surgeries
like some shark fifth year.
It's not cool,
okay? It's not fair.
Oh, I think I taught
you something today.
You don't give up a
once-in-a-lifetime surgery,
not for any reason,
not for anyone, not ever.
Watch your back, Karev.
I may decide to teach
you something tomorrow.
We'd be able to
practice and practice
every moment
until we got it right.
God, I wish you could've
been in there with me today.
Really? Me, too.
I'm sorry. I
wasn't... Oh! No, no.
I'm sorry. I was hearing things.
It was... Long day.
I'm just gonna... Okay.
Unfortunately,
every day of our lives
is its own performance.
She's gonna need rehab,
but the fact that her
legs are moving already
is a really good sign.
Is this a private party
or can anybody join in?
Here you go. Brandi, meet Andi.
She's the one who's been kicking
you in the ass your whole life.
Can we... Is it okay
if we touch them?
Of course you can.
Charley, look at them.
They're beautiful.
Look at them. They're perfect.
Hi.
It seems like even when we
get the chance to rehearse,
and prepare,
and practice...
Sweetie, you have to
go to sleep. You have to.
Just walk her around.
I am too tired to walk.
Oh!
Is that from today? Mmm-hmm.
She looks bigger.
Hey, are you getting bigger?
She is getting bigger.
She looks bigger.
Mmm-hmm.
Come on. Come get
the giraffe. Come on.
You're just the cutest
kid on the entire planet.
Why is that?
Oh, Derek, Derek. She's
walking. Where's the...
Where's the camera? Turn it on.
Hi. Hi, baby.
I can't open it.
Hi, baby Zola. Hi, baby.
I can't... Oh, gosh.
Turn it on! Turn it on!
I can't get it on!
There. Walk for me.
We're still never quite ready
for life's grand moments.
Oh, my goodness.
Oh, I missed it!
Good girl!