The infection indicates
flesh-eating bacteria.
It's not a strain
that we're familiar with.
Do you think this fire
has something to do
with the bacterial outbreak?
My gut tells me this fire
was deliberately set.
Patient zero,
Stuart Anderson.
He's been sending threatening
messages saying that
there's gonna be
some sort of apocalyptic
event in Chicago.
It's too late.
You can't stop it.
There are now
five confirmed cases
within the city
in the last 48 hours.
I saw what this infection
does up close.
If anything, people
aren't scared enough.
Hailey, is that
her blood on you?
She collapsed on me.
You stay right there.
Don't touch anything.
In the last 48 hours,
we've treated multiple cases
of necrotizing fasciitis.
That's flesh-eating bacteria?
No, it doesn't eat anything.
And it can be caused
by many different bacteria.
But it is fatal.
No. Only if it's not treated
in a timely manner.
Listen, there is
no need for alarm.
How do we know that?
It can only
enter the body
through a wound.
How can we be sure...
Listen, we will update you
when we have more information.
Thank you.
No cuts back here.
Looking good, Hailey.
How about your legs?
I just shaved them
this morning.
I'm gonna check them
for nicks, all right?
That girl
I brought in. Veronica.
Is she gonna be okay?
Tissue is pale
and malperfused.
Damn.
I can't
believe this.
BP's tanking.
70 over 33.
Marty, I need more time.
I'm maxed out
on pressors.
She's in septic shock.
If we don't get her
off the table,
we're gonna lose her.
Yeah. Well,
she'll die in ICU if we don't
get this dead tissue off.
So... give me
five minutes.
What happened here?
I don't know, I probably bit
a hangnail or something.
Is that a problem?
She's in v-fib.
No pulse.
Start CPR,
and push epi.
Maggie, get the paddles!
Paddles.
Charged?
Charged.
Clear!
Still no pulse.
Okay, one more of epi.
Charge again.
Charged.
Clear?
Clear.
She's asystolic.
She's gone.
Okay,
stop compressions.
Time of death, 10:38.
I'm Dr. Ethan Choi.
Where are we headed?
Follow me.
Okay.
Ms. Goodwin?
Dr. Danover, CDC.
Ms. Goodwin.
Ah, yes.
Welcome to Chicago Med.
We have expedited
a response team, so we...
Hi, Andrea.
Will Halstead?
You two
know each other?
Dr. Danover and I,
were bio majors together
in undergrad.
It's good to see you, Will.
You, too. Wish it were
better circumstances.
You tell us what you need,
and we'll assist you
in any way we can.
Our goals are containment
and treatment.
First, we need to isolate
where and how victims
are getting infected.
Then, we need to determine
a path to treatment
that will prevent death,
and eliminate the threat
of infection.
All right, you have
free rein over our facilities.
But, Dr. Halstead, do you mind
acting as liaison to assure
all of her needs are met?
Yeah, sure.
We've collected some
soft tissue samples already.
Great.
I understand you've already
ID'd a sixth victim?
Yes. Veronica Song.
She worked in the lab.
I'll need to speak with her
as soon as possible...
I'm sorry. We just lost her.
DISPATCHER OVER RADIO:
Ambo 61, man down
from unknown causes,
45 South Fairfield,
apartment 12.
Did your call just say
45 South Fairfield?
Apartment 12.
We just got one
for apartment 10.
Could be a duplicate.
We got one for
apartment 15.
Fire Department!
Drop two milligrams of Versed.
Got it.
What the hell
is going on here?
Ah. Dr. Halstead.
I just spoke with Sharon,
and she says the only way
to get this thing
is through an open wound.
But we just got five cases
on a single floor,
so how is that possible?
Clearly, there are other
modes of transmission.
Yeah, maybe
an insect vector?
Like, tick? Mosquito?
Or, it could be
physical contact.
People shaking hands,
touching their eyes,
touching their mouth.
Oh, my God.
You don't know.
Heads up, Chief.
Coming through.
I've never seen a staph
this aggressive before.
Look, my people are out there
dealing with this thing.
I want to know
that they are safe.
So, I need more
than guesswork.
We have to treat that building
like it's ground zero.
Hey, hey.
Excuse me. Excuse me!
Trying to get to my vehicle,
thank you.
I got nothing for you.
I've got nothing for you.
Ms. Goodwin, we've gotten
the go-ahead to evacuate
the apartment building.
I want every resident
transferred to quarantine.
Okay, I'll coordinate
with Fire, CPD,
and we'll quarantine
the patients here.
And I'm gonna need
an extra set of hands.
Dr. Choi?
Of course.
Once the building's clear,
we'll see if we can
locate the source
of the infection.
Okay.
Sharon?
Yeah.
Brett says that there might be
upwards of 30 patients.
There's not enough room
in the ED to quarantine
that many.
You're right.
Uh... April? Let's set up
the tents in the old wing.
Got it.
We're dealing with
an infectious disease.
Three more people
are dead, Maggie.
Sharon, if you're
concerned about me being
immunocompromised,
don't be...
Maggie, you're going home.
But, I just...
Don't fight me on this.
No, no, no.
I've got a meeting,
I've gotta get to...
I'm sorry, sir.
Afraid you'll
have to reschedule.
How long is this
going to take?
We'll get you back home
as soon as possible.
Uh, hey, need any help?
Excuse me?
Dennis Quan. I'm training
to be a fireman.
I passed the EMTB test
last week.
I'm scheduled to start
the Academy next month.
You live here?
Yeah. I know the terrain.
Well, appreciate the spirit,
Dennis, but we need
you to remain
a civilian for now.
I gotta get you in quarantine.
Whatever you say.
Manager says
there's a hold-out.
Sharlene Hughes.
You should check on her.
Let's go.
Ms. Hughes?
Sharlene?
You sure she's in there?
Yeah, she never goes out.
Open the door, please.
You have
no right to come in here.
Ms. Hughes, you're at risk
for having come in contact
with a dangerous bacterium.
You need to be examined
by medical professionals.
No. You keep away from me.
I'm sorry, ma'am,
but the officer will
remove you forcefully
if you do not comply.
Hailey.
Hey.
Did you finish interviewing
the lab personnel yet?
Yeah. No red flags.
We're checking on alibis.
What about people that
had access to the lab?
Vendors, security guards,
cleaning staff.
The lab keeps an
electronic visitor log-in,
so we're just
going through it.
Right this way, people.
Please find a tent.
Oh, man...
Okay, thank you.
All right, I'm gonna get
back to the case.
But the second I hear
anything, I'll report back.
Thanks, I appreciate it.
They did this
on purpose.
They're lying.
Ma'am, please, people here
are just trying to help us.
No, they're not.
It's the same they did
with Lyme disease.
And what did
they do, Sharlene?
Who are you?
How do you know my name?
I'm Dr. Charles.
And I know your name because
the manager of your building
gave it to me.
The CIA, they're behind this.
How? How so?
How does that work?
It's a biological weapon.
Just like Lyme disease
and AIDS. They sprayed it
all over the building.
And why?
Why are they doing that?
You know.
We're the guinea pigs.
You're gonna watch
and see how long
it takes us to get sick.
Oh, I see. You know,
that's a terrifying thought.
I can see why
you're so upset.
I need to get out of here.
Look, Sharlene. I know that
we don't know each other.
But I can see
that you're angry.
And you're... You're scared,
and I'd like to help you.
You just wanna drug me.
I won't let you.
Can I help you, son?
Uh... Yeah.
Um...
I think I might
have some information
that might be helpful?
So, this guy goes
to an interview for
a baby-sitting job.
And, today, he recognizes
the woman he talked to
from the news.
She's the Jane Doe
with the baby
who died from the bug.
They just
moved here from Utah.
Okay.
While she's
interviewing him,
she gets in a beef
with an exterminator,
she doesn't want him
spraying near the apartment
because it's toxic
and she has a baby.
Guess where she lived.
45 South Fairfield?
Ground zero.
Hi.
I'm Hailey.
Amanda.
How'd you wind up
here, Amanda?
I live in the building
where people got that disease
they're talking about.
Where are your folks?
It's just me and Grandma.
She was out.
They're looking for her.
She's at the River Casinos.
How old are you?
I'll be 15 in January.
Ninth grade?
That's a tough year.
Not for you, I bet.
For anyone.
All right, so, all of our
victims have come from
one of two places,
the CCU lab,
or this
apartment building.
Then there's some
mystery bug sprayer.
So, when was this?
This was
yesterday morning.
Well, it definitely wasn't
Stuart Anderson, I mean...
He was dying in
his hospital bed.
On top of that,
the OCD techs
ran the source code
behind
the threatening messages
on the college server,
Anderson's IP address
was spoofed.
Somebody made it look
like the threats
came from Anderson.
So, that's gotta
be our offender.
He's covering his tracks.
Hey, look, this guy had
access to the CCU lab.
He steals the bacteria,
then burns the lab down
to destroy any evidence.
So, let's track
where he bought
his bug spraying equipment,
and I want a full run down
on South Fairfield.
We're gonna nail
this son of a bitch before
he infects more people.
So, when we did
your initial intake, Amanda,
we didn't find
any cuts or bruises.
How are you feeling now?
Okay.
Any pain or numbness?
Does anything hurt?
No.
All right, well I'm glad
to hear that because
everything looks good.
I'll be back to check on you
again later, okay?
How about you, Hailey.
how're you doing?
I'm okay. How are you?
I should've asked you earlier.
I heard you got knocked
on the head pretty bad.
I'm doing fine, thanks.
Okay.
You guys hang in there, okay?
Thanks.
That was good news.
Yeah, I guess.
So, when did you know
you wanted to be
a police officer?
There was a sergeant,
her name's Trudy Platt.
When I was 12, this guy
robbed my dad's restaurant,
he pistol-whipped my dad,
stuck a gun in my face.
And they took me down
to the police department,
and I got to watch
the most badass woman
in the world doing her thing.
She commanded the room,
talked to officers and perps,
both like she was the boss
of everything and everyone.
And I wanted to be like her.
And now you are.
Not even close.
But, I keep trying.
Make sure to swab
all handrails and doorknobs.
Again, we are checking
anywhere people might
put their hands.
If this bug
is more communicable
than other strains of staph,
it could explain why so many
people are getting infected.
Hold on, I just got word
from my brother.
They think someone
may be spreading this
with a bug sprayer.
Bug sprayer?
Just found something
in the furnace.
Think you could take
anything off that?
Let's hope.
This is no outbreak,
it's an act of terrorism.
The bacteria in the nozzle,
it's the same staph
we found in the victims.
Okay.
So, now we start combining
antibiotics to extend
the spectrum of activity
and stave off resistance.
Now, if I remember
my microbiology,
some drugs attack the cell
walls, some the DNA inside.
Therefore, we have to hit
the infection from
multiple directions.
Now, there's the Will
I remember from undergrad.
Oh, my God.
Whoa. It did not look
like that a few hours ago.
I have never seen
anything like this.
It's reproducing so quickly.
It's unbelievable.
We need the people
from the university lab.
Maybe, they'll have some idea
how to deal with this.
Look, we still haven't
even ID'd the suspect,
let alone found the connection
to 45 South Fairfield.
So, I need to interview
the tenants of that building,
and see if they know anything.
Well, they're in quarantine.
And we can't release them
until we're sure that
they haven't been infected,
and that they're
not contagious.
So, I'll interview
them in quarantine.
A number of these people
are emotionally
extremely fragile.
I got one woman
who might even be psychotic.
She's definitely suffering
from paranoid delusions.
All right.
Well, you're a doctor.
Give 'em some drugs.
Sedate 'em.
I can't do that
without their permission.
There is someone out there
who targeted that building
with weaponized bacteria.
The key to why
may well be
within that group.
Now, you're telling me
some of these people
are emotionally fragile.
So, Dan,
then come with me,
keep 'em calm.
But I have to talk to 'em.
Upton.
Hey, Sarge.
Hailey, how you feel?
Like I should be
doing something.
I can arrange that.
Do you have any connection
to the CCU lab or know anyone
in the building who might?
No, I don't.
Yesterday, did you see
an exterminator,
a man spraying for bugs?
Oh, for God's sakes,
when are they gonna let us
out of this place?
If you're asymptomatic,
and your throat culture comes
back negative, you can leave.
In the meantime,
I would really appreciate it
if you'd try and answer
the detective's questions.
So, exterminator?
Yeah, he was wearing
this meth suit.
Did you see where
he was spraying?
Down the hall.
We have an ant problem,
so I thought that was why.
Can you describe him?
Race, height?
Definitely white.
I could see his face
around his mask.
He was on the tall side.
About 6 feet.
Anything else you can
tell us about him?
No.
Thanks for your time.
So, look, I'd like to,
um, take another crack
at Sharlene,
but I wanna
do it alone. Okay?
Okay.
Gimme five minutes.
Yeah.
Dr. Danover? Bruno Geller.
Hi.
Central Chicago University.
David Seldon.
How are you?
Heather Holcomb.
Microbiologists.
Hi.
Dr. Halstead,
Chicago Med.
Thank you for coming.
We hope you can help.
Do you recognize this staph?
Oh, my God. David?
That's E-87.
But that's changed.
How in God's name
did this get out?
Well, you tell us.
What was your level
of security?
Well, the highest...
Level four. There's no way
that could've gotten out.
Well, it did.
Why were you even culturing
something so dangerous?
For research.
Research for...
Well, we're working
to develop antibiotics
to help fight this kind
of resistant bacteria.
Well, did you have any luck
finding anything?
Actually, we might have
been quite close, but...
All our data was
destroyed in the fire.
Yeah.
Incredible.
Well, Dr. Seldon, Dr. Holcomb,
you have experience
working with this bacterium.
Would you assist us?
Um, hold on.
But that research,
whatever remains,
is proprietary.
The university can't just
hand over intellectual...
People are dying
and you're worried
about your bottom line?
No, that's not...
We will help.
Of course, we will help.
I mean, at the very least,
I can help you to rule out
the antibiotic combinations
I know to be ineffective.
Great.
Let's get to work.
Marty,
I need that epi.
One milligram, it's in.
Paddles.
Two hundred. Clear.
She's still in v-fib.
Damn it. Again.
Charge. Come on, Lynn.
Don't leave us now.
Epi's in.
Clear.
Damn it. Asystole.
Another round?
No, we lost her.
Stop compressions.
Lynn Messick,
time of death, 14:42.
Has the family arrived yet?
Not yet.
Okay.
I'm going to put on
some fresh scrubs,
and get something to eat.
Find me when they're here.
All right.
It turns out that
you were absolutely right.
Your building was deliberately
infected with bacteria
that was very likely
genetically altered.
By the CIA.
They have secret
labs everywhere.
But you know all about that.
You know, I wish
I could convince you that
I don't actually know
all about that, but...
You're not gonna drug me.
Hey, that's fine.
That's your choice.
But, um...
Sharlene, tell me,
how'd you figure it out?
I mean, this person who
was spraying your building,
how did you know
that he was CIA?
You're just playing
games with me.
You're trying to trick me?
Sharlene, I'm just trying to
figure out what happened here.
I promise you.
I'm not blind.
I see everything.
From my window, everything.
The drones with their cameras,
the helicopters...
Yeah, but the guy
that was actually
doing the spraying.
How did you know he was CIA?
He wasn't a real exterminator.
He didn't even have a van.
Just a little blue truck.
It was so obvious.
I see. And what kind of truck
does the CIA prefer
these days, like, what make?
They change it all the time,
so it isn't suspicious.
Well, can you remember
what kind this one was?
A blue one.
The one with
the silver circle.
The silver circle.
Somebody help me.
I need a doctor!
Help me!
April?
Somebody help me!
Need a wheelchair!
I thought
it was a bruise,
and it's just
got worse, and...
We're gonna
take you to surgery.
Somebody, help, help, look.
Help! Look at it.
Come on, let's go.
Sit down. Cover it up.
Let's go!
That's Mr. Quan,
he lives next door
to me and grandma.
And he's got it!
Okay. We don't know
what his exposure
to the bacteria was,
how strong his
immune system is...
Gotta be stronger than mine.
I mean, he's always
working out.
Amanda, stop.
Hey, hey, hey,
calm down.
Look at me.
Breathe.
You gotta think good thoughts.
All right, Dr. Charles
pulled some information
off one of the tenants.
I don't know
how reliable it is,
but according to her,
the vehicle in question
is a blue pickup
with a silver circle logo.
Okay, so that's gotta be
either a Toyota or a Nissan.
Nothing domestic.
Well, I got Burgess
dumping all the pods
outside the building,
running it through
the Secretary of State
and CHRIS system.
All right, I'll get with
Ruzek and Atwater,
we'll go through
truck rental companies.
Beautiful.
I understand
your concerns.
I do, but let's take this
one step at a time, okay?
You're in good hands here.
All right?
Okay, Mr. Quan, I'll be back,
all right? Hang tight.
How's Mr. Quan?
Meds are helping
him stay calm.
But he's scared
and rightfully so.
Did he tell you
he wants to be
a firefighter?
Yeah.
So, if he loses his arm...
Not gonna think
about that right now.
We should get scrubbed.
I'll be right there.
Okay, trimming layer
of fat and soft tissue
from the infected area.
You nasty bug.
Where did you come from?
Come on, Quan.
Show me the good stuff.
Is it still spreading?
Always.
You're in deep,
you son of a bitch.
Let's go. Show me
some blood flow.
Come on.
Damn it.
None of the muscle
is alive.
You're down
to the bone.
Mmm-hmm.
You can't
save his arm, can you?
No.
I made him believe
it was gonna be okay.
Hey, there's nothing wrong
with pushing hope.
I would've done
the same thing.
Give me the saw.
When you
spoke to us earlier today,
you said we had nothing
to worry about.
Look, we didn't have
all the information
that we have now.
The key is to be mindful
of hygiene and sanitation.
Wash our hands?
That's the best you can do?
That was our own Jim Myers
with Sharon Goodwin
from Gaffney Chicago
Medical Center.
Truly horrifying...
Flesh-eating terror?
That won't cause a panic.
I spoke to them for over
10 minutes. Gave 'em facts,
precautions,
but all they show
are 10 seconds
edited to sell fear.
Well, what do you expect?
Nine people have died,
Daniel. I expected that,
maybe, this time,
they'd take the high road.
Goodwin.
You saw them
take him away!
We gotta get out of here
or we're gonna get sick, too!
Listen to her.
She's right!
Yeah!
Sharlene, I need
you to stop yelling.
Okay, please don't...
You're the problem.
Let me out of here.
Let me out! Let me out!
Let me out!
Everyone stay calm.
The lab is analyzing your
cultures as fast as they can.
And as soon as
the results are in,
we'll start letting people go!
Let me out!
I'm scared.
Amanda, I'm not gonna
let anything happen to you.
You stay focused on me, okay?
Let me out!
You can't keep us here!
Sharlene, I need you to stop!
If you don't stop,
I'm gonna have
to medicate you, all right?
Let me out!
Five of Haldol,
IM number 7, right now.
No!
We just...
Please, we just need...
Let's go! Let's go!
Run, everybody! Run!
You're making
a big mistake!
You're a danger
to yourselves and the public!
Maybe we should go, too.
No, we stay put.
We're safe here,
I promise you.
Wait. Wait.
Listen, no more questions.
No more.
You guys have been
misquoting me, anyway!
Ms. Goodwin.
Yeah.
We were able to round up
most of the escapees.
But Sharlene Hughes
and a few others
are still out there.
I got names and descriptions.
Kevin, you've got
to find them.
If they are active carriers,
they're putting themselves,
and the city at risk.
I got you.
Okay.
We'll find 'em.
Thank you.
You can't do this.
What gives you the right?
No skin-to-skin contact.
Five feet apart.
I want more food, blankets
and water down here,
right away.
These people are exhausted.
Yes, sir.
Right on it.
You took my arm.
Yeah, I'm sorry.
But we did
everything we could.
The infection
was just too deep.
What am I gonna do now?
Well, we have
occupational therapists.
And I'll send one up
to talk to you.
Look, we saved a good part
of your upper arm.
All right, and when you heal,
we can talk about
a prosthesis.
Mr. Quan,
you are clearly a man
with a lot of focus
and determination.
Now, I'm certain
you're gonna find another
place to put that drive.
Okay.
Now, I'll come back
and check on you.
Dr. Marcel?
Nurse Sexton.
Bet you won't mind
when this day is over.
You don't have to do that.
Live life lightly,
Nurse Sexton.
Live life lightly.
Ms. Goodwin?
John Sorenstein from
the Mayor's Office.
You let 30 infected people
escape quarantine.
I expect it might make things
worse than they already are.
Have you made any progress
on finding a cure?
We're devoting all
of our resources...
So, no progress?
You are the public
face of this crisis.
Everyone's gonna be looking
to you for assurances.
For God's sake,
give 'em something, anything.
Tell them we'll be toasting
to a cure at Oktoberfest.
You need to
cancel Oktoberfest.
Are you joking?
It's one of the biggest
weekends of the year.
We're not canceling anything.
Well, that's your call.
But I'm not gonna lie.
This city is on the verge
of a meltdown.
And if that happens,
people are going to be
looking to assign blame.
I'm gonna make damn sure
nobody's pointing
a finger at the mayor.
Yeah. Well, blame is
the least of my concerns.
But then again,
I'm not a politician.
People are dying, sir.
And you're wasting my time.
Hailey. Good news,
your observation
has been cleared,
and your cultures came back
free of infection.
What about Amanda?
I don't know yet.
Her cultures
are still incubating.
I'll sit with Amanda.
Thank you.
Amanda, you're gonna
be okay, too.
All right? Look, I'm proof
that not everyone in here
contracted the bacteria.
I had my hand covered in it,
ample opportunity to get it.
You know what?
I gotta go back
to work.
But Dr. Manning's
gonna take my place.
Okay.
Could you see if they
found my grandma?
Yeah, I'll check.
Remember, only
good thoughts, okay?
So, Amanda,
what are you into?
YouTube clips? Memes?
Give it to me.
Amanda, what's wrong?
My leg, it feels weird here.
Kind of, like, numb.
All right, let me see.
When did this sensation start?
I don't... I don't know,
a few minutes ago.
Come on.
Let's get you upstairs,
and see what's going on
with that leg, okay?
Ah, there she is.
You all right?
Flesh-eating-bacteria-free.
Glad you're okay.
Thanks.
You okay to work?
Yeah, all set.
Good.
We got something, guys.
All right.
I got a blue pickup truck
two blocks away
from the apartment,
right in our time frame,
and check this out.
Hazmat suit.
License plate?
LEADS has
the vehicle registered
to Mersh Equipment Vehicle
and Rental.
You and Ruzek. Let's go.
Looks like the bacteria
are sensitive to the Vanc.
I know. Great.
No, it's not.
Damn it.
The Vancomycin
is only bacteriostatic.
It's slowing the infection,
but it's not
actually killing it.
We need something that works
stronger and faster.
Try gentamicin, then?
Dose it higher?
Yeah.
Let's do it.
How are you doing, Amanda?
You all right in there?
I'm trying.
Okay. We're almost
done here, okay?
Image is up.
There it is.
Air and fluid in
the deep fascia.
Yeah.
Ow!
Dr. Manning!
You all right?
It really hurts.
I feel something moving.
All right, just take
a deep breath, okay?
Keep breathing.
I'll take a look, okay?
Oh, no! No, no, no, no!
Call the OR, and tell them
we're on our way up.
And get me
an isolation gurney. Now!
It's okay. We're gonna
take care of this, all right?
Just keep breathing.
Am I gonna die?
No, you're not.
We caught this very early.
Dr. Marcel is gonna
fix your leg.
Amanda?
Hailey!
I'm right here. I just heard.
Let's go.
Everything's gonna be okay.
Thanks.
What's up, Dalton?
Uh, the sky.
Yeah, let me tell you,
we're not in the mood
for that.
What'd you need?
Blue Nissan Pickup,
Wisconsin license plate
WXT-221.
We need a list of who rented
it in the last two weeks.
Okay, y'all have a warrant,
or what's going on...
Listen, we don't have
time for this, pal. All right?
We're working the infection
case that's already killed
a half-dozen people.
So, we need you to focus,
we need you to
answer our questions.
Blue Nissan.
Yeah.
Yeah, that pickup's
only been rented once.
I got a name,
but it's Mike Smith.
He paid cash. So...
When?
Uh, three days ago.
Okay, let's try
a little harder?
Okay, what time?
Morning? Afternoon? When?
Yeah, yeah. Afternoon,
it was right before
I ate my lunch.
I take my break at 2:00.
So, it was right around then.
Great.
What did he look like?
Oh, white guy. Um, yea big.
Kinda his height.
I think he had a blue hat.
Is there a video?
Yeah, yeah.
But it's hosted off-site.
So, security company's
gonna have to dropbox you
the footage.
Call them. We want footage
for the entire day.
Right on.
Now, Dalton.
Yup, you got it.
NEWSCASTER ON TV:
An as yet undisclosed
number of patients
who fled quarantine
remain at large.
Authorities are working
diligently to track
them down...
It's wall-to-wall coverage
with this now.
While there is still
no sign of a cure...
Yep. Cindy called.
They're closing Luke's school.
Seems that somebody over
at that building happens
to be a janitor over there,
and now a bunch of
the parents are demanding
that the entire place
get disinfected.
Guys, this is that restaurant
up the street we go to,
Garcia's Hacienda.
What the hell?
It's one of those
conspiracy sites.
It's trending on Twitter.
What's it say?
That the outbreak is some kind
of MS-13 El Salvadoran plot
to get revenge on America.
Mama Garcia must be
somehow involved
because her food truck
was over at Soldier Field,
and her restaurant is
only a half a block
from the quarantined
apartment buildings.
That's ridiculous.
Mama Garcia is pretty much
the sweetest lady in Chicago.
Those who must commute
via train or bus
are wearing store-bought
protective gear...
That's the kind of news
that gets people killed.
...to remain calm.
In the next hour
we'll be speaking
with a representative
from the CDC, who will
give us a status report
on their research progress.
Truck 81,
public disturbance...
Blue hat,
right before 2:00.
Got it.
I know this guy.
He works at the CCU lab.
You see, Heather,
why don't you join
the others, get a bite.
Yeah. I could use it.
Bring you something?
No. No, I'm good. Thanks.
What're you doing?
I'm sorry?
You're destroying our work.
Oh, no. No, these were
contaminated samples.
You know what?
You need to stay right here.