- Your biological father
and I agreed
that we would never
contact you.
I broke that agreement.
- Maybe you could
just reach out
and ask him if he'd like
to meet me.
- Vanessa...
I can try to find him.
- The last time around
we got into some
pretty unhealthy patterns.
- I know
that we have history, Will,
but it is history.
- My units aren't
totally done yet.
Actually, one is livable.
If you want it, it's yours.
- Thank you.
- Pamela, what's going on?
- My hand at rest,
rock steady.
But when I pinch
my fingers together...
there's something wrong
with my hand, Crockett.
- I don't want to jeopardize
this investigation
because you can't handle
being in the dark.
- I care about you, Milena.
- I can't wait
for this case to be over.
- Yeah, me too.
- This is dispatch.
All teams report.
What's your status?
- Team Charlie,
target house 28,
offender in custody.
- Team Victor,
target 64 in custody.
- Team David,
target 52 in custody.
Shots fired! Shots fired!
10-1, 10-1!
Shots fired, target 16 house!
Officer down! Roll an ambo!
Stay with me, Sam.
Stay with me, Sa...
- I gotta go see what's up.
- No, you're undercover.
You're not supposed to be
involved with this.
- Doesn't matter. Just go.
You gotta get to the hospital,
okay?
♪
Morning.
- Morning.
- Thought I'd drop this off
before I do some consults.
- Thank you.
- Yeah.
- Got my MRI.
- Oh, great.
Progressive cervical
spondylotic myelopathy.
- You're gonna need surgery.
- I don't think I will.
- What are you talking about?
This is...
this is serious.
It's... it's spinal compression.
- I'm doing physical therapy.
I'll work through it.
- Recovery from surgery
is six to eight weeks,
and I've got a patient list
a mile long.
I...
I can't leave them
for that amount of time.
You might want another opinion.
- I'm happy
with the one I have.
♪
- Okay.
- Hey, Dylan,
got one coming in.
Juliette, I'm going to Baghdad.
- CPD Sam Devers, 45,
shot through and through,
right lateral chest
to right back.
Bullet was retrieved
from the back of his vest.
BP 98/66, heart rate 92.
- Hey, Sam, I'm Dr. Choi.
This is Dr. Scott.
- What happened?
- Drug raid.
Guys were waiting for us.
- Ambush.
♪
- All right, let's roll him.
- All right, ready? Roll.
All right, I'm seeing
two wounds,
probably an entry and exit.
Back.
- Sam? Sam! Oh, my God!
Are you all right?
- It's okay, Alice.
I'm sure it'll be fine.
- It is not fine.
You got shot!
- Please, ma'am,
if you wouldn't mind
waiting outside, we...
- I'm his wife.
I'm not going anywhere.
- All right, everyone clear
for an X-ray.
Clear.
- Hemothorax on the right.
- All right, let's set him up
for a chest tube.
- You only saw one entry wound
and one exit wound, right?
- Yeah.
- There's a bullet here
in his right hilum.
- Sam, you ever been shot
before?
- Uh-uh, no.
- You sure?
- Yeah.
- You know, it's
that new seafood place
on the river.
It's got a huge lobster tank.
- So you want me to pick out
an animal and then eat it?
- I'm sure you could get
a salad.
- Hey, Dad, I think
you might need this today.
- Oh, my God.
Honey...
- Yeah.
- Thank you so much.
Um...
this is my colleague,
Dr. Richardson.
My daughter Anna.
- We've... we've met.
We did the family therapy,
remember?
- Of course we did.
- Yeah.
- That's right.
- It's nice to see you again,
Anna.
- Um, anyways, I am late
for first period, so.
- Thank you, honey.
Thanks again.
Jesus.
- So does she not know?
About us?
- You know, I guess
she doesn't.
Um, I guess I haven't found
the right time to tell her?
- Is that really it, Daniel?
- What do you mean?
- Well, sometimes you try
to protect the people you love
by avoiding
difficult conversations
with them.
- Ahh.
Benefits of dating your shrink.
Um, no, that's not
what's going on.
Anyway, I gotta get upstairs.
So seafood tomorrow night?
We on?
- Sounds perfect.
- Nice.
♪
- Hey.
Those plants you got
for the building?
Nice!
- Thanks.
Six is good.
Did you know peace lilies
actually absorb sound?
Yeah, I'm trying
to cut down on street noise.
- Look at you, Mr. Google.
Hey, I have to ask, I noticed
that you haven't cashed
my rent check yet.
- Well, I...
no, uh, I didn't.
- Well, how come?
- Actually, it bounced.
- Why didn't you tell me?
- It's no big deal.
- Of course it's a big deal.
I'm good for it.
- You know...
- Dr. Halstead? Dr. Asher?
I'm having trouble getting
a visitor
to leave a patient's room.
- What's the problem?
- It's the patient's mom.
- We'll be right there, thanks.
Hi, I'm Dr. Halstead
and this is Dr. Asher, OB-GYN.
How can we help you?
- Well...
tell them, Mom,
how I'm a total failure.
I am 22, single, and pregnant.
- Yes, she's pregnant.
She shouldn't be working
as a hot yoga instructor.
She passed out.
- You see?
It... it's always the same.
I just can't do anything right.
I just want her to leave.
- Do you mind?
Trini can take you
somewhere comfortable
while we speak
with your daughter.
- I'll be waiting outside.
I'm sorry.
Anyway, um, I'm Kat.
I'm 26 weeks along.
- Hi, Kat.
So what happened today?
- You passed out?
- I got a little dizzy,
and then, yeah.
- Has this happened before?
- I guess I haven't really
been myself lately.
Like, I've been nauseous,
swollen,
feeling pretty run-down.
Um, it's a little worse today,
but it's just
normal pregnancy stuff.
- Maybe.
Though it is a bit late for you
to still be getting nauseous.
- Yeah, and your blood pressure
and temp are a little high.
- Are you concerned?
- Not necessarily.
But we would like
to get an ultrasound
and run a few tests.
- Okay.
- Just give us a little time
to get some answers, kay?
♪
- Oh, and, um, my mom?
- Would you like me to get her?
- No. No.
- Hi, Ms. Reed.
I'm Dr. Taylor.
- Hi, nice to meet you.
- Lydia choked
on some cereal this morning.
- I still feel like there's
something in there.
- I'm sorry.
Uh, has this happened
to you before?
- Uh, I thought I got a...
a doxycycline pill, uh,
stuck a few weeks ago.
I was taking it
for Lyme disease.
- Okay, um, how long ago
did you have that?
Turns out I didn't.
I also didn't have fibromyalgia
or MS or chronic fatigue.
You see enough specialists,
you get a pretty good list.
- Can I ask
what was going on
that made you see
all these doctors?
- Well, um,
a year and a half ago,
I... I... I got an... an eye twitch.
Uh, and I thought,
"Lydia, you are giving
200 talks a year."
I'm a motivational speaker.
"You're just tired."
But then my best friend
got diagnosed with ALS.
Scariest thing ever.
So I went to a neurologist,
but he ruled ALS out.
- That's good.
- Right.
But then I got coughing fits,
then stiffness...
Then exhaustion.
And nobody could figure it out.
Here I am.
- Well, hopefully, we'll
be able to help you today.
If it's okay, I'd like to order
some more bloodwork.
- Yes.
- And in the meantime,
I'm gonna take a closer look
at your throat.
- Okay.
- Prep pharyngoscope?
- And a CBC, CMP, and ANA.
- You got it.
- I'll be right back.
Hey, Mags?
- Mm-hmm?
- Were you able
to track down any info
on my biological father?
- Oh, no.
I wasn't able to find anything.
But, um, I'll keep trying.
- Okay.
- Morning, Maggie.
- Oh, hey, Sharon.
- Uh-oh. What's up?
Vanessa keeps asking
about her biological father,
and I promised her I would try
and get in touch with him,
but I haven't.
- Oh.
- It's been over 20 years.
I don't want
to disrupt his life.
But it's what Vanessa wants,
and I want to be fair to her.
- Good morning, Ben.
- Sharon, nice to see you.
- Good to see you.
- Oh, walking is something
out there.
Coffee after my checkup?
- Yeah, you bet.
- All right.
- Look, I know
that Ben wasn't so keen
on you getting in touch
with Vanessa
in the first place,
but have you discussed this
with him?
- No!
- Maggie...
- Sharon, no.
- Hey, where's Sam?
- Uh, just sent him to IR
for an embolization.
- Why?
Bullet tract went
straight through the lung.
The chest tube took care
of that.
- Yeah, but look...
the bullet we saw on the x-ray
caused a pseudoaneurysm
in a branch
of the pulmonary artery.
- That thing could have blown
anytime.
- You know, Sam said
he never got shot before,
so he must have got hit
twice today,
just didn't realize it.
- And we're missing
the other entry wound.
There's a lot
of air pockets and scatter
all over that CT.
- Hmm.
I... I've got an idea
how we might know for sure.
- The thing
about bodycam footage
is it's all live and unedited,
so it can get kind of violent.
You guys okay?
both: Yeah.
- Thanks, man.
- You got it, Doc.
- Chicago Police,
search warrant.
- Go, go, go!
- Police! Don't move!
- Drop the gun. Drop it!
- There... that looks like
the shot
that came out the other side
I found in his vest.
- You all right, Sam?
- Alice, Alice!
- Stay here, stay here.
- Call Alice.
- 10-1, 10-1!
Shots fired, target 16 house!
- So does he get hit again?
- Can you run it back slowly?
- Put your hands up!
Put your hands up!
Walk towards me! Drop the gun!
Come here! Get on the ground!
Get on the ground!
- No, just the one shot.
So if that bullet we just saw
was the one we recovered,
where did the one in his lung
come from?
- Didn't get it here.
♪
- Hey.
- Hi.
- Just saw Mr. Stevens.
Two days post-op,
incision's looking good.
- Yeah.
- Your button.
- Hmm?
- Oh. It's fine.
I should put on
some scrubs anyway.
- Hey, wait a second.
You can't button it, can you?
- Crocket...
- Pamela, you can't operate.
Not like this.
- You know I'd never do
anything
to endanger my patients.
- Yeah, well I have to question
your judgement on this.
You cannot do surgery.
It isn't safe.
- Are you serious?
- Yeah.
♪
- So your embolization
went well,
though it was
a little more complicated
than expected.
- The radiologist noted
that the bullet
had been eroding
into the vessel wall
for some time.
- Apparently,
when your lung collapsed
and reinflated again,
the movement was enough
to make the situation emergent.
- On closer examination,
we noticed a faint scar
indicating
an old gunshot wound.
It's pretty clear to us
you've been shot before.
- Yeah, I was.
Doc said it was 50/50
to take it out or not...
- You never told me?
- Alice...
- Sam, I'm sorry.
I was just trying
to make her feel better.
You know how you were okay
the last time.
- You told them you were shot.
They all know everything,
but you couldn't tell me?
- I didn't want to worry you.
- Let his friends
come sit with him.
They're all
he cares about anyway.
Alice!
♪
- You do have
some redness and irritation,
but I don't see
any foreign bodies.
Your labs are normal,
so if you're feeling better,
I feel comfortable
sending you home.
Lydia?
Lydia!
- I just don't know
what's wrong with me.
All I do is go to doctors,
and no one has any answers.
- I'm... I'm sorry.
- I used to travel
around the country,
speaking and helping people.
And now there are days
I don't even get out of bed.
Here, here.
Here, take one.
Okay.
Is there anything else
I can get you?
Maybe water?
- No.
I'm okay.
- Okay, um...
you know, let me speak
with one of my colleagues
and see if we can figure
something out.
♪
Dr. Charles?
I have a patient
who's been to a lot of doctors
for some pretty vague symptoms.
Her labs and exam
are all normal.
But she just got
extremely upset just now
when I told her
that I couldn't find anything.
I don't know,
something about it
just feels a little off.
- Okay.
How can I help?
- I don't know.
The long history,
the multiple diagnoses,
she... she could be malingering?
Do you mind talking to her?
- No.
Shoot me her chart?
- Okay.
- Well, labs don't show much,
but her pressure's
still creeping up.
Think this could be
pre-eclampsia?
- Could be,
but her LFT levels
are slightly elevated
and her glucose is low.
I'm wondering
if this actually might be
acute fatty liver of pregnancy.
- If AFLP is even
on the table...
I mean, missing it
would be catastrophic.
- Yeah.
We need to know for sure.
- Can you get this
up to Abrams for me?
Thank you.
- Crockett...
- Yeah?
- Got a minute?
- Yeah, what do you need?
- A liver biopsy
to check for AFLP.
- Okay, but if it is,
you do realize
that the biopsy site
could bleed considerably.
- Yeah, we need an answer.
If it's just pre-eclampsia,
we'll keep the baby in
as long as we can.
- But if it is AFLP,
the only cure is to deliver it.
- And if you watch and wait?
- There's a chance that
it could all work out fine.
But there's also a chance
that the baby, and even Mom,
could die.
We need this biopsy.
Right.
I don't know.
I'm not liking the choices.
- Crockett,
Dr. Asher needs the biopsy.
- I think Dr. Marcel heard me.
- Okay. I'll set it up.
- Great.
- You got it.
- Thank you.
- Hannah.
Hannah!
- Why do you constantly feel
the need to save me, Will?
- Save you?
- What you just did
with Crockett.
Not telling me about the check?
- Whoa, I...
hey, I'm just trying to help.
- Really, Will?
Or is it because
you don't think
I can take care of myself?
No matter what I do,
you are still stuck
on how you thought about me
two years ago.
- I want to support you.
I don't want to derail
all the hard work
that you've done.
- That is my responsibility,
not yours.
- I gotta tell you,
I don't think
she's malingering.
- Really?
But she's seen every specialist
in Chicago.
- Yeah, but true malingering,
I mean, at least
from a clinical standpoint,
would mean that she was
making up
or exaggerating symptoms
for some kind
of secondary gain, right?
Like drug-seeking
or because she didn't want
to go to work.
You know, I'm just not
picking that up.
I think she really wants
an answer.
- What if there isn't one?
All of her tests
came back negative.
- Well, maybe you have
to keep on digging.
Have you thought about,
I don't know,
a lumbar puncture
or an endocrine panel?
- Yeah, yeah, okay.
But the history
of doctor shopping,
and that meltdown before...
ugh, I don't know.
I'd also like to give her
a psychiatric questionnaire.
Just to make sure
we're not missing anything.
- Okay.
Let me, uh, know
what you find out.
- Okay.
- Excuse me, uh, but I know
an officer involved
with the raids this morning.
Any word on any other injuries?
- Details are sketchy,
but it's still dangerous
out there.
Hey, you got a name?
- Actually, no.
They're undercover.
- Well, I'll keep my ears open,
let you know
if I hear anything.
- Dr. Scott. How's Sam?
- He's stable,
but it's still too early
to tell
if the procedure worked.
- Dr. Scott? We need you.
- His chest tube's
putting out blood.
The embolization plug
must have dislodged.
- I need two units of blood
and FFP.
Tell CT we're coming up.
- All right.
- Oh, my God.
- BP's down to 78/52.
Pulse is thready.
- He's in V-fib.
Charge the paddles to 200.
- Sam?
- Charged.
- Clear.
- Sinus rhythm.
- All right, BP's good.
Let's get him up to the ICU.
We'll stabilize him there.
- I'm in. Go.
- Come on. Move, move, move.
Back up, back up.
♪
- Hey, I got your message.
- Hey, Sharon.
When I told you about
Vanessa's biological father,
there was a part I left out.
I loved him at the time...
deeply.
- Okay.
- But my life
is great right now.
Ben is great.
But this man, Grant,
if I see him again,
I'm afraid...
I'm afraid
of what I might feel.
What happens
if those old feelings
are still there?
And what happens
when he sees Vanessa?
Our perfect daughter?
Sharon, I'm lost.
- Maggie...
I wish I could tell you
what to do.
I can't.
But it does sound to me
like you're already thinking
ten steps ahead.
Whatever you decide,
it'll come from the heart.
And that's the best
any of us can do.
Yeah?
- Yeah.
♪
- Uh, Afra, can you put
pressure on that for me?
You got it?
Hey, guys?
- Hmm.
- So the biopsy site's
still bleeding.
If I can't get it to stop,
I'm gonna have to coil it.
- Path results.
- Okay, we need
to deliver her now.
Hey, Kat,
we've got some bad news.
Unfortunately,
you have a condition
called acute fatty liver
of pregnancy.
- It's an enzyme deficiency
that causes
rapid and life-threatening
liver failure.
- Oh, my God.
- We need to do a C-section.
- Okay, let's get
the hybrid OR ready.
- What? No. No, you can't.
It's too soon.
- The baby is viable.
We don't have
any other options.
- Okay.
- Okay, ready?
Let's go.
- Kat, what's going on?
- Mom, they have to deliver
the baby.
- What?
- This is really serious.
I'm scared.
Can she come with me?
- You can stay right outside.
She'll be right outside.
♪
- I'm not gonna do these.
You already sent
that shrink in.
It... I'm not crazy.
- No, I don't think that.
I just want to check...
- Why won't someone
take me seriously?
W... what kind of doctors
are you?
- Lydia...
- I am sick, damn it.
I am sick. Okay?
There... there is
something wrong with me.
- Lydia, please,
I just want to help.
- But you're not. You're not.
No one is.
No one is!
I am... I... I am so... so...
I'm so sorry.
- Lydia, what's going on?
I don't know
why this keeps happening.
- Well, what keeps happening?
- I've been so e...
emotional lately.
And it... it...
it just comes over me.
- Right.
A... and when that happens,
what... how do you experience it?
W... what does it feel like?
- I don't know.
It's, like, so much feeling,
and, um, it's...
it's overwhelming.
- Right.
But then it suddenly just ends?
- Like someone hit a switch.
- Okay, um,
could you give me a moment?
- It... it... it's gotta be
psychiatric, right?
- Actually,
these emotional outbursts
are making me think
it could be just the opposite.
I'll be right back.
♪
- Hi, Mrs. Devers?
We got Sam's CT results,
and he's gonna need
another procedure
to stop the bleed.
- Uh, do whatever you have to.
- Actually, uh,
we do need to make a choice.
And since Sam is intubated,
the decision falls to you.
- Please, have a seat.
So we can do a thoracotomy
and fix the vessel,
but it is a major procedure
that comes
with some significant risks.
- Or we can place a stent,
which is
a much less invasive procedure,
but it does mean
Sam would have to be
on anticoagulants
for the rest of his life.
- It could result in him
being pulled from active duty.
- He could still work,
just not on the street, right?
- Yes.
- Mrs. Devers, this is
a very big decision
that could potentially end
your husband's career.
So if you need more time,
or if you have any...
- No.
I'd like you to do the stent.
Okay.
- How's it looking?
- Almost there. You?
- Still not clotting.
Uh, keep up the FFP,
cryo, and blood.
More lap pads.
- All right, uterine incision.
There we go.
Here she comes.
Here comes baby.
All right.
Got her.
Here she is.
All right. Apgar, 6.
Baby needs to be intubated.
- I'm on it.
- Still got a lot
of bleeding here.
- Uterus is still bleeding too.
- Pressure's down to 82/54.
- I'm in.
Let's get her up to the NICU.
- Kat's hemorrhaging.
- All right, I need
2 milligrams methergine IM,
250 micrograms hemabate subQ.
Get me a Bakri.
- Keep up the leverage.
- She's bleeding from her nose.
She's in DIC.
- If she can't clot,
her liver's never gonna hold.
- Down to 70/42.
- Crockett?
- Yeah, her liver's ruptured.
Curve six, let's go.
- She's bleeding out.
I need more blood!
- Easy, guys.
- What...
no, K... Kat?
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Where are you taking her?
- Her liver ruptured.
We're trying to stop the bleed.
- What?
- Mrs. Miller?
This is Dr. Blake,
chief of our
transplant surgery.
We believe
that your daughter's gonna need
a liver transplant.
- A transplant?
- A section of liver,
ideally from a living donor.
- For now, we're gonna take her
to the ICU
and get her stabilized
until we can find a match.
We'll keep you updated, okay?
- Use me. I'm ready.
- Well, there's
a process to this...
- My daughter is not waiting.
I am the same blood type,
I'm healthy,
and I'm standing
right in front of you.
And I am not leaving
until I can make sure
that my daughter lives
to see her baby.
- Okay.
- Hi, I'm Lydia Reed.
And this is an issue
that many of us parents
deal with.
Because we value the truth.
But what we value even more
is our children's
happiness and safety.
So what happens
when those two values
come into conflict?
We know something
that's gonna hurt our kids.
So what do we do?
We put it aside.
When you find something
that you...
- Okay, halfway
through the IVC anastomosis.
How're we looking, Marty?
- Losing too much blood.
Pressure's down to 84/56.
- Come on.
Check that liver again.
Yeah, I got another bleeder.
Maya, buzz me.
Right there, go. Okay.
Damn it. Another bleeder.
And another.
- Dr. Blake, I could use
another set of hands.
- No, I can't.
- Pamela...
- I want the best outcome
for that woman's daughter,
Crockett,
and right now that's you.
Just focus on finishing
the anastomosis.
- All right, but she's losing
a lot of blood.
- You can do this.
Stop chasing the bleeding.
- 77/48.
- The faster you sew
that vessel,
the sooner you can get
out of there.
- All right.
Finishing the anastomosis.
72/40.
- Hold on.
- MAPs are in the 50s.
- Hold on!
Easy. Easy, easy. Okay, got it.
Cut me.
How're we looking?
- Pressure stabilized.
- All right.
Let's get this belly tied up
and get out of here.
♪
- So we've written down
a few sentences here.
Would you mind reading them
out loud for us?
Sure.
"When you find something
"you don't want
to tell your kids,
"that's usually the thing
you need
to tell them the most."
This was from a talk
I gave a few years ago.
- Yeah, five to be exact.
I have it right here.
When you find something
that you don't want
to tell your kids,
that's usually the thing
that you need
to tell them the most.
That's the thing
they need to he...
- I'm hearing
a marked difference
in your speech pattern
on the video.
It's not as halting
or pressured as it is now.
- Is that significant?
- I think it could be.
And these outbursts of yours,
they're sudden.
They're often unwarranted.
- Yes.
- It's called
Pseudobulbar Affect.
- What's...
- They're exaggerated
emotional responses.
They're not caused
by emotional instability
or an altered
psychological state.
Um, they're caused
by the degeneration
of certain brain cells.
- I'm really sorry to have
to tell you this, Lydia,
but I think that we might
be dealing with ALS.
- ALS?
No, no. It c... can't be.
The neurologist ruled it out.
- I imagine that they ruled out
a more common presentation.
I... I think that you have
a more rare form
which is called Bulbar ALS.
Much more difficult
to diagnose.
- I definitely have it?
- I have a really strong hunch
that that's
what we're dealing with here.
♪
- Lydia?
- I mean, I'm sad.
But I'm... I'm... I'm relieved.
ALS was my greatest fear.
But at least I finally have...
at least I finally have
an answer.
Right?
- Ethan.
I've been thinking
about it, man.
Sam would want the thoracotomy.
That's what
he should be getting.
- Well, look,
I've been looking
over the bodycam footage.
I got an idea.
- Mrs. Devers,
Sam's procedure
hasn't started yet,
but I was hoping we could talk.
My dad's a cop, my sister.
Before I did this, I was too.
And even though
I'm not anymore,
every time I hear sirens go by,
I wish I was in that car.
It's a part of who I am.
It's a part of who Sam is too.
- We wanted to show you
what happened today
after your husband was shot.
- This might be difficult.
But we think it's important
you see it.
Okay?
- Okay.
- Get on the ground!
- You all right, Sam?
- Alice. Alice!
Stay here, stay here.
- Call Alice.
- 10-1, 10-1!
- Alice.
- Shots fired, shots fired!
- Call Alice.
- Roll an ambo!
- Stay with me, Sam.
- Call my wife. Call Alice.
- He wanted you, Mrs. Devers.
He was calling for you.
- No one else.
- Yes.
- Alice, I know this is
very tough for you.
But we still have time.
Are you sure you want
to do the stent?
- Or we can switch
to the thoracotomy.
We believe
that's what Sam would want.
Do the thoracotomy.
- My CT's clear.
You ready to go?
- That deserves
some celebration.
- That'd be nice.
♪
- Here she is.
- Oh, my God.
I can't believe
she's really here.
- Oh, look at her.
She's perfect.
- She's so tiny.
Am I gonna be able
to take care of her?
- You will. I know you will.
♪
- Hey, listen, about before...
I have been treating you
like you need saving.
I'm sorry about that.
- Look, I know it wasn't
coming from a bad place, Will.
- Okay.
Does mean that,
as your landlord,
I'm gonna need
the rent tomorrow.
- Oh, well, actually,
I can do you one better.
I, um, picked it up
during lunch today.
- Thanks.
- Mm-hmm.
- She's set up with Dr. Abrams
for a full consultation.
- You know, a couple
of pretty exciting
clinical trials out there.
Between those, current meds,
PT, speech therapy,
there's actually quite a lot
we can do for her.
You know, I wanted to look up
that talk you used
about the truth
and being a better parent,
but it was really far down
on the list.
I'm just curious
why you picked that one.
- I don't know.
Good question.
Looked, uh... looked interesting?
♪
- Hey.
- Nice job today.
- Thanks.
Hey, look, if it, uh...
If it felt like I crossed...
- I scheduled my disc surgery.
- Oh.
- I was concerned
about leaving my patients
for a few weeks, but...
I see now they'll be fine.
♪
- That's great.
- Honey, you got a second?
- Yeah.
- Something I've been, um,
meaning to talk to you about.
Um...
What's going on? You all right?
- Luke broke up with me.
- Oh.
- And I...
I just really cared.
- Honey, I'm so sorry.
- I just feel so stupid.
- You sure it wasn't,
I don't know,
like, just a... just a fight
or something?
No, it's over.
Didn't you say you wanted
to talk to me about something?
- No.
It... it can wait.
- Thank you.
- Yeah.
Dr. Archer says he'll be
back on the street
in six weeks.
- Good.
Think she'll be able
to handle it?
- I hope so.
- At least she knows
a little more
about the person she loves.
♪
- Will, the Vas-COM trial,
please tell me
you're not gonna testify.
- I am.
- Don't.
These people will do anything
to protect themselves.
You don't know
what they're capable of.
- I have to.
- Then what about me?
You're gonna ruin my life.
They're gonna throw me in jail.
- Jessa, let go of me.
Let go of me!
- Dr. Halstead,
is there a problem?
♪
- Dylan.
- Oh, Milena.
Thank God, you're safe.
- Come here.
So some...
some gang members got away.
I'm afraid there's a mole
in CPD who tipped them off.
- If there is...
- I've been made.
- That's why you had the money.
In case you had
to get off the grid.
- Yeah, and I need to.
- Listen, it... it's too
dangerous to stay with me,
but I have a friend
who's fixing up a building.
I'm sure you could
hole up there.
- Okay, thanks.
Oh, Dylan, my name,
uh, it's Jo.
- Come on, Jo.
Let's get you safe.
♪
- Ethan?
Come in.
- Thanks.
Um, my dad liked
highland scotch.
I didn't know...
- I do, thanks.
Please.
♪
- My sister. My nephew.
My first day in the navy.
- I felt like you were all
my family too.
50 years.
We had a life together,
but no one could know.
♪
- You a... a scotch man
like your dad?
- I am.
- Funny story
about a bottle of scotch
your dad and I had in Dubai
after the Gulf War.
You want to hear it?
- Yeah, I do.
♪