♪ Ohhh ohhh ohhh ♪
Oh, the--the range of movement
is amazing.
You think that's good.
Hey, Pete.
Go on. Toss it to Colin.
Come on. Don't be afraid
to put a little heat on it.
I'm pretty good.
Nice catch.
I connected the arm directly
to Colin's nervous system.
The brain thinks "catch
the ball," and the hand does it.
The guys in my unit
would freak.
Oh, were--were you
in Iraq?
Afghanistan.
Yeah.
Feel free
to use words
like "genius"
or "brilliant" at will.
I don't have to
'cause you just did.
It was really nice
to meet you,
and, uh,
good luck with your arm.
Ah.
You okay?
No, something--
oh, it burns.
Help him, or he's gonna
pull out the neuro connectors.
Mm. Ah.
Ah.
You implanted a bolt
in his arm?
Osseous integration.
It's the only way
to carry the weight.
I know what it is.
It's also illegal.
In this country.
I sent him to Sweden.
Ah!
Ah! Mm.
Okay, it's infected.
He's burning up.
We've gotta get him
to the hospital.
Okay, well,
Maya's in your office.
She wouldn't even look at me
in the car on the way over here,
and now you got Sam and Naomi
in the conference room.
Do you want to tell me
what's going on?
No, I can't, Dell.
I wish I could, but I can't.
Guys, um,
very pregnant woman
squatting up and down
in the hallway?
Not mine.
She's mine. Lynn McDonald. She's
committed to natural childbirth.
She's been in labor
for two days.
Her water finally broke
last night.
Ooh. This isn't working.
Do you have anything spicy
in the fridge?
Like maybe--maybe
a Chimichanga, huh?
That'll speed up
the labor, right?
Yeah, I'll order you something.
Yeah. Okay, baby, come out.
And come out.
And... come out.
Well, let's go check out
your progress.
And come out.
Okay, Addison. What's this
important case that, uh...
Hey, Maya girl.
Hey.
What's up? Wait. Did you have
a half a day today?
No, no, no.
Was I supposed to--
no, no, no. I always keep
the half days in my calendar.
I keep 'em
in my calendar, too.
It's not a half day.
Maya has something
that she needs to tell you.
I...
Um...
Maya's pregnant.
No, she's not.
How?
When did you start
having s--
wait. No. No, okay.
This is--this isn't possible.
We discussed this.
We discussed birth control.
Your--two doctors.
Both your parents are doctors.
How could you be pregnant?
How could this be happening?
What were--
what were you thinking?
Hey, where you going?
Our daughter just told us
that--that--that
she is pregnant.
We need to talk about this.
I can't.
Mom--
Naomi, we are her parents.
I can't.
Naomi walked away.
Our daughter is pregnant,
and Naomi walked away.
I know.
She's in shock.
She's dealing with it.
I'm supposed to just wait
until she decides
that she's ready?
We need to talk
to our daughter now.
Sam, this isn't
the first time
I've delivered
this kind of news.
People need time. Give...
Give Naomi some time.
Colin, you have
a severe infection.
How long
has it been hurting?
A month. I thought
it was normal pain.
And I was afraid
that if it was the bolt,
then I couldn't keep the arm.
Well, Dr. Wilder feels
the bolt should come out.
No. Can't we do
more antibiotics or something?
Well, what do you say,
Dr. Wilder?
You specialize
in infectious disease.
You know alternative treatments.
What are his options?
There has to be
something up your sleeve
since you have two of them.
There are
experimental protocols,
but the f.D.A. Hasn't completed
safety studies,
and there are reports
of severe side effects.
I'm sorry. The bolt is
the source of the infection,
and the safest thing to do
is remove it
before the infection spreads.
Before I deployed,
I got engaged.
We wrote letters,
we planned the whole thing,
right down to the dance
that we're going to do,
which requires me
to dip her to the floor.
Now I'm living up
to my part of this.
I'm going to hold her
in my arms--both arms--
and I'm going to dance with her
the way I promised.
You came back alive.
You're healthy and alive.
I know you planned for more,
but I cannot treat you
in a way that will
jeopardize your health.
Dr. Wilder--
Colin, this infection
could kill you.
I know that's not
what your fiancée wants.
Why do they do this?
Why does the hospital
keep sending me samples?
It's like "gaslight,"
but with baby stuff.
"Gaslight"? Famous movie?
Never saw it.
Ingrid bergman.
Her husband
tries to drive her crazy.
Uh, when the petermans
get here,
will you put them
in exam room three?
I'm using exam room three.
Oh, actually room three
is for pediatrics.
And I have a 7 year old with
a urinary tract infection.
It's--it's about a marriage
that ends badly.
"Gaslight."
Marsha.
Hi. Violet Turner.
Uh, here's the situation--
I don't want
any more baby stuff.
So no diaper cream samples.
I've--I've called,
I've e-mailed,
I've mail-mailed
for the past six months,
but the hospital
just keeps sending it.
Most new mothers appreciate
our little freebies.
Well, I am not a new mother.
How old is your baby?
That's not what I meant.
I am not a new or an old
or any kind of mother.
I don't have a baby anymore.
Oh. Oh, my god.
I'm so sorry for your loss.
They're god's
littlest angels,
the ones we lose.
Could you just get
the form?
Of course.
I'm sorry, too,
for your loss.
Oh, no, no. It's just--
I-I was just--
no, no, no. You don't
have to explain. I-I get it.
I-i--
I lost my wife today.
Oh, my god.
A sentence you never think
you're gonna have to say,
you know, "I lost--
I lost my wife."
And, uh, every time
you say it,
you think you're not gonna
be able to breathe,
and it's like--it's like
somebody shot you or something.
And then i--and then I hear
that you lost your child--
your baby--and it's--
it, like, gives it
perspective, you know?
It--it's--it's--it helps me
to know you lost your child.
And I know that's
a horrible thing to say to you.
Um... my wife's dead,
and I've offended you,
and I'm sorry...
For your loss.
No, no. I'm--I'm sorry
for your loss.
They gave me this bag
with her... belongings.
It's...
It's funny.
I thought there'd be more
to take home.
Do you need...
Can I help you?
Is there anything I can do?
Uh, no. No, no.
I-I'm just waiting.
A friend's picking me up,
so...
Okay.
Well...
It was nice to meet you.
I'm Nathan pilsman.
Violet Turner.
It's nice to meet you,
Well, not nice,
but... it's nice.
You can't walk.
You're black.
What game are we playing?
The day
that you found out...
When they told you that,
uh, your legs--
that you would--you would
never walk again,
that must have been
the worst day of your life.
How did you deal with it?
Why would you assume that
that was my worst day?
Losing my legs
changed my life,
but, uh, it certainly
didn't ruin it.
There's a period
of adjustment,
but... you deal with it.
You're full of crap.
Naomi, what--what are you
doing here?
Mom, what are you doing?
What's going on?
Naomi,
what is going on?
I need you to give Maya
an abortion.
What?
Nai.
Mom, no.
I don't want an abortion.
I don't care what you want.
But, mom--
give her an abortion.
I can't believe
I slapped her.
I hit my child.
You were upset, clearly.
It's not an easy thing
to deal with.
I know, I know, but I...
Well, I can't--i lost it.
But c-can you believe her?
Can you believe her
saying no to me?
What?
You ordered her
to have an abortion.
So putting aside the fact that
you are personally against it--
you can't make someone
have an abortion, Nai.
No, no, no. This is--this--this
is not up for discussion.
I think it needs to be.
Well, you know what? If you're
not gonna do it, that's fine.
I will find another doctor
who will.
Okay, I don't even know
who I'm talking to right now.
This is not you.
It's the opposite of you.
You--you give people babies,
and whether or not I agree
with your stand on this issue,
this isn't you.
Don't do something now that you
will hate yourself for later.
Do you hate yourself
for your abortions?
Either of you?
No, I don't hate myself.
But I do think about it.
It stays with you even if you
do it for the right reasons,
and it is not a casual decision
that you can make for Maya.
This--this is my family.
You do not judge my family!
We're not judging.
You know that.
Look, this has hit you hard,
and that can make you change
what you believe--
stop it. Stop it.
Stop acting
like you understand,
because you don't.
You don't.
This is my child.
This is my child we are
talking about, my child...
Who I've done everything in
my power to raise and protect.
And now she's gone
and done something stupid--
stupid--
that's gonna ruin her life,
and I'm not
gonna let that happen.
I am her mother.
Naomi--
you have no right. You have
no moral high ground.
You walked away
from your child.
If you can live with that,
I can live with this.
She's just upset. You--
I know.
Uh,
I know this is a bad time,
but my patient--i-i could
really use your help.
Yes. Please.
Tell me she needs surgery.
That I can do.
Oh, don't need your help
opening a door.
You're not very good
at taking help, are you?
Oh, actually, I am. Your idea
about experimental protocols?
I contacted my friend
at the f.D.A.,
got the info, went with it.
You're not taking out
Colin's bolt?
You might be afraid to take
a risk, but I'm not.
I assumed
Naomi brought you in
because you were
just as cutting-edge
as everyone else around here.
I didn't realize you were
the safe alternative.
All right, you know what?
You--hey. Hey. Hey.
You can't just say something
like that and roll away.
Can't hear you
over the noise of my chair.
Hey, Pete.
Maya is pregnant.
Sam needs to drink.
You in?
Oh!
Uh, Lynn's in a lot of pain.
She shows no sign
of fetal distress,
but her labor
isn't progressing.
I thought
after my water broke...
Well, I can give you oxytocin
to speed up the labor
and something for the pain.
My birth plan says no drugs.
Lynn has a birth plan.
Oh, many pages...
And small font.
Yeah.
I want to experience
my child's birth.
Uh, Lynn--
I did my homework, okay?
I-I understand
that there are procedures
that, you know,
may become necessary,
but except in a case
of extreme emergency,
you know, I want to be given
the opportunity to accept or--
or refuse any procedure.
And as long as the baby's okay,
all right,
I want to have
a natural childbirth.
So to get the labor going,
I'm willing to try walking
or castor oil
or nipple stimulation--
well, it's
a little more involved.
If you fail to progress
in your labor,
you might want to consider
a c-section.
No. No.
Lynn, look, I know
this can be disappointing--
I've been in screaming pain
for hours.
I'm not--I'm not worried
about being disappointed.
You know, I-I married
a great guy.
You know,
I wanted to have kids.
He wasn't ready... ever.
And... when the divorce
was final,
I decided to let loose.
You know,
having a baby alone,
being pregnant by some guy
that I met at the Tequila bar,
is not every girl's dream,
but this is
what's happening, okay?
And I am having this baby.
So is it too much to ask
that one thing
goes according to plan?
Naomi has lost her mind.
I don't even know
who she was today.
Do you want Maya
to have an abortion?
Well, that's the point.
I'm a guy. It's--
it's--it's not my choice.
Well, right, but do you
want her to--
do i--i want her to not
be pregnant in the first place.
I want her
to never have had sex.
I want her to live in a world
where there are chastity belts
and convents
and little boys
by the name of dink don't exist.
That--that's what I want.
So don't ask me
if I want...
My baby girl
to have an abortion.
Don't--don't ask me that.
♪ Blowin' down a country Lane ♪
Because the answer
is probably yes.
♪ She's got the style... ♪
But it's not my choice.
You know,
it's not Naomi's either.
Look, just be glad you
and Charlotte don't have a kid.
Oh.
Once you have a child
with someone,
you are tied
to them forever,
even if they go nuts.
I'm--I'm sorry.
I didn't...
I didn't mean that, man.
♪ And the hills of echo park ♪
My daughter's pregnant.
♪ She is crinoline and satin ♪
♪ she is leopard skin
and lace ♪
Oh, I'm still here.
But then, so are you.
Well, I left and I came back.
I thought about you
and I was worried.
You don't have
a friend coming, do you?
No.
I'm not ready.
The thing is...
I can't leave
without my wife.
Obviously, I-I can't leave
with her.
So I can't leave.
♪ ...Berkeley girl ♪
Can I sit with you
for a while?
Sure.
♪ ...the moon and the sun ♪
♪ oh ♪
♪ ah ♪
Did you feel this way
when you lost your child?
Well... yeah,
walking out that door
was the hardest thing
I ever did.
But...
Yeah, yeah, I did
feel this way.
♪ Ooh ♪
♪ oh, Berkeley girl ♪
I have this tingling
in--in my stump,
in my shoulder and my feet.
It's like they're asleep.
I can't wake them up.
What is it?
What's happening?
Uh, a side effect
of the antibiotics
is neurotoxicity--
nerve damage.
Is this what Dr. Wilder
was afraid of?
No. I'm gonna lower the dosage
on the antibiotic.
That should lessen
the effect.
We'll give it a shot.
Oh.
Oh, god.
Oh, god! Oh!
Oh! Oh!
Oh! G--oh!
This is how today
should've gone down.
When we found out that
our daughter was pregnant,
we should've cried
on each other's shoulders,
we should've listened to what
our daughter had to say,
and then the two of us,
together, should have
discussed how to handle this.
That's not what happened.
Talk to me.
Deal with this.
I don't want to talk about it.
And I am dealing with it.
Maybe not the way
you want me to, but...
It's the only way I can.
I'll do it.
I'll have the abortion.
Her.
Oh, yeah. That's grief.
Definitely.
Dead husband? Dead kid?
It's dead kid.
It's her face.
She's got dead kid face...
Like you.
I'm sorry. That didn't
come out right.
No, it's okay.
It's all right.
What do you mean
about my face?
It's your eyes.
You--you've been someplace
that most people
have never been.
You've survived something
that no one would have
wanted to survive.
It's your eyes. It's...
They're, I don't know,
empty.
Well, I mean,
that could be just...
Doesn't have to be
dead kid.
It could just be...
Bad life.
No, it's dead kid
or dead something.
What about me?
Your face?
I mean,
I know you don't know me,
but do I look different?
You look like
you're in shock, Nathan.
something bad happened.
It's really nice of you
to sit here, you know,
but you don't--
you don't have to stay.
I'm sure that you have
someplace to be.
Uh... no, actually.
I don't.
Okay.
Sorry.
I thought you'd be
at the gym.
I just came to get
the rest of my stuff.
Yeah, well, okay.
I bought the latex jumpsuit.
For me.
You bought it for me.
What, are you gonna have
some other woman wear it?
Well, so should I
give it to you
so you could wear it
for some other guy?
Cooper, we can do this.
We liked each other once.
Actually, we didn't.
We disliked each other,
and then we had sex,
and then we fell in love.
We never liked each other.
I guess you're right.
I think you should leave
the practice.
What?
I'll take out a loan.
I'll sell my car.
I'll do whatever it takes
to buy you out.
No.
No?
No. I'm building a business.
I don't care
if you were there first.
I belong there just as much as
you do. I'm not going anywhere.
Useless, stupid love.
What?
Useless, stupid love!
Wasted time.
Just take your latex jumpsuit.
Find another woman.
Have a blast with it!
Oh, I c--
I will! I can't wait.
That's my towel you're wearing.
I want it back.
Oh, god! Oh, god!
You're doing great, Lynn.
Yeah. I feel great.
Uh, we--we could change
the music.
We haven't listened to
"chirping birds" yet.
I just wanted this
to be beautiful, you know?
All my books said
that the way a child
comes into the world
shapes them for life.
I just want to give him
the best chance
that he can have, you know?
Mm-hmm.
I-I don't want to shape him
to be some angry
or--or scared...
Damn it.
Oh.
I want him to have
a good life.
Okay, look... no matter
how today works out,
even if you decide
you can't take the pain,
you're still gonna have
plenty of opportunities
to shape your child's life.
So can I give you something
to help with the pain?
No. Just give me
the chirping birds.
Okay.
Yeah.
How many have you done?
More than I can count.
And they've all...
They've turned out...
Well, "fine"
isn't the word I'd use,
but without complications.
My daughter's having
an abortion tomorrow.
That in and of itself
is a complication.
Sam, is it weird
that it's me... doing it?
No.
Would you prefer
that I get a--
I'd understand if--
no, you do it.
You do it the best you have
ever done anything.
Do it like your life
depends on it.
It's Maya.
Oh. Oh. Ugh.
Colin, what happened?
Something's wrong.
I-I told 'em to call you. I--
I know you wanted to take
the bolt out.
You told me the antibiotics
were too risky, but I w--
this isn't even
the right dosage.
Dr. Fife lowered it. He--
it was--
he said
it was damaging my nerves
and he said that his arm
wouldn't work and--ohh.
Damn it.
The infection is spreading.
Get me a central line kit.
You have got to get
that bolt out.
I'll take it under advisement.
You--it--
this is his life,
and you are so concerned
with your invention.
It's what Colin wanted.
It's what you sold him.
Naomi was right about you.
You're full of crap.
You don't want to fix his arm.
You want to fix your legs.
No. I already tried,
and I can't.
Okay, is that supposed to
make me feel sorry for you?
I'm not doing this for me.
I've accepted what I lost
and I'll accept it for Colin
as well, but not yet.
You just don't want to see it.
Maybe, and maybe there is
something out there
that we haven't
thought of yet.
Look, I'm not good at asking
for help, but I'm asking.
My patient wants to pick up
his life were it left off.
It may not be
what you would choose,
but it's what he chooses.
So do it for him.
You did not just see that.
Isn't that what you
were wearing yesterday?
Uh, yeah. Just...
Helping out a friend.
Want me to loan you
something?
Did you move
all your stuff in here?
I sold my place.
I know.
It was a rookie mistake.
Giving it all up for a guy,
moving into Cooper's apartment,
moving into the practice
where he worked.
I changed my life
to be with him.
I went all-in on forever.
Does Cooper know that?
No point now.
He wants me out.
He wants to pretend we didn't
happen, that I don't exist.
Well, he thinks that's gonna
make him feel better.
But it won't.
It'll just make him feel...
A-Alone.
I know the feeling.
Me, too.
So...
Do you want to wear slutty
or professional?
Oh, Dell!
Dell!
This is a big one!
Still?
I...
Aah!
♪♪♪
♪ it sure is hard
to be apart ♪
♪ but our TV show... ♪
So we're here.
Okay. Is everybody, uh,
sure about this?
Just... do it.
♪♪♪
Maya.
♪ Does she still know ♪
♪ they're the ones? ♪
♪ Her favorite daughter's
favorite sons ♪
I couldn't stay upstairs.
Charlotte?
She won't leave.
And then Sam and Naomi...
I feel like I should--i should
do something for them,
like I should send food
or something, but...
Well, nobody's sick.
Sending a tub of soup
isn't gonna help.
I know. What am I supposed
to do, Pete?
About Charlotte?
Accept it, move on. I mean,
there's nothing you can do.
Sam and Naomi?
I don't know, man.
I... maybe that's why
people send soup.
Nothing you can do.
♪ You say you're worried ♪
♪ I say I am, too ♪
♪ it's okay, it's what
you're supposed to do ♪
Do you remember the day
Maya lost her first tooth?
It fell out in the yard.
We spent about four hours
looking for that thing
because without proof,
the tooth fairy
wouldn't pay up.
♪♪♪
And then there's today.
You know,
we're gonna get through this.
Once this whole thing
is over and done,
we're gonna get back there.
Say something!
Anything!
What do you want me
to say?
You want me to say that I did
the wrong thing? Okay.
I did the wrong thing.
Do I believe
that I'm going to hell
for forcing our daughter
to have an abortion?
Absolutely.
Do I regret doing
what I had to do? No.
♪♪♪
I would do anything,
I would give my life
to protect her,
and if it means that i'm
going to hell, then fine.
I'm going to hell.
Oh, Naomi--
I failed, Sam.
I failed...
First in our marriage,
and now at being a mother.
No. This is on both of us.
I thought I taught her
right from wrong.
But she didn't listen.
It's like nothing I did
made any difference.
I failed.
♪♪♪
You're gonna experience
some discomfort
and some bleeding afterward
for about a week.
The entire procedure
won't take long.
I'm gonna use this instrument
attached to suction
to remove the pregnancy.
You'll have some cramping,
just for a few seconds.
Do you understand?
Maya, it's really--
it's important that you tell me
whether or not you understand.
No.
I don't understand.
Okay.
Ask me.
Anything you want to know.
All my life, my mom told me
that she would never...
Never do this,
that from the second
they're conceived,
a baby is a life--
a gift from god--
and that abortion is wrong...
That it's murder.
Yes. That's what
your mother believes.
What about you?
What do you believe?
I believe that until a fetus
can survive on its own
outside the mother's body,
that it is not a life.
I believe that life
begins at birth.
So you think my mom
was wrong before
and that she's right now
because she wants me to do this?
I think that your mother
and I think differently.
That doesn't help me.
Maya, I can't help you
with this decision.
I can and will give you
an abortion
or I can offer other options
and see you through
this pregnancy.
But I can't help you decide.
I'm 15 years old.
Which is why you shouldn't
have been having sex
in the first place.
And I say that
as your aunt Addie, okay?
But... as your doctor, Maya,
since you already
have had sex
and because
you are pregnant...
Maya...
I know this is hard.
I know that this is...
An unimaginably difficult,
grown-up decision,
and it's not fair
that you have to make it.
But you did a grown-up thing.
And now you are in
a grown-up predicament.
So now it doesn't matter
what I believe
or what your mother believes.
What matters is what
you believe. It's up to you.
But my mom said i--
until the 24th week
of pregnancy,
what a woman does with
her own body is her business.
It's law. It's the law, Maya.
And of lot of fine women
fought a long time
to give you the right to do
what you think is best.
Your body, your choice.
Maya, you know
what you want to do.
In your heart, in your gut,
you know which way
you want to go.
I've done this enough
to know that.
You know what you want to do.
Okay? You just need
to tell me.
♪ Hey, mama ♪
I know you're tired,
but on this next contraction,
I'm really gonna need you
to push.
I can't.
Yes, you can.
It hurts.
Come on, Lynn. This is
what you wanted, okay?
You can do it.
I was wrong, okay?
My birth plan is stupid.
It's not working. I've been
awake for three days.
I feel like I've been
run over by a train.
Okay, just turn off
the hippie-ass flute music
and give me some drugs, now!
O-Okay, okay.
I-I can't give you drugs.
But I want drugs!
Okay? You said
I could change my mind!
Okay. I know it hurts,
but we're almost there.
- And that's why I can't give you any drugs.
- Please stop saying that.
Okay, listen...
You had a plan,
and you've stuck to it,
and not everyone can do that,
but you did.
And I am here with you, and we
are going to get through this.
- I promise.
- Oh.
Now push.
Obviously the results
weren't what we hoped.
I know it was just metal.
But... I swear,
when I caught that tennis ball,
I could feel it.
It was fuzzy,
just a little bit of give.
We have to remove the bolt
and a margin of tissue
to make sure
the infection is gone.
And we may need to remove
the rest of your arm,
possibly all the way up
to your shoulder.
That's one option. It would
definitely save your life.
But...
But what?
There's been some success
with biodegradable
antibiotic implants.
It's risky.
It requires surgery.
We'd have to implant
the antibiotics
directly next to
the bolt site.
Give you the life you want,
let you dance at your wedding.
♪ Oh, lover ♪
♪ Pass the silver ♪
♪ silver revolver ♪
Okay, you guys ready?
Okay, slow down.
We never had kids.
My wife wanted kids.
♪♪♪
I think we should leave.
Look, you--you have
lost someone here
who's very important to you.
And you're afraid
that if you go home
and walk into an empty room,
that'll mean
you're really alone.
I will be alone.
No. I'll...
I'll go with you.
♪ It's all in my head,
it's all in my head ♪
♪ it's all in my head ♪
I didn't do it.
What?
I'm not having
an abortion.
♪ It's in my... ♪
Mom! Stop.
What are you doing?
Naomi.
Ow! Ow!
Hey!
If you're coming in,
you better be taking pictures.
Is that what you want?
Addison, a little help.
I am not gonna let you
ruin your life, little girl.
All right, Lynn.
Now come on. Push.
You think you know what
you want? You have no idea.
You have no idea what you want.
Look at that. Look at that.
Okay.
Hi. Hi.
♪♪♪
But look at that.
♪ All I've ever been to myself ♪
♪ is my own enemy ♪
Mom.
Mom. Mommy!
I can't. I'm sorry.
I-I can't.
Nai.
It's okay. Shh.
Shh, shh, shh,
shh, shh, shh, shh.
Naomi. Nai.
This isn't
the end of the world.
You will get past this.
I need to get outta here.
Don't do this. You don't want to
turn your back on your child.
You just shut up!
Just for once, just shut up!
For a minute, for now,
shut up!
Well... this is fun.
It's fine.
Bet you'd be
a great date.
If my wife hadn't just died,
I'd ask you out.
That was funny.
Let's try
walking through the door.
We thought she had a cold.
A few years ago, we were
supposed to go on a skiing trip,
and we thought she had a cold.
But it never went away.
Cancer.
And I-I knew it was coming.
I knew it.
So I slept there.
I slept in that hospital
with her for months.
This house...
It was the last time
we were happy together.
♪ Turning ♪
♪ turning are the tables... ♪
One step at a time.
♪ Here before me ♪
♪ oh, but you're so lovely ♪
♪ lovely as you are ♪
♪ I know you'll leave me ♪
♪ High up in a tree
I can't climb down ♪
I thought...
I thought it would kill me.
Stepping back into this house,
I thought it would--
I thought it would
make her more gone.
But... she's here.
She loved it here.
And we were happy
in this house.
Thank you.
♪ Burning ♪
Violet?
That dead kid face?
♪ I'm turning ♪
♪ turning into me ♪
It's not my son.
♪ ...heaven ♪
My son isn't dead.
It's me.
I walked away from my son.
I gave him away.
So... I don't have
a bag of his stuff
or a last place
where we were happy.
He never
got to see me happy.
He's only
6 months old,
and now I've let
a total stranger
believe he's dead.
I have a son...
And his name is Lucas.
♪♪♪
Was I too nice to you, huh?
Is that what happened?
You thought
I was a nice guy, huh?
Dr. Bennett--
shut up. Shut the...
You shoulda been afraid of me.
You shoulda been terrified.
My face shoulda been
in your head
every single moment
you were with Maya.
So look at me right now.
Look long and hard
and remember me saying,
you will never
hurt Maya again.
Okay.
You got my daughter pregnant.
So help me god, if I could--
wait, wait, wait, wait.
Maya's pregnant?
You didn't know.
Dr. Bennett...
I love her.
Did you ever find your shoe?
No. Finish helping
that friend?
Yeah, I did.
I want to punch him.
I didn't want
a relationship, damn it.
I was fine being alone.
You know what I miss?
Your martinis.
You sure do know
how to change a subject.
No, I was just thinking that
you have nowhere to go,
and hotel rooms are...
Cold and empty, and, um,
I just--i just don't know
how to make a good Martini.
You're inviting me
to stay with you?
Uh, well, you know,
just until
you get things sorted out.
You're not gonna get all talky
about feelings or hair--
I just want a Martini.
♪ Old days and memories ♪
♪ are calling you now ♪
Evening.
♪ To glories that you... ♪
What, you're not gonna make
some warm-hearted comment
about me
being in a wheelchair?
I thought we were on a roll.
Sorry.
You okay?
♪ The old days are gone,
hallelujah ♪
Um...
♪ Out in the country ♪
My 15-year-old
daughter is pregnant.
♪ Searching... ♪
And I tried to force her
to have an ab-abortion.
And I don't believe in abortion.
I've gone
over the edge...
And I don't know
what to do.
♪ Hallelujah ♪
♪ Way over the water ♪
♪ tomorrow is coming to you ♪
♪ In the old days you held it ♪
♪ in the palm of your hand ♪
♪ the old days are gone,
hallelujah ♪
This... this never happened.
Damn right,
it never happened.
♪♪♪
I don't know
if what happened t--
or what didn't happen today
was...
The best thing or...
Or a mistake.
I don't know.
How can you know?
I mean,
you make a choice.
You do what you think
is right at the time.
I mean, the plan is--
meet a guy, fall in love,
have a family.
But you have to be specific.
Be older than 15,
meet the right guy,
stay in love.
Stay in love.
Mm.
I knew I forgot something.
Hmm.
♪ The old days are gone ♪
♪ hallelujah ♪