It's all about the tongue,
man. You stick it in their mouth,
but not all the way.
They like that?
Dude, they love it.
What are you doing? Climbing.
Just deep enough to lick her teeth: slow,
one at a time, like you're painting them.
This girl Rachel,
she's a junior.
- She's experienced.
- Mom says I gotta be home by 5:00.
Just chill, okay? And hop the
fence before someone sees you.
Are you sure this is okay?
Dave's mom's a Realtor.
If it's for sale and
empty, it's a clubhouse.
And if you say
anything, you're dead.
I told them you were cool.
These are very serious dudes.
Come on.
Cub Scout meeting's
down the street, boys.
What a loser. Lame.
- Gabe's cool, man. He's one of us.
- He better be.
Uh, I'm not thirsty.
- What's this?
- Club business, little man.
- What shall we ask?
- Put your hands on.
O dark spirit, will any of
us die in the year to come?
- You're moving it.
- Put your hands back. Now.
Who among us will die?
"G,"
"A"...
Oh, man.
"B,"
"E."
"Gabe." That blows.
That's it. We're
going to the hospital.
No, Mom. I'm too tired.
Come on, sweetie. You've had
a fever for almost a week now.
- Ow.
- Oh, my God.
Oh, Gabe. Are you okay?
Are you okay?
Baby, what's wrong?
I'm dying.
Twelve-year-old male.
Spiking fever, congested chest,
coughing up green
sputum, pain in breathing.
Baffling, though I vaguely recall a
disease called "meunomia"? "Pneumania"?
But his chest X-ray and
C.T. scan show an atypical
pattern for pneumonia.
Pneumonia! That's it.
Just a guess here, but
his parents big donors?
No infiltrate, just
enlarged hilar lymph nodes.
Tiny unicorns goring his
bronchial tubes would be cooler,
and the way you're ignoring the question—
Wow, they're extremely big donors.
He's not responding to
cefuroxime, his pulse ox is
dropping much faster than
it should for pneumonia,
and plus he's got
an odd little rash.
Excessive irritation. He's 12.
He's on auto-stroke. On his arm.
Papular lesion, one centimeter,
on top of a long, thin scab.
Ah, you need a dermatologist. If it's
dry, keep it wet. If it's wet, keep it dry.
If it's not supposed to be there,
cut it off. I never could master all that.
There you are.
Were you scared? It's
okay. You're home now.
Fine.
Cuddy.
- As a special favor to you— -
No. Admit it. I got you with the rash.
The rash is a total snooze, unless
it's connected to the pneumonia,
then it's party time.
Purulent sputum,
dyspnea, rhonchi bilaterally.
What kind of pneumonia causes this
kind of rash? Legionnaire's disease.
Usually means industrial
ventilation systems,
convention centers.
He's 12 years old.
Send off a urine antigen and
check if he's joined the Elks. Next?
Fungal.
Excellent. Maybe the
lodge went spelunking.
- Chlamydia pneumonia.
- Twelve-year-olds don't have sex.
Their mistake.
That's it? Other possibilities?
What if we're thinking
about this backwards?
The rash came first,
caused the pneumonia. Nice.
Rickettsial. Tick bite.
Nymphal ticks are out
now. They're
bloodthirsty little bastards.
- Rash would be more pustular.
- Not always,
and there's only one rash, which fits.
New Jersey, it's most
likely Lyme disease.
All right. Let's
keep him on fluids...
and the cefuroxime to be safe.
Biopsy that rash.
And take another history. Even if
we don't learn what's causing this,
we definitely need to know if
twelve-year-olds are getting any action.
- What are you doing now?
- We're collecting fluids from the rash.
Why? They know what
they're doing, Jeffrey.
Oh, great endorsement coming
from the woman who thought
it was a nasty cold. If I
had had him last week...
This isn't helping.
We're checking to see if
your son has a tick bite.
Gabe, have you been camping recently,
playing sports outside, anything like that?
I'm not that good at sports.
- No hanging out anywhere new,
strange places?
- We've been through this.
We don't let him run wild
through the neighborhood, right?
Okay. This might
be a bit delicate.
We need to know if
you're sexually active.
I beg your pardon?
- Mr. Reilich, we need to— - No.
Nothing like that.
We've gotta get another C.T.
scan, check his lungs again.
- Third floor, right?
- Yeah, Radiology is...
Sorry, medical personnel only.
Where's the machine?
Well, we passed it, actually.
A little tension in the room back
there. Thought you could use a break.
Your dad's a pretty...
high-powered guy.
Yeah. He was an air force
test pilot. Real Top Gun stuff.
Flew Mach 3.
Hard to deal with sometimes?
Guess I'm more
like my mom. Listen.
I promise to keep my mouth
shut, but I need to know.
You definitely haven't had
any sexual contact of any kind?
I wish.
You know what?
Girls like the cool guys
now, but give it a few years.
They start liking
the smart guys.
You'll be all right.
Can you keep a secret?
I have to. It's my job.
I'm cursed. I'm not kidding.
This séance thing the kids
did? It spelled out my name.
Said I was gonna die.
First name and last name? We've got a
Gabe upstairs who's very old, very sick.
No. It's me. I have
the worst luck.
One time I broke this mirror,
the next week my
parents got separated.
My parents split up too.
Every kid feels like
it's his fault. It never is.
So, what about the
rest of the stuff? Any
playing outside your
parents don't know about?
Anything like that?
Maybe you were somewhere
you weren't supposed to be?
Triage nurse, pick
up line 274. Oh, man.
Gabe, it's important.
A secret club. What's the
secret— they're all morons?
He fell on something in the attic,
scraped his arm, got the rash the next day.
Said it smelled
really moldy up there.
- Fungal pneumonia
without the cave. Clever.
- I'm gonna get a sample.
Dr. Chase, you
have a few moments?
Sorry, I've gotta go.
These young doctors. It's like
they don't care about people.
- No manners.
- My fault, probably.
That's an interesting accent
you have there. I'd say Czech...
with about 30 years of Aussie.
You have quite an ear.
You're Chase's dad.
Hard to miss—you know, the big
hug and how happy he was to see you.
Need a consult. With a patient.
Urgent doctor stuff.
Twenty-six-year-old male,
sudden loss of the ability to speak—
Just because you got out of clinic duty
doesn't mean everybody did. To his father.
Differential diagnosis? Chase?
Dad swoops in, Chase swoops out.
Dad say why he was
here? See? You asked.
Dad comes 5,000 miles, you're
more curious than Junior is.
Can’t just be about the divorce.
It's been 15 years, and Mom's been dead for
10 of them. You think Daddy murdered her?
You want to get to the bottom of
this, you're doing it exactly right:
Don't talk to the people
involved. Drag your buddy
away from work for some
pointless speculation.
You want to know how two
chemicals interact, do you ask them?
No. They're gonna lie through
their lying little chemical teeth.
Throw them in a
beaker and apply heat.
Even I don't like you.
You know, words can hurt.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, hold on,
guys. I don't care that you're up here.
- You a cop?
- Doctor. I'm treating Gabe Reilich.
- He said he fell over near some pipes?
- Yeah, over there.
- What, here?
- Yeah.
Any of you guys been feeling
sick lately? Rash, cold, anything?
No.
Oh, crap. He is a cop! Damn it!
He fell on it— Some
weird kind of insulation.
It's old. House
was built in the '60s.
What's it made of? Felt,
fibers of—what, cotton?
Sorry. Forgotten how
funny your dad was.
- Not as funny as you.
- High praise.
I know how protective
kids can be of their parents.
Not cotton. Animal hair.
Get me the C.T. scan.
First, find the name of the
company that made the insulation,
and second, tell me what I'm seeing
that makes me want to short their stock.
Uh, enlarged hilar lymph nodes.
- Peribronchial thickening.
- Pleural effusions.
Less obvious, more scary.
Well, the mediastinum
doesn't look right.
Slightly widened.
Oh, God.
It can be transmitted
through infected animal hair.
But the Gram's stain would
have shown— No. The cefuroxime
would have killed some
of it, clouded the result.
We've gotta get
this kid on levaquin.
What does he have?
Anthrax. This house
belong to old man Hussein?
Maybe he is cursed.
Anthrax. So, what—you think
there were terrorists in that attic?
It's a naturally
occurring bacteria.
- We believe it was in the insulation.
- How sick is he?
Anthrax is very dangerous,
but we've caught it early.
He's on levaquin. It's the
best antibiotic we have.
Lisa, you buy this? Jeff,
you've helped our hospital a lot.
I wouldn't have assigned
Dr. House to your
case if I didn't have
every confidence in him.
- Then who's this guy?
- Jeffrey!
There's all these weird
diseases that can cause
a rash. What about
Ieishmaniasis or filariasis?
Where'd you hear about those?
Internet. I did some research.
Well, those are very rare conditions.
Oh, and anthrax grows along the interstate?
Leishmaniasis doesn't cause
pneumonia, and filariasis—
Just look into everything.
This is my son, all right?
And I'm gonna stay on
top of you until I know
he's safe. I wouldn't
expect anything else.
Everyone's a doctor.
Breathe, baby. It's okay.
Breathe. I need you to breathe.
His breathing—
It's on the inhale.
What does that mean? It
means his airway's closing up.
Is the anthrax doin' it?
All right. Hold still, Gabe. This is
gonna be a little uncomfortable.
We've got you. It's okay.
- Nodules in his throat.
- Airway's occluded?
- We've got to intubate. Ativan!
- Pushing 3 c.c.'s.
Airway's too tight.
What's wrong? What's
wrong? No, you're killing him!
Jeffrey! Let them do their job.
Airway's too tight.
Get me a smaller tube.
- We're traching.
- Smaller tube.
- His lips are cyanotic.
- He's not breathing.
Foreman, we're traching.
No. I can do it. I'll get it.
- Foreman, you're not getting through.
- He's not getting air.
- We have to trach him right now.
- No, I can do it.
Betadine.
I'm doing this.
Got it.
He's okay.
Allergic reaction
to the antibiotics?
I don't think so. We
switched him to rifampin,
and there was no
change in the swelling.
We should try another
antibiotic. You really
think he's allergic
to two antibiotics?
I wanna know what
Dr. Chase thinks.
It's possible he's allergic—
Oh! I'm sorry. Not you.
Understandable mistake.
The other Dr. Chase.
Boy gets anthrax and happens
to be allergic to two antibiotics.
Hate to step on anybody's toes, but is it
possible your guys got this one wrong?
The rash is classic
anthrax. Except the color.
The rash hasn't turned black
yet. No necrosis, no anthrax.
Necrosis can theoretically
take as long as two weeks.
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
Guys, it's not a
competition. It's a diagnosis.
Okay. Who thinks Junior wins?
Four to one. It's not anthrax.
So we start over. What's changed?
What do the nodules tell us?
- Sarcoidosis.
- Excellent. Send an ACE level.
If it comes back positive,
put him on methotrexate.
We ran some tests and the
results point toward sarcoidosis.
It makes the body's
tissues swell up.
It seems to have gone after Gabriel's
skin and lungs and given him this fever.
Doctor.
We don't know what causes it.
But you're sure he has this one? We
have a world-renowned doctor consulting.
- He's convinced this is sarcoidosis.
- Is it treatable?
Very, actually. See, this is I.V.
methotrexate. It's an anti-inflammatory.
It should make all the swelling
go down and, uh, get you all better.
Stop.
My God, it's black.
Necrosis.
It's definitely anthrax,
and it definitely can't
be anthrax. It doesn't
cause throat nodules.
Only explanation is, this kid's
got anthrax and sarcoidosis.
Right— Two incredibly
rare diseases...
- just happening to strike at once.
- Unless you've got a better theory.
Anthrax plus an
allergic reaction.
Call the Lancet, because that's
one bizarre allergic reaction.
Come on. There's no reason
you both can't be wrong.
It's not allergy, but it's
not coincidence either.
Disease number one set
off disease number two.
Anthrax weakened
his immune system.
And triggered a
dormant sarcoidosis.
Keep him on antibiotics
for the anthrax, and start the
methotrexate for the
sarcoidosis. See what happens.
Fine.
Better go with him. Make sure he
doesn't snap and hurt somebody.
Yeah, but y-you're treating
him for both diseases.
We're covering all
the bases. What—throw
everything against the
wall and see what sticks?
Works for spaghetti.
A-Are you being
funny? Apparently not.
You know why I give
money to this hospital?
It's the only way to
get attention. See this?
Is this a magic trick? 'Cause I
am a total David Copperfield fan.
Although I thought that
tornado of fire— that seemed a
little fake. Pain in the wrist.
It won't go away for months.
Six doctors' brilliant
conclusion is to take it
easy. I write a check,
name goes on a plaque,
and 48 hours later I've got two M.R.I.'s, a
bone scan and a diagnosis: carpal tunnel.
I'm in surgery that afternoon.
Fascinating story. Have you
thought of adapting it for the stage?
I love my— Look at
me. I love my son.
I love him more than anything
else in the world. Start paying
attention to this case, or I'm
gonna make things miserable...
Go to your son's room.
Not until you get your ass...
There's a problem.
- What is it?
- I don't know.
Skin lesions are
spreading all over his body.
They're opening up, and the
fatty tissues are oozing out.
He'll be septic in a matter
of days. Death by dermatitis.
- Where's Robert?
- Uh, he has clinic duty this morning.
No, he doesn't. I
rescheduled you guys so you'd
be free. Yeah, but he
re-rescheduled himself.
It doesn't hurt yet. Keep going.
You page me?
No, I don't need you. Come on.
We all need help now and
again. You're getting a consult.
- Okay. We've got new skin lesions,
bigger and uglier. What would cause that?
- My hand hurts.
What if his body
worked so hard attacking
the anthrax that it
started attacking itself?
- Autoimmune.
- Wouldn't present this aggressively.
- It's not likely, but it is possible.
- What, in a twelve-year-old male?
- This isn't about me, is it?
- Gabe's dad found Ieishmaniasis and filariasis
on the Internet yesterday.
- They didn't fit then,
but now they kind of do.
- Sure,
except for the nodules, and we're
not working out of Calcutta General.
- Multiple neurofibromatosis.
- You think this is neurological?
The only reason you're thinking autoimmune
is because you're a rheumatologist.
If you were a proctologist,
you'd think rectal cancer.
Gotta go with Senior.
- He literally wrote the book on this one.
- Autoimmune is a big universe.
It could be anything from
scleroderma to Churg-Strauss.
Whatever it is, we should start him
on steroids, keep the swelling down.
A hundred milligrams of cytoxan—
It treats most autoimmunes.
Well, give it to him now before the
fat starts dripping out his eyeballs.
Hey, my fingers are numb.
Your watch is on too tight.
You're messing with my
head. Your relationship with
your dad is messing with
your ability to do your job.
Only because you made my
dad part of my job. Good point.
You haven't seen him in years, he flies
across the Atlantic to see you— Pacific.
- You breeze by him like he's a Hare Krishna
at the airport, don't ask why he's in town.
- It's probably a conference.
Probably.
I was hoping to do this
through sheer manipulation,
but if you insist on
talking, fine. Talk.
- What did he do to you?
- How would you feel if I interfered
in your personal life?
I'd hate it—that's why I
cleverly have no personal life.
I'm gonna biopsy
his skin lesions.
Good thinking. Prove your dad
wrong. That'll solve everything.
Who extubated him? I did.
Temperature's down two degrees,
and the swelling's almost gone.
And his skin looks better too.
Cytoxan is working.
- Feeling better, Gabe?
- Yep, a lot.
Dr. Chase, can you
and I have a word?
Your diagnosis is wrong.
No autoimmune disease.
The swelling's probably
just down because we've got
him on steroids. It's masking
whatever's really wrong.
A.N.A.'s are unreliable.
Phospholipid antibodies
are negative, so no lupus.
Same for Churg-Strauss.
You're arguing with
a rheumatologist.
There's about 20 distinct autoimmune
diseases— Why are you here?
S.L.E. conference.
You were in New York
last year for the scleroderma
conference. I didn't
hear anything from you.
Just wanted to say hi this
time. You said it. You're still here.
I miss you.
I was 15 years old when you walked
out. Now you're walking back in?
I left your mother.
I didn't leave you.
Mum was living on gin and
tonics. How was I supposed
to take care of her? She
wasn't your responsibility.
I know! She was yours.
I'm sorry she died. I'm sorry
you had to deal with that.
But she was falling
apart long before...
I've got to talk to House
about this treatment.
But the patient's
getting better.
In spite of the cytoxan.
On the other
hand—getting better.
Cytoxan makes him more
susceptible to infection.
The anthrax could relapse
and be more resistant. Better!
You want a negative test for every
autoimmune disease known to man?
- Fine. I'll get 'em.
- Be home by midnight
or you can't have the car this weekend.
You guys talk? Did he
tell you why he's here?
The S.L.E. conference.
Going back to the conference?
Afternoon panel. I hope I can stay awake.
I hope you can get in.
You're not registered.
I get it. You had
to make up a lie.
Can't just tell your kid
you're here to see him.
I mean, what father does that?
That little blue dot
under your collar— it's
a tattoo for guiding
radiation treatment.
I was looking for it after I saw what you
had for breakfast: brown rice, vegetables.
It's a macrobiotic diet— popular with
Hollywood starlets and... cancer patients.
Lungs. Stage IV.
- You look good.
- I'm not.
Came to the States to go to
Sloan-Kettering and see Dr. Wilson.
- What'd he say?
- Three months.
But you haven't told Robert.
You don't want to burden him,
because you were such a lousy dad.
I'd prefer you not tell him.
Yeah. That's better.
I'll get to see his face when
he reads his dad's obituary.
It's not your business.
I suppose it isn't.
You sure do a lot of tests.
If we figure out exactly
which autoimmune
condition it is, we can
get you better quicker.
Was that your dad before? Yeah.
That's so cool. Do you
guys work together a lot?
Not really.
When can I go home?
We'll see.
Looks like you got your
appetite back. That's a good sign.
Want some water? Yes.
- Ah!
- Here you go.
Whoops. That's all
right. Water's cheap.
- Oh, God.
- What?
I can't— I can't move my hand.
Can you squeeze my
fingers for me, Gabe?
He's getting worse. Now his entire
right hand and forearm are paralyzed.
And his fever's back. It's up
over 105. If we don't stop the
nerve deterioration quickly,
he'll be paralyzed for life.
Well, luckily, at this rate that
should only last about a week.
- Okay. So— - I told you we
should get him off the cytoxan.
This is toxic neuropathy.
We've been shoving drugs
into his system for a
disease he doesn't have.
- Well, it could be neurological.
- What kind of brain process
would cause a paralyzed hand,
skin lesions and
swollen throat nodules?
Robert was right. You said
multiple neurofibromatosis.
Are you saying that for
the chance at a beautiful
family moment, or is there
some medicine involved?
- Mm-mmm. Fits better.
- Too bad.
I was hoping for the other reason.
I was gonna go get my camera.
Get a C.T. scan—his
brain this time.
You'd think three copies
would be enough, right?
One's always been
more than enough for me.
Why didn't you tell me that
Rowan Chase was in to see you?
Excuse me.
Ethics, confidentiality—
Does any of this ring a bell?
You could have covered
yourself, called me in
for a consult. It is a
juicy piece of gossip.
You know what happened? I got all
focused on his cancer and lost perspective.
You can't tell Chase, but
I can. What should I do?
This is where I give
you advice and pretend
you're gonna listen
to it. I like this part.
Did Rowan ask you not to
tell? I promised I wouldn't.
My fingers were crossed,
though, so I'm wide open.
I was wrong. This is
the musing-out-loud part.
Do I actually need to
be here? Telling him.
Now, that's got real entertainment
value. Mm. He might even cry.
On the other hand, there
is the do-unto-others thingy.
Well, then I should definitely tell him.
I'd wanna know. You wanna know everything.
There's also the
keeping-your-promises thingy.
Oh, you never run out of thingies— like
that blonde thingy you were chatting up.
She's the hospital accountant. We
were going over billing procedures.
Double-entry bookkeeping?
What are you gonna do?
Billing procedures. They're
so complicated, aren't they?
You know, parents are never
as bad as kids think they are.
If you like my dad
so much, ask him out.
I'd make an excellent
stepmom. I'm very lenient.
He's your father. You
never see him, and he's here.
Unless he's done some unspeakable
thing, you should lighten up.
Great. Thanks for the tip.
Okay.
He beat your mom. He beat you.
What did he do?
Really, don't push it.
All this hate. It's toxic.
Then stay away.
There's nothing there.
No masses, no
fibrous tangles, nothing.
It's not neurofibromatosis.
Drs. Chase are 0 for 3. Even
when they agree, they're wrong.
So, next, what else could
cause neural damage as
- well as all the nodules?
- Berger's disease.
He's never been
out of the country.
Have his parents? They
could have brought it back.
- I don't think so.
- It doesn't matter. His lesions are in the
wrong place. His feet are the one clear spot.
- Kid's dad mentioned Ieishmaniasis.
- Yeah, and filariasis.
- But the throat nodules still don't fit with that.
- That's two diseases pretty much
exclusive to Southeast Asia.
What if the anthrax didn't
set off the second disease?
- We're back at coincidence again?
- No. What if something else
was the trigger?
- Nothing else happened.
- We happened.
Antibiotics?
We've been through
this. It's not an allergy.
I gotta pee.
- What did the C.T. scan tell you?
- Nothing.
Ow! Scale from one
to 10— how painful?
Not half as painful as when I punch you
in the face. Don't do that. It'll hurt you.
- Carpal tunnel surgery
obviously didn't work.
- Who are you?
The little ones call me Uncle Greg.
Your dad never had carpal tunnel.
You mentioned two obscure diseases to
Dr. Chase. How did you know about them?
- I read about them on the Internet.
- What did you search for—"Diseases from Asia
that don't match my son's symptoms"?
- You head about them in Asia.
- I've never been there.
Well, you probably just forgot.
Let me refresh your memory:
some remote, dusty village,
close quarters, at least a year?
- Starting to come back?
- I'm calling Dr. Cuddy.
Excuse me, what does
this have to do with our son?
Your dad's pissed
off. He should be.
Comes here expecting
us to do an extra-good job
because he gives a whole
lot of money to this hospital.
Don't talk to my son like that!
Just telling him my
job and my obligation...
Stop! What's going on?
There's only one thing
you guys have gotta do.
Tell the truth, or
your son will die.
How long were you in Asia?
Jeff, it's a simple question.
Two years, in India.
Why would you lie about
something like that? It was '87 and '88.
This, uh...
This guru— I-I thought
he had some answers.
I went to his ashram...
and, um, ended up with
no money and no answers.
I was embarrassed. I
didn't want anyone to know.
No.
No. You were a test pilot.
I'm so sorry, Gabe.
What does this have
to do with my son?
Clue number one: If I
were Jesus, curing this
kid would be as easy
as turning water into wine.
Demonic possession?
Close, but no wafer.
Clue number two:
Rheumatology Rowan was
almost right. It causes
autoimmune symptoms.
- Leprosy?
- Yeah, that's real big
in the Jersey suburbs.
It's leprosy. Run a Fite
stain. It'll be positive.
Daddy hung out on the
wrong kind of Indian ashram.
But it's obviously dormant in the
dad. How could the kid catch it?
It's not dormant in
the dad. It's just slow.
Damaged his ulnar nerves. Was
misdiagnosed as carpal tunnel.
Never trust doctors.
Run a Fite stain.
No wonder he got anthrax. The
leprosy weakened his immune system.
Vicious circle: The leprosy made
him vulnerable to the anthrax,
and the anthrax treatment
put the leprosy in overdrive.
- But the antibiotics we gave him—
they cure leprosy.
- Yeah. That's where the trouble starts.
The antibiotics hit
the nerve strands.
They kill the leprosy bacteria, and
the corpses get tossed into the system.
And as fascinating as our
bodies are, they're also stupid.
They produce antibodies
to beat dead bacteria.
And these aren't
the polite antibodies.
They're the ones that won't
sit still, kick during nap time.
They attack his
neural and fat cells,
causing inflammation and
all the rest of his symptoms.
So the cure's killing him.
I want you to call down
to Carville, Louisiana,
home of the last leper
colony in the Lower 48.
Get 'em to send up
some thalidomide.
Thalidomide?
Twelve-year-olds don't have
sex, right? So he can't be pregnant.
Make the call.
I need to speak to your boy.
Hmm.
Why does everybody
need to know my business?
People like talking
about people.
Makes us feel superior,
makes us feel in control,
and sometimes, for some people,
knowing some things makes them care.
I tell you my dad left,
my mum drank herself
to death, you gonna
care about me more?
Cameron would. Me, I
just like knowing stuff.
I know you hate your dad.
- Now, I'm gonna tell you
something— - I don't hate him.
I loved him until I figured out that
it hurts a lot less to just not care.
You don't expect him to turn up to
your football match, no disappointments.
You don't expect a call
on your birthday, don't
expect to see him for
months, no disappointments.
You want us to go make up— Sink a
few beers together, nice family hug?
I've given him enough hugs. He's
given me enough disappointments.
Okay.
- That's it?
- That's it.
Breathe. -
Breathe again.
Are you gonna have to
tell my friends I'm a leper?
You had the antibiotics.
You're not contagious anymore.
Well, what if they
already caught it?
Leprosy is incredibly hard to
catch. Even your mum didn't get it.
Right. I want
you to make a fist.
It's still kinda stiff.
It'll get back to normal in a month
or two. Your skin, two or three weeks.
Security 12, call 3662.
You haven't asked
about your dad.
He lied about everything.
He lied to my mom.
He lied to his boss.
He's just a liar.
He loves you.
I don't love him.
Yeah, you do.
Nothing you can do
about it. He's your dad.
It doesn't matter what he
does. You're gonna love him.
Here. Thanks.
Hey!
When's your flight?
You got time for a drink?
Wish I did.
Dr. Chase?
I got it.
You're gonna be gettin'
down to Oz anytime soon?
Not too long. Next
autumn, I hope.
I'll call ya.
Well, you're all set.
I'll see ya. Yeah.
I'll see you.
That's some bad hat, Harry.