The night that you left,
I kissed Crockett.
I'm sorry.
April? Really? Huh?
All this time,
acting like friends.
Hey! Hey!
Come on!
I couldn't let you
keep treating patients.
I had to make your
addiction known.
What you did
was a betrayal.
You're an
excellent doctor.
I wasn't about to let you
throw your life away.
You were right.
You gave me
my life back.
It's beautiful, Ben.
You're beautiful.
I pronounce you
husband and wife.
Whoo!
I'll say it
till the day I die,
there's no better pizza
than Chicago deep dish.
It is not even pizza!
It's lasagna.
We're gonna have to
agree to disagree.
I will not agree
to disagree. No.
You are flat wrong.
Flat, the way
the pizza should be.
Lasagna, huh?
That's good.
Smart lady.
No, Dr. Charles.
Not you too.
I didn't know that you
and Dr. Asher were...
Friends.
Yeah. Good,
that's good.
And?
And she needs
a strong support
system right now.
So, I'm glad
that she has you
as a... as a friend.
Look, I get it.
Romantic relationships
are discouraged during
the first year of recovery.
Neurochemically,
very little difference
between the dopamine
rush that we get
from drugs and alcohol,
and the rush that we get
from romance.
I'm sure, as with anything,
there are exceptions
to the rule.
I have never actually
seen that go well.
I mean, at least not
in my, you know,
three decades
of experience
counseling people
in recovery.
Next.
Yeah.
Hey. So, how are things
with Ethan?
Okay, I guess.
I've tried to get him
to talk about it
and he hasn't wanted to.
Hmm. Maybe that's
his way of processing?
Yeah, maybe.
Will, you're up.
Ambo has landed.
You're going
to Trauma Two.
All right.
Evelyn Myers,
49-year-old female
with progressive
early-onset Alzheimer's.
Passed out at home.
Did a 12-lead in the ambo.
She's got peaked T waves.
Hey, did she hit her head
when she passed out?
Her daughter, Molly,
didn't think so. No overt
signs of head trauma.
I'm pretty sure
that she didn't,
but I was in the other room
when it happened.
I shouldn't have
left her alone.
Evelyn,
I'm Dr. Halstead.
All right. On my count.
One, two, three.
Thanks, guys.
Yup.
Rhonchi both sides. Blunted
breath sounds at the base.
Two-plus pitting edema.
Yeah.
Yeah, Molly, is your mom
on any medications
for kidney disease?
Uh, I'm not sure. She takes
something called Capto...
Captopril?
I think so.
Sorry, I'm not with her
every day. I'm just home
for spring break.
Any family history
of kidney problems?
Um. Yeah, yeah,
my grandma, my mom's mom,
she had something wrong
with her kidneys.
My dad will know
what it's called.
CBC, CMP, stat...
What's going on?
Molly, I told you to call me
if anything happened with Mom.
Sorry, Dad.
I just freaked out.
It's okay.
Hi, I'm Dr. Halstead.
Elliot.
Elliot. Well,
we still need labs,
but I, uh, I suspect
Evelyn's in acute
renal failure
in which case, she'll need
emergency dialysis...
No. No dialysis. It's against
Evelyn's advance directive.
Don't listen to him.
He lies.
Evelyn, honey,
you signed an
advance directive.
Advance directive?
What is that, Dad?
No, I didn't sign
anything. No.
You don't want dialysis,
my love.
Yes. I do. I do.
Help me.
Hey, take a look.
Did you get Mrs. Myers'
lab work back?
She's profoundly uremic
and hyperkalemic.
She's not making urine.
If we don't dialyze her,
she'll die.
Well, I reviewed
her advance directive.
She prepared it shortly after
her Alzheimer's diagnosis.
And I'll tell you, Mrs. Myers
outlined a number of
interventions she didn't want,
including dialysis.
And she appointed
her husband to be her proxy
when she could
no longer speak for herself.
But she can speak for herself.
And she has changed her mind.
I mean, people can modify
their advance directives
at any time, right?
As long as they still
have decisional capacity.
Well, you do an evaluation.
And then we'll take it
from there.
Great.
Sharon?
Yeah.
Your assistant called.
Michael's plane has landed.
Oh, good.
It's silly, I know,
but he's 32 years old.
Mmm-hmm.
I still get nervous
when he flies.
I guess I just
feel a lot better
when I know he's got
two feet back on the ground.
He's your baby boy.
How long is he in town?
Just 24 hours.
Interviewing for a sales job
at Kender Bio Systems.
Would love to have
at least one of my kids
living in the city.
Okay.
Need some help over here!
This is Nick Elms.
Experiencing
severe abdominal pain.
Haven't finished uploading
his information
into the system.
I can tell you anything
you need to know.
I'm his wife. Alice.
Trini, where are we headed?
Four's open.
Just breathe.
All right, Mr. Elms,
we're gonna take you
right in here.
Ready? One, two three.
There you go.
All right.
When did
the pain start?
Last night.
Nick has a condition
called familial
adenomatous polyposis.
It causes polyps in his...
Colon and rectum.
I'm familiar.
When was he
first diagnosed?
Five years ago.
It had already developed
into colorectal cancer.
He had multiple
rounds of chemo
but it came back
again last year.
Developed congestive
heart failure from the chemo.
Nick, can you tell me
when you had
your last bowel movement?
Yesterday morning.
No, the day before.
All right. Well,
we do need a CT scan,
but I'm worried there's
a colonic obstruction.
Which means
a colostomy, right?
Mmm-hmm.
My doc warned me
that was coming.
Well, it may be
short-term.
In as little as 12 weeks,
they can reverse...
No, that's... that's
long-term for me, Doc.
I got four months left,
at the most.
I really gotta spend it
defecating into a bag?
Hey, Mags. Can you page
general surgery for a consult?
Patient is Nick Elms.
Late stage colorectal
cancer due to FAP.
Suspected colonic obstruction.
Mmm-hmm.
Thank you.
Got it.
Hey, Mags?
Mmm-hmm.
I can do the consult.
You sure?
Thought you were
clocking out.
Yeah, well, I got nowhere
to be till cocktail hour.
Have at it.
Come in.
Bert.
What's up?
Sorry to show up
unannounced.
I, um,
spoke with Michael.
With him in town,
thought it would be a good
opportunity to smooth things
over with him.
Our relationship
hasn't been the best
since the divorce.
That's between
you and Michael.
I just thought
if I told him
about us...
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Uh, told him
what exactly?
Just that we'd been
seeing each other.
I should've checked
with you first.
Yeah, that would
have been nice.
And now we're
seeing each other?
"We're seeing each other"?
We go out
once a week, Sharon.
What would you call it?
Look, Bert,
I don't have time for this.
Okay.
Babe, what are you
doing here?
And who's your sidekick?
This is Auggie,
one of my students.
Auggie, this is my wife,
Ms. Lockwood.
Nonsense.
You call me Maggie.
Hi, Maggie.
What's going on,
little man?
Auggie has cirrhosis
from something they
called chronic autoimmune...
Autoimmune
chronic hepatitis?
Yep, that.
And when he showed up
at school this morning,
he sounded winded.
He was running
a slight fever as well.
All right, little man.
Why don't you
come with me, fellas?
We're going
right here.
Babe, why don't you
help Auggie hop up
and grab a seat?
All right.
Why don't you scoot back,
Auggie? There you go.
And I am gonna grab you
all the fruit snacks
you could want.
I don't have any money.
You're a very
important person, Auggie.
The fruit snacks
are on the house.
Gimme a sec.
Earl, do you mind
keeping my friend, Auggie,
company for a sec?
No. Not at all.
Awesome. Auggie,
this is Earl.
He works here.
Hey, big man.
All right, buddy,
gimme some.
Did you get
ahold of his parents?
Auggie's in foster care.
I haven't been able to
reach his foster mom,
Ruth, just yet.
But I'll keep trying.
All right.
I'll go get a doctor
and some fruit snacks.
Oh! Babe,
did you remember to...
Call the spa at the resort?
We're booked for
a couple's massage
on the beach tomorrow morning.
Joy, you fractured
your distal fibula.
It doesn't require surgery,
but you'll need
to be in a boot
for six to eight weeks.
God, I feel
like I'm cursed.
You know, I started
this diet two months ago,
I can't lose any weight.
That's why I joined the gym.
I thought I had to
exercise more.
Babe, what happened?
You passed out
on the treadmill?
Dr. Choi, Nurse Sexton,
this is Max, my fiancé.
I was telling them
the reason I joined
the gym is...
I was having trouble
losing weight.
You look great.
Max, it's not
about that, right?
Now, I just
wanna get healthier.
Well, Joy, there are certain
conditions that can
make weight loss difficult.
But most of them
are common and treatable.
While you're here,
we can run some tests.
If you don't mind
waiting a bit.
Sounds good.
April, let's get
a CBC, FSH, TSH,
and a cortisol level to start.
Okay.
I'll see you in a bit.
All right. Thanks.
Hey, Ethan,
listen, man. I...
How'd it go?
Evelyn definitely does not
have decisional capacity.
I mean, she didn't understand
the treatment being offered
or even that she had
an issue with her kidneys
in the first place.
Well, did she seem
depressed? Suicidal?
No, I wouldn't say that.
So she still possesses
the will to live.
She just can't
articulate it clearly.
Well, except that
when she was of sound mind,
she made it very clear
in writing and
to her husband that...
Who she seems
highly suspicious of,
by the way.
That's not uncommon.
I mean, it's often
the primary caregivers
that get the brunt
of the paranoia
in situations like this.
Well, I don't know.
Maybe it's worth convening
an ethics committee, then?
An ethics committee?
Yeah. Just get some
other perspectives.
I really don't think
that's necessary.
I gave her
a very thorough evaluation,
I'm confident
in my assessment.
Yeah, but ultimately,
it is subjective.
Your opinion...
That's right. My professional
opinion. Which is based on...
Decades of experience,
I know.
That's right.
Decades of experience.
I'll see you.
Oh.
Why does it
look like that?
Ascites. Fluid accumulates
in the peritoneal cavity.
It can happen in patients
with cirrhosis.
Did you tell Ruth
that your belly was
hurting this morning?
She goes to work
before the school bus comes.
Auggie, I'm gonna need to
do a procedure
called paracentesis.
So, what I'll do
is I'll insert a needle...
A needle into my tummy
to get all the bad stuff out.
It's not so bad, Mr. Campbell.
It just sounds scary.
So, I'll be performing
the abdominal portion
of the surgery robotically,
while Dr. Castaneda works
endoscopically from below.
Dr. Manning,
perfect timing.
Good morning, Dr. Marcel.
Robots and endoscopes?
Doesn't sound
like a colostomy.
Yeah. Well, Nick and Alice
and I were discussing it,
and we're gonna
take a different approach.
Transanal total mesorectal
excision. TaTME.
I'm sorry. Forgive me,
I'm not familiar with it.
I am aware of TME,
which is a major surgery.
Right. Well, this is
a new approach
that allows for
better visualization
and removal of tumors
in the lower rectum.
Well, I'm sure
you've explained
the risks to Nick and Alice.
I sure have, yeah.
We're ready to move
Mr. Elms upstairs.
Great.
All right. So, I'll see you
in a couple hours.
Thanks, Dr. Marcel.
All right. Alice,
I'll see you.
Crockett?
Yeah.
Why would you suggest
a radical surgery
for a terminal patient?
Even if it's successful,
it is highly unlikely
it's gonna save his life.
But it could
buy him more time.
And a better quality of life.
Yeah. If he doesn't
die on the table,
which is a real risk
given his heart problems.
And I didn't sugarcoat
that risk.
He has seen many surgeons
and none of them have
put this option on the table.
Yeah, 'cause
most of them are gutless.
Obsessed with their stats.
Okay. You say gutless,
I'd say pragmatic.
Oof!
I see us edging towards
a semantics debate.
I know when
I'm outta my depth.
Why don't you
just stay with me?
No. Company's putting me up
at the Peninsula.
Oh, fancy!
They must really want you.
Mmm-hmm.
So I gotta ask about this
nonsense Dad was talking.
It's not for real, right?
Wait. You're not seriously
considering taking Dad back?
Michael...
He walked out
after 35 years
of marriage.
Ink was barely dry
on the divorce papers
when he started
seeing someone else...
Your father
and I had a drink.
Maybe he read more into it.
So you're not dating
or anything?
No.
I figured he was full of it.
So, we still on for dinner?
I got us a reservation
at Swift & Sons for 7:00.
No. That's too expensive.
Only the best for my mom.
And the company's
paying for it.
Oh!
Hey, are you busy tonight?
This new Thai place
opened up in my neighborhood.
Wanna give it a whirl?
Let's give it a whirl.
7:00-ish?
Works for me.
Dr. Choi!
Something's wrong.
Push five of Ativan.
Has Joy ever had
a seizure before?
No, never. Joy?
All right.
Babe? Well, I thought
you said all her labs
were normal?
They were.
Meds are in.
Well, so was this, like,
an allergic reaction
to something you gave her?
We only gave her ibuprofen,
and she's had that before.
"TaTME, Innovative Surgery
for Rectal Cancer"
co-authored by
Crockett Marcel, MD.
Oh. You
Internet-stalking me,
Manning?
Don't flatter yourself.
I found it when I was
researching the procedure.
Good for you.
You spent your lab year
studying the technique.
You did your fellowship
in the surgical center
that helped pioneer it.
Which makes me, what?
Highly-qualified to
perform the procedure?
No, it makes you biased
and motivated by
professional advancement.
You see what you wanna see.
Excuse me.
You are potentially
costing Nick the chance
to see the birth of his child.
What, so you can get a shot
at performing
a complex surgery?
I answer to my patients,
not to you.
Sats are down to 85.
Get her on a mask.
What's wrong with her?
She has fluid in her lungs.
Another dose of Lasix.
I gave her 10 milligrams
an hour ago.
It's not working.
Just do it.
Where's your father?
He went to get us coffee.
Sats are still dropping.
You have to do something.
Help her.
So, Molly, I would
need to intubate...
So do that.
I can't. It's against
your mom's advance directive.
Mom, you have to
listen to me, okay?
You want the doctor
to help you, right?
Mom, please.
What was that, Mom?
Molly...
That's right!
It's me, it's Molly.
She hasn't called me
Molly in months.
Evelyn, do you want me
to save your life?
Yeah, I need
a verbal response.
Do I have your permission
to intubate to save your life?
Yes or no?
Yes.
Intubation kit,
70 of ketamine.
Mom, it's gonna be okay.
Okay, I'm in. Bag her.
My God. What the hell
did you just do?
I mean, really.
This is like déjà vu.
Getting sued didn't teach you
why you don't ignore
an advance directive?
Ms. Goodwin, this is
a completely
different situation.
I wasn't ignoring
the patient's wishes,
I was honoring them.
And her daughter
will back me up on that.
Yes.
Peter Kalmick is waiting
for you in the boardroom.
Tell him
I'll be right there.
Excuse me, while I attempt
to clean up your mess.
Dr. Charles,
you weren't there.
Oh, come on, Will.
An Alzheimer's patient
has a fluctuation in cognition
doesn't mean they've recovered
their decisional capacity.
I mean, when Evelyn
was making her wishes known,
she certainly understood that.
The most important thing
she understood
is that, eventually,
this disease was gonna
take everything from her.
Signing that piece of paper
was her final act
of self-determination.
Alice?
Dr. Manning.
I was just heading up
to pre-op to meet Nick.
Oh, good.
I'm so glad I caught you.
You know, everything just
moved so quickly this morning.
I wanted to make sure that you
are on board with the surgery.
I'm not.
Well, did you tell Nick
how you feel?
I begged him not to do it,
especially after Dr. Marcel
warned us about the risks.
But Nick was adamant.
He said he wanted to help
improve the treatment options
for our son.
Even if it meant
he may not live to see him.
Your son. He could
inherit the FAP gene.
There's a 50% chance.
This pregnancy
was a surprise.
When we found out,
all Nick could think
about was our baby's future.
And doing everything he could
to prevent our son from
facing the same fate.
Trini, will you take over
for a minute?
I'll be right back.
A word, outside?
Auggie's primary physician
sent over his medical records.
Turns out he's supposed to
have paracentesis
every two weeks,
but he hasn't shown up
to his last couple
appointments.
No wonder his ascites
got so bad.
Yeah, I'm calling
Child Protective Services.
Whoa, whoa,
hold on a second.
Dr. Lanik, can you please
wait until we speak
to his caregiver?
Maybe there's a reasonable
explanation.
I thought she was MIA.
I'm working on
trying to reach her.
Fine.
You have until 4:00.
But if she is not here,
in the flesh,
I'm making the call.
Maybe you don't wanna
take care of her anymore.
You know that isn't true.
You know I'd do
anything for your mom.
Then you
can't let her die.
Molly, honey...
I won't let you.
Ms. Myers?
My name is Sharon Goodwin.
I'm in charge of patient
services here at the hospital.
Yeah, I saw you
talking to my dad.
What if I don't want
the doctors to take out
my mom's breathing tube?
Would I have to sue my dad?
Well...
Before we get into logistics,
are you sure
you want to do that?
Do you really believe
your father isn't acting
in your mother's
best interest?
I mean, he loves her.
I just...
I don't wanna lose her.
I don't know
what to do.
My mom kept me in the dark
about all of this.
You know, when parents
don't share things
with their children,
it's usually out of a desire
to protect them.
I suspect your mother knew
how painful it would be
for you to know her wishes.
And she didn't want to
place the burden of carrying
them out on your shoulders.
She put a lot
on my dad's shoulders.
Yes. Because she knew
he could handle it.
But, you're right,
it is a lot.
And he's going to need you.
You're going to
need each other.
Hmm?
Mmm.
Dr. Marcel,
you should be seeing me.
Yes,
seeing your sponge now.
Nice to finally meet up.
Okay. Let's bring
the pressure down to 12.
Ready to
take the rectum out?
You bet.
Here we go, Nick.
Joy, your seizure was caused
by high levels of ammonia
in your blood.
Well, how'd she get
ammonia in her blood?
Testing revealed
Joy has a urea cycle disorder.
It's a genetic condition
that causes a deficiency
in one of the six enzymes
responsible for removing
ammonia from the bloodstream.
But if it's genetic,
why was I never
diagnosed as a child?
With milder forms
of the disorder,
it's often undiagnosed
until a trigger unmasks it.
Such as childbirth...
Another possible trigger
can be a dramatic
increase in protein intake.
Could you be taking in more
protein with your new diet?
Not really. I actually cut out
red meat and most dairy.
And what about protein bars
or shakes?
No, I drink green smoothies.
Triggers aside,
how do you treat it?
Well, you're gonna have to be
on an enzyme supplement
for the rest of your life,
and maintain
a very low-protein diet.
We can manage that.
Right, babe?
Yeah.
Joy,
just so you understand,
if you don't regulate your
protein intake, there can be
serious consequences.
Understood.
Not even a few
high-protein meals.
I said I understand,
Dr. Choi.
What, do you think
because I'm fat,
I have no self-control?
No. Not at all. I'm just
suggesting if protein
is the trigger...
Yeah. And I just told you
that it wasn't.
Dr. Choi, may I speak
with you outside, please?
Excuse us.
What?
You're so suspicious of Joy.
I can't help but wonder
if you're projecting.
I'm not projecting anything.
The only trigger that
makes sense is protein.
So she's either lying
about what she's eating
or she's in denial.
I am so sorry
I missed your calls.
My manager doesn't allow us
to check our messages
while we're working.
This should
never have happened.
We know that Auggie
has missed his last two
doctor's appointments.
And I am really
sorry about that.
I do my best to get him there,
but the clinic's 40 miles
from my house.
I don't have a car,
and I can't
always get off of work.
Is there someone else
that could help out?
Maybe a babysitter
that could take him?
Who's gonna pay for that?
Ms. Johnson, we're supposed
to report this as neglect.
But if we do that, they might
remove Auggie from your home.
Maybe you should.
What?
Maybe you should report it.
I love that little boy.
I love him.
But it's too much.
It's too much.
And I can't.
Alice?
He did well, Alice.
Real well.
You can visit him
in the recovery room shortly.
Thank God!
So what happens now?
Evelyn's family is gonna take
her home to receive
hospice care until she dies.
I wasn't trying to
prove you wrong today.
If that's what
you're thinking.
Will, I've never thought
of you as a spiteful person.
But we all have
a tendency
to put blinders on
when we're confronted
with things that we
don't want to hear.
Okay. What I wanna do
is prolong this...
That's why Ruth thought
it would be better for you to
go live with another family.
Since she can't always
take you to the doctor
when you need it.
She doesn't want you
to get sick again, Auggie.
I know it's scary going
to live somewhere new.
I'm not scared.
I know why
she doesn't want me.
Oh, sweetie, it's not that
she doesn't want you.
She just...
No one wants a sick kid.
Max, I know
Joy wants to be discharged.
But this meal plan she's on,
is she adhering to it?
Yeah.
Because her test results
and what she's saying,
they don't add up.
Max?
Okay. Um...
I have an idea
of what's going on.
Sometimes, I wake up
in the middle of the night,
and I hear Joy
downstairs in the kitchen.
And in the morning,
there's food missing from
the fridge and the pantry.
Have you ever talked
to her about it?
No. I'm guessing
she's real self-conscious
and that's why
she does it after I'm asleep.
Yeah. It sounds like she may
have a binge eating disorder.
I'd like to bring in
psychiatry to come
speak with her.
No. I know her and an ambush
will just humiliate her.
This has to be
dealt with now.
If she overloads on protein
again, it could kill her.
God...
Tell you what, I'll let you
speak with Joy first.
Come on.
I can't do this.
Joy doesn't binge
in the middle of the night.
I've been slipping
protein powder
in her green smoothies.
Why?
I read protein powder
can make you gain weight
by increasing your
overall caloric...
Why were you trying
to make Joy gain weight?
I wasn't trying to
make her gain weight.
I was trying to keep her
from losing weight.
I know it sounds insane.
And criminal.
I wasn't gonna
do it forever.
Just long enough for...
for her to get discouraged
and stop dieting.
And I never meant
to hurt her.
I was scared that
if Joy lost weight,
she'd leave me.
You need to tell
Joy the truth or I will.
So, Alice and I
were talking, Doc.
Yeah.
And while we
really would like
to name our son
in your honor...
Aw.
We're just not sure
about Crockett.
It is a statement,
that's for sure.
I don't suppose
you have a middle name
that's a little more...
Nick? Nick, honey,
what's wrong?
Okay. Take slow, deep breaths.
Nice and easy, okay?
Nick?
Nick, bud? Talk to me.
Let's get a mask on him.
Let's go. Come on.
Drop it. Hey, buddy.
Heartrate's 133. BP's 77.
Nick?
Nick, I need you to breathe.
Hey, Nick? Nick.
He's in V-Fib.
Nick, honey, wake up.
Nick? No pulse.
All right, let's go.
Bag him.
Milligram of epi.
Let's go, come on.
Oh, my God!
Paddles and charge to 200.
Oh, my God.
Nick?
Charged. Clear!
Let's go. Come on.
All right.
Another round of epi.
Let's go. Charge to 200.
Charged. Clear!
Nick? Nick,
can you hear me?
I am right here,
honey... Nick.
Epi and charge. Let's go.
Clear!
You'll be fine.
He's asystole.
No. Come on, Nick.
No.
No. No. No.
Time of death, 16:54.
Nick!
Thank you so much,
Ms. Gastern. Bye-bye.
DCFS is gonna start looking
for a new foster placement
for Auggie tomorrow.
Mmm.
What about tonight?
Well, I got him a bed
on the peds floor.
And since Earl is back
for the night shift,
he promised that
he would try to check in
on Auggie upstairs.
That's good. Taxi's here.
We should, uh...
Right.
Baby, I just, uh...
Yeah. Okay.
I'll call the airline
and the hotel. Reschedule.
And we'll spend the night
with Auggie.
You know how amazing you are?
Mmm.
You're pretty
amazing yourself,
Mr. Ben Campbell.
I'm a lucky man.
Go ahead.
And, yes, you are.
Thank you.
Joy, you should know
what Max did
was a form of assault.
And I can call CPD and you can
press charges against him.
No, no.
You don't have to call them.
I'm not pressing charges.
Joy, he lied to you,
betrayed your trust.
You don't have to act
like nothing happened.
No, I know what Max did
was so messed up.
But we talked it out.
You know, and he was acting
from a place of
fear and insecurity.
And, you know,
Max is a good person.
I know his heart.
Can we just go?
Take care.
Unbelievable.
If it were me,
I'd be furious.
Anyone would.
Really?
Of course.
Then why aren't you?
What?
Ethan, I lied to you...
Oh, God, April.
I betrayed your trust.
Look, what do you
want me to say?
That I can't believe
you kissed someone else?
Someone we work with?
You know
how crazy it makes me
that I have to see that
son of a bitch every day?
Is this what
you wanna hear?
Yeah. I do.
I wanna know
what you're feeling.
Why? Why couldn't
you just tell me?
Why did it take physically
harming yourself
to come clean?
Are you in love with him?
What? No! Of course not.
It was just a meaningless
attraction. I don't...
Well, if it's so meaningless,
why are we even
talking about it?
Because you deserve
to know everything.
Ethan, I love you.
I made a mistake.
That day, when I found out
I couldn't have children...
You pushed me away
and ran into
another man's arms.
Hey...
You called it. Played out
just like you said it would.
We don't know
what killed Nick.
He was tachycardic,
hypotensive, and desatting.
Classic trifecta.
It had to be a PE.
If that's the case, then
the clot could have been
there prior to the surgery.
I mean, Nick had pretty much
been bedridden for months.
Surgery caused it.
End of story.
You don't know that.
You know, if I hadn't
put that surgery
on the table,
chances are
he'd still be alive.
Crockett.
Sometimes in the ED,
we get tunnel vision.
All we can see
is the patient
in front of us.
But Nick could see past that.
Beyond his own benefit.
And I think you did, too.
You know, with new surgery,
the more you do it,
the better you'll get,
the more lives you'll save.
Yeah, maybe
you couldn't save Nick's,
but maybe someday,
you'll save his son's.
Hey.
We still on for
the Green Mill, Crockett?
The next set
starts in an hour.
Yeah, 'course, darling.
Okay. Good night,
Dr. Manning.
Night.
Hey, Mom. You look nice.
Hey, thank you.
What's Dad doing here?
I invited him.
It's good to see you, son.
If he's staying,
I'm leaving.
Sit down.
Now, this cold war
you've got going with
your father ends tonight.
After what he did to you?
Forget it.
You don't know
the full story.
What are you talking about?
Look, I thought
I was protecting
you and David and Tara
by not talking to you
about the divorce.
But it was painful.
Yeah, and Dad
caused that pain.
Son, the end
of any relationship,
especially one with
a 35-year history,
is complicated.
But, the bottom line, Michael,
is you can spend
your whole life
looking back
and pointing fingers.
Or you could choose
to move forward.
Now, I don't know
what's to come
of your father and me.
But it's time
for this family
to start healing.
You need your father
and your father needs you.
Let's start
by having dinner.
You wanna come up?
I mean, I cleared out
my liquor cabinet,
but I do have a pretty
stellar tea collection.
But you know,
if tea's not your thing,
I can make a gin and tonic,
sans the gin.
No, it's not...
I wanna come up, I do.
I just wonder
if that's a good idea.
Okay.
You may be surprised
to hear this,
but there's actually
very little
neurochemical difference
between drug addiction...
And romance addiction?
And should something go wrong
inside the relationship,
it increases
the chances of relapse.
Yeah.
I've been going
to the meetings, Will.
This stuff's been
drilled into my head.
So, what do we do?
Let's go up and discuss it.