Good morning.
Hey, Alfredo.
You done already? No.
Not yet. I finish tomorrow.
Mexico playing
Argentina on TV? No, no.
My asthma is very bad today.
Six years, Alfredo.
You can't lie to me.
I'm throwing a dinner...
First thing tomorrow...
Party's tonight.
A little rain and I'm gonna have to
put buckets on the dining room table.
No clouds, no rain.
I'll tell you what.
You take off, but if it pours
into my guests' wineglasses...
Okay. Okay, señora.
I'll do it. Thank you.
Spinal cord seems intact.
Take a deep breath.
It hurts. Try.
Breath sounds bilateral. I don't
think he has a pneumothorax.
Just asthma. That and
probably a broken rib.
Tell me when it hurts the most.
Your two little fingers
are darker than the others.
They feel funny. Como needles.
How long have they been
like that? Never noticed before.
Is bad?
Judging by how it looks,
he could lose his hand.
How does falling off your
roof do that to a guy's fingers?
He could have tweaked
a vertebra in his neck.
Could impinge the ulnar...
Sorry, trouble concentrating.
That tank top really
absorbs moisture.
Could impinge the ulnar
nerve, cut the blood flow.
Or it could be disseminated
intravascular coagulopathy.
DIC?
Guy falls off a roof, the
first thought is always,
"It's a clotting problem."
Trauma can activate
the clotting enzymes.
Guy could lose more than
his hand. Thank you very much.
This guy's been working
for me for a long time, and I...
Do I get bonus points
if I act like I care?
Cervical MRI. Work up for DIC.
And start him on a heparin drip.
Who? You wanna know his name?
I'm sure it's in the file.
Or you could ask her.
She's his oldest, bestest friend.
They were in Cub Scouts together.
I'll get started on
the blood tests.
You haven't been a real doctor in 10 years.
You'll make a mess all over the sheets.
I'll do it. You
have clinic duty.
I still know how to handle
a patient. Get me blood.
Lots of blood.
They're better.
They've showered.
You don't need to see him.
One-handed handymen
aren't in big demand.
Talking. That's how
lawsuits are lost.
I know you, Lisa.
You go in, you offer to pay
his medical bills, his wages,
you'll say something
stupid like, "I'm sorry."
You think I'm an idiot.
I think you're not a
lawyer. Don't go in there.
Trust me, House's
people can handle this.
Yeah.
This might sting a little bit.
The medicine will thin the
blood and help it to circulate.
Those are pretty
nasty scars there.
I work construction.
How long will I
be in the hospital?
Depends how long it takes
us to figure out what's going on.
I need to work. I'll get fired.
I'm sure Dr. Cuddy
won't fire you.
I'm a janitor at fast food
six nights. I need to work.
My mother doesn't make
enough. I can work. I'm old enough.
You're old enough
when you finish college.
Why? You never went...
I never had a big brother
to tell me to shut up!
I promise we'll let you out of
here as soon as we're able to.
Look, I... I am fine. Okay? I
feel better. I go home now.
No. If this is a clotting
problem, it could be very serious.
All right? Look, you
can't make me stay.
Wait... You can't make me stay.
Turn your hand over.
I need to see your hand.
Where's Dr. Cuddy?
We've got a third
finger turning dark.
His PTT is prolonged and
the fibrin split products are off.
He's not clotting properly. It
looks like a mild case of DIC.
Well, obviously not that mild.
This keeps up, his hand is
literally gonna be dead meat.
His hand is connected to his
arm, and his arm is connected to...
I'm not sure, but I
bet it's important.
All this from
falling off my roof!
Yeah. If only he'd
fallen on his head.
Then he wouldn't have
any of these symptoms.
We need something
stronger than heparin.
Human Activated Protein C.
Looks like Cuddy, same cleavage.
Protein C is indicated
only for severe sepsis.
How many of his limbs have to
be at stake for it to be severe?
But this stuff is
crazy dangerous.
It can cause internal bleeding.
If he bleeds, he could stroke,
he could die. He could get better.
You know, if I try
to scheme like this,
you get that nasty wrinkly
face and screech like a hyena.
It's very sexy, I admit.
Do it.
Protein C is borderline
irresponsible,
except that the safe
stuff isn't doing squat.
It's exactly the type of thing
you would do. Obviously.
It's exactly the type of
thing he'd do. I know.
I think he's trying
to protect me.
Now, that's not the
type of thing he would do.
I overruled him.
He's the best diagnostician in
this hospital, and I overrule him.
You care about this kid.
Your judgment should
be worth more than his.
He also pointed out that I
haven't been a real doctor in years.
Now that sounds like him.
You were just
jerking Cuddy around?
She seriously thought
I wanted to stop her.
One thing Cuddy is
not is clueless. No.
First casualty of this
case is her sense of humor.
That's weird. There's nothing
funnier than almost killing a guy.
I'm just having trouble
getting up those steps.
When did you start
noticing? Oh, a week ago.
Your blood
pressure's a little high.
I've got something new
that should help you out.
It combines a nitrate
with a blood pressure pill.
It's targeted to
African-Americans.
Targeted?
Yeah. Well, see, we tend to
have nitric oxide deficiencies.
And the studies show this
drug counteracts that problem.
It's the first drug to... What
kind of studies you talking about?
What kind of studies are there?
They get some patients.
They give them some drugs.
I've had white people
lying to me for 60 years.
You think this is a tan? You
think they tell you everything?
The trouble with us black folk,
we can't tell the difference
anymore between racism
and everybody
gets screwed. Yeah?
Well, how about them cheap meningitis
drugs they're pawning off in Africa?
Gonna tell me that ain't
racism? That's just greed.
You really wanna screw whitey?
Be one of the few black men who live
long enough to collect social security.
Take the medicine.
Nurse.
Nurse! Help! Nurse! Help!
Nurse! What's up?
I can't move my arm! I can't move
my arm! Take it easy. Take it easy.
The Protein C side effects we
were worried about, they happened.
Where was the bleed? His brain.
It's causing right
side paralysis.
I've stopped the treatment
and called a neurosurgeon.
I can move it now.
It's okay now, yes? Can I go
home soon? The surgery went well.
But all we did was fix the problem
created by the medicine we gave you.
She says you... You look young.
Are you sure... There's five
of us working on the case.
The others are older.
Why doesn't Dr. Cuddy come to...
That doesn't sound too good.
His fingers are even darker.
His temperature's
102 and spiking.
And the x-ray now
shows lung infiltrates.
Well, the good news
is he won't be bitching
about losing his hand
if he can't breathe.
The trauma from the fall could have
caused acute respiratory distress syndrome.
Right. I forgot. Your roof.
It would cause lung
infiltrates and maybe fever
and conceivably
the cyanotic fingers.
The only question
is why. Why what?
Why her weird psychopathology
requires a diagnosis informed
entirely by personal guilt.
Let's assume we've
been wrong up until now.
Let's assume,
just for one second,
that the earth doesn't
revolve around Cuddy's roof.
What if he was sick before
he had his run-in with gravity?
He just didn't notice anything.
Well, pneumonia can cause DIC
which can cause cyanotic fingers.
Pneumonia doesn't
hit that fast. Sure.
Only pavement hits that
fast. It's not pneumonia.
He might have missed
a finger turning dark.
He's not gonna miss
breathing problems.
What else? It's pneumonia.
He wanted to go home.
I thought he was lying.
I told him I had a dinner
party. I made him go up there.
Well, why didn't you just
take out a gun and shoot him?
I thought it was just asthma.
You might've mentioned
this earlier, Doctor.
Maybe we could have sent
some blood cultures to the lab
instead of wasting a day
indulging your self-loathing.
If it's just garden-variety bacterial
pneumonia, he's gonna be fine.
So give him garden-variety Levaquin,
and a garden-variety echocardiogram.
And go check out
the kid's house.
The blood work will show us
which type of pneumonia it is...
If he's huffing nail polish or
pulling the wings off his pet parrot,
this way'll be faster.
And I bet Julio's just dying to
find out what's wrong with him.
Go with her. It's Alfredo.
And I can handle
getting a key and...
Rico and I no longer trust you
deciding what's important and what's not.
You ever think about writing
a book on office politics?
Trust me,
it would be a lot worse if I told her
that you had to break into her house.
What? Wait, wait,
wait... Cuddy's house?
See? It is shocking.
The guy's been working there
every day for the last three weeks.
You think it's impossible he
could've picked something up?
I'm not breaking into my
boss's house. I'm your boss.
She's scarier than you are.
She's a woman.
Relax. I'm coming with.
House is having lunch
with his juniors now?
No. Not a chance. Then where
do you think they're going?
I have no idea.
Then why don't you think
they're going to lunch?
Because it's not like House.
That was your point, right?
He had that smug
look on his face.
When he's that
pleased about something
he's gotta tell somebody, and
the only somebody he knows is you.
He's breaking into
Cuddy's home. What?
Why?
Medical reasons?
Why is he so
curious about Cuddy?
Why are you so curious
about his curiosity?
Why are you so
curious about me...
Because you dumped
him and you're married
and they are neither
of those things.
I'm just curious.
Nothing wrong with that.
No. Nothing wrong with that.
What do you think? Red thongs?
I think red thongs.
Okay, 20 bucks says I can get
through this door in 20 seconds.
You're on. Count me in.
No furniture polish, no paint thinner,
nor anything else worth sniffing.
Nothing in here, either,
except a few cockroaches.
Nice. Someone
should fix Alfredo's roof.
So, why haven't you fired House?
It's just, you guys are always
screaming at each other,
and I figure you hate
him, so... I don't hate him.
Why not?
He's a great doctor,
but any other hospital administrator
would have fired him years ago.
Four of them did.
The question is,
why did I hire him?
So, how'd you
know about her key?
You been doing a little
handyman work for Cuddy yourself?
Someone as obsessive and insecure
as Cuddy probably has three extra keys
hidden away within
10 feet of the door.
And you consider
obsession a negative quality.
Insecticide is organic.
Soap is hypoallergenic.
I got the bedroom.
This is where it all happens.
You both went to Michigan. Did
you know him while you were there?
I was still an undergrad,
but, yeah, I knew him.
He was already a legend.
So you just knew him as a
legend? My God, you're subtle.
Anything on your mind?
More cockroaches? Worse.
Beautiful.
There's no way you just
deduced where that key was.
Does this count as red?
You gave yourself 20
seconds and put money on it.
Oh, my God.
She's got pictures
of you in here.
Just you. It's like some
kind of weird shrine.
You're kidding. Yeah.
She uses super tampons.
What does that mean?
You two are just too nasty to
each other not to have been nasty.
I can be a jerk to people
I haven't slept with.
I am that good.
There's nothing here.
You ready to go, or you got
some more stuff you wanna sniff?
Whoa! Check this out.
It's fuzzy. It's
black. It's alive.
Patient's lung function's declining
rapidly. Levaquin's not working.
He obviously doesn't have
garden-variety pneumonia.
I'm glad you learned to take
his impending death in stride.
Guess what he does have. Rats.
Scars on his hand. Rat bites.
But he says they're
from construction work
so he won't have to
admit he's got rats at home.
Catholics are right. Pride will
kill you. He has streptobacillus.
Rat-bite fever.
Boogie oogie oogie. Fits
the symptoms perfectly.
That's certainly
one possibility.
But what about the aspergillus
fungus we found under the sink?
What sink? You ought to
clean your bathroom better.
You broke into my house?
No. No. You're
wrong. I had a key.
You had no right to
invade my privacy.
There was no medical
reason for that whatsoever,
and there was certainly
no moral reason for it.
Oh, damn.
You're right.
The focal consolidation makes
fungal pneumonia far more likely.
You're right I'm right.
On the bright side, it has the advantage
of keeping you totally responsible.
The treatment for
aspergillus is amphotericin.
That's hugely dangerous.
Yeah? Your point being?
Going the dangerous and aggressive
route didn't work the last time.
It's bound to work this time.
Start him on the amphoterrible.
Dr. Cuddy?
I'm Manny, Alfredo's brother.
How's he doing?
He's worried about money.
I wanna work for you.
How old are you, Manny?
Fifteen. Twelve?
I can paint. I mow lawns. I
rake leaves. I can start today.
Alfredo wants you
to finish school.
Like you care.
Manny, I've known
your brother...
He falls off your roof, and
you don't come see him once?
Bitch.
With a patient.
Not according to the log.
It's 3:15. Is it a commercial?
How's Cuddy doing?
She's not acting like Cuddy.
It's a pleasure. You know her.
She has trouble with these
situations, feels personally responsible.
The technical
term is narcissism.
You can't believe that
everything is your fault
unless you also believe
you're all-powerful.
Wow, does she sound messed up.
I don't believe I
can fix everything.
And I don't lie awake at
night, tormented by that fact.
No. You lie awake
tormented by how...
I thought we were
talking about Cuddy here.
She cares.
She enjoys feeling guilty.
Lisa cares. It's why she drives you
nuts. 'Cause it's not just a puzzle to her.
The patients are actually real,
their feelings
actually relevant.
And I'm telling her she
can't even talk to him.
My God, it's contagious.
You're feeling guilty, too.
I'm just saying, take it easy
on her. You owe her that.
From the moment I
saw you at the El...
Commercial's over.
So glad we talked.
Snap, crackle, pop.
You got some Rice
Krispies in there?
That bad, huh?
You were here yesterday.
I see from the chart that Dr. Foreman
prescribed medicine, not a miracle.
Got to give this
stuff more than a day.
I didn't fill that
Oreo's prescription.
On the theory that you didn't
trust him because he's black.
Well, I'm gonna prescribe the same
medicine and see if you fill it this time.
I'm not buying into
no racist drug, okay?
It's racist because it helps black
people more than white people?
On behalf of my peeps, let me just
say thanks for dying on principle for us.
Look, my heart's
red. Your heart's red.
And it don't make no sense
to give us different drugs.
You know, I have
found a difference.
Admittedly, it's
a limited sample,
but based on my experience
of the last 90 seconds,
all black people are morons.
Sorry, African-Americans.
I'll see another doctor.
Fine. Fine.
I'll give you the same
medicine we give Republicans.
I think the medicine is working.
They're lighter, right?
They don't look lighter to
me, Alfredo. How's the tingling?
Does not bother me.
Tell her the other thing.
He hasn't peed since yesterday.
Since last night? Afternoon.
It's not a problem.
I don't drink much.
I think we'll give you a little
rest from the meds here.
She says, "That's the medicine
that's supposed to cure me."
Just making a little
adjustment. Excuse me.
He's not making any urine.
I think we just destroyed the
kid's kidney with the amphotericin.
I think he's dying.
Dying?
Cheese it, the cops.
I guess she understands
a little English.
His kidneys are shutting down
due to the direct toxicity to
the proximal tubule epithelium.
Proof that my brilliant idea of
giving him amphotericin is killing him.
That wasn't a
complete waste of time.
His reaction shows that you
don't need to clean under your sink.
It wasn't aspergillus.
And blood cultures show he
was negative for rat-bite fever.
There's still plenty of
other cool pneumonias.
Tested negative for Moraxella,
Nocardia, cryptococcus.
He has a low titer for
chlamydia antibodies. Maybe...
No, no. His chest x-ray's all
wrong for chlamydial pneumonia.
But the titer points to...
He had an STD last year.
That explains the titer.
He has low sodium. Maybe it's
Legionella. No. His antigen is negative.
Well, that all sucks.
Maybe we were
right to begin with.
His problems are all caused by
DIC precipitated by falling off my roof.
DIC wouldn't cause
a fever this high.
See? My lap dog agrees with me.
How high?
Two hours ago it was
103 with acetaminophen.
What about on St. Alban's Day?
Only temperature I'm interested in
right now is his temperature right now.
Open up.
Okay. Let me clarify.
Open up and keep it open.
Yeah. Okay.
Under your tongue.
You're using your left hand.
Right one hurt?
No, I feel better.
What, it really doesn't hurt,
or you just figure
if you say no,
you'll get out of
the hospital sooner?
It doesn't hurt. I feel good.
You don't smell too hot.
Your hand is starting to rot.
Why are we here?
We are talking about
cutting off a kid's hand.
Yes, we're talking
about cutting it off,
not subdividing it
and putting in condos.
It's not a legal issue. Are
you being intentionally dense?
I think it's premature.
I've heard enough. What?
She says one word
and you take her side.
You should at least wait until she
actually gives a medical reason.
Otherwise I might take
it personally. Shut up.
If I were to somehow find out
that you two were in disagreement
over the proper
medical course of action,
it could make it awkward
for my client in court.
My client being the two of you.
So, guys, I'm a little busy here.
Why don't we pick this
conversation up in half an hour?
Okay?
All of his symptoms are
caused by his underlying problem
and the medicine we gave him.
What underlying problem?
You have no idea what
the underlying problem is.
You're the diagnostician.
Fine. It's all my fault.
Does that make you feel better?
His hand still has
an arterial pulse.
His hand is a cesspool.
And the crap is spreading.
You are being pretty aggressive
about destroying a man's livelihood.
I don't give a damn
about his livelihood.
He loses that hand, he
loses his job, all of his jobs.
He's not like us...
Can't work as a cripple?
He loses his home.
His kid brother drops out.
An American dream destroyed.
Very sad, very emotional,
not one medical fact in
the whole pathetic tale.
You have lost
perspective, Cuddy.
You've stopped looking
at this as a doctor.
You're acting like someone who
shoved somebody off their roof.
You wanna make things right?
Too bad, nothing's ever right.
I am happy to report
that we're now so in sync
we're actually wearing
each other's underwear.
Chop-chop time.
- Is this true?
- No. I'm lying.
It's stupid to do it with
her in the room, I guess.
This is a big
decision. We made it.
We should convene a
meeting of the ethics committee.
No!
Look, she is making a medical decision
based on never wanting to feel regret.
You're making a legal decision
based on wanting me to be wrong.
Greg, you have a
history of aggressive...
You wanted
superficial agreement.
You wanted everybody's
asses covered. You got it.
Now can I do the surgery?
Pretty, pretty please.
Lisa,
are you sure you're
okay with this?
I should be the
one to tell the family.
Your hand is dying.
The bacteria are eating it.
When they run out of food
there, they go somewhere else.
If you cut off my
hand, I'll be cured?
Unfortunately, no.
We still have to find the disease
that's making you sick to begin with.
But you won't die of
gangrene while we're looking.
I quit school when
I am 12 to get a job,
to help my family.
I know I never get a good job,
never save money or
own my own house like you.
But, Manny, he's smart.
He's the best in his class.
Well, maybe Manny doesn't have
to quit school. Maybe you can...
Are you sure I need to do this?
Yes.
Okay.
I gave one of my clinic
patients a follow-up call.
Your name came up.
I'm guessing an old black guy
who thinks the CIA invented rap music to
make your people want to kill each other.
He said you gave him
the white folks' stuff.
This is exactly why black
people don't live as long...
This isn't about race,
unless annoying is a race.
Is he not getting
better? He's fine so far.
I'm calling him back in. I'm
getting him on the right stuff.
Relax, Foreman, he already is.
I told him it was the white
stuff. I gave him the black stuff.
He was right.
You did exactly
what white people do.
You figure we don't need to
know the truth or can't understand it,
so you just lie to us.
Just a white lie.
Good one, massa.
Right, and I'm a racist.
Too bad that idiot will never know
for the rest of his long, long life.
Every slave master thought they
were doing the black man a favor.
Negro can't take care of
himself, so we'll put him to work.
We'll give him
four walls, a bed.
We'll civilize the heathen.
I'll tell you what.
Stop doing us favors.
If you're right, and we
end up back in the jungle
with lousy blood
pressure medicine,
it won't be on your head.
You okay?
You wondering if you
made the right call?
I've wanted to be a doctor
from the time I was 12.
I wanted to be a lawyer
from the time I was six
until my second
week of law school.
Sorry. Your story.
I graduated medical school at 25,
pissed off that I was second in my class.
Chief of medicine at 32, second
youngest ever, first woman...
Sad story.
If I had been
Alfredo's doctor...
You are his doctor.
I insisted on giving him Protein
C. We had to cut his skull open.
I insisted on amphotericin,
killed his kidneys.
I missed the
pneumonia completely.
I would have searched
his home and ignored mine.
I would have watched him
die trying to save his hand.
If I didn't have House
looking over my shoulder...
Are you saying you're not
as good a doctor as House is?
I'm saying House is right.
I was so anxious to get ahead.
I haven't been
a doctor in years.
His little finger is dusky.
Yeah, that's why
we're doing this.
No. I mean the other hand, the
one we haven't chopped off yet.
His O2 sats are down to 88.
His lungs are giving
out. He needs a ventilator.
And dialysis.
You're getting distracted by
the multisystem organ failure.
Pinkies are supposed
to be pink, right?
I mean, they're not
called "gray-ies".
But the organ failure
is gonna kill him.
But the pinky is weirder.
What does it tell us?
The same thing the right
hand told us before we cut it off.
- It's the same symptom.
- But at a different time.
His blood work
indicates mild DIC.
What if it's mild in the way that
when you get out of the ocean,
the water clinging to your
body makes the sea level drop?
It's technically true, but
it's completely irrelevant.
A lack of DIC would
explain everything
if there were also a lack
of anything to explain.
Endocarditis. His
heart's infected.
Little bacteria cauliflowers,
clinging to his valves.
Except sometimes they can't hold on.
They go swimming in his bloodstream.
Thursday, one breaks
off, goes to his right hand,
black fingers, gangrene.
Friday's child heads
for the kidneys.
And we all know what
Saturdays are all about.
Party with the left hand.
Also explains the fever.
It's perfect except
for the little fact
that we already
tested for endocarditis,
and he was negative.
Which means he
either is negative or...
What infection can cause pneumonia
and culture-negative endocarditis?
Prize value goes
down with every clue.
You're thinking psittacosis?
Alfredo doesn't
have any pet parrots.
Quit your squawking.
Give him doxycycline.
No! That'll just make his
clotting problem worse.
I liked you better when you were
coming up with wacky drugs for us to try.
We give him the doxy now, damn
it, maybe we can save his pinky.
He can teach his brother
to count all the way to five.
If you're wrong, he'll end
up with no hands and no feet.
Technically, if I'm wrong, he'll
end up dead, but I take your point.
What's his night job? He
cleans up at some fast food joint.
What, you think he got
it from a chicken nugget?
Since when do fast food joints
allow 12-year-olds to mop floors?
Alfredo is 20. Really?
Looks younger.
Where were you
going to work tonight?
What job do you do
on Saturday nights?
What are you doing? Wake him up.
We just cut off his hand.
Yeah. We need to talk
about it. It's not happening.
Honest, I've got no
idea what I just said.
Why didn't you say
you spoke Spanish?
Well, because she'd
wanna talk to me.
Or something like that.
She says he doesn't
work Saturday nights.
Give me the talking juice.
The fact it doesn't fit your
theory doesn't make it a lie.
When she was out of the room,
the kid brother insisted he was
gonna cover for Alfredo at work tonight.
Saturday nights he goes dancing.
Either it's a lie or he's
dancing with birds.
Give her the talking juice.
She doesn't know what
you're talking about.
Odds are it's gonna
be close to his house.
It's probably an abandoned
warehouse or factory.
Take the Scooby
gang and spread out.
What the hell are
we looking for?
Find somebody
who looks like crap.
Tell him you want
to place a bet.
It's Cuddy.
I already put him on
the psittacosis meds.
As soon as you left.
You're welcome.
What do you think the record
for one-handed juggling is?
You can yo-yo one-handed.
Good point.
I always wash my hands.
If a bird is infected, you can get
psittacosis just from breathing his dust.
But then, why do I get
sick and nobody else?
Your asthma made you vulnerable.
You're gonna be
all right now. Yes.
For saving my life.
He thanked me.
He should have.
We cut off his hand.
If we'd figured
it out earlier...
If you'd figured it out
later, he'd be dead.
I never figured it out at all.
Hello. What do you want, House?
If you're wallowing in self-loathing,
I've got something that might help.
We're getting sued.
You saved his life. He
admitted that. We'll settle.
He's got a stub where his hand
used to be. We have insurance.
Case seems pretty solid to me.
The new American
dream. Happy ending.
Kid's gonna be just fine.
Cuddy,
your guilt.
It's perverse and it
makes you a crappy doctor.
It also makes you
okay at what you do.
You figure a perverted sense
of guilt makes me a good boss.
Now, would the world be a better
place if people never felt guilty?
Makes sex better.
You should have seen her in
the last months of our relationship.
A lot of guilt. A
lot of screaming.
I know this wasn't just
because it was your roof.
Cuddy,
you see the world as it is, and
you see the world as it could be.
And what you don't see is
what everybody else sees,
the giant gaping
chasm in between.
House, I'm not naive.
I realize... If you did, you
never would have hired me.
You're not happy unless
things are just right,
which means two things.
That you're a good boss,
and you'll never be happy.
By the way, why does
everybody think you and I had sex?
You think there could
be something to it?
Cuddy feels guilty about not
diagnosing psittacosis any earlier?
I think so.
There's no way she could have.
No.
No way she could have.
It's raining.