Captioning sponsored
by WARNER BROS.
Susan? Susan?
Susan!
You have to get up.
What time is it?
It's a baby.
A baby?
In respiratory arrest.
One-year-old found
unresponsive in crib.
We couldn't get an I.V.
What did you find on arrival?
No spontaneous resps.
She's cyanotic.
Faint pulse at 200.
We scooped and ran.
What happened?
She just stopped breathing.
Has she been sick? No.
No. Any medications?
Any recent trauma?
No. Nothing.
Let's see if we can
find a vein here.
Shh!
Sinus tach 180.
Come on.
Laryngoscope.
Magill forceps.
Forceps.
Where are you?
An earring.
Hyperventilate her.
Blood sugar?
Twenty.
I'll need an 18-gauge spinal.
I'll go in interosseus.
Is she going to be all right?
I'll need dextrose.
Is she going to be okay?
Dextrose is in.
Okay, got it?
Got it.
Oh, my God!
Get a blood gas, chest
film, C.B.C. and chem seven.
She's going to be fine.
Hi.
You had an infant
in respiratory arrest
and you didn't wake me up?
You got an extra hour's sleep.
You should be thanking me.
I know, but...
We didn't need you for the baby.
Now we need you.
For what?
German tourists.
They got food poisoning
at some hofbrauhaus
on 46th.
Guten morgen.
Das ist Dr. Carter.
Guten morgen, Herr Doktor.
They need
stool wax.
Rectals?
One you've got to rule out M.I.
Two is that baby Lewis saved.
Three is some old guy
who keeps sticking
his hand up your shirt.
Four is chest pains.
Five is a kid with
an allergic reaction.
Where is the guy with the hand?
Good morning, Sue.
Morning.
Hey, Timmy, what's up?
Oh, hold please.
We've got four coming in
on a chopper, two critical.
How soon?
Five to ten.
Okay.
Hey. Morning.
Hey, Timmy.
Dr. Lewis.
Hold, please.
I got a chest pain
in Exam Room Four.
Night shift ran X ray and EKG.
You know, Timmy, I
really need a cup of coffee.
Cream, no sugar?
Yep. Thank you.
Want to help with a chest pain?
Yes.
I'll be right back.
Good morning, Mr. Zambano.
I'm Dr. Lewis.
This is John Carter.
In order to evaluate
pain, start with P.Q.R.S.T.
So, start.
Oh, great.
Provoking, palliating, right?
So, what brought on your pain?
I was in the shower,
and it just started.
And could you describe the pain?
It's like somebody
squeezing my chest.
Right.
Well, good.
Radiation.
Ah! Uh...
Does the pain move
anywhere? Neck? Back?
No. What is he, a beginner?
This is a teaching
hospital, Mr. Zambano.
Your E.K.G. is normal
your pain's subsided
and your history of angina
I don't think we need
to be too concerned.
Dr. Carter will
keep an eye on you
while we wait for your
enzyme results, okay?
It's been eight weeks.
Wait a second.
You mean, you haven't
even been out there yet?
I've thought about it.
I just haven't done it.
You and Hathaway were so close.
It's not going to get
any easier, Doug.
Just go.
Let's go.
All right. Two
majors, two minors.
Passenger space intrusion.
Guy ran a red light
T-boned a car at
50 miles per hour.
Head, neck, chest,
pelvic and right hip injury.
She's had three liters so far.
G.C.S? Point-one-one!
Pressure's 50/30. Pulse 120.
All right. Okay. Let's go.
Hurry up. Let's go.
What else you got?
Head, neck and abdominal pain.
Pressure's 65.
Pulse 150 and thready.
G.C.S... 4-6-5.
She's also got a
scalp laceration
and a deformed
right humerus fracture.
Right. Let's go downstairs
right away, all right?
We're going to
take her into Two.
Doug, take the
little girl into One.
Mommy!
Here. She's hypovolemic.
Okay. Let's go.
All right, people
we're going to do
this on my count...
And one, two, three, go.
Good.
Type and cross match
six units packed cells,
C.B.C., chem seven.
Let's get the "O"
neg moving now.
Mommy!
I need a chest tube tray.
Come on, people, let's move.
This isn't a museum.
Let's go. We got work to do.
Who else is on the floor?
Everybody's working today.
All right, call the O.R. and
let's see who they can spare.
Mommy!
Lydia, type and
cross match four units.
Positive.
Pressure's still 50
palp. Pulse's 180.
All right, sweetheart,
I want you to tell me
where else it hurts, okay?
I want you to concentrate.
All right, You hear me?
Mommy!
Okay? You hear me?
Tell me where it hurts.
Does it hurt here?
How about here?
Ow! Spleen.
Okay, we got to
get her to O.R. now!
Okay, just stay
really still, okay?
Mommy!
This the guy who hit them?
Yeah. Is he going
to be all right?
Yep.
Too bad.
We'll need blood alcohol.
Bet it's over 200.
350, easy.
Let's get a tox screen
and a C.T. of his head.
We have to rule out head trauma.
He done this before?
Five times.
Mr. Ring, we've
called orthopedics.
They'll be down in a minute
to take a look at your leg.
Are my wife and
daughter all right?
We're working on them right now.
I didn't even see him coming.
The light changed,
Janet screamed
and there he was.
We're working on your family.
Whew!
How many more do we have?
Three.
I have to check on a patient.
I'll be right back.
Whew!
Still feeling okay?
How much longer am
I going to have to wait?
Just a couple more minutes.
We are very busy today.
But you're feeling
all right otherwise?
Mr. Zambano?
Mr. Zambano!
Oh, damn! Mr. Zambano!
Hey! Hey! Hey!
I could use a
little help in here!
Hey!
Clear!
Hey! What the
hell are you doing?
Sorry.
You need help? I'm here.
Are vital signs stable?
Yes.
Sir, you're going
to be just fine.
Whew!
Pressure's 80/50. Pulse 120.
They ready for her upstairs?
All right, well, let's go.
Get ortho to the O.R.
We're taking you to
another part of the hospital
to make you better, okay?
Where's my Mommy?
We're taking care of her, too
and your daddy's
going to be there
when you wake up, all right?
Here you go, Doug.
Yeah. Thanks.
Is she going to make it?
Ruptured spleen.
How's the father?
Orthopods are doing his leg.
The driver's
sleeping like a baby.
Not a scratch on him.
How's the mother?
Maybe...
It's been eight weeks
since she attempted suicide.
You two were close.
You and Hathaway
shared a lot of things.
I stopped by.
A couple of times.
Never got out of the car.
Take her some flowers.
You don't have to stay long.
You want me to go with you?
I'm off Sundays.
That would be a good time.
I don't know. I don't know.
I'll drive.
It's me.
It's not your fault, Doug.
You got to forgive yourself
sooner or later.
Ay! Pop, pop! Just
like that, they shoot me.
For cigarettes!
Give him a gram of Ancef I.V.
No older than my grandson.
12 maybe, with a little gun.
C.B.C., chest
and shoulder films.
Little man, little gun.
15 Years
I am selling liquor
out of the same store.
Robbed seven times. Never hurt.
Nothing! Now I get shot by
sixth grader with baby gun.
Dr. Benton, you have a patient
in Two with abdominal pain
and a person in Trauma with
a stab wound to the forearm.
Well, Mr. Gregor, you're lucky.
The bullet went
straight through.
I'm going to send
you up to the O.R.
They'll explore the wound
for any serious damage
remove any dead
tissue and debris.
Work up the patient in Two.
I want a focused H and P.
And don't take all day.
I'll be there in ten minutes.
Ten minutes?!
Or less.
Hey, Doc, you like cognac?
I can get you a good cognac.
Smooth as silk.
That won't be necessary.
Cigars, then.
Cuban, maybe?
No, no, that's fine.
Thank you, though.
I don't smoke.
Dr. Carter, you
have nine minutes.
Good doctor, huh?
He's the best.
He has a low-grade fever,
slight productive cough,
postural hypertension,
and he's dehydrated.
I have to go home.
I know.
You told us your first name.
Do you remember your last name?
Uh... uh...
I have to go home.
Victor, you need to lie still.
Why don't you lie
back right here?
Hey, Malik, we might need
some restraints over here.
I have to feed my dogs.
Give him D5 N.S., 300cc's.
Do a head C.T., non-contrast.
Get Psych Services
down here for a consult.
Do a G.G.F.1.
A G.G.F.1?
"Grandpa's got a fever."
C.B.C., Chem 7, chest X ray,
U.A. and blood cultures X 2.
All right. Come on.
Give it to me quick.
65-Year-old male with severe
peripheral vascular disease
manifested by
claudication of the left calf.
He's ten days post-op
from Mercy General
after having an aorta
bi-femoral bypass.
Normal postoperative course
until about six hours ago,
when he began to
experience the gradual onset
of lower-left quadrant pain
without palliative
or provoking factors
other than a large
Mexican dinner.
Meds?
30cc's milk of magnesia.
Constipation.
Mother's maiden name?
He's joking.
Good morning, Mr. Thunhurst.
I'm Dr. Benton.
You have abdominal pain?
I called my doctor.
He isn't here yet.
Joe Arndt.
You know Joe?
No, I don't.
Is it sensitive here?
Mm-hmm.
Okay.
No rebound or guarding.
Leg is warm.
Cap refill is normal.
My leg is fine.
My stomach hurts.
Dr. Carter, what would you do?
Well, in view of his
history of constipation,
and the diffuse
nature of the pain,
I'd order a CBC, Chem 7,
U.A., Amylase and a K.U.B.
Mm-hmm. And if they're normal?
I'd discharge him.
Let him follow up with
his personal physician.
Yeah. Congratulations.
You just cost this hospital
a $2 million
malpractice settlement.
You could have a
thrombosis at the graft site
with potential
extension into the renal
or mesenteric arteries.
What the hell
is a thrombosis?
It's a blood clot,
Mr. Thunhurst.
They replaced an
artery in your leg.
Sometimes a clot
forms at the graft site.
It's unlikely, but
I'd like to rule it out.
Get him an arteriogram.
Shouldn't we wait for my doctor?
No. I don't think
that would be wise.
Let's notify radiology,
and get them
on it right away.
Thrombosis.
Uh-huh.
The mother's still in surgery.
The blood alcohol
come back at .435.
What about the drug screen?
It was negative.
There's no justice, is there?
Not much.
He's dehydrated, and has
a slight respiratory
tract infection.
The fluids helped,
but he's still
confused and agitated.
Sir... sir... sir...
I have two dogs.
Two? That's great, sir.
That's great.
Did you run a CAT scan?
Diffuse atrophy.
Nothing new or focal.
I'm out of here.
That's it?
What were you expecting?
I expected him to be admitted
to a Psych Services bed.
But he's got an infection.
He's senile, and he
needs psych support.
Now you're a psychiatrist?
I can recognize senile
dementia when I see it.
He's not medically
cleared to my service.
He has an upper
respiratory tract infection,
and he's dehydrated.
What he needs is
antibiotics and I.V. hydration.
I'll buff him up,
start the antibiotics
and pull the I.V.
Give him 2.5 Haldol
and have Social
Services do a follow-up.
I don't have a bed for him.
He needs our help.
You want me turning
away homicidal psychotics
because your patient's
got one of my beds?
Find him a medical
bed or release him.
I'm not admitting him.
End of discussion.
Whoo! Mm-mm-mm. Burn.
You fell asleep?
Oak Street Beach.
You fell asleep in the sun.
Yeah.
Can you sit down?
I don't think so.
Maybe we should just lean him
against a gurney
or something, huh?
Mark?
I passed.
The bar?
Yes!
Yahoo!
Hey! Hey!
Oh!
Yes!
She passed the bar exam.
I am so proud of you.
This is heartwarming,
but could I get some help here?
Um... Malik, can you
take some vital signs?
Sure thing, Doc.
Ouch!
Hi.
Congratulations.
Mmm.
Jen, what are you doing?
Remember the back
seat of your Celica?
Uh-huh.
Remember the trip to Hawaii.
Mmm.
Jen, you got to get accepted
to the bar more often.
Timmy, who was the car accident?
Hi, Mr. Ring.
I'm Dr. Benton.
Is my daughter out of surgery?
Not yet, but don't worry.
She's going to be okay.
We had to repair her spleen.
I need to talk to
you about your wife.
She's got a spinal fracture
and massive internal bleeding
and, well, now she
has what's called D.I.C.,
which basically means
her blood won't clot
as a result of all the trauma.
She's going to die.
Mr. Ring, did you and your wife
ever discuss organ donation?
He needs to be admitted.
On what grounds?
Change of mental status.
He's senile.
That's nothing new.
Give him antibiotics
and send him home.
He has no family.
There's no one
there to make sure
he takes his meds, to feed
him, to go to the bathroom.
That's what Social
Services are for.
They can't get to him today.
What about Psych?
Cvetic won't admit him.
He can be treated
medically as an outpatient.
We don't have the beds.
If Cvetic won't
take him, he's out.
Thank you, Timmy.
The emergency alarm's
going off.
Okay, Malik.
Grab the crash cart.
Susan, we got a Mayday.
Hi.
I, uh... I can't find
my earring.
Hi.
Your hand was on the
emergency call button
the entire time? Oh, man!
I miss all the good stuff.
I'm never going
to live this down.
Everybody thought you
were some kind of a saint.
I was going to start
calling you Mahatma.
What's going to happen
when Wertz hears?
You were with your
wife... Lucky you. Hey.
I'm chief resident.
I'm supposed to
set a good example.
Well, it's a big hospital.
Maybe Wertz won't
even hear about it.
Hey, Mark, um...
how's it hanging?
I'm a dead man.
Carter?
Doctor...
time to get up.
Clear!
I've got a rash.
Uh-huh.
I need a doctor.
Okay.
Are you a doctor?
Me?
She's got a rash.
Ah.
Can you help me?
Sure. I can try.
Pressure's 70 over 50.
Pulse is 120.
Resp's 32.
Temperature's 102.5.
Pulse ox is
only 85%.
You her husband?
Yes.
Mr. Franks, this is Dr. Greene.
What kind of
medications is she on?
I've tried to get her to
see our doctor for weeks,
but she wouldn't go.
Lasix, dig,
K.C.L., Isordil,
nitro, Captopril, Antivert,
Darvocet, Timoptic.
We need a chest film, EKG, CBC,
Chem 7, dig level, U.A.,
blood cultures times two,
blood gases, and hydrate her
with a 300cc bolus of saline.
Is she going to be all right?
We may have to
make a difficult choice
in the next few hours.
Um... we're dealing
with an impending
respiratory failure.
Please, do everything you can.
We're going to get
blood gases first,
and then we'll take
it from there, okay?
Okay.
So you're in your third
year of medical school.
Mm-hmm.
Must be hard.
It's pretty demanding.
Must be very...
hard.
Afternoon, Dr. Carter.
Oh, hi, Dr. Lewis.
Poison ivy... pretty nasty case.
I did my dermatology
rotation last fall,
so I saw a lot of this stuff.
You don't mind if I stick around
and observe, do you, Doctor?
Oh, he's doing fine on his own.
I'm sure he is.
No, sure, stay.
A Medrol dose pack
and some antihistamine
will clear this right up.
Yeah.
Remember the summer
when Jerry broke
his arm up at the lake?
And you were so worried.
I told you that
boys will be boys,
but you pampered him.
It's remarkable he turned out
as well as he did, isn't it?
Mr. Franks?
I'm troubled with the results
of your wife's blood gases.
How old is she?
Eighty-six.
Our options are limited.
Her condition is terminal.
If we put her on a respirator,
we may not be able
to wean her off it later.
We'd be prolonging her
life in a vegetative state,
or we can make her comfortable:
give her fluids, antibiotics,
let nature run its course.
You mean, let her die.
She'd die in peace.
Put her on the respirator.
Mr. Franks, are you sure
that's what she'd want?
We'll hold off
till we get another blood gas.
Hopefully, things will improve
with the nebulizer treatments.
She has 13 grandchildren.
Did you know that?
No, sir.
I didn't know that.
I just thought you should know.
So you're finally up.
What time is it?
7:30.
I must have really
tied one on this time.
I'll go get you a doctor.
Thanks.
Damn it.
Did I get busted again?
You don't remember?
No, not much.
What?
Am I hurt or something?
The policeman went
for a cup of coffee.
He'll be right back.
Boy, I must have really
screwed up this time, didn't I?
You hit a family.
The mother's dead,
and the daughter's
in intensive care.
You wanted an angiogram?
Yeah. They haven't
gotten around to it yet.
Radiology's backed up.
Thank God for small favors.
You're not concerned
about a thrombosis?
His urine came back positive.
I think his abdominal
pain is related
to a urinary tract infection.
He had a Foley catheter
during his surgery.
You don't think
it's serious, Joe?
I'll write you a prescription,
have you home
in time for dinner.
Well, that's the
same thing he said.
Excuse me, Doctor.
May I have a word
with you, please?
I, uh... I really think
you might want to reconsider.
What are you, a
third-year resident?
Second-year...
surgical resident.
Well, the next time
you want to practice
expensive, overly
aggressive procedures,
you do it on one of
your indigent patients.
They won't know
you're showing off
for your medical students.
I'll have you out of
here in five minutes.
Joe, that's great.
Thanks so much.
Right in the middle
of the reception,
she just starts
puking her guts out.
Honey, I'm sorry. I
just, just... oh, God!
There she goes again.
Compazine, ten milligrams
I.M., CBC and Chem 7.
Do you know what she ate?
I don't think she ate anything
until the reception.
Did you, honey?
Everybody had the
same buffet at Gerber's.
You're holding your reception
at Gerber's Hofbrauhaus on 46th?
That's where those
German tourists ate...
The ones from this morning.
How many guests at your wedding?
Couple of hundred.
I'll get some more
emesis basins.
She's become a
little more lucid.
Mm-hmm. Have her
blood gases improved?
PC-02's up to 70.
She's tiring.
She's getting better.
Your wife was
dehydrated, Mr. Franks.
She woke because
we gave her fluids.
Her respiratory
problem is worsening.
I'm very tired.
I know, dear.
Are you in any pain?
I'm dying, aren't I, Doctor?
No. You're going to be fine.
Mrs. Franks, you are
not going to be able
to continue
breathing on your own
for very much longer.
Do you want us to
put you on a machine
to help you breathe?
Yes, she does.
I'm asking your
wife, Mr. Franks.
For how long?
I don't know.
We've already discussed this!
No.
I don't want you to go!
Oh, I know.
Shh. Shh.
It's okay, darling.
It's okay.
A couple of hundred?
Yeah, but not everybody
had the potato salad.
Only about 60 are sick.
Man...
Oh, Connie, thank God.
I have never been so glad
to see anybody in my whole life.
Good night, everybody.
Just keep your head down, ma'am.
We'll be with you
as soon as we can.
Dr. Greene.
John, everybody
gets Compazine...
D5 N.S. I.V.s if they look
like they need it, okay?
Okay. Yeah. I'm holding. Yep.
What the hell was that?
Accordions. They moved
their wedding reception
into our waiting room. Night.
Dr. Lewis?
Yeah?
I need you.
Okay.
I'll be right back.
They found him walking down
the middle of Halsted, naked.
He was still wearing
his hospital bracelet.
Hey, Victor.
Hello.
My dogs... I have
to feed my dogs.
I know you do.
Want me to get Cvetic down here?
No. I want you to take
him to Psych Services
and check him in right now.
What if they won't accept him?
Then I'll sign him in
to Cvetic's service!
How you holding up?
I'll make it.
I'm off in three hours.
You on tonight?
No. Benton.
You should talk to
Doug about Hathaway.
It's been two months.
I did.
I even offered to
drive him out there.
Why's he acting like this?
They were together two years.
He feels guilty;
thinks it's his fault.
Well, I guess things
are better with you
and Jennifer, huh?
She passed her bar.
She was excited.
Yeah. So were you,
from what I could see.
So what happens next?
She gets a job?
She's looking.
Yeah.
Lewis?
Yeah?
What the hell do you
think you're doing?
You do not admit a
patient to my service
without a consult.
He needs psychiatric help.
Not in my opinion.
He was found naked,
wandering down Halsted.
He's senile, not psychotic.
He needs full-time care.
Admit him to your service.
Don't turf him
to mine. I tried to.
Wertz wouldn't let me.
Don't ever do that to me again.
Dr. Benton?
I'm sorry about what
happened earlier today
with the thrombosis patient.
I think you were right.
Is that so?
Yeah.
I think he
should have had the angiogram.
Great. I'll be sure
to notify the New England
Journal of Medicine
that you concur.
♪ You're the lover I
have been waitin' for ♪
♪ The mate that fate
had me created for ♪
♪ And every time your lips... ♪
♪ Meet mine ♪
♪ Darlin' ♪
♪ Down and down I go ♪
♪ Round and round I go ♪
♪ It's been... ♪
♪ Lover, the spin I'm in ♪
♪ Under that ♪
♪ Old black magic ♪
♪ Called ♪
♪ Love. ♪
She asleep?
Finally.
I'm proud of you, counselor.
Who'd have thought
I'd make it, huh?
Hmm?
I knew you'd make it.
I miss you.
Hmm.
I miss you, too.
Oh... we have to
make love more often.
The look on your face...
Well, it was a
little embarrassing.
We could pick up
where we left off.
What if Rachel wakes up?
We could stay out here.
In the yard?
Mrs. Navrocki sees us?
What if she did?
Hmm?
I have to be back in the
hospital in two hours, Jen.
I'm sorry.
You're never going
to leave, are you?
The hospital.
I don't know.
I need you, Mark.
I love you.
Hi.
How did you get...?
So let's go.
Where?
Your place.
I live with my folks.
My place, then.
Okay.
I mean, what are we there for
if we can't keep
a 75-year-old man
from wandering around
the Northside naked?
I just... I just get so frustrated
sometimes, you know?
I just... want to scream.
Well... we can't solve
all the world's problems.
That's what Wertz said.
Oh, he's very wise.
Listen, you have
to be very careful
how you deal with consults.
You can get yourself
in real trouble.
I just want to
make a difference.
Yeah, well, you also
want to have a career,
and not everybody's going to be
as understanding as I was.
Oh, yeah.
You're real understanding.
It's one of my best qualities.
Hmm...
Well, one of them.
Hello, Helen.
Can I come in?
No. You can't.
Go away.
Please.
Who is it, Mama?
I asked him to leave.
It's okay, Mama.
Hi.
You look beautiful.
How have you been?
Okay.
I just came by to
see you... to say hi.
You know?
It's good to see you.
Take care.
Dr. Benton?
What is it?
E.M.T.s are on their way in.
They think it's a
ruptured bowel.
His pulse is 140,
pressure's 60 over 40.
We've been pumping in fluids.
He's had 1,500cc's.
His abdomen's rigid,
extremely tender.
Guy says he was here today.
Something about a thrombosis.
All right, let's get a CBC
type and cross, six units.
Drop an N.G., call the O.R.
Tell them to prep
for an exploratory lap.
Let's act like we
know what we're doing.
We've done this before.
Everything's going to be fine.
On my count...
We've done it before.
Here we go: One, two, three.
Clear! Let's move, people!
Let's act like we
got things to do.
I need to drop an N.G.
Let's get a chest X
ray and abdominal.
Make it a portable.
Let's move!