Time stops when
you're in the OR.
You step up to the table,
you evaluate the patient,
you pick up a scalpel...
He's too big for that.
And then you go into a bubble.
It's just you and your surgery,
and nothing else matters,
not time, not pain,
not exhaustion.
Nothing.
Hey, just finished
my corpectomy.
Did I miss it? No, you're good.
Wow.
That was fast. What was fast?
I put out feelers with a
real-estate agent about the house,
and looks like I got an offer.
You're selling the house? No.
I don't know. Maybe.
Why do people constantly feel
the need to kill their arteries?
Are they here yet? Oh, did I
miss it? Tell me I didn't miss it.
Nope. I almost forgot.
I can't wait to see the beads of
sweat on their freaked-out little faces.
Oh, man. Did I
miss it? Nope. Nope.
I want to see someone
crap, actually crap.
Seen it, smelled it. Not
as fun as you'd think.
It's happening! The baby
chicks and ducks are here!
It happens in real life, too.
When something big
happens, something tragic,
you freeze.
You retreat into
your happy bubble...
Derek. MEREDITH: Derek.
Right. Meredith. Meredith.
For what seems like a second
until you look up.
And suddenly you realize
it's a whole new year.
Each of you today comes here
hopeful, wanting in on the game.
A month ago, you were in med
school, being taught by doctors.
Today, you are the doctors.
The five years you spend
here as surgical residents
will be the best and worst
of your lives. They will...
You have a question?
Yes. Why?
Uh, you raised your hand.
No, I'm sorry. I mean, why will these
be the best and worst years of our lives?
Uh, I was getting
to that. Sorry.
Um, where was I? Oh, right.
You will be pushed
to the breaking point.
Look around you.
Say hello to your competition.
Eight of you will switch
to an easier specialty.
Five of you will crack
under the pressure.
Two of you will
be asked to leave.
This is your starting line.
This is your arena.
How well you play,
that's up to you.
They look stupid.
They look like babies.
Were we ever that young?
They're so well
rested. And stupid.
And eager, like puppies.
No, not like puppies.
Chicks and ducks.
When did we start
calling them that?
You've been gone for a year.
Left to their own
devices, they would drown.
And take the patients
down with them.
God help us all.
They look good. Pretty good.
Some of them. I mean,
for chicks and ducks.
I'll at least get some
good ones, right?
You'll make sure I get some good
ones? Yeah. You're gonna hook me up.
Uh, listen up. This
is Dr. Edwards.
Some of you are lucky enough
to be under her supervision.
Listen closely to everything
she says. Observe. Learn.
She has the power to
mold you into fine surgeons.
Thank you, Dr. Webber.
Oh, and congratulations, sir.
Dr. Webber's getting
married this afternoon.
Wow.
Mazel tov, sir. Congratulations.
Hooray! Thank you.
Now, um, who's got Dr. Edwards?
I did not hook you up.
All right. I have three rules.
One, listen to the nurses.
Respect the nurses.
Do whatever the nurses say.
You may think you know
more than the nurses.
You do not.
Two, your life is now all about me.
- Charge to 200.
Not about you or your boyfriend...
- Charged.
Your fight with
your sister or your
nasty little rash down there.
So, when we are focused on me,
we are learning to be surgical gods.
When we are focused on you,
we're working at a gas station.
Three, no complaining.
You complain and
you are out. Got it?
You. Rules. Repeat.
Listen to nurses, worship
you, complain and die.
Good. Let's go.
Hunt. How much longer is
Richard gonna be interim chief?
Because I want to
expand my department,
and he has kind of a different
approach to the budget.
So, when are you
coming back? Uh, I'm not.
The board's gonna
appoint a new chief.
We are? When?
Why? Yeah, why?
Because I've been
chief long enough.
And it's time for
something else.
Dr. Meadows. Dr. Meadows.
Jackson. Jackson!
This is... You are
just making a mess.
What are you doing?
Oh. Do you want some?
Sweetheart, you don't have
to be here. Really, I'm fine.
I am supporting you.
I'm your maid of honor.
April said the job
of the maid of honor,
support the bride,
keep her company.
So, I'm supportin'. I'm
keeping you company.
You know, Meredith also
said that the maid of honor
drives the getaway car if
you want to make a run for it.
So, you know, you want to
make a run for it, I'm standing by.
Ready to go. Just
give me a holler.
Until then, we're
up on LA by four.
I thought April would be
with you when you came over.
Is everything okay?
Yeah. Fine. Mmm.
Well.
I know it's a challenge.
The woman that came
back from the combat zone
is not the same
girl that left here.
April has changed.
It would be understandable
if that created problems.
Jackson.
Is that Richard? Tell
me that he's here.
Tell me he's here, finally. I
told him not to go to that hospital.
We interrupt this program...
It's not Richard.
To bring you late-breaking
news from our studios
in downtown Seattle.
What's wrong?
These images are just coming in.
You know how many incoming? No.
We don't even know what
happened. But it is big.
I guess we're probably not making
it outta here in time for that wedding.
You did a lobectomy on a
dirt road? Well, we had to.
The nearest medical
center was 150 miles away.
Does anybody know what happened?
- Not a clue.
So, was it just a
24/7 adrenaline rush?
What was a 24/7 adrenaline rush?
The desert. No.
You get desensitized
pretty fast.
There's another group leaving
in two weeks if you're interested.
You're not living in a tent.
I grew up in a car.
That had doors.
We should both go. I'm
definitely not living in a tent.
Okay. Here we go.
What have we got? Mid-60s
female with crush injuries.
Massive blood loss at the scene.
We've done chest
compressions for 28 minutes.
A 49-year-old male.
Went into V-fib en route.
Shocked times three.
He had two rounds
of epi and vaso.
There are four more
ambulances behind us.
Every last one of them's
got nothing but DOAs.
What's going on? Why aren't
the ambulances unloading?
Because they aren't ambulances.
They're freakin' hearses.
All the patients are dead.
What the hell
happened out there?
A tunnel on 99 collapsed
during rush hour.
The north entrance
completely caved in,
trapping nearly 20
vehicles under the rubble.
Do we know how many victims?
They're trying to get people
out as fast as they can.
But for now, we're just waiting for
them to find someone with a pulse.
How many dead?
Thirteen fatalities so far. God.
Coming through!
We got a live one! Clear a path!
Scott Henry, 17 years old.
Penetrating trauma to the abdomen.
He arrested as soon as
we took him off the rig.
Let's get him into trauma one,
and page Karev! WOMAN: On it!
I know everyone wants to help,
but back up, give them room to work.
Dr. Karev to the ER.
We got one alive.
There could be more.
I wouldn't get your hopes up.
Three rigs pulling in now
with more right behind them.
They don't know how
many, but they'll bring
as much as we can handle.
We've got live ones
coming in, people,
and we want them
to stay that way.
We need surgical trays
by each trauma bed,
and reserve O-neg on standby!
There's always more.
Uh...
I Know. Look, I am sorry.
I was on my way to the hotel,
but we crashed the OR floor.
It was too big just to... I'm
not here to haul you out of here.
I'm here to help. I'm
looking for a pair of scrubs.
This. This is reason number 537
why you and I are
made for one another.
Surgery is sexy,
honey. It's hot. Yes, it is.
And tonight, on our
wedding night... Mmm-hmm?
Dr. Webber, I'm gonna
show you just how hot
a morning surgery
can make me. Mmm.
There are people dying.
You are so uptight
for a best man.
Now, don't worry.
You're not off the hook.
Good. I've never been
anybody's best man before.
You know they're
appointing a new chief soon.
I'm recommending you.
Unless you don't want it.
No, I've just heard you
say this once before.
About the board seat.
But then I find out it'd
been given to Alex Karev.
You're like the
chief who cried wolf.
Who's on the board
now, you or Karev?
Dr. Teller, extension 2219.
Heel, ducklings! Heel!
A 34-year-old pregnant female
with prolonged extrication
from a crushed vehicle.
Her name is Joan Paulson.
She's 40 weeks pregnant
and in active labor.
BP's 100 over 60.
She's been complaining
of severe neck pain
and an obvious
fracture of her right arm.
And who are you?
I'm Andrew. Sorry.
I was on my way into work. I
saw the collapse. I stopped to help.
We've got to go back!
We've got it from here, sir.
I'm a doctor. Actually a surgeon.
Her contractions are
five minutes apart.
Her husband's still
trapped in the car.
Let's page OB!
You've got to get Keith out!
Please, you've got to
go back and get him out!
Hey, don't you
worry, okay, Joan?
We just need to focus on keeping
- you and your baby healthy.
- All right, thank you.
That was Urban Search & Rescue.
They have a victim
they can't extract.
They need us to send a team.
Who's on the
field rotation list?
We've got Pierce,
Shepherd, Kepner, and Grey.
No, Grey hasn't
been cleared yet, sir.
I'll sub in for Grey.
And leave everything going
on here? It's a mass casualty.
Grey! You need me?
We're sending a team on-site.
You've been cleared. Go get ready.
She's still supposed to be
supervised. She had a year off.
You can't give her
special treatment
just 'cause something
bad's happened to her.
You can't spoil her
like that. The hell I can't.
Dr. Sanders, 1524.
Ow! Careful!
We're looking for our
friend! Are you a doctor?
One at a time.
His name's Scott. He's 17.
Uh, he was in the backseat
when this huge piece of
cement came down and...
He was really messed up. They
took him away in an ambulance.
We just got here. We're
not even from Seattle.
Okay. Uh, where
are your parents?
Back home. In Missoula.
They didn't come with us.
Our parents let us do stuff.
We don't get in much trouble.
We're... Dorks.
We're supposed to be
touring UW right now.
Wilson. We could use some more
hands on our kid in trauma one.
Is he talking about Scott?
He's not gonna die, right?
Is that Scott?
V-fib. ALEX: Push an amp of epi.
Charge to 150. Paddles!
Wilson, get in here and help bag!
- Clear!
Fetal monitor is
on. OB is coming.
And, we should get Ortho take
a look at her arm and her neck.
On it! Right away! My
baby. Is my baby okay?
Baby's looking just fine, Joan.
Heart rate's right on target.
Dr. Edwards, is it true that
the fetus can be compromised
if the patient is in
the supine position?
The fetus is compromised?
Out. I'm sorry, did you mean...
Out! This is not question time.
All of you just go to Radiology.
Check on the reads. I
will call you if I need you.
Where is Radiology... Scram!
The contractions
started this morning.
The doctor said we could take
our time, but I wanted to leave.
I made Keith take
that stupid tunnel!
He wanted to take the bridge,
but I said the tunnel was faster.
I'm constantly
telling him what to do.
How long have you
two been married, Joan?
We're not married.
We met each other nine
months and three days ago.
I barely knew him.
It's crazy what you
find out about a person
when you get knocked
up on the first date.
We're gonna get
married next week.
Please tell me we're
getting married next week.
Get some water over here.
Over here!
Tape, bandages, and a splint.
Will someone call my
husband? I need my husband!
- Help me! Help me!
- Okay, all right. Calm down.
- Please! Please!
- Tell me your name.
He's 10 years old.
T-shirt and jeans.
He was in the backseat? - Yes.
Ma'am, can you follow my finger?
His name is Tyler.
Stay with me, okay?
Help us.
You're the surgeons
from Grey Sloan?
We are. Where's the patient?
This way. MAN 7:
We're gonna help you.
What's his name?
Keith Gardner.
We got one. He's still alive.
My ear! I can't hear anything!
Help!
Car's been crushed by debris.
We got his wife out, but...
Oh, my God. He's in there?
He's alive? Barely.
Back on the truck.
All right, come on, you guys.
We're gonna get you
out, buddy. Don't worry.
Hey, Keith. My name is Meredith.
We're gonna get you
out of there, okay?
That'd be great.
How do we even start?
We just do.
The door's coming off!
I'm looking for my wife.
There. MAN 3: She's good.
I need some more
lap pads in here.
You got it, Doc. Here you go.
Keith, can you follow
my light with your eyes?
My fiancee, Joan, she
was with me. Is she okay?
We saw her arrive at
the hospital. She's alive.
Okay. Okay. Good. She
made it there. She's alive.
I need some packing!
Do you know we're having a baby?
Keith, we're trying to
listen to your breathing.
Stop talking, please.
It's hard to hear
breath sounds out here,
but he could have
a collapsed lung.
How's his abdomen?
Lot of blood, from
what I can see.
Keith, I'm just gonna
check your torso, okay?
He's impaled in two places.
It's pretty bad, huh?
It's pretty bad.
But I've seen worse.
Okay. Make sure you
got that crushed leg.
Call Respiratory for bed two,
and get a repeat crit on bed eight.
Thanks. ANDREW: Uh, Dr. Hunt?
Yeah? Hi. I'm Andrew DeLuca.
Oh, right. You came in
with the pregnant woman.
Yes. Is there any
paperwork I should fill out or...
You can do it later if you're good
to just jump in and keep helping.
Of course. Sure.
Oh, God, there's another one!
Okay. Keep breathing. Nice and slow.
Edwards, nice job
reducing the wrist.
Actually, Dr. DeLuca
did that in the field.
Doctor who? Me. Hi. Dr. DeLuca.
He was at the scene.
Paramedics ran out of splints,
so that's actually my tie.
Was your tie. Sorry.
It's not a problem. It was
my favorite one, though.
Oh, God! All right, 3
centimeters dilated.
I think she has a
fracture at C5-6.
What's a C5-6?
Joan, you fractured
a bone in your neck,
but it is stable for now, so we
will fix it after you deliver, okay?
Keep her in the collar
until her labs come back,
then we'll get her
upstairs so she can deliver,
- and repair the fracture.
- Got it.
Have them page me
when her contractions
become more frequent, okay?
- All right.
Thank you so much for
your help. It was my pleasure.
He's losing blood faster
than we can put it in him.
We should get him upstairs.
We need to open
his chest. Glove me.
Crack his chest and then what?
That still might not buy us enough
time to get to the OR and fix his injuries.
Then we stop time. How?
Put him on bypass,
drain out all of his blood,
and replace it with cold
saline, and then we operate.
Can you do that? No, he
can't. That's way too risky.
We put him in suspended
animation, cooling him from inside out,
his brain, his heart, his organs.
That buys us an hour or two.
Hunt! Ten blade.
Dr. Miguel...
How's it going out there?
Um, they're coming in
faster than we can treat them.
Um, listen, Catherine,
I hate to say this,
but, you know, under
the circumstances,
do you think we should
postpone the wedding?
I already did.
My assistant is notifying
our guests as we speak.
Oh.
You're sure you don't
mind? Of course I mind.
But we both know
where we need to be.
Hey, uh, Chief. We need you.
You can't just say
"suspended animation"
like it's a real thing.
It's science fiction.
It's called emergency
preservation and resuscitation.
Trauma programs have
been discussing it for years.
It's a way to save patients
who can't make it to an OR.
Yeah, a risky way,
an irresponsible way.
'Cause the safe option is to
keep transfusing him
and race him upstairs.
How do you do it?
We cannulate the aorta,
drain out his blood,
infuse cold saline,
then drop his core temp to 50
degrees. You put him in hibernation?
You replace his entire
blood volume with ice water.
You're gonna do what to him?
Get her out of here. So,
you induce hypothermia.
Hold on. We're not
gonna consciously kill a kid
over something you discuss over
beers with your trauma buddies.
Kid's gonna die anyway. At least
this way we can try to bring him back.
I say do it. No. It's
way too experimental.
And we would need
Pierce. She's at the site.
This is not a cardio procedure.
It is if you can't get
his heart beating again!
What are you gonna do if you
can't get him back after bypass?
What then?
That's why we don't do
things like this on a whim.
This is not a whim. This
is a Hail Mary. On a child?
The patient is a minor.
We don't have consent.
By the time you find the
parents, it'll be too late.
I agree with Jackson.
It's a no, Hunt.
We're wasting time
having this conversation.
Okay. We only need two
physicians to give consent. Karev?
Really?
That's how you
wanna play this? In.
Webber?
Chief?
Just do it.
I need a cannula!
Too many people have died today.
We're not adding
this kid to the list.
How's his airway?
His sats are okay.
There's definitely blood
in his chest on the left side.
Meredith, can you
get the packing in?
I'm trying.
I can't really reach
it from this angle.
Uh, I need some more trauma
pads and cellulose polymer, please.
What's going on?
Whenever I press on the wound,
blood is flowing out of his abdomen.
The metal is tamponading it,
but it's not going to last very long.
And he needs surgery soon.
If he doesn't suffocate
on his blood first.
I got to get a
chest tube in here.
Do you have access?
No. Maybe.
We have to get him out of there.
What about from the
other side of the car?
I could be your other hand.
Yeah.
Do you really think that
you can get me out of here?
I have to. You said it yourself.
You're having a baby.
Do you have kids?
I have three.
Wow, three. One
is freaking me out.
We did it backwards,
though, you know?
You meet someone,
you, uh, fall in love,
get married, have a kid.
It gets bigger, right?
Joan and I, we did
this huge thing first.
"We're, uh, having a
baby. Nice to meet you."
We're still getting
to know each other,
learning all
these little things.
It's good stuff.
She, uh, sleeps
with her socks on.
We like... We like watching
tennis... Get me a stethoscope.
But not playing.
She likes techno.
Would have been a deal-breaker,
but we got this big, huge
baby thing coming, so...
I really... I really love
all her little things.
It's like I'm home.
She's like my home.
I should really tell her that.
Right?
Come on, guys!
I got it.
I should... Hey!
Slow down! I'm sorry.
What is in your mouth?
A brie tart.
With prosciutto.
Brie? Brie!
Um, there are patients here
that had chunks of cement
fall on them during
their morning commute.
But, please, have some brie.
While carrying lab samples.
That's nasty. What's
the matter with you?
Oh. Where'd you get this?
It looks wonderful. What the...
Did you try this? I'll try that.
No, yeah. It's vegetarian.
Oh, hey, I heard Catherine Avery
had all the food from the wedding
sent here, you know, for the
staff, and I have two minutes.
How many sliders you think
I could eat in two minutes?
Is that pesto?
Do you think that Catherine's
gonna help pick the new chief?
I mean, why wouldn't
Hunt just do it?
I don't...
God, it would save
us so much trouble.
The 12-page resumes
and the phone calls
and the polite vetting and...
Who would want to
be chief? Would you?
I... Well, I had...
Are you asking?
Hunt should just do it, right?
Oh.
Those crab cakes
look really good.
But I don't want to
make a pig of myself.
Exactly what I was
thinking. Exactly.
Well, yes.
Yes, I would like to be chief.
Did you get ahold of
Scott's parents? Not yet.
We left messages. We're trying.
I mean, they should know
that you're killing their son.
I'm sorry, what? GIRL: Yeah.
We have some questions.
From our research,
we think this plan
is completely untried
and experimental.
Your research?
You're trying suspended animation
through induced hypothermia.
So, you heard Dr. Hunt.
It's basically science fiction.
It's still undergoing
clinical trials,
and there's no
documentation suggesting
that this will work on humans.
Whoa, whoa! Where
did you get this research?
Dr. Hunt, this procedure's
only been successful on pigs?
Wait, what?
It wasn't successful on humans?
It hasn't been tried on humans.
They've started trials, but
they have no outcomes. Not yet.
Core temp's down to 55.
Where are you getting this?
Those kids. His friends.
You said there were
techniques that were developed
and the studies were published.
The animal studies have
had incredible success.
And the technique
has to start somewhere.
I can name 30 soldiers this
technique would have saved.
So, you want to try it
on a high-school kid
without parental consent?
You better pray this works.
Even if we resuscitate him,
he could end up brain-dead.
His core temp's down to 53.
It doesn't matter now.
We're doing it. We've done it.
So, either get on board
or get out. Karev is right.
Anybody who doesn't
want to be part of this
is welcome to leave.
I'll stay.
We're there. Core
temp's 50 degrees.
Okay. He's cold.
We have an hour, 90
minutes tops. We ready?
Start the clock. Scalpel.
I said no. I know what you said.
If anything goes
wrong in that OR,
it jeopardizes our
entire surgical program.
It could be the boy's only hope.
I don't need you to defend
the technique to me, Richard.
I need you to follow orders.
Orders?
I'm an owner in this
hospital. I am, too.
But I'm also the
chief. It's my call.
You mean interim chief.
That boy had no chance.
We're giving him one.
I don't feel bad about that.
Now, if you'll excuse me,
I have another surgery.
We can't tell where Keith
ends and the door begins.
If we use the Jaws
of Life to get him out,
it'll rip him to shreds. He'll
bleed to death in seconds.
What about trying an ex-lap?
Then we can try to separate...
We're not sterile.
There's no blood bank.
This is not a
controlled environment.
I know. I know. I know.
We could put a balloon
catheter into his aorta.
It could buy us some time.
If we were closer
to the hospital,
I would say maybe,
but we're 25 minutes out.
He'll never make
it. Okay, what if...
He's a black tag, guys.
We can't do
anything else for him.
Then I'm calling it.
We're gonna cut him
out. Maybe we'll get lucky.
You should go.
No, we can stay...
I'll stay. You go save
people that you can save.
I'll do what I can for him.
Okay, Keith.
We're gonna cut you
out of there now, all right?
Sure thing.
Uh, Joan, Dr. Edwards asked us
to take you to the OR now. Okay?
And we can do that, because
we know exactly where that is.
I knew our first day
would be intense.
I figured we might get to
watch some stuff or start an IV,
but there was a
mass casualty today.
I've never seen so
many mangled people,
so many dead people.
Doctors from this hospital
just spent hours in the
field trying to extract a guy.
Hours. That's gonna
be us some day.
Did they get him out? The guy?
Huh? Oh, no, I don't think
so. I heard he was too far gone.
Can't breathe. So,
they just left him there?
Got it. I can't breathe.
I can't breathe.
Let me out. What?
Okay. Is it the
collar? I need this off.
I need to get out.
Okay. I can loosen it.
Not much, but maybe
a little. I need to get out.
- Should you do that?
- They left Keith.
They left Keith. He's gone!
No, don't!
There's a shock through
my body. What's happening?
We need to stabilize her spine.
Um, help me reduce
her dislocation.
I'll hold her steady and
you attach the tongs.
What, me? Yeah, I got her. Go.
If we hurry, maybe we can
save her from total paralysis.
But I can't.
I mean, I could try, but I
don't think it's the best idea.
What do you mean? Just
attach... I don't know how to do it.
Why? 'Cause I'm just an intern.
Okay? Today's my
first day. I was late.
I was on my way here. I
saw the tunnel collapse.
What? You're an intern?
Maybe if we...
It wouldn't have worked.
Yeah. No.
He didn't have a chance.
It was the right call.
Huh.
What?
What'd I do?
Wiggle your toes for me, Joan.
I can't. I can't feel anything,
not even my contractions.
- What did you do?
- Am I paralyzed?
We're working very,
very hard to prevent that,
but I need you to stay
calm. Can I do something?
You can go stand over
there with the interns, intern.
What the hell happened in here?
She dislocated her fracture
at C5-6. I'm decompressing.
Okay. Baby's got decels.
I'm getting the
first 5-pound bag.
How the hell did she dislocate?
She was having
trouble breathing.
I thought it was the collar.
Get out!
Okay. I need to get
this baby out of here.
Let's get her up to the
OR. All of you out now.
So, if this works, they're
gonna do this in the army?
Absolutely. We should go.
We should take a
year, do the program.
We'd spend our time doing
things like this all the time.
It would be amazing.
You're in the middle
of your residency.
I'll take a research year.
We could have an adventure.
I'm not looking
for an adventure.
Oh, crap. OWEN: What is it?
It's an infrarenal
IVC injury. Damn it!
How long's it gonna take to fix?
I don't know. About 30 minutes?
We don't have that.
Okay, he can live
without it. Just ligate it.
Got it. O silk ties.
There was a mass casualty today.
They needed us back
here at the hospital.
I know, but maybe
there was still something
that we could've... We
did everything we could do.
Why are you second-guessing?
I'm just saying that maybe...
I was willing to try an ex-lap.
Oh, my God, would you shut
up about the stupid ex-lap?
That is not the point! - No.
No, the point is that maybe
we should have stayed.
Maybe we didn't try everything
we possibly could have to save him.
We were all there.
We all saw that car.
And there's a difference
between knowing
when you can
realistically save someone
and when it's time to walk away.
And when is that, Meredith?
When is that point?
When do you look at
a horrible, sad situation
and decide that you are ready to
turn your back on it? I'm curious.
I'm curious how you
make those decisions,
you specifically.
When are you
okay making the call
that someone no
longer has any chance?
How do you look
around and decide that?
When do you decide that
you should walk away?
Dr. Shepherd? Dr. Edwards says
she needs you in trauma two right away.
I'm Dr. Shepherd.
Oh, sorry.
Dr. Edwards says she
needs you right away.
She wasn't...
They need you upstairs. Go.
Core temp's 98.6 degrees.
- No pulse.
Heart should be beating by now.
We're way over
time. The IVC repair...
- He'll come back.
- Come on, Scott.
If we lost him...
What the hell did you people do?
We put him in hibernation,
and we're bringing him back out.
Are we?
Okay. Let's get him off bypass.
We got a heartbeat.
The boy's reviving.
I'm thrilled to hear it.
I made the right call.
Talk to me when we see
what kind of brain
function he wakes up with.
Thinking like that would have
left that boy dead on the table.
I can assure you
that your successor
will be nowhere
near so cavalier.
I'll make certain of that
when I choose the next chief.
Oh, when you choose? Well,
it's not up to you, Catherine.
It's a board decision.
We'll see about that.
You can't just come in
here and think you can...
I don't need you to tell
me how this hospital works.
I've seen plenty of that today.
Dr. Thompson to Oncology.
I'm sorry about leaving
the patient there.
I didn't want to leave
him there, either.
And I am sorry for not
talking to you about the house.
You don't talk to me
about a lot of things.
And you're mad at
me for going away,
and I am sorry about
that. That's not...
I mean, I couldn't
breathe. I couldn't exist.
You know, I looked
around at that house,
and my kids, our kids.
I couldn't breathe.
You didn't call me.
I didn't call anyone.
I needed time.
I am a neurosurgeon. I
could have saved him.
And you didn't call me.
Amelia...
Who contacted you first?
The police? The paramedics?
How far away was the hospital?
How long were you sitting there
waiting for them to
declare him brain-dead?
How many hours later was it
before I was even informed?
How many chances did you have
when you could have called me?
Why didn't you call me?
There wasn't anything
you could've done.
He was too far gone.
You don't know that.
You don't know. Yes, I do.
What if I could've helped
him? What if I had a chance?
I pull off miracles
for a living.
I have proven that I can
reverse the impossible.
I should have been there.
If I had seen him or
treated him... It was too late.
By the time they...
It was too late.
How could you do it?
How could you unplug
him without letting me know?
I didn't get to see him.
I didn't get to
tell him goodbye.
I thought you would've at least
given me the courtesy and the respect
when my own brother was dying.
I didn't get to
tell him goodbye.
Because of you.
Damn it!
Hey. Sorry about the wedding.
Oh, no. It was the
right idea to cancel.
Postpone you mean. Right?
The odds aren't in
my favor, Miranda.
You know, I've
tried this before.
And failed.
Twice.
Well, it always comes
between choosing between
the woman and the work.
And when pressed, I...
You choose the work.
Yeah. You'd think I'd
learn at some point.
Sounds like you have.
You just need
to be okay with it.
But with Catherine and me,
it's already been a problem,
and it's still gonna
be a problem.
I'm not sure I want to go down
the road if it's gonna go nowhere.
Carefully. Carefully.
Okay. All right. You're
doing great, Joan.
Deep breaths.
What is it? Talk to us, Joan.
I feel something. In my fingers.
Okay. Good.
That means the
traction's working.
And in my toes!
Oh, thank God. I can
feel my legs again.
Oh, my God!
Oh, my God. I
can feel everything.
Oh, my God!
She's having a contraction.
All right, Joan.
Joan, I know it hurts, but
you have to keep still, okay?
We need to prevent your
neck from dislocating again.
You were right today.
I was taking a big risk.
You were lucky
today. Really lucky.
I understand.
Is Kepner back
yet from the tunnel?
I don't know.
I don't know much
about her lately.
She's different
since she came back
from her training with you.
And I'm glad that she found
something that makes her this happy,
I guess.
But it's weird.
We're just not on the
same page anymore.
Ever, it seems.
It happens. More than you think.
You go away, you come
back. The world has shifted.
Things that made sense
once don't anymore.
You heard that I'm
resigning as chief?
Give her time.
That's all you can do.
That's the face you're
gonna make? The kid's alive.
I don't want to have this fight.
What fight? This fight.
This "I told you so" fight.
This thing where this
insane surgery works,
and then you get
back on this army thing,
and then I tell you you're not
going, and then you get pissed.
You're gonna tell me
what I can and can't do?
You do that, I'm gonna
be more than pissed.
You know what? Screw
it. You want to go, then go.
What's your problem?
It sounded interesting.
And for a minute, I thought
it could be something that
we'd do together. Why not?
I have worked
really freaking hard
to get to where
I'm at right now.
I have finally found my
place, and it's at this hospital
doing this job
with these people.
Alex, I'm... Last year was crap.
And now Mer is home, and I
finally feel like things are back.
I don't need to go
anywhere. I don't want to.
I've put roots down here.
I've never put roots
down anywhere.
I'm not walking
away, not from this.
If you want to go, then
go. I can't stop you.
It's your life. Do what you
want. Go join the freaking army.
You're almost there,
Joan. Almost there!
Uh, hey, guys.
Okay. She's crowning.
She was only 6 centimeters.
I need to... I need to
push one more time.
This baby's coming now.
Edwards, hold her steady.
Occupied! Occupied!
Dr. Guillaume. Dr. Guillaume.
Hey.
I needed to ask you
something, but I didn't want to
because I knew you'd say yes.
Then don't ask.
I went away. I pressed
pause on my life.
And I really needed that.
But since I've been back,
I just... I can't unpause.
I just can't get
things going again.
I go home every night
to my house and it's...
It's not my house. It was
mine and Derek's house.
And now he's gone, and it
really just feels like a house.
I came back, but I'm not home.
And I really want to be home.
Can the kids and I come
and stay with you for a while?
Yeah. No big deal.
Well, you better check with Wilson
because you know how she gets.
Trust me, I don't need
to check in with Wilson.
No.
No. Well, then
explain it to me again.
When did this happen?
Mom, how can you say that?
Okay. You're doing great, Joan.
One more big push and
that should do it, okay?
I can't... I can't
do this. I can't.
He's supposed to be here
with me, with us, and he's gone!
Joan, we know it hurts, but we
need you to keep going, okay?
The head's out!
How do you step
back into the world?
Joan, you did great.
Keith was supposed
to cut the cord.
He was supposed
to hear the first cry.
Hold your baby.
Everything is fine.
Mom, say hello to your son.
It's scary.
This isn't how it's
supposed to be.
It's not part of the plan.
Keith should be here.
Keith should be here!
Hi, baby. MEREDITH:
Time stood still...
Mom, I have to go. I have, um...
Uh...
Goodbye.
And now it's speeding by.
ER? Yep.
I thought we'd
seen the last of it.
You are looking for a lifeboat.
You okay?
Yeah. Yeah, I'm fine.
Something to give you hope.
But are you really ready
to leave your happy little
bubble and step back out
into the big, blinding,
bloody, terrible world?
I stopped them from
trying to extract him.
I couldn't watch him
bleed out. You were right.
You said if he were
closer to the hospital,
he might have a chance.
So, let's give him a chance.
Are you ready to
achieve the impossible?