- Previously on The Resident...
- Today is the day
we introduce 3B Life
to the American public.
It's only a matter of time
before the board
realizes that you
swiped an opportunity
from underneath them.
- What do you want?
- A healthy percentage of our
growing supplement business.
I loved my sister very much.
The grief and guilt consumed me.
Emotions can enrich our lives,
but they can also destroy us.
I want you to be my
baby's godmother.
There was only one person
I wanted to hear me speak,
so I imagined that
person was there.
Dr. Pravesh, have you ever
saved a princess before?
You're fired. I don't
know who I am right now.
I don't know who I'll be if I
can't be a doctor anymore.
Mina, these intervals
look good to me.
- Second opinion?
- Agree. QT isn't prolonged.
Great. Azithromycin it is.
I am writing you a prescription
for five days of an antibiotic.
You can pick it up at the
mobile pharmacy outside.
- How many people have you seen?
- 18 or 19.
We have to see them
faster. I just looked outside...
The line's even longer
than when we got here.
Where are they all coming from?
Mountains, remote farms, towns.
It's a medical
dead zone for miles.
No hospital anywhere nearby.
It's hard to believe we're only
three hours outside of Atlanta.
But here we are.
I wheeze all the time.
Show us how you
use your inhaler.
Let me teach you how
to do that the right way.
No more spinning.
Thank you, that...
is that like some kind of yoga
or tai chi or something?
You're like some sort of guru.
Yeah.
They were able to
make your glasses.
I can read the sign.
- How do I look?
- Perfect.
That baby took a three-hour nap?
You have to tell me
how to make her
do that at night.
- Thank you.
- I'm going to propose
to my new nanny.
- Not what I expected.
- Um, why isn't Conrad here?
Do not tell him
I said this, but...
I miss seeing his
face at Chastain.
I know. Me too.
But Search &
Rescue just called him
for a last-minute mission. So...
Oh.
Search & Rescue,
that's very funny.
It's not for you.
- We found a lost kid
up in Sweetwater.
- Oh,
right. Your volunteer work.
Nic's volunteer work.
My volunteer work.
We're all volunteers.
Uh...
Look, I'm sorry about all this.
I-I just... I didn't see
the "no parking" sign,
it's-it's stupid, and I got a
ride share app on my phone,
but now my credit card
doesn't work, I... Well...
Family, no apologies.
Come on. I'll get you home.
Ah, this is my patient. Hold on.
Hello?
Dr. Hawkins, it's
Archer Loggins.
I wanted to thank you.
You've helped me and Adelaide
so much these past couple years.
Well, that's my job, Archer.
Is everything okay?
You'll stay on as
Adelaide's doctor, right?
- Keep an eye on her?
- Of course.
- Why you asking me that?
- Oh,
uh, no reason. No reason at all.
Just take care of her.
I know she's in good hands.
Thank you for all you've done.
Archer, what's going on?
Where are you right now?
This is Archer Loggins.
Leave a message.
Is everything all right?
I think my patient
might hurt himself.
We have to go check
on him. Let's go.
Oh. Well, look at
that. I didn't know
doctors still made house calls.
I got your address from a
friend in medical records.
I hope that's okay.
- Oh, sure.
- Archer called me,
he didn't sound like
himself, Adelaide.
Can I come in and
speak with him?
I want to make sure he's okay.
Of course. He's
taking a little nap.
The MS makes him tired.
- Hi, Kyle Nevin. Chastain angel.
- Come on in.
Pleasure to meet you.
Archer, hon? I have
Dr. Hawkins here.
He wants to say hello.
Why is this door locked?
Archer, open the door.
We've never locked that
door. Archer, answer me.
We need to break in
and check on him, okay?
- No. No, no, no, no...
- It's okay. It's okay, Archer. What did you take?
Call 911. Tell them we have
attempted suicide by overdose.
- The pills, Archer. I see oxycodone.
- I didn't take any yet.
- I swear.
- Archer...
♪ ♪
I got sneezed on. Twice.
And I'm 70% certain
that the puddle I just
stepped in was not water.
Oh, it's the ER. The
puddle is never water.
Embrace the gross.
Dr. Pravesh.
Nadine.
It's good to see
you again. Wh...
- What happened here?
- I'm, like,
the third Emory DJ
with one of these.
Someone set up a
new overhead shelf
in the sound booth.
I stood up too fast,
forgot it was there. Bonk.
Did you lose consciousness?
Any, uh, changes
in vision, confusion?
Mm-mmm.
A head bonk brought
you to the ER?
With your medical history, it
was smart of you to come in.
Nadine was recently
diagnosed with moyamoya
and had a cerebral bypass.
Okay. Look straight
ahead for me.
Pupils equal,
round and reactive.
Follow my finger.
So far everything looks fine.
She doesn't even need stitches.
Nadine, does your head hurt?
No, but could you
admit me overnight?
To be safe?
Why don't we start by letting
Dr. Dreyfuss finish your exam,
and you staying in the ER
a little while for observation?
Great.
Then I can spend
the day observing you.
Um... okay, but
there might not be
anything interesting
to observe. I'm just...
Well, I mean, there's that guy.
- Andrea.
- Hey.
- So, what do you got there?
- Samples of our new supplement.
And since Chastain is a partner,
they're letting me
set up a display.
- Andrea.
- Hey.
I didn't think we were setting
up the 3B displays today.
I know. The supplements
came in earlier than I thought,
so... surprise.
Sweet Mother of God. Y'all were
on that STV program.
And you are more
dashing in person,
if it's even possible.
I swear, I saw
that handsome face
come across my TV,
and the next thing I know,
$30 disappeared right
out of my checkbook.
- Can I get a picture?
- Oh, sure.
You don't mind, do you, hon?
'Course not.
The ladies at the book
club are gonna flip.
Cheese.
The ambulance is
- on its way.
- I-I don't need an ambulance.
- I didn't take any of the pills.
- Archer, this is
an interrupted suicide attempt.
Legally, you need a
full psych evaluation.
I never should have
had the surgery.
You have MS. You fell
and fractured your spine.
You were in pain. You
needed the operation.
But the bills.
The cost... It...
it's catastrophic.
Too young for Medicare,
too much money for Medicaid,
and our insurance deductible
is... so high.
We're already maxed
out on what we can pay.
And then, after the surgery,
this arrived.
Chastain used an
out-of-network anesthesiologist
who charged $15,000?
Did Chastain make you aware
of the out-of-network cost?
No. But we thought
that it was a mistake.
We couldn't pay that,
so Red Rock sued us.
What now? W-We go
bankrupt? And now my wife
- is going to be homeless
because of me.
- Shh.
- No, no. Come on, Arch.
- Don't...
You are not ending
up on the street.
I have life insurance.
- Archer...
- Enough to cover all of this.
I would rather live in a shack
with you by my side.
Uh, the ambulance is here.
No, I'm not gonna go.
Who's gonna pay
for that ambulance?
We've known each other
a long time... you know
I'll do everything
in my power to help.
But right now we need
to get you to the hospital,
and that is
nonnegotiable, my friend.
Hey. Keep an eye him.
Hey, Jen.
No meds. No restraints.
He'll come out
willingly. You just...
- What happened? He
had a gun in the drawer.
He pulled it out. He
pointed it at his head.
I tried to grab it from
him, and it went off,
- and it hit him in the stomach.
- Adelaide, put pressure here.
- Kyle, grab his legs.
- What?
- Grab his legs.
- Where are the paramedics?
After gunfire, they can't
come in until the police
get here... that's the law,
so we go to them. Let's go.
Let me guess,
you've been taking unregulated
colloidal silver supplements.
For how long?
Uh, over a year.
Well, that's why you're blue.
It's called argyria.
It's rare but it happens.
When did your
skin start to change?
Uh, it was a while ago.
It started off a
little light gray,
but then it just kept
going from there.
You know, I read an article
that said it would cure everything.
What needed to be cured?
Exhaustion. Sore joints.
The silver was supposed to scrub
all the toxins from
my blood, but...
this morning I could
barely crawl out of bed.
Well, we'll start by
running some tests, okay?
Just curious: when you
first went from gray to blue,
you didn't think, "I might
have a bit of a problem here"?
No. I thought it was cool.
Andrea Braydon.
Uh, Dr. AJ Austin.
Cardio-thoracic surgery.
Why do doctors always
name-check their specialty...
Is it so people will know
how important you are?
Well, this job is an extension
of our personality, so it just
seems natural to mention it.
And yes, it's so
people will know
how important we are.
What you got there?
Uh, 3B Life. It is a
revolutionary dietary herbal
and energy supplement.
Of course. So you are
Bell and Cain's new partner.
They're the new
partners. I'm the founder.
So now who needs
to feel important?
You want a sample?
My supplement can decrease
your risk of heart attack.
Oh, my heart is a specimen.
Improve your mental acuity.
My mind is at the
top of its game.
Increase your stamina.
Please.
Okay, right.
Tell you what, if you
change your mind,
give me a call,
I'll hook you up.
And if you don't
change your mind...
you should still call me.
Okay.
Unless you're spoken for.
Thanks.
- Oh, my God. I don't want to be here.
- Come on.
- You know what,
I said I didn't want to go.
- Come on, come on. We're coming.
- And besides...
- Come on. Joyce!
Last ones. You two are lucky
- you made it in time.
- Mm.
Four hours of back roads,
and with that one driving,
we're lucky we didn't
fly off the mountain.
- Stop it.
- So, which one of you is Joyce?
That one. I'm Bianca,
but this isn't about me.
My sister hasn't
seen a doctor in years.
- If it ain't broke, don't fix it.
- All right.
Well, let's check you out.
Deep breath in.
Lungs sound clear.
Mm-hmm. Told you.
What's that?
That is a ventricular
assist device.
Yeah. That's my VAD right there.
When my own heart went to crap
five years ago, they cut me open
and put it in.
This powers the machine
inside me so it can pump blood.
You know, like hearts
do when they're not crap.
I'm basically a
battery-operated woman.
Saved my life.
Why is it beeping?
Oh, must need a battery change.
Hold tight. I'll find 'em.
No, you won't.
They're on the counter at home.
I...
told you to put 'em in the bag.
Wh-Where's your hand pump?
That's at home, too.
Where's the nearest drugstore?
I can run out and
grab batteries.
A drugstore won't
carry that kind of battery.
We need a hospital or
the device manufacturer.
I'll call Life Flight, see if
they can arrange a chopper.
Maybe a local VAD
patient has an extra.
What-what if Bianca's
battery runs out?
Then I die.
Two VAD patients in the
area... Neither are answering
their phone, and Life Flight
doesn't have a free chopper.
The manufacturer has
batteries, but they're not local
and can't get them here in time.
The nearest
hospital is Chastain,
- three hours away.
- So this woman
will die because we're too
far from a friggin' battery?
Don't forget the
portable ultrasound.
Already in with
the VAD batteries.
Go. I'll text you
the coordinates
of the clinic van...
With any luck,
- you'll meet them there halfway.
- So if we
- don't hit any red lights...
- You'll have a chance
to get the new
batteries into your patient
before she dies. And, Mina...
- Ready?
- Okay, we're leaving. Thank you.
Drive safely.
Whoa, whoa. Uh, you ever
get any speeding tickets?
- No.
- Then I'm driving.
Gunshot wound in the abdomen.
80/50. Heartrate: 140.
We got to get him to the O.R.
You know we have to
take this from here, right?
Hey. We got him.
I promise.
Dr. Hawkins, please go
with him. You're his doctor.
I can't.
Wow, look who's back.
- Oh, you look great.
- Oh, thank you.
Oh.
My hair's still growing
back, so hence the wig.
- Oh.
- Yeah,
but at least I'm clear
for work, in theory.
Well, Chastain's
made a few changes.
There are two new scrub
nurses. We're looking for a third.
So you won't be working
any more double shifts.
Yeah. Doesn't look
like I'll be working at all.
I'm not on any
surgeon's schedule.
Well, word probably hasn't
gotten around that you're back.
Mm-hmm.
Or...
your colleagues just
want to ease you in.
Or... no one trusts me
in an operating room,
because my brain is, um...
Oh, like in a-a skillet,
a-an egg...
Your brain is not fried.
- Yeah.
- That's normal.
You're gonna have trouble
finding words for a while.
You're recovering
from major surgery.
Do you have any
trouble understanding
words that are spoken to you?
No.
Then you are ready.
And you'll be with me
today. Put her in six.
No. No, no, no. You don't
have to do that just to be nice.
Ask around.
Nobody's ever accused
me of being nice.
I'll see you in the O.R.
Bowel is torn to shreds.
Mm, close-range bullet.
No surprises there.
Lap pad.
At least no major
vessels were hit.
Lucky guy.
So you thinking
colostomy here, or...
Oh, I hope not.
That'd be a disaster
for this man.
He already has MS.
That's enough to deal with
without a colostomy bag.
Do you need the...
Retractor.
Yes. Perfect.
Why couldn't Dr. Hawkins
go with Archer?
Because he doesn't
work here anymore.
He doesn't? Why not?
The hospital let him go.
People are very upset.
They've got to be insane.
When do we hear
from the surgeon?
As soon as the
operation is over.
I don't understand...
how this happened.
How could I not see
that he was planning this?
What kind of wife am I?
Adelaide, I...
I-I don't know your husband.
But I do know one thing.
You didn't see any of this
because Archer didn't
want you to see it.
We always told
each other everything.
He was protecting you
because he loves you.
And he blames himself
for all this trouble that
you're both in, and...
So he feels ashamed.
I'm sure that he's
been racking his brain
trying to find any
way out of this,
any way to live out
his life with you and...
still make sure
that you're safe.
But he just couldn't
find any other answer.
Any way to save the
person that he loves...
and stop being a burden.
If someone is
desperate enough...
the worst solution in the world
starts to look like a
pretty damn good thing.
Says take a left here. Now.
I-It's louder. Wh-Why
is it doing that?
That's the VAD system telling
us that more battery has drained.
How much longer do I have?
15 minutes.
Maybe half an hour.
Then it will go to
the backup battery,
- and another 15 minutes.
- Where's the ambulance?
It's saying we're
still 52 minutes apart.
If we both go faster,
we can still make
it together in time.
This is my fault.
I didn't need to see a doctor.
Stop that. They're my batteries.
They're my responsibility.
I forgot 'em, and...
here we are.
Pay attention, Joyce.
Social security numbers.
Bank account passwords.
Um, the combo for
the lock on my bike.
I know nobody rides
it, but just in case.
In the left-hand drawer
in the laundry room
are the appliance warranties
and also the instructions
for the remote control.
I guess you get to
watch your game shows
every night after all.
Joyce.
All this time...
Your heart,
the batteries.
I thought I was
taking care of you.
But you've been
taking care of me.
We've been taking
care of each other.
All right, here's
where I keep the gold.
Wha... Gold?
I'm kidding. But I do have
that jar of pennies in the pantry.
The ambulance that's meeting us
better have its sirens on.
Can I have a word?
Absolutely.
I need to tell you something.
It's a little awkward.
Randolph Bell.
Used to be CEO, now he's not.
Used to be chief of
surgery. That's all done.
The guy can get
his hands on the ball,
but he can't keep it in the air.
That hasn't been my impression.
- What's your point?
- Don't get me wrong,
Bell's a decent salesman,
and the company will be fine,
but... it could be
more than fine.
I can help increase
revenues exponentially
through better marketing.
You shouldn't have to
waste your valuable time
with that penny-ante stuff.
I'm having dinner
tonight with an investor
from a major advertising firm.
You should join us.
Sounds promising. Count me in.
I'll do that.
Adelaide said you were out here.
The surgery was a
success. We repaired enough
of the bowel, he
won't need an ostomy.
So he will recover.
Well, there's no
cure for the MS.
And he'll need treatment
for his suicidal depression.
He won't be able
to pay for any of that.
Do you know why he shot himself?
- No, I don't.
- Mm.
Chastain billed him for an
out-of-network anesthesiologist
and then added on over
100,000 in unspecified charges
that his insurance can't pay.
And then, just to kick
him while he's down,
Red Rock sued him.
I won't bill for my
surgery today, and...
- Thank you. That's a start.
- And as for
the rest of it, I'll
see what I can do.
You know, what Red Rock
did to you was not right.
Well, they haven't
treated you so well, either.
What can I do for you?
Archer's my patient, and I'm
not even allowed to see him.
Nothing's filling that void.
Where's the ambulance now?
It's been in the same place for
three minutes. Traffic, maybe?
We're still 30 minutes away.
It says "backup battery mode."
- No! No, no, no.
- It's okay.
- That means 15 minutes left. Keep driving.
- Joyce...
- Drive faster.
- Joyce!
I got five years
out of this machine.
Bonus years I wouldn't have
had if it hadn't been for you
taking care of me
through the operation,
and after.
They were good years.
Thank you.
Pull over.
We still might be able
to reach them in time.
Math says we won't. Pull over.
Bianca, we are not
giving up on you.
Everyone in this van knows
the same thing: it's over.
You know where I
don't want to die?
The back seat of a van.
When I go out of this world,
it's gonna be under the blue sky
with the sun on my face.
With my sister.
Clara's down the road.
She'll wave down the ambulance
that's carrying the battery.
Be straight with me. This is it.
We all know it can't
get here in time.
There's still a chance.
Nic, listen.
I don't want any heroics.
No CPR that could break my ribs.
I promise.
Thank you.
What'll it be like
when it happens?
Uh...
well, the...
the battery will stop,
and, um, you might
feel a little dizzy.
And then you'll
close your eyes and...
it will feel like
falling asleep.
That's good.
Peaceful.
That's how I want it.
We know
you did everything you could.
Now, shoo.
I want to do my dying alone...
with my sister.
I love you so much.
The battery's less
than ten miles away.
- That's too far.
- So we keep her alive
until it comes.
- We can't do that.
- We can. If she's
not down for long...
Mina, stop.
She doesn't want
a violent death.
Jessie.
That moment outside her room...
When it was happening and
there was nothing I could do.
At least this...
We can let Bianca
go the way she wants.
That we can do.
It's slowing down.
Battery's running out.
I'm glad it's sunny today.
It's pretty.
Quiet.
She gets to hold
her sister's hand...
while she dies.
At least they have that.
Uh...
I'm actually not dead at all.
She's alive!
- Oh...
- Oh, my God.
My heart's beating.
- What?
- Well, that's different.
I'm definitely not dead.
Well, unless this is...
No, this can't be Heaven.
I mean, it's nice here,
but there should be,
like, a river of ice cream
and a field of roses
and Chris Pine.
Her pulse is strong and regular.
The VAD must have given
her heart time to repair.
Now that the VAD stopped,
her heart is working again.
How you feeling?
Let me guess: method actor
prepping for his Blue
Man Group audition.
Ooh! Smurf superfan.
Patient information is private.
I'm so tired of rules.
Nadine, what's really going on?
I hit my head. That was real.
But when I got here, I
was happy to see you.
You probably think
this is silly, but...
most people act all weird
because I'm a princess.
With a guard always around,
I'm never alone, but...
But you're always lonely.
You understand me.
I still can't keep
you here overnight.
But...
maybe there's
something we can do.
To be clear, now that
I'm not dead, I take back
that thing I said about
your game shows.
I can live with that.
Cardiac function is sufficient.
Did I even need the
VAD in the first place?
Yeah. The VAD saved your life.
And then once it was in you,
it gave your heart
enough time to heal.
If that battery hadn't run out,
we never would have known.
Now that there's no blood
running through
the VAD, it's clotting.
We need to get
her to Chastain now.
- Get the gurney.
- I'm gonna call ahead
to book an O.R.
- What's wrong?
- We need to get the VAD out.
There's a clot,
and if it dislodges,
it could be bad.
You mean my sister could die?
This time for real.
The gunshot guy
was exciting, sure,
but five people with sniffles,
a princess looking for love,
and a blue guy who
caused his own problems...
I mean, come on.
Wait, why are we out here?
Seems like you need
a break from the E.R.
Tell me, Ezra, why do you
want to go into anesthesiology
after intern year?
Fascinating
physiology. High stakes.
Life and death every day.
What else?
To be honest, great hours.
And I like patients
who can't talk
because they're asleep.
Do you have OCD, Ezra?
What? No, I do not.
That's absurd.
I've seen you pick
at your buttons,
double-check your
stethoscope's in your pocket,
check your phone
a billion times.
Fine, I-I'm... I'm a
control freak, okay?
I also check the lock on my door
ten times before bed.
I buy pillowcases in bulk
because I need a
fresh one every day.
I get up in the
middle of the night
to make sure the
stove is really off.
But that's because
I'm super careful.
If you're an anesthesiologist,
that's a virtue,
because you can't
make a single mistake.
I respect super careful.
So why don't you take another
look at Blue Billy's scans.
Fusion of the vertebral bodies.
Bamboo spine.
Mix with long-term chronic
aches and pains, you get?
Ankylosing spondylitis.
An autoimmune
disease. Very treatable.
Ezra...
the desire for perfection,
checking things
again and again...
All your patients need that.
Let's go give Blue
Billy the news.
It's a manageable condition.
We'll get you set
up with a specialist,
and your pain will be
under control in no time.
And everyone said the
pain was in my head.
It's why I took the silver.
Hey. How long before
the blue fades away?
Um...
never.
I'm sorry.
Awesome.
Eh.
I've put in hundreds of VADs,
but I've never taken
one out for this reason.
Hmm.
Bianca's ventricle is clear.
Now I will repair it.
Pledgeted Prolene.
It's funny.
The liver is the only organ
that can regenerate itself,
but the heart...
It can repair.
Evolve.
Adapt to meet its circumstances.
You're poetic today.
Yeah.
I guess I am.
Ready to take her off bypass.
Let's see how she does
on her own, shall we?
Hmm.
Her heart is strong and healthy.
All on her own.
And yet another Hollywood ending
to an Austin-Okafor
medical story.
It almost wasn't.
I really thought Bianca
was gonna die on that road.
She said everything she
needed to say to her sister.
She was at peace.
Also, it's an...
Okafor-Austin medical story.
Second billing.
I'll take it.
This time.
What would you say?
You know, if you knew
it was your last hour?
I don't know what I would say.
But I do know
the person I would say it to...
is you.
Our relationship
is one of the most
important ones in my life.
It is perfect.
Just like this.
Well, like I said in there,
the heart can adapt.
So you have a good night,
Mina Okafor.
Hold on, where
are you taking her?
For a quick scan.
No visitors allowed.
We're not really going
for scans, are we?
Nope.
Is your car ready?
I can take you to pick it up.
Oh! No, I think I'm gonna
walk out to the impound lot.
It's not too far away.
I need the exercise.
A little time alone
with my thoughts.
That was one hell of a day, hmm?
You're a hero, you know?
If you hadn't jumped
in to stop Archer
from shooting
himself, he'd be dead.
No, man, I was supposed
to keep an eye on him.
He should never have gotten
to the gun in the first place.
- That's on me.
- I think you should give
yourself a break.
Hey,
why don't you come
over to our place later?
I'm tired.
- Thanks, though.
- Come on,
we'll order some pizza
with Nic. It'll be fun.
- I'm fine.
- You sure?
I think you could use it.
My ass just got fired, so...
I know I could use it.
Uh, not tonight.
Thank you.
This is the best
scan I've ever tasted.
I guess I just had a case of...
trapped-with-a-guard-itis.
They didn't teach
me that in med school.
Mm.
You know, I wanted
to be a doctor.
Really?
Yeah.
I really liked the idea
of helping people.
But my parents put
the kibosh on that.
Not a life for a princess.
My life is very controlled.
Look.
This is the front
of my apartment.
What do you see?
That's a camera.
Over there, an alarm.
And this one,
another camera.
The whole place is like that...
Alarms and cameras everywhere.
They look like they're
there to keep enemies out,
but, really,
they're keeping
princesses caged in.
Well...
you're free-range now.
For a short time.
Thank you.
I'd like to see you again.
Yeah.
Please.
You're not gonna make
the first move, are you?
I'm at work. I...
♪ Baby ♪
♪ I was way past
the point of saving ♪
Don't worry.
I got you.
♪ But you didn't
try to save me ♪
♪ You just let it
be, called me up ♪
♪ Say, "Let's go get a drink" ♪
♪ We don't even
have to say a thing ♪
♪ But we talked a while ♪
♪ 'Bout our dreams ♪
♪ Our lives, our saints... ♪
♪ How you like
to hear me sing. ♪
They told me you were waking up.
Welcome back.
I have missed you.
- Michelle.
- Shh.
She's perfect.
Beautiful.
Strong. Growing every day.
She has... chubby little legs.
Ten fingers and toes.
Excellent lungs.
Especially in the
middle of the night.
Look.
Of course.
I'm not home, so now she sleeps.
You took good care of her.
Damn right I did.
For your information,
I am her godmother.
I... I am great with babies.
At least this baby.
There was a learning
curve, but I mastered it.
Ah. Here she is in the
outfit your cousin sent.
♪ ♪
Why is she making that face?
That's her pooping.
Sorry I'm late. I was just
pulling everything together.
- No worries.
- Manufacturing specs,
my first quarter projections,
new marketing ideas.
Sorry, um, I'll wait
for your investor.
Um, he actually just called.
His kid's sick.
He can't make it.
But maybe that's
for the better. I mean,
after all, if we're gonna
be working so closely,
we should get to
know each other.
Um,
business partners
should understand
each other's mind-sets, yes,
which is why I wish you
would've given me a heads-up
about the change in plans.
We'll make do.
A bottle of Sancerre
is on its way.
It's dense, delicate, flavorful.
Or if you prefer a cocktail,
I can...
Uh, I'm so sorry.
A friend in crisis.
It's a sick cat.
You understand. I
have to deal with this.
We'll reschedule.
- Your timing is impeccable.
- That's funny,
I get told that a lot.
♪ ♪
Wow. What's the occasion?
We both had a hard day.
I figured we could
use a distraction.
♪ I want to live ♪
You're the best
distraction I've ever seen.
- You're not so bad yourself.
- Mm.
♪ Ooh, baby ♪
Just so we're clear,
you're my one-hour person.
If I had one hour left to live,
I would want to
spend it with you.
I will take it.
♪ Oh, baby, baby ♪
♪ Thanks to you ♪
♪ Only you... ♪
But don't die.
Here you go.
Yup, have a good one.
- ♪ All I want to do is,
all I want ♪
- ♪ All around me ♪
♪ All I want to
do is, all I want ♪
♪ Everything's changing ♪
♪ All around me ♪
♪ All I want to do is ♪
♪ All I want to do is be alone ♪
♪ Write a song by myself ♪
♪ Lose my phone ♪
♪ Be someone else ♪
♪ Be someone else,
be someone else ♪
♪ Be someone ♪
♪ All I want to do is be alone ♪
♪ Be alone. ♪
Captioned by Media
Access Group at WGBH