When I was on
the COVID ward, I felt like
I was a part of something.
I'd like to feel that again.
The study's
exclusionary criteria
weed out a lot of patients.
I'd like to help.
The, uh, transfer to Arizona
came through.
You can't just take Anna
a thousand miles away
without discussing it
with me.
Dad, I don't wanna
go to Phoenix!
We really want to end up
in court over this?
I thought it was over
for us today.
Yeah, me, too.
You're good to go,
Dr. Halstead.
Booster in two weeks.
Thank you.
Will, good morning.
Morning. Thank you.
Pretty exciting day, huh?
I have to admit, I got
a little teary-eyed
walking in here.
After all these months...
Yeah, I know.
Finally, feels like
we're approaching
the other side of this.
Dr. Virani?
And not a moment too soon.
Morning, April.
Good morning.
Welcome back, Noah!
Hey.
Missed you around here.
How was the research rotation?
You know, it wasn't too bad.
Kind of interesting, actually.
Uh-oh. We losing him
to the bench?
Oh, no. I need him
where I can see him.
So, what's up with you?
Fresh cut, white coat.
What, big promotion,
or a girl?
Neither. I'm just trying
to step it up a little bit.
Look a little
more professional.
He is the co-PI on
a new clinical trial.
Okay, big time.
I'll catch you two later.
Leaving the little people
behind?
And I thought I was
a light sleeper.
Hey.
So, you slipped out on me
this morning. Didn't scare
you off, did I?
No.
I had to come in early,
catch up on some charting.
Thought you could
use the rest.
My place tonight?
We'll see.
Choi, Marcel, we got
two victims incoming!
Elderly couple found
unconscious in their home.
Both tested negative
for COVID in the ambo.
Phyllis Coleman, 68-year-old
female. Found pulseless
at the scene.
Compressions started
in the field, three rounds
of epi in the ambo.
We'll take her to Three.
Where's the husband?
Right behind me.
James Coleman,
69-year-old male,
obtunded but rousable.
BP 128/78. Pulse 110.
Any idea what
knocked 'em both out?
Gas leak.
Home reeked of sulfur.
Okay, what about this?
Looks like he fell out
of his chair after he
lost consciousness.
Here we go, on my count.
One, two, three.
All right. Lungs are clear.
Mr. Coleman! Can you hear me?
Maggie said you might
need some help.
Wait, is that Dr. Coleman?
You know him?
Guy's a legend.
Founded the largest free
clinic on the South Side.
That's right. Read about him
in the Trib.
Dr. Marcel, he's barely
protecting his airway.
Sexton, set up a nasal airway.
There we go.
Welcome back, Dr. Coleman.
What's going on? Where am I?
There was a gas leak
in your home. You and
your wife were brought here.
Phyllis. Where's Phyllis?
Yes, she's here.
I just need you to relax
for a moment.
Okay, no. I need you
to lie back down, okay?
Listen. Dr. Sexton's gonna
go check on your wife,
all right?
But I need you to just
stay calm for me, okay?
What's Ms. Coleman's status?
Couldn't revive her.
She's gone.
I'm so sorry.
No! Phyllis! Me! Take me!
No, Dr. Coleman, no.
All right. I need you
to take a deep breath.
No.
Sats are down to 88.
Shouldn't his sats
be coming up?
Yeah.
Maybe he aspirated?
Don't know,
something else is up.
All right. I'm intubating.
Let's go.
A hundred of sux,
20 of etomidate.
Come on! Laryngoscope!
Coffee for Charles?
Listen.
You're talking about
this morning, right?
Can you leave it
for a minute?
I'm at work.
I'm moving out.
Good morning.
Hey.
Ooh. You bought me a coffee?
Of course I did.
They spelled your name wrong.
Daniel?
You stole
somebody's coffee?
I left him five bucks.
He's an old friend of mine.
At least,
it's the way I like it.
I guess it's your lucky day.
Uh... Not so much.
Michael pissed me off
this morning, so, now,
he's sour with me.
Been back to work
one day, he's already
apartment hunting.
Huh.
I told him, I said,
stay put with me,
build a little nest egg.
You know, he's been
quarantining with me
since March.
You know,
what's a few more months?
What?
I don't know.
He's a grown man, right?
It's probably
a point of pride.
Please. I know Michael.
This is what he does.
He makes
impulsive decisions.
I'm all for him getting back
on his feet, but the ground's
got to be sturdy.
Fair enough.
Anyway, what's your day like?
Office hours?
Yeah. And, um,
mediation with Susan.
You mean she's really
serious about taking Anna
to Arizona with her?
Oh, she's serious.
And how does... How is Anna
taking this thing?
I mean, parents at odds...
Kids can feel like
they have to pick sides.
I think she's fine.
Yeah. She's fine.
And what were you
and lover boy
chatting about
this morning?
Crockett?
Yeah.
I was just asking
his advice on a patient.
Come here.
Okay.
I slept with him last night.
Nat! How was it?
It was good. It was fun.
Um, but before you
say anything, okay,
I am under no illusions.
I know Crockett's reputation.
I didn't think that was
your vibe, though.
It's not, but he's
got like this...
No! This other side to him.
All right. Okay.
Look, maybe I'm okay
keeping it casual.
All right?
Okay.
Anyway, enough about me.
How are you? How is Auggie?
We're supposed to get
his Heredity & Me
results back soon,
and see if he has
any relatives that
are willing to donate.
Man. That kid is so lucky
to have you in his corner.
You know that, right?
You really are
unshakeable, Mags.
Mmm.
Ugh.
I got my "highly encouraged,"
aka mandatory session
with Dr. Charles today.
Mmm. Fun.
Ugh.
Nat,
be careful. I don't want
to see you get hurt.
Thanks.
See, Mr. Booker, I thought
I told you
you were not allowed
back here.
Any excuse to see that smile.
Mr. Booker was my patient
in the COVID ward,
and he kicked COVID's ass,
so, he's not going anywhere.
Mr. Booker, hi,
I'm Dr. Halstead.
You're experiencing
some shortness of breath?
Yeah. Been totally bushed
these last few weeks, too.
Mmm-hmm.
Sure, it doesn't help me
working overtime.
The wedding, you know.
You getting hitched?
Me? Oh, no. But my daughter,
she's hopeless.
Too many romantic comedies.
Lean forward for me,
would you?
Huh.
What? Is it my lungs again?
I do hear some crackles.
It means you have fluid
in your chest.
Oh, God, this is what happened
before, right? With the COVID.
No, your swab was negative.
You don't have it again.
Is there some kind of
long-term damage? I thought
this was behind me, damn it.
Look, let's just let
Dr. Halstead run a few tests
before we get ahead
of ourselves, okay?
Now, Mr. Booker,
you just relax. We'll have
answers for you soon.
Sexton,
how's Dr. Coleman doing?
Oh, yeah. Just extubated him.
He's stable and resting.
Any of the tests up yet?
Affirmative.
Was just pulling them up.
Oh, wow.
Yeah. Explains why
he was decompensating
even after they removed him
from the home.
It wasn't gas poisoning.
Nope.
Hey, Dr. Coleman?
How're you feeling?
Anything we can do
to make you
more comfortable?
No.
Just wanted to say again,
how sorry we are
for your loss.
We'll let you rest, but while
it's still fresh in your mind,
is there anything that you
remember from this morning?
Not really. I just remember
sitting down in my chair.
And I must've dozed off.
I guess that's why I didn't
smell the gas.
Listen, can I go home soon?
I need to start
making arrangements
for my Phyllis.
Yeah, of course.
I understand.
But, uh,
before we can let you go,
we need to discuss
your blood work.
We found an extremely
high level of benzos
in your system.
Any idea how they got there?
Dr. Coleman?
This wasn't supposed
to happen like this.
Lisa wasn't supposed
to find us until tonight.
Lisa?
Phyllis' caregiver.
I hired her when Phyllis
was diagnosed with ALS.
See, Phyllis was terrified
of ending up paralyzed
inside of her body.
She made me promise
that I wouldn't
let it happen.
But when the time
came to help her,
I knew I had to go, too.
You see, we come here
together from Jamaica.
Nineteen years of age.
I can't live
without my Phyllis!
So, if Mrs. Coleman
died of a drug overdose
and not gas poisoning,
then what about the gas leak?
It was just a coincidence?
Dr. Coleman created the leak
to protect the clinic.
He didn't want the way
in which they died
to negatively impact
the work they're doing
in the community.
Wow.
All right, thanks, guys.
I'll take it from here.
Wait, what do you mean?
I'll notify PD.
Oh, PD?
What? No!
Noah, I have to.
Maybe we could, uh...
What? Sweep this
under the rug?
Guys, we have a confession.
And in the eyes of the law,
this was murder.
It was assisted suicide.
Not if she didn't
put the pills
in her own mouth.
She couldn't.
She was incapacitated.
Which means
she couldn't consent.
And, besides, you know
assisted suicide
is illegal in Illinois.
Yeah, but she did consent.
She told him this is
what she wanted
years ago.
And they even
considered moving to
a state where it's legal.
I'm not passing judgment.
That's not my place.
But I have to
protect my staff.
If I don't report this,
we're obstructing justice.
Hold on,
this wasn't murder.
It was an act of mercy.
I'm sorry, Noah.
So, you and Ben
have had... You're having
quite a first year.
Mmm-hmm.
I mean, taking in Auggie,
and then, now, COVID.
I mean, that's a lot.
Actually, I think it's only
brought Ben and I closer.
That's good.
I mean, that's great.
I'm sorry, Dr. Charles.
Sorry to be wasting
your time,
but I don't think
this is for me.
I'm a Lockwood woman.
We handle things.
We don't spend a lot of time
sitting around and just...
Talkin' about your feelings.
My mom had two jobs
when my dad
was in grad school,
also while raising three kids
and caring for her parents,
both of whom
were wheelchair-bound.
Really?
Sounds like
a remarkable woman.
She was.
Look, Mags, I know that
this first one was mandatory,
but I'm here.
I mean, there's no shame
in unloading.
I do it all the time.
Thanks, I'll keep that
in mind, Dr. Charles.
Am I dismissed, Doc?
I want to make sure
the ED isn't on fire.
You are dismissed.
Thanks.
Why does he always have
to be such a hard-ass?
Look, I'm the first one
to give Ethan
a hard time when he's
being too rigid, but...
Don't tell me
you're on his side.
All we asked him to do
was look the other way.
But now, that he's chief,
I think
that's a bigger ask
than you realize.
To be continued.
Yup, I see it. All right.
Hey, Will. Did you
get Mr. Booker's
test results back yet?
I did.
I'm sorry, April,
he's in heart failure.
What? He cannot
catch a break.
First he beats COVID,
now this?
The truth is, the virus
may have actually caused,
or at least exacerbated,
the problem.
What about your
clinical trial? Can...
So, I thought about that
already, and unfortunately,
Mr. Booker's serum
creatinine is just above
the eligibility cutoff.
He doesn't qualify.
Thank you
for looking into it.
If you don't mind,
I'd like to break
the news with you.
Of course.
Let's go.
Dr. Manning.
Anna? Hey.
Owen was just asking
about you. He misses
having you babysit.
Yeah, me, too. Um, listen,
can we talk in private?
Of course. Let's go upstairs.
Does your dad know
you're here?
No, and, um, I'd really like
to keep it that way, please.
Okay. Let's go.
Okay.
So, how can
I help you, Anna?
Is everything okay?
Are you okay?
Yeah, I'm fine.
Um,
there's nothing like that.
I'm not in any kind
of trouble or anything.
I just...
Um...
I need birth control.
Okay, um...
Do you mind if I ask
why this is such
a covert operation?
'Cause of my mom, really.
I brought it up
to her once,
and of course
she shut it right down.
She doesn't even want me
to have a boyfriend,
much less... You know.
But what about your dad?
I'm sure he'd be
really happy to know
you're being responsible.
No, I do not want to talk
about it with my dad, yeah.
Me and my boyfriend,
we're ready.
You know, I just
want to be prepared.
Listen, I think it is great
that you want to take
precautions, and I do
want to help you.
This is the part
where you say, "but,"
you need
my parents' permission,
or something?
No, but after I take
your medical history
and your blood pressure,
I do need to run
some lab work.
Okay.
And that will trigger
your parents' insurance.
All right. Forget it,
I'll just figure
something out, it's fine.
You know, Anna, wait, look.
This is a big step.
But if you're sure,
you do need protection.
So, I'll run the labs
off the record.
Thank you, Dr. Manning.
How about
the possibility of
working remotely, Susan?
I'm leading
an entire department.
I have to be there
in person.
Daniel, what about you?
Is there
a custody arrangement
you'd feel
comfortable with,
that still allows Susan
and Anna to make the move?
Look, I'm not crazy about
disrupting Anna's school year,
but the real issue
is seeing my daughter.
It's why we made
an agreement to live within
100 miles of each other.
And I get that,
but life happens.
I can't pass up this job.
What about my job?
I mean, with my schedule,
flying back and forth
every other week,
it's unfeasible.
It's been about your job
for the last 20 years.
Look, it comes down
to a simple choice, right,
either Anna moves with me,
or you get what you want
and you successfully
derail our lives.
I'm not trying
to derail anything,
all right?
It is in Anna's best interest
to have us both around.
Yeah, but when it
comes down to it, Daniel,
Anna needs me
more than she needs you.
The facts only,
let's avoid opinions,
please.
Okay, okay.
The fact is
that I've been doing
the heavy lifting
when he's been MIA.
When are you going to
get tired of beating
this deadbeat dad drum?
I've always been
a solid presence
in Anna's life,
and you know that.
I'm telling you, Daniel,
if you try to sabotage this
for me,
you will see a side of me
that you will not like.
Oh, I will see.
Classic.
Doesn't get what she wants,
and she disappears.
It's what she does. See?
I feel for the old man.
I actually went to that clinic
when I was a kid.
So, what happens now?
I've been in contact
with the state's attorney.
Flight risk isn't a concern,
so you do what you need
to do for him here.
Once he's ready for discharge,
we'll have to book him.
All right.
Hey, Trini,
mind giving us a sec?
I'm really sorry
about the police.
If it had been up to me...
It is what it is.
It's part of the job.
I know that.
Also, I, um...
I wanted to say thank you.
You're actually
a big part of the reason
I became a doctor.
Your clinic had this,
like, traveling tent
you'd pitch in parks
around the South Side.
Every Saturday morning.
One of those mornings,
my dad and I were kicking
around a soccer ball,
and you managed
to coax him inside.
He hadn't been
to the doctor in years.
His blood pressure
was sky high.
You made him promise
to follow up with his GP.
They found a pheochromocytoma
in his adrenal gland.
If you hadn't have gotten
that cuff on him...
You give me
far too much credit.
No. Your clinic
saved a lot of lives.
All praises go to my Phyllis.
Phyllis gave up everything
so that she could
help build it with me.
I only wish I could've
held up my end of the bargain.
What do you mean?
What you did for her,
it took courage.
I was a coward.
I couldn't let her go.
Even when I knew it was time.
I guess
this is my punishment.
My living without her.
There you are.
Hey.
So, has that "we'll see"
turned into a "yes" yet?
I'm sorry, Crockett. Um...
I don't think
tonight's gonna work.
Did I do something wrong?
No.
You sure?
Because now, I'm getting
the distinct vibe that
you're blowing me off.
I'm sorry, I don't
mean it that way.
I think I just need
a little space to think
about some things.
Okay.
Will.
Great news.
I looked into Mr. Booker's
medical records,
and it turns out, he's always
had high serum creatinine,
but never showed
any signs of reduced
kidney function or disease...
Yeah, it's just part of
his natural physiology.
It's well-documented
that black men often have
higher serum creatinine,
even when their
kidneys are functioning
perfectly normally.
Which means
that shouldn't preclude him
from joining
the clinical trial.
You're not jumping for joy.
Listen, April,
the exclusion criteria
aren't exactly flexible.
Why not?
The criteria are designed
to protect the participants
and prevent
any adverse effects.
If Mr. Booker's kidneys
are functioning normally,
he shouldn't be
at any greater risk.
Yes.
But it's also imperative
that every participant
meet the same qualifications
in order to protect
the data...
"Protect the data"?
I'm sorry.
At whose expense?
Tell me,
what percentage of your
participants are black?
I don't have
the numbers offhand, um...
Yeah, I think around 3%?
Only 3%
because of biases like this.
And yet, we are 30%
more likely to die
from heart failure.
April, I'm sorry, I just...
I'm not sure
what you want me to do.
Nothing, apparently.
Just like everyone else.
Hey.
I'm just texting
my boyfriend.
He said it's so cool
that you're gonna
help us out.
Um, why don't you
take a seat.
Okay.
So, uh, after getting back
your initial test results,
I'm afraid that, um,
birth control would not be
recommended for you.
Why?
You're pregnant.
What? I...
How could this happen?
Ryan and I
only had sex once. I...
It's okay.
There's got to have
been some kind of mistake.
Can you run the test again?
I ran the test twice already.
Okay, it's possible that
the condom you used broke,
or maybe it wasn't
put on properly.
God, no, no, no.
Anna. Anna,
look at me. Hey.
This is a lot to absorb
on your own.
Now, might be a good time
to loop in your mom and dad.
No. You cannot
tell my parents.
Listen, I cannot and
I won't share any information
without your consent,
but I do want you to
seriously think about it.
God.
Look, there is
some information
I want to get you.
I'll try not to be
too long, okay?
Hey, how's Dr. Coleman?
Think he's ready
to be discharged?
Nope.
What's the rush?
Come on, Noah.
Don't make this
personal, man.
Oh, personal?
We still got to take care
of Dr. Coleman's head lac.
All right. I'll let PD know
he'll be ready
within the hour.
Sorry, Noah, but it's out
of our control now.
Dr. Marcel,
everything okay?
Yeah, um...
Listen, let's, uh...
Let's go ahead and stitch
him up now, gotta head home,
personal matter.
If you need to go,
I've got Dr. Coleman.
You sure?
Of course.
Thanks, brother.
Draw up lidocaine with epi.
You know,
I need a bigger suture.
I'll grab it.
No, no, I'll get it.
I know what I need.
I'll be right back.
Okay.
No, Dr. Coleman!
No! Ow! Dr. Sexton!
I'm sorry, he grabbed it
before I could...
What's going on?
He's in v-fib.
No pulse.
Doris, charge to 200.
Noah, get on his chest.
What the hell happened?
He grabbed the syringe,
injected himself
with 10 CCs of lidocaine.
Charged.
Clear!
He's asystolic.
Amp of epi. Resume CPR.
Ethan...
I said resume CPR.
Where's that epi?
It's coming.
Epi's in.
Hold compressions.
Come on.
It's time to call it.
Time of death, 16:52.
Walk me through it again,
from the beginning.
I told you.
I set down the syringe,
went to grab the suture
and when I turned...
You set it down
within arm's reach
of a suicidal patient.
A patient with
the medical knowledge
to know how to use it.
It was a mistake.
You gotta write me up.
I get it. Go ahead.
I know you.
I taught you, Noah.
You don't make mistakes.
You sympathized with
Dr. Coleman, didn't think
we should call the police.
You did this on purpose, man.
What were you thinking?
Dr. Coleman had the right
to die on his own terms.
Man, come on, Ethan.
You really think
he deserved
to rot in prison?
It doesn't matter
what I think.
The minute
you called the police,
you buried him.
You think
it was easy for me
to make that call?
Yeah, it sure
seemed like it.
Just stop, man.
This isn't about me
or Dr. Coleman anymore,
don't you get that?
Now, when the police
walk through that door,
I'm gonna have to
tell them what you did.
You got a second?
Yeah, come in.
Sharon, do you know
a good family attorney?
Oh, the mediation
went that well, huh?
Afraid so.
I'm sorry, Daniel,
but, yes, I actually do.
Peter Kalmick's husband.
I really don't want
to go down this road,
you know, but, um...
You exhausted all of
your options, you gotta do
what you gotta do.
I remember when Anna,
she first moved back
to Chicago,
you know, it took
a little adjusting.
I mean, I don't need
to tell you, I can be
a little set in my ways.
"Cemented"
is the word I'd use.
Right. But now,
when I have her,
it's like we found
this little, uh, routine.
Mmm.
I pick up the takeout,
she sets the table...
On a rare occasion,
even though it can be
like pulling teeth,
I actually get her
to tell me about her day.
Now, when I think back
to my old life...
Mmm. Seems empty now.
I don't even know what
I used to do with myself.
I know a thing
or two about that.
Yeah, I bet.
So, who picks up the takeout,
you or Michael?
I cook.
He does the dishes.
Sounds like
a pretty nice setup.
Anyway, um,
you reach out to Peter for me,
just give him my number.
Sure thing.
Great. Thank you.
Hey, Doris.
It says in Mr. Booker's chart
that you gave him fluids?
Yeah, Dr. Halstead
put in the order.
He said he suspected
dehydration.
But his electrolytes
were normal.
Mmm.
Okay.
Oh, April, good.
Just about to come find you.
I re-tested Mr. Booker's
serum creatinine, since it was
so close to the cutoff.
Yeah?
Yeah, it turns out
the initial test was wrong.
He's within
the acceptable range.
He's gonna join the trial.
You gave him fluids
to dilute his creatinine.
You gamed the test.
I know it's not
the overall fix
you were looking for.
It isn't.
But with the next one,
we will get it right,
I promise you that.
Thank you, Will.
No, thank you.
Noah. Noah, what's wrong?
Yeah?
Oh, hey.
Maggie,
Ben's on the line.
Oh. Okay.
I'll take it over here.
Hey, honey.
Oh, really? That was fast.
Oh.
No, no, no.
No, I'll be fine.
I should get back to work.
Yeah, love you, too.
Bad news?
Yeah, Auggie's
Hereditary & Me results.
They didn't turn up
any relatives.
Oh, Mags.
You'll find a way,
you always do.
You're the strongest woman
I know.
Would you stop?
I'm not invincible.
Or whatever it is
that you think.
Mm...
Ethan, you know
the stakes for Noah.
He could lose his residency,
his medical license,
maybe even face
criminal charges.
Noah should've thought
about that before he acted.
Even if he did
what you suspect,
what if he felt it was
an act of compassion?
It is not worth
destroying everything
that he has worked for,
everything you helped him
work for.
I understand.
He's put you
in an impossible position.
But...
But what?
Lie to the police?
I can't.
Please. Please.
If you won't do it for him,
do it for me.
All right, seems like the team
did everything they could.
I got everything I need.
Anything else
I should know, Dr. Choi?
No. That's the account.
Copy that.
I think we're good.
You're fired
for negligence.
What?
You won't get reported
to the medical board,
and you can file
for a new residency
somewhere else.
No. Ethan,
just wait a second.
Don't...
If it had been anyone else...
Chocolate bar for dinner,
Dr. Charles?
Been that kind of day.
You?
I got some bad news.
Sorry to hear that.
But it's fine.
It's going to be fine.
Don't give me that look.
What look?
That thing we were
talking about this morning.
I think I wear
my strength like
a badge of honor.
Something passed down to me.
From your mother?
And her mother,
and her mother's mother.
Navigating through
this world as a woman,
a black woman.
Hmm.
You get a thick skin.
Necessary armor.
But it sometimes also feels
like it's an expectation
that people have of me.
Like I'm not allowed to
have a vulnerable moment.
A heavy burden
to carry, Mags.
It's just, I don't...
I don't want to let
anybody down,
and I don't want to let
that little boy down.
I know.
Noah, stop it. Okay?
We will figure something out.
I'm gonna help you fight this.
No, you're not.
Because I'm not
gonna fight it.
Noah.
I stand by what
I did today, April.
And if I have to go up
against Ethan,
I'll end up having to lie.
I don't want to do that.
You have worked
so hard to get here.
Hey, maybe
the change of scenery
might be good for me
and you.
Ever since we were kids,
you've always
had my back, April.
As long as I'm here,
you're always gonna
feel responsible for me.
So, what now?
Remember Dr. Kantwell,
our med school advisor?
She always said she can
get me into a residency
program at her hospital.
Isn't she in Atlanta?
You're just gonna
up and leave?
I'll be back.
Figure when I finish,
maybe I'll go work
for Coleman's clinic.
Try to pick up
where he left off.
Okay.
I'm gonna miss you.
I already miss you.
Hey.
I thought I was
picking you up.
Uh, I got dropped off.
Listen, can...
I really need to talk
to you about something.
Yeah, sure.
Dan, hey, I hear
you're looking for
a child custody lawyer.
I'll call you tomorrow, okay?
Uh, yeah, sure. Sorry.
Sorry about that, honey.
So, what did you
want to talk about?
Nothing.
You sure?
Yeah, no, uh...
It wasn't important.
Well, let's get
out of here.
Yeah.
Okay, what are we doing, Ma?
Michael, wait a second.
About this morning...
Look, Ma,
I really don't want
to get into it again.
I already said my piece.
Yes, and I hear you.
You do?
Yes.
I still don't think
it's the best decision
financially...
Yeah, you made that
very clear.
But the truth is,
that wasn't
my primary objection.
Son...
I've gotten used
to having you around.
Mom, I'm only moving
a few blocks away.
I know, but the thought
of coming home at night,
and you not being there...
Is that what
all this is about?
You missing me?
Okay. All right.
I'm gonna miss you, too, Ma,
okay?
Hey.
Oh, come on, get off me.
You know, when I moved in,
I swear we were
gonna kill each other.
But quarantining with you
hasn't been half bad.
You better
not be a stranger.
I'm gonna be by plenty.
You know you keep
the good wine.
That's right.
Take me home.
Yeah! All right.
Natalie?
Hi.
Here, come in.
Okay.
Listen, you should know...
No, before you say
anything, um, I just...
I wanted to say that earlier
when I said I needed space,
it wasn't about you.
I was so caught up
in wondering
what people would think
about this, about us,
and I don't even know
what "us" is,
but, um,
all I do know is that...
Whatever this is,
I don't want it to end.
Natalie, I don't...
Sorry, I didn't know.
Uh, Natalie,
this is Claire, my ex-wife.
I was trying to tell you.
Hi.
Nice to meet you.
Uh, Claire, she sold
her house in New Orleans,
packed up a few things
she thought I might want,
just came by
to drop them off.
I'm sorry.
I should've called...
I was just
getting ready to leave.
You don't have to leave.
No, it's okay,
I'll let you two...
I'll see you at work. Bye.