♪ Ohhh ohhh ohhh ♪
♪♪♪
Curtain three.
Dr. Wilder is on call.
Got it.
What's happening?
Is the baby okay?
That's why I paged
Dr. Montgomery.
This is Elana stone.
She's 33 years old, 22 weeks.
Presented with diffuse pain
localized more
in the abdominal area.
I think
I'm having a miscarriage.
Okay, Elana,
I'm gonna do an ultrasound, try
to figure out what's going on.
She's had chronic pain
for the last five years,
sensitivity to touch,
migraines.
Seven doctors,
no one could find anything.
Ow!
Elana, I need you to hang in
a little longer, okay?
Okay.
Ow!
Is our baby okay?
He looks just fine.
But the pain...
Lately even breathing's
been hard.
Well, it's possible
that the pregnancy...
Ow!
Is exacerbating the underlying
condition. I'm sorry.
Please.
You have to help me.
A cluster of
unrelated symptoms
including severe pain
with no obvious cause?
You think it's fibromyalgia?
I've had patients with it
before, and it's maddening.
You can't give them
a definitive diagnosis,
treatment's complicated.
Yeah, we can't give her
anything too strong
over the long term.
It'll hurt the baby.
Alternative treatments
can work.
That'd be great if we had time,
but she needs help right now.
Well, if we can't give her meds
and alternatives are too slow,
then what do you suggest?
Yeah. Thank you.
Betsey. Hi.
Hi. It's so good
to see you.
I'm Monica Bratton,
Betsey's aunt.
Hi. I-I'm Violet Turner.
I'm so sorry for your loss.
We all are.
You know, Dell was...
He--he was family.
I spoke to a Dr. Freedman
on the phone
when Betsey first came
to live with me.
He said if we ever needed
anything, to be in touch.
Yes. Uh, he--well, he's with
a patient right now.
Would--would you like--
I suppose
I could just tell you.
Look, I don't have kids. It's
a choice I made a long time ago.
Uh, yes. I-I understand.
It can be a big adjustment,
but sometimes--
and when Dell died
and I took Betsey in,
I did it because it was
the right thing to do.
But I can't keep her.
Is it wrong that I want
to punch aunt Monica?
On several levels,
but so do I.
Look, despite what is clearly
a limited emotional capacity,
I think aunt Monica did what
she thought was best for Betsey.
Come on. She left her in
our office like Paddington bear.
The only thing missing was
a note pinned to her jacket.
She brought her back to the only
family that she has left.
But we're not her family.
She needs Naomi.
Well, Nai was the only one
who really bonded with Betsey.
Dell and Betsey
lived with her.
Well, she's away
on foundation business
for the next month, so...
Maybe we could take her home
for a couple nights?
She's not a puppy, Cooper.
The department of children
and family services
is set up
for situations like this.
You know, I-I have a friend--
we're not placing Betsey
in the system.
Everybody in her life
has abandoned her.
They died, Violet.
I understand that, Charlotte,
but in her mind, they--
the system is there to protect
kids exactly like Betsey.
And more often than not,
it still screws them up.
Either way, Betsey's gonna
have some serious problems.
Her mother was an addict.
Both her parents are dead.
Betsey needs--
help. She needs help, which Dell
would've given any one of us
without a second thought...
If he were still alive.
What's going on?
It's worse. I can't...
You have to give me some drugs,
a shot, something.
Unfortunately, anything
strong enough to help you
would wind up
harming the baby.
So what,
she just has to suffer?
If the pregnancy's
making this worse,
can't you just
take the baby out?
No, the baby's not viable yet.
But there are
alternative treatments
that could help
for the remainder of your term.
I would be with you
every step of the way,
and once you deliver,
the level of pain might subside.
That's another
three and a half months. No.
If you can't
take away the pain,
I can't have this baby.
She can't abort our baby.
Elana's in agony.
If she doesn't feel
she can carry to term--
she didn't want a kid.
I pushed her,
and finally she agreed,
but I've never...
I've never felt my son kick.
Elana won't let me touch her
because of the pain, but...
That's my baby.
And I won't let you kill him.
I'm not crapping in a cup.
It's the only way
to find out what's wrong
with your stomach.
I'm not doing it.
Okay.
How about the truth then?
Come on. Everybody knows
that a stomachache
is the best way
to get out of school.
You can't prove it.
You can't disprove it.
Why are you faking?
But I'm not faking--
ah, th--it's the truth
or the cup.
Your choice.
All right.
There's these kids at school.
And they don't really like
the stuff that I'm into,
so they do things to me.
Like?
Like I had pictures
in my locker,
and then they tore them down.
I'm assuming they weren't
pictures of girls.
Anime.
You know, they're--
cartoons, yeah.
People with big eyes
and impossible-to-pronounce
names.
Well, they're Japanese fantasy
and action animations, but...
Yeah.
Anyway, so I was trying
to get my pictures back,
and then the asshats
dragged me out to the quad
and duct taped me
to a flagpole.
Oh, that's, uh, not good.
Yeah. It was my dad that
got me into all this stuff.
If he hadn't died,
he'd probably
help me kick their asses.
Yeah.
Look, can't you just
write me a note?
Then what, homeschooling,
witness protection?
I mean, you know,
teenagers can be jerks,
but you can't hide forever.
So find the other kids
that are into anime
and, you know,
you're gonna be fine.
Yeah, I'm trying. But what
am I supposed to do right now?
Well, what would the hero
from one of your stories do?
Oh, please don't tell her.
She's just
gonna make it worse.
Does he need a cuddle
or a kick in the backside?
Um...
Well, a bug's been doing around,
but I think he's on the mend.
Um, just to be
on the safe side,
I'd keep him home
for the rest of the day,
make sure
it's out of his system.
Okay. Sound good to you?
Yeah.
She's in unbearable pain,
and it's gotten worse
with the pregnancy.
But do you think
it's bad enough that
she should terminate a pregnancy
that's almost viable?
That is a decision
for Elana.
But there are treatments
she hasn't tried yet
that alter the release
of neurotransmitters
and increase
her pain tolerance.
Pete, I am not eager
to terminate her pregnancy,
but I'm also not gonna
look her in the eye
and tell her
she needs to be tougher.
Is she
having trouble breathing?
Yeah, she mentioned that.
Swallowing?
Yeah, it's in her chart.
Order an m.R.I.
Yep, I'm brilliant.
Get used to it.
And get me that brain scan.
Hey, I was looking for you.
Feel like getting a snack?
This is my daddy's office.
He used to have crayons
and paper.
Yeah.
I remember. You two had
a lot of fun in here.
You know,
he loved you so much.
And I know that when
someone you love goes away,
it feels icky.
And it's confusing because you
have all these big feelings
that you don't understand.
But I want you to know
that...
All of us here
care about you...
So much...
And that
you can tell anything to me.
Okay?
Anything at all.
Where am I
gonna sleep tonight?
How about
you come home with me?
♪♪♪
Should we have offered--
mnh-mnh-mnh-mnh-mnh.
Don't--don't even say it.
Oh, come on, Sam.
Addison...
Betsey needs
more than we can give her.
And it's not our place.
Really, it's--it's not
Violet's place either.
Yeah, but it's only
for a few nights.
I mean, I took care of Lucas
for months.
I know,
but Lucas was a baby,
and--and all due respect,
I mean, you were warm hands
to hold him.
Oh.
Wait. I didn't mean for it
to come out like that.
I-I'm just trying
to say that...
For you,
when you had to let go,
how'd it feel?
She's old enough to understand
and get attached.
And it would be brutal.
Why isn't Lucas crying yet?
Because he understands
that I worked a long shift
at the E.R. last night,
and there's another kid
in the house.
And he's thoughtful...
Just like his daddy.
Good morning, boo-boo.
Rise and shine.
Good morning.
Pete!
Pete,
Lucas is not in his crib!
My daddy and I used to
watch cartoons together.
I thought maybe Lucas
would like them.
Try to relax, Elana.
We're almost done.
The sedative is helping.
Too bad we can't
keep her doped up.
Well, there's always herbal tea
and Chinese gongs.
Okay.
That's a little harsh.
Come on, Addison.
We're surgeons.
You're not saying that you
really buy into his whole
bad-juju-caused-my-cancer rap,
do you?
Pete helps a lot of people.
Mm.
And just because
you disagree with him
doesn't mean he's wrong.
Well, he's wrong this time.
Elana doesn't have fibromyalgia.
She's got a chiari malformation.
The herniation's putting
pressure on her brain.
You think that's
what's causing her pain?
I do.
What can we do about it?
What I do best...
Cut.
Hey.
How was your first night
with Betsey?
Good. In fact,
when I woke up this morning,
she was watching cartoons
with Lucas.
That sounds fun.
It was sweet, actually.
Yeah, she, uh,
she took Lucas from his crib
while I was sleeping.
That sounds...
Uh, unnerving.
No. I mean,
w--it was for a minute,
but I know
she'd never hurt Lucas.
Yeah, well, we hope, you know,
but Betsey is troubled.
She needs help. She needs
someone to care. That's all.
What I mean is,
you need to be cautious.
I think you're blowing this
out of proportion, Sheldon.
She's a child.
Betsey does need help, okay?
Years of help.
And those aren't
going to be easy years.
Now come on.
You know that, right?
Well, I think we owe it to her
and to Dell
to do whatever we can
for her.
But the best thing
you can do for her
is to help her start a new life
as soon as possible.
Meaning without me?
I think you'd help Betsey most
by letting her go.
So you want
to do brain surgery
on a woman who's almost
six months pregnant?
Yeah, if I release
the intracranial pressure,
it should reduce her pain.
If we don't help her now,
she's gonna terminate
the pregnancy.
I can help her.
Not fast enough, Pete.
You think surgery
is the better option?
Apart from the fact that it
might not help Elana,
it could also kill her.
It could kill her baby.
This is not
a complicated procedure,
and there is a huge upside.
For chiari malformations,
inversion therapy
has the same upside.
It can relieve the pressure
on the cerebellar tonsils
and diminish her pain
for weeks.
You're gonna keep
her upside down
for the rest of her life?
I can get her through
the pregnancy.
Then you can cut
as much as you want.
All right, look, either way,
Elana and Steven
are gonna need
some guidance here.
Fine. He makes his pitch,
I make mine.
I'm horny.
Want a quickie?
Well, Emily post
would be proud.
Mm.
Mm. Hey, do you think
we should, um--
less talk. More hands. Mm.
Do you think we should
do something?
I'm trying to do something.
I mean about Betsey.
I mean, you know
if it was our kid,
Dell would step up.
We don't have kids,
Cooper.
Okay, if we did...
It's just, she's here,
and every time I look at her,
I think that...
Yeah, you hate me
right now, don't you?
A thousand things about you
that make me
want to pull my hair out...
But you caring too much
is not one of them.
I'm not gettin' laid, am I?
When you're feelin' Randy,
you know where to find me.
They called me to come get
my son because he brought
a knife to school!
A knife, Dr. Freedman!
He says he's being bullied,
and that's your sage advice?
I never said--
how could you not tell me
what was happening?
He's only 14.
Mom, please.
No--
Jackie, Jackie, let's sit down
and we can talk--
and--and do what? What are you
gonna tell him next?
I'm trying to help.
Really? You could've
gotten him killed.
Let's go.
Ma'am, hi.
My name is Dr. Wallace.
I'm a psychiatrist.
Can we talk for a minute?
No.
What do you want from me?
I'd like to help you
if I can.
There's nothing wrong
with Kenny.
I'm not suggesting there is,
but you did arm yourself.
And I think I can help you work
through some of your issues.
My son can talk to me.
I'm sure he can,
but does he?
Elana's brain
is too large for her skull,
and like any body part
that gets shoved
into an area that's too small,
it can cause pain.
But if I shave off
a small part of the bone
at the back of the skull,
remove a patch
of the brain covering,
and sew in a new, bigger one--
her pain goes away?
Maybe.
Likely.
But there are risks.
What are they?
Elana could die,
or your son could.
But there's another option.
I can position your body
to relieve the pressure
that's causing the pain.
I would work with you every day
for the rest of your pregnancy
to help you manage it.
Dr. Montgomery?
What do you think?
I think that both options
are viable.
Oh, please.
Don't be diplomatic.
Just tell me
what we should do.
I think you should have
the surgery.
I'll be there to monitor
the baby the entire time.
How soon can we do it?
Elana, no. I don't want
a life without you.
With all this pain, what kind
of life have you had with me?
Oh.
I want the surgery.
That's an interesting choice
of t-shirt.
It's anime.
"Takao's turn."
Genius kid finds a pen,
and anyone whose name
he writes with it dies.
You're a fan boy?
I'm an action guy.
What about you?
Well, fantasy, mostly.
I like the ones
where the bad guys get
what's coming to them.
Well, that makes sense.
Is there something wrong
with that?
Not in theory.
I was protecting myself.
A weapon seems excessive
in response to humiliation.
Well, they did more.
You want to tell me
about it?
They kicked me,
and they wouldn't stop
till I took off
my anime shirt.
Look, I don't want
their acceptance, Dr. Wallace.
What do you want?
I guess I just want
what Dr. Freedman said,
to stay
in one school long enough
that I can find kids...
Like me.
How many times
have you changed schools?
Six times in two years.
That's why I didn't want
my mom to find out,
'cause she
just keeps freaking out.
Do you know what it's like
to be the new kid in school
over and over again?
Posterior fossa decompression,
that's risky
on a pregnant woman.
Yeah, she's in a lot of pain,
and if we can't help her,
she says she wants to abort.
Dad's desperate.
It's just--
it's a bad situation.
Y-You see how hard
all these people work
to become parents,
and the lengths that Naomi goes
through to get them pregnant,
and everything that you do,
and you wonder--i wonder--
you know,
is it even worth it?
How can you think that?
You have Maya.
Yeah, Maya who is 16,
has her own baby,
and is married
to a guy named dink.
I mean, Naomi and I,
we did everything that we could,
a-and Maya had
so many advantages,
but still...
I don't know. I-I look at Maya,
and I look at Betsey,
and... I think sometimes,
it's just futile.
Okay. I'm not gonna repeat
this speech
to the mother who's about
to have brain surgery
to save her baby.
I'm sorry. I...
Look, I feel really...
Really bad about Betsey.
I do. But I just
want to make sure
that we're on the same page
about her.
What do you mean?
I mean that if Violet
didn't take her,
that I still would've said no.
I already have a child,
Addison,
and a grandchild.
I don't.
Well, can you even--
I don't know, Sam.
But you want to?
I don't know that either.
Well, then why are you
putting me on the spot?
Because... I want to believe
that if I did want
to have a child with you,
that you would.
Give her a minute.
You--you want to try?
Aah! Oh!
Can I stay with you forever?
Hey.
So he--he's a good kid,
right?
He's a cool kid...
Actually.
Well, in his way.
Were you a Kenny
growing up?
Smart but kind of different,
couldn't really find
your place?
Actually,
I bedded the prom queen
three years running,
and the last one's sister, too.
Okay.
But I...
I'm assuming you were.
Well, I was pretty into magic
for a while there.
That was, you know,
cool in its way.
Okay, I got pushed around,
took a lot of dead arms,
the occasional linebacker
stuffing me into a garbage can
until the summer
after tenth grade.
I grew 5 inches.
I traded in my trick cards
for a date with Norma Jacks,
and no one ever
screwed with me again.
Kenny's dad bought him
his first deck of pokémon cards
when he was 7.
Now anime
is a world he can go to
where his dad is still alive,
and the dimwitted bullies
don't get to win.
That sounds like
a better place for him to be.
They're hurting him, Cooper,
and it's not the first time.
And Kenny says
Jackie's response is always
to pull him out of school.
Well, she wants to keep him
out of the line of fire.
Yeah, but figuring out
how to adapt,
learning how resilient
you can be, I mean, those skills
are essential to developing
into a competent adult.
I told Kenny
to stand up for himself
until he could find his people,
there'd be safety in numbers.
But if Jackie's never gonna
give him that chance...
Well, then
he'll never learn to cope.
That's a point I'd like
to make to Jackie,
but... talk about worrying
someone's gonna kick your ass.
Kenny will be home soon,
so say
whatever you have to say and go.
He mentioned you were
pulling him out of school.
The school where he was beaten?
Wouldn't you?
We know why you want
to shield him, but--
no "but." It's my job.
No, this has happened before.
Right? The bullying?
Jackie, the worst in people,
it starts in high school,
but it doesn't stop there.
And part of growing up is
learning how to deal with that.
Now if--if you don't
give him time to adapt--
I will not send him back
to be attacked.
It takes everything I've got not
to go in there and kill them.
Tempting as that may be,
if you let me,
I can help Kenny develop
the skills to handle this.
Skills?
He's 14 years old,
and he comes home and cries
every day, like a baby.
It kills me, but...
It also drives me crazy.
After my husband died,
I-I let it go for a while.
But now... I love him,
and I would do anything
for him.
God knows, I've tried.
Everything--
pep talks,
and--and karate lessons, and...
Look, um...
Kenny's a wimp.
Right?
He's, uh, he's just...
He's just weak.
You know what that's like,
knowing that you...
Raised a-a weak little baby?
Mom.
It was the only thing
I could think to do.
Well, it seemed
like it worked.
Oh, just to see her smile...
She'll need daily therapy,
at least at the beginning,
but I think we could see real
improvements in a few months.
Wait. You want her to stay
with us all that time?
I think we should adopt her.
Violet, that's not
a good idea for any of us.
When you think about it,
we are exactly
who should be doing this,
'cause I'm a therapist,
and--and even more than that,
I get Betsey.
That sense of being damaged?
I know what that can turn into.
We're building a family.
And there's no reason that
Betsey can't be a part of that.
We can do this.
Can we?
Absolutely.
You don't think
I can do this.
I have it in me after...
I'm fine. I am fine now.
Violet, I'm not--
she's a child.
She needs someone.
She needs us.
And I am fine.
If we could just
get Kenny to realize
that the rest of his life
is not gonna be like this.
Yeah, well, we will.
I will.
Oh, yeah? You think
Jackie will let you?
Well, I can be persistent.
Hey.
Hey. Where are you off to?
Hospital.
Amelia's doing brain surgery
on my pregnant patient.
Don't ask.
Well, good luck.
Oh, hey, uh...
Can I ask...
I need your help
with Violet.
Uh, it'll have to wait till
my next night with her.
I only get two a week--
she wants to adopt Betsey.
Wow. And you don't?
We're just getting
into a rhythm, the two of us,
and with Lucas...
I think it's too much.
Have you... told her that?
If I try to explain this to her,
she's just gonna think
it's an excuse,
like I'm being selfish,
but I have to think about
all of us. Am I wrong?
Pete, I'm her best friend.
You--
am I wrong?
No, you're not wrong.
♪ Baby, now don't look back ♪
There.
Nice work on the craniectomy.
Look at the lady doctor,
all up on the neuro.
Your brother used to
like to talk shop at home.
Well, I hope Sam
is more imaginative.
♪ When you're pulling it... ♪
Heart rate's good.
Everything okay
with you two?
Fine.
♪ Baby, we're holding on ♪
I don't think
he wants kids.
Do you?
I want the option.
Well,
what's it worth to you?
♪♪♪
Hey.
You want to adopt Betsey?
Look, I am trying
to separate out
my feelings about Betsey
from my professional judgment.
And I know,
I know the reason I'm having
a hard time letting this go
is because it's my do-over.
Last year,
I was aunt Monica.
Oh, you're not aunt Monica.
You could handle this.
Which is why I should.
Don't you think?
Oh, go on. Say it.
Lord knows Pete isn't.
I think you could do this,
but I don't think
that Pete can.
He just got you back.
You just got married.
You gotta cut him some slack.
♪ ...our vanity ♪
Well, if we don't take Betsey,
then where is she gonna go?
We will find her somewhere.
We need to find her someone.
We will.
I don't know, Cooper.
I don't know.
What if...
What if
I'm supposed to help Betsey
to make up
for what I did to Lucas?
♪ Oh, yeah, we're holding on ♪
Your do-over
is not with Betsey.
It's with Lucas.
♪ To the world ♪
No news yet.
When I met Elana,
I fell hard... and fast.
She had this thing.
Been there.
But then, she changed.
And maybe it's the disease.
I don't know.
But... I woke up one day,
and the thing was... gone.
♪♪♪
Been there, too.
I sit in the car at night,
hoping when I go inside,
she'll be asleep.
I know what that makes me,
but...
Elana doesn't smile anymore.
When I try to hold her hand,
she pulls away.
It's the pain.
But...
The person
I fell in love with left.
♪♪♪
"Sickness and health."
I meant it.
How long am I supposed to wait
for her to come back?
♪♪♪
How long would you want her
to wait for you?
♪ all the trees
stand like skeletons ♪
Violet wants to adopt her.
Pete doesn't.
Pete's a smart man.
You realize I was adopted?
That's what this is about...
Some kind of
pay-it-forward obligation?
♪♪♪
I don't want Betsey.
♪ If I had more ♪
Then why'd you offer
to take her home?
Because part of me knows
what a difference
we could make in her life.
But the other part of me knew
you'd never let me do it.
Nice to know
I'm that predictable.
I got lucky.
A great family found me.
It made all the difference.
Every kid should at least
get a chance.
Betsey?
♪♪♪
Kenny?
Mm-hmm.
For both those kids,
it will get better.
We don't know that.
Maybe Betsey will get adopted
by a nice family,
and they'll all die.
Maybe Kenny will go to
a new school, and this time
the bullies will have
a knife or a gun.
Listen to me.
Two years ago, if someone
had told you we'd be engaged,
in love...
Things change, Cooper,
when you're not lookin'.
♪ His feet,
they have touched the ground ♪
♪ I could feel the boom ♪
Ooh.
Don't answer it.
Just go faster.
It's the hospital.
♪♪♪
Elana made it through.
And, uh... my baby?
The baby's gonna be fine.
♪ It was a thrill ♪
Did it work?
Well, time will tell.
♪ Time ♪
Listen, I-I hope you know
that I didn't mean
any disrespect
when Elana asked me
what she should do.
You gave her
your honest opinion.
Amelia's good.
I never doubted it, and I
didn't take it personally.
Okay. It just felt--
it felt a little tense.
It's not that.
Is it Betsey?
Yeah. It's brought up
some issues for Sam, too.
Because he didn't want
to take her?
I'm not even sure if I do.
I probably don't, but yes.
Violet wants to keep her.
Well, that's not surprising,
right?
But she can't. We can't.
♪ And I can hear ♪
♪ your mother
crying in your room ♪
It's hard being a family.
♪ I wear this face
for both of us ♪
Call neuro down.
Where's Kenny?
The doctors are working on him,
but they won't let me in there.
I'm so sorry.
I thought the school
would be able to stop them.
It wasn't the bullies,
Dr. Freedman.
Kenny tried to kill himself.
♪♪♪
They're still working on him.
Uh...
You're good with kids...
For an hour.
I'm with my kid every day,
and I do my best.
But a boy needs his father,
and you waltz in,
and you give him bad advice,
and now he is in there--
Kenny gave up, Jackie.
He just... he gave up.
What the hell kind of therapist
are you? Why didn't you know?
He didn't want me to.
I knew Kenny was struggling,
but he kept me in the dark
just like he did you.
Oh...
Yeah, because if, um...
If he dies,
oh, my god, if he dies,
i'm, um...
It's my fault.
I did this. I did--
I did it.
Dr. Freedman?
The hard part's over.
She's not in any pain
right now.
She's just got a headache,
which is normal
after brain surgery.
It's okay.
Come be with your wife.
You did good today.
I know.
Elana?
The baby...
He's kicking.
What the hell did you do?
I stabbed myself
in the stomach.
What were you thinking?
Suicide is never the answer.
It is never, ever the answer.
Yeah, I know that... now.
Life is long,
and your horizons
are gonna get bigger.
But to try to get out
of it early, it's a huge--
when I was your age,
I was a runt, I had, like,
two friends, and it felt like
it was never gonna get better.
But you know what? It did.
Somehow,
when you're not looking,
things change.
Now i'm, you know,
I'm a doctor,
I'm engaged to this
ridiculously beautiful woman,
and I can
beat the crap out of, um...
Well, you know, some people.
Anyway, the point is,
it gets better.
If you hang around,
it gets good.
But you don't get to see that
if you're not here.
Dad would be
so pissed at me.
Yes, he would.
Look, I...
I just...
I don't want to switch schools,
all right?
Please just give me a chance.
Um, only if those boys
are expelled,
and every teacher there
knows exactly--
mom, mom, no.
I'll talk to Dr. Wallace.
I want to.
And I'll be careful.
But you have to
let me do this, okay?
You have to.
Okay.
Cooper already talked to me.
I just asked his opinion.
I didn't ask him to--
no, you didn't,
but you kinda did.
He made the point, Pete.
I wanted to talk to you.
I did.
But things have been
so good between us,
I just didn't want to risk--
Cooper's not my husband.
And this tiptoeing around me,
it's not gonna work.
You know, I mean, we're in this,
we're not going anywhere.
We need to be able
to get mad and fight and...
And know
that we'll get through
whatever we need
to get through.
You don't want
to adopt Betsey.
It is what it is.
As much as I feel
for Betsey...
We need time.
I know.
But you have to know that...
That I'm fine.
I am fine.
You are.
I miss Dell.
Hey.
So Pete and Violet
aren't going to adopt Betsey.
That's good...
For Betsey
and for everyone.
Dell used to make me crazy.
But the thing is,
he was there...
For Maya.
He died taking care
of my child.
Sam, no one expected you
to take Betsey,
including me.
No, but you still
want to know
about us...
And if--
I don't need to know.
Not now.
♪♪♪
♪ I am the one ♪
I-I need to ask
if anyone here
is willing to...
Take Betsey.
Please.
♪ The racing heart
of a teenage kid ♪
Because I can't, and, um...
One of us needs to step up.
♪ The brightest mind ♪
♪ to see, to see ♪
Please.
♪ You've broken my heart ♪
♪ No, no, no, no ♪
♪ it's the shame,
shame, shame ♪
♪ I'm kidding myself
as I'm standing here ♪
♪ in the pouring rain ♪
♪♪♪
Don't you want
to take care of me?
I love spending time
with you.
Where will I go?
Um...
I don't know exactly.
But...
Here's what I hope
will happen.
I hope that you will get
to go to a home,
a home with a mom and dad
who have always wanted
a little girl,
a mom and dad
of your very own,
who will love you so much
because they're gonna see
how special you are.
And that will be better
for you than living with us,
because your new family...
They have been waiting
just for you.
Doesn't that sound good?
♪ I'm kidding myself
as I'm standing here ♪
♪ in the pouring rain ♪
♪ and I wo-wo-wo-won't ♪
♪ be the same, same, same ♪
♪ I'm kidding myself
as I'm standing here ♪
♪ in the pouring rain ♪
Okay.
♪♪♪
You must be Betsey.
My name is Gladys.
♪ You've broken my heart ♪
♪ you've broken
my heart ♪
♪ no, no, no, no ♪
We did a bad thing here.
You all know it.
We did a bad thing.
♪ In the pouring rain ♪
♪ and I wo-wo-wo-won't ♪
♪ be the same, same, same ♪
♪ I'm kidding myself
as I'm standing here ♪
♪ in the pouring rain ♪
♪ no, no, no, no ♪
♪ it's the shame,
shame, shame ♪
♪ I'm kidding myself
as I'm standing here ♪
♪ in the pouring rain ♪