All we want to do
is help our patients,
but what they don't teach
us in medical school is:
there are so many
ways to do harm.
Previously on The Resident...
- The surgery was canceled.
- They can't do that.
Yes, they can.
Is your pride really worth more
than the life of a patient?
Chief of Surgery. Resident.
Try to remember that.
You don't have the
right to play God, Conrad.
There's always art
balanced with science.
- You okay?
- Just worried about him.
Fortunately, I happen
to be Rembrandt.
I think Lane's overtreating
her patients, including Lily.
We have to do
something about Lane.
We're gonna find out
what it is. Together.
We need to have a
physician running Chastain.
The CEO will see you now.
Guess who's on a break?
- Me.
- Yeah, you and me.
Chastain can take
care of itself right now.
Our downtime is
finally synced up.
It has been a while.
Patients are fine,
a quick page away,
which is why I've
taken it upon myself
to acquire these beauties.
In the interest of time...
Our chief resident,
Dr. Benjamin,
is at a medical
convention in Denver.
These keys are to his office.
With a sofa and a locking door?
A shower and a locking door.
♪ Buy yourself a dream ♪
♪ How's it looking? ♪
♪ Buy yourself a car ♪
♪ And a house to live in ♪
♪ Get yourself a girl ♪
♪ Someone different,
buy yourself a dream ♪
♪ And it won't mean nothing... ♪
Just leave it.
Damn it.
Mine or yours?
Mine.
911.
♪ It all could be different ♪
♪ Time to do something new ♪
♪ I've given everything ♪
♪ I want to be a
happy man, too. ♪
Secret admirer?
Someone's getting jealous?
They're for you,
but Phoebe in the flower
shop does have eyes for me.
I may have flirted
my way to a discount.
- Phoebe, huh?
- Yeah.
Half Asian girl with...
High-pitched voice,
drenched in perfume.
I know Phoebe, and...
I admire her work, but
this was unnecessary.
Well, my perfectly
stitched heart begs to differ.
Can you stay?
I wish I could,
but I have a case.
Newborn,
sick heart the size of a walnut.
We have to reroute blood
flow so she can get oxygen.
She's extremely high risk.
What are her odds?
Part of Mabel's heart
is underdeveloped.
The defect is more
severe than we thought.
Without surgery, two days tops.
With surgery,
she's got a real shot.
Yeah, a long shot.
Mr. Thoms, your wife
brought these beautiful twins
into this world together.
It is my mission to reunite
them in a few hours,
and I am not in a losing mood.
Rarely am I.
I feel dizzy.
Hey, stay calm.
Okay? Just stay calm. Stay cool.
Your pulse is ridiculously
high. Look at me.
We can't have you stroking
out before I bring Mabel back
to her brother
Matt, you hear me?
- Help is on the way.
- Yeah.
- Let's go.
- Okay.
Today,
a once-prominent
Atlanta oncologist,
Dr. Lane Hunter, was arraigned
on one charge of murder
and 12 charges of insurance
fraud and money laundering.
Dr. Hunter is accused
of fraud and murder.
She provided false medical
information to cancer patients
in order to charge them
thousands of dollars
in unnecessary chemotherapy.
Did you take a shower?
Don't worry about it.
Where did you take a shower?
Mr. Thoms,
Dr. Hawkins, this is Dr...
Pravesh. We met in the
ER when my wife came in.
- How's she doing?
- She's resting.
And I'm gonna head back down
shortly again and check on her.
We stopped by to make
sure you're feeling okay.
BP a little high?
Have a seat.
Any palpitations?
My baby girl's in the OR,
my baby boy won't stop crying,
labor almost killed my wife.
Now she's in the ICU.
Yes. Palpitations.
BP's 180/120.
Normal protocol would
be to send you down
to the ER for observation.
There's no way in
hell I'm leaving my son.
Oh, we get it,
but there's a rule
against dads having
heart attacks in the NICU.
Let us run some labs,
get an EKG, start you
on some blood pressure meds,
make sure that doesn't happen.
What do you say?
- Okay.
- Yeah?
- All right.
Um, I want to
check in on my wife.
Dr. Pravesh.
Melanie. Welcome back.
You gave us quite a scare.
You lost a lot of
blood during delivery.
How are you feeling?
How are my babies? Mabel?
As you know, Mabel has
hypoplastic left heart syndrome.
Prenatal imaging can
only tell us so much,
so we didn't know the
severity of her heart deformity
- until she was born.
- Is she okay?
I haven't even met her yet.
Soon after birth, she
was taken into surgery,
but I assure you that she is
in the best possible hands.
Dr. Sharavino
called and said you're having
another flare? What's going on?
Oh, fever, body
aches, yeah, the usual.
Our mom also had lupus,
which led to kidney failure,
and then she died,
so "the usual" can
be fatal in our family.
Well, we'll be extra careful.
Any, um, sore
throat, congestion?
Peeing a lot, a little pain.
Okay, well, we'll definitely
run your blood work,
but if it's anything like
your last three
admissions, it'll be a UTI,
so we'll get you started
on doxycycline to make sure
it doesn't turn into
a kidney infection.
Oh, she has a mild allergy to...
To doxycycline. An antihistamine
should help head off the hives
you got on your last visit.
Um, will a doctor
be in soon or...?
I'll be back shortly.
- Can you get off that thing for,
like, a second?
- I would,
but it's way more interesting
than you are right now.
Run this blood work. Thanks.
Hot, hot, hot, hot!
NEWSWOMAN: Legal experts note
that if Dr. Hunter were
found guilty, she may face
the death...
We need some help!
Bypass.
Scalpel.
Thank you.
Ready for this?
And here...
we go.
♪ ♪
Will Matt be okay? And Mabel?
Is she-is she in surgery?
Do they have power? Is
she okay? What's happening
- with Mabel?
- Mabel's with the best surgeons
I know.
Matt will be fine.
What about these other
babies? Are they all right?
It's gonna be fine. Stay calm.
I got this.
Stopped crying. Why
isn't he crying anymore?
Get me an Ambu bag.
He could have died.
What is going on?
The power went out.
Likely due to the storm.
Backup power kicked on now.
It's limited, but we
got emergency lights
and necessary equipment,
so we're good to go.
- You okay?
- Yeah, yeah.
All right.
Took too long for those
generators to come on.
Yeah, that wasn't cool at all.
I'm gonna go to the basement,
make sure everything's okay.
Until full power's restored,
revert back to
standard triage protocol.
Put the sickest together, get
ready to evacuate if needed.
Find me if he
has a heart attack.
All right, gather around.
We're operating on
backup power now,
so no computers,
no digital charts,
and the paper ones are
buried in the basement, so...
so, write pertinent
information on each patient.
Write clearly, write
concisely, follow me.
5920... monitor urine output.
We need him peeing like a champ.
5921... alcohol
withdrawal, taper diazepam.
5918... do not
ask about the cats.
It gives him PTSD.
5917... check vitals every 30
minutes. Come on, keep up.
Dr. Bell, should we deploy
emergency protocols A or B?
Dr. Bell. Dr. Bell, all
computer systems are down.
Dr. Bell, trauma is
completely jammed.
Is that why you're not
taking any patients in the ER?
Do you have a better solution?
Dr. Bell, we're almost
at capacity down there.
Dr. Bell, ortho has a dozen
scheduled cases. Keep or cancel?
- Is that why you're not taking any patients
at the moment? Computer systems are down.
Mr. Bell, why is this happening?
It's Dr. Bell.
I recommend thinking
before you speak.
If that's too much of a
challenge, don't speak.
There's a massive storm outside.
The power grid is down.
There's a team
working with the city
to get it restored
as soon as possible.
The fire department
is on their way to help
with emergency power, if needed.
Treat all current trauma
patients, then shut it down.
ER stays open to capacity.
Let me know the
second that happens.
Ortho hits pause. Don't
cancel a single surgery.
Slide 'em an hour.
When we're back up,
start cutting. All
hands on deck.
Focus. Communicate.
The hospital and our
patients will be fine.
Decisions go through me.
Get back out there.
Albert, why are you still here?
In regards to the trauma center,
I think we can
consider a better option.
Not unless you want a
one-way ticket to Caracas
as your last stop
on the surgical train.
Leave.
You know, policy dictates
that we abandon surgery
until full power is restored.
Closing now is a death sentence.
No doubt. But, legally,
baby Mabel was
simply a sad casualty
of unfortunate circumstances.
What to do, what to do?
Don't be dramatic. You
know what we're going to do.
Oh, look who put their
big girl pants on today.
Okafor...
if we continue
and Mabel doesn't survive...
Coin toss at this point...
Are you willing to lay
your head next to mine
as Bell lowers a steel blade
to the back of our
beautiful ebony necks?
Gladly.
Is there anyone here
who is more concerned
with their career than
saving Mabel's life?
Quick show of hands.
Nurse What's-Your-Name,
set the timer for 40 minutes.
Yes, Doctor.
Dr. AJ Austin's
Lonely Heart Club Band
plays on.
Backup power in the
ICU isn't working right.
- I'm going to the basement.
- I was there. It's not good.
Get back to the ICU. Start
triaging for evacuation.
- What's going on?
- Just go.
We're stuck between floors.
I'm claustrophobic.
And you got in an elevator?
Well, my bathmophobia is worse.
I don't know what that is.
It's the fear of stairs and...
and-and st-steep slopes.
Steep... steep slopes.
Oh, my God, it's hot in here.
Seems Mother
Nature has gifted us
with some mood lighting tonight.
- The storm
knocked out the power?
- Yes.
And unfortunately has
held up Dr. Sharavino.
But not to worry.
I will be with you
your entire stay.
Uh, is her lab
work back yet or...?
Not until the power's back,
but knowing Joplin's history,
we have a good
course of treatment.
No offense, but my sister needs
to see a doctor, not a nurse.
Your sister needs an antibiotic
to treat a UTI that is quickly
becoming a kidney infection.
I diagnosed it,
so I will treat it.
If I need to tag in an
attending, I will do that.
Badass. I like her.
You're also gonna
have to stay the night
for observation.
I sort of dropped out of
college and have no future plans,
so all good.
All right, well,
here's your antibiotic,
and I'll be back in a bit.
I didn't know
nurses do all that.
I'm a nurse practitioner.
We do most things doctors do,
just with better bedside manner.
Storm's still a'ragin'.
I like storms. It's
Earth's way of venting.
Poltergeist. They had some
big-ass storms in that movie.
Yeah, when that tree came
alive and snatched that kid
out of the bed, I was like,
"Yo, Spielberg knows what's up."
How much time do
the generators give us?
Could be four hours,
could be two. Hard to tell.
That's your estimate, isn't it?
For the backup generators?
Eh, give or take.
- Emphasis on "take."
- How do you know that?
I've never worked in a hospital
that's done proper
generator maintenance.
Now, maybe Chastain
will surprise me.
- Where's your money?
- 34 minutes.
That isn't enough time
for the first phase, and
then you have to close
after we place the graft.
Now you're being dramatic.
Trust.
If all goes well without
one single hiccup,
we will sail through this
painfully intricate surgery
by the skin of our teeth.
Suction.
Every moment we turn
away or transfer patients,
we hemorrhage money.
Atlanta General and
Emory still fully functioning.
The storm hasn't affected
them, so worst-case scenario...
Is happening now.
Dr. Hawkins, this
is a strategy session
- for department heads only.
- Half the generators are down.
And the ICUs...
They don't have
any backup power.
- How many patients
on life support?
- 36.
There are six empty beds
in Neuro with backup power.
The others... We don't start
relocating them to
a different hospital...
Yeah, I know. They'll die.
Time to start an evacuation.
Ah, look at that.
Perfect fit. I'll
hold it steady,
you start the
proximal anastomosis.
- Without video assist?
- Yep.
I-I can't get good
visualization.
If I'm a millimeter off, that's
a hiccup we can't afford.
That's why the
sutures must be spaced
closely together in the corners.
- This area here
is prone to bleeding.
- I think I got it.
Of course you got
it. Now keep stitching.
We need to know what's
happening out there. Right now.
Dr. Okafor, I need you to focus.
Nurse, grab the house phone.
Make a quick call.
An update on all
things Chastain.
Specifically ICU room 3124,
- Micah Stevens.
- That's not necessary.
We'll check on
playboy, then we'll
cross your worry for
him off your to-do list.
I do not have a to-do list.
Liar, liar, scrubs on fire.
You have a list,
you checked it twice,
and now it's scratching the
surface of your brain space.
- Stop it!
- Hell no!
Your inability to
quell your concern
for teacher man could
distract you enough
to make the
slightest of mistakes.
Not on my watch, princess.
- Are you waiting for the world
to change or what?
- Oh...
Make the call.
ICU.
Yeah, we're doing
okay down here.
Micah?
Yeah. Tell Mina he's
fine and he's staying. I will.
Mina's in the OR. She's fine.
- Good.
- No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
- Ms. Thoms, no.
- Are you out of your mind?
- Ms. Thoms...
- No, take your marker there
and change this "go"
to a "no way in hell."
- Ms. Thoms...
- Melanie, calm down.
- Need a hand over there?
- No, I got it covered.
Ma'am, this is in
your best interest.
Her baby girl is in the OR.
I got to get 30
heads out of here.
She's one of them.
She's on oxygen.
I don't have a choice.
Pravesh, why don't
you just let me handle...
Put her on portable
oxygen. Take Mr. Sykes.
TBI after an MVC.
Barb coma for a week.
Bell will lose his mind.
That barb coma
has already
billed a quarter mil.
Wow, Bolton, really?
Bell freaks, it's on you.
Yeah, I'll take it.
Dr. Pravesh and Hawkins
are needed in the ER, 911.
I'll take care of Melanie. Go.
Thank you. Thank you.
- I need a tank.
- Right away.
Yes, sir. I understand.
Yes, I told him
already. Hold, please.
Eastside General has
power and open beds.
There is no Eastside General.
There's Atlanta General
and Eastside
Medical. Which is it?
Just ask.
Oh, no, this is
an incoming call.
It's Marshall Winthrop.
Return.
But he's the
chairman of the board,
and he's called three times.
You can inform Conrad
Hawkins's dad I'm a little busy.
He can wait. Indefinitely.
It's not the storm.
Our problem has nothing
to do with the electric grid.
Chastain's under
attack from cyber pirates.
Pirates?
That... can't be a thing.
Classic move from an
organized foreign crime syndicate.
They paralyze an institution,
cause disruption,
ask for ransom.
- You don't have security
in place?
- Yes.
But it needs an upgrade,
which I mentioned multiple times
and the administration ignored.
The upgrade you proposed
took us off-line for days.
We can't afford that
kind of shutdown.
Well, now we're
shut down anyway.
Ye...
How much will it cost
and how long will it take
for you to fix this?
There's no way to tell.
The attack program that
hacked in keeps replicating.
So if you want to
get this done quickly,
your best bet is
to pay the ransom
when the demand comes in.
Your professional IT advice
is to wait and pay?
Yes.
Good-bye.
What?
- I'm sorry,
you can't come in.
- Hundley.
- Talk to me.
- No... We're at capacity.
Eight-year-old. Gunshot
wound to the abdomen.
Hypotensive and tachy.
I'm afraid, man. He's dying.
Dr. Bell made the call.
We're closed to trauma.
Make room for one more.
You don't understand
what's going on down here.
There are no working ORs,
and this boy needs surgery.
We have no way to help him.
I don't think he makes it
to another hospital alive.
Zero chance he makes it
to another hospital alive,
so we roll the dice here.
Audra! I need an airway.
Check his breathing, heart
rate and BP. Page Nolan.
Pagers aren't working.
- Conrad, we can't save him here.
- Just get me Nolan.
- Park him there.
- How'd you find him?
Returning my rig, and I saw
the kid laying on the sidewalk.
I was only a block away,
man. I didn't know you guys
were closed. It's my first
week. He's my first kid, man.
- Please, I can't lose him.
- You made the right call.
One, two, three.
I need a trauma surgeon now!
There's blood entering
his abdominal cavity.
No breath sounds
on the left side.
- Where's Nolan?
- We're getting him.
Thready pulse.
He's about to code.
Get me a sterile blade
and a thoracotomy kit.
Right now this isn't your
fault, but if you cut and he dies,
it's on you. Don't risk it.
#10 blade.
Are we really doing this?
His pulse is stronger.
Get Nolan down here now.
I need help stopping
this bleeding.
- Oh, what the hell have
you done? Kid was dying.
- I had to cut.
- You never have to cut.
You're not a surgeon.
You don't make
the decision to cut.
I decide that.
Let's say, as his doctor,
I decided to save his life
by any means necessary.
Feel free to help.
Begin the massive
transfusion protocol.
Hang four units O-neg now.
- We have to get him up to an OR.
- No.
The generators are
busted. The entire OR
is about to be pitch-black, so
there's no OR to send him to.
Well, he's not stable
enough to transport him
- to another hospital.
- Do the surgery here in the ER.
No, no, no. There's not
enough room. It's not sterile.
And, once again, it's
about to be pitch-black.
I'm sorry, what's this?
Wh-Where are you going?
Wh-What is this, cut and run?
Where you think you're going?
To build you an OR.
There's no viable ORs.
You can't do the surgery
here. I'll build you an OR.
Did it all the time in the
Helmand Province in Afghanistan.
You just keep that
kid alive. Come on.
♪ Young boy ♪
♪ Trying to rule
the world, I see ♪
♪ Well, golden ♪
♪ But first you
gotta listen to me ♪
♪ I'll tell the truth ♪
♪ I promise you ♪
♪ This world may frown
upon the things I have you do ♪
♪ Oh, na, na ♪
One, two...
three.
Portable floodlights
make a lot of heat...
- They'll melt the drapes.
- Good call.
Have them angle the
rig toward the window.
♪ 'Cause the people going
nowhere are the ones ♪
♪ That are flexing, I'm not
trying to be a preacher ♪
♪ I was never a reverend,
but I can take your... to church ♪
♪ And show you glimpses
of heaven you better ♪
♪ Run in some type of
direction, 'cause the people ♪
♪ Going nowhere are
the ones that are flexing ♪
♪ I'm not trying
to be a preacher ♪
♪ I was never a reverend ♪
♪ But I can take
your... to church ♪
Go.
♪ Run ♪
♪ Run from the devil... ♪
All right.
All we need now is a patient.
♪ You better run ♪
- ♪ Run from the devil. ♪
- Give me four units of O-neg
and a cooler on standby.
Time to head out.
If word gets out this is
happening, it might not be good.
Head up to the ICU,
they need you up there.
Pressure's stable. 100/60.
- Good. We got a fighting chance.
- Depending on what we find
inside this kid's abdomen.
Scalpel, please.
Why are all these
patients moving?
Uh, with an extended
power outage,
we have to move
life support patients
- to different facilities.
- Oh.
- Joplin need something?
- No. I, um,
- I owe you an apology.
- Oh, don't worry about it.
No. Earlier, I
was rude. I just...
Ever since our mom died,
I feel such a responsibility
to help Joplin be the best
and the healthiest and...
and I am babbling, and
you are very busy. Um...
Just... You are beyond capable,
- and I'm really sorry.
- Hey, you were being protective
of your little sister. I get it.
And she's lucky to have you.
We're not gonna make it, are we?
You should take over stitching.
No. Yours are pretty perfect.
I'm only half done with
the graft. You're faster.
If that were true,
I'd be doing them.
Perfusionist, get
out the manual crank.
Wait, the power's running out?
We'll have no lights,
no suction, no perfusion.
Party people,
it's time for you
to get in touch
with your not-so-secret
love for the Sugarhill Gang.
Why? Because in
less than eight minutes,
we are not just
going old school,
we are going O.G., baby.
Calm breath out.
Imagine someplace peaceful.
A bubbling brook.
You're not helping.
What's your happy place?
Happy. Think happy.
Can I put my head in your lap?
- Please.
- Sure.
Okay.
Why me?
- Okay.
Yeah.
- Better.
- Mm-hmm.
Looks like our bullet nicked
his descending
aorta and his spleen.
Can you repair it? Well,
depends what I find in there.
So, just to clarify, am I firing
all of you because an internist
accepted a trauma patient
after the hospital was
closed to all ambulance traffic
or because a doctor
took it upon himself
to cut a kid open
with no working ORs?
He wasn't gonna survive
transport, so I made the call.
I'm the attending
trauma surgeon on deck.
I made the decision
to keep him and cut.
He had seconds to live.
At least now he's
got a fighting chance.
But you had no faith
in the first responders
- to keep him alive.
- I've been a first responder
at a war front, and his
wounds are up there with any
artillery damage I've seen.
He was bleeding out.
He had seconds.
It's like Niagara Falls in here.
The aortic damage
makes it almost impossible
to stop this bleeding.
Can you use an
extra set of hands?
Dr. Bell, this is one life.
At the command center,
you're saving many lives.
Dr. Bell. I-I'm sorry to
interrupt, but this is urgent.
Well, spit it out.
It's not a foreign
cyber crime ring.
The IP address that
launched the malware
came from inside Chastain.
Are you kidding me?
This isn't the storm?
- How long have you known?
- Are you telling me
we're being attacked
by one of our own?
That's exactly
what I'm telling you.
Hey, it's Mabel's dad.
I found him collapsed.
He's been vomiting.
He's weak, disoriented.
I treated him for severe
hypertension earlier.
Jason, have you eaten?
Okay. With his high blood
pressure from this morning,
I'm afraid he's having a stroke.
We need to get him
up to CT for imaging.
All right, I'll handle him
here. You run up to imaging,
force your way to
the front of the line,
- and throw elbows
if you have to.
- Okay, you know I will.
All right.
You are going to be in
position for a long time,
- so I suggest you get your
stretch on. 37 seconds and counting.
Nervous nurse, when you crank,
you are this baby's
heart. You hear me?
You are responsible
for circulating
oxygen-rich blood through all
of her tiny organs, so...
feel the heart.
Be the heart.
Now say it with me.
Feel the heart.
Be the heart.
Louder, so I can believe you.
Feel the heart. Be the heart.
- Better. Not great.
- Ten seconds.
All right, position for lights.
Seven, six,
five, four, three...
Here we go.
Be the heart.
Feel the heart.
Be the heart. Feel the heart.
- Go for perfusion.
- Feel the heart.
Be the heart. Feel the heart.
- Be the heart.
- Suction.
Feel the heart. Be the heart.
A hacker tried to get
into our system before.
Almost released the
worm a couple months ago.
It's hard to believe that
one of us would do this.
Is it, though?
Oh, God, what is that banging?
Come on. Come on.
Linda, need some help?
I am sick of this crap.
My patient needs sedation.
All right. There's a trick.
You know, when they
brought these computers in,
they said life would be easier.
My day got an hour longer
and I get to spend even
less time with my patients.
That works when there's power.
This works when
there's no power.
You've done that before.
Yeah. Hey, you know what?
Smash all the computerized
do-dads and gizmos.
I won't tell anybody.
Maybe we can actually
start looking people
in the eye again
instead of staring at
screens all the time.
Hey, I'm not bitter.
Yes, I am.
I mean, she's not wrong.
You think she knows how
to write computer code?
Definitely not.
You said the hackers
tried to shut us down before.
Do we have dates? I mean,
we can see who was working
on those days and go from there.
No, no, no, no,
no. Don't tell me.
Dr. Pravesh, no more power.
CTs are shut down
until further notice.
- You got to be kidding me.
- Unless you got a generator
- in your pocket.
- Oh, come on.
- Dr. Wilson.
- Make it good, Pravesh.
Blood pressure's
been 180/120 all day.
Weak, vomiting, abdominal
pain. Good enough?
Good catch. Could be
a hemorrhagic stroke.
Get him over to Atlanta
General ASAP for a CT to confirm.
I'll call ahead and
have Neuro waiting.
Helipad. Go.
Your wife and children
are in good hands.
We got to get you checked out
before things get worse, okay?
Let's go. Let's go, let's
go, let's go. Come on.
Wait, hold on.
Oh, my God.
- Whoa. What?
- Get me a BP
- and a blood sugar
reading, please.
- Okay.
Squeeze my hands. Squeeze them.
- We're ready to take off.
- I need just a second.
- Okay. It's okay.
- Okay, smile for me...
Pupil's reactive.
If we don't go now while
there's a break in the weather,
we don't get out.
Blood sugar is 88.
BP... 90/50.
His blood pressure is dropping.
He's not having a stroke.
- He's having an
anaphylactic reaction.
- You sure?
It really looked like a stroke.
It presented with GI symptoms,
so I didn't catch it at first,
- but I'm sure.
- So is he staying or going?
He's staying.
Jason...
Jason, what are your allergies?
Hey! Do you have an epi?
Peanut butter, kale,
honey, broccoli...
It's okay. It's okay.
Come on, come on.
Mangos.
I'm allergic to mangos.
Second to last ingredient.
Oh, my God.
Jason, you're gonna be okay.
All right. Let's see
what's going on.
Mmm, any good drugs?
Can I get in on the fun?
There you go, sister.
Ready to relax and
explore your humanity.
Okay...
Hmm.
Is there something wrong?
Joplin, where are the
pills I gave you earlier?
- In my belly.
- Try again,
because you have an
allergy to doxycycline,
and I haven't given
you an antihistamine yet.
And I'm seeing no
hives, no reaction, so...
you clearly didn't
take the pills.
Okay, Nancy Drew.
You're right, I flushed the
antibiotics down the toilet.
What?
I mean, if you're not
gonna do what they say,
why are we even at the hospital?
Joplin, what are you doing
on your phone in the
middle of the night?
Just, like, texting,
Instagramming?
Uh, no. she writes
code for different apps.
It-it doesn't pay much,
but it's something.
What were you studying when
you dropped out of college?
Software engineering
at MIT. What's going on?
Better question is why
I'm not at MIT anymore.
Answer: hospital bills so
crippling, I had to drop out
and she had to
declare bankruptcy.
Are you faking
symptoms to be here?
Look, we want less
hospital, not more...
Why would she fake her symptoms?
Because I think she hacked
into our system to shut us down.
That's crazy. Joplin...
This isn't the first time
that someone's hacked
into our computer.
The attacks started on July 4.
You were here then.
Is this true?
Did you do this?
- Why? Why would you do...
- Are you kidding me?
Medical bills ruined us.
Chastain ruined us. I
can't get the job that I want
without the degree from MIT.
We are making it work.
We are barely getting by.
You're working two jobs
in order to make payments
to Chastain for my
bill. And for what?
So the hospital can get rich?
Damn right I hacked
into the billing department.
To get our lives back.
To wipe our slate clean.
Wait, the billing department?
No, your cyber
attack is responsible
for this entire power outage.
That's not possible.
The code I created
was only to wipe out billing.
Whatever you intended,
it did a hell of a
lot more than that.
You severed our
connection to the grid.
You said that was the storm.
We were wrong.
Well, I-I messed up.
- It must've rep...
- People's lives
are in danger because of you.
I... I-I can try to fix it.
Let me try to fix it.
If she can fix this, do you have
to tell anyone what happened?
You saw the damage
her virus caused.
Joplin's a good person
who did something stupid.
Young people do dumb stuff.
I hear you, but right
now let's just focus
on getting the hospital
back up and running again.
Look, I know I'm asking
for too much, but...
so far, no one's
gotten hurt, right?
We are barely
surviving as it is.
I honestly don't know how...
Please, I know this is bad...
Here. Uh, i-it's a full backup
of-of the hospital
computers I made
before I did what I
should've never done.
A-All hackers make 'em, in case.
Give it to I.T. They'll
know what to do.
I deserve whatever
happens to me, but
Rachel didn't know anything.
Make sure they know that.
And that I'm sorry. I really am.
I'll pass that on.
God. I'm sorry.
- Sorry...
- Don't...
I gave the drive to I.T.
Power's being restored now.
But Bell doesn't
need to know that yet.
No, we're gonna
lie to help Joplin out.
I like that way
you think. I'm in.
We can get you the
antidote to the malware.
The person is remorseful
and asking for leniency
before they hand it out.
Blackmail?
Let's just call it negotiating.
Well, what are we talking about?
A nurse demanding
more mental health days?
Some millennial intern's crusade
for more acai bowls
in the cafeteria?
A patient
whose life was
destroyed by Chastain.
And a PR nightmare.
Don't need another one of those.
Chastain's computers
were vulnerable.
- Our generators
weren't up to code.
- Not my fault.
- Press won't see it that way.
- Patients' lives
were in jeopardy. It's
unlikely they'll put the blame
on Charles the I.T. guy.
What is it with you two?
Sticking your necks
out for some patient
you just met a few hours ago.
Seriously?
Chastain shined during
a crippling power
outage likely caused
by...
bad weather.
And a young patient's life
isn't completely ruined.
That's a win-win.
Well, nice try, but hacking
into a hospital database,
cutting off its power,
endangering countless lives...
I need a name.
We're not asking for anonymity.
We're just asking for leniency.
Well...
handling this
quickly and quietly
is in everyone's best interest.
So, deal?
Yeah.
Wait for it.
Wait for it...
Ah.
And then there was light,
and he saw that it was good.
We saved that kid's life.
He's gonna make it, by the way.
You sure you're gonna make it?
That improv surgery is the
craziest thing I've ever done
in my life. I mean, I don't
know whether to thank you
or to punch you.
Hey, I carried a fully-grown man
up three flights
of stairs today.
And you're telling me this why?
Because I broke a sweat
and you know where
there's a secret shower.
Dr. Benjamin's office.
You earned these today.
But... you didn't
get 'em from me.
You have my word.
You do know Benjamin
is back in the office now?
Good.
Uh, what happened
in the elevator
stays in the elevator.
Not something I'd
want to advertise.
Right.
Looks good.
Make sure he takes it
easy for the next few days.
Not sure that's how
this new-dad thing works.
I've got my eye on him.
I'll keep him in line.
Uh, thank you, Dr. Pravesh.
We can't... can't
thank you enough.
Mr. and Mrs. Thoms, someone
here is excited to see you.
Your daughter's a warrior.
We repaired her heart,
and it's even stronger
than we expected.
How long has he been crying?
Since they took
Mabel for surgery.
Nothing we've tried
has calmed him.
I have an idea.
Until today, these
babies shared a womb.
They don't know an existence
without the touch of the other.
And then they were thrust
into a huge, cold world,
alone.
They missed each other.
Everything's gonna be A-OK.
I don't think it's working.
- Give it a moment.
- ♪ You are my sunshine ♪
♪ My only sunshine ♪
♪ You make me happy ♪
♪ When skies are gray ♪
♪ You'll never know, dear ♪
♪ How much I love you ♪
♪ Please don't take ♪
♪ My sunshine away ♪
♪ The other night, dear ♪
♪ As I lay sleeping ♪
How's the baby?
Resting comfortably.
How are you?
♪ When I awoke, dear ♪
Feels like I'm never
getting out of here.
♪ I was mistaken ♪
♪ So I hung my head ♪
♪ And I cried. ♪
You're fired.
What?
- I just saved your neck.
- You risked.
I saved. Get out.
First thing tomorrow,
we need to...
You're wholly incompetent.
- Meaning?
- You're fired.
Talk to HR about severance.
Any available resident to ICU 3.
Dr. Bell.
You wanted to see me?
Great save today.
Thank you. You know, it's
days like this that make...
Just cut the crap and tell me
exactly what happened in the ER.
Who was there?
Who made the first cut,
you or Conrad Hawkins?
My place?
I don't know. I'm so tired.
Oh, we'll be sleeping like
babies before you know it.
That sounds amazing.
Captioned by Media
Access Group at WGBH