Who? Who was it? Who
the hell were you talking to?
The shopping network, I
swear. MAN: At 3 in the morning?
I couldn't sleep. I just
wanted some earrings.
- Don't lie to me.
- Stop it, Brian!
Who were you talking to?
Nobody. BRIAN: Who?
Nobody, I swear. Brian, please.
Somebody, help
me! BRIAN: Shut up!
- Help me!
- Shut the hell up!
- Stop it, Brian! Stop it!
- Shut your lying, filthy mouth!
- Rachel, can't sleep?
- I was hungry.
- What are you eating?
- PB and chips.
- It's good.
- Pass them over.
I miss the part where the giant tomato's
chasing Mason Dixon down the sidewalk?
- You know this movie?
- It's a classic.
- I don't really get it.
- What's to get?
- The tomatoes are killers.
- Yeah, I figured that part out.
- This is good.
- Told you.
This reminds me of when I'd
get up at 5:30 in the morning...
to watch The Smurfs with you.
- You like Smurfs?
- You liked The Smurfs. I liked the news.
- So we did what I wanted to do?
- It's hard to argue with a 2-year-old.
It seems like last week.
We need some milk.
- Watch this.
- What?
Watch.
Ew, that's gross.
This is so stupid.
- You weren't out, were you?
- No, I went for a walk.
- Where?
- Nowhere.
- Three in the morning?
- It's the only time I can.
- Except you can't.
- I'm under house arrest now?
Not yet, but you're
making me think about it.
You talk to my teachers, screen
my calls, search my room...
which even my guidance
counselor considers uncool.
- Enough.
- I have to report to the hospital.
- It's like living in a prison.
- Go to bed.
- Mark?
- Here comes the warden.
Hey.
Why won't you treat me
like a thinking person?
- Hey, what's going on?
- Show better judgment, maybe I will.
Yeah, I should have when I
decided to come live with you.
- I said turn it off.
- I just want to watch the movie.
Well, that's too bad.
I'm calling Mom. I'm
moving back to Saint Louis.
It's not that easy.
Why? You don't
want me here anyway.
Hey, quiet, both of you.
You're gonna wake the...
baby.
Okay. Thank you.
All set, ma'am. Your
complaint will be kept on record.
My complaint? What about hers?
- She says it was just an argument.
- Yeah, it was an argument.
- He was beating her.
- She says he wasn't.
- She was screaming for help.
- Not anymore.
Is that it? COP: Not
much else we can do.
But we appreciate the call.
Okay. Let's get
some rest, honey.
You must be a
real light sleeper.
- Did I wake you?
- Late shift.
- I'm sorry.
- No, I had to get up in two hours anyway.
- You don't drink coffee.
- Actually, I do.
- I distinctly recall you hating coffee.
- Yeah, when I was 15.
It wasn't that long ago.
What would you
like for breakfast?
- Ha, are you offering to cook?
- Momentary weakness. Take advantage.
All right, eggs.
Have you, um, spoken
to your father recently?
Uh, yeah, he called
a couple days ago.
Where's he staying?
He, uh, rented a
place on Michigan.
- Scrambled?
- Whatever.
- Do you have his number?
- Yeah.
- Why?
- He didn't give it to me.
- Well, I'm sure that he intends to.
- Did he say something?
Maybe you should just
let it sit for a little while.
Actually, I was hoping that
you would call him for me.
Sure. Or better yet, the three of us
could dip ourselves in a vat of acid.
We made mistakes, John.
I made mistakes, I know.
But I don't believe
that it's too late to fix it.
Sorry.
I know we argue a lot. We
didn't mean to bother you.
- You were screaming for help.
- I know.
I called help.
Brian and I have been
together since high school.
And there's a lot of
history and a lot of passion.
Passion?
Anyway, sorry to bother you.
- Is it your ankle?
- I'm okay.
- Let me take a look at it.
- I don't need any help.
- Joyce.
- I'm sorry, I'm late for work.
It's gotta be hard. CARTER:
She should deal with it herself.
- Maybe she doesn't know how.
- Mom's not the retiring sort.
She's tougher than he is.
Nobody's tough when
your life's falling apart.
Ah, you haven't met her yet.
- They're out of vanilla.
- Thanks.
Jennifer Lampkin.
Her ex-husband.
Where are we on Mrs.
McCabe's gallbladder?
- I convinced Surgery to take her.
- How'd you manage that?
I explained that she'd been
to the ER over 10 times.
The pain meds were
no longer appropriate.
- They accepted that?
- Even got her Medicaid paperwork started.
That's excellent. I have Attendings that
can't turf a stable patient to Surgery.
Have her call me at the
hospital. It's about Rachel. Thanks.
- What?
- Someone's a teacher's pet.
Rumor is he's about to
be promoted to hall monitor.
- You snitch on somebody, Gallant?
- No.
- What's all this?
- Weaver's got a crush.
I thought I noticed a
little something there.
- Mm-hm.
- Or I'm doing well on my rotation.
Whatever it takes.
Michael, have you ever
seen the erythema multiforme?
- Just in the books.
- Come here. Now's your chance.
Oh, so it's "Michael" now, is it?
- Anybody home?
Dr. Greene, 42-year-old prisoner,
stab wounds to the face and abdomen.
Good vitals. ETA, 10.
Uh-huh. Give it to Susan.
She's great with inmates.
David Zachery, beat up in a brawl in
an after-hours hip-hop club. No LOC.
- Have trouble breathing, David?
- Ain't my name.
- He goes by "Dimon Z."
- Do you have chest pain?
- BP, 120/70. Pulse, 90.
- No, my back. And the twins is moping.
- What?
- I got some serious junk damage.
- What does he mean?
- My boys hurt.
- Ah. Did you get kicked?
- Not there.
Okay. Can you wiggle your toes?
ZACHERY: Oh, damn! That kills!
- Whoa, what happened to your lip?
- Some bitch with a ring.
- Who started all this?
- Bunch of thugs looking to crank a name.
- Oh, yeah? Dimon's famous?
- A major label signed him a month ago.
- Hey, Chuny, can you give...?
- Aisha.
A room? MARQUEZ: Sure.
You take care of
my man, all right?
What's a common etiology
other than drug reaction?
- Viral infection.
- Any one in particular?
- Dr. Weaver, Sandy Lopez called back.
- Herpes?
- What?
- That girl firefighter.
- Right.
- Sandy Lopez from the 38th?
- That hot one?
- The gay one.
Get out of here.
My cousin Rico used
to have a crush on her.
- She wouldn't give him the time of day.
- I saw your cousin. I don't blame her.
Abby, 50 of Benadryl in Exam 1.
Cover the lesions with 1% hydrocortisone.
- I just got here.
- Clock in, get busy.
She said she'd stop
by before her shift.
- What?
- Lopez.
- You guys friends?
- I treated a man in her unit last night.
Fifteen-foot fall, femur
fracture, blunt head trauma.
Gallant, let's get a good
neuro exam on Mrs. Barisch.
Abby, you okay? ABBY: What?
- You look a little tired.
- Thank you, Frank.
Grab a gram of cefotetan. BP's
stable. Pulse, 100. Protecting his airway.
- That your prisoner?
- Yeah. What happened?
Jumped in County holding.
He's testifying against a lifer.
I didn't snitch. I
was subpoenaed.
No blood in the nares. Foreface,
stable. Neck, non-tender.
- You're beautiful.
- Thank you.
Four, maybe five superficial
cuts no deeper than the sub-Q.
Draw up 40 cc's of lidocaine.
No rebound or guarding.
- Push a hundred mics of fentanyl.
- No. No drugs.
- You're in pain.
- Reminds me I'm still alive.
- Push the meds.
- They must be next door.
You get the narc keys, Yosh?
- No scrubs?
- I didn't have time to change.
- Where's a Foley?
Belly's benign, non-tender.
Dimon, we're gonna have
to put a tube in your penis.
- Ah, you are so wrong.
- It might be uncomfortable.
- For you, because I ain't doing it.
- We have to check your urine for blood.
I'll pee in the cup, dog.
Keep that tube away from me.
- Carter, your dad's on line two.
- Take a message for me.
DTRs are two plus and equal.
Toes down, going bilaterally.
- Where's the fentanyl?
- They haven't restocked. Try the lock-up.
HemoCue is 14, urine dip is positive
for heme and leukocyte esterase.
- Gross blood?
- No, but it's cloudy.
Okay. Send a UA. Over 50 red
cells, and we'll image the kidneys.
Where did Abby go? I
need a 20 of lido with epi.
I'll get it. He says he'll
call from New Orleans.
- What?
- Your dad's flying to New Orleans at 3.
What?
- How about a head CT?
- It's not necessary.
She's never had headaches
before. Subarachnoid bleed?
That presents as sudden onset of severe
pain. She's got a mild chronic headache.
She could have hydrocephalus.
I think a CT is a good idea.
An out-patient
workup should be fine.
Okay.
Hi, it's Kerry. I heard you were
gonna come by before your shift...
but I'm a little backed up
here. So let me call you later.
Thanks. Bye.
- Where's Aisha at?
- Getting her lip sewed up.
- Marcus Welby, I'm gonna live?
- No internal injuries.
- I was worried they put a cap in you.
- When I go, I'm taking the world with me.
- Can I talk to you?
- This is my boy CC.
- Hey. I want to go over your lab results.
- It's cool. He can stay.
I got to stay in bed for a week,
be waited on hand and foot.
The LS, uh, spine
series looks good...
but your urine was cloudy.
Is that why it
burns when I whiz?
- You got chlamydia.
- Chlamydia?
The good news is,
it's very treatable.
- You get that from nasty booty, right?
- It's sexually transmitted, yeah.
No, Aisha's clean.
- Got any other partners?
- No, man. I love my girl.
- Are you two practicing safe sex?
- Ain't hurt nobody yet.
- That would be a "no."
- Are you saying Aisha's stepping out?
Well, let's run some more
labs. We'll see where we are.
- I need your consent for the HIV test.
- No, man. She's true.
No, it's standard for
any patient with an STD.
- He needs one of those?
- I'll have the nurse come draw blood.
Whatever. Hey, can I
get some more pudding?
I will see what I can do.
- Abby, can I get a red top in 2?
- Yeah.
- You okay? You look a little...
- Don't say it.
- Tired.
- That seems to be the general consensus.
- Too much clubbing?
- Well, I was up most of the night.
- Really?
- Not for fun.
I don't know, but I think I saw Frank
a little drag-assed this morning too.
You caught me. I was up all
night slapping Frank's ass raw.
- Raw?
- Have you seen him sit down today?
Come to think of it... Hey,
Frank, have you sat down today?
- What?
- Nothing.
- You a little sore today?
- No, why?
Uh, your split lip vagalled when
she saw the lidocaine needle.
- Aisha?
- Mm-hm, the rapper's girlfriend.
Better add on a DNA probe.
He's got chlamydia. Dad, hey.
- John.
- I got your message.
No, I was wondering
if you wanted lunch.
- Dr. Weaver, Romano called again.
- What'd you tell him?
I told him you were tied up.
He said to leave your personal
life at home and get to his office.
No, if you're already at Midway,
I'll just come meet you there.
Yeah. Okay. See you then. Bye.
- John, do you know why Dr. Chen's here?
- Deb's here?
Did she say anything to you?
No. Actually, I haven't
really talked to her lately.
Doctor, uh, listen. I
wanted to ask you...
- can I get me one of them tests?
- What tests?
Chlamydia.
You know that's only, uh,
contagious through sexual contact?
Right.
- Right.
- Okay. Right.
Uh, Abby, can you
start a new chart here?
Sure.
You can never trust these ETAs.
I'm still waiting on that hypotensive TC.
- It got diverted to Mercy.
- Oh, great.
I'm waiting for a chest pain.
- Hey, did you reach her?
- Who?
- Jen.
- Mm-hm.
- What did she say?
- She wants to think about it.
Think about it?
She's her mother.
We can't let Rachel
make these decisions.
Act up, get angry at one and then
punish us by moving back to the other.
You know, you might
consider boarding school.
- She could use some structure.
- Yeah, I could sell her off to pirates.
You develop a sense of
self-worth, community, responsibility.
It worked well for me.
- Yeah, but...
- But what?
You're British.
- Mark, she's out of control.
- Thank you, Elizabeth. I'm aware of that.
Yes. And she's
disrupting our entire life.
I am working on it.
Are you? Or are you just
waiting for it to blow over?
Julio Echeverria, passed out in
the cab line at the Bismark Hotel.
GCS, 14, complaining of
shortness of breath and chest pain.
- Mr. Echeverria, any heart problems?
- I don't think so.
How many am I getting?
- Maybe three more.
- Oh.
You got lucky. These aren't deep.
Whoever did this didn't want to kill you.
- Yeah, I'm well-liked.
- Or you did it yourself.
Misplace that "get
out of jail free" card?
Yeah, something like that.
You're the first woman
I've talked to in 14 months.
Yeah, I get that a lot.
In high school I was voted
"most likely to marry a convict."
- You know, you don't have to do that.
- It could get infected.
Yeah, I wouldn't want to die
before they get a chance to kill me.
- You're on death row?
- Cell number FD414.
Scheduled June 6th, 02.
Almanac says it's gonna rain.
Who believes the weatherman?
Yeah.
Well, at least I know
how, when and where.
Not like all these poor
saps you see every day.
Go to work in the morning
after fighting with their wives.
They never get
the chance to say...
I'm sorry...
or...
goodbye.
Uh...
- I'm out of gauze.
- Would you...? Would you, uh...?
Would you keep me here a while?
Just so...
I don't have to be
there a little bit longer?
Uh...
You might need to be
observed for a couple hours.
Thank you.
Kinney, let her go.
- I'll straighten him out.
- Uh.
It's all right.
- Don't lose my tie. It's a rental.
- Ah, we'll put everything into a bag.
- Where were you going?
- Our Lady of Grace.
Pulse is 90, sats are 95%.
Bilateral crackles
two-thirds of the way up.
- EKG.
- Rather harsh pansystolic murmur.
You have cardiac damage. Maybe
a heart attack started last night.
- I have to go. It's my daughter's wedding.
- I'm afraid you're gonna miss it.
Uh, emesis basin!
And aspirin. Five of Metoprolol.
Probably mitral-valve
regurgitation. We'll need an echo.
Mr. Echeverria, you're
too sick to go anywhere.
We have to put you on a monitor.
Would you like us to call your daughter?
No, don't ruin it.
She'll wonder where you are...
when there's no one
there to give her away.
She won't.
That was fast.
Nucleic-acid
amplification test. It's new.
- What'd it say?
- Positive for chlamydia.
But we can clear that up with
a single dose of azithromycin.
- Is that okay with protease inhibitors?
- You're HIV-positive?
For a year now.
I do the clinics.
- Does Aisha know this?
- Aisha? No.
- Zachery.
- Thanks.
- Uh, are you on the triple cocktail?
- My CD4's pretty good...
but I'm just hoping they'll develop
a once-a-day before too long.
Wait here.
I'm with this girl,
her name was Lydia
She was so freak,
she gave me chlamydia
That ain't even funny.
- Aisha, can you give us a minute?
- Get me a soda, Boo.
- Root beer?
- You know it.
What's up?
- Your rapid HIV test came back.
- Yeah?
Aw, ha-ha.
No way.
- I come here with a bum back, and you...
- I'm sorry.
I don't do needles,
and I ain't no faggot.
You're positive.
How?
I don't know, but Aisha
should be tested too.
- I told you, she's clean.
- She needs to be tested anyway.
I got confidentiality, right?
Mm-hm.
- You can tell her.
- What if I don't want to?
She's at risk. You
need to tell her.
The high-five is heavy. I
ain't letting that word spread.
Dimon, it is really important that we
find out how you contracted the virus.
- No root beer, D. Grape?
- Let's jet.
- You need to sit in the chair.
- This is messed up. We're out of here.
No. Aisha, I need
to look at your lip.
We need to run some tests.
- She's fine.
You could be at risk for STDs.
- At risk?
- What's going down?
- Don't get into it.
- You got it?
- Back off.
- You got to come clean!
- Shut it!
We're past the
fronting here, dog!
- You a punk, dog.
- D, are you tripping?
- Shut up! We're going.
- What are you doing?
Enter.
Ah, Kerry, your response
time is impressive as always.
I didn't know that
we had a meeting.
- You remember Dr. Chen.
- I'm on shift, Robert.
Dr. Chen would
like to be reinstated.
We're fully staffed
at the moment...
but if something opens
up, I'll keep you in mind.
I'm not asking
you to consider it.
It was your choice to step down.
I've changed my mind, then.
I'm sorry that only with
hindsight you decided...
I didn't decide anything. You
decided I was expendable.
I'm not the doctor that
blew out that man's aorta.
No, you're the doctor
who wasn't there.
You were reprimanded
for making a mistake.
The only mistake I made was
allowing you to sacrifice me...
like you did Malucci,
to save your own ass.
Easy, ladies. If I want to see a
good catfight, I'd watch The View.
Let's try to keep this civil.
I respect your abilities as a doctor,
but the position's already been filled.
We're prepared to file suit unless
that and two other conditions are met.
Dr. Chen's record
needs to be expunged.
And an official statement of
correction attached to her file.
- We're trying not to tarnish reputations.
- I don't respond well to threats.
- Dr. Weaver.
- You know what? You can't screw up...
and then whine about being
mistreated. Jing-Mei, you need to grow up.
No, I don't think it's broken...
but I want to get an
x-ray just to be safe.
He's got it, doesn't he?
- What do you mean?
- Dimon. He's got the high-five.
- What?
- HIV.
We can't discuss Dimon's
medical status with anybody but him.
I feel you. But I see he's tripping,
because he never hit me before.
Does he know that
you're HIV-positive?
My viral load's been
zero. He only gives.
I told him, "Wear
a rubber anyway."
He said, "What for?"
It wasn't sex to him.
He's on the DL.
- Uh, the DL?
- Down low.
See, he ain't gay.
You can't be a
faggot and be legit.
He only does guys because
women get so stressful.
Uh, does Aisha know about this?
I was just keeping it going...
waiting for the day he'd
come around and get real.
- I didn't even think about her.
- CC, it's really important we find her.
- She has a pager. I don't know the digits.
- Think you can get it?
- I can try.
- Thank you.
Order a Water's view to
rule out an orbital-rim fracture.
Page me if he gets that number.
- So "down low" is bisexual?
- No, "on the side," "in secret."
- "In the closet"?
- To be in the closet, you have to be gay.
- He is gay.
- Uh, CC's gay. Dimon's on the down low.
Well, if he's having anal
sex with his friend, he's gay.
Not to him. He's got a girlfriend.
He just gets down for release.
- So "down low" means "in denial"?
- Yeah.
Have you injured it before?
- No.
- You feel a pop or a snap?
- Uh, I'm not sure.
Over the bone or to the side?
- Both.
- Okay. There?
- Yeah.
All right, that's a pretty good
sprain. How'd you do that?
Oh. My husband bought
me those roller shoes.
I was practicing
in the apartment.
- It turns out I was worse than I thought.
- Has the swelling increased?
- You triage her?
- We're neighbors. I saw her this morning.
Oh. Could be an avulsion off the
lateral malleolus. Get an ankle series.
Is it broken?
I don't see a fracture, but
Dr. Weaver's gonna have to check it out.
- Am I gonna have to get crutches?
- Maybe until you can bear weight.
You're gonna need help getting
around. How are you getting home?
I called Brian.
It's not all him, you know.
I give as good as I get.
Well, I don't see him sitting
in an ER needing x-rays.
Well, it's not the way it seems.
Our walls are
pretty thin, Joyce.
He's the only guy
I've ever loved.
Will you talk to
a social worker?
Someone with experience who
could maybe help you lay out...
some ways you might
want to deal with this.
Joyce, I think you came here
for a reason. I can help you.
Yeah. I came here because I didn't
want to answer a bunch of questions.
If a patient with the same
history presents again tomorrow...
I expect you to order the
workup I requested today.
- Do you understand?
- Yes.
Dr. Weaver, glad I caught you.
You can go away now.
I was gonna page you, but I couldn't
be sure you'd be wearing your pager.
Robert, you're not gonna be
intimidated by these baseless accusations.
- They have someone on record, Kerry.
- About what?
A waitress at that dump across the street
said you were looking for your pager...
the night Chen and Malucci killed
that guy. That's an important detail.
- Robert...
- I don't need to hear it.
No explanation.
No spin. Just fix it.
- Fix what?
- All she wants is an Attending position...
with standard pay scale and
a personal apology from you.
- I can't do that.
- A first time for everything.
I wouldn't have any
kind of authority over her.
We've settled with
this dead kid's family.
I won't open it up again because
you have a management problem...
created by your own
negligence and deceit.
She's not interested in taking
you down. All she wants is her job.
Give it to her today. And super-glue
the pager to your forehead if you have to.
Excuse me, I'm looking for Julio
Echeverria. He had a heart attack.
- Check in at the desk down the hall.
- Dr. Weaver, I need help in Trauma 2.
- That's Dr. Lewis.
- Sats are dropping.
- What's wrong with him?
- I don't know.
Fifteen liters by mask. Sir, I
need you to take a deep breath.
- Did you get a 12-lead?
- No ischemic changes.
- What happened?
- Decreased breath sounds on the right.
Lung exam was
normal 15 minutes ago.
Is this new?
Yeah, they had to
straighten me out.
Prep for a chest
tube. I need lidocaine.
- What are you doing?
- A broken rib collapsed your lung.
We need to put a tube
in to help you get oxygen.
- No.
- We have to.
- I don't want it.
- You'll die if we don't inflate your lung.
- I don't care. I'm ready.
- Ten blade.
Hold on, Kerry. We need consent.
- I'm done anyway. Please.
- Kerry.
A curved Kelly. Susan,
I need the Kelly now.
Please. They'll
keep beating on me.
Susan, open up
some Vaseline gauze.
Susan, now.
- Sorry. I was looking for a parking place.
- You want a drink? I'm, uh, boarding.
- I should be boarding now.
- Oh. No, thanks.
- So, what's so urgent?
- Nothing really. I was just checking in.
- So how's the new place?
- Sparsely furnished.
But there's something
to be said for that.
For sparseness?
Final boarding...
- for all passengers.
- Clarity.
If I knew your mother
was moving in...
I would have taken some
of the New York furniture.
Yeah. She mentioned to me that
she doesn't have your new number.
Mm.
You should give
her a call, check in.
- Why?
- You were married to her.
She wants to negotiate. Who knows
when she started looking at life...
the way other people read the
stock reports, but, uh, it's over.
I don't think she
shares that assessment.
- You're her ambassador now?
- No.
I'm just suggesting you take time
to make sure this is what you want.
I do. Thanks to you.
- Me?
- I was part of this lie...
this illusion we were living
in order to hold it together.
It took losing Dad and
thinking about what you said...
to make me see that I was lost.
I can't find my
way back with her.
Final boarding call
to all passengers.
I don't know.
I've never, ever seen her
reach out like this before.
That's my flight.
Careful, John, she's
an emotional vampire.
Is he dying?
He's had a pretty big heart attack. He
may need surgery to replace a valve.
Why didn't you tell
me you were coming?
I was scared you
wouldn't want me there.
After all this time, you show up
now? I've got 200 people waiting.
Go. Go.
Be happy.
Six years and nothing?
Why, Papi?
I should have let
you come back home.
It was a mistake.
Why now?
My little girl's
getting married.
It's supposed to be
the best day of my life.
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to ruin it.
And you're not going to.
I'm happy now. Rene
is a wonderful man.
And I don't need you anymore.
Maria?
Miss Echeverria.
I've got the best caterer in
Chicago setting up at the Hilton.
- Let me talk to you.
- Nothing's refundable.
- Your father is very sick.
- I don't care.
- Don't leave it like this.
- He didn't care when I called him...
from Wichita, begging
him to let me come back.
- He wanted to see you get married.
- Look, he abandoned me. Okay?
Turned his back. Nobody does
that. Only a stubborn, heartless man.
- He's trying to reconnect.
- You're not gonna make me cry.
This makeup took three hours.
- He was fine when I left him.
- I didn't touch him.
He has broken ribs
and a collapsed lung.
He was flailing against the
side rails. We had to restrain him.
- With your nightstick?
- Why do you care? He's a murderer.
He killed two teenage
kids on the way to a movie.
Oh, my God. Get it off
of him. What happened?
I was looking at the x-ray,
and he flipped the gurney.
- Are you all right? Help us!
- Chest tube's out of his Thora-Seal.
- Asystole! LEWIS: No, no,
no, he pulled his leads off.
One, two, three.
- Mr. Kinney.
- Low sats. He's dropping to 85.
- Mr. Kinney, open your eyes.
- Blood from the ear canal.
Mr. Kinney?
Left pupil is 9
millimeters and sluggish.
GCS is 1-2-1. Probably
an epidural bleed.
Twenty of etomidate, 100 of sux.
An 8-O ET tube. Bag him, Susan.
- Kerry...
- Get a head CT and call Neurosurgery.
The guy's gonna die in a
couple months by lethal injection.
- Bag him now.
- He asked for no heroic measures.
He's a death-row
inmate attempting suicide.
He can't ask for a DNR.
Tube him now.
Whatever you say, Kerry.
- Hey.
- I got your message.
- Yeah, we've been backed up all day.
- You told me to come by.
Actually, I left another message on your
machine that I'd get back to you later.
Well, I'm here. Okay? I came
to see Marty from the 38th.
- What do you want to say?
- Dr. Weaver, Dr. Chen's looking for you.
Yeah, tell her to wait.
I just wanted to make sure that you
were all right. I heard it was a big fire.
- I'm fine.
- Good. Good.
Can you sign an order for
a social-services consult?
- They won't come without a signature.
- Not now.
Well, it's Joyce Westlake. The ankle.
There is domestic violence involved.
Yeah, I'll come
down and talk to her.
So that's it?
What?
- You're gonna keep playing this game?
- I'm not playing a game.
- So you just want to check on me?
- Is that all right?
Just write the order,
I'll take care of it.
No, I'm the treating
physician. Okay?
- I'm sorry.
- It's all right.
- Why are you avoiding?
- I'm not. Can you tell I'm a bit swamped?
Kerry, excuse me, you want
to talk to me, talk to me. Okay?
I'm not gonna hang
around for your convenience.
- You know, forget it.
- Please wait.
No. Bye. WEAVER:
Let me just check on...
- Sandy...
- You know...
Goodbye, Dr. Weaver.
- You packed me a lunch?
- We call this an escape kit.
Money, medication, phone numbers,
anything you might need is in here.
For what?
In case one night you decide...
you don't feel safe
and you have to get out.
He's my husband. I don't
need that to feel safe.
Okay. Um, but it can't
hurt having it around. Right?
So I'll put it with
the rest of your stuff.
Hi.
Hi. Joyce, this is Adele. She's a
social worker here at the hospital.
- I told you I don't need a social worker.
- In situations like this...
it's policy for me to
interview the patient.
- Situations like what?
- Abby, I need you.
Brian's gonna be here. If
he finds her, he'll get upset.
- Okay, I'll be back.
- Well, has that happened before?
Kid named Ricky gets on the
phone, transfer to Trauma 1.
- Who?
- Choirboy.
He's gonna hold up the
phone from the church vestibule.
Did you see it?
- What?
- Me either, but I heard it was steamy.
Your rehiring will necessitate the
scaling back of the hours of others...
so don't be surprised if your
return is not met with open arms.
I'm sure they'll look to you
for any scheduling complaints.
You start tomorrow at 7.
- A.M.? Hmm.
- P.M.
- You're putting me on overnights.
- Under the circumstances...
I don't think you're in any position
to complain about your schedule.
You know that's not true,
Kerry. So let's stop lying. Okay?
I'm getting my job back
with the following conditions.
- I didn't agree to any conditions.
- I'm returning as an Attending.
I expect shift equity
and equal pay.
I'll report to more experienced
faculty, but not to you.
We both know what you did here.
Yes.
And we know what you did too.
So while we're being
truthful, let me just say...
it's not me with blood on my hands.
If you were a more thorough doctor...
you wouldn't have needed
me there in the first place.
- A kiss could mean anything.
- Not that kind of kiss.
I guess Kinney's gonna
get executed after all.
The inmate. He's in a post-op
coma, not even triggering the vent.
Well, we did what we had to do.
$4000 a day to keep this
guy alive so they can kill him...
hardly seems like the
best use of resources.
You know what? Just save the patient.
I'll worry about our resource management.
Oh, John.
- Is Dr. Carter here?
- Welcome back.
Carter. CHEN: Thank you.
- Aisha. See you tomorrow.
- See you tomorrow.
I got a page. Dimon's always had an
act, but I thought he was real with me.
No, no, I'm just
glad you came back.
- What do you need, Malik?
- Nothing.
Yeah. Well, then why don't
you find something to do.
Warm for January. Maybe we'll
luck out and have a mild winter.
Why are we going this way?
Thought it'd be nice
to walk by the river.
- I have a lot of homework.
- I called your mom today.
And did you tell
her I'm going back?
We talked about it, and I
decided that it wasn't good for us.
- You and me, or you and Mom?
- You and me.
- I don't have a say?
- Maybe in a few years, but no, not yet.
Rachel, I want you to stay here.
I missed too many things in your
life to let you leave angry with me.
I'm your father. I'm not gonna
pass you off when things get rough.
And what makes you
think things will get better?
We both try harder. Neither
one of us is very good at listening.
I just don't want to
be treated like a kid.
Good. I don't want to be
treated like an old man.
- Brian? Brian? BRIAN:
Hi. What happened?
Hi. Uh, everything's okay. Uh,
Joyce's ankle was bothering her.
She sprained it pretty badly.
I told her those things don't have
ankle support. She's not a great skater.
They can be dangerous.
Listen, I'm sorry you got pulled
into this little domestic drama.
- I think you got the wrong idea.
- Evidently, I did.
We have tempers. And once
in a while things get out of hand.
- This is really none of my business.
- If it infringes on your life, it is.
Our neighbor in San Francisco
thought there was an earthquake.
It was just Joyce smashing all
my softball trophies because...
I went to a game instead of going out
with her folks when they were in town.
Right.
They told me Room
3. It's over here.
Yeah, it is. Uh, Joyce
is almost finished.
You could pull your car
around, and I could wheel her out.
- And we can meet you.
- I can get her.
But it's a long walk
to the parking lot.
And she's really supposed to stay
off the ankle for a day or two. So...
Well, is there a problem?
- Abby?
- I'll, uh, talk to you later.
Mm-hm. ABBY: Thank you.
- Hey, baby. How's it going?
- Better. The throbbing stopped.
Did they give you lots of drugs?
- A few.
- You hungry?
- A little. Yeah.
Why don't we go
over to Angelino's...
and get some pasta,
a bottle of merlot?
- Mm. I feel more like a cheeseburger.
- Ah, it's your call.
- Thanks, Abby.
- Uh, is this yours, Joyce?
No, I have what I came with.
Bye.
- Who are you? LOPEZ:
We got a call, Kerry.
- No. I mean, who the hell are you?
- I live my life without apologies.
Right. You make choices for your
life. You don't make choices for mine.
I didn't choose to be lied
to or have my time wasted.
- I never misrepresented myself.
- You pretend to be something you're not.
- Lopez, let's go!
- You know what?
It's my employees, my
colleagues, my workplace.
I choose to keep my
private life to myself.
You can't separate who
you are from what you do.
- That is not your decision to make.
- I stand up and face it every day.
You want the life without hardship.
You don't get one without the other.
Not with me anyway.
So you did this out of spite to
teach me some kind of lesson?
I did you a huge favor.
You just don't know it yet.
- What are you doing?
- The light went out.
- Why don't you tell Henry?
- I'm not incompetent.
I'm capable of
changing a light bulb.
- Damn it.
- Here. Come down from there. I'll get it.
- No, screw it. I'll get it later.
- Whoa.
Have you been drinking?
Um. Norman Tucker
sent Millicent a bottle...
of 40-year-old Bordeaux
as a get-well gift.
And you what,
helped her open it?
I spent the entire afternoon at that
children's cancer center for Millicent.
There was this, uh, one boy...
I came home, and I made the
mistake of getting in the middle...
of an argument between
Millicent and her physical therapist.
Yeah, Gam's having a little
trouble losing her independence.
Whoa. Hey, hey, hey. Sit down.
She told me that my presence
was, in fact, hindering her recovery...
that if she needed a caregiver I
would be the last person she'd call.
That's a defense mechanism.
- What are you doing?
- Checking your pulse.
Did you speak to your father?
Sixty and weak. Are
you taking something?
Xanax.
- He's giving up on me.
- When did you start taking Xanax?
- I have a prescription.
- And you took it with alcohol.
- How many pills did you take, Mom?
- I'm so sorry.
I'm sorry. You shouldn't
have to go through this.
How many?
Two.
I just took two.
She asked me to leave.
Do you want me to leave, John?
No.
You're right.
I've failed you.
I failed your brother.
- And then I failed you.
- Mom...
- He was tired before we left for France.
- That was 20 years ago.
Millicent insisted he just
needed some fresh air.
He'd been inside all winter.
It delayed the diagnosis
by less than a month.
It wouldn't have
changed anything.
I was his mother.
I just stood by while
it was eating him alive.
I just stood by.