I am telling you, once we
got these doctors talking,
it was a horror show.
Shh. I just got Sofia back down.
Oh, and Portland
Gen has quotas now.
Yeah. It's unspoken,
but it's understood
that you have to churn out a
certain number of procedures.
And no research?
Nope. Pegasus is only interested
in high-volume,
high-price-tag procedures.
Barely any patient interaction.
So no research, no innovation,
no opportunity to do what it
is we got into medicine to do.
Well, we won't let
that happen to us here.
Oh, yeah? That's
what they said at first.
And then the people that
fought management got fired,
and the rest wore
down or they left.
They say there's one sure
sign of a successful negotiation.
Now, I don't want to
leave. None of us do.
You guys, come on.
We have to do this.
We have to buy the hospital.
Hold on.
Maybe she's right. Just wait.
It's that when the
parties leave the table...
What if we don't want to?
They both feel like
they've been screwed.
Yes. Oh, yes.
Is it, is it this?
Or... Or that?
Oh, that. Oh, exactly that.
The goal is a compromise...
Okay.
Your turn.
A situation where
everybody wins.
I'm sorry. It's never been
my dream to run a hospital.
Okay, well, you might
not have to run it.
Cristina should be here.
I have been texting her.
I just got back to work.
And, Derek, you just
got your hand back.
Don't you want to just work?
Work where?
I don't want somebody telling me
which patients I
can and can't treat.
Or putting a stopwatch on how
much time you can spend with them.
Yeah, if we ran the place,
we could make policy
decisions based on experience.
No offense, but that is
a naive way of putting it.
The job is much
harder than you think.
I wanted it once,
and I hated it.
We should stay the course.
I made a deal with Pegasus
that apparently will help the sale.
What deal? Nothing, it's stupid.
But maybe that's how we
make it work, from the inside.
What about Hunt?
I mean, he's pushing
for the Pegasus sale.
He thinks it's a good deal.
So what's he gonna say?
Oh, it's Cahill.
You know, she just
wants to strategize.
At 3:00 a.m.?
I bet she does.
You know the nurses
are threatening a walkout,
and I have to talk them down?
You know what? No.
Let's just not talk about this.
I just want to be here
for a few hours with you
where there are no problems.
Okay.
You know, the sale to
Pegasus closes in three days.
And Cahill says the
buyers are getting twitchy,
and if there's a mass
exodus of the staff,
even if there's a tiny exodus,
I mean, basically
if anybody leaves,
then the buyers
are gonna back out,
and we lose the sale, and...
The hospital closes.
That's not gonna happen.
You sure?
You can be a little more...
Maybe?
Convincing. Okay.
That's not going to happen.
What are we talking about,
like $100 million, $200 million?
You know what
we're talking about.
We have more than we're ever
gonna be able to spend anyway.
We have more
than we'll ever be...
- No, that's not true.
- But I don't know.
This is a massive undertaking.
Nobody knows
what it's gonna cost.
So what are you saying?
Are you saying that
they take everything?
I mean, everything from
the lawsuit, from all of us?
I have no idea what it's gonna
cost to buy Seattle Grace,
but I can guarantee you
it's more than the four
of us have combined. I...
That's only $60 million.
I had some money before
all this. I've got about...
700 grand I can
get to right away.
It's true. We have money in
the IRA. And we have about...
No, let's not get
ahead of ourselves.
Well, just the lawsuit
damages then.
And we've got Mark's share, too.
Mark's share?
Yeah, and Lexie's
maybe? Is that rude of me...
I mean, I would have to
ask her... Our, our father...
Don't worry. Excuse me.
Yes, this is rude of you.
Okay, I'm sorry, but we can't
waste time on politeness here.
And Mark's share is not
our money. It's Sofia's.
You should've talked
about this with me...
That's what we're doing.
I mean privately with your wife.
Where is Cristina?
I don't know. I
keep texting her.
She would say yes to this.
- How do you know that?
- She knows.
Leave us alone.
Get some sleep.
This isn't all on
your shoulders.
It shouldn't be.
It is right now. If I can't...
You know, if I can't talk
the nurses into staying...
You will.
I just don't know
what's gonna happen,
with or without Pegasus.
I keep running through the
worst-case scenarios and...
All I know is...
That I'm happy here with you.
Whatever's falling
apart, I just...
You and I, we're...
We're safe.
Right. Right?
Exactly right.
I don't think that it's right
to spend all of our money.
It is an investment.
Of all of our money, Callie.
If your parents had ever
made you have a summer job...
Oh, come on. That is so
unfair. You might understand.
No, you are ready
to bankrupt us.
You're ready to let Pegasus
Horizons turn us into a bunch of robots.
You are ready to sink $50
million into maintaining a good vibe.
So what's the
alternative? We leave?
No, I don't want to leave.
This hospital is not
something that we lucked into.
This is something that we made.
And Webber hired
us, and he set a tone.
Hunt sets a tone,
and it's something I
am proud to be a part of,
and it's worth fighting for.
Shoot. Sorry. Is
that mine or yours?
It's mine, but she's
gonna wake yours.
I think Callie's right.
This isn't about a
financial investment.
It's a much bigger
opportunity... Right.
To stay and make the place
we dreamed of work again.
Yes. Oh, God.
Will you two stop it?
We are not spending this money.
If I have learned
anything in the past year,
it's that we don't get to know
what's coming around the corner.
Anything can happen,
to you, to me. Anything.
And our daughter deserves as
much protection as we can give her.
And we have the chance
to not have to worry
no matter what happens,
a chance to be prepared
should the worst happen...
I don't want to
live like that...
Getting ready for disasters
that may never happen.
Well, we have an opportunity
right now to do something about it.
And maybe we have a
responsibility to do that...
Oh, don't try and
make me feel selfish.
Don't try and make me feel
guilty just because you do.
Who said I felt guilty?
I think, I think
you feel guilty.
But that's not, it's not...
No, no, no, no,
no. Let's go ahead.
Tell me.
Some of us died.
And some of us are
gonna live with challenges
for the rest of their life.
And you, you got the money.
And then you got your hand
back and you got your career back,
and I think that
you feel guilty.
I think you feel guilty
about your decision to sue
and I think that you feel guilty
about having all this money.
And now I think that
you want to be the one
that comes in and saves everyone,
and you have to be the hero.
And it's selfish and
it's egomaniacal,
and now it's
affecting my family.
So just stop. Okay?
Everything that you've
done to make it better
has actually made it
worse. So please stop.
I think we should go.
You should.
Hey, Derek, I owe
you an apology.
Oh, no. There's no
need. No, no, I do.
It was late, and I was
tired and stressed out.
Well, we were all stressed out.
We're just trying
to do our best.
No, I know, but I had no
right to call you egotistical.
It was "egomaniacal," I think.
Yeah. I was out of line.
On the other hand...
You're Pegasus'
"Face of the Hospital"?
Cahill said it would
be some brochures,
some schmoozing,
not... All of this.
Not a whole lot of
practicing medicine either.
I hope you know
what you're in for.
No offense, Derek. I
mean, it's a great face, but...
This is a lot of it.
I mean, this is kind of gross.
This is unacceptable.
Dr. Shepherd, hold up!
Yeah? Love the picture.
Love it. Your head is gigantic.
I'm prepping for our AVM.
Do you prefer OR two or four?
He's doing an AVM
under hypothermic arrest
where he drops the brain's
temperature to avoid stroke risk.
I know what it is.
He's the only one in
the region who does it.
I've always wanted to see
it up close. Can we go now?
I'm not doing it. Cahill
wants me to meet the buyers.
He's the new face of the hospital
now. And the hair. Lucky us.
Great. Just make it go away.
Oh. Oh, my God.
Can we talk about the
giant pictures of myself?
Do you love them? I
want 'em down, all of them.
I agreed to a brochure.
"And other marketing materials
and collateral." This is that.
What are you ashamed of?
Telling people
that your hospital
is more than just
a set of clinically
sterilized walls and equipment?
That it is full of people
who are intelligent
and passionate
about caring for them?
'Cause that is what
your face tells people.
Says who?
Well, three focus
groups can't be wrong.
So just give it a few days.
You'll get used to you.
You ready for the nurses? Mmm.
Marcia Lowe to CTU...
It means a lot to me, Derek.
I know this is not you. I
know this is a sacrifice,
but this sale is our last shot,
and I feel like I've been
fighting this battle alone.
And to have you in
the fight with me...
That means a lot.
I don't, uh...
I don't want to do this anymore.
Oh. Oh, um...
No, no, no, no.
No, no, not, not this.
I want to do this. Lots of this.
I just don't want
to do it... Here.
I want to take
you out on a date.
Someplace that doesn't have...
Wheels...
Yes, okay. That would be nice.
And where fewer people
have bled to death.
Oh, well, now I'm totally sold.
Tonight?
Okay. Great.
I can't wait to see you
out of those clothes.
I meant scrubs.
Uh, in regular clothes.
Not that you don't
look great in scrubs,
'cause you would
look great in anything.
Like coveralls or a parka.
7:30?
7:30.
Oh, and if I'm late,
it's because I'm still
banging my head
into a wall over
how this just went.
It went great.
Could be a volvulus.
Let's intubate and
put in an NG tube.
Draw .8 of etomidate.
When was the baby delivered?
Twenty-five minutes ago.
Vomiting, distended abdomen.
I need those films back, stat.
Give me the etomidate.
Sedatives in a newborn
need a light touch,
so I like to do it myself.
Shh. Shh, shh. It's okay,
buddy. You go to sleep.
I promise you won't
remember any of this crap.
What are you smiling
about? Nothing.
Cut it out. We need
to tell his parents
their brand-new
baby needs surgery.
His bowels have twisted
around the blood supply,
causing an obstruction.
So...
We need to do an emergency
surgery to correct that immediately.
So... We are going to...
Do that.
Mr. Finch, uh, can I speak
with you outside for a sec?
I know this is a lot to take.
Are you and your wife okay?
Who, Langer?
I don't know. I don't
know her that well.
That's my kid, but she...
But she's not my wife.
We work together.
We hooked up one time.
We tore one off
at an office party...
And his condom breaks
because he's too cheap
and stupid to buy decent ones.
I'm almost 40, I want
a baby, so I told him,
"You're off the hook,
but I'm keeping it."
And he says that he
wants to do the right thing.
I'm gonna raise that baby.
I mean, financially, yeah,
but I'm gonna be there.
I want to, you know...
Be a father to that kid.
He's a complete asshat,
but he makes a good living.
She's a bitch on wheels,
but she's smart and she's
tough. A kid could do worse.
And right now all I
care about is my baby.
Is my baby gonna be okay?
Tell me my kid's gonna
be okay. Can you do that?
Whoa.
So the chemo didn't work?
Just like the radiation.
A.J.'s cancer has
continued to spread.
So what, surgery now?
I mean, you said that
surgery could kill him.
You said he was too weak.
Well, Dr. Bailey here is
suggesting another approach.
Yeah, it's called
genome mapping.
If we can identify the
specific DNA sequence
of A.J.'s tumor,
it could open up a
variety of treatment options
and targeted drug therapies.
And no surgery?
You can do that here?
Uh, no, not yet.
We would have to contract
out to another facility.
I'm just waiting for approval
from the hospital advisory board,
and I think we'll
have that today.
We would just need to
have your consent to try...
Um... We will
take this as a "yes."
Okay.
Okay, I have salary
and bonus breakdowns,
benefits packages,
pension stuff...
Don't be nervous.
I'm not. I can
talk to my people.
Well, I hope so, 'cause
if not, we're in trouble.
You trying to make me nervous?
Hey, Dr. Hunt?
Uh, Bailey, I have to...
No, I just wondered
what you heard back
from the advisory board.
Uh, about?
About my genome mapping.
The request I
submitted to sequence...
Right, right. Sorry.
Um, they turned it down.
Well, no, no, no. It's,
it's just one sequence...
It's a "No." For...
Sorry.
Okay, so what is
the big secret plan?
We want to pool our
winnings from the lawsuit
and buy the hospital.
I was hoping you'd be on board.
Maybe I misspoke.
So that is the plan?
Yes.
That is so stupid!
You don't know the first
thing about owning a hospital
or running one,
and neither do I.
Well, Pegasus Horizons
knows how not to run a hospital.
I mean, you should
hear Callie's stories.
It's this or go somewhere else.
No. No one leaves.
Owen says if
people start leaving,
the sale won't go through,
and we're screwed.
That's why we want to buy it,
because we're doctors,
and we know how it runs.
Did you know you'll have to
file a declaration for land use
for approval by the
state attorney general?
Will we? I don't know.
I just made that up.
But see? We don't
know anything about this.
I'm surprised. I thought
you'd be on board.
Or you'd leave again.
Hey, no one leaves.
Owen is killing himself trying
to keep the hospital open.
Can we please stop talking
nonsense and have his back?
Hey. Our, uh, panniculectomy
was discharged. Said to say thanks.
Liposuction day?
High-volume, high-price-tag,
'cause when Pegasus
trims the fat, so do I.
What's the matter?
Nope. Can't talk about it.
Why, 'cause of her?
Mrs. Berkus.
Mrs. Berkus!
She's blotto. What's up?
No, I can't talk
about it to you.
I could when we
were friends, but now...
We seriously can't
be friends now?
Yes, we can. Just...
This is too much.
How about this?
I will tell you a thing I would
tell you when we were friends.
My mom, she is driving me nuts
about taking a bigger role in
the Harper Avery Foundation.
"Grow up, child.
Get your legacy on."
It's not bad advice.
I know that, but I'm
working my ass off here,
and I'm not even
an attending yet.
You know what?
You're a crappy friend.
You're supposed to side with me.
See? Now you go.
Um...
So I've been seeing
this paramedic.
I'm aware.
Too much? No.
I told you I was seeing
Stephanie the intern.
Was that too much?
No. I mean, it's not a thing.
It's just, you know, fun and...
We're not serious.
We both know how that
can turn out. That is true.
Okay, your turn.
Okay. So...
He asked me out... On a date,
like our first real date.
And it's really,
like, our fifth date.
And, and this real date
is probably gonna wind
up at someone's apartment.
And it's... Going in a
direction, you know?
And it's one thing to tell a guy
that you're a virgin and
hope he understands,
but to tell him
that I was a virgin
and then wasn't
and now am again...
I just feel like there's no way
he's gonna understand that.
I mean, who understands that?
But I really like him and I just...
It's all gonna end tonight.
Oh, God. Too much.
Nope.
Oh, way too much, April.
Look, tell him exactly
what you told me,
and he won't care whether
you're a virgin or not.
He won't?
He'll be worried
you're mentally ill,
because you
sound like a nut job.
Good to have you back, pal.
Hey, I'm kidding.
No, I know. See ya.
Come on, April.
I guide the parachute
into the heart,
open it...
So it will block off the damage
caused by his heart attack.
It should keep
the rest of his heart
from working so
hard while it heals.
That is crazy balls.
I'm in position now.
What did your friend
at UC Davis say?
Are the other interns
still dropping like flies?
Yeah. There's at
least four openings.
What are you talking about?
Mousy, speak.
Um... Some of us
are talking about...
Looking elsewhere.
Why?
Last year, Seattle Grace
was the residency match
you dreamed of getting.
The last few weeks, it feels
like automotive trade school.
God.
Where is your sense of loyalty?
There are people here
fighting to make sure
this hospital stays open at all.
And at the first sign of trouble,
you show them your ass?
No. No, it's just that...
I'm sorry.
I only have five years to get
as good at this as I possibly can.
And I want to be excellent.
I want to be the best, so I
can't waste another minute.
I mean, would you have
when you were an intern?
Honestly?
There's the volvulus.
All right. Retract
there. I'll dissect.
Do you think they can work,
workplace relationships?
What? What do you mean?
Look at these two,
coworkers who wanted
a quickie and got a baby.
Well, they both seem
to want the baby.
Yeah, but they don't
want each other.
And now they're
stuck seeing each other
at the kid's recitals
and at staff meetings?
It's a disaster, right?
I don't know.
Everybody's different.
True.
You've had relationships
with coworkers.
Yeah. And look
how those played out.
You're single and alone.
When I met you, you had
a mattress and one bowl.
Come on. That's...
Yeah, well...
It's just... More trouble
than it's worth, right?
What happened?
Hematoma on the liver. It burst.
2-0 chromic.
Crap. It's tearing.
Pack him. Pack him gently.
I need thrombin and fibrin glue.
Get some factor VII in here now.
Right away, Doctor.
I got your page. I thought
you weren't doing the AVM.
Oh, we're not.
Pegasus wants to do some
photos of me in surgery.
It's not real. You
know, it's just pretend.
But we need some more bodies. I
thought you'd like to come in there.
Uh...
With all due respect,
sir, may I not?
What?
Dr. Yang's testing
a new protocol.
I'd learn more from watching
that than pretending to do surgery.
I mean, if you
really need me to...
No.
It's okay. Go.
Thank you.
This is ridiculous.
I have had the same
schedule for six years.
And now we're splitting shifts?
My husband works two jobs.
Who picks up my kid now?
Pegasus breaks
up shifts differently.
I don't need this.
And we get shafted.
I'm not taking this.
Who's taking this?
If you know how to talk to your
people, you should start now.
I am. They keep coming
back... Cahill, chief.
Look, I'm sorry, but
this is not gonna work.
No, Shepherd. I'm sorry. I've
been waiting for 20 minutes.
Chief, I just wanted to ask you
again about the genetic screening.
Bailey, I'm sorry...
All right, look, I am
trying to work with you.
But I'm not gonna reschedule my
surgeries so I can do a photo op.
Maybe when this hospital is
on a firmer financial footing...
No, this isn't about me
looking for extra credit.
This is about a specific... No,
you have enough pictures of me.
Bailey... I want...
Now look, if you
just read the chart,
then you can talk
to the stupid board...
Bailey... And make
them understand...
Bailey, they
didn't say no. I did.
I didn't bring it up to them
because it will not be approved.
So we're just gonna...
The answer's no, Bailey.
Yes, sir.
Never mind then.
What is it, Shepherd?
Nothing. I'm good.
It's Derek Shepherd.
I have an idea, a crazy idea,
and I need you to
tell me how crazy.
Whoa. This isn't weird.
I know. I wanted to
meet outside the hospital.
And then with the rain...
No, I like it. It's very
cloak-and-daggery.
You must be Dr. Torres. Oh, God!
Callie Torres, Stan Grossberg.
He's my financial advisor.
I think I might have
died for a second.
I asked him about the
feasibility of our idea.
Stan, tell her what you told me.
Under federal law,
physicians cannot own
and run the hospital
for which they work.
So we're hosed.
However, you could ally
yourselves with a for-profit
or not-for-profit agency,
which would be owner pro forma.
Then the five of you could form
your own management company,
which would be hired
by this foundation.
So we're not hosed.
Basically, you would run
the day-to-day operations,
much like a board of directors.
And again I ask,
who wants to do that?
Just let him finish.
I'm sorry, but I'd rather be in
an operating room
than a boardroom.
Besides, I thought we didn't have
enough money to do this anyway.
Well, I'm working on that.
Estimating the number of beds,
the overall operating budget,
the property and business taxes,
the franchise tax
board payments...
Okay, right, right, right. I'm
asking, is it possible for us to do?
That's what he's
saying. It is possible.
It is very possible.
Okay, well, how much
more money would we need?
That's what I was
saying, I don't know.
Not until I see a hospital
financial statement.
How do we get that?
Owen can get that for us.
Um...
If we have a hope of
outbidding Pegasus,
the element of surprise
is sort of crucial here.
Owen can't know any of this.
We're gonna go behind
Owen's back to steal the hospital?
No, Owen will still be Chief.
He's legally obligated
to tell them of anything
that might interfere
with the sale.
He signed non-competes,
non-disclosures.
If he breaches them,
they will fire him.
They will sue him.
There could even be jail time.
He can't know any of this.
You want me to lie to him.
No, I want you to just
not say anything for now.
You want me to lie to him.
The nurses aren't being
unreasonable. They have valid concerns.
And I'm worried that you don't
know how to address those concerns.
Yeah, well, I'm worried
you're asking me
to sell them something
that I don't even believe in.
You're a doctor.
You know sometimes you
have to swallow some bitter pills
in order to get well.
This is a bad pill.
Yeah, well, why
don't you tell 'em that?
They need to hear it
from someone they trust.
Okay.
Do you remember last week
when we operated, the logger?
Before that, I didn't
think that I ever would
or could step up to
an OR table again.
I was scared the whole time.
As scared as I have
ever been in my life.
I had no idea. I know.
The only reason I
was able to do it...
Was because you were there.
And I barely even knew you.
But you were so calm and sure.
And if you were
okay, I would be okay.
Not many people
have this quality.
What happened? Can I ask?
It's not a good story.
Sorry. It's none of my business.
No, I mean, it's not
an interesting story.
You've heard it a hundred times.
I choked is all.
Listen...
I am good at this job.
So you can believe
me when I tell you
that only you can help
these people understand
that something that
hurts them in the short run
will help them in the long run.
When you tell someone
that everything will be okay,
they'll trust you.
You know you hold
this place together.
Every doctor and every
patient here knows that.
I know that you are
the cornerstones.
I need you to be strong
right now in this transition.
Transitions are scary, I know.
But believe me, I...
I would not be asking
you to go through this
if I did not believe that what
Pegasus Horizons offers
is the best thing for all of us.
I mean, if I didn't, I
would leave with you.
I'm asking you to stay,
trust me,
work with me.
Just...
Help me get us through this.
Can we do that?
We can try.
Right?
I'll try.
Give it a go.
I can try to repair the liver,
but it's incredibly delicate,
and there's a high risk that it
will be permanently damaged.
And the baby dies.
It's a risk.
The other option
is, we sit tight
and hope the bleeding
stops on its own.
And hope he survives that.
What? What, what?
Say something.
Decide.
Well, I say we wait.
Don't do anything.
Right.
No, that's stupid.
Do the surgery.
No, I don't know.
I don't know. I can't...
I can't decide.
I can't. I can't do this.
You do it. I can't.
Hey, hey, hey!
Listen,
we both decide.
Okay? I'm scared, too.
I'm as scared as you are,
but you are the biggest,
meanest, ball-busting,
ice-queen, nightmare
bitch that I have ever met.
So if I can do this, you can.
Okay?
Let's...
Wait.
Okay.
Can I have a glass
of water, please?
And a maxi pad for
my girlfriend here.
Nice.
Look at that.
It's bad enough that
they're up there at all,
and now I have
to deal with this?
We'll put a stop to it. I'll
have this one taken down.
I want them all taken down.
I didn't do it.
Do you believe it?
What do you mean?
What you said to the nurses,
"Pegasus will lead us
to a brighter tomorrow."
Do you really believe that?
It is the only option that we...
It's just us now. It's me.
No.
No, okay? No. No, I don't.
It's a bitter pill, and we
just have to swallow it.
And honestly, I don't even know
if this is gonna make
us better or worse.
Then why are you fighting
so hard for something...
There's no other choice.
This is our only shot.
Okay, but what, what
if it wasn't, though?
What if it's not all on
you to fix everything...
But it is. It is all on me.
No, Owen, Owen, listen...
I put you all on that plane.
I'm sorry. It's... Cahill.
Yeah.
What?
Today?
No, no, no, no, no. No, that is,
that's... Amazing.
I'll come find you. Okay.
What?
It's almost over.
This is so stupid.
This is the only way I can
think of getting in there.
So we're in a heist movie now?
Stan needs to see the
financial statements.
I will schmooze,
distract, and then you...
What, stick one down my shirt?
I don't know.
All right, just... Let's
go. Get me in there.
Gentlemen and ladies,
I'm sorry to interrupt you,
but I'd like to introduce you
to my wife, Dr. Meredith Grey.
What a pleasure it
is to meet you, sir.
Oh, my goodness.
I'm so sorry. Meredith.
Oh, no. I am so sorry.
I am a little clumsy.
They are not approving
the genome mapping at this time.
But you said that...
We were sure that it was
gonna go the other way.
So I'm sorry.
So now we're
back to a colectomy.
I want to wait another
day to see if A.J. improves,
but... It needs to be soon.
Is that our only option?
Yeah, I'm afraid that that's...
No. There's one other option.
You can go someplace
that will find an approach
that works for him,
someplace that will give
him the care that he deserves.
He won't get that
here. I say leave.
Leave Seattle Grace and
go someplace else, fast.
What the hell was that?
That was the only medical advice
I could give them
in good conscience.
I'm thinking I need
to take it myself.
Whoa. What are
you talking about?
I tried. I tried to
put on the smile
and knuckle down
and make it work,
but maybe I can get a job in
LA, be where my husband is,
and Tuck...
Tuck's dad's never gonna let
me move him out of the city...
No, no, maybe I
can talk to him, right?
Maybe we can work something out.
Stop it. Stop it. You and
Tuck aren't going anywhere.
I don't want to
work here anymore.
It makes me feel small.
I have to make myself
smaller to work here.
I feel like if I do that,
I feel like I won't want
to look my son in the eye.
I don't recognize
this place anymore
or the people.
I don't want to hang
around long enough
that I don't recognize myself.
I've had some sucky jobs here,
but doing nothing sucks the worst.
Shh.
If his SATs stay above
93 for one more minute,
he's out of the woods.
I think it could work.
What can?
You know, people,
coworkers getting together.
I mean, don't judge
it from those lawyers.
They don't even like each other.
Look at Grey and Shepherd.
I mean, they tried to avoid it,
but it was like
fate or whatever.
They had to be together.
It was just right, you know?
That's beautiful.
You should write
poetry or greeting cards.
I'm just saying it could
work. Ten seconds.
You have a blog that I
could follow? Shut up.
You ever write poems about
horses, just pretty, pretty horses?
Shut up. Five...
Four, three, two...
One.
Yes. Yes.
Shh.
Oh, shut up.
I'm sorry? No, not you. Sorry.
April.
Tell him who you are.
If he doesn't get it, then
you don't need him anyway.
But I really like him, and...
I think if I tell him,
it's all gonna be over.
So wait...
A little while, let him
get to know you better.
Once he does, he's gonna
want to follow you anywhere.
Trust me.
Thank you.
I could marry you
again right now.
You're so hot when
you're nefarious. Hold on.
Arizona wants to
meet with all of us.
Where is our van?
Someone moved it. Why?
It's what vans are
for. Bailey's quitting.
What?
If this can happen, we need
to make this happen, fast.
Wait, wait. Are you in?
I'm in.
So what's the next step?
Well, we don't
have enough money.
We're gonna have to find
the rest somewhere else.
Can we do that in three days?
Two now. What about
Cristina, is she in?
I don't know now.
Well, ask her.
It's happening, tonight.
Pegasus wants to
move up the closing.
They want to buy
the hospital tonight.
What? DEREK: How do you know?
Owen told me. Well, did
you say anything to him?
No, I didn't say anything,
but we have to do it, for Owen.
We have to do this now.
Before tonight? We can't.
No, there's not enough time.
We have to stop them.
How? There's
nothing that we can do.
There's one thing we can do.
Hey!
Stop right there.
We're thrilled.
Very excited.
Shall we start?
First is the letter of intent.
Sign here. Initial here.
Oh, Dr. Shepherd.
Come in. We were just...
Sorry to interrupt. I'd like to
talk to Dr. Hunt for a second.
What's up?
Guys?
I'd like to tender
my resignation,
effective immediately.
Me, too. I quit.
I quit, too.
Me, too.
He thinks we stabbed
him in the back.
Well, all we did
was buy some time
to slow down the sale so we
can come up with the money.
I know. I know.
All right, Stan says he
can meet with us now.
Okay, I'll go get my stuff.
Yeah, we get all our
stuff 'cause we just quit.
What about our patients?
We'll get 'em
covered by someone.
Dr. Shepherd,
this young man has
something to say to you.
Did you get them all?
Pretty much.
Good work, Ross. Go home.
Something's going on here.
What's going on?
You'll know soon.
Did you see the
look on his face?
Oh, Richard will be fine.
No, Owen.
This is wrong. I'm gonna go
talk to him. I have to explain.
No. Cristina, no.
It's the right thing
to do, for his sake.
When the time is
right, we'll tell him,
and he'll understand.
I don't know if he will.
Wait.
Nothing. Never mind. Sorry.
Okay, we should, um...
We should, though,
uh, stop.
Um...
Okay, there's something
I have to tell you.
And I don't want to,
'cause I think it might
be the last I see of you.
Oh...
This is... This is only
gonna go so far tonight.
God.
'Cause I am, uh...
Saving myself for marriage.
Oh, God.
Oh, dear God.
Yeah, I know.
It's, it's weird
and it's not something
you hear every day,
but it is something
that I believe in.
And I can completely understand
if you can't hang with that.
No. No, I can.
I can hang. I do.
I...
I am, too.
Are... Are you messing
with me right now?
'Cause...
No. No. No.
I am, too.
Only there's, um...
There's just this one thing.
What?
Nothing.
I am, too.
What the hell was that?
Did you know that they
were gonna pull that?
There's a way to salvage this.
Salvage what?
They withdrew the offer.
Losing those surgeons,
losing Shepherd,
completely changes
the value of the hospital.
You'd better do
something and fast.
I, um...
There's, there's no way
that we can replace
them. There's...
I can't reposition.
I can't find new buyers.
By tomorrow morning, the
whole industry will know.
I can't. I can't.
You have to. I can't.
You say this is
what you're good at.
It better be, because everyone
that I thought was in my corner
just walked out, and you
are all that I have now.
So either go and get Pegasus
back or find another buyer.
You say you trust me.
Then trust me when I say
you can do this,
because you have to.
They say that
negotiation is an art form.
Yet, when we negotiate...
His BP looks good.
His labs look great.
We'll watch him
closely overnight,
but I think he's
gonna be just fine.
- Thank you.
We have a strategy,
we use tactics.
All right, can you please move
your fat head so I can get a look?
Tool.
That's gonna be fun.
I'm especially excited
for that kid's next 18 years.
Hey, you want to go get a beer?
Oh, I would love to,
especially after today,
but, um, I actually
already have plans.
Tomorrow night? Is that cool?
Yeah, that's cool. Okay.
Hey. Who is that guy? Hmm?
That is...
Chest Peckwell.
What?
It's not his real name. We just
called him that before we knew it.
OB resident.
Jo's been mooning over
the guy since he got here,
and she finally grew herself
a pair and asked him out.
Yay, Jo.
She didn't tell you about him?
Yeah, she did.
Okay.
"Strategies" and "tactics"
aren't words we use for
seeking a compromise.
Cristina!
Those are words
for going to war.
The first thing you'll need
to do is to form an LLC
so that you can legally get
all your funds from one place.
And you'll need a name
for your new corporation.
What did we just do?
Do you know what you'd
like to call yourselves?
How about The Bitter Pills?
Epic Failure?
Death Spiral?
Blind Leading the
Blind, Incorporated?
It could be anything.
Let's keep thinking.