- Hi, there.
It's me, Ryan Eggold.
I play Dr. Max Goodwin
on "New Amsterdam."
We are very proud to bring you
our season two finale.
It's a good one.
But first, I want to take
a moment
to thank all the healthcare
professionals
who right now are working
their buns off
to keep everyone safe.
You guys are our inspiration
for every story
we tell every episode we make,
and now you are everyone's
inspiration,
so thank you, and keep up
the heroic work
that you are doing.
We all dearly appreciate it.
It's because of that admiration
and a sense of caution
that we decided not to air
tonight's
originally scheduled episode,
which was titled "Pandemic."
It hit a little too close
to home,
and we didn't want to make
entertainment
out of a story that's
a little too scary,
a little too real
at the moment.
But we're gonna show you
that episode later
once some time has passed.
But the good news is
that we're gonna show you
a little teaser
from that episode
because it introduces
one of our newest characters
played by the incomparable
Mr. Daniel Dae Kim,
who I would like to hand it to
right now.
- Thanks, Ryan.
And aloha, everybody.
Ryan is absolutely right.
The storyline you're about
to see
introduces my character,
Dr. Cassian Shin.
Now what we've done is pulled
together
all of Cassian's scenes
to give you a sense of his
character
and how he's gonna change
more than a few things
around the hospital.
As you guys may know,
this storyline
turned out to be very personal
to me
because I ended up contracted
COVID-19,
the disease caused by
coronavirus,
while I was in New York
shooting this very episode.
Now, thankfully, I was
fortunate enough
to have experienced
a full recovery.
But too many others have not.
So on behalf of the entire
casting crew,
we'd like to dedicate
this season finale
to those still fighting
the illness.
We're rooting for you.
- How can I help?
- We're down two
trauma surgeons.
I had to call in our new hire
a week early.
- You sure that they're
ready for this?
- No.
That's why I need you
to help him through it.
- Dr. Shim?
- Hang on.
Yes.
- Hi, I'm Dr. Helen Sharpe,
Deputy Medical Director.
We really appreciate you
starting early.
- Yeah, Max said almost
half your staff was down.
- And our patient load
has almost tripled.
- Any recent traumas?
- Thankfully, no.
But I need to get you
to the ED straightaway.
- Which way is the men's
locker room?
- Uh, it's back that way.
There's a bathroom
just along here.
- I need a hot shower.
- And we do need you in ED.
- Yeah, but I need
that shower more.
The hospital's in the middle
of a crisis.
- I know--the dispenser
was out of body wash.
- This is your new pager.
As you can see,
it's being paged,
so maybe it's time to wrap up
this beauty routine
and join me in the ED.
- How about I put on
some pants first?
- This is Casey,
our head nurse.
Casey, this is Dr. Shin,
our new trauma surgeon.
- Oh, thank God.
Follow me.
I got a kid who appears
to have swallowed
some rare earth magnets.
- Ah, that's a surefire way
to get attention, huh?
Hi, I'm Dr. Shin.
Casey, do you know the risks
when adjusting multiple
magnets?
- Uh, if the magnets
were to connect internally,
they could twist
the intestines,
force hemorrhages,
intussusception.
- Even a strangulated bowel.
- They can also do this.
Cool, right?
But you only swallowed
one magnet, didn't you?
- Mm.
- So that should pass
in a few hours.
Turns out you don't need me.
- Uh, in case you haven't
noticed,
we have a full ED of patients
who need your help.
Where do you think
you're going?
- I always show up
when I'm paged,
but I only stay
when I'm needed.
- Dr. Gilmore to Pediatrics.
Dr. Gilmore to Pediatrics.
- Should I go
for the energy drink
or the protein bar?
- Why would you need energy?
You seem intent on doing
virtually nothing.
- So you vote protein bar.
- I know that trauma surgeons
like to play the aloof
cowboy, but that's not--
- That's not how
you do things here.
- No, yes, it's not.
- I know.
Don't you think I researched
this place
before I took the job?
- Then you should also know
Max's motto.
- "How can I help?"
Yeah, that's catchy.
- It's words that we live by.
Everybody chips in.
Everybody helps.
- Right now I am helping.
By eating a protein bar.
Hm. Duty calls.
Well, maybe.
So what you got?
- Lucas Jarvis.
Nail gun mishap.
- It slipped.
- Well, Mr. Jarvis,
you're very lucky.
- This is lucky?
- Well, the fact that your new
nail appendage
missed the bone in every one
of your fingers is.
You know what?
- Don't you dare.
- I'm thinking Dr...
- Turan.
- Dr. Turan here gets
to practice
her nail extraction skills.
- Now, a little numbing agent
and some gentle retrograde
pressure,
and that sucker should
come right out.
- Dr. Shin--
- You got this?
- Yeah.
- Dr. Shin!
- Mm?
- Where are you going?
- Nap time.
I don't want to hear it.
My friend is sick,
another is gone,
this hospital is slammed,
and I'm gonna need you
to be a team player
for once,
do you understand?
- I'm always a team player.
Kit Brower, 25.
Multiple lacs
from a large explosion
at his home.
- What exploded?
What's that smell?
- I make beer.
My fermenting vat--
- Book an OR right now.
Grab a side.
Nurse, I need two units
of O-neg on a bear-hugger.
- Hold on, the entire wing
is contaminated.
No more surgeries until we can
disinfect every OR.
Hey, welcome to New Amsterdam.
- Oh, yeah.
Great place.
But look, he needs surgery
right now.
How about an ICU?
- Attendant's in quarantine.
- I got a place in mind.
We got to turn around.
Thanks.
- You guys need something here?
- Yeah, we're commandeering
your rig.
Help me get him in.
- Wait, where are we going?
- Nowhere--we're doing
the surgery right here.
Grab an OR tray and any
supplies you need.
You in?
This is trouble.
When the glass tank exploded,
it blew apart
the housing cabinet,
pieces of which are all over
Kip's abdomen.
- If wood doesn't show up
on an X-ray.
how are we gonna find
all the splinters?
- BP's dropping.
- Turn off all the lights
and cover all the windows.
Now, flip that switch
to your right.
Certain types of hardwood
turn fluorescent in blacklight.
This ambulance has a UV light
to keep infection
under control.
Are you just gonna sit there?
Everybody chips in,
everybody helps, right?
Ready to drive now?
- You know, when I saw
the shards of wood,
I honestly didn't think
he was gonna make it.
- What are you saying?
- I'm saying...
Just what I said.
- Oh, okay.
'Cause, you know, that kinda
sounded like a compliment.
- Would you like a gold star
on your report card?
No.
But if you're gonna
compliment me,
it should sound
like a compliment.
- It was implied.
Despite the fact that you took
a job in a public hospital
and then refused to help.
I didn't take the job
to help out everyone.
I took the job
to save trauma victims.
If a patient who needs
a trauma surgeon rolls up,
I need to be
at the top of my game.
And that may require
a shower or a nap
or a protein bar,
but whatever it takes,
I'm gonna do it,
because I need to be ready.
Self-care saves lives.
Might not be the New Amsterdam
way, but...
it's my way.
What?
- Nothing, um...
that makes perfect sense.
- But?
- But I save lives
every day too.
And without naps.
- It was totally packed.
I mean, every seat was taken,
but I desperately wanted
the aisle.
- So I swapped with her
and endured the horrific middle
seat like a proper gentleman.
- And the rest as they say
is history.
So how 'bout you?
How'd you two meet?
- Uh, that is a very
funny story actually,
because I work for the, uh,
Yankees.
- Don't be modest, babe.
He's the general manager.
And I, believe it or not--
I worked for the Mets.
- The Mets.
And she's
their general manager.
- Wait.
Seriously?
- Yeah, I know.
It's kind of hard to believe,
but it's--
- We met at
a General Managers Convention.
- That's--yeah--
- Wait, I didn't even know
those were a thing.
- Oh, yeah.
No, no, no.
We don't call it inside
baseball for nothing.
- You're funny.
- Dad! Mom!
Come look at this!
Coming, honey.
- It was so nice to meet you.
- You too.
- You guys are like
the perfect family.
- All right, bye.
- Bye.
- See ya.
- Hey.
What are you doing?
Mmm.
- Oh.
Hey, buddy.
You okay?
Wanna get up?
Oh, you got it?
- Liam.
- Hi.
- I'm--I'm so sorry about that.
- How'd you get so far
ahead of me, buddy?
- No, no.
That's okay.
Um, I don't mean to pry,
but does your son often
have difficulty standing?
- Uh...
- He's always been
a bit clumsy, but...
Nothing out of the ordinary.
- Yeah, why?
- Only asking
because I'm a doctor.
Do you have a pediatrician?
- Not at the moment.
- Um, um, we just moved here,
and with everything we're--
we're still--
- Does...
- Liam.
- Liam, does he have, um,
difficulty going upstairs,
or does he get tired easily?
- Why, is...
Something wrong with him?
- How about this?
Come to New Amsterdam with me,
let me run a few tests
just to be sure.
Lead the way.
- Okay.
Mm, come here, buddy.
- Wha--
- Oh!
Mom.
- Darling, you can't just go
barreling into people
like that.
You're gonna break my arm
or something.
- Okay, okay, look, I love all
the time we've spent together,
I do, but...
- Aw, me too, sweetheart.
- You cannot just show up
here every--
whenever you wanna
see me, okay?
We need boundaries.
- I know.
I agree, and I understand.
But I'm not here to see you.
- Hmm?
- I hope you have
a fabulous day.
- Okay.
- Casey, hi.
Shh.
Okay, okay.
Thank you so much.
Yeah.
- Has my mother
been harassing you?
- I don't know your mother.
- I just saw you two
out in the hall.
- Oh, yeah, that's right.
Uh, we just met.
- You were hugging.
- Were we?
- Yeah.
- Incoming!
Construction scaffolding
collapsed near 46th and Lex.
There's five more
after this one.
- Okay, let's, uh, get them
to Bay 23 and um, page Ortho.
Okay, we got multiple burns.
Let's start a line.
I'm'na be right back.
There's so much blood.
- Okay, you just need
some stitches, okay?
Let's get her to Bay 29.
Hang two liters normal saline
wide open.
You see anything
that interests you today?
- Mmm,
nope.
- Always a pleasure, Dr. Shin.
Kay, keep breathing.
Keep breathing.
- Do you know what this is?
- If I say yes,
will you not tell me?
- No,
it's the needlessly complicated
and brain-numbingly
detailed application
for the state hospital
accreditation review.
- Hmm, don't you have
another year until that's due?
- Yes, we do,
but if I wait that long
it's never gonna get done,
so if we just knock this out
today, it'll be off our plates.
- I think--
I think you mean your plate.
- Uh, our plate.
Like, shared plate.
Like tapas, you know?
Two hours.
Tops.
- Fine.
- Great.
- See you after work.
- Plasma exchange
is still considered
to be one of the most effective
first-line therapies
for autoimmune encephalitis.
- They didn't have hazelnut,
honey.
Of course they didn't.
- Mmm.
- Your husband is all set.
The process will take
several hours,
but I will check on you
in a bit.
- At least I brought a book.
- Hang on.
Dr. Kapoor.
What's going on with you?
- What's going on?
- You look different
from our last visit.
Do I?
- Don't be modest.
- Well, I can't imagine...
- Whatever you're doing...
It's working for you.
Mmm.
- Congratulations,
you are officially halfway
through your chemotherapy.
- Does my ovarian cancer
know that?
- How have you been doing
at home?
- Humble.
Can't eat.
Can't get outta bed.
Can't even shower by myself.
If not for Oliver,
I don't know what I'd do.
- "In sickness and in health."
- Guess you should've read
the fine print.
What?
What is it?
- Lena has necrotizing
fasciitis on her calf...
- From the cancer?
- No, it started as a small cut
that got infected.
We need to get her
to the ED straight away.
- I can't believe
I missed a cut.
I guess I just never look
at the back of her legs.
- It's okay.
These things happen.
- Dr. Ignatius Frome
is offered as administrator
to the appellant's
ERPOmandated
psychological evaluation.
Mr. Phillips, do you accept?
- We do.
- State of New York?
- Good by us, Your Honor.
- So ordered.
We'll reconvene once
Mr. Phillip's evaluation
is complete.
We're adjourned.
- Brendan, hi.
Dr. Frome.
- I can't believe
this is happening.
- Well, why don't we take
a little walk up to my office,
and we'll have a chat, okay?
- How do the cops have any
right to take away my gun?
I'm trained, and I'm licensed--
- Well, yeah, the issue is not
if you're licensed.
The Red Flag Law
was put in place
to determine if you are an
immediate danger to yourself
or to others.
That's it.
- I can't believe Ellie
did this to me.
- Yeah, divorce makes people
see the worst in each other,
for sure,
but that is why it's important
to have an impartial evaluator
in the process.
You ready?
Any idea why your wife
would say you're so dangerous?
- Yeah.
'Cause I almost killed her.
- Your feet make good drums.
- Hey.
- Hey, we'll be right back.
- We sequenced your son's genes
and were able to determine the
cause of the mobility issues.
- It's bad, isn't it?
- Your son has
what's known as DMD,
Duchenne Muscular Dystrophy.
It is a rapidly progressive
degenerative disease
that affects
around 1 in 5,000 boys.
- But he's gonna be okay,
right?
- There's no easy way
to say this.
There is no cure right now.
As he ages he will experience
continual muscle loss.
He'll be confined
to a wheelchair by his teens.
And by his twenties,
he will likely succumb to it.
- I don't--
how did he...
- It's inherited.
It's a mutation
of the dystrophin gene
on the X chromosome passed down
from mother to son.
- I did this?
- No.
There's nothing
you could've done.
- This can't be happening.
My baby boy.
Oh, my...
- Thank you, Oliver.
- Anything to help.
- Okay, you two
just hang tight.
I need to perform
a debridement
on Lena Luzan in Bay 28.
- Local anesthesia or a top--
- Little help here!
- What happened?
- No clue.
His heart rate
just fell off a cliff.
No warning.
- The same thing over here!
- Bradycardia!
Need a crash cart, STAT!
- Two more crashing over here!
- What the hell is happening?
- It's everyone who came in
from the scaffolding accident.
- At least everyone is stable.
- What was that all about?
- And he emerges
from the break room.
To what do we owe this honor?
We got a incoming trauma
actually worth your time?
We'll see.
Hey.
- Hey.
Incoming!
30-year-old male in MVA.
1965 antique roadster
versus a concrete divider.
- What is that?
- What's left
of the steering column.
- Now we're talking.
Right this way.
- "Hey."
- I have no idea
what you're talking about.
- Maybe her hand just, like,
grazed your leg accidentally.
- This woman definitely
cupped my buttocks.
- That's a sentence
I hoped never to hear out loud.
- Why is it so hard
for you to believe
that this woman
is actually attracted to me?
- Because at Walter's
last session,
they kept going on and on about
renewing their wedding vows.
- Yes.
I guess timing is suspect.
- All I'm saying is,
is it possible
this is all in your head?
- Robin.
- Uh, my husband's ready
for his next round.
The question is, are you?
- There's a dozen
active clinical trials
studying potential treatments
for Duchennes.
Our job will be finding one
that works for Liam.
- Oh, we're not picky,
Dr. Goodwin.
- I know, but they are.
Each trial has a rigid set
of inclusion criteria
and only accepts patients
that meet them all.
They don't make it easy.
I say we start
with the East Coast,
and uh,
look at gene therapy trials.
See what we can find.
- I have to go
to the bathroom.
- Okay, kiddo.
Can you walk it?
Okay.
I gotcha.
Up, up.
- I was sound asleep.
Around 1:00 a.m.,
I hear this noise.
Someone's in the house.
I grab my Glock,
and I head downstairs.
- Was it loaded?
- Someone was breaking in.
- Where do you keep your gun?
- I was protecting my home.
Last time I checked,
it was my right.
I don't have a record.
Not even a misdemeanor.
- Okay, so,
you were heading downstairs
with your loaded gun.
What happens next?
- I see someone in the dark.
I raise my gun,
I tell them to hit the floor,
and then I realize it's Ellie.
- But you did aim your gun
at her.
- I mean, yeah.
But I lowered it the second
I knew it was her.
- Ellie claims
that she was just there
to pick up some of her stuff.
Had she officially moved out?
- No, she'd just been staying
at her sister's.
- Brendan, how would you say
you're handling this divorce?
- That has nothing to do
with anything.
- Well, except it does because
I'm trying to get a better idea
of your mental state--
- Do you own a gun?
Do you own a gun?
- That's not--
this is not about me.
- Are you sure about that?
Tell me.
Are you in favor of open carry?
What about
the Second Amendment?
- Brendan--
- I'm the one whose house
got broken into.
I'm the one whose rights
are being stripped away,
and you sit there,
and you claim to be impartial,
but from over here,
it sure as hell seems your just
another bleeding heart liberal
who made up his mind the second
he heard the word "gun."
- Well, that's very good news.
Maybe we should cut it down
to twice a week.
- Sorry to interrupt.
Dr. Cholokian?
- Yeah, you found him.
- Great.
- You know,
I was just reading up
on your clinical collaboration
with Children's
in Sacramento and I--
- Let me stop you right there.
- Really?
I haven't even gotten to
the glowing praise part yet.
- You've heard about
my DMD clinical trial
because you have a patient
you want to enroll.
- Well, uh, guilty as charged.
- Has your patient already
submitted a pre-application
to the Biomedical Research
Application Portal?
- My patient just got
the diagnosis this morning.
- I'll take that as a no.
- Uh...
yeah, I was just thinking that,
uh--
- What, you could
sweet-talk me?
You don't think I want to help
as many children as I can?
I do.
But my trial has over two dozen
exclusion criteria
for a reason.
We have limited resources
to work with.
- I know, I read your criteria.
Trust me.
Liam Cafferty is a perfect fit.
- There is no perfect fit.
- Except for Liam.
He's six and a half,
he loves building with blocks,
and right now,
he doesn't qualify for
any other gene therapy trial
in the country, so
this could be his only shot...
- You know why we only accept
patients through
the online portal?
So we can remove
the advantage of privilege.
Like you cornering me in my lab
to make a personal plea
for one patient.
I'm sorry, Dr.--
- Goodwin.
Medical director
at, uh, New Amsterdam,
where you dump
a lot of your patients
to keep
your infection rates low.
So tell me again
about privilege.
- Two conditions.
I need a psyche eval of
the boy by the end of the day
along with a completed
pre-application form.
- Done.
He'll need to pass
his physical fitness
requirements.
- Got it.
Thank you.
- Casey?
- Zoll pads are working
for now.
As if being crushed by falling
scaffolding wasn't enough.
- Whatever they were
all exposed to,
it's not messing around.
- The sputum samples should
be back in a few hours.
- Okay, well, uh, until then,
you, uh,
care to tell me why
you and my mother were hugging?
Lauren, I already told you...
- Ooh, God, here we go.
This is Jake Holstein
all over again...
- I feel like you want me to
ask who Jake Holstein is.
- No, I don't need you to ask.
Jake Holstein
was this super cool senior
who liked me
when I was a freshman.
But every time he would try
to hang out with me,
he would get dragged into these
long, flirty conversations
with my mother,
because Jeanie always has to be
the focus
of every guy in the room.
I need a code team here!
Lena.
Lena!
Her heart rate just crashed
out of nowhere.
- Is she going to be okay?
- We're working on it, sir.
Please give us some room.
- Sudden drop in heart rate,
normal O2 saturation.
Same symptoms as
the construction site.
- But Lena came from me.
She was never near
the accident.
- So whatever's happening
to our patients,
we're the ones
doing it to them.
- Uh, you okay?
- What?
Hi.
Um...
I might be making premature
judgments from a place of bias.
- That's great, because I need
you to blindly sign this.
- Whatever happened to,
"how can I help"?
- No, don't have time for that.
This is a psyche eval
for a patient
you're never gonna meet.
- Max, I'm--I'm actually
struggling with something
really big right now,
I don't think cutting corners
is the best--
- His name is Liam Cafferty.
He is a 6-year-old boy
with Duchennes.
Right now he is struggling
to get into the only
clinical trial in this country
that could possibly
extend his life.
You're the best, buddy.
- Um...
Thanks.
- Iggy, Iggy.
- Hi.
- I need your advice.
- No, actually, BJ, I'm going
through something big.
I need you to maybe--
- I am being
sexually propositioned
by a patient's wife.
- My God, everyone has
such good comebacks today.
All right, okay, all right,
I'll bite.
Are you sure
that she's hitting on you?
- Why is it so difficult
for anyone to believe it?
- Mm, mmm...
- That woman rubbed
my shoulders,
she whispered into my ear,
and she cupped my bottom.
Please tell me what to do.
Please.
- Oh, okay.
Well, actually,
that does sound a lot
like "erotic transference."
- Okay, let me explain.
I'll explain it.
If someone is in
a heightened emotional state,
oftentimes they will redirect
their emotions
to their therapist
or their doctor, okay?
- Hmm.
- She's vulnerable,
she's grateful,
she's probably isn't even fully
aware that she's doing it,
so just talk to her.
Let her know you want to keep
the relationship professional,
and the bottom cupping
should subside.
- Thank you.
Thank you.
All right.
- Maybe you want
to stretch your legs,
get a breath of fresh air?
You've been sitting vigil
all day.
- Yeah, I'm fine right here.
- Can I ask, do you have anyone
helping out at home?
- Just me.
And that is fine.
I don't mind.
- It must be so overwhelming.
- Lena's always been the one
to take care of me,
so when she got sick, I knew
it was my turn to step up.
And I wanted to.
I wanted to take care of her.
Cooking, bathing,
whatever she needs...
I handle it.
- Oliver,
when was the last time
you took time for yourself?
- I'm okay, Dr. Sharpe.
Really, I'm fine.
Right now, my focus is my wife.
She's all that matters.
- Okay, Brendan.
Sorry about that.
- I own a gun.
A Cricket .22.
It was a gift from my old man.
Yeah, I was, um,
I was eight
when he gave it to me.
And I was so excited because
that gun meant that I could
finally go hunting
with him and my brother.
- So you have a kid's gun?
- Well, growing up
in Wisconsin,
believe me,
I had more than just the one.
A bolt action
deer hunting rifle.
A Remington.
Eventually, I got myself
a .270 Winchester...
- Accurate weapon.
- Especially with
the iron sight.
I never thought twice
about my dad's gun collection.
And I could tell you firsthand,
I know the patience
and the discipline you learn
when you're hunting.
And I'll never forget looking
over at my old man
and knowing that he believed
he was teaching me
and my brothers something.
Knowing that he was proud.
Also knowing that might be the
closest I'd ever feel to him.
Guns are no longer
a part of my life,
but I still have that
Cricket .22 disassembled,
under lock and key.
- I get that.
- Yes, Brendan, I am a bleeding
heart liberal New York doctor.
- That's true.
But I also have no problem
with the Second Amendment.
I have absolutely no problem
with responsible gun ownership,
which is why I need you to
start answering my questions.
You think you deserve
that Glock?
Let me help you get it back.
- Okay, we now have 14 patients
who have crashed
without warning.
This spreadsheet lists
every single medication
they have received.
- Find the common link.
- They've all got
normal saline.
- Well, apart from these two.
- What about Ativan?
- No, Lena didn't get that.
Oh, wait.
They all had bandages?
- And alcohol swabs,
but how would that make sense?
- My patient's crashing.
I need an Epi drip
in here stat.
Let's get the drip started
at 2 micrograms a minute.
- Copy that.
- Wild guess.
His heart rate just plummeted
out of nowhere?
- Yeah, faster than a drunk
on a mountain bike.
- What drugs did you give him?
- Uh, a shot of morphine
through an autoinjector line.
- All our other patients
were administered morphine
using the same injector system.
- That's gotta be our link.
- You think an overdose?
- It doesn't make any sense.
These injector syringes come
prefilled at two milliliters.
There's no way that two
milliliters of morphine
cause this kind of reaction.
- Unless what's inside
isn't morphine.
- Liam's labs are all
within normal range.
He meets the age
and weight criteria.
All that's left is
a TTSTAND unassisted.
- Hey, Liam.
Do you like games?
Come check this out.
This is a game we can play.
You can lay on your back
on this mat like me.
Right?
Yeah.
All the way...
Perfect.
And then when we say "go,"
you're gonna roll over
and then you're gonna stand up
as fast as you can.
Can you do that for us?
- Yeah.
- Cool.
All right, buddy,
you stay there.
We'll get us to--wait, wait.
Not yet, not yet.
You stay there, and we're
gonna watch right here, okay?
- He needs to come to a full
standing position unassisted
in under ten seconds
to qualify.
- Ten seconds?
- Well,
I know it sounds extreme,
but it's a marker
for muscle damage.
If he can't meet that time,
we won't benefit
from the trial.
You got this, son.
All you gotta do is get up.
- And begin.
Yay!
Great job, buddy.
That was great.
- I'm sorry.
- So...
that's it?
- The exclusion criteria
is clear.
- No, no, no.
Hang on.
He's--he's just warming up.
All right, let's--
let's give him another try.
Okay, come on.
Come down here, buddy.
Hey, look at me.
Look at me.
That was great.
Okay, great, but uh...
even faster this time.
Okay, can you--
can you do it faster?
- I think so.
That-a-boy.
I know you can.
All right, let me put you back
on your back.
And, uh, nice and fast.
Okay?
Okay.
He's ready.
- And begin.
- Come on, honey.
You can do this.
You got this, son.
- I did it.
- Yes, yes, yes, sweetie.
Yes, sweetie.
- I'm very sorry.
- I may have found something.
It's in Seattle,
which I know is not ideal,
but it's something.
It's a Tier Two trial
that has shown mild success
in slowing down
the degeneration.
- "Mild success"?
- I know.
It's not...
It could buy you
a little more time as a family.
- Can Liam even get in?
- He's in if you want it.
- Yeah, of course we want it.
We slow it down now,
and then we keep our eyes open
for better studies,
for more promising trials
coming down the line,
and then if there's ever
a big breakthrough--
- Well, it doesn't exactly work
like that.
What do you mean?
These trials use
a deactivated cold virus
to deliver the new gene.
So once Liam's exposed, his
body will develop antibodies.
- Meaning?
- Meaning that
if we ever tried again,
regardless of the trial,
his body would just
destroy the gene.
- So we only get one shot
at this?
- Unfortunately.
- That--that's ridiculous.
There must be something else
that we can do.
- I wish there were.
- We'll do the trial.
- We have to talk about this.
- What is there to talk about?
- You heard what he said.
Best case is mild success
at slowing it down.
- It is better
than doing nothing.
- Is it?
- Of course it is.
- What--what if next year
they develop a cure,
and we have blown our one shot
with this--this half measure?
- He's sick.
He's dying.
How can we do nothing?
- Um, yeah,
divorce can be life-altering.
That idea of the future you had
in your mind, it's gone.
How does that make you feel?
- It hurts.
I loved her.
- I bet it's hard to hear
that she thinks
you're capable of violence.
- She doesn't.
Ellie's just being dramatic.
She wants to take everything
from me.
- Well, who wanted the divorce?
- She says that we,
"grew apart,"
which is just code for,
"she felt like it,"
as far as I'm concerned.
And now the courts
are bending over backwards
to make sure
she's not taken advantage of.
God forbid someone should care
about my rights.
- 'Cause she broke into
your house, right?
- That's right.
- And I bet over
these last few months,
you've really felt like you've
lost control over your life.
- To say the least.
- The night she broke in--
you heard the noise, right?
You grabbed your gun.
Did you feel afraid?
- Hell no.
- What did you feel?
- In charge.
- What else?
- I felt like a man again.
- So you went towards
the sound,
gun in hand,
down the stairs.
What did you wanna do?
- I wanted to handle things.
I wanted to protect
what was mine.
- You aimed the gun, you
realized it's not the burglar,
it's your wife.
- Yeah.
- What'd you do then?
- Nothing.
- You lowered the gun.
- No.
I just kept it there.
Just trained on her,
just for a second or two.
You should've seen
the look on her face.
- Did you ever think about
pulling the trigger?
- No.
Of course not.
I just wanted to scare her.
I wanted her to feel
like I felt for once...
Powerless.
- Mrs. Kent,
thank you for coming.
We have something
quite important to discuss.
- Hmm, that sounds enticing.
- You can leave the door open.
I--
Okay.
Where should we do this
discussing then?
The sofa.
- No, no, no sofa.
I believe what's happening here
is that you are mistaking
your feelings of concern
over your husband's diagnosis
with my own.
- Mmm.
- I mean, you are transferring
your erotic nature to me--
wait, no, no--
- Ooh, what are you trying
to say, Vijay?
- I am not great with words.
- Oh, we don't have to speak.
- Mm-hmm.
Your eyes.
- Go on.
- Oh, Lord.
Come with me.
Hurry up.
- Ooh!
- Robin Kent's MRI results.
- She has a meningioma?
- The tumor is pressing up
against her pleasure center.
It's what has been causing
her heightened libido
and lowered inhibitions.
- She needs surgery right away.
I can schedule it.
- Thank you.
We must make sure
she's healthy enough
to renew her wedding vows.
- How'd you figure it out?
- I saw an uneven dilation
in her pupils.
- You two had to be
pretty close
to notice something like that.
- How can I help?
- I don't think you can.
Jeremy and I just see things
differently.
He wants to wait for a trial
that can cure him,
even though a trial like that
doesn't exist.
- What do you want?
- I...
passed this disease
onto my son.
It came from me.
And I just feel like
I have to do something.
Anything.
- Liam is, um...
he's smart.
He's funny.
He's kind.
Ridiculously adorable.
- And he's strong.
That's what you passed on,
if you ask me.
And you have time
to pass down even more,
regardless of what you
and Jeremy choose.
All we can do...
As parents, really.
I mean...
just try to pass down
the best of ourselves.
To our kids.
In the limited time
that we have.
- Okay, Casey's at the lab with
some of the prefilled syringes.
We'll see what they find out.
- Well, if we can't figure out
what we're giving him,
this man's gonna die
right here on the table.
- Mass spectrometry
test results
are gonna take
at least an hour.
- You have a better idea?
- I'm not sure it's better.
- Lauren!
- What is it?
- It's morphine.
- But it can't be.
Because then that means...
- This isn't why
our patients are crashing.
Heart rate's bottoming out.
- Start with these.
- No.
This steering column's
made of metal.
- If the pads fire
then the charge will arc
through his chest.
- Well,
that limits our options.
- I'm cracking open his chest.
I need a scalpel
and a sonic bone saw.
- I'll get him prepped.
- I'm starting
the mid sternal thoracotomy.
- Wait!
- Wh-what are you doing?
- What is that?
- It's Narcan.
Heart rate's rising.
- Saturation's up.
- It's working.
- How did you know?
- This.
That's more than two mls
of morphine.
I'll wager
it's three times that.
- So it wasn't the wrong meds.
- No, these prefilled syringes
were designed
so we wouldn't have to think
about measurements
in the heat of a crisis.
- And these ones came to us
overfilled.
- Which we would've never have
found out in time
if you hadn't
have popped one open.
- We can't be the only hospital
that uses these.
- I'll sound the alarm.
We have a Class Two Recall
on our hands.
-Dr. Frome, you completed
your psychological evaluation
of Brendan Phillips
for the ERPO proceedings?
- I have, your Honor.
- What did you find?
- Uh, Brendan Philips,
he exhibits signs
of repressed anger.
Um, his impulse control
leaves--
- Objection.
- Already ahead of you,
counselor.
Dr. Frome, this is
out of your jurisdiction.
The Red Flag Law asks
two simple questions:
is Brendan Phillips an
immediate threat to himself?
- No.
- Is Mr. Phillips
a threat to others?
- I would say that
he intentionally traumatized
his wife emotionally--
- This isn't a therapy session,
Dr. Frome.
- Mm-hmm.
- Is Mr. Phillips
an immediate threat to others?
Yes or no?
Is he likely to go out
and shoot someone?
- No.
- Thank you.
The ERPO is hereby revoked.
Mr. Phillips, your gun is to be
restored to you by the state,
immediately.
- I knew it.
I knew this wouldn't
do anything.
- Yes, these laws
are far from perfect,
but they're the best
that we have for right now.
- Well, Brendan won't be
the only one armed.
I just bought myself a gun.
- Your heart rate
is back to normal,
and your fasciitis is healing.
I could discharge you today.
But I've been wondering
if that is the best option.
- What do you mean?
- Have you heard
of Respite Care?
- No.
What is that?
- It's like
a temporary nursing home
where Lena could receive
full-time care.
- I--I missed one cut.
I know.
But that doesn't mean
we have to ship my wife off
to a nursing home.
- Respite Care
and Palliative Care
are not just
for terminal patients.
We have a unit right here
at New Amsterdam.
Lena could stay for a month,
even two.
You could visit every day, and
it could give you both a break.
- I can do this, Dr. Sharpe.
- I know you can.
But caregiver burnout
can be just as serious
as Lena's cancer.
Not just for her
but for you.
Respite Care exists
so that you can recharge...
And Lena doesn't feel
like a burden.
- You--you feel like a burden?
- Ollie, are you not
taking care of yourself?
- I--I'm trying, love.
- It's not a respite
from each other.
Because if you cannot
look after yourself,
then you can't look after Lena.
- Okay.
Okay.
- Hey.
We've discussed our options.
- And?
- And, uh,
we decided we'd rather
spend this time together.
As a family.
- And hold out hope that a
better trial might come along.
- There's, uh,
no guarantee that it will.
- There's never a guarantee.
So...
Better not waste
the time you have, right?
- Well, I'm always here.
- Thank you.
- Tough case.
- As a woman who has
lived a full life,
who's, uh,
who is vital and--
and attractive,
you will understand
how I had a certain itch.
People stop seeing you
as a full person
with wants,
and desires, and passions.
We're not invisible.
I'm sorry, Madam Chairwoman,
for speaking out of turn.
- Goodnight, Dr. Kapoor.
- Incoming!
Happy birthday to you
Happy birthday, dear Lauren
- Whoo!
- It's not my birthday.
Did I get the day wrong?
- You got the season wrong.
- Oh, dear.
- Ugh, I'm thinking about
her sister's birthday.
- Nope.
Not even close.
- Well, somebody's birthday,
right?
Wait, is this--
this is why you two were
chatting outside together?
My God.
Mom.
You know, let's get some forks
and some plates.
We're not letting good cake
go to waste.
- Some forks and plates,
people.
- Yes.
- You are right on time.
- I'm always on time.
- Walk around this way.
- This is nice.
Just the two of us.
Although today,
Bobbi said she missed you.
- Did she?
- Well, technically,
she said, "I miss mass,"
but she's not Catholic,
so...
I'm just assuming
she meant you.
-  I know they're not mine
- Is everything okay?
- Just thinking about
our "perfect family."
I know, that was so awkward.
- I don't know about you,
but I feel so far from perfect.
- Well, yeah, plus the part
where we're
not actually a family.
- I think that's the problem.
I mean, Bobbi and Luna
think we are family.
-  Don't be so caught up
- And why wouldn't they?
It was all pretend.
- I really liked pretending.
-  I see problems
down the line
- Me too.
I like pretending,
that I'm not...
Still grieving.
I like pretending
that Luna has a mom.
And I think we know
we're pretending, but...
But they don't.
- It's not fair, is it?
-  But there was a dirt
upon your hands
- I wish I met you
in a few years.
Then maybe...
- I had so much fun.
And I didn't think
I could anymore.
-  I see problems
down the line
I should go.
-  I know that I'm right
- Okay.
-  Don't let the darkness
eat you up
- Bye.
-  Don't let the darkness
eat you up
- Bye.
-  Don't let the darkness
eat you up
Don't let the darkness
- Max!
I'll see you at the next
General Manager's Convention.
-  Don't let the darkness
eat you up
Don't let the darkness