Previously on "ER.."
‐ Want a bite?
‐ No, I'll just watch you eat.
‐ Where's that going?
‐ What do you mean?
You and the desk clerk?
'Would your grandmother'
consider this clinic idea?
She'd probably look at it.
After I pay my landlord
the med school bills,
my phone bill, the gas bill
that should leave me
about four bucks.
Oh, yeah. Me, too.
You've not worked
with Dr. Romano?
Rocket Romano?
Rocket's sponsoring my BTA.
‐ Damn you people!
‐ You son of a bitch!
That's enough!
Believe me,
it won't get any better.
You belong in jail.
I wish it was me
who kicked your white ass.
I hope I didn't wake you.
No. No.
I smelled the coffee.
Oh, well, uh,
let me get you a cup.
Okay.
You're cheerful
this morning.
Did you talk to
the foreman yet?
Yeah, yeah. He gave me
the same old, same old.
All crewed up.
But I talked
to Tommy Styles.
Tommy styles? I thought
he moved to Atlanta.
Yeah, he's a
general manager
of a construction
company down there
that got some contracts
during the Olympics
and, uh...
things just grew
from there, and..
...they can't get enough
guys to fill their gigs.
Good for him.
Yeah.
He said, uh..
He said a guy with
my skills could..
...make some real good
money the first year out.
In Atlanta?
Yeah.
I mean, it could be
a chance for a fresh start.
Better job
opportunities
better weather.
We already know Tommy,
my sister's down there..
...and it's a chocolate city
so socially‐‐
Sounds great.
But..?
But we're not kids anymore.
We can't just start over.
Why not? Hmm?
Why not?
Why can't we just
wipe the slate clean?
Because we have a mortgage
and I have a job.
But I don't.
You know, I'm being
frozen out up here
and after that
fight with Bill
I can't just hang out
and watch the football game
with the guys.
My life is over
up here.
In Atlanta..
...we wouldn't have
to tell anybody.
Nobody would know.
Hey. How many patients
do you think
we see in the hospital
every year?
Too many.
'Could you be a little
more specific?'
‐ It's for my grant proposal.
‐ Uh‐huh, that's right.
Tonight's the Carter family
foundation night. You nervous?
No, I figure the worse
she can say is no.
And then I'm back where I
started, clueless and penniless.
‐ Good morning, all.
‐ Hey. You in a good mood?
Well, the hospital settled
the Kenny Law malpractice suit.
No more process servers,
no more depositions
and after today,
no more work
because I've got three days
of vacation time before me.
Any plans?
Uh, sleep, sleep
and sleep.
Mark, how many patients
do you think
we see in the hospital
every year?
Oh, would that be real
patients or turkeys?
Forget I asked.
Look, your count will
be about 95 percent higher
if you count
all the wackos.
It's a little harsh.
Alright, Carol,
I'll make you a wager.
Uh‐huh. Uh.
A wager on
the turkey‐to‐patient ratio
over the next 12 hours.
‐ No, thanks.
‐ Come on.
I'll give you
two‐to‐one odds.
Can I get a doctor quickly?
Help, please? Anyone?
You see?
Here's a real patient now.
You're already
up by one.
Anna?
‐ 'Anna?'
‐ Hey, Carter.
I'm running late.
Sorry.
Oh, I must have read
your handwriting wrong.
I thought it says 4D.
It does. Here.
Come in.
Oh.
I had to get my shower in
before the guy in 4G.
He stands in there
for, like, an hour
listening to Howard Stern.
Hey, can you give me a ride
to journal club tonight?
Sure.
Thanks.
Make yourself comfortable.
I'm gonna go
get dressed.
This is a nice place.
Please. It's a dump, but you
get what you pay for, right?
What you gonna do?
Especially on what
we get paid?
'Right.'
If you want, there's uh, some
pop‐tarts on the counter.
Can I, uh...make you one?
No, it's okay.
I like them cold.
Me, too.
Really?
Oh!
Damn landlord won't
fumigate the place.
I...write letters,
call the management office.
You better believe
he doesn't have roaches
around his fat‐cat estate
in Evanston.
You know, you could report
him to the health department.
Cockroaches are
a health hazard.
Really? That really works?
You tried it?
Yeah.
Wow. I never would
have pegged you
for a guy who knew
slumlord politics.
You seem so milk‐fed
middle class.
Well, you know my family
always had enough to get by.
Uh, never went
hungry or anything.
Hey, what do you say
we go over this
journal stuff
at breakfast?
I know a place that's got
a $1.99 pancake special.
‐ You buying?
‐ My treat.
Alright. Thanks.
Get an AP lateral
on that knee.
What happened to this guy?
We were doing
a performance piece‐‐
I was doing "William Tell's."
An artist taking the risk
as the average Philistine
is not willing to take.
All this stupid idiot had to do
is shoot the apple out
from in between my legs.
You're lucky he
didn't aim higher.
In a way, it makes it
even edgier, sir.
You've shed blood
for your work.
Are you Max Prole? Are you?
No, no I'm sorry, it's just the
blood on the gallery wall
made a bold splatter
and I‐I‐‐
Do I look like
Jackson Pollock?
I'm sorry, sir. I'm sorry.
I just, I‐I think this can work.
Carol, let's give him
ten of morphine.
Wait, I have an idea.
The piece can go on and live
and breathe on its own.
I will be the canvas.
No morphine.
I want to experience
the sensations.
Mr. Prole, you've a bullet hole
in your leg, now take the drug.
Sorry, Carol.
Score one for me.
Hey, Shirley, do you know
where Dr. Hicks is
doing her 8:00 A.M.
gastroplasty?
‐ Did.
‐ Excuse me?
She pushed it up to 6: 00.
They should be done by now.
Hey, what's going on?
Just finishing
up my night.
Dr. Hicks changed
her surgery?
Yes, she had to make rounds
for Dr. Sloman.
‐ You weren't here yet. So..
‐ Why wasn't I called?
I didn't want
to disturb you.
That was my gastroplasty.
I know, but you have limited
time with your family, so..
Is that what you
told Dr. Hicks?
Peter, I thought I was
doing you a favor
but if you're thinking
I wanted this surgery..
Hey! Hey! Hey!
Whoa, whoa. Did you?
Look, why don't you take my
ischemic bowel at 11:00
and we'll call it a trade.
Okay, yeah.
Why don't we do that?
Good. You smell
of talcum powder.
That's so sweet.
‐ Hey, Jeanie.
‐ Hey.
Your husband called.
Did he leave a message?
Yeah.
I wrote it down.
"Mint juleps,
night blooming jasmine
and warm southern breezes."
‐ Oh. That was it?
‐ Yeah.
I don't know what it means
but he sounds
like a real romantic.
Yeah, sometimes
I wish he wasn't
as much of a romantic.
Oh, you don't like being
swept off your feet?
Uh, it's the landing
that's a problem.
This Synergix group
has balanced budgets
much deeper in the red
than ours.
Yeah, I've made some
real progress.
Oh, that's very laudable,
but I still think
you should hear
what they have to say.
What if I don't
like what I hear?
I'd plan on liking it, Kerry.
Otherwise, you can talk
to the board of directors.
‐ Explain ER's massive deficit.
‐ I see.
But they're looking for
scapegoats. Don't be one.
It was a complete accident.
I promise.
Mr. Prole made me do it.
He wanted me to do it
‐ This is our guy.
‐ Dr. Greene.
Come on, buddy.
Couple of questions.
I told him I was a bad shot.
‐ 'He wouldn't listen!'
‐ Got to love the crackpots.
Could you cover me
for a few hours?
Anspaugh's sending me
to some dog and pony show
for these
ER management groups.
If I have to.
He just zeroed in
on every bit
of flab
in the budget.
Said we're overstaffed
or doing too many tests.
He wants the whole thing
turned around yesterday.
‐ Sounds bad.
‐ There's no money.
Resources are stretched
as it is
and he still wants me
to lose another 98,000.
Something's
got to give.
Yeah. It's just
I don't know what or who.
Let me know
when you're back.
What have you got?
Matthew Lindermulder.
His spotter at the gym
was asleep as the switch
dropped a free‐weight bar
on his head.
Ooh. I knew there
was a reason
I let my gym
membership lapse.
BP 120/80. Pulse 88.
Pupils equal,
round and reactive.
Uh, Babinski's
down going
and he withdraws
to pain.
Okay, let's get a CBC,
cross‐table c‐spine
and a non‐contrast
head CT.
Oh, man.
'What's that?'
It's a Klan tattoo.
Danny, can you hear me?
How long was he seizing?
His cellmate screamed
for us about an hour ago.
He seized all the way
here and it stopped
'just as we were pulling up.'
‐ BP's 100/70. Pulse 100.
‐ Hmm.
‐ Has he been here before?
‐ Don't know. I'm new.
Wet himself in the van
on the way over.
Okay. Look can you not use
those cuffs, please?
Whatever you say, doc,
but I got to stay with him.
He's waking up.
I hear it ringing.
Does he have any
history of epilepsy?
‐ 'Not that I know of.'
‐ Slower.
‐ How you feeling there, Danny?
‐ Oh, no. Oh, no.
Hang on. That's alright.
Hang on.
Alright, he's bit his tongue.
Let's get a head CT
and a tox screen.
Can I talk to you
outside, please?
Sure.
So what do you think?
Kid has textbook
seizure symptoms.
Yeah, maybe a little
too textbook.
Well, it's a pretty
convincing performance.
I've seen some Oscar winning
performances from prisoners
looking for a
"Get out of jail free" card.
Maybe Mark Greene's
rubbing off on us.
He's seizing again.
Labs are back on that
weird guy in one.
Anna, weird guy in one.
Okay. Thanks again
for breakfast, Carter.
‐ Sure.
‐ Carter.
Could you wrap up
a patient for me?
He's not stinky, is he?
No, straightforward
concussion most likely.
The guy just makes me
feel uncomfortable.
Hold on, hold on,
you're passing off a patient
because he makes
you feel uncomfortable?
Uh, Dr. Carter?
It's, uh, the lab.
He's a member of
the Ku Klux Klan.
Um‐hm.
Did he make any remarks?
No, he's unconscious,
but when I was working him up
I noticed he had
a KKK tattoo.
Alright, Jeanie,
if we all sat around
waiting for
the perfect patient
the lounge would be
standing room only.
So, if there's a problem,
call security.
Until then, try
and remember Hippocrates.
No pupil dilation.
Oral mucosa's intact.
Lucky landing.
I'm sorry, Officer Jeffrey
this doesn't look good.
Nurse Hathaway, will you prepare
the H20‐NA treatment, please.
Oh, but, doctor,
that's experimental.
What do you mean,
"It doesn't look good"?
Well, it's our only hope.
Um, officer,
do you have the name
of Mr. Scheibe's next of kin?
Either he's going to snap
out of this seizure
or he's going to be forced
into an irreversible coma.
‐ Coma?
‐ 'Give it a few seconds.'
'If it doesn't work,
we'll call the coma team.'
What? What? Who?
Amazing.
‐ Yeah, salt water.
‐ Where am I?
'Right now, you're
in a hospital'
but in five minutes,
you're going to be
on a bus headed
for prison
in very wet pants.
We got your gram stain back,
Mr. La Fontaine.
Please, for you..
Vinny.
Okay, Vinny,
you have gonorrhea.
From the looks
of your chart
you're familiar
with the protocol?
Occupational hazard.
It's the price
of being a player.
You sing?
No.
That's a damn shame
'cause, uh..
...I been in the, uh..
entertainment industry
for numerous years
and, uh,
with a face like yours..
...you could sell
a lot of platters.
This is a single dose
of Floxin and Zithromax.
They do the same thing
as the other antibiotics
you're used to.
I remember
when it used to be
an elephant gun
of, uh, penicillin in the ass.
Huh, have you been tested
recently for HIV or syphilis?
Oh, yeah, I get tested
down at South Side clinic.
I am clean and pristine.
‐ Is the coast clear?
‐ What do you mean?
Fake seizure kid from juvie.
I'd rather Dr. Greene
not see this one.
'Probably not a patient
I should bring up'
'to your grandmother,
right?'
Oh, jeez. Your clinic proposal,
that's tonight, isn't it?
Yeah, Oak Park, 7 o'clock.
I thought that's what we said.
Yeah, we did, we did.
I just spaced it.
I made plans with Anna,
but I can change them.
‐ Plans with Anna? Huh?
‐ Yeah. Journal club.
So it's a colleague
kind of thing?
So far. So you got all
your facts and figures?
Gamma loves
facts and figures.
Yeah, I'm just waiting
for some numbers on the census.
That's cool.
Nah, you'll do fine.
Just don't mention
politics or religion
and you'll stay
on her good side.
‐ Politics, religion. Right.
‐ Or baseball.
She's still pissed off
over that inter‐league play.
'Anything else?'
No, you're a natural.
You'll do fine.
How long has your wrist
been bothering you?
About two weeks ago.
‐ I think it might be a thing‐‐
‐ Let me take a look.
Yeah.
Can you hold this a second?
‐ Sure. I'll just sit it down.
‐ Dr. Greene.
‐ Consider yourself served.
‐ Excuse me?
If you have any questions,
there's an attorney's
name and number
on the inside.
Too late but this case
was settled this morning.
But you know
I have a suggestion
where you could stick
this summons.
Is that another
process server?
These guys are unbelievable.
He impersonated a patient.
That's gotta be illegal.
Yeah. They should really get
their story straight.
Mark, this isn't
a malpractice summons.
‐ It's a civil suit.
‐ What?
Yeah, Chris law's
claiming you violated
his brother's
civil rights.
He's not suing
the hospital.
He's suing you.
So I think the facts
speak for themselves.
'When you partner with
Synergix Physicians group'
we will increase revenues,
streamline management
and cut costs
making your department
a center of excellence.
Now, I'm sure that some of you
have questions, so..
‐ Yes, sir?
‐ I'm Eric Norris.
‐ Director of St. Joseph's ER.
‐ 'Oh, yes.'
'And the principal
author on thrombolytics'
'and pulmonary embolism
in the September annals.'
‐ 'Welcome, sir.'
‐ Yes.
What are your billing charges?
Ah, now that is the beauty
of the SPG system.
Collective billing of our
125 contracted facilities
enables us to keep
our billing costs
down below five percent.
‐ 'Yes.'
‐ Yeah, I have a few questions.
‐ The first of which‐‐
‐ 'I'm sorry. And you are?'
Uh, Kerry Weaver, acting chief
of emergency services
at County General.
Five percent
is an impressive number.
But what's
the actual percentage
that Synergix retains
in management fees?
Well, we retain the current
physicians' salaries
and we balance your budget
through maximizing reimbursement
and cutting costs.
I'm sure you've heard
of the Pentagon.
'And the $5,000 hammer,
Dr. Weaver?'
Yeah, I'm not talking
about hammers
and, um, you haven't answered
my question, Mr. West.
Well, it's Dr. West,
but please, call me Ellis.
'The number you're looking
for is dependent'
upon a multitude of factors:
Uh, payer mix, daily census,
physician reimbursement
just to name a few.
But we should talk
about this later.
'Uh, right now,
I'd like to answer'
'a few more questions,
if I may.'
'Yes? In the back?'
‐ 'Dr. Romano.'
‐ 'Lizzie!'
Just the person I wanted to see.
Check this out.
Someone's gonna be
limping for a while.
Uh‐hm. Some wacky artist
got shot during a performance.
Completely imploded
his cartilage.
Yeah, I see there's a
cylindrical defect
of the medial distal
femoral condyle.
You called it. A perfect
candidate for your research.
He's all yours
if you got the time.
Uh.
Well, actually, I have
but we'd need to get his consent
look for a donor femur.
The consent's already
been taken care of
and I took the liberty
of trolling the morgue.
Found a femur
that matches.
All you need to do is
start growing culture cells.
‐ An osteochondral allograph.
‐ Mm‐hmm.
Didn't think
I'd ever get to do one.
Well, I'll start the cultures
right away, uh..
Thank you so much.
Who looks out
for you, huh?
I was just talking to a guy
named Ivan Sheldon.
You remember him?
Uh, night court judge
from Evanston
with a six handicap?
Right.
I told him what was up.
He gave me the name
of a good attorney
the guy who defended
the civil rights case against
the Kallenback Meat Packing
Company, a few years back.
Now, you're discussing
my legal problems?
with your golfing buddies?
Just Sheldon.
He's a judge.
I didn't ask you to mind
my business or save my ass
or whatever it is
you're trying to do.
I thought I was
just being your friend
which is getting tougher
and tougher to do these days.
‐ Yeah?
‐ Mark.
That environmental allergy
woman is waiting for you.
And why is that?
You've been in
a bad mood for months.
And I don't know
how to talk to you anymore.
‐ Then don't.
‐ Okay.
What's the statute
of limitations
on post‐traumatic
stress?
Cut him some slack.
I think we've all
cut him plenty.
‐ He needs some help.
‐ He doesn't need a shrink.
He needs friends
who are supportive.
Uh, he's not going
to have any friends
supportive or otherwise,
if he keeps this up.
Your tattoo guy
is back from CT.
The grand wizard?
Yeah, he's regained
consciousness.
Needs his scalp
and shoulder sutured.
Great. We'll have him up
and cross burning in no time.
I hate to say it, but he's
actually very polite.
Uh‐huh.
Mr. Lindermulder,
you're gonna need sutures.
Are you gonna make me look like
Frankenstein's monster, uh?
First your shoulder.
Please lower your gown.
'Is there any way
the nurse could do them?'
'That little blond lady
who was in here before?'
It's not her job.
You're gonna have to
settle for me.
It's no offense,
it's just..
...go ahead.
I got to hand it
to you people.
"You people"?
Paramedics, nurses
'physician's assistants.'
Dumb ox like me gets
a barbell dropped on his head
and here I am, getting
the best care on Earth.
Well, we treat
everybody here.
Have you been
saved, miss?
Boulet.
Do you walk
with the Lord?
What does that tattoo
have to do with the Lord?
I'm sorry you had to see it.
'That's why I asked
for the nurse before.'
'It's a reminder
of what I left behind'
intolerance,
ignorance, hate.
I was reborn through
the love of Jesus Christ.
Uh‐huh.
I built a new life, Ms. Boulet.
You don't believe
that's possible, do you?
Sure, I do.
Listen, we didn't really get a
chance to finish our discussion.
Yeah, I think I heard everything
I need to hear, thank you.
Oh, but I haven't.
Listen, Kerry. I'm surrounded by
number crunchers all day long.
When a confident, intelligent
and attractive woman
walks through my door
I must at least
try to ask her to lunch.
Yeah, I have to
get back to work.
No, no, no.
I'll make some calls.
I'll tell Chicago
not to get sick for an hour.
We can go down to the oak room
and I will tell you
all my dirty
management secrets.
What do you say?
Come on.
Not to mention
the Japanese strain of staph
that's resistant to
the most powerful antibiotics.
Scary stuff.
Hi, I'm Dr. Greene.
Whoa.
What are you doing?
There are germs, doctor.
Uh‐ha. Well, you can
put that away now.
Dr. Greene is
very sanitary.
You don't have to worry.
I'll be the judge
of that.
Why don't we
take off the mask?
This is a charcoal
particle filter mask.
Twenty percent of people get
sicker in the hospital.
I don't want to become
another statistic.
So, you complain of fatigue,
dry mouth, shortness of breath.
Heart rate's 130.
Resps 32.
Ah, and you've been here before
for anxiety attacks.
This is not
an anxiety attack.
I'm allergic
to my apartment building.
Why don't you move?
Is that your medical
opinion, doctor?
I have environmentally
based allergies.
Or you're having some anxiety
and looking for attention.
Mark!
Why don't you
get a blood gas
and call me
with the results.
I see Dr. Corday handed you
off one nasty ileum.
I'm just helping her out.
Well, uh‐hm..
I'm glad that you two
have some camaraderie.
It'll come in handy
with Dr. Romano.
Excuse me?
He's looking for
another surgeon
for his team, and, uh...
I recommended you.
Well, thank you, but..
Stapler.
Thanks, but what?
Well, I'm more interested
in working with surgeons
who challenge my skills
than dazzle me
with technology.
Technology is
the new technique
and if you don't master it,
somebody else will.
When I saw how the flaws
in the system trickled down
and affected the
day‐to‐day operations
of an ER..
I just knew I would be more
effective in management.
And then you went back
and got your MBA?
Yeah‐yeah‐yeah,
and then up
the corporate ladder
and blah‐blah‐blah.
Look, I didn't kidnap
you out of that conference
to tell you my life story.
I want to find out
more about you.
Pick your brain
a little bit.
Grapevine says you're doing
great things at County.
I don't know about great.
Ah, my spies tell me about
your waste reduction program.
Yeah, well, saving a syringe
here and some gauze there
is not the kind of dent
my bosses are looking for.
Sounds serious.
You want to bend my ear?
Maybe I can help.
Long story short.
The board is convening
at the end of the week.
‐ That's tomorrow.
‐ Yeah, don't remind me.
And they need to cut ten percent
out of the budget immediately.
We're already down
to the bone as it is.
Are they making suggestions
or just handing you the axe?
Well, they figure
I can chop eight percent
by getting rid of half
of the physician's assistants.
That's not a bad idea.
On paper, maybe.
Not so great if
you have to fire a friend.
So this is about more
than just the bottom line.
Well, it's never easy
letting people go, Kerry.
But there are ways
to make it less painful..
'...and sometimes
less permanent.'
Shall we get some coffee?
Sure. With what
I have waiting for me?
I'm in no rush to get back.
Carol, do you think people
are capable of change?
Starting their lives over?
Yeah, sure. Why not?
I did. I used to have
nothing but deadbeat jobs
and go out with loser guys
and...now look at me.
Did a blood gas come up
on that germ lady?
Uh, yeah. In curtain two.
Actually, Dr. Greene
she seemed a little
upset when she left.
Wanted to get out of here.
So she left before
the test results?
Uh, yeah. She made
a quick phone call and sprayed
the entire receiver with
disinfectant and walked out.
‐ She left AMA.
‐ 'Why would she do that?'
I don't know.
Maybe because Mark was rude
dismissive and patronizing.
I'm sure
that's not true.
It's not my job
to be their best friend.
No, just their caregiver.
What's all the brouhaha?
Dr. Romano and
Dr. Corday are doing an
osteochondral allograft.
Well, hot damn.
That's the first ever
here at County.
Even had the Channel Five news
here covering it
for their sci‐tech segment.
See what I mean, Peter?
The future...is now.
Excuse me.
‐ Excuse me.
‐ Oh, sorry.
‐ Huh?
Vincent Scarletti, 82,
found down in his bathroom
He was in full arrest
on our arrival.
We shocked him twice,
got a rhythm and a pulse.
Mrs. Scarletti,
how long between the time
that you found your husband
and the paramedics arrived?
‐ W‐w‐what is that? What?
‐ She's hard of hearing.
Mrs. Scarletti, how long was
your husband unconscious
until the paramedics
showed up?
Oh, I don't know.
Uh, ten minutes, 15 maybe.
He was here two weeks ago.
They said he was just fine.
We're going to do
everything we can.
'On my count.
One, two, three.'
‐ BP's 80/50.
‐ Pulse ox 90, pulse is 48.
Alright. Start dopamine.
Titrate to a systolic of 100.
Atropine 0.5 migs.
His pupils
are fixed and dilated.
No deep tendon reflexes.
Carol, get a CBC, chem‐7
EKG, blood gas
and a portable chest.
Lily, call respiratory.
Have them set up a vent.
What is it?
What's wrong with my Vincenzo?
It's okay, ma'am.
Please stand back.
He's a good man. We have six
children and 11 grandchildren‐‐
Mrs. Scarletti, you need
to wait outside.
‐ I need to what?
‐ Carol, could I get an assist?
Mrs. Scarletti, come on.
Let's go wait in the hall.
Help him...
‐ Carol?
‐ Mrs. Scarletti.
Come on, we need to let the
doctor do his job. Come on.
Come with me.
'Have you seen Anspaugh?
He's late for a hot appy.'
I think he's doing a AAA.
Oh, those can slog on.
You got something juicy?
‐ Yeah, hernia repair.
‐ Mine's a hot appendix.
Still, they can't all
be newsworthy, eh?
Unlike your osteochondral
allograph this afternoon, huh?
You intentionally sidelined
me for that, didn't you?
What?
'Handed me off to Anspaugh'
'so you could be with Romano.'
That's the silliest
thing I've ever heard.
He called me in to consult,
not the other way around.
Hmm.
If you say so.
No. It's not just what I say.
That's the way it was.
Do you know when Anspaugh
started the AAA?
An hour ago.
My patient's prepped.
I hate to get backed up.
Yeah, you are busy today.
Anspaugh wouldn't mind
if I just started, would he?
It's painting by numbers.
I haven't seen him mind yet.
So you're okay finding another
ride to journal club tonight?
Sure.
I can still give you
a ride home.
‐ No problem.
‐ I just totally spaced it.
I agreed to have dinner
with my grandmother tonight.
Hmm, so, uh, the hot dog's
just an appetizer?
Uh, cooking is not
exactly something you‐‐
Hey, Carter, Anna over here.
Breathe, I can't breathe.
I can't breathe.
Just relax. Hang on.
You're going to be okay.
I'm going to take
this off now.
‐ Okay?
‐ No, no! It's for my allergies.
I already told
the other doctor.
What other doctor?
Come on, let's get a gurney.
‐ Is that Mr. Scarletti?
‐ Yup.
‐ Pretty advanced lung cancer.
‐ Did you pull up his records?
Yeah, he was in two weeks ago.
They told him the cancer had
spread and was now inoperable.
‐ He never told his wife?
‐ Apparently not.
‐ What's her name again?
‐ Margaret Scarletti.
She's sitting over in chairs.
You want me to talk to her?
I'll do it.
Mark. Mark, I apologize
for being late.
I had lunch
with a rep from Synergix
and he had
some interesting ideas.
We're slammed here.
So you're‐‐
Mark, that crack‐head in three
is screaming his head off.
He'll have to wait.
I thought we could discuss
the staffing situation
over at some point.
Since it...
affects us both.
Kerry, I don't really know what
the hell you're talking about.
So why don't you write it down
in a memo and I 'll sign it?
Dr. Greene, this woman
collapsed outside.
‐ She said she saw you earlier.
‐ Yeah.
It's probably anaphylactic
shock. I'll be right there.
I'll get her.
The back pain in two
wants more Demerol.
‐ Yeah, in a minute.
‐ 'Hey, Mark..'
Could you sign off
on this for me?
‐ No. Not now.
‐ We could use the beds.
What should I do
about the back pain?
Well, why don't you
get Doyle to check him out.
Dr. Greene, it's the hospital's
insurance attorney?
Take a message.
Mrs. Scarletti, could you
come with me, please?
My husband, will he be okay?
Will he live? H‐how is he?
I don't think we should
discuss this right here.
What did you say?
Is he going to live?
I said, we need
to find a place to talk.
I'm so worried about Vincenzo.
Please, can I go see him?
‐ No. No, no, no. Not‐not now.
‐ I just want to see how he is.
Look, Mrs. Scarletti,
your husband has no chance
for a meaningful recovery.
He will recover okay?
Oh, thank you so much.
No, no, no, no, no.
I said, your husband
has no chance
for a meaningful recovery.
I‐I don't understand.
What are you saying?
I'm saying that your
husband lied to you
about his condition.
He's going to die.
Jeanie, can you
explain‐explain it to her?
Come on, come on.
Let's talk this one out.
Come on.
Shouldn't somebody go
after him?
‐ Dr. Corday.
‐ 'Oh.'
Heard you were elbow deep
in a rather dicey AAA.
'Oh...I heard
you were doing the appy.'
All finished.
20 minutes and done.
You performed an operation
without an attending present?
Just an appendicectomy.
There weren't any complications.
The complication is...that you
disregarded hospital policy.
'With something as basic as this
I assumed there was leeway.'
You've been here
several months.
Have you seen any surgery
performed without an attending?
No.
I apologize.
In Britain,
we do minor surgery
all the time
without supervision.
I was led to believe..
...the same standards
applied here.
By whom?
I was mistaken,
that's all.
It won't happen again.
Is it true
he just walked out?
Cynthia hot
on his heels.
He always seemed like
such a sensitive guy.
He is a sensitive guy.
Doesn't everybody have
some work to do?
You can't do anything until he
does something for himself.
Ah, man, I'm not going
to make it home to change.
Big plans?
Yeah, I'm gonna hit up this
foundation for a lot of money
and I don't have
anything to wear.
I have a, uh, jacket
in my locker you can borrow.
It's, uh, from the goodwill,
but it looks decent.
‐ Aw, thanks, that'd be great.
‐ Sure.
From what Carter tells me
his grandmother's
a real piece of work.
Carter meaning,
uh, John Carter?
Oh, yeah.
Even though it's called
The Carter Family Foundation,
I get the feeling
the grandmother holds the purse
strings with an iron claw.
‐ The Carter Family Foundation?
‐ Yeah. They're loaded.
Carter's real blue blood.
I figure it's this whole
upstairs, downstairs thing.
Yeah. Uh, you know, it
might help you to take
a doctor along with you
to make your case.
I wrote some pedes
clinic grants at CHOP.
‐ You sure?
‐ Yep.
‐ I'd love to come along.
‐ Okay.
It's like I can't breathe.
I‐it's like there's something
inside of my head
that's, like, pushing,
trying to get out, and then..
Every time I think
I have things under control
it just goes south.
I‐I'm babbling.
No, if you don't want
to talk about it..
Oh, no. It's‐it's..
A few months ago, I was attacked
in the men's room in the ER.
By this gangbanger
who blamed me because his
brother died of a gunshot wound.
Oh, my God.
That's the creep
who's suing you?
They settled the malpractice
suit for three million dollars.
And now,
the bastard's suing me
for violating his
brother's civil rights.
I mean,
figure that one out.
I can't believe it.
He attacked me
from behind.
I tried to fight back,
but I‐‐
But he‐he could
have had a..
...a gun
or been on drugs or‐‐
I didn't even
think about that.
My adrenaline
was pumping so hard, but I..
You're right, I mean, people
on PCP, they..
He could have killed you.
Mark..
...you're so used to handling
everyone else's problems that
you're not used
to asking for help.
‐ Jeanie.
‐ Hi.
I always save these
horse pills till the end.
They're the hardest to swallow.
‐ We should talk.
‐ Mm‐hmm.
I know. Today has been insane.
Any word from Mark?
I've been in talks
with Dr. Anspaugh
about the ER budget.
He's very concerned
about our deficit.
Uh‐huh.
I‐I think
the overages can be
contained with
structural changes
if we aggressively pursue
industrial contracts.
Kerry, wait.
What are you saying?
I have to lay off some of the
staff including two PA's.
The fairest way to do that
is to give preference
to those with seniority.
Are you firing me?
Jeanie, I'm sorry.
I don't have a choice.
You were the last one hired.
Uh, listen. You can work
through the end of month.
Cobra Insurance will
cover your meds.
I've talked to the people
in physical therapy.
They think they're gonna
have an opening
coming up in the next
couple of months.
That's great.
Except it pays not a third less
than what I'm making here.
I want this to be
short‐term.
We're pursuing
outside contracts
and when the new system
is up and running
I'm hoping we can
bring you back.
Guess I'm just
supposed to wait
by the phone
until that happens?
Jeanie..
You know I value
you professionally
and as a friend.
And I 'm gonna do everything
I can to work this out.
I don't care. Please don't
go to any more trouble.
‐ Do I look okay?
‐ You look great.
Whoo!
Ms. Hathaway and, uh..
I'm Dr. Del Amico, Anna.
Yes. Uh, Mrs. Carter
will be a few moments
but she insists
you have a cocktail.
So what may I bring you?
Uh...spring water
would be fine.
Yes.
And you, ma'am?
Uh, what kind of
beer do you have?
Heineken, Grolsch,
Amstel lite‐‐
Oh, actually,
you know what can you just
make that another
spring water?
Certainly. Will you
follow me to the music room?
Please.
Oh, my God.
Ah, that's Mr. Carter in 1985.
He and Marigold took home
a number of blue ribbons
at Tempel Farms that year.
Mar‐marigold?
His thoroughbred.
Please, make yourselves
comfortable.
'Hey, Carol, did you
find the place okay?'
Hey, Carter.
Nice place you have here.
‐ ER..
‐ Any word from Mark?
No, but everybody else
keeps calling.
Doug, could you sign off
on this for me?
‐ Sure.
‐ Mark never got around to it.
‐ Some day, huh?
‐ Yeah, some day.
This is a horrible job.
When is the temp clerk
getting here?
‐ ER. What do you want?
‐ Alright. I am out of here.
‐ Oh, uh, Doug, it's for you.
‐ Tell them I already left.
Uh, it's long distance, collect.
Hello.
This is Doug Ross.
Yep. Okay.
Yeah.
Uh..
When?
Mm‐hmm.
Okay. Are you sure?
Okay. Uh, yeah. Hang on.
Do you have a pen?
Okay.
Thank you.
‐ 'Is everything okay?'
‐ Everything's fine.
No, I mean, I've seen it.
I've seen the kind of thing
nurse Hathaway's talking about.
An ER is about emergent cases.
It's about speed.
Patients that need
continuity of care
tend to, um,
fall through the cracks.
You know, I had a teenage
diabetic the other day‐‐
John, I 'm sure
your diabetic is fascinating
but I 'd like to speak to the
young lady with the proposal.
Sure.
Of course. I'm sorry.
Alone.
Ah!
‐ Right.
‐ Me, too?
Why don't you give Dr. Del Amico
a tour of the grounds?
Okay.
Excuse me.
Dr. Corday,
I'm‐I'm changing.
Shedding your old
skin, Dr. Snake?
I beg your pardon?
You knew full well
I wasn't permitted
to perform
that appendicectomy
but you let me walk
right in there anyway.
Like you knew full well
I should have been notified
about that gastroplasty
this morning, right?
You were home, Peter.
Hicks wanted to
go straight away.
Somebody needed to step in.
Like you needed someone
to step into the ischemic bowel
so you can end up
with Romano.
How dare you accuse me of
trying to manipulate you.
I deserve better than that.
Besides, if I 'd
really wanted to
you wouldn't even
have been aware of it.
Alright, alright.
I suppose I could've called you
but between your
being at home and
my not having done
a gastroplasty‐‐
Look, Dr. Corday,
you are not
the only one
who likes to cut.
No, but if I 'm
the only one here
then I won't be
a‐ashamed of doing it.
Well, then I 'll have
to make sure you're not
in that position again.
Why, thank you, Dr. Benton.
‐ Ah, Dr. Romano.
‐ Yeah?
I'm sorry.
Do you have a minute?
Absolutely.
I was, uh, wondering if
you were still looking for, uh
an extra set of hands.
Would those
be Benton hands?
‐ Yes.
‐ So!
You think you're going
to like the looks
of the 21st century,
is that it?
He simply wants
to keep an eye on me.
Don't you, Dr. Benton?
Someone needs to.
Well, I'll give it some thought.
We'll talk more.
You remember Weebles?
Those little
egg‐looking things?
"Weebles wobble
but they don't fall down"?
Gamma used to hate it.
But I would take
the Faberge eggs
and I'd put them with my
little Weeble family.
As pets.
Alright, I 'm sorry. You know,
I should have said something.
But you were
so anti‐rich people.
I'm even more anti‐liars.
Well, I wanted you
to get to know me first.
Okay...and, uh, meanwhile
I take you to my
favorite thrift store
give you a tour of
roach manor this morning
'and...you must have been
laughing your head off.'
No. Not at all.
I loved that stuff.
A little slumming,
is that it?
You know, before you knew
about all of this
you saw me for what I am,
a regular guy.
A regular guy
doesn't patronize people.
You went out of your way
to make me look like an idiot.
Anna, I'm sorry.
Forget it, Carter.
So, that's it?
My family has a few bucks
and everything changes.
A few bucks?
Is that what this is to you?
It's a figure of speech.
That's exactly what
I'm talkin' about.
To you, this is all
a figure of speech.
To me..
I'm just going to go wait
outside until Carol gets done.
Mark?
It's Doug.
‐ Hi.
‐ Huh.
Cynthia.
Uh, I'm looking for Mark.
Um, I think he might be asleep
already but I 'll check.
‐ I‐oh..
‐ Who is it?
Come on in.
‐ Hey.
‐ Hi.
What's going on?
Uh..
Might be a bad time, huh?
Yeah. Yeah.
Uh, kind of.
You okay?
Hey, um..
Well, I just...wanted to make
sure you were okay.
I'm fine.
I know you've been going
through a rough time.
We're all worried
about you.
I'm okay.
Okay.
Alright.
I'm taking a few days off.
I got a call from California.
Uh, my dad died.
‐ What? W‐w‐what happened?
‐ Nothing, I don't know.
Some car wreck or something.
They weren't real clear
on the details.
Um, but I got to go...
claim the body
and stuff like that. So..
I'm sorry.
Yeah.
I...uh, know.
Alright, I'll talk,
I'll talk to you later.
‐ 'No, no. Hey, come on in.'
‐ No, it's okay. No, no.
‐ I'll talk to you later.
‐ Come on in. I'll make coffee.
‐ Come on.
‐ Alright.
I looked him dead in the eye
and I said, "That might fly
"with your Hollywood
chippies, Mr. President.
But I am a lady."
So, what did he do?
He took his hand off
my rear and apologized.
And that was it?
Then I slept with him.
May I freshen you up?
No, thank you.
I have to drive.
And it's getting late.
Time for the fat lady
to sing.
I like you, Carol.
‐ You remind me of me.
‐ Thank you.
I think you might
just possess the..
...extreme bullheaded
stubbornness..
...to make this
clinic thing work.
How would you like some seed
money to start you off?
Seventy‐five thousand dollars?
Uh, you haven't even
read my proposal.
It's my foundation.
Just don't tell my grandson.
I have a stern,
unapproachable image to keep up.
Oh, well, as far as
I'm concerned
this meeting was hell
from beginning to end.
‐ Exactly.
‐ Thank you so much.
Wow.
Good, good. Ha‐ha.
You're not too late.
I wanted to get
this celebration rolling.
Celebration?
I got a supersaver ticket
to Atlanta.
Tommy's gonna introduce
me to some people
and his sister‐in‐law
is a realtor.
‐ So, you had a good day.
‐ No, not just me.
Tommy‐Tommy knows some doctors
at the County hospital.
Oh.
Sounds too good to be true.
We can make this happen.
We can make this work.
Hey.
What's wrong?
Hi, Kerry.
Ellis.
I know this is strange.
We‐we just met and, uh
here I am calling you up
to come have a drink.
I‐I hope you don't
misunderstand.
Oh, no, please.
You saved me
from having to watch
the local news.
I don't usually do
this kind of thing.
Sure.
That's what they all say.
What's on your mind?
I had to lay off a pretty close
friend this afternoon
and she didn't seem
to appreciate my suggestions
for getting through this.
She just felt fired.
Which is exactly
what she was.
That's right.
When you work your ass off
to try to get her job back
she's not gonna
appreciate that either.
Welcome to the wonderful
world of management.
Can I get you
another drink?
That would be great.
Thanks.
I wish you'd wait
and leave tomorrow.
Nah, I just want
to get on with it.
At least let me give you
a ride to the airport.
Nah, I'm just gonna
leave the car in parking..
...pick Mark up on the way.
I'm glad
he's going with you.
Yeah, it's probably
a good idea for him
to get out of town
for a while.
I'm gonna miss you.
I love you, Carol.
I love you, too.