One minute, I'm freezing,
the next I'm burning up.
I can't keep anything down.
Sir. It's probably the
flu. It's going around.
Oh, I got body
aches, nasty cough.
I really need to see a doctor.
Have a seat. We'll
get to you in a minute.
That's what you
said an hour ago.
Hey. I need to go home, chief.
Forget it, Malucci. We're
shorthanded as it is.
No, really. I just
puked up my breakfast.
So did half the Radiology techs.
I got a fever, all right.
Feel my head.
Feel your own head.
Well, cold and flu season
has hit with a vengeance.
Yes, take your pick.
Fever, sore
throats, runny noses,
assorted aches
and pains, vomiting.
Why don't these people go home?
My point exactly. I got
it coming out both ends.
Thanks for sharing, Dave.
Okay, the lab is backed up.
It's taking four
hours to get a CBC.
They're 40 behind in Triage.
You look awful, Kerry.
Yeah, and I look
better than I feel.
No telemetry beds, we're
boarding seven patients.
Carol called in
two... registry nurses.
God only knows
when they'll get here.
Nasty cough, Kerry.
You should see a doctor.
I should too. You don't want me
exposing the patients, do you?
Take some Imodium. Wear a mask.
Did you touch the thermostat?
No, I just cleaned
out the sediment.
Morning, Mark. Good morning.
Hey, Mark. Did you
let the faucets run?
Yeah, for, like, 10 minutes.
It was freezing cold.
I had to boil water on the stove
and wash my hair in the sink.
I'll have to call a
plumber. No, no, no.
Let... Let me look at it again.
A plumber will want
to sell you a new one.
It's old, not dead.
What?
Kovac is fixing
your water heater?
Well, trying to fix it.
He was dropping
me off, Mark. Oh.
From work.
I was complaining about
it making some noise,
and he w... Why am I
even explaining this to you?
Beats me.
No, it's not what think.
Then what am I thinking?
I don't know, but
it's not. It's not what?
It's not anything.
Move back, now.
We're coming through.
If you've got the
flu... Excuse me.
It's too late for a flu shot.
I'm Abby Lockhart.
ER, please hold.
I'm supposed to
be... ER. Please...
ER.
Abby. Yeah.
Did they send you
down here? Um, yeah.
Oh, God. I was wondering
when we were
gonna get some help.
Carol. Hathaway.
Right. You were my
OB nurse. Thanksgiving.
Twins girls. How
are they? Great.
Sleeping through the night.
Just not at the same time.
I don't know how
do you do it. Well,
it's not easy, but neither
is managing 36 patients
when we're short two
nurses. Well, actually...
Coming through. I
found him in the L station.
I asked him to
move. He can't walk.
What's open, Carol? If
you can find a bed, grab it.
Oh.
Sorry. That's lovely.
Somebody call Housekeeping!
Yeah, great. Med students.
They think we're their maids.
We are so swamped.
Right. But actually...
Can you send Mr. Sranski
up for a chest film?
Sranski? Flu patient.
That helps.
You're gonna need
scrubs. No. I don't think...
Haleh, do we have any
scrubs? I don't know, I don't care.
We really do get along.
Hey, Carol, you
believe in zombies?
What? Night of the Living Dead.
Human cadavers walking the earth
after they've died?
No. What's Earl Cartesh's
body still doing in Exam 1.
I called Transport. What do
you want me to do about it?
Piggyback it to the morgue.
I need the bed.
Residents. Only thing
worse than students. Right.
Can somebody take this?
I've been waiting five minutes.
Did you call ahead?
Yeah. Todd Sullivan, 5,
of the sledding
Sullivans. Good vitals.
But he took a nasty header
while sledding. Mom's coming.
I lost my teeth.
Oh, sweetie, don't worry.
They're your baby teeth.
Hey, Malik, can you call a doc?
Yeah, right. Good luck.
He's avulsed his front incisors.
We need a C-spine and a head CT.
Yeah, if we can
find a doc to order it.
I could do it. What?
Med students work on
patients, right? Yeah.
I'm a third-year. I start
my ER rotation today.
You're a med student?
Yes.
What can I say? I crossed
over to the dark side.
His facial films are clear,
and I paged an oral surgeon.
Luka, do you want me
to update his tetanus?
He had one a year
ago. Uh, guess not.
By the way, I'm Luka Kovac.
Abby Lockhart. I'm a third-year.
Another new resident
in the middle of the year?
Well, I'm a med student. Oh.
Another half gram of Ancef?
Uh, Abby?
Uh, sure. Sounds good.
Okay. Nice job.
Well, we never had
doctors like that up in OB.
Hm. Easy on the eyes, isn't he?
I'll say. Is he single?
He doesn't talk
about his personal life.
Ooh. Tall, dark, handsome
and mysterious, huh?
What are you doing? Cleaning up.
Oh, don't worry. I
got it. Don't be silly.
No, really, I got it.
Okay.
Um, Carol.
I'd love to see some
pictures of your girls later.
Sure.
He has to take his
blood-pressure pills every day.
Well, sometimes he forgets.
Well, maybe you can remind him.
S-sometimes I forget.
Well, maybe you can put a
note on your medicine cabinet
to remind you.
That's a good idea.
I'll try to remember that.
Hey, Mark, I'm...
I'm feeling horrible.
Can you cover
the rest of my shift?
Must be bad. I don't
remember you taking a sick day.
I'd rather die at home.
Oh, and we have a
new medical student.
Make sure she
doesn't kill anyone.
Hey, Malucci, leave
her alone. Abby...
Give me a break,
chief. Yeah, suck it up.
Abby Lockhart, third-year,
Mark Greene, Attending.
We've met. Good.
Good. I'll see you tomorrow,
if I live through the night.
So she wasn't hallucinating?
No, I'm a med student.
And an OB nurse.
Well, I take a shift
occasionally to pay the bills.
Right. Well, welcome
to the glory that is ER.
Has anybody given you
the $3 tour? No, not yet.
Well, you start
here by signing up
for your patient on the board.
Grab a T-sheet based
on the chief complaint.
Nurses' orders go here.
Labs and x-rays
go here for the clerk.
Any questions? So far, so good.
That's Curtain Area 1.
This is Curtain Area 2.
That's Yosh Takata.
Wave hi to Yosh.
Hi.
That's Trauma 1,
Trauma 2. Haleh...
We've met. Hi.
Still hurting, Todd?
A little. Yeah?
Uh, we gave him
four, uh, morphine.
Can we give him two more?
Why not. You sure
you need this tour?
Couldn't hurt.
Then come on. The
tram doesn't stop.
You need to keep your hands
and arms inside at all times.
What do you got, Carter?
This is Darnel Smith, 13,
with muscular dystrophy.
Visiting us with a
possible forearm fracture.
What happened, Darnel?
Loser pushed me down the stairs.
In your wheelchair? Duh.
Yeah, he got into
a fight at school.
Cleo's got the pusher.
All right. Well, let's keep
the two of them apart, shall we?
Oh, that was Carter. Got it.
And this is the Pedes ER. It's
really just a large exam room
with, uh, pediatric equipment
and murals on the wall.
Hey, Cleo.
Hey.
I was just going to class,
and then he just started
freaking out on me
in the hallway when
I tried to get past him.
That's no reason to
push a kid down the steps.
Yeah, well, he...
Especially in a wheelchair.
I didn't even push the psycho
until he stabbed
me with his pencil.
What are you looking at?
Darnel, don't be rude.
Well, the good news
is his arm's not broken.
I can't believe one
of his classmates
would be cruel
enough to do this.
Well, I heard that he
might have provoked it.
Darnel, is that true?
No.
He's been acting up lately.
At home and at school.
Is he in special ed?
No. He's in a regular classroom.
We wanted his life to
be as normal as possible.
It says here you have cancer.
They're gonna
chop off your penis.
Hey, that's enough
of that. Darnel!
He's just kidding.
Mrs. Henry, why don't
you go wait in Chairs.
I don't like to leave him alone.
Well, I still need to check
him for other injuries.
Oh, all right. You
behave yourself.
A-and I'll be right
out in the waiting area
if you need anything, honey.
So, Darnel...
sounds like you're having
a little trouble in school.
That wouldn't
have anything to do
with your muscular
dystrophy, would it?
So suddenly you don't speak.
I can't feel my toes.
It looks like you have
frostbite, Mr. Clayton.
Do we need to
débride? Is he diabetic?
No. He has a
respiratory infection.
Probably the flu.
But his lungs are wet.
All right. Skin is pliable.
Frostbite is superficial.
Start him on a rapid rewarm
of 105-degree circulating water
for 20 minutes, okay? Thanks.
Is anybody in
this city not sick?
It's like the damn
plague down here.
I don't suppose you're here to
lend a helping hand, are you?
Why mess with natural selection.
A good influenza epidemic
thins the herd. Where's Kerry?
She went home sick.
They wonder why we
call them the weaker sex.
Oh, did you, uh,
book an O.R. for 3:00?
Oh, yeah. I saw an
opening, so I grabbed it.
I'm assisting Dr. Ashcoff
on a facial-scar revision.
Why can't that be done
in the Plastics clinic?
Multiple scars. Ashcoff
wants to do it under General.
And what does that
have to do with you?
Well, the little girl's
a patient of mine.
I'm following up on a dog
bite from six months ago.
Yeah, so?
Well, Medicaid won't cover it.
So, uh, I got Ashcoff
to donate his time.
I was hoping that...
Whoa, whoa, whoa. We provide
medically-necessary services
to the poor.
That does not include
cosmetic surgery.
What's next,
liposuction for fat kids?
A little girl is disfigured.
Look, Peter... I admire
your noble effort.
But this is exactly
the kind of thing
that could lose our
state funding, okay?
I'm sorry, big guy.
I won't get lead poisoning,
will I? From the pencil?
They use graphite in pencils.
Temp's 99.2.
Did that hurt?
Ah, no. No. It's just cold.
Oh. Sorry.
How did you get these bruises?
Uh, I don't know.
Who hit you, Marty?
Some kids at school.
Are you sure?
Oh, yeah, I'm sure. I mean,
I'm there when they do it.
Do your parents know about this?
No.
What about the
teachers or the principal?
Yeah, so that they
can really kill me?
What's this?
Uh... Mosquito bites.
In February?
They must be hungry.
You have quite a few.
Look, is my dad coming?
He's on his way.
I'll be back.
Get a CBC, Chem-20,
and a tox screen.
Those are infected track marks.
What exactly am I looking for?
Top of page 4. I was enjoying
my first free morning in ages.
Sat down with a
paper, when I spotted it.
What?
Oh.
For Pete's sake.
"University of Chicago's
Department of Astrophysics..."
Blah, blah, blah. "will
present a symposium."
Blah, blah. "Guest
speakers include..."
"Isabelle Corday." Your mother.
Yes.
I see the resemblance.
I look like my father.
See, you didn't tell me your
mother's coming to town.
I didn't know. It's so like her.
You guys having a fight?
No. No. She's just
being Mother. Oh.
You know, you should call her.
I'm supposed to come to
her, that's part of the game.
Or don't call her.
I won't. I'm not
playing anymore.
Get off me! I'll kill you!
Yeah... I'll kill
you! Hold still!
Was he trying to hurt himself?
No, he's just freaking out.
Is he on any medication?
He's on drugs.
Yeah. Looks like PCP
to me. What happened?
Jumped out a third-story window.
Let me go! I'll kill you!
He didn't even feel it. He
tried to walk away from it.
He'll feel something soon
enough! Get out of the way!
What are you doing?
I wanna tape this so he sees
what he acts like on this.
Chris, We're trying to help.
Bilateral tibial deformities.
He's broken both
legs. Exposed bone.
Ever seen an open
fracture? Not up close.
He's taching away.
Pulse is strong.
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Ten of Haldol, I.M.
Get those restraints on.
Get that out of here!
Please back up,
let the doctors work.
No, no, this is too good.
Now! CORDAY: CBC, coag panel,
tox screen, UA and a myoglobin!
I'm gonna kill you, you bitch!
I need that Haldol now!
What? More restraints or Haldol?
I got it. CORDAY:
Okay, tetanus booster,
gram of Ancef! Let me go!
Okay. Roll him.
Give it in the thigh interior.
Ow! Ow.
You okay? Yeah.
I'm gonna need a culture swab.
Set me up for P.M. splints!
Let me go!
You had Heptovax, right?
Yeah. But the patients
generally don't bite in OB.
Yeah, it's an occupational
hazard down here.
Serologies will
be back tomorrow.
Don't sweat it.
Bet you didn't expect to
be your own teaching case.
Well, I expected the ER to be different.
- Ow!
Well, if you would stop
squirming, I could get it in.
Well, could you be any rougher?
Could you whine anymore?
Dave. Be glad she's
not putting in a Foley.
We have a tradition down here
that once you've been
bitten by a raving lunatic,
you're ready to see patients.
I don't know.
Grab a chart.
And yell if you
get into trouble.
Okay.
Carol... can you
keep an eye on her?
Sure.
Oh, and update her tetanus.
I want you to press on my hand
like you're stepping on the gas.
Uh, that's good.
Let's do the other foot.
You do much driving, Darnel?
Okay.
Now I want you to
squeeze my hand.
And if you make me scream,
I'll give you a prize.
Give me a break.
He speaks!
Okay, come on.
I wanna see how the MD's
affecting your body.
Duchenne's muscular dystrophy
is an x-linked
genetic disorder...
characterized by the progressive
wasting of skeletal muscles.
First you lose your
legs, then your arms,
and then you die.
That's how it's
affecting my body.
I want you to
hold his head still.
I'm sorry, he's
gotten to the point
where he really hates hospitals.
It's okay, Conner,
don't be afraid.
We wanna make you better.
He's really a good-natured kid,
you know, considering
everything he's been through.
What kind of surgery has he had?
He had a Nissen fundoplication
for gastroesophageal reflux.
He's had a hemicolectomy,
and a few laparotomies
for adhesions.
When did he start vomiting?
This morning.
Okay, mucus membranes are moist.
Were you feeding him
orally or through his G-tube?
Well, I gave him a little
bit by mouth last night.
But not enough to induce this.
I'm praying it's just the flu.
But I'm afraid he's got
another bowel obstruction.
Abby. Can you get this?
We have a foreign
body ingestion in Exam 2.
Sure. Just a sec.
Luka? Hm?
Can I steal Abby from you?
We're really
backing up out there.
Yeah, yeah. It's okay. Go ahead.
So, what do you think it is?
I'm not sure.
I'm gonna have to
take some x-rays first.
Carol, uh, can I get a weight
and a three-way
abdominal series?
Sure.
You dehydrated or something?
How'd you guess? Jeremy Barnes.
Three days of abdominal
cramping, some diarrhea.
Maybe a low-grade fever
with a history of a triple-A.
How are you feeling, sir?
Lousy.
Mm-hm. Any vomiting?
No. I... I... I feel
real nauseous now.
When was your aneurysm repaired?
Uh. Year and a half ago. I...
Any complications?
No complications. I...
I was feeling great
until last week.
Well, it's benign.
It's just the flu.
Thank you. Mm.
You're welcome.
Maybe he's telling the truth.
Mm, kids his age,
school can get kind of rough.
This isn't roughhousing. He
has skin-popping abscesses.
You get a tox screen?
It's negative. Only the
white count's up. He's clean.
You can't be sure.
Tox screen doesn't
cover everything.
What are you
thinking? I don't know.
But, uh, maybe you
can bluff it out of him.
Lucy, you okay?
Somebody stole my patient.
Peter, did you
steal Lucy's patient?
Check the lost and found.
Dr. Benton?
Hi. Mrs. Fulton. Hi.
I took Tia up to
surgery to register,
and the nurse said she can't
have her operation today?
Uh... You... Actually,
I tried to call you.
Please, have a seat. Come on.
Um, there's an availability
problem in the O.R.
Mm-hm. Did Dr. Ashcoff
change his mind?
No, no, no, no, no.
We just have to reschedule.
Well, we came all
the way down here.
We can wait.
Tia hasn't eaten in
eight hours like you said...
We can't... do it today.
I'm... I'm sorry.
I'm not gonna get 'em fixed?
You waited this long.
A few more days
isn't gonna hurt.
Hold on a minute, honey.
Can we...?
It has taken me
months to get Tia
to step out of the house.
I can't give her false hope.
Now, if this isn't
gonna happen...
you need to tell us.
It's gonna happen.
I just need a little
time, that's all.
Thanks.
Mr. Barnes needs 5 of Compazine.
Then run a liter
of saline through
and check his electrolytes.
Can't you get a
nurse to do that?
Rumor has it you used to be one.
Well, that's not why I'm here.
You're absolutely right.
You're here to learn.
And this is a great
opportunity for you to learn
how to check his stool for...
fecal leukocytes.
Thanks.
What's his pulse
ox? It's down to 82.
And how much O2 is he on?
Ten liters.
The flu is making it
difficult for you to breathe.
Ah, it ain't... just the flu.
It ain't...
No. You also have
what's called
congestive heart failure.
And we need to put a tube
down your throat
to help you breathe.
No. Thank you.
Do you have someone we can call?
No.
All my friends is homeless.
No phones.
Any family?
None.
Okay.
I really think you need
to go on a ventilator.
No.
Thank you.
I... always hoped I might...
die in a warm bed.
W... With clean sheets.
If it's all the same to you.
X-rays show nonspecific
bowel gas pattern.
So it's not another adhesion?
Right.
Blood gas is back.
PH is 7.38. PCO2 is 30.
Is it respiratory alkalosis?
Partly. But, uh,
also an acidosis.
It's... It's complicated.
Are you a nurse?
Oh, no. I've just
read every book
and every Internet
article on chalasia.
Last time, did they
do an upper GI?
Six months ago. They
thought he might have
a gastric outlet blockage.
You're not gonna have
do that again, are you?
It will rule out an obstruction.
Oh, no, please. It was horrible.
He couldn't swallow the barium.
T-they had to put an
NG tube up his nose.
He wouldn't stop
crying. Mrs. Brant,
I know Conner has
been through a lot.
But he has a severe
metabolic disorder,
and we... We have to find
out what's making him sick.
And I'll be as
gentle as possible.
Okay?
Okay.
I'll be back.
What?
You tell me.
Nothing.
We tested your blood, Marty.
Yeah? So?
So where do you
get the dirty needles?
What do you mean?
Marty, I know.
You can't tell my dad. Please.
He's not gonna understand.
You can't use dirty needles.
You're getting an infection.
And if you share,
you could get HIV.
Do you know what that is?
Yeah, don't even worry.
I stole them from
my grandmother.
She's got diabetes.
Why are you doing this?
Mm. Kids with crooked
teeth get braces, and...
my mom got laser
surgery on her eyes.
You know, why
can't I use hormones?
For what?
To grow taller.
You're injecting human
growth hormone?
Where do you get it?
Look, it... It's not illegal.
You can't get HGH
without a prescription.
Where do you get it, Marty?
Off the Internet.
Then you don't even
know what's in it.
Do you have any idea
what sort of health risks
you've exposed yourself to?
W... Well, it can't be any worse
than being beat up every day.
I mean, even that stupid
kid in the wheelchair
thinks that he can pick on me.
Look. If you can get
me the real stuff, I-I...
Hormone therapy is for kids
who have problems,
not for healthy adolescents.
Yeah, well, I'm not healthy.
You know, I go to
school every day
knowing that I'm
gonna be beat up
or shoved into a locker
or dragged into the
girls' shower room.
Do you have any idea
how embarrassing it is to
be stuffed inside a trash can
while the whole
cafeteria's laughing at you?
Hormones aren't
going to help that.
Yeah?
Well, being bigger will.
Hey. Hi.
You okay?
Oh, yeah.
Have you seen the Cetacaine?
No. I haven't used any.
We always keep
it on this counter.
Sorry. Ugh.
Um, Carol?
Are you...
uncomfortable
with my being here?
Why would I be?
Well, I know, sometimes
it's hard for nurses
when nurses go to med school.
Kind of like I switched
teams or something.
I think I'm gonna be sick.
No, you know, actually...
Um, I almost went
to med school myself.
Is it something else?
It's just stupid.
Oh, my God!
Mr. Barnes. Have
you had an ulcer?
Oh, my God. What's
wrong with him?
I don't know. Uh,
prep the section.
I'm gonna go get a
doctor. Okay. Um, uh...
I-I need a Yankauer. Top drawer!
Peter!
I'm gonna start a line.
What is it? Check his BP.
Uh... Had some Compazine,
and he just started
vomiting bright red blood.
Okay, what's the history?
Um, looks like triple-A.
I think he came
in with an ulcer.
You think? He's not my patient.
Okay, here we go. Here we go.
All right. Set me
up for a central line.
Carol, squeeze in two liters.
Get me four units O-neg.
Typing cross for eight.
What's wrong with him?
He's bleeding out
through his GI tract.
Somebody call the O.R.
What the hell happened?
Aortoenteric fistula.
We need an airway.
Should we get him to
the O.R.? No, tube him.
8-0 ET.
Ah, damn it.
Come on, Malucci. Now.
Why wasn't he sent upstairs?
Corday said it was the flu.
His pulse is weak. BP's 50 palp.
He won't make it to the O.R.
unless we stop the bleeding.
Lines in. What's your name?
Abby Lockhart. A med student.
Can you sew this? Y... N... Yes.
Uh, just an interrupted suture?
I don't care. As long
as it doesn't pull away.
Let's move.
All right, prep
his belly for a lap.
You can't do a
laparotomy down here...
We don't have a choice. Scalpel!
All right. Do a small
midline incision
and clamp below the diaphragm.
You got that? Almost.
All right. Let's go. Let's move.
Pressure's up to 90.
This'll hold till we
get him upstairs.
Call O.R. Tell 'em we're coming.
Two units of O-neg
in. I need more.
Operating in the ER,
Peter? Shame on you.
He had an aortoenteric fistula.
Then why the hell didn't
you admit him to surgery?
He presented with flu symptoms.
This look like the flu...
What's your name... Malatucci?
Malucci. No, but the
patient was bleeding out.
If it wasn't for
Dr. Benton... Yeah.
Save it for the hearing, kid.
Peter, let's get
this guy to O.R.
before you use up the
rest of our blood supply.
You got to admit, that was...
That was pretty cool.
Can I go home now?
Not just yet.
I want you to try
something first.
What?
Computer.
I've seen one or two.
I was thinking maybe you
were having trouble at school
because the MD's
affecting your motor skills.
Wrong.
In which case, a computer
might help you keep
up with the other kids.
Who says I want to?
The school is full of losers.
Oh. Well, come on.
Just give it a try.
Oops.
Feel better?
A little.
You want to smash
something else?
Maybe.
Is that the best you can do?
Yeah. You can
do better than that.
Here.
Yeah, that's it. That's it.
Now, let me see
you write your name.
Why are you doing this?
I'm trying to help you.
I'm tired of people trying
to help me all the time.
I can do things for myself.
People trying to help
too much sometimes?
I don't need to
be pushed around.
have my food cut.
I don't need my mom giving
me a freaking bath all the time.
I'm not a baby.
No, you're not.
I'm gonna go talk
to your mother.
Why don't you clean this up?
Me?
You helped me make the mess.
You can help me clean it up.
Okay.
It's okay, honey.
It's almost done.
There. No more.
Luka, I need to talk
to you for a minute.
Hold on. I have to
give the contrast.
It'll just take a second.
Okay. I'll be right back.
Good boy. Good boy.
Yeah. Good boy, honey.
Good boy.
I tried contacting
his pediatrician.
Mm-hm. He doesn't have one.
Which seemed kind of
weird to me for a kid this sick.
So I called around.
I called Northwestern,
Rush, Mercy.
Conner's been
admitted to all three ERs.
Several times,
multiple admissions.
Several laparotomies.
I know. I've seen the scars.
Yeah. But he's only ever
really needed surgery once
for his fundoplication.
All the rest were
exploratory procedures,
and they didn't find anything.
He has a metabolic disorder,
and he is still at high risk
for adhesions and obstruction.
But nobody has been
able to document anything
since his first surgery.
I know. But something's
making him sick.
You've thought about the mother?
Yeah. What about her?
Well, maybe she's intentionally
inducing his symptoms.
Carol, she's done
everything she can
to find out what's
wrong with him.
Maybe she likes the
attention. Attention?
You mean... What, she'd
hurt her child for attention?
I've seen parents do it before.
Okay, how? I mean,
how is she doing this?
I don't know. Yeah, but
you can't say this kind
of thing without proof.
What happens when
his upper GI is negative?
CT shows nothing?
Are you gonna
admit him for surgery?
I've just started the work-up.
Give me a chance
to figure it out.
Will you just consider it?
Yeah. I'll... I'll consider it.
Okay.
There's nothing wrong with him.
He's being abused
by his classmates.
So he needs to
learn to fight back.
That's not a solution.
Look, Dr. Finch.
My son's short. So what?
I'm short.
And, yeah, I got picked on.
But I learned to deal
with it. And so will he.
How? By injecting himself
with God knows what?
That's not gonna happen
again. I can assure you.
Dr. Finch, Marty
spiked a fever of 103.
How are you feeling, Marty?
Pretty crummy.
What do you expect after pumping
that crap into your body?
Have you had a fever recently?
Last week he had the flu.
There's a pansystolic murmur.
What does that mean?
Has he had a heart
murmur before?
No. He's got
splinter hemorrhages.
What's going on?
Yosh, get three sets
of blood cultures.
We'll start him on
pentox and gent.
And order a cardiac echo. Okay.
Is there something
wrong with my heart?
The needle you kept using
may have put bacteria
into your bloodstream...
causing an infection
of your heart.
Mr. Spencer?
I'm Abby Lockhart.
I need a private room.
I don't think we have any.
Well, there should be.
With this flu
epidemic, this place
is one big petri dish.
Would you take a deep breath?
What if somebody
comes in with TB,
or leprosy or something?
What seems to be
your problem today?
I think my pulse
is thready. Really?
My stomach's upset.
My chest feels tight.
I'm fatigued.
Uh, my head is pounding,
and I can barely hear anything.
Do your stools glow in the dark?
What?
Your ears are full
of wax, Mr. Spencer.
Oh, man. I read
somewhere you can get that
from food additives or
environmental toxins.
I can clean them out for you.
How do you do that? I was
told never to put anything
in my ears smaller
than my elbow.
Well, we use a special drill.
A... A drill? I'm kidding.
I use peroxide.
Mrs. Brant? Radiology's ready.
Okay. Okay. Here we go, sweetie.
What about my palpitations.
I think I need an EKG.
I'll try to find one. Carol,
where's the EKG machine?
Uh, Try the Trauma rooms.
Do you need me to draw labs?
No. I got it.
We can wheel him
out on the gurney.
No, I'd rather carry
him, if that's okay.
Okay. Sure.
Dr. Romano, I'm still
on shift downstairs.
You should've considered
that before you decided
to turn the ER into your
own private operating room.
But I'm not doing anything
here. It won't kill you to observe.
You obviously still have
a few things left to learn.
Somebody turn down the heat.
It's a hundred degrees in here.
The thermostat's set at 68.
Maybe you have the
flu. I don't get sick.
Maybe you're going
through the change.
DeBakey clamp.
I can finish up if you'd like.
What I would like is
for you to stand there
and shut up while I try
to save this man's life.
Suction.
What did you find?
No obstruction. The
study was negative.
So, what do we do now?
We should do a CT scan.
What about endoscopy?
I don't want to put your son
through an another
invasive procedure
if I don't have to.
Okay, but I feel
we're wasting time.
Shouldn't a surgeon see him?
After the scan.
Sats down to 78.
Put him on 100%
nonrebreather mask.
Mr. Clayton, is there
anything else I can do for you
to make you more comfortable?
My lunch box.
This?
There's $118 in there.
Give it to my friends.
Is there a specific shelter
you want it to go to?
Oh, just... throw
it off the roof.
Throw the money off the roof?
Yeah. They'll find it.
Conner's GI series was negative.
You seem surprised.
After you said that
about the mother,
I was hoping to find
something wrong with him,
but, uh, she wants an endoscopy.
Almost seemed disappointed
when I wanted to wait.
And, uh, I-I think
you might be right.
Is this going to hurt?
No. It's just peroxide.
You might feel a few bubbles.
Bubbles? What if they
get into my bloodstream?
I could get an embolism.
That's not gonna happen.
Um, I forgot a
curette. I'll be back.
What about my chest
pains? Your EKG was normal.
Yeah, but that doesn't
rule out unstable angina.
Maybe I should
have a stress echo.
I don't think that's necessary.
What is the sense of having
all this sophisticated
technology
if you die before you
get a chance to use it?
Hey!
Sorry about that.
That's okay.
How's he doing?
Oh, uh, well, not so good.
Uh, it's the same story.
Lots of tests,
and they can't figure out
what's wrong with him.
Well, I'm sure Dr. Kovac
is being as thorough...
Did he call for a
surgical consult yet?
I don't know. I could check.
Would you? Sure.
Another 3.0 Prolene.
Get that rake out
of my way, please.
Oh, man!
Dr. Romano, sure
you're okay? Yes.
You just spent
the last 20 minutes
over-sewing the duodenal defect.
There's no substitute
for precision, Peter.
Lizzie. Come to join the party?
I heard Mr. Barnes
eroded his aortic graft.
Is he a friend of yours?
Well, I evaluated
him downstairs.
I thought he had
gastroenteritis.
Really? Peter, you
never mentioned that.
How valiant of you to
not have ratted Lizzie out
on her gross oversight.
How's he doing?
Fine. Now that he's been
competently diagnosed
and brought to a proper O.R.
Peter, you're dismissed.
Lizzie, scrub in.
Well, I'm off, actually.
No, actually,
you're not anymore.
Give me a peanut.
I'm gonna dissect the small
bowel off the aorta now.
You'd be better
off using a Metz.
Peter, I'd quit while
I were ahead if I...
Ah! Ow! Damn it!
Robert? I'm fine. Uh... Robert?
God, he's burning up!
I got this. Open up a new tray.
Let's get Metz and pick-up.
Get a gurney! He's got a
weak pulse! Tachy at 140.
The suction. 3.0
Prolene. Let's get ready.
You're not afraid
you'll catch cold?
Hey, if I haven't
caught one by now...
They're not stacking
up again, are they?
No. I think it's over.
Figure out what was
wrong with that kid?
Yeah, he got
tired of being short,
so he injected himself
with bogus growth hormone.
Of course. Why
didn't I think of that?
His echo shows vegetations
on his mitral valve.
Endocarditis?
Kept reusing Grandma's
insulin needles.
What did Cardiology say?
They admitted him. Put
him on triple antibiotics.
Hopefully, I caught it
before he needs surgery.
Wooh. All of that for
a couple of inches.
Yep.
You're releasing too
early when you shoot.
Oh. Why don't you show me?
You don't want any of this.
Oh, I don't? Trust me.
Okay. Show me what you got.
What is it? Something's wrong.
His stomach is distended.
Give me a syringe.
I told you to call a
surgeon! He's getting worse.
W-what? What are you doing?
Hold on.
Oh, my God. What is
that? Is he bleeding?
No. It's an indicator
mixed with saline.
Turns red in the stomach acid.
What are you talking about?
That's not mine.
Th-that belongs to
the doctor or the
nurse, whate...
Whoever it was,
she left it here.
Well, actually, we
had her leave it.
And it's not
peroxide. It's saline.
I don't know what
you're talking about?
Oh, yes you did, Mrs. Brant.
You've been poisoning him.
And this proves it.
Security to Curtain 3.
Okay, okay, wait. Stop, stop.
I... I didn't give you
permission to do this.
We are leaving! No,
I'm afraid you're not.
I can't allow you
to keep hurting him.
I love Conner.
I would never hurt him.
Mrs. Brant... you need help.
Oh, God.
Okay, sweetie. It's okay.
It's okay, sweetie.
They're not gonna hurt you.
Mommy has you.
Mommy has you, honey.
It's okay.
Amira, call Transport.
Mr. Clayton in Exam 1
needs to go to the
morgue. That old guy died?
From the flu.
Put him into
respiratory failure.
I knew I should've
gotten that flu shot.
Someone give you a tip?
He had a daughter. Who?
My homeless man who
died told me he had no family.
And what? You're the
executor of his estate?
Something like that.
Hey, Abby. Hey.
Did you know it's a
tradition for the residents
to take students for
a drink after day one?
Thought you were sick.
Well, maybe you could
nurse me back to... Whoa.
Wow. You... You
look... Sst. Wow!
Uh, y-you know...
Did you have a hot
date or something?
Maybe.
Excuse me, you're
drooling on my chart.
Sorry. Um... So... yeah.
How about that drink?
You're kidding, right?
I'm just...
How's he doing?
Grouchier than ever.
He has a kidney stone.
Ah. You're kidding.
Not as big as
we'd like, mind you.
He won't need surgery.
Passing through
the old plumbing.
That can't be a lot of fun.
Thanks for covering for
me. You didn't have to.
But I really appreciate it.
Anybody could've
missed it. Well, I hope so.
My mind was elsewhere. Yeah.
So you're going in to gloat?
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, I wouldn't take too much
glee in this if I
were you, Peter.
No, no, no. I just
came to tell you
that Mr. Barnes is,
uh, stable in Recovery.
It's a good thing I was
observing when this happened.
Suppose you think this
means I owe you something.
I'll settle for a thank you.
How very gracious of
you, Peter. Thank you.
And the O.R. time that I need
for the little girl's
facial surgery.
Look, you finished a repair
and closed for me. Big deal.
How can you be
against a little girl
getting her face fixed?
This is my job.
If word gets out that
I do favors for you,
I'll have to do
them for everybody.
Which is why we never
had this conversation.
So that means I
can have the O.R.?
I don't want to
know about... Mm.
Ah. And good luck with that.
Thank you.
You're welcome, Peter.
Abby, thank you for
helping back there.
I know it was bizarre. Oh, sure.
Did she actually pour
it down his G-tube?
Yeah, it didn't take her long.
I bet you were never part
of a sting operation upstairs?
No. It's the first.
Welcome to the ER.
Abby? Yeah?
Do you have a patient
named Spencer?
The hypochondriac, yeah.
He's having a heart attack.
What?
All right, start him on
dopamine, 10 mics per kilo.
Oh, God. What happened?
Is this your patient? Yeah.
Did you give him medication?
No. I cleaned out his ears.
BP, 70 palp.
All right. Did he complain
of any chest pains?
Yeah, he complained of
everything. His EKG was normal.
Not anymore. ST
elevation on the 12-lead.
He's having an acute MI.
He had a history of reflux.
There was no
cardiac risk factor.
HemoCue is six. Hang
two units of pac cells.
He's gonna need
nitroglycerin and a heparin drip.
I'll start a second line.
V-tach.
Charge to 100.
Synch cardioversion.
Chuny can get that. Take those.
It's your patient.
Clear.
Elizabeth. Hello, Mother.
What are you doing here?
Oh. I live here, remember?
Yes. I meant to call you.
I just got in last week.
Oh, Elizabeth, save
me the pouty face.
I'm not pouting. I
just can't believe
you were going to travel several
thousand miles and not call me.
Yes. Well, I'm here now.
And freezing.
So if we're going to
continue this conversation,
could we find somewhere warm?
Preferably where
they serve alcohol.
Or have the
Americans banned that
together with tobacco?
Anyone ever tell you
white men can't jump?
Now, that was a foul. Ha.
Oh, I get a foul
because you tripped.
No, you hip-checked me.
Dr. Greene?
What is it?
You said call if I
got into trouble.
Yeah.
Well, um...
He was a hypochondriac.
All his tests came back normal.
MIs don't always present
textbook symptoms.
You didn't get a blood count.
White count was 1800.
Crit was only 18.
What does that mean?
Aplastic anemia.
Bingo. Decreased
oxygen-carrying capacity
is a risk factor.
You're gonna need Hematology
down here for a consult.
They're gonna want to
do a bone marrow biopsy.
I'm sorry. No, I'm sorry.
I should've protected you more.
It's great that
you were a nurse,
but you gotta start
thinking like a doctor, okay?
You don't have to do it all.
From now on, make sure that
the nurses order your labs.
Okay? They have a
standing order on CBCs.
See you tomorrow. Okay.
I don't know how you managed
to keep your complexion here.
Wind. Nothing but wind.
I don't work on a
construction site.
Oh, that's right.
You cut people
up, like your father.
How is Charles?
Happy. We had a lovely time
when he was in town last.
You know, Daddy
stays at my place.
How delightful.
Would you like to
come and stay with me?
Whatever for?
Because I have a spare room.
Uh, because I haven't
seen you in three years.
That's not my fault.
I'm just saying, I'd like
you to come and stay.
All right. I agree.
I'm honored.
You do look well.
You must have a man.
Do I need a man to look well?
It helps.
So... have you?
Yes.
I suppose he's a doctor.
Actually, yes.
His name's Mark.
And he's lovely.
Come on, chicken.
We never finished that game.
You were down by eight points.
Yeah, well, I was pacing myself.
Good night. Quitter.
All right. Bring it on.
Good night, Mark.
Nice hat.
Hey. Hi.
Uh, you're the new
med student, right?
Yeah. I'm Abby Lockhart.
Lucy. Nice to meet you.
How was your first day?
Um... Well, let's
put it this way.
I haven't had one
of these in two years.
What happened?
It's more like,
what didn't happen?
Ah, I used to work in OB,
and up there, I
would deliver a baby.
And then I would deliver a
baby. Then I would deliver a baby.
And today, I was
puked on, spit at, bit...
And then I tricked
a psychotic woman.
And then I almost killed a guy.
That sounds about right.
Fortunately, in the ER,
"almost" doesn't count.
What are you doing?
Patient's last request.
Toss some. You
might feel better.
Do you have to say a
prayer or something?
I don't think so.