I'm okay. Let's just go home.
You're getting checked out.
I tripped on the ice. Eight other
kids tripped. This is embarrassing.
You said you were just
gonna hang with your friends.
I turn around, and
you're out there on the ice.
I'm fine.
You don't know that.
You fell awkwardly.
No, I didn't.
You don't know how to fall.
I'm 16. I've been falling a lot.
I think I'm getting the
hang of it. And I checked.
And now the doctors
are gonna check.
You don't think that
you're overreacting?
I don't need you
to fix every booboo.
Then stop getting them.
I was just playing around with
my friends. I was having fun.
You know you can't do that.
Oh, I can't have fun.
You know what I mean. I'm going
to have a talk with your friends.
No! They need to stop.
No, I don't want you
freaking them out.
Fine. Fine, we'll go to the hospital, but
they're going to tell you that I'm fine,
and they're going to tell you that
you don't need to worry about...
Mom!
Mom?
Hello?
Mom, you gotta wake
up. No one's coming. Mom!
911, what's your emergency?
We got into an accident along the
Canal Road just outside Kingston.
My mom's unconscious.
Are you hurt?
I'm fine.
Mom? Mom?
Where's Foreman?
He's down here somewhere.
"Somewhere." Very helpful.
Do you have any idea
when he's getting out tonight?
Sometime.
I realize you can't predict.
I just thought you might be able
to estimate. It's Valentines Day.
I've planned a surprise getaway.
Get away.
Is my mom okay?
She's gone to surgery.
Foreman, your girlfriend wants to
know if you're available for Valentine's.
Act surprised. What are
you doing down here?
There's a snowstorm. ER's short-staffed.
We're all supposed to be here.
You're supposed to be here.
You're an ass. Act surprised.
This could sting a little.
Can we hurry this
up? Make sure that...
Take your time.
What's your name?
Hannah Morganthal.
You have CIPA,
No, I don't.
We have to do x-rays to make
sure you don't have internal injuries,
blood tests to make
sure no infections.
EEG for neurological anomalies
and biopsy a spinal nerve.
Congenital insensitivity to pain is one
of the rarest conditions on the planet.
There's only been about
60 documented cases.
Yeah, and I have seven reasons
to think that she's one of them.
She says she's not.
And that's reason number one.
She knew what it was
without us telling her.
Two, she's still wet from the snow.
She's not shivering. That's odd,
unless she can't sweat
or feel hot and cold.
The ambulance was warm.
I want to see my mother.
Three, scarring around
the lips and tongue.
When she was a baby, she
chewed on herself without feeling it.
I fell through a window
when I was a kid.
Four, when you
cleaned the wound,
she flexed into the cleaner
instead of away from it.
It's hard to fake pain
when you've never felt it.
It takes an imaginative leap, Ms.
Morganthal. That's one of them Jew names.
Ashkenazis are a
higher-risk group.
On the other hand, she
says she doesn't have it,
and she'd be dead by now if
she'd never been diagnosed.
They killed our Lord.
You're gonna trust them?
She wants to see her mom.
She admits having CIPA,
she knows we're not letting her go
anywhere without a battery of tests.
You said you had seven reasons.
I pulled a number
out of the air.
What, five isn't enough?
Five lame reasons aren't.
I'm taking her to see
her mom as soon as...
I can hit her again
if six isn't enough.
Do the tests.
Need to bail on
the ER. I got a case.
Why are you wearing perfume?
Is this a real case
or one of those imaginary cases
that happen when you're bored?
CIPA.
CIPA is a diagnosis.
Diagnoses happen
at the end of cases.
She's got no idea what's
going on in her body.
There's bound to
be something wrong.
In other words, she
could be perfectly healthy,
but you're curious about
someone who can't feel pain
because you always feel pain,
so you want to go exploring.
She was in a car accident.
She needs x-rays, blood
tests, EEG, nerve biopsy.
I also note that, although snow is
coming down in sheets this morning,
you left your hat at home,
and you used earmuffs.
Do your tests, except for the...
So while everyone else was
just worrying about getting in,
you were concerned
with hat head.
Blind dates are
never a good idea.
Only reason to wear a scarf like that is
as a beacon to identify you in a crowd.
Do your tests, except
for the nerve biopsy.
I need the nerve biopsy.
You'd risk paralyzing her.
It's neurological.
You have no evidence of that.
She tripped.
Do you have any
evidence, other than the fact
that a typically clumsy CIPA
patient tripped on an icy day?
If the EEG reveals a
problem, we can talk then.
Could have left the scarf
at home and just told him
you'd be wearing a
look of desperation.
Spiking on leads C-3 and O-2.
She could be
going into a seizure.
Hello? I think there's
a simpler explanation.
You're not gonna find anything.
I'm fine! I want to see my mom!
So sedate her.
She won't consent.
She's a teenager.
No dad. Mom's still in surgery.
What do you want us
to do? Hold her down?
Well, only until you inject her with
a sedative. Then you can let her go.
We tried.
Seriously?
She's strong and doesn't care.
We'd have broken something
before we can get her to
sit still enough to inject her.
So break her arm.
She won't mind.
You're cranky. I'm in pain.
Come on, let's go break her arm.
Nurse Shortie, your biznitch, how
long are you going to waste her time?
I'm so glad we're
walking somewhere.
Another 60 feet, and
this conversation is over.
When you guys are out of this
program, Cameron will find somebody,
Chase will find eight
somebodies, and you'll be alone.
Thirty feet. You'll
date, and you'll date,
but you're the ultimate Darwinian.
You have to fight for everything.
Anybody else would
just slow you down. Yeah.
I'm still with her, aren't I?
Yeah.
I can only imagine it's because she
hasn't given you an excuse to break up,
and you don't have the guts
to recognize your own reality.
I want to see my mother.
Hi again.
I'm sure I could say this
without being condescending,
but then you'd get the false
impression that I respect you,
so you're a kid, you're
scared, you're stalling, grow up.
I'm not scared.
I'm never scared.
See? How juvenile was that?
You can't feel pain.
Nothing left but pleasure.
Why don't you tell me
how wonderful that is?
It sucks.
Better than being
in pain all the time.
Get in the chair.
Every morning, I
have to check my eyes
to make sure I didn't
scratch a cornea in my sleep.
Oh, God, stop. I'm
in a pool of tears here.
I can't cry.
Neither can I.
Every morning, I check
my eyes for jaundice
in case the Vicodin's
finally shot my liver.
I can't run anywhere
without examining all my toes
for swelling. I can't run.
Boys can't hold me for too
long because I can overheat.
Girls can't hold me for too long
because I only pay for an hour.
I need an alarm on my watch to
remind me to go to the bathroom.
Know how many humiliating
experiences before I thought of that?
Bathroom is 50 feet from
my office. Every drink of water,
I weigh the pros and cons.
After everything
I do, I self-check.
Mouth, tongue, gums for cuts,
count teeth, check temperature,
fingers, toes and joints
for swelling, skin for bruises.
I got shot.
I sat on a stove when I was
three. Want to see the coil marks?
Yeah. You think I'm lying?
You think I would just want
to check out your tuchus,
as your people would say?
Put her in the chair and run the damn
test. If she moves again, give her nitrous.
You weren't shot because of leg pain.
You were shot because you're a jerk.
Some think the
two are connected.
He didn't have to do that.
Yeah, he did.
I'm sick?
No, your EEG was normal.
X-ray showed no break.
Blood tests showed no
infections. Urine indicated no...
Hannah?
Call a code! Oh, God.
Need ice packs
and cooling blankets.
Got saline in there?
She's not flushed.
She's not sweating.
You must be...
She has a temperature of 105.
Wow, she's actually sick.
We got her temperature down
below boiling. It could be infection.
No, LP showed normal
proteins and no white blood cells.
High bilirubin. Could
be a liver problem.
Nope, transaminases were
normal. Could be drugs.
She's smoked pot
since she was 11.
No again. Tox screen was clean.
We're doing this case backwards.
We do the tests, and
then she gets sick?
Maybe we did something to her.
Maybe she got sick after the tests.
We should rerun them.
And biopsy a spinal nerve.
You want to risk paralysis
because she's got a fever?
I want to risk paralysis because I
don't know what's causing the fever.
If it's neurological...
It's a fever.
In a CIPA patient. Obviously things are
a little different in her upstairs wiring.
And have been since
the day she was born.
Yeah, it's much more likely
that whatever it is was
cleverly waiting and hiding
until you guys
were done testing.
Where are you going?
You're all against this, right?
And you're all gonna stand on
principle and refuse to do it, right?
I'm going to get
Cuddy's approval.
How long are we going to keep
Hannah in the dark about her mother?
Long as possible.
Side airbags should be standard.
I'm sure she'll agree.
She should know
her mother's situation.
Breaking that news is
that surgeon's problem.
Any word from House?
No.
Well, maybe Cuddy will say no.
Cuddy never says no.
That's not true.
Nobody ever says
no. We don't say no.
You don't say no.
He'll come back.
He'll browbeat us.
He'll give us seven reasons, and eventually
we'll fold. We all will, not just me.
The only way we can avoid
biopsying this kid's spine
is to find the answer
some other way.
All the tests were negative.
We need a better history.
How much more
paperwork do you need?
We've got pediatric records,
a few dozen ER records,
our own admission questionnaire.
What's the first question?
Insurance coverage.
Okay, second question.
Just make your point.
"Where does it hurt?"
If we knew where it hurt,
we could diagnose her.
You do know CIPA
means she can't feel pain.
No, CIPA means
she's insensitive to pain.
She still has scattered nerve
fibers that could conduct pain,
but the signals don't
make it to the brain.
What if we give her more pain
signals, a lot more pain signals?
Maybe some of them
will make it through.
You want to torture her?
No.
Yes, we do this to
anybody else, it's torture.
Doing it to her is no
different than pricking a finger.
We keep poking
sharp sticks into her,
eventually we'll find the
part that's already tender.
So what does a
Dean of Medicine do?
Oh, can we please
not talk about that?
I will talk about anything else. I'm
just trying to get away from work.
Metaphorically, because
geographically, the coffee place
around the corner from the hospital
probably isn't the furthest you could get.
Well, the snow!
The roads are clearing,
but it's a good place
to beat a retreat from.
You usually expect
your dates to go wrong?
Experience has taught
me to have an escape route.
Well, low expectations,
that's in my favor.
Whatever happens, I
need you to understand
that there are certain aspects
to my life I'm not happy about.
Need a nerve biopsy.
And you had to come here
personally to tell me that?
And how did you
even know I was here?
I had to bring the file,
and this was the most noncommittal
location in walking distance.
You left your car keys in
your desk. Greg House.
You two must have met online.
Either that, or you've got a
friend who secretly hates you.
Don Herrick.
Yeah, we connected through
SingleBallroomDanceLovers.com.
Why would he volunteer
that information?
Why would I hide it?
You didn't tell him that anything
he said would be held against you?
So what line of work are you in?
Auto maintenance,
changing oil and filters.
Great, 'cause my place overcharges.
Can't trust anything you guys say.
Where are you located?
In 14 states. I
own Eastern Lube.
Most CIPA complications are
infection, and she's got a fever.
LP? Urine?
Clean. Normal.
Same with the
white-blood-cell count.
Cancer? Nothing on the scan.
I think it's her nerves messing
with the temperature control.
Amyloid, sarcoid,
there's a lot of candidates.
I want a biopsy.
Fine, if that's what
you need, go get it.
He seems a lot nicer than that one
from WiccaNeedsADaddyFigure.com.
One of these is warm,
and the other is very hot.
Start here. Move to the hot one.
Just a few seconds, then back.
We're gonna monitor activity
in your brain while you do it.
If you feel any response to the heat,
it could indicate a vascular problem.
How's my mom doing?
She's okay. Do
you feel anything?
No.
What does "okay" mean?
She's still in surgery.
They tell me it's going okay.
Can you take your hand out?
And you didn't
ask anything else?
Take your hand out of the water.
What's going on with my mother?
Hannah!
You just got
second-degree burns.
I'll be fine. What's going on with
my mother? Is she gonna die?
They said she's
okay. Surgery this long
is typical when there
are internal injuries.
Naloxone and kinase proteins in.
And that's gonna
make me feel pain?
I didn't feel anything when you
guys screwed this thing into my head.
It'll replace missing chemicals in
your nerves, heighten sensitivity.
We're gonna be drilling
directly into your skull.
A response should
indicate sarcoma.
What does it feel like?
It hurts.
I'm sorry.
Bone pain is the worst
there is, so you need
to let me know as soon
as you feel anything.
She's ready.
So, what, I just sit here while
you guys drill a hole in me?
You wanna talk?
Just you and your mom, huh?
You two must be pretty close.
We were, until I got
arrested. Third time.
Drugs? Fights.
You got an advantage.
Not really. Never
know when to stop.
You piss a lot of people off, or are
you just trying to piss off your mom?
Those are pretty much the
only two choices you have.
Hannah? You want us to
stop? Stop the drill! Stop the drill!
It's okay. What did you feel?
Where did you feel it? Hannah,
I need to know how it hurt.
Hannah!
I am so tired of
this. Did you know
that the new nurse from Cardiology
is sleeping with that weird lawyer
from the board?
The guy with 11 fingers?
He has 11 fingers?
How do you not notice that?
The nurse used to be a man.
She's not anymore? But
we can't talk about that.
I thought we were. We were
supposed to talk about that.
I came here to talk about that, but
on the way up, I ran into Cameron.
You've got a CIPA patient?
Tranny nurse is
more interesting.
Oh, it's way more interesting, but instead
I've got to be your damn conscience.
I'm tired of being your conscience.
I don't enjoy being your conscience.
No one enjoys...
You're studying her.
She's actually sick.
Which you found out
after you took her on.
I was curious. Since I'm not
a cat, that's not dangerous.
I don't think that metaphor was
designed to actually warn cats.
You don't care about her
illness. You care about CIPA,
which means your focus is gonna
be on getting your answers, not hers.
Thank you. Forewarned
is forearmed.
What do you think
you're gonna figure out?
Do you think her lack of pain is
somehow the answer to your pain?
I think if you'd stop
talking to Cameron,
then right now we could be
ranking nurses in order of do-ability.
I need you. What did
the nerve biopsy show?
Never did it. Well, then do it.
Can't. Why?
She's gonna jump
off the lobby balcony.
You think I can catch her?
Get away from me!
I'm not gonna hurt you.
Yes, you are. You're just
jealous I can do anything.
Hannah, you're having
a paranoid delusion.
I don't believe you.
Did you think she would?
This is real. You want me to
be in pain. You even said so.
If we wanted to hurt
you, we'd let you jump.
Just let me see my mother.
Fine, we'll take you to
our OR observation room.
I don't believe you!
Your mother is fine.
I just spoke to her
surgeon. I don't believe you!
Hannah, what do you want from
us? What do you want us to do?
I can't feel my legs.
You're trying to pull the
same stunt twice in 10 minutes.
I'm not pretending. They don't
hurt. They're just... They're...
Anything? We're
not looking for pain.
Anything at all? Pressure?
Nothing.
You have six broken bones, a fever,
a concussion, erratic heart rhythms
and a complete lack of
sensation below the waist.
I feel fine.
Is my mother out of surgery yet?
Not yet.
This is excellent.
The paranoia seems
to have dissipated,
but her vitals keep getting
worse. She could be dead in hours.
But if you're gonna die
a miserable, lingering
death, pain-free
is the way to do it.
Are we sure the fall
didn't cause the paralysis?
The paralysis caused the fall.
Spine's clean. No vertebral fractures
or spinal cord compression.
Even better.
The nuttiness and paralysis mean there's
definitely a neurological component.
Could be a nerve disease.
Which is why we need to look at
the nerve that you didn't biopsy.
There are other tests.
HIV? Syphilis?
She was negative for all STDs.
Vascular? No, ANA was negative.
Cerebral clot? No, MRI was...
Thyroid storm.
Makes sense given her glucose
reaction was slow, and potassium's down.
Yeah, I'll check with
an endocrinologist.
Bennett's on call.
Perfect.
No. Need a consult.
I already okayed
your nerve biopsy.
Need an endocrinologist.
Bennett's on call.
Won't pick up.
His cell phone must be broken.
Mine's working.
Had to give you the file.
I assume you're thinking thyroid
storm. Have you done a hormone panel?
Normal. TSH was on the low side.
Is that a cheery fire I
hear crackling nearby?
No, what about CPK enzymes?
Elevated, 275.
People light fires for themselves,
but then they don't deny it.
He's here?
CPK isn't high enough.
Potassium's what you'd expect
because of the bronchodilators.
Oh, my God! You're
not wearing a bra.
It's not thyroid storm.
You just met him.
I like him,
and I like sex. Do I need
to stitch a letter on my tops?
No. Might be worth taking
out an ad in the local papers.
Do you like me, House?
I was on the phone with Bennett 15
minutes ago. His cell phone's working.
Your MO is to
avoid me at all costs,
and suddenly you need my input on
every move you make. I can only assume
it's because I'm on a date.
When we met, I noticed...
You noticed he was a Shriner
because of the way he parted his hair.
You noticed he was a mama's boy
because of the way he blinked his left eye.
I'm not interested.
I'm not impressed.
There are only two reasons anyone
would want to screw with me tonight.
Either they're an
altruistic decent person
who's worried about my well-being,
or they want me for themselves.
You left out the third option.
Evil bastard who just wants to
mess with other people's happiness.
Good night, House.
We won't be bothered again.
It's late. I should go.
Why?
I part my hair on the
left, and I'm a Shriner?
You heard the conversation?
I'm not interested in him.
I don't blame you.
I only said those things so
that he wouldn't come back.
I don't really care
about my job. I do it well.
I provide a service, but my goal
was always to make enough money
to do the things I really
like. Music, travel...
I like those things, too.
You like them, but they're
not really important to you.
I don't know whether it's House,
your job, or you just thrive on conflict,
but you should hear yourself
when you're talking to him.
Nothing else in the world's going on.
You're focused, confident, compelling.
Don't take this the wrong way,
but I'd like to go out with that woman.
I can get her on the phone.
Where did you go?
She's getting worse.
It's not thyroid storm.
Give me a spinal nerve.
There are still other tests.
She just said the
girl is getting worse.
You really want to wait?
We'll be risking infection,
maybe make the paralysis worse.
It is worse, and we're making it
worse than worse? Do the biopsy.
We could paralyze her and
get no useful information.
Do the biopsy.
If you're thinking
peripheral neuropathy,
we should take a nerve a
little further away from the spine.
A little further from the
truth. We're talking paralysis.
There's a good chance
the spine is relevant.
If this thing is progressing,
it could kill her in hours.
Give me back my papers.
Is he asking for a spinal nerve?
How did you know?
Give us a minute.
Did you know they recently found a
protein that speeds up nerve growth?
Fascinating stuff. If
you put that protein
with the insulation
from a spinal nerve,
you could grow your own little
garden. If that spinal nerve...
Yeah, yeah, yeah, if it happened
to come from a person with CIPA,
I can grow pain-free nerves and graft
them into my own leg. What an evil plan!
You'd have to be on
immunosuppressors for life.
Risk of infection,
shorter lifespan...
Shorter but normal.
Usually jealousy expresses itself by
trying to destroy what someone has.
You're more ambitious. You
actually want to change medical fact
to get this thing...
Medical fact
changes all the time.
You're risking
your patient's life.
That's how medical fact changes.
A doctor risks...
To serve their patient's health,
not their own.
This is medically justified.
Are you sure? Are you sure that you're
the right one to be making this call?
Biopsy whatever nerve you
figure you could safely get at.
God, Wilson's annoying.
Past 3:00 a.m. on
Valentine's Day night.
I assume you had
a date with Wendy.
She'll survive. She
knows the deal.
You're lucky. I know.
Someday, when there's time, I
would like to actually have a social life.
Someday? Come on.
If there's one thing a good-looking
woman can have whenever she wants,
it's a social life.
You mean a sex life.
There's nothing wrong
with a little companionship
until the real
thing comes along.
I had the real thing.
Forgive me if I
don't want to settle.
Right. What does that mean?
Nothing.
You think I didn't
have the real thing?
I have no idea what you had.
And yet you're judging it.
It's late. I'm cranky. Sorry.
I didn't have the real thing.
How could you even know?
You married a dying man.
You thought, "Six months,
a year, it'll be tough,
"but then I'll recover, and
I'll have the rest of my life."
It's like willingly getting the flu or
joining the Peace Corps, short-term.
Wow, you nailed it. It's
basically like a wasted weekend.
The sacrifices you made were huge, but they
were at the height of your love for him.
Commitment is only commitment
because it has no expiration date.
You stand next to someone and watch them
floss for 30 years like my parents have,
then ask for sacrifices. That's
how you know the real thing.
Cameron, I wasn't
criticizing you.
People who avoid commitment are
people who know what a big thing it is.
This isn't right.
CIPA can't cause this
much degeneration.
A few nerve fibers we teased out of
the center have some insulation left,
but the insulation around the
bundles has been stripped bare.
Means the damage must
be coming from the outside in.
Which means it's secondary demyelination,
which means the source is somewhere else,
which tells us it's
not a nerve disease.
It's something systemic
that's affecting the nerves,
which means that we need to...
Where are you going?
Kid's mom is
finally out of surgery.
I'll be right back.
So what?
Hannah should see her.
Yes, immediately after we're
done chatting about saving her life.
Most likely causes
are metabolic.
They found brain swelling. They're
prepping her mother for another surgery.
Again, so what? Get
a nurse to take the kid.
There are more than 60
different metabolic conditions
that could account for what she's
got. There's only three of you guys.
She's scared. She should be.
She'll die if we
don't diagnose her.
So diagnose her.
Mom?
How bad is it? Are you okay?
I'm okay, Mom.
I'll get better. I
always get better.
Are you checking
yourself, your temperature?
Mom, could you just let it
go? You shouldn't be worrying.
Baby, I'm sorry.
I should have seen
that car coming.
No, Mom, I did this to
myself. I screwed up.
You were right. You were
right, and I was wrong.
No. No.
I shouldn't have gone out on the
ice. I shouldn't have fallen down,
and I shouldn't have made you rush
me to an ER for the 10th time this year.
Mom?
Mom? You okay?
They have to take
her back to surgery.
Hannah, your BP is way up.
We need to get you some rest.
My hand's wet.
You're crying.
I can't cry.
My head's killing me.
So what does the pain tell us?
No tingling or itching,
so we can rule out...
It tells us nothing. It wasn't
physical pain. It was emotional.
Exactly. What were they doing
when she got the headache?
Saying goodbye.
You said they were arguing.
They weren't really arguing.
She was just frustrated.
What were they arguing about?
Whose fault it was.
Peripheral neuropathy, fever
and intermittent paranoia.
Lots of metabolic conditions can
explain those things. What if we add guilt?
Guilt? As a symptom?
Alzheimer's can cause
euphoria, pain causes depression,
and B12 deficiency causes
guilt, along with all that other stuff.
If she felt guilty, she wouldn't be
making her mother's life miserable.
She wouldn't be getting
in fights, getting arrested.
Maybe she's fighting
because she feels guilty.
She's showing her mom she can
take stupid risks and still be safe.
Means mom can let go.
Which is rational.
If guilt is a symptom,
it's caused by the illness,
not by a thought process,
and it would have to be new.
Couple years ago, she
was a model student.
This is pointless. If the
headache was caused by guilt,
she has a B12 deficiency.
If it's just because she
was sad, it's meaningless.
How the hell do
we test for that?
We don't.
Give her a shot of B12. When
she gets better, I was right.
We already did. ER gave her
B12 when she was admitted,
part of a multivitamin supplement.
Apparently, she's just sad.
Why are you still here?
Trying to get a couple pages into a
drug trial. Paperwork's due tomorrow.
Why are you here?
Still haven't figured out why.
No, I meant here, in my office.
Just dumped a cool B12
theory. Moved on to leukemia.
Very pedestrian.
I'm not happy.
Her white-blood-cell
count was low.
The ones she's got, it's
just a lot of eosinophils.
The immunoglobulin
E-level's borderline.
If you want to be 100%
sure, check the bone marrow.
The team's doing
a biopsy right now.
It turns out the
weird lawyer knew
that she used to be a man.
And he's cool with that?
Turns out that his previous
girlfriend also used to be a man.
Yeah.
Is it possible for you
to just watch me eat,
or do you get some primeval thrill out
of beating the other hunters to the food?
See you later.
You still haven't figured out
that I don't need sedation?
It's so you don't move
during the procedure.
Is that nitrous? What,
are you trying to kill her?
We gave her nitrous
during the EEG.
That's what made
this thing rear its ugly...
What thing?
B12 deficiency.
Are you having déjà vu?
We've had this conversation. She
was given B12. She didn't get better.
Because someone else
ate it. Get an abdominal MRI.
What? What are you
doing? Don't touch me!
Don't touch me! See?
There's she goes.
Don't touch me! Another
paranoid delusion.
At the rate she's going downhill,
forget the MRI. We need an OR.
Leave me alone!
Occupied!
Her hernia can wait.
Help! They're trying to kill me!
Okay, you can either believe
that we really are trying to kill her,
or you can assume she's
suffering from a medical condition.
Seeing as this is a hospital,
and we're all dressed like doctors,
and there are easier
ways to kill somebody...
Bev, help them. I'm
gonna need iodine,
scalpel numbers 10 and 15,
forceps and a largish salad bowl.
Okay, hold her down.
Come on, weenie,
she's in a cast.
Swab.
Fifteen.
You're not gonna
anesthetize her?
Relax. It's just a magic trick.
She's faking it. We're
not falling for it this time.
Okay, keep that retracted.
Forceps.
Lake fishing can be fun. It can
bring the generations together.
But if you don't cook
that trout or perch well,
you'll be giving room
and board to this fellow,
and by "free board," I mean
all the B12 you can take in.
I could have a tapeworm in me?
Not likely. You'd
be in a lot of pain.
It's gotta be 25 feet long.
Damn it. World record's over 60.
Hannah, wake up.
Somebody here to see you.
She's got limited
motion on her left side.
You might have to take
care of her for a while.
You don't feel it, but you're
about to rip your stitches out.
Take care of yourself. Then
you can take care of her.
You haven't gone home.
Sorry I screwed
up Valentine's day.
I'm dating a doctor. I'd be an
idiot to expect anything else.
I did get you a gift. MGH.
Best teaching
hospital in Boston.
You want to be a nurse
practitioner? That's as good as it gets.
I made a few calls, and
you're in if you want in.
This is why you've been helping me
get my surgical hours for accreditation.
I thought you wanted... Stupid.
You've got 10 feet of
personal space around you.
I step forward, you step back.
I've shared a lot
of things with you.
Which is why you're
breaking up with me.
You can't stand to be close.
Wendy, you think I'll stay with
you because you're angry with me?
I'm upset
because I care.
Only you'd expect an
argument to be rational,
you and that ass boss of yours.
Well, you could ask
her for the spinal nerve.
She's got no reason to give it.
She owes you.
The hospital will
send her a bill.
I'm just saying, if you want to do
it, do it while her B12 is still low.
Guilt can be your friend.
Breakfast?
Yeah.
Happy Valentine's Day.
Holiday that only applies to
people who are already paired up.
For everyone else,
it's Wednesday.
Wow, thank you for
that dash of cold water.
Don't get me wrong. I still
think true love's out there.
It's just very far away,
possibly in another galaxy.
We may need to develop
faster-than-light travel
before we can make contact.
So I'm thinking we
should have sex.
That makes sense.
Despite the wisdom of pop songs,
there's no point putting our lives
on hold until love comes along.
We're both healthy and busy people.
We work together so it's convenient.
Like microwave pizza.
And of all the
people I work with,
you're the one I'm least
likely to fall in love with.
Like microwave pizza.
The point here is to make things
simpler, not more complicated.
Someday, there'll be time to
get serious about someone.
Meanwhile, we already had sex
once and didn't get weird about it, so...
I get it. I get it. So what if I'm
offended by your judgment?
Then you're not the
man I'm looking for.