That day, when I found out
I couldn't have children...
You pushed me away
and ran into
another man's arms.
This is Auggie.
One of my students.
I haven't been
able to reach his foster mom.
It's too much,
and I can't...
No one wants a sick kid.
DCFS is gonna start
looking for a new foster
placement tomorrow.
And we'll spend
the night with Auggie.
You wanna come up?
I just wonder
if that's
a good idea.
There's actually
very little difference
between drug addiction...
And romance addiction?
Let's go up
and discuss it.
Did you really use
all of my floss?
I told you, if we're gonna
keep doing this,
I need a toothbrush.
I don't know.
I feel like it gives a guy
too great a sense of security.
Or does it just
prevent cavities?
No, that is
a gateway toiletry.
And before I know it,
you're gonna have your
own curling iron here,
you'll have your
own loofah...
You've clearly given this
a great deal of thought.
Maybe a little bit.
It's been a really
good couple of weeks.
Yeah, it has.
And not just us.
You've been knocking it
out of the park.
I mean, work.
Everything. Rehab.
I'm really
proud of you.
Just so you know,
the more you kiss me,
the more it makes
me think I should get
you that toothbrush.
Oh, yeah?
Mmm-hmm. Yeah.
What's nice is
as we progress
through the surgery
we can slide
the retractor down,
there you go,
go ahead and bring
that blade down.
Now, you wanna keep
the most tension on,
so go ahead
and tighten it up.
Hey, April?
Never mind.
Ethan!
Ethan, hey.
He was showing me
some new equipment.
I'm sure he was.
I'm his Hybrid OR nurse.
You know that.
Learning is part
of the job.
Right.
What is this?
You're sleeping
on the couch,
you want nothing
to do with me.
Why do you care?
Hey, Dr. Marcel,
I'm sorry.
No, it's all good.
I gotta deal with some
inventory anyway.
We'll finish up later.
Morning, Dr. Manning.
Morning, Crockett.
How's your day?
Great.
You realize you say
that every day.
Every day is great.
We got two
traumas coming in.
Dr. Choi!
You're going to Two.
Dr. Marcel?
Take her to Baghdad.
Copy.
What do we got?
Zach Brand, 15,
says he fell off
an overpass.
Is that true?
You fell?
Fractured his left arm,
he's got a pretty good
bruise on his head.
GCS 13, pressure
and heart rate
are good.
All right, Zach.
Any of this hurt?
Uh-uh.
All right.
He looks stable,
but let's get a chest
X-ray and a pan scan
just to be safe.
Let's get ready to transfer.
Wait a second.
Zach, where did this
glass come from?
Zach?
We'll figure this out.
All right, let's transfer
on my count. Ready?
One, two, three.
I've got Terrie Cross,
intubated in the field.
Status post-MVC,
car versus divider,
GCS 3T, BP 95 over 60,
heart rate 130,
satting at 86%.
Yeah, I'm not
liking this rhythm.
Gimme an EKG with
trops and trauma labs.
Let's go.
She's coding.
No pulse.
Get him up for those scans.
I'll check in as soon
as you're back.
Here we go.
Come on, folks.
We know what this is.
What's up?
She's in v-fib.
Let's go.
On my count.
One, two, three.
Gimme the paddles.
Charge to 200.
She could be in
blunt cardiac arrest.
Charged.
Open it up.
Clear.
I got a pulse.
Sinus tach.
For now.
What happened?
Single vehicle crash.
Any drugs or alcohol
on board?
Rapid tox
was negative.
Why'd she hit the median?
Stroke? Seizure?
Wait, wait, wait.
She's got glass
shards on her.
So does the kid in Trauma Two.
It's from her windshield.
How do you know?
He fell off an overpass.
And landed on her.
No breath sounds
on the left.
Let's set her up
for a chest tube.
What do you got?
Some fluid on the right,
but I can't find her spleen.
What do you mean
you can't find it?
I mean it's not there.
It's gotta
be in there
somewhere.
Go back up.
Right there.
That's the tip.
Can't be.
It's too high.
That's right, 'cause
it's in her chest.
All right.
She must've ruptured
her diaphragm.
Chest tube's ready.
Nope, she's hypotensive.
We're going to
the Hybrid OR, now.
No, no, no, no. Stop.
If it's a tension pneumo,
we can't move her
till we decompress the lung.
There's no time.
I'll do it in the OR.
Let's go. Come on.
Easy, easy.
We just
wanted to come
say a quick hello
before we finished up
the paperwork.
Of course.
Maggie,
Madeline's found
foster parents
for Auggie.
That's great.
He can't wait to get
out of the hospital.
So?
What a sweet kid.
He is.
Except when he doesn't get
his Nutella for breakfast.
Oh, and he doesn't
like anything but
bubblegum toothpaste.
No fruit flavors and
definitely not mint.
As you can see,
Maggie has become
quite attached in the
past couple of weeks.
We know how it is.
We've been fostering
for 12 years.
Auggie is going
to a loving family.
So let's cross the T's,
dot the I's,
hopefully you'll be
able to take him
home tonight.
Who's winning?
We both have 16
life points left,
but as soon as
my Jace uses his
Ultimate, he's toast.
I have no idea
what's going on.
So, what did you
think of those people?
They're nice.
Yeah?
I'm sorry, you two,
but I gotta get to school.
Finish this later?
Wanna drag it out?
Mmm.
I'm good.
Okay, honey.
You keep an eye
on this guy.
Oh, I will.
You mind
if I take a look?
Okay.
Yeah?
Ooh.
Your tummy hurt?
Mmm-hmm.
You getting cold?
You know what
I'm gonna do?
I'm gonna ask my
friend Dr. Manning
to come and take
a look at you.
Just to make sure
everything's all right.
Okay.
Meanwhile, why don't
you get some rest?
And when
Mr. Campbell comes?
Don't go easy on him.
Hey, Zach.
So we got
your scans back.
Good news, it's just
a simple fracture.
Okay.
And your parents
are on their way.
Mind if I check
your eyes?
So, how did you
go over the edge
of that overpass?
The railing
was kinda low,
I guess.
Okay.
But, uh, I mean,
were you fooling
around with your friends?
You lose your balance?
Could...
Could we do this later?
My head really hurts.
Sure.
But I do wanna
make sure that
you're okay
and that something like this
doesn't happen again.
So I'll have another
doctor come in and
see you in a bit, okay?
Maybe you'll feel up
to talking then.
I have to ask.
Do I think he jumped?
Yeah, I do.
We're out looking
for witnesses now,
but if he did jump,
we'll have to arrest him
for vehicular endangerment,
and possibly
manslaughter.
Easy, Rosado.
If Zach attempted suicide,
first thing that happens,
we put him
on a psych hold.
Hey, Trini. Call Dr. Charles.
Tell him we need a consult.
What do we got?
Marcie Burton,
19 weeks pregnant
with mild
vaginal bleeding,
vitals stable.
Okay, thanks.
I called the ambulance
just to be safe.
Good. Hi, Marcie.
I'm Dr. Halstead,
this is student
Dr. Curry.
I'm not losing
the baby, am I?
We're gonna take
a look right now.
When did
the bleeding start?
This morning.
It wasn't much,
but it hasn't stopped.
This will be
a little cold.
Is it moving?
Is it okay?
Well, the fetus is fine,
but you do have
placenta previa.
Is that bad?
Uh, it depends. It could be,
if the bleeding gets worse.
Then you need
to stop it.
Well, we are certainly
gonna do everything
we can.
I have brain cancer.
I'm sorry?
Stage four.
Which means this
is my last chance
to have a family.
How long ago were
you diagnosed?
Eight months.
Though her tumor's
been stable lately,
and the scans
have been good.
Ron.
I don't have time
to start another pregnancy.
And my baby
will be viable in just
a few more weeks.
So, please...
Help me.
Okay.
Let me go over
your chart
and have Obstetrics
come down to take a look.
Then we'll figure out
where to go from there.
Thank you.
Call Dr. Asher.
Dr. Asher? What?
Are you sure?
Yeah. She's the best.
He has a GI bleed
and his liver
is getting worse.
What are you
gonna do?
Send him for
a TIPS procedure.
You think
he needs something
that invasive?
Any more damage
moving forward
will be irreversible.
Sooner we can take
the pressure off his
vasculature, the better.
He was really hoping
to go home with his
new family today.
Well, TIPS has
a pretty quick recovery.
Maybe tomorrow.
Yeah.
I'm gonna
call over to IR.
Okay. Thanks.
Rhythm's not great.
We gotta move.
I'm on it.
I need better
exposure.
Okay, you remember how
I showed you to insert
the larger blade?
Yes, I do.
No, slide it
all the way.
Okay.
Loosen it up,
loosen it up.
Okay. Got it.
Okay, good.
Let's do this.
Nope, I need
a better angle.
Okay.
How do I know...
Okay, hold on.
Switch with me.
She's not gonna
hold out if you can't
get this going soon.
Yeah, I gotcha,
Marty.
Okay, there we go.
Don't let go.
Sorry,
Dr. Marcel.
Don't sweat it.
Just get a 2-0 ready
for the diaphragm.
One, two, three.
Dr. Marcel?
Yeah.
I think you should start
training a new nurse
for the Hybrid Room.
What are you talking about?
I slowed you down today.
No. Hey, it was
a tough case
with new equipment.
No, it was because
of the whole
thing with Ethan.
It got in the way
and there's no
excuse for that.
Look, April,
you're my nurse
and you're the best.
I'm not gonna
train anyone else.
Okay?
Okay.
Dr. Choi,
Zach's parents
are here.
He fell off
the overpass?
How is he?
Is he all right?
Zach has a broken
arm that he's getting
cast right now,
but otherwise,
just some scrapes
and bruises.
Oh, thank God.
Mr. and Mrs. Brand,
I'm Dr. Charles.
I haven't actually
met Zach yet,
but I was looking
forward to saying hello
in a few minutes.
Psychiatry?
I don't understand.
I just wanna ask him
a few questions.
Get a better sense
of what happened.
What does that mean?
Well, just that.
Wait. Don't tell me
you think he jumped.
Based on Dr. Choi's
assessment,
it seems like there
might be a possibility
and so, I just,
I wouldn't be doing
my job if I didn't say
a quick hello.
Oh, my God.
Honey, no, no.
That's ridiculous.
It's those kids
he hangs out with.
They're wild.
They were probably
goofing around
and it went too far.
Very possible.
But it's not so easy
to accidentally fall off
one of those things.
You know what?
I bet he got pushed
by that homeless guy.
Yeah.
Homeless guy?
Yeah. There's this man who
stands on that overpass,
screaming all day.
He's psychotic,
and dangerous.
Huh.
Okay. Well, I'm sure
the police will
look into that,
but in the
meantime,
we just wanna make
sure we're not
missing anything.
Zach could've
died today. Okay?
The last thing he needs
is to be interrogated
by a shrink.
Now, which one's
his room?
Treatment Five.
Are we gonna have
a hard time
with them?
The dad, yeah.
The mom,
not so sure.
Hey, Mom.
Hey.
Okay.
Michael, tell me.
Meet the newest
Clinical Device Specialist
for Kender Bio Systems.
You got the job.
Yeah, joining the Kender
team right here.
Here at Med?
Mmm-hmm.
And given the size
of the contract,
they need more people.
That's wonderful.
Mom, I know you always
wanted me to be a doctor.
Michael, I just
wanted you...
...to be happy.
I know,
but believe me,
Kender's training
is like going
to med school.
I'll know more
about the devices
than the docs
and I'll be in the OR
right alongside them.
I'm so proud of you.
I gotta hook up
with my supervisor.
Take you to lunch?
It's a date.
All right.
Zach, how you doing?
I'm Dr. Charles.
He's a psychiatrist.
Legally, we have to let
him talk to you.
Harris.
I'm really just
here to help,
Zach, and was hoping
to ask you a few
quick questions about
what happened today.
Okay.
Okay. So...
So, this morning
you left your house,
and where were
you headed?
Nowhere. I was just
taking a walk.
Okay.
By yourself.
Yeah.
Okay. Got it.
So you get to this overpass
and what happened then?
Tell him about that
homeless man, Zach.
Like you told us.
Yeah. There was...
There was this guy who was
yelling and acting crazy.
Right.
And, uh, he started
shoving me
and I tried to get out
of the way, but he...
He wouldn't stop,
and before I knew it,
I lost my balance.
All right.
Well, um, you know,
Zach's been through
a lot today.
Has anybody asked him
if he wants anything to eat?
No.
No?
Are you hungry, buddy?
How about a sandwich?
Maybe turkey.
Okay.
Um, why don't
we get going on that
and then when we get back,
maybe we can talk a little
bit more. Okay?
Nice to meet you, Zach.
Thank you.
You know his parents
coached him to say that.
Are they worried
he's gonna get arrested?
Probably.
Look. Even if Zach
won't admit he jumped,
we gotta put him
on a psych hold
for his own good.
A forced hold?
Taking a minor
away from his parents,
a very high bar
to clear, you know?
And more importantly,
it doesn't really
tend to work
unless you get buy-in
from the whole family.
But we can't let
a suicidal kid
walk out of here.
I hear you.
Look, let's see
what a turkey
sandwich gets us. Okay?
Moms love to see
their kids get fed.
Her cervix isn't
handling the weight
of the growing fetus
and is starting
to open up.
She's already dilated
one centimeter.
Then she's going
to lose the pregnancy.
Maybe not.
I'd like to try her
on progesterone,
see if we can stop her
from dilating any farther.
Wait, is that safe?
I mean, given her
increased chance of
infection and bleeding?
This is a unique situation,
due to her limited
time frame.
This pregnancy
is very
important to her.
I'd like to try
and save it.
Okay, then. Thanks.
Dr. Halstead,
I've read the literature
on cervical insufficiency
with bleeding in
high-risk patients
and trying to intervene
is not the standard of care.
Dr. Asher
is the specialist
and I trust her.
She's had
a drug problem.
That is irrelevant.
You are way out
of line, Ms. Curry.
He's cold,
and he's getting
a little short of breath.
What's taking IR
so long to get him
down for his TIPS?
They're always
backed up.
I'll give them a call.
Wait. He's not even
on the schedule.
What?
I put the order
in an hour ago.
Uh-uh. It says
he's been denied. By DCFS.
Can they do that?
I don't know.
Come on.
Madeline!
If this is
about Auggie,
I'm sorry,
but until the Kramers
get final approval,
the state is
still Auggie's
legal guardian.
What?
He's getting worse.
He needs this.
According
to the Illinois health
service protocols,
TIPS is only indicated
if two other previous
treatments fail.
That's just a guideline.
Every patient is different.
Which is why
I've already
escalated this
to a physician mediator
appointed by the state.
That's gonna take days.
He needs this now.
All right, look.
He's at risk
for encephalopathy,
peritonitis...
I understand.
Madeline,
he needs someone
to advocate for him.
And I'm trying my best.
There's nothing
else I can do.
Dr. Lanik.
Do you remember
Auggie Roberts?
Foster kid? Sure.
He's getting worse.
I was wondering,
could you write a note
saying that he'd
do well to receive
a TIPS procedure?
He's upstairs now.
Get his pediatrician
to do it.
She did. But there's
some red tape.
I thought if we had
a double doc
we could convene
an ethics committee
and we could...
Oh, so my "quick note" is
turning into an afternoon
in front of a committee?
Dr. Lanik...
Maggie, I have
patients to see
and you have
a waiting room full
of them to process.
Three centimeters.
You're still progressing.
So what do
we do now?
Well, we can
try increasing
the progesterone.
Give you a little more
time to see if we can
turn this around.
I agree.
Are you sure?
The longer we wait,
the greater the chance
of a serious complication.
I don't believe
we're there yet.
What do you think
we should do?
Terminate
the pregnancy.
At this point,
it's the safest option.
What? No.
Ms. Curry
is a medical student,
not a doctor.
I need to have
this baby.
So my husband can
have someone to love
him as much as I do.
And someone
he can love.
If I can have that,
then I'm okay to die.
We'll increase your
meds and check
back in a little bit.
You gonna get your nose
out of that laptop?
I'm sorry, Mom.
I've just got so
much prep to do.
Let me ask you,
Dr. Latham,
CT surgeon,
you know if he's
into anything,
any hobbies?
No, not really.
We don't socialize.
A lot of CT surgeons
are into cars.
You know,
vintage, racing...
Yeah, that doesn't
sound like Dr. Latham.
How about Dr. Abrams?
I hear his wife makes
some kind of power drink.
Is he a gym rat?
Why are you asking this?
Well, I'm gonna be working
with these guys.
It'd be nice
to have something
to talk about.
Well, what about
the medical devices
they'll be using?
Well, that's a given,
but you know how touchy
these surgeons can be.
Since I'm gonna be
coaching them,
I want to establish
a rapport.
Well, our surgeons
are at the top
of their game.
I doubt if they
need any coaching.
Sure. It's just
we have a lot of
exciting new products
I'll be introducing
them to.
And, you know,
business is all
about relationships.
I'm sorry, Dr. Charles,
but the Brands'
lawyer is here,
and apparently
you can't
speak to Zach
until Legal gets it
straightened out.
Mr. and Mrs. Brand,
I just wanna let you know,
the field officers have
completed their
investigation.
Did they find
that homeless man?
No. In fact,
we couldn't find any
eyewitnesses at all.
So, Zach can go?
Hold on.
There's still one
more witness.
The woman who
was driving the car.
Oh, for God's sake,
are you just trying
to get my son arrested?
No, I'm trying to get him
the help he needs.
Mr. and Mrs. Brand,
if it turns out that
Zach did, in fact, jump,
then I would be able,
hopefully with
your blessing,
to put him on a hold
and we can start
to address this.
He would likely
be charged,
but I will personally
advocate for him,
and under
the circumstances,
can practically guarantee
he would not be prosecuted.
My son
is not suicidal.
The driver's
still unconscious.
If she wakes up,
we'll question her then.
But in the meantime,
I can't keep him
here any longer.
I gotta let him go.
Thank you.
Rosado.
Don't let them
leave just yet.
I'll be right back.
Crockett, I need you
to wake her up.
What? Why?
The boy needs our help.
All right,
she's our
only chance.
If she confirms
he jumped,
we can give him
the help he needs.
Yeah, I'm sorry,
but she's not ready.
Why not, huh?
She's over-breathing
the vent,
her vitals are stable.
I just rebuilt her diaphragm
and her belly's open.
She's not there yet.
Come on, man.
You're telling me you
can't lighten her sedation
for five minutes?
If I wake her up now,
she could still go into
a metabolic crisis.
And if you don't,
there's a severely
troubled kid
who can't get
the help he needs.
Well, I don't know
what to tell you, man,
but I'm gonna do
what's best for my patient.
That boy tries
to kill himself again?
That's on you.
His pressure's
dropping.
We need more
suction, blood,
and drugs to intubate.
What happened?
He was coughing
and then he just started
throwing up blood.
Esophageal varices.
The pressure must've
opened one up.
Auggie, I need you
to calm down, okay?
We're gonna take
good care of you.
Auggie. Auggie,
listen to me.
No...
Auggie...
Drugs are in.
I know this is scary,
but you're so brave.
I need you to be brave
just a little bit longer.
Can you do that for me?
All right.
He's out.
I'm in. Bag him.
All right,
let's get him up
to the IR for a TIPS.
Let's go.
It's emergent now.
No need for consent.
Yeah, we can do both.
Dr. Asher! Dr. Halstead!
Okay.
She's losing
the pregnancy.
Marcie, I'm sorry,
but we need to get
the fetus out now.
No! No!
Marcie!
It's okay.
Dr. Halstead.
Please don't let
my baby die.
Hannah.
Okay.
We could try what's
called a cerclage.
It's a procedure
to tie your cervix closed,
but in your case,
we would have to go
in through the abdomen.
What? With the placement
of her placenta
and her bleeding,
that would be
extremely risky.
How risky?
Well, the chances
of catastrophic
bleeding are high.
Not to mention the
significant cardiac
risks of anesthesia.
It's true. There's no
guarantee at all that
you would survive this.
Honey... That sounds
like a bad idea.
Do it.
Marcie, we can
always try again.
No, we can't.
You know that.
Do it!
All right. Let's go.
Come on.
Marcie. No!
I love you.
That's why
I have to do this.
Elsa, call the OR.
Dr. Halstead,
this is crazy.
Odds are that woman
is gonna die.
That's a risk she's
willing to take.
Well, are you doing
this because of your
feelings for Dr. Asher?
Call the OR, now.
Please, it is a mistake
to send Zach home.
I believe your son
is depressed.
Depressed?
I hate that word.
It's just an excuse
for weakness.
Our son is not weak.
Dr. Charles.
I think that we have
said everything there
is to say, Dr. Choi.
Unless, of course,
there's something
that either of you
feel like you
might've left out.
Her vitals look good.
How's her rhythm been?
Stable. Dr. Marcel
was talking about
lightening her sedation.
Yeah, I'll take
care of it.
Don't try to talk.
You're intubated,
in the hospital.
You're safe.
I just need to know,
did you see the boy
who landed on your car?
Okay.
Did he get pushed?
Or did he jump?
Okay, please.
Just think.
You were driving
toward the bridge.
He was on it.
You saw him.
Did he jump?
Okay.
Mr. Brand,
we forgot to validate
your parking.
Come with me.
I'll be right back.
Mrs. Brand,
I think that your
son needs help.
Now, I recognize that
your family situation
is complicated.
And I can't imagine how
challenging that must be
under the circumstances.
But, listen,
here's my card.
I hope you will
call me any time
of the day or night.
All right?
The only thing that
you don't wanna do
is let your son go
through this alone.
Thank you.
Okay.
Hey. How's he doing?
He finally
got his procedure,
no thanks to you.
Maggie, you know
that under
the circumstances
I did everything
I could.
Did you? Because it took
him hemorrhaging
for him to get this.
I can
see the cervix.
Hold it gently
so I can get it isolated.
Mmm-hmm.
It's bleeding.
It's too vascular.
Laps to me.
Give her a gram of TXA.
Still bleeding.
More laps.
Pressure's dropping.
We may need
to terminate
the procedure.
Watch her rhythm.
She's throwing PVC's.
I think we need to call it.
Switch to a hysterotomy.
No.
Her water's still intact,
and we've got plenty
of blood in reserve.
We can still do this.
Are you sure?
Yes.
Okay. Talk me through it.
Release the laps
so I can get
some celox in there.
Lap?
It's working.
The bleeding's slowed.
Okay,
hold it steady
so I can get it packed.
We did it.
How's she look?
BP is coming back up,
but I still can't shake
these irregular beats.
Then we're not
out of the woods yet.
Let's get ready
to place the stitch.
Where is he?
You got a lot
of nerve interfering
with my patient.
I had to.
The boy needed help.
The boy.
Don't kid yourself.
This wasn't about him.
It was about me.
The hell it was.
You've been pushing
against me all day.
Because you deserved it.
Oh, come on!
You know
what this is about.
It's about April.
No, you don't
wanna go there.
No. I wanna end this.
So, what's it gonna take?
You need to hit me?
That it?
Huh, big man? Go on,
take your best shot.
There it is.
Okay. And, snip.
Okay.
Cerclage is complete.
Ready to close.
Her pressure's dropping
and she's got ectopy.
I don't
see anything.
It's here.
She's hemorrhaging.
The placenta.
We need to terminate
the pregnancy.
Trigger the MTP and convert
to a hysterotomy. Now.
What do you need?
Cut the cerclage.
She's in v-fib.
Damn it! Gimme
a scalpel, start CPR.
Starting
compressions.
Charged.
Placenta out.
Charge to 200.
Get some
blood in her!
Charged.
All right. Clear!
Still in v-fib.
No pulse.
Charge to 200.
Give her an amp of epi!
Charged.
Clear!
Come on.
Give another amp of epi
and charge to 200.
Hannah...
What are you waiting for?
Shock her!
She bled out.
Time of death, 18:04.
Hannah.
Oh, boy.
You, uh... You all right?
Did Zach leave?
Yeah.
You know, I was finally able
to talk to his mom alone.
Poor thing.
I don't know.
She did take my card.
I don't get it.
The boy is so deeply troubled,
but the dad just doesn't
want to face it.
Well, you know,
maybe it's just, uh,
easier for him to focus
his anxiety
and anger elsewhere,
rather than face the pain
of looking at the real
problem, you know?
Anyway...
See you tomorrow.
Now, the Amulet of Krog.
What do I do with it?
No, it's Kroog.
Kroog.
Okay. I'll be right back
and I'm gonna beat you.
Is he going to be okay?
For now, at least.
Good. But I'm afraid
I've got some bad news.
The, uh, foster family
backed out.
They felt he would
just be too much
to handle.
So, he'll have to go
back on the list?
I'm afraid so.
I'm sorry.
Sharon?
Yeah?
We'll do it.
We'll foster him.
Maggie, you don't
have to do...
No.
We want to.
Are you sure?
Okay. I'll let
DCFS know.
Mr. Burton.
I'm so sorry.
My wife made it
very clear what she wanted.
Thank you for honoring
her wishes.
I always knew this day
would come.
Still, it's so hard...
Hey, Hannah, today
was a tough one.
But you made
the right decision.
Yeah, but...
Doesn't make it
any easier.
I need...
I need to go
to an NA meeting.
Okay.
I'll drive you.
Hey, Mom.
I'll see you tomorrow.
See you tomorrow.
Dr. Lanik.
Hey, Michael.
Your son,
he's a good salesman.
Yeah?
Yeah, he somehow knew
I was a scotch drinker.
Gave me this great
bottle of single malt.
Your eye okay?
Yeah, I'll live.
So, you sure have
been making
a lot of new friends
since coming over
to the day shift.
Yeah. That's what I do.
Make friends.
Are you okay,
Crockett?
Oh, yeah, that lidocaine
works fast.
That's not what I meant.
I know what you meant.
Let's just keep it
at the lidocaine.
Really? You hit him?
Yeah.
The thing is, April,
it was so easy for me
to see Crockett
as the problem.
Yeah, and I told you
whatever happened between
me and him in the past...
Yeah. I know.
I get it now.
Because the real problem
was always right here.
Between us.
April, whatever it is
you want...
It isn't me.
Ethan, that's not true.
What are...
Where are you going?
What are the bags for?
I'm gonna find a hotel.
No, Ethan, stop! Listen!
Take as long as you need
to find a new place.
What? Ethan!
Oh, my God.