- Previously on The Resident...
- I also know a desperate man.
You've been a locum tenens
for the last 36 months, hopping
from hospital to hospital.
I'm Julian Booth, device rep
for QuoVadis. I was a dancer
until one day, I was hit by
a car. Total hip replacement
gave me my life back and
made me a true believer.
This is a business.
It's not a charity.
- How much does he make?
- A million five.
You're gonna have to
learn to work together.
- Nic, I'm trying.
- This was never our problem.
- Then what was?
- Not here, not now.
I got the cue ball curving
while chilling with Irving.
A few more drinks, and
he might start swerving.
Looking like that, I'm
surprised they let us in.
And my rhymes are so sick, but
I don't need your bad medicine.
- Oh!
- That was... was not great.
Well, I don't have to
be good to love hip-hop,
so put that in your
pocket and lock it.
Noted. So are we getting
back to the game or what?
- Who's shot is it?
- Mine.
I got to be honest. I'm
pretty tired of beating you.
Ouch. Words hurt, man.
♪ You're looking for Joanie ♪
♪ Was Joanie there? ♪
- ♪ But if you find Judy... ♪
- That's not cool.
No, what's not cool is you guys
hogging the table for two hours.
Yeah, people are waiting.
And if you've been shooting
like that, you're cheating.
The rule is, one foot on
the ground at all times.
- I'm pretty sure I did.
- I'm positive you didn't.
Why don't you show us
how it's done...
whoever you are?
Oh, what a gentleman,
giving me the cue
that's loose in the
middle, chipped on top.
Every bar has a crooked
cue, and I'm looking at it.
You're not slick.
I don't... like you.
You make the shot,
you get the table.
♪ That you surely
don't want to find ♪
♪ You're looking for Joanie ♪
♪ Was Joanie there... ♪
Oh.
♪ But if you find Judy... ♪
Deal's a deal.
♪ Better leave it alone ♪
♪ Leave it alone... ♪
- Have a good night.
- You too.
♪ Leave it alone, you
better leave it alone... ♪
See you at Chastain. We
start as interns on Monday.
♪ Leave it alone... ♪
Great, just what we need...
A new batch of arrogant,
know-it-all interns.
♪ Leave it alone,
leave it alone ♪
♪ Y'all better leave it alone ♪
Hello?
Nic?
Are you with me?
Irving's three-year
Chastain anniversary bash.
404 Tavern. You're going, right?
Excuse me. Coming through!
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
Linda?
- I told you, we don't have any.
- Come on.
- I know you have a stash.
- What about
my patients? They need it
just as much as yours does.
My patient is young,
immunosuppressed,
with a history of
a liver transplant.
She had a syncopal episode.
BP 82/40, heart rate 120.
Two days of
vomiting and diarrhea.
- She's severely dehydrated.
- She just got married.
Help her.
Excuse me. Coming through.
Oh, miracle
workers, both of you.
We'll start getting
some fluids in your wife,
and figure out what's going on.
Thank you, Dr. Feldman.
Glad you were passing
through. Thanks for helping out.
We're a level-1 trauma center
and we can't get
a bag of salt water.
Things like this happen
in third world countries.
They're not supposed
to happen here.
It's gonna continue to
happen until someone in power
decides to fix the problem.
Where you going?
Speak truth to power.
♪ ♪
Well, evidently, my
revolving door of assistants
is either charmed by you or
asleep at the desk,
which is more likely!
Either way, I-I don't have
time for whatever this is.
The staff is hoarding
and rationing saline.
Patients' lives are at risk,
and if that doesn't get you
to focus, it's lawsuit
waiting to happen.
Yeah, I'm fully aware.
I have a plan in motion.
See yourself out.
Please tell me your plan
doesn't involve my father.
How is that any
concern of yours?
My father invests in
companies, he makes his money,
and then he moves on,
leaving scorched earth behind.
I can handle your father.
Then I guess we'll see.
I got your page.
Everything okay?
It is. You've been requested.
Mr. Candelora would
like you on his wife's case.
I pulled up reviews on Chastain.
Dr. Hawkins has five stars, but
Dr. Feldman only has four, so...
Dear, don't you think we
should have discussed this first?
What's to discuss, my love?
You deserve the best care.
You're being rude. I need
you to relax, relate, release.
I wish I could, but
my wife passed out
at a coffee shop
she made me stop at
on her way to
the doctor's office.
It's not constructive
to place blame
during intense discussions.
We're having an argument...
Just call it an argument.
Good luck.
Uh, conflict minimization.
It's a technique Brianna found
to keep the honeymoon alive,
even though we're
still newlyweds.
The honeymoon
phase is a state of mind.
Can we please
have Dr. Hawkins treat you?
It's okay. If I ever
get married, I hope
to be just as good
at fighting for
my wife's health.
Well, you've got
some big shoes to fill.
I didn't get my new
liver from just anyone.
John was my donor.
I didn't have a choice.
World's better with you in it.
Back at you.
So will you let them
look at your cough?
I'm fine. Um, could Brianna
be rejecting the liver?
I'll ultrasound her abdomen,
send off some labs,
see what that tells us.
You sure you're okay?
I will be once we figure out
what's wrong with my wife.
I can't believe you.
- Baby, just...
- Sit down. Sit.
- You are stressing.
- I'm not stressing.
- Look at you. You've got tubes in your nose.
- Just breathe.
You're stressing out.
- Yeah. - I love you. 50%
of all saline is made in
a factory in Puerto Rico,
which isn't operating...
since the hurricane.
Two other companies
have a monopoly on the rest.
They can't handle the
shortage, and on top of that,
they're using the high
demand to drive up prices.
But I have a plan
that'll solve that problem
and also increase our revenue.
We form a consortium
with other health care providers
and manufacture
saline ourselves.
You're talking about
creating a new company.
That's a big undertaking.
Well, the numbers
will support the risk.
I'm not worried
about the numbers.
You don't have enough experience
- as CEO to pull this off.
- You know, I have
a pretty firm grasp on what
I can and cannot handle.
Well, I don't see it
happening, Dr. Bell.
We're tabling it.
That's... Yeah.
That's a... Didn't realize
we'd dispensed with
Robert's Rules of Order.
Very well.
All those in favor
of letting Dr. Bell proceed
with the consortium?
Great. Let's turn to page two.
You stacked the deck.
Well played.
I'll be joining you
today at the conference
to meet the CEOs you hope
will be our future partners.
I insist we travel together.
In my jet.
Looking forward to it.
I've been struck by lightning.
I don't see any
burns on the skin.
- Have you had any muscle pain?
- Nope.
Strong as an ox.
How about any
hearing or vision loss?
Is that a crack at my age, son?
No, sir.
- Any chest pain?
- Yup.
- Bad ticker.
- I see you had
a defibrillator and
a pacemaker put in.
Oh!
See? Struck by lightning.
Your defibrillator is going off.
The pain that you're feeling
is from the electrical shock.
We'll run some
tests, and I'll call
the company that made the device
and have them bring
in some equipment
to run a diagnostic, okay?
- I got the card right here.
- Great.
Um, I see your
surgeon was Dr. Austin.
Didn't he explain how
defibrillators work?
He used big words.
When he started talking,
I stopped listening.
Okay. Be right back.
Dr. Austin,
your billing with the
Titian... Non-existent.
I am aware. Good talk.
The Titian's a two
million dollar machine.
Chastain needs to make
a return on its investment.
Well, the former
is not my fault,
the latter is not my concern.
Your contract
has a billing quota.
Which I exceed consistently.
Okafor, show him the numbers.
Why would I have those numbers?
Somewhere,
someone's got numbers.
Take a gander. Good talk.
The quota includes
robotic surgeries.
Every surgeon has learned
and started billing with
the Titian except you.
Well, I'll tell you what.
You find me a study
that shows that the
robotic approach is better
than the standard CT
surgery, and I will consider it.
Consider this:
everyone's replaceable
if they don't play
ball, even you.
Good talk.
I can't seem to catch my breath.
I feel like I ran a marathon.
Dr. Hawkins, do
you see anything?
Well, I don't see any overt
signs of organ rejection,
but we'll need to do a
more extensive scan,
some blood work,
maybe even a biopsy.
BP 85/60, heart rate 130.
Tamponade.
Well, how bad is this? Tell me.
Fluid has built up
around the heart.
It's keeping the heart from
beating normally.
We need to drain it.
Let's get her upstairs.
It's gonna be okay. It's
just a bump in the road.
- Team Johnna can handle this.
- You know I prefer "BriaJohn."
I'm good with whatever you want.
I, uh... I still
don't understand
about the fluid
around her heart?
It's probably been there
for weeks and getting worse.
Is this related to
her transplant?
Not sure yet, but
certain medications
or inflammation can
cause fluid build-up.
We'll send out the fluid
for analysis to figure it out.
Uh, Dr. Hawkins, you're,
uh, you're a resident, right?
Shouldn't an attending be
supervising this procedure?
You strong-armed
Dr. Hawkins into
taking my case.
Now he's not qualified
to be my doctor?
Hey, don't worry. I've done
this procedure hundreds of times.
She's in good hands.
I should know. I was
there the first time he did it.
Sounds like a
pericardial tamponade.
You're right. I need an
18-gauge spinal needle
and a 60cc syringe
to drain the fluid.
Whoa, whoa. You're an
intern. You can't do procedures
- unsupervised.
- Well, while we wait for
the attending to come down,
the patient will die.
So, you help me,
or you get out of my way.
Careful, Hawkins.
You're gonna need
people like me.
Somebody get me an IV.
♪ ♪
Looks like you just went
rogue to save a patient.
Wouldn't be the first time.
Whenever you're
free, I'd like...
Friday at 8:00. I'll eat
pretty much anything.
I hate white tablecloths,
so let's keep it casual.
♪ ♪
Thank you.
I've been looking
into the three CEOs
you said were
interested in starting
a new saline
company with Chastain.
Not necessary.
I'm handling it.
Sarah?
1947 Sager.
30 grand a bottle.
So, you're meeting them at
the conference to pitch them.
- Yeah.
- It's a big deal.
- A lot at stake. Nervous?
- You know,
when you've held someone
else's life in your hands
as many times as I have,
you don't get nervous.
To a successful pitch.
You know, we want the
same thing for Chastain.
In one instance, we
temporarily disagree.
Let's move on.
Club soda.
Okafor, I better be here
to watch you build a
Barbie Dreamhouse.
You're not. You're here to
learn how to use the Titian.
Did you not
understand me earlier?
I'll try using different
words. I operate with these.
- They're better than any robot.
- Yes, I understood you.
Did you understand Bell?
Uh, his mouth was
moving, but I wasn't listening.
Everybody loves a shiny toy.
They'll spend double,
triple, thousands more
for a mindless, metal cyborg.
But the patient's
outcome is no better.
- This thing is a
two million dollar rip-off.
- Hmm.
You pretend to have
high-minded motives
for refusing this machine,
but I know the truth.
You can't do this.
I can teach you.
Be careful.
Let me introduce myself.
I am Dr. AJ Austin,
triple board certified,
named top CT surgeon
by U.S. News & World
Report four times.
Chastain has given me
the nickname "The Raptor."
I don't know who came
up with it, but I like it.
The raptor is a bird of prey,
ruthless, intelligent,
king of the sky,
slave to none.
So...
let's not forget
who's the teacher
and who's the student.
Lesson for today: never
underestimate The Raptor.
Irving said you haven't
RSVP'd to the party
at the 404 Tavern.
Oh, sorry. I must
have forgotten.
Somebody help!
- What's happening?
- He's wheezing.
We need to get your
husband to the ER.
Coming in with oxygen.
Let's get him up.
Okay. All right.
Here you go.
There we go.
I want to be with him.
No, no. It's better
if you stay here.
- You take him. I'll stay with Brianna.
- Okay.
Thank you.
They've stabilized him,
and he's being admitted.
- So, what now?
- Well,
since John's experiencing
the same pulmonary issues
as you, I'm wondering
if you caught the
same infection.
You said you got
married recently.
Where did you honeymoon?
The Big Island, Hawaii.
Spent most of the
time in the hotel.
I feel so selfish...
not making him see a doctor.
I had no idea he was this sick.
John loves you.
I'm sure he was just
trying to show you that
by putting you first.
He feels guilty.
He cheated on me
when we were dating,
and I left him.
We weren't together anymore
when I was diagnosed
with liver disease.
And yet he still volunteered
to be your organ donor?
It was the worst
time in my life.
I don't know where I'd
be if he hadn't been there.
New Year's party started early.
- Sorry.
- No, it's not your fault.
You've been amazing.
Conrad, I have
everything I need. I'm okay.
You don't have to
stay here all night.
I'm not going anywhere.
Wish there was more I could do.
I felt off yesterday.
Conrad, I'm so sorry.
Please,
- don't.
- - I should have gone to see my doctor.
The miscarriage
is not your fault.
There is nothing
anyone could have done.
These things...
they just happen,
and no one knows why.
What would you
have wanted to do?
We will get through this.
Mr. Yokum,
this is Julian Booth,
device rep from QuoVadis,
the company that made
your dual pacemaker
and ICD device.
She's here to check it
and, if necessary,
help us fix it, okay?
- Yes, sir.
- All right, perfect.
Nice to meet you, Mr. Yokum.
Hi, sweetheart.
You're about to
unbreak my metal heart.
- You call me Hugh.
- Okay, Hugh.
- May I?
- Yes, ma'am. Thank you, thank you.
This will be quick and
painless, I promise.
I can wirelessly
pull information from the
defibrillator's hard drive.
The defibrillator is misfiring.
It'll need to be replaced. Was
this implanted at Chastain?
Dr. Austin put it in. Big guy.
Rude. Took my hat away.
Dude tried to wear a
cowboy hat in the OR.
- I'll get started
on pre-op labs.
- Well, good.
We will schedule surgery
as soon as they come back.
- Do you have a replacement
for the device?
- Ready to go.
All right. Alert me if there
are any complications.
I was with Hugh when
the defibrillator went off.
It seemed extreme to me.
Are there cases
when an ICD device
misfired so badly that the
shock killed the patient?
I've never heard
of that happening.
But it is possible, isn't it?
There's a phenomenon known
as "the cure is the cause."
When the treatment
results in more problems
than the disease itself. That's
not what's happening here.
I think you're overreacting.
All right.
I really don't understand
your problem with the Titian.
It's capable of steady
and precise movements.
Oh, yuck. Look who's
toeing the company line.
- Ooh!
- I don't want him to fire you.
Do what Bell wants.
Human hands, robotic hands,
cutting is cutting.
Pay attention, Okafor.
Robots literally
and figuratively
stand in between
me and the patient.
So, no, all cutting
is not the same.
Not to me.
And it shouldn't be
to you. And trust me,
Bell is not gonna fire
me. I am too valuable,
- and he knows it.
- Yeah.
His ego is as big, if
not bigger, than yours.
Firing you may not
be the smart thing,
but he'll do it just
to prove a point.
- And that point would be what?
- That he
is the most powerful
person in the room.
So if you don't sacrifice
your beliefs, the next stop
on your locum tenens journey
will be Who Cares, New Jersey.
So, what you got against Jersey?
We compared your
X-rays and other tests.
You both have significant
pulmonary damage.
We believe it's
because of an infection,
but we don't know
what caused it.
So we'll look at
your travel history,
see if anything sticks out.
Even though Brianna has a
compromised immune system
due to the drugs she takes
to avoid organ rejection,
John's lungs are
in a worse shape.
Which may mean that
John got the infection first.
Something you want
to share with the class?
I have a crazy itch down there.
All right, let me see.
You have a rash.
Since we seem to
share all our symptoms,
why don't I have a rash?
Maybe John got his
doing something without you.
We were on our honeymoon,
we did everything together.
Didn't we?
You didn't sneak
out of our hotel room
while I was asleep?
That's not an STD, is it?
Let's not jump to
any conclusions.
- Who is she?
- Keep your oxygen mask on.
What, the waitress
from our hotel?
The guide from our tour?
John. John?
We need to intubate.
70 of roc, 20 of etomidate.
John! What's going on?
He can't breathe. We
need to do it for him.
John.
I am thrilled you've
agreed, in principle,
to partner with Chastain.
We'll produce our own saline,
get out from under
monopoly, help our patients,
and make a few
dollars along the way.
- Cheers.
- Hear, hear.
So sorry to intrude
on the celebration.
Everyone, this is
Marshall Winthrop.
He is the chairman of the
board at Chastain Park Memorial.
These three amazing CEOs...
Oh, I know who they are.
Apparently better
than you do, Randolph.
Dr. Curtis, does your board know
that you're being investigated
for massive tax evasion?
Mr. Price, you have
quite the résumé.
BA from Harvard.
MBA from Wharton.
Tell me, how is the
weather in Arizona,
where you actually
went to college?
And Kevin Finnerman, you
have driven your hospital
to the brink of bankruptcy
with administration overhead
that crushes what you
spend in patient care.
You don't have the coin
to partner with anyone.
Stick to what you know
and leave the
business of business
to the big boys.
John's getting a chest CT
and a little test for STDs.
Syphilis or chlamydia
could explain his symptoms.
Yeah. If he passed
something on to Brianna,
it'll explain hers, too.
You okay?
She was holding
on to a honeymoon,
when maybe there never
should've been a marriage.
John says he's changed.
Let's give him the
benefit of the doubt.
They went through so
much. Things changed.
I'm not sure that people can.
Are we still talking
about the patient?
We broke up because we
had issues, and then Lily died,
and your dad came
back, I got arrested.
If those things didn't happen,
do you think we'd
be back together?
Uh, yes.
Of course.
Don't you?
I don't know.
I'll let you know when
John's results come in.
Thank you so much. Thank you.
I'm honored to be here
among the tribe I value most:
doctors, health
care professionals,
dedicated to making
their patients' lives better.
We make decisions when
a life hangs in the balance.
We treat and cure, all while
risking unfounded blame
and lawsuits.
But I'm here today
not to list our
challenges and virtues
but to issue a clarion call
to this group that
I consider heroes.
It's time for us to suit up
and take on a new fight,
and we need to do it together.
Because bad things are
happening in our world,
and we can't fix them
because we've lost control.
We've surrendered our power
to the medical industrial complex,
and it is time to show those
who would stand in the way
of the common good that
we will no longer surrender.
It is up to us, not
ignorant businessmen,
to fight that good fight.
I suggest we can do it by
solving a simple problem.
Hospitals cannot get
ahold of one of the cheapest
and most effective treatments
on Earth: saline solution.
There's a handful of companies
that control the market.
They hold us all hostage.
We need to change that.
Dr. Conrad Hawkins.
I got your page.
The Raptor is here to help.
Let's just say I'm
embracing the nickname.
Our patient has acute
- respiratory failure.
- I'm aware.
Listen, as someone who has
gone toe-to-toe with Bell and won,
I need your advice on
how to handle a situation.
He wants me to start
billing with the Titian.
It's a machine I loathe
as if it were a real person.
I agree.
But if I don't use it,
he says he'll fire me.
Well, then you got a choice
to make. You do what Bell says
and save your job, or
stand up for your principles
and risk getting fired.
Okay, that's not the
answer I was looking for.
That's all I got.
Whoa. Looks like your man
John needs a bronchoscopy, stat.
Look at those lungs.
Most of it looks chronic.
This means John's health was
impaired before his honeymoon.
Oh, long before, brother.
Based on this scan,
I'd say his lungs
have been taking
a beating for years.
But why did John and
Brianna's symptoms only develop
after they got back
from the honeymoon?
Well, I don't know,
but the Raptor
does not envy you right now.
John's organs are shutting down.
First his lungs,
now his kidneys.
Did you get Hugh's
pre-op labs back?
Um... any second.
I'm sorry if I was
a little short earlier.
I love my work.
- I get defensive.
- Understandable.
Admirable, too.
I hear you have a
wedding coming up.
You studying up to
do a Bollywood dance
- at the reception?
- Yeah.
My fiancée, Priya, insists.
I don't want to
disappoint her, but I...
I have two left feet.
Well, maybe I can help.
I was a dancer, remember?
Page Dr. Austin.
His heart rate's dropping.
Get the pacer pads.
His device has
completely failed.
Start pacing at 80.
Can we sedate him?
His pressure's too low.
- It's not capturing.
- Pravesh, talk to me.
- His device isn't working.
- He needs a transvenous pacer.
Well, in my infinite wisdom,
I ordered these on the way down.
Pravesh, suit up.
I'll talk you through it.
Come on, let's go.
Now, access the right internal
jugular vein with
the finder needle.
Good. Now advance the guidewire.
Okay,
and guide the
catheter over the wire.
Remove the wire.
Stay cool, Pravesh.
Don't look at the monitor.
Listen to me.
Now insert the wire
and inflate the balloon.
Grab the pacer generator.
Set the heartbeat to 80,
and the output at ten milliamps.
Slowly advance, Pravesh.
Keep going.
Keep going...
There.
Blood pressure's back to normal.
Deflate the balloon.
Dial back on the output.
All right, let's get this guy up
to ICU and change his device.
But for now, you saved his life.
Well done.
You're a natural.
- I'm ready to leave the ICU?
- Yes, but we're still gonna keep
a close eye on you.
I feel bad for leaving him.
I should be doing something.
The best thing to
do is help figure out
what you've both
been exposed to.
John's lungs were
severely damaged
- long before your honeymoon.
- But your symptoms didn't start
until after you returned home.
- We're missing something.
- I told you everything
I can remember about
our medical history.
All right. Well, then,
let's trace backwards.
When was the last
time you were sick?
Uh, we both had a
cold around the holidays
and a bout of food
poisoning a month ago.
- From what?
- Undercooked chicken.
John took it off
the stove too soon
because it was
smoking out the kitchen.
I lived with him in that
house for two years,
and every time he
cooks something with oil,
the whole place
smells like smoke again,
which makes John's
cough even worse.
You've mentioned
his cough before.
Has he had it for a while?
Yes. It's been on and off
since he bought the
house three years ago.
We tested it for mold
but didn't find anything.
I have the same
cough, but we figured
it was just some
sort of allergy.
We don't normally
do house calls,
but do you mind if
we go have a look?
You're late.
I had a few last-minute
deals to shore up.
So, just for your information,
after my speech,
six new CEOs expressed
interest in starting
- our own saline factory.
- We won't need them.
I just bought a
manufacturing company
to produce our own
saline, and I'm working
on getting fast track
approval from the FDA.
So you bought a factory...
threw away a much
larger opportunity
just to keep me
from having a win.
I got into a business
with a proven track record.
It's not all about you, Bell.
That's something you seem to
have a hard time understanding.
Club soda.
No weird smells. No animals.
I don't see anything hazardous.
John's STD test came back.
Negative.
Brianna will be relieved.
Maybe he did change.
Testing negative does not
mean that he didn't cheat,
but we'll give him the
benefit of the doubt.
Still, it can't be easy
for her; she never forgot
how their relationship
ended the first time.
Kind of like you never forgot
what happened at the 404 Tavern.
Wish I could.
Seriously, none of them?
- None.
- Not even the first three.
- I don't like lightsabers.
- Ugh.
Okay, what about Battlestar...
The concept of girl Starbuck,
boy Starbuck... That
means nothing to you?
What?
Wow. How has this never come up?
I wish it hadn't.
Okay. Clear your
Saturday and your Sunday.
Movie marathon. Me
and you. It's happening.
- You and me.
- Uh, all right.
I'm gonna need
more beer for that.
Pick your franchise.
♪ Baby... ♪
Hey! What the
hell are you doing?
Hey, hey. Whoa,
whoa, whoa, Conrad.
Conrad, stop. Open the door.
Do exactly what
I tell you to do.
You go out there and
you apologize to the lady.
- Unlock the door.
- Conrad!
I'm really, really sorry.
Stop it.
He put his hands on you.
What do you expect me to do?
Don't you pretend this
has anything to do with me.
It's not the first time I've
seen you lose it like that.
What are we doing?
Let's get out of here.
- I'm fine.
- No, you are not fine!
Nic, okay, I
overreacted, but you...
you're doing the
same thing right now.
You know, Conrad, the way
that you handle things scares me.
- That's not fair.
- Whether it's Afghanistan,
losing the baby...
- Don't.
- No, you need to hear it.
'Cause that's the truth.
You bottle everything up inside.
I never know what
you're thinking,
I never know what you're
feeling, and now this?
Dragging some
guy into a bathroom
because some bomb goes off
in you, and I can't see it coming?
This is not normal.
I'm sorry, Conrad. I can't...
I can't do this anymore.
I'm not the same
guy I was back then.
And I want to believe that.
- I hope it'll be different.
- It will be.
Because I'll be different.
Do the work, get the help.
You make me want
to be a better person.
That's one of the
reasons why I love you.
I know you love me, and I know
that you believe
everything you just said.
But if this is gonna work,
you need to believe it, too.
Yeah.
Sorry, I just realized
there's pottery
all over the place.
And I think they
make it themselves.
Maybe somewhere in the house.
Only one place left to look.
You developed a condition
called chronic silicosis,
scarring of the lungs
caused by inhaling silica.
A mineral found in
clay used for pottery.
You and John have been
inhaling harmful levels for years
due to poor ventilation
in your workshop.
John moved into the house first,
so he was exposed
for a longer period.
And that's why he
got sicker faster?
But why didn't we get sick
until after our honeymoon?
Volcanic ash is a
trigger for acute silicosis,
which you inhaled
while you were in Hawaii.
It can take a few weeks
for symptoms to show up.
And the rash?
The bronch on his lungs revealed
an infection called nocardia.
You both got it in Bali,
but it's more common for men
to develop a rash than women.
Silicosis and nocardia...
they're treatable.
But John's chest CT
revealed an empyema...
Pus and dead tissue in the lung.
He needs surgery.
You have my consent.
Go help my husband.
I hear you're doing
Mr. Candelora's empyema.
We're heading to the OR now.
I assume you're
using the Titian.
Well, you know what they
say about assumptions.
Dr. Austin, I was crystal clear.
Yes. You were.
And I made a medical decision
based on personal principles.
I will forever do
the best job I can
using the finest
tools available.
Now, I assume that
a surgeon like you
would understand
that. But, if not...
fire me.
I keep my bags
packed at all times.
I think that's wise.
This might be our
last dance, Okafor.
If Bell was going to fire you,
it would've just happened.
So, not our last dance.
How was the conference?
Oh, inspiring. Educational.
Your father's approach
to just about everything
is an acquired taste.
I'm gonna guess
he insinuated himself
into whatever your plans
were for the saline shortage.
Oh, Marshall, on his own,
wrote a check, bought a
company... just like that...
To manufacture clean,
safe saline for Chastain.
We'll never be short again.
And now he'll sell the
surplus and make a killing.
You know, you
better open your eyes.
He's certainly here
to scorch the earth,
but trust me, he'll
be sticking around
to make a mint off
the carbon he creates.
Long day?
Yeah, it's not over.
Got a couple more phone
calls to make, a few e-mails.
- You can do it tomorrow.
- Not my style.
Chastain isn't like other
companies you've taken over.
I think I can handle anything
this hospital throws my way.
Like a saline shortage?
You might not believe
this, but I have no ill intent
in starting the saline factory.
I believe you.
Well, I want to take
the olive branch,
but I'm curious
where it came from.
If I want people to
believe I've changed,
I need to consider that
maybe you have, too.
I, uh...
hope you can see now that...
you're a lot more like
me than you realize.
Good night... son.
Good night... Dad.
♪ ♪
Is slow dancing a
part of Bollywood?
I just want to see how you move.
Get the nerves out.
We'll start with
something you know.
Okay. Sounds good.
Uh, let me just
apologize in advance
for stepping on your feet.
That's not gonna happen.
Okay.
♪ ♪
♪ I can feel it ♪
Mm-hmm.
♪ Coming on ♪
♪ I think I want to change the ♪
♪ Whole world ♪
♪ Can you see... ♪
I've been thinking about
creating my own medical device.
Watching what you
do gave me the idea.
You know, there's
a secret to this.
People who dance
well, their lips don't move.
♪ Coming on ♪
♪ I think I want to change the ♪
♪ Whole world ♪
Well, I just want to
say one last thing.
I think you're leading.
That's why it's working.
♪ It's all good, it's okay ♪
Come on.
Look how good you're doing.
♪ I'll be there ♪
♪ Through the night ♪
♪ I can feel it ♪
♪ Coming on... ♪
You're here.
I'm not going anywhere.
Me neither.
♪ Phenomenon ♪
♪ Been living on a prayer ♪
♪ All along ♪
♪ All along, all along. ♪
♪ I want you to move me ♪
♪ Like we're in
Babylon tonight ♪
♪ I want you to hear me ♪
- Hey.
You're here.
I'm here.
I love you, too.
♪ Yeah, I said, yeah ♪
And I do think it'll
be different this time.
♪ Angels and demons ♪
♪ I have fallen ♪
♪ Kicked from heaven ♪
♪ Good-bye ♪
♪ My only sin was ♪
♪ To want you... ♪
Are you ready to
go down in defeat?
People may change,
but I'm not sure your
pool game can be saved.
Those are fighting words.
I'll let my 12-game
lead do the talking.
All right. Watch this.
- 12 ball, corner pocket.
- Difficult shot.
I seem to remember
you missing that one a lot.
Not this time.
Captioned by Media
Access Group at WGBH