When exposed to trauma,
the body deploys its
own defense system.
Do you know why I resent you?
I gave up everything for you.
From the first second the
brain receives the signal
that a catastrophe
has happened...
You have a piece
of paper? For what?
We need to make vows.
I have Post-its.
What do we want to
promise each other?
The blood rushes to the
organs that need help the most.
Blood floods into the muscles,
the lungs, the heart, the brain.
The brain makes a decision
for the rest of the body.
Either face the
danger or run away.
It's a mechanism designed to
protect the body from harm...
from knowing that what has
happened might be irreparable.
To love each other even
when we hate each other.
No running.
We call it shock.
The person who cares for
your kids is an important choice.
You want to make
sure it's the right fit.
So we'll sit and talk.
I'll find out about your
needs, you'll learn about me...
Right. Just, right now,
I'm a little pressed for time.
Oh, absolutely. You're busy.
That's why we're here to help.
Yeah, there's a trauma
coming in, and I...
Of course. Listen, I've worked
with doctors before, many times.
I know the drill.
How about if I wait in the
lobby until you have some time?
That's great. I'll
find you. Okay.
Who was that?
Uh, new nanny, hopefully.
You got a nanny?
I had to. Derek left.
What?
We don't have
numbers yet... Meredith?
But be prepared for as
many as 20 casualties,
many of them kids.
What happened?
A woman drove off a bridge
with her two kids in the car.
Witnesses are saying that
the woman started speeding,
she rammed a bunch of vehicles,
and then took a sharp right
off the bridge into the water.
Police believe
this was intentional.
Oh, my God. With her kids?
Let's cooperate with the
police and do our jobs, okay?
God, is she one of
those crazy moms
who tries to drown her kids?
Oh.
Maybe she needed a nanny.
What kind of mother
does that to her own kids?
Why is it somehow worse when a
woman kills her kids? That's sexist.
Women are just as crappy
and homicidal as men.
Is there something
you want to tell me?
Or a grand jury?
Shut up. I'm just
making a point.
It's not like I'm
advocating killing your kids.
Oh, hi, Dr. Kepner.
You heard Dr. Hunt.
We've got at least
six criticals on the way.
Why are you both standing
here? You're right. I'm sorry.
I told Jackson about the baby.
Oh, God!
I was just standing here
shouting about killing kids.
Why didn't you
tell me to shut up?
Does she know? Uh, I don't know.
No. Right? I
mean, if she knew...
If you found out that your
unborn baby had a fatal disease,
you wouldn't be at work, right?
No.
What do we got?
Ten-year-old female, Mia James.
GCS of 14 but was
unconscious at the scene.
Deep facial lac.
Little brother and mom
are right behind us.
Mia, I'm Dr. Hunt.
Can you hear me?
Where's my mom? Is she okay?
We'll find out as soon as
we can. Let's get her inside.
Parker James, age five.
Minor injuries include facial
lacerations, left-arm deformity.
Normal vitals.
Where's my sister?
She's right inside, Parker.
We've got you, okay?
We got a Brooke James,
submerged restrained driver,
unresponsive since
we arrived on the scene.
She is hypotensive, tachycardic.
Wait. Is this the driver? Yeah.
Let's move. Come on.
Police want to question her, but I
said there's no way in her condition.
Did they say what
happened? Did she go nuts?
She could have lost her
footing on the gas pedal.
We do not know.
We do know she's hypotensive,
had a low D-stick reading
and free fluid in the belly.
She's too unstable for a CT.
Let's get her up to the OR now.
Hunt. Driver's in bad
shape. We're taking her up.
I'm gonna alert the OR.
I'm looking for
my wife and kids.
Brooke James.
Kids are Mia and...
Parker, right?
They said some woman hit
their car and drove off the bridge?
Mr. James, your wife
is on her way to surgery.
Your kids are being treated.
Your wife was the driver.
She drove off the bridge.
What? No. That's crazy.
Sir...
No, she wouldn't
do that. That's crazy.
Mr. James, can you
come with us? Excuse me.
She wouldn't do that.
Can you come with us?
Mr. James. Thank you, sir.
She'd never do that. It's
a lie! WOMAN: Dr. Grey?
I'm here. We're on our way up.
I'm gonna want more scans,
3-D renderings, so I can
get to know this tumor better.
I'm gonna need to draw up
measurements and trajectories.
When do I get to speak
to her previous doctors?
Um, as soon as I
talk to Dr. Herman.
Great. When are you doing that?
It's a big cliff. You
just got to leap.
I stole medical records.
I racked up about a
thousand HIPAA violations.
It's not a cliff. That's prison.
And I'm too pretty for prison.
Arizona, you are
saving her life.
I'm saving her life, but
you made it possible.
Once you tell her,
once she understands,
she will be okay with it.
She'll be happy.
Ultimately, she
will be thrilled.
You want me to tell her?
No. I have to do
it. I have to do it.
I just need to figure
out how and when.
How and when.
That's my tumor.
That's my tumor!
Where did you get it
and why do you have it?
You showed my tumor
to other doctors
without my consent?
I needed to understand...
You have no right.
You stole them.
I had to.
Do you know how many
laws you're breaking right now?
You weren't telling me anything!
I can remove the tumor.
I don't know who you've
been seeing for this.
I'm sure they're great.
I'm sure they are
the best in their field.
But I can only tell you
they lack imagination.
They lack scope.
Your tumor is smart.
It's brilliant.
But so am I. I can beat it.
I will beat it.
I have a surgery.
Chief, uh, just
wanted to let you know
that I don't think Kepner's
gonna make it in today.
We had some news...
April's here.
Wait. What?
Yeah. She's been
here all morning.
She's just on her
way up to surgery.
Everything okay?
Uh, yeah, yeah. Thank you.
You know what? No.
Actually, I need you to pull
her out of surgery right now.
Avery, I can't... No, look.
She shouldn't operate.
She shouldn't even
be at work today at all,
so she should definitely
not be operating.
I need you to trust
me when I say that.
Kelly, more lap pads?
I think I see the
source of the cut.
I got it.
Owen?
Grey. Kepner.
How we doing in here?
It's a mess, but we've
got it under control.
April, I'm tagging you out.
I'll take this one.
Why?
I'll just...
I'll take this one.
April.
I'm good. You can go.
It's okay. I'm tagging you out.
No.
Owen?
Listen, it's okay.
We've got this.
Go ahead and go.
Do we have a problem here?
No.
Yes. Yes, there is. Jackson.
Jackson's my
problem, right, Hunt?
He went to you,
and now you know,
and you've decided
what's best for me.
Jackson's downstairs,
and he's waiting for you.
I'm working here.
April.
I am taking over for you.
Is this an order? Is
that what's happening?
Are you ordering
me out of my OR?
I'm asking you.
Then, my answer is no.
Then it is an order.
That is an order, Kepner.
Fine.
You're in so much trouble.
Shut up. You are.
You wanted to go out.
Got some bruises and
contusions, nothing surgical.
You guys had a
pretty rough ride, huh?
It was awesome.
That car slammed right into us.
And then they flew off
the bridge, into the water!
And then all the other cars
started slamming
into each other!
It was like Grand Theft Auto!
Son of a bitch. Dad's gonna
freak when he sees the car.
Language.
Where is your dad?
You can't tell my dad.
Yeah, 'cause he's gonna
ground you till you're dead.
Shut your mouth, assface!
You're an assface.
You want to be so cool,
but you're a crappy driver,
and your mustache is stupid.
Wait. You were driving?
How old are you?
Eighteen.
Yeah, and I'm 25, assface.
Duodenal perf,
duct looks severed.
Head of the pancreas
is badly injured.
What do you think,
trauma Whipple?
Looks like it.
What happened
with you and Kepner?
Nothing.
It better have been something.
You kicked her
out of her own OR.
She shouldn't even be in an OR.
She's got personal stuff.
We all have personal stuff.
My husband left me. I'm here.
Wait. What?
I thought he would have
e-mailed you by now.
He went to D.C.
When did this happen?
Last night.
You want to throw me out?
Should I go get my nails done,
have a good cry?
Listen, Jackson didn't tell
me what it was, just that...
Oh, so her husband
tells you to do something,
and that's enough...
Okay, it's about their baby.
It's bad.
Good.
And then your mom
started driving faster.
Did she say anything?
She told us to shut up.
She said that?
She's never said that.
We weren't even making noise.
And then we started
to hit other cars,
and then we went into the water,
and then a fireman
pulled me out.
God.
You said "shut up"
was a bad word.
You said...
No, it's okay. You're okay.
It's true, Parker.
You're a lucky kid.
All you need is a little splint
on that wrist, but that's it.
Okay. Your daughter's
still just a little groggy.
Just need to stitch up
that laceration on her face.
- She's good to go.
- Yes. Of course.
Please, do whatever
you have to do.
Dr. Avery, a word?
Uh, excuse me.
One second. Uh-huh.
Hey. You all right?
I'll get somebody to cover
for me, and we can just go...
What is wrong with you?
Letting a cop interrogate
a five-year-old?
They needed to know...
Those kids were almost
killed by their mother.
They're terrified.
Okay. Slow down.
They're in shock.
Listen, listen, I think
you're in shock, actually.
They shouldn't even be down
here. Get them out of here.
Get them someplace
safe. Get them admitted.
Okay. Let's just go home.
Have you seen
those people in there?
What that woman did?
I know, and there are
plenty of people here
that can take
care of them, right?
You need to...
I... I need to be in an OR.
But you seem to be making all
sorts of decisions for me today.
I'm trying to help you.
Yeah, you're not helping.
You go to Owen, and
then two men decide
what they think is
best for the little lady,
like I'm some helpless idiot,
and then I suddenly find myself
standing outside of my OR?
That is not helping!
Why don't you tell
me what is, then?
Talk to me instead
of running away.
Tell me what you need. Tell me
what I can do. Tell me how you feel.
Tell me something, anything.
Say something. Talk to me.
I'm trying to help you.
That's all I'm trying to do here.
Okay, okay. You
want to help? Yes.
Just get that family into a room
and stitch up that girl's face.
Everything okay?
No.
Everything is not okay.
We need your parents' names.
They need to know that
you're here and you're safe.
Just cough it up.
You don't say a word.
You're a brick wall.
Dylan's CT shows
mesenteric stranding
and some thickening
of the bowel wall.
Could be just a
mesenteric injury,
but it also looks like
a bucket-handle injury.
I'll just go in and take a look
first with the laparoscope.
Uh-uh.
No. Come here.
No, we need to get in there,
open him up and
see what's happening.
Laparoscopic isn't the standard.
You could miss a bowel perf.
But I'm trying to save this kid
a massive scar
and a long recovery.
Yeah, but we shouldn't risk...
Why do you keep saying "we"?
You're not doing
it at all. He's a kid.
You don't tell me what
I'm doing and not...
You're a kid.
I'm an attending pediatric
surgeon, and he's a kid.
It's my call,
and I'm going in
laparoscopically.
Oh.
Is that how it's gonna be?
Yeah. It is.
And maybe while I do that,
you can get his
little rat brother
to roll over on his
parents. Okay?
Let's get him ready to roll.
You're a brick wall, Jack.
Brick it!
Okay, that should
prevent any tamponading.
One woman loses it, and look
at all the damage she can do.
There's a chest contusion with
intermittent arrhythmias in bed six.
Can you take a look at
that next? Mmm-hmm.
Boy or girl? What?
Oh, are you guys
not finding out?
I am such a control freak.
I don't think I could
handle not knowing.
I would want to have
a list of names in mind.
That would be the hardest
part, I think, choosing the name.
Bed six, consult. Now, please.
Okay.
Uh, I'm looking for Greg
James. Is he still down here?
I need to talk to you.
Okay. So, you talked to Jackson.
Are you okay? Can I do anything?
You saw something
on my ultrasound.
Yes.
Yes, you saw something,
and you didn't say anything.
I know. I...
I was right there in the room.
It was my baby,
and you said nothing.
Nothing.
I just wanted to be
sure before I told you.
Oh, but you had no problem
going and telling other people.
You had no problem
telling Jackson
before I even had a
chance to process. I'm sorry.
To have you, of all people,
knowing before I did.
I'm sorry.
Yeah, you should be.
Mr. James is upstairs.
His kids were admitted.
Hello. This is OR one.
Did he tell Amelia? Did
he pass off his cases?
I'm sure he did. Derek
wouldn't just leave his patients.
Pickups.
Or his wife or his kids.
It's just hard to believe.
He did.
And what do you need?
Someone to blame?
It's my fault. I did
it. I told him to go.
Stapler.
Dr. Grey, her tox screen's back.
Any drugs or alcohol?
Antipsychotics? Antidepressants?
All negative. Damn it!
What are you after?
An explanation. Something.
Someone puts her
whole family in danger,
you want to find out
there was a good reason.
You want to believe she
didn't have any choice.
Have you talked to Cristina?
I presume you guys talk
all the time, especially now.
Yeah, we usually get on the
phone Friday nights for me,
Saturday mornings for
her, pour drinks, settle in.
So, today's Friday. You
gonna call her today?
Yeah, I've missed
the last couple.
Why?
Before she left, she said
something about Derek and I,
and she was right.
And I don't want
her to be right.
Hmm. Hmm.
Okay, so, no history
of diabetes in the family.
What about, uh, current
illnesses or mental illnesses?
Are you asking if
my wife's crazy?
No, we're trying to
see if there's something
that could have made her do...
To hurt my kids?
Nothing. She wouldn't.
I didn't think she would.
Brooke. I mean, she's, uh...
She's busy.
You know, she's
tired and stressed.
And she forgets things.
She's got a lot going on
with getting them from
school and violin and baseball.
And making sure they're happy.
And I...
I work too much.
I don't know.
I...
I don't know my wife.
I don't know anything anymore.
I left you alone
for a few minutes.
Am I gonna find my
wallet in your pocket?
I'm sorry that I went
behind your back.
You're understating it.
You betrayed me. I
thought I could trust you.
Shepherd is fully convinced that
she can do a complete resection.
She's convinced...
Shepherd is in a party of one.
If there's even the
slightest bit of hope,
don't you want to know that?
Robbins, can you
name the single worst,
most malignant symptom
of terminal cancer?
It's hope.
It's recurrent, and it
keeps creeping back in,
no matter how many
times it gets ripped apart.
Mayo gave me hope in a
phase three clinical trial. It failed.
NYU hoped that radiosurgery
would work. It didn't.
And Barrow had high, high hopes
for a potent combination
of chemo and ablation.
No go.
And every time the hope goes,
it takes chunks of you with it,
until you can only find comfort
in the one thing that you
know you can count on.
That this thing
is gonna kill you.
So you tell Shepherd to
keep her hope to herself.
Better yet, tell her
where to stick it.
Okay. Let's start
the anastomoses.
Yep. 4-0 Prolene.
Husband says there's
no history of diabetes.
Anything else? Uh, yeah.
She's been exhausted,
forgetful, stressed,
running around,
taking care of the kids,
I don't know. Maybe she snapped.
Running around
taking care of her kids
doesn't sound like a mom
who's about to kill herself,
in my experience.
Hmm. It doesn't make sense.
Her blood-sugar levels were
so low when she came in.
My mother always used to say,
"The pancreas is the
self-destruct button of the body."
And her pancreas
was really friable.
And her husband said
she's been forgetful.
I bet there's a tumor
on that pancreas.
Insulinoma.
That would explain her anxiety,
confusion, erratic behavior.
That would explain everything.
Yeah.
I need to call
your parents, Jack.
Look, you're scared.
You think you're in trouble now.
But believe me, the longer
you wait, the worse it'll be.
Your parents are
scared right now,
wondering where you are.
And they're getting more
and more scared by the minute.
When they finally see
you, they'll be so relieved.
But...
I mean, all that fear has
got to go somewhere.
All that fear will turn
into white-hot anger
that will banish you to a world
with no video games forever.
Trust me. I have
a little boy, too.
I'm a brick wall.
Give me your cell phone.
I'm seven.
Would you give your
seven-year-old a cell phone?
Look, I am trying to help you.
If you don't cooperate,
then I'll have to call
Child Protective Services.
Do you know what that means?
Hey, you want to
do this the hard way?
Then I will make that call.
You do what you've got to do.
I stole a car once,
when I was 12.
Didn't make it two blocks.
What stopped you?
A dumpster.
Mmm. First time I stole a
car, I sideswiped the mirror.
First time?
Second time, I ran out of gas.
Third, I got away with it.
Fourth... Fourth?
Flat tire.
Are you messing with me? No.
Was there a fifth?
Yeah. I lived in that one.
Damn it. JO: What just happened?
Mesentery's bleeding like
crazy. We got to open him up.
I thought that's what
we were trying to avoid.
We have no choice.
We got to get in there,
and we got to get in there now.
10 blade. 10 blade!
Are you almost done here?
I've got two tib-fib fractures
and an L45 compression
fracture in trauma four.
Okay. Hang on. All right,
I'm gonna count to three,
and then I'll do it, okay? Okay.
You ready? Yeah.
One, two...
Ah.
Always better when
you don't see it coming.
Go ahead and put a
shoulder sling on him, please.
All right, Kepner. What's next?
I already told you, if
you'd been listening.
What is going on? I'm fine.
No, you're not, and I know
because I'm the queen of taking
my personal crap
out on other people,
especially you,
and it looks like this.
What's going on? I
don't want to talk about it.
And I don't want
you snapping at me.
You can't have a
baby. Excuse me?
And it's what you want.
All you want is to have a
baby and love that baby
and nurture that baby
and raise that baby,
and this woman, this woman,
throws her perfectly
healthy kids off of a bridge.
Doesn't that just enrage you?
April... I'm saying
how are you not screaming
right now at what she's done?
To her kids? To
all of these people?
How is any of this fair?
April! April.
April.
Okay, now...
Patients are waiting.
Uh...
Will my daughter have a
scar for the rest of her life?
Oh.
I took my time.
Any scar, it would
be very minimal.
Ah.
Every time she looks in a
mirror, she'll remember this.
My kids,
they lost everything.
They have you.
I don't... I'm not
sure how good that is.
Look, I missed
this. You know, I...
Whatever was
happening with Brooke,
I just wasn't seeing it.
You know, you worry
about everything.
But I was not prepared for this.
Should I have seen it coming?
How could I have
prepared for this?
Why do we want to avoid
putting in another port?
Each incision increases the
chances of rupturing the membranes.
Exactly.
Hi. Robbins?
Um, sorry to interrupt.
I wanted to ask if I could
meet with you and talk.
You and me and April.
Her hands are a little
full right now, Doctor.
Of course. We're
almost done here.
Yeah, I meant after.
But soon, please.
I just, um...
I need to be prepared
for whatever it is.
We need to know
everything we can.
Just what it is, what we can do.
Everything.
I'll come find you.
All right.
My friends, the baby with
osteogenesis imperfecta.
Hmm. I see. You're
clear on what to tell them?
Yeah, I know.
Just remember what
I said about hope.
Don't make it any harder
for them than it already is.
Can you take this,
please? Robbins.
I am done here.
Robbins!
They examined every slice?
I stood in path
and watched them.
Have them do it again.
I did. There's no
evidence of insulinoma.
Get me the ultrasound.
The tumor is in here.
It doesn't have to be.
The husband says she
was stressed and overtaxed.
Sounds like she was headed
for a nervous breakdown.
It sounds like she's
a mother, Owen.
Where is that ultrasound?
I'm just saying people have
breakdowns for all kinds of...
Owen. Shut up.
You're not gonna find anything.
I'm not?
Give me your hand.
What's that, right there?
It's tiny. Feels like
the head of a pin.
Right. But it's there.
I knew it was there.
Excellent work, Dr. Grey.
Edwards. Scrub in.
Okay.
Whew! OWEN: Hmm.
Give me your phone.
I don't have a phone.
Give me your phone!
It's not mine. It's Dylan's.
This is not a game, Jack.
Your brother is very badly hurt.
He is lying open on
an operating table,
with two doctors working
very hard to save his life!
There are no restart
buttons. There's no replays.
This is not a game.
When it's over,
it's over. It's real.
Now, he needs his parents!
So what are you gonna do?
It's all my fault.
I wanted to go to
the ice-cream shop,
and I asked him
to drive me there.
I want to go home.
I want my mom.
She should wake up soon.
A tumor?
Benign, but it secretes insulin,
which causes major
fluctuations in glucose levels.
And that was...
The exhaustion, the
confusion, the forgetfulness,
the accident, it was the
tumor. And it's gone now.
I'm sorry. I should
have never thought it.
Not for one second.
I should have never thought
that you would hurt them.
I'm sorry.
It's only 4:00 a.m. there.
I told Cristina to go, too.
It was the only thing to do.
She had to go.
If she'd stayed, it
would have been worse.
I know that now.
Tell her "hello" for me.
Robbins, you don't
ever walk out of an OR
in the middle of
a procedure, ever.
You have a shot!
You have a chance!
And it may be small and it
may be risky, but it's a chance.
A chance that my friends
would give anything to have,
and you're ignoring
it, you're wasting it.
Dr. Grey?
I'm still here.
Lynn, the nanny?
Oh, Lynn!
I'm sorry. You're still here?
I am.
It's fine.
Uh, now, tell me what
it is you're needing.
Uh, I, um...
I need help with
the kids, obviously.
More specifically?
Uh, I need support.
My life and my work
is very unpredictable.
And I need someone
who understands that
and who can be
there when I can't
and who understands
that if I can't be there,
it's because I must
be where I am.
And I need someone
who believes in that
and who supports that.
I need a person
who is in it with me.
And who believes in that.
And I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
I know I seem like I'm crazy.
And I'm really not.
But I've just had this day.
No, no, no.
It's okay.
Let's talk.
See this here? This
linear hypointensity?
It is a CSF plane.
That's what can give
me a clean dissection.
If I leave behind one
billionth of a malignancy,
the tumor will be back,
so I am going to have to
use every tool in the box,
CUSA, lasers, fluorescein,
radioactive seeds.
I will not stop until I have
completely decimated
each and every last cell.
Chief? What do you think?
It is complex, and it is risky.
I see three scenarios here.
One, Shepherd operates
and I die on the table.
Two, Shepherd operates
and resects
something she shouldn't
and I wake up gorked.
And three, least likely of all,
Shepherd operates,
removes all of the tumor,
and I wake up alive,
deficit-free. Am I right?
Yes. But as I...
How far does the
tumor need to reach
before it becomes impossible
to resect in its entirety?
Nicole, we need to do this now.
How far?
Once it goes through
the optic apparatus
and breaches the hypothalamus,
there's no way.
I won't touch it.
If you clot or
bleed, it's too risky.
Great. Then, we wait.
And when the tumor starts
threatening the optic nerve
and heading to the
hypothalamus, you can operate.
That is a dangerous plan.
It's a stupid plan.
This is the plan.
You get at my tumor,
you get at my knowledge,
I get at my life.
Everyone's happy.
When did the parents get here?
A few minutes ago.
I'm waiting to see
if they hug that kid
or slap him.
You're a really good mom.
What makes you say that?
You've been riding me all day,
making sure I don't screw up.
Crap, you've been
doing it for years.
It sucks, it's
annoying, but it's nice.
Tuck stole a candy bar
a couple of weeks ago.
I only found out
about it last night.
I got so mad. I yelled at him.
Turns out, Ben already
made him go back to the store
and pay for the damn thing.
I didn't even know about it.
I'm so busy at work, I
haven't been there to...
How do I watch out for my
own kid if I'm not even there?
How do I do that?
I stole a bunch of stuff.
I turned out okay.
Take her up to the ICU and
check her coags every hour.
Yes, Doctor.
Who's next?
That's it.
Take a look at the board, babe.
Everyone's been either
admitted or discharged.
No, there were at
least 25 patients here.
And you treated every one.
It's damn good you
were down here.
Listen, um,
you and I have a real
chance here, you know?
We're able to see
this thing coming.
Then we are gonna
find out exactly what it is
and prepare ourselves.
I already talked to Arizona.
She's gonna sit down with us.
We're gonna get some answers.
I already have answers.
Jackson, I spent all
night looking it up.
I pulled case study
after case study.
Yeah, I did the same thing,
but those are other cases.
There are four types of
osteogenesis imperfecta,
ranging from a manageable
disability to completely fatal.
Types II and III
are the most severe.
I'm talking about our baby.
So am I.
I studied my ultrasounds.
Best case,
our kid gets
surgery after surgery.
Worst case, our kid lives
only minutes after birth.
Mmm-hmm.
I don't... I don't need answers.
What I needed today
was just to do something,
to treat things I could treat,
to help people I could help.
At the very least, undo
some of the damage
this lunatic woman
did to her kids
and all of these people here.
She had a tumor.
It turns out she
had an insulinoma.
Causes cognitive deficits.
Hunt told me all about it.
Look, she was not
trying to hurt anyone.
She had no control.
Why?
Why would that happen?
Why would God give her kids,
give her a family, and let that...
Why would God let that happen?
I don't understand it!
You can do everything
right, and it doesn't even...
Why?
I don't know.
I... I just...
I don't want you to hold me
'cause if you hold me, I'll start to cry,
and I don't want
to start crying.
'Cause if I start crying,
I will not be able to stop.
I will never be able to stop.
Okay.
Whatever you need,
I'm here.
Did I tell you that it's a boy?
We're having a boy.
When shock wears off,
when the body can accept
that a trauma has happened,
when it can let
down its defenses...
Are you there?
Uh, no. I'm about to, um...
Meredith?
I don't want to fight anymore.
I don't, either.
And I don't want you gone.
I know that I told
you to go, but...
I mean, this isn't us.
This isn't how we end, is it?
I don't want it to. I'm trying.
I'm trying, too.
Listen, my flight's
been delayed all day.
I'm still at the airport.
I can come home.
It's a scary moment.
Do I come home?
What do we want to
promise each other?
That you'll love me,
even when you hate me.
To love each other even
when we hate each other.
It's vulnerable.
No. No, go.
Meredith.
You know, in a good way. Go.
And do what you have to do.
We can do this. People do this.
No running, ever.
Nobody walks out, no
matter what happens.
People do, yes. Okay.
So, go and do
what you have to do.
And we will figure this out.
We can do this.
Okay.
Call me when you land.
And, Derek?
Yes?
I'm going to miss you.
This can work.
We will make this work.
We will.
Are you still there?
Meredith?
Meredith? Meredith,
I'm losing you.
Derek?
This is forever.
Sign.
Now what?
Now I kiss the bride.
The shock response
had protected us,
and it just might have saved us.