Truck 81, Squad 3, I need
search teams.
It's a long way down.
Can't we take the elevator?
Hey, you're in the way.
She's alive!
Casey, what's it looking like
up there?
Mr. Halstead is
in rough shape.
I need a hand.
Dad.
Mayday, mayday!
It's Stella... Kidd.
She took in a lot of smoke.
How did you
let this happen?
She was trying
to save you.
Got another wave
of patients coming in.
Let's look alive!
Monique, what do we have?
I triggered
the mass casualty
protocol.
Yeah?
Everyone's prepped
and ready to go.
All right, let's continue
to decompress the ED.
Get all non-critical
admitted or discharged.
On it.
All right, Doris,
talk to me.
I'm getting real-time
updates from the Office
of Emergency Management.
All right, I want to
know how many are still
down at the scene
and how many
we've got coming.
Copy.
All right, Dr. Manning.
Status on your burn patient?
I need to get her up to the OR
to have her burns excised.
Have you been able to
reach her parents?
We're still trying
to track them down.
Poor kid.
Maggie.
Yeah?
You page Dr. Rhodes
for my dad?
He's coming down
in five.
Hey, how are you
guys doing?
Choi kicked us out.
Yeah, he needs room
to work, Kelly.
Try to be patient.
Get her on the vent and make
sure she's 100% oxygenated.
Right.
She's waking up.
Push 4 milligrams
of midazolam.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Easy, easy.
Easy.
All right.
BP and heart rate are stable.
She's settling down.
Draw a blood gas with
carboxyhemoglobin.
Yes, Doctor.
Hey.
What's happening?
Her vitals are holding,
but she's in pretty bad shape.
We're running some tests
and should know more soon.
Blood pressure
and sats are dropping.
All right, she's bleeding
in her airway.
Hang a unit on
the rapid transfuser,
suction her ET tube,
and get a chest X-ray.
Yep.
Pop tried
to play hero.
He forgot he was
in his 60s
with a bum ticker.
Yeah, well.
This is your fault
to begin with.
Me?
Yeah.
Stick me in that fire trap.
Pop, stop talking.
You said
you liked the place.
You close on the EKG?
Just about.
What's the point of this?
Easy.
Paramedics said you were
complaining of chest pain.
Did you forget you had
a quadruple bypass
a few weeks ago?
Come on, stay still.
Hey, if it isn't
my favorite patient.
How you doing,
Mr. Halstead?
Fine.
So you felt some tightness
in your chest, huh?
It's nothing.
Well, you might be right.
I don't see any ST
elevation or depression.
No left
access deviation.
Looks like a strong
and healthy heart to me.
Yeah, good. We done?
Nope, not yet.
You still have a pretty
nasty inhalation injury.
Can I get a CBC, CMP,
and a carboxyhemoglobin?
And add a full
cardiac workup.
Dr. Rhodes?
Dr. Choi needs a consult.
Yeah. Mr. Halstead,
a pleasure as always.
Thank you, Connor.
I don't need all this.
Calm down, you're getting
yourself worked up.
What do you know?
You're no doctor.
Pop.
Forget it.
You had no right
to sell my house.
You want to talk
about this again?
It was a wreck. You couldn't
take care of the place.
You just wanted my money.
Hey.
You don't have any money,
you thankless old prick.
Whatever.
Jay.
Blood's coming too fast.
Every time I suction the tube
it fills back up again.
Hang another unit and just do
your best to keep up.
Where's the X-ray?
Here you go.
She's got
a massive hemorrhage
in her right lung.
It's impossible to say
where it's coming from.
All right,
call the blood bank,
trigger the MTP.
Can you stop the bleed?
First I've gotta find it.
Let's set up
for a bronchoscopy.
Okay.
We're already maxed out
on ventilators
and even
if I brought more down,
all my rooms are occupied.
I have nowhere
to put these patients.
And Rhodes' pet project
has us down a room.
This hybrid OR
was a terrible idea.
I told you.
Maggie, call Respiratory.
Tell them to send down
as many vents
as they've got.
Dr. Lanik, open up
the doctors' lounge
and the cafeteria
and get them equipped
for the overflow.
Maggie.
Yeah?
I need a nurse to help
with some dressings.
Take Doris with you.
She's with a patient.
Then Monique?
She is too.
All right. Go down
the phone tree again
and get us more nurses.
Meanwhile, I'll give you
a hand, Dr. Manning.
Thank you.
As soon as
an operating room
becomes available
your husband's gonna
go into surgery.
Can I get you
a bottle of water?
Yes, thank you.
Okay. Okay.
Damn it.
You all right, Otis?
Yeah. Yeah, yeah, fine.
Happens when I don't eat.
It's...
Low blood sugar.
Of course.
Dad's stable.
Why don't you go in
and talk to him?
You know, make up?
Well, he started it.
And thanks a lot.
We agreed that we were
gonna sell that place
and you just stood there.
You didn't say anything.
What's the point
in arguing with him?
He's old, he's sick,
just let it go.
That's fine for you to say.
You're not the bad guy here.
Jay, come on.
No, seriously.
All those times you were away,
and all those times you said
that you couldn't
leave the hospital,
who took care
of Dad?
Me.
I did plenty for Dad.
I still do.
Who goes
and checks on him?
Keeps him on his meds?
Yeah, all right.
Tell you what.
When he gets out of here,
you find him
his next apartment.
This is Leslie
and Ryan Scott.
Blair's parents.
I'm Ms. Goodwin,
this is Dr. Manning.
Hey.
We were both at work.
Heard there was a fire
at the apartment, but...
Never expected this.
Is she in pain?
No.
We've given her medication
to make sure
she's comfortable.
You've got to save her.
We're going to do
everything we can for her.
I've reviewed
the imaging.
This is Dr. Bekker.
She's a cardiothoracic
surgeon
we asked to consult.
One of your
daughter's injuries
is to her right
carotid artery.
What does that mean?
The artery is damaged.
Blocking blood flow.
Don't worry, I can repair it
while her burns
are being excised.
Is Blair going to...
No.
Blair's burns cover
almost 80% of her body.
Once her blood pressure
is stable enough,
we will take her
up to the OR
to begin excision
of her burn tissue.
I am afraid she will need
to remain in the ICU
for several months.
Several months?
While the doctors continue
to excise and graft her burns.
But then
can she come home?
Yes, however, your daughter
is going to need physical
and occupational therapy
to regain her ability to walk,
talk, eat,
even dress herself.
No...
We understand there are
many challenges ahead,
but with proper treatment
and patience,
Blair can recover.
Oh, my baby.
Oh...
Take this one.
Got one more for you.
Hey, Maggie. This one...
Yeah.
I'm gonna get some air.
You just...
You page me if
there's anything
happening with Stella, okay?
Will do.
Otis, you okay?
Yeah.
Otis?
Otis, you okay?
Get over here, Curly!
Get me a gurney.
Ooh.
Let's take you down.
Easy, easy, easy, easy.
Go get the gurney.
Yeah, I got this.
I got it.
Stay with me.
I understand Otis
had some kind of episode?
Yeah, looks like
an inhalation injury.
I'm giving him
a neb treatment.
Took blood
to run an ABG.
He's doing much better,
but he needs an extensive
physical exam.
Dr. Choi, I need you.
You go ahead.
I'll take a look at him.
Like to keep my chops up.
Thanks.
We've got another burn
victim coming in.
Desmond! Talk to me.
Early 20s, female,
found down at the scene,
unconscious due
to smoke asphyxiation.
Intubated on the ride.
Mags, let's get her
in a room.
Afraid it's
the doctors' lounge.
Doctors' lounge?
Unless you want to go
to the cafeteria.
Doctors' lounge.
Okay.
We were taking her
to East Mercy
but they went on bypass.
No ID or identifying marks
so we're treating her
as a Jane Doe.
Right here, right here.
Yep.
Let's transfer her
on my count.
Everybody ready?
One, two, three.
Start a second IV
and get her on the monitors.
Right away.
What do we have?
No gross deformities,
but she's got some
pretty nasty burns,
including a full thickness,
near circumferential
on her lower left arm.
We need to get fluids in her.
Bolus 500 of ringers
at 200 per hour.
Got it.
Wait, shouldn't we
use Parkland?
Calculate fluid input based
on percentage of burn area.
First 24 hours are critical.
We should start with
a higher volume of fluid.
That's not standard procedure.
I've had experience
with burns in the military.
We can always titrate down
based on urine output.
Your party.
Thanks for that.
All right.
I really feel fine now.
You're a little
tachycardic.
Can you feel
your heart racing?
Yeah, it usually happens
when I get a physical.
You know,
what do they call it,
white coat syndrome?
You know,
doctors, needles...
I hear you.
Probably why your blood
pressure's a little high too.
You ever experience
this before?
Yeah, a couple times.
Nothing serious.
You know. Smoke.
Right.
Ever happen
when you're off duty?
No, why would it?
I'm just going
to make sure
that you don't
have a retinal
burn, all right?
You don't have to go
to all the trouble.
Just checking
all the boxes, bud.
Will you close
your eyes for me?
Doc Charles,
my eyes feel good.
Just humor me.
You see anything?
Colors? Patterns?
No.
Nothing.
Okay.
Just sorry you had...
Such a tough day
at the office.
I heard there were
a lot of victims.
We've got
16 critical patients,
24 stable,
and a dozen more
treated and released.
We've got the doctors'
lounge and the cafeteria
open and running
for the overflow.
What about fatalities?
We've taken three
down to the morgue.
We have two DOAs,
and one more that we weren't
able to resuscitate.
Good work keeping
the trains running.
Let me know
if anything changes.
Will do.
Mags.
Yeah?
The burn patient
we just brought in.
Early 20s, Latina,
no ID, and no family.
Can we make some calls
on a Jane Doe?
Yeah, I'll put out a bulletin
and see what I can find out.
Thanks.
Dr. Halstead, you got that?
Dad?
He was talking
just a minute ago.
No pulse. Bag him.
Wait, he's your dad.
Shouldn't another
doctor run the code?
You got one handy?
What's going on?
He's in V-fib.
Charge to 200
and give me the paddles.
Clear.
Still no pulse.
Push a milligram of epi.
Got it.
Will?
Charge to 200.
Charging.
Clear.
Nothing.
Another milligram of epi.
Yep.
Hi.
Good news.
An operating room
has opened up.
We'll be able to take
your daughter upstairs
for burn surgery.
And to repair
her carotid artery.
No. Please stop.
No treatments,
no surgeries.
What?
We don't want any surgeries.
I don't understand.
But if we don't take Blair
up to the OR now,
she won't survive.
My wife and I have
talked about it.
Blair wouldn't want this.
But with proper treatment
she could still have a life.
Look at her.
What kind of life?
These last few years
have been so hard for Blair.
She struggled with
body issues, bullying.
Just recently she was able
to lose weight,
change schools, and...
She finally felt good
about herself.
And now this.
Everything she's
been through...
We can't do this to her.
But people react
differently to trauma.
You don't know.
Surviving this might
actually make your
daughter more resilient.
We know our little girl.
Mr. and Mrs. Scott...
No.
We have to let her go.
Dr. Manning should be clear
about the parents' wishes
before calling me
in to consult.
It was a waste of my time.
I'm sorry?
They're withholding treatment.
How long before you
restored sinus rhythm?
He was down
around five minutes.
Well, that's consistent
with what I'm seeing.
Almost no EEG waveforms.
What does that mean?
You want to tell him?
Are we not seeing
some brain activity?
Artifacts.
Distortion, interference.
Dust on the window.
Okay, I am...
I'm not following.
Your father is brain-dead.
So he's just
not coming back?
Like, you... What,
you're saying that there's...
There's no chance?
If I had to calculate
the odds,
I'd say
1,000 to one against.
This vent could be
put to better use.
What?
Are you serious?
Jay.
The hell is wrong
with you, man?
Are you kidding me?
We'll talk about it.
Thanks, Sam.
She's lost
a significant
amount of blood.
Unfortunately,
the only way
we can be sure
to completely
stop her bleed
is to remove
her entire lung.
What?
Yeah.
Kelly, it's the best chance
we have of saving
Stella's life.
She can't be a firefighter
if she only has one lung.
There's gotta be something
else you can do.
April?
What if we tried ECMO?
It would rest her lung
so we have enough time
to locate the bleed...
No.
We'd have to give her
anti-coagulants to keep
the lines open.
It would make her
bleed even worse.
Isn't it worth a shot?
She's too unstable.
Believe me, Kelly, this is
the best course of action.
Sounds to me like
you've thrown in the towel
before you even tried
to save her lung.
Being a firefighter
is the only thing
Stella cares about.
I'm not gonna let you do it.
I'm sorry.
But it's not up to you.
We haven't been able
to reach her family
so it's our decision.
Get her upstairs.
I won't let you do this.
Kelly, please.
No. No.
Kelly, you have to let me...
No!
Get off! Hey!
Security!
Whoa,
whoa! Ethan?
No!
Kelly...
Come on!
Ethan...
Please escort this man out.
Ethan.
Sir, come with us.
Don't... Don't touch me.
I'm sorry, Kelly.
Don't do this.
Please, sir.
Excuse me.
I was at the fire
and I thought I was fine,
but...
I have a headache now
and I'm feeling
a little dizzy.
Fill this out
and we'll get to you
as soon as we can.
I appreciate it.
Thank you.
Hey, Mags.
Yeah?
Any luck on ID'ing
my Jane Doe?
Nothing yet.
I don't like that guy, man.
I want a second opinion.
He's our top
neurosurgeon.
So all your degrees,
all that money,
all those years in school,
this is the best
you can do?
Jay, Dad almost died
two years ago.
He's been living
on borrowed time.
Abrams didn't say
Dad had no chance.
A thousand to one
is no chance.
You just want
to give up?
I'm trying to be realistic.
I've seen a lot of patients
in his condition.
There goes that doctor voice.
I'm sorry,
but I am a doctor.
Yeah, don't worry.
We got that message.
And Dad knew you thought
you were better than us.
We always came in second,
you weren't there,
and now you want to
decide what happens?
That is not true, Jay.
There you are.
Ms. Garrett,
this is my brother, Jay.
Yes.
I'm the hospital's C.O.O.
I heard about
your father.
I'm very sorry.
Thank you.
I want you
both to know
that there's no hurry
in making any decisions
about Mr. Halstead.
You have the full support
of this hospital.
And we will provide
your father with any
and all resources.
I appreciate that.
We take care of our own.
This...
Is my cell phone.
You call me
if you need anything.
It's decided.
We're not giving up.
Dr. Manning.
I have the consent form.
They're gonna
let her die.
I don't think
it's that simple.
You ready?
Mr. and Mrs. Scott,
per your request,
this form gives
the hospital consent
to remove Blair
from the ventilator.
I need you to sign it
in my presence.
You sure?
We'll leave you
with your daughter.
Kelly.
They shouldn't have
done that to you, man.
All I care about
is Stella.
She's lucky
to have you.
She loves
what she does, April.
It's her life.
They can't take
out her lung.
I get it.
But since we can't
reach her family,
it's up to the doctors
to make the decision.
But they don't know her.
There's nothing we can do?
Hey. There you are.
I just heard about your dad.
Are you okay?
Just hard to believe.
He was such a force.
How's Jay taking it?
Not good.
They're a lot alike.
Stubborn.
Gwen didn't help.
I mean, she said she would
use the hospital's resources
to keep Dad alive.
Really?
That doesn't
sound like her.
Yeah,
it surprised me too.
I love you.
Let me know if there's
anything I can do, okay?
Here are the ABG results
for Brian Zvonecek.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Dr. Charles.
Mr. Zvonecek.
When can I get out of here?
So here's the thing.
Your blood gas
shows low CO2,
low carboxyhemoglobin,
and normal oxygen.
That's good, right?
Well, what it means
is that you didn't have
an inhalation injury.
More than likely
you passed out because
you were hyperventilating.
Huh.
All the same,
I'm not sick.
Okay, but...
Why were you
hyperventilating?
And when we can't find
a physical reason,
more often than not it's...
You know, due to
an emotional reaction
to some sort of...
Wait, wait, wait.
Where you going?
What, PTSD?
I didn't use
that label.
I'm just saying
it would explain
the tachycardia,
the elevated
blood pressure...
No. No way.
You know, full disclosure,
I noticed a little hand
tremor earlier today.
But I told you, that
was my blood sugar.
Otis.
You were shot
earlier this year.
I mean, that alone,
it's gonna precipitate
a little
post-traumatic stress.
And that I can tell you
from personal experience.
And after what you went
through today, I mean,
why don't you let me
take you upstairs
for a quick evaluation?
No.
I get it.
You're a shrink,
so everybody you see
has got to have some sort
of mental problem, right?
But not me.
I feel great.
I'm trying to help you.
It's just been...
Dr. Rhodes.
Sorry, guys,
I gotta get scrubbed.
We just want to talk
to you about Stella.
Really, April?
Just hear them out.
We don't want you
to remove her lung.
There has to be
another option.
Look, guys,
I understand your concerns.
But as her doctors,
we've decided on the best
course of treatment,
and only Stella's family
can override that decision.
Dr. Rhodes.
We are her family.
That's true.
She'd tell you
the same thing, Doc.
Another walk-away.
There's another way.
What do you mean?
The majority
of lung bleeds
originate in
the lower lobes, right?
So?
So what if I clamp at the base
of the pulmonary artery?
Connor, you made
the right call.
We have a good
surgical plan.
But what if we resect
the lower lobe first.
If the bleeding stops,
we won't have to remove
the entire lung.
No, it's too risky.
But if it doesn't work,
we can still remove the lung.
After wasting precious time.
Have you forgotten we're
trying to save her life?
I think we can do that
and give her the life
that she wants.
She's a young woman.
She can find
another career.
I have to try.
I owe it to her.
I owe it to them.
Connor, being a firefighter
isn't gonna mean a damn thing
if Stella dies
on the table.
I can do it.
Don't... Connor!
Time, Dr. Rhodes.
Where are we?
I'm almost there,
but every time
the lung inflates
it obstructs my view.
Marty, can we deflate
the lung
any further?
No way.
I'm barely keeping her
oxygenated as it is.
Take it down
another 20%.
It's too risky.
I only need to reach
the lower lobe.
I'll find the bleed
and make my resection
before you know it.
Make it fast.
You're quite the patient
advocate today.
Did you do it for Stella
or for Kelly?
I've known him
since we were kids.
You didn't answer
the question.
I did it because
it was the right thing to do.
Marty?
BP's down to 88 systolic.
I'm close.
Let's hope so.
You are not going
to make it.
We have to open her up
and remove the lung.
BP's at 82.
Up her pressers.
Can't, I'm already maxed-out.
Connor, please.
Just give me a second.
The sats are at 78,
that's all she can tolerate.
I'm re-inflating the lung.
No, wait. There.
That's it.
That's the bleed.
You found it, but do you
have time to fix it?
What happened?
Her hand's ice-cold,
I can't get a pulse.
The forearm's tight.
She's got
compartment syndrome.
Get Maggie.
I told you to use
the Parkland formula.
You gave her
too much fluid.
No. I've been monitoring
her urine output.
Everything's been normal.
Then what's your explanation
for this?
What do you need?
Find us an OR,
this woman needs an
emergency fasciotomy.
I'll tell you right now
all the ORs are occupied.
You're gonna have to wait.
How long?
20 minutes?
We can't.
20 minutes, she'll end
up with an amputation.
Get me a soft tissue
tray and a scalpel.
We'll relieve
the pressure now.
Right here.
Prep the patient.
Come in.
Ms. Goodwin.
Oh, Dr. Halstead.
I'm very sorry
about your father.
Did you know?
Did I know what?
Gwen Garrett made a special
point of telling me and Jay
that there was no hurry
in taking my dad off the vent.
Okay?
My dad's chart. His bypass
surgery was 29 days ago.
Twenty-nine days ago.
I see.
I can't believe
the hospital would do this.
Not to me.
Not to my family.
Hey, Jay.
We gotta take Dad
off the vent.
What?
No, no, no. He...
I've been sitting with him
and he blinks his eyes.
And I grabbed his hand
and he squeezed my hand.
He squeezed my hand.
Those are just reflexes.
They don't mean anything.
I'm telling you, man,
he knows that I'm here.
He doesn't.
He can't.
We can't, he's...
He's gotta come back,
man, 'cause...
That can't be
the last conversation
I ever have with him.
Look, whatever regrets
you have,
you're not gonna
resolve them here.
You just gotta accept that.
Don't tell me
what I got to accept.
Jay, the reason Gwen
encouraged us to take
our time with Dad?
His bypass was
29 days ago.
If he dies
before 30 days are up,
regardless of why,
it's a fatality
for the hospital.
So what?
So Gwen's just trying
to keep Dad alive
for one more day
so the hospital
doesn't take the hit.
I get it.
You feel betrayed.
I don't care.
I care about Dad.
And you think
he'd want
to be kept alive
to buff some numbers?
You need to get out.
You got to get out, man.
They're using him.
That's your problem.
Jay, he's gone.
Doc, you okay?
You got my discharge?
Gotta be honest,
I'm just not comfortable
signing off on you
going back to work yet.
You're gonna
keep me from working.
Look, I'll make you a deal.
Commit to some therapy.
Twice a week.
Once a week.
You don't get it.
I can't be a firefighter
if I have PTSD.
What, you can't be
a firefighter
and have feelings?
Look, I have no problem
keeping this out of your chart
if that'll make
you feel better.
If I see a shrink,
people are gonna
find out.
I can't have that.
Tell me something.
When I asked you
to close your eyes
earlier today,
what did you see?
What'd you really see?
Otis, you can tell me.
Okay.
I had to get a mom
and a baby out
of the building.
I lost contact.
Told her not
to get in the elevator.
She got in the elevator.
The elevator got stuck.
When we finally
got the doors open...
There they were.
Burned alive.
Their faces were gone
but I knew it was them.
I can't get it
out of my head.
It's called
an intrusive memory.
I can help you with that.
Doc Charles...
It means life's not
a stroll across a meadow.
These things I see...
They're part of the job.
Every firefighter sees them.
We cope.
I'm out of here.
You want to destroy my life,
write whatever you want
in your chart.
Dr. Manning?
Yes.
We need you.
Veronica.
She's still breathing
on her own.
Yes. Her oxygen levels
are good.
It's been hours.
Her heart rhythm
is strong.
She's holding on.
She wants to live.
My little girl,
she wants to live.
And we were going
to let her go.
What do we do?
How can we help her?
She needs to go
to surgery right now.
Do it. Help her.
Tell the OR
we're coming up.
Scissors.
Okay, pressure's
been relieved,
but that's not fluid.
It's blood.
Her ulna's broken.
That's what caused
the bleeding.
Compartment syndrome
was caused by fractured
hematoma, not fluid.
It wasn't
your fault, Dr. Choi.
They found her
just outside the room
where the fire started,
so how would she
have broken her arm?
There's also
extensive bruising
around her ribs and pelvis.
This woman wasn't just burned.
She was beaten.
You guys put me
in a terrible position.
But we were able
to isolate the bleed,
and we only had to take out
a portion of her lung.
It was a thoracoscopic
procedure, minimally invasive.
That's all to say that...
She should be back
to work in no time.
Oh, my God.
Hey...
Dr. Rhodes...
You're the man.
Yeah, you guys are okay too.
Thanks.
Why don't you bring
Kelly back in?
Thanks, Doc.
You got it, bud.
You were extremely lucky,
you know that?
Extremely.
Kelly.
She's awake.
Wants to see you.
Stop.
I'm so glad you're back.
Of course.
Come here.
Hey.
You okay?
I could have been
a better son.
Could have been
a better brother.
Oh, Will...
Your dad knew
you loved him.
And so does Jay.
Oh, no.
I got it.
Here you go.
Thank you.
Sir,
can I help you?
My uncle was
in the building
with the fire.
I thought they might have
brought him here.
Okay, sir, so I'm gonna
need you to go back
into the waiting room
and give the nurse
your uncle's name.
She'll let you know
if your uncle was admitted.
All right.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Told you you were
going home, huh?
Dr. Choi discharged him?
No, I did.
Really?
Yeah.
He's in pretty good hands.
For now.
I'm sorry, Jay.
For everything.
For not being there
for you and Dad.
And for not giving
you space to grieve.
We'll keep him on the vent
as long as you want.
Who am I kidding, man?
I know
he's not coming back.
Let him go.
Just let him go.
Take these too.
Maggie?
Yeah.
What happened
to our Jane Doe?
Dr. Choi?
She turned off
the monitors.
She has serious
internal injuries.
If we don't find her soon,
she's gonna die.