There's this family in
Italy who never slept.
They suffered from a genetic disease
that kept them awake for months,
until their bodies
just shut down.
Even after all these years,
scientists still don't
really know why we sleep.
We just know we have to sleep.
Because without it, we
make poor decisions,
we say things we shouldn't.
And sometimes we see
things that aren't there.
What do we got?
MVC with abdominal trauma,
severely hypotensive
since he arrived.
FAST exam show fluid in
the right upper quadrant,
lots of it.
It's gonna be a long night.
Don't say that. I
haven't slept in 48 hours.
Thought I saw you
go home earlier.
You did. I got off
an 18-hour shift
to go home to find Zola,
who is boycotting sleep,
and Ellis, who had an earache.
By the time I got
the last one down,
I got the call. Where were you?
Four-hour lysis of adhesions.
Then a triple-A
ruptured in the ICU.
Pierce and I had to do a
balloon catheter bedside
- before rushing him to the OR.
- Oh, that sounds...
Then a GSW to the abdomen that
Edwards caught. A duodenal repair.
- How long have you been here?
- What day is it?
Scalpel.
How do you know when
you're too tired to operate?
Right about when you
make your first mistake.
I hate that answer.
You don't. You just keep going.
Don't love that one, either.
Okay, Edwards,
grab a hemostat to lift.
Dividing the fascia.
Okay, Edwards, get lap
pads in here. Get in there.
We got massive bleeding here.
Okay, we're gonna
need a Bookwalter now.
- Edwards, I can't see a thing.
- I'm trying.
Wipe.
- Got it, got it.
- Thank you.
Okay, let's get more
lap pads in there.
Let's bring in another suction, and
we are gonna need the cell saver.
Good evening, surgeons. I
heard we've got a good one.
I'm here to give you
another set of hands.
Yeah, we could use
it if you're available.
Available? I'm primed.
I napped all afternoon,
ate a balanced supper,
and just had a cup of coffee.
- Well, that's nice.
- Did you?
Someone tell me what
we've got on our table.
A mess, sir.
Grade four liver lac,
portal triad looks intact.
We've just packed
all four quadrants.
- Wow! That liver's...
- Destroyed. Like I said, a mess.
Okay, hematoma's
tracking into zone two.
Edwards, let's do a right
medial visceral rotation.
Got it. Medium clip, please.
How many units has he had?
We've gone through
at least a dozen.
He's bleeding out
everything we pour into him.
- Clamp.
- Okay, keep suctioning.
- Other lap.
- Retractor.
Suction right there.
- I need two more clamps.
- You know, back in the day,
I would always come
into the hospital overnight,
even if I wasn't on call.
That's when the most
interesting surgeries came in.
Best learning
opportunities, am I right?
Yeah. Yes, sir. Bovie up.
I'll never forget this case, back
when I was a second-year resident.
It was about 3:00
in the morning,
and I'd been on my
feet for about 42 hours.
Right angle.
This fella came into the ER
with terrible abdominal pains,
claimed that an alien baby
was inside, eating its way out.
That's funny. Dr. Grey,
do you see this?
This kidney's cracked in half.
Exactly. It was his kidney.
Well, a kidney stone. It
was the size of a coconut.
It was six hours in the OR.
This seems like a
grade four injury to me.
- Mm-hmm.
- Any way we can salvage it?
- No.
- Yes.
If someone could clarify...
Okay, it was the size of a
dinosaur egg. It almost glowed.
Actually, sir, I was
talking about this.
This liver is shredded.
We don't have the
time or the blood volume
to spend an hour
fixing a kidney.
We could better control
the extra blood loss
if we fix the kidney.
Well, there will be no blood
loss if we just take the kidney out.
I'm very happy to
keep discussing it,
but I really think a final
decision would be good.
- Take the kidney out.
- You know what, Grey?
- Let's hold on for a minute.
- Patient doesn't have a minute.
Should I clamp the hilum?
No, we're gonna do
a partial nephrectomy.
That would be useless.
- And why is that?
- What?
I wasn't asking for myself.
I was asking for
Edwards. Why is that?
What does Edwards
have to do with this?
Well, she's our resident here.
This is an excellent
teaching case,
and she'd benefit
if you'd elaborate.
It's fine, really.
Richard, please...
Now, look, you and Dr. Hunt
are chiefs of general
and trauma surgery.
If we don't make a decision,
we're gonna be here all night.
I'm going to repair
the kidney. Suture.
- Hunt!
- Now, look, you two
should want this resident
to learn from this patient.
Owen, if you do this,
Edwards is gonna
learn from this patient
when he's a cadaver in my lab.
Dr. Webber, I'm sorry.
- You're tired.
- No, it's not... It's just...
- Fine. Let's do the partial.
- Good.
Retractor.
- Edwards.
- Yes, sir?
Tell me about the patient.
Uh... Okay. He came
into the ER unconscious.
No, no. Tell me his name.
Well, he didn't have any ID,
so as of now he's John Doe.
The car sped up a freeway
ramp the wrong way,
smashed into another car.
One guy's in OR five, and
the other one's right here.
Do we have the reckless driver,
or do we have the
innocent victim?
We don't know.
So, we don't know if
this man had a family,
we don't know if he was
running from something,
and we don't know if he was
the good guy or the bad guy.
We know nothing.
What do we need to
know in order to do our jobs
and not simply be mechanics?
How are we... We're
not being mechanics!
You're treating this patient
like a sack of organs on a table!
Now, here's what we're gonna
do. We're gonna play a game.
And how is this the
best use of our energy?
Now, here's how we start.
This patient is no
longer John Doe.
- Who is he, then?
- Basin.
We make him someone.
Anyone we want.
- What is he doing?
- He likes to teach.
When he's pissed,
he really likes to teach.
- Surgicel snow, please.
All right, first things first.
We need a name. Who's got one?
Brandon.
All right, Brandon.
Now, who is he?
I think he's the guy in
IT who parks next to me.
Okay, is he a good
guy, someone we like?
I don't know.
We've never spoken.
Okay, well, then
pick someone else...
and make them someone good,
and they don't have to be a male.
All right. How about Joanie?
- Now, why Joanie?
- 'Cause you didn't like Brandon.
How about Gail?
Gail's nice.
Let's go with Gail.
She's 45... No.
She's 46.
What is it we like about
Gail? And be specific.
I mean, do not stop
until you picture this
woman on the table,
until you can truly see her.
Do not stop until we can hear
her voice, what she has to say.
Well, this is going to be fun.
So, who is Gail?
Why do we like her?
And why would we go to
such lengths to save her life?
Sorry, shouldn't we want to
save her even if we don't like her?
Yes, but let's make
it easier on ourselves.
I mean, we need to fill Gail in.
I mean, Really give her something
that we can sink our teeth into.
Does she have hobbies, or...
Or is she known for something?
Right lobe is still bleeding.
- Over here, too.
- Okay. Large clip.
Well, what if Gail
plays the cello?
Edwards?
Uh... Sure.
My mother forced me to learn.
Something about
learning an instrument
would help instill discipline.
Remove the top blades.
- What are you doing?
- Remove them. Scissors.
Pringle didn't make
a dent in the bleeding,
I'm gonna try and
create more exposure
with a subcostal... Ten blade.
That's what this guy needs is
more incisions to bleed from.
Okay, suction is
blocked. Fix it now.
Okay, what else? We
need to make Gail more real.
Okay, she plays the cello.
Someone answer
him. I'm too exhausted.
- You started it.
- You're the one who was...
Oh, my God.
Dr. Webber, I have
a question about Gail.
Okay, go ahead,
Edwards, and don't be shy.
Does Gail...
have a dog?
Excellent question, but no.
Gail doesn't have
time for a dog.
She's got two...
No, three young kids,
so her house is already mayhem.
- Three boys?
- No, no.
Two boys and a girl.
That's nice, right?
Hey, stop
terrorizing your sister!
- Don't make me come over there!
- Stop. Stop.
Hey! You're the
oldest, act like it!
Boy, you roll your eyes again,
I'm gonna shut 'em for good.
I imagine Gail's
work keeps her sane.
Does anyone have any idea
what she does for a living?
Maybe... she's an engineer?
Or something with
research, politics.
Maybe she's whatever
Dr. Webber says she is.
Gail dreams of being Principal
Cello for the Chicago Symphony.
She practices relentlessly
every morning and night.
But in between, she teaches
music to kids in the neighborhood,
and she helps lead the
local high school orchestra.
If you could just hear
this one student of mine
play Bach's "Sonata
Number One in G Minor,
"Fuga Allegro." She
learned it just like that.
- Pressure's dropping.
- It's gonna continue to drop.
He's still bleeding despite
any move we make.
We should just cut
our losses and stop.
Damage control?
We should just pack him up,
and when he's stronger we
can come back in and finish.
No, we're gonna concentrate
on the retrohepatic area.
We'll try and repair
the vascular injuries
- that are in there first.
- I agree with Hunt.
How do you expect
to even see anything
behind this liver
to get a clamp in?
Trust me, we close
and let the body heal.
Somebody call up to ICU and
let them know we're coming.
We should keep going in
here, try and repair the damage.
At this point, this
patient wouldn't survive
the elevator ride to the ICU.
Look at this liver.
At this point this patient
is not surviving anything!
So you wanna give up now?
Leave Gail to die
in a bed upstairs?
Is it better if Gail
dies on the table?
It's better if Gail lives.
- What if we call UNOS?
- Wait, really?
Wait. Can we list him for
an emergent liver transplant?
- No!
- Why not?
You know why not!
He'll be dead before
a liver even gets here.
And if he's not,
he'd be too unstable,
and he'd reject it immediately.
It would be a waste.
We'd be taking an
organ from a stable,
far better candidate
who could really use it.
Edwards. Tell me the indications
for an emergent
traumatic liver transplant.
Acute hepatic failure,
portal vein thrombosis,
uncontrollable hemorrhage.
Exactly.
And I don't remember
many case studies
of this procedure
being successful.
Which is why we're not doing it.
I disagree with your decision.
Well, I'm sorry, but...
- But what?
- But he's not your patient!
My hands are in his body.
I'd think that'd make him
as much my patient
as yours or Dr. Hunt's.
But it's still my call.
We've got three attendings
here, and a senior resident.
We need to discuss the options.
- No, we don't.
- Why not?
Because you also have
the chief of general surgery
in here, Dr. Webber,
and I outrank you.
Of course.
And I'm saying no.
We are not listing
him for a transplant,
and we're done talking about it.
Do you think you can
stop this retrohepatic bleed?
I can try.
Okay, if it doesn't
work, it's up to the ICU.
If you're not on board,
feel free to leave.
Okay, medium clips. Another one.
Another!
I mean, this isn't working.
The clips aren't even holding.
- Sure hope it was worth it.
- What?
Whatever this guy was doing
that put him on the road
in the middle of the night.
Well, maybe she
didn't have a choice.
"She"?
Oh, Gail. We're still playing.
Maybe money becomes tight,
She picks up
extra work at night.
Their father left for the war,
and I couldn't say no
when the boys wanted to go
to a science camp at the museum.
Or she takes her
shift in the evening
at a reception desk
at a nearby hotel.
It isn't all night,
but it's late enough.
- How much longer?
- I need more visualization.
Mobilize the liver
more anteriorly, please.
Yeah, on it.
- You know, this isn't working.
- Just give me a minute.
Hunt,
- why don't you take your turn?
- Excuse me?
Try the game. I mean,
turn John Doe into someone.
I'm not good at
making people up.
Sure you can think of someone.
Richard, I don't need to.
I operated on
hundreds of John Does
when I was in the army,
and I did just fine. Malleable.
Load of crap.
I call load of crap...
giant load of crap.
- On what?
- Whenever we had a John Doe,
first thing you would
do is yell at someone
to go find the patient's tags.
Yeah, 'cause I didn't want to
have to do all the paperwork.
- Uh-huh.
- Where the hell is that Rummel?
Maybe ask for it nicely
and someone
will bring it to you.
I already did, and I
shouldn't have to ask twice.
Dad would say that. Oh,
God! You turned into Dad!
That is a thing
anyone would say.
You got his nose and his chin and
his unreasonably high expectations
- of everyone around you...
- You know what?
That no one could
possibly live up to,
but not his beard.
His beard was good.
- Yours is just sad.
- My beard is fine.
Actually, I shaved this morn...
Why am I even explaining this to you?
Feel free to stop.
I need that Rummel
tourniquet now!
Screw it. I can't reach it.
Okay, I'm gonna open the chest.
- Scissors.
- What? Why?
Total hepatic
vascular isolation.
We're gonna completely stop
the blood supply to the liver,
find the source of the
bleeding, and then we'll repair it.
All right, that's smart.
That'll give you
infrapericardial control.
Cutting him from stem to
stern right now is reckless.
Just get control of the IVC
from above and below the liver
from the incision we've made!
Yeah, that is what the
textbooks would tell you to do,
but any trauma
surgeon will tell you
it will not work
without a sternotomy.
Edwards, it's all you.
Saw.
Doesn't have to
be pretty, just fast.
We're racing against
the clock here.
I'd love to know
what is so hilarious
when my patient
is fighting for his life!
"Trauma surgery is fast
and a race against time."
If it's a race, you're losing,
because you suture
like a dumb tortoise.
I like my sutures to hold.
Oh, and your beefy, fat
hands slow you down?
Do they have to special-order
those gloves for you?
I am trying to teach.
You've never supervised
trainees, so you don't get it.
Oh, I get it.
Enough to know that you don't
know what to do with your patient.
Am I right?
Why are you stopping?
I don't know if this is gonna
work. He's still bleeding.
I wanted to close, and you
said you could isolate the liver.
- I know, but...
- Then do it.
- What's wrong?
- Nothing.
- Stop.
- I'm not doing anything.
You're giving me
that look, I don't like it.
Mom does it, too.
- Well, you should call Mom more.
- Will you just go away?
You're the one that
brought me here,
and you usually only bring
me around when you feel guilty.
Why are you guilty, Eeyore?
- I am working.
- Is it Nathan?
You feel bad about
being nice to him lately.
- Nope.
- It's fine.
Well, I mean... it's not fine.
He cheated on
your little sister, but...
I don't feel guilty
about anything!
Oh, well, that's a first.
Well, something's wrong.
What is it, then?
- New wife isn't working out?
- I'm done talking to you.
You're not gonna choke
anybody again, are you?
Will you shut up? Shut
up for God's sakes.
Hunt!
Uh... Uh...
Suction's full.
Change it, please.
Obviously. She's
what's wrong with you!
No!
What happened?
- An affair?
- No, we're just friends.
Well...
- I like her.
- Yeah, well, good for you.
You should have married her.
- Then you'd have kids. I
didn't wanna marry her, okay?
I just... I wanted it... I'm trying
to save this guy's life here.
Who the hell is this guy anyway?
What does that matter?
Because I can see his
liver, or what's left of it.
You've really been throwing
out some bold moves.
You're monopolizing the OR,
you're wasting hospital
resources and personnel.
It's not a waste if
we save the patient.
Owen, why won't you call it?
You know where this is headed.
Because you don't stop, okay?
You don't stop until
you've got the final answer.
you've saved them, or...
you find out that they're...
That they're dead.
Owen.
This guy isn't me.
- Pressure's dropping.
- I know.
Surgicel, EVARREST.
Give him ten units of cryo.
I see bruising on
his neck and face.
Okay, let's pack him, get
ready to bring him upstairs.
- I miss you.
- No.
Cut it out. You have to focus.
You know what you have to do.
- DeBakey clamp.
- What are you doing?
Edwards, call UNOS.
Send them everything
we have on this patient.
- I'm sorry?
- What?
Go now!
- Owen...
- Webber's right.
Transplant's the only
way to save this patient.
I'm removing his liver.
It's only making him worse.
- Scissors.
- Do not make that cut!
Basin.
Clips, please. Boki.
We decided not to list him.
No, you did.
And we were never supposed
to take out the whole liver.
How the hell is the patient
supposed to survive without a liver?
His liver already wasn't
working in his body, Grey.
Removing it while we wait for a
match won't make much of a difference.
How do we know a match
is even gonna come through?
We don't,
but we're gonna do a portacaval
shunt to bypass the blood supply.
That should give
us an hour or so.
I imagine Gail is
pretty tough, right?
Gail is tough as nails,
on her feet 16 hours a day.
She wouldn't let up even
when the pain in her back
started keeping her up at night.
You know, I thought
it was my mattress.
The thing must have
been at least 15 years old,
so I replaced it, but...
that didn't help much.
She's one of those people
whose bag rattles all the time
because she carries around a
bottle of aspirin everywhere she goes.
We got bleeders.
When you said an hour, did
you mean a minute and a half?
- Hang two more units.
- UNOS has everything.
Okay, did they
agree to list him?
He's listed as 1A, and
he's a fairly easy match,
so fingers crossed. There's
blood in his ET tube and nares.
Check his coags and a D-dimer!
Also, the lab tech mentioned
his platelets were clumping,
so I was thinking...
Edwards, you were right.
Looks like he's in
DIC. Let's jump back in.
No, actually,
that's not what I...
The azygos is bleeding.
It can't be. I clamped it.
Well, it's bleeding again.
Must be coming
from his renal vein.
Let me see if I can
feel it from where I am,
got a better angle.
Something else might be going
on. There is blood in his urine too.
- And the neck bruises.
- They can't hear you.
If you want them to listen, like,
really listen, you gotta be louder.
Found it. It's small, but it's
definitely a venous bleed.
- Really? Is it the azygos?
- It is.
- I got it. Give me a tie.
- I got it.
- You don't trust me?
- Not really.
I did what was
best for the patient.
You lost your damn mind.
This tissue's falling
apart in my hands.
We'll clamp this, and then
I'm gonna secure it with a tie.
- Move your hands.
- Dr. Hunt.
Just a second, Edwards!
Just tell him! You
know what it is.
I don't think the patient's
decompensating because of DIC.
We spent months
reading about it.
- You know it. It's...
- It's his platelets.
We'll give him more.
No, the patient has
a platelet disorder.
There's this cool lab test
that helps prove the
platelets don't clump.
The lab already saw
abnormal findings,
they can confirm it
with the blood sample.
Okay, fine, fine.
For now, just get in
there with some suction,
so I can see what
I'm doing. Damn it!
It's too friable.
We need to take him up to ICU until
we find a more permanent solution.
That won't work!
According to chapter 21 of
Hemostasis and Thrombosis...
Hemostasis and Thrombosis.
Dr. Grey, if we close
him, he's gonna get worse.
Okay, push bicarb.
You know what
Nurse Paula would say.
Owen, he can't handle any more.
She'd yell, "If you got
something to say..."
- I think he can. I think...
- "...speak up!"
I think I'm gonna watch
you kill this patient.
Okay, stop, all of
you! Listen to me!
Something you needed to say?
Repairing the azygos
won't stop his bleeding at all.
And you can take him to the
ICU, but he's still deteriorating.
This patient has an
autoimmune disease,
specifically idiopathic
thrombocytopenic purpura.
- ITP is extremely rare.
- According to a study in Ku...
- Kuwait.
- Kuwait,
there's an incidence of 125 cases
per one million people per year.
It's more common than we think.
Edwards, the body is shutting
down because of the trauma.
- Talk fast.
- That is because
the trauma is the
only thing you see,
because trauma is all
that you are used to seeing.
I see a body that's attacking
itself from the inside,
and every time
we give him blood,
his body chews up the
platelets one by one.
It's like we're filling a
giant tank with a hole in it,
and the only thing
we need to do to stop it
is to give him steroids, a lot
of them as soon as possible.
- He doesn't have a liver.
- Thanks to you.
If we administer steroids,
then without being
able to metabolize,
- it could become toxic...
- And before you argue
about how risky it is,
let me just say, we
have very little time,
and you should listen to me,
because I know all about this stuff.
If I were on the table,
I'd want the risky thing.
- I'd want to survive.
- Yes.
Where did you
get all this again?
When you're stuck in a
bed for your whole childhood,
you kind of get obsessed
with the thing that put you there.
I read... a lot.
Good catch, Edwards.
Thank you.
Send up a blood sample and
give him a gram of prednisone.
This is a reach.
Then you and Webber
should be all over it.
And we'll need
some more platelets.
Dr. Grey, we might have an ID.
A woman came in, said her
husband was working late,
then he never came
home. She saw the news.
Go ahead.
He's in V-tach.
I mean, this really hurts.
This isn't normal, is it?
And it's not just my back.
I can barely get a pulse.
Push 300 of amiodarone.
Did we push the steroids?
It won't matter. It's
because of his liver,
or the fact that he
doesn't have one.
Okay, internal
paddles on standby.
Look, we still have time.
Go find out if he
belongs to them.
Something's wrong...
really wrong.
- He's in V-fib!
- Starting heart massage.
- Okay, internal paddles?
- Saline! Charge to 20.
Okay, clear.
- No change.
- Push one of epi. Let's charge to 30.
Clear!
Damn it! Push another epi.
It's him!
The wife confirmed
the ID from the photo.
- What's his name?
- Carl. Carl Henley.
Are we done with
Gail? Is Gail Carl now?
- Are there children?
- A little boy and a girl.
They're with her
downstairs in the lobby.
Okay, charge to 50!
Clear!
Still no pulse.
The shunt put too
much strain on his heart.
Liver's only been
out for 20 minutes.
The shunt will bypass
everything for at least an hour.
And then what? We
still have no donor.
Not to mention, Carl
probably has ITP.
And how was I
supposed to know that?
Edwards didn't have a
problem figuring it out.
Can Edwards not be involved?
Every step of the way, you
and Webber just took over.
- Grey, what is your problem?
- My problem?
Ever since I
walked into this OR,
you've been negative at every
step, shooting down every approach.
What do you think
I'm doing right now,
massaging this
heart for exercise?
Dr. Grey, you've been
doing that for a while.
- You want me to take over?
- No! Go again at 50.
Okay. Clear!
I've done everything I
can to keep Carl alive.
It's a miracle
he's come this far
considering the shape
he was in when he got here
and all these Hail Marys.
Since when have I
taught you to play it safe?
You taught me to do no harm.
Look, as long as Gail
is on this table, you'll...
Carl! His name is Carl.
Where is Mommy?
She's with the doctors, sweetie.
Is my daddy with them?
Let's just wait for your
mom to come back, okay?
Someone should
go talk to the family.
We're in the middle
of resuscitating him.
Someone needs to tell
them what's happening
and prepare them for
what's about to happen.
- We've got a rhythm!
- Will it last?
It's faint, but
it'll do for now.
Okay, let's close him
and rush him to the ICU.
- With no liver.
- It's our only option.
It's time to
compromise, for all of us.
Hey, guys. Hey.
Where's Daddy? Is he here?
Remember, Daddy was driving...
- in his car?
- Yeah, is he coming home soon?
No, he was in an accident.
Oh.
Well, is he hurt?
He was.
Are the doctors fixing
him? Is he going to surgery?
- He's hyperkalemic. Push calcium.
- And one amp of bicarb!
- How are his MAPs?
- Barely in the 50s.
No, they can't fix him.
Then you should go
in there and fix him.
- Zola...
- You fix everyone.
Zola, I can't fix him.
Why?
I can't fix him...
because...
Because no one can fix him...
Because he's dead, Zola.
Daddy died.
You didn't make Gail up.
You come up with
what you need to.
Whatever helps. An old patient.
"Someone good."
It's okay, son.
You were only ten years old.
There was nothing you could do.
My mother, she hated doctors.
Or at least that's
what she said.
You know, I think she
just didn't want to worry us.
We thought everything was fine.
Okay. Wound-vac, please.
She still taught music
classes every day,
yelled at us about our
homework, fixed us dinner.
We grew up listening to that
damn cello all day, every day.
She played it for hours...
Bach...
Vivaldi...
Elgar.
She would shut
the bedroom door...
and tell us not to knock
unless someone was
bleeding or something's on fire.
I hated it...
that constant drone
of classical music...
until one day it stopped.
The house was silent.
I missed it.
That's when I knew it
meant something was wrong.
What was wrong with her?
You're the doctor, you tell me.
Forty-six year-old woman,
backache, sudden weight loss,
fatigue...
Multiple myeloma?
Breast cancer?
Or... were there any
signs of jaundice?
Good question. Yes, there was.
Was it gallstones?
Did one of them get
trapped in her bile duct?
No.
It wasn't hepatitis, was it?
It was pancreatic cancer.
Stage three or four.
She had six months.
Pretty sure we're almost
done here if you need to take...
I'm fine.
We just need to finish
the... The closure.
The three of us can handle it.
Wait.
We should stop closing.
You've been pushing
to close him for hours.
I know, and now I'm
pushing to stay open
because I think we can
save him right here, right now.
Meredith, we've
tried everything.
We haven't tried
a liver transplant.
But we don't have a donor liver.
We have a liver there. Boki.
The right lobe is
completely destroyed.
We do a partial
liver transplant.
Look, we ditch the right
lobe, we repair the left,
and graft the remaining
vessels. It'll work.
But we couldn't repair
it inside of his body.
How are we gonna
do it on the outside?
The main damage was behind
it, where we couldn't reach it.
Now we have total
access. This'll work.
We've done liver autotransplants
with tumors, but with trauma?
It's risky. I've
never seen it done.
Because people give up
by now. It's a Hail Mary.
Hail Mary. Your turn.
Okay, great. Webber, you and I
are gonna go at that back table.
I need a scrub
nurse and irrigation.
And, Edwards, you and
Hunt are gonna go prep
for the anastomoses.
We gotta work really fast.
Nice save, Grey.
Should have
thought of it sooner.
All right, I'll get him up to ICU,
and... then I can update the family.
I can update the family.
Thank you, Edwards.
Thank you.
All right, let's go. Thank you.
Sorry... for things that I said.
It's okay.
No, it's not. You were right.
I was tired, but... I have
to learn to push past it.
And you did.
Have you always done
that with your mother?
I didn't used to.
Back then...
I was trained to
depersonalize the patient.
Tissue was tissue,
faces were covered,
and blood was a
mess on the floor.
We were to stay focused,
and our hands were
inside just mannequins.
So, what changed?
One afternoon, I was in the OR,
and we lost a patient on the table,
and I went along
to inform the family,
you know, tell them
the horrible news...
and I was numb.
I watched them sob
and hold each other and...
And it didn't
affect me... at all.
That patient died from the
same thing my mother died from...
and I was a robot.
After that...
I started changing the rules...
and it made me a better surgeon.
We've all hit that
point of exhaustion...
the point where nothing
makes sense anymore.
You've saved her now...
about 1,000 times.
I suppose.
Goodnight, Meredith.
Goodnight.
Your body hurts, your
brain becomes foggy,
and you feel like you're
trapped in a tunnel...
when all you want is your bed.
So... how do you keep going?
How do you not just
sit down and give up?
Sometimes it's easy.
Sometimes you play
games in your head.
You make up someone...
someone good.
Hi.
I'm sorry. I didn't think
anyone was in here.
Whatever you need...
It's all yours.
To keep you going.