I heard you and 2.0
are a match made in heaven.
Well, it's a remarkable
advancement.
We need an OR.
2.0 is open.
Better imaging's available.
Emergent trauma
is not the time to play
with your fancy toy.
Things haven't
been great between Ben and I.
I know it must be hard
not having him around.
Ben?
Sorry it took me
so long.
I probably shot up,
like, a half dozen times
during my first trimester.
Going cold turkey
is really hard.
I don't want anyone
taking my baby away.
Hello?
Hey. No, no, no, no.
Hey. What did I tell you?
Day or night.
Doesn't matter.
What's going on?
You're... you're having
an urge to use?
Uh-huh.
Okay. Can you
get yourself to Med?
I can pick you up.
Okay, great.
Okay. I'll meet you
in the ED.
Wow. So Ben moved
back home?
End of last week.
Wow. I'm so glad
to hear that.
It was like
this huge cloud
has just lifted.
I'll bet.
Thanks for being
a shoulder throughout
all this, Sharon.
Always.
The result of over
a decade's worth
of testing and research,
here at Gaffney Chicago
Medical Center.
They're doing
infomercials
for 2.0 now?
Jack Dayton insisted.
But I have
a budget meeting
to get to,
so enjoy the show.
I will.
Predict complications
before they happen,
generate highly accurate
imaging in real time.
The OR 2.0 is to surgery
what GPS was to travel.
Nitrazine swab.
I've noticed
more discharge.
And the baby doesn't
seem to be moving
around as much.
She usually
kicks up a storm.
I told Hannah
that she's gonna be
a flamenco dancer.
So you two
know each other?
Yeah, we go
to the same gym.
Okay.
So your water broke, Liza.
What?
But I'm not due for,
like, another week.
You see this?
When this touches
amniotic fluid,
it turns blue.
That also explains
why you stopped feeling
much movement.
After your water breaks,
the baby has less room
to wiggle around.
Is she gonna be okay?
Yes.
This just means we need
to get you upstairs
and give you medicine
to induce labor.
Can you let L&D
know Liza's coming up
and page Dr. Patchefsky?
Sure thing.
Thanks.
Dr. Patchefsky?
Mm-hmm
No, no, no.
I want you.
Well, Liza, I'm sorry,
but unfortunately,
I need to stay in the ED.
But hey, Dr. Patchefsky's
gonna take great care
of you and the baby.
You know me, Hannah.
You know my history.
I don't feel comfortable
with anybody else.
Please.
I can't do this
without you.
Okay.
Let me see
what I can figure out.
Dr. Marcel?
Yeah?
There's the movie star.
Oh, come on now.
Oh, can I get
your autograph?
Jack roped me into it.
Sure he did.
Need some help
over here!
Hey. What happened?
Rob here, he was working
a circular saw, and...
He was slicing
some sheet metal.
He cut himself.
Follow me.
Number three's open.
How long ago
did this happen?
Not exactly sure.
I found Rob by the machine
about 20 minutes ago.
He was just lying
in a pool
of his own blood.
Let's get him up.
We were working
at a job site
around the corner.
We just thought
it'd be fastest
to bring him ourselves.
Okay. Mag?
Yes.
Gentlemen.
Why don't I show you
where the waiting room is at?
Dr. Marcel will update you
as soon as possible.
Wait, wait.
What do I do
with this?
Dr. Marcel?
Yeah?
We do the right thing?
Thought you're supposed
to put it on ice.
Yes, you did
the right thing.
Thank you.
Thank you, gentlemen.
It's okay.
I got you, bud.
Well, Liza doesn't
have a primary OB,
but I've seen her in the ED
throughout her pregnancy
for various complaints.
Uh, Doris, room seven.
There's a hypochondriac
with a hangnail.
So get an intern on it?
Yeah, read my mind.
Dr. Hudgins,
you're needed in
treatment seven.
I'm sorry.
You were saying?
My patient, Liza Martin,
doesn't have a primary OB.
Okay. Yeah,
I heard all this.
What's the ask?
I'd like to follow her
upstairs and deliver her.
You're my only OB
in the ED.
I can come back and forth
while she's in early labor.
And I'm also just
an elevator ride away
in case something urgent
comes up.
But I'm Liza's
only continuity, so...
You know,
she's comfortable
with me.
We go back a ways.
Yeah. Okay, go ahead.
Really?
Yeah, just don't
dillydally.
Yes, sir.
As you know, we have
a seat opening up
on the board.
Oh, did you get
a chance to review
my nominee?
I sent her CV around.
Sorry. Remind me
the candidate's...
Gloria Jeffers.
She's chaired
the fundraising committee
for eight years.
She volunteers
here regularly.
She brings a lot
of donors to Med.
Well, sounds like
a strong candidate.
She is.
Now, are you familiar
with Dr. George Thomas?
Well, the name
rings a bell,
but I'm not placing it
right offhand.
Well, George
is a close friend,
a renowned urologist,
and a former Wisconsin
state legislator.
Now, he's mostly retired
but still lobbies for some
biotech companies part-time.
I think that
his connections could be
very advantageous for us.
While my nominee
is just simply
a devoted volunteer?
Look, Sharon,
I'm not gonna try to make
you into a turncoat,
but take a lunch
with George?
Of course.
Just give his information
to my assistant,
and we'll get something
on the books.
Well, I hope you don't mind,
but I already took the liberty
of talking
with your assistant,
and it turns out
you're free
for lunch today.
What are you saying?
And as luck
would have it,
so is George.
Is that right?
Hmm.
1:00 in the executive
dining room?
And I assume
you'll be joining us?
Oh, listen, I wish I could,
but I am slammed
with meetings today.
Hmm.
I'll be sure to check in
afterwards, though.
You know, Sharon,
I really think you two
are gonna hit it off.
You just hang in there.
And I'll get you
an update soon, okay?
All right.
That was
Rob's wife, Louisa.
Was getting her
up to speed.
What are the odds
that he'll keep his hand?
Not good.
Immediate replantation
is impossible.
Too much contamination?
Yeah, well,
the proximal stump's
gonna need at least
a week of daily debridement
just to get it cleaned up.
Real shame too.
What do you mean?
'Cause the hand's
actually in good shape,
all things considered.
I'll bet it's salvageable.
Maximum six hours
without blood flow, and...
Hand's gonna die.
Yeah.
But what about
putting it on
a perfusion pump,
like you would with
a heart and lungs?
Well, it's a good thought,
but...
That won't buy us
more than a day.
If only we could find a way
to perfuse the hand long-term.
Well, but like you said,
it's a shame.
Jackie, going to
treatment four.
Got it. This is
Isaac Collins.
53-year-old male.
Motor vehicle collision.
Ambulatory at the scene,
refused board and collar.
He was rear-ended.
My fault, though.
Facial bruising's
from the airbag.
I switched lanes
without signaling,
then jammed on the brakes
to make a turn.
It was a bonehead move.
Luckily, the other guy's
all right.
Glad to hear it.
I'm Dr. Halstead,
by the way. Vitals?
Blood pressure's
a little high, 150/97.
I'm always hypertensive,
especially when I'm due
for dialysis.
I've got end-stage
renal disease.
I appreciate you
letting me know.
On my count, folks.
One, two, three.
Thanks, guys.
I see you've got a fistula.
Yeah, I've been through
a few of 'em.
Going on five years
of dialysis.
Dr. Cuevas.
Isaac.
Dr. Jones told me
the good news.
I was hoping
I would see you today,
but not in the ED.
What happened?
She's my shrink.
I'm actually not, Isaac.
Do you mind if I disclose
to Dr. Halstead how
we know each other?
My wife, Samantha,
and I attend Dr. Cuevas's
support group.
For patients and families
living with chronic illness.
Which, by tomorrow,
won't be us anymore,
which leads me as to why
I was driving like a maniac.
I got the call.
I'm getting a new kidney.
Congratulations.
Anyways, you can see
I couldn't wait to get
to the hospital fast enough.
But I'm... I'm fine.
Like I told the paramedics,
nothing feels broken.
Now, when you say
nothing feels broken,
anything feel tender?
No, I'm good, really.
You know, Isaac,
when I spoke to Dr. Jones,
he said that the organ
wouldn't even be here
for several hours.
There's no rush.
Why don't you
let Dr. Halstead
check you out properly?
Neck and back's
a little sore, I guess,
but it's really
not that bad.
I just don't want anything
to mess up the surgery.
Well, even if you have
a sprain or a minor fracture,
it shouldn't postpone
the transplant.
But better Dr. Jones
and his surgical team know.
That way, they can
avoid aggravating
any injury further.
All right.
Yeah, makes sense.
Let's get a CT
of the CTLS spine.
Sorry I keep you waiting.
Mmm.
I was talking
with my friend.
No prob.
Chamomile tea,
blueberry muffin,
chocolate croissant.
You're very sweet,
but I can't eat.
My stomach is in knots.
What's up?
My friend thinks we may
be out of work very soon.
What?
Is this about your
union's renegotiation
with the hospital?
Yeah.
Well, I knew they were
trying to iron out
a new contract,
but I mean, honestly,
I haven't been paying
that close attention.
She says talks
are breaking down,
that neither side
will budge,
and the union
may ask for a vote.
A strike
authorization vote?
If I miss work for weeks,
even for days,
this is not good.
I send money
home to my parents.
But I mean,
even if a vote passes,
that doesn't mean
they're gonna strike.
It's just...
It just gives them more
ammunition when they
go back to the table.
These things, you know,
tend to take time.
You've got to
let it play out.
I'm guessing they're gonna
make a deal.
I think
it's gonna be okay.
She just started having
fetal heart rate decelerations
with tetanic contractions.
I turned down the Pit.
Hannah,
it hurts so much.
Okay, stop the Pitocin.
Liza, we're gonna
see if it's time
to push yet, okay?
Can you bend
your knees for me?
I'm gonna check you out.
Okay, you're only about
six centimeters dilated.
What?
We need to get you
onto your hands and knees
to let us help you
turn you over, okay?
What's going on?
What's wrong?
Your umbilical cord is
being squeezed somewhere.
That's what's causing
the baby's heart rate
to drop.
Moving positions can help
relieve the compression.
I know. I know.
All right. I'm gonna
check you out.
Uterus is still rock hard.
Let's give her 0.25
of terbutaline, sub-q.
Liza, you can lie
back down now, okay?
Gently.
Gentle.
We're trying
a uterine relaxant.
Now, if this doesn't work,
we're gonna need to deliver
your baby via C-section.
Let's get an OR ready.
No, I don't want that.
It's okay. Just one
step at a time.
Let's first see
if this medicine works, okay?
Baby's heart rate's
coming up.
That's really good.
Give it about
a half hour,
and restart
the Pitocin slowly.
Mm-hmm.
But let's keep
an OR ready.
If the baby's heart rate
drops like that, I'm doing
an emergency C-section.
So you want to surgically
attach Rob's hand
to the back of his leg?
It's called ectopic banking.
You see, what the hand
needs in order to survive
is adequate blood flow.
And his leg
can provide that?
The posterior tibial artery,
to be exact.
The PTA, it runs along
the back of the lower leg.
So you'd bank my hand
on my leg for a week or so?
That's right.
And then
you'll reattach it
to my arm, right?
More than just
reattach it.
Using the OR 2.0,
I believe that
we can restore
a remarkable amount
of function and feeling.
So I can keep working
construction?
Yeah.
I gotta be able to feel,
or I'm a liability on
a construction site.
Yeah, of course.
Okay, so, uh...
Well, 2.0's predictive
modeling estimated a...
85% likelihood of regaining
some or more sensation
in the hand.
And that's after many,
many months of physical
therapy and rehab.
Right, Dr. Marcel?
Maggie's correct.
Yeah, it's gonna be
a long road ahead, for sure.
And that's if you decide
to go with the surgery.
There's other options,
of course.
There's been incredible
advancements in prosthetics.
And that's if this
banking thing doesn't work?
Then we can
talk prosthetics.
But I want
to give this a shot.
You've got this, Liza.
Keep going.
Why isn't she coming?
Just do the C-section.
It's too late for that.
Please.
I know you're exhausted,
but you've got this, Liza.
So when I count to three,
I need you to give me
everything you've got, okay?
This is it. Look at me.
One, two, three.
Yes! Yes!
You did it, Liza!
Is she okay?
Yes.
Oh, hi.
Isn't she beautiful?
She's perfect.
I think
she needs something.
Can you check her again?
No, she's fine.
It's okay.
Crying helps the fluid
get out of her lungs.
But she won't stop.
It's okay.
The longer
she's on your chest,
the more she'll calm down.
Please, just take her.
It's a really
good idea... Okay.
Please just take her!
Here we go. Okay.
Shh...
I'm sorry.
I'm just...
I'm so tired.
Of course. You just
ran a marathon.
Okay. We'll get the baby
up to the nursery and let you
sleep a bit, okay?
It's okay, baby girl.
Just rest, okay?
Got Isaac's CT back.
He's got a compression
fracture at L2.
Well, that's unfortunate.
But like you said, it won't
delay the transplant, right?
Well, take a look.
I could be wrong,
but the bone
around the fracture
has a lytic appearance
to me.
Do you think Isaac
has cancer?
I think
there's a possibility.
Lytic lesions are commonly
associated with metastases.
And if the bone
was already damaged
from cancer,
well, even a minor trauma
could cause a fracture.
Okay, but you're not sure
that it's lytic, right?
There's still a chance
it could just be a traumatic
compression fracture?
Which is why I want
to get an MRI.
It'll show us if there are
other lesions and just
give us a better idea
if it's traumatic
or pathological.
And if it is pathological,
that means a biopsy.
And Isaac is definitely
not getting a kidney today.
No.
I wish Samantha was here,
his wife.
Where is she?
On a flight to Seattle
for their granddaughter's
first birthday.
Isaac got tired
of both of them missing out
on milestones.
But one time she goes out
of town, he gets the call.
You mind delivering
the news with me?
In her absence,
I think a familiar face
might be comforting.
Yeah, of course.
All right.
Hey.
You got a second?
Yep.
Uh, okay...
Is this operation
really worth the risk?
If anything
compromises blood flow
to the hand or the foot,
Rob could develop
an infection
and become septic.
The 2.0 will be
assessing blood flow
every step of the surgery
as well as predicting
if perfusion can be
maintained post-op.
Okay, clearly, you know
this technology
inside and out,
but it's also never been used
for this type of procedure.
So what are you saying?
What, I oversold Rob?
No, but I think
that you've got
a lot invested in 2.0,
and maybe you feel
a certain pressure
to use it.
I'm not gonna gamble
with a patient's life
just so I can show off
my shiny, new toy, Maggie.
Of course not.
I'm just saying that...
Crockett!
Here's the man
I'm looking for.
Anything else?
I didn't mean to chase
Nurse Lockwood away.
No, she had to get back
to the ED. What's up?
Dr. Song briefed me
on the ectopic banking case.
Very impressive.
Yeah.
And my videographer's
gonna film it.
We'll want to document it
and get as much
press as possible.
Jack, I don't want anybody
in there taking pictures
while I'm in the middle
of a complex surgery.
You won't even know
he's there.
I'll keep him out
of your way, I promise.
See you
in the amphitheater?
Yeah, right behind you.
Okay.
Hey.
Hey. Hope you're not
in any kind of hurry.
Elevators taking
their sweet time today.
I am fine.
I'm not exactly anxious
to get where I'm going.
Meeting with a friend
of Jack's
whose seat on the board
is all but assured.
Man, hospital politics.
Yikes!
Mm-hmm.
Speaking of which,
what are you hearing
about what's going on
with the negotiations
with the custodial
workers' union?
Liliana seems to think
they're getting all tense.
Between us, I don't...
I don't foresee a strike.
That's what I told her.
Yeah.
A strike would wreak havoc
on the hospital system.
I gotta say, though,
it does make me wonder
why we can't give
our lowest paid employees,
I mean, even a 6% raise.
Well, it would be
setting a precedent
that we can't afford to make
with the other unions, Daniel.
I mean, once we finish
with these negotiations,
we go into talks
with the nurses' union.
And then,
it's the plumbers' union.
I mean, you get
the picture, right?
If I had just checked
my blind spot,
we wouldn't be talking
about an MRI right now.
I'd be upstairs
getting prepped for surgery
tonight, right?
And that still might happen.
Yeah, I'm sorry, Isaac.
I could not have predicted
the CT would reveal this.
Dr. Halstead,
I've waited five hellish
years for a kidney.
I've blown out
so many veins,
they're running out
of access sites
to even deliver my dialysis.
If the fracture looks like
it's just from the accident...
Well, that's still
a possibility, but...
Then that's good enough
for me.
I'm not gonna fault you
for not running
any more tests.
And no one else
will either.
Please, I'm begging you.
Hey. I thought
you delivered
your patient.
I did, yes.
Well, why are you
still up here?
We need an OB consult
in the ED.
Okay, I can head back down
with you right now.
Just give me one sec
to let Liza know.
Okay.
Oh, hey.
Where's Liza?
Yeah, she... She, uh,
she had to use the bathroom.
I'm Mike.
I'm her boyfriend.
It's not safe for her
to use the restroom alone.
She seemed
all right to me.
Hey, Liza, it's Hannah.
Are you okay?
Give her a minute,
will you?
Get your hands off of me.
Get your hands off me!
Hey, you heard her!
Liza.
Help me get her
back into bed.
Okay. Watch her neck.
Support her head.
Yeah, we got her.
You have no idea how hard
Liza worked to stay sober.
You have no idea.
Well, I don't doubt that.
But we just found her
strung out on heroin.
She was overwhelmed
and exhausted
after a grueling labor
and had a serious
lapse of judgment,
but I know
that she could
get back on track.
Hold it. Wait, you're not
actually suggesting
that we send a baby home
with that woman?
No, of course not.
I want to find a sober
living situation for Liza,
a facility where she could
still receive treatment
while still caring
for her baby.
You are swerving
so far out of your lane,
not to mention
that you are mandated
to report this...
No, not until...
To, yes,
the appropriate
department.
Not until I figure out
a way to keep Liza
and her baby together.
Then you let DCFS
take care of it.
They're far
better equipped.
What if they can't, huh?
Liza doesn't have family
in the area. Who's gonna
take the baby?
Obviously, you care
a great deal about her.
Because I am her.
I have been her.
And the only reason
that I'm standing here
right now
is because people
didn't give up on me.
So I am not giving up
on Liza.
You have till
the end of the day.
Okay.
Dr. Song,
what's the recommendation
for anastomosis?
Any deviations
from the plan?
End to end ulnar
to posterior tibial artery
anastomosis.
Okay. What's the venous
drainage?
Anastomose the main dorsal
vein to the saphenous vein.
Okay, great.
Whoever that belongs to,
turn it off right now.
Sorry, that's me.
It's my next meeting.
This is Jack Dayton.
Great. Well...
Do you mind moving
to the right just a hair?
It'll give me
a much cleaner shot.
No, that's where
he needs to stand.
Let's keep noise down
to a minimum
from here on out, folks.
In terms of speed
and efficiency,
you're already performing
above and beyond
2.0's predictions.
We're on a good trajectory.
All right.
Let's say we forgo the MRI.
He gets the transplant.
If it turns out
he does have cancer,
the immunosuppressants
he'll be on could interfere
with his cancer treatment.
And the treatment itself
could destroy his new kidney.
Valid concerns, yes.
But a malignancy of any kind
is a contraindication
for transplantation.
He'll be taken off
the transplant list.
Right, which is...
All the more reason
to look the other way?
I have an ethical
and legal obligation
to disclose this finding.
I fail to do that,
it could compromise
our status
as a high volume
transplant center.
I know it's a risk,
but, Will,
this could be Isaac's
only shot at a kidney.
I hear you. I know.
But it'd be irresponsible
to let the transplant proceed
until we know more.
I'm sorry, Nellie.
What, did Jack steamroll you
into having lunch with me?
What? Uh, no.
No, not at all.
Jack's a good friend,
but when he wants something,
he can be like a dog
after a bone.
Yeah, well, that has been
my impression as well.
Yeah, but in his defense,
he's trying to do me a solid
'cause he knows
how eager
I want to be a part
of Med's board.
Well, I'm curious.
How did a former legislator
turned lobbyist become...
Girl, what did he do,
tell you about
my whole side hustle?
Look.
That's what my daughter
calls it.
Mmm.
Listen.
I'm not trying to be
a part of your board
so I can be
a mouthpiece for some
special interest groups.
So why do you want
to be on the board?
To start with,
I was born
in this hospital.
Get out. You're kidding.
No, ma'am.
I'ma be honest with you,
my very first broken arm
was fixed right
within these walls.
So this is a homecoming
of sorts?
Well, my ex-wife
was a professor
at UW Milwaukee.
We raised
the family there.
But Chicago's home.
And this hospital
has always held a very
special place in my heart.
I'd love to be a part
of its future.
But I should warn you,
I'm not one of those
board members
that's only gonna show up
at special fancy parties,
cut a check, and is
never heard from again.
Yes, I know
that type as well.
I got a lot of time
on my hands.
And I also
have a lot of ideas.
I'm all ears.
Oh, hey, Hannah.
I'm glad I caught you.
Would you mind pointing me
to one of your patients?
It's a Liza... Sorry.
Uh, I think that
there's been a mix-up.
I didn't make
a call to DCFS.
Well, I actually wasn't told
who made the call,
just that an eval
was requested.
Well, that's definitely
an error.
Oh, uh, okay.
I'm sorry
you had to come down.
I'm the treating physician,
and that patient
doesn't need an evaluation.
Uh, okay.
Well, in that case,
I guess I'll just head
back up to my office.
Yeah.
What were the patient's
vitals on intake?
Let me check.
Well, you should
have this on the tip
of your tongue.
Hey, I told you
I was working on it.
You had no right
to make that call.
Give us the room, please.
I'll check back
later, yeah.
Okay, you do not
dress me down ever,
and definitely not
in front of a resident.
I repeat, you had no right
to make that call.
The hell are you
talking about?
You called DCFS on Liza.
No, I did not.
Hannah, I'm serious!
Well, then who did?
Okay.
I'm gonna remove
the clamp.
Nice and easy. Okay.
Lap pad.
Yeah, the ulnar side's
showing some good perfusion.
But yeah, there's not
enough circulation
through the palmar arch.
And the radial side's
looking dusky to me.
Could we hook in
the radial artery
to something,
give it
independent inflow?
I'll have 2.0 run
through the iterations.
It's assessing a number
of variables.
It probably just
needs a minute.
Not enough information.
Confidence interval
is too low.
I think it just needs better
mapping of the radial artery
in the palmar arch.
Let me see if I can
recalibrate imaging.
Not enough information.
Confidence interval
is too low.
Unfortunately,
the real-time data
is insufficient.
And the pre-op imaging
is inadequate.
What other artery
am I gonna use
to plug into the radial?
Without adequate blood flow,
the hand's not gonna survive.
I'm afraid 2.0 doesn't
have enough data
to offer recommendation.
There's just not enough
published literature
to draw from.
So what am I supposed
to do here?
Use your best
critical judgment.
Oh. Of course.
I'm not getting the MRI,
not till after
the transplant.
How about that?
I refuse.
Dr. Jones won't proceed
with the surgery until he sees
the results of an MRI.
You had no right
to tell him anything.
Isaac, I had
an ethical duty
to notify your
transplant surgeon...
I should have just
stuck to my story
and told you I felt fine.
Never should have
mentioned any pain.
Isaac, I know
this is upsetting...
Just do the damn
MRI already!
Get me Dr. Jones!
Okay, he'll be
here shortly.
I'll put in the order.
So you requested DCFS
be called?
Liza, why?
When I held my little girl
for the first time,
I could feel her
depending on me,
needing me
for everything.
I couldn't take it.
I broke.
Liza...
These last few months
have been the hardest
of my life.
And it took everything
in me to stay sober,
but I did it for her.
And now, I just...
I can't muscle my way
through this.
Okay, I've been there.
Every time I got sober
for someone else,
a family member,
a partner,
it lasted a year
at the most.
Every time, I'd relapse.
It finally stuck
when I got sober
for myself.
Care for dessert?
Coffee or espresso?
No, thanks.
None for me.
Thank you.
Oh, my goodness.
It's almost 3:00.
I really hate
to cut this off,
but unfortunately...
The place
won't run itself.
Uh, not yet, although Jack
is working on it.
Yeah, I imagine
he would be.
Well, this has been quite
a productive conversation.
Well, you know,
we can always continue
the conversation.
Should you join the board?
Thank you.
Is that your
more subtle way
of asking if I'm gonna
support your nomination?
No, ma'am.
That's my very
unsubtle way
of asking you
if you'll join me
for drinks tonight.
Oh.
Well, that's a very
tempting idea,
but, um,
I'm gonna have to...
Politely decline.
Politely.
Well, I appreciate you
considering it.
I hope the rest of your day
goes easy on you.
And the same for you,
Dr. Thomas.
Ah. George.
Sharon.
You're back.
I am.
And I could use
your expertise.
Tell me.
How do you calm
your nerves
when your heart
is beating very fast?
Well, um, the first thing
you do is you sit down.
And, um, just take
a couple deep breaths,
and well, tell me
what's going on.
I'm nervous because
I'm going to speak
with a reporter
from Tribune tomorrow.
Our union boss, Mr. Wilson,
he's meeting me to prepare.
Wow. How did
that come about?
You remember my friend
I was telling you about
from this morning?
Yeah.
She's told Mr. Wilson
about me.
And he asked me
to go on record
for a story the newspaper
is writing
about the negotiations,
what's at stake for us.
I wonder if that's really
the best tactic
for the union
to take right now,
to talk to the press
while negotiations
are still ongoing.
I mean, it could be seen
as a bad faith move.
And honestly, Liliana,
I would be worried
about possible
personal repercussions
for you.
Yeah, that's what
I thought first too,
that it would fan flames,
cause more harm
than good.
Exactly.
But my friend, she tells me
Mr. Wilson tells her this:
the hospital
is flying in workers
from all over
to replace us.
They're flying in scabs?
They're putting them
in hotels and everything.
That's why I said
I would go on record.
Hey, Sharon.
Yeah?
George has been
blowing up my phone.
He was eager before,
but now he's ready
to go to the mat
for this board seat.
Well, I will say
he's a very
appealing candidate.
I still think Gloria Jeffers
would make an exceptional
board member,
but I'm glad you brought
Dr. Thomas to my attention.
So you'll support
his candidacy?
I won't challenge it.
Hmm.
You know, not to gloat,
but, I told you, didn't I?
Sounds like
gloating to me.
Sharon, hospital's
negotiating with
scare tactics now?
They're flying in scabs?
Yeah.
I... I don't like it either,
but it's also
a necessary precaution.
Did you know about this
when we were talking
this morning?
I mean, I thought you
told me that the negotiation
was going well.
No, what I said
was that I didn't
foresee a strike.
But look, we still
have to be prepared
for the possibility
of a work stoppage, Daniel.
I mean, anything less
is negligence.
What I'd say to the board
is I'd say, look, isn't a 6%
bump for a custodian
a fraction of what
it would be for a nurses?
Daniel, I don't ever tell you
how to do your job.
And I'm not telling you
how to do yours.
I'm telling you people
are scared
'cause they can't afford
to miss a paycheck.
Yeah, and that's
the last thing I want.
That's why I'm trying
to do everything in my power
to avert a strike.
I can't give you all
of the details.
I expect you,
of all people,
to trust that.
Get the MRI back?
Yes, and it showed evidence
of a pathological fracture.
When are they doing
the biopsy?
Tomorrow morning,
but Dr. Jones
ordered an SPEP
and a UPEP after
he saw the MRI,
and both blood tests
came back positive.
Multiple myeloma.
In all likelihood, yes.
Isaac hasn't been told yet.
Dr. Jones wanted to wait
until it was confirmed
by the biopsy.
Just this morning,
Isaac thought his luck
was changing,
he was finally getting
a new kidney.
And now,
he's potentially facing
a terminal cancer.
Or maybe not.
Maybe, thanks to
your diligence,
we caught it early.
Maybe that MRI
just saved his life.
Hey.
I spoke to Dr. Song.
She said the surgery
went well
and Rob's hand has
excellent blood flow
and venous return.
Yeah, things are looking
all right.
I had a moment in there.
It's like I didn't know
how to trust my own judgment,
mostly 'cause I haven't
needed to in some time.
I'd just ask 2.0.
That's the price we pay
for ease and convenience.
I suppose.
Marilyn has been
fostering newborns
for over five years,
ever since she retired.
So you have a lot
of experience then?
I do.
And, Liza,
like we talked about,
the goal is
reunification, always,
so soon as you finish
the treatment program,
we'll reassess things.
All right.
Okay.
Do you have a name
picked out?
Yeah, it's Hannah.
Hey, Dr. Song.
Glad I caught you.
I wanted to let you know
you can sleep in tomorrow.
What happened
to the exploratory lab
we had scheduled
for 8:00 a.m.?
Yeah, it's still on
the docket. I just
moved it to a normal OR.
If this is about
what happened today...
It's not. I mean, it is,
but not because
I lost any confidence
in 2.0.
Okay.
Um, you ever turn off the GPS
while you're driving
just to see
if you still know
the roads?
No, never.
Fair enough.
Me, I need to do that
from time to time.
For my own confidence.
If you change your mind,
it takes a double shot
of espresso, and I am up.
Good to know.
Good night.
Daniel, wait.
Oh, no. Oh, no.
No, I didn't want
to interrupt.
No. No, no, no, it's okay.
Good you're here, actually.
How's the, uh...
How's the prep going?
Okay, I think.
Mr. Wilson was asking
if I know any doctors
at hospital
who would be willing
to speak out.
How do you mean?
Uh, for newspaper article.
Talk to reporters,
share why you support us,
our demands.
Because for me,
that would be a violation
of my employment contract.
I'm not allowed to...
To speak to the media without
talking to the hospital first.
Mr. Wilson said you don't
have to go on record.
Um, you would just...
We'd just say
your department.
No names.
Liliana, I would love to help,
but I mean, I just think
that people would...
You know, they'd connect
the dots pretty quickly.
Don't you think?
I understand. It's okay.
Really?
You know how much
I support you.
You don't have to explain.
I'll, uh, call you later?
Sure. Okay.