I don't like questions
without any answers,
like, "Where do we
go when we die?"
I mean, I know what happens
physiologically speaking,
but beyond that,
what really happens?
Anything?
That's what you start asking
yourself when you live on a clock.
All these questions
without any answers,
they'll drive you nuts.
That's why I like what I do,
fixing babies, birthing babies.
No ambiguity there, no
questions, just answers,
clear, precise, obvious answers.
And life, beautiful new life.
Hope for the future.
God, I miss that.
Morning!
Robbins, are you
ever not chirpy?
Does that ever happen?
Are you ever not snarky?
Also, you snore.
I can't crash here again
tonight without earplugs.
Okay, so, we have seven cases
today. The first one is in two hours.
Also, it's Friday, so that's
MRI day. You know the drill.
47 minutes of my very
limited life-span wasted.
Come on, come on.
God! I'm coming.
Stop chirping.
Stop snarking.
After this, we've got
the diaphragmatic hernia.
Baby's 27 weeks. We'll do a
tracheal balloon occlusion...
Hey.
Figured you could use this...
Which should, if we're
lucky, ensure the blood...
before the big lecture.
Um, thanks. Thank you.
They already scheduled
a follow-up procedure
on the baby, as well.
You're cultivating quite
a bit of buzz, you know?
Really?
I heard from two hospitals
wanting us to record your talk.
But we won't be too
close to the due date.
And if... I have a lot
on my plate right now,
just with Herman and her tumor.
Her surgery.
I really need to focus...
On the tumor.
Don't need any
distractions, and you're...
Very hard to ignore.
Hey, I... It was just coffee.
No, I... I so
appreciate the coffee.
I was just getting some
coffee for myself, and...
It's good coffee.
It's great coffee.
I can just get my own if you...
I mean, you can get
your own so easily.
I don't want to get
my own coffee. I...
I mean, I do. I can. I will.
I can get my own coffee
all day long. I just...
Owen.
Thank you for
bringing me the coffee.
I really like it.
You're welcome.
So, how's my head?
The tumor seems stable.
I was worried about
the inferomedial margin,
but the good news is,
there's no sign of growth.
It hasn't invaded
the optic nerve yet.
Well, how long till it does?
I need a number, Shepherd.
I have things to plan.
About six weeks,
maybe eight if you
go in for the localized radiation
treatments I've prescribed for you.
I'd like for those
to start today.
No, no, no, no. I
tried that. Hated it.
Doctor's orders.
It is our best chance to shrink
the part of the tumor
on your optic chiasm.
Crap. MIRANDA: Glenda Castillo!
We're headed to surgery,
Dr. Bailey. No time to talk.
But you haven't
given me an answer.
Actually, I have. It was no.
But you haven't given
me the right answer.
You could at
least meet with her.
I've seen the case, okay?
I'm sorry, but I'm working
on a very limited time frame
with a very specific list of
surgeries to teach Robbins,
and Glenda Castillo
isn't one of them.
Okay, well, as a personal
favor to me, just me...
I have no time to
make it personal.
It's a no. I'm sorry.
I'll get you some
names, good people.
She can see one of them.
Um, sorry.
Three down, all these to go.
We've got four months'
worth of surgeries up here.
I mean, how are we gonna
get four months of surgeries
done in eight weeks?
We just do, I suppose.
You'll do the next
one yourself. I'll watch.
What?
No. No, thank you. I appreciate
the vote of confidence,
but I'm not even actually
sure that I know how...
I need to see what
you've learned,
what you can and
can't do on your own
while I'm still around to
fix it when you screw up.
Gee, thanks.
It's not a vote of
confidence. It's a necessity.
Training wheels
are off, Robbins.
Time is up. What's next?
Your radiation treatment.
Ugh.
Radiation hasn't worked yet.
I don't see why it's suddenly
supposed to start working.
Radiation is bull...
Shepherd says
that it's necessary.
She's the doctor here.
"Life will out."
The origins and lessons of life
and evolution are
long and complex,
but what they basically
boil down to is, life will out.
Life will always find a
way to continue. Always.
Life... Will... Out.
This is a massive
grade IV astrocytoma.
I want you to take a look at it.
Really look.
Look at its size.
Look at the way it
invades healthy tissue.
Look at its vasculature.
It is blood and
tissue and flesh.
It's growing,
adapting to its environment,
struggling to survive, to stay alive.
It is alive.
We don't like to
think of it that way,
but it's nested in the
womb of a human brain,
feeding on its host,
growing and fighting for life,
almost like a fetus.
No, scratch that.
Let's just for science and
giggles say exactly like a fetus.
Because like a healthy
fetus, it is thriving.
You know, there are even some
types of tumors that grow teeth,
hair,
a stray eye.
Have I repulsed you?
It's gross, right?
Yeah.
I mean, that is a problem.
Nobody wants something
that nasty in their head.
I'd like you for one
moment to consider the idea
that, to the tumor,
we are the problem,
we are the invader.
We are the danger.
To the tumor, we are the cancer.
And the tumor?
Well, the tumor sees itself as
a sweet, cute, fat-cheeked baby
just trying to make
its way into the world,
and we want to
stop it, destroy it,
tear it from its happy
little home like barbarians.
To the tumor,
we are the soulless,
murderous monsters.
Why do I do this?
Why do I call it "baby"
and talk about killing it?
Because this kind of
tumor deserves respect.
It deserves a little humanity.
Charming, isn't it?
They put clouds on the
ceiling to distract you.
Least they could do is put
something interesting up there,
like porn.
It's not just a tumor.
It's ingenuity.
It's strength.
It's adaptability.
It's poetry.
It's one of God's masterpieces.
It is alive.
You okay?
Sure.
And like any living thing,
it wants to stay alive.
Like any living thing, it is
going to fight like hell to survive.
And when I saw open that skull
and come face-to-face with it,
with that tumor,
with that living thing,
it will be almost
impossible to remove...
Well, I'll see you after.
Because it would rather
destroy the brain that holds it
than go gently
into that good night.
It is alive.
And what's it all come down to?
Life...
Will...
Out.
So, our fat-cheeked-baby tumor
that's nestled in that brain,
it's a creature of habit.
It has the same routine
day in and day out.
To grow, to spread
out, to take up space.
That's it.
At this point, our baby tumor
is so enmeshed, so invasive,
it's touching virtually
every single brain structure.
It's pushed existing
tissue aside,
shoved brain matter out of
the way to find room for itself.
How do you remove it without
destroying the brain around it?
How do you kill the baby
without killing the mother?
I stare at these scans, and
the tumor stares back at me,
daring me to try to extract it.
I mean, this tumor
is bold and brazen.
This tumor thinks
it's in charge.
it owns the place.
I don't have to
explain myself to you.
You missed your radiation
session this morning.
I told you, I'm not
doing that anymore.
That is not your call.
My tumor, my head...
It absolutely is my call.
The tumor will be exponentially
easier to remove
after the radiation.
Nicole, please.
Go to radiation!
I will think about it.
Okay.
The thing about
a tumor like this is,
you can't let it intimidate you.
The tumor isn't
smarter than you.
You just need a plan of attack.
Here. Feel that?
You must be methodical.
You want to find a spot
with just the right
amount of give.
That's where you
want to cut. Scalpel.
Point of access is key.
- You're up, Robbins.
- I know.
I've never done
that part before.
So, um, you were
really serious about that?
It's time. Make the cut.
But I don't know...
I've never...
Make the cut.
And then you start.
That is the most daunting step,
pushing a blade into that
first squishy blob of flesh...
Because the first cut
is what sets the tone.
It determines every single
move from that point on.
So, you have to be careful.
You have to be sure.
Or you're in trouble.
It's like a...
Just look at them.
Who?
Arizona and Herman, they're
practically joined at the hip.
I'll take one of those, too.
Well, she is Herman's fellow.
Isn't she sort of supposed
to follow Herman around?
They're laughing all the time.
And Arizona seems so...
Happy, like really happy.
So?
You seem happy... Ish.
What do you even care?
I don't, obviously.
I'm just making conversation.
Don't you guys think it's weird
how they're always together?
They're not always together.
They do bunk up
together sometimes.
What? Alex.
Robbins has been
crashing with Herman.
She hasn't slept at
the house all week.
What? MEREDITH: Alex.
I don't mean like that.
They're not together
together, and you know that.
Mmm-hmm.
Arizona used to hate her.
Now they're having sleepovers?
Well, it's a good thing, right,
that they're getting along?
Herman's not exactly
the warmest person, so...
Yeah, whatever.
When you talk to Derek tonight,
would you ask him something
for me without saying it's for me?
I don't know that I...
Just ask him what he'd use
to avoid disrupting
the Gratiolet radiations
off the geniculate
body of the thalamus.
Why don't you ask
him that? No, no, no.
No, no. That's the point. You
ask him. I can't ask him for help.
I cannot listen to the
smugness in his voice.
You can hear it.
He has transcontinental
smugness. You know what?
Forget it. I'm fine.
I don't need him.
I don't need Derek. I
will figure it out myself.
When did this happen?
She found the perfect rebound
without having to actually find a rebound.
I mean, she just gets all
the good times and the fun,
none of the bad times or the
mess, no chance of getting hurt.
You don't even have
to wax. It's not fair!
Oh, my God. Am I seriously
wishing for a sexless relationship
where I don't have to groom
myself? Is that where I am now?
It sounds good to me.
Welcome to my life these days.
You two chicks need to get laid.
That also sounds good to me.
Not without the grooming.
It's in there. He can find it.
What, he can't do
a little work first?
I like her.
Eddie.
Excuse me?
Glenda Castillo, the patient you
and Herman turned
down last week,
her husband's name was Eddie.
I lost him six months ago
after he was injured
in a head-on collision.
My hands were inside of his body
when his heart stopped beating.
My hands held Glenda's when I
told her Eddie died on my watch.
Three weeks later, she
found out she was pregnant.
She's not insured, but she
remembered me and this hospital,
so, she came here to see if I
could give her some prenatal care,
and guess what we found out.
Her baby has a tumor,
a large, dangerous tumor
that's not just messing
with the baby's system,
it's messing with hers.
I couldn't save her husband's
life, but I can help save her baby.
I owe this woman that much.
Herman has to take
her on as a patient.
Just have her meet
Glenda, all right?
Then she'll... I can't, I can't!
I can't trick her into seeing a
patient she doesn't want to treat.
Who's in charge of her schedule?
Who tells her where
to go and when?
Who tells her what surgery or
post-op or anonymous consult
she should see next?
I'm concerned about
her blood pressure.
It's increased to 140
systolic in the past week,
and her swelling's gotten worse.
I used to have ankles.
Now I have balloons with toes.
So, your baby has a large
tumor in his lower back.
It's most likely benign,
but because of its size
and vascular nature,
it could cause an accumulation
of fluids in the baby.
But the tumor can
be removed, right?
Dr. Bailey says amazing
things about you,
that you're one of the best.
Bailey said that?
How flattering.
That was Glenda Castillo.
I told you no twice now.
And you, how am I
supposed to trust you at all
when you pull
something like that?
She didn't do anything
except try to get your help on
a patient who needs your help.
But if you heard her
story, if you knew she was...
Is that how Bailey
convinced you?
It's a tactic, Robbins, appealing
to your sad, bleeding heart.
Doesn't work with me.
Well, then, let me
appeal to your ego.
You walk around
here telling anyone
who will listen
that you're the best.
Well, then, be the best.
You can save her baby's
life, so save that baby's life!
No.
What the hell? Robbins, drop it.
No, I get that I've seen
tumors like that before,
but this can't all be
about my education.
I mean, at some
point, I have to...
At some point, we have to
make decisions and stick to them.
I wish we had
time, but we don't.
We have very little control
over the time we have,
and we have a plan.
Can't we make an exception?
Can't we just, you know,
sort of adjust the plan?
You... Fine. You want to?
Adjust the plan.
What are you doing?
Take down one of these cards so
we have time to help Mrs. Castillo.
Which one?
How about Meghan Carlson,
congenital airway obstruction?
Her husband's in Iraq right now.
Or Julie Hall, vasa previa.
She went through two
years of fertility treatments.
So, pick one.
Decide which baby
doesn't get to live
so Glenda Castillo's does.
Go ahead.
Pick a card. You choose.
That's what I thought.
No.
Get me out!
Get me out of here!
You have to. I don't.
The radiation treatments
are going to help.
They are gonna shrink
the borders of the tumor,
which will make
it easier to resect.
It's a minimal gain for you.
I will take what I can get. I
am trying to save your life!
You are making me
feel like I've already died.
I'm sick. I'm losing my hair.
I refuse to spend the
last few months of my life
feeling like a pile of crap.
No more.
That's final.
Dr. Stanley, please report...
I am going to give you
more than a few months.
I am going to save your life.
And I am about to get up
in front of a bunch of people
and tell them how
I plan on doing it.
It makes it really
hard for me to do that
or even care about doing that
when you don't seem to care at all!
Well, that's your problem.
Well, the word's spreading.
This was a good idea, Hunt, a
master class in neurosurgery.
This is gonna put Amelia
Shepherd on the map.
Unless it fails.
It won't.
If it does,
there's a lesson in that, too.
So, she just spitballs
this stuff with you?
It's just the two of you
hanging out, talking tumor?
Pretty much.
I want to talk tumor!
I want to talk tumor so bad.
Oh, my God. Look
at that thing. Yeah.
Previous attempts to treat
Dr. Herman's tumor with radiation
proved unsuccessful.
I had hoped
to use high radioactive
doses to reduce the margins,
but at this juncture, that
course seems to be unrealistic.
But that's not enough
to make me quit.
This tumor is fierce and
intimidating and aggressive,
but so am I.
Now, the trick to this is,
you can't touch the vessel
while you're lasering the mass,
not even a little
bit. If you do...
The field fills with blood,
obscuring the camera,
and visualization
is compromised.
First, I need to see
the tumor, all of it,
every margin, every
last ripple and ridge.
So, what do you do?
I have two choices,
open her up and stop
the bleeding if I can,
or deliver the baby
regardless of how early.
Very good.
So, I will employ
fluorescein dye
to delineate every
border of the tumor,
to help me anticipate every
possible problem before I get to it.
I don't want to leave
anything up to chance.
What happened?
The pressure's dropped.
She's in a lot of pain,
and she's cramping.
It hurts! It hurts, it hurts!
It's okay, Julie. We've
got you, we've got you.
She has a vasa previa.
She's scheduled for
an ablation tomorrow.
I've been trying to get
her pressure back up,
but there is no fetal heartbeat.
Damn it. Where's her husband?
Is that blood? I'm bleeding?
Gown me. Keep him out of here.
Robbins, you're gonna get this
baby out right here, right now.
Here?
We need a C-section
tray set up in here.
Call peds. Get
an incubator, stat.
Wait! What? I'm gonna
have the baby now?
Julie, I'm gonna give yo u
something to calm you down, okay?
I never had to do a crash
"C" on my own before, okay?
- I mean, not like this.
- You know what to do.
It's the same three basic steps,
just like any other C-section,
open the abdomen,
open the uterus, deliver.
Okay, I'm okay.
Pressure's steady at 100/60.
Okay, I can do this. Betadine.
Okay.
Robbins? I'll
do... I'll do this.
It's fine, Robbins. I'll do it.
Scalpel.
I'm so sorry.
We did everything we could do.
Good job. Let's go.
Stop crying.
For the love of...
Stop crying! I'm...
Stop it now! Just...
Stop it right now.
There's no time for crying.
We have work to do.
What? How... How can you even...
'Cause that's the
way it goes, Robbins.
Call Bailey.
Tell her we're on.
Now, arguably,
the most important
part of the brain
is the part that makes us hope,
dream,
imagine.
One singular, almost
immeasurable part
is what makes you you
and me me,
and everyone, everyone.
It's technically
called the fornix,
but I call it the "dream box."
The question is
what happens when the
dream box is being invaded,
when a tumor is so
large, so demanding,
it's sucking the dream box dry?
It's taking over, it's stealing
away hopes and dreams.
Imagine, when that
tumor is removed, what...
What will actually be left?
Or, rather, who is left?
Anything?
Anyone?
I remember my
mom telling me once
that when we die,
we go to heaven.
I couldn't picture it.
All I could imagine was
what we see in cartoons,
little people in robes with
wings, sitting on clouds.
But nobody really knows
what's up there, do they?
When I was a kid, I used to
think that we were like dandelions,
like, the part that makes us us
would just blow away
and land and grow into...
I don't want to be buried, by
the way. Have me cremated.
Excuse me?
If I survive the surgery
but don't wake up,
give me five days, a week, tops,
then pull the plug. This is...
We don't need to
be talking about this.
If I do wake up but I'm
dependent on vents or tubes,
pull the plug then, too.
You know what? You're
not... You're not dying.
You're not gonna wake up gorked.
Shepherd knows what
she's doing. She does.
Okay. Sure.
She does! I heard you.
That bird is gonna poop on us.
What's next today?
Glenda Castillo.
I'm so glad you
brought me back in.
Have a look.
Well, the teratoma has grown.
It's showing early signs of hydrops.
Is everything okay?
Glenda, your
baby's retaining fluid,
which is starting
to affect his heart.
I'm recommending we
do the surgery tonight.
Tonight? No,
that's way too soon.
The tumor is creating
pressure on your placenta.
It's not only
endangering the baby,
but now it's
putting you at risk.
But my baby wouldn't
survive, would he,
if you suddenly had to deliver?
'Cause I'm only 24 weeks along,
and I know that it would help
him if he had time to grow, right?
If I could just hold on
for a few more weeks...
It's not what's best for you.
I don't care about me.
Glenda, if Dr. Herman
thinks that...
No, my husband is dead.
But this baby that
is inside of me,
this baby of ours, I
cannot risk his life.
I won't.
So, if there is a choice between
helping me or helping my baby,
I choose my baby.
What does she think
we're trying to do here?
I am not negotiating
with a patient.
I am the doctor. I'm
gonna tell her when we're...
I'm sorry.
Robbins, what the hell?
What's funny about this?
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
It's just... It's just...
It's funny listening to you
get so bent out of shape
when this is the
exact same thing that
you've been doing
to Amelia Shepherd
ever since she
offered to save her life.
I mean, she has. Exactly. "We'll
do the surgery when I'm ready."
And it's so frustrating. It's
torture, and it drives us crazy.
So, it's just fun to
watch it happen to you.
It's like divine justice.
Pretend that I'm not
here. Keep going.
I will give Ms. Castillo an extra
week, but I want her admitted.
And if she so much as hiccups
funny, I'm taking her to surgery.
Understood.
Hey, thank you
for taking her case.
Oh, shut up.
I can't...
Holy...
How do I access that area of
the brain when it's so hidden?
And once I access that area,
even with the perfect
tools, the perfect approach,
how do I keep
from screwing it up?
If there's edema,
it's post-fixed.
It's too narrow, too
close to the fornix.
If I hit the hypothalamus,
game over.
Not gonna work, not
gonna work, not gonna work.
Come on!
Do you want some food?
Have I figured this out yet?
No.
Then I don't want any food.
This has never been done before.
All these steps
in this order on this kind of
tumor, has never been done.
Is that a good
thing or a bad thing?
Who do I even think I am?
Who am I to even try this?
Okay, a bad thing.
Have you called your brother?
What did I say about my brother?
I know. You don't need him.
I was just thinking you could,
just to have someone to
bounce these ideas off of
who understands this kind
of thing the way that you do,
a peer.
He might have a suggestion.
I do not need my brother!
I am not stuck! I am
thinking! I am figuring it out!
I am right on the
edge of figuring it out,
of making the
breakthrough of a lifetime!
I am this close!
My genius is flying
around this room right now,
trying to find a clear
path to land on me,
but I can't clear the runway for
landing because I can't find any quiet
because some idiot
resident keeps talking to me!
I shouldn't have said
that. I didn't mean it.
I'm tired, and
I'm frustrated. I...
I am so sorry. I just...
This tumor is making me crazy.
Edwards.
As bad as you want
to get that tumor,
that's as bad as I want to
watch you get that tumor.
You're tired and frustrated
and terrified, but guess what.
I don't give a damn. You're
supposed to be my mentor.
You are my mentor.
I believe in you, I look
up to you, I want to be you.
That's an enormous responsibility,
so don't call me names.
And stop pouting because
you don't understand what to do.
Be worthy of being believed
in, of being looked up to.
Or if you can't
actually be worthy,
if I am actually
wasting my time,
if there is nothing about
you that is special or wise,
for God's sake, at least have the
decency to pretend that there is.
Get it together, Dr. Shepherd.
Okay, bye.
Bye.
Hey. Um, how are you?
Uh, good.
How's Dr. Herman? Is she
good? Is everything good?
Yeah, I mean, she's killing me
with back-to-back surgeries but...
Yeah, and Amelia's
plan? You good with that?
Callie, what are you...
What?
I'm not... I'm just
checking in, okay?
I'm just seeing how
you are and how...
Callie?
Well, it just seems
like you and Dr. Herman are
getting along really, really well,
and you used to complain
that she was killing you,
but now you're happy
that she's killing you,
and it seems like you
really, really like her.
I do. Actually, I do.
She's great. I mean,
she's amazing.
And she's sick.
So, I worry.
Amelia's got it covered.
She's gonna be fine.
I worry about you.
I know I shouldn't.
I know it's none of my
business, but old habits.
Well, that's, um...
Thanks.
- I got to go.
- Okay, okay.
That's tall.
Yeah. Really big.
Just so you know, the
auditorium is packed.
The fire marshal actually made
me move a bunch of people
out to an overflow room.
Amelia.
Just give me a minute.
Hang on.
You can talk to me.
You're wound pretty tight.
I just want you to
know you can talk to me.
My whole career, I have
been the other Dr. Shepherd.
He's the real one.
I'm the other one.
Right now, this plan
of mine is theoretical.
It's just talk.
But at some point, I am going
to slice into Dr. Herman's brain,
and I have this sick feeling
that when I face that tumor,
I will discover that I am not
just the other Dr. Shepherd.
I'm the wrong Dr. Shepherd.
Hey.
911? What's going on?
Look, I know you've been having
me take the lead so I can learn,
but you need to handle this
case. Why would I do that?
Because it's emergent, and I've
never tried cutting umbilical bands.
First time for
everything. Well...
Listen to me, okay? I'm not
ready to take this over yet.
Doesn't matter.
Stop! Stop!
You... You're not hearing me.
It does matter. I'm not ready.
And you think I am?
You think this is easy for me?
You think I'm ready?
I was fine. I got
fine with dying.
And then you infected
me with your stupid...
With Shepherd and her
plan and your stupid hope.
And now it's harder than ever
to hand all this over.
I don't want to.
I'm scared to.
And I'm scared to let go of
it, and it's all your fault, so...
I think the very least
you could do is deserve it.
Take over, do well,
make me not regret it.
Can you do that?
Please?
This is the part where things
get a little fast and furious.
It is arguably the
most dangerous,
most precarious
portion of the operation.
It also needs to
happen the fastest.
Every step, every
move before this
has laid the groundwork
for this very moment,
the moment where I
place the radioactive seeds.
It requires precision...
I just need to slip these
shears under the band.
And accuracy and speed,
things that do not
go together well.
I can't get the last band.
This grip's not flexible enough.
Can you coax it through?
It's not... No. It won't give.
You have to cut
that last band. I know.
Have you tried a
smaller scissor?
It's not the problem.
Imagine picking
up little grains of salt
while wearing oven mitts.
That is what I'm doing
inside somebody's brain.
Hand me a glove.
What? Somebody hand
me a glove. Scissors.
There's this thing that
we used to do in peds.
I think it'll work.
I just need a more
flexible opening,
and I can make
it out of a glove.
That's not in my notes, Robbins.
- Are you serious?
- It's gonna work.
But once I do it,
once I place the final seed,
well...
It's smooth sailing.
Ha! Did you see that?
It worked! It absolutely worked!
'Night, 'night, tumor baby.
It has been lovely,
but we are done.
I'd like to open things
up to a few questions.
Yes.
Are you nervous?
I'd be crazy not to be.
Yes, of course I'm nervous,
but I'm also very excited.
This is history.
This surgery will be history.
How could I not be
excited about that?
Excellent, excellent.
You should be very
proud of yourself.
Close up now.
Where are you going?
What you're describing
is seven different surgeries
all using the hardest
techniques you've ever tried.
How long do you anticipate
the entire surgery actually taking?
18 hours.
Give or take some hours.
Follow-up question.
Do you need a second
resident on the case?
Not unless Edwards is
planning to bail on me.
You planning to bail, Edwards?
No, ma'am.
Yes, in the back.
Will you have help?
Um, sorry?
Well, I'm just...
Well, are you gonna be doing
this whole surgery yourself,
or is Derek,
Dr. Shepherd coming?
I'm... I'm just...
I'm just asking.
I mean, given everything,
is it a good idea?
Should you be
doing this yourself?
Well, I am, so...
Next question.
I need you to scan me.
Something's happening.
I'm experiencing symptoms.
Fuzziness around the
edges, a little like blinders,
and it's dark...
Darker than it
should be, I think.
Okay.
Let's go.
Bailey? Where's Dr. Herman?
She stepped out.
What do you need?
Uh, it's Glenda Castillo.
Hey, I need Herman right now.
Glenda Castillo's
baby is in distress,
and Glenda is
severely hypertensive,
showing signs of heart failure.
We need to operate on her
immediately, so if you could finish up...
What are you doing?
Why are you standing
there? I... Arizona.
Oh, God.
It's time.
Now?
I'm gonna go...
Get an OR ready.
Okay.
You ready for this?
Mmm-hmm.
Amelia.
I'll get an OR prepped.
You'll inform the patient?
Oh, Robbins.
Surgery's all finished?
Yeah.
I see.
Shepherd's prepping the OR?
Yes.
If I had to guess,
I'd say the tumor's
invaded the optic chiasm.
My chariot awaits.
A little privacy, guys?
Did you need me for
something, a patient?
Yeah.
Glenda Castillo's
baby has hydrops.
Mom is mirroring, and
she's going into CHF.
Wow.
Looks like a big
day for both of us.
What you need to do first
is try to embolize the
vessels fetoscopically.
Make sure her blood
pressure is stabilized.
She has you.
Amelia has you.
This is the point where
you trust her, okay?
Don't go in without
checking Glenda's
platelet counts
and crossmatching.
This is the point where
you trust her, okay?
All set.
Don't let Glenda's
platelet count drop below...
100. I know.
Will you tie me? Yeah.
Let's do this.
I never placed much value in
wondering about an afterlife.
My concern was always this
life, what would I do with it?
How would I make my mark?
Be sure, be fast. You don't
have half the time you imagine.
Try to ablate all the vessels,
but don't wait too long.
Don't be afraid
to make that call.
If she's awake, she'll
tell you for the 15th time
to save her child's
life before hers.
Listen to her, let
her say her piece,
then you do what
needs to be done.
I don't think... I don't know...
I don't know if I can do this.
I can't. I can't
do this. You can.
Nicole. You will.
Let's get you inside now, okay?
I wanted to break new ground.
I wanted to leave a legacy.
I wanted my life, my
brain, my existence...
To mean something.
Hey, hey, hey, you're
gonna be fine, okay?
Amelia's got this.
You've got this.
The thing I never really
thought about, though,
the thing I never really wrapped
my brain around until now was...
Wait, Robbins.
No. Don't you dare.
Don't you dare say it, Nicole.
In order to do that, in
order to be remembered,
in order to leave something
significant behind...
Time to go.
You have to leave.