Doug?
Doug, you slept
through the alarm.
Hmm.
Doug?
Hmm?
Come on.
Jake's going to be up soon.
No. Come on. You're
going to get me started.
Two nights in a row, huh?
Didn't you need the bathroom?
No. There's one at work.
I'll lock it, okay?
You forgot to lock it yesterday.
Okay. All right.
Yeah. I'll see you.
Later.
Carter, go to Radiology.
Pick up the film on O'Shields.
Chen, work on
those med renewals.
I've got a gallbladder
this afternoon,
then I've got to start
those sub-I evaluations.
But placements
aren't until next month.
I need your procedure
books by 7:00.
I thought we had
until next week.
Well, you did. Now you
don't. Is that a problem?
It's not fair.
You have been here longer.
You've done more
procedures than I have.
There's a few I
haven't done yet.
Four or five. How many
intubations have you done?
Lost count. Chest tubes?
Did a femoral
cut-down yesterday.
Oh, but I did. You didn't.
How long have you had
this pain, Mr. McDowall?
Since Friday... bowling night.
When I can't bowl,
I'm not a happy man.
Well, we want you happy.
Okay. Chem seven, CBC, LFTs
and abdominal ultrasound.
An ultrasound?
Could be appendicitis.
Could be gas.
Yeah, I know, but...
Is there a problem?
How you doing, sir?
Not too good. Stomachache.
Kept him from bowling.
That's a shame.
Mr. McDowall, this is
Dr. Swift, our
attending physician.
Cancel the CBC,
Chem seven, LFTs and ultrasound.
Excuse me?
Dr. Greene, what's
your diagnosis?
Probable gastroenteritis.
Stomach flu.
Why are you ordering
$1,000 worth of tests?
Rule out appendicitis.
It's ruled out. Trust me.
He has pain in the
right lower quadrant.
And so would you
if you were full of gas.
Sir, go home.
Take nothing by mouth
for six hours.
And when you do, take
little sips of clear fluid.
If it gets worse, you come
back and see us immediately.
All right?
You'll be there to get
her moved this afternoon?
I'll be there.
I'll tell her she's
going to the home,
but I need you to
back me up, Peter.
Listen, Jackie, I, uh...
I want to be the
one to tell her.
Please, Jackie.
All right.
Petey!
Hey, Ma.
Hey, Ma, how you feeling?
I'm leaving today.
I've been trying
to make my hair up
the way Daddy liked it.
Could you help me, honey?
Ma...
Hmm?
Uh... Jackie and I
and the doctors...
th... think you need more
care than we can give you.
You need to have
someone around all the time
to make sure that you're okay.
We found this great place...
The Melville Home.
We'll make it just as nice
as your house, Mama.
Yeah. Jackie's going
to make you curtains.
Yellow stripes,
Mama. Your favorite.
Do I have to go, Peter?
Yeah, Ma.
You... you do.
Swift was way out of line.
He was right. I
ordered too many tests.
What for? Talk to him.
You still want the
attending, don't you?
He's already made
up his mind about me.
What do we have?
He works for the
electric company.
Took a 20-foot fall.
High-current burns.
Got it from here, Doug. Thanks.
Start a central line.
Okay. Carter, over here.
Have you ever
done a central line?
No, but I've seen one.
You're going to do one now.
Put the long 14-gauge
on the 6cc syringe.
B.P. 120 palp, pulse 120.
Prep five migs morphine.
Give him a liter
of Ringer's first.
Aim at the sternal notch.
80, 90 kilos.
Yeah. Right.
You have blood refill.
Remove the syringe...
and feed the guide wire through.
Lucky guy.
No S.T. changes.
Slide it in the
subclavia. Do you want
a tetanus?
Get it.
300cc's Ringer's.
Here are the X rays.
They'll do that upstairs.
Leave enough guide wire
at the end so you
can pull it back though.
You're doing
a central line?!
Yep.
Get an X ray to check
the placement.
Excellent.
Get him ready for transfer.
Talk to me.
He fell from a utility pole.
Third-degree burns
to upper extremities.
No cardiac changes.
C-spine, chest,
pelvis... all are negative.
No long-bone fractures.
Okay. Let's get him up.
Let's go.
Here we go.
Rolling. Rolling.
Any fever, Mrs. Ryan?
No. Just the headache
and some dizziness.
I think I'm going to throw up.
And nausea.
Okay, Janette, we'll get you
fixed up right away. Okay?
What's wrong with her, Doctor?
It's probably just a flu bug.
That's what most of the kids
have been coming in with.
Her heart rate is
a little fast though,
so we want to run some tests.
Winnie, you want to put her
on a monitor? And let's
check her rhythm strip.
A monitor?
Yeah. Heart monitor.
Isn't that serious?
Not necessarily.
We just want to
keep our eye on her
while we run the tests.
Doctor, are these tests
going to cost a lot of money?
You have insurance, don't you?
No.
Well, we'll work something out.
How long have
you had that cough?
You can give me medicine, okay?
How long, Mrs. Salazar?
A week. Two.
Have you been coughing
anything up, like blood?
It's not so bad.
I have to go.
Could you have been exposed
to tuberculosis?
Tuberculosis?
I don't know what you mean.
Does anyone else in your
family have this cough?
Anybody you work with?
I don't work, okay?
Mi esposo has green card.
He work. My children at home.
I need to go.
Mm-hmm. Have any
of them been sick?
Fevers? Night sweats?
My daughter.
I have to go home!
Mi madre, she take
care of her now.
If your daughter is sick,
and you have tuberculosis,
we need to see her.
It's very contagious.
Now, I can't make
you stay, Mrs. Salazar,
but I would like to
strongly advise you
to take these tests.
There's no questions
asked, okay?
Okay. I stay a little bit.
What's she so afraid of?
She's probably illegal.
She doesn't want to
be put into the system.
Lydia, we've got
to get Mrs. Salazar
into an isolation room.
She needs a chest
X ray, acid fast stain
and a sputum culture.
Carter, why don't
you find her a mask?
Sure.
I want you to stay
away from me, Shirley.
You could have
killed Mr. Munchy.
No such luck. It
was your fault, Sari!
You said the road was clear!
Didn't say it would
stay that way!
I told you to step on it!
It's not safe to speed!
You were going
five miles an hour!
Shut up. This is all your fault.
Two sisters, slow-moving MVA.
One with a nose lac, the
other dizzy with headache.
Vitals stable.
The only danger they're
in is from each other.
Thanks, Sancho.
Somebody help!
Please! Please!
Pulse is thready.
Start a line. Get her some O-2.
Get the crash cart with
pediatric paddles now, please.
My God. What's happening?
You have to stay back right now.
B.P. 70/50.
Lydia, give me some Adenosine.
Janette, you're going
to have to help me out.
Blow on your thumb
like you're blowing up
a balloon, really hard.
Two milligrams Adenosine.
Three I.V. push.
Not registering a B.P.
I can't feel a pulse.
She's out.
Oh, my God.
Set it on 50.
Hit the synch switch.
Clear.
She's in V-fib.
Turn the synch switch off.
Charge to 100 joules.
And clear.
Normal sinus rhythm.
Pulse bounding.
What's that?
It means she's okay.
Welcome back, kiddo.
It's going to be okay.
Your mom's right here.
You're fine.
"A-R-Q-P-T-X."
That was completely wrong.
Why don't you try the same line
with your glasses?
Oh. Yes.
Here we go.
"N-T-O-A-
W-R."
Damn it, Shirley.
I can't see squat.
I'm going to kill you!
We've lived
together for 50 years,
and I'm not dead yet.
You're a bully, Sari.
Well, now I'm blind.
Are you happy?
Ladies, please.
She's no lady.
Hold still.
I'm concerned about your vision
and your headache.
We need to get a CAT scan
of your head.
Which glasses are yours?
How should I know?
I can't see.
Why don't you try these?
Here.
Oh.
Oh!
I thought you'd be older.
Young man...
Just one second.
Carter, got a
procedure for your book.
Really?
Mm-hmm. Pelvic.
I already have a ton of pelvics.
Lady asked for you personally.
I'm so thirsty.
Some water, please.
There you go.
Hey.
So, Janette has
supraventricular tachycardia.
It's sort of like
a short circuit in her heart.
So she needs to be
admitted into Cardiology.
Now, somebody
from Social Services
is going to come down here
and help you with your
applications for Medicaid.
Your daughter's going
to be fine, Mrs. Ryan.
Just fine.
Lunch later?
Yeah. Sure.
Doc McGoo's, the cafeteria
or the vending machines?
It doesn't matter.
Wild Willy wants you
to see the lady in Three.
Have you talked to him yet?
Nope. Don't plan to.
Why? What's to lose?
She's in her eighth month...
Complaining of stomach cramps
and frequent urination.
Uh... why don't you take it?
Why?
'Cause I asked you to.
Do I know you from someplace?
No.
Well, why did you ask to see me?
Well, um... you treated
my friend Barbara.
She recommended you.
The truth is, I don't really
have cramps.
Why are you here, Mrs. Blum?
Well, Barbara and her husband
have been trying to
have a baby for years.
They've tried everything.
Last month, she
came in with cramps,
and you examined her.
And, the very next week,
she got pregnant!
You think I had
something to do with that?
Barbara certainly does.
When I told her that
Dan and I were trying,
she said, "Go
see that Dr. Carter.
He's got the magic touch."
Dr. Greene.
Your name's on the board
for that pregnant woman.
Why is Dr. Lewis with her?
I gave it to her.
I see.
I understand you lost
a mother during delivery
a couple of weeks ago.
Jody O'Brien. Pre-eclampsia.
She bled out.
I'd like you to present it
at the case conference today.
Today?!
2:00.
I need time to prepare.
No, you don't.
You know what happened.
Mrs. Salazar...
your tests are positive
for tuberculosis.
We need to get your family
in here as soon as possible.
I bring them manana.
No, no, no.
Today, Mrs. Salazar.
You shouldn't be
leaving the hospital.
You are very sick.
I feel better.
Really. I can go.
You understand the
seriousness of your illness?
What matters is your
family, Mrs. Salazar.
I don't care if you're illegal.
I just want to make sure
your kids are okay.
They're fine.
You are going to infect
every person you
come in contact with...
Your children, husband,
the people you work with.
Dr. Greene.
Your family at home
needs to come in
and be seen in this hospital!
Mark.
What's the matter with you?
She's leaving A.M.A.
with infectious TB.
I'm not supposed to
be angry about that?
Well, how do you
expect her to trust you
if you're screaming at her?
I wasn't screaming at her.
Now you're screaming at me.
Okay, fine. Forget it.
She leaves, she leaves.
Well, rule out sepsis.
We made a supra pubic tap.
You're kidding.
Step right up, Doc.
Temp's 102.
I gave him four
ounces of clear liquid
like you said. Nothing.
Gave him four more.
Eight ounces?
It's dry as a bone.
Isn't there some other way
that you can find the
source of the fever?
This is the easiest way.
Carter, I want you
to swab the area.
Hold the syringe in one hand...
That's okay, kiddo...
And palpate the pubic symphysis.
What now?
We use a small needle
to get a urine sample.
Be careful not to push too hard.
How do you know what's too hard?
Oh! Ew!
That's probably too hard.
Your husband brought you in?
The old fuddy-duddy.
He thinks I have
paranoid psychosis
with highly elaborated
delusional systems.
He reads too much, that's all.
Do you ever hear voices
when no one else is around?
Of course not.
Ever have frightening thoughts?
No.
Are you ever afraid
that someone is
trying to harm you?
Of course. The streets
aren't safe nowadays, are they?
Mrs. Gainsley,
have you ever been
under the care
of a psychiatrist?
Yes. Would you like his number?
Let's see. Where'd I put it?
It's somewhere.
Just give me a second here.
Yikes.
Oh. Sig Saur 228.
Nine millimeter, double action.
13-round clip.
Little heavy, but lethal.
Would you mind if I gave
this to Security, just for now?
Not at all.
I've still got the Beretta.
Still here?
Waiting for the
ambulance to transfer her.
How are you, Ma?
She's been quiet.
Let me talk to her for a minute.
Ma, you're going
to like the place.
I saw it.
It's nice and clean.
You'll have your
own TV in your room.
There's a little
courtyard outside.
I've got surgery.
Jeannie's going
to go with you now.
I'll come by later, okay?
I love you, Ma.
We're ready.
Hey.
Conference?
Yeah.
You nervous?
Oh, no. I love an inquisition.
You'll do fine.
Are you kidding?
They'll be out for blood.
We've all been there.
Oh? How many young
mothers have you killed, Doug?
Mark, listen.
Hey.
Sorry I can't be
there with you today,
but you're going to do okay.
Thanks.
Good luck.
Excuse me.
Isn't there supposed to be a
conference in here at 2:00?
Not enough space.
They moved it
to the sixth floor.
Oh, yeah? What room?
The auditorium.
Finger lac in Two.
I have to finish
the med renewals.
What's the matter?
You got enough finger
lacs in your book?
I told you, I'm busy.
Yeah. Right.
Carter, why in the hell did
you give Mrs. Baba water?
Who?
The little old lady in Two.
She was thirsty.
She was N.P.O.
Scheduled for gallbladder
surgery this afternoon.
No food, no water.
She was your
gallbladder patient.
Just read the chart.
Now, because of you,
she can't have surgery.
I'm doing a small bowel.
Chen, scrub in.
To the O.R.
Really?
Ah, good. You're here.
I hope it's instructive...
for the other residents.
Down there.
Do you know the diagnostic
criteria for pre-eclampsia?
Blood pressure
greater than 140/90,
persistent proteinuria
and edema.
She had hypertension.
Which I attributed to a
urinary tract infection.
Her pressure was high
on only one occasion.
You should have taken
it again in six hours.
My index of suspicion
should have been higher.
She seized in the parking lot.
I treated her
seizure aggressively
with magnesium
sulphate and Ativan.
Have you had a chance
to review the ultrasound?
I missed the
placental abruption.
Did you know what
you were looking for?
The AFI and biophysical
profile were excellent.
There was a normal
fundal placement.
Yet she abrupted.
I had no clinical
reason to be suspicious.
There was no vaginal bleeding,
shock, abdominal
pain or fetal distress.
What are the criteria for
operative vaginal delivery?
Mainly a favorable fetal lie
and a small baby...
Under 4,000 grams.
The baby was nine
pounds, three ounces.
Macrosomia.
I used the Leopold
Maneuver and fundal height
to estimate baby
weight and size.
I was off.
What risks do you run
using forceps on a
Macrosomic baby?
A 23% chance of
shoulder dystocia.
Yes. Which happened.
What qualifies you to manage
high-risk O.B. in an E.R.??
We're not here to question
Dr. Greene's training.
Stick to the case.
Why a C-section in an E.R.?
The baby was hypoxic
and bradycardic.
Had to do it in minutes or we
ran the risk of brain damage.
How many crash
C-sections have you done?
I've scrubbed in on
several. That qualified you?
I give Dr. Greene credit
for crashing her when he did.
Knowing the outcome, what
would you have done differently?
I should have taken
her up to O.B. myself.
Immediately.
I've induced before.
Delivered babies before.
I assumed that I could
handle the situation.
I was wrong.
Anyone else?
Thank you, Dr. Greene.
That wasn't too bad.
I knew, once you had a chance
to talk it through,
you'd feel fine.
I'm supposed to feel
some sense of relief?
Is that it?
I got to get back to work.
By the way,
that stomach flu this morning...
The next time you
disagree with my diagnosis,
don't do it in front
of the patient.
Where are we going?
Follow me.
All right. Hold that a second.
What do you think?
It's a little small for you.
Yep.
Whose is it?
Yours.
Mine? Doug...
It's the same as yours.
That's right.
18-speed, grip-twist shifter,
hyper-sprocket drive
and other stuff I
know nothing about.
Hey, come here.
Come here.
You ride bike, you wear helmet.
Where's your helmet?
I know you mean
well, Doug, but it's...
Come on, Doug Race you!
You're on!
You should have
talked to me about this.
I'll be back.
Where's Anita Salazar?
Eloped. Can't find her.
Want me to send Public
Health out to get her?
Give it a try
but, ten to one, it's
probably a fake address.
Mark, we could use your help.
We've got an MVA coming in.
Rollover, T.C.
Thrown 20. Heavy E.T.O.H.
Lac on his right leg.
No apparent fracture.
He's yanked two I.V.s.
Calls himself Smiley.
No I.D.
Aw! I'm in the wrong place.
Get a portable down here.
CBC, Chem seven, blood alcohol.
Watch his neck.
Transfer... one, two, three.
B.P.'s 90/50.
Someone get him undressed.
Hit your head?
Does it hurt?
How should I know?
Drunk as a skunk.
Scalp's okay. No lacs.
All right, cap refill's slow.
He's hypovolemic.
Do you think it's his spleen?
I don't know.
Bloods are drawn.
Shoot a cross-table C-spine.
CBC type and cross for four.
Peripheral pulses are cool.
Lungs clear.
Shooting.
Stand back.
Hold your breath.
Clear!
O-2's here.
This hurt?
Get your hands off me!
His abdomen's rigid.
I think it's the spleen.
Prep for a lavage.
Smiley, we're very
concerned about you.
We're going to make sure that
you're not bleeding internally.
We're going to take this
tube and put it in your nose,
let it go down
into your stomach.
It's not very pleasant.
Go to hell!
It's not the highlight
of my day, either.
Don't come near me with no tube.
One percent Xylocaine with EPI.
You are drunk out of your mind.
We need to take care of you.
So this is our
decision, not yours.
Hey!
Just keep breathing.
Keep breathing.
Okay, come on.
Good. Good.
Assisted on a laparotomy,
and closed the
incision in the O.R.
Two new procedures.
Finally, I have a chance.
Uh-huh.
Can I get you anything, Haleh?
Coffee? Cake?
You want to get me coffee?
Sure.
Cream and sugar.
Where we putting Fareau?
Oh. Exam Two.
Oh, and, if you could,
here is a list of
procedures I still need,
so if any of them come
in, throw them my way?
Sure.
You can start by helping
Wendy get an I.V. going
on our junkie friend in Two.
Oh, I.V.'s not on my list.
It is now.
Maybe we should get a doctor.
I'll find a vein.
Always do.
There's one.
Oh, no good.
I'll get Dr. Lewis.
What for?
He hasn't got a
vein left anywhere.
He's going to
need a central line.
He's bleeding out.
We've got to find out
where the source is.
How's the lavage coming?
Almost there. Chest normal.
Got to find the bleeder.
Could be retroperitoneal.
Where is he bleeding?
Any output? Nothing yet.
Hang two units now.
This is soaked through.
Will four units be enough?
Get four more.
Cap refill's bad.
Whoa! Whoa!
Found it.
Femoral artery.
It's a pumper.
Let's get vascular on the line.
Let's get an angiogram.
Let's get him up.
Call the blood bank.
Get the blood
to the cath lab.
Let's move!
Deb?
Almost... done.
There.
Are you crazy?
You're not allowed
to do a central line.
I was just going
to get it started
but then it seemed so easy.
You'll get in trouble.
I'll get fired.
It's fine. Look.
Oh, my God.
Where's the...?
What's wrong, Deb?
Oh, my God.
What's going on?
Where's the guide wire?
You lost the wire?
Deb, where is it?
Ah, there it is.
Cath lab, stat.
What happened?
Deb, what happened?
I need a cath lab.
Two open? Fine.
Come on, Carter. Move.
We're going to need to
put a line in and snare it.
Get a fluoroscope.
And order an echo.
Call Transport to take him up.
Deb?
Deb, wait a minute.
Deb, wait!
Find Deb?
No, and there's no
answer at her house.
I almost feel responsible.
Why? You're not the one
who nearly killed a patient.
Carter, where's Chen?
I have no idea.
Well, I don't care
how you do it. Find her.
Swift wants to talk to her.
How's the patient doing?
Well, we got the wire out,
if that's what you mean.
But whether or not we'll be sued
is another story.
Hey.
You shouldn't have
bought Jake that bike.
Why not?
He has one. He doesn't
need another one.
He wanted it.
There's a lot of things he
wants, he doesn't get, Doug.
All right, well,
I'll take it back.
You miss the point.
Doug, at the back door...
12-year-old hit
by a delivery truck.
Okay. I'll be right there.
I don't get it.
I was just trying to
do something nice.
It's too much too soon.
He doesn't know what it means.
Neither do I. What does it mean?
You can't go through
him to get to me.
That what you think?
That's what he
hopes you're doing.
Doug, Trauma One!
12-year-old ran a
red light on his bike.
Hit and thrown 20 feet.
L.O.C. at scene,
B.P.'s crashing 60/40.
I think he's got a left pneumo.
Name's Billy Schmoo.
Jennifer left?
I can't believe you
waited this long to tell me.
It's not like I was going
to make an announcement
over the intercom.
What did you tell Rachel?
I took the high
road on that one.
Nothing.
I don't think I could
bear losing her.
I hardly see her as it is.
Yeah.
Well...
that's kind of the
problem, isn't it?
With Jennifer, not just Rachel.
She wants to be in Milwaukee.
So what?
Figure something out.
Call her. Go see her.
I'm going this weekend.
That's so like a guy
to wait four days.
Go tonight.
I work tomorrow.
I'll cover tomorrow.
I owe you.
Thanks.
Lacerations look superficial.
Pulse is thready at 150.
He looks dusky.
Tension pneumo.
18 gauge.
Set up a Pleurovac.
There we go.
All right.
Pulse ox is 65.
CBC, Chem seven.
How many units O-neg?
Six.
12 lead. Call X ray.
Cross-table C-spine
and a portable chest.
He's on his way.
Scalpel.
What size?
28 French.
There you go.
The belly's soft.
Bowel sounds normal.
Got that chest tube ready?
Yep.
All right.
Breath sounds are good...
but his B.P.'s crashing.
Distant heart sounds,
dilated neck veins.
Prep for pericardiocentesis.
All right, kiddo.
Alligator clamp.
Okay.
B.P.'s falling.
Come on now, damn it.
Where are you, little heart?
Whoa. Too far.
It's okay.
Come on, where are you, damn it?
Come on, little heart.
I know you're in
there somewhere.
All right. Got it.
Oh, yeah, that's much better.
Call O.R. and a thoracic team.
We've got a live one.
B.P.?
Coming up... 60/40.
Cross-table C-spine.
Let's get a chest film.
You're going to
be just fine, buddy.
We'll take him up.
Great.
You okay?
I'm heading home.
What's not to be okay?
Pepperoni or salami?
What?
On your pizza.
Salami.
Too bad. I win.
All right, all right,
but only on one-third.
Okay.
See you in a bit, babe.
Bye.
Pizza'll be there in 20 minutes.
Thanks.
For what?
For staying.
Yeah, well, you're
buying the pizza.
Look at your daddy.
That silly hat!
Oh, I am so tired.
Well, Ma, why don't
you get some sleep?
Here.
Let me take this.
Pete...
do you still want
to be a doctor?
Ma...
I am a doctor.
Your talent is
God's gift to you.
What you do with it
is your gift back to God.
Go ahead... get some sleep.
Okay.
Hi, Jen. How are you?
Rach?
Good.
I want to come up
and see you guys.
I want to talk.
No, no. Tonight.
How about tomorrow?
Okay, well, we'll
see you Saturday.
Rachel there?
No, no, no. Don't wake her.
I just... I miss her.
Jen, I love you.
You there?
Yeah, okay.
Oh... sorry.
Chloe?
Hi, Susie.
Hi.
Um... let's go to the kitchen.
I really didn't care
about the patient.
I just wanted the procedure.
By tomorrow,
everybody will forget.
I won't.
I'm quitting.
You can't quit.
Sure, I can.
Deb, listen. You're
smart, and you learn fast.
What's that got to do
with taking care of people?
You're going to
be a great doctor.
I don't really like it.
No, that's not completely true.
I like the science of it,
but the patients,
the sickness...
Sometimes, it almost scares me.
Scared the hell out of me.
When I was a kid,
my older brother
was really sick...
In and out of the hospital.
When I saw how the doctors
treated him, and how they treated me,
I knew that this was
what I wanted to do.
See, that's the
difference, John.
You think about
treating patients.
You take the time
to talk to them.
You listen to them.
You care.
So what are you going to do?
Join the party.
My parents' wedding anniversary.
I'll wait to tell my
folks afterwards.
Mother will throw
up... Should be fun.
Thanks.
Mm-hmm.
Mark?
You've got visitors.
Mrs. Salazar.
Hi.
Hola. Esta es mi madre, Maria.
Hi, Maria.
En mi nina, Cristina.
Hi, Cristina. You're
the sick one, huh?
You guys grab the bag.
Here. Eat this.
It'll warm you up.
I don't want to put
you to any trouble.
Yeah, right.
Ronnie sold my stuff.
You're kidding.
I'm shocked.
You were so right about him.
Actually, you were
right about all of them.
Yeah, well, they're all
basically the same person.
That... that is not true.
Norm was a good guy.
Sure, the two hours of
the day he was awake.
Chloe!
What did you do to my coat?
I hitched a ride
with this family.
A kid got carsick.
I switched to ultra lights.
You've seen a doctor
for the baby, haven't you?
A couple times...
Once.
Recently?
Sort of.
I am so glad to be here, Susie.
I'm glad you're okay...
Sort of.
Oh...
I'm so tired.
I know.
I'm scared, Susie.
Don't worry, Chloe.
Don't worry.
We'll be okay.
Captioning sponsored
by WARNER BROS.