Mark? Mark?
Mark, please ask your
father if he wants a burger.
Mom. I know. You're
defending the free world.
Please ask your Dad
if he wants a burger.
Dad?
Dad? Mom wants to
know if you want a burger.
Mom, I don't know what
he wants. You ask him.
Aunt Arlene!
Want a burger?
Okay.
The guy drove his wheelchair
into a pool. House would love that.
He'll be bored. It's a great
visual, but it's diagnostically boring.
What about
post-hair-transplant aphasia guy?
Infection-throwing clots. House will
shoot it down and call you an idiot.
Oh, well, we wouldn't want that.
What about yoga girl?
It has a good hook.
Should we lead with it?
His first day back, he might
want to flex his sarcasm muscle.
Maybe we open with
one of the weaker pitches.
You ran here?
It's just eight miles.
Why did you...
Why does a dog lick its
workplace-acceptable euphemism
for testicles? Because he can.
What have you got for me, boss?
I thought you said you
needed eight weeks of rehab.
You should have been back
here... If I'd come back sooner,
then I'd only be able to run six
miles. I never would have made it in.
What have you got for me?
You're completely pain-free?
The ketamine
treatment can wear off.
It's been two months.
It's not wearing off.
What have you got for me?
You can take as long as...
Why are we having this discussion?
Want to hear me thank you again?
Thank you, Doctor Cuddy,
not just for removing the bullet,
but thank you for putting me
into a ketamine-induced coma
and changing my
life. Happy? I am.
Middle-aged man had hair
transplant about two months ago...
Infection-throwing
clots. You're an idiot.
Except you're not an idiot,
and she is holding a file
for a 26-year-old female.
What have you really got for me?
Girl was doing an inverted
yoga pose, neck snapped,
paralyzed from the neck down,
except the x-rays show
no evidence of spinal injury.
And she's cute.
Oh, well played, sir.
What about Stephen Hawking
trying to do the 500 butterfly?
Forget it. Brain cancer, brain surgery.
There's nothing left to diagnose.
I would take the other one.
I'll take them both.
You don't think he
had brain cancer?
Of course he had brain cancer.
Even oncologists don't
screw up for eight years.
So if there's no diagnostic issue,
why are you taking the case?
Treatment can be
interesting. Not to you.
I've changed. No, you haven't.
No, I haven't. So why
are you taking the case?
The guy tried to kill himself.
The guy had cancer. He's a lump.
He hasn't been able to touch
his wife, speak to his kids.
He's been in that chair for eight
years. His muscles have atrophied.
Maybe I can help
him with the pain.
Isn't that enough of a
reason to want to help?
Not for you. I've changed.
No, you haven't.
Then why am I taking this case?
Let's start with the cute
paraplegic. Welcome back.
Hey. You look...
Healthy.
Quad with no broken
neck. Struck me as odd.
You can take a whole two
minutes to ease into being back.
I would've taken a whole
month to ease back,
but eight weeks is the
maximum rehab time
for a gunshot wound to the
stomach and neck, so go.
We heard they never found
the guy. There's no new leads.
What? You think he might
have shot this patient, too?
It would explain her
symptoms. It could be MS.
See? It's not so
difficult. It's not MS.
She had no symptoms before
she climbed onto her head.
Unless she's been upside-down
for the last 10 years, MS ain't it.
Could be transverse myelitis, swelling
in the disks, choking off nerve function.
MRI is negative for that.
Your leg looks fine.
Totally pain-free?
When did this turn into, "What did
you do over your summer vacation?"
It's a little weird
to discuss the case
while you're staring at
your blood on the floor.
I asked Cuddy to
replace the carpet.
I like the carpet. What did
you do over the summer?
Redo the tests.
Let's see if the source of the problem
is in the limbs or the spine. Do an EMG.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
We've got a whole other quad to cover.
This guy's still got fluid in his lungs.
You don't think that's
from the pool he drank?
Give him an O2 mask. His
leg muscles have atrophied.
Tendons have shortened from
disuse, causing intense pain.
Tendon surgery will make
him more comfortable.
Comfortable?
Scoot.
Thanks for being here.
Not a problem.
My Dad wouldn't kill himself.
You haven't spoken
to him in over six years.
I know my dad. Mark,
the doctor's just trying to...
- He wouldn't kill himself.
- Fine. I'm wrong.
You obviously have a better
understanding of this man
who drools in front of
your TV set 24 hours a day.
Doctor House?
Look, he must have been confused,
all right? It must have been an accident.
I hope it was a suicide attempt.
If he was trying to kill himself, then
he knows how miserable his life is.
It means there's still
something there to kill.
It means your dad's still there.
Sorry. Need you.
Thank you.
We were doing the EMG, but we never got
past the insertion of the conduction pin.
Did she just say, "Thank you"?
I loaned her some
money. What went wrong?
Nothing went wrong.
If nothing went wrong,
then something went right.
You're not gonna tell
me why she thanked you?
me what went right?
You did something for which she
is grateful, and you're embarrassed?
For you. She saw you coming up,
thought you were a 14 year-old boy.
I set her straight.
I am not telling you
what went wrong or right
until you tell me why
she said, "Thank you."
Oh, you got me. You know I
need to know. I am so gonna fold.
Except you're forgetting
there's one thing I can do now.
It's either that or
a reflex response.
What happened?
Okay.
This is Doctor House.
House, this is Caren...
Pleasure's all mine.
What happened?
When we inserted the
conduction pin, she flinched.
She flinched? Did you hear?
Does that mean
I'm getting better?
How big is a flinch? Bigger than
a twitch? Smaller than a spasm?
Do you smoke?
Socially, not a lot.
You do yoga, and you smoke?
I know it's hypocritical, but...
No, the world sees your legs.
No one's checking out your lungs.
How would smoking cause...
It wouldn't. I just
needed a lighter.
House. Oh, my God!
The case was looking so
promising. Hey, I'm not faking.
You moved, therefore
you can move.
Get this lunatic out of
here before she bores again.
I'm not faking!
I heard you were watching
surgery with a patient's family,
talking to a patient's family.
It's because of your hallucination,
isn't it? After you were shot.
You chose life. You
decided you wanted meaning,
so you took a case with no mystery,
something any doctor could do,
a case with no upside
except the satisfaction
of helping another human being.
She thanked me.
And you felt nothing.
I wasn't sure what I
was supposed to feel.
It's like your leg. It's atrophied.
Keep working it. The feeling will come.
Sorry. Need you again.
I told you to get rid of her.
It's a good thing we didn't.
Tightness in her chest.
She can't breathe. It
could be pleural effusion.
Right. Either that or she's holding
her breath like a four-year-old.
Relax. I'm not
gonna burn you again.
I'm going to stab you!
Look, either you're faking, or
you've got a pleural effusion.
That's a buildup of fluid around
the lungs, which is very serious,
and I would have no choice but to
stab you in the back with this needle
and suck all of
the fluid out of you.
So... CAMERON: We
should give her a local.
That would defeat the
point of me being nasty.
Ready?
Down. She can't
breathe if she's down.
Down. She can't...
Down, down, down! Come on!
That's not a pleural effusion.
The problem's in her heart.
Can't fake that.
Had to relieve the pressure
three times in the last two hours,
so either we figure out what's causing
blood to build up around her heart,
or I follow her around with a
needle for the rest of her life.
Echo was clean. No
structural abnormalities.
It could be an
infectious process, TB.
Or vasculitis would
also explain the effusion.
But not the paralysis. Let's
assume that she wasn't faking it.
She moved, therefore she
could move. She wasn't paralyzed.
Doesn't mean she was faking.
It could have been a delusion.
Now, either she was faking
and coincidentally got
a real cardiac problem
at the exact same
time, or it's a delusion,
and the fake paralysis is a
real neurological symptom.
Are you thinking vascular
tumor on her spine?
Her platelets are normal.
And she's been scanned
up and down. It's all clean.
So open her up and find it.
So what do you want us
to do? Just start at her neck
and just keep on cutting down her
spine until we stumble on something?
That should work.
His heart rate's a little
high. Should I be worried?
Probably just means he's still
in discomfort from the surgery.
I'm gonna up his
morphine a little.
You've been so nice to us.
It's the job.
No, I mean, all the other doctors, all
they did was obsess on the cancer,
the treatment, the
damage, just trying to fix him.
You're the first doctor that's ever
given a damn about the quality of his life.
His heart rate's come down.
The morphine worked. I was right.
What a touching moment.
That's why we become doctors,
for these rare moments
when our hearts are warmed...
Would you like to get a drink?
Are you serious, or are you
just trying to change the subject?
No, I'm serious.
I drink. You drink. We could do it
at the same time, the same table.
If you eat, we
could do that, too.
I mean, if the answer's
no, that's cool, but...
No, it's just you're just coming off of
surgery, and you're not yourself yet,
and I work for you, and
even though last year's...
You're smiling. I'm saying
no, and you're smiling.
Well, don't take it personally.
It's just 'cause you're full of crap.
You have no interest in going out with
me. Maybe you did, when I couldn't walk,
when I was a sick puppy that
you could nurture back to health.
Now that I'm healthy,
there's nothing in it for you.
You are not healthy.
Cuddy wants to see you.
You've been back
at work 24 hours,
and you're already playing
hide-and-seek in a woman's spine.
Who won the pool?
There's no tumor.
Her platelets are
normal. The scans didn't...
What's the worst that can happen?
Might paralyze her. She won't even notice.
Her lawyers might. You're
not doing the surgery.
And lower the morphine
on your other patient.
Fine, I'll lower it if you
let me do the surgery.
What? You want to trade?
We're not swapping a couple of
goats for your help putting up a barn.
You want something. I want
something. We compromise.
It's the grownup way to
resolve our differences.
There already is a
mechanism for that,
it's called the
employer-employee relationship,
I get what I want,
and you don't.
You tried to swap?
Ran a few more tests. They came
back negative. The surgery's on.
You really don't
give a crap, do you?
Does that make me evil?
Yeah.
The girl's life is at stake. All
we're talking about with the guy is...
All we're talking about is the reason
you took the case, to help someone.
Too bad for them.
Too bad for you.
The reason we crave meaning
is because it makes us happy.
The first level of happiness...
I'm not going away.
The fifth level of happiness
involves creation, changing lives.
The sixth level is heroin. The
seventh level is you going away.
You're saving lives, which is
tantamount to creating lives,
but all you're taking
away from this is the game.
You don't have to listen
to them thanking you.
You don't have to change the cases
you take or even how you handle them.
You just have to know
that you made a difference.
House! You're
not... I'm not an idiot.
Move. SURGEON:
House, leave her alone.
Close her up. You
want to know why?
The room's no longer sterile.
True, but it's not the
most interesting reason.
That is not a sexy big toe.
You'd never put
that in your mouth.
What the hell does
that got to do...
I told you it was interesting,
but it gets even better.
Scurvy?
Yeah. Drink.
Like what sailors get
when they don't eat right?
Aye, aye. Your arms and leg
tissues are choked with blood.
It makes it hard to move. It also
damages your hair and toenails.
But I'm on this great diet,
lots of protein, lots of...
No vitamin C. Now drink.
Well, thank you.
And thank Doctor House.
You can send him a note.
The nurse changed his morphine.
I thought you were worried about...
It's just post-op discomfort.
He's ready to go home.
So he won't have any pain?
Eventually.
Thank you.
Everything else
will be the same.
Well, you took away his
pain, and that changes a lot.
Why don't you put him
in some sort of facility,
some place without a pool?
Yeah, I could dump him there,
except he's my husband.
He's my son's father.
Right. Kids need a dad,
someone to play catch
with, talk about girls.
You know, Mark's learning that
you don't have to abandon someone
just because... Get a dog.
I'm taking care of him for the
same reason you helped us.
Because some guy shot
you, and you hallucinated?
I have a responsibility.
So he's just an anchor, weighing
you and your family down,
sapping your energy, wasting your life?
That's the meaning you take from this?
I want to take care of him.
You enjoy this?
I can't abandon him.
So you don't want
to take care of him?
Taking care of him doesn't
fulfill you, make you happy,
but not taking care of him
would make you miserable?
Hmm.
Okay, here we go.
Okay, slowly.
I don't need your help.
I've done this a million times.
Here, lie him like that.
Do that again. Make that sound.
What was that?
That was talking.
You guys are lousy doctors.
You were in such a rush to
make the patient feel better,
you forgot to check
what was wrong.
Yoga girl walked out of here
two hours ago. You fixed her.
Not her. The other guy.
He had brain cancer.
They removed it eight years ago. His
condition's been the same ever since.
Until last night. He spoke.
What'd he say?
He grunted?
You want us to
dissect eight years
of medical history with
grunting in the differential?
Sounds good. Call
me when you're done.
You're fabricating a mystery
because you're bored.
I am not bored.
Damn it!
You didn't tell the wife
it was only a grunt?
Of course not.
'Cause then she would
never have consented to
I don't remember
you being this bitchy.
The Vicodin dulled it. In the
sober light of day, I'm a buzz-kill.
You're giving false hope to
a family that's been wrecked.
Don't torture them. Let it go.
Tell the wife it was only a grunt.
Tell her to go home.
I can't let her down like that.
I pumped her up with
too much false hope.
I stuck that primo!
How rad am I?
2002, patient had dry eyes.
Dry eyes plus a grunt.
It all makes sense. Could
be a neurological issue.
I get hay fever, I put drops in my
eyes. I don't go to a neurologist.
Dry eyes could indicate
an autonomic dysfunction.
It goes on the board.
What about coughing or boogers?
Should we include boogers?
I'm happy we're doing this.
I'd much rather do this than
lengthen some guy's tendon.
Patient's headaches increased.
Doc scanned his head, found a tumor.
You like wasting your
time? I'm learning.
To do what?
Reconsider solved cases
because you don't wanna
deal with the real world?
He's pushing where
there's nothing.
Cameron, you are
an excellent doctor.
You'll get lots of tearful
thank-yous from grateful patients.
Yeah, aren't I such a
bitch for wanting that?
No, it's not a bad thing,
but it's not why I'm here.
I took this fellowship
to learn from House.
He's teaching you
to be a masochist.
Dry eyes goes on the board.
In eight years, the patient
experienced 214 symptoms,
many of them repeated.
Any patterns?
Fever plus frequent urination
could mean prostatitis.
Or a urinary-tract infection.
White count was
normal. No infection.
If you add pain
into the mix, fever,
frequent urination could
indicate a kidney problem.
I like it.
No, creatinine and
BUN were both normal.
Not the kidney
part. The pain part.
Abdominal pain plus all that
stuff could equal a pancreatic cyst.
Perfect. You managed to pick
the one symptom he never had,
abdominal pain.
It's the first symptom
on the board, "grunt."
Grunting isn't pathognomonic
for abdominal pain.
No, the traditional diagnostic marker
is compression of the diaphragm,
vibration of the larynx,
leading to the audible sound,
"I have a pain in my abdomen."
Richard's symptoms are culled
from eight years of medical history.
They're not patterned. These are
random, individual events over time.
Illnesses have incubation periods.
Do an upper endoscopic ultrasound.
His throat will collapse.
Muscle degeneration in his
neck won't tolerate the scope.
It's an automatic trach.
You're talking about him
like he's an invalid.
We were insensitive.
Does he drool? Can he hold his neck
straight? Does he choke on his food?
His neck's fine. His
throat's not gonna collapse.
Cameron, get
consent from the wife.
Open.
I need you to swallow.
Sorry about that.
Here we go.
We're passing through the
lower esophageal sphincter
into the antrum of the stomach.
There's the tail
of the pancreas.
Looks clean.
Moving medially. The body and
the head of the pancreas look clean.
Get it out. Get it out.
It's stuck. I can't move
it. His throat's collapsed.
His vitals are all over the
place. We're losing him.
Cutting.
We trached him, endoscopically removed
the probe, and he's breathing again,
so, all in all, great idea.
Get a look at the pancreas
before the world ended?
It was clean.
Which means,
barring anything else,
meaning you, he can
go home tomorrow.
This man nearly died.
How can you discharge him?
His throat collapsed
because of what we predicted.
You stick something
down someone's throat,
they gag, spasm, which he did. It took
us a half an hour to get the thing out.
Except our patient's
throat was sedated,
which means the brain should
have sent a signal not to do anything.
This could be cancer or some
bizarre neuro-degeneration,
even a new type of vascular...
Stop it. You're enjoying this.
I find it interesting.
It's interesting
only if you're right.
If you're wrong, we're
torturing this guy to amuse you.
Half hour to remove the probe?
House.
It's not a spasm.
His throat didn't
collapse. It locked down.
The brain is supposed to tell every
muscle in the body to relax and contract
at the same time. This
muscle was only contracting,
which means the signal from
the brain was not getting through.
There are no lesions on his brain,
nothing to interrupt any orders.
All it takes is one wire down.
You have no evidence
of any wires down.
A few microtumors on the meninges,
and suddenly you're choking to death.
You want to look at
the lining of his brain?
The amount of contrast material
you need to pump up there just to see...
He'll bleed into his
brain! No, he won't.
Because that wouldn't be interesting.
You can get permission this time.
The brain is enclosed in a
sack called the meninges.
Does this mean
the cancer's back?
No. No, no, no. House.
If we found cancer, it wouldn't
be the original cancer. It'd be new.
So, what, more
surgery, more radiation.
Might not be the worst thing.
If this isn't just ancient history, then
maybe it's something we can correct.
Might even get some
brain function back.
He could get better?
No.
But understanding what
you're saying will be nice.
Maybe you could figure
out ways to communicate.
Thank God he spoke to you.
Mrs. McNeil, the test to do
this is very risky. He could die.
He's already dead.
Chase, go slow.
I've already injected
it into his spinal canal.
Next stop, his brain.
Contrast material entering
into the fourth ventricle.
No parenchymal bleeds.
Blood pressure's
high, but it's holding.
Meninges are
intact. No bleeding.
Oh, God. Foreman, get in here.
Surgeon repaired the CSF leak.
You're lucky he didn't die.
I'm lucky? He's the
one who didn't die.
We told you he'd hemorrhage.
You told me he'd bleed into
his brain, not out of his ear.
You've got to drop this.
We're missing something.
We did a dangerous test, and
something bad happened. That's all this is.
Give me a tour of the brain,
Foreman. Walk me through the scans.
1998, what happened?
Five-centimeter, grade-four
astrocytoma between the parietal...
Nothing. Next? The speck on
the superior temporal region.
It's a re-growth, benign.
The star thingy next
to the Rathke cleft?
Scar tissue from a biopsy.
House, every speck
is not a suspect.
It's years of surgeons digging
around in his head. Let him go.
Redo every blood test he's
ever had. Rescan his head.
No.
He's been sick and
suffering for eight
years. I'm not gonna
help you make it worse.
I'm not gonna help
you make it interesting.
That's okay. Foreman's
better at that stuff than you are.
We need five-millimeter cuts through
the occipital and hypothalamic regions.
No.
How many millimeters?
I can help him.
That's it? That's your argument?
It seems like a good one.
If I thought for a second you wanted
to help him, you'd have carte blanche.
You're doing this
because it's fun.
Does nobody in this hospital
have anything better to
talk about than my motives?
My motives have nothing
to do with the case.
Your motives have everything
to do with your judgment.
For the first time in years, I
got no opiates in my body.
Now you question my judgment?
Twenty-four times a year, you
come storming into my office,
spouting that you can help someone,
only you never say those words.
You say something like,
"His pancreas is gonna explode
because his brain is on fire."
You come here with
medicine, not with platitudes.
I didn't wanna bore
you with the details.
There are no details.
You have a hunch.
House, you don't use hunches.
You always have reasons.
This hospital doesn't exist
for your whims. I'm sorry.
As of 7:00 a.m. tomorrow morning,
I'm sending your patient home.
The answer's no.
Cuddy called 30 seconds after you
left and said you'd try an end-around.
My leg hurt.
How bad?
Enough that I'm telling you.
Did it go away?
Ached for a while.
First time I've felt anything
there since the surgery.
But it went away?
It was muscular. There
was some cramping.
What are you smiling about?
You're 40-something years old.
You've been running God
knows how many miles a day,
fallen a hundred times off that skateboard,
and you're shocked to have some soreness?
Just give me a prescription.
For Vicodin?
House, people get
aching joints, cramps.
They put on an ice pack.
They take some ibuprofen.
I know what the pangs
of middle age feel like.
No, you don't because
you've been stuffing Vicodin
every five minutes since
you turned middle-aged.
The surgery didn't work.
Don't play me.
You think this is a scam?
I think you want me
to feel sorry for you
and either do the end-around
on Cuddy or give you the drugs.
Either way, you get the
high you think you need.
House, your surgery
worked. You're fine. It's
just gonna take time
for it to feel good.
Circumventricular
system senses cytokines
released in the early stages
of the immune response,
but CVOS releases prostaglandins
that reset the hypothalamic
set point upward
unless it's countered by antipyretic
therapy, so, yeah, his brain is on fire.
The suicide attempt
was not a suicide attempt.
He drove that
wheelchair into the pool
because he couldn't
regulate his body temperature.
He had a hypothalamic
dysregulation.
And you discovered this when
you stepped into the university pool?
Fountain. I can cure him.
Cure him!
Even if the fountain
proved anything,
fixing hypothalamic dysregulation
isn't gonna regenerate brain.
No, but if the scar tissue
on his hypothalamus
is resting against
the pituitary,
the adrenals would shut
down. Addison's disease.
You didn't see any scar tissue
on his MRI, his CT scans...
His brain is functional.
His temperature's normal.
There is nothing wrong with
his hypothalamus or his pituitary!
I can make him walk. I can
make him talk. This is a wild guess
that came to you because
you were sweating.
Inject him with cortisol. The guy
will have sex with his wife again.
He'll hug his kid again. Hopefully,
that's the combination he was using.
It'd be a shame if I
had cured a pedophile.
You're smiling.
That's a bad sign.
You're high.
I told you, I haven't had
anything in three months.
This is as high as you get,
a theory that ties your
case up in a neat little bow,
but you don't have a lick
of substantiating proof.
Your decision doesn't make any sense.
There is no risk to a cortisol injection.
If I'm wrong, big deal.
He goes home a vegetable
like he already is, but if I'm right...
This is not about downsides
or risk management.
It is a big deal for you to
understand the word "No."
I'm sorry, House.
He's on his way out of here.
I figured you'd be on your
scooter, racing down the halls
to stab the patient in
the neck with cortisol.
She was right to say no.
I had no objective reason
to think that I was right.
Just needed the puzzle.
Hold on a sec.
Is everything all right?
Yeah, it's just
something I forgot.
What's that?
This is cortisol, and
it's to fight infection.
Want to hold onto that?
Let's put a bandage on it.
Is he okay?
Yes.
Can we go now?
You can go.
Excuse me.
Richard. Richard.
Dad, you okay?
Richard? Richard! Richard!
Richard!
Richard.
Richard, you're standing.
Thank you.
He got up.
I have to go tell House.
No. Cuddy, you can't tell him.
I have to tell
him. He was right.
Why did you do it? Why did
you think he might be right?
Because he's House.
Medically, what made
you think he was right?
Nothing. He got lucky.
That's all that happened.
Telling him no was a good thing
because next time, he won't
get lucky. He'll kill someone.
Just because he was right
doesn't mean he wasn't wrong.
I see him every
day. I can't just...
Everybody lies.