Autism, a mental condition
characterized by
difficulty in communicating.
Does it sound like I'm
describing a surgeon?
You saved his life.
I'm Dr. Shaun Murphy.
Never forget, you're the smart
one. And I'm proud of you, Shaun.
My brother went to heaven...
In front of my eyes.
He's got a serious deficit.
We hire Shaun, and we give
hope to those people with limitations
that those limitations are
not what they think they are.
That they do have a shot.
If Shaun doesn't live up to
everything I know he can do,
I will resign my position
as president of this hospital.
Where to?
San Jose Saint
Bonaventure Hospital.
I'm a surgical resident.
Today's my first full day.
I meant floor.
Oh. Ground floor.
I'm taking the bus.
This is Mitchell Brand,
55 years old, post-op day one
from a radical prostatectomy.
Morning, Mitchell.
I'm Dr. Melendez.
These are my residents,
Dr. Browne and Dr. Kalu.
Your surgery went perfectly.
Yeah? Am I ever
gonna walk again?
Yes, of course.
This is Mitchell Brand,
I reviewed his chart.
He's 55 years old, from Chicago,
divorced with two children.
You did a radical
prostatectomy on him yesterday.
There are many possible complications
but none related to motor neurons.
There is no chance you
won't be able to walk.
He... He wasn't
worried about his legs.
Oh, yes.
There's a significant
chance of impotence.
Dr. Murphy, you're late.
The bus was late.
The schedule was
clear. They post it online.
But the 4 bus was
late, which meant...
- You're late.
- Five minutes. We've all been...
On your first day, no less. It is
your responsibility to be here.
If you are not, you have
failed in your responsibility,
- which makes it your fault.
- Okay. How can it be my fault?
I did nothing wrong. The bus...
This is gonna work out great.
The board clearly made
the right choice in hiring you.
Thank you.
Dr. Melendez, we've got an
emergent consult in the ER.
You should be fine if you leave
it alone for a couple of days.
Four days of indigestion,
bloating, constipation, and nausea.
And a lot of pain, apparently.
Did you give her morphine?
Yeah, 10 milligrams. It
hasn't touched her pain.
You have time to get a CT?
Yeah. That's why I called you.
It's very big.
Yes, it is.
What are we looking at?
It's definitely abutting the
aorta and the left kidney.
Renal angiomyolipoma?
Do you see an
extensive blood supply?
No.
Maybe some kind of neurogenic
tumor. Or maybe a lymphoma.
She has a sarcoma,
a malignant tumor.
"Malignant"?
That means it's
killing me, right?
- Yes.
- Not necessarily.
We're just
speculating right now.
No, it's definitely malignant.
If it weren't malignant...
- Please stop saying "malignant."
- Shall we talk outside?
Give her more morphine.
As much as she wants.
Okay.
Hang in there.
You scared her.
- You didn't need to be so blunt.
- Why?
Her prognosis is terminal without
immediate medical intervention.
Isn't that scary?
Well, that fear
does her no good.
Does she have a
malignant sarcoma?
Are we gonna be
doing a laparotomy?
We'd need intra-operative
staging with a biopsy,
extensive dissection
of the retroperitoneum,
and excision of the mass
with wide, clear margins.
I want in.
You do know you're
drooling, right?
About cutting open
a 40-year-old woman.
Real person. Right
behind that door.
It's called bedside manner.
No such thing as
outside-the-door manner.
It is exciting, Claire.
We'd be saving a life.
And we'd be learning.
- See?
- Dr. Browne, you're my number two.
With all due respect, Doctor...
Comments that start that way
rarely come across that way.
I was going to say
that's an excellent call.
Thank you. Jared,
prep the surgical team.
Sir, what do I do?
- Scut work.
- What's scut work?
Today I'm gonna need my
surgeons to have no distractions.
So I'm gonna need you to
handle those distractions.
All the work they do every
day that they hate doing...
You're handling it for them.
Make sure they know we still
need a consent on that one.
- Am I being punished for something?
- No.
Okay.
So that's it?
You just accept my
answer at face value?
Why?
You're very arrogant.
Arrogant people don't
think they need to lie.
So, you must be
doing this to teach me.
I look forward to
learning from scut work.
Say, "Ah."
- How long will this be?
- Seven minutes.
Without any complications,
it takes seven minutes
to do a discharge
examination properly.
Dr. Dunsmuir has already cleared
him to go and we need the bed.
Okay. Protocol requires that the
surgical department also clears him.
You have an ear infection.
Yes, that's why he's here.
My hearing's been a little
muffled and I've had some ringing.
They gave him amoxicillin,
and we're sending him home.
Which is why you're
here. To send him home.
I'd like an MRI of the head
and internal auditory meatus.
I'm not being discharged?
What do you think is wrong?
I'll tell you when
I know for sure.
I don't wanna scare you.
Shaun. What are
you doing down here?
I'm waiting for her to fart.
Flatulence. But I'm using the
word "fart" in front of the patient
to be more casual.
But you're the
president of the hospital,
so I'll say "flatulence" to you.
Well, I appreciate that.
Why are you doing that?
She had her deviated septum
repaired. Before we can release her,
we have to be sure she isn't
suffering from postoperative ileus.
This is what Dr. Melendez feels
you'll be most useful doing today?
Waiting for farts?
I'm not just waiting for farts.
- Thank goodness.
- I'm doing all the scut work.
Well, welcome to
your surgical residency.
Thank you.
There. I think that was it.
I don't think so.
I'll wait a little longer.
This is important.
The procedure is
called a laparotomy.
Yeah, your heart sounds good.
So, we make a long incision
down the middle of your abdomen...
- Expose the tumor...
- Am I going to die?
Dr. Melendez is the best
surgeon I have ever seen...
Can this all wait?
You have a very serious
condition. It's not advisable to...
Just a couple of weeks. My son
is getting married next weekend.
They look very happy.
After the initial incision...
They've been planning this for
months. If they have to reschedule...
Well, this is complicated
surgery, but if all goes well,
recovery's pretty easy.
No need to reschedule anything.
And if it doesn't?
If it doesn't go well?
My husband died in a car
accident a couple of years ago.
Mark is our only child.
I can't die right before
his wedding. I can't.
You're not gonna die.
You will be at the
wedding. Looking beautiful.
Okay.
You're not supposed to make
promises like that, Dr. Browne.
I told her what
she needed to hear.
Officially, our legal department's
policy is to tell the ugly truth.
The uglier the better.
Is that what you did?
- I don't think that's what you did.
- Yeah, well, it's a dumb policy.
She needs to have the surgery.
Scaring her would change nothing.
Right. Because a much better policy
would be to lie to all of our patients
whenever it makes
you feel better.
No, it doesn't make me feel
better. It makes her feel better.
I'm pathetic.
- What?
- I am pathetic.
And here's my thinking,
so just bear with me
because it kind of
insults both of us.
You met that woman an
hour ago and you lied to her.
A pity lie because you
obviously care about her.
A pity lie that has absolutely
zero upside for you.
But I can't make you,
the world's softest
touch, care about me.
Hey.
I need a consult.
You have a question about this?
This patient's
perfectly healthy.
There's not even any
artifact on these images.
Yeah. Which, in turn, raises
an interesting medical question.
Why the hell did this
patient get an MRI?
I don't know
anything about this.
Yeah. Someone on your team
ordered it. It's your responsibility,
which makes it your fault.
How did you...
It's my department, it's
my job to know everything.
Well, then, since
I work for you,
doesn't that make all
this actually your fault?
Sorry. I stopped listening
after "I work for you."
- Does that hurt?
- Yes.
- How much are we paying for this?
She has a tummy ache.
That's what they do, they ache.
She's just trying to
get out of school. Again.
Where do you think
she learned that from?
You don't think she
hears you calling in sick
to work right before
you go golfing?
I like school.
Me, too. What did you
eat for dinner last night?
- Cereal.
- I thought you made meatloaf.
I did. And it got cold while
we were waiting for you.
I want D-dimer,
lactate, and amylase...
What tests are you ordering?
D-dimer, lactate, and amylase.
- For a tummy ache, hmm?
- Yes.
I'm concerned it may be...
Shall we talk outside?
- Told you something was wrong.
- You're happy she might be sick?
- I'm happy you're wrong.
- Yeah, let's talk outside.
Have they been bickering
like that the whole time?
I didn't notice.
They aren't sick.
Yeah, they're what
we call a vector.
A carrier. A cause of disease.
- You mean the parents?
- Yeah.
That little girl
has a tummy ache
because Mommy and
Daddy won't stop fighting.
This isn't a medical
issue. Send them home.
It could be intestinal malrotation,
which could quickly become fatal.
And every patient in this
hospital could have malaria,
but that doesn't mean
we're gonna go around
testing for every condition
we think they could have.
For example, that MRI you ordered
on the guy with the ear infection?
- Nice call, genius.
- Thank you.
I was being sarcastic.
It's normal. He's healthy.
Send him home, too.
- Why are you smiling?
- Because you're right.
So, you thought he was making
a mistake and didn't say anything?
You just stood by
watching, taking notes,
while he wasted
everybody's time?
Is that your job?
In my experience, doctors
don't listen to nurses.
And they only talk
to us to lecture us
when they figure we
screwed something up.
From now on, you don't run
any tests you don't have to run.
How do I know if a test is
needed until after I run it?
She'll tell you. Today,
she's your boss.
I could never eat
before surgery.
Puke? I could do that.
I get cranky if I don't eat.
I hear Shaun made the call.
He's an excellent diagnostician.
You should get him
a job in radiology.
He doesn't wanna be a
radiologist, he wants to be a surgeon.
That's what we hired him to be.
That's what I worked
damn hard to hire him to be.
Not a glorified orderly.
Every resident does scut work.
So you're treating
him like anybody else?
- Are you?
- Yes. Yes, I am.
He more than earned
the right to be here.
He has had to get
past people like you
and their prejudices
every step of the way.
- "Prejudices"?
- Yeah, prejudices.
Do you have any idea how many
patients he scared the crap out of today?
How many wasted
tests he ordered?
- So teach him.
- I'm doing that.
I'm teaching you both
that he doesn't belong.
Okay.
You're gonna make me
pull rank, I will pull rank.
This is my hospital.
But it's my team.
You can't tell me
how to run my team.
Hey. How are you doing?
What's the point of sarcasm?
Um... Uh, I...
Well, I guess
sometimes it's a way of
critiquing people in a way that's
funny, so they don't feel quite so bad.
Isn't it just lying?
Well, it's not lying, because
people know you're lying.
I'm not good at that.
You may remember
me from last year.
We sell chocolate
bars every year
to pay for our class
trip to Mount Rushmore.
Okay.
But this year we're not
going to Mount Rushmore.
Because Kenny can't
go. He's got cancer.
So, Samantha had the idea that
if he can't go, none of us would go,
and we all thought
that was a great idea.
So we're gonna have a
party at the hospital for him.
There are two
Kennys in your class.
Is it Kenny L or Kenny M?
No one's sick.
You mean you lied?
- You aren't supposed to lie.
- Yeah.
And you and me aren't supposed
to starve. We need money for food.
- Was any of that true?
- Yeah.
We're not going to
Mount Rushmore.
I can't discharge people if I
think they might still be sick.
Of course not. Why would you?
Dr. Melendez made Nurse
Fryday my boss today.
Should I speak to Dr. Glassman?
No.
What did you think this job was?
- To save people's lives.
- No.
I mean, yeah, sometimes
we do save lives.
But the job... It's doing
whatever Melendez asks us to do.
Paging Dr. Browne. Paging
Dr. Browne to the OR.
I'm Dr. Claire Browne.
I'm First Assist today,
and I'll be leading the
time out. Patient's name?
Stephanie Willis.
Scheduled surgery?
Excision of an indeterminate
retroperitoneal tumor.
We don't anticipate any
complications with the surgery.
Thank you, Dr. Browne.
- Ten-blade.
Let's remove a tumor.
No.
It might be infected.
- It's not.
- There is some discoloration.
He's 82 years old.
Everything is discolored.
Once we get through the
muscle layer, proceed carefully.
Blood pressure, 120 over 70.
Heart rate, 60.
She's holding steady.
I've opened the fascia.
You kept your puke?
Yeah, I thought
you'd wanna see it.
It looks like puke.
No. No, no. It's not
the regular color.
- Your puke has a regular color?
- Yeah.
It is a bit of an unusual color.
We could order some...
- I'm sending you home.
- You're sure?
It's safe for me to go home?
I don't know what to say.
You'll learn. By doing.
Hi.
My brother said there's a kid named
Kenny and he's sick and there might...
You should give us money.
So, am I okay?
Am I okay?
According to all hospital rules and
direct instructions given to me, yes.
But...
Whoa.
We need better
exposure of this tumor.
Now, let's get the
deep Balfour in here.
Deep Balfour retractor.
Let's get this thing open. I've
got to see where it's safe to cut.
I can't see anywhere where the
tumor hasn't encased her arteries.
Claire, tell me
you got something.
I've got nothing. This tumor is way
bigger than it looked on the scans.
I... I can't even see her aorta.
That's a problem.
Is that the girl with
the bickering parents?
Didn't we send her
home? Four hours ago?
Dr. Murphy? Dr. Melendez
needs you in surgery.
That won't be necessary.
The tumor has entirely encased
the large abdominal arteries.
That's very bad.
If it's in the artery walls,
it's going to be impossible
to cut out without killing her.
You should get a biopsy to
determine where the margins are.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
I was being sarcastic. Again.
Oh, I see, because you
already know everything I said,
and you already sent
a biopsy to the lab?
Yes. 'Cause I'm a doctor too.
Yes. But you need me?
Yeah. I need you to run down
to the lab and hurry them along.
I'm Dr. Shaun Murphy.
I'm a surgical resident.
Dr. Melendez sent you a biopsy.
When will the results be ready?
When I get to it.
It's very important.
They're all very important.
Let me see the
other test orders.
I'll tell you which ones
are most important
and you can do
them in that order.
I'll be honest and fair.
That is not the
way that it works.
Now go wait your turn.
Do it again.
- Get the hell away from me, you moron.
- Let's get out of here.
Wait, wait, wait.
If you wanna get anything in life,
Shaun, there's one thing you gotta do.
Never be afraid.
You're the moron!
If you don't do
Dr. Melendez's test right now,
I will throw a rock
through your window.
Well, I wouldn't want that.
Go have a seat.
Your results will be
ready in 15 minutes.
You got a minute?
I have a patient lying in the
OR waiting for lab results,
and I'm sitting here, trying to figure
out what the hell I'm gonna do next
and I don't like any
of my options. So...
Yeah, unfortunately,
it seems I do.
Okay. We can talk another time.
Glassman talked to you.
I don't have a problem
with an autistic doctor.
No, you just have a problem
with one working for you.
Really? That's how you see me?
- Let's not make this personal.
- You're accusing me of prejudice.
I have a problem with a doctor who
has a problem with communication.
Okay. Let's make this personal.
Who do you respect
at this hospital?
You and Glassman.
And who do you not respect?
It doesn't bother you that it looks
like you're on the wrong team?
If the tumor hasn't invaded
into the arterial walls,
we could create a
plane of dissection.
Well, if it's a
non-invasive liposarcoma,
we can work it off
from the outside.
Blunt section, tissue forceps.
Peel it off, piece by piece.
It's a leiomyosarcoma.
Well, that sucks.
- Yes, it's sad.
- The surgery's impossible.
Well, might as well wake her up.
Let her know she has
three months to live.
Offer palliative care.
The surgery isn't impossible.
Just very, very, very difficult.
Yes. In the sense that
we'll be operating blind.
Yes, because the left
kidney is in the way.
The healthy left kidney.
Both kidneys are healthy,
Jared. She only needs one.
Without the left one,
it's theoretically possible
to access the
tumor and remove it.
You're suggesting we cut
out a perfectly healthy organ
- just to get a better view?
- Yes.
- But she might die anyway?
- Yes, quite probably.
I have to go. I
have a boil to lance.
I mean, that's a brilliant,
very, very, very terrible idea.
Close her up and wake her up.
Who wants to join me when I tell
her she has six weeks left to live?
There is one possibility.
If we remove the left kidney,
we might be able to get
a good enough view to
successfully remove the mass.
Take out a healthy kidney to
get a better view? That's insane.
A good view is half the
battle in any operation.
Most likely outcome is we'd be depriving
her of what little time she has left.
But if we succeed...
You wanna do this 'cause it's
exciting. You wanna be a hero.
But if you fail,
this woman dies.
She misses her son's wedding.
Well, that's the
issue, isn't it?
You promised this
woman she'll be okay.
She had to do the surgery. I
might as well tell her good things.
The reason we don't make
patients promises isn't just for legal.
Jared's right, your
judgment is compromised.
- I still think...
- But you're not objective.
Who the hell is?
We should at least wake her up,
explain what we found,
what we're hoping to do,
and get a new consent.
What we're hoping to do is exactly
what you told her we were going to do.
Remove that tumor.
The only thing we'd be explaining
is why you undersold the risks.
We're doing the surgery.
And Jared, you're
my new number two.
- Mayos.
Going to open the fascia
and expose the kidney.
- You clamp the renal hilum.
- Clamp.
Clamp.
We just cut off the blood supply
to a perfectly healthy kidney.
If we needed color commentary,
I would have hired
Jeff Van Gundy.
Shaun, I believe
you've met Trevor.
Yes, I sent him home.
Yes, well, he didn't go home.
He actually came to the
president of the hospital instead.
He said you sent him home even
though you thought he was sick.
I specifically never said that.
I made sure not to say that.
- No. No. What the hell does that mean?
- What does that mean, Shaun?
- Am I healthy?
- Probably.
You're a doctor, you're
supposed to know.
No, we're not. Nobody
knows anything for sure.
Anybody could drop dead
of a heart attack at any time.
Who is this guy? Am I... Am
I gonna have a heart attack?
Shaun has some difficulty
with certain social interactions...
- But if he says...
- I don't give a crap what he says.
What do you say? Am I healthy?
I've reviewed your chart and I
can say with complete confidence
that you are in peak
physical condition.
Thank God.
Shaun, people need reassurance.
I told him he was safe to
go home. I was very clear.
With your words. Your actions
said something completely different.
No, they didn't. My actions
were completely silent.
When you reassure someone,
they have to receive it.
You have to gauge whether
they actually are reassured.
You understand?
When did you
review Trevor's chart?
I didn't.
It's not really a lie. If you
say that he is safe to go home,
then I know for a fact
that he's safe to go home.
I sent a girl home today.
How often do people develop
stomach issues because of their brain?
Based on my personal
experience, every single day.
I want D-dimer, lactate, and
amylase for a 10-year-old girl,
Martine LaDuff.
She might have a tummy
ache caused by stress.
Or she might not.
- Hi, Shaun.
- Hi, Carly.
That's a lot of tests
for an upset stomach.
- You could get in trouble.
- That's definitely true.
Remove the kidney.
Okay.
Let's get in there with
some suction, Claire,
so we can get a better view
of what we're dealing with.
There it is.
It's a mess.
Yes, it is.
But now it's a mess we can see.
Everything is
within normal range.
Slightly elevated
lactate and amylase.
And she's very small. Normal should
be lower. Normal should be lower.
What do you think she has?
Thank you.
What the hell? It's after 1:00.
I ran tests. The results
were ambiguous.
I think Martine has
intestinal malrotation
and that a volvulus
has occurred.
"Ambiguous" tests told you this?
It's a genetic condition.
The symptoms are
very similar to stress.
Call us in the morning.
Okay. She may not
be alive in the morning.
Does your boss know you're here?
No, I think he'd be upset
with me for being here.
I am not waking my daughter up
in the middle of a school
night because of some freak.
And you don't need to
call me in the morning,
because I'll be calling
your boss in the morning.
Were you being sarcastic?
- How hard is it to get rid of someone?
- I told him...
You're right, I'm weird.
Part of my weirdness
is that I perseverate.
That means I keep
thinking about things.
So I will keep knocking on your
door until I know Martine is okay.
Martine.
Martine?
- Martine?
- Martine, you need to wake up.
- Honey...
- Martine?
She vomited.
- I can't wake her.
- I'll call 911.
No. There is no time.
- Do you have a car?
- Yeah.
Shaun! What's
wrong? What's wrong?
Hey. Hey! You called
me. What's wrong?
Hey, look at me. Look at me!
What's... You don't have to
say the whole thing, okay?
Just one thing, okay?
- One thing.
- My brother...
Hold on, Shaun.
Hold on now. Hold on.
Her pulse is too weak
to perfuse her organs.
What? What does that...
- Jerry...
- Please hurry.
Patient is a 10-year-old female.
She has bradycardia
with hypovolemic shock.
She needs oxygen, IV adrenaline
and a litre of saline
wide open, please.
Coming through!
Her pulse is better.
She needs an ultrasound.
That is it.
Whoa.
- I think you got it all.
- You "think"?
No, you definitely did, I
just can't quite believe it.
It was your idea. You
should have more confidence.
Nice work, Doctor.
There.
The small bowel is twisted around
the superior mesenteric artery.
Martine needs
surgery immediately.
We need to confirm
with Dr. Melendez.
No, Dr. Melendez is in surgery.
Part of Martine's bowel is
dying and killing her with it.
No. You cannot make
these calls on your own.
Dr. Melendez was very clear.
He was very clear.
It's past midnight, which
means it's tomorrow.
Which means you're
no longer my boss.
Is this the OR scheduler?
Yes, this is Dr. Murphy.
Prepare an OR for surgery.
Ten-blade.
I'll take it from here.
Nice diagnosis. I'll
handle the repair work.
- Is Stephanie okay?
- Yes.
Jared had an excellent
idea and she's gonna be fine.
- Light.
Would you like me to assist?
Pretty basic. I think I can
take this one on my own.
Go home. Get some sleep.
Let him stay.
Dr. Andrews,
I believe our opinions on the
wisdom of hiring Dr. Murphy...
That battle is lost.
Shaun is here and
we have to accept it
and we will treat him
like any other resident.
- Sir, it's my team.
- And it's my department.
Dr. Murphy.
Back on suction.
Congratulations.
Suction ready.
I am gonna get a drink. I am
way too wound up to sleep.
You care to join me?
- For either?
- Don't think so.
Seriously? We were just
part of something amazing.
We reached into that
woman and we healed her.
And you're what, cranky?
Maybe you could learn
something from me.
Like what? To steal credit?
Make yourself a hero
with Shaun's idea?
No, but I fought for it. I
went out on a limb for it.
I deserve credit for that.
Why didn't you rat me out
as soon as I brought it up?
It seemed beside the point.
No, you didn't rat me out 'cause
you thought the idea was crazy.
You would let me take the fall.
Is that fair?
My idea if it fails, but
Shaun's if it succeeds?
But I'll tell you what,
I'll accept that you're right.
I'll apologize to
the whole team.
If you prove to me that
you're not a hypocrite.
How am I supposed to
prove something like that?
Our patient's about to
come out of anesthesia.
Tell her the truth.
When she wakes up
and hears what we did,
how we miraculously
saved her life,
be honest with
her, about credit.
Tell her you
didn't want to do it.
Tell her that you wanted
to send her home to die.
I hear you got Shaun off
scut and back into surgery.
I heard you tried.
You're welcome.
Just a friendly warning. I
know you have no interest
in helping Shaun.
You figure you give him a little
authority, he'll screw something up
and then you will be done with
him, and then you'll be done with me.
You're right about
me. I am getting old
and maybe a little emotional.
Maybe I over-committed.
But you're wrong about Shaun.
He's gonna handle
anything you throw at him.
Either way, if he succeeds,
I'm the guy who just
backed him. And if he fails,
I'm the president.
Everything went great.
Thank you. Thank you. Thank you.
- There were complications.
- But I'm okay?
- Yeah. But the surgery...
- I don't care.
You saved me. Thank you.
My son's going to be here soon.
I told him you said it would
be okay, but he flew in anyway.
You saved me.
You're gonna be a beautiful
mother of the groom.
Go on in, take a
bow. You've earned it.
Why does it matter
who gets credit?
It matters because the
people who get credit...
They don't have to do scut work.
Dr. Murphy, thank you so much.
Thank you.