There's no milk.
Oh.
Damn, I forgot.
All I ask is for you
to get the groceries.
And I forgot. I'm sorry.
You know, it's not
like I'm sitting around.
I'm looking for a job.
Well, now we're gonna
have to stop for coffee
before you drop me off at work.
Even good marriages fail.
One minute you're
standing on solid ground.
The next minute, you're not.
Baby's up. You change
the diaper. I'll get the bottle.
And there's always
two versions...
Yours...
And theirs.
So they're living
together at your house,
Kepner says.
This is my house.
Did she say how they're doing?
No. I didn't ask.
I don't care.
You...
Want me to ask, for you?
No. I don't care, either.
Hand me a rock.
Okay. I'm... I can't.
I can't have sex
when there's a baby
from a broken home
in the next room.
I...
Both versions start
the same way, though.
Both start with two
people falling in love.
Yeah, you can.
Just look at me.
It's just you and me.
Dude, you snore like a truck.
I'm gonna put a
note in your chart,
'cause you mix apnea
with your heart crap,
and you're dead
before you're 60.
Excuse me.
Hey. Hey.
You guys going to
that breakfast thing?
Yeah, after we drop
her off at day care.
Oh, my God. Look at
her. She's so beautiful.
Oh, oh. Hey.
Hey, you are so
beautiful... Here you go.
And you've got the best mommies.
Did you know that? Yes, you do.
Oh, you do.
Oh, you so do.
Hello. Hello, hello, hello.
What is wrong with her?
She's getting laid. She's
unnaturally cheerful.
Peekaboo.
A month ago you were in med
school being taught by doctors,
and now you are the doctors.
Will we be going
into an OR today?
Oh, I hope so.
Oh! New interns.
I hate new interns.
Seriously? Ugh. Mmm-hmm.
I love new interns.
They're the future,
the next generation,
filled with hope and
promise, innovation.
Wow.
The sex with Henry
must be really good.
Earth-shattering.
Shh.
Not even Yang's
gonna get me down.
No, she's not.
Good morning, and welcome
to your fifth year of residency.
Oh, morning. Morning.
See you guys up there. I
hear there's an omelet station.
You have a good day.
Okay, now. Bye-bye.
Okay, um, I'll see you
later at the thing. Okay.
She slept through the night...
Hey, Zola. And ate like a champ.
I missed you. Can we talk?
I want to spend time with Zola
before I drop her off at day care.
Are you gonna call Glen today?
I don't know, you know...
The guy is an ass.
Do I really want
to work for him?
Maybe you should
stop being so choosy.
Well, I just got laid off
four months ago. All right?
I mean, these things take time.
It's all about pursuing leads
and making connections.
I know how a person
gets a job, Danny.
I have one, remember?
Good morning,
and welcome to your
final year of residency.
Um...
This breakfast is the one time
when all the fifth years
and the attendings
will be in the same room.
So use your time
wisely, residents.
Find a mentor,
ask questions, get
advice on your futures.
And I see you're already
chatting away, so that's good.
Just carry on.
Hey. Dr. Bailey,
how did you do it?
I put down the
English muffin first,
then the bacon, then
the eggs. Oh, no...
Now some people may
be surprised by this method,
thinking you put the
bacon on top of the eggs,
and those people
would be right because...
You see what I'm doing?
Bam! An extra layer
of bacon right on top.
Then you put on the
other half of the muffin.
And there you go. That's
a breakfast sandwich.
No, no, uh, I mean,
how did you get people to
listen to you as Chief Resident?
Dr. Kepner, I am eating.
Leave me alone with my food.
Figure it out on your own. Uh...
Did he talk to you?
No, he won't even look at me.
You tampered
with his clinical trial.
He thinks that's
kind of unforgivable.
It was for Adele and
the chief. I know you...
You regret that you messed up
his trial but not what you did, I know.
You don't have to
defend yourself to me.
I'm kind of...
Unforgivable myself, remember?
But you're not.
Not yet, at least.
Have you told him?
Well...
I call him, he doesn't pick up.
He sees me, he walks away.
Okay, I'm not gonna yell,
"I didn't get the abortion
yet" down the hallway.
Well, so are you going
to go through with it,
or are we gonna sit there
again and not get the abortion?
Tonight. 6:00. I'm doing it.
Oh. Gotta go suck up to Teddy.
You want plastics?
I don't see it.
Is this about Lexie? 'Cause I
thought you were good with that.
This isn't about sex.
It's about medicine.
Then I don't understand.
You're a good surgeon.
Not a great surgeon,
which is why I was surprised
Lexie was even into you.
But this isn't about Lexie.
Nope.
How's she doing, by the way?
Wow.
"Oh, God. What
is she doing here?"
I don't... What?
Is what you're thinking, right?
I mean, you thought that I
would run away to Germany
and you wouldn't
have to see me again,
which was a relief,
I mean, after all the drama that
we've been through in the last year.
I'm right. Tell me I'm right.
I... Okay, so here's the deal.
I'm here and I'm in a happy
place and I'm done with drama.
So if you want to
learn, I want to teach.
Great. Yay.
Alex, this is serious.
If you want the Peds
Fellowship next year,
you're gonna have to earn it.
I just brought over a bunch
of sick kids from Africa.
Well, did you publish
an article about it?
Because all the people
applying for Peds Fellowships,
they've all been published.
You're already getting resumes?
Yes, and you're way behind.
Listen, I hate to kick a
guy when he's down, but...
I know. Who's
down? I'm not down.
Everybody hates you because
you narced on a fellow surgeon.
You're a pariah.
You're living in the hospital, and
you look like a bum and you've...
Got really bad breath.
Really, really bad.
Do you need me to go on? I...
No, I'm good.
Oh! Look, here's the chief!
Chief, is there anything
you'd like to say
as we embark on our
final year of residency?
You all know what you're doing.
Just don't kill anyone.
Uh, Meredith, can I
see you in my office?
Well, that was
very inspirational.
Thank you, Chief.
Nobody gets married
thinking it's gonna fail.
Well, you're the one who
needed the big wedding.
What is that supposed to mean?
It means, if we still
had our savings,
my being laid off wouldn't
be such a big deal.
No, we decided on that together.
We both wanted that wedding.
No, we didn't.
You and your mother are the...
Stop the car. Calm down.
I mean it, Danny.
You're being crazy.
What, are you gonna
walk to work from here?
What the hell are you doing?
Stop the car!
You think yours is the
one that's gonna make it.
Derek's refusing to
work with me, isn't he?
The board met this morning.
They feel that a suspension
would send the wrong message.
They feel that what you
did disgraced the hospital.
The profession.
I'm sorry.
I did everything I could.
So what are you saying?
You're fired,
effective immediately.
You're no longer a
doctor at Seattle Grace.
And so it always
comes as a shock...
The moment when
you realize it's over.
You walk away,
and I swear, that's it.
All right, I am not
gonna chase after you.
You get out of this
car and we are done.
Aah!
Susannah!
Whoa! Oh!
One minute you're
standing on solid ground.
The next minute you're not.
We're going to the scene
of an onsite amputation
woman's trapped under her car.
You guys are gonna
get swamped with bodies.
Kepner, you're in
charge till I get back.
Yes, sir. Have fun.
At an amputation?
Uh, I meant good luck.
You know what? There's
bound to be piles of head trauma.
Derek's gonna
have to talk to you.
I got fired.
What?
The chief fired me.
You son of a bitch.
I mean, are you happy now?
'Cause this is all
because of you.
You and your big, fat, stupid mouth!
- Get off!
Kepner, control your people.
Stop! Stop! All your fault!
Get off. There's no hitting.
No hitting. Would
you stop right now?
Ow. Ow. Ow. Ow.
You going to the scene? Yes.
Wait, wait. I didn't tell you
you could go. I need you here.
42-year-old female. Lost
consciousness en route.
Unable to get airway
secondary to tracheal injury.
Last BP is 89 over 60.
Don't worry. We'll
figure something out.
Make sure there is a crike tray
set up with the intubation kit.
Yes, Doctor.
Come on. You can't
be here. You need to go.
It's not stable. Get
away from there.
Dr. Torres? Yeah, hi.
Dr. Hunt?
Karen Lorenz, in charge
of search and rescue.
We're still pulling
victims out of the debris,
but we have a couple,
Danny and Susannah Wilson,
stuck down there.
He has a head wound
and his ankle's messed up,
but I don't see any
other obvious injuries.
We could potentially
bring him up,
but he won't leave
without his wife,
and her leg is
stuck under the car.
Take it easy.
You'll be all right.
I hope you've got me
with a decent resident.
I'm not babysitting any
first-day first-years today.
Yep, I got you with Meredith.
Coming through. Wait.
No, that's not gonna...
That's okay. Not a
problem. I can fix this.
Jackson, can I get
you with Bailey today?
I'm already with Sloan. Sorry.
Uh, okay. Yang! Yang.
Can I get you to... No.
Okay. Um.
Sorry, hang on.
Let me just, um...
Just figure this out.
Hey, Grey. You're
with me. Yes, ma'am.
Uh, okay, great. There we go.
Dr. Kepner, three
more coming in.
Okay.
It was a water
main break on 3rd.
Probably been going on for
weeks, and it just gave way.
Here you go. Thanks.
We've got a vitals monitor and
a camera, so we have a visual.
Danny, can you hear me?
She's not talking anymore.
You gotta get down
here. We need help.
Danny, Danny, I'm Dr. Hunt.
Can you read out for me the
top three numbers on the monitor?
87.
63.
122.
BP's 87 over 63. She's shocky.
How do we get down to her?
You don't. It's too unstable.
The whole thing would cave
in if we sent you down there.
By the time we get it shored up
enough to get someone down there,
she'll be dead for sure.
I thought that's why we're
here, for the amputation.
You're gonna
talk him through it.
You want him to
cut off his wife's leg?
Hey, you guys, I
think she's dying.
Get down here!
Please hurry. Hurry!
Dr. Yang, can you tell me why
you entered the pleura
with a Kelly clamp?
Why? What's wrong? Am I too low?
Do you suspect a
traumatic herniation?
No, no. I just want
to know your thinking.
'Cause that's how
you put a chest tube in.
Why? What do you mean, why?
So you don't kill the
person when you do it wrong.
Well, tell me like I'm an idiot,
like I'm a medical student.
Why?
I need to make sure that
your foundation is solid.
Why?
I'm asking the questions,
Cristina, not you.
Tell me why you entered
the pleura that way.
What? Is Zola all right?
It's not... She's fine. It's me.
I have to go. Derek...
Meredith, I can't. I just...
I got fired.
What did you think
was gonna happen?
Danny, you've got a kit.
Now, they're sending
down a second harness.
The doctors are gonna
talk you through this, okay?
Okay.
What can I do?
Kepner called. She wants
you back at the hospital.
I can't go back there.
Yeah, it sucks that
everyone hates you.
But you're not
hiding out here. Go.
Did you get the kit open?
Almost.
Oh, my God. No.
No. No. No. No. I can't do this.
Danny, Danny, you can do this.
We have one chance
to bring you both up.
In order to do that, you have
to amputate Susannah's leg.
No. No. No.
Oh, God.
I need a C-spine!
Coming through, people.
Come on, watch your back.
You guys headed
back? Yeah, we are.
Does anybody have a kid?
Has anybody seen a kid around?
Where'd they pull this guy from?
We'll need immediate
transport for her.
Yeah, give me just a
minute here, Doctor.
I just gotta stabilize her.
I need some help over here!
He's not breathing.
Get an Ambu-bag and
some oxygen over here.
Right away, Doctor.
Oh, jeez. What happened? No.
No, no, no, no,
no, no. I need help.
I think my patient's coding.
You think your patient's coding?
What's his rhythm?
Uh...
SVT? Sinus tach?
There shouldn't be a question
mark at the end of that sentence.
I'm freaking out. It's
my first day of internship.
How could this be happening?
Go back to your patient.
Does he have a pulse?
He has a pulse. Good.
Now check for breath sounds.
I kinda hear some, but
maybe the right sounds less?
You gotta stop
with the questions.
It kinda looks like he's
barely breathing at all now.
Move, move, move.
Tension pneumothorax. Grab
the biggest needle you can find.
What are you doing?
Tension pneumo.
This guy's freaking out.
Step away, Grey.
Uh, 14-gauge? 16-gauge?
The biggest needle you can find!
Okay. Get this man a chest tube.
And next time,
call your resident.
I'm sorry. I thought
that she was a resident.
No, she is not a resident.
She was fired by this hospital.
Had this man died
under her care,
the hospital would be
sued, you would be sued,
hell, maybe even
I would be sued.
Now get this man a
chest tube, and Grey,
get the hell outta here.
Pulse is not good. His
breath sounds are shallow.
His name's Nicky Hoffman.
Pulse is minimal
on this side, too.
Come on, Nicky. I need
you to do better than this.
Thready pulses,
multiple rib fractures with
decreased respirations...
His body's shutting down.
Could be compartment syndrome.
That could be why his radial
pulses are so decreased.
We need to do bilateral
fasciotomies and relieve the pressure.
Do we have a scalpel?
Push 5 of morphine. Got it.
Okay.
All right.
Okay, you do the fasciotomies.
You're the fifth year.
All right.
Okay.
Okay, his pulse is stronger now.
Good. Do the other one.
Sponge.
Here you go. Thank you.
Nice job. You got this?
Yeah. All right.
Hey, Nicky. I'm Alex.
I'm a doctor.
You had a pretty bad accident.
We need a Gunther.
Dr. Bailey, it's the
first day of fifth year. I...
And they're at each other's
throats. We need a Gunther.
I've got more pressing problems.
I'm trying to find a new
spot for Meredith Grey.
You know, I heard
they have a new
Research Fellowship at Mass Gen.
I thought a recommendation
from you might...
You want me to write a
recommendation for Meredith Grey?
By the end of the
day would be fine.
"To whom it may concern,
"Meredith Grey is
an excellent example
"of the kind of resident you
absolutely should not hire.
"She undermines
groundbreaking clinical trials,
"she has absolutely no
respect for rules, authority,
"or, as it turns out,
"the oath that she took
when she became a doctor.
"She will most likely
tarnish the reputation
"of you, your doctors,
and your hospital.
"Sincerely, Dr. Miranda Bailey."
Meredith Grey is the
reason we need a Gunther.
Jerry Hoffman.
CT showed a traumatic
subarachnoid hemorrhage.
I cleaned and splinted
his humerus fracture
and sutured his
facial lacerations.
Well, he won't need surgery,
but let's do a neuro exam
every two hours just to make sure.
Let's take a look
at your handiwork.
Oh, dear God.
My grandmother could sew up
a stuffed turkey better than this.
It was
pretty jagged in there, so...
You ever heard of
burying your stitches?
All right. So I will fix it.
Oh, Jackson.
There's a new patient in
bed three. Kinda busy, April.
Yeah, kinda busy turning
this guy into Frankenstein.
Go. Go. Make yourself useful.
All right, I'm gonna
fix this. Mmm-hmm.
Don't you think you're
being a little hard on the kid?
He's a lightweight.
Be thankful you have Meredith.
She was fired.
She okay?
I don't know.
Mr. Hoffman?
Dr. Shepherd.
You're at Seattle
Grace Hospital.
There was an accident.
A sinkhole collapsed.
My son?
Nicky's on his way in.
He's had some severe injuries
that they need me to assess,
but I promise you, I'm gonna
take good care of your son.
Nicky Hoffman,
sustained crush injuries
and was very
unstable in the field.
Robbins is holding
a trauma room.
We called Shepherd
from the field.
Which one are they in? Um...
Oh, God. I don't know.
Well, find out.
Well, it's supposed
to be on the board.
People, I need you to make
sure you're updating these boards.
April, I need you to
reassign these cases.
Uh, Yang, take over
Meredith's cases.
No.
Cristina. I'm with Altman.
And Meredith should
keep her cases.
I am your Chief Resident.
You have to do what I say.
April, it's fine.
I can wait. Just sign them
when you have a minute.
You're just gonna give up?
I was fired.
So what are you
gonna do about it?
You have to go
talk to the board.
The board fired me.
Yang.
What are you doing?
I presented as thirsty, so...
Treated the symptoms
with eight ounces of water.
Now that I'm finished,
I will place this bottle
in the recycling bin
so as to avoid excess
strain on Seattle's landfills.
That's funny.
You're a funny girl.
Come on. We have patients.
You need a plan.
Come up with a plan.
Okay, now pour
on that brown soap.
And pick up the
thin silver knife.
Good.
Okay, now here's the thing.
You're gonna have to
really put your weight into it.
Try for smooth cuts, okay?
Okay.
Now you see that area
just below the tourniquet?
That's where you're gonna cut.
Do it horizontally,
as deep as you can.
Are you...
Are you sure she's not
gonna feel anything?
No, she's unconscious,
Danny. She won't feel a thing.
Okay.
I can't.
Danny...
Take that blue towel
and cover her face.
It'll help.
All right, now remember to
put your weight behind it, okay?
Here we go.
One...
Two...
Three.
Oh, God!
I hit bone. I think I hit bone.
That's good. That's good.
Okay, put the scalpel down now.
Now take the curved clamp
and move it back and
forth beneath the bone.
God. God, I can't... It won't...
Put your hand in the
incision to get more traction.
I can't.
Danny, I know this is hard,
but we need to create more space
so you'll be able to
saw through her bone.
No, but... No, I can't.
Okay? This is
my wife. All right?
I'm gonna kill her.
She's bleeding now...
Danny, you can't stop.
No, you need to come
down here. I can't do this.
I won't do this!
I'm going down. No.
Dr. Hunt, I can't let
you go down there.
He can't do it. Yes, he can.
He can't. We are
asking too much.
I'm going. If it starts
to go, I'm bringing you...
I should go. I'm the
orthopedic surgeon.
You have a wife and a child.
I'm going.
You're breaking up.
Can you repeat that?
Hey!
What?
I have a plan. Okay.
I'm gonna be a mom.
Okay. Mer, there's a giant
sinkhole. Teddy is all over me.
Don't page me 911
unless you have a serious...
This is serious.
Maybe getting fired
was a good thing.
What do cheerful people say
when something crappy happens
and they make it sound
like it wasn't crappy?
A blessing in disguise?
Yeah. Maybe that's what this is.
This is that.
And I can...
Make jam and drive car
pool and have playgroups.
And maybe that's enough.
And maybe I'll be a great mom.
Okay. Okay. I'm gonna go vomit.
Call me when
Meredith comes back.
And maybe you
want to be a mom, too,
and that's why you
can't go through with it.
I wish I wanted a kid.
I wish I wanted one so bad,
'cause then this would be easy.
I would be happy.
I'd have Owen, and my
life wouldn't be a mess.
But I don't.
I don't want a kid.
I mean, I don't want to make
jam. I don't want to car pool.
I really, really, really
don't want to be a mother.
I want to be a
surgeon, and please...
Get it.
I need someone to get it.
And I wish that
someone was Owen.
I wish that that at any minute,
he'll get it and show up for me,
but that's not gonna happen.
And you're my person.
I need you to be there at
6:00 tonight to hold my hand,
'cause I am scared, Mer,
and sad,
'cause my husband
doesn't get that.
So I need you to.
I am a terrible person.
I know. Awful.
I got Meredith's surgeries.
I'm reaping joy from the
fact that my sister got fired.
A terrible person wouldn't feel
terrible about reaping the joy.
Jackson, Jackson!
I need you to take over
on a couple of these.
I can't. I have to see a man
about redoing some sutures.
Please.
I'll take one.
Thank you. Bed four.
Bailey needs her spleen
patient taken to the OR.
Uh... He's in bed three. So...
He just... He needs
a consent form.
Make sure that the consent
form gets put on his chart.
Right.
Zola, peekaboo.
Peekaboo.
Hi, Janet.
Hey, Meredith.
I'm just finishing
up your home study,
and I thought I'd check
and see how Zola's doing.
She is doing great.
I heard about the
sinkhole on the radio.
I figured you'd be busy today.
Yeah, I'm just in
between surgeries.
So... How are things going?
Is she sleeping
through the night?
Um. No, not really.
She's up a few times.
But it's fine. I don't mind.
Just you, or are you
guys taking turns?
No, he's great with her.
Derek's great with her.
Dr. Grey, are you
taking Zola home now?
Because it says here that
Dr. Shepherd's got her tonight.
Wait. I don't understand.
You two aren't together?
No. We are. We take turns
dropping her off and picking her up.
I'm not taking her home.
I just came to say hi.
I actually should
get back to work.
Okay, Zola. I'm gonna go.
Okay.
It was nice to see you, Janet.
You, too, Meredith.
How's Nicky doing?
I gotta do my final exploration,
check for any missed
bleeders, and then I'm out.
The kid had a renal
artery thrombosis.
I thought his
kidney was a goner,
but Alex did an interposition
graft and saved it.
He's doing an amazing job.
I need to stabilize
his spinal fracture.
So what do you got,
about another hour or so?
Well, with the rock star
over here, you never know.
I'd keep your pager close by.
Dr. Shepherd. Mmm-hmm.
Janet Meyers with social
services needs to speak with you.
Oh, now what?
She's waiting in the lobby.
I heard about
Meredith. I'm sorry.
But you know, Meredith's strong,
you're strong.
You're gonna make it.
Could you guys
just keep it down?
I'm trying to
concentrate. Please.
All right. Just page me
when you're ready, okay?
I'm... I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. Danny?
I'm sorry. Danny, look at me.
You're doing great.
Now I need you...
I need you to cover her head.
Keep her head safe, all right?
All right.
I Couldn't do it. I couldn't...
I couldn't do it. I
couldn't. Danny, you did it.
You did the hard
part. All right?
Now, Danny...
Danny, look away.
All right, she's free. Good job.
I'm gonna finish up, and
we'll both be right behind you.
All right?
Take him up.
Meredith, what'd
you say to Janet?
Nothing. Why?
I just finished answering
a whole slew of questions
about Zola's sleeping
arrangements.
She's finishing her home
study. That's routine.
Okay, there was nothing
routine when she said
that there were
inconsistencies with our stories.
What did she say?
She said that she spoke to you
and that some red flags went up.
Well, I did see her earlier,
but I didn't say anything.
I gotta go. I got a surgery.
Well, I'll talk to
Janet and I'll...
No. Don't.
Don't do anything. Don't talk
to her. I will talk care of this.
You've already...
Don't talk to her.
Dr. Sloan, I think you're
gonna be really impressed
by the buried
sutures I did here.
After you.
That is impressive. It is.
Gender reassignment, huh?
Yeah.
Normally they don't
teach that till next year.
That's a mistake. This is not...
Call me when you
find the right patient.
I don't have time for this.
Hey, I need you
to prep trauma one.
We got another sinkhole
victim on the way.
Stop asking me to do
your work. Do it yourself.
And how about you tell me where
Jerry Hoffman is? Jerry Hoffman?
Um. Well, he's supposed
to be in bed one.
That's what the board says.
He's not there?
Does it look like he's there?
Oh, wait. Wait.
That can't be right.
'Cause if the patient
from bed two is in bed one,
then that means the patient
from bed three must be...
Oh, no.
Oh, no, no, no, no, no.
The patient is
Mr. Chuck Wallace.
He's having a
splenectomy secondary
to injuries sustained
in the sinkhole.
Yes, Dr. Grey, let's move on
before my patient bleeds out.
Okay, I'm almost
ready, Dr. Bailey.
I just have to have the nurse
show me the consent
form as part of the checklist.
Scalpel.
Wait a second.
Dr. Grey, you're
sterile. What are you...
Okay, hold on.
Wait a minute. I'm...
I think that there...
Something might be... Off.
I'm thinking that
maybe this is...
Not our patient.
Then whose patient is it?
I Don't know. I just...
You don't know? I'm
holding a scalpel in my hand.
I think you had better find out.
Stop! Don't cut!
It's the wrong patient.
That's Mr. Jarvis, who
needs a lung resection,
not Mr. Wallace with
a splenic hemorrhage.
I'm sorry.
I am so, so sorry.
Would you make sure this gets
to the medical staff office, please?
Yes, Doctor.
Meredith.
What?
Nothing.
Grey, we've got a guy
with severe crush injuries,
and Callie's come in
with a field amputation.
Let's move. We gotta get
these trauma rooms ready...
I got fired.
Okay? I got fired.
I'm sorry. I didn't know.
Yeah, well, now you know.
I have to go. I have a...
Owen.
She didn't have the abortion.
She wants to and she
can't do it because of you,
because she loves you.
And instead of loving
her, you're punishing her.
For what?
For being the woman
that you fell in love with?
This isn't any of
your business. Okay,
do you know what
will happen to Cristina
if she has a kid that
she doesn't want?
It will almost kill her.
Trying to pretend that she loves a
kid as much as she loves surgery
will almost kill her,
and it'll almost kill your kid.
Do you know what
it's like to be raised
by someone who didn't want you?
I do.
To know you stood in the
way of your mother's career?
I do.
I was raised by a Cristina.
My mother was a Cristina.
And as the child
she didn't want,
I am telling you,
don't do this to her,
because she's kind and she
cares and she won't make it.
The guilt of resenting her
own kid will eat her alive.
All right. Coming through.
No one was updating the board
even though I kept telling them to.
I know, I know. I have to
make people listen to me.
But in all fairness, I've been
Chief Resident for 12 hours,
and yes, a man could've lost
his his perfectly good spleen,
but he didn't
because of a checklist
that I implemented.
Not that that excuses
what happened.
I...
You...
It's okay. Just yell at me.
I can take it.
Uh...
It's okay.
No. I can take it.
Really. I swear,
I can take it. I...
How deep are you
placing the tube?
21 centimeters exactly.
Hallelujah, I'm in.
Great.
Now explain why you chose
that size endotracheal tube.
Because I'm in my
fifth year of residency
and I know what size tube
to use for a basic intubation.
Why are you treating
me like a first year?
Because no one ever did.
I bet your first year,
you could do things
better than most third years.
Well, yes, I could. Why
are you punishing me for it?
I'm happy.
That makes me
see you differently.
Your arrogance
is not your fault.
You're arrogant
because you're so good.
People let you
slide by, skip steps.
They gave you the hard stuff
but let you skip the easy stuff.
I have no doubt
that you can tell me
how to do a coronary
artery bypass.
But I'm not sure
that you can tell me
why you chose that
size endotracheal tube.
Look, I know what you heard,
but Meredith Grey is
one of the most qualified...
Yeah, I understand.
Yeah. Thank you for your time.
Not now, Karev. I'm in no mood.
You need to get
Meredith her job back.
What do you think
I've been doing?
I've spent the whole
morning trying to get her a job.
Meredith doesn't need a job.
She needs this job.
It's not gonna happen.
The board's already
made their decision.
Let me talk to them.
I mean, maybe I
don't know what I saw.
Maybe I lied to get
the Chief Resident...
I can't let you say that.
Oh, the hell you can't.
Karev, this is not on you.
Yeah, it is.
It's all on me.
Looks perfect, Jerry.
Second time's the charm.
Sutures look a lot better.
Really?
That's great. No. No,
no. Not great. Better.
Which isn't saying much considering
the crappy job you did the first time.
You just said it
looked a lot better.
This guy just fell
into a sinkhole,
his kid's in surgery,
and now he's got a scar
to remind him of this terrible
day for the rest of his life.
You want to go tell
him that, big shot?
Go ahead.
Dr. Sloan.
Is Nicky out of surgery?
Dr. Avery was just
about to go check on that.
Um...
Wait. Bailey paged
you, too? Any idea why?
Who cares? As long as it
gets me away from Altman.
Oh, God.
She's gonna fire us, isn't she?
Why would she fire us?
There was that patient
mix-up in the OR.
Oh. You should be fired.
Me? You guys didn't
update the board.
That's why she
looks so pissed off.
That's not good for it.
Let me see that chart.
What is she looking for?
What have you got?
A field amputation with
complicated extrications.
Still assessing her
multiple crush injuries,
but I felt a broken pelvis for
sure, and her BP's in the toilet.
Yeah, this is a Gunther.
Really? Really.
Think they can handle a Gunther?
Oh, I think they need a Gunther.
What's a Gunther?
Hey. I got your
message. What's up?
We should wait till
your husband gets here.
You paged Derek?
Well, he's in surgery.
That could take hours.
Can't you at least tell
me what this is about?
I could tell something was up
when I ran into you
at Zola's day care.
So I made some calls.
It would have been better if you
told me that you had been fired
and that you and
Dr. Shepherd were living apart.
But I can explain...
I'm sure you can.
But you understand my concern.
So what happens now?
Worst-case scenario.
Let's not even go there.
Well, they couldn't
take Zola, right?
I'm not really comfortable
discussing this without your husband.
Well, this is urgent, so I'll go
get him and I will be right back.
Do you have what it takes?
If your marriage is in trouble,
can you weather the storm?
When the ground gives way,
and your world collapses...
He's losing his SSEPs.
Push IV steroids.
Maybe you just
need to have faith...
Scrub in. I need you.
I just got your page.
And trust that you can
survive this together.
Maybe you just
need to hold on tight...
What did I do?
And no matter what...
Don't let go.