Previously on The Resident...
Dr. Bell?
Here's the clamp.
Something's wrong with me,
and I'm not quite sure what,
- but I think it may be serious.
- Want me to examine you?
The results all under the radar.
We're gonna need
to set some rules.
No one here needs to know
that we're related,
or that
you're my biological son.
- Agreed. It's none of their business.
- Mm-hmm.
I talked to your boy.
He thinks I recommended him
to Chastain.
- I did no such thing.
- I did.
You didn't just break protocol.
You broke every rule
of medicine.
Are your patients just pawns
to prove how smart you are?
Now that
you're spending more time
on research and clinical trials,
we need a new ER doctor.
All I know is that Nic wouldn't
want you to be alone forever.
For your sake and for Gigi's,
you deserve to be happy.
Hey, Marion!
We are gonna go get
some ice cream
- if you would like to join us.
- I would love to.
Marion, I just want
to say it again.
I know.
Boundaries clear.
- We both had fun.
- Yes, we did.
Conrad, it's okay. Truth?
You're not my type.
Well, okay.
Besides, I've got a mad crush
on someone else.
- Someone much younger.
- Oh, ouch.
And...
shorter.
Like your daughter.
- Daddy?
- And there she is.
She never gets up this early.
I'll be quiet.
See you later.
Daddy, you need a shirt.
Yes, I do.
You're up so early.
I wanted to pick out
the perfect outfit for my trip
to the aquarium.
Oh, look at that.
- Yeah?
- Yeah. Yeah, definitely thumbs up.
Get this sucker on you, okay?
What are you gonna color
over here?
- I don't know.
- Huh? You don't know?
Hmm. Let me think.
What is that?
What if I color that in there
like that, with that blue?
Oh, my gosh, who is that?
My favorite babysitter!
Hey, my love. Are you ready
to go see the fish?
Yes!
I will bring her back
tonight, Dr. Hawkins.
Thanks for this.
Your purse, sweetheart.
There's some mad money in there
for both of your tickets
and a nice lunch.
Make sure you pick up the check.
Mwah.
Have fun.
Thanks.
- Come on.
- Bye-bye.
Bye.
*THE RESIDENT*
Season 05  Episode 10
Episode Title: "Unknown Origin"
Aired on: December 07, 2021.
Your heart and lungs
sound good, your blood pressure
and cholesterol are both low.
You're in good shape.
But?
I'll see you later,
and we'll talk.
No. Talk here. Let's go.
Lots of the tests aren't in
yet. I'm not gonna speculate.
You have a differential.
I know you do.
Cancer? Stroke?
ALS? I thought of that one, too.
I just...
And I'm reassured because the
lack of muscle fasciculations,
- but... just perhaps?
- No.
Your exam isn't consistent
with ALS.
This could be something simple
and treatable.
- You know it's not.
- I don't know anything yet.
I'll have more information
at the end of the day.
- But in the meantime...
- Yeah. No, I know. I know.
Don't operate. Trust me,
I don't want a repeat
of what happened in the OR.
Bolting mid-surgery,
leaving Dr. Devi,
who I'm supposed to be teaching,
for God's sake.
I got to go.
Kit's new Flight Go Team
just got activated
for the first time.
Yeah, that's a big step forward
for any hospital
with a level-1 trauma center.
Doctors flying to emergencies
EMTs can't handle.
Okay, go. We're finished here.
- Till later today, all right?
- Yup. Yup. Yup.
- I'll see you then.
- Yup, yup.
♪ All systems go
any moment now ♪
♪ High stakes, tightrope,
never looking down ♪
♪ All grind, all shine,
all day, all night ♪
♪ All together now,
all together now ♪
♪ Take, oh, take it over ♪
♪ Time ain't over till
we cross that line ♪
♪ Say you'll never... ♪
There's been an accident
on I-20 involving a bus.
Multiple victims are
being transported here,
but one is trapped,
can't be moved,
and is in need of the highest
level of critical care.
This is why you created
the Flight Go Team, right?
Listen to me.
The situation is dangerous
for the victims
and the rescuers.
- Save lives, but stay safe out there.
- Copy you.
♪ Break on through to
the other side ♪
♪ Hey ♪
♪ All together now ♪
♪ Hey, all together now ♪
♪ Hey ♪
♪ Hey. ♪
Bus carrying
a college women's softball team
flipped over the guard rail,
landed on that car.
The passengers
in the car died instantly.
We got everyone out
of the bus except one.
She's critical, and if we tried
to move her, she won't make it.
She's pinned down with
a penetrating abdominal injury.
The firefighters are trying
to cut her out, but
- they're running out of time.
- Top windows the only access?
Yeah, it's the front of the bus.
The door's jammed shut.
We're working
on opening something else up,
but no luck yet.
Ah, so it's like that, huh?
Pass me the stuff.
It's a good thing they
called in the Go Team,
'cause this is definitely
something EMTs couldn't handle.
I know what you're thinking,
but the first rule
of penetrating trauma...
Never pull it out.
If we pulled that out of her,
and it lacerated
any vessels,
she could bleed out in seconds.
I'm well aware.
Pulling it out is a risk,
but we can manage that risk.
Okay, what's your plan? Go on.
You get the meds,
I'll get ready to intubate.
Let's push 100 of ketamine
and 150 of roc.
Keep her paralyzed and sedated
so she doesn't move an inch.
Then we get her unpinned.
Okay, we got a good plan.
Help me.
We got you.
Push the meds now.
Now for the tough part.
Let's pack that with wet gauze.
And tape it. I'm on it.
I'm here.
Give me the bag.
On my count. Three...
Two, one.
Okay.
Perfect timing.
Wait.
There's someone else in here.
There's a gas leak
under this thing.
Smoke means there's fire, too.
It's gonna blow.
Keep going. We'll catch up.
Come on, guys.
- What's your name?
- Jill.
Jill, you're gonna
be okay, all right?
Oh, God. Oh, God.
Posterior elbow dislocation,
possible fracture, with
brachial artery compromise.
This is gonna hurt.
Take a deep breath.
Got it.
Hey, you,
get out of the bus, now.
I thought I heard a noise.
It's a cat.
It must be the team mascot.
- Not exactly a bobcat.
- Run!
At least you saved the cat.
Okay, that was kick-ass.
Yeah, it was all right.
- Uh, Dr. Pravesh.
- Hey.
Look, I know I gave you
some trouble
the last time I worked with you,
and I just want
to let you know that...
Apology accepted,
but you have one strike
and a lot to prove,
so don't forget it.
Now, I hope you have
your big boy pants on
because we have
a very difficult case.
Hi, there. How we doing?
Temp 102. BP 170/100.
We gave Mr. Parker
meds 40 minutes ago,
and his fever hasn't budged.
Mr. Parker is my dad.
Call me Jerome.
Uh, I've had the fever
for ten days.
Oh, um...
That's the, that's the call bell.
We're here.
I wanted to make sure it works.
Um, preliminary test results
came back inconclusive.
Your chest X-ray and urine tests
did not show
any sign of infection.
No headache, diarrhea,
stiff neck, nausea, sore throat.
Which means we can consider this
a fever of unknown origin.
Unknown origin?
Wait, so you have no idea
what's wrong with me?
Well, it's a mystery for now,
but you have
two motivated detectives
on the case.
What we need is more
information, so we're gonna
run some more tests
and a thorough history,
and... that should be
the key to figuring
this out, okay?
Oh, God.
Where's BooBooBear?
- That's his service dog.
- I have panic attacks.
Boo is the only thread that, um,
keeps me from unraveling.
Your dog is tied up outside.
We don't allow
animals in the ER.
No, no, wait, no. Um, please,
you don't understand.
I... I need her.
- I'm beginning to freak out.
- O-Okay.
Okay. Okay, um,
I might be able to clear
the dog through social work.
I'll call Winston.
Three, two,
one, mark.
Two patients. That's the limit.
We'll hitch a ride
on an ambulance.
You okay? You got pretty cut up.
- Let me take a look.
- I'm fine.
That needs to be cleaned up.
Might need a stitch or two.
Are you two headed back
to Chastain?
I got space
in the back of my rig.
Thank you for getting me
off that bus.
I almost went up in flames.
I was worried about the cat.
That you didn't know existed.
Good point.
Truth is,
I'm more of a dog person.
I'm a chicken guy.
- No way.
- Oh, yeah.
I'll have to hit you up
for some eggs.
Oh, man.
Is that little fluff nugget here
to comfort stressed out doctors?
Because I am in need.
That little fluff nugget
is an infection risk.
Service dogs are allowed
in hospitals, Nurse Hundley.
Some areas are off-limits,
but this isn't one.
Hmm.
- BooBooBear.
- Hey, hold on.
Lyme disease is on
the differential.
Uh, Boo has no parasites, ever.
She's groomed,
gets a monthly topical
tick repellant, and her paws
barely touch the ground.
See?
I-I carry her in this pup pack.
We'll run a Lyme test anyway.
Preliminary history
is unremarkable.
No contact with anyone else
who was sick.
No recent travel
or relevant medical issues.
Jerome is a computer programmer
who works from home.
- Okay. What next?
- You build the differential
using the latest test results,
but be patient.
Fever of unknown origin
can stump the most
experienced doctors.
- What do we got?
- Two adult females.
Young 20s. Traumatic
penetrating abdominal injury,
evisceration.
Intubated at the scene.
And the other one?
Posterior elbow dislocation
with vascular compromise.
Dr. Hawkins
reduced in the field.
She's C.S. 13.
Repetitive questioning,
possible head injury.
Is Mindy going to be okay?
Easy. We'll take care of her.
We need to page
Sutton and Voss now.
Okay...
Hey.
Good work.
I only have a few minutes.
We have traumas
from the crash site coming in.
What can we rule out?
Jerome took an HIV test a week ago.
That came back negative.
Plus, he has an elevated
white blood count.
So?
That means we cross off
all AIDS-defining illnesses,
fungal infections like, uh, PJP.
What else?
Lupus, R.A., probably out.
I mean, the list
is brutally long.
He could have almost anything.
- Go talk to him again.
- Okay.
- About what?
- Anything.
What did he have for breakfast
two days ago?
Do his parents
have heart trouble?
Does he kiss his pet salamander?
Wait.
What does a salamander
have to do with it?
Well, salamanders
carry salmonella,
specifically osteomyelitis,
which can cause a fever.
My point is,
the answer is almost always
in the patient history.
I'll tag in when I can.
You aren't on the Go Team.
Where'd the chopper pick you up?
Atlanta General?
Yeah.
They're not level-1 trauma.
Where'd you learn
your field medicine?
A lot of places.
How about you?
Afghanistan.
Yeah, Navy corpsman. Two tours.
Back to you.
Are you an ER doc?
Trauma surgeon?
I'm double board certified.
Emergency med and...
We're picking up
a patient en route.
Female, 35,
pregnant and in active labor.
Who doesn't love babies?
Looks like we're in
for more fun.
We're stacked up
and more are incoming.
Medivac just landed.
We need a bay.
Severe abdominal lac.
She needs to be top of the list.
I saved you a trauma bay.
Follow me.
Looks like Conrad
repacked the bowel on-site.
- Team did a good job.
- Free fluid in the abdomen.
Her intestines may have been
lacerated by the impalement.
Mindy.
My name is Dr. Devi.
You've been in an accident,
but we're gonna
take care of you, okay?
Hundley, start her
on her propofol drip.
I'll get someone to book an OR.
Gonna get you down to X-ray.
Ortho and neuro page?
Uh, Bay Two. Jill Rhinehart.
Dislocated elbow
and an epidural hematoma.
I thought you could use
an extra hand.
Nolan.
Hi, Jill. I'm Dr. Voss.
And I'm Dr. Sutton.
I'm just gonna do a quick exam.
How's the arm feel?
It hurts bad, really bad.
We'll get you something
for the pain.
Let's get her 25 mikes
of fentanyl.
Can you follow my finger?
She needs an OR.
I'll join you.
Compartment syndrome.
We'll likely need to take that
down with a fasciotomy.
- I'll prep her.
- Thanks.
Jill, I'm gonna need
your consent for surgery.
You're in good hands
with Dr. Nolan.
- What a mess.
- And more coming.
- Who are you operating on?
- I'm not.
It's-it's better if I stay here.
If they need a trauma surgeon,
they'll page me.
All right.
- I'll see you in a bit.
- Mm-hmm.
Ten times out of ten,
a person with injuries like this
dies in the field.
Genius work by the Go Team.
Well, she has gross
contamination of her abdomen,
and she's in septic shock.
Okay, so we get in and out fast.
What's first?
Identify the ligament of Treitz,
run the bowel,
look for vascular injuries,
and cut out anything
that's not viable.
Very good.
We cannot miss anything.
- If we leave contaminants...
- She dies.
So, we're fast,
but we're meticulous.
We need to avoid
ICP elevating meds
and prep her for a right-sided
decompressive craniotomy.
The arm looks terrible.
Life and limb, literally.
Thank you.
Ma'am, how far apart
are your contractions?
Speaking Creole...
Creole. She's Haitian.
Guess I know where you learned
your field medicine.
It's her third child.
Which means it can come
very quickly.
Uh, no exotic foods?
Raw fish? Wild mushrooms?
I have a...
a delicate stomach.
Okay. Um...
Any sexual encounters recently?
I need my dog
just to leave the apartment.
Definitely not
hooking up with some rando.
Jerome?
Uh... Uh...
Hey, I-I need help in here.
Here.
He's burning up.
Fever 104.2.
We're heading into the red zone.
Orders, doctor?
Dr. Daniels.
Uh, let's push 30 ketorolac,
get a cooling blanket on him.
- Okay.
- I'll call Dr. Pravesh.
Significant hemorrhage
and ecchymosis,
but the compression on the brain
should be much less.
Now, I have to find the source.
100% compartment syndrome.
Thank goodness Conrad
reduced it on-site.
Found the bleeders.
Middle meningeal artery.
Cauterizing now.
Good job, Dr. Sutton.
Now, if I
can just try
not to nick an artery.
Won't be pretty,
but when the swelling goes down,
she'll have a functional arm.
Banner day for the Go Team.
Quick question. Is Bell okay?
What do you mean?
He's a surgeon, not emergency.
Pulled himself from
the board for the entire day.
Austin's taking a case
for him in OR One.
I did not know that.
I'm not one to tattle.
Something's up.
Uh, pink bowel is healthy.
Gray we resect.
BP's dropping to the 70s.
Heart rate's 130.
Cranking pressors. She's already
had four liters of fluid.
We got a bit of luck here.
Looks like the blood vessels
escaped getting torn apart.
I've got eyes on the duodenum.
First part of jejunum
looks good.
Oh, no.
Bowels are leaking
into the abdomen.
All right,
find the healthy margins
and staple them, both sides.
We're at 100 centimeters.
Now 125.150's the limit.
She's gonna be at risk
for short gut syndrome.
I'm about to
clip the next segment.
Uh, s-slow down.
You can adjust to make the
viable tissue a little more
visible in the field.
Clip, and then you can staple,
and... toss.
This is my OR,
thank you very much.
However,
good advice is good advice.
Adjusting to get a better view.
Just under
150 centimeters total.
BP's coming up.
Backing off pressors.
Right.
Good call, Bell.
How far are we from Chastain?
20 minutes.
Ever delivered a baby before?
A few.
Ever delivered one
in a moving ambulance?
This day just keeps getting
more and more interesting.
It's one for the record books.
Speaking Creole...
Hey. That was
good work with your
hematoma and compartment
syndrome patient.
It'll be a tough recovery,
but she should make it.
You checked in on us
during surgery?
N-No. I-I got the report
from Jessica.
Oh, by the way,
is Conrad back yet?
No.
- What do you want with Conrad?
- He wanted to see me.
AJ mentioned that you were
in his bowel trauma
in OR Two.
It is my area of expertise.
Thought I could be there
if they ran into the weeds.
He said you made a good call.
Uh, it was nothing.
Really. I was superfluous.
No other procedures that need
your experienced hands?
I understand you've canceled
your surgeries.
Yeah, I felt
some flu-like symptoms,
just a touch...
It's an abundance of caution.
Of course.
No fever.
Perhaps, when you feel up to it,
you'll tell me
what's really going on.
How's it going?
Fever spiked to 105,
and he's hypotensive.
We broadened his antibiotics,
got cool saline, ice packs,
acetaminophen, ketorolac.
We finally found a
cooling blanket, but he's so...
- It's not doing a thing.
- Give me the service dog.
I'll take care of her.
- Come on.
- I think this is beyond
BooBooBear's expertise.
Okay. Okay. Good girl.
How'd he get this bad
this quickly?
Whatever it is has been
building in his system for days.
I don't like where it's going.
He was just talking to me
a bit ago, but he's so...
altered. I...
Well, he might need
to be intubated.
Let's get an ABG.
Yeah.
- Hold on, hold on.
- Here.
Your patient. You do it.
Okay.
Oh, come on. He-he won't settle.
This is awful.
- I can't do this.
- I'll hold him.
Got it.
Okay.
I'm in.
- Oh!
- Uh...
- Hold pressure, quick. Come on.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Hold pressure.
- Did you check his platelets and INR?
- Of course.
160 and 1.8. Not normal,
but not catastrophic.
Well, they must be getting worse.
He's not clotting.
Possibly in DIC or liver
failure. He's decompensating.
I don't understand
what's happening. Explain.
I can't.
We can't fix him if we
don't know what's wrong,
and we're running out of time.
Wait.
You mean he could die?
- I...
- Hundley.
35-year-old woman,
BP steady, pulse in the 70s,
but also we have a newborn male,
healthy, Apgar off the charts.
Who could use labor and delivery
and an OB-GYN.
She gave birth in the ambulance.
Peachtree and Seventh.
Perfect corner
to come into the world.
Great deli there, too.
Speaking Creole...
Mèsi.
Hey, Conrad, listen.
We've got a 30-year-old male
who came in with a week of fever.
No clear source,
and he's going downhill
fast, and we're
nowhere closer to a diagnosis
than when he first came in.
We need all the help we can get.
The antipyretics,
cooling blankets,
antibiotics,
none of it's making him better.
He's going into shock.
We're gonna get started
on norepinephrine.
Let's get him to the ICU.
Still waiting on a bed.
ICU is short-handed today.
Well, we can't keep him
down here indefinitely.
I'm double board certified.
Emergency med
and intensive care.
If there's anything
I can do to help.
This is my patient.
I'm sorry, I don't know you.
Do you have privileges here?
He has a point.
I'm vouching for her.
I'll get Kit
to meet us in the ICU.
Sounds good.
Let's grab you some scrubs.
Hi. I'm Chastain's CEO,
Kit Voss.
Thanks for pitching in.
I know we're desperately
short-staffed here in the unit,
but I have to clear you.
Understood.
My name is Kincaid Sullivan.
I'm an ER doctor,
and I also cover the ICU
at Atlanta General.
You can call them
for recommendations.
- And the state board, of course.
- Hey, Go Team.
You with us?
I'm issuing you privileges
on an emergency basis.
Come to my office
when you have a moment,
and we'll do the paperwork.
Ejection fraction's at 15%.
His heart is failing, too.
Damn it.
She's the ICU doctor.
She should run the room.
Go.
Okay, as far as I can tell,
we've got a 30-year-old man,
otherwise healthy,
febrile,
now in multisystem
organ failure,
with undifferentiated shock,
respiratory failure,
liver failure,
all complicated by disseminated
intravascular coagulopathy?
That cover it?
No urine output
in the last three hours.
Add renal failure to the list.
He's nearly maxed out
on norepi and vaso.
I think we should start
epi next.
Agreed, but he needs
more access.
We'll need to place four lines,
minimum, a central,
- a dialysis catheter.
- An arterial, and a PA-line.
All right, team.
Let's keep this man alive
long enough to find out
what's wrong with him.
What should I do?
Go back to the white board
and go over
every detail we know.
Find answers,
and be ready to report back.
My sixth surgery of the day
starts in ten minutes.
Please tell me
this coffee is hot.
That's why God made microwaves.
Oh, bless you.
Ooh. I smell panic.
I'd rather smell a warm muffin.
What's going on?
We have a patient
who started out
with a fever of unknown origin,
and is now
the sickest guy in the unit,
and if we don't get a diagnosis
soon, he's gonna die.
- And this is the differential?
- Uh-huh.
Good luck.
I mean, how do they expect me
to figure this out?
I'm supposed to see what
Hawkins and Pravesh don't?
Wild guess,
they're teaching you to look.
And you may never get an answer.
You know, by some estimates,
one in four patients
who die in the ICU
never get properly diagnosed.
Despite our best efforts,
the human body is a mystery
that keeps its secrets
more than a quarter of the time.
- Okay, that's-that's so...
- Imperfect.
Remarkable.
Human.
What have you got?
Well...
everything on that board
and nothing at all.
It's okay.
It happens.
We'll keep looking.
But there is something
you can do for your patient.
What?
What's going on?
A kid came in, drowning victim.
They couldn't save her.
They tried over an hour.
Okay.
I need BooBooBear.
For Jerome.
Aw. I was wrong
about this little pup.
She's really good at her job.
Wait.
- Don't forget this.
- Thanks.
His bacterial cultures
all came back negative.
We have him on
broad-spectrum antibiotics
and added antifungals.
Looks like the labs are negative
for vasculitis and autoimmune.
What if it's something
more insidious?
Like an underlying
malignancy leading to HLH?
It's a good thought, but
the ferritin isn't consistent.
- Ingestions?
- Tox screen, negative.
Extended panel, negative.
This was in the dog's backpack.
- A map?
- Uh-huh.
A trail map to a state park.
We've already established
the dog's feet
never touch the ground,
and we've already
- tested for Lyme.
- No, no, no.
Boo's feet
didn't touch the ground,
but Jerome's have.
In a Georgia state park,
where there are other
tick-borne diseases,
not just Lyme.
I looked it up.
It could be babesiosis.
Babesiosis is rare.
So rare we never considered it.
But the symptoms fit.
It's an incredible long shot.
But possible.
So we start him on clindamycin
and quinine, stat,
and if the smear is positive,
we start pheresis.
No matter if this is wrong
or right, good work, Trevor.
Hello.
Hi.
How's Jerome?
Blood test confirmed babesiosis.
- Wow.
- Yeah, he's responding to the meds.
His fever is still high,
but it's coming down.
Incredible save.
Who was that kid?
An intern?
He's gonna be one of our best.
All credit to him.
And to the team.
You...
You ran the room.
Does every day on the job
with you go like this one?
Just one surprise
- after another?
- No, thank God.
Today was particularly intense.
And I still don't know
your name.
I don't know yours, either.
Although, "Hey, you"
- worked surprisingly well.
- Conrad Hawkins.
Kincaid Sullivan.
Cade to friend and foe alike.
I'd like to have a word
with your foes.
No, you wouldn't.
Believe me.
I'm gonna guess you were in
Haiti doing earthquake relief.
Twice.
How long you been
at Atlanta General?
Not long.
What's with the third degree?
Dr. Pravesh, Jerome's doctor,
is gonna be spending more time
doing clinical trials,
and we need somebody to fill
his slot in the ER, so...
He's having a hard time
finding good people.
You seem
like good people.
- Is that a job offer?
- No.
That's up to Dr. Voss, our CEO.
But Pravesh
already talked to her.
She's making a few calls.
She'd like to talk to you.
Thanks.
I don't remember much.
I guess it got bad.
It did.
Don't go hiking
in the woods again
without buttoning up your shirt,
tucking your pants
into your socks,
and wearing a hat, okay?
Trust me, I won't.
I might not ever leave
my apartment again.
I'll be back to check
on you later, okay?
How does it feel?
Making a diagnosis
no one else could make?
Feels good.
It was one of the good days.
We live for these.
You were the hero.
And I'm proud of
what you did.
Thanks.
We have to care
about our patients, Trevor,
but this could've gone
the other way.
If it had,
it would not have been
your fault.
That was odd.
What's that?
She keeps on
being nice to me.
Possible she has a heart?
She does have a heart, Trevor.
Bigger than you know.
Fever's still high,
- but he's starting to feel better.
- Hey, guys.
Dr. Sullivan checks out.
The folks at Atlanta General
sang her praises.
Though, she's only
been there a few months.
Well, where was she before that?
An ER in Chicago, also briefly.
Before that, there's
a two-year gap in her record.
Yeah, she said she spent
some time in Haiti
- doing earthquake relief.
- She told me that as well.
Well, how'd she do
on her interview?
We didn't talk for long,
but she's obviously
smart and capable.
I could see her ICU
leadership was top notch.
But?
She was a bit evasive, frankly.
Like she was hiding something.
Did you hire her temporarily?
We need someone now.
Yes,
but if we're going to make her
a permanent hire,
I'll need more information,
considerably more.
That's odd.
Eh, she wasn't real talkative
about her past with me, either,
but she's a hell of a doctor.
I'd hate to lose her.
Well, you'd be amazed at what
a five-minute Internet search
can dig up on a person.
That's worth a look.
So, one in two people
leave their social media
open to the public.
Pay attention
and you can find out
somebody's favorite color
and who they dated
in high school.
All right.
Kincaid.
Sullivan.
M.D. Atlanta, Georgia.
Huh.
No Facebook. No Insta.
Okay, um, I'll try
broadening the search.
I'll add her work history
and education.
No results.
Try changing the spelling
of her name.
Add that she's an ER doc.
Nothing.
Not a single hit.
That's weird.
Given that she's not
an 80-year-old
with a flip phone, yeah.
It's like someone scrubbed
her entire Internet presence.
Test results.
Patient's been waiting
for them all day.
Go.
I'll keep digging.
Yeah, thanks.
Yeah.
I've got what we need now.
I think
I know what's going on.
Let's sit down.
Captioning sponsored by
20th CENTURY FOX TELEVISION
and TOYOTA.
Captioned by Media Access Group
at WGBHaccess.wgbh.org
Sync corrections by srjanapala