- What?
- It's time to wake up.
- Mm-mm. It's still dark outside.
- I'd like to have sex.
As romantically as that was put,
it's too early, Shaun.
It's exactly early enough to have sex
for the average duration it takes us,
and still allow precisely enough time
to get ready for work.
How long have you been up
figuring that out?
Since 4:53,
but it only took two minutes.
And you've been waiting since then
to propose this?
I let you sleep as long as possible.
That's...
very considerate.
Oh.
Sorry I'm late.
- I'm Dr. Shaun Murphy.
- Kayley has a sore throat.
More like this feeling
like there's something stuck
in my throat,
and I fainted a couple times,
which I first thought was just random,
and obviously losing my voice.
Since I've only just met you,
I have no idea what your voice
normally sounds like.
Not this.
And sometimes when swallowing
I get a super intense pain, like...
worse than an ice cream headache.
My internist sent me
to an ear, nose and throat guy,
an orthopedic surgeon, um,
three gastroenterologists, uh,
- voice issues specialist dude.
- An otolaryngologist.
A neurosurgeon who thinks it might be
a messed-up nerve
connecting the throat to the brain.
The ninth cranial nerve,
glossopharyngeal neuralgia.
- He recommended brain surgery.
- Microvascular decompression.
Which a second neurosurgeon
said I don't need.
You're not happy with the answers
you're getting
from a bunch of recommended
specialists,
so you came to the ER?
I ran out of recommended specialists.
Hmm. It is an intriguing combination
of symptoms.
We'll admit you and run some tests.
Uh, Dr. Murphy?
You're...
interesting.
I have autism.
That's so cool.
I mean, no,
it's not cool that you are...
Be more insensitive, Kayley.
Um... It's cool that you're this...
totally chill,
super knowledgeable medico.
Compliments...
are very awkward.
Cute doctor who's going to cure me.
Severe abdominal discomfort,
fever, tachy, hypotensive.
- It's okay, sweetie.
- What's your name?
That's Marla.
No one to leave her with.
I'm going to take care
of your mommy.
Abdomen tender and distended.
Dehydrated.
Delayed capillary refill.
Rapid respiratory rate.
Skin cool and bluish, looks cyanotic.
- Going into shock.
- We need aggressive fluid resuscitation!
Start broad spectrum antibiotics.
Place an NG to decompress
distended abdomen.
Trend her lactates
and initiate complete sepsis bundle.
Her CBC, BMP, autoimmune panel,
nasal swab, and blood cultures,
all normal.
Oh. That's exciting.
Negative tests are exciting?
No one's been able to find out
what she has.
I'm going to get brain FIESTA
and time-of-flight MRI
to assess the cranial nerves
and vessels, and doppler ultrasound to...
I have to get back to work.
Our pre-dawn romantic interlude
made me late.
Yes, there was a flaw
in my methodology.
My calculation was based
on the mean duration
of our sex overall,
but generally we take statistically
significantly longer in the morning...
than at other times of day.
Well, maybe we can discuss
this whole timing-our-sex thing
at lunchtime.
Mm. No, thank you.
I can't have lunch today.
Too much to do.
Sorry, I'm late.
I was going to cancel our lunch.
Let me guess.
A patient more interesting than me.
Exactly.
Yeah.
She has a mysterious condition,
but I realized I could use our lunch
to help understand it.
- I ordered you a salad.
- Thank you.
How do I get an ice cream headache?
I've never had one.
You don't want one.
Brain freeze is horrible.
The scientific term
is sphenopalatine ganglioneuralgia.
The trigeminal nerve reacts to rapid
temperature change in the mouth,
sending a signal to the brain,
which responds with changes
in blood flow and dural irritation,
which combat what it perceives
as a dangerous noxious stimuli,
but is just ice cream.
I need to experience that.
Okay.
The technique I usually use
is eat way too much, way too fast.
I'm quitting my job.
The job you came back
from Hershey for?
Don't tell Glassy,
he already thinks I'm a flake.
You kicking me out
is just what I needed.
I was in a complete rut.
In my personal life, at work,
super stale.
We weren't developing anything,
just market-testing designs.
Ow. Ow.
Ow, ow.
- That's awful! What's the cure?
- Time.
- How much time?
- Depends.
Do you think I should include my job
in Hershey on my resume?
It hurts so much!
Or does it make me look like
I'm not able to commit to anything?
Ow!
Okay.
The ultrasound showed your colon
is distended.
We've placed a rectal tube and an NG
to try and get that decompressed.
- Mommy, can we go home?
- Not yet, sweetie.
It'd be helpful to find out
what could have triggered this.
Any history of Crohn's
or ulcerative colitis?
No.
I, um...
I have had some UTIs lately.
- That's likely not connected.
- Okay.
Diverticulitis?
Any recent international travel?
I have a 3-year-old and no husband.
Okay, we're going to need to keep you
on IV antibiotics, monitor the distention.
In the meantime, is there anyone
who can look after Marla?
No one.
My whole family's back East.
It's just us.
I'll get a social worker
to look after her.
Thank you.
Go ahead, honey.
Why is my mom upset?
If her anterior inferior
cerebellar artery
is encroaching on her glossopharyngeal
nerve, it's very minor.
Certainly not enough to justify
microvascular decompression surgery.
I agree. It could also be
acid reflux, temporal arteritis,
laryngopharyngeal dysesthesia.
We need to...
We need to do $50,000 of tests
and it might be acid reflux?
Or temporal arteritis, or...
It's a constellation
of relatively insignificant symptoms.
Have you ever had
an ice cream headache, Dr. Andrews?
Yes, I believe it didn't require
brain surgery, Dr. Murphy.
As a compromise, we could do an MRI,
and CT her neck,
- and a swallow study...
- Shaun.
You don't compromise with your boss.
Start her on Dilantin for her pain
and send her home.
Can't I leave her with you?
I'm a receptionist,
not a social worker.
And I'm a surgeon.
I didn't mean I'm more important,
I just meant we both have
more important things to do.
When will the social worker be here?
- Half an hour.
- Can you page her again?
I want my momma.
Why don't you play with the toys?
Do you have her number?
I'll call her myself.
I made Mommy sick.
No, sweetie, it's not your fault,
sometimes people just get...
Mommy drawk my poop.
- Your mommy drew your poop?
- No.
Drawk! Mommy drawk!
- Drank?
- Yes.
Mommy drawnk my poop.
The good news is we've ruled out
glossopharyngeal neuralgia.
You don't need brain surgery.
Never good news without bad news.
We've got a list of a few things
you don't have,
but we don't know what you do have.
- So you'll run more tests.
- We can't.
There are 21 different things
this might be,
but they don't want us
to run 37 more tests.
Well, this is lame. I can afford
the tests, I make good money,
I can't keep talking like this!
I need a...
She's hypotensive! Code stroke!
We need stat brain CT and MRI.
Call Angio, she may need
mechanical thrombectomy.
Three cc's of two percent lidocaine.
Wow.
I didn't drink it. I just...
I just used her stool
to do a home fecal transfer.
- And you didn't think to mention that?
- You said my UTIs were unrelated.
They didn't get better
with antibiotics,
so I did exactly
what I was supposed to do.
The video swore
that it was completely safe.
Make sure your friend
is completely healthy.
I've had the best results with vegans.
Though if it were between
an 18-year-old carnivore
and a 60-year-old vegan,
well, don't make me choose.
Now we're gonna
add the saline solution.
Should be a one-to-one match,
more or less.
Then...
we're gonna puree...
puree, and then puree some more.
While it's mixing...
let's talk enema bags.
Marla must have seen her
using the blender...
- assumed she drank it.
- Yeah, that's the mystery.
Not how anyone this stupid
is still alive.
It's not completely irrational.
The E. coli strain in drug-resistant UTIs
can hide out in the gut.
Repopulating the colon microbiome
using FMT
has shown some success.
In a hospital, under controlled
and sterile conditions.
Prep her for surgery.
Between dilation and rigidity,
there may be colon perforation.
And test Marla's stool for toxins
and infectious bacteria.
She was suffering a mini-stroke
and I saved her.
I saved her. I need to celebrate.
Outside?
I want to celebrate
by kissing you. A lot.
Inside would be inappropriate.
Eagle Syndrome is very rare.
A longer-than-normal styloid bone
coming off the base of the skull.
I only get a five-minute break.
It impinged on her nerves,
causing the confusing symptoms
that baffled eight expert doctors,
and then when she turned
her head suddenly,
it pinched her carotid,
causing her TIA.
Yeah, it's him!
It's Dr. Murphy!
How do I know you?
He is cute!
Is that his girlfriend?
Kayley's hotter.
He's so cute.
My personal...
Chernobyl.
Seriously... Guys... Oh, come on!
A zone of exclusion
should be imposed around my kitchen.
Millions of people have watched that?
As of 9 a.m.
You're an influencer.
And you posted how I saved you?
But I take it I'm not yet,
you still have to operate.
A normal styloid process
is 2.5 centimeters in length.
Yours measures... Don't do that.
There are two surgical options.
Transoral, where we go in
through your mouth.
It's non-invasive
but creates surgical challenges
for physical and visual access.
The alternative transcervical procedure
involves an incision in your neck,
with none of those access issues,
but with some
post-operative scarring.
So one way is safer
but the other I'll look better?
It's a pretty badass scar.
Can I take a bit to decide which?
Of course.
You had no right to tell the world
about me.
- It was flattering.
- Not everyone wants to be famous.
If it's any consolation,
you've had over 70 marriage proposals.
It's not.
Some of us are more comfortable
in the spotlight than others.
I think you're great.
Thanks.
I don't have to poop.
Be patient.
I don't have to poop!
Is there something your mom does
to help when you can't go?
Sometimes she hold my hand.
Would you like me to?
You're not my mom.
Well, just keep trying.
Sweetie, we really need you to go.
If you can't, there is another way
we can do this.
How?
Uh, it's not fun...
for either of us.
Isolate and divide
middle colic artery and vein.
It's an epidemic.
People taking online medical advice.
It's not the problem, it's the symptom.
Medical care's a financial stress
for lots of people.
Not to mention physician arrogance,
incompetence, impatience.
So it's our fault?
Resect and cut colon proximal and
distal to the perforation with GIA stapler.
A friend of a friend self-diagnosed
her own Cushing's disease online
after a series of doctors
barely listened to her,
told her to get more rest.
Guessing she didn't then perform
do-it-yourself brain surgery at home.
Claire's right.
I was supporting your point.
She convinced me I was wrong.
Divide mesentery with LigaSure.
We have a bleed. It's major.
Tension during mobilization
must have caused a splenic capsule tear.
Need to do a splenectomy.
Cut connecting attachments.
- Kidney.
- Diaphragm.
Take the vascular pedicle
with a white load stapler.
Do not get the tail of the pancreas.
Dr. Melendez?
- Can this wait?
- I'm not sure.
The fecal sample your team sent me,
it might be normal,
but was it mislabeled?
It seems to be from a
70-year-old.
It's from a 3-year-old.
SCFAs, elevated isobutyric
and isovaleric acid.
She's at high risk
for serious cardiac problems.
Her social media posts have gone viral.
I've got reporters clamoring to speak
to the twice-exceptional Dr. Murphy.
Bad idea. Luckily he won't do it.
He went off on Kayley
about his privacy.
Publicity would be
good for the hospital.
I'm sure Dr. Glassman
can make him see the wisdom of that.
I'm with Andrews.
It smacks of patting ourselves
on the back.
Could also come off as exploitative.
But the bigger issue is
it could blow up in our face.
Shaun's a complete communications
wild card.
Who knows what he'll say
about you, about me,
about being demoted, about screw-ups.
- We'd coach him.
- Do we have six years
before they need to go to press?
I can go with him, manage the situation.
No, no, no.
If we consider Shaun an asset,
we shouldn't treat him like a liability.
I'll talk to him. See what he says.
You can see the proximity
of her elongated styloid
to the nerves and carotid.
The trick is to break off excess length
without injury
to local neurovascular structures.
Well, if done trans-cervically,
entry point is key.
Minimizes risk of a marginal
mandibular nerve injury.
- Has she made a decision?
- Not yet.
I'd like to lead.
Being that it's a rare surgery, I may not
get another chance at it during residency.
When I have the benefit
of supervision.
And it wouldn't have anything to do with
hoping Kayley might then
post about you?
- Not at all.
- Undoubtedly, a little.
Given the attention this has drawn,
I think we should put our best,
most experienced choice forward.
This is a teaching hospital...
it's exactly the type of surgery
we'd give to a third year,
the fact that she has
an online presence shouldn't be a factor.
And yet here you are,
the chief of surgery,
working a case you say
a third year can handle.
It might reflect well on this place
to have a young woman
be the face of Kayley's surgery.
Assuming it goes well.
Live by the Internet, die by the Internet.
Still want to lead?
Yes.
It's yours.
Ann?
Ann.
- Am I okay?
- You're fine.
We had to wake you up earlier
than we'd like
because we need to discuss
something with you. Do you understand?
Your gut biome showed markers
for elevated cholesterol.
Which you don't have.
Your daughter does.
Marla has high cholesterol?
She has a genetic condition,
hyperlipidemia.
Coronary testing showed 90 percent
narrowing of the left main artery
to her heart.
I'm afraid your daughter needs
urgent heart surgery.
I don't want to.
Okay.
I'll tell the reporters that,
but can...
Can we talk about why?
Your computer just beeped.
I know.
I can think of a few reasons
why you might be reticent.
- You're shy.
- No, I'm not.
Well, you do have trouble
with social interactions,
and you have trouble anticipating
what people might ask
and how you might respond.
Yes, that is a problem
when I'm meeting with a patient,
or I'm at a job interview,
or I'm on a date.
Then my answers matter.
But if I'm talking to a reporter,
they don't matter. It beeped again.
I know, we're digitizing.
Every time a patient needs to take a drug,
we send a reminder.
For some unknown reason
they keep sending me one too.
I think stories do matter.
I think what you do
and what you have done
might be inspirational
for people to hear.
- Okay.
- Okay, you'll do it?
Okay, you've convinced me
I should be nervous.
Now I have two reasons not to do it.
- What's the other reason?
- I'm busy.
Between doing my job and having sex,
I don't have a lot of free time.
You should hire Lea.
- No.
- Yes.
She's very good at tech,
and isn't happy in her job right now.
I'll tell you what, Shaun.
You think about this,
you really think about
how your story can benefit people,
and I will...
interview Lea.
Excellent.
I'll think about it.
I'll really think about it.
Okay.
Some people definitely thought
I would look amazeballs rocking
a neck scar,
but the consensus was
there's only so many turtleneck days
in a year.
So I'm going
with the no-scar approach.
Which one did you vote for?
Well, these are my people,
I mean, they know me,
they know what's best for me
and my brand.
- Wisdom of the crowd.
- My warrior goddess lead surgeon.
We'll get you prepped.
New blouse? It's nice.
Dr. Murphy, do you have a minute?
I really am sorry I upset you...
and I really am grateful.
Being sick was...
You don't need to explain
why you're grateful
we diagnosed your illness.
Well, I do.
You saved me and my career.
At first, my followers
were into what I was going through,
but after a while...
you just start being "the sick girl."
You give up your privacy,
doesn't that bother you?
I have nothing to hide.
No one should.
We should all just be who we are.
We are...
the decisions we make...
and you let other people
make them for you.
So you're not being anyone.
You know how you and I
like to do things together?
- We make clay mugs.
- That's right.
Mommy was sick, and...
she needed to be fixed...
and you're sick too.
- I don't feel sick.
- That's good.
The doctors just want to make sure
everything's all better before you do.
How?
- They're gonna go inside you, and...
- How?
- They're gonna make a little cut...
- No.
- You're gonna be asleep...
- Just like Mommy, I didn't feel anything.
- No! No!
- I'll take good care of you.
- Breathe, count to three.
- Sweetie, you have to be brave.
No!
Code blue!
What's happening?
Please help my baby.
She's had a heart attack!
Marla! Marla!
Marla! Baby, I'm right here.
Marla!
Oh, would you like my CV?
No.
I know you who you are.
I don't need to see a list.
Where do I work?
It's a tech company.
- You were there.
- Cars. Something about cars.
You have no interest in hiring me,
do you?
- No. It's not personal.
- It's a little personal.
I'm doing a favor for Shaun.
I don't really need anyone.
Did he ask you to waste my time?
You know, it's okay.
I didn't really wanna work for you anyway.
You're a bit of a grouch.
But make sure whoever does the job
shores up your firewall.
- A kindergartner can hack it.
- Thank you, I'm sure we'll be fine.
And you're right, you know,
we are not a good fit,
and our mutual affection
for Shaun isn't enough
to stop us from killing each other.
Your Chronicle subscription
is about to expire
because they don't have
your updated credit card,
the coffee maker you ordered,
third new one in the last six months,
will be delivered Tuesday,
and you're deducting way too much
out of Debbie's check for FICA.
Would you like to hear
your Google searches?
Thank you.
Lea!
Severe proximal LAD disease
with mid-total occlusion.
Angioplasty won't resolve
that stenosis.
High risk of rupture
in someone this young.
A stent?
Won't be enough
effective vascularization.
She needs a left IMA
to LAD anastomosis.
I've never done a coronary bypass
on a 3-year-old.
Neither have I.
Guess it was right to put
her daughter's poop up her tush.
Cost her a chunk of her colon.
- Saved her daughter's life.
- Lucky coincidence.
I'm sure the mother
doesn't regret a thing.
At least she shouldn't. I'm with Claire.
Do you have time for lunch?
- And by lunch you mean?
- Lunch.
I need advice.
I need to really think
about something.
Oh. Then yes, of course.
It could be patronizing,
being put up as some kind of
feel-good human-interest story,
or objectified and glorified
as some kind of a symbol
for people who are different.
But I also know that when I told
my sister your story,
she cried.
- She was sad?
- No, she was inspired.
I don't know what your advice
is telling me.
I don't know what you think
I'm supposed to do.
Shaun, you aren't supposed
to do anything.
Except what you believe is right.
Oh.
Thank you.
Now I'm going to go see
what Lea thinks.
- I thought you had a surgery.
- I'm just going upstairs.
Lea's meeting with Dr. Glassman
about a job.
- A job here?
- Yes.
Lea told me at lunch yesterday
that she was looking
for different work so...
Wait, you had lunch with Lea yesterday
and you kept it from me?
I didn't keep it from you.
There was no reason to mention it
until just now, when I did.
Shaun...
you know how I feel about how Lea
hovers over our relationship and...
you're just sneaking around with her?
Arranging for her to work here,
where she'll just loom all the more.
She won't be looming or hovering.
She'll be on a whole other floor.
Yeah, where you can go
and get her two cents
whenever the advice given
by your actual girlfriend
is deemed insufficient.
Yes.
Hey.
- What are you doing?
- Fresh air. You?
Shaun lied to me
about having lunch with Lea.
No, he didn't.
Shaun is incapable of deceit.
He must have genuinely thought
that you wouldn't mind.
Well, then, he's completely tone-deaf
and insensitive,
which are not better qualities
in a boyfriend.
True, but not exactly unanticipated
when you get into a relationship
with Shaun.
And it's never really about the lie,
it's what's underneath.
- You're jealous of Lea.
- I am not jealous.
- I am concerned...
- You don't need to justify.
I'm on team jealousy.
It's flattering, stimulating,
it means you're committed
and you care.
It's ugly and reflects underlying
trust issues that I don't want to...
Yeah, yeah. Like all things,
a little is good and a lot will kill you.
My advice...
admit you're jealous,
give in to it, and then get over it.
Finding the styloid
via digital palpitation
of the tonsillar fossa.
There.
Making incision vertically
along the mucosa of mandible.
Next?
I will free the styloid process
from its...
muscle and ligament attachments.
Done.
Dissecting away
from the internal carotid medially...
and external, laterally.
Now, fracture and excise the styloid.
- Bradycardia.
- Hypotensive.
Loss of EEG waveform.
Cerebral ischemia.
May have injured the carotid.
- Or compressed it by
fracturing the styloid.
See if the fragment is impinging
on the vessel.
Dr. Murphy, extend her head.
Yes! Found it, easing it away.
Carotid decompressed.
EEG back to baseline normal.
Resuming styloid extraction.
Kayley's in ICU, stable,
CT shows no signs
of any permanent damage.
No reason to anticipate
any future problems.
So the question is,
what do we tell her?
That the surgery was a success.
She had cerebral ischemia
on the table.
That did no damage,
and there's no evidence of.
Hospital policy is transparency.
We don't tell them what music
we played, what we talked about,
this isn't relevant to the outcome
or to her prognosis.
Would you be taking the same position
if Kayley wasn't someone
- whose criticism could go viral?
- I don't know,
but it would be delusional
to think it's not relevant.
Dr. Reznick, any thoughts?
I don't think I can fairly offer
an opinion,
because my career
could hang in the balance.
None of us are disinterested parties,
given that the hospital's reputation
is also at stake.
Did you screw up?
Could that crisis have been avoided?
If it could have been,
then we are all responsible.
We were watching everything
she was doing,
and none of us told her to stop.
This is an easy call.
There is only one reason
to tell her everything,
and that's you might feel guilty
if you don't,
and there's the future of this hospital.
Okay.
Now, Shaun, if the patient
asks for details about the surgery,
can you limit your answers?
I don't know.
- Okay, we need to know if...
- No.
Dr. Murphy,
I hope you'll limit your answers...
but I won't order you
to defy your conscience.
We don't normally
have patients share rooms, but...
She's...
- Going to be completely fine.
- When she's recuperated,
we'll begin her on statins, Ezetimibe,
and she'll undergo lipid apheresis.
Kind of like dialysis,
but it'll allow us to extract LDL
out of her blood.
Should get her cholesterol
to within normal range.
She'll need drugs
and that other stuff the rest of her life?
Yes, but, hopefully a very long one.
Thank you so much.
Thank God I did what I did.
Everything went great?
Repair was successful,
you should have no issues...
Everything went great!
Say it. Say it to your fans.
Everything went great.
You rocked it!
You'll be with us another few days, then...
She rocked it, right?
She was lead surgeon
in a successful...
And how gorgeous is that hair?
Dr. Morgan Reznick, take a bow.
She was wrist deep all up
in my mouth, y'all. She's a damn hero.
- You've got work to do.
- We're proud of you.
Any reason you screwed up?
I didn't,
it could have happened to anyone.
Not anyone suffers
from arthritic pain.
- That didn't affect anything.
- You sure about that? Because I'm not.
Did you speak to Lea?
Yes.
I know she's a good friend...
and it would be unfair
to expect you
to cut her out of your life...
but you going to ask her opinion
right after I had given mine,
it just called up Wyoming
all over again.
That you preferred Lea to me.
I was jealous...
and that's something
that I have to work out.
For the two of us to work out.
Together.
What was Lea's advice?
That it'd be selfish
not to share my story with the world.
I liked your advice better.
Hey.
Uh-oh.
Actually, yeah.
There's something awkward
we need to talk about.
You and Claire.
You can reopen the door.
There's nothing remotely improper
going on.
I received an anonymous
favoritism complaint.
We need to deal with it.
I don't want to talk to reporters.
I know.
So...
if I talked to reporters,
it wouldn't be honest
to who I really am.
Well, sometimes, Shaun...
people present
a different version of themselves
depending upon the circumstances.
Like, I'm not always...
the same here as I am at home.
I don't.
No, you don't.
I considered all the arguments.
I want to be known...
as a good doctor.
Not a good autistic doctor.