Previously on ER:
It'd help if you'd
write a letter.
- All right, what kind of work?
- An EMT.
I'll help your brother out.
- I just don't know how I fit in.
- Oh, I understand.
Well, you won't
have to wait long.
So we're still waiting?
- It's only been a week.
- Okay.
- Well, I sent you a few e-mails.
- Never got any of them.
Where are the groceries?
I gave you $100.
- How much you got?
- I don't know.
Smile for the
camera, birthday girl.
Ovarian cancer.
First time around.
- First?
- But they say the third time's the charm.
Happy birthday.
I'm gonna send Alex away.
I just can't help but feel
like I'm giving up on him.
We both know that's not true.
It was so smoky I
could barely see.
The flames were eating the
walls like maggots on dead meat.
So where was the little boy?
Well, I looked
everywhere for him...
when they radioed
me to get out...
something told
me to check again.
- Well, was he there?
- Yeah.
- Hey, Neela.
- He was behind a dresser.
He could barely breathe.
Just about the time I
went to get him: Boom!
The second floor caved in.
Tony, have you heard this?
Time for you to go to school.
Well, it's teacher conferences today,
and me and Mike are having a marathon.
Mike needs to go find a job
and you need to go to Heather's.
Heather's sick.
And I start at Home
Depot tomorrow.
- Isn't that great?
- Yeah.
Great.
You rechecked the K
on your diabetic in 2?
I did. It was 3.6.
- Still ketotic.
- But only one plus now.
Forty-year-old female...
observed syncopal event
with LOC at a travel agency.
Oh, damn.
A and O times three,
pulse 88, resps 26, sat 96.
- Well, listen to you.
- He hasn't hurt you, has he?
I'm fine. I just got dizzy.
All right, I'm Dr. Pratt. We're
gonna take a look at you, okay?
I didn't eat breakfast.
I just got dizzy.
And I wanna go home.
We'll try to make it
quick. Put her in Curtain 2.
- Newbie, you finish up the run sheet.
- No problem.
- Not bad, man.
- Tight, huh?
Very tight.
So this your first day?
Two MIs, a MVC on the Dan Ryan,
and the shift's not even half over.
- How's Dumar treating you?
- He's cool, man, real cool.
He's not giving you a hard time?
He made me stock the
rig and get the coffee...
but it's not like I had to
shine the rims or anything.
Make sure it doesn't
get into schoolwork.
It won't.
Hey. Pratt, you see this?
Kovac is having a mandatory
department dinner next week.
Now, why would I wanna hang
out with you losers on my free time?
Ha-ha. Hey, it's better than the time
Weaver took us to the Olive Plantation.
Ha-ha. I was hugging the toilet for days.
- Okay.
Too much information.
You met my brother?
It's his first day.
- Hey.
- Hey, congratulations.
- I heard you start today.
- Thanks for everything.
You got it. Be careful,
the ladies love the uniform.
We'll see.
Look. Here, department dinner.
That sounds like fun.
Obviously, you haven't been.
Yeah, beats work.
All right. Speaking of which,
Marquez, staple gun lady in 3.
Sam, liter of NS and get
an EKG for the new one in 2.
What's this dinner all about?
Well, after County's lousy
Joint Commission survey...
Kovac probably just
wants to boost morale.
Hmm. Great.
What about emergency
power for the rooms?
- We're getting to that.
- Bathrooms still aren't ADA-compliant.
Upgrade the nurse call systems
and get automatic fire doors.
- You'll have time when we close.
- Give me another week.
- I gave you a month.
- We're busy.
We're busy every day.
- Soccer player has a positive culture.
- Start Vancomycin.
I haven't even
prepared the staff.
Well, you have the rest
of your shift to do so.
What about the patients?
We've increased capacity
at the urgent care clinic.
You promised shuttles
to other facilities.
We don't have enough money.
You have no idea what
it's like to be down here.
I covered trauma in
this ER for 20 years.
We're trying to improve
the way it works.
- How long will you shut down?
- As long as it takes.
So we can comply with rules?
Without accreditation,
we can't run this hospital.
- Come on, Donald...
- In 12 hours, we close the ER.
End of story.
You heard what he just
said. We're closing down.
- It's only temporary.
- How do you know?
Old boys run around here, and
now we're having some dinner.
Oh, we have the dinner every few
years. It's just drinks and dancing.
Usually, you can't bring a date.
Maybe I'll bring Wilson.
- The cop?
- Mm-hm.
They say white men
can't jump, but he sure...
Who you bringing?
I don't know.
You know, Sam, it's obvious
you got some stuff going on.
You don't need to keep it
all in. Nurses stick together.
No, I honestly, I have...
Don't know who I'd bring.
It's the first time in my
life I've really been alone.
You're kidding me.
No. Now that Alex is out of the house,
I gotta find something to do with myself.
Girl, it's called The Rabbit.
It costs a grip, but
it's worth every dime.
Oh, God.
You'll be saying more
than that. Trust me.
Excuse me. Hold on.
Oh.
Get that look off your face.
How are you?
Mets to the...
Liver, lungs, bones.
Not a Kodak moment.
I'm sorry. Are you
getting chemotherapy?
No, I'm done.
Keep him on the monitor
and call for an ICU bed.
Hi. This is Diana Moore.
She's here for syncope.
History of ovarian cancer.
- I'm Dr. Kovac.
- Not history, Sam.
It's right now.
Metastatic.
End stage.
Doctors need to know that.
You two know each other?
She'd been here before.
Not as a patient.
Diana's a photographer.
She's doing a project
on hospice patients.
Oh, that's right.
Yeah, I remember you.
Wow, you've got
pretty bad ascites here.
Your abdominal cavity
is accumulating fluid.
I know what ascites is.
I took a picture of it.
Looks like I'm pregnant.
BP's 92/58.
She's depleted intravascularly.
Okay, run in a liter of NS.
No, no IVs. I told
the paramedics.
I'm DNR.
- It's just an IV for rehydration.
- No, I know, I know, okay?
I know how this starts...
and then you get sucked
into the hospital vortex...
and it never ends up well.
The fluids will
make you feel better.
No, listen to me.
No.
No IVs.
No blood tests, no
monitors, no medicines.
I'm going to Costa Rica.
What's in Costa Rica?
- The beach.
Sam, give her a liter of
oral rehydration solution.
Just stay long enough to show
us you can hold that down, okay?
Okay.
Hey, shouldn't we
drain some of the fluid?
We can't do a paracentesis.
It will help her breathe
easier, make her comfortable.
- You heard her, no blood tests.
- It's a needle in the belly.
It will take you five
minutes. Come on, Luka.
Ray is right. We can't tap
the fluid without checking labs.
She could be anemic,
coagulopathic. Not a good idea.
She doesn't want any treatment,
Sam. So let's respect that.
Your favorite skin popper
won't let me I and D her abscess.
Sign her out AMA
and get her out.
- But she knows you, maybe if...
- No.
We can't keep convincing
if they don't wanna be here.
We can't even take care of
the ones we already have.
Okay, listen up.
Got reassignments for all
of you during the ER closing.
How they just gonna
tell us this today?
Thought I'd prevent this,
but Anspaugh's not budging.
How long we shutting down?
- Not sure.
Great. I'm sure I'll wind up
giving enemas in Geriatrics.
No, you're going to ICU.
Malik to Geriatrics.
Pratt, Family Medicine.
- Abby, you're going to the NICU.
- Oh, I'm not going to the NICU.
Right. I'll fix that.
- Gates goes to Anesthesia.
- What about me?
- You're going to the cafeteria.
- The cafe... What?
Give me a jockey suit
and sit me out on the lawn.
- Do we get to keep the same shifts?
- Get our choice of schedule?
Talk to your supervisors
about shift scheduling.
Are they gonna shut
down the Residency?
These are alternate
rotations until ER opens again.
That's what they told
MLK in Los Angeles.
They're scrambling for
spots in other programs.
Our didactic programs for
the Residents will continue.
For Attendings,
there'll be administrative
duties to help correct
the JC deficiencies.
We'll also be assigned clinical
shifts in the urgent care center.
Great. Med refills,
URIs and back pain.
Yeah. I bet we're
closing for good.
I'm with you. Something stinks,
and it's not the diarrhea in 4.
Who has Johnson?
Oh, I did.
No pneumonia. But are you
aware he has rib fractures?
Yeah. The kid plays rugby.
So guess who's...
Guess who's going
to Family Medicine.
I don't know. Who?
Yours truly.
No nights, no weekends.
Now, maybe you can
come over for some dinner.
We can crack open a bottle.
You know?
Yeah, maybe.
Hey, Betina.
I saw your abstract on
neuroimaging and autism.
Pretty cool stuff.
Paper's coming out in
Neuroscience next month.
Wow, very impressive.
But not surprising...
considering you managed to enroll
such a big cohort of autistic children.
And the way you correlated the MRI
findings with the tissue specimens.
I mean, no one's ever done
that on this scale before.
- You actually read it.
- I sure did.
If you have time to talk
about it more, I'd love to chat.
I'm looking for areas to focus
clinical research in the ER.
I'd be interested in collaborating
with your department.
Oh. Are you free for lunch tomorrow?
- Sounds great.
Okay. Great.
What just happened?
Blunt trauma to the head and
arms. Assaulted with a baseball bat.
- Alert.
- Got it.
Okay, put him in Trauma
1. What happened?
I was at a sci-fi convention, and
some Romulan started beating me. Aah!
Get a c-collar.
He accused us Intergalactic
Rebel Warriors of being inferior.
He was being uppity, because
Romulans are biological cousins to Vulcans.
- Of course.
- Where's your pain?
Mostly in my shoulder.
My arm hurts too.
Let's get a line in.
Get him morphine.
And c-spine film to his right
shoulder and left forearm.
It hurts.
Now, you dislocated
your shoulder anteriorly.
- Am I gonna die? Ah-haah-haah!
- Not today.
- Have you seen that patient?
- She stumbled off.
- Can you find my doctor?
- I'll send someone.
Today? Next year? During
Cinco de Mayo? When?
- Have you seen Diana?
- Who is that?
- The photographer lady in Curtain 2.
- No.
Sam, where are the glucometers?
They're packed up. They
were supposed to leave one.
- The test strips?
- You're on your own.
I get the Klingons used to
be enemies of the Federation...
- but we have nothing to do with that.
- Move your toes.
Good. You feel me touching your foot?
- Yes.
Never heard of
Intergalactic Rebel Warriors.
What show were you on?
We're still in the conceptual
stage, but we're about to land a deal.
Looks like right anterior
shoulder dislocation.
C-spine is clear.
He got a nightstick
fracture of the left ulna.
Let's get a sugar tong splint.
Let's give him 100 of
propofol for shoulder reduction.
- Propofol?
- Yeah, I just got credentialed to use it.
We try scapular manipulation.
Put it in without knocking him out.
No, reductions are easier
if you have good sedation.
Sedation has risks.
Morris, dispo some
patients out here.
We got a full waiting
area. Come on.
Okay. Let's get set up for the propofol.
We'll do the reduction when I get back.
All right. Let's get him prone and
we'll try the scapular manipulation.
What? Morris said he
wants to use sedation.
- He's a kid with a toy.
- The kid's the Attending.
- Even if you're right...
- We'll try.
If it goes in easy, great.
If not, try the propofol.
- Ah-ha-aah.
- Let me roll you over.
Hey.
Been looking all over for you.
I gotta get an airline ticket...
- before the price goes up.
- Come here. Come on, sit down.
Please?
Uh...
Got malaria once.
I didn't feel...
as bad as this.
Look, the fluid in your belly
is compressing your lungs.
If you let us take it off, it will
make it easier for you to breathe.
I just wanna get on the plane.
I understand that.
Okay. But you are
breathless and you're pale.
And flight crews are trained
to spot people just like you.
I'll wear blush.
Paracentesis will only
take a few minutes.
Sam...
I have friends in Costa Rica.
And they're waiting for me.
And it's all planned out.
This is your only
chance to get there.
Come on, trust me on this.
ICU has beds for
our intubated patients.
Only three beds, but
these can go to Telemetry.
We have 11 patients going to medicine.
They can use the GYN floor for overflow.
- What about the waiting room?
- Send to urgent care.
The ER is closing at 8.
How do you say, "This is gonna
hurt" in Intergalactic Rebel Warrior?
Aaah!
- What the hell are you doing?
- He did it.
- What?
- Gates thought to try it this way.
Yeah, and it worked.
No need for propofol.
- Well, who made that call?
- I did.
- His shoulder's back in.
- Not the point. I gave you an order.
So do what a boss does. Take
credit for my resourcefulness.
I'm writing you up.
Because my approach was
better than the Attending?
Go home. You're done.
- You can't send me home.
- You should have thought that before.
- I helped the guy without sedation.
- You went against my orders.
- You're supposed to be a soldier.
- I am.
- A real one.
- Could have fooled me.
- You're acting like I killed the guy.
- I am sick of you not taking orders.
Time you got here, you've placed
subclavian line without supervision.
You tapped a VP shunt without
even calling Neurosurgery.
You overrode an Attending to give
Digibind to a guy who was brain-dead.
You keeping score?
- Transpose numbers, you falsify charts.
- You sound like a high school girlfriend.
And still you act like
you're God's gift to medicine.
Like you're too good to
seek advice or need help.
You're arrogant and
dangerous, I've had enough.
We all have. Go home.
Where's Kovac?
- This is my call, not his.
- Okay.
- What was that about?
- I sent him home.
I tried that once.
Yeah. Well, this time, he's
getting a letter in his file.
So how did you cut your leg?
I was trying to
get the chip out.
What kind of chip?
A neurogenic biomatrix
nanosilicate chip.
The aliens put it there.
And did the aliens do
anything else to you?
Not that I didn't consent to.
Look, they want me to go
back and report my findings.
Really?
I'm willing to give a report, but
I don't want them tracking me.
Sam. Can you page Psych...
for a consult, please?
- Katey's already down here.
- Katey?
We're gonna move you to Exam 3
to do the procedure, but you're all set.
One ticket to Costa Rica.
Tomorrow evening, 7:55.
Seat 13B.
You ever been to Costa Rica?
Only on the Discovery Channel.
That's where my dad
bought me my first camera.
My family lived there...
when I was 15, for six months.
Real magical.
Very beautiful.
The sunsets, the beaches.
Sounds romantic.
Yeah.
It's where I met Paul.
He was a journalist for the BBC.
The only guy who ever got me.
Is he gonna meet you there?
No.
He died in Baghdad.
He was embedded with a Marine
unit, and they drove over an IED.
I'm so sorry.
Sorry.
Yeah.
I never had his kid.
What do you think?
We should put her
on a 72-hour hold.
She cut a leg open.
She's a danger to herself.
- She's a crazy bird.
- Heh.
Aren't we all?
My best friend thinks I'm nuts
sitting around waiting for you to call.
Okay. Look, I'm sorry.
No, I'm sorry.
The moment I jump
in the pool, you get out.
Katey, that's not...
Hey, this is Katey Alvaro.
Fourth year on Psych.
Do we have any beds?
WOMAN Let me check.
And I pulled out
my best for you.
Hey, don't get me wrong.
The sex was great.
I'm not talking about the sex.
No, that's great.
I'll bring her right up.
- I should have called you.
- You should have called?
- You dropped off the face of the Earth.
- It was wrong.
No, it was more than wrong. It
was wussy, immature, 10th grade-ish.
You're right.
What happened?
You start dating
Neela or something?
Okay, can we talk about this?
What's there to talk about?
You're stupid, and I'm done.
Did Morris tell you not
to do the procedure?
Well, yes, but scapular manipulation
doesn't pose any real risk.
That's not the point.
I saved the guy
from being sedated.
You were out of line, now
going over his head to me.
My way was better, doesn't
merit being written up.
It does. When an Attending tells
you something, do it or discuss it.
- Come on...
- You'll go home and think about that.
Am I in trouble?
Morris, that's one of the
best moves you've ever made.
See? I knew it.
He can't go against me. He shouldn't
be able to go against Residents.
- There was a Resident?
- Leave me out of it.
- Should've stopped him.
- Like he'll listen.
- He doesn't even listen to you.
- I should send you home too.
Okay.
Well, not today.
But I'll do it, Abby.
Don't test me.
- It wasn't life-threatening.
- Doesn't matter.
Morris is the Attending.
It's his decision.
Got my Coltrane.
Margaret Bourke-White books
and a timer for my camera.
Well, you seem at peace. - Yeah.
Why stress this?
My friend's gonna cook.
Drink wine on the beach.
That necessary?
Uh... It's a precaution
for the invasive procedure.
I said no blood.
It's just platelets.
Your count's a little low.
I'm still gonna get out of here?
I promise you.
Platelets running.
Belly's prepped.
Lido's drawn up and ready.
I gotta get my film
to my publisher.
And my camera to Yolanda.
Who's Yolanda?
This little girl I mentor in
a photography program.
Okay, a little sting so you
won't feel the big needle.
- Vitals?
- A little tachy, but BP is good.
Okay.
You're gonna feel
some pressure here.
That's it.
If the bottle fills up, clamp the tubing
before you switch to an empty one.
Yeah, I got it.
I need to see if I have
enough miles to upgrade.
Why skimp on
your last plane ride?
She refused the morphine.
Okay. The painful
part is over anyway.
Fluid's bloody.
Just a little. Shouldn't
be a problem.
Oh, I don't know.
I feel weird.
Diana?
Diana, come on.
Systolic's only 84.
Get the crash cart.
- Come on, Diana.
- Sam, she's DNR.
No, no, no. We
talked her into this.
We gotta get her
back to where she was.
- Please?
- No crash cart, no CPR.
Give her a liter of NS and
lower the head of the bed.
BP's 88/45.
Damn it. Urticaria.
- Another liter of NS, DC the platelets.
- Crackles at the bases.
Fifty of Benadryl, and
get on the non-rebreather.
Diana? DIANA: What happened?
You had a bad reaction
to blood products.
Okay, I'll start another line.
No, no, I don't want that.
I don't want any of this.
You dropped your
pressure. No choice.
Yes, I do. Stop.
- We need a way to get in fluids fast.
- No, no.
Listen, this is very serious. Platelet
allergy can be life-threatening.
Especially in your condition.
- Great.
What is it about hospitals?
This is a toxic environment.
Everybody gets worse here.
One-twenty-five of Methylpred
and epi at the bedside.
It's gonna be okay, Diana.
Really? I don't think
I'm gonna be okay.
Want me to start a subclavian?
She's coagulopathic.
Let's give the meds a chance
to kick in, and then reassess.
Hang in there, Diana. We'll
come and check on you soon.
- Sam shouldn't push that.
- It was Diana's chance to get on a plane.
Dr. Kovac, people are
asking about this dinner.
Just tell Marquez to
officially close us the Trauma.
How are we affording
a fancy place?
- It's not Ladokern.
- Don't worry about it.
- Get with a pharmaceutical company?
- We have a lot of work.
Say it isn't so. They're
Satan, trust me.
A 14-year-old with altered mental
status and respiratory distress.
We were walking home.
He said his back hurt.
- He sat down and stopped making sense.
- Please, hmm, mm...
Ray, can I get a hand over here?
- Your friend's name?
- Demitri.
- Your friend have medical problems?
- I don't know.
Demitri? Hey, man.
Wake up, Demitri. Wake up.
One, two, three.
- Sat's only 76.
- You sure it's picking up?
Yeah, we got good waveform.
- All right.
We got shallow resps, decreased
at the bases. Throw me the bag.
Does he take any medicine?
We're in orchestra.
We're not friends.
Anybody call his parents?
- Timmy's on it.
Pulse is thready. Tachy at 125.
- You take drugs? TODD:
We don't mess with that.
Did he fall? Did
you get in a fight?
He just passed out.
We gonna need the tube.
- One seven-0 and a MAC-2.
- What do you want?
CBC, trauma panel, tox
screen, type and cross.
Call for a portable chest, and let
Surgery know that they need to come down.
It's not my fault, I swear.
Let's get an ABG.
- Hey.
- You didn't call me back this morning.
- What?
- You didn't call me back.
- Morris is such a bitch.
- What happened?
- He's sending me home.
- What did you do?
- I reduced the shoulder.
- That's what I did.
- I don't get it.
I was trying to do
what was safest, right?
And then he shows up and
he pulls this big power trip.
- So you went against him?
- Not the point.
- It kind of is.
- It kind of isn't. The point...
I don't even
wanna talk about it.
Why don't you just
tell Morris you're sorry?
I'm not sorry.
So, what?
So, what? I'm not a kiss-ass.
- So you wanna get written up?
- He doesn't have the balls.
- Neela.
- What?
You've been ignoring Dr. Crenshaw's
pages. He asked me to read this.
"Get your ass into
the Trauma room now."
- I gotta go.
- Where you going?
- What did you have to say?
- Nothing.
Just go apologize to Morris.
Suction. All right, I'm in.
- Bag him up. MALIK:
Sats in the 70s, Pratt.
Blood gas is ugly.
- PH only 7.02.
- What's happening?
He may have taken something
that's making him acidotic.
There's no gap. Know what?
Listen, Todd. It's very
important you tell us the truth.
Did you guys take any pills?
I told you, we were in
orchestra practice all day.
Can't bag him above 80.
PRATT: Because of this.
Yikes. What is that, pneumonia?
It seems unlikely
without a fever.
Seven-fifty of ceftriaxone.
It hurts me when you ignore my
pages. Truly, it wounds me to the core.
You rang?
We got a 14-year-old
with hypoxia and this film.
- Pneumonia?
- H & H is back.
- Hemoglobin's 6.2.
- Pulmonary hemorrhage.
What I'm thinking.
History of trauma? - Yeah.
We don't know. His
buddy's not helpful.
- I told you, I don't know anything.
- Look, Todd...
if you know something,
you gotta tell us right now.
Hey, hey, Todd. Get back here.
- SonoSite, please.
- A chest tube...
Todd.
What did you do to him?
- What did you do to him?
- Nothing, I swear.
Yeah? Then why are you running?
You know your friend could die?
He could?
Yes, did you do
something to him?
I wanted the solo.
What did you do?
I kept praying he'd get sick,
but when that didn't work...
we did this experiment in
chemistry where we used sulfur.
I saw what happens when you heated it,
so I figured eating it couldn't be good.
You...
You put it in his food?
Our school orchestra goes to
Milwaukee, and I want to play the solo.
I didn't mean for
all of this to happen.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry this didn't
go the way we wanted.
Why don't you...
just sign me out?
You know that I
have a plane to catch.
You can leave, but nothing's changed.
They're not gonna let you on that plane.
But why?
We can send you home.
Hospice can bring
you pain medications.
- No, but I'm not in pain.
- Not right now.
Sometimes when people die this
way, they get really uncomfortable.
Well, why can't you do
another paracentesis?
We can't risk you bleeding.
Okay.
Why can't I just fall
asleep and not wake up?
You've seen this. It doesn't
always work that way.
The fluid in your body is
gonna continue to build up.
And as it does, it'll compress your lungs
and make it harder for you to breathe.
I'll feel like I'm drowning.
We'll not be able to get to
everyone before the ER closes.
What about my headache?
I can't wait till next week.
I've got yeast infections.
You'll have to find a doctor somewhere.
We got a list of local clinics here.
- How long will the ER be closed?
- We don't know.
- We need a room.
- We're closed.
- You guys know that
- You gotta take this.
- No. Go to Good Shepherd.
- Listen, it's Dr. Pratt's brother.
Chaz?
He kind of overdid it.
Somebody, I'm
not feeling too good.
- What happened?
- Happy hour overload.
- We need a gurney over here.
- Trauma 2's open.
We got this. Give the
nursing report on Diana.
- We got a bed for her.
- My appendix.
- She's going home.
- Wants to be admitted.
What? To the hospital?
No. She's not dying here.
Sam, just make the call, okay?
Hey, Sam. I got these
kids doing fence-plowing.
What the hell is that?
Knuckleheads run into a
fence and try to break it.
- Do we have time?
- They have to be out of here in an hour.
- Hey, Pratt.
- Yup?
Go to Trauma 2.
Your brother's here.
Yeah, I know. He's working.
- No, he's drunk.
- What?
Demitri's parents just
called. He's got sickle cell.
You're kidding.
At least it makes sense.
Yeah, it means the white
out is acute chest syndrome.
What's that?
Dr. Barnett will explain
everything. Take them upstairs.
- Where you going?
- It's my brother.
All right, let's go.
I just spoke to Dr. Kovac.
- It's okay.
- No, it isn't.
It's fine, Sam.
No, this isn't what you
want. It's the hospital vortex.
You said it yourself.
Let me take you home.
We'll tell your friends to
meet you there instead.
It's okay. It's okay.
Don't say that. Come on.
Sam, look.
Actually, there is no one, okay?
I just...
I did my thing.
My whole life, and I didn't
develop real relationships...
and I don't have any kids.
So...
Okay.
But you are still
not doing this here.
Not like this.
Sam, I can't.
Now, look at me. I
can't do this alone.
Pulse ox is dropping.
- Breath sounds equal.
- Chaz, wake up.
- Breathe for us, buddy.
- I have one beer.
Hell, I have four beers,
but 15 shots of tequila?
- It's a paramedic tradition.
- What the hell were you thinking?
- Sat's only 89, he needs a tube.
- No, 15 liters O2 by mask.
- That will not work.
- What are you, frat boys?
You guys see people die from
alcohol poisoning all the time.
- Still got a gag.
- Barely.
Chaz, come on, man. Chaz, hey.
Pratt, his GCS is trending
down, so are his sats.
- We need to tube him.
- Not yet, he's arousable.
- Bro...
- See, look at that, he's talking.
- MAC-2 and an eight-0.
- No.
- You're not putting a tube.
- It's gonna be a mess.
- Extubate him.
- Not putting him on a vent.
Marquez, place an NG.
- We'll evacuate his stomach.
- That's gonna make him vomit.
Chaz, come on. Wake up, man.
He better wake up
or I'll kill you guys.
Hey, come on. Hey, hey.
Hey.
- I'm sorry.
- Sat's up to 92.
Good. That's good.
- Let's put him on a non-rebreather.
- I'll call for a med/surge bed.
This is nice. Heh.
It's very chic.
Here.
Did you do all these?
Uh... Yeah, mostly.
Some are some friends.
I thought you had no friends.
Well, they're the kind of friends
that you bunk with in Kabul...
let you sleep on their
floor in Marrakesh.
I haven't told them.
Diana...
They'll read
about it in the obit.
Bet you underestimate them.
That's Paul.
Hmm.
Right before the bomb went off.
I'm sorry.
Here. Let me help you.
I got you.
Sit down.
You know, Sam,
you don't have to...
You don't have to stay. I'm sure
you have family to go home to.
Uh... Actually, my son
is away at school, so...
He's been, you know,
having problems.
A picture?
- What's that?
- Picture?
Yeah.
Yeah, I do.
- There's Alex.
- Ha-ha-ha.
It's an old one, but
he looks the same.
- Well, he's beautiful.
- Thanks.
I used to think you had to
choose between family and career.
By the time I figured
out you could have both...
it was too late.
I was already sick.
Yeah, well, I got
pregnant at 14.
So by the time I realized
you could have a career...
my kid was in preschool.
So nursing isn't
what you wanted?
Ah.
Actually, I never thought
about what I wanted.
Feeding Alex was the reality.
Hmm.
Well...
It's never too late to choose.
You have time.
The room is ready for
Mrs. Sherman on four south.
And the surgical step down says
they'll make room for our pertussis kid.
You think it's good to put a toddler
in a room with post-op patients?
- No, but it's the only option.
- Dr. Kovac.
- You can't send me out, doc.
- Can you sign this discharge?
We'll give you a taxi
voucher to get to a shelter.
You know what
them shelters are like.
I'm afraid that's all we can
offer. You don't need to stay.
Dr. Barnett, I finished packing
up Trauma 1 and I found this.
It's a violin. My patient must've
left it. I'll take care of it. Thanks.
Hey, how's he doing?
We're gonna
monitor him overnight.
Hey, you know, if you get
admitted, you can't be a paramedic.
- Is he for real?
- Afraid so.
- Oh, hell, no.
- It's a joke.
- Sit your ass down.
- Ha-ha-ha.
Oh. What happened?
His first day as an
EMT, got initiated.
Damn traditions.
I'll be up in a sec.
Hey, Betina, Betina.
About earlier, I'm sorry
about how I came off.
"How you doing? Maybe
we could have dinner?
Crack open a bottle of wine?"
Yes, yes, yes. But I do wanna
hear about your research.
Then you're going to have to
read up like your buddy, Morris.
I'll do that.
But I still wanna take you out.
There's this ER department
dinner next week, Thursday night.
An ER dinner. You're kidding me.
And I thought maybe
afterwards, we could get a drink.
In a bar.
In a public spot.
Sounds better.
Come on, what do you say?
Call me.
Hey.
You forgot this?
- Thanks.
- Mm-hm.
Demitri's still not awake?
Well, he's got a tough
road ahead of him.
But the disease did
this to him, not you.
You sure?
Yeah, I'm positive.
Sulfur doesn't make
you sick. Not like this.
You know you got lucky.
I know.
Look, when the time is
right, you'll get the solo, okay?
Have you ever
felt, like, jealous?
Wanted something
someone else had?
Sure. Heh.
Hey, but in the end, I believe
people get what they deserve.
And if you're patient and committed,
then you can get what you want.
Whatever you want.
Whether that means a
violin solo, or a better grade.
Or even a girl.
Sarah?
Sarah.
I didn't like Happy Feet.
What? What kind
of a kid are you?
Everybody likes Happy Feet.
Well, I'm not everybody.
- Hey.
- Hey, you're home.
Yeah, I got off early.
Where you guys been?
The video store.
We ran out of movies.
You know, if you
want, you can join us.
- We got a bunch of Jackie Chan movies.
- It's Charlie Chan.
Okay. Charlie Chan.
Sarah, can you give Mike
and I a second to talk?
Sure.
What's up?
What's in the Thermos, Mike?
I haven't been drinking.
- So, what's in the Thermos?
- I felt like having a bit of orange juice.
- Yeah?
- What's your problem?
- Prove it.
- I don't have to prove.
- You need to relax.
- I need to relax?
You've been
drinking while driving.
- I was not.
- Oh, yeah?
What's gotten into you?
- Give me that.
- No.
Let go.
That's it!
I'm done with you.
Tony.
Come on, Tony.
It was only a little...
You're out. You're moving out.
- We just went around the corner.
- Shouldn't let you in.
- What are you doing?
- I fall for this crap every time.
- No, please, Tony. Listen to me.
- I'm done listening too.
You're a drunk. You'll
always be a drunk.
- Come on, Tony.
- Get out of my way.
Look, I'll change, okay?
That's what you want.
How many times
have I heard that?
Tony, what are you doing?
- Stay here.
Tony.
- I got a job.
- Yeah.
And the day the
rent's due, you'll blow it.
- That's not true.
- It's true. It's always true.
You know what else?
You weren't a fire chief.
You're a captain, got demoted because
none of the guys wanted to go with you.
- You son of a bitch.
- Face facts, old man.
You killed that
rookie, didn't you?
You left him. You left him
burning in that building.
Too out of it to go save him.
Why don't you just face it?
You can't talk to me like that.
You killed him.
You killed your career.
And the only way Mom could
escape you was to die herself.
You did it, Dr. Kovac.
- I don't like this.
- Hey.
It's not all Mercedes
and racquetball.
I know that.
But I'm beginning to feel like the
politics aren't worth the paycheck.
First, you make me fire Weaver.
Then I spend half my
time in BS meetings.
- I'm flooded with paperwork, and this.
- Well, welcome to management, Luka.
This isn't me.
I'm resigning as chief.
Luka, part of being the
boss is being the bad guy.
I'll leave that to someone else.
I just wanna be a doctor.
Well, good night.