Previously, on
"Grey's Anatomy"...
You can always come back,
okay?
I'm pregnant with your baby.
Dr. Grey, if you don't squeeze
all the love and joy you can
out of this one life
you've been given,
I'm gonna haunt you
from my grave.
- Yes.
- Yes to...?
Drinks.
You gave up your job
and your husband.
You need to get some help.
I'm so sorry.
It's your mom.
- What?
Did you hear that? Oh, my God.
We're gonna die in here.
But if this is how I die,
it's okay.
♪ Underneath electric light ♪
We all need
a place to feel safe.
♪ Strangers standing
side by side ♪
To feel sheltered.
Protected.
For most people,
it means a home.
For most surgeons,
it means a hospital.
I don't care if
100 utility poles are down.
You need to get
the damn lights back on.
No, I don't.
That's what
the generators are for.
Well, then, why
aren't they doing it?
'Cause it takes them
a little while to kick in.
See?
That's why I'm in charge
of the building.
Smug.
That's smug.
I don't care for it.
In the hospital,
we're rarely blindsided.
This is weird.
The power's back on,
but are we moving?
Do you feel like
we're moving?
And there's always something
to keep us busy.
What?
- It doesn't matter.
- Doesn't matter?
I just mean that no one's asking
for anything from you.
No one's asking for you
to give up anything or... anyone.
It's just you needed to know.
What?
Teddy's pregnant.
It's yours?
We always know what to do next.
Okay!
It's a cozy little box.
I, uh, think we're stuck.
I can't be.
I have to be in surgery.
I have to procure
a heart for Cece.
Maggie is waiting for us.
I can't be in here.
You got to get us
out of here.
All right, uh...
I have a transplant!
Okay.
What are you doing?
Well, under this
light fixture,
there should be
a trap door somewhere.
What? No!
You're not doing
some action-hero crap
where you climb up
an elevator shaft.
I meant use your phone.
- Well, I don't get any signal in here.
- Well, neither do I.
Then why did you ask me
to get us out of here?
Because I...
can't be in here!
Help!
So, um, her spine,
then?
Chondrosarcoma.
C5 to T1.
Extensive local invasion.
When did she tell you?
Why... Why did
she tell you?
She didn't.
She doesn't want
anyone to know yet.
But I couldn't know this
without telling you.
Especially you.
What do I do?
- I feel, uh...
- Helpless.
I know.
I've never felt less
like a doctor in my life.
Oh, no.
My... My patient, Cece.
She's in the O.R.
Her pressure is dropping.
Go.
Whatever I can do...
Go. Go.
- Cece, what's going on?
- Her pressure keeps dropping.
We started her
on pressors again.
My old heart is jealous
of my new one.
It seems to want
to quit on me.
Well, then,
we're just in time.
Titrate the drip to keep
her MAPs above 50.
Qadri, go to O.R. 2
and see how Dr. Bailey's doing
on the procurement.
I need to know how far out we are.
Got it.
What do we do?
We keep doing what
we're doing.
You pump the bag.
Get the O2 in the blood,
keep the organs viable,
and we... wait.
But we're trapped.
- Not trapped, delayed.
- We can't be!
Cece's in the O.R. right now.
We have to get these organs...
- Helm, get your head together.
- It's just, uh,
she's been waiting for this,
and she's, uh...
God, I... I think I'm...
I think I'm having
a panic attack.
No, no.
You're not.
S-Stop it.
Do you understand me?
No one is having
a panic attack.
Is anybody out there?!
Help!
*GREY'S ANATOMY*
Season 15  Episode 09
Episode Title :
"Shelter From the Storm"
Synchronized  by  srjanapala
So, I don't understand.
You've been here since...
Weeks.
Weeks. For weeks.
- Yeah, a long time.
- Did you just find out?
No, no. You knew.
That's why you came here.
Because you were
pregnant, and you...
Yes, yes, I-I knew for a while.
- and you didn't tell me?
- I did tell you.
Just now!
He's bottomed out.
Uh, I don't feel a pulse.
Maybe it's
a cardiac tamponade?
Maybe the plate
punctured his heart.
All right, well, if it has,
compressions aren't gonna help.
We have got to
get him into an O.R.
Hey! Hey!
Guys, guys, guys,
we don't have time.
Worst-case scenario
is the door won't open
till after he's dead.
Yeah, we have to
open him up.
- In here?
- In here.
Look around and see what
we have to work with.
Uh, two units of extra blood.
Great, do we have a...
- Test tube tray.
- Jackpot. I've got a scalpel.
All right, Shepherd,
can you bag him, please?
We're really doing this?
Yes. Come on.
Trauma is the choice
between doing something
that could maybe
kill him...
Or doing nothing...
- which will really kill him.
- Which will really kill him.
Hey, we're
not going anywhere,
so what else
do we have to do?
You're supposed to be
honeymooning.
And you're supposed to be
sleeping.
Look, they opened the bridge.
The storm's calming down.
- Come back to bed.
- Oh, come on, Jo.
It's a basket of crap
over there.
No, no, it's fine.
- No, it's not fine.
- Mm, it is.
A pole fell down in the ambulance bay.
- You're kidding.
- No, no, no. The power went out.
- The... The elevators aren't working.
- No.
We've got doctors and we've
got patients trapped.
- Bailey will have...
- Bailey... trapped.
On an elevator.
- We should go.
- No, I should go.
- You're drunk.
- Okay, you should go.
Stop that.
Stop what?
Looking at me.
It's a small room.
There's not a lot to look at.
You know what I mean.
Okay.
I'll stand over here
where I can't look at you.
I just hate not knowing
what's going on
out there.
I can tell you
what's going on out there...
Maggie's probably
already started
on Cece's
heart transplant
'cause Bailey or Webber
or literally anyone else
already did
the organ recovery.
And that same person is gonna do
the kidney transplant.
You're a brilliant surgeon,
Meredith,
but this procedure
only requires a surgeon.
Thanks, I think.
Thank you.
It's like the TARDIS
from "Doctor Who."
It that some nerd thing?
Because I'm not fluent.
No, I mean, me neither,
but I used to watch it
when I was a kid in Italy.
"Doctor Who" had this,
uh, phone booth
that was a time machine,
and when you stepped inside,
you were, like,
outside of time
and space.
And the world went on,
but you were in this whole other
little... bubble...
A secret place where
the normal rules don't apply.
The rule still apply.
This isn't the Turdis.
TARDIS.
Whatever.
Call the Fire Department
and have them get those
elevators open!
- They're not coming.
- They're not coming?
They're on limited operations
because of the storm.
Look, I don't know
why you're yelling at me.
Because the damn building
isn't working,
and you're in charge
of the damn building!
Do better!
This is Catherine Fox.
Please leave a message.
Uh...
Y-Y-You're Betty, right?
You need some help to find someone?
Oh, no. That's okay.
I was just waiting
for Dr. Shepherd to get back.
I just got a bit restless,
you know, in the E.R.
Right, right.
Um, you know what?
I'm little bit
antsy myself.
I mean, I find
the best thing to do
is to help someone else.
Got a lot of patients here
and none of the elevators
are working.
I need to stay busy, and so do you.
That's okay. I can just...
Now, come on.
Let's make ourselves useful.
This is Catherine Fox.
Please leave a message.
Mom, it's me again.
Call me, all right?
Tell me where you are
and what I can do to help.
Do you know where
Dr. Bailey is?!
Qadri, what is going on?
Dr. Bailey
is in an elevator.
You just asked me
where she is.
Cece Colvin's on the table
for a transplant.
Dr. Bailey is stuck in an
elevator with the donor organs.
Dr. Pierce wants me
to find them,
but I don't know how
I'm gonna do that.
- Coming through.
- Hey!
What? The elevators...
I need you to open them up.
- I can't. The elevators are down.
- I know that.
They're computerized, okay?
So they need a while to reset.
- They'll be back up eventually.
- We don't have till "eventually."
I'm asking you
how they get opened.
Well, I'd call the elevator guy,
but he's not coming.
You know, there's
a hell of a storm out there.
Yes, I r...
Is there anything by chance
that you know
that I don't?
Oh!
Okay, Doctor.
No, I don't know.
Can you tell me how many ground
fault circuit interrupters it takes
to keep you
from getting fried
every time you reach
for a defibrillator?
No, you can't.
You just pick it up
and say, "Clear!"
and somehow you're a hero.
'Cause doctors are so cool.
Don't hyperventilate.
I'm not. I'm okay.
Don't hyperventilate
the patient.
Oh, sorry.
I just, uh, think
we're gonna plummet
and, uh, Cece will die
and Phoebe never got a chance
to say goodbye to her mother,
and she would have died
for nothing...
With a stupid selfie stick
in her face...
And this thing's
gonna plummet
and we're gonna
plummet with it!
They say if you jump
as it hits the ground,
- we might be okay, but...
- That's nonsense.
It's basic physics. You can't... Right.
First... First,
we'll hit the ceiling,
and then we'll smash into
the floor like tomatoes.
We'll just be
a puddle of us.
Nobody's plummeting.
These things plummet
all the time.
In movies,
not in buildings.
Do you know that?
There's special brakes
and things.
How... How do you
know that?
I don't know that!
I made it up.
'Cause if our brains are
determined to scare us to death
with made-up scenarios where
everyone we care about dies
and we are turned
into tomato sauce,
then why can't they
also make us feel good
about made-up good things?
Like, uh,
hydraulic air brakes.
And stop inflating
that woman!
What if we, uh...
We all breathe together?
Okay?
Should, uh...
Should we do that?
In.
And out.
I
was gonna tell you sooner.
I was gonna tell you
the night that I got here,
but you had already
started a family.
- In record time.
- Nice.
Well, is it not true?
It was a little snarky.
Decompressing
the pericardium.
I'm sorry.
I-I-It was a little snarky.
You're right.
- This is a clamshell.
- Mm-hmm. - Yes,
it is a total clam...
- is that like a cluster...
- I can't see
where the bleeding
is coming from.
Yeah, the incision...
We do a clamshell incision.
- We need more visibility.
- Right.
Yes. I knew that.
I've just been very specialized
- for a very long time.
- It basically means we, uh,
pop his chest like
the hood of a car.
All right, Owen, uh,
grab the scalpel...
We'll do the right thoracotomy.
Yep.
We're gonna need to find
something to crack that sternum.
Yeah, I'm thinking
I'll, uh, figure it out.
And so Carina stayed back
with my father,
and I moved out here
with my mom.
Why did your mom leave?
I... My dad is, uh...
Was a pretty famous surgeon
back in Italy.
Wow.
I wouldn't know anything
about having
famous surgeon parents.
You wouldn't.
Your mom got awards.
My dad got... acquittals.
I've never really
told anyone about him.
Oh, well...
you can if you want to.
I don't think that I do.
I mean, I just meant that
you could if you wanted to
and it wouldn't leave
this room.
Because I don't think
we're ever leaving this room.
Speaking Italian...
But he's also the man
who took me on the back
of his motorbike
and taught me
how to kick a soccer ball,
taught me the names
of the stars.
So, it's complicated.
There. I told somebody.
Thanks.
Do you really think there's
a trap door up there?
Uh...
I just came in here to
get out of the wind.
- Same.
Well, I should
get back in there.
And you should get back
in there, too!
Now!
Yep.
Yes, sir.
Done.
All right. How are we
gonna crack the sternum?
I got that. We're gonna lose
that heart monitor.
- Why?
To crack the sternum,
I usually use a Lebsche knife
and hit it with a mallet.
But we don't have either,
and that battery
is heavy enough
to use as a mallet.
And the Lebsche knife?
I'm gonna need you to put
pressure right there
- when I pull this out.
- You're gonna use the license plate?
Fun.
Great idea, Hunt.
Okay. Ready?
1... 2... 3!
Aah!
Okay.
So, what did you mean...
What did you mean
when you said
"Nobody wants me
to do anything"?
Do you think maybe
we might want to wait to talk
about that until we're...
No, no.
I'm - I'm...
I'm interested, too.
Is he supposed
to choose now or...?
No!
No, no, no.
There...
There is no choice.
Owen, you and I
are off the table.
So you and Amelia can just...
be whatever you want.
Hey, thanks.
But I am gonna stay
in Seattle.
I mean, my child
deserves two parents,
and I deserve my friend.
And so you can
stay with Amelia.
Who is right here.
- Okay. You ready to go?
- Yes.
Oh!
Oh, God!
Wow.
Great.
Okay.
Here you go.
Ready?
Get ready.
1, 2, 3.
All right.
Oh, I love brain surgery.
Okay. All right,
the left heart looks good.
Sometimes,
there's only like a teaspoon of blood.
I feel like, if I can
get clean for like three months,
then I can get it
under control, you know?
Get Leo back.
Just sort of get my life back.
Betty, just take it
one day at a time,
and don't ever make the mistake
of thinking you're cured.
That sucks.
If you do it alone,
it sucks.
But if you let people help you,
it's not bad at all.
Ah, I've got
a patient coding.
- Can you... That's cool.
- Can I go back to the E.R.?
Just see what else
I can do?
Yeah, you do that. Mm.
Hello?
- Hello?
Anybody there?
- You good?
- Shh.
Hello? Hey!
- Hello!
- In here!
Great! They're in here!
There are transplant organs
trapped in this elevator.
Give us a hand.
Let's get this open.
Whoa, hey, hey!
What do you guys
think you're doing?
- Trying to get this open.
- No, no, no.
You can't access
a stalled elevator car.
Someone can get killed.
If we don't, someone
will get killed.
How the hell do
we open this thing?
Look out.
Don't do that.
No.
No, no, no, no!
Aw, come on! Can you see that?
You guys just do whatever you want.
You got no respect
for the facility.
Hey, listen to me,
all right?
You want to be a hero?
You want to save lives?
There's a woman
whose life depends
on you getting that door open
for us right now.
- I can't do that.
- I'm useless here.
You're
gonna help me do it.
We're gonna
get Cece her organs,
or you're gonna wake up
tomorrow without a job.
Whoa, hold on a second.
Cece the...
The matchmaker lady, Cece?
- Yes.
Oh, she...
I-I was in her room
for just like 15 minutes once
fixing her TV,
and she sized me up
and introduced me
to a nurse
down in critical care.
We've been together
ever since.
She changed my life,
that lady.
She, uh, put, uh,
joy in my life.
Pardon me.
May I borrow this?
That guy
has joy in his life?
Or maybe her name is Joy?
It's not coming.
Watch out.
There we go.
- Come on! You got this.
- You got this! That's it!
It's like "Lord of the friggin'
Flies" in here.
What happened? Bailey's in
there with donor organs.
They're for Cece.
Hey.
Karev.
Welcome.
This is the last
unit of blood.
Do you want me to take over?
I got it. Thanks.
How long?
Oh, I'd say about
five more minutes
with this unit of blood
unless the door opens.
How far along are you?
16 weeks.
And did...
Have you had...
Have you been
to appointments or...?
Yes, we're... we're fine.
Baby's fine.
I'm fine.
So, you know if it's a...
No. Not yet.
I'm so sorry.
I should have told you soon...
You think?
This is not the way...
Do you think that
this is the way
- I wanted to do this?
- I-I-I don't know.
I don't know. You seem to
know what everybody wants.
Do you feel anything?
There should be, like,
a-a handle or something.
It might be a keyhole.
Like, it feels like
I need a key.
Damn it.
Remind me again why this
is such a bad idea for us.
Because it's a bad idea.
No, I hear you.
I'm just asking why.
Because I'm an attending,
and you're a resident.
And that happens
all the time.
It's happened for you,
I think.
Well, I'm trying to learn
from my mistakes.
I promise not to tell your kids
that you called them that.
My marriage and my kids
aren't a mistake.
Then what are you
learning exactly?
I don't know.
Just go back to
speaking Italian.
I liked it better.
Speaking Italian...
Wow.
Yeah.
I was the one who said
let's talk about this later
- so that you didn't have to do this now...
- Well, I have a stake in this.
- I have children here, too. We do.
- I know. I know.
- I have children. We both do.
- I understand that. I know, I just...
Can we all just...
Let's go! Let's go!
Let's go!
Watch out.
All right, great.
Coming through!
All right, you're next.
Uh...
What if,
when I'm halfway through,
it plummets
and chops me in half?
Helm!
Come get this patient
and her life-giving
organs to the O.R.
Yes, ma'am.
All right.
Let's get her to O.R. 2.
Uh, we need some help
with the stairs.
- Yeah, we got it.
- Ow.
Oh, hey.
Ooh.
We got you.
No, I'm good. I'm good.
I'm good.
Go help Cece. Go!
Oh, God!
No, no, no, no!
Oh, God! Oh, God!
Hit the button! Hit it!
Is it bad?
Are they gone?
We got you, Jed.
We got you, buddy.
Okay?
What is the deal
with this elevator?
I'm screwed.
I'm getting fired.
Barely been here, and this is my
first impression on the Chief.
Please, I've been making
impressions for months,
and they're all
this bad or worse.
I am getting fired.
This is not a good sign.
Mnh. Mnh-mnh.
Let's start her
on some norepi.
It's getting
cold in here.
Shouldn't we
be getting started?
Not much longer, okay?
How's Dr. Avery?
Cece.
Maggie,
this is not normal.
I have received
organs before.
And this is not
a normal amount of time
to wait in an O.R.
There's a problem.
And I'm frightened.
Because
I've loved this life,
and I don't know for sure
what's next.
I'm frightened.
It might help me
to be a little less
frightened
if you talked to me
about you and Dr. Avery.
Okay. Okay.
Dr. Avery and I are
kind of a mess right now.
We had a big fight,
and, um,
I don't really know
where we stand.
I feel like he could...
I feel like we could
fall apart at any minute.
I don't think I'm...
You don't feel safe.
Mm-hmm.
Yeah.
In my experience,
that means
one of two things...
Either he is terrible
for you
or he's so good for you,
you're scared
you'll lose him.
Was there ever a time
he made you feel safe?
When my mother died.
That's a good time
to do it.
Yeah.
Cece, no! No!
Crash cart!
And tube her. Now!
I had panic attacks
as a kid.
Before dance recitals.
And... And spelling bees.
But, also, I-I really thought
that elevator was gonna plummet.
I need you to stop!
Good. You're here.
What is it, Karev?
We need to get the maintenance
guy down to the O.R.
- The maintenance guy, why?
- Elevator nearly took his legs off.
- I knew it!
- No.
Uh, I'll go find an O.R.
for him.
You come do this for me.
You want me to do
an organ recovery?
You can perform an organ
recovery, can you not?
Yeah, but you're
already doing it.
I need to get to the E.R.
I need...
I need to do that.
Look, I'll look after
the hospital, Dr. Karev.
Go scrub and get in here.
Okay, and we're good.
- Flow is good.
- Let's isolate.
I've isolated the injury.
I need a 4-0 prolene,
please.
Uh, do you think
we should do a graft or...?
What can I do?
Uh... I think...
I think we're good.
Uh...
- How's she doing?
- Not good.
We've shocked her twice,
but we can't put her on bypass
- until we have organs.
- Bailey's already started.
Scalpel.
There's extensive
tissue damage,
but the nerves here
look salvageable.
Yeah, this left femur
is looking gnarly.
But the right... The right
looks like maybe an ex-fix.
- Where have you been?
- I, uh...
He was blown in
the ambulance bay.
The wind threw him
into an ambulance.
It was bad.
You okay to work?
- Yes.
Yeah, we'll definitely
take the left.
Jury's out on the right.
What if we don't
take either?
Dude,
this leg is a no-go.
It's crushed musculature,
open comminuted
femur fracture,
a hashed neurovascular
bundle.
We should amputate...
Dude, place some rods.
- What?
- Or a plate or an ex-fix.
I mean, fix the legs.
Okay, yeah, the nerves
are crushed,
but they're still
intact, right?
I could do an arterial
anastomosis.
I can get some
blood flow in there.
He'll have a better outcome
with a prosthesis.
Please tell me
you know that.
I know that he's here
because of a patient.
I know that he did
everything he could
so that she could survive.
I want to save his leg.
I can do that.
Well, maybe you can, but that
doesn't mean that you should.
Even if you save
the blood supply,
if he doesn't regain
function...
Doctor, if you're not
gonna fix his femurs,
then maybe your fellow
can give it a shot, huh?
All right.
It's metal shop.
I want plates.
I want the modular
rod tray open.
Schmitt, give me
some suction here.
And some large Weber clamps,
a large lobster claw...
I need curved
micro scissors
and, uh,
jeweler's forceps, please.
Keep an eye on his MAPs,
and I want a strict
urine output
and make sure that
there's a vigileo in his ICU.
He's gonna want
that license plate.
That's a keeper.
So, uh, you're...
You want me to be involved?
With the baby?
Yes.
Because I want
to be involved.
Owen. I know.
I know you.
I want that, too.
How's it gonna work,
do you think?
It'll figure
itself out.
We'll figure it out.
Yeah.
Hey.
We're gonna have a baby.
We are.
- We'll figure it out.
- Yeah.
Okay.
Mm-hmm.
♪ No, I can't handle ♪
♪ Let out the air
and sink to the bottom ♪
♪ No one can hear me down here ♪
♪ Came down a comedown
where I don't fear ♪
♪ Somebody seeing my tears ♪
♪ I feel safer down here ♪
♪ But I'm sinking deeper ♪
- 4-0 prolene.
- I'll follow.
♪ I'm sinking deeper ♪
♪ Than I ever thought
I would go ♪
♪ Too many times that I've been ♪
♪ Too proud to let it out ♪
♪ But it feels so much
to handle ♪
♪ So many times that I've been ♪
- ♪ Too proud to let it out ♪
- All right.
- You good?
- All good here.
Good here.
- Let's take her off bypass.
- ♪ And then I start to get nervous ♪
♪ What if I never resurface? ♪
♪ No one can hear me down here ♪
♪ The pressure gets worse
the further I fall ♪
♪ The dimmer the light,
the lower I go ♪
We got a heartbeat.
It's beating on its own.
Whew!
Thank God.
She told me she would haunt me.
♪ Too proud to let it out ♪
Okay, let's give her
a kidney.
♪ No, I can't handle ♪
♪ No, I can't handle it ♪
♪ No, no, I can't handle ♪
We keep the drugs
in a big machine.
- You need a passcode to get to them.
- No, no, no.
- Some patient asked me to, uh.
- Is that why you came back?
To steal drugs?
Please don't tell Amelia.
I'll just go, okay?
Just let me leave.
Betty, if I did that,
I couldn't call myself a doctor.
Renal vein looks good.
Yeah.
Good length on the ureter.
- What is it?
- Her rhythm is deteriorating.
She's bradying down.
Push a mg of epi.
Helm, what is her lactic acid
and base deficit?
Minus 12, and her lactate is 6.
What is it?
It could be
metabolite washout...
It could be anything.
Yeah.
Let's go back on bypass.
I'm gonna massage her heart.
Let's give her a kickstart.
Let's put her
on an epicardial pacemaker.
Come on. Come on.
Come on.
You can have
your job back.
I guess you already
took it back, but fine,
'cause I'm never gonna be
talked to like that again.
Karev... No, I'm not gonna
be told to sit in a corner
whenever you feel
like stepping in!
There was a crisis
I needed you to handle.
I couldn't get here
because of the crisis.
But I did anyway.
But it doesn't matter...
So screw it, screw you!
I never even wanted
this stupid job, anyway.
I was in crisis.
I needed you to
do that surgery.
I was worried I might
nick one of the organs.
I needed to be somewhere
where I couldn't do any harm.
What?
Is it Warren?
What is it?
What?
Please don't quit.
Um...
I need time to...
get some things
straightened out.
I need your help.
Hey, whatever you want.
It's okay.
It's all right.
No pulse.
Give me another epi.
- Should we start bypass?
- No.
Paddles.
Charge to 20.
Clear.
Come on, Cece.
Please.
Charge to 30.
Clear.
Please.
Again.
Aron Wright's "How You'll
Be Remembered" plays...
I nearly kissed
the Italian one.
♪ You were here ♪
I may kiss
the other one, too.
♪ For a while ♪
Because, I mean,
look at him.
♪ In this feverish place ♪
I don't know if I'll ever
find love again.
But I'm happier than
I've been in a long time.
- ♪ Then left without a trace ♪
- I'm having fun.
And when I do,
I hear your voice.
Thank you, Cece.
♪ This is
how you'll be remembered ♪
Hey.
I just went to see Leo.
How's Betty?
Um, apparently, she's been
with Webber all day, so...
Okay, well, good.
- Amelia, I'm so sorry. I just...
- Please.
I'm the one who said,
"Go to Germany.
Go see Teddy."
I should've said,
"Take condoms."
It's funny...
I think back to that,
and, um, I really...
wanted it to work
for you.
I wanted you
to be happy with her.
So maybe this...
No. I am gonna be there
for the baby, okay?
But anything between
Teddy and me isn't happening.
It's not an option.
That's not true, Owen.
She's here.
- ♪ This is how you'll be remembered ♪
- She's Teddy.
And she's pregnant
with your baby.
♪ Ahh, ahh, ahh ♪
She's an option.
♪ This is
how you'll be remembered ♪
You are such
a good man, Owen.
And I am gonna give you time
to consider your options.
Okay.
I gave this building
everything.
Then it tried to eat me.
Shut up.
You were almost killed,
you dummy.
- He's a hero.
- Ha!
So, what's going on, Doc?
Do I still have legs?
Are they under
all this stuff?
They are.
In fact, Schmitt,
you want to do the honors here?
Now, that signal there...
That means good blood flow.
And there seems to be
a little nerve response,
even this early.
It's tiny, but it's good enough
to give us hope.
♪ Can you tell if I'm cold? ♪
- ♪ If I'm out of daydreams? ♪
- We look for shelter in a storm.
- But, sometimes, we can't find it.
- ♪ If I lose ♪
♪ What is loved? ♪
♪ Will a new love await me? ♪
That can't happen.
What happened today
cannot happen.
- I understand.
- I'm so sorry.
♪ I am touched by wonder ♪
On-call rooms,
storage closets,
that weird, little
radiology room on 4.
Those rooms have locks.
- Understand?
- Yes, sir.
Completely.
♪ Don't swim with me, darling ♪
God. Think.
♪ I prefer the sun of you
when you are away ♪
- Good advice.
- Oh, my God.
I think I just peed.
♪ Ah-ah-ah-ah-ah ♪
♪ If I am left with a rose
in my hand, let it die ♪
Sometimes we're at
the mercy of the winds.
We have nothing left
but to accept it.
I screwed up, okay?
- I just screwed up.
- And I want to help you.
I'm trying to.
But I need you
to help yourself,
and you can't do that
yet.
So I have called a rehab.
I've gotten you
a bed there,
and I can take you there now
if you will let me.
If you'll try.
Will you try?
When we face the storm,
no matter how scary,
no matter how much power
it has over us...
Have you, uh...
Have you talked
to Mom at all?
No, I haven't.
Why?
Um, can we find
a place to talk?
When we face it,
we find
- we are the shelter.
- ♪ It's the beauty in forgotten love ♪
♪ And I don't care... ♪
We'll survive.
♪ ..If you don't understand
why I cry ♪
Yeah, I know it's quiet.
Really quiet.
It's gonna be fine,
buddy.
We're gonna be great.
♪ Hun gar férilisserana irsser ♪
Let's get you to bed.
♪ Ruriguere, ruriguere ♪
We find ourselves coming out
the other side...
stronger for it.
♪ Fîri lisinof ♪
Hey.
You okay?
Yeah.
I just...
I really liked her... Cece.
- ♪ You are the reason ♪
- I know.
♪ I can dance within the
fire of goodbyes ♪
- You, uh... You took the elevator.
- I did.
So you don't learn
from your mistakes, then?
DeLuca,
when did you get so cocky?
When I realized that you like
this just as much as I do.
I think the problem is we need
to get out of these clothes.
Whoa.
You just skipped
a whole lot of steps.
No, I mean the scrubs,
the job.
We need to go out together,
out of this hospital.
- Tonight.
- There she is.
Dr. Grey.
I wanted to see if
you still wanted to...
♪ It's the beauty
in forgotten love ♪
Sorry. could Dr. Grey
and I have a minute?
Actually, we're just right in
the middle of something, so...
♪ It's the beauty
in forgotten love ♪
I'm sorry.
I'm being haunted.
♪ Oh, oh, oh, oh ♪
- ♪ It's the beauty in forgotten love ♪
- It's been a long day,
and I'm going to go home
and see my children.
I will see you later.
- You'll see...
- who later?
We might even find
ourselves happy.
Synchronized  by  srjanapala