Previously, on Grey's Anatomy...
Oh, uh...
I'm... sorry.
Mom! What are you doing here?
What's going on? Are you okay?
Just a little consult.
- Breast cancer?
- I am so sorry.
Would you like me to
grab Maggie for you?
Oh, no.
- I had a baby.
- Had?
He lived for 43
minutes without a brain.
And it almost killed me.
- Tell you not to come home?
- I cannot keep doing this.
- Doing what? I'm not...
- I don't want to have a baby!
I think about you a lot,
and I'm telling you, I am in.
If you are. What do you think?
Keep it moving, folks. Come on.
Move out, please. Move on out.
So he says to me
that when I figure it out,
I should give him a call.
I mean, who says that?
She found her mom
in baggage claim.
Anyway, he's an arrogant ass.
And Maggie has
terrible taste in men.
I don't like the guy.
I mean, the sex is great.
Maybe I shouldn't be
picky about great sex.
You should be picky
about sex. You're hot.
Well, you have to say that
because I let you eat my food
- and live in my house.
- Yes,
- but it's still true.
- Thank you!
There she is.
Stuff comes apart.
An eggshell is never
gonna come back together.
A window will never unbreak.
Thirty seconds in, she's
talking about her boobs.
That's what's on her
mind. Her boob job.
Her boobs, which are
perfectly fine, by the way.
You know what? When
she gets in the car,
you look at them, and you
tell me they're not perfect.
I'm not gonna check
out your mom's boobs.
It's called the Second
Law of Thermodynamics.
It's also called life.
- Oh, it's good to see you,
Meredith.
- Hi! It's good to see you!
Alex, right?
What did you tell them?
What?
I'm not the one getting
the ginormous boobs!
Stuff rarely comes together...
but it'll always come apart.
Wait. You're saying that you don't
have the budget for dozens of babies
- and their tiny,
beating baby hearts?
- Don't. Uh-uh.
No. Every time
you want something,
you say, "But the tiny
babies. The teeny, tiny babies."
But you are the doctor
who cried, "Tiny baby."
Doctor Webber, you tell her.
Robbins wants new
wireless fetal monitors,
- when the ones we have are...
- Not my concern.
Well, damn.
It's not you, it's me.
I pissed him off, too.
- Not like I did.
- Yeah, a little bit
like you did.
- What did you do?
- I have a patient.
Dr. Spano to Oncology.
- Hello.
- Incoming!
DeLuca! Incoming.
ETA less than a minute.
I didn't know you were back.
They said one of the
patient's had syncope.
You'll need a neuro consult.
I just meant how are you doing?
It's nice to be working.
But it's... But it's
gonna be a busy day.
I'm hoping this will
be quick and easy.
Elsie Clatch, 95,
fainted while hiking,
but now GCS is
15, vitals are stable.
- Gently, gently. She's been injured.
- Please, Lewis, all this fuss.
- Hiking?
- How do you think
I made it to 95?
- Alert and oriented times three.
- Sir, did you injure your wrist?
Uh, no, it's fine.
He fell, too. He wouldn't
let go of my hand.
No reason to take a
chance, sir. Let's go.
Her syncopal episode
lasted at least 60 seconds.
Oh. It sounds like you've been
watching a lot of medical shows, sir.
- He's not gonna like that.
- I'm a cardiothoracic surgeon.
One, two, three.
Don't be pompous.
You were a surgeon, so was I.
- They're surgeons now.
- She'll need a head CT.
Still, we'd like to
rule out other injuries.
It's nothing. I just got
a little lightheaded.
You don't know it's nothing.
I know as much as you do.
I fell down.
I'm old. I'm allowed.
We'll need an EKG and
labs with cardiac enzymes.
You heard the man.
- Hey.
- Hi.
Pierce asked if she
could discharge the triple-A
that you guys were working on,
if you didn't have any objections.
Nope, not at all.
Great.
So, did you have a...
chance to think about it?
Oh, no. I don't need to think
about it. You can discharge him.
No, no, no. I mean the
thing that I said about...
- how I think about you.
- No, I haven't thought
about it. I...
I have three kids.
And a job. I'm a surgeon.
Right.
Take your time.
How are you feeling?
I'm good. Just a little tired.
Yeah.
Chemo's not my
idea of a great time.
Sure. Well, I spoke
with your oncologist.
She gave me a full report,
and the chemo's been working.
Your repeat scans came back,
and they show a good response.
You are her star patient.
Ooh, and the prize
is a mastectomy.
Your reconstruction is gonna
go perfectly. It'll be my best work.
Today, we just focus on
getting your pre-op taken care of,
and we get our
oncologist up to speed.
Did you want, um, Maggie
here before we continue?
- Diane, you didn't tell her yet?
- It's too much stress.
Which is exactly why
she needs to know.
This is gonna be
stressful enough for you.
- We're already fighting today.
- No, as your doctor,
I can't, in good confidence,
continue to let this go on, all right?
It's bad for you both.
It's bad for everyone.
- Well, just not yet.
- When? Your surgery is tomorrow.
After.
I can just have the
surgery and tell her then,
and I can tell her
that I had cancer
and not that I have it.
That's not the best idea.
It's how I want to do it.
Is that understood?
Dr. Fields to the NICU.
So did Doctor Avery
answer all your questions?
He sure did.
So you discussed
everything? Even size?
We discussed everything
I needed to discuss.
So what did you
decide, size-wise?
I just want to be prepared, you know?
I've been hugging the same person
for the last 30 years,
you know? This is a big...
- Maggie.
- This is a big renovation.
Maggie...
I don't want to
discuss this with you.
- Just leave it alone.
- Fine.
Well... I hope you'll
enjoy being a nice,
self-involved, lonely person
with an incredible rack.
Pretty straightforward
modified rad.
I'll remove the breast tissue,
then do a lymph node dissection
and leave you to
the reconstruction.
Sounds great.
Need something?
Yeah, I'm on your service today.
No, you're not. I didn't
request a resident.
Dr. Minnick assigned me to you.
All right, I'll talk to Dr. Minnick
after I finish up here,
but no, thanks. I
don't need anyone.
- Okay, sorry. You all set?
- Yeah.
- I'll see you tomorrow.
- Thanks very much.
This is Diane Pierce?
No, no, no. Do not look at
that. You're not on this case.
Is this Maggie's mother?
- Wilson, please.
- Jackson!
Hey.
What the hell?
Why am I locked out
of my mother's file?
- I'm a doctor.
- Yes, well,
she requested privacy.
I'm her daughter.
She can't handle the fact I might
have an opinion about her boob job.
She's anxious because
she's going into surgery.
Now you're telling me how
my mom feels, Jackson?
What is going on
here? Level with me.
You saw what happened
the last time she was here.
And I thought we
could actually fix it.
I wanted to talk
and actually try,
but she has been shutting
me out from moment one.
Why is she doing this?
You know, I really...
I really couldn't say.
Is she embarrassed
about the boob job?
- Then why is she getting it?
- She's scared...
about her surgery. I
mean, she needs support.
She needs your support
So I'm awful is
what you're saying.
It's... You know
that's not what I mean.
Okay.
I'll try. I will leave
it alone. I will try.
Thank you.
Just tell me, are they
gonna be "huge" huge?
Maggie, please. Just trust me.
Okay, thank you.
Wow!
No, no, no, don't. I don't need
to remind you of HIPAA, right?
Okay? Nothing to be discussed.
Right. Sorry.
Well, you know now.
So I guess I can use you.
- Only if you can...
- I... I can.
All right. Then go
ahead. Get prepped.
Close the door, please
We do this hike every other day.
I don't know why
today I got so wonky.
Squeeze my fingers,
Elsie? Hard as you can.
- Very good.
- I'm sorry.
Are you the Doctor Clatch?
Uh...
I'm one of two, yeah.
You... you are.
Uh-huh...
You worked with Doctor Raven.
Jeez, don't remind me.
You helped develop the
cardiopulmonary bypass machine.
The man was a
blowhard and a grabass!
- That is true.
- Right.
So, were you there when
he first connected a child
- to his mother's circulation?
- Okay, let's all focus, please.
Was I there?
- Yeah.
- I did most of it.
DeLuca, take her to CT, and
page me when she's done.
All right. Dr. Clatch,
I'll be happy to show you
where you can wait, okay?
No, you will not. I'm
gonna stay with my wife.
- Oh, stop. You don't know brains.
- I know enough!
Doctor Clatch? Okay.
- Follow me.
- Huh? Yeah.
Would you page me when
her studies are back, please?
- Hey.
- Just stop it.
- Stop what?
- Pretending like we're doctors.
- We are doctors.
- I'm your husband!
You can't hide in plain
sight from me and...
ignore the fact that we haven't
talked, and that we have things...
- I'm at work. We're...
- You're trying to act...
like nothing happened.
You ran out on me!
You ran away from home!
From your husband.
You're married.
- We got married!
- I know!
We took vows...
for better or for worse.
Amelia, you...
Running out, acting this way...
It's not how a marriage works.
So I need you to
tell me right now.
Are you ever coming home
so we can work this out...
or not?
Perfect.
You need to decide
what you want.
Because I know.
I know what I want.
And at some point, you
need to figure that out, too.
Just pull it together.
So, you weren't into the idea
of her being a surgeon at first?
- I was.
- He wasn't!
I was halfway through my
residency, and Lewis said to me,
"Elsie, this surgeon business
is not making you any friends.
You need to think of
something else to do."
I was trying to
take care of you!
- But you didn't, did you?
- I did not.
- Good.
- Because you knew
what you wanted.
Oh! This one gets it!
Well, it was a different
time back then.
It was. It was.
All right, let's give
the Clatches some air.
They are not here for your
entertainment, guys. Time to go.
Oh, let them stay. How
else they gonna learn?
They have a lot of work to do.
Well, this is a teaching
hospital, right? So teach them!
It's all right. Come on back.
I can see by your faces
that the news is bad.
So just tell me how bad.
You have a brain bleed.
A loculated acute on
chronic subdural hematoma.
Oh, God!
Elsie, the bleed is only
gonna keep increasing.
It could become
catastrophic at any time now.
Now, I could do a craniotomy...
and decompress the hematoma.
With a chance it would
give me some more time?
Yes, but Dr. Shepherd
doesn't think that's a good idea.
She didn't say that.
Didn't say, "I want
to" or "I need to."
She said, "I could."
That's what we tell our patients
when we don't want
to give them nothing.
I'm sorry, kids. Lesson's
over. Got it, folks? Okay?
- Hey! How's it going?
- Boobs.
Oh, you have to let that go.
My mother wants basketball
boobs. You let it go.
Mom boobs again?
It doesn't stop.
What reason does she have
to defile her body that way?
Are you sure you
want to know that?
My mother wouldn't let me
pierce my ears until I was ten.
She told me that
masturbating made Jesus cry.
She said that nail
polish was for prostitutes.
That woman wants stripper
boobs? Yes, I want a reason.
Her reasons are for sex.
- Why would you say that?
- Okay, well maybe she
just wants her, um...
shirts to fit better.
Okay, now, that's
almost understandable.
To get more sex.
I am asking you guys for advice.
Okay, okay. Sorry,
sorry, sorry. Okay.
Okay, tell me again.
Am I just...
supposed to accept that this
horrifying thing is happening?
Am I just supposed
to get on board, fold?
Make a decision to
support my G-cup mom?
No, you're right.
- You do need a reason.
- I do!
She can't expect you to
just blindly jump on board.
You should demand a reason.
- That is bad advice.
- It is?
She doesn't owe
you an explanation,
and you don't have a right to
tell her what to do with her boobs.
No, I'm... I'm...
- not...
- It's her body. It's her boobs.
She doesn't have to justify
her decision to anyone.
I mean, don't come at her
demanding anything. Just...
give her some support.
I wanna know what you
did to Richard Webber.
Nothing.
- Oh, it was bad. Really bad?
- Okay! Shh!
I kissed Eliza Minnick
and he caught me.
Mm-mm, mm-mm, mm.
Mm-mm, what?
I get why he's mad at you. That
was way worse than what I did.
How is that worse?
You gave away his job.
And you put your mouth
on the person who took it.
See, mine was a business
decision. You made it personal.
That doesn't even make
sense. I mean, listen.
This has nothing to do with him.
Bros before potential
love interests.
I wouldn't talk to you, either.
That's...
unprofessional, disappointing.
You know what?
You just feel guilty.
You know that you did wrong, and you're
just trying to make yourself feel better.
- Whatever helps you
sleep at night. Mm-hmm.
Lewis, let her talk.
I've...
I've heard all I need, Els.
A successful surgery would
definitely buy you more time.
But as you know, the amount
of shift, combined with your age
and aspirin usage are
bad prognostic signs.
Surgery holds higher
risk for you, much higher.
So it's settled. No surgery.
- Nothing's settled.
- But she just said...
I know, but if we don't do
anything, I'm gonna go, anyway.
Well, that's better than me
walking out of here alone tonight.
Will you listen to me?
You're not getting this surgery.
- Will you excuse me, Lewis?
- El...
But I would like to
talk to my doctor alone.
Dr. Clatch, how about
we go get a cup of coffee?
Okay.
Now, you were saying?
Elsie will talk her into a
surgery. She's stubborn.
I need to talk to that gal's boss
right away. He needs to back her up.
She is the head of
the neuro department.
She is the boss, and she's
as stubborn as hell too.
Dr. Clatch,
I know Dr. Shepherd...
very well, and
you can trust her.
She's not gonna be
talked into anything
that she doesn't
want to do, okay?
Okay, come on.
Dr. Cooper to
Occupational Therapy.
Come on.
Dr. Clatch, I worry you
won't survive the surgery.
And based on your age alone...
it could kill you.
Or it could give me more time.
I need more time.
I need time to help him
learn how to be alone.
I also want more time with him.
You believe...
60 years is not enough?
Nurse Friedman to
the Instrument Room.
I can take no for an answer.
- Don't.
- I prefer it, actually,
to no answer.
Why do you always
have to do that?
Why do you always have
to make a joke of everything?
- Are you serious, or aren't you?
- Of course I am.
Because I'm not joking.
This isn't funny to me.
You know, you keep pushing me,
but you're not giving
me anything to go on.
Man. We have been going around
and around with this for months.
I feel like I don't know you.
And everybody that I
know, that knows you,
they don't like you.
And you just keep making jokes like
somehow that doesn't matter to me.
That's not true.
This isn't up to me to make a choice.
It's up to you to give me a reason.
Okay, you want a reason?
Yes.
Okay, there are, there are
all sorts of reasons to like me.
Actually.
Name one.
I have to go.
- I thought
you weren't doing surgery.
- I never said that.
You said you thought
it was a bad idea,
and I practically assured
Lewis that you wouldn't.
Why would you do
that? She's my patient.
I thought you'd made
a decision, or at least
consult with him before
you changed your mind.
Okay, enough! Stop it, Owen!
No more.
All your pre-op tests
came back looking terrific,
so just two more things
before we get you home
for some much needed rest.
Okay, number one, no
eating after midnight, right?
- Okay.
- And number two, we...
are gonna tell Maggie.
Oh no. I told you,
uh, after the surgery,
- after the cancer is out.
- I'm not gonna
perform the surgery,
Diane, unless we tell Maggie.
- You can't do that!
- Of course I can. I'm your doctor.
- But it's not your business.
- And it would be
an irresponsible
course of treatment.
Okay? Maggie is your
only support system here.
- I'll just get
another doctor then.
- No, you won't.
She told you I was
the best 'cause I am.
You trusted her then,
and you trust her now.
I understand. It's
okay to be afraid.
You don't have to
be afraid for Maggie.
She's not scared of cancer.
She would just want
to fight this with you.
Let her be there for you.
I should've told her months ago.
- It's not too late.
- It's too late.
Mom?
You ready to go home?
- Maggie, sweetheart, I...
- Mom, it's fine.
Good luck tomorrow.
I hope that your implants are
everything that you want them to be.
- I'm not getting implants.
- Mom, it's fine.
I have breast cancer.
I have breast cancer, and they're
doing a mastectomy tomorrow.
What are you talking about?
What is she talking about?
Here.
Come here, honey. Let...
She really said that? "I
need more time with him"?
That's what she said.
Deluca, suction there.
Sixty years of
marriage. Wow, that's...
It's never enough time.
If it's 60 years
or it's six weeks.
It's never gonna be enough time.
Well, these people
are an anomaly.
What? You're saying two people
can't have a long and happy marriage?
I'm saying maybe this is an
unrealistic ideal of marriage.
Sixty years of good,
bad, and ugly. That's...
everything.
What's wrong with wanting that?
Nothing.
There's nothing wrong
with wanting that, DeLuca.
Scissors.
Well, Webber's pissed. And,
honestly, he's got a right to be.
When does it end, though?
It doesn't solve anything, for
him to walk around scowling at me.
When does the
cold shoulder stop?
Yeah, well... he'll come around.
Oh, uh, Shepherd's decompressing
the hematoma. Fingers crossed.
Mmm.
- Sixty damn years.
- Mmm, Right?
You have it in you?
Hey, when I said "I
do," I meant "I do."
Even though I know what
you're gonna be like in 60 years.
And what am I going
to be like, Dr. Warren?
Bossy.
You'll be retired and
jonesing for the days
when you ran a whole hospital,
bossing me around,
and Tuck, and...
Tuck's poor wife!
Lord, help that woman.
Ah, like you're gonna
be some walk in the park.
Me? I'm gonna be distinguished
with a little touch of gray.
And one of those guys that tells
the same stories over and over
and exaggerates it every time.
"And then I sliced a woman open
on the kitchen table
during a rainstorm."
You have it in you?
If the stories come
with foot rubs.
Deal.
Huh. Hi.
Saturation levels have...
remained the same all night.
She's stubborn,
but she's right, as usual.
Sixty years, not many
couples last that long.
You want to know the secret?
- Everyone wants
to know the secret.
- I'll take it if you have one.
There isn't one.
Just stayed married
to her, I guess.
I would never have had
the life I did without her.
So I just stayed married to her.
If there's something
else, some other secret...
she's the one who knows it.
I don't know a damn thing.
'Cause you never stop yapping.
Oh, Elsie!
No more.
No more locking me
out of my mother's chart.
I want to know
anything and everything.
I want to be CC'd
on every chart,
every post-op
report, every test.
No secrets.
I did want to tell
you, you know.
How could you let
me talk to her like that?
You could've stopped me.
What is wrong with you?
We're supposed to be friends.
Why didn't you just tell me?
I am your friend,
Maggie, but I'm also her doctor.
Go fix her.
I want two-hour neuro checks and
call me immediately for any signs
- of increased ICP.
- Got it.
Nice job.
Thanks.
I know I was against it, but
it looks like you were right.
I think you gave that
couple more time together.
I don't care what you think.
Amelia, stop.
You don't have any
right to an opinion.
And you certainly don't
have the right to bully me.
Bully you?
You don't have the right
to give me ultimatums
about when to come home
and make up my mind.
- Okay.
- For better or for worse.
That's what you said.
Well, guess what?
This is the "for worse"!
And you don't have the right to just
decide that I don't have myself together.
Okay? You... You don't
make me the one who is wrong.
I am tired of being the
messed-up one, okay?
Because I'm not. You are
at least as messed up as me.
- You disappeared!
- You are suffocating me!
- That is unfair.
- Really?
I would love to ask Christina
how suffocated she felt by you,
by your needs, by your idea
of a baby, by what you want!
All right!
Stop!
Not here.
I only wanted the same
thing you said you wanted!
- You told me...
- Okay, why do you even
want a baby?
- Have you asked yourself that?
- What?
- Why do I want a baby?
- Yes, yes.
What do you need
that you don't have
that you think a baby
is going to bring you?
- I want a family.
- You have one!
You and me, that
makes one. What else?
What do you need?
- I mean, it's normal to want...
- No, you don't get to call
what is normal!
You don't know!
You want a dream, Owen.
And when you have a child,
you might not get to
have what you asked for.
You get what you are given.
And it might be wonderful.
And it might be painful,
and it might be both.
I know you're scared, but...
Amelia, I think you'd
be an amazing mom.
I was already an
amazing mom, Owen.
For better and for worse.
Are you here for that?
Or do we just play by your
rules, by your "normal" rules?
'Cause that's not life.
It's not a marriage.
Not one that's gonna last.
How we doing? Feeling
better? A little more...
Sixteen twenty-two.
I'm sorry?
The time of her death.
For when you
want to put it down.
I looked.
Dr. Fields to Medical Records.
- Okay, all right.
- Got it.
I think that we should talk about
what you saw with Eliza and I.
Arizona,
you've always had
a active love life.
If I worried about who
you've been kissing on,
it would leave me little
time for anything else.
Okay, you're mad.
You didn't mean that.
Yes, I did.
No, I didn't.
Damn it.
This is what I've turned into.
I've become this person who
takes sides and counts votes.
It's ugly, and it's
bitter, and it's small.
- This is what
Bailey's done here.
- I'm... I'm so sorry.
You said you were
with me, Robbins.
- I believed you.
- I was. I am.
I just...
I just didn't expect to feel this
way, okay? I... I didn't try to.
Okay, you know what?
I need some time, okay?
I'll...
I'll come around, but...
I need some damn time.
Take all the time you need.
Well, I can call the morgue
and I can finish her paperwork.
Hey.
Hey, look, she was 95.
Okay, you were right. They
had way more time than most.
They wanted more.
She wanted more.
That was the only
reason to do the surgery.
And we took away
what little time they had.
Shepherd said her co-morbidities
made it unlikely that she'd...
Why do we do it?
Why do we do any of it? Why...
If we can't do...
what we say we
were gonna do, then...
If we actually
have no control...
then how dare we tell
them we can, you know?
I think I'm in love with Jo.
I might be. I...
I'm pretty sure.
Stop talking. Stop talking.
I want more.
All right.
- Hey.
- Go away.
- I'm sorry.
- Hey.
- No!
It's okay.
I don't have a good reason.
I tried to come up with one.
So then I thought,
"Well, why do I like her?"
And I don't know.
From the first time I saw you,
you were at the O.R. board.
You were talking with Pierce,
and she said something
that made you laugh, and...
I couldn't move.
Then I had to wait for you to write
your name on the board because...
I just needed to
know who you were.
So, I don't have...
a good reason
for you to like me.
I didn't even try to like
you. I didn't want to.
I certainly don't want to have to
think about you all the time, trying to...
come in early, see
your name on the board,
come up with that one
thing that's gonna make you
smile so your eyes
do that thing they do.
Anyway, so that's why
I joke so much and...
to keep from having
to say anything like this.
So, I don't have a good reason.
I'm sorry. I wish I did.
Okay, so you should
ask me out to dinner.
- Do you want to go
out to dinner?
- Yes.
Dr. Grey, Dr. Pierce needs you.
Okay. Sorry.
So, another signature here.
- Um...
- Do you know what funeral home
you want yet?
No, our church might know.
Do I have to fill all this out now?
Can I do this in the morning?
Of course, you can. Everything
can wait until tomorrow.
- Okay.
- Is there anything else
I can do for you?
Well,
I don't have a car.
Elsie and I came...
in an ambulance.
Well, let me call you a cab.
No, it's... it's fine. Just...
tell me where I can get
one. I'm all turned around.
Well, just go out here, turn
right, and at the corner. But...
Dr. Clatch, please, let me just
- get you a...
- No, I...
I have to figure things
out for myself now.
I... I... Okay.
- Go home.
- Thank you.
- Here. That's for you.
- Oh...
Thank you.
Everything comes
apart at some point.
We all will. It's the law.
It's what we were
designed to do.
My mom is really sick.
We have to face
it and accept it.
And try to hold it together...
for as long as we can.