Fran? I'm Robin.
Please come in.
Cute home. Two
bedroom, one bath?
Yeah.
A guy I know collects those. Says
they're worth a fortune on the internet.
Yeah.
You've never used our
agency before, have you?
Is it that obvious?
As you can see, we offer
a full range of services.
"Round the World"?
Our deluxe package.
Offers all the
services of A, B, and C.
How much? $1,000.
And satisfaction is
guaranteed. Twice.
I'll get the money.
I'll get ready.
Harrington?
Harrington, what are
you doing up there?
All right, now don't take this
personally but you're gonna have to go...
Fran.
Is this okay?
Fran, you all right?
Oh, God.
Fran?
Yeah, I need an ambulance
at 500 North Sycamore.
I don't know, my
friend collapsed.
And what were you
doing when you fainted?
We were just...
Looking for her cat.
And have you banged
your head recently?
No.
Is this a motion sickness patch?
I must have forgotten to take
it off. I just got back from a trip.
Scopolamine can cause
dizziness and blurred vision.
You probably hit your head when
you fell, and that caused the blackout.
I thought those patches were
supposed to prevent you from getting sick.
Every drug has a side effect.
But it might be a good
idea to keep your eye on her
for the next few hours
to make sure she's okay.
Actually...
She has to get back to work.
Is it important?
We just don't like people to
be alone after they leave here.
I'm fine. Really.
I'm... Fran?
Fran?
I got a seizure. Code cart.
What's wrong with her?
I have no idea.
Where's House?
I want my blankie! I want
my blankie! I want my blankie!
Antique vintner's
cane. Cost me $900.
It had a corkscrew in it.
That would explain
the vintner's reference.
It could be used as a
weapon against the pilot.
Only if he's stuck in
a bottle of zinfandel.
You'll get it back when we land.
I want my blankie!
Give her 20 milligrams of
antihistamine. Could save her life.
'Cause if she doesn't
shut up I'll kill her.
Delivering goodwill to
yet another continent.
You only forced me to
deliver a speech, not goodwill.
You gave a three-minute speech.
You know how much WHO
accreditation means to the hospital?
Well, it may have been
short, but it had girth.
And the room service
thing was just spiteful.
I was hungry. $300
for a bottle of wine.
I was thirsty.
$120 on video services.
I was lonely.
That's 500 in
expenses I can't justify.
Don't worry. I'll
take care of it.
Right.
Here you are, sir.
You're welcome.
Welcome aboard, Mr. House.
You're right here in 2-A.
Ms. Cuddy you're in the
next cabin and to the left, 9-C.
No, I booked two
first-class tickets.
This must be a
mistake. No mistake.
I just arranged for a
$500 fare reduction.
Expense problem solved.
Where did you travel? Duluth.
To visit my sister. Really?
Is this her artwork?
"Fire butt"?
I was a little drunk.
Where were you a little drunk?
I turned 58 last March.
Same age my mother
was when she died.
Next week I packed
a bag, I went to JFK,
looked at the big board, took the
first plane that went to a warm place.
Caracas. Oh, my God.
Did you drink the
water? Eat salads?
Any raw foods. Yup.
And?
I also did mescal shooters and snorted
cocaine from a homosexual man's stomach.
Did you have sex? No.
Not with him. I had
sex with El Gordo.
He was a large man.
Oh, my God.
I never do things like that.
I should have gone to
visit my sister. It was stupid.
That's why I'm sick, isn't it?
It's possible.
Here you are. Rib
eye, medium rare.
Thank you.
Some more Pinot Grigio?
No. I think I will
switch to the Syrah.
Sir, are you all right?
He's drunk.
See?
Does anyone speak Korean?
Is anyone a doctor?
Yes.
I'll go get her.
What do you want?
Do you really think I was gonna
leave you stuck back here for 18 hours?
Go on, enjoy.
With the Vicodin and the
wine I could sleep anywhere.
Thank you.
We should put her back
on the scopolamine patch.
She can't wear motion sickness
patches for the rest of her life.
No, but if it does relive her
symptoms it'll narrow down our search.
Anything else you two
guys wanna agree on?
You have a problem
with us agreeing?
No, I have a problem with
the other thing you're doing,
which makes me question
your motive for agreeing.
I'll put her back on
the patch. What else?
It's gotta be
something neurological.
We should do a CT,
look for a brain tumor.
Could also be an allergy
or something environmental.
We should check her home.
Bit more likely she got sick in
Caracas than in New Jersey.
Right, I forgot. There
are no toxins in the US.
I think I'm starting to
feel sorry for House.
Get a tox screen, chem-20,
STD panel, blood cultures.
Then you run a CT and
you check her house.
Please.
Not funny.
Wasn't supposed
to be funny ha-ha.
Fever, headache,
severe abdominal pain,
and a rash all
over his lower back.
It's serious. Maybe contagious.
We just attended a
symposium on pandemics
and you run right into
one on the flight home.
Talk about a small world.
If it's meningococcus,
half the passengers
on this plane could get
infected and die before
we reach New York.
Is someone sick? No.
Someone has a hangover.
He had a snootload of
Bloody Marys before dinner.
Watch the movie.
That booze did not give him the
rash. It is textbook meningococcus.
It's also textbook
allergic reaction to pollen,
peanuts, and the semen-stained
polyester blanket he's lying on.
Mr. Peng's throwing up again.
We have to turn around.
What? Why do we have to...
We don't. You misunderstood.
Dr. Cuddy just meant that
he might feel less nauseous
if he was facing in
a different direction.
She didn't mean to panic
a planeload of people.
We're about to head
over the North Pole.
We don't turn back now,
the next ER's 15 hours away.
He'll be fine.
I'm a doctor, too.
You haven't examined him.
Korean male, mid
30s, 5'9", 160, bald,
scar on the right side of his jaw,
medic alert bracelet on his left wrist
indicating that he's
allergic to, at least, penicillin.
Without any way to do an
LP or rule out meningococcus,
our only choice is
to assume the worst.
Good point.
On the other hand, I am a board-certified
specialist in infectious disease.
She assigns parking spaces.
Please let me know
if he gets any worse.
Think we should feed the cat?
Bowl's full.
If he wants it, he can
get it. Cadmium yellow?
Heavy metal poisoning would
explain the ataxia and the seizures.
Not unless she was
painting with her tongue.
Was Foreman right?
Did you agree with me
because of our relationship?
"Relationship"? You
know what I mean.
You mean because of
our lack of a relationship.
I mean, because
we're having sex.
Yes. Foreman's right.
I thought you were completely
wrong about the medicine,
but agreed with you anyway
because I figured then you'd
do me in some old lady's home.
Then well played.
Come on, we're supposed
to be looking for toxins.
We agreed it was a
brain tumor. What?
He's watching.
Haven't you had
anybody watch before?
Is that guy really sick? No.
He's all better. I
don't believe you.
Look that way. Why?
Because you're gonna throw
up and I don't want it on me.
I'll get some towels.
Give her a banana. Monkey see,
monkey barf. You smell vomit...
Okay. Wasn't expecting that.
I need help.
Who doesn't?
I need someone to talk to.
Can you say, "Crikey, mate"?
Crikey, mate. Perfect.
Now no matter what I say,
you agree with me, okay?
Okay. Nicely done.
And you disagree
with everything I say.
Sorry. Not understanding.
That's close enough.
And you get morally
outraged at everything I say.
That's a permanent
marker, you know.
Wow.
You guys are good.
We are looking for the simplest
way to explain these symptoms.
Organophosphate poisoning. Some
international flights spray pesticides.
Could be.
Sorry, English not so nice.
Is this a joke?
Just passed the halfway mark.
Can't turn around. Nice call.
No worries.
We think it's
pesticide poisoning.
We don't spray these flights.
Dramamine overdose.
Wouldn't explain the fever.
Jet lag. Wouldn't explain
the abdominal pain.
Deep vein thrombosis.
Wouldn't explain the nausea.
Food poisoning. What
was on the menu?
Steak and sea bass in First Class.
Fettuccine and seafood kebabs in Economy.
Since when does food
poisoning cause a rash?
Sea bass, seafood kebabs?
He had the sea bass.
Please tell me she
had the kebabs.
I think so.
Ciguatera poisoning.
It's an instant-onset toxin.
Symptoms include...
E. All of the above.
It's only found in certain kinds
of tropical game fish such as...
Sea bass?
Make sure you get
a resume from him.
Hello? Excuse me.
Ladies and gentlemen, I have a brief
announcement concerning your meals.
If you ate the sea bass
or the seafood kebabs,
you have ingested
a dangerous toxin.
However, if you proceed to the
restrooms both on your left and right
at the rear of the plane and
vomit as soon as possible,
the toxic effect should
be minimal. What?
Thank you, and
have a pleasant flight.
Meningococcus makes
just as much sense.
I know.
What did you find?
Nothing in her house.
Big waste of time.
Medically.
CT was a complete waste.
She was negative for tumors,
her blood was negative for drugs,
heavy metals, tropical diseases,
food poisoning, and STDs.
Also no sign of lead
poisoning or sepsis.
Apparently Venezuelan tattoo
parlors have standards after all.
Good to know.
We sure she's even sick?
Two more seizures
in the last two hours.
Which is slower than she was having
them before you put the patch back on.
I'm an idiot. She's exposed herself to so
much crap I just assumed it was a zebra.
It's breast cancer.
Since when is breast cancer
treatable by motion sickness meds?
It's not. But the inflammation caused
by the paraneoplastic syndrome
caused by the cancer can
be reduced by anticholinergics.
Hey, here you go.
Is he gonna die?
We're doing all we can. We don't
know what's wrong with him yet.
Am I gonna die?
No.
Here, chew on these.
Good news is all the
pilots are red meat men.
Although I was kind of looking
forward to landing this puppy myself.
Peng's getting worse.
That makes sense.
First Class ate before Coach.
He digested more of his
food before he threw up.
Or you're wrong and we're gonna
start seeing neurological symptoms soon.
Seizures, paralysis, ataxia.
We're not gonna see ataxia.
You're so sure you're right. No.
It's just hard to show clumsiness when
you're lying moaning in a fetal position.
Hey, stand up.
Does nobody speak
Korean on this flight?
I assumed you did.
I know how to ask him
if his sister's over 18,
I just don't think
that's gonna help.
Hey, stand up. Stand up.
Don't play the
cripple card with me.
Oh, hi. I'm leaving.
Work.
Okay.
Important client. Sure.
Listen.
Are you close?
Why?
She needs a mammogram.
Oh, God.
I know I'm throwing a lot at you.
She just has no family in town.
And I really think she
could use a friend right now.
Okay. Put your hand here.
You don't have to stay.
No, it's no problem.
But why?
You don't even know me.
You gotta be scared.
I almost hope it's
breast cancer. No.
Then it wouldn't be my fault.
Whatever it is,
it's not your fault.
That's not true. You
can control things.
Not everything.
But you don't have to take
stupid risks. I was being an idiot.
You were having fun.
You have regrets?
Yeah.
Robin?
Hold still.
Good.
Okay, we're gonna get just one
more. I'm sorry, I know it hurts.
It's not that.
It's my eye. My right eye.
I can't see.
It's definitely ataxia.
And it's definitely a rash.
You gonna look at it
for five more minutes
before concluding it's
also definitely a leg?
Thin leg.
It's been in a cast. So?
So it could be
radiation poisoning.
From a broken leg?
From the x-rays they took of it.
He could break
every bone in his body
and still not have enough
x-rays to cause radiation sickness.
Unless those x-rays were
performed in Wankoff, North Korea,
by a third-grade dropout
with a 50-year-old imager.
Which accounts for
the absence of fur.
Radiation poisoning
accounts for all his symptoms.
I have hair. I haven't had an
x-ray since I got my teeth whitened.
You're pregnant.
I'm what?
Explains the nausea,
abdominal pains, fever,
and why you're stuffing
your 36Cs into a 34B bra.
And her rash?
PUPPPs. Common pregnancy rash.
I can't be pregnant.
You a virgin?
No, but...
You're pregnant. Mazel tov.
Let's get him into the chair.
Two different diagnoses.
I thought you didn't
believe in coincidences.
I believe in statistics.
Two hundred passengers on
the plane, 10 should be gay,
two should be with child, and
one should be incredibly annoying
with an extra ass
chromosome. House.
Get him some iodized salt to
protect his thyroid. I'm going back...
House.
You're wrong.
I said we should have turned back.
You should have listened to me.
Now we're eight
miles over the Arctic...
I'm trying to listen to
you now, so shut up.
Heart's fine.
Breasts are firm.
Is it contagious?
A lot of the
passengers are scared.
Tell them there's
nothing to worry about.
Is there something
to worry about? Yeah.
Tell them there's nothing to worry
about. And get me a flashlight.
Cover your left eye with this.
Photophobia.
Symptom of meningitis.
We need antibiotics.
I'll call down to the pharmacy.
You're creeping me out.
Then get me a lab.
Pseudomonas smell
yeasty, staph smells musty,
and some liver disease
smell of ammonia.
House. I'm not in heat.
Citrus-y on the nose with
a blush of toasted coconut.
I need to get a better
look at your rash.
Use your imagination.
Fine, should I go with Lifeguard
Cuddy or Mother Superior Cuddy?
Three more passengers are sick.
If we don't get drugs, we're gonna
have a lot of dead passengers.
Blindness in her right eye
indicates it's not breast cancer.
It's likely neurological.
I just met her today.
You should go.
She needs someone here.
That's not your job.
Please let me know
that she's okay.
It's just sex.
There's no such thing.
Other eye.
Are you saying women can't separate
the physical from the emotional?
No one does it well,
women do it worse.
You just want us to stop
because you think it's affecting...
Me. Yeah.
Polyspikes are over 01 and 02.
That's her left eye.
Burst suppression on every lead.
Fran?
She's comatose.
Nothing. Nothing.
Nothing.
Come on, nobody has no meds!
Excuse me. Open your mouth.
Where's the acyclovir?
I'm not on any meds.
Well, you better get
some. You've got herpes.
What do you know? He's got
some. This must be your lucky day.
This is for real.
People are sick.
Some of us will be deplaning in
body bags unless you cough up.
Here. Over here.
Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you.
God bless you.
Her brain is shutting down
because of intracranial pressure.
Or her nerves are dying.
Because of the
increased pressure.
She has a bleed in her brain.
You said the CT showed...
No tumors. But if she has an AVM
leading to a cerebral hemorrhage,
we could've missed it. She
needs a burr hole to relieve...
You wanna drill into her brain because
of an invisible bleed the CT couldn't see?
We should do an LP to confirm
the presence of red blood cells.
And her brain herniates
and then she dies.
Right. Better to
kill her in the OR.
Chase, what do you think?
Here's a cliffhanger.
I think it would help to know what she
has before we start digging into her brain.
Might be better to play
it safe to start. Do an LP.
Sex better be damn good.
Lot of apples, not
many candy bars.
Any antibiotics?
Three caps of Augmentin.
For six patients.
Give them to Peng.
He's allergic to penicillin.
The First Aid kit
has two epi pens.
If he has a severe reaction,
10 epi pens won't save him.
You take the pills. He's worse.
He's a guy who
doesn't speak English.
Give him the meds.
If it's not meningitis, we're risking his
life and flushing meds down the toilet.
Then do an LP on
him. If it's clear, you win.
If it's cloudy he gets the
Augmentin. And we risk a reaction.
Sounds like a plan. All except for the
part where we don't have an LP needle.
And the shaking of the plane means
I'll probably pierce his spinal cord
and cripple him for life. But, I
mean, it totally sounds like a plan.
You're right. Let him
die. Give me the meds.
Got it. Damn.
What is it?
Shut up. Don't get hysterical.
Just tell me
what the hell it is.
House. We should
have turned back.
We should have turned back.
House.
Hold this.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we have a passenger with a
confirmed case of bacterial meningitis.
Unless we land as soon as possible,
the passenger will not survive.
It's very likely that some of
you have been infected as well.
As soon as you start feeling symptoms, we
need to isolate you in First Class cabin.
Fever, rash, nausea,
and in the late stages
tremor in the left hand.
I've got that. Oh, God.
- What do we do?
- It's really bad.
Break out the bubbly.
Yo, listen up.
The bad news is, you have an illness.
The good news is it's not meningitis.
It's not fatal, it's
just embarrassing.
It's conversion disorder, more
commonly known as mass hysteria.
It happens often in high-anxiety
situations, especially to women.
I know it sounds sexist, but science
says you're weak and soft. What can I do?
House, you're wrong.
Look at my hand.
Yeah. Look at her hand.
Shaking left hand. What
is that a symptom of?
Not meningitis. It's basically
a symptom of nothing.
I put the idea into their
heads and watched it happen.
Same thing Peng cruelly did
with the puking and the rash.
The rash is in my head?
Your mind controls your body.
If it thinks you're
sick, it makes you sick.
It just started.
If you'll all just calm down, your
symptoms will soon go away.
And to facilitate this process,
your flight crew will move through the
cabin with a complimentary bar service.
Thank you and, as always,
have a pleasant flight.
Still feel like puking? No.
How did you know?
LP was negative.
I came up with an alternate
theory and I tested it.
Couldn't have done it without you.
Rage is a symptom of mass hysteria.
Just one more thing to clean
up. Peng set off the mass hysteria.
What set off Peng?
He really is dying. Yeah.
I haven't the faintest idea why.
What's extension pasturing?
It's when you're molested
by a priest's cousin.
Do we really need these three?
Worried they'll
make you look bad?
Could be symptomatic of
head trauma, cerebral infarction,
or intracranial
hemorrhage. Thoughts?
How long until we land?
Too long to wait.
His head's as smooth as
a baby's bottom, no bumps.
So I think we can
rule out head trauma.
But you gotta choose between
what's left, a clog or a leak?
You're talking of toilet?
House, is this actually helpful?
Not so far.
What about syphilis?
Well, first of all, he apparently
speaks a language no one else speaks,
which makes talking up
the ladies a little rough.
We're flying out of Singapore.
If he has a credit card and a
condom, he can get anything he wants.
What?
Condoms.
He has focal limb paralysis.
His legs got paralyzed
by a condom?
No, by cocaine.
It was inside the condom.
It's now spreading
through his digestive tract.
You think he's a mule.
I think he's a jackass.
We're gonna have
to operate. Cool!
They're gonna kill
her. We were wrong.
Which means Foreman was right.
Maybe Foreman's right about us,
too. Maybe we should just stop all this.
I mean, if it's
affecting our jobs.
It's not affecting our jobs.
We had sex in a patient's bedroom. A
bedroom we were examining for toxins.
Yeah, our judgment's
right on the mark.
All right. No more sex in patient's
homes, no more sex with cats watching.
Anywhere else you
wanna cross off the list?
The bowl. What?
Has she eaten since
she's been here?
She's been sick
since she's been here.
What if it's a symptom?
Well, why would you think...
The bowl was full.
You're gonna need to hold him
down. He's not gonna like this.
Do you really think he's a mule?
Fits the symptoms.
You sure he's not contagious?
Pretty much.
You can't be pretty much
sure. Means you're not sure.
Oh, aren't you clever?
Come on.
I know you're pretty
much unconscious,
but as has been pointed out to
me, pretty much doesn't mean squat.
Okay, hold him tight.
The faster we do this, the
less likely he is to die of shock.
Tighter.
Sorry. Do that again.
Ease off and then press down.
Pressure on his
joints relieves his pain.
Okay. Wrong again.
Where's his wallet?
Scuba certification card.
Big deal. I have
one of these. Yeah.
But do you also have a receipt from
Tekong's Scuba Rental dated yesterday?
Tell the Captain to drop as
low as he can, under 5,000 feet.
We're at 38,000...
Peng's got the bends.
He went diving yesterday.
Like an idiot, he surfaced too
quickly, and like a bigger idiot,
he boarded a flight which is
pressurized to 8,000 feet above sea level.
Low pressure is killing him.
Tell the pilot to dive until we can
club baby seals out of the window.
And get him some oxygen.
Fifty years ago, it was one estate. The
two homes shared an electrical system.
Unfortunately, the
exterminator didn't know that,
so when they
fumigated next door,
the poison gas flowed through
the old pipe and into your house.
The scopolamine patch was
masking the effects of the poison.
You'll have to stay here for a few more
days, but after that you should be fine.
I'm sorry about your cat.
And your hair.
For 12 years, Harrington
never left the property.
I thought I was being
punished for going away,
but really I was being
punished for coming home.
Thank you. I saved
your life. You owe me.
I wasn't sick.
But you didn't know
that. You owe me.
I know it now.
Your mind convinced your body
to get a rash, photophobia, vomit.
How do you know it wouldn't have
shut down your cold, cold heart next?
I don't owe you.
You're mean.
That's how I compensate
for being weak and soft.
I just wanted to say thank you.
You're extremely welcome.
And I'm in New
York every Monday.
Are you handicap accessible?
Hi, Robin?
This is Dr. Wilson.
Fran's doctor. James.
It was a toxin. We caught it in
time, and she's gonna be fine.
Yeah, it is.
Listen, I was just wondering if you
were coming back in again to visit.
Nice catch.
Thanks.
Think even House
would be impressed.
I don't know about that.
Any idea how you
wanna celebrate?
What?
I want more.
I thought you were
getting a little worn out by...
No, that's not what I meant.
I know.
I was just hoping you'd take the
hint and pretend you never said that.
I want this to be
more than it is.
I thought we were clear.
In the beginning,
but you can't tell me...
Yes, I can. And I don't.
It was fun. That's it.
And now it's over.