Previously on ER:
I work nights at a burger joint.
Caught myself by putting
my hands on the grill.
Too young to have
high blood pressure.
- This is my dad.
- Hi.
Longer you stay, harder it's
gonna be on him when you leave.
Well, maybe I
won't leave this time.
She left the money to me.
She left the house to me.
She trusted me to make the
right decisions for the future.
I doubt she'd agree that's
what you're doing now.
Pleasure meeting you.
I look forward to getting
the wedding announcement.
- What else did we get?
- Another book...
from...
Elizabeth Corday.
Elizabeth. Who's that?
Surgeon. British.
The American Way of Birth.
Don't let Dr. Ford
catch you reading that.
Oh, yeah? Why not?
Because it argues that the shift
from home births and midwives...
to hospital births and C-sections is
the result of American OBs' greed.
- All right, what do you think?
- I'll read it today.
- No, about the paint.
- Oh...
Maybe something with more blue.
Maybe?
You know, Americans are way
too neurotic and technology-reliant.
I mean, with all your
money and equipment...
your infant mortality
rate is still terrible.
Oh, you'd rather be back in Kivu,
giving birth on a concrete floor?
You're, like, 34th or
something, behind Guam.
I like the second one.
Mm. Too much gray.
Well, why don't we ask George?
- Oh. George?
- You don't like George?
- Oh, please.
- I like George.
It's the name of first president of
the United States, the quiet Beatle.
The current occupant
of the White House.
Well, no name is
perfect. Hey, George.
It's Dad.
Say, listen, would
you rather be born...
on the filthy dirt floor
of a primitive mud hut...
in Central Africa, or...?
I do not live in a mud hut.
Or in a modern hospital...
surrounded by the finest doctors
and equipment in the world?
Kick once for America,
twice for the mud hut.
- I resent your characterization...
- Shh. He's deciding.
- He's not deciding.
- He's deciding.
- You know what, he's sleeping.
- No.
- I'm back.
- Hey, you get there in time?
Yeah. It's a
nice-looking school.
It's kind of heavy-duty
security, though.
They have a drug shootout
there recently or something?
What the hell is this?
Honey, you knew what that
was when I met you at 15.
Where did he get it?
He saw it with my stuff, and
he wanted to know what it was.
So you gave it to him?
- He knows not to take it to school.
- A condom?
Hey, look. Come
on, I'm sorry, all right?
It's no big deal. I shouldn't have
had the thing in my damn pocket.
Picked up a few, just in case.
- You're not on the pill right now, right?
- Me?
A boy can dream, can't he?
You look good, baby.
I missed you.
- What are you doing?
- What you like.
It's still what
you like, isn't it?
No. I gotta go finish laundry.
Hey, can you hang with Alex
tonight? I got something I gotta do.
A date?
Yeah, sure.
I can't believe we
graduate tomorrow.
Neither can future patients.
Today, ill-prepared students.
Tomorrow, doctors with the fate
of countless helpless victims...
in capable hands.
They ought to make
them wear caution signs.
"Danger: New Doc" in
big letters on your coats.
Thanks for the pep talk.
Happy to lend
encouragement to the newbies.
- Jerk.
- Bastard.
Putz.
How long will it take me to
get to O'Hare at midnight?
- Midnight?
- My family's arriving from London.
- I had to get the cheapest flight.
- How many are coming?
- Nineteen.
- How many?
Really. Eighteen if my uncle's hip
is still dodgy. Your families coming?
Father and mother, Dad's
new wife, Mom's new boy...
- Abby, any family jetting in?
- No. We're not that close.
We're more like survivors of a particularly
brutal carjacking than a family.
Hello, ladies. Let's get a
move on. It's your last chance...
to learn something before you start
screwing up your malpractice premiums.
- Wanker.
- Turd.
Dick.
- Is Alex coming with us?
- No.
It'd be fine with me if he did.
- Just you and me.
- Where do you wanna go?
Just hang out. I miss you.
Eighty-five-year-old male,
combative and uncooperative...
wandering around
naked at board and care.
Give me my watch
back, you bastards!
- Thinks we took his watch.
- I want it back, you son of a bitch!
It's on his wrist.
- You want restraints?
- Not yet.
- CBC, chem panel, UA and chest x-ray.
- Somebody call the cops.
And let's see if we can find
a reason for his deterioration.
Hey, back so soon?
- Lucky me, huh?
- Abby, you free?
What, everybody just decide to
not file anything for two months?
Frank, my man. Ha-ha!
Thank God you're back.
You start blubbering, I
swear I'm gonna smack you.
- Back to work already?
- Wife threw me out of the house.
I think I was getting on her nerves.
She was definitely getting on mine.
- John?
- Yeah.
- God, how long have I been asleep?
- About an hour.
- Here, drink this.
- No, thanks.
- No, really, I don't want it.
- Come on, come on, come on.
- You been doing your kick counts?
- What? No.
The baby squirms
like mad all the time.
You've been reading
too many books.
I'll count, okay?
Just go do something useful.
Unpack a box, paint, do something.
- Go, go.
- Okay, okay.
Dr. Pratt, remember that kid with
high blood pressure last week?
- Nope.
- Burnt his hands on a grill?
His belly CT came back. No pheo,
no coarc, no renal artery stenosis.
Nothing indicates cause
for high blood pressure.
- So?
- He has primary hypertension.
What? That big kid
who flips burgers?
- What'd you tell him on discharge?
- To lose weight, get some exercise.
Gave him a scrip for
hydrochlorothiazide.
And referred him to
Family Medicine Clinic.
- Voilà. You're a miracle worker.
- Look at his cardiac echo.
- Left ventricular hypertrophy.
- You call the clinic?
- He hasn't made an appointment.
- Call and remind him.
He has end-organ damage. He
could have CHF or arrhythmia.
Neela, he's a kid, okay?
That would take decades.
Call him, tell him to get his butt to
the clinic sometime before he's 30.
No fever, no pneumonia, no UTI.
- Something metabolic?
- Pulse ox is 98.
Sodium's okay. Sugar's
normal. No anion gap.
- Mr. Ferguson, you have to stay in bed.
- I have to go feed the cat.
We'll make sure the cat's taken
care of, but you have to stay in bed.
- What else? ABBY: Uh,
could be toxic ingestion...
but there's no toxidrome. I think
it's just a worsening of his dementia.
Five hundred cc saline bolus
and D5 half at 100 an hour?
Yep. You graduate tomorrow?
- Eight short years later, yeah.
- You got your boards results yet?
- No. MORRIS: Dr. Kovac,
you got a minute?
They gonna let you graduate?
I can walk, but I don't get
my diploma until I pass.
- You haven't passed your boards yet?
- I took them last week.
Wow, I had to take mine, like,
six months before my graduation.
Morris, what do you need?
Hey, Malik. Can you hang 500
saline for the old guy in Exam 3?
- You got it.
- Dr. Corday is a surgeon.
She'd be on the sixth floor.
I went there first. They
told me to come here.
- Yeah? Well, they were wrong.
- Rachel?
- Jerry, how've you been?
- Oh, my God. Look at you.
- You're all grown up.
- Frank, you remember Rachel, right?
Rachel Greene.
Dr. Greene's daughter. - Oh!
No bleeding, right, and no
contractions? Nothing hurts?
Hey, slow down, honey.
You're scaring me.
Did your membranes rupture?
Could've happened in the shower.
I saw Dr. Ford yesterday,
and the membranes are fine.
Hey, you can't park here.
- It's okay. I'm a doctor.
- Good for you. You gotta move it.
It's a tow-away zone!
All right, thank you.
When he does come in, would
you get him to call me back, please?
Thanks. Bloody hell.
"Bloody hell" already?
It's not even lunchtime.
I'm trying to find a hypertensive
17-year-old with end-organ damage.
No answer at home. Hasn't
turned up for work, either.
Organ damage in a hypertensive
teenager? Is that even possible?
- Anybody know whose patient that is?
- Mine.
Malik. Larry Godiva's taking
another afternoon stroll. Thank you.
One of you Samantha Taggart?
- You a process server?
- No.
Then that's me.
Better eat them quick. They
gonna start melting soon.
- Ice cream?
- Anybody want a sundae?
Somebody sent you ice cream?
Yeah, she's here right now.
Uh, with a boy, yeah.
BJ. Right, okay.
All right, thanks, bye.
- I called your mother.
- How is she?
She's surprised you're here.
BJ, could you give us
a few minutes, please?
Cafeteria's on the first floor. Could
you get me some fries, Diet Coke?
Cool.
- You good?
- Yeah, fine, thanks.
So your mother tells me that
you're not living at home anymore.
- Moved in with a friend from school.
- Living with her family?
No, got our own place. How's
Ella? Can't wait to see her...
Excuse me, Elizabeth. Can
I borrow you for a moment?
Yeah. I'll be right back.
I've got a bad mesenteric
occlusion. May need the O.R.
Fine, sure.
I got those Itzhak
Perlman tickets for Sunday.
- Shaw's first?
- Right, yeah, yeah.
- Where'd you say the patient was?
- Angiography suite.
I'll be right there.
Um, I'm sorry, Rachel. I
have to get back to work.
Who was that?
- Colleague, Dr. Lawson.
- Handsome.
- So we can stay with you, right?
- How long for?
Couple of days. I wanted to check
out U of I, maybe Northwestern.
You know you're always welcome.
- Separate bedrooms, of course.
- Of course.
I was 15 when we met.
I was scooping ice
cream at the mall...
little apron, white
hat, whole bit.
- Anything left?
- Help yourself.
Hey, you just had bypass
surgery, like, seven weeks ago.
A treat now and then is
not gonna kill anybody.
In your case, that little truism
might not be completely accurate.
Steve and his buddies
would come after work.
He was working
construction then.
He was all tan, sweaty,
little cowboy boots.
- How old was he?
- Twenty-three.
- And you were 15?
- Yep. Disgraceful, huh?
He'd come to my school...
and pick me up in this old Mustang
GTO he was always fixing up.
We'd go out driving or go
play "X-Men" in the arcade.
Lots of times, we'd just park
somewhere and steam up the windows.
And your parents had
nothing to say about this?
Pfft.
They had plenty to
say, but I didn't listen.
- So, what happened?
- Alex happened.
When was the last time you
were sure you felt the baby move?
In the bath, this morning.
- No bleeding, no cramping?
- No.
A little buzz here.
And again, a little buzz.
You sure you had that
positioned over the head?
Yes.
The amniotic-fluid
index? If she's got poly...
John, sit down.
Take Kem's hand.
I've been looking
for over five minutes.
There's no heartbeat.
There's no gross body movement.
There's no response to
acoustic stimulation. I'm sorry.
John. Kem.
I'm so sorry.
The baby died.
It could have been an
infection, a cord accident...
erythroblastosis, preeclampsia.
We may never know.
I'm gonna admit you so we
can get started on induction.
An induction?
We should get this baby
out as fast as possible.
I have to go through labor?
I'm sorry.
I'll go order the epidural and
get started on your paperwork.
Vicki?
- Blood pressure was fine.
- Yeah.
- Rh-positive, she's afebrile.
- We're gonna do an autopsy...
after the delivery and
see what we can find.
I'll ripen the cervix with misoprostol.
We'll start Pitocin about four hours after.
- How long will that take?
- Twelve to 24 hours.
Sometimes it's longer
for first-time moms.
- LV wall thickness is 18.
- Is this Burger Boy again?
Called in sick at work. No
one's answering at home.
Seventeen-year-olds do not have
trouble with high blood pressure.
Left ventricular hypertrophy in
teens can lead to heart failure.
And sudden death
from cardiac arrhythmia.
You're a cardiologist now?
- I looked it up on the internet.
- Everything on the internet is true.
I wanna go by his house and see if
he's there. He lives 10 minutes away.
I can take a BP cuff, some
IV supplies and oxygen.
Don't forget a thoracotomy tray in
case he needs a heart transplant.
Where does he live?
Morgan Taylor Homes?
Ha! Bring an armored personnel
carrier and a squad of Rangers.
- You can't go in there.
- I'm taking my lunch.
- I'll be back in 30 minutes.
- Hey, Mother Teresa.
I get off at 6. I'll take you.
But you owe me vindaloo after.
Who's got the geriatric flasher?
- Ferguson has dementia.
- Had him in self-restraints.
- Keeps getting loose.
- Use the Posey vest.
I don't wanna see his "wee Willy
Wonka" wagging around here anymore.
- I'll go make sure he's okay.
- Nail him to the bed if you have to.
Hey, Kovac, Security's on the
line. They say your car alarm's...
going off in the garage.
It's driving them crazy.
So you like Indian food?
I love Indian food: chicken
tikka, masala, naan. I love it.
When you open your match letter,
maybe I can take you out to celebrate.
- Might not be anything to celebrate.
- You're gonna do great. You're smart...
cute. You work your ass off.
Got nothing to worry about.
Not like Lockhart.
Some residency program's
gonna get a shock...
when they find she
hasn't passed boards.
- I need to go and see a patient.
- So are we on?
Sure, maybe.
Your TV control is here,
on-button, volume, channels.
It's gonna feel a little tight.
This is the call button, straight to
nurses' station. If you need anything...
- All set.
- You thirsty?
I'll get you some ice chips.
Hey.
You know, your
alarm's a little sensitive.
You might wanna raise the
motion-detection threshold a bit.
It's a nice ride.
- What'd it set you back?
- What do you want?
The sports package.
Should hold up
pretty good on resale.
I really screwed this
thing up with my family.
But I'm gonna make
it right this time.
And I need time
to make it right.
Let Sam see how
much I've changed.
Time to be a father to my son.
We belong together,
Sam, Alex and I.
And Sam knows that.
You paid that kid $10
to stay with your car?
I want there to be wheels
on there when we get back.
Thanks for doing this.
He's here, we yell at
him to get to the clinic.
If not, just leave a
note, and that's it, okay?
- Lifts are over there, I think.
- Trust me, the elevators don't work.
- Thirty-nine, right?
- Yeah.
So much wire mesh.
So they don't throw
things on folks below.
- Like trash?
- Like bricks.
Nobody's home. Got the note?
Come on, would
you? I'm starving.
- Elgin?
- Great.
It's Neela from the hospital.
I just get a little winded
climbing the stairs. It's no big deal.
- You remember Dr. Pratt, right?
- What's up, man?
You been taking your
hydrochlorothiazide? Why not?
Because you told me if I
exercised a little, I'll feel better.
I said you could stop taking it in six
months if you exercised and lost weight.
- Is that dinner? Cheeseburgers.
- Yeah.
My mother's working tonight. I have to
pick up the kids from Ms. Johnson at 7.
158/94.
Can someone look after the kids so you
can come to the hospital for more tests?
- I'm feeling okay.
- Take your pills.
Come in next week for a
blood pressure check, okay?
- All right. Thanks, doc.
- You got it.
He needs an EKG
and a chest x-ray.
He needs to pick up his family
and get them fed. You found him.
You told him what he needs.
Unless you plan on adopting
the kid, let's get something to eat.
What time is your
graduation ceremony?
Noon.
- You're not gonna go?
- I'm off.
Thanks, but no. It's boring.
It's boring, and I'm not even
sure I'm gonna go myself.
To your own graduation?
Yes. It seems pointless
considering the fact...
that I might not actually get to practice
medicine, so I would rather no one come.
- Abby, got a minute?
- Yeah.
But thanks.
- Anything new on Henry?
- No, no, uh, thank you.
Abby, did you get confirmation
of your match list yet?
Couple of weeks ago, yeah.
Well, with your clinical skills,
I'm sure you'll do very well.
Off the record, I can tell you
that we ranked you in our top 20.
If County's top of your list,
you're guaranteed to match here.
I thought we weren't
supposed to talk about that.
No. No, of course not.
You found out I
failed my boards.
Well, I took them
again last week.
The hypothetical concern would
be that if you don't pass again...
and you match with a program,
whatever that program might be...
you would be ineligible
to begin your internship.
And the program
would be short an intern.
Programs can still delete applicants
from their match lists until Friday.
That way, the applicant would
match with his or her second choice.
And if he or she didn't pass their boards,
the second-choice program would be...
the hospital short a body.
Well, I guess if
that happened, um...
If that happened, the applicant that
was deleted would lodge a complaint...
with the National Board indicating
he or she'd been approached...
by the chief of staff in
violation of clearly stated rules...
governing how
matches are conducted.
- Hey. Where to? I'm starving.
- Hey.
Um, I'm gonna have
to take a rain check.
- Everything all right?
- Yeah, yeah, fine. I'm just...
just tired.
This have something
to do with Steve?
Because I keep telling him he's
gotta find another place to crash.
I just think it's maybe
confusing for Alex.
Alex isn't confused.
It's not that simple.
Can I give you a lift?
No, that's okay.
Hey, it's morning in Kinshasa.
You want me to call your family?
Kem, do you want
me to call your family?
You sure?
- What's that?
- Have you told anybody?
No. No. Been here with you.
I don't want anyone to know.
Okay...
- You didn't restock.
- No, I didn't.
- Just restock when you use something.
- I will, when I actually use it.
You need anything? Do you?
I don't want anyone
to know, okay?
- Ella's asleep?
- Mm-hm.
Guy named Dave called.
Wanted to know if you were
still up for a movie Saturday night.
He has a daughter,
the same school as Ella.
Guy at the hospital,
tall British guy.
- You dating him too?
- How are you liking school?
- Don't worry. I'm going to college.
- Do I look worried?
My mom's worried.
Rachel, why are you here?
I just wanna look at
a couple of colleges.
I need a prescription
for Plan B.
The, uh, morning-after pill?
Why didn't you
go to your mother?
Five centimeters, 100 percent
effaced. You're moving along.
- How much longer?
- Hard to say. Hours still.
My legs are completely numb.
We can turn the epidural down. I'll
come back and check on your progress.
I'm gonna go get a cup
of coffee or something.
You'll be okay for a
couple of minutes?
One more big push.
That's it. Push.
Push. That's it. Good.
Long night, huh?
- Yeah.
- Your first?
- I got three already.
All girls.
This one gonna be a girl too.
Even our cat's a girl.
You know what time it is?
- Yeah. It's almost midnight.
- Midnight.
I am dying for a cigarette. But
you gotta go all the way down...
halfway across the building to
get to one of them smoking areas.
So I'll probably see you
around the hallway later on, huh?
- Good luck.
- You too.
Didn't mention anything
about the ice cream.
It was a big hit.
- God, you're beautiful, Sam.
- Yeah, this is me at my finest.
No, really.
- You're all grown up.
- You're drunk.
A little bit.
Hey, did you go to the hospital
and say something to Luka?
Sam, I want another chance.
Well, I don't want you
going to the hospital, okay?
I gotta get up early.
Come on. Steve.
Do you remember those cottonwood
trees down by the river we used to go to?
Used to lay under those trees
for hours, just drinking Schnapps...
and rum-and-Cokes with no ice.
Making love, Dave Matthews...
coming from my car stereo.
Listen, Steve. Please.
Sammy, I love you,
sweetie. I love you, Sammy.
Please, Steve.
Please, Steve, what?
Let me... Let me by, please.
- I can't feel anything.
- Head's almost out.
One, two, three,
four, five, six...
- Bear down. Hard as you can.
- Shoulder's out.
- I got it. I got it.
- It's almost over.
He's out. He's out. It's over.
True knot. Clamp.
Your baby twisted and squirmed
in such a way that he tied a knot...
in his umbilical cord.
Send 5 cc's of cord blood
to the lab for Rh factor.
There's nothing you could
have done to prevent this.
Not genetic. It's
not an infection.
It was just bad luck.
- Would you like to see him?
- No. No.
Are you sure?
John?
It's okay, son.
It's okay.
- Stillborn?
- Yeah, true knot in the cord.
- Oh, how terrible.
- Oh, I can't even imagine.
- I'll try and get up there after rounds.
- Those poor people.
- Seven months old?
- Almost eight.
Yeah, tough break.
What? I was being sincere.
This is the admit area
where we keep track...
of all of the patients
we have in the ER.
That's Jerry. He makes this
whole place work, and he's very big.
That's Frank, works with Jerry.
Had a massive heart attack and...
shouldn't be eating that
doughnut. And this is the ER staff.
- Staff, this is my family.
- Nice to meet you.
Okay, well, lovely
to see you all.
Down this way are the
trauma and exam rooms...
where we save the lives of
unfortunate souls who end up here.
On a busy shift, we'll see over 120
patients, sometimes as many as 200.
Back there is the Suture Room,
where we attend to minor skin wounds.
That's a naked patient.
Let's step through this way.
- Is that too tight?
- No, it's fine.
Would you like a lock?
To keep?
Good morning. You look radiant.
Liar. I was up half the night.
Doing what, one might wonder?
I was hoping you could
do me a very large favor.
Will there be a
very large reward?
I need you to write me
up a scrip for Reglan...
Yasmin and two
packets of Plan B.
John?
I'm off in a few minutes. I asked
them to get a room for you downstairs.
I wanna watch Kem
for the rest of the day.
Just make sure
there's no bleeding.
Has she held the baby yet?
I've been doing this
for over 20 years.
There's nothing more difficult
than what you've been through.
But if Kem doesn't say
goodbye to her child...
she will regret it for
the rest of her life.
And a three-month supply
of oral contraceptives.
- Birth control pills?
- You'll still need to use condoms.
- Who's Dr. Lawson?
- He's a friend.
Why didn't you do it?
When your mother
discovers these...
in your dresser drawer, I'd rather
she didn't know they came from me.
Lawson. Was he that
British guy from yesterday?
Your gynecologist back
home can write you a refill...
for the Yasmin when it runs out.
Do you like him more than
the guy from Ella's school?
Rachel.
They're both nice, you know, but it's
just an occasional meal. It's a movie.
You know, I have Ella.
I'm very busy with my work.
It's okay. Dad would've
wanted you to be happy.
Do you miss him?
Yeah.
Yeah, I do.
Me too.
I appreciate you both coming.
But you should go home.
I don't want you to miss your
graduation. That is today, right?
I was gonna miss it anyway.
They didn't have any bagels,
but the coffee was fresh.
I was just saying, Dad, how much I
appreciate you guys all being here...
but I think that we're okay.
And, um... I think
you guys can go.
Okay.
You know, if you...
I know.
You too, Dad. You can go.
Oh, thanks. I think I'll stay.
Lester, have you seen Abby?
Abby. Have you seen her?
No.
Kem?
They want us to move
to another room soon.
And they're gonna take
the baby when we go.
Would you like to hold him?
Campbell, Edward
Barrington the third.
Ann Marie Barstow.
Corazon, Linda Benitez.
Bennings, Jonathan Bett.
Hey.
- What did I miss?
- Molly Ivins gave a kick-ass speech.
- Who?
- They haven't gotten to Abby yet.
I thought you were on bed rest.
Please, I'm already a week late.
I am desperate to get this kid out.
Lily Yay Lin Chang.
Lee Son Chow.
Robert David Betterman.
- I can't breathe.
- Wet crackles to the apex.
He's in pulmonary
edema. Hey, I know you.
Pratt's patient? Pratt,
think this one's yours.
- Pulse ox is 78.
- He needs Lasix.
What's going on?
- 17-year-old with pulmonary edema.
- Elgin?
- We need a nitro spray.
- Had two in the field.
- Want an intubation tray?
- What? No.
- Just got a little hypertension.
- He has a little congestive heart failure.
Start a nitro drip at 40 mics
and 25 sublingual captopril.
- Sats dropping to low 80s.
- Page Cardiology.
We need a stat
echo down here now.
Never seen a kid this
young in heart failure before.
- I don't see Abby, do you?
- No, said she probably wouldn't come.
To her own graduation?
Lester Rodney Kertzenstein.
Andrashi Lapoor.
Abigail Marjorie Lockhart.
Congratulations.
Robin Jay Nancy.
Neela Rasgotra.
- Neela!
When your brother died...
the thing I hated the most
were other people's platitudes.
There are no words.
You don't know where you'll find
the strength, but somehow you do.
You can have another child.
It was an accident. A tragic...
unforeseeable accident.
The whole thing was an accident.
No, it wasn't.
You love each other.
Everybody can see that.
I don't know that she'll want
to have another baby with me.
Sure she will.
Just give it some time.
Abby?
- Congratulations.
- Thanks.
Hey, this is so
great. Good for you.
We're gonna get something
to eat. Wanna join us?
- Um, no, I'm tired. But thanks.
- Okay.
And thank you guys for coming.
- See you at work.
- Okay.
I'll be back.
Hey, Mom, it's Abby.
No, no, everything's fine. We
just haven't talked in a while, so...
Yeah, it's good to hear
your voice too. Hey, Mom?
Guess what. I graduated today.
Really.
Can you believe it?
Kem.
They're gonna come down and
take us to our new room soon.
And when they come,
they're gonna take the baby...
and we're never
gonna see him again.
I don't know what the
right thing is to say.
I don't know what
the right thing to do is.
It was an accident.
It was nothing that you did wrong.
It was nothing that we did wrong.
It just happened.
I love you, and I want to spend
the rest of my life with you.
But we have to say
goodbye to our son now.
I have to help you to do that,
and I don't know how to do that.
Please, help me.
Please.
Yeah?
- He's beautiful.
- Oh, my God.
I love you so much.