♪ Ohhh ohhh ohhh ♪
♪♪♪
I guess
I should've called first.
Uh, n-no, no.
It's fine.
So you and Addison...
I'm--i'm--I'm sorry.
I didn't even...
Addison, hello.
Hi.
Wow.
He's gotten so...
He's so big.
♪ there's no way ♪
Violet.
I'm crying. I know.
I know. I'm crying.
But look at him.
He's, like, 15.
He's not 15.
He's 15.
And I haven't been here.
I was in the crazy
and then I... was in Costa Rica
and then New York
and...
You--you were in New York?
Then I got out of the crazy
and I came back here,
and he's 15, and, uh,
now I'm just a stranger to him,
and--and you and Addison
are, uh--
it's okay, Violet--
no.
No, it's not.
♪ There's no way ♪
I'm his mother.
I am his mother.
And I haven't...
I'm so sorry I didn't...
I'm so sorry...
That I couldn't... i'm--
I am so, so sorry.
♪ I know I'm gonna miss... ♪
Would--would you...
Would you like to hold him?
♪♪♪
Can I?
Hey. Come here, pal.
Come on.
Here we go.
Look.
That's your mom.
Hi.
That's your mommy.
♪ Look what you've done ♪
Hi.
♪ I hurt you ♪
♪ forgive ♪
♪ me ♪
Stop hovering
and come in here.
I said that we shouldn't be
hovering, but Charlotte--
I said you needed space.
We didn't want to pressure you.
I'm fine. I'm fine.
Hey.
Oh. Violet, she's here.
You're back.
Oh, come on, Sheldon.
You knew I was back.
Somebody called you.
Well, there may have been
a text from Charlotte on--ow.
Look, I'm fine, you guys.
But--but go ahead and ask.
I know you're dying to ask.
So you're not all messed up
and freaky anymore?
Charlotte.
Well, she said we could ask.
I had this amazing breakthrough
while I was away,
and, um... well, I know
better than anybody
that it doesn't happen
overnight,
but... yeah, I'm ready...
To be Lucas' mom.
That's my girl.
Morning.
Good morning.
Hey.
Well, I'm gonna go do...
Some work.
Yes.
Yes. Okay, well, I got ten weeks
of patient notes to catch up on.
Thank you.
Uh... okay,
you seem a little old
for a pediatrician, but--
Oliver had to use
the restroom.
Um, Dr. Freedman, I am Kelly.
This is my husband Scott.
Okay. Nice to meet you.
It says Oliver has
a stomachache.
Is that just today
or has that been going on?
It's a little more
than a stomachache.
It was kinda hard
to see.
Wow. Look at you. Uh, you
a hockey player, Oliver?
No.
Okay. Well, um...
I'm Dr. Freedman.
We're gonna have to
take this off so we--
uh, I can't.
My parents don't let me.
Oliver, um...
He eats things.
He eats things like
ice cream and too many cookies?
He ate part of his pillow
last night.
Well, it started out small,
you know, pieces of
the couch cushion,
um, stuffed animals.
It started after Kelly and I
got married last year.
I don't know
if it's the change or...
I think of Oliver
as my own.
And I hate to think my coming
along has set him off somehow.
Will you help him?
Please.
Hey.
I thought I'd stop by
and see if you were okay.
I'm fine, Pete.
I know that this is weird.
No, it's--it's great
that Violet's back.
It's great that she wants
to see Lucas.
I mean... it is great,
right?
She called me this morning.
She wants to see him again.
I told her I'd bring him
to the office tomorrow.
Is that okay with you?
You're his father.
You have to do
what you think is best.
Addison--
I'm not his mother.
Violet is.
Yeah, but you're always
putting him to bed,
you play with him, you feed him,
you give him a bath,
you hold him when he cries.
You're not nobody to him.
Yes, but he's her child.
I want you
to be okay with this--
me letting her try.
This is scary for me.
I don't even know
if Violet is ready.
But if she is,
I need you... to help me
be okay with it.
I'm okay.
Really, I am.
This is...
This is gonna be good
for Lucas.
Thank you.
This is embarrassing.
If the guys in my unit knew
I was being checked out
by a gynecologist,
they'd never let me
live it down.
You smacked your head
passing out on the toilet.
This isn't the embarrassing
part of the story.
The gyno gave you a referral.
I promise you,
I only do brains.
I'm fine, okay?
This is crazy.
I probably passed out
'cause of too much r&amp;R.
I talked my way
into three weeks
to come back
and see the baby born.
I'm just used to living
like this.
Clean sheets, no gunfire--
it's not normal.
Has anything like this
ever happened before?
Sometimes I get dizzy.
The summers in Iraq
are brutal.
Have you noticed
any visual changes?
Numbness or weakness?
Nope.
I'm U.S. army,
top grade-a specimen.
Well, there's
no evidence of a concussion.
His head's fine.
See, honey, I told you.
Clean bill of health.
But your screening E.K.G. is
showing some subtle abnormality.
I don't understand.
You said his head was fine.
Oh, she's saying
that there might be
a problem with your heart.
Hi. Oliver.
Am I a freak?
Do you think you're a freak?
I ate part of a book once
in class.
No other kids do that.
So I got in big trouble
with the teacher.
You see what I mean?
It--it--
you know, when...
Kids eat like you do,
you know, weird stuff,
it's usually
something called pica.
Other kids do it, too?
Yeah.
I mean, it's rare, but that
makes you pretty special.
So it's a thing?
You can cure him?
I can prescribe fiber
for the stomachache.
But pica can have
all sorts of causes.
Oliver...
Do you know
why you do this?
I don't know.
I just...
I can't stop.
Okay.
Oh, hey.
What do you know about pica
in 10 year olds?
Well, if a kid's got
a mouth full of splinters,
and you're missing a box of
tongue depressors, it's pica.
It's not really that simple.
I mean, that kind of behavior
could be o.C.D.
Or a nutritional deficiency,
neurological or trauma response.
I mean, sometimes,
we never figure it out.
Well, I'll give you
a head start.
The kid's got
a new stepfather.
The problem started
around the same time.
The stepfather's solution is to
lock a hockey mask on his face.
I was gonna talk to Violet about
it, but it's her first day back.
I don't wanna...
Could you see him?
Sure, sure.
I'm happy to be second choice.
Thanks.
See ya.
You know, I'm glad
Sheldon is thorough,
but next time
I go out of town,
remind me to have someone
cover my patients
who takes
less copious notes.
So...
So?
So what's up
with you and Charlotte?
I was asking about you.
You said "so."
Yeah,
which means "how are you?"
I'm good. Can't I be good?
Two months, no phone calls,
no e-mails, no postcards...
Now... you're good?
I am.
I'm good.
You know,
i-i-i would be better
if I had known that Pete
was sleeping with Addison
before I came home.
Oh, yeah. I'm sorry
about that. I should've--
oh, wait. No phone calls,
no e-mails, no postcards.
Okay.
Okay. I'm sorry.
Thank you.
So what is up
with you and Charlotte?
I'm maintaining a mature,
professional distance.
She wants to be friends.
And what do you want?
Life is sucky and hard.
Preaching to the choir,
baby.
Oh, I'm glad you're back.
Mm.
Lucia... I know that
you're worried about Carl.
But if there is a problem
with his heart,
Dr. Bennett will find it.
I hope so.
He's the best.
No, I mean, I hope he will...
Find something wrong.
This is
his fourth tour of duty.
When I hear on the news
that a roadside bomb went off
killing six,
I wonder if one of them
was Carl.
When officers come around,
I pray that
they don't stop by my house.
I just feel like
I'm waiting for him to die.
I'm not sure
what you're asking me to do.
If you could find something
or say there's something,
something that means he can't
go back to Iraq at all...
I love him.
Help me keep him alive.
Hey.
Are those, uh,
Carl's cardiac c.T.S?
So what, are you not
talking to me now either?
Because you know what? I really
can't handle that today, Sam.
So be a grown-up.
Use your words.
Vanessa and I broke up.
Oh. I'm sorry.
I am. I know that we didn't
always get along--
you hated her. You hated
that I was with her.
So don't say you're sorry.
It's a lie. You know it,
and I know it.
See... you want to have
your cake and eat it, too.
But you know what? You can't,
because I'm the cake.
And from here on out,
I'm taking the cake away.
No more cake for you.
I'm good cake, too.
Double chocolate, cream-filled
with the little raspberries
on top.
So no more cake for you.
So just shut up.
Okay.
Carl has a block in his l.A.D.
It's called a widowmaker.
We're lucky we found it.
Coulda killed him.
So what are you gonna do?
Well, he's a perfect candidate
for a stent.
After the procedure,
he should be good as new.
Maybe drug therapy
would work.
Wait. The kid's serving
in a war zone, Addison.
You want to slow down
his heart, his entire system?
You know,
do you think he can perform
to the level he needs to
on--on beta-blockers?
Probably not.
He'd be discharged.
So you're saying you want me
to do something less effective
so that they'll pull him
out of military service?
This is not about me, Sam.
Lucia's gonna have his baby.
She wants to keep him around.
Well, you can't always get
what you want.
Ugh.
I don't know.
Surgery sounds risky.
But if I take the medication,
I can't go back?
I can't make
that determination,
but will it have an affect
on your performance? It might.
But, honey,
if you're sick, then--
look, I'm not sick.
I'm not. I have a thing,
and Dr. Bennett can fix it.
I locate I.E.D.S, bombs.
I have people in my squad
who depend on me to stay alive.
I depend on you
to stay alive.
Your baby depends on you
The army can replace you.
I can't.
Can you fix this with surgery,
make me as good as new?
I can.
I want the surgery.
I'm a soldier. It's what I do.
And I want to go back.
So how's it been
with your stepdad Scott,
you know,
since they got married?
He's pretty cool.
I've never had a dad before,
so we get to do
some stuff together, fun stuff.
But I think
he's a little freaked out
by this whole eating thing.
What about your mom?
She got me the mask.
Your mom got you the mask?
Yeah.
What do you think of it?
Well, it's uncomfortable,
but it does
kinda help me stop.
Without it, I just--
I see something and I eat it.
I don't know
what's wrong with me.
I'm not even thinking,
and I do it.
Well, that's not uncommon,
even for adults.
I mean, if there's an open bag
of salt and vinegar
potato chips in the house
when I'm watching
"house hunters"...
Forget about it.
Hey, no. That's potpourri.
Spit it out.
Y--
Spit.
Thank you.
You know,
there's a simple solution
to you getting a job.
Just call your brother.
One recommendation from Derek,
and you'll be on the top
of everyone's list.
Yeah, at a price--lectures
and "I told you sos"
and "you screwed up agains."
Well, there's always a price.
♪♪♪
Fight for her, Sam.
I don't follow.
Addison.
♪♪♪
Fight for her.
I mean, you love her, right?
Addison is with Pete.
And the mother of his baby
just came back,
and it's all weird.
It's a perfect opportunity.
And you didn't
answer my question.
Do you love her?
♪♪♪
Well, then fight for her.
Amelia, you're--you're--
you're like family,
uh, so I'm gonna
say this nicely.
Stop talking.
♪♪♪
♪ and lay out on the deck ♪
It's just interesting
that in the O.R., you are
this kick-ass, take-charge,
take-no-prisoners surgeon,
and you can't do that
in your real life.
♪ Like the worker on a... ♪
She's not here.
You mind if I wait?
Come in. I'm drinking.
Oh, well...
Could I have one?
From the woman
you called a sex toy?
♪ The silver light ♪
I never should've said that.
♪♪♪
What we had...
Was more than that.
Yeah, right.
Charlotte... look at me.
♪♪♪
It was more than that...
A lot more.
♪♪♪
I should go.
You should.
Tell Violet I stopped by.
Okay.
♪♪♪
♪ Well, if I was
a berber's son ♪
Maybe I should post a sign.
"Yes, I'm here.
Stop staring."
I'm glad you're here
and that you're better--
or that you think
you're better.
I am, Pete, better.
And taking off,
going to Costa Rica,
that helped?
Uh, well, c-Costa Rica
was a mess.
It was a lot of alcohol.
But, um... one day,
I-I went to the airport,
and I just...
I just couldn't get on a plane
and come back to L.A.
I just couldn't.
So I went to New York,
and I decided to live there.
I even interviewed
for a job.
You were gonna live
in New York?
No, no. I mean, yes,
I thought I was, but...
No, not really.
I-It's what we therapists call
a crisis point.
I-It was kind of the beginning
of me coming back here...
To Lucas.
♪♪♪
Does that makes sense?
No. Nothing about your life
has made sense
for quite some time.
It's not your fault.
You earned your crazy.
But you gave Lucas to me
and you asked me
to take care of him.
And I-I have. I am.
That's why
I have to ask you...
Really ask you...
Are you back, Violet?
Yeah.
I am.
♪ Silver light in ♪
♪ a silver light ♪
Something's wrong with Cooper.
You mean like
he's having a heart attack,
and we all have to rush
to the hospital
or like you find his lack
of attention aggravating,
and you want to talk about it,
but it makes you feel petty,
so you want to
beat me up for a while
before you actually
get around to it?
Shut up, Sheldon.
Okay, so, uh, the latter.
He came over last night,
and granted,
he was looking for Violet,
but still, he came in,
he had a drink--
tell me
you didn't sleep with him.
I didn't anything with him.
A kiss almost happened.
But then suddenly,
he was running for the door.
Well, some people
might call this a pattern.
Yes, that's it, a pattern.
He comes close, he runs away.
The man is bonkers.
Huh.
Hey.
Oh.
Hi. Hi, good morning.
Wow, this looks nice.
So, um, I packed his snacks
in this orange thingy.
He likes
the smiley-faced elmos.
Okay.
We've got diapers, wipes,
a few toys.
Oh, he loves
the squeeze froggy..
Thing.
What happened to the pull
monkey? I thought he l--
well, he likes that, too,
but the squishy frog...
Is the--
the real crowd-pleaser, huh?
Yeah.
Okay, squishy frog, pull monkey,
smiley snacks--
I think I got it.
If you need anything at all,
just call me or Addison.
That's your frog--
your frog.
Can I have him?
Oh. Oh, yeah.
Oh.
Okay, big man.
Here you go.
Hi. Hi.
You guys can go.
It's okay.
Okay.
Hi.
Mm.
You give him vitamins
and an hour of therapy,
and then he goes home
and eats dirt. Literally dirt.
As I tried to explain to you
yesterday, we can work with him.
But there isn't always
a simple answer.
Now all we can do is work
to redirect his urges
to other things.
Straight out of
the flower bed--dirt.
I'm sorry.
Kelly, don't you think that
he wants to change this?
I think if he wanted to,
he would.
And I'm afraid this whole thing
is gonna be too much for Scott.
He has been patient.
He has been a Saint
with all this.
But what I need from you,
you professionals,
is to do something.
So basically,
what you're saying is,
you care more about keeping
your husband
than you do
about helping your child?
Cooper.
I just...
Want him to be normal.
Putting a mask on his face
does not make him feel normal.
I am trying to help him.
Are you?
Why don't we dial this back?
Look, I see a lot of kids
with a lot of issues,
and all I'm trying to say is,
Oliver is hurting.
He is hurting in some way,
and you need to let me figure--
you--you need to let Dr. Wallace
figure out what that is.
And however hard it is on you,
it is harder on him.
That was unprofessional
in there.
She should be worried
about her son,
not her husband or herself.
Oh, and you think telling her
off is gonna make things better?
Look, you are agitated
about this patient
and about Charlotte.
Charlotte has nothing
to do with it.
Maybe, maybe not.
But something about her
still pushes your buttons.
Button-pushing, we call it.
Yeah. She told me
about last night.
Oh, that is
so none of your business.
When it affects our patient,
it is.
I'm not trying to fix something
because my life is broken.
My life is fine.
It's the patient that is broken.
Fix him.
Is everything okay?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
He's, uh,
just having a bottle.
Violet, if--if...
If this too much for you--
no. No.
It's not too much.
It's not enough.
I mean, it would be one thing
if I was a bad mother,
if I was mean to my kid
or hit my kid.
But i'm...
Not a mother at all.
You are.
You're his... mother.
You're more of a mother
than I am.
Violet...
I'm sorry.
You saved my life.
You saved Lucas' life.
And I am grateful for that,
really.
It's just that...
This...
You and Lucas,
you and Pete...
I mean, I expected a lot
of things when I came home,
but my son loving you
was not one of them.
I can't have kids.
Did you know that?
I've got, like, one egg left
or something horrible...
Like that,
and--and I'm okay with it.
I am. I had made... my peace.
I... Wasn't
one of those crazy women
who cried, you know,
every time she saw... a baby.
I just shut it down.
But then, uh...
Pete and I happened, and...
That meant Lucas, too.
And it was so scary for me,
you know, to...
Allow myself to...
Enjoy him, to... love him.
But when I did,
it was like...
It was like I was broken...
And Lucas fixed me.
And now I can't imagine
my life without him.
I can't. I just...
So you coming back--
and--and I'm thrilled...
That you're back,
genuinely,
because I...
I like you, Violet,
and what happened to you
was so...
But for me, it means--
i-i...
It just--i'm--it's--
I'm saying,
it's hard for me, too.
I want to hate you
so badly.
I want to punch you
in the face.
Well, I should go.
And you...
You're doing fine...
With him.
I know.
Right?
I mean, I wasn't sure
if I would.
I-I've never been good
with kids--
other people's kids--
but, uh...
I'm good at taking care
of my son.
He'll pick you...
Because you're his mother,
you know.
In the end,
he'll pick you.
What are you talking about?
Babies get adopted
all the time.
They love
their adopted mothers.
They--they don't even think
about their birth mothers.
I wasn't
talking about Lucas.
What happened?
Oh, my god. Scott and I
got in an argument.
It was over Oliver. He overheard
it. He got upset and he ran--
I found him in the garage.
He was looking white
and he was scared.
What's in the garage?
Everything--bug spray,
uh, uh, gardening stuff.
Oliver, can you
tell me what you ate?
Hey. Can you tell me
what you ate?
I need a chem panel,
a tox screen,
and let's give him
50 of charcoal.
What--what is that?
What are you doing?
They're going to pump
his stomach.
Oh!
Oliver. Hey, buddy,
you're gonna be okay.
It's a routine surgery.
I'm coming back.
Your wife really loves you.
I mean, it's gotta be
hard on her,
worrying about you
all the time.
What, you think that I don't
worry about her, especially now?
Hell, I know that
I should be here. I do.
A man
should be with his child.
But, you know, Lucia's gonna
be here when I get back,
and if I stay, I can't say
the same thing about my guys.
There are other guys
who can take your place
over there.
If everyone said that, who'd be
there fighting for us?
Well, I'm guessing your wife
would rather
you were fighting for her.
It's a girl thing.
Well, you pull me
through this,
and I'll make sure
I fight for both.
His vessels have calcified.
I don't know
if the stent's gonna hold.
I'm gonna open up his chest
and bypass the vessel.
The stent should compress
and seal the tear.
You could wait,
see if it holds.
I mean, you convert to bypass,
he's not going back.
All right, notify O.R.
I'm gonna bypass.
So lawn furniture,
huh, Oliver?
You ate
some moldy lawn furniture.
Just the cushions.
Oh, yeah. I know. I saw it
while it was coming up.
Your throat's gonna be sore
for a little while,
but we'll run some tests,
we'll make sure you're okay,
and then we'll get you home.
All right?
I'm just gonna eat
more stuff.
Why don't you just
keep me here
and sew my mouth shut?
Hey, believe me. If I could
sew a kid's mouth shut,
I would be
a really wealthy pediatrician.
You just worry
about getting better.
I'll figure this out.
I'm gonna get you some water.
Oh...
Hi.
Hey.
Um... Lucas isn't here.
The nanny went--
oh, that's okay.
I wanted to talk to you
about us.
Yeah?
Oh, not--i mean...
Not "us" us.
I-I meant what we're gonna do
about Lucas.
What do you mean?
Uh, well, um,
I ordered a crib online,
and it should be here
on Thursday.
And, uh, my house was
already childproofed.
And I ordered, uh, diapers
and car seats and toys
and all that stuff.
You don't have to
buy him things, Violet.
Well, I mean,
I'm gonna need it.
And I figured we could
work out a schedule,
and I could pay half of
the nanny bill,
and I'm totally willing
to reimburse you
for any back child care
or any other expenditures
that you may have--
w-w-wait--wait a minute.
Wait a minute.
What are you talking about?
W--look, I-I know this is not
gonna happen right away.
I know it's a process.
So I figured we could
transition Lucas very slowly.
Start out with daily visits,
then maybe an overnight,
maybe one week with you,
one week with me--
no.
No?
You've been back
for two days.
Let's...
Take this slow.
You were recently thinking
about moving to New York,
for god sake--
right, I-I told you,
that was a crisis point.
Which to me means I'm not
letting you have Lucas.
Okay, Pete, Pete, just--let's
just slow down, start again.
All I'm saying
is that I want to share--
no.
What--
my son is not going to be
part of your therapy.
I'm his father.
And I'm his mother.
Who gave him away.
You showed up at my doorstep
and you gave him away.
That was low, Pete.
You know what I've been through.
You know what I...
Y--you know me.
Come on, Pete.
You know me.
I do know you,
but this isn't about you.
I have to do
what's best for Lucas.
So...
Your son
is struggling with pica,
and you have it, too,
and you didn't say anything,
to him or to us.
You lied.
How long do you think
you've had it?
Since I was a kid.
But only
when I was nervous
or when things
were really bad.
But I got it under control.
I just...
Made myself stop...
Until today.
With Oliver so sick,
it was just so stressful, i--
stressful for you?
It's stressful for him.
He's 10 years old.
And he's feeling weird enough
about this problem,
and he has impulses
he doesn't know how to control,
and instead of telling him
that you have it, too,
you put a mask on him.
Well, I thought
that would stop it.
I wanted to spare him that.
But you lied to him,
making it so he can
never trust you...
About anything.
When we opened you up,
your coronary arteries
were too calcified
to hold the stent.
Now if I hadn't
converted to a bypass,
you would've had
a heart attack.
But now you're okay.
So what's the recovery time?
I don't think you'll be able
to return to active duty.
I know you're upset--
I told you
that I didn't want this.
This isn't what I wanted.
You're alive, Carl. You've got
a wife who loves you,
a child on the way.
This is not a bad outcome.
This is
what most people want.
This... is what
most people fight for.
It was hard for her.
Lying to your kid
is what should be hard.
You want to be a parent,
you should not... do that.
You should not lie.
No. No, you shouldn't.
No parent should.
And if they do
and if it leaves a Mark,
if that kid or any kid
is troubled by some lie
or something
that wasn't said,
then they're really gonna need
to talk about it eventually.
Why don't you come in
and sit down?
Why don't we just talk?
Nothing to talk about.
♪♪♪
♪ still can't bear ♪
♪ the silence ♪
Hey.
♪ ...with no response ♪
So Amelia told me
what happened with Carl.
Why'd you do it?
♪ ...time ♪
I didn't have a choice.
Well, you could've done
a stent.
Yeah, but instead,
I saved his life.
♪ This time ♪
You were right, Sam.
You are... cake.
Really good... cake.
♪ Cause a madness ♪
You're a good guy.
And I know
it may not feel like it,
but what you did
for Carl and Lucia,
it's the right thing.
"The right thing"...
I'm so sick of doing
the right thing.
Maybe once...
♪ I'm doing fine ♪
♪ just fine ♪
I should do the wrong thing.
♪ I'll cry ♪
Sam.
♪♪♪
No, s--
no, Sam.
♪♪♪
Mm.
♪ I'm fine ♪
What the hell are you doing?
♪♪♪
I am sorry. He kissed me
and I didn't stop it.
And I just--i just can't--
I don't want to be in the way.
All right?
Lucas needs a mother,
and you should be with Violet.
No, no, no. Don't do that.
I am sick of your excuses.
You get a little scared,
so you act a little crazy.
Boo freaking hoo.
Get over it!
Because, you know,
I've had crazy.
I'm not doing that again.
So if you want to be a mess,
be a mess.
If you want to be with Sam,
be with Sam.
But don't jerk me around,
Addison.
You're right.
I'm scared.
I love you
and I love Sam.
And you love me
and you love Violet.
And the thing that...
Tips the scales
all the way around is Lucas.
I love Lucas
so much.
I...
I'm a single dad.
I am not
doing this for kicks.
So choose me
or don't choose me,
but I'm not gonna wait around.
I hate her.
She lied.
Well, lying's wrong.
And she made you
feel bad.
But, you know,
she was scared
and--and... when parents
are scared,
sometimes
they make mistakes.
Yeah. Well,
I still don't forgive her.
She could've helped.
She's the grown-up.
She's the one who's
supposed to do what's right.
Hmm.
You know, when I was
just about your age,
I found out that my parents
had lied to me,
and I would not forgive them.
And... that's not
a good way to go.
It really messed me up.
What'd they lie about?
Well, they had
had a kid before me.
His name was Andy.
And for eight years,
he was their son,
and then one day...
Well, he was very, very sick
and he died.
And then a couple of
years later, they adopted me.
But they never told me
about Andy.
And, you know, so I grew up
thinking I was the only one.
And when I found out...
I felt like a replacement.
I felt like they hadn't told me
because they loved him more.
And I would not
forgive them.
Yeah, and then you did,
and everything
turned out great.
Happy ending.
Blah, blah, blah.
No.
No, I didn't forgive them.
I still love them.
And I know the reason
they lied to me
was to protect me
from their pain.
And I wasn't a replacement.
I know they loved me
for who I was, for who I am,
just like your mother
and Scott love you.
But I have not forgiven them.
Which is surprising,
because I thought I did.
The point is,
don't be like me.
Find a way to forgive her.
You gotta work
really hard on it.
Okay?
♪♪♪
Hey. Can I hide out with you?
It is tense over there.
I mean,
Addison and Pete are, like--
yeah, yeah, I know.
Are they breaking up?
This is a good thing--
will you shut up?
Please shut up.
Y--what are you even
doing here?
Running around
watching surgeries,
watching other people's lives,
trying to fix things,
and not doing anything
about your own life?
You raise a girl from the dead,
you don't have a job
because you don't want
to talk to your brother,
yet, you're giving me advice
on my life?
Deal with your own mess
before you get into mine.
Now if you want to sit there,
fine. Sit there.
But keep your mouth shut.
♪ And it's shining
all over the world ♪
♪ on every man, woman... ♪
You are hot when you're mad.
No wonder Addison l--
Amelia.
♪ ...fine ♪
♪ when the sunshine shines ♪
♪ it warms your skin ♪
♪ and your soul within ♪
At least you know
what you want.
All right.
No, Sam.
I mean, you know...
Who you are
and... and what you want
and...
What's important to you.
I mean, me, i'm--I'm a mess.
I don't have anything
or anyone
or even any kind of an idea
who I am
or what I am doing or why.
And I have done stuff, Sam...
I have done bad stuff,
and I...
♪ ...in the ocean waves ♪
♪ today they both feel saved ♪
I don't know
what I'm doing anymore.
♪ And it sure feels fine ♪
♪ when the sunshine shines ♪
I'm shutting up now.
♪ It warms your skin ♪
♪ and your soul within ♪
♪ and the birds sing
do do do ♪
♪ do do do do ♪
♪ do do do do do do do ♪
♪ do do do ♪
♪ do do do do do ♪
♪ hey, and the birds sing
do do do ♪
♪ do do do do ♪
♪ do do do do do do do ♪
My parents had a kid
before me who died.
Really?
Yeah.
You never told me that.
Well, I probably
never would've,
except for the fact that
Sheldon is annoying.
♪ Said what you gonna do
when the storms come? ♪
Do you think it's possible
that I was so angry
with Charlotte because I felt
like a replacement
for her first husband
like I was with my parents?
♪ 'Cause one day ♪
♪ the sunshine
will shine again ♪
Yeah, being second choice...
Forgiveness issues--
that makes sense.
♪ ...world ♪
Wow. Cooper.
This is big.
This is good and big.
Yay.
♪ And girl ♪
You think I should try
to get her back?
I think you should try.
♪ When the sunshine shines ♪
Do you think I should try
to get Lucas back?
What do you mean,
get him back?
I'm gonna sue Pete
for custody.
♪ Do do do do do ♪
Do you think I could win?
♪ And the birds sing ♪