I can't find the artery.
I can't find it.
Dean, you can do this!
Dr. Charles helped me.
And he can help you, too.
PTSD just doesn't
go away, Dean.
I don't need therapy.
I have a daughter, Vanessa.
I found out that she was
in medical school and...
So, you don't intend
to see her again?
Of course I want to.
Yeah, what was your
impression of her?
Good candidate.
It'd be great to get her.
The medication
was supposed to be
sent back to Kender.
Package for Kender?
Someone already
picked that up.
Is it even that
big of a deal, though?
I'm gonna have to find them,
one way or another.
Welcome, and congratulations.
You've all done well enough
to get this far.
But this ED only accepts
one med student a year
from this audition,
so, these next few weeks
are your one and only
opportunity to impress.
No pressure.
Now, you're new,
so I'm expecting
some mistakes.
But I'm also
expecting you
to display the confidence
to push through
those mistakes.
And if some of the nurses
take a liking to you,
that wouldn't hurt, either.
So, which one of them
are you so keen on?
Huh?
The student application
that you asked me to move
to the top of the pile?
Vanessa Taylor?
That's her right there.
Ah. How do you know her?
Friend of the family?
No, she... Residency fair.
She just stood out.
Maggie? Hi. I'm not sure
if you remember me or not,
but...
I do. You led me
to Beecher Hall.
And you played the Scarecrow
in middle school.
Scarecrow?
Good memory.
Vanessa Taylor,
this is...
Sharon Goodwin.
I was up last night
doing research,
'cause I couldn't sleep.
I'm a bit excited,
if you can't tell.
Pleased to meet you,
Miss Taylor.
Yeah. I should get back
to the group,
but thank you both
for this opportunity.
She's a go-getter.
Good morning.
Morning.
Oh. Hey, Dean, you wanna
grab lunch today?
Wednesday is Reuben day.
This wouldn't happen
to be your subtle attempt
to sit me down
for one of your casual
check-ins, would it?
Busted.
Yeah.
I'll tell you what.
You have my full permission
to tell Dr. Choi
that we spoke,
if it gets him off your back.
Everybody who works here
has gotta do this,
including Dr. Choi.
It's no big deal.
It'll take five minutes.
We can talk about gardening,
if you want. I gotta
cross you off my list.
Thing is, I've found that
what works best for me
is when I steal away
for some quiet,
personal time every day.
Unfortunately, I've found
that the only time I have
for that is my lunch hour.
You understand.
I am gonna have to
pin you down,
or Goodwin's
gonna get mad at me.
They're playing
my song. I gotta...
Treatment Four.
Neil Dietrich, 24.
Collapsed at the park
with severe abdominal pains.
Wouldn't let us
take his vitals,
but we were able
to get a saliva swab.
COVID negative.
What's going on, Neil?
It's just
a stomach ache, okay?
Whatever is wrong with me
will go away on its own.
I don't know. Maybe you should
give us professionals a shot.
One, two, three. Okay.
This isn't necessary.
Stop. Leave me alone.
A hundred-point-nine.
You have
a fever, Neil.
Your body's way
of telling us
something's wrong.
Yeah, I'll be fine.
Hmm.
And that pain you're
experiencing, I can make
that go away, easy.
A little morphine
will have you feeling like
it's a day at the spa.
Please, just leave me alone!
Okay. If you won't let us
treat you, maybe there's
something else we can do?
No. Nothing you can do
will matter.
How could you believe that
nothing we do will matter?
Nothing?
Because...
Because?
Come on, Neil. Level with me.
I can take it.
Because none of this is real,
okay? It's just a computer
simulation.
It's obvious,
every facet of our lives
has been pre-programmed.
The richest 1% of the world
owns 99% of basically
everything.
How's that possible?
Excellent question.
Where does it hurt, Neil?
I'll be fine.
It's possible because
the game is rigged.
Right.
And who exactly
is playing the game?
All real people are players,
they have no choice.
Obviously, there's some form
of higher intelligence.
They created
this simulation
for a reason.
Which is?
That's what
I'm trying to find out.
Clearly, some part of it is to
keep real people compliant.
Right. Are you a real person?
The real question is
are you a real person
or are you an NPC?
What's that?
A non-player character.
A computer construct
to maintain the order
of the simulation.
Despite our different
beliefs, we can all agree
that with the fever
and the intermittent
stabbing pain,
that you are unwell.
And now's a good time
to do something about that.
No. I'm sorry. I'm not gonna
change my mind on this.
Neil,
let's say you're right.
What I don't understand is
that your pain is obviously
very real to you.
And all we're trying
to do is figure out
what's causing it.
You don't wanna
let us do that?
No.
Because you'd reverse
the effects of the red pill.
The red pill?
There's this red pill you take
that initiates the process
of waking you up
outside of the simulation.
So, you took
one of these red pills?
Yeah, thankfully.
Whatever you ingested
might be making you sick.
Yeah, see,
that's exactly what
an NPC would say.
But you're right.
Whatever I'm feeling
right now,
it's probably the red pill
starting to work.
If that's what it takes to
wake up in the real world,
so be it.
How much longer do I
have to stay here?
Um, give Dr. Archer and I
a couple minutes,
and we'll be right back.
Well, if he hasn't poisoned
himself with whatever he took,
he probably has appendicitis.
Yeah. Look, there's
always a psych hold.
It'll antagonize him,
and we'll never find out
what he took.
Slow roll
the paperwork a bit.
Yeah, all right.
I wanna study up on this whole
simulation thing a bit,
see if I can get in
better sync with his logic.
Logic? He thinks we're living
in a computer game.
Hopefully, we'll dispel him
of that notion.
All right.
It's called the emergency room
for a reason.
Working fast is key,
but not at the expense
of working smart.
If you can do both,
that's what we're looking for.
Good morning, Ms. Royko.
Our patient is 62 years old,
experiencing a persistent
headache,
blurry vision, and has
a known history of diabetes.
All right.
What's your differential?
I suspect hypertension.
Do we know her BP yet?
226/115.
That would qualify
as hypertension.
What would your course
of treatment be?
I'd push ten of hydralazine.
Well done.
Doris, push ten
of hydralazine,
as recommended
by Student Dr. Mims here.
Excuse us.
Moving on.
Vanessa, hey. I couldn't help
but notice, it seemed like
you had the answer yourself.
Obviously,
she has hypertension.
I raised my hand.
I just didn't get called on.
Frankly, I think Cardizem
would be better
than hydralazine.
If I may,
a word of advice,
it wouldn't hurt
to assert yourself
a bit more.
Student Dr. Taylor,
you with us or not?
Maggie?
We need a room!
What's going on with your mom?
She's been passing out
intermittently,
started before breakfast.
What's Maggie
doing here? What?
Carol, we're gonna
take good care of you.
Herbert?
Yeah.
Go ahead.
I'll call the cardiologist,
tell them to come down.
No, Nat? I'm gonna
page Dr. Young.
You go be with your mom.
Will? What are you
doing in here?
What do you mean?
I'm up.
And it's your mother.
She's having
syncopal episodes?
Yeah. I think it might have
something to do with the LVAD.
Okay. Her lungs are clear,
so that's a good sign.
But your extremities
are super cold, Carol.
I know.
Let's do an EKG.
Hmm.
Thank you
for stepping in,
but I've paged Dr. Young
and I think that we can
manage until they come down.
Please don't go.
I'm really scared, Will.
Could you stay, please?
I'm not going
anywhere, Carol.
Mom...
Okay. Okay.
I promise.
We'll just get some
preliminary tests going.
Give Dr. Young
a head start.
All right.
I'll run a panel.
Remind me again,
what medications she's on?
What?
I assume
she's on a beta blocker?
Uh, yes. Metoprolol,
25mg, twice daily.
Plus, Lasix, the same,
and, um, Rosuvastatin,
I believe it's 10mg
once a day.
Okay.
And don't forget about
that, um,
new pill you gave me.
The one that's supposed
to help my heart pump.
New one?
Yes. I put her
on a fish oil supplement,
that's all.
Okay.
No, it's a little blue pill.
I'll show it to you.
It's in my bag.
No, no, no. Mom,
your bag is in the car.
I'll just go get it.
No, Mom,
you don't need it.
I need the stuff
that's in there.
Okay, Mom,
I have to go move the car.
I'll bring it in.
I'll be right back.
All right.
Okay.
You're each gonna be
working one-on-one
with the attendings.
Dr. Driskell here will have
your assignments. Follow him.
Taylor.
Yes, sir?
You start with me.
You can't go on
like this, Neil.
I have to. It's the only way
to see what real life is.
Oh, good. No red pill.
Neil, are you familiar
with the butterfly dream?
The Chinese philosopher
who dreamt
he was a butterfly...
Yeah. Only he woke up
only to question
whether or not he was
the butterfly or the man.
Right.
But you're not
gonna convince me
I'm wrong 'cause there
have been other philosophies
about hypothetical
simulations.
But what struck me is,
he did wake up.
Right? And then was able
to acknowledge that one of
those experiences was reality.
Right?
You're making my point. Okay?
I'm trying to wake up.
That's my goal.
I know what I'm doing.
I've heard
that before.
So, a few years back
in Afghanistan,
I was working alongside this
joint task force hunting down
Taliban extremists.
Now, let me tell you, we saw
some pretty gnarly stuff that
you would not believe.
And these soldiers,
they didn't come any tougher.
When they had a mission,
that was all that mattered.
Even with the worst injuries,
they would not be deterred.
I get that.
I know you do.
But sometimes, those same
injuries that they ignored
ended up killing them.
These were
preventable deaths.
And I do not
wanna see that
happening to you, Neil.
You don't seem to understand.
Okay? I can handle death.
I have to die to live.
Having witnessed
that firsthand,
that is patently untrue.
Look, it's just whatever
you think you saw over there,
none of that
actually happened.
You just think
that it did.
Okay.
It's part of the game.
All right.
I told you not to touch me!
Hey, no, I'm sorry, sorry.
I wanted to find out
where you're most sensitive.
That's all.
Dr. Charles.
A word, please?
All right. He's guarding
his lower right quadrant.
He has appendicitis.
I've seen this
100 times, all right?
If we don't do
anything about it,
his appendix will rupture,
and if that happens,
his life is gonna be
in jeopardy.
Yeah, I'm aware of what
a ruptured appendix means.
But why did you palpate him?
He wouldn't let me
come near him, otherwise.
I needed to get a read
on him. He's not even
gonna get a scan.
I completely get
how upsetting it must be
to hear
your military experience
characterized that way.
But, Dean,
this guy's delusional.
You misread
the moment, Dr. Charles.
I don't blame you
for thinking
that's what you saw.
But I was honestly
trying to make a diagnosis.
And now, that I have,
it's time for you
to get a court order,
so we can force treatment.
You know, if and when
I determine that the patient
lacks decisional capacity,
I'll absolutely reach out
to a judge.
If? Are you kidding me?
This guy's a box
of loose screws.
No. Actually,
he's a patient.
Where are they taking me?
To get an echo, Carol.
Okay.
A transthoracic echocardiogram
will show us exactly how your
heart pumps.
This could be because
of the LVAD, right?
We'll see.
Mom, it's a really
simple procedure.
I'll be right here
when you get out.
Okay? I love you.
Hey.
Sorry, didn't mean
to startle you.
Hi.
No, it's okay.
I've been
a little on edge today.
Yeah, I saw your mom
was here.
Yeah. Dr. Young
still doesn't know
what's going on,
but something's affecting
her circulation enough to
cause her to pass out.
Oh, I'm sorry to hear that.
Yeah. She's up
for an echo now.
So, we should know more soon.
Well, hope the echo brings
some good news.
Thank you.
See you.
Hey, Doris.
What's going on in there?
We got a drug addict in there
whose veins are shot to hell.
Can't get a peripheral in.
Ethan's asking for a...
Triple lumen kit?
Yeah.
Here you go.
Thanks.
Listen, I'm feeling
a little restless
just directing traffic.
I got an itch
to slip on the gloves.
How about you and me
swap places for the day?
I get to hold the brick?
Thank you.
Here you go, Dr. Choi.
What happened to Doris?
You got me instead.
You disappointed?
Never. So, you ever
insert a central line?
Plenty of times
in med school, yes, sir.
Show me what you got, then.
All right, Shawn. We're gonna
get you prepped for this.
Pull down your gown.
Lidocaine?
Yes, of course.
Thank you, Maggie.
Ethan? Goodwin's requesting
your presence at the 2:30
budget meeting.
All right, I'll be
right there.
Yeah.
Taylor?
You think you can
handle this yourself?
Yes, of course, Dr. Choi.
I'm confident I can
do this on my own.
I've assisted a million.
I got her back.
Great. Any problems,
you notify an attending.
I'll be back in a bit.
Crockett, you're up.
Yeah? Okay.
Cesar, Baghdad.
What've we got?
Edgar Fuentes, 25,
took a GSW to
the leg in a drive-by.
Vitals are stable.
Applied a pressure dressing
en route.
Bleeding's controlled.
Mr. Fuentes,
I'm Dr. Marcel.
I'll be taking care
of you, okay?
This hurts like hell!
Yeah.
He was working on the car
out front. He wasn't even
doing anything!
Right.
My wife, Rosa,
our baby, Ada.
I'm sorry we all
had to meet this way.
Okay, folks, on me.
Ready, set, lift.
Nice and easy, you're okay.
Can you wiggle
your toes for me?
Yeah, but hurts.
You got two wounds,
lateral thigh,
nowhere near the blood vessel.
Probably through and through,
but let's get an X-ray
to prove it.
And 50 of fentanyl, please.
You're gonna be okay,
Mr. Fuentes.
Come here.
He's gonna be okay.
It's just a flesh wound,
all right?
It looked so much worse.
We're gonna get an X-ray
just to be sure.
Oh, my God.
Is she okay?
Huh? Huh?
Your baby, is she okay?
Ada?
May I?
What? What...
Wait...
Hey, sweetheart.
What is that?
Your baby's been shot.
What?
I need help in here!
What? Oh, my God! No!
Yep. There's the bullet.
Pressure's still low.
Want me to hang
another unit?
No, let's do it up in the OR.
Let's move now.
I heard the gunfire, but I
didn't hear a window break.
It could've come
through the wall.
I've seen it before.
She was bundled up.
She seemed fine,
she wasn't bleeding...
The pressure from the swaddle
probably stopped the flow
of blood.
How could I not have noticed?
You didn't do
anything wrong.
Look, I'm gonna do
everything in my power
to save your baby's life.
All right, let's go.
Put back pressure
on the syringe
and walk the needle
down the clavicle,
until you hit the vein.
I lost the vacuum.
It's just filled with air.
I must have hit the lung.
We'll worry
about that later.
We still have
a line to put in.
Now, pull the needle back,
and eject the air.
Now, try again
until you find the vein.
Wait a minute.
What's going on?
It's okay, Shawn.
We're working on it.
Go ahead.
All right,
I'm drawing blood.
Perfect. Well done.
What about the lung?
I should go tell Dr. Choi.
Let's just finish
the procedure, okay?
So, physically,
there's something
very wrong with you.
By all indications,
your appendix
is about to burst.
So, what I'm asking is
if you would please
just let us do a scan.
I'm not getting a scan, okay?
No matter what it would show,
it's just the simulation's
explanation of what
the red pill is doing.
Neil, I respect
your point of view.
But you need to understand
that my reality
is that I'm a doctor,
and I can't just let you die.
Which is why I'm seriously
considering going to talk
to a judge this afternoon
about taking away
your ability to make your
own medical decisions.
What? Because you think
I'm delusional? Of course
you would think that.
That's actually
not what I said.
Can I ask you something?
Why is it that my belief
is the one being questioned?
Hey. I'm sorry to pull you
out of your meeting,
but it's important.
What's going on?
I have
an appendicitis patient
who's refusing treatment
because he believes
that we're living
in a computer simulation.
A what?
Yeah, I know.
It's... He's nuts.
Just page Dr. Charles.
No. See, Dr. Charles
is the problem.
He's dragging his heels
on forcing the treatment
that the guy needs.
Is it emergent?
I believe it is, yeah.
All right. What can I do?
I want you to weigh in.
With another sensible voice
in the room, maybe the two
of ours can drown his out.
I'll take a look, but I can't
imagine double doc-ing
Dr. Charles
on a decisional
capacity ruling.
Uh-huh. You know what?
Forget it.
'Cause I'm not interested
in having a courtesy consult.
Hey, Dean, I know how
frustrating it is
to be in your position...
I've butted heads
with Dr. Charles on this
same issue in the past.
Oh, yet, now,
you sit on your hands?
Watch it, Dean.
You're right. You're right,
uh, that was over the line.
All clear.
Just like I thought.
There's a pneumothorax.
This happens all the time.
Even to the most
seasoned doctors.
It happened
to Ethan last week.
Don't beat yourself up.
I'll go find Dr. Choi.
Or, you can
fix it yourself.
Insert a chest tube?
Mmm-hmm. You're comfortable
doing that, right?
Sure, but I...
Listen, Vanessa,
everyone makes mistakes.
But this way,
you can show Dr. Choi
that you know
how to correct yours
on your own.
I don't know.
If you want to win
a permanent spot in this ED,
this is how you do it.
All right.
Yeah, let's do it.
Hey, Shawn?
It appears that
when we did the procedure,
we hit your lung.
It's nothing serious.
But in order to fix
the problem,
we're gonna have to put
a tube in your chest
and we need your consent.
Is it necessary?
Unfortunately, it is.
But we're gonna numb you up,
give you a bit more sedation,
and you'll hardly
feel anything.
Okay.
All right.
You lay back and relax.
How'd it go?
No luck.
No CT. Okay.
Nurse Sexton!
Yes?
He's not protecting
his airway, I need to
intubate him. Get a line.
Order a CT, call the OR.
Make sure they have
a room open
in case we need
to bring him up for surgery.
Wait. Didn't Neil say that
he didn't want to be treated?
He did, but now,
he's unconscious.
You're just gonna disregard
what he wanted?
When a patient
is no longer able to
make medical decisions,
and there's no one
to stand up for them,
the hospital assumes
power of attorney.
Twenty of etomidate,
100 of sux.
Should I not intubate him?
He doesn't have a DNI.
Tell me!
I have to admit,
when your mother
came in this morning,
I assumed it was because
her heart was on the brink
of failure.
But that's not what
the echo is showing.
Looks like her heart
is beating more effectively.
I mean, when you have
the kind of underlying
disease Carol does,
the heart can behave
inconsistently.
But rarely does it show
this kind of improvement.
Yeah, that is odd.
So, why does my mom
keep passing out?
It's a phenomenon
called "suck down."
The heart's
contracting so hard
that the ventricle wall
is getting sucked
into the LVAD, too.
The poor blood circulation
is leading to a lack
of cerebral perfusion.
What do we do now?
I'm gonna consult
with Dr. Latham as soon
as he gets out of surgery.
There's a chance he'll want to
sew the left ventricle shut
to help the LVAD
work effectively.
Well, I mean,
this is good news, right?
I hesitate
to call it good news
until we figure out
exactly what's going on.
Thank you, Dr. Young.
Thank you.
Wow.
That's not something
you see every day.
Yeah.
Must be the fish oil
she's taking.
Wait...
What are you doing? Will!
Why are you going
through my mom's bag?
What are you doing?
Let's see what these magic
supplements look like.
God!
So embarrassing. Will!
Nope, that's
the beta blocker.
Stop!
That's the statin,
and those two are Lasix.
Where'd they go, Natalie?
What are you talking about?
The trial drugs
that went missing?
The blue pills?
I know you took them.
What'd you do with them?
I can't believe you're
accusing me of this...
The improved function
in your mom's left ventricle.
Your sudden interest
in the drug's side effects
last week.
Come to think of it,
you never did tell me
the name of that trial patient
with the dry cough.
I wonder who it is.
Oh, please, come on.
This is ridiculous!
You are dosing your mother
with an untested clinical
trial drug, Natalie,
without supervision
or monitoring.
We don't know how the drug
interacts with an LVAD.
It could kill her!
You need to come clean.
Right now.
Will...
Will, I...
Give me that.
No. Will, wait. Wait!
You heard the cardiologist!
Mom's heart is pumping harder!
The drugs could be working!
We don't know that for sure.
Please, I was desperate.
And everything you said
about the drug was good.
I didn't think
I was putting Mom
in any danger.
This is really bad, Nat.
Will, please.
Please. Please...
Am I interrupting?
Not at all. I was just
talking to a judge,
trying to get a court order,
so we could treat Neil.
But without definitive proof
of his medical condition,
he couldn't help us.
It doesn't matter,
because Dr. Archer
took Neil up to surgery,
and is removing
his appendix right now.
Wait. Did Neil agree to that?
No. But he went
into respiratory distress
and needed to be intubated.
Leaving Dean to make
medical decisions
on his behalf?
Yeah.
I saw how frustrated
Dr. Archer was
with Neil before.
Definitely.
It got me thinking.
Could he have...
Could he have
overmedicated Neil
to knock him unconscious?
Oh, God.
Will.
Sabeena. I didn't know
you were coming in today.
Just passing through,
thought I'd see
how you were doing.
I have a meeting
with the head lab technician.
Yeah, no.
Everything's all good here.
Just taking a break.
Okay.
Hey, the drug we're testing.
Any idea how it might affect
a patient with an LVAD?
The drug's an inotrope,
essentially a chemical LVAD.
Why would anyone do that?
Just a hypothetical.
I can't imagine why
it would ever be prescribed
in that situation.
But, listen,
we're a few months out
from seeking FDA approval.
If there's a patient suffering
any adverse reaction,
it needs to be reported.
No, nothing like that. Yeah.
The baby's
still hypotensive.
I don't know if she's
gonna survive this.
I'm trying to find
the source of the bleed.
What do you
want me to do?
Just keep giving her
more blood.
Okay.
Come on.
Hey, Shawn, how you doing?
Much better. Thank you.
Let's check your work.
Line placement looks good.
As does this chest tube,
though, I don't remember
our patient requiring one.
Sir, when I made
my first attempt at placing
the central line,
I noticed air coming
out of the syringe, so, I...
So, she ordered an X-ray
to see if there was a pneumo
and there was, so she...
Yeah, I understand.
Student Dr. Taylor,
can I have a word
with you outside?
We'll be right back, Shawn.
Placing a chest tube
is considered
a surgical procedure
that requires
prior consent
from the patient.
We okayed it with the patient.
"We"?
Maggie and myself.
Consent for the procedure
can only be obtained
by a licensed physician.
Neither you
nor Nurse Lockwood qualify.
I'm sorry, I didn't realize...
You acted recklessly.
By not notifying
your supervisor,
you put me
and the ED at risk.
Don't worry. I'll fix this.
Ethan?
Listen. Vanessa was just
following my instructions.
Look.
She's gonna be a doctor.
What happens
in that treatment room
is her decision.
But this is my fault.
She's a top notch student,
she's head of her class.
What are you talking about?
Student Dr. Vanessa Taylor.
I was assisting her,
I gave her some bad advice.
But she solved
the problem herself.
Mags, why are you going
so far out of your way
to help this student?
Please Ethan,
give her a second chance.
She shouldn't have to
pay for my mistake.
I'll give it some
consideration.
Thank you.
Why were you assisting her?
Doris and I just
switched places for a bit.
I have to relieve her now.
So, I understand that
we have an update
on our patient?
Unfortunately,
we waited so long,
his appendix perforated.
So, I removed it,
washed his belly out.
And he's recovering
in the ICU.
And how did that
happen exactly?
He stopped protecting
his airway, so I had
to intubate him.
Which then gave you
the authority
to make medical decisions
for him.
Oh, hey, if I hadn't
come upon Neil when I did,
oh, he'd be dead.
Oh, yeah.
He'd stopped breathing.
From appendicitis?
Mmm-hmm.
You know that'd be
a first, right?
He was septic.
His appendix ruptured.
And why the hell am I
getting the third degree?
You're the one who was
about to almost let
a crazy person kill himself!
Dean, stop!
No, no, no!
Remember,
at the end of the day,
it's my word versus Neil's.
The guy who thinks
this whole thing
is a game of Tetris!
Enough. Dean, take a walk.
Someone wanna tell me
what's going on?
Mr. and Mrs. Fuentes.
Is my Ada okay?
She's currently
on a breathing machine
up in the PICU.
Now, we're not
out of the woods yet,
but I was able
to stop the bleeding.
She's alive. Yeah.
Thank you, Dr. Marcel.
Yeah, my pleasure.
I don't know what I would've
done if we'd lost her.
She's gonna be all right.
Hopefully, we'll get her
extubated tomorrow.
In the meantime,
Nurse Trini here,
she's gonna escort you
up to the PICU here in a bit.
You can see her. Okay?
Thank you.
Yeah. My pleasure.
Thanks.
Hey.
You been in surgery?
Yeah. Seven-month-old
baby with a GSW.
She's gonna be okay, though.
Are you?
Yeah. Yeah,
I'm gonna be fine. Thanks.
Um, listen, I wanted to talk
to you about something.
But I was a little nervous
about how you might take it.
Which I know is out
of my control, so...
Natalie, you got a minute?
It's about your mom.
Oh. Yeah.
Go ahead.
Sorry.
I feel incredible.
Your hands are warm.
And your color's
starting to come back.
Oh.
I want a pastry.
I am famished.
Okay, I will get you one.
Go take a seat.
Yeah, I will get it myself.
Let me feel like
a normal human being again.
Okay. We'll be
right over there.
Okay.
This is amazing.
What changed?
I tried a little experiment
before the surgeons
weighed in.
I turned her LVAD as low
as it could go to see
what would happen.
And?
Her heart's functioning fine
with barely any assist.
In fact, now, the LVAD's
just getting in the way.
Does that mean that...
It appears as if
the drug is working.
We should
keep her overnight,
monitor her,
but looks good.
I wish I could
go back in time,
just insist that
my mom sign up
for the trial meds.
We can't ask Kender
for a compassionate
use exemption.
And who knows
what they'll do
when they find out?
Maybe they don't need
to find out.
Here.
How many pills
do you have left?
Maybe a week's worth.
I'll try to secure more
before she runs out.
Will, I do not want to
put you in this position.
You let me worry about that.
In the meantime, I think
we should talk to Dr. Young
about removing
her LVAD altogether.
We wanna try our chances
on the transplant list.
Are you sure?
Yes. Natalie, if we can keep
from getting caught,
your mom may not ever
need a transplant.
I don't even know
what to say.
No one else
can find out about this.
You understand?
Yeah.
Neil, how you doing?
Neil, this is my
colleague, Dr. Choi.
Hey, Neil. I'd like to discuss
what happened today.
It was working, the red pill.
I was finally gonna be able
to experience reality.
A world that's not constantly
trying to manipulate me.
And then
you so-called doctors,
you took that away.
Can you tell us
more about that?
Like you don't already know.
Well, we're actually
trying to get
a better picture
of what happened
this afternoon,
when Dr. Archer
checked in on you.
Can you walk us
through that?
What you remember,
anyway?
He cut me open
and rewired my circuitry,
so that I'll never be able
to unplug from the simulation.
Even if I could get
another red pill,
it doesn't matter. Okay?
I'm stuck here forever!
Buddy, we're gonna
get you out of here
as soon as possible,
okay?
Not necessarily the most
reliable witness. Poor guy.
No. But at least
he's alive.
Yeah.
In any case, I'm gonna
go have a talk with Dean.
Oh, my goodness.
Be right back, Mom.
Hey, Carol.
Hi!
Hey.
So, I saw on the surgery
schedule that they're removing
Carol's LVAD?
It was actually causing
her problems.
But they lowered it
and she got better.
Wow. With her level
of heart disease...
never seen that.
Is this what you
wanted to tell me?
Yeah, I just... I was afraid
of how you'd take it.
I didn't want you to feel
responsible, or anything.
No, I get it.
All right, good.
I should get back in there.
Um, but I'll see you
tomorrow, okay?
Sure.
Vanessa!
Hey. Good news.
I spoke to Dr. Choi.
He realizes now
that what happened
was entirely my fault.
In fact, he told me
that he admired
your handiwork.
Said that your chest tube
was placed spot on.
So, trust me,
if nothing else,
he's gonna remember
who you are now.
Hey, you should
feel good about today...
Look, I'd really appreciate it
if you didn't tell me
how I should feel
about being humiliated.
I'm sorry, that wasn't
my intention.
I was just trying
to help.
You know what, while I'm here
these next few weeks,
I'd just prefer
if you left me alone.
Vanessa, I...
Maggie?
Everything okay?
Yes. I was just talking
to Student Dr. Vanessa Taylor
and...
You know, I should've known
when I saw her this morning.
She's your daughter.
She doesn't know,
does she?
No. And I don't
intend to tell her, so...
Oh, Maggie, what happens
if these three weeks
turn into something
more permanent?
What if she's accepted?
I'll manage it.
I'm telling you,
this is not gonna
be a problem.
Looks to me
like it already is.
I'm sorry. My character was
being called into question,
and I overreacted
and I let my emotions
get the best of me.
Did you snow him to
force him into surgery?
Why would I do that?
No, really. Why would I risk
my job and my career for that?
Why would I do that?
I don't know, Dean.
But given the circumstances
that happened today, I...
It certainly seems plausible.
What do you want me to say?
You want me to tell you
that I can't sleep nights,
and I'm always looking
over my shoulder,
and that's the way
it's been for years? Is that
what you want to hear?
Of course not.
I want you to be okay.
The idea of looking
at what happened over there,
putting that
under a microscope?
No way, I'm not doing that.
That scares
the hell out of me.
That's why I keep pushing you
to talk to a psychiatric
professional.
If not Dr. Charles,
then someone else.
Yeah, I will. I will.
I'm serious, man.
I promise you.
I will. I promise.
Dean, if you want to
keep working here,
you have to deal
with your issues.