Okay. Ha-ha-ha.
- Okay.
- Aah!
Okay.
This is terrifying!
And very fun!
Are you ready to try lying down?
Because I am ready, Shaun.
I am very ready.
Carly...
Six-hundred-thread count
microfiber sheets,
a shredded memory-foam pillow.
A 40-watt A-19
incandescent bulb.
I'm sorry.
You didn't return my calls
this weekend.
After a ride up Skyline Boulevard,
60 minutes of Muay Thai,
and a 15-year reserve Scotch,
I had a moment of clarity.
What you said about my objectivity
in the Fields case wasn't about me.
You were in pain.
I was taking responsibility,
and asking you to take your share.
It was a good surgical plan.
You need to accept that despite
being a gifted surgeon,
you are fallible.
I think I should run my procedures
by Glassman from now on.
Audrey, we need some checks
and balances.
I am checked and balanced.
And I'm the chief
of this department.
You will continue to run
your medical decisions past me.
Browne, you're with Melendez.
Murphy and Park, meet me in the ER
observation unit in 20.
I thought I was on ER consults
with Park today.
If I'm being bumped
because I took off the other day,
- Dr. Browne was every bit of...
- Your first lead surgery.
Thank you.
Scheduled for tomorrow.
Study the images,
prep your patient.
Yes! I rock. I rock.
The surgery gods know it.
I know it.
And apparently, so does Andrews.
Boasting doesn't have the same impact
when you're picked last.
He was obviously waiting
for the right case to come along.
No.
You're kidding me.
This is much better
than my first surgery.
Damn right.
A med student could do an appy.
The carotid endarterectomy
takes serious finesse.
Fair to say it's really
a fifth-year procedure,
but I don't have time to sit around
debating semantics.
I have the Holy Grail
of resident surgeries to prep for.
The tumor was found on my left lung
at my medical fitness exam.
Tricky spot.
Curable, but tough to remove
without taking the entire lung.
- That's what they said.
- You didn't like that answer?
I need my lung.
I'm going to the moon.
When did the chest pain start?
- Around 9 this morning.
Okay. I'm gonna look at your heart.
This gel may be a little cold.
You see a cardiologist.
Did you use the nitro he prescribed?
It usually relieves the angina,
but not this time.
Are you the same Rosalind Elion
who just published a study
on IDH-2 inhibitors
in myeloid leukemia
in the Journal of Pediatric Oncology?
Yeah.
Wow.
You're famous.
I used an IDH-2
on a kid with AML.
- Now he's doing great.
- Oh.
And your study's revolutionized
leukemia treatment.
- It's an honor to meet you.
- That's kind of you to say.
Noticing anteroapical
wall motion abnormalities.
- Is your chest pain worsening?
- Yes, how did you...
She's having a heart attack.
Contact her family, meet us in Surgery.
She needs a triple bypass.
- The moon?
- The moon.
In 2020.
It's a private venture partnership
with NASA.
Floating in an expanse
of uninhabitable emptiness
200,000 miles
from the nearest Starbucks.
Not for me.
You never wanted to be an astronaut
when you were a kid?
Had enough challenges here on Earth.
Did you?
- I was a Trekker.
- Ha-ha-ha.
All my friends had Spock ears.
I was all about McCoy.
There's our tumor.
It's embedded in the hilum.
NASA doctor was right.
- We'd have to take the entire lung.
- Not necessarily.
The tumor's growing
into the upper lobe.
If we can remove it from the main
bronchus, we can get a clean margin.
The rest of the lung can stay.
- No-go.
- You'd have 80 percent of your...
If treatment reduces
my lung volume at all,
- I'll be unfit for space travel.
- The mass is too deep.
Major blood vessels,
your airway esophagus,
and heart are right there.
The next opinion you get
will be the same. Or worse.
Thank you for your time.
- What do you see at the apex?
- I see perfusion abnormalities.
Her LAD and PD
are completely occluded.
She listed her husband as her proxy.
Update him as soon as he gets here.
The entire left side of her heart
is compromised.
He's not coming.
They've been divorced for two years.
He hasn't spoken to her
in almost that long.
Murphy, anastomose the
internal mammary to the LAD.
See if we can give her heart
a blood supply.
Tracked down her sister
in Santa Cruz.
Hasn't seen Rosalind in years either.
That's a lot of legwork for a
surgeon. No social worker available?
It's good you didn't find anyone.
Family members are the least
qualified people in the room
to make medical decisions.
Judging by the state of her myocardium,
there's only one choice anyway.
She needs a new heart.
I think it's possible to spare her
upper lobe using a surgical robot.
Wren Braxton came to see me.
You're her second opinion?
Or fourth or whatever she's up to?
Surprised you didn't offer
the robotic option.
It's the type of surgery
I usually send your way.
I didn't offer it
because with the robot,
if I nick her pulmonary artery, she'd bleed
out before I open her up to control it.
She's gonna keep looking until someone
gives her the answer she wants.
Then what?
What do you think her odds
of survival are
if some hack tries to cut the tumor out,
leaving the lungs intact?
- Roughly zero.
- I agree.
- And with you? With the robot?
- Still lousy.
You can do this.
You're overestimating the risk
and I know why.
And you're doing exactly
what you did last time,
assuming that I can do anything.
So everyone else is biased
except for you?
The one who just had
a patient die on him.
If it's had any effect, it's to make
my judgment more acute.
I won't risk having Wren leave here
the same way Patty Fields did.
People risk things to make
their dreams come true.
If you don't wanna help her,
I'll do it myself.
The intra-aortic balloon pump
will support your heart
until we find a donor.
And when might that be?
A heart is the most
difficult organ to procure.
But since yours
is so badly damaged,
you are very high on the list.
I suppose that's a good thing.
- Not really. The...
- We're doing everything we can.
Thank you.
- Is there anyone you want us to call?
- Yes.
My lab assistant.
The next few days are crucial
to my monoclonal antibody study.
Hannah needs to stay
with the cultures around the clock.
I don't want five years of work
to go to waste.
Can I ask why you listed
your ex-husband
as your medical proxy?
I had to name someone.
Leo is the only person
I ever discussed my medical wishes with.
Now, if you don't mind,
I have a lot of work to do, which...
as you've indicated,
I may not have a lot of time to do it.
How are you, Shaun?
These are stat cardiac labs.
I have to go.
I hope you're not embarrassed
about last night.
I want to have sex with you.
That's nice.
I think about it very often.
Even when I'm supposed to focus on
more pressing matters.
Like 15 minutes ago when I was
filling out that lab requisition,
- I almost forgot to add a BNP.
- That's good.
No, it's not.
We need a BNP to monitor
her cardiac function
on the balloon pump.
I've been thinking about you too,
sometimes when I shouldn't.
- That's bad.
- Not really.
I've been doing some research.
I came across this therapy
psychologists use to treat phobias.
Apparently it works
in people with autism too.
If you're game,
we could try tonight.
I'm game.
I need a different first surgery.
Is there a problem
with your patient?
The plaque dissection is too advanced
for a third-year resident.
I was nervous as hell
for my first surgery,
and it was only a tonsillectomy.
I could take out a pair of tonsils
blindfolded.
It's not nerves.
This is a fifth-year procedure.
- You're setting me up to fail.
- This is why I picked you.
You come to me scared
and you couch it in arrogance.
It's rare that a resident
has what you have.
The aggressiveness, the work ethic,
and talent to be a leader.
I'm not setting you up to fail,
I'm setting you up to shine.
Or am I wrong about you?
No, sir.
I want you to do my surgery.
The one Dr. Lim suggested.
It was Dr. Lim's idea.
She's an excellent surgeon
and my superior.
And you think I'm an idiot.
I am afraid of this surgery.
And I'm afraid of going
to the moon.
But it's not about the moon,
it's about the fear.
It's about getting beyond that.
That's how great things happen.
How they've always happened.
Because someone took a chance.
From what I've read about you,
you're exactly the kind of person
I need in my corner.
Exactly the kind of person I would
have thought would understand.
Fear is also what keeps us alive.
What are the odds of you
not coming back from the moon?
The reason it's heroic,
the reason it's exciting,
is because you don't know
what to expect.
You can't anticipate everything.
One, two, maybe 5 percent.
Sixty percent.
This surgery, if I were doing it,
there is a 60 percent chance
that you'd die on the table.
It's called exposure therapy.
We'll lie down on the bed
side-by-side,
fully clothed and not touching
for 15 seconds.
When this timer goes off,
you'll go into the other room
for a three-minute break.
And then we'll go again
for 20 seconds.
Over time, we will progress
to longer intervals
and start to lie closer together.
This seems like a good approach.
Whenever you're ready.
Are you okay?
What are you feeling?
I don't know.
I don't... I don't know,
I don't know why it didn't work.
- It's okay, Shaun. We'll try again.
- No. No.
No. No, I can't.
We'll try for less time.
I can't do this.
Go.
What?
Go. Get out of here.
We can watch the end of...
I got the sheets,
the pillow, the damn light bulb,
I read 18 psych journals.
And you give up
after eight seconds?
You're right,
this isn't going to work.
Go home.
How are things with Carly?
I lasted eight seconds.
She kicked me out of her house.
First time is difficult.
I'm sure she didn't...
We tried timed exposure therapy
to get physically closer, but I...
couldn't do it.
So try something else.
When I lie close to her,
I feel diaphoretic.
My heart rate is elevated
and mouth gets dry.
I don't know
how to not feel that way.
You want this, Shaun?
Yes.
Very much.
Then rely on your strengths.
Treat it like a surgical problem.
Do your research.
Carly came up with a solution,
it didn't work,
but that doesn't mean
the next one won't.
Give me good news.
I had a potential donor in San Diego,
but the heart
was just too damaged.
I'm at the GE junction now.
Now she has complete right-sided
failure too.
It's time to discuss a DNR.
She's got one day left in this world.
Let's keep her comfortable.
Sixty percent? That number
is grossly exaggerated.
I spent an hour convincing my patient
I'm not trying to kill her.
She came to me,
I gave her my surgical opinion.
- I could fire you for this.
- Because I contradicted
your opinion after you
contradicted my opinion?
I gave her an option
you were too afraid to present.
No, you proposed a potentially
deadly surgery to a woman
who was desperate for any option.
- You don't have the authority...
- Authority?
I thought we were talking
about the patient.
It was unprofessional, disrespectful...
- If anyone showed a lack of respect...
- Doctors.
My office.
I wouldn't wanna be kept alive
on life support.
Not if there was no hope
for a recovery.
There wouldn't be.
As your heart failure worsens,
you may get short of breath
from fluid build-up.
We can use diuretics
and vasodilators to help control that.
- I recommend both of those.
- Of course, yes.
If that doesn't help,
we could insert a catheter
in your chest to drain the fluid.
The procedure does risk
a lung puncture,
which would worsen
your symptoms.
You should give us every option
to keep your breathing easy.
And we'll be on call all night to make sure
you're as comfortable as possible.
Thank you.
I went through this with my mom
when she was dying of leukemia.
I'm so sorry.
Was that recent?
I was 10.
I remember feeling so helpless.
You should reach out to Leo.
It's too late.
I don't believe that.
There were, uh, things
between my wife and I...
that I thought we could never
get past.
But last Christmas...
we almost lost our son.
And when I reached out,
Mia was there.
Leo...
always made me feel pressured to
choose between my research and him.
Eventually,
I realized he was right.
So I chose to go where
I was needed the most.
To call him now would be
hypocritical and...
unfair.
It took a lot of time
and dedication to push
our understanding of leukemia
as far as you did.
I'm glad I have treatment options
for my patients.
You made a good choice.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
I assume that some of this
is professional,
the other 90 percent
is personal.
- Am I right?
- It's a very difficult case.
We're both just overly invested.
Actually, I'd love for you
to weigh in on this one.
Dr. Lim, are you confident
in this surgical plan?
- Good luck.
- Thank you.
You didn't even look at the case.
- The pulmonary...
- Dr. Lim is my chief of surgery.
I trust her judgment.
I'm sorry things got out of hand.
It won't happen again.
It better not.
If you two can't control
your interpersonal squabblings,
I'm gonna have to lose one of you,
at least.
We need an endoscopy suite to fetch
the spoon out of this guy's stomach.
Cool.
How's the intimacy research
going?
Dr. Elion has had
a very successful life
without a relationship.
So can I.
Success and happiness aren't the same.
You need to decide what will make
you happy in the end.
I don't know
if it's being a great surgeon
or being close to Carly,
but I'm better at surgery
than I am with her.
Dr. Elion is wrong,
you don't have to choose.
I fly to Phoenix to spend time
with Mia and Kellan.
Then you won't be great at either.
I think Dr. Elion is afraid.
I think it was never about the journals
and the lives she could save.
I think she's always been afraid.
Afraid she might lose Leo
just like she lost her mother.
And you,
you lost the person you loved the most
when your brother died.
Your elevated heart rate,
sweaty palms,
they're not about
your sensory issues, Shaun.
It's what we all feel.
Fear.
Why would anyone want
to feel afraid?
Because the thought of
ending up alone is scarier.
I don't think Dr. Elion
refuses to call Leo
because it's hypocritical.
I think she's afraid he won't come.
- Can you handle the spoon?
- Yes.
Okay.
- Morning, Dr. Glassman.
- Morning.
Which shoulder would you like
to hurt for the next 24 hours?
I'm not here for a vaccine.
Okay.
Wrist and thumb joint pain.
I need cortisone shots.
Surgery's in two hours.
Can I ask you something?
If a patient, say a violinist
who concertized three
or four times a week
would have come to you
with achy joints,
would you give them a cortisone shot
or tell them to lay off?
Better question,
if he or she came to you
with achy joints
and pretended they needed
a vaccination,
what would you do then?
It's...
It's because I wanted you to know
and no one else.
I saw a rheumatologist last month.
I have rheumatoid arthritis.
Well, I'm sorry to hear that.
My mom had it too.
It destroyed her wrist
and finger joints.
Maybe I should leave
Saint Bonaventure.
Berkeley's chief is retiring this year.
I could apply to replace him.
We are entitled to have
differing opinions,
- we can argue...
- Apparently, we can't.
I love you.
I want our relationship to work.
And I wanna be chief.
If we can't find a way to work together
with me as your boss...
something has to change.
Looks like you caught it early,
without any noticeable erosion
of the joints.
That's good.
What's your D-MARD dose?
Twenty milligrams,
but Dr. Baxter just started it.
Okay.
You're gonna have to postpone
your first lead surgery for a while,
see how you respond.
I'd have to explain why
to Andrews and Lim.
As you should. A cortisone shot
is just a temporary fix.
Do you know what the chances are
the D-MARD can maintain
the dexterity you need to perform
an operation in the long run?
Forty-five percent.
- It'll change the way they see me.
- Yeah, you have a condition.
- A medical condition.
- They'll expect less from me.
They'll be looking for me to fail.
That's why I'm confiding in you
instead of them.
You advocated for Shaun
when everybody else thought
he couldn't be a surgeon.
I'm sorry,
you're comparing arthritis to autism?
I'm comparing people's assumptions,
people's prejudices.
I'm asking for a chance
to prove myself.
In this surgery today,
you're gonna have to create a plane
as thin as paper between
two delicate layers of tissue
without disrupting
the major blood flow to the brain.
If you miss by one-tenth,
one-tenth of a millimeter,
the patient will suffer
permanent brain damage, or worse.
Right now it's a matter of pain,
not function.
You think I would put
a patient's life at risk?
That's insulting.
I'm sorry.
Without the pain,
I can do this.
You believed in Shaun.
I need someone
to believe in me too.
Okay.
Leo Adan?
That's me.
I'm Alex Park.
I'm Rosalind's doctor.
She's dying.
She wants to see you.
Why didn't she call me?
Why'd she send you?
She doesn't know I'm here.
Even when we were married,
I never topped her to-do list.
She wasn't cheating on you,
she wasn't doing anything
except saving lives.
She deserves to be cut
a little slack.
Yeah.
She was saving the whole damn world,
she's a saint.
I made partner, she wasn't there,
everybody understood.
My mother died, she wasn't there,
Well, I didn't.
Look, maybe I was a selfish jerk
for wanting my wife to be around,
but I did.
She didn't send you.
Good for her.
She's not a hypocrite.
That hasn't changed.
Assistant port is secured.
Load the forceps
and electrocautery.
My chief's doing a difficult surgery.
I'm here to help in any way I can.
Instruments are ready.
Time of initial incision, 11:32.
- How is she?
- She's really short of breath.
I gave her vasodilators
and diuretics, but she's not settling.
She has bilateral pulmonary edema.
She needs 40 milligrams
of furosemide.
I'll push two lorazepam too.
I can't... catch my breath.
You've got fluid in your chest.
This medication should help ease
your breathing.
She should be improving,
but she's not.
Maybe we should insert a drain.
Shaun, this isn't about the fluid.
She's scared.
Rosalind,
I know this is frightening,
but you are not alone.
I'm here
and I am not going anywhere.
As long as you need me.
Leo...
I see the base of the tumor.
There's a lot of bleeding
teasing off the pulmonary vein.
Put a bipolar electrocautery
instrument on the right arm.
It's way more friable than it looks,
the tumor's invaded the vessel wall.
I need to load more
hemostatic matrix.
If I keep going, I'll end up
with a bleed I can't control.
I need to take the lung.
Prep her for an open thoracotomy.
I need a prostatectomy kit.
Now.
Prostate cancers tend to grow along
the surrounding nerves.
Equipment's designed
to dissect the tumor
without injuring the nerves.
Substitute arteries for nerves
and you've got our situation.
Load the hot shears.
Unclamp the proximal and distal end.
You have good shunt flow.
Loupes.
Forceps and dissector.
Is there a problem, Dr. Reznick?
Nice work, Dr. Reznick.
Did you...
We got it all.
And you'll still need that
flight suit.
Thanks, doc.
He might have helped a little too.
The tumor was more entangled in your
arteries than it appeared,
but Dr. Melendez
pulled off a remarkable win for us.
This is the reason
you still have two complete lungs.
Sign it.
Both of you.
I'm gonna leave it on the moon.
She's very close.
I'll pronounce her.
I'd like to do it.
Thank you.
I hope it's not too late.
It's fine. Come in.
You were right.
It was a crazy surgery.
But not as crazy as I thought.
It wouldn't have even happened
if it wasn't for you.
You were right too.
I'm not objective
when it comes to you.
I blew off your concerns
about the risks
because I thought
you'd lost your mojo.
Great. We're both right.
And we found a way
to work together,
and our patient's better off for it.
Today.
What about the next time?
We won't make the same mistakes.
I'm not sure they were mistakes.
I think they might have
just been our nature.
I don't think I can give you
the unconditional support
you deserve from a partner...
and the objectivity
you need from a chief.
And...
I don't wanna give up on my dream.
I love you...
but it's not enough.
Good night, Neil.
Dr. Reznick.
Dr. Glassman.
Thank you for your support.
My pain is 90 percent better
than it was.
The shots helped.
Well, you did a remarkable job.
I'm fine.
Congratulations.
I did extensive further research
on intimacy treatment for autism.
And?
And I found nothing.
You were right.
Exposure therapy
is the most effective option.
You're very smart and thorough.
Thank you.
I'd like to try again.
It's time to take a break.
I know.
This is terrifying.
And...
very nice.