♪ Uh-huh, yeah ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ If you want me to
stay I'll be around today ♪
♪ To be available
For you to see ♪
♪ Well, I'm about to go
And then you'll know ♪
♪ For me to stay
here I got to be me ♪
♪ You'll never be in doubt
That's what it's all about ♪
♪ You can't take me
for granted And smile ♪
♪ Count my days I'm gone
Forget reaching me by phone... ♪
What do you got?
LOL, ALOC. Where
do you want her?
Curtain Area 3.
I'll be right there.
Oh, yeah, turn it up, Jer.
♪ ...I hope that you have been ♪
♪ The kind of person
That you really are now ♪
♪ Got to get them straight
How could I ever be late... ♪
Go, girl. Go.
Have we got a deal?
I don't know, Mark.
If you don't think I
should be an Attending,
you should just say so.
I'm not comfortable
with this bargaining
on Susan Lewis' behalf.
It lacks dignity.
It's the way of the world.
Yeah, but whatever
happened to advancement
based solely on
merit and ability?
It went out with hoop skirts
and smoking jackets.
Damn it, Jerry! Turn it down.
So do we have a deal?
Jerry!
Hold on. Hold on.
It's my favorite
part right here.
♪ I'll be good ♪
♪ I wish I could ♪
♪ I'd get this message
Over to you now ♪
♪ Aah! ♪
Now you can turn it down.
Thank you.
Sorry, Dr. Weaver.
They made me do it.
That staff meeting
starts in four minutes.
So you really think
Susan Lewis would make
a good chief Resident?
Honestly?
Yes, I do.
Okay, then.
What was that all about?
I think I just sold
my soul to the devil.
What do you got?
LOL, vitals normal,
oriented times zero.
Lady Godiva, here,
was au de natural,
running around
Buckingham fountain,
singing songs from My Fair Lady.
Carousel.
"June Is Busting Out All Over"
is Rogers and Hammerstein,
not Lerner and Loewe.
Well, whatever. Just
keep her restrained,
or little old Junie, here,
is definitely gonna
be busting out all over.
It ain't pretty.
CBC, Chem-7, tox
screen, glucose,
non-contrast head CT.
Ma'am, do you know your name?
June. June.
June? June what?
Uh... Allyson. Allyson?
June Allyson? That's your name?
So do you know your real name?
Uh... uh...
Yes, I know my name.
It's... I do.
It's okay. Don't worry.
It's not important.
I... I... I know my
name. I know my name.
Probably Alzheimer's.
Call the police.
See if anyone's
reported her missing.
A family, a residential home.
She belongs somewhere.
She's too clean to be homeless.
I know. I know,
but, folks, if we can't
control our office supplies,
particularly paper expendables,
then Admin's gonna
come down here
and control them for us.
So please, tell your people,
no unnecessary Xeroxing, okay?
Okay?
Thank you. Next item.
Replacing Marty Cannon
as an Attending in the ER.
He's done a great job
for us. Thank you, Marty,
but he's leaving
for greener pastures
at the University of Iowa.
Godspeed.
Godspeed. Godspeed.
As to a replacement,
Kerry Weaver has everyone's vote
except for Mark.
You've been dragging
your feet on this.
Have you had a chance
to kick this around?
Come to your senses?
I think Kerry's
a terrific choice.
Oh.
Well, that's great.
So you no longer have
any qualms about this?
You'll be working together
every day, week after week,
pulling on the same oar.
Teammates. Partners.
Seriously, Mark,
if you're not
excited about this,
I don't see how it
can possibly work.
I'm looking
forward to it, really.
Oh, that's great.
Just great.
Good.
Well, case closed.
Uh, parking...
What are you still doing here?
Timing seemed a little off.
You're gonna miss
your appointment.
I'll reschedule.
No, you won't.
It's a bunch of crap, anyway.
I'm fine.
No, it's not.
You need to see somebody, Shep.
I don't need to see
no shrink, okay?
The hell you don't.
You're not sleeping,
you're losing weight.
God, I'm terrified to
get in a car with you.
I'm afraid if someone
cuts you off at the light,
you're gonna get out
and beat them to
death with a tire iron.
You're starting to
sound like Riley.
He's right.
What?
I lied for you to
that investigator guy.
You didn't lie for me.
Yeah, I did, and I'm
not gonna do it anymore.
No, you didn't lie for me,
and I'm not seeing a shrink.
Shep, you need help!
If you don't get it,
something awful's gonna happen!
Know what I need?
I need for everyone
to stop pushing at
me and pushing at me,
and telling me what to do.
I just need a little time, okay?
I mean, is that okay?!
Is that okay with you and
the whole city of Chicago?
Shep...
It's only because I
care about you. Shep!
Everybody's gonna be there...
My folks, both sets
of grandparents.
My sister flew in from Paris.
My godparents,
my aunts, my uncles
a whole bunch of my cousins,
Jeffrey, Jody, Rob,
Sarah, David, Keith,
Barry, Margaret, Susan...
Carter, Carter, okay, look,
I don't need a
whole family tree.
I get the picture, okay?
So I was hoping
that you were
maybe going to come.
What?
It's at 4:00,
and I was thinking
you could stop by
and meet everybody.
Carter, I didn't even go
to my own graduation.
Really?
Really.
They've heard a
awful lot about you.
Yeah. All good, right?
Absolutely.
Nothing but the best.
The very very best.
So if you can't
make the graduation,
my dad's throwing a
cocktail party for me
at 6:00 at the Drake.
Good food, great wine.
It's gonna be a bunch
of my mom and
dad's stuffy friends
from the club,
but the mayor's
supposed to come by, so...
Carter, you've got
your Residency.
I've turned in the
end-of-the-year evaluation.
Just relax.
You don't have to keep trying
to brown-nose me, okay?
I wasn't trying to
brown-nose you.
Well... I appreciate
your invitation,
but I'm not going
to your graduation,
and I'm not going to
some cocktail party
that daddy's
throwing at the Drake.
Look, Carter, you were
my assigned med student.
I was your assigned Resident.
You don't owe me anything, okay?
All right, what do we got?
Morning, Carol.
What's good about it?
Kerry, you got it.
Really? The Attending's job?
Yeah.
Oh, that's great.
Wh... When do I start?
Uh, I don't know.
I guess after Marty
Cannon leaves next month.
Is the salary fixed
or negotiable?
Uh, fixed, I guess. I
didn't negotiate mine.
There's usually a
little wiggle room.
Right, well, you'd
have to discuss that
with Morgenstern.
What about benefits?
Pension plan
through the hospital,
or can you set up your own 401k?
Uh, hospital, I
guess. I never asked.
You know, this is very exciting.
We'll finally be
able to facilitate
some real change around here.
Have you read "Managing
Through Example...
12 steps to a more
efficient workplace?"
No. I haven't.
I'll loan you my copy.
I've highlighted a
number of passages.
I hope you don't find
that too distracting.
I'm sure I won't.
Mark, paramedics
are four minutes out.
Male infant,
respiratory distress.
Kerry...
I do have your support
for Susan Lewis as chief, right?
Susan Lewis?
You know, Linda Martin
would be awfully good, too.
Kerry, we had a deal here.
Mark. I'm kidding.
Where's your sense of humor?
Ah, you wouldn't?
She isn't?
What are we talking about?
Weaver's the new Attending.
Oh, my God.
Guys, don't look
at me like that.
She's a good physician,
a terrific administrator,
and an excellent diagnostician.
It was the right choice.
I'm glad I made
it, and that's it.
Oh, man, it's gonna
be a long year.
It's forever.
Two-day-old male infant,
full-term vaginal delivery
found cyanotic in his crib.
Resps 50, heart rate 160.
When was he born?
Tuesday night.
Heel stick a glucose?
You bet.
When did he come
back from the hospital?
Yesterday morning.
Twelve hours later?
They said it was okay.
We wanted to stay longer.
He's in heart failure.
Where's Ross?
I'll find him.
I'm gonna put in
an umbilical line.
Prep 0.1 Dig.
Pulse ox 86.
Sinus tach at 150.
What's wrong with him?
His lungs are filled with fluid.
Conni, could you
please show them
to the waiting room.
No, I want to stay.
Come on, honey.
Dig 0.1. Lasix?
Yeah, four mgs.
ABG, CBC, Chem-7,
chest x-ray, and an EKG.
Temp's 98.2, glucose 110.
Paged Ross.
Somebody sent a
mother and a child home
after one night.
Yeah. Welcome to managed care.
Who gives a damn
what the insurance
company wants?
What kind of a hospital
sends a newborn home
after only one night?
Our kind.
Joseph Morgan Randall.
Delivered on the fifth
floor in OB two days ago.
Chuny, could you
do me a favor? What?
I need you to draw some blood.
I'm kind of busy right now.
You can't do it yourself?
I need you to draw
some of my blood.
Al?
Yeah. I've been putting it off.
Sure. Do you want
me to do it right now?
If you don't mind.
Nobody's in 4.
Yeah.
Dr. Davitch?
I'm John Carter.
I'm a med student.
I met you once last year.
I'm on rounds, Mr. Carter.
Yeah, I can see that.
Talia Lucas, the little
girl with biliary atresia.
I've sort of been
keeping an eye on her,
and you moved her
up here last night.
Yes, I did.
I thought she was
Dr. Berglass' patient?
He's attending his
daughter's wedding
in London.
I'm covering for him.
Her ascending
cholangitis worsened?
She's not responding
to the antibiotics.
I'm worried about pseudomonas,
so I moved her up to the ICU,
and I jumped her to Status 1
on the transplant list.
Do you know her parents?
Yeah.
They're in the waiting room.
Why don't you join me.
They don't know yet?
It's been a busy
morning, Mr. Carter.
Hey, everybody. Miss me?
Oh, a little one.
Two days. Cyanotic in the crib.
No detectable murmur, CHF.
He's had Dig and Lasix
with no improvement.
Pulse is up to 200.
Mother gave birth Tuesday night.
OB kicked her out
Wednesday morning.
Get an EKG?
Right axis deviation.
RAH, RVH, no Q-wave in V6.
Okay, hyperventilate him.
Get an amp of Prostin
VR down here now, please.
What the hell is it?
Hypoplastic left heart syndrome.
They sent the mom
home the next morning?
Yep. Wham, bam,
thank you, ma'am.
Damn it. All right,
let's get an echo.
Find out who's on call for
Pediatric Cardiology, please.
Is he gonna make it?
If we can keep the
ductus arteriosus open,
he's got a shot.
Son of a bitch.
Mr. and Mrs. Lucas?
Hi. I'm Dr. Davitch.
Dr. Berglass is
out of the country
for a few days.
You already know
Mr. Carter, I believe.
Jason, Annette.
They told us downstairs
T.C.'d been moved
to Intensive Care.
Well, unfortunately,
your daughter's condition
has worsened overnight.
She's not responding
to the antibiotics.
I don't have much confidence
that your daughter's liver's
gonna function much longer.
So we have moved
her from Status 2
to Status 1 on
the transplant list...
And we're gonna do
everything we can for her
while we wait.
So she'll be having the
transplant operation soon?
Well, that would
certainly be our hope.
How soon?
Mr. Carter, you're familiar
with the UNIS procedures,
aren't you?
Yeah, sure.
Mr. Carter will
answer your questions,
and then he'll take you back
to see your daughter, okay?
Why don't we take a seat?
D.A.'s open, so he's
still got a fighting chance.
I'm going to go
tell his parents.
This is unbelievable.
Now, there is an ugly,
vicious rumor going around.
Kerry Weaver...
Don't start with me.
So it's true.
I don't know what
everybody's upset about.
Kerry Weaver's not that bad.
She's great.
She grows on you.
You been hitting
the Prozac again?
I got a call
from a pharmacy
on the North Side
looking for you.
Mm-hmm.
You wrote a prescription
for 100 Percodan?
What?
Karen Hines.
Isn't that that redhead
you've been seeing.
Yeah, she's got a bad knee.
A hundred? Pretty bad knee.
She travels a lot.
Doesn't know when
she'll be able to get them.
Mark, I need you
in there. Rule out MI.
You tell them it was okay?
Yeah, but I told
them you'd call.
Yeah.
Hey, Jeanie...
Hi.
How'd your appointment go?
They gave me a
bunch of stuff to read.
You should read it.
Uh, thanks for
staying last night.
Well, it's tough, that first
night home from the hospital.
My health plan gave me...
assigned me a doctor,
specializes in the disease...
A Dr. Arabian. You know him?
No, I can ask around.
Thanks.
He said that my...
my CD4 count is 450.
He sounded excited about that.
Yeah, that's good.
What's it supposed to be?
Fifteen hundred.
He gave me a... a lot of stuff.
Uh, AZT, something
called 3TC, and... Sacinaver...
Saquinavir.
Whatever. It's
gonna cost a fortune,
and, uh...
he gave me...
a couple of packets
of condoms too.
Kind of seems like
the horse is out of
the barn on that one.
It was a joke.
It wasn't funny.
You get tested yet?
Yeah.
And? Not back yet.
Doctor said I may
have been HIV positive
for as long as 10 years.
He wants me to make a list
of all my...
past sexual contacts.
Let them know.
It's gonna be quite a list.
It's not much to
be proud of now.
Wasn't much to be proud of then.
Well, I... I better go home.
I've got a lot of reading to do.
If that baby'd
stayed in the hospital
an extra day,
somebody would
have picked up on it.
Most babies are fine
going home the next day.
Well, a lot of problems
don't declare
themselves right away.
Intussusception,
pyloric stenosis.
People trust us.
The woman took her baby home
because we told her it
was safe, and it wasn't.
It's not a bottomless pit.
Every dollar we spend
on a perfectly healthy
postpartum mother
is another dollar we don't
have to help someone else.
♪ June is bustin'
out All over! ♪
♪ All over the
meadow And the hill ♪
♪ Buds are bustin'
Outta bushes... ♪
There's something
you don't see every day.
♪ Every little wheel That
wheels beside a mill ♪
♪ June is bustin' out... ♪
I thought she was in restraints.
She was.
Malik... can you give me a hand.
Do I have to?
♪ Now the young
Virginia creepers ♪
♪ Have been huggin'
The bejeepers out of all... ♪
Hold that elevator!
Dr. Benton.
Dr. Vucelich.
Congratulations on being named
Resident of the Year.
Thank you.
I understand
you were instrumental
in my selection.
I merely expressed my opinion.
I'm glad that others concurred.
I read your aortic
aneurism study.
Yes. Well, it's been
extremely well-received.
The drug company's pleased.
They granted the
hospital over $3 million
for phase-four trials,
additional research facilities.
You know, I, uh...
I couldn't help but
notice the inclusion
of the negative outcome patients
that we had discussed.
Mm-hmm.
It seemed the prudent course,
given the circumstances.
They weren't, however,
statistically significant
in the final analysis.
Well, I was glad to
see them there, anyway.
Yes, I'm sure you were.
Mm, Carter.
Ooh, Armani?
Hugo Boss.
Nice. Um...
The parents of that
kid with the liver failure
called down.
Said they had some questions.
Some more questions, you mean.
I spent an hour with
them this morning.
I'm supposed to meet my
folks at Trotters for lunch
in 20 minutes.
They called three times?
Five. I quit writing it down.
Okay, well, if they call again,
will you tell them
I'll be up there later.
My father hates
it when I'm late.
Mr. Carter, you got a minute?
I'm completing the assignments
for the first-year
surgical interns.
We're breaking all
the surgical residents
into teams next year.
Now, you indicated
on your application form
that you're
interested in Vascular,
Neurosurgery, and
Plastics rotation?
Absolutely.
Good. Good.
I've got one spot
left on the red team.
Really?
It will be primarily second
and third-year residents,
but seeing as you're our only
locally grown prodigy,
we'd give you the
home field advantage.
That would be great.
It'll be quite a leg
up on your peers.
Oh, I'd be honored.
Dr. Langdon will be
your supervising resident.
Do you know Nancy?
Oh, sure. Yeah, she's great.
So I won't be working
under Dr. Benton anymore?
Nope.
Dr. Benton will be
anchoring the blue team
next year.
General surgery,
the ER, proctology,
real meat-and-potatoes stuff.
Unless you'd rather
be with Benton.
No, no. I was hoping
for the red team.
Good. Excellent.
Dr. Morgenstern.
Peter...
Weaver's gonna
support you as chief.
Really? We should
talk about that.
Uh, Dr. Greene,
your wife called.
Ex-wife.
Right. She said
you're late for lunch.
She's mad as hell.
With Weaver on
board, I think it's a lock.
So do you want to
have dinner tonight
and celebrate.
I don't know.
Check with me later.
Mr. Brannigan?
Kenny, please.
Hi. I'm Dr. Lewis.
Sorry to have kept you waiting.
Yeah. Well, at least
she stopped singing.
So you've had a
persistent cough?
Couple of months now.
I haven't been able to shake it.
Coughing up any blood?
No, no... well, not much.
But some. Yeah, once or twice,
but it's no big deal.
I pour concrete for a living,
so stuff gets in your lungs.
Are you a smoker, Kenny?
Yeah.
You're not gonna lecture me?
Doesn't sound like I have to.
So how much do you smoke?
A couple of packs a day.
Sometimes more, sometimes less.
120/80.
When was the last time
you had a tuberculosis test?
I don't go to doctors much.
Ah. All that lecturing,
I guess, huh?
Sorry I'm late.
Like old times.
Nice to see you, too.
Look, if this is about
getting Rachel this weekend,
you can forget it, okay,
because I got
tickets for the Cubbies
on Saturday.
Rachel hates baseball.
That's not true.
This weekend's fine,
Mark. That's... that's fine.
You gonna finish those fries?
Go right ahead.
I can't eat this food.
This place should
have been cited
and shut down by the
health department years ago.
Hospital fights to keep it open.
It's good for business.
Food poisoning, stomach pumping,
gastroenteritis.
This joint's a gold mine.
Craig and I are getting married.
What?
In September.
You're kidding.
I didn't want you to
hear it from Rachel.
Rachel knows?
She's excited.
She's helping me
pick out a dress.
Something non-traditional,
I hope. Perhaps in red.
Look, I knew you weren't
gonna be happy about this,
but I thought I should
be the one to tell you.
You should have kept the goatee.
It made you look dangerous.
Hey!
Hey, yourself!
School let out early?
Well, I was on all night.
It looks like
you're still gainfully employed.
Well, I'm on probation.
I lose another 250 grand,
it's back to
card-counting in Vegas.
Really? You did that?
In a previous lifetime.
Yeah. Don't ask.
So how's your knee?
It's, uh, okay.
How's yours?
The prescription
that I wrote out
for the Percodan?
Yeah?
Was for 10 tablets.
You know, I wondered about that.
Those damn things
cost me a fortune.
So you didn't change it to 100?
No, I didn't.
Prescription pads for
narcotics, they come in triplicate.
I can check my copy.
Well, maybe you should do that.
Maybe I should.
Count them, boyfriend.
They're all there.
I don't need to count them.
Sure, you do.
Mr. Brannigan,
sorry it took so long.
Do you have a
personal physician?
No.
You have a density
in your left lung.
Tuberculosis?
I don't think so.
Cancer.
We'll need to run more tests
to rule that out.
How much are these
tests of yours gonna cost?
Do you have insurance?
No. I work construction
for a lot of different
companies.
No benefits.
Maybe you qualify for Medicaid?
When my last kid
was born, we didn't.
It cost me, uh, a
couple of grand.
I'm still trying
to pay that off.
Well, I can't tell you exactly
how much the tests will cost.
We could get someone
down from Admitting
if you have any questions.
I, uh, got a couple of kids
and a mortgage,
and I'm just scraping
by as it is, huh?
You have a potentially
serious condition
for which you need
immediate evaluation.
Mr. Brannigan, you
really need to stay here.
Mark, Loretta's back.
Oh, no. What this time?
Oh, I think she's just
frightened and overwhelmed
by the surgery.
They only released
her yesterday.
I started an IV. She's in 4.
Well, tell her I'll be down
there as soon as I can,
and make sure that
she's comfortable.
So we're just going
to let him leave?
Well, what do you want
to do, tackle the guy?
He said he can't afford it.
Who am I to say that he can?
A full course of chemotherapy
and radiation'll cost
him minimum 50 grand.
I don't understand what
we're arguing about.
You let the hospital bill him.
He can declare
bankruptcy if he has to.
And if he dies and leaves
his wife and children
in bankruptcy?
At least he wouldn't be dead.
I advised him to stay,
he chose to leave.
That's his prerogative.
What are you doing out here?
Oh, just enjoying the fresh air
and the sunshine.
The last few months,
whenever I can,
I like to get outside.
It's about time
you gave those up.
My last vice.
So they sent you home yesterday.
Yeah. I don't think I was ready.
You been able to eat anything?
I haven't been able
to keep anything down.
How are the kids?
Hell on wheels.
I wanted to ask you something.
Shoot.
I was wondering if
you'd be guardian to my kids.
Not that anything bad's
ever gonna happen to me.
It's just that they
don't have anybody.
My folks are dead.
They like you.
I know it's a lot to ask,
but they're really good kids.
What about their father?
Fathers. Plural.
Good luck.
I never could quite
figure that one out.
You don't have to answer now.
I have time...
at least, a little bit, I think.
I'm honored you'd ask...
But you can't.
No.
I can't.
I'm sorry.
Besides, you're gonna make it.
Damn right, I am.
Hey, you're up. How you feeling?
Kind of tired.
Where are your folks?
They were looking
for me earlier.
They went downstairs
to get something to eat.
In the cafeteria? Big mistake.
My mom just kept crying.
I think my dad was worried
she was gonna scare me.
Well, tell them
that I stopped by.
I gotta go.
I'm graduating in a half
an hour, and I'm late.
Everybody in here
looks pretty sick.
Yeah, well...
they get better.
It just takes time.
The boy who was in that bed?
I don't think he got better.
Am I gonna die?
You're very sick, T.C..
My mom says I'm Status 1.
What does that mean?
That means that as soon
as the next liver's available,
you get first dibs.
Somebody has to die, right?
Yeah.
Kind of weird.
Some kid's out there,
and they're okay,
and I'm here
waiting for something
bad to happen to them.
You're not making
that bad thing happen.
I gotta go.
I'll see you later.
How long till I
have an operation?
Could be a week, could be two,
could be less.
Could be anytime.
But what if nothing bad
happens to anybody this week?
It will.
Unfortunately,
something bad is always
happening to somebody...
somewhere.
Like what's
happening to me, right?
Want me to stay
for a little while
till your folks come back?
Yeah, that'd be
great, if it's okay.
Sure. I can be a
couple minutes late.
Oh, man, this day just
gets worse and worse.
Hey, Mark, Linda Martin?
What was she, the only choice?
I think she's kind of a bitch.
For what?
Chief Resident.
She is kind of a bitch.
Look, Linda Martin's not
going to be chief Resident,
so don't worry about it.
She is going to be chief.
It's on the memo.
Damn it.
Jerry, where the hell is Weaver?
Uh, Trauma 1.
You said you were going
to support Susan for chief?
Julius Cadena, meet Mark Greene.
Mr. Cadena's small intestine
seems to be eviscerated.
IV's wide open.
We had a deal.
Rapid infuse four
units of O-neg.
I offered it to her,
she turned it down.
She what?
Ask her yourself.
Gram of cefoxitin IV.
Alert the O.R.,
page Benton to get down here...
Hey, Peter.
Hey...
Got a minute?
Sure.
Al's got AIDS.
I...
Conni, give us a
moment, will you?
I'm just after some coffee.
Yeah, I'll bring you a cup
in a few minutes, all right?
Sure.
Cream, no sugar.
I got tested today, but
I don't have the results.
I know what you're thinking,
because I was where you
are now a few days ago.
You want to feel
concerned for me,
but you're wondering,
"What about me?"
Al and I barely had sex,
much less a marriage
these last few years.
You and I were careful,
but not that careful.
Get tested. I'm sorry.
12-year-old girl hit by a bus
while riding her bicycle.
Pain in the left ankle.
Obvious deformed fracture.
Good distal pulses.
No head or chest pain.
She was wearing a helmet.
Gently now.
IV, saline, TKO,
0.25 liters cannula.
Three milligrams
morphine in the field.
Name's Monique.
It hurts!
I know it does. I
know it does, honey.
Now, does your neck hurt?
No!
Any tenderness?
No! No, just my leg!
You were wearing
your helmet, Monique.
That's really good.
Monique, do your
parents know you're here?
No.
Well, if you give me
your phone number,
I can call them,
so they can come down
and be with you, okay?
Good dorsalis pedis
and posterior tibial pulses.
BP's 90 over 60.
Pulse ox 99.
Let's get an ice pack, an H & H,
and dip a urine for blood.
My sister's gonna
be so mad at me.
I bet she's just gonna
be happy that you're okay.
No!
Sure she will, sweetheart.
Let's get a left ankle
and tib-fib films,
and give her another three
of morphine for the pain.
Dr. Randa Jane Berkowitz.
Dr. John Truman Carter.
Dr. Carter?
Well...
I think Dr. Carter must
have found a facial laceration
to practice a z-plasty on.
Dr. Ming Wu Chang.
Two, three, flip.
You taking them off the top?
Yes, I am.
Go.
Okay, one more
time. Two out of three.
You've already lost five times.
Yeah, but I'm getting better.
She always wins.
Thanks for staying with her.
How's she doing?
I'm okay.
Yeah, she's hanging in there.
I hope you didn't
have to be anywhere.
Nope. Not anymore.
I'm gonna go,
and then I'm gonna come back,
make sure you're not
getting into too much trouble.
Thanks.
Hi, sweetheart.
Comminuted
trimalleolar ankle fracture.
What a mess.
Definitely unstable.
Yeah. Gonna need surgery.
Are her parents here yet?
In the waiting room.
Monique was right
about her sister.
She was mad about her bike.
So splint her leg,
and I'll call an
ambulance to move her.
Mover her? Move her where?
Her insurance company
wants her transferred
to Midway
for orthopedic admission.
I can't apply a plaster splint
without moving the ankle.
It's gonna hurt like hell!
We'll medicate her.
Do her parents know about this?
I'm going to tell them now.
Mark, we're gonna splint
an unstable ankle fracture,
send a 12-year-old
girl across town
for an operation
we can do upstairs?
Look, I don't like this,
any more than you do,
but that's what her
insurance wants done.
I thought you were the doctor.
I am the doctor,
but if I admit her here,
her very nice parents
are gonna get slapped
with a surgical bill
for tens of
thousands of dollars.
I quit.
What?
I quit!
You can't just leave.
Watch me.
We sent a newborn home
with a congenital heart problem.
A guy comes in with lung cancer
and he can't afford
the treatment,
and now, we're
shipping kids across town
with unstable fractures.
Don't give me that
holier-than-thou crap.
We also treated a couple
hundred other people
who had nowhere else to go.
You're gonna feel
stupid about this
in the morning.
I'm gonna feel great
about this in the morning.
You okay, Dr. Benton?
Yeah. Yeah, I'm fine.
Have you seen Dr. Morgenstern?
He left a message for me
saying he wanted to talk to me.
He started a ruptured appendix
about a half hour ago.
Well, I'll catch up
to him tomorrow.
Hey, how was
your cocktail party?
I missed it.
You missed your own party?
Yeah.
My parents had a
good time, anyway.
It was mostly their friends.
I missed my graduation too.
Oh, really?
Yeah. You missed yours, right?
What were you doing?
An emergency hemorrhoidectomy.
I was playing cards
with a scared little kid.
T.C., that little girl
with liver failure.
They moved her up to Status 1.
I was just keeping her company
while her folks
talked to the doctor.
Now you're the doctor.
You graduated, right?
Yeah... that's right, I am.
It's kind of weird.
I, uh...
I don't know any more
than I knew this morning.
I really wanted to graduate too.
Oh, well.
Anyway...
Take care of yourself, Carter.
Right.
Hey...
Hey, yourself.
Carol Hathaway just quit.
I know. I heard.
What was that all about?
You got me.
You turned down chief?
Yes, I did.
I agreed to support
Kerry Weaver as Attending
because she agreed
to support you as chief.
I didn't ask you to do that.
No, you didn't.
You know, my whole life,
I've always done what
everyone else wanted me to do.
Today, I had this guy
come in with a cough.
Lung cancer, 46 years old.
I get one of these cases
every couple of months.
Children, husbands, wives,
their faces all start to
blend together, but it hit me...
How long do we have?
Any of us?
And how are we
gonna fill that time?
I had something. Little Susie.
And now I don't.
All I have is this.
Work.
You know what, Mark?
It's not enough.
What are you doing here?
Waiting for you.
You don't have your keys?
Why are you still
wearing your scrubs?
I quit.
You're kidding.
Nah, to hell with them.
You can't quit.
You're great at it.
I'm sick of it.
They kept cutting
back my shifts,
making me work more nights.
I'll make more doing
home care or per diem.
You're never gonna
see that shrink, are you?
Ugh...
Why couldn't we just keep
going the way we were?
I was happy.
Weren't you happy?
Things changed.
It's not my fault.
It's not your fault.
Raul died. It a terrible thing,
but something
happened to you, Shep.
You know it's true.
Man, you gotta deal with it.
I'm doing okay.
No, you're not.
I can't do this, Shep.
I have finally gotten
my life together.
It's taken me a long time.
You need help.
I love you, but you need help,
and if you can't get it
together to get that help...
I can't be with you.
I can't.
Jennifer's getting
married again.
Really? That was quick.
No kidding.
I was hoping to be the first one
to get remarried
or at least living
with somebody.
I mean, it makes me
seem kind of pathetic,
don't you think?
She's planning a guest list,
and I'm still fumbling around
with pick-up lines
in singles bars.
It gets you off the hook
with the alimony, though.
I wasn't paying any.
She makes more money than I do.
You know, I never
really liked her.
What do you mean?
You acted like you did.
I just did that to
make you feel better.
I never cared for her.
Unsupportive, controlling
and manipulative...
Do you want me
to go on with this?
Yeah, please. I'm enjoying it.
All right, demanding,
skinny legs...
Wait, what were you doing
looking at my wife's legs?
I'm your buddy, I'm not dead.
I'm just saying you
could do better...
much better.
Thanks. Thank you.
All right, listen to this,
I talked to Karen
about the Percodan.
You didn't prescribe that many?
The prescription was for 10.
What did she say?
She denied it.
She said that it was
some kind of a mix-up,
and she gave them back to me...
Actually, she threw
them back at me.
Yeah? Do you believe her?
I don't know.
Get away from her, Doug.
She sounds like trouble.
Yeah, I know. You're right.
I probably should.
But you're not going to?
She's kind of cute.
She's got great legs.
You were looking at
my girlfriend's legs?
Look, I'm your
friend, I'm not dead.
So what else did
you notice about her?
You want a list?
Yeah. I want a list.
Dr. Morgenstern,
you were looking for me?
Yeah, we missed
you at graduation.
Where were you?
With a patient.
How was the ceremony?
Oh, one of the best
we've had in years.
Pomp, circumstance,
all the trimmings.
If you'll excuse
me, it's very late,
and I'm finally on my way home.
Hey, I was wondering
if it's too late
to change my choice for
Surgical team next year.
I was hoping to sign
up for the blue team.
Once you switch your selection,
there's no going back.
Yes, sir, I know.
I was... still hoping
for the blue team.
I'm sure Dr. Benton
will be very pleased
to have you on his team.
See you in a few months.
Right. Thanks.
Hey, Carter...
Dr. Benton left something
down here for you.
Hey, Carter, what
do you call the person
who graduates
last in their class
from medical school?
What?
Doctor.
Hey, what are you
still doing here?
Oh, just hanging out.
Well, want to try out
that new white coat?
MVA, drunk driver
hit a carload of kids
on the way to the prom.
The units are just pulling in.
Sure.
17-year-old male, head trauma
GCS eight, BP 120
over 60, pulse 60,
probable fractures
of the left femur,
right tib-fib.
Dr. Carter!
Okay, Trauma 2. Notify the O.R.,
and see who's on call for Ortho.
Dr. Carter?
We've got three
more on the scene.
Guy in a pickup
came up the off-ramp
on the Kennedy.
Clipped four cars before
he t-boned the prom kids...