There's a thing we say
when someone dies.
We say it to the
patient's family.
There are on-call
rooms for that.
We say, "I'm
sorry for your loss."
With type II, we're dealing
with low birth weight,
underdeveloped lungs,
swallowing problems,
respiratory problems.
If carried to term, type
II infants typically die
within a few hours of
delivery, sometimes days.
Your baby's also at high
risk for intrauterine fracturing.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. Um...
Did you say intrauterine?
Yes.
My baby's bones are
breaking inside of my belly?
The place he's supposed to
be safe, his bones are breaking.
No, I just...
Um, can he feel it?
His bones breaking?
I mean, he can feel it, right?
So, he's in... He's in pain.
Again, I am so sorry.
It's a pat little phrase,
and an empty one.
It doesn't begin to cover what's
actually happening to them.
Clear.
It lets us empathize
without forcing us
to feel their
devastation ourselves.
It protects us...
Time of death...
from feeling that pain.
That dark, sinking,
relentless pain,
the kind that can eat you alive.
And every day, I
thank God for that.
I thought they went home.
They wanted to talk some more.
I'm not sure it helped.
Why didn't you call me?
I mean, I can help them.
They need someone who knows
them and who cares about them
and who can make it...
Who can make it what?
Nice.
I want to make it as
nice for them as it can be.
And you're not nice.
You really care
about them, don't you?
Yeah, I do. They're my friends.
And that right there is why you
have no business in that room.
There's only one set of feelings
that matters here,
and it's not yours.
I don't know what's gonna
help them, but it isn't you.
April Kepner is no longer
your patient. Excuse me.
There's no way,
no way for me to do
what I need to do...
April.
And what I believe
that I should do.
Shh, shh, shh.
There is a way, sweetheart.
There's always a way.
Now, here's what we'll do.
You will choose a day. Soon.
Set it aside and
arrange to be induced.
And you'll give birth to
your beautiful little boy.
And you'll give him a name
and have him baptized
right then and there.
Then you're gonna
get to hold that baby.
And you'll pray for
him and sing to him.
You're gonna look at him.
You're gonna look at him
and memorize every
little detail of his face.
And you will do that
as long as he lives.
You will do that
until God takes him.
That's how you will do this.
We can do that.
Can you do that for me?
Of course I'll do that for you.
I'll do that for you
and him and us.
Okay. Okay?
Okay.
So, I'll just...
I'll just hold him
until God takes him.
That sounds lovely.
Maybe God won't take him.
Maybe there will be a miracle.
Okay.
I'll just pray for a miracle.
Okay. Okay.
Lord... Bailey!
Grey! What?
Sorry. I have a favor to ask.
I'm on call this
weekend. Can you take it?
Why? What do you need to do?
I want to go see Derek.
I don't really want to
talk about it in here.
No, I can't.
Little Tuck is with his father,
and Ben and I have the
weekend to ourselves.
Which is exactly why I'm asking.
Then you know exactly
why I'm saying no.
Huh!
Lord...
Oh, well, crap.
You know what I was gonna say.
Somebody get me an OR, please?
Move beds three and
four to the burn center.
Coming through!
It's a mess in here.
Yeah, Kepner's out. Things
don't run right without her.
We have a GSW in five.
Bailey, can you take that?
Yeah, but how are
they? Kepner and Avery?
No word.
I'm admitting that
femur break in bed six.
Bed five needs a RT consult.
Okay, hold on. Hold on. Uh...
Okay, where's Kepner?
I can just tell her.
Uh, she and Avery are out today.
Oh, God, today?
Okay, what are we
gonna do for them?
Flowers? No, that's weird.
Yeah, no, what else
can we do for them?
Do for who? BOTH:
Kepner and Avery.
Oh, God, what do
you do? Flowers?
Vetoed. Food?
Who cooks?
Nobody cooks. Oh, Kepner cooks.
We could do a fruit basket?
Oh, stop.
We could all sign a card.
Okay, I'm stopping.
I lit a candle in the chapel.
It made me feel better.
You can all just, um,
give them privacy.
That's all they're gonna want.
Uh, Shepherd.
Uh, you said you wanted to go
over Dr. Herman's tumor plan.
You want to get lunch?
Oh, uh...
I can't. I got to push it.
Drew Hawkins,
in for a surgical resection
of a butterfly glioma.
Can you see the
light even a little?
Nope. It's just black.
Total blindness now
for about a month.
But I can still smell.
What is that, lilac perfume?
Lavender shampoo.
And why has Drew gone blind?
The blindness in both eyes
is caused by a lesion
in the optic radiation.
Nailed it, Dr. Lavender.
Oh, can we show her the trick?
Sure.
Catch! Oh, wow!
Pretty fly for a
blind guy, right?
How?
Drew has cortical blindness.
His eyes still see,
but only the subconscious part
of his brain receives the signals.
Your subconscious saw the pen.
Once I decompress the tumor,
I may be able to free
up the visual cortex,
possibly restoring your sight.
And maybe I'll see again?
Drew, we talked about this.
I am gonna try
for total resection,
but at the very least,
I will buy you time.
I know, I know, but
there's a chance?
There's a chance.
What do you have for me?
Brenda Bonaman, 44. Isolated
shotgun wound to the neck.
She has right shoulder dislocation
status post mechanical fall.
Who shot her? My husband.
Your husband?
Not like that! Not on purpose!
It was an accident.
Was it, Howard?
Was it an accident?
Did you confuse me with a moose?
Brenda, if I wanted to shoot
you, I'd have done it in the woods,
you'd still be out there.
Okay, let's calm it down.
Let's get her to trauma one now.
Shoulder dislocation.
The acromion's fractured.
I'm gonna need to do a
reduction under anesthesia.
Might as well wait. She's
got a zone two injury.
Wounds from the
cricoid to the mandible.
She's got to go
straight to the OR.
Oh, God. Brenda, I'm sorry.
Howard, shut up.
And, uh, why were we pointing
a shotgun at our wife today?
I was putting it away, and...
We had just come
back from duck hunting.
Duck hunting, his big
idea of an adventure.
It was fun! You had...
I wanted to go to Belize.
Well, it rains in Belize, too.
I don't get shot in Belize!
Brenda, what's hurting?
Everything hurts!
Doctor, here's the x-ray. Okay.
Okay, yeah, it's this pellet. It's
close to the major blood vessels.
And we'll know for sure
once we open her
up. Come on, let's go.
Oh, God! Howard.
Baby. Brenda, honey,
I'm here. I'm sorry.
All right, we got to go. Sir,
could you move, please?
Warren, follow up on her labs.
And have them rushed quick.
I need them upstairs.
Is she... What is
happening to her?
Listen, you can wait
right over there, okay?
And listen, as soon as we know
something, we'll come get you.
We are gonna take
very good care of her.
All right.
Um, what do I do with this?
Uh, that's a patient's
personals release.
But, uh, you
take it to the clerk.
But first, take
these up to the lab.
Tell them to rush
the results. You got it?
What time did you
come to bed last night?
I didn't until this morning.
Ugh. My palms are so sweaty.
Hi.
So, I just need a few
signatures before we begin.
Um, so, what exactly
happens after this?
How do we get started?
Well, uh, after we're done
here, I will take you to your room.
I'll give you the medication
that starts dilation,
then the Pitocin.
And your body will know
what to do from there.
So, this is for the
birth certificate.
Have you decided on a name?
Uh, we are still
working on that.
We're... Yeah.
Okay, you can just sign now
and we'll fill in the rest later.
Uh, these are the consent forms.
I think we signed
those. Not these.
Uh, what we're doing today
is an induction termination.
You're at 24 weeks,
so, technically,
we could intervene to keep
the baby alive after the delivery.
And these are just forms to
make it official that you don't.
I need both signatures.
What are those other forms?
Uh...
These are, um, for
the death certificate.
Really?
Can we not yet?
It's better to get all of the
paperwork out of the way,
and then you never have
to worry about it again.
Do you need a
minute? Yes, please.
All I wanted was to
start a family with you.
Oh, I know. I know.
This isn't fair.
None of this is fair.
You're right. I know.
I don't care what she
says. I'm not signing these.
I didn't even know
this place was here.
Shh.
Okay, let's go.
I found it first. Their
baby's problem.
I know, but that isn't...
I wished horrible
things for them, Jo.
Jackson left me for her,
and I wished them misery
and fights and breakups.
I mean, I'd see them sitting
together in the cafeteria,
and I'd wish them
food poisoning.
Then I found this.
You would never
have wished them this.
You know that.
If you hadn't have found it,
somebody else would have.
It wouldn't have
changed anything.
It's not on you.
If anything, it just means
that you're a good doctor.
Okay.
I'm gonna go make
a blind man see.
Zola's gonna push
for cookies after dinner.
Don't fall for it.
And Bailey's blanket
is in the dryer.
Yeah, why don't
you tell this to Jo?
She's gonna be doing it. What?
You offered. I
didn't offer. Jo did.
I'm on call all weekend.
What's going on?
I can't leave my kids with
Wilson. Wilson is a hoodlum.
I leave my kids with my person.
Cristina did it all the time.
Cristina Yang
watched your kids? Yes.
I don't buy that for a second.
Talk to Jo.
No Jo!
She asked you to watch her kids?
Yeah, she's wigging out about
trying to go to DC to see Derek.
Why didn't she ask
me? I'm a person.
That's not what she meant. What?
And you don't
want to be, trust me.
It's a pain in the ass.
All right, let's
get her prepped.
We need to put her under.
It hurts. It hurts!
Okay, we know, but we're
gonna put you to sleep,
and then we can
attend to that shoulder.
No, no, my stomach!
Uh, hold the anesthesia. She's
complaining of abdominal pain.
I'm here. Where do you need me?
Uh, can you bring
the ultrasound?
All right, I don't see any wounds
in her torso or her legs or...
Uh, Bailey? I don't think
you'll need that ultrasound.
Come here and tell me if I am
seeing what I think I'm seeing.
Oh, my goodness.
What? What's going on?
Uh, let's page OB! - Okay, okay.
Brenda, how far along are you?
What? I don't know...
Why didn't you tell us
that you were pregnant?
Because I'm not!
That's impossible.
Tell them to get here fast!
Yes, Doctor. Bring
me the stirrups.
No, I'm not pregnant!
I can't get pregnant!
I can't have a baby!
You are having one.
I'm looking at its
head right now.
Anderson?
That's a last name
as a first name.
I hate last names
as first names.
I have a last name
as a first name.
This is gonna be too big on me.
I should've brought
something from home.
Come on. I still like...
No!
I'm sorry.
I know he's your favorite uncle,
but you can't name
a child Norbert.
Norbert's the kid that gets
his lunch money stolen.
He's the kid that gets
punched on the playground.
That's not gonna be our kid.
All right, ready for...
I'll come back.
Okay. I think it's time
to put on the gown.
No, it's not time. We
don't have a name yet.
We can't do this without a name.
We may only have a couple
of minutes with our son once...
I am not gonna spend that
time trying to figure out a name.
Can we just...
Just give me a minute, okay?
Just wait.
I just, I want... I just
want to wait in case...
In case what?
It happens.
Jackson, they happen, all right?
Miracles, they happen to people.
There are documented
medical cases
that cannot be
explained by science.
What if this is one of those and
we're deciding to do this today,
when if we just...
I don't even know why
I'm talking to you about this.
I'm not doing this.
I thought I could, but I can't.
I won't. April.
Where are you going?
Okay, call OB again!
Here, hold pressure.
Uh, get a baby warmer in here.
Uh, gown us, please.
How does someone
go through nine months
and not even know
she's pregnant?
It happens. How did we not know?
What happened to
those damn lab results?
I don't know! I gave them
to an intern, and I told her...
I gave them to
you, not to an intern.
So you damn well better find
out what happened to them. Now!
Who the hell left this here?
Uh, what do you need?
This kind of crap would never
happen when Kepner's here.
I'll take it up there.
So, if OB doesn't get
here, um, who's catching?
Uh, you are. Oh, I was
gonna say you were.
Uh, I fix bones.
You guys are wrong!
I'm not pregnant!
Is that another contraction?
No, my... Ow! My shoulder!
Okay, more lidocaine.
Brenda, we can't put you
under until the baby's born.
All right, someone,
uh, call peds!
I'm having a baby? I am?
Yes, you are, Brenda.
I can't have babies.
I want to, but they
told me I can't ever.
Well, they were wrong, sweetie.
You can and you
are, so get ready.
On the next contraction, I'm
gonna need you to push. Okay?
Pulse ox is dropping.
The hematoma's
compressing the trachea.
She's gonna lose her airway!
Oh, God, okay.
Okay, all right, we're
almost there, Brenda.
I want you to push for me, okay?
One, two, three, push!
That's great. That's great.
Okay, try it again.
One, two, three, push!
No! No, no, no. Don't push.
She's straining too hard.
She's dislodged the clot.
Uh, lap pads, lap pads.
Hold pressure with me here.
Bailey. Bailey, it's okay.
It's okay. You did
it, Brenda. You did it.
Brenda, you have a little girl.
Hey, you know how
this is done? Not a clue.
Hey, uh...
Did Yang ever watch
Meredith's kids?
See, I knew it.
Mer's full of crap.
I don't have to babysit
for her. No, no. She did.
Cristina would take
Zola. She'd take her home.
And then when
the diaper blew out,
she'd hold her up to me
like a bag of medical waste.
Cristina would study.
She'd eat all of Zola's snacks.
And I would be the
one down on the floor,
playing with blocks,
so yes and no.
What are you doing this weekend?
I'd do it for Cristina,
I'm not doing it for you.
Damn it.
So, his eyes still work, it's just
the communication to the brain?
But his tumor's in
the corpus callosum,
pushing into both
occipital lobes.
Right. He'll probably
never see again.
But you said...
I said we'd try.
What's this? Taking
on new cases?
You told me you were going,
"All my tumor, all the time."
Giving up on me?
On the contrary.
I'm going to use a CO2 laser
to peel a man's
glioma off layer by layer.
It's the same technique I'll
be using on your optic nerve.
It's how I'll keep you from
going blind when I save you.
Ah. And here, I thought I'd
won you over to the dark side.
Never.
Keep hope alive.
So, we're practicing on him?
On Drew for Herman?
Even though you don't
think he's gonna see again.
That's one way to look at it.
Another way is we're giving him
time, more years to live. Let's go.
Have radiology send
everything up to the OR.
Okay, put her
out. Let's intubate!
Wait, wait, can I hold her?
I'm here! Glove me. We
need to help you breathe now.
I just need to see her.
I need to hold
her. She's crying.
Where's my baby?
No, oh, no.
I'm gonna take her
and do an exam.
She'll be here when
you wake up, okay?
Let me hold my baby!
Look, if we do, she
might lose you, honey.
There's no time. Let us work.
Please...
I'm so sorry, Brenda.
Oh, she's throwing
multifocal PVCs.
What the hell!
Uh, it's...
Uh, ultrasound! Here.
Let me have those films.
Okay.
Where are you?
Oh, damn it. Where is what?
There was a pellet
at the vessels.
It should be right
there, and it isn't.
Which means it
moved into her heart.
Runs of V-tach!
Okay, uh, 75 of lido.
Let's get a repeat chest film!
Page cardio!
Brenda, no more surprises!
It was a urine sample
and two blood draws.
I gave it to an intern,
and I told her to...
I found it sitting
on a supply rack.
Which intern? I don't know.
She was about this
tall, dark-haired?
Hey, Richard. When
you find her, find me.
No, when I find her,
I'm gonna kill her.
Hi. So, I'm on
call this weekend,
and I was wondering
if you could take it.
Oh, I'm sorry. I
might have plans.
Catherine Avery's in town,
and she's going through hell.
And I'd like to
be able to tell her
I'll be available if she
needs me for anything.
Never mind. I'll
find someone else.
Is there a problem?
Uh, it's not a big deal.
We can just drop
it. Everything okay?
Yeah, it's fine. Really?
You can tell me.
I'd rather not.
You said it was important.
It's just, mmm, sex.
Emergency sex with my husband.
Should've dropped it. Told you.
April.
Let me go. Just wait.
Okay, you're right
about miracles, okay?
Sometimes they happen.
There are hearts that
start beating again.
There's cancer that just
goes away on its own.
I know. I've seen it.
It happens sometimes.
But this, April,
this is not that.
I know.
This isn't fair.
It isn't just.
And I have spent my life
believing in a God who is just.
He gave me a calling,
and I followed it.
I save lives every day.
I feel like I'm finally becoming
the person that
he wants me to be.
And then this?
To be handed this?
It's cruel.
I feel like God is
laughing at me.
If this is a test, I fail.
All those years trusting
and believing and praying...
And if this, if this were just,
even a tiny bit,
then I could maybe...
I can't. I have to
go back to work.
I have to go to work.
You're messing with me. I'm not.
You are.
I'm not.
That's your little girl.
It's a mistake.
Brenda couldn't have a
baby. She wasn't pregnant!
She was and she did.
It was your wife. Shotgun wound.
Had a baby.
No, she couldn't get pregnant!
We tried! For years!
We saw doctors. All of
them said we couldn't.
And Brenda was so sad.
And mad, at herself, and at
me 'cause we can't have a baby.
You do.
We didn't know it?
We just didn't know
she was pregnant?
It happens.
This was the whole
reason for the hunting trips
and the jet skis,
trips to Bali and stuff.
I said to her, "Babe,
if it's just gonna be us,
"let's make us an adventure."
But she really wanted a baby.
We both did.
You can hold her if you want.
Yeah?
Yeah. Yes.
How's my wife?
She's gonna die if
I don't get that out.
The pellet is bouncing all
around the right ventricle.
That's what's causing
her arrhythmias.
I'm gonna have to open her up.
Let's get ready to
put her on bypass!
Damn it, how did we get here?
Look, she had a baby she
never had a chance to hold,
- so if you could just...
- That's not helping.
I'll prep the femoral artery.
- She's arresting!
- Crash cart!
Charge to 200.
Husband wants to
know how she's doing.
Clear! ALEX: Oh, crap.
- I have a pulse.
- We have sinus!
Splash her with Betadine.
Get me some towels.
For what it's worth, this
is kind of a miracle baby.
I mean, they never
thought they could have one.
So, you might be
saving a whole family.
None of this is
helping me! Ten blade!
She's gonna die if
I don't get that out.
God...
I don't know.
I don't know, uh,
if you're out there or not
or if you can even hear people
who don't know if you're out there.
Or if you give a crap
about what they say.
But, um, God, Yahweh,
Buddha, E.T., whatever...
April knows.
Right? She believes.
And she needs you. So, uh...
Um, show up for her?
Please?
Show up for April.
She loves you. She needs you.
Please, uh...
Show up for her.
Please.
Didn't expect to see you here.
They asked me for some
privacy, so I'm staying away.
What can I do?
How many months has it
been since that day in Boston?
Um...
About six.
Six months. Six.
Yet it took something like this
for you to pick up
a phone and call.
I wanted to, uh,
several times, I...
Richard, I think we don't need
to talk about that right now.
Okay.
If there's any way I can help,
if there is anything
that I can do for you,
or for them, I'm here.
I think I just want to be alone.
And you have to keep the
laser moving all the time.
Remove the tumor cell by cell
like zapping dust off of a carpet.
Without singeing the carpet.
- Exactly.
Now, when we use
this on Herman's tumor,
it'll be on her optic
chiasm and nerve.
And rather than
restoring Drew's sight,
we'll have to keep
her from going blind.
See. There. You just said it.
Said what?
You said, "Restoring
Drew's sight."
You need to let
that go. I knew it.
You wouldn't have said
it if you couldn't do it.
You wouldn't have even tried.
The tumor is everywhere.
It's impossible. I knew that
20 minutes into this surgery.
Okay, so, why don't you
stop? Why are you still working?
To improve my technique.
That's...
You should stop. Why?
You don't feel the
slightest bit guilty?
Guilty? Why?
For using this nice, funny man,
for turning him
into a skills lab.
I can't use a human
being for practice.
You feel guilty because
you are thinking about you.
And this has nothing
to do with you.
This is about Drew.
This was his last hope.
The chances were
slim, and Drew knew that.
So I am thinking
about what to say to him
when he finds out that
that last hope is gone.
That is what you
should be thinking about,
not your own guilt.
Clamps off. Up with the flow.
Come on, start beating.
All right, we're gonna
have to use some electricity.
Charge the paddles to 20.
Charged. MAGGIE: Clear.
Oh, God. Again.
Her heart's been
through a lot today.
She got shot and she had a baby.
Clear!
Brenda! You are
going to hold your baby.
Do you understand me?
You have a little girl
who wants to meet you,
so you are going
to show up for that
and you are going to hold her.
Clear!
I got things covered. You
don't have to be here if...
You don't want me here? No.
No, this place doesn't
work without you.
It's been a mess here today.
I need you here, but not if
you don't need to be here.
I want to be here.
No one has seen my mysterious
intern. No one's even heard of her.
I run the ER. I
know every intern.
What's her name? I don't know.
I mean, she's dark-haired, she's
got a vacant look on her face,
and she's right there.
Hey! Hey, you.
Why didn't you do what
I asked you to? Warren.
I'm sorry. I don't know if...
And why do you still have this?
I told you this
morning to just...
Stop it right now.
You don't work here, do you?
What's your name? Wendy.
These are personal release
papers for a deceased patient.
Who is this patient?
My fiance.
You came in last night.
I couldn't go home.
Michael and I were driving
home from this lodge.
We thought we might
have our wedding there.
And then there was
a big truck, and then...
Everyone's been really nice.
They got me cleaned up.
Someone gave me
these clothes to wear
because mine were covered in...
I went down to the cafeteria.
I think they thought
I was a doctor.
They gave me food.
I went upstairs to the
nursery. I looked at the babies.
And it made me
feel a little better.
I'm sorry if I messed up
things for that one doctor.
I wasn't sure...
They told me I could take
Michael's things home with me
when I was ready.
I haven't been ready.
I know.
We were gonna do so many things.
This was our beginning.
We had so many plans
for a life and a family,
and now they're gone!
They're gone.
Wendy, do you believe in God?
Yes.
But he didn't.
Michael didn't believe.
It's okay.
You can believe
enough for the two of you.
You have lost somebody,
and you are hurting,
but you will get through this.
You can survive this.
You are strong.
It's okay.
You are gonna be okay.
I promise.
Samuel Norbert Avery.
That should be our son's name.
It should? Yeah.
I think I got what
I was waiting for.
You did?
Let's go back upstairs.
I'm ready now.
Meredith?
Uh, my plans have changed.
I'd be happy to take
your weekend call.
You should go.
Thanks, but it's fine.
I can go another
time. It's not a big deal.
Take it from a man
who has spent his life
regretting the
flights he never took.
Get on the plane, see Derek.
It is a big deal.
But I don't have
anyone to watch my kids
and Amelia is working, so...
I am here. What?
I said I'm here.
I moved here alone and
I have made one friend,
and I consider you my friend.
Oh, I just... I mean,
I didn't even...
No, I'm just saying.
If you ever need something,
like if you ever
need help moving
or, like, a ride to the airport,
like, I'm that kind of friend.
But I can't ask you
to babysit my kids.
Are you kidding
me? I would love to.
I was a Girl Scout,
and I was registered
with a babysitting
service as a teenager.
And I'm good.
I mean, I'm a "play on the floor
and cook for them" babysitter.
You cook? And I bake.
Kids love baking, and I love
babies, and babies love me.
And, you know, they're
my niece and nephew,
so I would love
to. I would love to.
You don't have to bake.
Okay, but can I?
We were pretty successful.
We were able to remove
about 98% of your tumor,
so you've got a few
more years coming to you.
Oh, well, I haven't been able to
bring myself to open up my eyes yet.
Why don't you do that now?
Okay.
Somebody say something
so I know who's who.
You can see? Yeah.
It's blurry, but it's... Yeah!
Okay, that may
improve, it may not.
Drew, we'll run
some tests, but...
It's... But that's... I didn't
think that I should hope.
Dr. Lavender.
You did it.
I mean, I knew you could do it.
Even when you said
it was impossible.
Because it was.
But you pulled it off!
And you said to stop.
That's the difference.
I know what it is to
walk into a hospital OR
with little or no
chance of success,
to do all of the planning
and hoping and labor,
knowing that in the end,
it may amount to nothing.
It's impossible. But it
is what is asked of us.
And if you can't do it,
if you aren't willing to
keep looking for light
in the darkest of
places without stopping
even when it seems impossible,
you will never succeed.
What I am doing next with Herman
is much, much harder than this.
I only need to be better, and I
am gonna get there any way I can.
If you are not
willing to do that,
then you shouldn't
be working with me
and you probably
shouldn't be a surgeon.
Understand?
Everything all right?
Yep.
Hey, the candle thing
does work, by the way.
So, thanks for that.
Howard? Are you okay?
Yeah.
No.
This is just a lot for one day.
For a lifetime.
You ready?
Yeah.
Oh, that's her.
She's real?
Here she is. Oh!
Here's mama.
Oh.
Look at you.
Oh, look at you.
You look just like your daddy.
You have his nice chin.
Oh.
He squeezed my finger.
And then he let go.
We can't get too close.
If we felt even a little
of the love and the joy
and the hopes that our
patients are saying goodbye to,
we'd never be able to function.
Is it over? Yeah.
I'm giving them some time.
Thank you for today.
I think that it would have
been harder to be in there.
It's never easy for anybody.
So we say, "We're
sorry for your loss."
And we hope it offers something.
Can you just take me home?
Take me home, take me to bed,
and just hold me?
Some little bit of support.
Some bit of peace.
Some bit of closure.
Something good.
Some little piece of beauty in
the midst of some place dark.
My baby lived for 43 minutes.
An unexpected gift
just when it's needed most.