Every little kid knows
the words to the song.
"The foot bone's
connected to the leg bone."
I think you're beautiful.
"The leg bone's connected
to the knee bone."
In med school,
you learn it's a little more
complicated than that.
I'm trying to love you.
Why won't you let me?
But still... Have a baby?
This isn't pizza versus Thai.
You don't give a little on a baby.
Cristina, I am asking...
I am saying no!
The song's not wrong.
It hurts
to love you.
Everything is connected.
I'm still shaking.
You do that every day?
Not on the weekends, usually.
I'm pretty sure I'd be an
alcoholic if I had your job.
They kind of frown upon
alcoholism in my line of work, so...
Whoa.
Nice.
See? That's why I
could never be a surgeon.
Thank you for the drink.
I gotta go.
One more.
Come on. Please.
It's the least I can do.
And then what happened?
Cristina.
Cristina, I don't know
what good this is doing.
There isn't any good. This...
Seriously, how could
this be doing any good?
I'm not saying... Cristina, I...
Stop saying my name.
The foot bone's
connected to the leg bone.
The leg bone's connected
to the knee bone.
I want to fix this.
Whatever you want
me to do, I will do.
But this...
You're asking me to hurt you.
You're asking me to
torture you with the details...
Of you having sex
with another woman.
Yes.
And if you take one piece out...
I wanna know
every detail.
You wanna fix this?
I wanna know how this happened.
The rest just
falls apart.
You've found a 7.5
centimeter triple-A
on your 85-year-old patient. Go.
Get an angio, assess his
pulmonary and cardiac function,
and see if he's a candidate
for an endovascular repair.
Nope. Why not?
Because the patient's dead.
You killed him. He's dead.
I didn't kill him.
I did a stent graft
and now he's living without
the threat of a rupture,
which is not dead.
Hmm. I think you should buy
him flowers, 'cause he dead.
He is not dead.
I saved him the complications
of an open procedure
with a minimally
invasive technique.
He's not dead.
Why are we stopping?
Because we're done.
Because I killed him? I
told you, I did not kill him.
I know, and so do you, even
when I try to psych you out of it,
which means
you're ready for the boards.
The Torres method is inside you.
So I'm gonna go home to my wife,
because I am sick of pushing
this baby around this park
every morning at the
butt crack of dawn.
And I...
You're free, Grey. Go
do whatever it is you do.
Okay.
Don't get me wrong, I love this.
I like that, too.
But this is your
"drink coffee in the
"tunnels with
Cristina, bitch mode,
"griping about the world" time.
This is your Yang
time. What's going on?
Nothing's wrong.
You want me to stop?
I didn't say you should stop.
I asked you what's wrong.
Damn it.
"Excellence is not an
act, but a habit," Aristotle.
Avery, what is Aristotle
doing in our staff meeting,
and why are you even in
here handing these out?
You mean when I could
be practicing medicine
or studying for my boards?
Yeah, I've asked myself
that same question.
Mmm! This is delicious. When
did Hunt bump up the donut budget?
As Chief, I'm a firm believer
that a nice variety
of baked goods
is the right way to
start any meeting.
As Chief? What are
you talking about?
Seriously? Seriously?
Wait. What happened?
Okay, calm down, everyone.
Dr. Hunt and Dr. Yang
are down with the flu.
I'll be acting Chief in
Dr. Hunt's absence.
Could be a day. Could be a week.
What do we got for today?
Let me get this straight.
Dr. Hunt asked you
to fill in as Chief, you,
Mark Sloan, by name?
Yes, he did.
Any other questions?
I like the part about "Excellence
is not an act, but a habit."
Hey, so I got us a reservation
at Jane's on Market.
It's the one with the little
twinkly lights all around it.
Have you been
there yet? It's new.
We haven't. It's beautiful
and kind of romantic,
and I realize that ladies' night
is different than date night,
but I have been in the
lab for the last two weeks
and smelling like
formaldehyde, and I just...
I need to be
someplace beautiful.
Yeah, of course.
Great. Good. I'm excited. So
excited. This is gonna be great.
Am I talking really fast?
Not in a weird way.
I'm sorry. I'm just wired.
The house is so quiet
when it's empty, you know?
I've been leaning
really hard on the coffee.
But anyway, okay. So
I'll see you guys tonight.
Ladies' night.
I have no idea
what just happened.
I told her last week that
we'd do a ladies' night.
Like at a girl bar?
Do we need to have a
talk about boundaries?
No, no, not a "ladies'
night" ladies' night.
Like a just a night
out for Teddy.
Okay, so do we
have another lady,
or is it just two lesbian
moms and a widow
at Seattle's most
romantic restaurant?
Ooh! Bailey.
Really, that's your go to?
What?
So, um, Teddy...
Poor, sad, widowed Teddy,
wants to have a girls' night.
Ladies. Ladies' night.
Absolutely not.
No, it's her first night out.
It's a big step. She needs us.
She has you, the two of you.
That's about as much happy
as any person can bear.
She made a reservation
at a romantic restaurant.
I mean, would you want
to be a third-wheel widow
at a restaurant with us and
a bunch of twinkly lights?
You're buying.
I figured everyone
could pitch in
for our dear friend, the widow.
Okay, fine. We're buying.
See you tonight. My god.
I've got some good
news for you, Neil.
Oh?
You've changed your
mind about euthanasia?
We found you a donor.
For the whole thing?
The whole thing.
Dr. Webber, you know I love you,
but I believe you stood
me up at this dance before.
A couple of times, but I
am here with a new corsage.
Dr. Grey.
Neil Sheridan, 62, presents
with short gut syndrome
caused by a resection
of the small intestine.
Years of T.P.N. has
caused the liver to fail,
resulting in the need for
a multi-organ transplant
of the small intestine, large
intestine, stomach, pancreas and liver.
All from one guy.
Try to find that on Craigslist.
And we've scheduled
you for surgery today.
I'll believe that when I see it.
Neil, do you want me to call your
family? I'm sure they'd love to visit.
Don't worry about me, sunshine.
My family came to
say their good-byes
the first two times.
"We love you. We'll
miss you." It was sweet,
but I've heard it.
I told 'em not to
bother this time around.
Okay.
If you change your
mind, you let me know.
I will. Okay.
But I won't.
Where have you been?
We're halfway through
the new batch of flash cards.
Yeah, Hunt and Yang
are out sick today,
so Sloan's the Chief,
and I am the Chief's bitch.
Lucky me.
No distractions.
Kepner, hit me again.
Okay, a woman with
dysuria, incomplete voiding
and a palpable suburethral mass.
Urethral carcinoma.
Damn it. I had one
of those last year.
Um... Uh...
We did radiation
and surgical excision.
No! Would it be chemo?
An ectopic ureter,
or it could be.
I mean, I scrubbed
in on one of those,
but I don't remember the
technique the urologist used.
Sounds like
urethral diverticulum.
And if it's proximal, I
would do a partial ablation
because it's much less
likely to result in a fistula.
You don't even need to know
advanced urology for the boards.
But I do, because the
Torres method is in me.
Total crap. You get
to study with Torres
while the rest of us
get to sink like rocks.
I hope you're happy when
you're alone in the OR
and the rest of us are working
the free clinic at the mall.
My whole brain is crammed
with so many hypotheticals,
I can't even remember
what real cases
I was actually there
for. I am screwed.
I'll tell you who's
screwed, Yang.
The boards are
around the corner,
no one's seen her
study, she's out sick.
She's gonna get
creamed. Yang is fine.
You can't just pass the
boards on raw talent, okay?
It is an artificial environment,
which requires
massive amounts...
Cristina is fine. Okay?
What is the point?
The point is, I wanna know.
The point is, I have a right...
You don't have
a right, not to this.
No, I have a right as your
wife to know what you did.
I'm not gonna do this. I am
not gonna tell you every detail.
I cheated. Yes.
I cheated. I did
a horrible thing.
I know. I know I
did a horrible thing.
But this is not what
we're gonna do.
I'm not gonna
play a little movie
of all of my crimes so that you
can decide that I'm a monster.
Okay, then get out.
You want me to leave?
You're answering the phone?
It's Meredith. She's
called, like, five times.
If I don't answer
it, she'll come over,
because we have
the flu, remember?
Hey. Hey.
How are you feeling?
I'm okay. It's just the flu.
I should come and check on you,
because it could be something
more serious than the flu.
No, it's fine. It's the flu.
Owen's there?
Yeah, Owen is
here. He's sick, too.
Oh, I bet he is.
Cristina, I... I gotta go.
Cristina, wait.
Cristina?
So am I staying or am I going?
That's up to you.
It was the day after
we quit therapy.
And I met her at the hospital.
Yeah. We're fine.
We're fine.
I should be your person!
Be my person!
Be my person, Owen!
Be my freaking person!
Be my person.
29-year-old female.
MVC collision with a truck.
Take her to trauma one.
Hypotensive in the field. She
received two liters LR en route.
Okay, let's get trauma labs
and set up for an ultrasound.
All right. I'll check it.
Is anybody with her?
I am.
What was her name?
Honestly? I...
I don't remember.
He's in the car.
Chief.
See, from 1:00 to 2:00, you
have "Lunch with the Chief."
I told you to call it
"Beef with the Chief."
It's got a ring to it.
You got a beef, come
meet with the Chief.
I didn't realize you
were serious about that.
You need to let people get
the little things off their chests
before they become big things.
I'm serious about
this Chief thing, Avery.
It's my shot. I
want to do it right.
"Beef with the Chief," put
it in the schedule tomorrow.
Dr. Shepherd, Dr. Warren.
Here.
Mr. Cooper. How are you feeling?
Like I would kill my own
mother for a burger and a shake.
Jason Cooper,
29-year-old male with
advanced juvenile arthritis,
causing fusion of the jaw
and extensive fusion of
the C2, C3 and C4 vertebrae.
He's been on a feeding
tube for the past eight months.
No solid food at all.
Don't worry, Mr. Cooper.
After we break your jaw
and put in those sweet
titanium hinges I made for you,
you'll be eating
burgers again real soon.
Could we have a word
with you outside, please?
Of course.
Ben and I don't think we
should do the surgery today.
Why not?
With his cervical fusion, lying
him down on an operating table
is gonna put pressure
on the base of his spine.
Not to mention that orotracheal
intubation is
impossible on this guy.
I'll do nasotracheal, but if
there's any compromise to the tube
while he's under and
he's got no mobility...
Let's just say, I can't
guarantee anything.
What's your recommendation?
We postpone the surgery
until other plans can be made.
And, Dr. Avery, what would
support performing the surgery
as soon as possible?
The patient has a major
abscess in the back of his mouth.
Which could lead to
sepsis or endocarditis.
Infection's a killer, which
is why this can't wait.
So let's figure out a way to get
Mr. Cooper into
surgery on schedule.
Frankly, I don't know what
you think I can do for him
by 3:00 this afternoon.
Rise. Excuse me?
You have it in you.
Lost causes, right?
Making the impossible possible?
Rise to the challenge,
Shepherd. I believe in you.
Rise.
All right, guys.
So you take orders
from Sloan now?
Hey! Where do you think
you're... You just can't take those.
I was just gonna copy 'em
and bring 'em right back.
It'll take two seconds.
They don't teach you
about HIPAA in med school?
You don't see a copy
machine, do you?
That's because these
charts are private.
They don't get copied and
they don't leave this room, ever.
Come on.
I'm a fifth year. I'm just
trying to study for my boards.
I need real cases. So read 'em.
Read 'em all, but
they don't go outta here
except in your
brain, understand?
Yeah, I think I do.
There you go.
Hey, you got a busy
schedule today?
Why?
Do you need help
with that thyroidectomy?
Because I've never done one,
and I was just reading about
how it can sometimes cause
a thyroid storm, which is...
How cool is that, you know?
Yeah, maybe.
Listen, your whole
photographic memory thing,
how does that work?
You want me to memorize these?
Yeah.
All of them?
That'll take forever.
Lexie, we need your help.
We can't keep doing stupid
hypotheticals off index cards.
We need someone to
question us off real cases.
I have rounds. I have post-ops.
Lexie, next year when
Karev and I are attendings,
we will be assigning surgeries
and putting in our recommendations
for chief resident.
Are you sure you want to
get off on the wrong foot?
No.
Great!
It is so much fun that you're
gonna be studying with us.
You get to watch
the game tonight.
I do?
I gotta go to some girls' night
Callie and Arizona
put together for Teddy.
I mean, that's good, right?
Wasn't I gonna get some
long story about how this is
"the game of a lifetime,
"and if you would just
sit still for five minutes,
"you might appreciate
the beauty of..."
You and I have been on
completely opposite schedules
for, like, two weeks.
Tuck is at his dad's.
So I wasn't planning on
watching the game tonight.
You weren't?
Thank you, Doctor. Nope.
What were you planning to do?
I could say it out loud, but...
Here you go.
It would be inappropriate
for the workplace,
so I'm just gonna think it.
Oh...
I'm gonna get
out of girls' night.
Mmm-hmm.
I got the donor scans.
Great. Let's see what you got.
There.
Bowel looks good, small
intestines, large intestines,
and that's a
good-looking pancreas.
Look at that on
the liver right there.
Looks like a tumor.
That makes him an
unsuitable organ donor.
Not necessarily. Could
be a benign adenoma.
My patient's been in
for two other transplants,
and they both fell through.
He's not gonna live much
longer without a new liver.
We could resect it.
It's a little unconventional
to operate on a donor,
but there's no reason
why it wouldn't work.
That's a great idea, Bailey.
Great idea? You want to put
compromised organs
into a transplant recipient
and give your guy cancer
on top of everything else?
I think we owe it to my guy to at
least excise the tumor and test it.
I don't agree.
Dr. Sloan, are you arguing
surgical protocol with Dr. Webber?
Dr. Bailey,
are you arguing with the
decision of the Chief of Surgery?
Call UNOS.
Tell them this
donor's unsuitable.
Put Mr. Sheridan
back on the list.
We've put you back
on the transplant list.
And a new set of organs
can come in at any time.
Cut the crap, Dr. Webber.
You and I both know
I'm not gonna make it
to see the sunrise tomorrow,
let alone to stick around
for some other poor,
sad sack to kick it.
Mr. Sheridan, is there
anyone we can call for you,
your family, your
sisters, your friends?
Are you kidding?
Thank God my family's
not around for this.
It's like Lucy with a
football, except it's my life.
It would kill them worse
than the first two times
to come in here and
say good-bye to me.
We're all alone in
this world, sunshine.
Anybody who tells
you any different is lying
or trying to sell you something.
Now you...
You are the best
doctor I ever had.
So don't beat
yourself up about this.
It's done. It's over.
You did everything you could.
No.
No, I didn't.
Sir.
Bailey, your tumor
resection idea was sound.
And there was no reason
why those organs wouldn't work.
The donor is still
on life support.
The organ recovery
for the heart and
lungs isn't scheduled
till this afternoon.
But Dr. Sloan...
You let me deal
with Chief Sloan.
When you're the Chief, you
gotta make the hard decisions.
Webber knows that.
It comes with the job.
Who's our first
appointment, Avery?
No one on the schedule, Chief.
That's why you shoulda
called it "Beef with the Chief."
People would've
shown up for that.
You got a beef?
Actually, I would really love
to go study for my boards.
No.
I know, I don't have
an appointment,
but do you have a
moment to talk about
Jason Cooper's
jaw reconstruction?
That's fine. He's wide
open. Have a seat.
There you go.
I think I can carve
out of foam a cradle
that holds the patient's
head and neck during surgery,
reducing the chance of
respiratory complication.
That's a good idea.
But you can do
better. Excuse me?
Foam's fine if
nothing goes wrong,
but it won't be flexible enough
if we have to adjust
him mid-surgery.
It's a good idea,
but... Are you aware...
I'm aware... Of what?
That that surgery is
taking place at 3:00,
and Jason Cooper's
airway needs to be secured.
So rise, Shepherd.
Rise.
I can't do ladies' night.
Sorry. What?
But we need you.
I can't come
because Ben and I are
taking dance
lessons tonight, salsa.
You and Ben... Yeah.
And salsa?
No, you just want to
go home and get laid.
We have a long-standing
salsa appointment tonight,
and... Sorry.
You're on your own.
Right. I bet it's gonna be long.
Mmm-hmm. Real long.
She's almost finished.
She has read all of your
charts and none of mine.
Yeah, I found her.
I brought her here.
Lex, can you take a look
at some of my cases, too?
Or not. I mean, it's
fine if you don't want to.
It's okay. I can. I will...
No, no, no, no, you will not.
Not until she's finished with mine.
Okay, these take
priority, Lexie.
You don't need
Lexie. You got Torres.
They're for Cristina.
She's not even here.
Which is why she needs the help.
She does not need the help.
She just needs to finish
mine. And you know what?
Shh!
Yeah, but you know what?
There is no compromise.
You don't have half a baby.
I don't want one.
We live like you want,
and how you want.
You get whatever you want!
I didn't realize
how late it got.
I know. Me, too.
Okay.
Well, good night.
Good night.
Thank you again for
saving my friend's life.
Oh, oh... This...
It's just my job.
Kiss me.
I'm drunk. I'm drunk.
So? Kiss me anyway.
I am married.
So?
Kiss me anyway.
I can't.
Yes, you can.
You...
You're trouble.
You are trouble.
So?
Kiss me anyway.
No.
You've gotta fix this thing
with Cristina and Hunt.
Zola. Zola.
What? Don't tell
me nothing's wrong.
Yang has never missed a day at
work because she's been sick, ever.
And Sloan as Chief?
He's driving me crazy.
I can't fix it.
Come on.
I can't fix this.
He cheated on her.
What?
When?
I don't know. I don't
know the whole story.
She didn't tell you?
He told me.
Hunt told you?
He told me, but he didn't
really know he was telling me,
but that's how I know.
Does Cristina know you know?
She knows. I mean, she
doesn't know, but she knows.
I know she knows.
So don't you want
to talk to her about it?
But I can't talk
about it with her,
because then we
would be talking about it.
Don't you want to talk about it?
Yes, but not like that.
I hope they figure it out.
Because you can't
stand Sloan as your boss?
Among other things, yes.
Zola.
I'm gonna get you.
He does have a point about
stabilizing the spine with foam.
I got your page. What's up?
Slight change of plans.
You're taking Sofia tonight.
Yeah. We can't.
No, we got a ladies'
night with Altman.
You're taking
Altman to a chick bar?
It can mean other things.
It's your night with Sofia.
I don't know how late I'm
gonna have to be here tonight.
Seriously? Seriously.
I have chief stuff to do.
And you still owe me
for Valentine's Day.
Kepner.
Here you go, Doctor. Okay.
Remind me, how long's
it take to do an appy?
If you perf the bowel, then
it takes... It could take hours.
Or if the patient
hemorrhages, or if the patient...
This isn't your boards, Kepner.
How long does it take to
do an appy in the real world?
Forty-five minutes to
an hour and 15, tops.
Then why do Bailey and Grey
have eight hours blocked in OR two?
Maybe it's a really
complicated appy.
Kepner.
Dr. Webber was the Chief
for a really, really long time.
Do not touch that patient!
Dr. Sloan, if you would
just let us do our jobs...
I'm doing my job, Dr. Bailey.
And today my job is to
be the Chief of Surgery,
and as the Chief of Surgery, I told
you not to perform this procedure.
So do not touch him.
Take him back to his room.
Put him back on
the transplant list.
See?
I told you this
would never work.
Dr. Webber.
Chief Sloan.
Was I not clear this morning?
You mean this?
This is a benign adenoma.
I've been a general
surgeon for almost 30 years.
I know a benign
adenoma when I see one.
I'd stake my career on it.
If there's a tumor in the donor
organs, then they've been compromised.
You know this. I
didn't make those rules.
You're a good doctor,
and you may one day make
a great Chief of Surgery.
But you're a plastic
surgeon, Chief Sloan.
You're a perfectionist.
And you want everything by
the rules so it'll end up pretty.
I don't need pretty.
And I don't need perfect.
What I need is for this to work.
And what's gonna make it work
is for me to take out that tumor
and put these healthy organs
inside my very sick patient.
It won't be pretty,
but it will work,
and it will keep
my patient alive.
Stand down, Chief Sloan.
Stand down.
A little more
suction right here.
Cristina, please.
Open the door, please.
Cristina, if you
don't open the door...
Are you okay?
Cristina...
Are you hurting
yourself in there?
Cristina, please. I
don't know what to do.
Cristina, if you don't open the
door, I'm gonna have to break it in.
I'm gonna have to, so...
If you're all right,
just open the door.
Okay, I'm breaking in the door.
So if you're close to the
door, then just get back,
'cause I'm breaking it
in right now. I am. So...
All right. One...
Two...
Three.
Ouch.
Yeah, that was pretty lame.
I look like a total...
Cristina?
I have an M.D. and a PhD,
I am a freaking
cardiothoracic surgeon.
I am supposed to be
studying for my boards,
the most important
exam of my life,
and I'm...
And I'm locked in
a bathroom crying.
Because of a boy.
I think it would be
easier if she was
someone you had
fallen in love with.
No, it wouldn't
have been easier.
No, it would.
It would be clear and clean.
You would be leaving me for her.
You would've fallen out of
love with me and in love with her.
When you slept with her,
you wouldn't have
been able to control
yourself because
of all the love.
Cristina, it would
not have been easier.
It was just sex?
It was just sex.
Just once.
I don't understand.
What? What don't you...
I don't understand how you...
I don't understand
why you would sleep
with another woman.
Cristina...
I don't know. I...
I was lonely because
we were fighting and...
I was afraid of what
was happening to us,
and I just got drunk
and I did an
incredibly stupid thing.
And people make mistakes. I
make mistakes. You make mistakes.
Okay, if you're gonna
bring up the abortion again...
If you're gonna say that
you had sex with someone
because I had an abortion...
I had sex with someone
because I was hurt.
And you wanted to hurt me back?
I don't, Cristina...
You wanted to hurt me back.
Oh, my God. You
wanted to hurt me back.
Mark can't take Sofia tonight.
Or won't.
He can't.
What are we gonna do?
We could have ladies'
night at our place.
Just the two of us,
at home, with Teddy?
I hate ladies' night.
It could be great if
we could ditch Teddy.
That's so, so horrible.
Come on. We can
do some salsa dancin'.
But do you think Teddy
would understand?
Yeah, we'll reschedule.
It's not like we're canceling.
Are we bad people?
We're bad ladies.
Maybe.
Maybe very bad.
Okay.
Out with the bad.
And in with the good.
On the count of three.
Ready. One,
two... Careful.
And three.
Easy. Watch the clamps.
I have the clamps. I got 'em.
All right. Easy, easy, girl.
Okay. Okay.
So the beanbag will stabilize
Mr. Cooper's cervical spine.
And it's flexible enough
that Dr. Warren can intubate
and reposition if he needs to.
Once he intubates, I will
leave the surgery to you.
A beanbag?
Inspiration can
come from anywhere.
In this case, day care.
You see that?
I plant the seed of innovation,
I nurture it and voila.
You rose.
Am I a fantastic leader or what?
All hail the Chief.
When's Hunt coming back?
Not soon enough.
Thank you, Doctor.
Hey. Hey.
You okay?
Yeah, yeah, I'm good. I just...
I just need some
more coffee, I think.
Listen, if you're
too tired, you know,
we don't have to go out tonight.
Oh.
You don't want to go out?
No, no, no, no. I mean, I
didn't say that I don't wanna...
Oh, my God. When am I
gonna stop freaking people out?
I don't mean to be
the big, sad widow,
and I don't mean to
bring the room down.
I don't want to ruin
other people's fun.
Teddy, I'm just... I
thought you were tired.
So we're super excited
about ladies' night out.
It's gonna be fun. Yeah?
Yeah. Okay.
Yay! Yay!
We are bad, selfish people.
A woman is counting on us.
She is leaning on us when she
is feeling vulnerable and alone,
and we are talking about
dancing and getting it on
and not even being
halfway decent friends to her
in her time of need.
You were gonna ditch
her so you could get it on?
Where do you think
we got the idea?
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Anyway, look, I only canceled
because I knew the two
of you would be there.
Now what's your excuse?
I wanted to salsa.
No, nobody gets salsa.
We get ladies' night with Teddy.
And you will be there
and you will be there.
I have... No excuses.
No excuses.
I read so much.
There's so many charts.
I just got so full, I think
things are falling out.
There's nothing in my brain.
Lexie, why aren't you
in the reading room?
I can do it. Okay.
I can, let me do...
No. No, no, no,
you're not doing it.
No. No more using my
sister like a database.
We broke her.
It's over. Done.
Done.
So I'll come back and get the...
The rest of my
stuff another time.
Okay.
Bye.
I'll always be in love with you.
You're the love of my life.
I will never love another woman.
You don't even
remember her name.
You take care of yourself.
Hi, Neil.
Am I...
Alive? I'm afraid so.
Where is everybody?
You didn't tell anyone
you were having surgery.
They didn't call just
to check up on me?
You told them not
to several times.
What does that matter?
They're my family. They
should know not to listen to me.
I could've died.
They should've come.
I can't believe that
they didn't come.
Let's call them.
Should we call them?
Yeah. Okay?
Yeah. Okay.
I got those ginger
cookies for dessert.
No, no, no, no dessert. No,
we're having a glass of wine,
plate of food, then
everybody's on their way.
School night.
What'd you tell Ben, you'd
be outta here in like an hour?
Forty-five minutes.
I'm late. I'm sorry.
I couldn't figure out whether
we wanted red or white or rose.
And then I realized, why choose?
I mean, we've got
the whole night.
That we do.
And movies. Dirty
Dancing and Beaches.
Movies.
Cristina, are you there?
I can hear you
breathing. Are you okay?
I'm here.
Are you feeling better?
Yes.
I'm better. I...
Cristina...
I know that you don't
want to talk about it,
but I'm here, so...
I just want to stay
on the phone with you
until you want to hang up.
I'm here.
The human body is made
up of systems
that keep it alive.
There's the one that
keeps you breathing...
And the one that
keeps you standing...
Hunt.
You feeling better?
What?
The flu.
Oh. Yeah. Yeah. Fine.
You mind if I join you?
Not at all.
You know,
Sloan turned out
to be a good Chief.
Sloan? I asked for you or
Webber if you wouldn't do it.
Sloan was Chief? Mark Sloan?
Yeah. He wasn't bad.
Don't let him know
I said that, though.
The one that makes you hungry...
And the one that
makes you happy.
They're all connected.
Take a piece out,
and everything else falls apart.
So do you know why I brought
you all here this morning?
To help you,
because even though we
all take the boards alone,
if we work together,
we can all pass.
And it's only when
our support systems
look like they might fail us...
If you're not at the
hospital, you're here.
You sleep here, you eat here.
There are no distractions, no breaks.
This is the Grey
method, and it starts now.
That we realize how much
we've depended
on them all along.
I'm gonna fail my
boards. I need to study.
Come on in.