Doctors live in a world
of constant progress...
and forward motion.
Stand still for a second...
and you'll be left behind.
But as hard as we
try to move forward,
as tempting as it is
to never look back...
the past always comes
back to bite us in the ass.
Meredith! Hey.
- Thanks for meeting me here.
- Are you OK? Where have
you been?
I'm fine. I've been in
Chehalis with my mom.
This is not Chehalis.
Where the hell are we?
We're in Seattle, Dr. Singer.
This is Dr. Grey, my friend.
This is Dr. Singer. He was
my high school science teacher.
A brilliant man. He fought for me.
He's the reason I became a surgeon.
I appreciate your taking
the time to see us, Dr. Grey,
but I promised Isobel's Algebra II
teacher I'd have her back in time
- for fifth period.
- I'm confused.
So is he. Nursing home
diagnosed him with Alzheimer's,
but he's been falling.
He could have a bleed.
He's wearing pajamas and
an overcoat. What'd you do,
- sneak him out in the night?
- No.
- This morning.
- You kidnapped him?
Can you please just
sneak him in to see Derek?
- Put him
on the schedule? Please?
- You've been in Chehalis,
and the only reason you came
back is to bring a confused, sickly man
- for Derek to look at?
- Yes.
- Ow! Ow! Stop hitting me!
- We were worried about you!
- I was worried about you!
- Look, please,
can you get him in to see Derek?
I'll be back later. I'll be back, OK?
- No. You cannot leave him here.
- I'm not going in.
- You need to let Alex
know you're OK.
- I am not going in there.
Yes, you're going in. So he
got you pregnant, so what?
- You're pregnant?
- No. He thinks
I'm 15 years old.
- Right.
- You're gonna go
into that school
and show those cheerleaders that
you have nothing to be ashamed of.
Those little bitches
are poisonous.
And as history shows
us again and again,
those who forget the past
are doomed to repeat it.
Cristina.
- Dr. Yang.
- Dr. Avery.
- Look, OK, about the kiss...
- Kiss? What kiss?
There was no kiss.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
- So do you have a boyfriend...?
- Never gonna happen.
Got it. Thanks.
- Hey. You paged us?
- I paged you. One second, Dr. Avery.
Um, I know you think I don't
understand you. So I got you a present.
Come on. Come on, I don't
wanna lose him! What do we got?
Defib paddles!
- You got me a cardiac trauma!
- - I didn't just get you a trauma.
I got you a Cardio god.
- Or goddess.
- Saline! Lock and load to 50!
Clear!
Nothing! Come on. Come on!
Nice to meet you. Jackson Avery.
- Teddy Altman.
- Teddy Altman?
I've... I've never heard of you.
Cristina Yang? I've never heard
of you either. That makes us even.
Teddy and I, we
served in Iraq together,
and she's gonna be
joining us for a little while.
OK. Come on, I'll
introduce you to the chief.
- Great. You look good.
- Thanks.
- You put on a little weight.
- I have not.
- Have too!
- Who the hell is she?
Go to the PACU and write the
post-op note on Mrs. Murdoch. Thanks.
Want me to page you if
there are complications?
Yes.
- Miranda, there you are!
- Adele?
You all right? Is everything OK?
Richard didn't come home
last night, and didn't call.
Tell me he's not lying
somewhere in a ditch, dead.
The last time I saw him
was... last night, in his office,
- working on the budget.
- Why didn't he answer his pager
- or his cell phone?
- OK, hold on. Hold on.
And why doesn't anybody in this hospital
know where the chief of surgery is?
Dr. Bailey, have
you seen the chief?
One of his patients
needs an emergency chole.
OK, I'm on it. Uh...
You go ahead and prep the patient.
You get yourself a cup of coffee. Decaf.
I will find the chief.
- So you're
an evolutionary biologist?
- Mmm, I was.
I was part of a research team on
my way to the Galápagos Islands,
and, suddenly, my father died.
And, of course, I had to go home.
Next thing I know, I'm back in Chehalis,
marrying my high school sweetheart
and teaching biology to kids who
would rather be anywhere else.
- I hear you're
an excellent teacher.
- Isobel's an excellent student.
She's gonna be a
doctor herself some day.
If she doesn't
get too distracted.
Hmm.
Well, everything
looks good, Dr. Singer.
- What we're gonna do is
take some blood - Ouch.
- And run some tests. OK?
- OK.
All right. Stevens?
How long has he been like this?
Um, I talked to him at
Christmas and he was fine.
He was still teaching. The school
only let him go six months ago.
- Is he on any medication?
- Every medication.
Alzheimer's meds, Parkinson's
meds, anti-depressants.
- What was his diagnosis?
- Dementia. The guy was useless.
- He might as well
have said old age.
- Possible.
He's 67. And if he
fell and hit his head,
he could have an intracranial
bleed, no one would know.
- Hmm.
- His wife is dead,
he has no kids...
Where have you been? You
missed your IL-2 appointment.
You told Cristina I was
here? Who else did you tell?
Well, well, well.
Look who's back.
This guy? You told the
guy that got me fired?
I didn't tell him. I don't know
him. It's my first day back.
Dr. Percy is on
my service today.
And I didn't get you fired.
You did that all by yourself.
Dr. Percy, Dr. Singer needs
a full dementia work up.
Dr. Stevens will
give you the details.
Hmm. I wish Dr. Stevens
would give me the details,
but I'm just the person
who saved her life.
- OK.
- You know that if you miss
- another IL-2 treatment...
- I got my treatment
at Seattle Pres.
I may not be a doctor,
but I'm not an idiot.
Iz...
- You heard from Casella?
- Yeah, I heard he took
another tour.
I'm sorry, where
were you before?
- In Baghdad with Dr. Hunt.
- No, before that.
- Where'd you do
your fellowship?
- Mayo.
- With Paul Moak?
- Moak is in Rochester.
I worked primarily
with Joshua Moore.
Oh. You went to Mayo in Florida.
Moore wrote that paper on
retrograde coronary sinus perfusion?
- I worked on that with him.
- I almost... I considered Mayo...
- Where'd you go to med school?
- Dr. Yang is a little thorough.
UT Southwestern. I did
my residency at G-W...
Have you published?
According to Google,
you don't exist.
Oh, my God. It's raining!
- It's Seattle, it rains a lot.
- Whoo! Hunt! How awesome
is this?
She's been living in the
desert for a long time.
- That is not a Cardio god.
- She is an incredible surgeon.
This is great!
So what's your story with her?
There's no story. We're friends.
How long is she here for?
The chief offered a limited
contract to test the waters.
Look, I really
appreciate the gift,
really I do, but you
need to take it back.
- Cristina...
- Take it back,
and exchange it for
a real Cardio god.
Just give her a chance. I
promise, she's gonna surprise you.
I guess you do have a boyfriend.
Are those his results?
Let me see them.
If you were a doctor here,
I could. They're normal.
All of them. Blood
work, CT, all normal.
We need to do a spinal tap. He
could have a subarachnoid hemorrhage.
What, did you think if you
made some great neuro save,
Shepherd would give
you your job back?
I'm not here to get my job back.
- Hello!
- Good, 'cause it's not gonna happen.
Dr. Singer, I'm here. I'm here.
What's happening?
One minute I'm in
class, the next minute...
- You're here
at Seattle Grace Hospital.
- I am not!
- Yes. I brought you here.
- No! It's not possible!
- I have a class! What time is it?
- Please! Come back to bed!
- No, let me go!
- Dr. Singer!
Oh, my God. Dr. Singer?
What's happening to me?
Chief!
- What we got?
- An emergency chole,
a new cardio attending and
your wife is here to see you.
- What?
- You in trouble. Drink your latte.
He needs a spinal tap. He's fallen
and could've burst an aneurysm.
Some bleeds show up on a
spinal tap that don't on CT.
And some doctors enjoy torturing
patients because they messed up
and don't know what they're
gonna do with the rest of their lives.
You are the one that got me
fired. You owe me this, you bitch!
Unless you want me to find
that snotty... what's her name?
And tell her how much
you love her? 'Cause I will.
Sick sinus syndrome.
She needs a transvenous
pacemaker now.
Dr. Yang, want to take this? I
haven't done one in ten years.
- Excuse me?
- I do.
- Great. It's all yours.
- You don't remember how?
I've been working primarily
on soldiers, Dr. Yang,
most of whom are well
under the age of 70.
Use the right IJ, Dr. Avery. It'll
give you the most direct approach.
Dr. Altman, will you
excuse me for a moment?
I just need to talk to the
chief about something.
She has been staying
with her mom in Chehalis.
I don't know how long
she's staying, if she's staying.
She has been keeping up with
her IL-2. That much I do know.
That's all I know.
I was up till all hours,
working on the budget.
By the time you
realized what time it was,
it was too late to let Adele know
you were going to sleep here,
what I will tell her
while you're in surgery.
- Thank you, Bailey.
- Chief?
Not the time. Chief
has emergency surgery.
The Chief has an
emergency cardio situation.
New attending doesn't know
how to put in a pacemaker.
- Yang...
- Do not engage.
Did you or did you not ask this
man for a new Cardio attending?
- Yes.
- And did he or did he not
bring in attending after attending,
none of whom seemed to please you,
and all of whom you ran off?
- That is not a fair assessment.
- Dr. Yang, has it occurred
to you
that you might be the problem?
Yeah, right. Leave this man
alone, go torture the new attending.
- Sir...
- Yang, do as Bailey says.
And you are due in surgery.
Bailey, what would
I do without you?
Let's hope you
never have to find out.
Is your trauma patient
stable for skin grafting?
- With the pancreatic
duct rupture?
- Miranda?
Adele! I'm so sorry. I sent the
chief into surgery. Do you want me...?
What I want is for
you to tell me the truth.
Are you having an
affair with my husband?
I... I am not having an
affair with your husband!
I saw the way you
handled him just now.
I did not handle him!
There was no handling.
We work together!
You spend every waking moment together.
You finish each other's sentences.
You read each other's minds. You're
more married to that man than I am.
Yeah, but that's just because
they're husband and work-wife.
- Excuse me?
- The chief
is your work-husband.
You're his work-wife.
You look out for each other.
You take care of each
other. It's like me and Sloan.
- Excuse me?
- Nobody's talking to you.
He's my work-husband, but he
has a girlfriend. I have a girlfriend.
- Nothing going on between us.
- There was at one point...
- You're not helping.
- Neither one of you are.
Adele, I promise you,
there is nothing going on.
Something is going on because
he hasn't been in his bed all week.
- What?
- Really?
The last time he acted
like this, disappearing,
sleeping at the hospital every
night, he was with Ellis Grey.
He may not be having
an affair with you...
He's not. I promise you.
I promise you he's not.
OK.
But wife-wife to work-wife,
someone in this hospital
is sleeping with our husband.
How we doing, Dr. Yang?
Gary Clark, 57. ST elevation
in leads one through four.
- Which would indicate?
- Anterior heart attack.
Blockage in the LAD. He's
ready for an angioplasty.
- Talk me through the procedure.
- Because you don't remember
how?
No, that was actually
a teaching moment.
Access the femoral artery,
thread the catheter to the heart,
- inject dye,
then open up the blockage.
- Good.
Use the pigtail
catheter to get a good...
Like this one?
Huh. Look at that. Dr. Avery,
what can we infer from this?
- Wall motion abnormalities.
- Yes, in the left ventricular
wall.
- Let's get into
the left coronary tree.
- Already there.
Oh. OK. Um...
Well, you want to make sure
you get images in many planes
- so you have
to shift the fluoro...
- We use rotational angiography.
- It does that on its own.
- Huh. Look at that.
- I guess I learned
something today.
- Yeah. Look at that.
- Chief?
- Uh-huh.
OK, I understand you are under
a tremendous amount
of pressure right now,
and that you haven't been
able to spend time at home,
and that a man, in your
position, has certain...
needs,
and that, when a
man is as powerful
and as attractive as you are,
those needs might easily be met by...
- Dr. Bailey.
- Yes, sir?
- Are you hitting on me?
- Your wife just showed up here
asking me if you and I
were having an affair.
No, no. I don't want to know
anything about anything.
What you do with your
business is your business.
And I was not hitting on you.
- Understood.
- Mm-hm.
Dr. Percy is almost done getting
the spinal fluid sample he needs.
- Yeah. Not that
I had any choice.
- That makes two of us.
You're doing great. Almost done.
What's going on with you and
Karev? Have you even talked to him?
- How is that any
of your business?
- It's everybody's business.
It's all anybody talks about
here, Stevens and Karev.
Have they talked? Are
they talking? So are you?
That's it. You're all done. I just
need you to lie flat for a while, OK?
See? That wasn't so bad, was it?
So this Karev... he's the boy?
The one who got you in trouble?
- Well, he didn't
help matters much.
- Did he propose?
Well, whatever you
do, don't marry him.
If you do and you have this child,
you'll never become a surgeon.
You'll probably never
even make it out of Chehalis.
What you will do, though, is
end up angry and frustrated and...
alone.
You gotta do
what's good for you.
And if this boy really cares
for you, he'll understand.
- How'd you find me here?
- The nurses love me.
They're my spies.
And they're pissed you're
desterilizing all their equipment.
What else was I supposed to do?
I haven't been able to
get on a surgery all day.
Before I left, there were five people
to compete with, and now there are 25.
You'll get in the
OR soon enough.
You know, there was a
moment, for like five seconds,
when hit-by-a-bus guy wasn't George,
and Izzie had just come through surgery,
and you and I had
just done our Post-it.
Mm-hm.
Five seconds when everybody
was happy. I keep closing my eyes,
- trying to get back to that.
- Here. Turn around.
Close your eyes.
One.
Two.
Three.
Four.
Five.
- How was that?
- Almost perfect.
Five almost perfect seconds.
Call me when you
want five more, OK?
Stevens?
Results of the spinal tap.
They're normal. Damn it.
I'm sorry for wasting your time.
Dr. Singer?
Isobel?
Isobel Stevens? Oh, my God!
- Look at you, all grown up.
- I am?
What...? What am I doing here? Why
am I in my pajamas? Is something...?
Is there something
wrong with me?
- He's lucid.
- Go page Shepherd.
Dr. Bailey? Do you mind if I
scrub in on the chief's ileostomy?
Yes, I do mind. That man is
old enough to be your father.
- Dr. Bailey, have you
seen the chief?
- No! Uh-uh...
You don't need to be seeing
the chief, either one of you.
But something's wrong with
his emergency chole patient.
OK. So you tell me,
and I'll tell the chief.
- What's wrong with him?
- He's yellow.
Oh.
This is the yellowest
man that I've ever seen.
- Right? He's lemon-yellow.
- Like, mustard-yellow.
We get it, he's yellow!
I'm trying to find out why.
Ultrasound shows dilated ducts.
Which means obstructive jaundice, but
the chief only took out the gallbladder.
We never saw any signs
of liver disease or cancers.
Could that mean...?
- Chief clipped
the common bile duct?
- Oh, my God!
OK, stop. Right
now. Both of you.
Did you actually see the
chief clip the common bile duct?
- No, of course not. But...
- But nothing.
That's one of the most serious
mistakes a surgeon can make.
So let's not make
this accusation lightly.
- It wasn't an accusation.
- Stop talking.
Just get an ERCP to find the exact
cause of this man's... discoloration.
And doctors? If I find out that either
of you has said a word about this
to anyone, I will make sure that you are
the ones who require emergency surgery.
You have a condition called NPH:
normal pressure hydrocephalus.
It's a buildup of cerebrospinal fluid
in your brain, very hard to diagnose.
- But thanks to Dr. Percy...
- The spinal tap removed
some fluid,
relieving pressure in your
brain, resolving symptoms,
which is how we
came to your diagnosis.
- Hmm.
Dr. Shepherd wants to
put in a permanent shunt.
It'll drain the excess
fluid to the abdomen.
That sounds like major surgery.
It's 45 minutes. It's a very common
procedure. I do it all the time.
Hmm.
I don't think I could afford it.
My savings, my retirement...
It all went to my late
wife's medical care.
So...
What do I do?
- Dr. Shepherd.
- Stevens?
I hate to ask this of you
after everything you've done,
but is there any way Dr. Singer's
surgery could be pro bono?
If you get the chief to sign off on
this, I'd be happy to donate my time.
- You don't think it's Bailey?
- No!
Really? I kinda
like them together.
- It's not Yang?
- What are you talking about?
You haven't heard? The Chief...
Mark, you are a terrible gossip.
- I'm an excellent gossip.
- Mind if we join you?
- No. Have a seat.
- Not at all.
How's your first day? You
ready to go back to Baghdad yet?
I'm actually really impressed.
The facility, the equipment,
- caliber of residents.
- Have you met Cristina Yang?
Mmm. Cristina Yang may, in fact,
be the best resident I've ever seen.
- You think?
- Yeah. I do.
I don't think she
likes me, but yeah.
- Ooh. She doesn't like you?
- Mark.
No, you're probably right.
Just because Yang drove off
the last three Cardio attendings...
- She did not.
- Burke.
- Come on, that...
- Hahn.
She had nothing to
do with Hahn leaving.
No, that was me.
- Dixon.
- Cristina just needs
a strong Cardio attending. She
deserves a strong Cardio attending.
Cristina? Huh. Wow.
So... So you and Yang?
- What happened to you and Beth?
- He didn't tell you?
Beth showed up at the hospital one
day. She didn't even know he was...
Ow!
- Did you just kick me?
- That was me.
So... wait.
When you called me up and told me about
this great job at this great hospital,
you were just bringing me out here
as a present for your new girlfriend?
It is a great job
with great people,
one of whom just
happens to be...
Yeah. Yeah.
That's OK. I'm not mad. I'm
just gonna enjoy all the ways
you'll have to make it up to me.
OK.
So how do you like your present?
Who, Private Benjamin over there?
Owen said she would surprise me.
Well, guess what? Surprise! She
doesn't know how to do surgery.
- Leave her alone,
it's her first day.
- Why are you defending her?
- She went to a state school.
- So did I.
- She's skinny and blond.
- So is Mer.
- She's annoying.
- So are you.
Where is your wife, by the way?
Uh... What did you say to Owen?
That she's gotta go.
He knows how important this is. I need
someone to take me to the next level,
and he brings me this
Desert Storm Barbie
who hasn't seen the inside
of an OR in ten years?
I mean, if this is what he thinks of
my talent, I gotta break up with him.
Have you talked to Izzie
yet? Has anyone talked to her?
You know what? No one's
allowed to talk about Izzie while I eat.
Am I the only one
who's concerned here?
- What?
- It's my first day back.
I wanted to have a
normal lunch together.
Oh, yeah. Take a look around.
Nothing's normal.
- It's a 45 minute surgery.
- It's a $10,000 surgery.
And this hospital has
a pro bono budget.
You are no longer a doctor here.
And you have no right to come in here
and commandeer a clinic, a neurosurgeon
- and a resident.
- I gave you eight
million dollars
to build that clinic that you
happily accepted at the time.
So I have no problem going to
the board or the press if I have to
to get Dr. Singer
the surgery he needs.
Where did you work with Jordan
Hamlin? She's been at Stanford forever.
Jordan Hamlin and I were bunkmates
at Camp Taka-toka when we were 11.
That girl can make
a mean lanyard.
You guys paged
me? What's going on?
This is Casey, age
eight, asthmatic.
- Nebs at home
haven't been working.
- We added steroids,
- but he's having
trouble breathing.
- Casey, I'm Dr. Robbins.
- I'll look at your X-rays. You mind?
- No, go ahead.
Hey, Casey. Just
gonna take a listen.
- Dr. Altman, are you...?
- Trying to concentrate,
Dr. Yang.
Has Casey had any
other medical issues?
A febrile seizure
at three months.
OK. Can you sit up for me?
Did he scream a lot when you
brought him home from the hospital?
Yes.
Has his asthma gotten better
or worse as he's gotten older?
- Worse.
- OK. Thanks.
- Book an OR.
- What? Why?
- Because I said so.
- But he has asthma.
- Cardiac asthma, Dr. Yang.
- And you know that because...
That seizure he had?
It wasn't from a fever.
He had a heart attack then,
and he's having one now.
Book an OR, because I'm your attending,
and when I tell you to book an OR,
book an OR!
I like her.
I'm going to say a name. And
then you are going to tell me
you are not having
an affair with her.
- Izzie Stevens.
- What?
That's why you ignored the DNR.
That's why you fired her.
That's why the two of
you were in your office
screaming at each other
just... It is not funny, chief!
That girl has cancer
and a husband and...
OK, I know it's none of my business,
but it's now affecting people's lives.
Patients' lives.
What's this?
It's the ERCP results of your
emergency chole this morning.
It seems that you may have
accidentally clipped the common bile duct.
- How's the patient?
- Stable, for now.
I told Grey and Adamson
to prep him for a repair.
Which I'm happy to
do, if you don't feel...
We caught it early enough that,
if we can repair the duct, there
should be no long-term damage.
No one knows about this, sir.
And no one's going to know.
But whatever it is
that's distracting you,
whoever or whatever it is,
I just hope you get
a handle on it soon.
- The birds on your
scrub cap are cute.
- Thank you.
- Is he on full bypass?
- Yes.
See the anatomy here?
Coronary artery is attached to
the pulmonary artery, not the aorta.
It presented as
asthma, but it's ALCAPA.
How did you know?
You only listened to him and
asked his mom a couple questions.
I saw some cardiomegaly
on his X-rays,
and heard a holosystolic
murmur through wheezing.
You'll know for next time.
And after today, Dr. Yang,
you'll know how to fix it.
Me? I...
- I thought you
and Dr. Robbins were...
- Dr. Robbins,
- do you mind if
Dr. Yang first-assists?
- Not at all.
Maybe we'll both
learn something today.
The guy Izzie brought in has
NPH. Derek's operating now.
I snuck her into the
gallery so she can watch.
So if you want
to go talk to her...
- OK?
- Just explain her to me, OK?
Because I don't
get it. I don't get her.
And I do? I'm like you.
She's bright and shiny, after everything
she's been through. I don't get it.
But you're the one who married her,
so you're the one who has to figure it out.
I can't solve everything.
I lost the better part of my
liver trying to solve everything.
So if you want an explanation,
you have to go talk to Iz.
OK. Here we go. The moment of
truth. Let's see Dr. Yang's handiwork.
- V-fib on the monitor.
- - Thank you for that update.
The bleeding's behind
the coronary anastomosis.
My Anastomosis. What'd I do?
It doesn't matter what you did.
What matters is what are
you going to do to fix it?
Feel free to jump
in here at any time.
You can do this. Tell
me what you want to do.
- I want to defibrillate.
- Then defibrillate.
I'll unclamp.
Charge to 20. Clear!
Nice.
Now, keep your eyes on the
field and do exactly as I say.
We're gonna try to fix this without
rearresting the heart. You with me?
- Yes.
- Good.
You need to apply a suture
proximally and distally.
Good. Dr. Avery,
are you watching this?
- There will be
a quiz afterward.
- Believe me, I'm watching.
Good.
- So are you back or...?
- Oh. Did you want me
to come back?
Because you told the chief you had
serious doubts about my abilities...
- What?
- You went behind my back
and told the chief I
wasn't ready to be here.
He was making cuts.
I was protecting you.
- You got me fired, Alex.
- Is that what you think?
This job was the
one thing I had left.
The one thing, and you
took that away from me.
You interfered and got me fired.
I have forgiven
you for a lot, Alex.
I've had to forgive you for a lot,
but I cannot forgive you for this.
You made an assumption.
You decided I did something.
You didn't ask. You
didn't hang around to talk.
I am your husband, and you didn't
give me the benefit of the doubt.
So you know what? I
can't forgive you, either.
Chief, you all right?
- You did the repair?
- Yeah. No complications.
We're hoping for a full recovery.
And, like I said, nobody knows.
I'm not having an affair.
Well, what is it,
then? Is it the merger?
Is it Jennings and the
board, or you and Shepherd?
'Cause your wife is right.
There's something going on.
I've decided to take a step
back from surgery for a while.
- There's no reason to do that.
- I've got enough on my plate
as chief.
I can't afford another mistake.
I'd like you to take over my
surgeries for the time being.
- Chief...
- If you don't mind.
- How's the patient doing?
- Mmm. Perfect.
It's like someone just
switched the lights on.
Dr. Shepherd said you did great.
We can get you home, get
you out of that nursing home.
You could go back
to teaching if you want.
Are you crazy? I'm never going back
to those sex-crazed, teenage alcoholics.
- No way.
- OK.
- What are you gonna do then?
- I don't know.
But... thanks to you,
I have a few more mental
faculties to figure it out with.
How about you?
I don't know yet, either.
You're still my best student.
Let's get you home.
- Guess what I did today?
- Whatever it was,
it's better than getting surgeries
stolen by Mercy West residents.
It was. I did a Takeuchi repair.
- You did not.
- Not all by myself.
But Altman did let me do the
coronary artery anastomosis.
- Wow. Maybe she is
a Cardio god.
- Yeah, I know.
Here are tomorrow's surgeries.
We can go over them in the morning.
What...? What's going on?
The chief's taking some time
off from surgery for a while.
- Because he's having an affair?
- Because of the merger.
He's not having an
affair! He's exhausted.
Now, I've lost my work-husband
and my husband-husband.
- So I'll be your work-husband.
- You already have Sloan.
That's true. What
about Shepherd?
Are you kidding? All that hair?
I can't be looking at that all day.
- Hey.
- So...
- Mm-hm.
- Cristina Yang...
- Yeah.
I probably should've told you,
but I didn't want to bias you.
I didn't want you
to favor her for me.
I just wanted her to
stand on her own talent.
When did you break up with Beth?
Um... Well... I don't know,
that was a while back.
I thought you
would've called me.
- Oh, God.
- What?
I guess it really
was all in my head.
- What? What was in your head?
- Nothing. Nothing! I just...
I... I... I always thought that if
you and Beth ever broke up,
that I... I just... I thought
that you would call me.
- Teddy...
- It's OK, Owen.
It's OK. I clearly made
up this whole story.
I mean, it was... It
was a good story.
It was all tortured and
Bridges of Madison County.
And...
It's all right. I...
Now I know, and...
I can...
I can let that story go.
Good night.
Hey!
Mmmm! Thank you for my present.
And I'll try to get over
the birds on the scrub cap.
Teddy's best friend,
she was this bird person.
- She loved birds.
- Really?
And...
Well, she died in
the second tower.
That's why Teddy gave up her
attending position at Columbia
and she joined the Army.
I told you she'd surprise you.
Thank you.
Sometimes, the past is
something you just can't let go of.
I think she'll be back.
And sometimes the past is
something we'll do anything to forget.
You want to keep drinking?
Another club soda, Joe?
You're going home after
this or back to the hospital?
Another club soda, then home.
I'm gonna need your keys.
I'll call you a cab
when you're ready.
- Richard's not - Talking to me.
- What? Why?
He's not himself.
You've been drunk a few
days. I was drunk for years.
What happened?
There was a time you would
have convinced me to do this.
Now your first instinct is
no? What happened to you?
For every miscalculation
you think you see,
there have been a hundred things
I've gotten right, and no one knows.
There is no one who understands
and cares more about Seattle Grace...
I'm still the chief of
surgery at this hospital.
Then start acting like it!
You have a disease, Thatcher.
When you're in
it, you can't stop.
That has been the system that
has been in place since this merger.
- Your system.
- You're fired.
Immediately. Get the
hell out of my hospital.
Please don't do this to me.
I don't have anything left.
- Please...
- - It seems that you may have
accidentally clipped
the common bile duct.
And sometimes we learn
something new about the past...
that changes
everything we know...
about the present.