- Previously on The Resident...
- Hey, it's a long story,
but everything's
gonna be just fine.
This is not on you or her.
I knew she was exhausted...
Focus on what you can do now.
Would it be moving too fast
if I invited you
to Thanksgiving?
I spend Thanksgiving
with my family.
Maybe there's something
we can work out.
Jessie's gone, and
she is not coming back.
You're all I got, kid.
We're Team Nevin, now.
On a first-name
basis with Dr. Cain?
We go way back... he's
the one who got me this job.
You have no background
in health care?
I have a background...
in profits.
If I were back home in
Queens, I would be playing
flag football right now.
But you're not living
your Thanksgiving
- traditions because...
- Intern year.
The only major holiday I've
gotten off is Presidents' Day.
- Mm.
- How about you?
You here for Jessica?
Yeah.
She sent her family
back home to Tennessee
to care for her
Great-Grandma Addie.
Man versus turkey fryer...
40-year-old male with full
thickness burns on his left leg.
Okay, Bay Three.
Ow, my leg! God, it hurts.
I swear I just thought
using a turkey fryer
would cook a frozen bird faster.
Fryers make frozen
turkeys explode.
Over and under on turkey-related
injuries today is at a 12.
You're on... 50 on the over.
You'll see, Pravesh.
Thanksgiving is the most
dangerous holiday of the year.
And retractor.
After we're done, there's
an orphan potluck here.
I went last year... We
all said our gratitudes
and everything.
Family Thanksgivings are hell.
Orphan Thanksgivings are worse.
But what-what's worse than hell?
Small talk with
strangers. Dry stuffing.
Drunk Aunt Sally getting
handsy under the table.
Not my aunt.
For me,
being in the OR is
the perfect holiday.
No interruptions.
No CEO duties.
No rushing to get to meetings.
To celebrate the
holiday for giving thanks,
I'd be so grateful if
you'd let me close.
♪ ♪
Thank you.
Is Howlin' Wolf too
throaty for Thanksgiving?
Maybe Miles is a safer choice.
Don't stress over
music genres, Gussie.
The genre is key, Mom.
And stress is a given.
I'm meeting my
biological brothers
for the first time.
You're meeting my bio parents.
I know Austins
don't scare easily,
but this one is quite terrified.
Baked yams cure all... taste.
Nah, I'm-I'm good, Pops.
Acid reflux kicking up.
Ah, hmm.
Mm.
- Hmm?
- Mmm, delicious.
- Mm-hmm, of course.
- What's AJ so worried about?
Oh, he's afraid his new
brothers aren't gonna like him.
No, I'm afraid they're not
gonna like Miles Davis.
Don't be silly...
Everybody likes Miles.
Mm-hmm.
I'll make you some ginger
tea to settle your tummy.
Mm-hmm.
That's your daddy.
Yeah.
♪ ♪
♪ Well, my heart
was a long time... ♪
I like it, I like it, but, uh...
"sexy Thanksgiving"?
That's a bit misleading.
You don't think this is sexy?
Eh...
No work.
No family.
Nobody to clean up after.
Just takeout, movies,
and if you're up for it...
My mistake... so sexy.
See, see? Sexy Thanksgiving
is the perfect
way to give thanks.
♪ My will is ♪
♪ Fading... ♪
Did you already order takeout?
Nope.
Surprise!
Happy Turkey Day, Nicky!
Dad, uh, I thought
you went fishing.
Nah, the fish will
wait till tomorrow.
I know how much you
hate cooking on holidays
and cleaning up after,
so I came to take over
and simplify things for you.
Ooh!
This is Sadie.
Hi!
She's my sous chef.
Hi, Happy
Thanksgiving, everyone!
- Oh, thank... thank you.
- Here you go.
- Hey.
- Oh, it's beautiful.
Wow.
♪ ♪
- Yeah.
- Can you think of something
that isn't made better
with a twist of lemon?
Off the top of my head, no.
Thank you.
- There you go, Dad.
- Oh, thanks.
Mm-hmm.
I hope it's okay
that we're here.
Yeah, yeah, it's fine.
I'm happy to see you, uh, but...
who's Sadie?
My friend. She's my friend.
No! Nic, no, no, no.
I-I promise, I swear to you
my inappropriate dating
years are long over.
Mm-hmm.
How did you meet her?
She came in ODing on oxy.
They saved her, but...
it was some scary stuff.
But you know what they say.
Addicts have to find
their rock bottom.
And she did.
She's been clean a month.
So this is her first
drug-free Thanksgiving?
Yeah.
You know how hard
the holidays are for addicts.
And their families.
Right.
And I'm sure she has to
make amends with hers.
I just need to get her
through today clean.
I know, I know.
Sober is her choice.
I just, I just want
to support her.
And what better way to do that
than a nice dinner
with you and Conrad?
Well, you should know
we're ordering takeout
from Trina's Taqueria.
Trina's "what-eria"?
No! Come on, no.
We got to do the real
McCoy... A turkey, all the fixings.
You got to do a
proper celebration.
- It's Thanksgiving.
- Dad,
there is literally zero
food in this house.
Well, I can handle that.
- Sadie.
- Yeah?
Got to get ourselves a turkey.
- Okay.
- And some stuffing, some
- cranberry... Let's make a list.
- Okay.
Right back.
You know, I could
just talk to Kyle
and gently suggest
he and his friend
celebrate somewhere
else so we can
return to sexy Thanksgiving.
Thank you, but...
it is our first holiday
without Jessie.
Mm-hmm.
Maybe he needs family.
And I'm afraid that is us.
Yes, it is.
And I wouldn't want
it any other way.
Aren't you supposed to be at
Denise's, meeting her family?
Yeah, that was the plan.
Asked her to
marry me last night.
- Congratulations.
- She did not say yes.
- Oh.
- Apparently she's...
in love with somebody else.
Ooh... Sorry, man.
But it sounds like
you dodged a bullet.
Could be worse.
Though I can't see how.
Happy Thanksgiving.
- You, too.
- VIP, Bay Ten.
One of you admit him before
the paparazzi shows up.
- What do we have?
- Who do we have?
Oh, my God, that's
Delandre Harris.
Mr. Harris, it is a pleasure
- to meet you.
- My man.
Your Sensitive Darth
Vader impression
is the funniest
thing I've ever seen.
I would do it for you,
but I got something
jamming the pipes, man.
- I'm sorry, sir.
- Mm-hmm.
Did you swallow
something, Mr. Harris?
- Mashed potatoes.
- D...
you're supposed to be eating
mashed cauliflower,
not potatoes.
Manage my career,
not my meal plan.
I'm a grown man sneaking out
to the kitchen to inhale
some leftover mashed potatoes.
Don't judge me.
You've been there.
We've all have.
- Hey, I'm a stuffing guy.
- I feel you.
Hell, with a little
-bit of gravy on
that thing, -Mmm.
All goes down smooth.
Except it didn't,
'cause something
was in them damn potatoes.
And now it's all
jammed up in my throat.
Damn achalasia, man!
When was your esophageal
disease diagnosed?
A few years ago.
Even with a few procedures,
it still worse than ever, Doc.
Let me take a look, okay?
Mm-hmm.
Open up and say ah, please.
Ah!
It looks clear.
Mm-hmm.
I feel crepitus.
Air where it shouldn't
be, so whatever you ate
caused a perforation.
You sure you can't just
butter up what's in there
and just yank it
up out of there?
- No! No yanking.
- Come on, man.
Delandre needs his voice
- when all this is over.
- All right.
Let's start you with
an X-ray, okay?
- My man.
- All right.
All right.
Gobble gobble?
Gobble?
Not funny?
You've done better.
Oh, honey, don't be gloomy.
My family's gone and I always
spend Thanksgiving with them.
And here I am, looking like
a freakin' lollipop
and getting ready
- to watch football all alone.
- I'll be here.
I promise... my shift
ends in a few hours.
You hate football.
Love football.
First and ten, Astroturf,
Peyton Manning, "Da Bears."
You're so cute
when you're clueless.
You know, football is
very serious business
in my family... My Uncle
Larry once punched
my dad in the face, 'cause
he forgot his lucky socks,
and he ended the
Cowboys' winning streak.
No.
Go. Your patients need you.
Just like my Grandma
Addie needs my family.
I promise I'll
stop feeling sorry
for myself and I'll be grateful.
I'm grateful you're still here.
Me, too.
So grateful.
Even with this sad little
screen to watch football
and this hideous helmet
covering the scars on my head.
I'll be back as soon as I can.
Okay.
Hang in there.
That is an intact
turkey wishbone.
How do you swallow
a wishbone whole?
However it went in,
the only one way it's
coming out is surgery.
And it's not as simple as
repairing the perforation.
Might have to remove
the esophagus.
You want to break it to
the patient or should I?
Looks like Red Rock's latest
golden boy's already at it.
Mr. Harris, I have personally
interceded so you get the best.
Dr. Torres here is a
magician in the OR.
A magician, huh? Just
make sure you don't
pull no rabbit out my
throat, you hear me?
That's a good one, man.
I have to have Delandre
back on set Monday.
Shouldn't be a problem at all.
Mr. Kim,
a word.
Yeah.
- Mm.
- Excuse me.
So glad you're here.
TMZ is outside.
I'm going to introduce
them to Torres,
and it would be a nice touch
to have the chief of
surgery by my side.
Mr. Harris is my patient.
- Not anymore.
- This is
a medical decision.
I'm the chief of surgery.
Ergo, it's my
decision, not yours.
The patient's achalasia
makes the esophageal
repair complicated.
Torres is a brilliant surgeon.
To sign him, we won a
bidding war with five hospitals.
- He's a star.
- I'm well aware.
Then you should also
be aware that it's my job
to keep him here, and that
means to make him happy.
Even with a
reputation for brilliance,
a famous patient
is not appropriate
as a trial run for
a new surgeon.
Torres is young,
charismatic and diverse.
He is the story
that we want to tell
to the cameras waiting
outside that door.
But if something goes wrong,
it's a PR nightmare,
which we can't afford.
Don't tell me how to do my job.
I have been the spine of
this hospital for over a decade.
And amply demonstrated
it's too much for one doctor.
A top tier of surgeons is going
to lead this hospital forward.
I sincerely hope you can
be one of them, Dr. Bell.
- Elf? Really?
- How could you not love Elf?
- How can you not love Die Hard? "Yippee-ki-yay."
- Okay,
- Planes, Trains
and Automobiles.
- Sold.
- I love John Candy.
- All right.
Hey, Nic? Where's
your turkey roaster?
Coming.
Put the movie on.
Oh! Hey there, neighbors.
- The boys here to feed
the chickens? Come on in.
- Hey.
I was actually hoping you
wouldn't mind taking a look
- at Tommy.
- Yeah, of course.
Sorry to impose,
but Barbara's visiting
her family in Long Island.
Tommy's been coughing, and...
- I mean, it's probably nothing.
- No problem, Anthony.
I'm happy to take a look.
He's a little warm.
Did you call his cardiologist?
I tried, but he's
away for the holiday
and... isn't returning calls.
Now, let's see what
we got going on here.
Dad?
Is Tommy gonna be okay?
Hey. Don't worry, Ryan.
Your little brother's
in good hands.
Who pushes someone through
a plate glass window over a toy?
Delusional, selfish,
narcissistic helicopter parents.
Sorry.
Just...
I'm just worried about Jessica.
She's going stir-crazy.
It's not unusual after spending
that much time in the ICU.
It's called post-ICU PTSD.
Yeah. I know.
Doesn't help me fix my
woman's crappy Thanksgiving.
Dislocated shoulder. Bay 11.
Backyard football gone wrong.
Mm-hmm.
You were definitely right
about it being the
most dangerous holiday.
Why'd you page me?
Our splenectomy
isn't for another hour.
I'm reassigning
you to assist Torres
on Delandre Harris'
esophageal repair.
Torres? I thought
you were doing it.
I decided to be a team
player. Torres is taking the lead.
I just want him to have
the best assist he can
on such a high-profile case.
You want me to spy on him.
Yeah.
Just find out if he's as
good as Kim thinks he is.
Morally questionable.
But it's a cool case,
so I'm in.
Bonnie, you see this house?
Our boy's done well for himself.
Maybe we should've put
all our kids up for adoption.
AJ's in a different life
stage than our sons.
Look, Lamar, I know you
mean well with our sons.
Just, please, for today, give
Camron and Marcus less advice
and more praise.
Well, I am desperately
looking for something to praise.
Believe me.
Don't say things
like that, for example.
- I was kidding.
- Well, get your kidding out
before Marcus and
Camron get here.
They're meeting their
full biological brother
for the first time.
It's a delicate situation.
And remember, they're grown.
They don't have to spend
their holidays with us anymore.
Are you kidding me?
A purple man bun?
Just leave it.
They're here.
- We got this, son.
- Don't worry.
Your brothers would be fools
not to love you as much as we do.
Everything's gonna be wonderful.
So, um,
Marcus, Camron,
are either of you in the
medical field like your mom?
Well, Marcus is at Atlanta
Community College.
But he... will be
graduating this year.
Is he really though?
Been giving us that
same line for five years.
You literally dance
on street corners, bruh.
'Cause that's where
hip-hop lives, bruh.
Well, how 'bout that turkey?
You need any help, Carol?
'Cause I got great
hands. Put 'em to work.
Well, uh, Yee is the
chef in our family.
He's incredible.
No turkey. Duck.
That sounds wonderful.
Well, that's one way
of doing Thanksgiving.
The Austins celebrate
our multicultural heritage
by having my father's
most revered dish.
Peking duck. It's
a Chinese delicacy.
Bro, you're not Chinese.
Genetically
speaking, you're right.
But, culturally, my
father raised me
with a deep love of Chinese
heritage and tradition,
so, actually, I'm
about as Chinese
as any third-generation
Asian kid with a black mom.
With his heart defect, it's
good that you brought him over.
I need to get him to the ER,
where I can give him
a more thorough exam.
Oh, my God. Should we call 911?
We're so close.
It's faster if we drive.
I'm going with
you. I'll call ahead,
- so they'll be waiting for us.
- Okay. Come on, Ryan.
Okay.
I will be back as soon as I can.
Leave the kitchen
for me to clean.
I'm fine. Go.
That doesn't sound good.
I'll deal. Go.
Make sure Tommy's okay.
Oh!
Blackwell Award for Science.
Glad to know you
inherited my scientific brain.
Which I am grateful for.
He had an early start,
growing up in Yee's kitchen.
Cooking is chemistry.
Which I am also grateful for.
Bonnie, if you don't mind.
We need AJ over here.
- Something's wrong with Yee.
- What's up?
I am fine, son.
Dude can't stop smiling.
Maybe it's the first signs
of a stroke or something.
I mean, nobody's
this happy all the time.
Actually, Pops is, all the time.
Whoa. Oh!
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Here, let-let me help you with that.
Oh, I'm sorry. My bad,
man. We're just trying to find
the soundtrack to this circus.
You feeling some '90s hip-hop?
Come on, Cam. Just
pick Dad's favorite R&B.
What do you got, AJ?
Hey!
Look, whatever you decide,
let me put the delicate
vinyl on the turntable
with my own two
hands, all right?
Each of these
records is a work of art,
and they deserve to be
handled appropriately.
What you doing, an
impersonation of Dad?
No, man, I think
that's just who he is.
Conrad. What's up?
I'm on my way.
Was that the hospital?
Yeah, I just got called in.
It's urgent. It's an emergency.
Well, looks like the party's
over. We can all go home.
Nice meeting everyone.
Sit down, boys.
How long do you think you'll be?
It's impossible to say. But I
will be back as soon as I can.
And everyone is welcome to stay.
Well, hopefully,
it's a false alarm
and you can return quickly.
- Hey, you gonna be okay?
- Of course.
Go. Save a life.
- All right.
- Just, uh,
get back here as
quick as you can,
okay, son?
I will.
♪ ♪
My college squad and I went
on an ayahuasca vision quest
for Thanksgiving.
I volunteered to
carve the turkey, but...
Hallucinogenics
and sharp objects.
Not a great combo.
- Can you wiggle your fingers?
- Yeah.
- But it hurts real bad. It...
- Mm.
Dude, has anyone ever told you
you have incredible pores?
Clean,
but tight.
But clean.
Definitely still hallucinating.
Joey, you're gonna need
to ride out your trip, okay?
Let's take a look here.
Hustle! Got to
get out right now,
- we got additional vics.
- Copy that. Go, go, go. Come on.
Hundley, did Dr. Hawkins
arrive with that boy yet?
- They're landing any second.
- All right.
Happy Thanksgiving, Dr. Austin.
Hey, back at you.
What are you grateful for?
A job where I am in demand
and far away from family.
Hey, would you make sure
there's a pediatric crash
cart in Trauma Bay 11?
Already taken care of.
Hey.
I'm grateful for you.
I'm grateful for you, too.
Austin, it is good to see you.
- In here.
- What's the update?
Two episodes of
syncope in the car.
I'll get him on the monitor.
Get an IV.
Let's get him on oxygen.
His heart rate is 150.
I think it's atrial flutter,
but it's hard to tell.
Trial of adenosine?
Get the pads.
We need to cardiovert. Now.
Oh, my God.
Let's give them
some space to work.
- Did Tommy's heart just stop?
- Come on, Ryan.
- No! No, my brother's dying.
- He's not dying.
Dr. Austin is taking very
good care of Tommy.
I promise. Come on.
All right, charge to 17.
- Clear.
- Tommy!
All right, let's try it again.
Charge to 33. Clear.
It's gonna be okay.
Did something fall?
Yeah. Yeah, your father.
He's terrible at the moonwalk.
She's right, and I
should be able to do this.
The '80s was my decade.
All right, come on.
Are you okay, Dad?
Yes, fine. I'm fine.
Everything except for my pride.
I guess I should
give up my dreams of
dancing for Alvin Ailey.
No, no, no, I want to see this.
- No. No.
- You got this. One more time.
- Okay.
- All right. One-one more.
One more. Here we go.
Oh, my God.
Okay, that's walking backward.
- There's no moon involved there.
- You're the one who said
- I got this.
- Yeah, well I was trying
to be supportive.
- I didn't know it was that bad.
- Oh, what? You can do better?
- Hey, floor's all yours.
- Oh, no, no.
Last time I danced, I
sprained my ankle, remember?
Oh, that's right. Family camp.
- Oh.
That number we did
was so embarrassing.
Oh, for all of us. My
mom choreographed it.
Or at least tried to.
Nobody could do her
moves except for Jessie.
Who's Jessie?
Precise anastomosis.
Your handling of the
gastric conduit is so delicate.
At this juncture, it's
all about soft hands.
Do everything possible to
limit trauma to the tissue.
So, how did it go?
He's an excellent
surgeon... Skilled, efficient
and a great
addition to Chastain.
Well, that's great.
Even better.
A perforated gallbladder.
Too much turkey.
It's ours for the taking.
Why does this
holiday turn people
into such gluttonous animals?
I'll book us OR Six.
Third call in a row.
Do you need to take it?
Yes, Lamar.
Yes, I'm still busy.
Listen, you will
know as soon as I do
when I can get back, all right?
Can page another surgeon
if you need to get home.
Thank you, but...
I'm happy where I am.
His Glenn is unobstructed,
but his tricuspid valve is failing.
Because of his hypoplastic
left heart syndrome?
Yeah, and his lungs are already
starting to back up with fluid.
Is he strong enough
to survive surgery?
Certainly not in the
hands of a mere mortal.
But I'll be cutting, so
his odds just inched up.
None of this is ideal.
If the Petersons lose Tommy
today on Thanksgiving...
holidays will
haunt them forever.
I know. I've seen it before.
Is there a way we stabilize him?
We take the chance tomorrow?
Hawkins, I wish there was,
but we don't have a choice.
Without surgery today,
little man will not make
it past Thanksgiving.
His pressure's been tanking.
Hang two liters of LR
and get a bedside lactate.
And page Dr. Bell.
I know, I know.
Don't try to talk.
Okay, hang in there,
Delandre. Hang in there.
Torres said the
surgery went well.
His lactate is through
the roof. Temp is 102.
He's in septic shock.
- Is he okay?
- Get him on Vanc
and piperacillin.
Is this a complication
from surgery?
I'm gonna need imaging
to know that for sure.
- I'll get Dr. Torres.
- I already paged Dr. Bell.
- It's Torres' case.
- Then get him here now.
Linda, let's get
Delandre to CT. Let's go.
It's completely raw.
Well, the oven's
not hot. Is it broken?
It wasn't even turned on.
- What?
- Is Sadie okay?
This isn't her fault.
This was my job. I'm sorry.
I heard you ask
her to handle it.
Why are you covering for her?
Did she just leave?
She probably heard
what you were saying.
Sadie? Sadie,
nobody's mad at you.
- Sadie, get back here!
- Oh, no.
These are my favorite earrings.
Sadie?!
She stole my jewelry.
Don't worry. I'll find her.
- Dad...
- She's gonna pawn your jewelry
to buy drugs.
I got to stop her
before she OD's again.
You'll get your stuff back.
Just let it go. It's not worth
it. You're not gonna save her.
This is a matter
of life and death.
The last time Jessie
used, she almost died.
She is not Jessie.
Don't you see what you're doing?
Look...
I know that you and Jessie
had a special relationship.
You were extremely close,
and it's Thanksgiving, so,
you find this girl, you
bring her here, and she's...
Same age, same issues, but...
Is it a given that
one Nevin will always
screw up Thanksgiving?
I'm sorry.
It's okay.
Look, at least we
have each other, right?
I am sorry.
You need to take care
of this. I understand. I...
Why are you looking
at my patient's scans?
I was paged when he
went septic in the ICU.
- I'm going to book an OR.
- N-No. That isn't necessary.
Dr. Torres is here.
He'll take over.
Delandre Harris is dying.
His gastric conduit is
ischemic, he's in septic shock.
A rare, known complication.
No, agreed. I'm not saying
you did anything wrong.
What's your plan?
I will rebuild his stomach
once I find the best option.
Or we could harvest
part of his colon.
Colonic interposition?
- We-we could do that. That would work.
- Great.
Dr. Torres, get him prepped
right away and take care of it.
Of course it's an incredibly
complicated procedure.
It should only be
attempted by a surgeon
who's performed it many times.
- How many have you done?
- It's a rare procedure.
I've witnessed it a few times,
but I've never performed it.
How many have you performed?
Well, enough that my
techniques have been published.
But that's irrelevant, of
course. I'm a team player.
- It's Dr. Torres' case.
- Dr. Bell, uh,
you're-you're doing
the surgery now.
Ask nicely.
Dr. Bell, please,
will you do the surgery?
Of course.
I'd love to scrub in and watch.
You're welcome to.
Last stitch around the
annulus, and it's all yours.
Nice and tight.
Stitching a heart the
size of a clementine.
Now that is the true
meaning of Thanksgiving.
Yeah, it is.
Reinforce the sutures.
Okay.
Time to take him off bypass.
All right, if this
works, blood should
flow normally through the heart.
- His heart's not beating.
- I have eyes to see.
Paddles to me now.
Clear.
- He's in V tach.
- Give 80 of amio, charge to ten.
Clear!
Come on, Tommy.
I'm gonna get you
back to your brother.
A happy outcome, when I wasn't
sure we were going to get one,
makes the moment of family
reunion so much sweeter.
Yeah.
Ryan's always been so
sweet with his little brother.
So protective because
Tommy's been sick.
Well, you know, they say the
people we love most are the ones
we take care of, not the
ones who take care of us.
- Ah.
- Yeah.
That's why it's been
so hard for Kyle and Nic.
They took care
of Jessie so long,
letting her go... it's...
it's nearly impossible.
You have siblings?
Only child.
I always wished I wasn't.
I'm happy for you.
- Why is that?
- Eh, well,
yesterday you were riding solo,
and then, out of
nowhere, you got brothers.
Yeah, but I don't think you
can manufacture the kind
of relationship those two have
with no shared history.
Your history starts today.
Wow. Well, you know what?
With that shared
wisdom, I'm headed home.
Happy Thanksgiving.
To us all, my man.
We're at 12
Thanksgiving-related accidents.
One more and I win.
We have half an
hour left in our shift.
Let's just call this a draw.
And you should probably head
out to watch the game with Jessica.
Not so fast, Pravesh.
Gentlemen, a patient for you.
Bay Seven.
Is it Thanksgiving-related?
I'll let you decide.
Oh, yeah.
Hi.
I told him it was
bad luck to hang
the Christmas decorations
on Thanksgiving.
I fell off the roof. Ten feet.
And Rudolph and his
bright nose were waiting.
I win.
Oh, no. Christmas-related
doesn't count.
Let's just call this a draw.
There's still time.
Suturing the last piece
of the transverse colon.
Is that enough blood supply?
Yes. Textbooks will
tell you that the left colon
has the best blood
supply for the conduit,
but I find the
transverse colon is best,
particularly in cases like this.
- Less chance of ischemia.
- Mm-hmm.
Your grafting is impressive.
You did nothing wrong, you know.
There was no
tension on the conduit.
The-the anastomosis was
excellent, from what I can see.
Complications happen.
Welcome to attendinghood.
I'm doing a lap
hemicolectomy tomorrow.
Care to join?
I look forward to it.
It's the best I could
do on short notice.
It's perfect.
- I thought we were going to PT.
- We will.
- First I want to
show you something.
- Oh!
There she is.
Hey, girl. How are you feeling?
Love the Bears helmet.
- Nice touch.
- You did all this for me?
I wanted to get you out of the
room. Have some game day fun.
I don't know what to say.
Well, they do. Don't worry. I
vetted everyone in this room.
- Mm-hmm.
- They're fully prepared
to talk all things football.
- Oh!
- Go ahead. Test them.
Mm...
How many yards
are in a first down?
Ten.
Okay.
How many teams
are in the league?
- 32.
- Not bad.
Nolan,
how many players are
allowed on the field?
11 per team. Although,
many consider the fans
to be the 12th man.
Okay. All right, guys,
the game -IRVING: Hey.
- Is starting. That's kickoff.
- Oh. Okay, come on.
Yep, she's up.
You did good, babe.
Thank you.
How's the Jell-O?
As good as Mom's?
Absolutely.
You're a terrible liar.
Mmm.
Hers was like magic.
You think she put a
secret ingredient in there?
I think she was the
secret ingredient.
It's funny, life.
You look right,
and suddenly
everything goes left.
Medical screwup.
She got so sick so fast.
I remember sitting at the
table that Thanksgiving.
We were about to say grace.
I felt her hand was so hot.
Suddenly she's shivering.
She's back in the
hospital, and she...
She never came home.
No wonder we hate Thanksgiving.
I don't know.
Maybe we can turn
this whole thing around.
You can, Nicky.
You got Conrad.
So do you.
When he gets home, let's just...
Let's go to a restaurant,
eat a nice dinner, hang out.
I think I'm just gonna
walk this whole mess back.
You'd have been
just fine if I hadn't...
barged in here.
- That's not true.
- You're sweet.
But I'm exhausted, and I...
I think I'm gonna turn in early.
Are you sure, Dad?
Yes, I'm sure.
Thank you for sharing the
evening with me, sweetheart.
I love you.
Linda? Up his fentanyl to
75 micrograms per hour.
Course, Dr. Bell.
We need to talk.
Throughout the day, your tone...
I saved a man's life.
I also saved Chastain
the embarrassment
of a bad outcome
with a high-profile
patient. I think the words
you're looking for
are "thank you."
I'm not done talking to you.
Happy Thanksgiving, Mr. Kim.
- Mm-hmm.
- Good night, Pops.
All right.
Hey, yo.
You guys leaving already?
Party's just getting started.
Sorry, man, Cam's got a show.
Yeah. Thanks for
inviting us, though.
Safe drive and
happy Thanksgiving.
Wh-What time is the show?
- Huh?
- I mean, I just got here.
I w-I was hoping we could,
you know, we could
hang out for a little bit.
You got time for
a beer, don't you?
Look, man, no
shade, but the thing is,
look, we've been here
for a minute already.
I can have a beer with you, AJ.
Look, I got back
as soon as I could.
My patient was a little
kid. He could've died.
Great, so you saved a
life. We ain't mad at you.
Seriously, we
know how this goes.
Our mom's a doctor. We
learned to make plans around it.
A happy work-life balance
is really what you need.
It's done wonders for Bonnie.
We're not quite at the place
where you get to
criticize me yet, okay?
Criticize? It was advice.
Advice is criticism in
a cashmere sweater.
You can keep both
to yourself indefinitely.
You sound just like your mother.
I was quoting Carol.
She says it all the time.
Bonnie says the same thing, too.
- Both wise women, no doubt.
- Hey,
you never back down
that easy with us.
I'm raising you. I
have to be the bad guy.
I have to say no.
Yeah, you might learn
how to stop saying it.
Be the good guy sometimes.
Maybe.
Well, if you two will come in
and have a drink
with your brother,
I'll lay off you two.
For tonight.
What you think, Cam?
It's your show.
I guess I got time for one beer.
Oh, my boys coming
through for me.
Ah, proud dad right here.
And I'm getting the T-shirt.
You tell your
mother I said that.
- Come on, let's go. Let's go.
All right.
- Camron, thank you, man.
- No problem.
Oh, my. Lookee here.
Oh, August Jeremiah Austin,
you were a troublemaker.
Your mother's been
showing Bonnie
your wall art phase.
Oh, and you didn't stop her?
Look at this
perfectly pudgy face
spreading peanut butter
- all over my brand-new
wallpaper. Oh!
He looks so proud of his work.
He was even prouder
during his graffiti art phase
- when he was almost arrested.
- Hey.
You show me your tag,
and I'll show you mine.
I don't want to see
either of your tags.
Bonnie, I think
we dodged a bullet
by not keeping him.
Lamar!
- What? It was a joke.
- Oh, he's right.
- That was funny.
- It kind of was.
- Too soon, people.
- It was.
Too soon.
Hey.
Let me. It's been a long day.
- You should relax.
- No, it's good.
I'm almost done.
First holiday without Jessie.
You know, she was
such a slob in the kitchen.
Especially at Thanksgiving.
I mean, the worst.
And I was always
stuck cleaning up.
- Every time.
- Mm.
Maybe a bit too much.
I miss her so much.
I'm so sorry.
I'm really glad you're home now.
Can I help?
- Sure.
- Girl-girls,
come on, be careful.
Nicky, why don't you go
help Mom in the kitchen.
- Okay.
- This is the best day, Daddy.
I love Thanksgiving,
and I love you.
This is the best day, Daddy.
I love Thanksgiving,
and I love you.
Captioned by Media
Access Group at WGBH