Freezing. Choking.
Getting tongue-tied.
It's what we call it
when your mind goes
from brilliant to blank.
We should only be
gone a day. Two max.
If you need me before
then, you can just...
Please...
Harriet's dying for some
quality time with her grand mom.
I could've just
taken her with me.
You can prepare all you want.
Aren't you gonna
say, like, "Go, child,
"you're being ridiculous"?
But the feeling can still
hit you, out of nowhere.
If you're having
second thoughts,
we could bring
your patient here.
No, I told you, we've got a...
a girl who needs a throat
transplant and a donor
in the same exact hospital.
We can't risk
moving either of them.
I know.
I just meant...
So when it hits you, when
your mind shuts down,
when you open your mouth
and no words come out,
the good news is...
If you have something
to say, say it.
Nothing.
I'm sure you'll be just fine.
It happens to all of us.
Wait. Where is Grey?
Since when is April coming?
Oh. Grey called to tell
me that Zola has the flu.
And you didn't
think to tell me that?
I knew you'd need a
capable surgeon to assist
- and April's more than capable.
- It's unbelievable.
- Hello. Hi, Catherine.
- Hi.
You have everything you need?
Yes, of course.
Okay. All right.
You ready?
- I'll put her in the car.
- Jackson, go.
Miss Harriet and I have plans.
No medical journals, all right?
I don't need her looking at
flayed open surgical fields.
Give me my child.
Bye, baby.
Can I take your bag, Dr. Grey?
Oh, uh, it's Dr. Kepner.
I'm so sorry. The
manifest said...
It's okay. Dr. Grey got
hijacked by my mother.
This is amazing.
Why have we never
taken your plane before?
It's... it's not my plane.
It's your name right out there.
Right on the wing,
great big letters: Avery.
- Yeah, but...
- So it's your plane.
No, it's the family plane.
- It's not my plane.
- Well, yeah.
It's Catherine's, too. I mean...
I mean, she did make the
Avery Foundation what it is.
Seems right she
should get to fly
- anywhere she wants like this.
- Really?
Can we not talk about
my mother right now?
Yes, I will have some champagne.
You should not
have any champagne.
We are going
straight to the hospital.
- Uh, club soda?
- Same for me, please, Katie.
- Thank you.
- Coming right up.
Welcome, welcome.
Here are your
charts, Doctor Avery.
- Dr. Grey.
- Kepner.
- Right. Sorry.
- I... I know his name
because it's on
all our stationery.
Right.
A patient and a donor,
two of them here together,
same time, same
day, perfect match.
It's like winning the lottery.
I mean, if you call
a brain-dead kid
a lottery ticket, then, yeah.
Of course.
And it's a horrible
loss. Uh, that was...
I'm just thrilled that you're
both here to make this possible.
The donor patient's room
is at the end of this ICU...
And you have the
donor consent forms?
Yeah, before we get to that, uh,
Mr. Young is going to need you
to explain to him why there's
nothing more you can do for his son.
Why? No one's told him that yet?
I thought he knew
we were coming.
Well, he does,
It... It's just that,
he's had a bit of trouble
accepting what's happened,
as I'm sure you can understand.
You told me very clearly
that the patient's
father was on board.
Now, hold on. I never
said that he agreed.
- I merely said...
- So he thinks that we're coming
to save his kid,
not take his organs.
I thought that once you
had examined the boy,
it'd be better coming from you.
I'm just glad you're here.
I mean, Dr. Corridan said
that there's nothing he could do.
Then he said there
was another doctor
who was coming in from Seattle.
I was like, "It's great,"
right? That There's hope.
So, okay. What's the plan?
I mean, you... You...
You wanna do some tests?
Surgery? Obviously,
you want to examine him
but how long before
you think he'll wake up?
- Mr. Young, I'm af...
- Eric, Eric, please.
- Eric...
- It's his birthday.
Did I tell you that?
Double digits, he kept saying.
I mean, he was having the time
of his life up on that mountain.
"Just one more run, Dad...
Just one more run..."
Eric, I'm afraid we
have some difficult news.
We've looked at Brian's
scans, and unfortunately,
Dr. Corridan was right.
There's nothing that
we can do for your son.
Oh my...
Then why are you here?
We are here...
because we wanted
to talk to you about...
donating your son's organs.
No.
You're here...
to help my son.
I understand how
difficult this is...
Difficult? If you understood
what you were
asking, you wouldn't...
- Mr. Young...
- I know what we're asking.
When all you want is to
have him back, to hold him.
I know the thought
of letting any part
of him go feels...
impossible.
You're the only one that
can make this decision.
We understand that.
We wouldn't ask
you to do something
that you're not
comfortable doing.
And if ultimately you don't
want to do this, that's fine.
We are here to
support you, either way.
All I know is...
is when I lost my son...
I just needed to find
a little meaning in it.
Where do I sign?
This way to Caroline's room.
Her parents are very
eager to meet you, Dr. Avery.
This is Risa and Mary Hodges.
Well, it's a pleasure
to meet you both.
Listen, we're grateful
that you're here,
that you came all this way,
but our daughter's
met dozens of doctors,
each one ordering more tests,
putting her through more hell,
making promises they
had no business making...
Mary, maybe let
the guy say hello.
She needs the tumor gone.
But she needs her vocal cords.
She needs her voice.
So if this throat
transplant isn't real...
I mean, if it's just another
rug you're gonna pull out
- from under her, then...
- You're scared.
I totally understand.
Let me, um... let me start over.
It's my fault. I'm Dr. Avery.
I am a double board
certified plastic surgeon
and ENT specialist.
I'm also a dad.
Now, I've come a long way
because I know that I
can help your daughter.
And I do not make
promises that I can't keep.
I just... I still don't know
if this is the right thing.
The laryngectomy
is still the safest...
No, Mary, we agreed. They
are not taking her vocal cords.
What if you go in
there, Dr. Avery...
and you cut open her throat,
and the transplant doesn't work?
In that case, we'd be
looking at a permanent trach.
Permanent. See? And
you want to risk that?
He wouldn't do it if he
didn't think that he could.
- Would you?
- This procedure gives her
the best chance at survival,
at getting her voice back,
her whole life back.
Mary, come on.
Okay.
- Why are you doing that?
- Doing what?
Telling those moms you're a dad
to charm your way into the room,
- using Samuel to...
- It's my life.
- It happened.
- Yeah, it's my life, too,
- but I don't use it to...
- To what?
Help that dad make his decision?
Help those moms find
a little bit of comfort?
April, if you don't like
it, that is your problem.
I'm not the one that asked you
to come here in the first place.
Look, we have tonight
to prep for the surgery.
I have somewhere that I
need to be. I will find you later.
What... where do you need to be?
- It's Montana.
- I'll find you later.
- April.
- I laid out all
of Caroline's charts.
Chinese food is on the way.
I know things are not the
greatest between us right now,
but if we're gonna
do the surgery...
Yeah, no, I need to prep alone.
- I'll talk to you tomorrow.
- Um...
Okay.
Carl!
I thought your doctor said
to cut down on the red meat.
That's why I'm sharing.
You good?
On the house for new customers.
Well, enjoy that.
Hello?
No, this is Dr. Kepner.
No, I don't... I don't know.
Have you tried his room?
I'm sorry. What?
There was a lesion
on the donor's throat,
which means the transplant
is no longer an option.
- I am so sorry...
- Don't tell us you're sorry.
You talked me into this.
You said this was the solution!
And now, I mean,
if there's no donor,
- how do you fix our daughter?
- Mary, please, stop yelling.
If there's a time to
yell, Risa, this is it.
The best way to help
your daughter is to do
- the laryngectomy,
which means...
- No, we know what that means.
That is removing her vocal
cords and her ability to speak.
And we told Dr. Avery
it's not an option.
At this point, I really
think it is her best chance.
And... and what about Dr. Avery?
Is that what he thinks, too?
I don't know where you
are or what you're doing,
but call me!
Damn it!
Oh my... where have you been?
I have been looking
everywhere for you.
Corridan's called a dozen times.
- I have been calling, texting...
- Calm down. You sent one text.
No organs, no surgery, right?
Didn't hear anything after
that, so I figured I'd have a drink.
Uh, battery died.
Well, that's not very
helpful now, is it?
- You're drunk.
- You're pissed.
Yeah, yeah. Uh-huh, I am.
We lost the donor,
Caroline's repeat scans
show more extensive
esophageal invasion,
her parents are a wreck, and...
and you're... you're
here getting drunk?
Jackson.
I got off work,
and I had a beer,
April.
Four beers, actually, and
some whiskey on top of that.
What is wrong with you?
Nothing. Nothing wrong with me.
We have a patient!
- No. Not us, me.
- Who's counting on us!
And there's no organs,
there's nothing I can do,
so just leave me the hell alone.
I mean, this isn't you. You
don't get wasted in bars
- and bail on your pat...
- I didn't bail on anyone!
So, how we doing over here?
- Dessert?
- No, he's going home
to sober up. He has work, right?
In that case, let
me call you a cab.
I'm walking.
Can I get you something?
No, I'm good.
He left his book.
Techniques in
Oropharyngeal Surgery.
Hmm.
Airway reconstruction?
Uh, throat transplant.
Uh, supposed to be
a throat transplant.
It just got scrapped.
Total laryngectomy
not an option, huh?
I was a surgeon. That
was many lifetimes ago.
Really?
You gave that up for this?
Well, this isn't
all that different.
People come to you in need,
you provide them comfort.
They leave here feeling
better than when they came.
And the hours are
better, and nobody dies...
That I know of.
- Welcome to Bozeman, Doctor...
- Uh, Kepner. April Kepner.
Robert Avery.
Avery. I'm, I'm sorry.
Like the hospital?
Kinda. Once upon a time.
Let me know if you
need anything, okay?
I... I will.
We still need to find
a way to help Caroline.
- What time is it?
- It's early.
- What?
- Are you okay?
Yeah, I'm fine.
Hurry up and get dressed.
We should get to work.
Sure.
I hate this. I don't see
how we could do anything,
but the laryngectomy,
but I hate the laryngectomy.
Seems like she'd
have had a better shot
if you'd taken
her to Grey Sloan.
She's not stable enough to move.
- You know that.
- No, not now.
I'm just saying, I don't know
why we had to come
all the way out here.
Do you?
The last time I worked on
a kid with a throat tumor,
we did a staged procedure.
I did a radical excision
and a trach first,
and then we did a skin flap.
She doesn't have
that kind of time.
Yeah, I, I know. I'm just...
And if we'd gotten
to this last night...
Then we still would not have
had enough time for the flap.
I mean, come on.
You made your point.
I was drunk, April. I
get it. I don't need you
- to monitor everything...
- I'm not!
I am just trying to come
up with a fix for our patient,
regardless of the fact that
you don't even want me here.
And yet you're still here.
Cause you and my mother
are such good friends
that she chose you instead
of asking me who I want.
Oh, my God! I was
friends with her long
before you and I were even...
I respect her!
- I respect what she's built...
- Great!
- And what the means...
- Good for you!
You know, your mom
says the difference
between the two of us is
that you were born with money,
and I had to earn it. It's
why she and I are more alike.
You think this is a contest
between you and me?
Who's the most alike?
Who's the most appreciative?
No, Jackson!
That is not the point
- of any of this...
- Shut up.
What? Don't tell me to shut up.
- Are you kidding me with...
- Shut up.
If her airway's collapsed, we'll
have to crike her right away.
Take her straight to the O.R.
Dr. Corridan, what
are we looking at?
The nurses paged us, 911.
What is happening here?
Caroline is being discharged.
What! No, she's not
stable enough to move.
The doctors at
Baylor think she is.
What doctors at Baylor?
The one we called.
I spoke with Dr. Rapkin there.
She has a new method she
believes will help Caroline.
Aggressive chemo radiation
with staged excision
after two weeks.
Yes, we have
already rejected that...
We've gone through
every possible alternative.
Risa, there comes a point
when you just have to hear...
You think I don't hear you?
All of you?
My daughter has no voice.
We are her voice.
We are not gonna let her down
just because we
stopped asking questions.
We asked, you said no.
We're leaving.
They have the right to move
her if they feel it's necessary.
No. It is too dangerous
to move her anywhere.
That girl could choke
on her tumor, okay?
If you move her,
she could die. Period.
Okay. So you... you'll
need to fill out an AMA form.
Uh, legal reasons.
Tell us what you have.
Tell us why we should stay.
We've been down
every road, every one.
There are no other options.
We do the laryngectomy,
Caroline lives.
It's that simple.
We're going to Baylor.
It's what she wants,
what we all want.
We'll fix it. We
will fix her voice.
Listen, what Dr. Avery
means is that...
I have an idea is what I mean.
I told you that I don't
break my promises, right?
I promise you this.
I have an idea that I
think is gonna work.
All right, I'll call
Dr. Rapkin. I will.
I'll call everybody that I can.
This is gonna work, okay?
Give Dr. Kepner
and I a little bit of time
and do not move her.
Please.
We get on a plane
tomorrow at three.
You've got till then.
Okay. So what's your idea?
I don't have one.
- What? You just...
- Yes, I lied,
but they can't move her,
and I just needed
a little more time.
What is the matter with you?
Why are you
torturing this poor girl?
You... You just made a promise
that you know you can't keep,
- that you know we can't deliver.
- We can find a way to deliver.
Where? Where? Where
are we gonna find it?
At the diner?
What?
When are you gonna tell
me that you found your father?
Your father, Jackson, your
long-lost, deadbeat dad.
The distinguished, hippie
former surgeon Dr. Avery,
who slings hash
at the local diner.
He's the whole
reason we're here!
- No, I came here
to help a patient.
- Don't lie to me.
And worse yet, don't lie to
Caroline and her parents.
We are only here 'cause
of your freakin' father,
and now that kid is gonna die.
- Night, night, baby.
- Sleep well.
Be good for Grandma, okay?
- Love you.
- Love you, nugget.
Why didn't you just tell me?
All right.
Forget it.
"You good?"
What?
I sat there, staring at
him across the room.
Figured, you know,
eventually, he'll...
see me, recognize...
something.
My face, my eyes, just...
anything and that's...
all I got was...
"You good?"
Like, literally, that's it.
No recognition, nothing.
Like I was...
anyone.
No one.
- So talk to him.
- Yeah, I tried.
I, I wanted to.
I went, and I sat there...
waited...
I got a million things
to say to that guy.
Thinking about it my whole...
Tell him what an ass he was
for walking out
on his family, his...
kid.
He couldn't hack it as
an Avery. Join the club.
Could still show up.
Pick something...
birthday, graduation.
Show the hell up.
That's what I was
gonna say, all that.
Then, uh...
Then he...
He looked me right in the eye.
He doesn't know his own son.
So make him know you.
- This is stupid.
- No, it's not.
- All right, well, you can go.
- I'm not going.
We're not married.
It's not like who I talk to
or don't talk to is any of
your business anyway.
Yeah, it is my business,
because we have a job to do,
and you're not here.
And you're not gonna be here
till you say what you need to say.
So go say it.
Then it will be over...
and we can get back to work.
Hey, back again.
Sorry, we're closed.
I've got some meatloaf
left over in the back.
I could fix up something
to go if you'd like...
I'm Jackson Avery.
I'm your son.
Oh, my God.
Jackson.
Oh, son.
Oh, Jackson!
Oh, good God!
Oh, my God. Come
inside. Oh, Jackson.
I'm sorry, it's just my brain
is going a little... You know?
You want to sit? Of course
not. You've been sitting.
Why didn't you just... I
mean, I don't blame you, but...
I'm sorry, I do not
know what to say here.
Are you here for work,
too, at the hospital?
You and your friend, uh,
April, was it? The surgeon?
Yeah.
You're a surgeon.
I am, yeah. Plastics and ENT.
Of course. Of course,
you are. Good God.
And your mom? Is she here, too?
This your place?
It gives me a roof over my head
and weekends off to play golf,
food on the table.
Speaking of which...
Oh, wait right there.
My own blend.
I've been working
with these local guys.
Great guys. You'd like them.
I don't know why
I just said that.
I've no idea who you'd like.
Anyway, we're thinking of
opening up a little business
on the side. Nothing
big, you know? Just...
putting it out there for
the tourists and such.
- You're right.
- Incredible, huh?
Chicory.
Listen to me...
yapping away like
some kind of idiot.
Tell me something.
Anything, everything.
I know nothing.
Here.
Here we go.
God, it's good to see you.
Look at you.
I'm head of plastics
and board chair
at Grey Sloan Memorial. I'm...
developing a new
protocol with skin grafts,
- particularly burn victims and...
- No, I'm not talking, um...
Of course you're amazing.
With your mom's
help, your name...
I'm sure you're successful.
No, what I mean is, uh...
What you do, your family.
Are you married?
Kids?
I guess what I'm asking is...
are you happy?
- Yeah, of course.
- No.
Not "of course."
I'm happy.
Are you?
Honestly, yeah. Yeah, I am.
But for me...
the whole Avery thing...
I just couldn't do it.
If it works for you, great.
For me...
the galas, the hand shaking...
it wasn't my thing.
Your thing.
But when I found out what was...
you couldn't drag me away, pal.
From your diner in Montana?
The night that I
met your mother...
it was an...
annual Avery Gala.
I was stuffed in a
thousand-dollar tux
and she...
was the most beautiful
woman in the room...
going toe to toe with some rich
dinosaur about God knows what.
And she had a laugh. Oh...
I introduced myself...
and she ignored me half
the night just to spite me.
I was born into that life,
but she was born for it.
So you took off.
You know your mother.
Her expectations are...
crushing.
How about you don't
talk about her anymore?
I'm sorry.
You're right. She
is your mother...
It's true, she is my mother.
And I don't know you.
Jackson...
- Forget it.
- Listen.
- How'd it go?
- Don't.
- Jackson...
- Just don't ask.
We got to come up with
something to save this girl's voice.
There's got to be
something, right?
You want to talk about it...
what happened with your dad?
You know? Maybe we
could do a staged procedure.
I could excise the
tumor now, we could wait
- on a transplant donor.
- No, it wouldn't work.
She'd need another
course of radiation,
which would make her
a bad surgical candidate.
Yeah.
Yeah, we talked.
He talked, really, a lot.
About how hard it was
being an Avery and...
surgery and...
Temporary stent.
- Erosion and bleeding, right?
- Crap.
He was just so
damn polite, and...
What about, um,
the animal studies?
Okay.
I just kind of clammed
up. I didn't say anything.
Really, he was...
just like...
warm? I don't
know, he was happy!
I definitely didn't picture
him, like, happy without me.
He talked a lot, didn't
say anything about me.
Nothing.
Talked about mom's laugh,
his stupid tuxedo, coffee.
I felt really stupid.
You're not.
Never occurred to me, all
that time, that he didn't even...
He really didn't even miss me.
- You don't know that.
- Oh, I do now.
I really do. It
didn't even occur
to the guy to pretend otherwise.
How do you go up to
somebody and tell them
what an ass they've
been when they're just...
smiling at you, talking
about chicory coffee?
I just stood there with
my heart in my guts...
guts in my throat, whatever
the stupid expression is.
It's heart in your throat.
- No, that's not it.
- Yeah. Yeah, it is.
There's something about guts...
No, you feel it in your gut,
but your heart's in your throat.
What?
That's it. She needs a valve.
Right? She needs something...
- Okay. What is?
- That's it.
Her guts...
for her throat.
And we can use her
own guts for her own...
- throat.
- Throat.
- We lost the transplant, okay?
- Okay.
- We lost the vocal cords.
- Yeah.
All right, so what if...
what if we just
made her new ones?
I mean, what if we just used
Caroline's own intestines
to create her a new valve?
She's already got an
ileocecal valve here.
Right? I could use
her attached appendix,
and... and I could
build a vocal tube.
And she'd be her own donor.
Literally be putting her
own guts in her own throat.
That's still not the expression,
but do you think it'll work?
No. I mean, maybe. Yeah.
Okay, well, which one
you want to go with?
Yeah, I don't think so.
Well, we've
examined all the risks.
We feel like the
benefits outweigh them.
Yeah, the parents have
consented. They both want this.
It's never been done before,
and if something
were to go wrong, or...
Well, that is exactly
where the magic happens.
Okay, it's never
been done before.
- Mm-hmm.
- Until we do it.
Like today. Like right here.
Don't you want to be a
part of this magic, Steve?
Don't you want a
place at the table
when we turn that
young girl's stomach
into an actual throat?
When we make history?
Well, I...
- At the table?
- At the table.
At the table.
I... I still don't know
if I can get approval.
Yeah, well, luckily,
you don't have to.
- I'm sorry?
- It's my name on the hospital.
As an Avery, I officially grant
us permission to make history,
- together.
- At the table.
Exactly.
She is gonna do great.
Dr. Kepner and I will be sure to
update you as soon as we can.
I am giving you as much
love as humanly possible
because you're her doctor...
and I believe in you.
Thank you.
You just make sure
she comes back alive.
You hear me?
If we were back at home,
we'd have a full gallery,
a webcast.
I can't believe
nobody's gonna see this.
I'll see it.
Ah, Dr. Corridan. Join us.
Good luck, doctors.
Here we go.
- Scalpel.
This is gonna work, right?
We did it.
Damn right you did.
I am so tired I could drop.
And yet I am so awake.
That... was...
I know.
Oh, don't even bother.
They'll let us know
when she's awake.
It's gonna be a
couple hours, anyway.
In that case, I'm...
I'm gonna go sleep.
- Like the dead.
- Yeah.
Unless you think we should
go check back in on the patient.
No, no, I think you're
right. I think we should rest.
Maybe we should
go do that, then.
Sure. No, agree.
- That's a good call.
- Okay.
- What?
- I'm just...
thinking about our
track record in hotels.
What about it?
I know why my mother sent you.
Wanted me to have some backup.
She must've figured I was...
probably gonna see
him and knew better
than to try to
talk me out of it.
She wanted me here.
- Just in case.
- That is so...
Catherine.
I was gonna say
infuriating, but yeah.
Jackson, I know
what a good father is.
I've had one my whole life.
You are a good...
father.
You took us both in.
You took care of
her when I couldn't.
And you haven't stopped
taking care of either of us since.
Even with everything that's
happened between us...
you never bailed.
And he couldn't do that.
You came here to
tell him something.
Don't leave till you do.
Hey, hey. Sit, sit. I
got something for you.
I can't stay long.
We're headed out.
I can make you something
for the road, if you want.
I just came to say goodbye.
Okay.
Listen...
I'm really glad you came by.
- Maybe next time, if...
- Yeah, I don't think there's...
gonna be a next time.
Okay.
- Jackson, listen...
- I have a daughter.
Her name is Harriet.
Harriet.
Jackson.
Wow. That is wonderful.
I'm a grandfather.
No.
No, you're not.
My mom's a wonderful
grandmother, and you seem...
like a decent guy.
But you're not a grandfather.
You're not my father.
I figure, when you have a
kid, you're making a promise.
And I don't break my promises.
That's the real difference
between you and me.
- Look, Jackson...
- Take care, Robert.
I'm really glad that I met you.
Goodbye.
Freezing.
Choking.
Getting tongue-tied.
There's a reason it happens.
Take a deep breath now.
Take your time.
Okay. Take your time.
I... ma...
Hi...
Mama.
We lose our words
because the stakes
are so high...
Hey!
And we have so much to lose.
And there she is!
Thanks, Grandma.
- Everything go okay?
- Yeah.
Good.
Jackson said I could
get a ride home?
- Oh, of course, of course.
- Yes?
Come here, little
baby. Good girl.
Hi!
- Thank you.
- Oh, please.
- That's what grandmas are for.
- No.
I mean...
What?
- What, baby?
- Just...
Thank you, Mom.
For everything.
We're petrified of
saying too much
or saying it wrong...
You ready?
Let's go home.
When the truth is,
the only wrong
thing you can say...
is nothing at all.