If you'd like I could come
in for another interview.
As a matter of fact, I
could come in this morning.
Yes, I know. But you
said you were interested.
Well, you... Actually, you
said you were very interested.
Right. But if you could just...
Well...
Right, right, right.
Uh, thank you.
Thank you.
Want some breakfast?
No.
Going over applications? Yep.
I thought you took
the position at Loyola.
Withdrawn. Why?
I don't know. Maybe
because I took another job
somewhere else.
Have you tried
Northwestern? Fully staffed.
U. of C.? What do you think?
Right now, I think
you're being an ass.
You barely say anything.
And when you do, it's rude.
I talk to you, Cleo.
Not about this.
Why don't you let
me help, Peter?
I don't need your
help, all right?
I need a damn job.
I should have left County
when I had a chance.
Out for fresh air?
Man found down.
ETA is any minute.
Ah, they're letting
you work on traumas.
Provided I only handle
two patients at a time.
Really? Weaver's rules.
Ah. Play by 'em or
die by 'em. Thanks.
She didn't exactly ask me if I
wanted to be assigned to the ER.
What are you supposed to
do while you wait for labs?
Catch up on medical
journals. That sucks.
Showtime.
You with me on this one? Yep.
Fifty-year-old male found
in the park. Full arrest.
That's one well-fed bum.
How'd you load him on a rig?
Paid a bunch of
his buddies 5 bucks.
Okay. Come on. Let's go.
One, two, three.
Large lac to the
occipital scalp.
Not sure if he was rolled
or fell out of his tree.
What's he doing in a
tree? Maybe he lived in it.
In asytole. Why didn't
you intubate him?
His neck's like a power pole.
We couldn't find the cords.
It was 40 degrees last
night. He's hypothermic.
We might still get him back.
Oh, yeah? With
what, a blowtorch?
No. Active core rewarming.
Let's set up for pleural
and peritoneal lavage.
I'm in. Bag him.
Who's got scissors?
Good air bilaterally.
So, Carter, you know
anyone who plays hockey?
Nope. Get me some warm blankets.
I need an extra guy for
a game tonight. I'm busy.
Yeah, I was asking
if you knew anyone.
Okay. Looks like
we're in fine V-fib.
Core temp is 86.
So is his pulse ox.
Charge the paddles to 360.
Why? He's a frozen dinner.
Excuse me. Put two
chest tubes in on the right.
Run warm saline
through the rapid infuser.
You're kidding, right? Not
dead until warm and dead.
I'll prep the chest.
32 French okay?
Yep. Okay, everybody clear.
What the hell?
Where did the pigeons come from?
Give me an amp of epi. All
right. Charge again. Clear.
They must have been in
his coat. They're attacking.
Still in V-fib.
Damn it, Dave! Get over here
and do CPR. Charging to 360.
Do CPR? The guy's brain-dead.
Not until I say so. Clear.
A bunch of beauty contestants
were in the salon
getting final touches.
A worker mixed the wrong
chemicals, and boom.
Who's the worst?
Ah, that would be
Audrey Hoffman.
Miss Skokie.
She's got lacerations
and partial-thickness burns
on her legs, and
smoke inhalation.
Hi, Audrey. I'm Dr. Greene.
My legs. Are they bad?
I'm gonna check
your breathing first.
Can you lean forward?
Any shortness of breath? No.
Uh-huh. Any chest pain?
Not really.
Miss Tri-State is tonight. Mm.
Is it bad?
Well... nothing that won't heal.
Does this mean that I'm out?
We're gonna do
everything that we can.
What's your talent?
Rhythmic dancing.
With hoops and ribbons. Mm.
Malik, how many times you
gonna pass by with the same cart?
I got a spot on my hockey
team. Do I look like I play hockey?
What about your pal in
cards? Big East-Indian dude.
Malucci, I can skate.
I played in college,
if you're in a pinch.
Yeah, yeah. Sure thing, G.
Dr. Chen. Hey, hey, hey.
Cute guy, Curtain 3. Daddy
material. Just say thanks, okay?
Oh, Malucci, wait...
Chen. What?
Your mother's been
holding for 10 minutes.
Not very pleasantly,
I might add.
Oh. Just tell her I'm
with a patient. Thank you.
Lying might be part
of your job description.
It's not part of mine.
Yeah. Hello, Mommy.
I... Well, I've been busy.
Morning, Dr. Weaver.
Frank, any messages?
Yeah. Quite a few.
Thank you. Power
meeting today, huh?
Yeah, I have a seminar
that I do not have time for.
Could you remind me
to leave by 6, please?
Seemed like a
good idea at the time.
Superglue.
I hope that's one of two.
The bird man still dead?
It's one of one, actually. Is
there any traumas coming in?
No. But I've got a guy in Exam 3
who cut his hand
on a tin can. Ooh.
Dr. Gottschalk... do
you have a minute?
Uh, unfortunately, I'm on my way
to a conference,
and I'm very late.
I'll make this quick. I'd
like to discuss with you
the faculty position here.
I really have to go.
I just need a minute.
I apologize for bothering
you like this, but...
After you turned us down,
we offered it to someone else.
Well, has it been
accepted? Well, not officially.
Well, then you can withdraw it.
Our candidate's
credentials are excellent.
Well, so are mine.
He has positive
recommendations. And I don't?
I'm not at liberty to discuss
your current standing.
Which means Romano
said something, didn't he?
I can't get into this.
No, what did he tell
you? Dr. Benton...
No. I need to know what that
man said and who he said it to.
You may have difficulty
finding work locally.
That's all I can say. I'm sorry.
It's 1100 hours. Excuse me?
I need to ship out.
Okay. Sir, if you're
waiting for a... A transfer
to another facility... Why
don't we have a nurse help you.
We're taking
Inchon. I... Inchon?
Korea. Huge battle,
if memory serves.
Sorry. He's a wanderer.
What's his story?
Seventy-two years old. From
the Golden Glen Nursing Home.
Altered mental status.
He became combative
and got punched in the nose.
History of dementia?
Uh, no. The military talk
started a few days ago.
Anything on exam?
His nose isn't broken.
But he's got a low-grade temp
with no obvious
signs of infection.
CBC, Chem-7 and UA.
And if his pulse ox is
low, get a chest film.
Ah. Damn tab busted off.
You ever think about
using a can opener?
Yeah, sure. But then what's
the point of having a tab?
I started digging
around the edges there.
Well, it looks to me like
you may need a few stitches.
Of course then the
tuna juice leaks out.
And then it gets
greasy all over.
And then, bam. The knife
goes right into my hand.
I'm going to do a regional
block to numb the, uh, area
around where I'm
gonna be suturing.
You sure you've
done this before?
Sorry. I need some I&D kits.
You might feel a
little burning. Uh-huh.
I'm going to the 8:00
tonight, Abby. How about you?
I don't know. Maybe.
The exact same thing
happened when I tried
to open a milk carton
with a pair of scissors.
The bruises just sort
of sprang up overnight.
That's why I brought
him in here. Hm.
He has Niemann-Pick's Type A.
I have some material here...
if you're not familiar.
Oh, no. That won't be necessary.
Hm, his liver and
spleen are both enlarged.
That's from the sphingomyelin
deposits in both organs.
Yeah, well, a big spleen
chews up platelets.
That's why he's bleeding.
Is there anything we can do?
Well... we can make
him more comfortable.
I'll order an IV and start
him on some morphine.
Would that make him unconscious?
Because I want him to be lucid
for as long as he can be.
Um. It'll be a very
small dose of medicine.
What about the spleen?
You said that's
causing the problem.
Well, if it's taken out, that
might help stop the bleeding,
but... you do know
your son is end-stage?
Yes.
We'll get an ultrasound
of his abdomen,
and... I'll have a
surgeon come take a look.
Thank you. Okay. You're welcome.
Dr. Chen? Yes?
I usually wait for
labs to come back
before consulting Surgery.
He's got splenomegaly.
Pretty clear case of bleeding
due to thrombocytopenia.
I thought you said
he was end-stage.
That doesn't mean
he can't have surgery.
I'd think about whether
it's appropriate at this point.
Hi. Hi.
I need to get...
Thanks.
Abby? Yeah.
You... You have a
feather. I have a...
Oh.
We had these...
It's not...
Thank you.
What?
Um...
I was just thinking... uh...
I... I was just wondering, if
you wanted, maybe we could...
Could, um...
We could... what?
Go out sometime.
Oh, you mean,
uh, l... Like a date?
Uh, yeah. That's...
sort of what I was thinking.
Tonight?
Sure. Tonight works.
Okay. Okay.
Okay. Yeah.
See you then. Okay.
Romano.
Peter. Back for a
visit? How are you?
How the hell do you think I am?
Well, judging by your demeanor,
I'd say you were
a tad dyspeptic.
Been trashing me all over town?
Oh, having trouble
landing a job, huh?
Thanks to you. Oh,
I'm offended, Peter.
You've made enemies
all over this hospital.
Why assume I'm the
only one with something...?
You're preventing me
from earning a living.
No. No, actually,
I'm willing to help.
What?
Look... your personality sucks.
But you don't have to prove
that you're a great surgeon.
Now, I am willing to offer
you a per diem position.
Per diem? Yeah.
It has no benefits
and even less stature,
but, uh... it's yours
for the asking.
You can kiss my ass.
I take it that's a "no"?
You couldn't pay me
enough to work for you again,
you arrogant little prick.
Fair enough. Just keep working
on those people skills, Peter.
Labs are back on
Mr. Mellonston. Oh, good.
Great color. Thanks.
UA's full of white cells.
He's got a rip-roaring
urinary-tract infection.
Sorry I called you
down here prematurely.
Always happens with
nursing-home patients.
Take an old guy,
give him a bad UTI,
next thing you know,
he's General MacArthur.
I called the home, and they've
already given his bed away.
Hey! Any family members
who can take him in?
No, he's at the mercy
of Social Services.
Hey. Back to work.
Get back to work.
Come on. The show's over.
Maybe not. He talks like a vet.
If he is one, he could
qualify for the VA.
Yeah. That'll take
days to process.
I know a caseworker at
North Chicago with pull.
Maybe we can transfer
today. Do you want me to call?
Sure. If you think it
can be done. Mm-hm.
Anybody missing an old
man looking for brass cleaner?
He just walked
into a pelvic exam.
Mr. Mellonston!
Mr. Mellonston?
Hey, Kerry. Hold on.
Peter. I thought you'd left us.
I could be talked into
coming down to the ER.
As an Attending? As
a liaison to Surgery.
As a surgical resident
you went out of your way
to take every
procedure away from us.
But think about this. If you had
a surgeon teaching residents,
more procedures would stay here.
How? I could expedite
cases to the O.R.
We have surgical
residents for that.
Could you tell me if there's
an elderly gentleman in there?
Uh, does 47 count?
No. Thank you.
Right. See, I could
do scheduling and...
God knows we could use
the help. Kerry, hire me.
Look, I'd love to. Get
Romano to pay for it,
you got yourself a job.
Trolling for work, Peter?
Dr. Chen. Uh.
I'm interested to see
what required the
interruption of my lunch.
As I explained on the phone,
splenomegaly and
thrombocytopenia.
So you'll operate? Well... no.
I would if he didn't
have Niemann-Pick's.
Snow him and wait.
No, we can't just let
him slowly bleed to death.
It's a terminal disease.
Surgery will only slightly
delay the inevitable.
Well, if the surgery
were successful,
then the family would
have more time with him.
Yeah. And if wishes were horses,
we'd all be knee-deep in crap.
Look. I didn't become a
surgeon to torture dying children.
Let the boy die in peace.
But the mother wants it.
No surgery, Dr. Chen.
What the hell is this?
Explosion at a hair salon.
Sad cultural
commentary, isn't it?
Pursuit of beauty at all costs.
Nice legs, though.
There you go.
Oh, God. What am I going to do?
It probably won't scar.
Yeah, but they look hideous.
I can't go on-stage like this.
Can you wear pants? Not
in the swimsuit competition.
You know, you probably
think this is so stupid.
I'm just trying to win a
scholarship. I'm premed.
So I can give you something
for the pain if you'd like.
It's okay. They look
worse than they feel.
Okay. Excuse me.
Malik, can you get ahold of
Miss Pruitt at Abbott and Sons?
Oh, yeah, Miss
Pruitt. You mean that...
Don't ask. Just do it.
Hey, Dave? Yeah.
Did you find anybody yet?
Uh, for what? For
hockey tonight.
Oh, uh, yeah. A friend
of mine. He might sign on.
Former pro. Just
looking for some exercise.
Oh, okay. Yeah.
It's kind of a rough
game we play, actually...
So y-you don't
think I can handle it.
Oh, I didn't say that. I...
I used to play
varsity, second line.
Well... if he can't
make it, I'll call you then.
Type and cross for four.
Start two units of O-neg
on the rapid infuser.
What happened?
Multiple GSWs. One to the chest.
Looks like a
hemopneumothorax on the right.
Five hundred cc's out.
Lost the pulse.
Starting compressions.
We need to crack her chest.
Right-sided GSW's an
indication for the sternal saw.
Can I do it?
Next time, Carter. Ten blade.
Hold CPR.
Sternal saw.
She needs a
central line. I'll do it.
Mr. Mellonston?
Mr. Mellonston.
He said he lost his
razor on Old Baldy.
Wanted to borrow mine.
Gil didn't really
need it though.
All he had was peach fuzz.
I'm sorry. I don't understand.
A... mortar shell
took his head off.
Why don't we take you back to
your bed so you can rest? Mm.
Okay? Here we go.
You... You've seen
war, haven't you?
Actually, no. I have not. Mm.
But you've seen men die.
Yes. Mm.
Mr. Mellonston,
I-I-I'm afraid I have
some... rather unfortunate news.
Uh, you've lost your
bed at the nursing home.
But we've already
called the VA... No!
To see if there's a placement.
No. They won't take me.
Well, I'm sure that you qualify.
I won't go there! Please try...
I can't go there. I won't!
Please, calm down.
We're only trying to help.
I can't go there. I won't.
Malik! Malik, come over...
Mm. No, please!
Don't let them take me.
Don't let them take
me away. Please.
His nose stopped bleeding.
What did you find out?
Well, the surgeon feels
that it's too great a risk
to operate on Kenneth.
But he's suffering.
Can't you see that?
Miss Stein, Kenneth
is barely conscious.
That's not true. He
squeezes my hand.
He understands me.
That means everything that
can be done should be done.
Yes. But there's a good
chance that Kenneth
won't survive the operation.
I know what you're thinking.
I'm selfish.
I'm keeping my son
alive for me, not him.
Miss Stein, I'm not
thinking... He's my child.
I want every minute
I can with him.
Wait till you're a mother.
Then you'll know.
Get him this surgery.
Looks like a small-caliber
GSW to the right ventricle.
Okay. That should do it.
Heart's not filling.
She's had five units.
We need more volume.
Prep the paddles.
Ooh. Can't shock an empty
heart. You'll never get her back.
Run in another two
units. Give me some 0 silk.
Hold compressions. What
are you doing, Carter?
Beck's suture.
All right. Keep
traction on that.
I'll check the back
side of the heart.
What do you see?
Exit wound in the left
ventricle. Give me 2-0 silk.
I can repair it.
Not from that side.
I have a better angle here.
Hm.
I saw blood welling
up behind the heart.
I thought there
might be another hole.
Okay. Charge to 20.
Okay. Now cut it.
Okay.
Clear.
Still V-fib.
Okay. Charge to 30. Clear.
Got a rhythm. Sinus tach.
Got a pulse. Nice job, Carter.
Notify the O.R.
She's got a septal
defect they need to repair.
Dr. Kovac. Mrs. Danzer's
having more chest pain,
dropped her pressure to 90.
I'll be right there. You
gonna take her up? Mm-hm.
Sterile saline dressings
and hang the FFP.
Great save, Carter.
Very slick. Thanks.
Ativan? Yeah, 0.5.
He's pretty subdued.
Excuse me.
Did you hear from the VA?
There's good news and bad news.
I found Mr. Mellonston a bed.
But it's in a brig. He's AWOL.
AWOL? From where?
Korean War. 1951. Army corporal.
Deserted on leave.
Unfortunately, my VA
contact took it upon himself
to notify the active military.
Why care about someone
who deserted 50 years ago?
Who knows? They may
want to slap him on the wrist.
They may want to
court-martial him.
Oh, for God's sake.
He's 72 years old.
I know.
Is there anything we can do?
Legally? No.
Hey. Peter. What
are you doing here?
Did you get any of my messages?
Yes. Uh, and I
meant to call you.
I've just been incredibly busy.
Uh, I just didn't
know what to say.
Yeah, well... it's okay.
No. No, it's not okay.
I've been avoiding you for days.
Yeah. I got that.
I'm sorry. What
Robert did was wrong.
And I've told him as much.
I just wish there was
something I could do.
Yeah, well, I didn't exactly
expect you to resign in protest.
That's a relief.
There is something
you can do though.
You can put the word out.
I know you've got a lot of
contacts at other hospitals.
Of course.
I'm surprised you haven't
been snapped up already.
Yeah, well... it
seems that lately
my reputation has taken a hit.
He's a horrid
little turd, isn't he?
You know what?
I spoke with a friend
of mine in Philadelphia
who's looking for someone.
I just wasn't sure
you'd care to move.
At this point, I'm
open to anything.
Dr. Benton, they
need you in the ER.
I no longer work
at this hospital.
Weaver called. Your
sister Jackie is down there.
What was the last BP? 100/60.
Okay, let's go. I'll
grab the drug box.
How is she? Who are you?
Her sister.
She was shot in the
chest. She's critical.
She needs surgery.
You can go wait in...
Oh, Lord. What happened?
Call Security now!
Oh, my God! Carter!
Carter? Are you all right?
Heart stopped beating.
I'll start compressions.
Any rhythm? Agonal
at 34. Looks like P.E.A.
Amp of atropine, amp of
epi. Mix up the dopamine.
That girl must've
been a gangbanger.
Chest is dry.
Pupils are fixed and dilated.
There's gray matter everywhere.
You won't get her back.
Blew her brains out.
Hyperventilators,
70 of mannitol.
Check cold-water
calorics, and we'll call it.
Somebody call the police!
What happened?
Jesse got into a fight.
You don't know, all right?
I was surprised when
they said you were here.
I had to take care of
something. How is he?
Superficial lac
above the eyebrow,
mild periorbital swelling.
But no bony deformity
or tenderness.
- Nothing serious.
- Told you.
He was bleeding pretty bad.
Did you hit your head? Pass out?
He slammed me into the
locker once, all right? That's all.
You get a CT? No.
You think he needs one?
Maybe.
There was no LOC,
no focal neuro deficits.
They say with head injuries,
you can't be too careful.
Jackie. He's fine.
He's fine.
Come on. Hey, Jackie.
How about I buy
you a cup of coffee?
Are you sure? Yeah. Come on.
How are you doing? I'm okay.
They found the shooter. Good.
Only 15 years old.
Why don't you go home?
I'll be all right.
Go home.
You've probably seen
enough trauma for one day.
I'll tell Kerry.
He's a teenager.
It's normal stuff.
No. He's changing.
You're just not around
enough to notice anymore.
What does that supposed to mean?
He's got a girlfriend
now. She's pretty rough.
You try talking to him?
We've tried everything.
Grounding him is a joke.
Doesn't care. Goes out anyway.
I can't have him locked up.
The other day he
shoved his father.
Took everything
Walter had not to...
You all right?
Can you talk to him?
Can you try?
Uh, talking to him? Mm.
Maybe he'll listen to you.
Yeah.
Hey. Hey.
You look nice.
Thank you. You too.
So, uh, what did
you have in mind?
Dinner? Movie?
I was thinking of something
a little more physical.
Well, not if you go
in laparoscopically.
Recovery time is reduced,
and he gains back weeks,
maybe even months of his life.
No, I don't understand. Are
you saying that it's too risky
for you or for the patient?
Yeah, whatever. Thank you.
Problems? Can't find a surgeon.
Is our department booked?
No. Just uninterested.
This your kid with
Niemann-Pick's?
Yeah.
Tough situation.
I all but promised his
mother I'd make this happen.
Now you can't?
Well, there are a few
other people I can try. Ah.
But you know
they'll... turn you down.
You know, sometimes as
much as we like to give it...
hope can be cruel.
Dr. Greene.
Think fast!
Eight o'clock...
tonight. You're in.
I can't believe the VA
is moving this quickly.
They're not. I got
him into another home.
Borrowed a Social
Security number
from a corpse at the morgue.
Sour cream and
onion? No. Thank you.
Y-you borrowed a number
from a deceased person?
Yeah. We do it all the time.
Oh. I don't wanna know this.
You said you felt bad.
Hey, that is not the point.
I work with a lot of
elderly homeless.
You learn a few tricks...
Not another word,
please! You have to.
Dr. Weaver. Time
for that seminar.
Thank you, Frank.
"Advances in
Neuroleptic Therapy"?
Yeah. How did you know?
I'll be there. Save you a seat.
So where is this body?
The patient is right here.
Audrey? Can I go home now?
Not yet. This is Miss Pruitt.
And she's here to help you.
She's an expert cosmetologist.
Can you cover all of this
in time for the pageant?
Honey... I've worked
on worse. Trust me.
Yeah, but I've got open wounds.
You're on antibiotics.
But afterwards,
no makeup until
you're fully healed.
Thank you,
Dr. Greene. Good luck.
Thanks.
Isn't that the gal who does
makeup on dead people?
Whatever works.
Mark. There you are.
You know we were meant
to leave half an hour ago?
For what?
We're looking at
artwork tonight.
Oh. I'm subbing in a
hockey game. What?
Malucci. He asked
me to play hockey.
Malucci? Are you mad?
Wha... What?
Well, you never said one
word to me about hockey before.
You never asked.
Do you play well?
Well, why don't
you come find out?
You could wear your sweater.
You could bring some pom-poms.
I'd be in uniform.
I didn't know sports
had this effect on you.
Has something happened?
No, why?
You're home early.
Yep.
You never leave
the hospital early.
Someone fax you my schedule?
I know when you
left this morning.
And I know the kind
of hours you put in.
Yeah, it was slow,
so they sent me home.
So it's been all right? Yep.
What you expected?
Ooh. I'm hungry.
How about you? Have you eaten?
I'll take you to Dominic's.
John... to be honest...
I hoped that you would
feel so uncomfortable there
that you wouldn't want to stay.
I know.
So that I wouldn't
have to ask you not to.
Well, then don't.
Just give me five
minutes. I'll get changed.
John.
I know your heart
is in the right place.
I know you enjoy being a doctor.
Start a practice.
I'm not fighting you
on that anymore.
Can't we just agree
to disagree on this?
No. There are other
ways to help people.
You don't have
to destroy yourself.
Gamma...
That place nearly
killed you, John.
It killed your friend.
It drove you to drugs.
No. I did that on my own.
You don't owe them anything.
You don't have
to prove anything.
You have a beautiful spirit.
I've seen them beat
that spirit out of you.
Gamma. I'm gonna be fine.
I promise.
I wish I could believe you.
Gamma?
Wait. Stop spinning.
You're not supposed to spin.
How am I supposed
to keep you from...?
Ah!
It's all in the wrists, really.
I-I think I pulled a muscle.
Oh. Maybe we
should take a break.
Good idea.
Draft, please. Abby?
- Oh. Can I have a club soda?
- Club soda.
Okay.
So, uh, next time
I choose the sport.
You know, something
more civilized.
Uh. Such as?
There's a pool
table at my hotel.
Your hotel?
Yeah. I mean. I don't own
it. I just... Just live there.
You live in a hotel?
Yeah. As a doctor.
I take care of the tourists.
They give me a
break on the rent.
Huh.
No, it's a good deal.
I mean, maid service,
laundry, amenities.
No, it's... It's... It's great.
You'll have to come see it.
Your hotel room? Yeah.
I-I mean... I
mean, no. I mean...
I'd never ask such
a thing of a lady.
Well, especially
after just one kiss.
No. I should hope not.
♪ Reach out to me ♪
♪ For satisfaction ♪
♪ Call my name ♪
♪ Give me action ♪
Of course, that makes it two.
♪ Hey, hey, hey, hey ♪
♪ Hey ♪
Come on. Rematch.
We out of here or not?
Yeah.
After we talk.
About what?
Ahh.
Your mom says you've
been hanging out a lot lately.
So? So she worries about you.
She worries about everything.
That's what she does.
You got new friends?
New girl. That's it.
Using a condom? Uncle Peter...
I'm serious.
I'm not stupid.
Good.
I'm not doing
anything, all right?
It's just...
I'm a man, you know?
And my folks just can't
get used to it. That's all.
Well, maybe they would if
you treated them with respect.
You mean do what they say.
Look...
sometimes you gotta do
what you don't wanna do.
That's part of being a man.
Peter. Do you have a minute?
Uh, yeah. Hold
on a second, okay?
Just...
Just do what your
mother says, all right?
That job's yours if you
want it. Are you serious?
You're a full Surgical Attending
on the academic track. Oh, man.
Thank you. I'm so happy for you.
What's all of the
celebrating about?
I got a job.
That's great.
Yeah. Uh, Elizabeth pulled
some strings with her friend.
Where? Hahnemann.
They made me a full Attending.
In Philadelphia.
Anyway, um, he's
expecting your call.
Oh. Oh. Right, right. Thanks.
Sure.
I didn't have much of a choice.
I mean, I'm being
blackballed here.
When will I see you?
Well, it's only an hour by air.
We'll, uh, work something out.
I guess so.
You coming home with
us? No. I gotta make a stop.
Can you do me a
favor and take him?
Of course.
I'll, uh... I'll call you.
Okay.
What? All I'm saying is:
You were at four and
then you were at six.
That's because I
scored very quickly.
You're a bad sport.
I can't handle
losing to a girl, okay?
Oh, no.
I'm... I'm kidding. I actually
enjoyed losing to you, Abby.
Thank you. Thank
you. That's much better.
Your hands are freezing.
You wanna catch a cab?
No. This is strolling
weather in Minnesota.
Is that where home
is? It's where I grew up...
Luka!
Give me your purse.
Give me the purse.
Give me the damn...
Give me the purse!
Luka!
Luka! Stop!
Stop! Luka! Stop!
Stop it!
Let's play the game.
You okay, Dr. Greene?
I thought you said this
was a no-check league.
There's no such thing
as a no-check league.
Thanks for the tip.
Hi. I thought you'd
left. Um, briefly.
You know, you don't
need to finish your shift.
I still got a couple hours left.
Carter. I think that
you'd be better served
by taking it easy.
I'll go to a meeting
after my shift's over.
If that's okay with you?
I need to finish.
All right. But not too much.
Keep it to minor medical.
Thank you.
Have a nice night. You too.
What's open? Trauma 2.
I thought you two went home.
This guy attacked us.
Blunt head trauma
with LOC. GCS of eight.
Three seizures en route.
He's had four of Ativan.
Luka, you're
bleeding. I'm all right.
BP 180/100.
I'll take it from here. Luka.
Get someone to take care of him.
Hey, Carter. I need you in here.
Uh, Dr. Weaver doesn't want...
I don't care. Get in here.
We've got a major head trauma.
On my count. One, two, three.
He's seizing.
Two of Ativan. CBC, chem panel,
coags, type and cross for four.
Give me some suction
now. He's vomiting.
Get X-ray in here for a C-spine.
All right. I'll
stabilize the neck.
Ativan's on
board. Still seizing.
Hey, Carla.
Peter. Uh, we need to talk.
Here, okay? Really
busy tonight. Sure.
Here you go. Pick it
up. Table eight first.
I called the hospital.
They said that Reece
could stay until the
end of the month.
Good. That gives us more time
to find another daycare center.
It'll be hard finding him
a place he loves more.
Yeah, I know. Listen, uh, I
just got an Attending position
at Hahnemann in Philadelphia.
Really? Yeah.
Good for you.
So we just need to work out
Reece's visitation schedule.
Uh, maybe he could fly down
every other weekend
or something.
I'm sorry. You're not really
suggesting I put my son
on a plane by himself, are you?
Carla... we have joint custody.
In Chicago.
I already took the job.
Mm. Wish that had worked
for me when I wanted to move.
That was Germany, nine
hours away. Completely different.
No. It is completely the same.
What is this about? Payback?
No, it's about our agreement.
Now, either you stay local
or you give up custody.
I can't find a
decent position here.
Oh. That's right. You
have your career to think of.
The rest of us just have jobs.
Table six needs more bread.
This is the only way for me
to keep my momentum going.
Yes. And Germany was Roger's.
No, Carla, I'm asking
you not to do this.
I'm not doing anything. I'm
just playing by your rules.
Hang Dilantin. One
gram per 1000 of saline.
Looks pretty deep.
You need suturing.
I'm okay.
Someone should sew
it up, Luka. I'm okay.
Dr. Kovac?
Detective Stetler.
Can I have a moment?
Can you tell me
exactly what happened?
We were walking by
the river. He jumped us.
Was there only
one assailant? Yeah.
Seizing stopped at 2142.
Lateral neck looks good.
We need some more Kerlix.
He's soaked through these.
Whoa, we got a
pumper. Curved Kelly.
Pressure's sky-high,
260/140. Pulse down to 42.
Start the Nipride. Blown
right pupil. He's herniating.
Eighty of mannitol. Prep
for a posterior burr hole.
Hurry up, Carter. I
need you to assist.
Perforator drill with
a chisel-point bit.
Damn it, Carter, tie
that off! I'm trying!
Well, stick a finger
on it, for God's sake.
V-tach. No pulse. Starting
chest compressions.
Charge to 200. HALEH:
Carter, can you grab paddles?
I'm controlling the bleeder.
Get a pressure dressing on it.
Give me those four-by-fours.
Haleh, I need that
drill. Come on, come on.
Okay. Clear.
I didn't see him coming.
After he hit you from
behind, what happened?
I went down.
Did he take your wallet? Yeah.
And you felt your
life was in danger.
Mine and hers.
V-fib. No pulse.
Did he threaten to hurt you?
I'm not sure.
Did he say, "Give me
your money, or I'll kill you"?
He had a pipe.
Uh, uh...
He was going after Abby.
And you can corroborate that?
Yeah.
Okay. Let's wait
and see what happens.
Seems clear it was self-defense.
Shouldn't be a problem, doc.
There. That's the inner table.
Irrigate the bone dust.
Looks like a subdural.
More irrigation,
Carter. Eleven blade.
Five minutes since the
last epi. Give another amp.
Opening the dura.
Get ready to suction.
Can you see the source?
No. Let's just pack it off.
What's the rhythm?
V-fib. Charge to 300.
I need saline gauze.
Clear.
Sinus brady at 50. Got a pulse.
Excellent. Decompress the brain.
Amp of atropine.
Let's check the pupils.
How about phenobarb?
Go with pentobarb...
200, slow IV push.
That'll induce a coma, you know.
It's either that
or watch him die.
Luka, Abby told me about what
happened. Can I take a look?
It's superficial.
Did you lose consciousness?
For a moment, yeah.
Come on. Let's fix you up. No.
Do you have a
headache? Leave me alone!
I'm... I'm fine,
okay? I'm... I'm fine.
Clear.
Still V-fib.
How long's the
bretylium been on board?
Five minutes.
Clear.
Asystole. What now?
Open up the dopamine.
It's been 45 minutes.
Ah.
I know.
Luka.
Luka, wait!
Luka, wait.