Hey. Thanks.
No, no, no... Here.
You got this whole
thing wrong, Em.
It's the rock star that's supposed to
be late, not the rock-star photographer.
Sorry. Morning
sickness. Touch the belly.
It's the first time I've
been asked to do that.
Come on. It's good luck.
Okay.
Hit the Kinos behind the drop.
So what do you think?
I think people
aren't gonna get it.
Come on. "All-American Rejects."
Juxtaposing a classic image of
Americana with modern pop culture youth.
Oh, yeah.
Everyone loves a
good juxtaposition.
My fans were born in the '90s.
You know what? You do this
picture, you'll gain 40 years of fans.
Yeah? Yeah.
I love the Rockwell
thing. I thought so.
Okay. Kill the
house lights. Let's go!
Hang on. Hey, who's in
charge of the backdrop?
Naomi? Yeah?
What's wrong with it?
Well, the words are
completely jumbled.
What, you can read that?
Of course.
You okay? No. Oh, God.
I could be having a...
What's the mnemonic?
"F" is for face. Is
my smile crooked?
What are you doing?
"A" is for arms.
Arms.
You should really sit down.
Can someone get her some water?
"S" is speech.
I'm slurring? I'm slurring?
"F-A-S-T."
"T" is for time.
Hurry. Somebody, call 911.
Tell them I'm having a stroke.
Hi. I'm Dr. House.
My boss says you're important.
Personally I don't get
what's so hard about
making Scarlett
Johansson look pretty.
Arms out in front of you.
Palms up like you're
holding a pizza.
Close your eyes.
It's so easy you should
consider a career change.
Probably make a lot more money.
Dr. Mackman tell
you the clot was clear?
Yes.
And he said that you
and the fetus are fine?
Yeah.
He didn't mention
your pronator drift?
What's that mean?
Means Mackman is an idiot.
May I? Yeah.
So,
you take thousands
of photos of someone,
but only one has to look good.
Kind of the opposite
of my business.
It's not about looking good.
People are always hiding things.
I just keep shooting until I can
see what's really inside them.
My eyes okay?
Eyes are gorgeous.
The vessels don't look so hot.
Microaneurysms
predict further strokes.
This is gonna happen again?
Unless I can figure out
the underlying cause.
Puff up your cheeks.
You should be able to keep the air in.
Means there's weakness around the mouth.
So where'd you learn to
self-diagnose a stroke?
Oh, my baby's biological
father is a neurologist.
He once told me the FAST mnemonic
could save my life one day. So...
Interesting pet name.
Most people go with
"husband" or "pookie."
He's gay.
Just a sperm donor.
So when you...
You turned him for a night?
Just straight for one date?
Okay.
He took a magazine and
a cup into my bathroom.
A man after my own heart.
Different magazine obviously.
I'm rescinding Mackman's
discharge order.
My lackeys will be
in to do some tests,
take some more blood and
empty your catheter bag.
Not a moment
you'll want to cherish.
This is definitely different.
It looks almost like...
He's caring.
Find anything else in the
patient's folder? Like a diagnosis?
Urinalysis revealed excessive
protein and red blood cells.
Chem panel showed a
creatinine level over 2.5.
So first she strokes, now her
kidneys are shutting down. Why?
Ultrasound showed
no tumors or stones.
No signs of fetal distress.
No urinary tract obstructions.
BP is fine. No pre-eclampsia.
Any of you guys ever
been to the Galápagos?
Was our patient there?
Dengue fever, avian
pox, even West Nile.
No.
I'm looking for a vacation spot.
That mean we get vacation?
How would that differ
from your current status?
You're gonna do what? Relax?
Visiting family.
My uncle's a giant turtle.
What if the kidney
failure came first?
Kidneys could've caused the
stroke not the other way around.
Kidneys don't often
get stuck in the brain.
I'm saying it threw a clot.
Early symptoms of kidney failure
are nausea, vomiting, ankle swelling.
She would've mistaken
it for morning sickness.
Heart's way more likely to
throw a clot than a kidney.
Echo was normal. The history
indicates no sign of cardiac problems.
No, but if one were to
read the history closely,
one would notice that
she had six cases of strep.
In her throat. That's the one
about 10 inches above her heart.
Let me rephrase, six
cases of untreated strep.
She was prescribed antibiotics.
No one takes them all.
They stop when they start feeling
better. All strep is untreated strep.
What happens when
strep goes untreated?
Leads to rheumatic fever.
Which leads to... Cameron?
Mitral valve stenosis.
Which is a thickening in
the valve of the... Kidney?
No.
The kidney doesn't
have a mitral valve.
We'll go look at her heart.
Be easy to find.
It's the big red pumping thing
about 10 inches below her throat.
That was weird.
He was the way he always is.
Which is weird.
Very still, Emma. Sorry.
No problem.
He caught us with your hand up my
shirt. He's gotta have a reaction to that.
You think that's
what the vacation is?
Yes.
The pain of losing you is
obviously forcing him away.
Coronal slice appears normal.
There's no way House
just lets this slide.
He's gotta be
planning something.
Maybe he just
doesn't give a crap.
Sagittal slice is clean.
You think he just
stumbled into that closet?
He knew we were there and he
wanted us to know that he knew.
Or you wanted him to know.
Now he does and you're
annoyed because he doesn't care.
Right there.
Trans-axial slice. Calcified
mitral valve. Barely.
That's not big
enough to throw a clot.
Obviously it is, because it did.
House was right.
A valve in your
heart is narrowed.
It caused the clot
which lead to your stroke,
and the reduced circulation caused
the problem with your kidneys.
And this will fix it?
The balloon will force the valve
back open and you'll be fine.
Can we do this
without a sedative?
It's very mild. There
really is no risk to the fetus.
We'll monitor your baby's
heart rate separately.
We won't allow it to decrease
anywhere near dangerous levels.
Thank you.
You're both gonna be fine.
Go ahead, Dr. Cameron.
Listen to that
heartbeat. It sounds so...
Start threading the catheter.
No, I don't want a layover in Frankfurt,
Taipei, Singapore or London, Ontario.
That's why I asked for a
direct flight to Phnom Penh.
How hard is it to not land?
Does it matter what I answer?
Well, then fine. I'd
be delighted to hold.
What's new? Can you tell
Cuddy to stop interfering?
It's her job. What's new?
Good news is
Emma's heart is fixed.
Bad news is it's not her underlying
problem. Her kidneys are still failing.
You're vacationing in Cambodia?
You gonna unwind in
the Killing Fields? Nope.
Gonna catch me a fish this big.
Mekong giant catfish.
Weighs over 600 pounds.
Aren't those catfish
critically endangered?
That's why it's my last
chance to catch one.
All of our operators
are currently...
If the mitral valve had been properly
fixed the kidney should be getting better,
which leads us to the conclusion
that you screwed up the procedure.
Or you screwed up the diagnosis.
The mitral valve thickening
was so insignificant
it probably wasn't the cause
of the kidneys or the stroke.
Probably never
would've been a problem.
She needs dialysis and
we need a new theory.
There are only a
few possibilities.
Patient's pregnant,
could be pre-eclampsia.
We eliminated it
before because...
Re-check for proteinuria
and low platelets. What else?
Hypoperfusion.
The fetus is basically a parasite
stealing nutrients, minerals, blood.
Put her on telemetry.
Or the pregnancy is irrelevant.
Could be infection,
sepsis, HUS/TTP.
A cholesterol embolism
is just as likely.
Tiny particles of cholesterol rain down,
clog up the small vessels of the kidneys.
Get a smear and ultrasound
her vessels for plaque.
That's it. Has to
be one of those five.
You know what would be even better?
If we'd narrow it all the way down to one.
Thank you for holding.
We are experiencing
extremely high call volume.
Thank you for your patience.
She's 0 for five.
Either the differential was
wrong or she's faking it.
Kidney failure has
to be precipitated by...
One of the five we've
already ruled out.
The body only has so many
ways of screwing with the kidneys.
The labs must be
wrong. We did the labs.
No one else had access.
That's not quite true.
You put all your patients through this
many tests or just the important ones?
We wanted to
explore all possibilities.
And?
We've eliminated
all the possibilities.
You telling me I'm dying
and you have no idea why?
Your body is
functioning properly.
So why are my kidneys failing?
The other body isn't.
There's something
wrong with the fetus.
Welcome to the world of
maternal mirror syndrome.
Mom's body is like
an intricate German
metro system.
All the trains run on time.
When she gets pregnant, it's like a
new station opening in Düsseldorf.
Bunch or rookies running
things. Bound to be mistakes.
Kids play on the
tracks, get electrocuted.
Before you know it, the trains
are backed up all the way to Berlin
and you've got a bunch of angry
Germans with nowhere to go.
And we all know that
ain't good for the Jews.
Who are the Jews
in this metaphor?
A few things can happen
to a fetus in distress.
It can become a
miscarriage, stillbirth,
a very sick baby or on
rare occasion a time bomb
that kills mom while it's dying.
Good news is, we fix
the fetus, mom gets better.
It's the diagnostic equivalent
of a two-for-one sale.
I have read the outcome of mirror
syndrome is almost always unfavorable.
"Unfavorable." Is that
doctor speak for "dead baby"?
You think she'll be less
upset if you phrase it nicely?
We can tell her the
truth, that she'll be fine
as soon as we diagnose a person
who weighs about one pound.
Can't touch it, can't ask
where it hurts, can't see it.
If only there existed giant machines
that could look through human skin.
Mirror syndrome has a limited
number of known causes.
Tachyarrhythmia, fetal
anemia, placental chorioangioma.
All of which are fixable.
Which would be
un-unfavorable, right?
Could also be trisomy 13.
Ebstein's anomaly, an
aneurysm of Galen's vein.
And Dr. Storm Cloud
rained all over the differential
and killed the
beautiful little baby.
Heart's easiest to see,
easiest to fix. So let's start there.
When you did Mom's MRI, did
you get a look at the fetus's heart?
It was in the range but blurry. The
fetus was moving all over the place.
So we need another scan. Yeah.
We'll just ask the fetus
to lie very, very still.
No need. I'm
going to paralyze it.
You wanna paralyze
Emma Sloan's baby?
Let me guess. Cameron?
Cameron and Chase
both had their concerns.
No, Cameron had concerns.
Chase just agreed with her
because he didn't want to lose
his all-access pass to her love rug.
They're sleeping together?
If by "sleeping together" you mean
having sex in the janitor's closet.
Here?
No, the janitor's closet
at the local high school.
Go, Tiger Cats!
Do you have one of those camera
phones? 'Cause I got a MySpace account.
I will deal with them
after I deal with you.
Oh, come on. Let's
gossip some more.
I'm sure she's into bondage.
Paralyzing a one-pound
baby risks damaging...
Not paralyzing the thing risks
not getting a clean MRI of its heart,
which we need to save its life, which
we need to do to save Emma's life.
You're gonna need
to get her consent.
Well, that shouldn't
be too hard.
"Sign here or you and
your baby both die."
I'm going with you.
Oh, good.
You said sedation was
risky. This sounds insane.
The injection goes
into the umbilical cord.
The baby won't feel a thing.
Fetus.
I'm lowering expectations.
It works here and on dates.
The benefits outweigh the risks
and the paralytic will
wear off in an hour, okay?
Must be easier to hear you
might die than your baby might die.
But if there's anyone I
would trust to save my baby,
it would be Dr. House.
Fetus.
Hold this.
Dr. Cameron. The
MRI results back?
The fetus's heart
is structurally sound.
The problem's with the bladder.
It's four times normal size.
Let me see.
The bladder's so engorged
it's taking up the whole torso,
squeezing all the other organs.
There's no room for
the lungs to develop.
The baby has a lower
urinary tract obstruction.
We can fix that by
inserting a shunt.
I'll give Emma the news.
Are you taking over the case?
House won't care.
He has his diagnosis.
Doctor Cameron.
Dating Chase can only
end in one of two ways.
House told you?
You get married and
live happily ever after,
or somebody gets hurt and
you two can't work together,
and I have to fire somebody.
I would hate to see my personal
life become such a burden to you.
I'm telling you this
for your own good.
I assume you're gonna have this same
conversation with Chase for his own good.
Chase isn't the one
that's gonna get hurt here.
There's only room for one
but I could skooch over.
My social life
is my social life.
Couldn't agree more.
What goes on in the privacy of a janitor's
closet is nobody's business except...
She told me to end it.
Is that what you want?
I was actually hoping
she'd fire one of you.
What are you doing?
Trying to avoid
altitude sickness.
Couldn't score a direct
flight to Cambodia,
so I've decided to scale Argentina's
infamous Mount Aconcagua.
Perfect except for the
fact that you can't walk.
There's a tribe of Mocoví Indians
who actually carry the elders up...
You're insane.
I'm an insane genius.
I set the chamber for low
pressure instead of high.
Thinner air builds up
the extra red blood cells,
creates new capillaries.
Few more days in here, I can
save myself six weeks at base camp.
Where's my MRI?
There's a blockage
in the urinary tract.
Simple terms,
your baby can't pee.
His bladder is swollen
and it's crushing his lungs.
Can you fix it?
We can insert a small
tube in the baby's bladder
that makes the urine come
out straight through his belly
for the duration
of the pregnancy.
The bladder decompresses and the
lungs will be able to develop normally.
When the baby gets
better, you should get better.
First we just have to do a test
to determine whether the baby's
kidneys are functioning properly.
And what if they're not?
If they're already too damaged,
then there's really nothing we can do.
If this doesn't work out
you can always try again.
I miscarried twice
when I was married.
After the divorce, I tried in
vitro like four times before this.
I'm 42. Maybe it's
just not meant to be.
What are you doing?
You're trying to be me, so
I thought I'd try to be you.
You don't have
the cleavage for it.
But I have a much tighter ass.
Think every day should be naked
Thursday or is that an oxymoron?
Let me see the results
from the bladder tap.
They aren't back yet.
They're gonna be inconclusive.
You think my diagnosis is wrong?
Fetus doesn't pee,
amniotic fluid should be low.
Mom's level is fine.
Doesn't mean I'm wrong.
Could just mean we
caught the obstruction early.
Either way your test
will be inconclusive.
The urine you've collected has been
sitting in that fetus's bladder for weeks.
As my pappy always said,
"Stale pee is useless pee."
Fine. I'll do another tap.
Just as useless.
Old urine drops down from
the kidney right after the first tap
'cause it's so backed up.
Bladder tap number three
will give you the freshest pee.
That's when you'll find out if this
fetus has even a fighting chance.
Thank you.
I'll run two more taps.
Since when does the Dean
of Medicine run bladder taps?
She's an important patient.
Because she takes pictures
or because she's you?
Woman in her 40s, single,
using a turkey baster as
a last gasp at motherhood.
Maybe you want to make sure she
succeeds so you'll still have hope.
You can't be a good
doctor if you're not objective.
It's your file. I don't want it.
Then why did you
just say all that stuff?
To humiliate you.
You're taking the case
back. I don't want it.
Your diagnosis is right.
I want to go on vacation.
You can go on vacation
after you've cured her.
Good news.
The fetus's urine had appropriate
levels of protein and electrolytes,
so its kidneys aren't damaged.
Oh, wow.
We're gonna put the shunt in.
Your baby's lungs should
have more room to grow
and your symptoms
should go away.
But he'll still need
surgery, after he's born?
That's when we'll remove
the blockage in the ureter.
You'll be the only mother on the planet
who appreciates the value of a wet diaper.
Hey, could you hand me that?
I'm keeping a visual memory book
of this entire surreal process and
this is the best part of the story so far.
Yeah. Sure. Thanks.
When'd you take this?
She did the second bladder tap.
You should keep it.
Oh, I see her all day
at work. I don't need it.
Maybe you want to
see her after work.
I'm right, right?
I saw the way you look at her.
Thanks.
The shunt is in
the right position.
Bladder is starting
to decompress.
No infection.
Did House say
anything else? About us?
I thought you didn't care about his
reaction. Trying to make him jealous?
I like my job.
He can't fire you just
because we're together.
We're not "together," and
House can do whatever he wants.
How's my baby?
Doing just fine, Emma.
So are you.
My stomach's killing me.
That's not her stomach.
Can you open your eyes,
Emma? I just need to take a look.
What is it?
Emma's jaundiced.
Her liver's shutting down.
Figures. Just booked
my trip to Johnston Strait.
I thought you were climbing
Mount Whatever in Argentina.
Apparently I'd have to live with
the Mocoví Indians for 20 years
before they'd
consider me an elder.
Decided to go kayaking with
orca instead. No legs required.
Can't leave yet. Liver failure puts
her case back into the unsolved pile.
Increased AST, ALT and
her bilirubin's off the charts.
Even fetuses lie.
We diagnosed a lower urinary tract
obstruction because we saw one.
What if that's not
the whole story?
What if the little bugger
is hiding something?
The real reason for
the mirror syndrome.
Have we looked under its bed?
We checked its diary?
If it's not GU,
could be the heart.
Hypoplastic left heart syndrome.
There were no structural
problems. The lungs.
We won't be able to get a
good look until they develop.
It'll be weeks... She's
not gonna last weeks.
What do you want to do?
Maternal mirror syndrome
has one sure fire cure.
Deliver the fetus.
That's not viable at 21
weeks. You'll kill the baby.
Fetus. Semantics
make you feel better?
Pretend it's not a person?
Can it play catch? Can it eat?
Can it take pretty pictures?
Who wants to tell her?
The swollen bladder
was not the only problem.
We can't leave it inside
you. We have to terminate.
Well, can't you deliver him?
Put him on a respiratory machine
till you figure out what's wrong?
We can. And it won't matter.
The fetus is still at least two
weeks away from being viable.
Well, I'll suffer through this
for two more weeks then.
You're on dialysis for your
kidneys. Your kidneys can wait.
They don't make
dialysis for your liver.
You're not gonna
make it two more days.
I'm not gonna let
you kill my baby.
It's killing you.
I'm not having an abortion.
It's not a baby. It's a tumor.
I understand dying for a cause.
Sacrificing your life so your child
might live. But that's not the choice here.
Either it dies or you both die.
Or you fix him and we both live.
I can't fix it.
I'm scheduling a D&C.
I won't consent.
So I guess you have
two days to figure it out.
Her kidneys are
almost irreparable.
She's developed severe DIC.
You have to force her to terminate.
Did you give corticosteroids to
speed up the baby's lung development?
No. I dropped an anvil on its
chest to prevent lung development.
I'm trying to extinguish the
human race one fetus at a time.
Give the lungs more time to
expand so you can see inside them.
See if they're the problem.
My real patient is dying.
Very quickly. Like I wouldn't
advise her to buy any green bananas.
The fetus is nothing more
than a parasite at this point.
Removing it is an instant cure.
You're not gonna get
Emma to see it that way.
She's probably
already named the baby,
read him books, had
conversations with him.
See, you get it.
She'll listen to you. No.
If you let this woman refuse to terminate,
you're helping her commit suicide.
As her doctor my
recommendation is against suicide.
If the baby had a doctor,
I think she would recommend exhausting
all possibilities before taking its life.
Then she'd be an idiot.
Too bad she's your boss!
What if our original
assumption is wrong?
It isn't.
If we assume she doesn't
have mirror syndrome,
then terminating her pregnancy
isn't gonna help her liver at all.
We eliminated all
other possibilities.
The fetus is hydropic
and in distress.
Emma's kidneys and liver are
failing. The diagnosis is solid.
Wow! The ass-kisser
won't agree with you.
You must be even
wronger than I thought.
Fine.
Let's assume she
had mirror syndrome
but we fixed it when we
fixed the baby's bladder.
That means that her failing liver
would be completely unrelated.
If it is, we can fix it and
we don't have to terminate.
So her theory is that our
patient's liver problems
were just a giant coincidence.
It's not a surprising
coincidence.
Pregnant women can
develop liver problems.
If this is the case, we can
actually do something here.
Don't you guys think
that's worth exploring?
Acute fatty liver of pregnancy
would have the same symptoms.
Thank you. Brownnoser.
Viral hepatitis, HELLP
syndrome. Oh, look.
Sticking up for your girlfriend.
Who says chivalry's dead?
He's not joking?
Be patient. She's going through all of us.
She'll get that jungle fever eventually.
I'm not going through
anyone. You love him?
This can probably wait until after
you biopsy Emma's liver, right?
We can't. Her
platelets are too low.
Once we pierce her liver, it'll be
next to impossible to stop the bleeding.
Come in from above.
Instead of going straight
in through her abdomen,
go in through the
veins in her neck.
Transjugular hepatic biopsy.
If the liver starts to bleed, it'll
bleed right back into her own veins.
Why don't you start
your vacation now?
Threading the guide wire through
the right internal jugular vein.
So, the sleep lab...
You and Cameron not sleeping.
How serious is it?
It's nothing.
She's only doing it to
make House jealous.
Then why are you
doing it? You kidding?
You're approaching the
inferior vena cava. Slow down.
You better not hurt her.
She already has a
big brother. She does?
You obviously care
very deeply about her.
I'm not protecting her.
I'm protecting myself.
A heartbroken, lovesick Cameron
would be even more
unbearable than she is now.
You're through the hepatic vein.
I'm firing the needle.
Heart rate and BP
spiking. Get that out of her.
Fetus's heart rate
just dropped to 50.
We've got contractions.
Pre-term labor.
Start a terbutaline drip!
We were able to control the
pre-term labor with tocolytics.
The contractions
have subsided for now.
And the liver biopsy was negative.
This is definitely mirror syndrome.
Her baby's doing this to her.
We're out of options.
Did the biopsy cause the pre-term
labor or did it happen on its own?
It doesn't make a difference.
Pre-term labor can
be a new symptom.
New information gives us new
theories. Isn't that how it works?
Not in this case.
Her body's trying to do what you refuse
to, get the baby out and save itself.
Patient's transaminases
are 10 times normal.
Her liver is on the verge of
shutting down completely.
A torch test could...
We don't have
time for more tests.
We have to
terminate or she'll die.
Then let's work faster.
Medicine doesn't work faster
just because you hope real hard.
But it could help to see
what the baby's been hiding.
The only organ we haven't been
able to look inside is its lungs.
The problem must be in there.
We haven't been able to see inside
because they're underdeveloped.
We've already got her on corticosteroids,
but it'll take weeks for them...
Then let's drown them in
corticosteroids, multiple courses.
Speed up their development.
Giving the baby more than one course
will suppress adrenal gland function.
Have long-term adverse effects
on fetal organ development.
Worse than death?
Emma's already on tocolytics.
The combination could put
her into pulmonary edema.
You'll just kill her faster.
It's the only chance we have
to see inside those lungs.
We're just gonna have to make the baby
better faster than we make Emma worse.
Come on! This is the kind of
thing House does every day.
House thought we should
terminate six hours ago.
I'll do it myself.
Anybody gonna stop her?
Stopping the madness is her job.
Somebody's got to
be Cuddy's Cuddy.
Nurse!
Pulmonary edema? Who
tattled? It doesn't matter.
There's a reason we don't give
multiple courses of corticosteroids.
Gee, thanks.
It's time to terminate.
That's not what she wants.
Look at her.
She didn't want to be an incubator for a
dead baby, but that's what you've done.
Either get me a
laryngoscope or get out!
You were right.
You were all right.
Now the mom's lungs
are shutting down.
She's dying faster than the
baby's lungs are developing.
I had to stop the
corticosteroids.
Have you spoken to the family?
The only family
she's got is that baby.
Well, he's biased.
What do you think
House would do?
House wants to terminate.
I mean if he didn't.
If he shared my position,
what do you think he would do?
He wouldn't share your pain.
He'd be objective.
Right.
He would prioritize
his problems.
He'd terminate.
He wouldn't be afraid of screwing
with her lungs if there was a bigger issue.
There is no bigger issue.
She needs her
lungs. Not right now.
She's already on a respirator.
The machine is
breathing for her.
I can do whatever
I want to her lungs.
If you're playing catch in the living
room and you break your mother's vase,
you may as well keep playing
catch. The vase is already broken.
Yeah, except that room
can't breathe without that vase.
I'm putting her back
on corticosteroids.
It worked. What worked?
I got the baby's
lungs to expand.
We should be able to
figure... Cab's on its way.
I have to finish packing.
I have a whole new
appreciation for what you do.
How hard it is to believe
when everyone around you
is telling you
that you're wrong.
Helps to know they're idiots.
Do you think I'm an idiot?
You're not objective.
But you're not an idiot.
These lungs are still two
weeks away from being viable.
But big enough for a diagnosis.
These tissue buds are new.
Could indicate
bronchopulmonary sequestration
or diaphragmatic eventration.
I was thinking bronchogenic
cyst or bronchial atresia.
Could be lung lesions, CCAM.
What about...
Move.
Thought you
started your vacation.
Somebody had to save
our boss's rotundous ass.
Latest MRI of the Sloan fetus.
Small buds in the lungs
could indicate... Thanks.
Got the multiple
choice all worked out.
Question is, how do we pick between
A, B, C, D, and none of the above?
Portable MRI is in her room.
We could get a current image.
The fetal lungs are so tiny the
MRI won't give us the detail we need.
What would we do if this
patient were not just a tadpole?
Say it was an actual person.
He is a person.
Thanks for playing along.
Pretend it's a one-pound adult.
Forget the mom, forget
the womb, the placenta.
How would we get a better
look at what's in the lungs?
Transesophageal echo.
Can't access his esophagus.
High resolution CT
could give us a clearer...
Too much radiation
for a one-pound person.
You can't just shoot
everything down, Chase.
You're not me. Collaborate.
A ventilation perfusion
scan would be next.
How do we get a fetus to breathe
in a radioactive isotope, idiot?
If it were really a person
and we had no other options
we'd do an exploratory surgery.
Cut into its chest and
have a look around.
Let's do that.
You're the one who insists
we treat it like a person.
I'll put it back when I'm done.
Me again.
It's your friendly
neighborhood belly squirter.
We're gonna do
open fetal surgery.
Open the uterus, cut out the
fetus so we can look around.
I know you can't talk so I need
you to look petrified if you consent.
The umbilical cord won't be cut.
During surgery, your body will basically
serve as the baby's heart/lung machine.
We find what's
wrong and we fix it.
If we can.
Don't lower expectations if
you want them to do something.
She should know
what she's facing.
This is incredibly dangerous.
It risks both your lives.
The only reason
why we're suggesting
it is because there's
nothing else we can do.
You all here for
the fetal surgery?
'Cause we're way over capacity.
Mind each other's
personal space.
There are sharp
implements in the room.
Like this one.
Uterus is fully exposed.
And we're in.
Start draining
the amniotic fluid.
Have you never sucked beer
out of the bottom of a keg?
Where'd you go to
college? Give me that.
Affix the pulse ox to the palm.
House?
Sorry.
Just realized I
forgot to TiVo Alien.
Fetal heart rate
good. Stats are stable.
Position him for the incision.
I see three
well-defined lesions.
It's definitely CCAM. I
should be able to resect them.
It's the mom. She's in V-fib.
Charging.
Clear! I'm clear.
Looks like asystole. Paddling
isn't going to do anything.
It's fine V-fib. I'm
going again. Clear!
We're gonna lose
them both. Clamp!
The surgery's not doing
this to her. The fetus is.
Step away, House.
I'm going again.
The only way to save her is to cut
away the anchor holding her down.
You keep going, you're
gonna get electrocuted.
Clear!
Going again. Clear!
Heart rate's
returning to normal.
Continue with the lobectomy.
So my kidneys, liver and
lungs are all fine just like that?
Just like that. That's amazing.
What's amazing is how
blonde your baby's hair is.
My baby?
The thing in your belly
that tried to kill you.
You've never called
him a baby before.
Any pain?
Nothing I can't deal with.
You can only get out of
bed to pee, pooh or shower.
And absolutely no sex.
So stop flirting with me.
Sorry.
So this really worked?
He'll be normal?
Well, if you call being
born twice normal.
Hey, thank you.
Don't thank me. I
would've killed the kid.
Wanna grab a bite? In a minute.
Emma asked me to
bring up her camera.
I'll walk with you.
When'd she take
this picture of you?
You look so...
I'm smiling.
I have a nice smile.
No, I've never
seen you like this.
She got you to glow.
What were you doing?
What did she say to you?
I always glow.
House.
Need you to take
a look at something.
I'm off the clock. Just open it.
A first-class ticket
to Vancouver Island.
Shoot! The wrong envelope.
I think it's great. Yeah.
Who doesn't like
Canadians? It's big.
You're trying to have a life.
You're trying to enjoy yourself.
You didn't need to apologize.
I'm not. I told you why I...
Screwed up.
I saved a life. I
saved two lives.
You
let your maternal instinct get the
best of you and nearly kill two people.
Case like this, you terminate,
mom lives 10 times out of 10.
You do what you did
mom and baby both
die 9.9 times out of 10.
Sometimes point
one is bigger than 9.9.
No, it's smaller.
Exactly 9.8 smaller.
Always is. Always will be.
Well, not for Emma.
And not for her son.
Now go away and be happy.