Yeah, it's... No, it's
my pager number.
Yes. Dr. Kerry Weaver.
No. It's nothing serious. I just have
some personal information for her.
- All right. Thank you.
- Good morning.
Good morning. You all set?
Oh, yeah. I forgot how jammed
the El can be during rush hour.
- Is there any chance I could get a locker?
- Oh, sure. Fourth to the right.
I'll have them
take the name off.
- Welcome back.
- Thanks.
Hey, watch out! Coming through!
I heard it, but I didn't believe it.
- Malik!
Oh, we missed you!
They actually talked you
into coming back here.
- Bad idea?
- I didn't say that.
Frank, call Housekeeping.
Someone took a dump in Exam 2.
Our mad crapper's back, huh?
- If I catch him, he'll
be pooping in a bag.
- What happened to the board?
- Weaver.
Spanky's in Curtain 3 complaining
of incontinence. I'm not touching him.
- I'll take him.
- I don't think you want that.
- Here. Leg injury, Curtain 1.
- Welcome back, Dr. L.
- Thanks. What's the story with Spanky?
- He likes nurses. A lot.
Dr. Lewis? Are you Susan Lewis?
- Yes.
Cleo Finch, the Senior
on nights this week.
Nice to meet you.
- I have a few pass-ons.
- Okay.
Curtain 3, worst headache of his life.
Do a spinal tap if the head CT is negative.
- Okay. No problem.
- Well, well, well.
- Dr. Susan Lewis.
- Dr. Benton.
Just when I thought
it was safe to come in.
- I missed you too, Peter.
- I know.
So can I buy you breakfast?
I just got here, but you
can get me lunch. Oh, sorry.
I have to sign out and
get to Schaumburg.
- Another interview?
- No, the job's mine.
- Meeting the medical director today.
- Congratulations.
Nosebleed in
Suture's got Merocel.
Check on him. Wear
a mask, he's a spitter.
Right. Are you going somewhere?
I've been offered the chance to run
a pediatric urgent care. Five doctors...
- eight-hour shifts, no overnights.
- Yeah, but it's...
- What?
- In Schaumburg.
It's 40 minutes away. IV drug
user with a shooter's abscess.
Whisked off to Echo
before I could drain him.
- Anything else?
- Yeah.
They just brought in a
homeless lady with maggots.
I'd see her before they
start crawling away.
Thanks.
- Mark, can you get the water?
- Did you see my vertigo notes?
I got it. CORDAY: What?
- My vertigo notes. They were right here.
- We need to leave in 10 minutes.
- As soon as I find my notes.
- When did you last have them?
- Last night.
- That will be fun.
Okay, hold on. Dad, can
I go to a party tonight?
- It's a school night.
- Something's burning.
Just for dinner. It's
Claire's birthday.
- Who's Claire?
- A girl from school.
Sorry. Do you want
some cereal or something?
- No. I'll get something later.
- Dad?
- Let me talk to her mother.
- Is your mom there?
Mark, I have an
8:00 thyroidectomy.
Hi, this is Mark Greene. Yeah,
Rachel's dad. I just was wanting to...
- So how did you meet Claire?
- She's my partner in art class.
Uh-huh. What are you working on?
Call me after dinner
and I'll pick you up.
Cool.
- Katherine's early.
- Good.
Gonna need to get
dressed in the car.
- Hi. Is Rachel ready?
- Who are you?
This is Andrew. He's
driving me to school.
- Nice to meet you.
- Here are your notes. Dining-room table.
- When did this happen?
- Oh, sorry, I forgot.
Andrew has a car while
his dad's out of town.
- You have a license?
- Yeah. Well, I got it in June.
- I have no accidents, you know.
- We can take you to school.
No, no, it's good. Now you
guys won't be late for work.
Well, I guess she's
making friends.
- I don't like taking my clothes off.
- You have to to be examined.
Can't you just listen to my stomach?
I think something's, like, blown loose.
- It keeps making these weird noises.
- Maybe you're hungry.
And maybe I'm
bleeding into my belly.
Could it be a complication
from my surgery?
I don't know. My x-ray
vision isn't working.
- Are you mocking me?
- No.
- It sounds like you're mocking me.
- I'm taking you seriously...
which is why I'll examine you
as soon as you get undressed.
- You just wanna see me naked.
- I want to examine you.
Yeah, examine me naked. Can I get
a male doctor in here? A straight one?
First day of school,
already making friends?
- I'm a shoo-in for homecoming queen.
- So far, so good.
Oh, yeah. Foul abscess, a
neurotic granny, naked boy here.
And I had to break
into Chen's locker.
- Did you steal her stuff?
- Weaver gave it to me.
What are you using for
maggots these days? Cetacaine?
Good thought, but
Kerry's immune to it.
- You're enjoying this, aren't you?
- Colonel Dixon's Magical Maggot Mix.
Seriously, you
paint it on with milk.
Paramedic radios over this. Dr. Greene
and Dr. Lewis, two of our Attendings.
Welcome. Don't kill anyone.
And I'll mix you up a fresh batch.
Dr. Lewis is a wealth of knowledge,
but don't ask her where anything is.
She is just getting re-oriented
after a five-year sabbatical herself.
Five years?
- Posttraumatic stress.
- What happened?
You don't wanna know. Fill
these out and then come find me.
- Do you have a pen?
- Come prepared. Want the tour?
I think I can find my way around
again. New group of neophytes?
- I get to babysit them too.
- It's the burden of being Chief Resident.
- You've heard?
- Yes, I have.
Oh, nurse? Nurse? Nurse?
- Are you talking to me?
- I don't know your name.
You haven't met Abby yet.
Abby Lockhart, Dr. Susan Lewis.
- Susan, Abby. Susan used to work here.
- That's the rumor.
Could you set me up
for suturing in Exam 3?
- Set you up?
- Open a kit...
some 4-0 nylon,
number-seven gloves, Betadine.
It's all in the room. New chest pain in 2.
- Altered LOC over here!
Hey, Mooney. Get started on the
chest pain here. You know the routine.
- Oxygen, aspirin, nitro times three.
- I can't believe you're back.
- You look great!
- So do you. I love your hair.
Hey, my brother
could be dying here.
- Ready, steady, lift.
- No response to Narcan.
We were just talking.
That's it, talking.
- Is he taking any medications?
- Not that he's told me about.
Lack of disconjugate gaze and conjugate
deviation rules out a structural lesion.
CBC, chem panel, 12-lead,
tox screen and a head CT.
- Did he have a stroke?
- It's too early to say.
The abrupt onset suggests CNS bleed,
seizure, even cardiopulmonary anoxia.
- Pulse ox is 99.
- Don't let him die.
No tremor...
asterixis or myoclonus, suggestive
of a metabolic encephalopathy.
I'm trying to listen.
- You want a portable chest?
- Ask Professor Carter.
How would you
describe your pain?
It hurts.
- Is it stabbing? Burning? Tearing?
- What's the freaking difference?
Okay. I'm gonna give you some
medicine under your tongue.
And open.
- Let me know if it's better.
- Three sprays?
- Yeah. Nitro times three.
- At once?
I don't feel good.
What's happening?
I'm gonna put your
head down for a minute.
- I feel so dizzy.
- What?
Everything's blurry. - Okay.
You're gonna feel a little bit more
oxygen flowing through your nose.
- How's the pain in your chest?
- Worse.
- 80/60.
- Is it bad?
- No, just a little bit low.
- Was that the wrong medicine?
No, everything's okay. This
just happens sometimes.
Dr. Mooney is one of our best.
- I'll go write my note.
- Yeah, do that.
- Neuroleptic malignant syndrome.
- It's in the differential.
- Where did you come up with that?
- Photographic memory.
And I delivered a lecture
on coma last week.
- Ridiculous.
- What?
Time. Yesterday it seems
you couldn't start an IV.
It was longer than yesterday.
- Carter.
- Yeah?
- Mooney saw my patient.
- What'd you tell him about nitro?
- The basics. Three sprays.
- Three sprays. Right. Bam, bam, bam.
- All at once?
- No, you give them every five minutes.
- You left that out.
- How's his pressure?
- Zero over zero. He's dead.
- I'm kidding.
- Ha-ha.
I pulled him through. Keep a
short leash on your students, huh?
- All clear.
- I'm gonna go check on this guy.
- You got this?
- Yeah, I think so.
Did you see him get hit?
No. I went to return the shopping
cart and he was just laying by the car.
- What do you got?
- Weak pulse, shallow resps.
What's your dad's name? - Alan.
Alan, can you open your eyes?
- GCS is 2-4-5.
- Is he waking up?
Not just yet.
Mark, look at this.
We need a backboard.
Blood count's normal. Chemistry's
okay. Nothing on the tox screen.
- All of his labs look good.
- Why is he still in a coma?
How much longer up there?
- Has he ever seen a psychiatrist?
- I don't think so.
Sorry.
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Coming through!
Need a portable chest and pelvic.
Your brother has signs
of psychogenic coma.
- What's that?
- When we open his eyelids, they flutter.
He responds to a Q-Tip in the
nose. I don't think it's a real coma.
What do you mean, he's faking?
What about the shaking and the
frothing at the mouth and everything?
I'd like to get a
psychiatric consultation.
Yeah, yeah. That would be great. He
has been under a lot of pressure lately.
- Hey, what's taking so long?
- You're still dressed?
- We'll move him to a quieter room.
- Great.
Do you have a gown? I could catch
cold. It's bad enough I'm bleeding out.
Go back to your bed.
The nurse will bring one.
How long until the
psychiatrist gets here?
I'll let you know.
Can I just talk to my
surgeon? British chick, red hair.
Will you shut up?!
- Systolic's up to 100.
- Let's roll him. Set up the SonoSite.
- Cross for 6. GREENE:
Large abrasions to the back.
Did the car crush him
against something?
I didn't see. ALAN: Tracey...?
- Daddy? GREENE:
Sir, you're in a hospital.
- Do you know what the date is?
- Daddy, I'm so sorry.
You didn't see me. - Alan?
- What's he saying?
- I don't know.
- Sorry for what?
- Were you in the car?
- I'm sorry.
- Looks like a liver lac.
- I'll go get her.
- Let's intubate. Etomidate and sux.
- Where were you stationed?
- In Birmingham.
- I have an uncle in Birmingham.
- Does he work in the steel mills?
The university.
We handled mail
for 7 million soldiers.
Sixty-five thousand
pieces every eight hours.
- My goodness.
- Nothing beats a letter from home.
Ooh!
What do you think?
It's a perforation. A
small hole in the colon.
It's from her
diverticular disease.
I'm afraid you'll need
an operation to fix it.
- Is that really necessary? She's so weak.
- It's really the only option.
Can't we wait a few days?
Then she'll become extremely ill,
and surgery could be dangerous.
If I were your mother, would
you recommend the operation?
Absolutely.
- Then we'll do it.
- Dr. Corday?
I have a Mr. Ashman who
says you repaired his hernia.
- Chubby, drug-seeking hypochondriac?
- Complains of abdominal pain.
- What's his exam like?
- Didn't do one.
Then why are you talking to me?
Some surgeons treat
their patients primarily.
- Not this one.
- Well, he's going to say he's tender.
- You'll be seeing him eventually.
- Maybe, maybe not.
- Oh, I'm pretty certain.
Abby. ABBY: Malik.
Who gets the vent? - Curtain 3.
- I have to start a dopamine drip.
- Curtain 2, he's still fully clothed.
- He needs a gown, don't you think?
- Sure.
Stop! Ah!
Hey! HOWARD: Somebody!
Ah! Ah!
- You thought you could fool me?
- Mr. Norden!
Stop it! Security!
You take a loan from Mr. Bennett,
he expects his money back.
You pay it by Monday or next time it's
gonna be your head, you understand?
I need a nurse in here. Oh,
my God. Are you all right?
- He broke my legs.
- He's not your brother?
- Want me to call your mom?
- No. No. It's just us.
God, we were having
such a great day too.
He took me out to lunch
because I got into law school.
Early acceptance?
He even...
He even laminated a copy
of the letter to his toolbox.
- What is that? What are they doing?
- They're just taking x-rays.
- Is something broken?
- He may have a crushed pelvis.
- Is that really bad?
- Possibly. He might need surgery.
God.
He had to have been run over
or pinned against something.
It was a wall.
What?
Look, I thought
I was in reverse.
It was such a tight space. He was
out front waiting for me to back out.
I thought it was in reverse.
- Mr. Stegman's troponin is positive.
- I sent Mooney to the library.
- Good call. CPK on Norden.
- That's Susan's patient. Dr. Lewis.
- Has she always been high-maintenance?
- She's not. She's great.
- Could you get a rectal temp in Room 4?
- Anything else?
- That should do it.
- I heard about your hit man.
More like an enforcer.
- Never a dull moment.
- I could use a dull moment.
- Pick a chart. Any chart.
- This is a setup.
No, just go ahead. Pick.
- Are you sure?
- No.
Female abdominal
pain. What did you get?
Suture removal.
- This is definitely a setup.
- On a scrotum.
Maybe not.
All right, where is he? - Who?
Mr. Ashman. You
paged for a consult.
Curtain 2. Epigastric
tenderness on exam.
- As predicted.
- Better hurry before he finds his clothes.
Dr. Corday, there's a code in
the SICU, one of your patients.
You'll have to keep him hidden.
Amal? AMAL: Yes.
Hi, I'm Dr. Lewis. How long have
you had your stomach trouble?
Since yesterday. How
long is this gonna take?
I don't know. It depends
on what's wrong.
Well, I need to be home in
two hours, no matter what.
Pressure's good, 110/60.
TKO the saline. Send
up the last two O-neg.
- Is he okay?
- He's responding to blood transfusion.
- But he needs surgery to repair his liver.
- Hold the elevator!
- Can I go with him?
- Take her to the surgical waiting room.
Wait right here, I'll
come back and get you.
- You want one-shot IVP?
- We'll do it upstairs.
- It's two-plus for heme.
- Got it.
Dr. Greene? Did you get
a BAL on the daughter?
I smelled alcohol on her breath.
A DUI with injury is a felony.
- She wasn't driving.
- Now she says she was.
- Did you get the CT? Radiology's waiting.
- Peter took him to the O.R.
She's changing her story.
- Did you smell alcohol on the
daughter? WEAVER: I don't know. Maybe.
- Are you arresting her?
- You can still draw a level.
Give her a break. Her
father's in critical condition.
Because she hit him
while under the influence.
- Doesn't seem drunk to me.
- Forget it.
I'll call a phlebotomist
from the station.
You'll get your draw. Just wait
until her dad's out of surgery.
- How long?
- A couple of hours.
My sergeant wants me back
on the streets. I can't babysit.
Well, come back. She's
not gonna go anywhere.
Take your time
and think it over.
No, you don't understand.
I have to have an abortion.
- You have other options, you know.
- No, not for me.
My parents are so strict.
- They'll kill me.
- Everybody thinks that.
No, it's different for us.
I have to be a virgin
on my wedding day.
- I think if you give them the chance...
- No.
If they find out
that I've had sex...
I'm no longer their daughter.
They'll send me away,
out of the country.
And I don't want
to live there. I can't.
- Hmm.
- What?
Do you know what an
ectopic pregnancy is?
A miscarriage?
Not exactly. It's where the
fetus grows in the fallopian tube.
- So then I have to have an abortion.
- It's more complicated than that.
- You'll need surgery.
- An operation?
- Right now.
- Well, how long does it take?
- You leave the hospital by tomorrow.
- I have to be home for dinner in an hour.
If you don't have surgery, it
could rupture. You'll bleed to death.
- Then I'll come back Saturday.
- You may not make it to Saturday.
- I don't care.
- I need a doctor in Trauma 1 right now.
Pregnancy is confidential. We
don't have to tell your parents.
- Dr. Lewis, status epilepticus.
- You stay right there. I'll be right back.
Amal, okay?
Paramedics gave 4 of
Ativan, but she's still seizing.
- How's the airway?
- Borderline. You may have to tube her.
- Give another 2 of Ativan.
- Oh, you got this one?
- Who are you?
- Susan Lewis. It's my first day.
- Resident?
- Attending.
Tachy at 130.
- We'll do it together.
- Okay.
- How long has she been seizing?
- Got the call 20 minutes ago.
- Any history?
- Husband only speaks Spanish.
- Okay, let's prep a gram of Dilantin.
- We should intubate.
Go ahead.
- Push 70 of Zemuron.
- What?
- Rocuronium.
- I have to go to the pharmacy.
- It's the best non-depolarizing agent.
- Maybe, but we don't stock it.
Hundred of sux.
I'll get the airway.
Push the Dilantin.
360. Clear. NURSE 1: Clear.
- Still in fib.
- How long since Cordarone?
- Twenty minutes.
- 360 again. Give an amp of epi.
- I just did.
- Trying to raise the dead, Lizzie?
Clear. NURSE 1: Clear.
Septic hemicolectomy. Maxed
out on dopamine and Levophed.
- Asystole.
- Go directly to the morgue.
- Do not pass "go." Do not collect $200.
- Okay, that's it. I'll call the family.
Not that I'm keeping score, but isn't
this your third post-op death this week?
Congratulations. We
call that a hat trick.
- Thousand of Dilantin onboard.
- Get ready with phenobarb.
The husband.
Sir, does your
wife have epilepsy?
- Can we get a translator?
- No, it's okay.
She's on an anti-TB
med. Isoniazid.
- What?
- It's an overdose...
because the label is in English.
It says, "Take once a day."
O-N-C-E. In Spanish, that means 11.
She took 11 pills a day?
We need pyridoxine, at least 6 grams.
It's the only way we're gonna stop this.
Check the blood gas. She'll need
an amplified carbon. She's acidemic.
- Pavulon while we wait.
- What did you say?
I said we'd help her.
- I am diabetic. I need water.
- Well, then we'll start an IV for you.
- I drink. I throw up. I feel better.
- No. Nothing to drink.
You have gallstones
the size of golf balls.
- I have "golf" stones?
- You have gallstones.
- Can you start a line? MAU:
How do you charge this?
The crash cart. He's
crashing. Looks like V-tach.
Does he have a pulse?
- I don't think so.
Charge to 200. Stanley, have
you ever shocked a patient before?
- This one's all yours.
- That's okay.
- I am right here. ABBY:
Charged and ready.
Apply firm pressure. And before you
press the buttons, back off, say "clear."
Okay. Clear. CARTER: Ow!
Did you get shocked?
You're supposed to say
"clear" before, not after.
- Normal sinus rhythm! I've got a pulse!
- So does he, thank God.
Were you touching the
bed frame? EKG lead?
- No. His arm right here.
- Oh, ouch.
Hold on. I'll get
you an ice pack.
Feels like someone
kicked me in the chest.
Well, consider yourself
lucky, Mr. Stegman.
- How long has she been seizing?
- Almost an hour.
Four grams of
pyridoxine onboard.
She needs 1 gram per gram
ingested. Give another 4.
- We don't have another 4.
- Go to the pharmacy.
- I can't.
- Send another nurse.
This is all we have
in the whole hospital.
Okay, send couriers to Mercy,
Northwestern, Parkside...
Parkside closed last year.
Every nearby hospital. We
need all the pyridoxine we can get.
V-fib. Starting compressions.
Charge to 200.
- Daughter was driving?
- Crushed him against a wall.
You wonder why
I don't have kids.
- Lizzie, what you got?
- Perfed diverticulum.
Clean under your fingernails.
Don't want another post-op infection.
Dr. Benton, there's a
Roger on the phone.
He's in surgery.
- Take a message.
- He says it's important.
- Hold the phone.
- He's crashing!
Get four more units of packed cells!
- Good news can wait.
- Bad news will never go away.
- Tell him I'll call him back.
Hold compressions.
- Asystole.
- Start pacing at 140.
Courier's got pyridoxine from
Mercy. It'll be here in 10 minutes.
Turn up the gain.
- No capture.
- Resume compressions.
- How long has she been down?
- No cardiac activity for 35 minutes.
You want to keep going?
PH is 6.8.
We'll never get her back.
I'm calling it. Stop CPR.
Put the husband in a
quiet room. I'll be right there.
Good pickup. Once.
I would have
missed the diagnosis.
A lot of good it did.
- Feeling any better?
- Yeah. The boys bounce back quick.
Ow! I think I might've
tweaked it again.
Want one of the doctors to take a
look at your back? Or your front?
- Is that Yetna?
- Mm-hm.
She's tossing her cookies.
No cookies. Chicken,
potato and ice cream.
- Dr. Carter, I'm really sorry.
- It's not your fault.
- Should we order an x-ray?
- No. It's just a spasm.
Could be somatic dysfunction
at the myofascial junction.
I studied alternative
medicine in Hong Kong.
I could try a
muscle-energy technique.
I think you've done
enough for one day.
Help me mobilize the liver.
- Bovie and pickups.
- Get a good look at the IV seal.
- Peter! Where's Reece?
- What?
- Reece isn't in the playroom.
- You were picking him up.
- He wasn't there.
Free up the falciform.
- Where is he?
I thought you had him here.
- No.
- Who let this guy in?
- Carla's mother pick him up?
- No. PERRY:
Systolic's down to 60.
Four-sucker bleed. Lap
pads! Let's pack off the liver.
- Her name is on a card at school.
- Okay. I'll try her.
Good idea. You call Grandma...
and I'll roll this guy over so
we can all kiss his ass goodbye!
Sign here.
- Corday finally see him?
- No. I drank that Russian water.
- Yetna's water?
- Yeah. I'm better now, no thanks to you.
- Take this, you'll need it.
- You seen the girl in Exam 1?
- She took off. She'll be back at 9.
- Why didn't anyone get me?
- You were busy with the arrest.
- She has an ectopic.
- You didn't tell me.
- Where's the chart?
- It's here somewhere.
- Could you find it, please?
Could you pull up "Razavi" on the
computer and print out a red sheet?
Excuse me. We're here to
see Dr. Carter. She fainted.
- I did not faint. I was dizzy.
- You'll need to see a triage nurse.
- Is that you?
- Through those doors.
We should go through those
doors and right back to the car.
- Please. John Carter.
- Dr. Carter's very busy.
John!
If you wanna see a doctor,
you need to sign in at triage.
- Gamma, what are you doing here?
- Ask him.
- She fainted outside Marshall Field's.
- I did not.
- Did you hit your head?
- No. I didn't faint.
- This is your grandmother?
- Gamma, this is Susan Lewis.
- Pleasure.
- I'm terribly sorry, ma'am.
Well, I guess you're
only rude to strangers.
- John... CARTER: Do
you have any chest pains?
Mrs. Wilson? Mrs. Wilson,
your surgery went very well.
- You're finished?
- Yes. You're on your way to recovery.
Good. I need your address.
Gotta send you a thank-you note.
- Dr. Corday? Dr. Corday?
- Yes.
Carmen Torino from Infection
Control. Do you have a minute?
- What do you need?
- To speak to you in private.
Okay. Keep her fluids at 125
an hour. Vitals Q 15, CBC in 30.
You lost another
patient today from sepsis.
Yes, but he was
debilitated before surgery.
I understand.
However, his death triggered
a formal investigation.
- Excuse me?
- You need to be cultured.
- Cultured?
- In case your body's carrying bacteria...
that's infecting your patients. Can
you stop by the clinic in an hour?
That's impossible. I have
a patient waiting for me.
Your surgical privileges
could be suspended.
If you have concerns,
talk to my chairman.
I already have.
Drs. Romano and Anspaugh
have given us their full support.
- She signed out AMA?
- No.
- Call her back.
- She thinks she'll be deported.
Tell her parents that she
needs surgery for an ovarian cyst.
Falsify a consent form? I'd
rather keep them in the dark.
She's pregnant. They
don't have to know.
- You trust her to come back?
- I think so. I hope so.
- Dr. Greene, Dr. Corday on two.
- Okay.
- Home yet?
- Susan.
Hi. I heard you lost
one, the INH overdose.
- Yeah.
- Yeah, those can be tough.
How long is it gonna take?
I've been meaning to talk to
you about the nursing shortage.
That blood alcohol came
back just over the limit.
- The girl who hit her father, .092.
- Is he still in surgery?
Want me to tell the cop?
- I will.
Anyway, if you could pitch
in, it'll make everyone happy.
- The nurses are complaining?
- Yeah.
I explained that you're
used to better staffing...
so they'll cut you some
slack until you're up to speed.
Okay, okay. No problem.
Can you cover my last hour?
My first day back,
you're dumping on me?
Elizabeth's stuck. I have
to get home to the baby.
LP results are pending on
Etzler. And Nguyen's getting a V/Q.
- Anything else?
- Yeah, pick me up some milk and Huggies.
BP's 120/80. ROMANO:
Excellent. Take down packing.
Peter. Carla's mom's been home all day.
- Try Jackie.
- I tried. I got Joanie.
- Did she pick him up?
No.
- Retrohepatic caval injury.
- Call the police, now! I gotta go.
- Lost another 2 liters.
- Do a Pringle before he bleeds.
- Shirley, get Edson.
- Prep number-eight atrial shunt.
- I need to be relieved.
- Take your hands off, he'll die.
- Your EKG looks good.
- I told you, I'm fine.
Alger means well, but sometimes
he's annoyingly condescending.
You gave him a scare.
I was a little woozy
getting out of the car.
We call that near syncope.
- I call it skipping lunch.
- Well, you need to eat.
I'll do it.
You been sleeping okay?
Are you depressed?
- I miss him, John.
- Me too.
- Have you thought about therapy?
- I said, I miss him.
- I'm not mentally unstable.
- Sometimes it's good to talk about it.
What's to talk about? He's
gone. And I have things to do.
If I leave now, I can still
make the donors' reception.
We need to monitor
your heart overnight.
In here? I don't think so.
Let's just wait for your
blood-test results to come back.
I've been waiting. I've already
missed two appointments.
If everything checks out, you'll
be back on your feet tomorrow.
There are no more
tomorrows, John. This is it.
Your grandfather and I used to
think we had a lifetime of tomorrows.
Hello, is Amal
there? Oh, I'm sorry.
This is Susan, her
friend from school.
I just had a question
about our math homework.
Oh, okay, great. Yeah, I'll call
back after dinner. Okay, thanks.
- Dr. Lewis, Mr. Cardazco's still waiting.
- Who?
- His wife died. The overdose.
- Oh, damn it! I completely forgot.
No.
No! No, no, no!
Sorry. It has to be a
nasopharyngeal sample.
Oh!
Oh, sorry. It felt more
like a brain biopsy.
The enterobacter from your
patients is a very resistant strain.
I'm aware of that.
You may be colonized.
Open wide.
Quick swab of the tonsils.
God.
- So are we finished?
- Just need to do a pelvic.
You've gotta be kidding!
A surgical tech in Ohio was passing
nocardia from her vaginal flora.
Thank you for sharing that. I'm nursing.
You want a sample of my milk as well?
Absolutely. Then a cath'd
urine and a stool sample.
If you can't go now, take it home
and bring it back in the morning.
Inflate the balloon
and tie off the Rumel.
- How is he?
- They're still working on him.
Why are you leaving?
How much longer?
I have another emergency.
Just wait in the room, okay?
They want us to
make out a report.
This is Dr. Benton at County
General. Send a detective here.
My son is missing! So do your
job and send someone down now!
- ETA?
- Two minutes.
- Flip you for the airway.
- He's already intubated.
- What are we getting?
- Mercy's sending a GSW...
- and we're out of beds.
- You coming?
Move Trauma 1 to Exam
1. Whose chart is this?
Oh, that's mine.
Code the charts at time
of discharge for Billing.
- I'll do it right now.
- Yeah, and be sure the nurse's notes...
- This patient left the hospital?
- Not sure.
- You're not sure? She's an ectopic.
- It's under control.
What do you mean?
She's not here.
- I'm trying to protect her privacy.
- You should be protecting her life.
- She'll be back in two hours.
- If she's still alive!
Lost his pulse on the scene.
- I told her I wouldn't tell her parents.
- You're putting her life at risk.
- Get 4 of O-neg.
- Trust me on this one.
- Prep for a thoracotomy.
- Gown.
Call your patient now.
You're being irresponsible.
- If she's sick, they can bring her in.
- Not if she's dead.
- You got too many names on the list.
- Everyone helps out.
The school can't keep
track of 10 people.
Any stranger could
say he was his uncle.
We've never had a problem before.
You sure you got there on time?
What are you doing
here? Where were you?
- What's going on?
- You picked him up from school?
Yeah. He was acting
out. He bit a little girl.
- You were in surgery. They called me.
- You had us worried.
I left a message
on your voice mail.
It wasn't Peter's day to
pick him up, it was mine.
- You're still picking him up?
- Every Tuesday and Thursday.
He's had three fights
at recess this week.
You fighting?
Teacher wants to know if
there are any problems at home.
She thinks he may
need a little more stability.
What are you trying to say?
- Just telling you what she said.
- He wasn't fighting...
when he lived with us.
Maybe he needs to just live
in one home for a while, okay?
Peter, he's my stepson.
We've got an agreement.
Yeah? Well, we need to think
about what's best for Reece.
He's acting out because
he lost his mother.
Look, we'll talk about this later. I
need to call the police and get him home.
Dr. Weaver, O.R. called. They don't
think Mr. Pomeroy's gonna make it.
Okay, I'll go up. Can you
do the coroner's forms?
Chuny, tell my grandmother
I'll be five more minutes.
And see if Dr. Lewis
called that ectopic girl.
Gamma.
- What are you doing?
- It's late, John. I've been a good sport.
You cannot leave. Fainting can be a
warning sign for heart attack, for stroke.
I'll take my chances.
You'll be signing out
against medical advice.
- I've already done that.
- There's still more tests we need to do.
I'll see you at home, John.
Don't forget to turn out the
porch light when you come in.
- Check on her in about an hour.
- Certainly.
- Good night. MILLICENT:
I feel like a steak, Alger.
We'll stop at Morton's first.
- Yes, ma'am.
Oh, dear, I'm very hungry.
Filet mignon, creamed spinach...
- Sorry if I offended her.
- Oh, don't worry about it.
She never takes me seriously.
What do you expect?
She changed your diapers.
That's true.
- Any focal neuro findings, EKG changes?
- No. I monitored her for three hours.
Yeah, she should be okay.
- Did you call your ectopic girl?
- I'm gonna give her till 9.
- That's a bit of a risk.
- "Danger" is my middle name.
Any other catastrophes?
It's been like an acid
flashback without the good parts.
What was I thinking
when I said I'd come back?
You weren't.
- But at least you're working with friends.
- Yes.
Excuse me. Pickman's
got a woman in active labor.
Showtime.
Denise Frankel,
full-term. She's crowning.
Showtime is right.
- Ah! I need to push!
- Go ahead, push.
- Membrane's ruptured. Fluid's clear.
- How many kids have you had?
- Two. LEWIS: Well,
this one's coming fast.
Take your foot off
the pedal, bed's rising.
- I'm nowhere near it.
- Must be a short.
- What's happening?
- Technical difficulty.
Oh, man. When her water broke,
it must have flooded the switch.
Late decel. We have
to get this baby out.
- I can't deliver like this.
- Get Luka. He's tall.
- Carter, take over.
- What...? Where are you going?
What are you doing?
Excuse me. Get down. Get down!
Okay, just blow.
Drop your arm over the
side, I need to start an IV.
- Give me a hand.
- Oh, you're kidding me.
- What are you doing?
- Setting up some equipment.
- Fetal heart rate's 140.
- Don't drop my baby!
Don't worry. Dr. Carter
used to be in the circus.
As a clown, right?
- Human cannonball, until I got fired.
- Okay, give a big push. Push!
- Ah!
- Push! Head's out. Relax.
- That cord is tight around the neck.
- Reduce it?
- I don't think so. How about a clamp?
- Toss it.
Second clamp.
Scissors.
Is it a boy or a girl?
One more push and
we're about to find out.
It's a boy.
- Is he okay?
- Oh, he's beautiful.
Can I see him?
Yeah, as soon as we
strap on a parachute.
Oh, yeah.
"Hi, Mom."
- I killed him! Oh, my God, I killed him.
- I'm so sorry. I'm so sorry.
I need to see him.
Miss Pomeroy? We have to leave now.
I'm required to place you under arrest.
It was an accident! He was my father!
- Calm down!
- You have the right to remain silent...
- Is this really necessary?
- We only had a couple glasses of wine!
- Let her say bye.
- Where is he? Where did you put him?
- Let her say goodbye.
This way.
God, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
- I got Ella's diaper culture.
- You didn't need to do that.
- Hey, not with the food.
- I triple-bagged them.
- Did I hear a phone ring?
- No.
- She still hasn't called?
- Not yet.
- The party was over at 8.
- I know.
- So call her.
- I don't have her phone number.
- Look it up.
- I didn't get Claire's last name.
Mark, you need to
know these things.
I talked to the parents, I
thought everything was okay.
- We don't even know where she is.
- I told you about the party.
- You know what time it is?
- It's only 10:15.
You were supposed
to call two hours ago.
- I'm sorry.
- How'd you get home?
- Andrew.
- I think I'll check on the little one.
All they had were hot dogs and
burgers, so some of us went to eat.
- Some of us, or you and Andrew?
- Dad!
- I need to know these things.
- Sounds like something Mom would say.
I wasn't drinking. I'm not doing drugs.
I'm just making some new friends.
- All you had to do was call.
- I tried.
The pay phone was broken.
If you don't believe
me, call the restaurant.
Don't ever let
this happen again.
Okay?
Okay.
If I had a cell phone,
we could keep in touch.
- Yeah, right.
- Seriously, just for emergencies.
We'll see.
Thanks.
You guys do good work.
- So do you.
I'll call you when it's time
to build his tree house.
- Amal.
- Dr. Lewis.
I'm so sorry I'm late. It
was hard to sneak out.
- I am so glad you came back.
- I told the nurse I'd be here at 9.
- Well, people say a lot of things.
- You said it was important.
- Abby, can you find us a room?
- Yeah. Good to see you.
- Where's her chart?
- Weaver's got it.
- Amal's chart? Why?
- I don't know.
- Where is she?
- She's on a call in the lounge.
- Oh, damn it!
- Kerry, get off the phone.
- I work at the ER...
- She's here. You don't have to call.
- Susan...
I told you she'd be back.
- Who?
- Amal, the ectopic.
I didn't call her.
Oh.
Hello. Hi. I'm sorry
we got disconnected.
No, actually, I got your
number from an investigator...
who specializes in
finding birth parents.
Did you give up a
daughter for adoption?
I understand.
No. I...
I am sorry. I thought this
was from a reliable source.
I will not bother you again.
Good night.