Come on in.
I'm not doing any more chemo.
Good plan.
You'll be dead in five months.
We went for a
cure, it didn't work.
I've thought about this a lot.
Five more months on
this Earth is reasonable.
A year in the hospital
in excruciating pain is
not.
With two weeks on,
two weeks off of chemo,
you could have way
more than a year.
Maybe two or three.
House.
I'm sorry.
I'm not gonna let you just die.
Hey.
You know, management
research shows that
the best ideas come
from casual contact.
So, one set of season tickets.
I got the seat next to you.
First game is October 8th.
It's about one month after
Wilson's expiration date.
This isn't an
unstructured collaboration.
You're trying to
be the new Wilson.
I'm trying to show you there are
other people who care about you.
Relax. I'm probably
not gonna fall apart.
Five, six, seven, eight. One, two,
three, four, five, six, seven, eight.
One, two, three, four, five,
six, seven, eight. Here we go.
Cradle. One...
Put down the pom-poms and
step away from the computer.
46-year-old oncologist
refuses treatment.
Foreman already gave us a case.
Wants us to keep
things as normal
as possible for as
long as possible.
Wilson is dying, Chase is gone,
how close to normal do
you think we can come?
19-year-old
cheerleader, admitted with
massive nosebleed and dizziness.
Wow, cool, I just completely
forgot that my best friend is dying.
Wait, that just reminded me.
Head CT is clean.
How can we turn Wilson
from a terminal idiot
into an interminable
pain in the ass?
A mini-stroke could
explain our patient's
neuro symptoms
and his butterfingers.
But not his bloody nose.
My best friend is
trying to kill himself.
He just wants to die
with a little dignity.
There's no such thing.
It's not your choice, House.
Your only choice here is
between acceptance and misery.
It's a midline granuloma.
Get your patient a PET scan.
No lesions along the optic
track... You already covered that.
Maybe we should get
someone else to take this case.
Why? Because someone
somewhere is dying?
Oh, crap! Turn off the mic.
It is off.
Not according to his brain. His
temporal lobe is completely lit up.
Auditory portion. He's
hearing something.
Foreman's trying to date me.
I assume that's
because you called him.
No, I...
Did you put something
in my coffee?
You know how you can be there
for me five months from now?
Don't be dead five
months from now.
Hey, Wilson...
Seriously?
Just a little picker-downer.
I assume this unwanted interruption
means you're looking for me
to discuss the
latest development
in a case I don't
want to discuss.
Our patient is hearing voices.
He denies it, but the
PET scan says otherwise.
He's at the right age for
the onset of schizophrenia.
Yeah. You really need me.
Ultrasound his abdomen
to check for schizophrenia.
We already ordered a psych
evaluation, but drugs could also cause...
Tox screen was clean.
Ultrasound his dorm.
Whoa! You guys can't just come
busting in here without a warrant.
We're not cops. We're
your roommate's doctors.
Any idea what flavor of drugs
would be making your roommate sick?
Objection. Entrapment.
I'm pre-law.
Derrick doesn't party.
Look at this.
Why would he have a
picture of a little boy?
Maybe it's his
nephew or something?
Hidden in his sock drawer?
Whoa!
Creepy.
We need to talk to Derrick
about some medical matters.
Well, she's my girlfriend.
She can be here for that.
We found this in your dorm room.
Who is that?
Nobody.
Then why was it
hidden in a drawer?
Derrick, what's
she talking about?
It's my brother, Christopher.
You never told me
you had a brother.
Well, he's been dead
almost 10 years, so...
Is that the voice you
hear in your head?
Mmm!
And, Io, he is risen.
So now my hair's
gonna fall out next week?
No, all I did was temporarily
kill you. How was it?
Look, I wasn't dead.
I was unconscious.
No dreams or thoughts.
You experience nothing.
Now, imagine that without
the waking up on the couch part.
Just nothing, times infinity.
You didn't just prove death is
nothing. You proved propofol is.
You're saying the
end is not the end?
I was expecting, "Nothing is
better than something lousy,"
but not, "The angels
are waiting for me."
I'm not having
this conversation.
Why? Because it
doesn't make sense?
Because I'm not gonna change
your mind, and I don't care.
More importantly, you're
not gonna change mine.
There is no heaven,
there is no hell,
your soul is not gonna
float out of your body
and join some great,
unifying energy force.
The fact that you're dying
is not gonna change that.
Please, just go.
House.
I have spent the last 20 years
holding the hands of people as they die.
When I watch that
transformation...
I'm sorry, I don't believe that
we're just a bag of chemicals.
So are we gonna talk about
the patient, or wait for House?
Viral encephalitis.
It's been going on for 10 years.
I'm gonna go in there and
invite him to participate.
I think he'd welcome
the distraction.
Come with me?
Why?
When was the last time House
listened to anything we said
about anything personal?
Maybe you'll feel better,
but sometimes, the truth is,
there's nothing anyone can do.
Temporal lobe epilepsy.
Causes voices, dizziness.
Trauma from a seizure
would explain the nose bleed.
You know about
all of my siblings,
and cousins, and
aunts and uncles, and...
You're overreacting.
Because you don't trust
me enough to tell me about...
Sorry. It's time to
go down for your test.
If you want to wait here,
it'll only take about an hour.
No, she's leaving.
Derrick, come on. I mean,
we should at least talk.
No, I'd rather you just leave.
And you don't need to come back.
Time. Any odd tastes or smells?
No. Feel fine.
Things looked
fine on my end, too.
So you won't admit
to your doctors
that you're hearing
your brother's voice,
which is dangerous.
And now, you lost
your girlfriend over it.
Which is stupid.
I assume there's
more to the story?
That's how I was raised.
Short story. Yeah.
My boss is losing his
best friend to cancer.
And instead of
talking about the pain,
he's pretending
there is no pain,
because everything can be fixed.
My father tried to deal with it.
Ironic that he'd drink
himself into oblivion
after my brother was
killed by a drunk driver.
Do you need a tissue?
After Dad left, my
mom moved us away.
She got rid of all the pictures of
Christopher and never mentioned him again.
It was like he never existed.
And that worked for us.
And, yet, you kept one.
Uh... My right eye...
I was seeing spots, but now I
can't see at all. Is that from the test?
No, this is something else.
Ah! That hurts! Sorry.
How many fingers?
Two. Fuzzy ones, but two.
It's a clot in the artery behind
your eye. I just broke it up.
Is that bad?
Don't know. Because I
don't know why it happened.
Hey.
Saved us a table.
There are no tables.
I recently hacked
into your old files.
Found a 6-year-old boy
with bilateral retinoblastoma.
Doctors wanted
to take his eyes out
before the cancer
spread to his brain.
But you fought them. Advocated
for a new photon beam radiation.
Saved the kid's vision,
probably saved his life.
That was my first case
at PPTH. Mikey Kimble.
It's Michael, now.
Oh, yeah, this is our table.
Wow.
How are you?
I'm doing great.
Graduating next month.
Already? Little Mikey?
And I got accepted to Princeton.
I'm planning on
going to med school.
He's going to be a doctor.
Instead of being dead.
Dr. House told me all
about your situation.
That's why I came.
There's just so much
good that you can do,
even in a small amount of time.
I wonder...
Hey!
Is there anybody else here who's alive
today because of Dr. James Wilson?
Gastric adenocarcinoma.
Fifteen years in remission.
Six grandchildren that
I never would have met.
Thank you, Dr. Wilson.
Squamous cell lung cancer.
Twelve years in remission.
I was able to walk my
daughter down the aisle last May.
Thank you, Dr. Wilson.
I did the math.
Seventy-four children are
alive today because of you.
Fourteen grandchildren.
Mikey Kimble started
kindergarten before the age cut-off.
He would have graduated
high school last year.
I flunked a year?
Was anybody in this room
really a patient of mine?
They're somewhere.
They're giving you a
standing "O" somewhere.
They exist. You
saved their lives.
It's actually more impressive
that they're too busy to be here.
What's this?
A glowing letter
of recommendation
you just wrote for
me on my laptop.
I noticed it's lacking your
signature at the bottom.
Don't you think you're being a bit
premature predicting House's demise?
Not demise, just implosion.
He's going through a rough time.
But, so far, he's
been handling it...
House?
Your shoes are wet.
Glad to see your
emotional turmoil
hasn't dulled your
powers of observation.
I know you're responsible.
No, you don't. Because I
didn't do it. Whatever "it" is.
But if I had shoved those
season tickets down some toilets,
I would have done it
because you asked me to.
You wanted to replace Wilson.
I prank Wilson all the time.
Enjoy.
I got you three,
but I drank them.
You didn't have to call me,
but I appreciate I made the list.
It wasn't entirely unselfish.
I didn't feel right approaching
any of my terminal
patients, but...
What is it like?
Hmm...
Does it ever stop being surreal?
It'll stop in about five or six
months, give or take, in your case.
You know what
happened to me today?
One of my patients
suddenly started crying.
It can't be your first.
It was the first one
who was crying for me.
It's the human response.
It's either overly saccharine,
because giving sympathy
makes them feel better,
or they ignore you,
because hiding from mortality
makes them feel better.
Well, why can't they just say
something that makes me feel better?
Like what, exactly?
I don't know. No.
Mmm...
You'd be doing what? Two
weeks on, two weeks off?
So maybe do your first
round, see how it goes.
May be not as
horrible as you fear.
Then do the second round,
enjoy your two weeks off,
and revisit the
decision. Rinse, repeat.
I just can't envision
spending my remaining time
in a chemo suite in Princeton.
I want to enjoy myself
with family and friends.
Friends, or friend?
Hi, this is Greg House
again. Third message.
Hopefully indicating how
much I want you to call me back.
I'd say that your son is
dying to increase the urgency,
but you probably
already know that.
The fake people who care that
Wilson stays alive didn't work,
so I need the real people
who care about him
to tell him what
an idiot he's being.
Where are we going?
Well, I just got paged
to go to the bathroom.
I don't know where the
rest of you are going.
Some of our patient's
symptoms might be physiological
and some might be psychological.
You think being forced
to bury painful memories
is making his symptoms worse?
Grief avoidance can lead to
all sorts of anxiety disorders,
which can manifest
into physical illness.
Let's assume that all his
symptoms are real symptoms.
So we're going to
avoid grief avoidance?
Studies after September
11th showed that
repression was
actually better for coping
than dwelling in misery.
What about polycythemia vera?
RBC's are slightly
elevated, but not that much.
Hodgkin's lymphoma?
Would have shown
up on the PET scan.
What if our guy
got hurt at practice
and, like everything else,
just didn't tell anyone?
Could have set off DIC.
Would explain everything.
I thought you had to
go to the bathroom.
I didn't say I had to go in.
Need some more mops in here!
What exactly are
you looking for?
Blood. If your spinal fluid
is yellow instead of clear,
it means you've had a
subarachnoid hemorrhage.
What does your
brother say to you?
Does he tell you
you're gonna be okay?
It doesn't really
work like that.
I think you hear your
brother's voice for a reason.
I thought you guys said that I
hear things because I'm sick.
Yes, but that doesn't explain
why you don't hear a different voice.
I think your mom
didn't let you deal
with the grief of losing
your brother properly.
There are people here
who could help you with that.
Okay.
The opening
pressure's way too high.
The prodigal daughter returns.
You taking me up
on my offer to off you?
I think I've still got
some leftover propofol.
I spoke to Wilson.
He's angry because I want him
to live longer. Who wouldn't be?
Friends respect
each other's decisions,
even if they don't
agree with them.
It's called loyalty.
Loyalty is a tool to get people
to do things they
don't want to do.
But you do want to.
And you may have
rationalized it 100 different ways,
but the fact is you
fired me so that
I'd be forced to spend
the rest of my life
doing exactly
what I wanted to do.
It was probably the most selfless
thing anyone has ever done for me.
And you don't even
like me that much.
I surrender.
I have been a disloyal,
disrespectful jerk.
I should've listened
to what you wanted.
I'm still not letting my
parents return your call.
I made a reservation for two
at Carmine's. Tonight, 8:00.
No more tricks. No
more manipulations.
Said Machiavelli.
Just two friends enjoying
the time they have left.
Please, don't... I'm not.
I promise.
Just dinner?
That depends on how
much you have to drink.
Sounds nice.
Mom.
I came as soon as
I got your message.
Is he gonna be okay?
We're hoping it's
just excess fluid
on his brain from
an extreme migraine.
Which isn't good,
but it's treatable.
He's scheduled to get an MRI as
soon as these meds start taking effect.
We found that picture
in his dorm room.
I'm not sure what
Derrick's told you,
but he's been hearing Christopher's
voice for the last 10 years.
And it's possible that
repressing all that grief he's felt
is actually causing some
of Derrick's symptoms.
I don't even know if this voice in
my head is something I invented,
or if it's what Christopher
was really like.
With no photos, no video,
my memories,
I really don't have any anymore.
Maybe you could just
tell me a little bit about him?
I'm sorry. It was
a long drive in.
I'm gonna go get a coffee.
Okay.
Seventy-nine years old and
you told her she was pregnant.
Well, it cured her hiccups.
I'll say I didn't expect
her to cry for quite so long.
Now, I know that the
tiramisu is great here,
but I actually ordered off menu.
Greg, I told you you didn't
hang the bear bag high enough.
It was a smart bear.
I'm almost certain
he untied my knots.
Well, he wasn't that smart.
He left the Oreos behind.
You hiked for 32 miles eating
nothing but creamy filling.
The black stuff is overrated.
To climbing the hill.
Okay.
If I did decide to stick
around a little longer...
Don't do that to me, Wilson.
No, I'm not. I'm just...
I do feel pretty good,
and maybe I should try it.
For a little while.
I think that's reasonable.
Are you conning me?
You're conning me.
What?
Just because you folded, that
means it must be some evil plan?
Well, that's usually how it works
with you. You drown me in nostalgia,
so I'll think about our friendship
and feel some kind of loyalty,
and agree to more chemo.
That was real nostalgia, it was
real emotion, it's a real decision.
A decision that I
just made for you.
I need you, okay.
I want you to be around
as long as possible,
because I don't know what
I'm gonna do without you.
No! No. Don't do that.
I don't owe you anything.
Our entire relationship
has been about you.
My dying is about me.
Look at you. You
don't wanna die.
Of course, I don't wanna die.
Then fight.
I did. I tried.
One time.
House, get out of my car.
You don't have
to just accept this.
Yes, I do have to accept
this. I have five months to live.
And you're making me
go through this alone?
I'm pissed because
I'm dying. That's not fair.
And I need...
I need a friend.
I need to know that
you're there. I need...
I need you to tell me that
my life was worthwhile.
And I need you to tell
me that you love me.
No.
I'm not gonna tell you
that unless you fight.
Blood vessels are
non-reactive. It's not a migraine.
I'm not feeling so
great, how much longer?
Finishing up.
Thank you, Dr. Adams.
It looks like the
ceiling might...
What are you doing back here?
We got a case. I assume the
status is patient's getting worse,
you guys are confused.
You think actually
showing up for work
is enough to make
up for ruining an MRI?
Endangering the
patient, injuring us?
I've got an airtight
alibi that I'm working on.
This isn't about the
damage. You're back
because something's
going on with Wilson.
I'm done with Wilson.
What does that mean,
you're done with Wilson?
If he's not dead, you're
not done with Wilson.
Suddenly, you think you're
gonna make a difference?
You can't just abandon him.
It's in his hands
now. Did you get
any good pictures
before the MRI drowned?
Enough to know it
wasn't a migraine.
And the patient
mistook me for Adams.
Come with me.
Hey.
So what do you
think's gonna happen
when I stick a needle
into his eardrum?
You quizzing us?
This is a good quiz.
He'll scream in pain.
Don't listen to her.
Very small needle,
very steady hands.
Now, when I pull
back on the plunger,
what do you think
is gonna come out?
Air.
Boy, that air sure is red.
Persistent Stapedial Artery.
It should disappear
in the embryonic stage.
But just like his dead
brother, he really can't let go.
So the artery's been pressing
against the temporal lobe of his brain,
right above the ear canal.
Explains the voices,
the dizziness, everything.
Now you guys can explain how
we're gonna make him better.
Will my brother's voice go away?
You're being an ass.
I just cured a patient.
How about you?
You can't just
give up on Wilson.
You know he needs you.
You know he's making
an impossible choice.
He just doesn't
want to live in pain.
Life is pain.
I wake up every morning and
I'm in pain. I go to work in pain.
You know how many times
I've wanted to just give up?
How many times I've
thought about ending it?
You here to yell at me,
or give me hockey tickets?
Had to delay the surgery
because our patient
drank ammonia
from the janitor's cart.
I guess he didn't want to
live without his brother's voice.
Where are you going?
You can't wait to die?
Here, let me help you.
Hey! Hey! House!
House!
See? You wanna live.
He did something stupid.
He's not gonna do it again.
You're resisting me because it's
our human responsibility to stay alive!
You've made your
point, House! Stop!
You've spent your whole
life looking for the truth.
Well, sometimes,
the truth just sucks.
Um, um...
I'm going to be leaving, uh... Quite a
bit earlier than we had talked about.
Next day or two.
What happened?
Something between you and House?
He's not my child.
I cannot be responsible for
the happiness of Gregory House.
I'll give these to Frankel.
Okay, thank you.
And you are responsible.
The past 20 years,
you've had three wives,
hundreds of colleagues,
thousands of patients.
But you've kept
that one best friend.
He wants me to suffer a misery
that I don't want to go through.
Chemo won't make
your life any better.
But caring will.
Enduring pain to do some
good for someone you care about.
Isn't that what life is?
Mom.
Yeah?
That picture of Christopher
that I had on the stand,
did you take it?
Yes.
Did you throw it out?
If I agree to get this surgery,
can you bring that picture back?
Not home. WILSON: House.
I'm ready to start the
next round of chemo.
Why?
Because you need me.
And I don't think that's
a bad thing anymore.
No.
You're the only one I listen to.
And the last couple of days, I
didn't. I almost killed my patient.
So I think it's time
for me to accept
that you're just
smarter than I am.
Are you really okay that
there's only five months left?
No.
But it's better than nothing.
Um...
How do we start?
Well, I'm not gonna
say, "I love you."
Thank God. Got any Oreos?
Hey. How you feeling?
The surgery worked.
How can you tell?
Because Christopher's gone.
And this is the peak.
Almost 8,000 feet.
You do realize that my leg
situation has deteriorated a little
since the last time
we went hiking.
So add another day.
This is Matt Johnson,
the hospital lawyer.
Yes, I have decided
not to proceed
with the sexual harassment case.
Are these yours?
The plumber retrieved them
from the hospital outflow pipe.
They caused the sewage
back up that ruined the MRI.
And they have your name on them.
Gregory Danger House?
It's a very common name.
These apparently have your
finger prints on them also.
Okay, well, why don't you
tell me how many hours
of picking up trash
you want me to do?
House, I tried to
keep this internal.
The fire department handed
the tickets to the police,
who contacted
your parole officer.
It's felony vandalism.
He's gonna revoke your parole.
There's nothing we can do.
You have to report to
Mercer County Jail on Monday
to serve out the
rest of your sentence.
And that's how long?
I'm sorry. How long?
Six months.