Captioning sponsored
by WARNER BROS.
Dr. Greene?
Dr. Greene!
What is it?
Patient for you, Dr. Greene.
Can't the intern take it?
No. It's for you.
What time is it?
5:00.
All right.
Can't the intern take it?
It's Dr. Ross.
Dr. Ross.
I'll be right there.
We got some up on Four
South to take care of, too.
Come on, Doug.
Marky, boy.
Yeah.
Did I wake you up?
Yes, you did.
You are a real friend.
I want you to know that.
Getting out of bed for me.
Room Three is free.
Three is free.
Free for three. There we go.
Come on, Doug. I got you.
♪ But come ye back when
summer's in the meadow... ♪
Hi.
Ow! Oh, man.
I got it.
I can't tell you how much
I appreciate this, Mark.
Mm-hmm.
I'm a little under the weather.
Here you go.
I know. Yeah, yeah.
All right.
D5, NS. I need the dextrose.
Give him 600 of ASA.
Aspirin. I almost
forgot aspirin.
So, anyway...
she says to me...
She says, "I didn't know
that pediatricians
could be so sexy."
And I said, "Honey, you
ain't seen nothing yet."
Ow! All right.
All right. Give me a fast drip.
I need the hydration.
Don't worry, Doug.
Just lie back.
Ho, ho!
How's your beautiful
wife? How's Jennifer?
She's fine, really.
You two settle your problems?
Yeah, everything's okay.
Hate to lose you in
the ER, You know.
Lie back.
I am.
I can't tell you how
much I appreciate this.
Really do.
Here's your aspirin.
Give him 2,000cc's
in a fast drip.
Keep an eye on it.
Don't let it run dry.
Does he always do this?
Only on his nights off.
I'm going to bed.
Wake me at 6:30.
Dr. Greene.
Dr. Greene?
Mark!
What is it?
Can I give Mrs. Williston
some more Demerol?
She's complaining of pain.
50 Milligrams IM.
Thanks, Mark.
Dr. Greene?
What is it?
6:30, Dr. Greene.
Hey, Timmy.
Good morning, Dr. Lewis.
Oh, Dr. Lewis?
Yeah?
Thank you.
Morning, Dr. Benton.
Hey, Jerry.
This was the scene
at 6:15 this morning
in the Loop where a building
collapsed during construction...
You got any estimate
on the injuries?
How long before they arrive?
Has left at least 12 people
injured and two dead.
Oh, yeah? That soon?
Hey, what's up, Timmy?
Hey, Dr. Benton.
Notify Trauma.
They got an
accident in the Loop...
12 injuries, seven critical.
It's a good day for us surgeons.
Mrs. Williston, in Room
Four, needs a CBC.
The man in Five
is a rule-out MI,
waiting for cardiac enzymes
and another 12 lead.
Dr. Ross, he's in
Three, sleeping it off.
Why don't you wake him
and get him out of there?
Nine, I need a uric acid.
Do you know what this is about?
Building collapsed in the Loop.
They're sending us
a dozen hot ones.
Yeah? Well, who's on?
Just us.
Okay, forget all that.
Call Susan Lewis.
Call the seventh
and eighth floor.
Tell them we need
anybody they can spare.
Why don't you do that now?
Take him to Trauma Room Two.
What's your name, sir?
Can you tell me your name?
Next to Three. That way.
Which way?
That way.
Huh?
Surgical One, down
to the end on the right.
Last door on the right.
What's your name, sir?
Edward Wilson.
What is your address?
40... 47...
Mr. Wilson? Mr. Wilson?
Okay, people. Let's go.
Let's bring him in.
And on my count.
On three. One, two, three!
How you doing, sir?
Don't worry.
Everything will be fine.
Sorry about your suit.
So, was it just your hand?
Well, let's have a look. Light.
Light! Let's move.
Have nice, pleasant thoughts.
Everything will be fine, sir.
Let's have a CBC,
type and crossmatch.
We got a pre-op here.
Notify the OR. Get us a room.
Call Vascular and
call Orthopedic.
Tell them to come down here now.
This is their lucky day.
Mr. Wilson, your hand is
still attached... not by much...
But it's going to be okay.
EKG, and X ray of his
chest, wrist and hand.
Can you feel
anything in your hand?
No.
We're going to save your
hand. Don't worry about a thing.
Clear!
Mr. Jackson, where does it hurt?
Where does it hurt, Mr. Jackson?
In my chest...
Does it hurt when
you breathe in?
Have you been
coughing up any blood?
Okay, let me take a listen.
Dr. Lewis!
Okay, where we taking him?
I just want to check this, okay?
Do you have any
pain in your head?
No.
Your neck?
All right.
What I want you to do...
Tell me if it hurts
when you breathe.
Uh... no.
I don't get a BP.
Start two large-bore
IVs saline, wide open.
Type and cross for ten units.
Four units "O" negative stat.
Drop an NG. Tube and
get Dr. Benton in here.
This is no place
for a pediatrician.
No sensation, radial,
median or ulnar. No pulses.
Color and
temperature as you see.
He's gotten 500cc's
saline. Crits 32.5.
Type and crossmatch
sent. X rays waiting.
OR says they'll have
a room in ten minutes.
Okay. Let's get him out of here.
You think you can save the hand?
Looks pretty good. I think so.
I told him you could,
so he's counting on you.
Peter, you're a smartass.
You'd love to do this case
yourself, wouldn't you?
Yeah. I'm ready. I'm strong.
Yeah. I could do it.
You're a resident.
You're years from
a case like this.
How many fingers?
Three.
What's your name?
Jeff Barr.
Where are you?
Cook County General.
What's today?
St. Patrick's Day.
You're fine. Get a
set of facial bones.
You're going to be
just fine, Mr. Barr.
You're beautiful,
Doc. Thank you.
You married? No. I'm a doctor.
Well, then, listen...
Take it easy, Mr. Barr.
You wouldn't want
to fall on your face
twice in one day.
How much did she vomit?
A couple hundred
cc's, all over Dr. Ross.
Ma'am, would you
please take a deep breath?
Good. Now another.
Any pain there?
No.
How about here?
Okay. It's okay.
Call the OR. Get a room.
What is her crit?
23.
Whoa, wait a minute!
Here we go. No pulse.
She's coding. Code
blue! Call the time.
It's 8:37.
That's a shockable rhythm.
Let's go.
Nice and easy.
Clear!
Okay, give me an amp
of epi and 100 Lidocaine.
Let's move, now. Here we go.
Okay, what do we got here?
Where are the paramedics?
Come on. Get his clothes off.
Give me something.
I can't stand it!
We'll give you
something for the pain.
Just hold on.
Notify the orthopods we
have an open fracture.
Give him tetanus and
five of morphine right away.
Does it hurt anywhere else?
My knee!
Need help?
Yeah. Check his knee.
Okay, there we go.
Here we go.
Dr. Benton, we got patients
on Surgical Two and Three,
and one of them looks bad.
This woman's heart
stopped, and she needs it
pretty badly. Call the AR.
The residents are in Surgery.
Get them out of Surgery.
Can't you see I'm busy? Time?
Two minutes.
Come on, sweetheart.
You're making us
a little nervous here.
Okay, paddles. Let's go.
Clear!
Okay.
Is that a blip?
Recharging.
There it is!
Come on. Come on back to us.
Keep it pumping.
Keep it pumping!
I think she's coming back.
Bring her back for me, baby.
Come back to us.
Come on, baby. Yes!
That one's in Trauma Three.
That's down the
hall and to the left.
Call Pathology.
We've got a customer
who isn't going to
be charged services.
The name's Canelli.
I'm looking for relatives
of Robert Canelli.
Right here.
I'm his son.
Hi. I'm Mark Greene.
My father, he's, uh...
Your father was in
an accident today.
You know that?
Come with me, please.
No. Just tell me.
He's here, right? Just tell me.
Mr. Canelli, your
father had a heart attack
and we were
unable to revive him.
I'm sorry. I'm...
Bastard... you bastards!
You're sorry?
Through here.
The morphine should
make you feel a little better,
and we'll have you in
the OR in no time, okay?
Any others?
No. That's it.
That's it?
Yeah. The last two were DOA.
Well, that's it.
Yeah, for now.
Orderly, please bring a
wheelchair to Admitting.
What happened to Ross?
He went to change.
Somebody threw
up on him. That lady.
The lady who arrested?
She make it? Yeah.
We got her going again.
She's got a junctional
rhythm, but she's going.
What about that guy's hand?
They're still in surgery.
They're going to be working
all day on that one.
Anybody want any coffee?
Yeah, I do.
How do you take it?
Same as yesterday
and the day before that.
And they call me a smartass.
You get any sleep last night?
About an hour.
Oh, damn it!
The nurses have been in
here raiding the coffee again.
Why don't they
just make their own?
I'm going to tell...
Never mind. Never mind.
Okay. Never mind.
Aren't we supposed to be getting
some new students today?
Yeah. I think so.
I hope they're good.
The last two were
really hopeless.
Is something wrong?
Oh, you bet there is.
We're out of coffee again
because the nurses
have been taking it.
That's what's wrong.
So make some more.
Make some more?
We work 36 hours on, 18
off, which is 90 hours a week,
52 weeks a year.
For that we are paid
$23,739 before taxes,
and we also have
to make the coffee?
My heart is breaking.
Where are the filters?
In the refrigerator.
Dr. Greene, your wife
is waiting in the cafeteria.
Oh, damn it.
Everything's fine.
Morning, Dr. Greene.
Morning.
Hey, Mom, look.
Two more bites, baby, please.
Then you're done.
Hi, Rachel.
Hey, Dad, look.
Oh, look.
A grilled cheese
sandwich for breakfast.
I gave in. What can I say?
You're late.
Sorry. We had a big one.
Building collapsed.
Mommy's reading about tarts.
Torts.
Are you getting any sleep?
Yeah, yeah, yeah. I'm okay.
You look tired.
Yeah, Dad. You look tired.
Oh, I do, do I?
Are you going
to finish that?
You mind if I eat it?
Dr. Harris' office called
to confirm your meeting.
Oh, geez, that... that is today.
You can still go, right?
Yeah. Yeah, I guess.
You're not going to
forget or get too busy?
I'll go.
What's so funny?
You know you're
going to hate it.
Maybe not. At least, there,
the patients don't
throw up on you.
Who threw up?
Who threw up?!
Nobody threw up.
It's just that, between
your hours and my studying,
I feel like we never get to
see each other anymore.
I'll go meet Harris today, okay?
Okay.
I just hope you like it.
Oh, no. Would you
look at this?
That's the first
tailored white coat
I've ever seen.
Isn't he lovely?
Lovely.
Think he knows anything?
He knows how to dress.
Well, he's my student.
I'll find out.
John Carter?
Yes, sir.
Peter Benton.
You the surgical student?
Yep. Third year.
Good. We're going to be
spending a lot of time together
so let me show you
around so you'll be oriented.
This is the admitting desk.
If you need someone paged or
a chart called up, you do it here.
This is Timmy.
Don't shake his hand.
He's afraid of disease.
This is the way to the lab.
We do crits, counts, spindowns.
Chemistries are
marked with these slips
and left at the front desk.
Mark everything "stat"
whether you want it fast or not.
The chem lab is 7022.
The heme lab is 6944.
Memorize it.
Everybody gets an IV the
minute they walk through the door.
Use an angiocath
with a 16 needle.
You need a large bore
in case they're bleeding
and you need to transfuse them.
Do you know how to start an IV?
Actually, no.
I thought you were third year.
I am, but all I've done are
dermatology and psychiatry.
The well-dressed
specialties, huh?
Well, you'll find that
surgeons actually
try to help people,
not just bill them.
Now the best way to do
this is to pull the skin tight
so the veins don't
roll and go in low.
Once you're in, pull the gizmo
out and hook it up to here.
This is Carol Hathaway,
the head nurse. John Carter.
Hi. Hi.
She's terrific, isn't she?
She goes with an
orthopod that used
to be a Big Ten tackle
and looks like King Kong.
Now, what you want to
do is you want to tape it.
Moderate flow,
two or three drips per second.
That's it.
That's all there is to it.
Okay?
Uh... um... okay.
All along here you have
the medical examining rooms.
This is where the pill
pushers kill their victims.
But this... this is
the surgical room.
This is where
the real action is.
We use this phone
to call the OR... 6440.
X Ray is around the corner.
They're a bunch of idiots.
They scare the patients
and make them wait too long.
So whenever you can
make sure you go with
the patients to X Ray.
Don't let them get scared.
Don't let them get hurt.
Now, here's Dr. Morgenstern.
He's the head of ER.
Watch out. He eats
students for lunch.
David Morgenstern. John Carter.
When did that
severed hand go up?
Vascular took it up an hour ago.
I just hope they
can do it right.
Dr. Benton is one of the
best residents we have.
You learn everything
you can from him
except attitude.
He didn't mean that.
Yes, he did.
Your room will be down here.
That's where you'll
sew people up.
Do you know how to suture?
Uh... No.
Okay, I'll teach you.
Do we have anyone to sew up?
How would I know?
You know, I love this
great spirit of camaraderie.
Everyone wants
to help, you know.
Okay, Here's the
suture room. Let's see.
Good morning, ma'am.
I'm Dr. Benton.
This is Dr. Carter.
Good morning.
Okay, let's have a look.
How did you do this?
Broke one of the
breakfast dishes.
Well, don't worry.
We'll have you
fixed up right away.
Now, can you feel this?
Yes.
Can you move your finger?
Of course. It's just a cut.
Dr. Benton, we have
a policeman coming in
with a gunshot wound
to the lower extremity.
Put him in Room Two.
Notify X Ray.
I'll be right there.
Now, here's all your stuff.
Ask the patient if she's allergic
to the locals or any drugs.
Now, this is lidocaine,
but call it novocaine.
They've heard of that.
Ma'am, are you
allergic to novocaine?
My teeth are okay.
No reactions, rashes, anything?
No, of course not.
Now, you inject both sides of
the wound, expelling as you go.
Then you have to put on
surgical gloves by yourself.
You know how to
do that, don't you?
Great.
Here we go.
Hey.
Here you go, Dr. Ross.
Thank you, Nance.
Dr. Ross.
Hi, Tracy Young.
I'm your third-year student.
Well, hello, Tracy Young,
it's nice to meet you.
Listen, for the next few days,
we'll be working
very closely together.
Well, not that closely, Dr. Ross,
but I'll do my best to help you out.
So, if you tell me what to
do, I'd like to get started.
Just trying to be friendly.
I've got all the
friends I need. Thanks.
Shall we get started?
Yeah.
Now evert the wound
edges and space them
because the tissues will be
swelling over the next 48 hours.
Space them the way
that you see here.
Dr. Benton, the
policeman's here.
Okay, I'm coming.
Here. You finish.
Okay, this isn't
going to hurt at all.
Now, can you tell me
what happened, Billy?
His school sent him home.
They said he vomited blood.
Can you tell me how
it happened, Billy?
He's a very high-strung child.
Always has been very
tense, very nervous.
Mrs. Logan, maybe you better
wait outside while I examine your son.
Why?
It's just a procedure.
Well, I think I should be here.
I'm worried about
Billy. He needs me.
Please wait outside.
Look, Doctor, I don't
know who you think you are
but this is my son, and I want
to be here when he needs me.
He's very high-strung.
Mrs. Logan, you're
absolutely right.
You love your son, and you want
to see him treated
as soon as possible
so it's best if you have
a seat outside here
and we'll be right with you,
Doctor... and we'll
be right with you.
It's okay.
Hey, kiddo.
All right, did you
vomit blood, Billy?
Do you have any pain?
Okay, can you point to the pain?
Right in here.
Have you vomited blood before?
Many times?
Okay.
That's okay.
First eight-year-old
ulcer patient I've seen.
You still here?
What do you think you're doing
the Sistine Chapel?
Finish her up.
Start an IV in Room
Two. Bye, ma'am.
Nurse, could you bandage
this for me, please?
Thank you, Doctor.
You're very welcome.
When do I come to have
my stitches come out?
Oh, uh... three weeks.
When my son had stitches
in his foot, they said ten days.
Really? Well, ten
days, three weeks...
Any time in there, okay?
Hey.
We need an
anesthesiologist to ICU.
Please report to the ICU stat.
250 milligrams rocephin IM
for the gentleman in room four
and remind him he has to come
back in two days. Thank you.
Right.
Hey, Carol, are we
out of oral ampicillin?
Yeah, we ordered some
yesterday. Call down again.
Hey, Carol, Dr. Greene
wants to know
if we have any more lasix.
We were out an
hour ago. Check it.
Hey, Carol, Dr. Ross wants to
know if we have any PKU cards.
Tell him no.
He's going to have to try to
get a blue top from the baby.
He says he can't get one.
Carol, are you sure
that you don't have
a PKU card tucked away
in that special stash of yours?
Like this?
I can always count on you
even if you do
prefer football players.
You had your chance.
I was young.
I was a fool.
You're still a fool.
Do you happen to know
what is the worst-paying
medical specialty?
Pediatrics?
You were right the first time.
Hey, Carol, did that
lasix come up yet?
'Cause we need it now.
Good morning.
I'm Dr. Carter.
What seems to be the problem?
What's it look like?
I shot myself in
the freakin' leg.
Oh.
Well, uh...
we'll have you
fixed up in no time.
Yeah, you guys keep saying that.
But first, we have
to start a little IV.
Just hurry it up, okay?
Yes, sir.
Hey!
Excuse me, sorry.
Okay.
I tell you, I wanted to belt her
right in the mouth.
I really did.
Uh-huh.
Then I go and shoot
myself in the leg.
These things happen.
I bet you see a lot
working in a place like this.
Yeah, oh, yeah.
All the time.
Uh, okay.
Look, Doc, you don't mind
my asking... Have
you done this before?
Officer, I'd hate to tell you
how often I've done this before.
You're going to feel
a little needle.
Ow!
Come on, that wasn't that bad.
But we missed the vein.
We're going to have to
try this one more time.
My wife is not that bad.
We don't argue that
much, just once in a while.
I mean, in this case, it's
lucky I didn't kill her, right?
Oh, man.
I'm afraid we missed again.
We have to try one more time.
You have very tough veins.
My wife is
a very beautiful woman.
Uh-huh.
I mean, I'm not proud
of beating up any woman
even when she's asking
for it, but just sometimes...
In this case, it's
lucky I didn't throw her
through the wall
and break her neck!
I got it.
Don't move.
Don't move. It is in the vein.
Just do not move at all.
There you go.
Officer, you got yourself an IV.
And everything's
going to be fine now.
Can I move?
Yeah, sure. Move
around. You're fine.
Well, that's about all I can
do for you for the moment.
They're going to be coming in
to take you down to X
Ray and then to surgery.
Surgery?!
Yeah, but believe
me, the worst is over.
This happen when you woke up?
Yes, when I got out of bed.
And are you seeing double now?
No.
How many fingers? Three.
Have you had any trouble
with your eyes before?
No, never.
Did you have any pain while
you were seeing double?
Headache? Trouble
with your balance?
Funny taste in your mouth?
Flashing spots before your eyes?
Weakness in your
arms and legs?
No. None of those things. Never.
Well, I'll tell you, Mr. Ervin
I can call a neurologist
to go over you
but that'll cost
you another $200.
If you don't have
any symptoms now
I'd leave well enough alone.
Come back if you
have any further trouble.
Who's next?
You're just saying
that because I'm black.
Just trying to save
you money, Mr. Ervin.
I know you don't have insurance.
Uh-uh. You wouldn't talk
like this if I wasn't black.
You're Jewish, right?
Call a Neuro
consult for Mr. Ervin...
Cc: transient
diplopia... And bill him.
Hello, somebody, hello!
What is it?
I got a lady pregnant
in my cab outside.
Why'd you do that?
Hey.
We don't do deliveries
here, I'm sorry.
You have to take her up to OB.
She's going to have a baby
whether you deliver 'em or not!
Hey, you busy?
No.
Why don't you come with me?
Get us an OB nurse.
Okay, okay, ma'am. Come on.
Let's get out, okay?
You're going to be fine.
When did it start snowing?
Come on, Doctor.
Give me a hand.
All right, ma'am.
Up on the gurney.
There you go.
Is this your first child?
No, no?
Okay, let's go.
Ooh... it's starting.
It's coming.
Hold the head in.
We don't want to
deliver in the hallway.
What?
Put your hand
between her legs
and hold the head in.
Keep breathing, ma'am.
Blow through the pain.
Get me anesthesia.
Call the pediatrician.
Hook up those stirrups.
Are you doing an episiotomy?
I don't have any time.
She's already crowning.
Blow through the pain, ma'am.
Blow through the pain, blow
through the pain. That's right.
What shall I do?
Just what you're doing, Doctor.
Is it snowing out there?
When I'm done scrubbing
I'll take over, and
you can scrub.
Where's the OB Resident?
They're all called, Doctor.
You want a gown?
I don't think I'm
going to have time.
I have to catch this
one any way I can.
No kidding.
All right, dear.
You're going to be just fine.
You just have to
blow. Okay? Blow.
Is it snowing?
Yeah, it's snowing.
It's snowing on March 17.
This is unbelievable.
It's okay, ma'am.
You are going to be just fine.
Okay, okay, let me take over.
There we go.
Okay, ma'am, we're going to
push on the next one, okay?
One, two, three...
Okay, one more. This
is it. This is the one.
And push... push
push, push, push, push.
Okay, one more push.
We're going to get him out.
Here we go. One,
two, three, push.
Push, push.
Good, good, shoulders are clear.
You have
a beautiful little boy.
Clamp.
Okay. There you go.
God...
He's a cutie pie.
Yes, he is.
You did a good job there.
Dr. Carter, you have
three suture cases
waiting for you.
You're not on the
Medical Services.
These people don't
need your help.
They can botch
things up on their own.
Come on. Let's get cracking.
Patient Martin, Jonathan.
Anterior and lateral
right lower extremity.
Femur articulation
patella, tibia, fibula
all appear normal.
There is a radiolucent
density in the soft tissue
superficial to the
mid-shaft of the fibula.
A bullet. A bullet is
what it's called, Steve.
There is no apparent
fragmentation
of the foreign body.
Distal tibia and fibula
all appear within...
Come on, Steve. Normal limits.
Impression: foreign body
in the right lower extremity
consistent with possible bullet.
Is that it?
Thank you.
I'll take these.
There's a guy upstairs
with a bullet in his leg
who'd like to go to the OR
and have it out.
So, you're not feeling any pain?
No pain here in your back?
No.
Well, you know what?
All you got is a
fracture to your ankle.
Everything else is fine.
Now, what's the story, Doc?
Do I get worker's comp?
The story?
The story is
you're still alive.
Great, but I got
a few bills, and...
All right.
There it is, nice and red.
He has otitis media.
He'll be fine, he'll be fine.
Give him 50 milligrams
of oral amoxicillin.
If he doesn't get any
better by tomorrow morning
give me a call.
All right? It's nice to see you.
Bye, tiger.
He's very handsome.
He knows it.
That's right. We got
a UA and a sed rate.
The patient is Rebecca Morton.
M-O-R... what do you mean?
We sent this to you an hour ago.
Don't give me that. It is 1:40,
and it was a stat determination.
What are you guys doing
down there? Picking your noses?
Chest pains, two
hours. Question AMI.
I will talk to you any
damn way I want to.
If I send for a stat chemistry
I want it within an hour,
not sometime next month.
Yeah, we're a
little busy here, too.
Wait till they start
going to lunch.
Then things will really
start slowing down.
Everybody's all sewed up.
What do you want me to do?
Go to lunch.
Actually, I'm all right. If
there's something you...
Excuse me a minute.
Look, don't be a hero.
If I tell you to go
to lunch, you go.
It's a long time before dinner
and we may be too busy
then to stop and eat, okay?
You never know how long it's
going to be until your next meal
so whenever you can, you eat.
Now, get the hell out of here
and don't take more
than half an hour.
Okay.
Hi, I'm Dr. Greene.
What seems to be the
trouble, Mrs. O'Rourke?
I'm not Mrs. O'Rourke.
Mrs. O'Rourke?
Is there a Mrs. O'Rourke here?
What is it?
Crack dealer.
Took five shots from an Uzi.
We need some muscle in here.
He's just a kid.
Thirteen.
Call security. Why?
I think the other gang members
may come and
try to finish him off.
All right, everybody.
Let's keep it calm.
Here we go.
This is Tracy Young in ER.
I need someone in
Trauma Room One.
Thanks.
Strap! Strap!
Surgical Two.
Turn right and down.
Tell the surgeons
we have a motorcycle
accident coming in.
The guy wasn't wearing a helmet.
Oh, terrific. Those
are the stat labs.
I'm going across the
street for a minute.
I promised my wife I'd
go to this appointment.
Can you get Susan
to cover for me? Okay.
No! Not there!
Surgical Two! Two!
I'm Dr. Greene
to see Dr. Harris.
Everyone has a family, Mark.
My wife wants to
shop, kids grow up.
You want a private
school, college.
You got to think about that.
Now, the office for
our next associate
is here.
As a junior man
you'll do all calls and weekends
for a year or so.
Compensation: You'll start out
at $120,000 per
year, plus bonuses.
Now, the group has a condo
in Jamaica and one in Aspen.
Do you ski?
No, I haven't had
the opportunity.
Oh, you should.
It's a great sport.
David Morgenstern tells me
you're the sharpest
guy the ER ever had.
But I'll tell you
the ER is a young man's game.
You think you're doing good
but there's a lot to life
especially this one.
And we find the practice
intellectually challenging
so we send our physicians
to all the major conferences.
Last year, Maui, Paris, Rome.
We're proud to practice
the best possible
medicine we can here.
It seems great.
You like this?
We had Prescott redesign it.
We redesign every
couple of years.
Keeps us looking fresh.
Terrific.
Oh, you have time for lunch?
We can go to the Crown Club.
They have a great
porcini pasta. No oil.
I've got to get back. Sorry.
Melissa, would you bring
Dr. Greene's coat? Yes.
Maybe next week?
Mark, we'd really love
to have you.
Thank you.
Mrs. McCormick, how are you?
There you go, Dr. Greene.
I thought the Field
Museum Ball was wonderful.
Well, aren't you sweet?
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Cheer up, Doctor.
It's only 3:00.
3:00. What am I doing this for?
I must be crazy.
That's a very good insight.
When did it start raining?
It's raining.
It has been for an hour.
How's your new student?
Very capable. Tough.
Uh-huh.
So, I hear you went
up to Harris's today.
Did he offer you a job?
Yeah. I think I'd have to go
to a lot of charity balls.
There are worse things.
I guess.
Must be.
By the way, what's this I
hear about you and that tech
up on surgical four?
I'm a married man.
So?
So whatever you
heard is not true.
Oh. I heard that she
was seriously cute,
but you are
faithful to your wife.
Is that what you're telling me?
Yes.
Why would you do
something like that?
'Cause I'm too tired
to do anything else.
We'll know more when
we have the x rays.
How much do you smoke?
Two, three packs
a day sometimes.
Uh-huh. And how long
you been doing this?
Since I was about 14, I guess.
You really should stop that.
Yeah, I know.
Excuse me.
You can put your
clothes back on.
Hello?
Uh... hi.
Listen, I can't talk
at work unless it's...
It is?
Well, what...?
No, I'm on all night.
Oh, thanks.
I get off tomorrow
night at, uh, 6:00.
Paul, I-I thought we broke up.
Oh, Paul, come on.
Damn. What? No. Not you.
It's just, uh...
I have to tell a
patient something.
Listen, is everything all right?
I'm sorry, but I just...
Yeah. Okay. Fine.
We have your x rays, Mr. Parker.
You can see there's a density
in the right middle lobe there.
What does that mean?
It means there's
something abnormal
within the structure
of your lung.
There's something in my lung?
Yes, that's right.
What is it?
Well, it could be
any number of things.
It could be an infiltrate,
a dense area of tissue
from an old infection.
It could be an
inhaled foreign body.
It could be a
granuloma of some sort.
It could be a lot of things.
Well, what do you think it is?
There's no way to know.
You'll have to undergo
a bronchoscopy
and possibly exploratory surgery
before we know for sure.
I understand, but...
what do you think in
the meantime? Just...
I think in the meantime,
you could consider it
a potentially serious finding.
So, you're saying I got cancer?
I'm not saying that.
I'm saying we don't
know anything for sure.
Doctor, let me explain something
to you, okay? I'm 40 years old.
I have a wife. I
have three children.
I have a house
that is not paid for.
I have a mother who has a house
that isn't paid for.
I have a lot of
responsibilities.
So I need to know.
I need to know what you think.
I think you should
regard your condition
as very serious
but should await a
final determination.
I don't understand the problem.
Is it so hard? Are you
afraid to tell me the truth?
Your history of coughing blood
weight loss, and this x ray
is suggestive of cancer
but the diagnosis has
not been confirmed
and it may very well
be something else
and none of us should
jump to any conclusions
until we know.
That's what I think.
How long do I have?
Six months to a year.
Well, do I have six
months for sure?
No, not for sure.
Okay. Yeah, I was just wondering
because I always wanted
to take my wife to Nassau.
We talked about it a lot...
We always talked about it...
But we never did
it, so I just figured
spring's coming.
It's getting too late
to go to Nassau
and she always wanted
a... suntan in the winter
to show off to the neighbors
and stuff, you know.
I understand.
Yeah, yeah.
So, I guess I better go.
Summer's going to be
here before you know it.
So I guess I better
go pretty soon, huh?
Doctor, I want to thank you.
I want to thank
you for your help
and thank you for
being straight with me.
I really appreciate it.
I guess I don't have
to quit smoking.
Mr. Parker, if there's one
thing you learn in my job
it's that nothing is certain...
Nothing that seems very bad
and nothing that
seems very good.
Nothing is certain.
Nothing.
I'm sorry.
Oh...
Good evening.
How's it going
tonight, Mrs. Raskin?
Timmy, I have a problem
that requires medical attention.
See Dr. Greene.
He's on duty tonight.
Oh.
Dr. Greene. How nice.
And... Good evening
Dr. Greene.
He says he doesn't drink...
I require medical
attention, Dr. Greene.
Give me a minute, Chris.
What is it, Mrs. Raskin?
Well, I have this troublesome...
hangnail.
Mrs. Raskin...
I'm afraid it may be infected.
Mrs. Rasking, if we treat you
it's going to cost you $180.
You do know that.
Oh, I wish you'd do it
for me.
You're such a nice young doctor
and I do appreciate
your taking the time.
Okay.
We'll handle this in the lab.
The lab?
Oh, gracious.
I had no idea how
complicated it was.
I'll be excising Mrs.
Raskin's hangnail.
I'll stand back.
Well, at my age
you can't be too careful.
Please, have a
seat, Mrs. Raskin.
Thank you.
Dr. Greene, you look tired.
How have you been?
Fine, thanks.
And your wife?
Is she still studying
for her bar exams?
Next month.
We won't see much of each other.
This alcohol may
feel a little cool.
Hey, Mark, you
got time for coffee?
Maybe in a half an hour.
She's very cute.
She work here at the hospital?
She's a medical resident.
Did I tell you my
sister got remarried?
No.
Well, how long has it been
since I've seen you?
Hmm... just a week or so.
Here we go.
Don't make such a fuss.
Thank you, Dr. Greene.
Now...
you be a good boy
and go home to your wife.
Another day, another dollar.
Good night, Timmy.
See you, Wendy.
Good night, Connie.
Hey, Rick.
Hey, Tim.
How you doing?
I'm good.
Yeah?
Yeah. Ready to work.
Hey, Carol, can you get...?
Sorry. I'm off.
Oh, I forgot. See you later.
In three, the lady with
pulmonary edema...
She gets lasix and
a nitroglycerin drip.
In four, there's some kid.
Dr. Ross is looking after him.
Five, there's a question
pulmonary embolism.
Labs are coming.
Can I get two grams
of chloramphenicol?
Sorry. You're going to have
to get it from the next shift.
See you tomorrow.
Good night.
Malik needs two grams
of chloramphenicol.
Coming right up. All right.
Good night.
See you.
See you guys tomorrow.
ER.
Come on. It's not that bad.
It's a very minor cut.
Three stitches.
It's not the cut.
It's the car.
I smashed the car.
Oh.
I wasn't supposed to drive it
and I took the keys,
and I smashed it up.
And it was brand-new.
My father loves that car.
Well, it might not be
as bad as you think.
Oh...
it was a brand-new Cadillac...
with power steering...
and... air conditioning.
Oh, God, he'll kill me.
It was the first new
car he ever had!
Ow!
Suzanne!
Daddy...
Suzanne...
Oh, my...
Oh, my God.
Oh, Daddy.
Uh, uh, could we
not move, please?
Is she going to be all right?
Yeah, she's going to be fine.
Oh... oh, honey.
Daddy?
Yeah?
I trashed the car.
That's all right.
The important thing
is that you're okay.
Oh... oh, Daddy.
What car?
You mean the Caddy?
Oh, Daddy, I am so sorry.
You totaled my new Seville?!
Suzanne!
God!
Oh, God...!
My Cadillac!
Oh...
It doesn't matter.
Dr. Carter, you have six
in backup. That's not good.
Look, this is St. Patrick's Day.
The worst is yet to come.
Let's move.
Okay.
Who was that idiot?
Why did he do it?
I don't know.
He just got his hands
on it and he swallowed it.
Jimmy, why did you do it?
Because.
You see? He's impossible.
Here's the KUB.
Mm-hmm.
There it is all right.
You mean, that's where
it is? It's in his stomach?
You said he swallowed it.
What do I do now?
Check his stools, Mrs. Edmunds.
He'll probably pass it.
That's not what I mean.
How do I get into my house?
I'm locked out.
You...
you don't have another key?
It's not funny.
I'm sorry.
You know, it is possible
to become pregnant
without actual penetration.
I mean, just by fooling around.
I'm not pregnant.
It's very important
you tell me any reason
why you think you
might be pregnant.
No reason.
Because If you are pregnant
you might have what we
call an ectopic pregnancy.
In which case, you'd have
to be operated on right away.
It's very serious.
It could be a matter
of life and death,
and I'm not exaggerating.
I'm not pregnant.
Okay.
Excuse me for one second.
How old?
She's 13.
And she's got a pain in
her lower left quadrant
and she's not pregnant?
Mm-mm.
Okay, let's see.
Hello, Miss Murphy.
I'm Dr. Benton.
Can you tell me
how long has it been
since you've had
your last period?
I don't know.
Well, just think back.
Tell me roughly.
It was after Christmas.
Okay.
So, it's been a few months?
I guess so.
I haven't really
paid attention.
And you've had
sexual intercourse?
Yes.
Dr. Carter...
what you have is
an ectopic pregnancy
and she needs to be scheduled
for ultrasound and
surgery right away.
How'd it go?
You've been to Harris's office.
You know what it's like.
It's like a nightclub
or something.
He offered you a job?
Yeah... but I don't know.
You don't want to do it?
It doesn't seem like
real medicine to me.
So what's the problem?
You know what the problem is.
Jennifer?
Yeah.
You can't live your life
the way someone
else wants you to, Mark.
I know.
Especially a lawyer.
She's not a lawyer yet.
You know what I mean, Mark.
It's got to be your life.
It is.
She just keeps talking
about how she doesn't
see me anymore.
Well, she probably never does.
I mean, I never see Paul.
I thought you guys broke up.
Well, we did, but... you know.
Yeah.
Well...
Dr. Greene.
Yeah, yeah. Right away.
Come on. We got to go.
What?
We got to go.
Mark, what?
Did you hear?
Yeah.
Yeah, yeah, she's on her way.
It's incredible.
I don't know how
this happened...
to her, of all people.
I don't know.
Okay, people, come on.
Let's break it up.
Lots to do.
Let's get back to work.
Come on. What do
you expect to see?
Hey, let's get back to work!
We're going in here.
We're going in here, head first.
Oh, my God, it is Hathaway.
All right, move her on
three. One, two, three.
Come on, people.
Let's get her clothes off.
Let's go. Let's go.
Let's go.
Call respiratory.
We may need to intubate.
Do you know what she took?
I don't know. She just went
into the medicine cabinet.
We've got a lot of stuff around.
So you have no idea
what she has taken.
I want a drug screen right away.
Two milligrams of Narcan
and an amp of d-50.
You want to pump her?
Yep.
Malik, call Neuro, call
the nursing supervisor.
Did you call her family?
I don't know her family. We
were only roommates three weeks.
Why did she do it?
It doesn't matter
why she did it.
We don't ask that
about any other OD
that comes through these doors
and we don't ask
it about this one.
I want blood gas
and electrolytes.
How hypotensive is she?
80/60.
She have anything to drink?
She had a scotch.
More than one?
I don't know.
Maybe. I don't know.
What are you people
standing around for, huh?
Do the arterial stick.
She got a Babinski?
Yeah. Positive.
How's the oxygen?
15 liters and running.
Morgenstern's on his way.
Her serum barb is 45.
Is that a mistake?
It was repeated twice.
Malik, close the curtain.
This isn't a show
over here, people.
ER.
Yeah.
And what's the nature of the...?
I see.
Call Dr. Benton.
We got a shotgun wound
to the chest coming in.
What a night.
Gas distension distal to
the duodenum is apparent
with fluid levels in
the proximal ilium.
Impression... acute
small bowel obstruction.
This is a surgical candidate.
Oh, you guys are incredible.
What would we do without you?
It's nice to see you, Peter.
A man of many
talents... All unproven.
We got a new
barbiturate level yet?
It just came back.
Still 45.
Pupils mid-range and sluggish.
90/70.
We just got her
barbiturate level.
It's 45 micrograms
per milliliter.
She's intubated. We're
alkalinizing her urine.
We're getting her
ready for hemoperfusion.
But if she's decerebrating...
you know the question, Mark.
Should we be trying
any of this at all?
It doesn't look hopeful
but I think for the
morale of the unit
we got to do everything.
I mean, she was...
is very popular.
The unit's looking to you, Mark.
You set the tone.
Yeah.
She was one of us.
We loved her, we worked with her
and now something's
happened to her.
It makes us feel guilty.
It makes us feel angry
and scares the hell out of us
but we take care of her, and
then we go on with our jobs.
Yeah.
You set the tone, Mark.
You get the unit through this.
I'm fine.
Okay.
Call me if anything happens.
Anything at all.
Boy, she really
did it, didn't she?
Yeah, she did.
She seemed okay today.
Yeah. She seemed fine.
She was making jokes.
Everything was great.
She was funny.
She was joking like always.
She was great.
Go get some coffee, Doug.
We need a scrub nurse in OR Six.
Scrub nurse, report to OR Six.
Come on. Let's get him up.
Let's get him up.
All right. Good, good.
Whoa! Knife wound.
I thought it was supposed
to be a gunshot wound.
Excuse me. I feel ill.
Oh, that's okay. I
didn't need you anyway.
Listen, notify the
OR. Let's get us room.
Come on. Let's go. Move him out.
Here we go, buddy.
Jerry, can you hold that?
Feeling better?
Yeah.
I'll be okay in a minute.
It just got to me
all of a sudden.
Keep your head down.
There's no rush. Just relax.
Ah, it stopped raining.
I thought I was
going to be sick.
I'm sorry.
Don't ever say
you're sorry.
See, there's two
kinds of doctors.
There's the kind
that gets rid of their feelings
and the kind that keeps them.
If you're going
to keep your feelings
you're going to get sick
from time to time.
That's just how it works.
Keep your head down.
People come in here
and they're sick,
dying, and bleeding
and they need our help
and helping them is more
important than how we feel.
But it's still a pain in
the ass sometimes.
You know, sometimes I just
want to quit and do something else.
Yeah.
Why don't you, uh,
take a few more minutes.
By the way
I was in medical
school with Benton
and he used to
get sick all the time.
So don't let him
give you any crap.
You're going to be fine.
What's the score?
DePaul is down.
You okay?
Yeah.
Good.
Don't worry
about what happened out there.
Just don't make a habit of it.
Okay.
She's been on
dialysis for three hours.
She's still comatose
and unresponsive.
She must have taken
short-acting agents.
She knew exactly
what she was doing.
Has the family been notified?
I don't know. I think so.
Is she fully covered
on the hospital policy?
As far as I know, yeah.
Has anyone talked
to the press office?
Let's face it: this
is bad publicity.
Some damn TV
network will get ahold of it
and try to make
a sentimental movie about her.
I'm going to get on it.
Anybody know why she did it?
No one has any idea.
Her fiance didn't
know anything either.
Supposed to get married in June.
Who's next?
I am, doctor.
Now lean forward.
Uh-huh.
You feeling any pain?
It's better when I
lean forward, yeah.
Okay, okay.
Uh, Lydia, can I
borrow your pen?
Mr. Lawkowski, I'm going
to admit you to the hospital
and start you on
a medical regimen.
There's some question in my mind
as to whether that's necessary
but I think it's better
to be safe than sorry.
Oh, God!
Mr. Lawkowski, what is it?
What's the matter,
Mr. Lawkowski?
I know the truth. You don't
have to hide it from me.
The truth.
I know you're being nice to me
but you can tell me, it's okay.
I want to know the truth.
Mr. Lawkowski,
you have a duodenal ulcer
with complicating pancreatitis...
Rather mild pancreatitis,
judging from the lab figures.
That's all you have.
Come on. You
can tell me, please.
You don't have
cancer, Mr. Lawkowski.
Geez! Oh, I knew it!
I knew it!
It's cancer!
And you were hiding it!
Oh, God!
Mr. Lawkowski, every person
that comes into this hospital...
Whether they have a
heart attack or a skin rash...
Everybody's
worried about cancer.
You don't have cancer.
I swear to you.
You do not have cancer.
It's not cancer.
No.
You have an ulcer
which flared up today
because you went to a
party and drank and smoked
both of which
you're going to have to quit.
Quit smoking and drinking?
Yeah, that's right.
What, are you kidding me?
Uh, we're going to have to get
some x rays on him right away.
Right away, Doctor.
How did this happen?
He fell out of his crib.
Okay, okay.
And he, he was crying all
night, so I brought him here.
I bet he's been crying.
When did he fall?
I don't know. I don't
want to get into trouble.
Ma'am, your son has multiple
contusions. He's not my son...
Whatever, whatever
your relationship is.
I'm his baby-sitter.
This child has been beaten.
I'm going to call Children
and Family Services.
Please!
It's the law.
But I'll get into trouble!
Stay here.
Yes, Doctor.
I don't believe this.
You want to make a guess
on the diagnosis of this one?
I burned my legs.
I see.
It's not funny.
Um, well, if you'll just
come with me, Miss,
I'll take your name.
You're a college student?
Uh-huh. Sacred Heart.
And how'd this happen?
I was pouring some
hot water into the sink
and it splashed onto my legs.
Well, it's not bad...
Just first-degree burns.
There's no blistering
and there won't be any scarring.
It's very sensitive skin.
Uh-huh.
Your touch is nice.
This medication
will make you feel a lot better.
Your fingers are very long.
Mm-hmm.
Long and strong.
Hmm.
I wanted to change first and
put on some new underpants.
Hmm.
I knew you'd be
seeing my underpants...
and touching them.
You're going to want to
keep these bandages very dry
for a day or so.
Um, don't take any
showers or baths.
Just, uh, sponge bath.
Why is that nurse in the room?
Hospital policy.
Well, she's not doing anything.
She doesn't have to be here.
Are you afraid of me?
You're going to be
just fine in a few days.
Thanks, Lydia.
Okay.
After dinner?
Yeah, right after dinner
I... I, I felt this
little aching
this burning, you know?
Low?
And you have an aneurysm?
Yeah. They're going to
operate on me next month.
Okay, Mr. Harvey,
uh, we're just waiting
for your old film, so
you just rest easy.
We'll have you
fixed up right away.
We'll take care of him, ma'am.
Thank you, doctor.
Okay, thank you.
This guy's leaking
blood into his belly.
He could go any minute.
Who's on the floor?
Ashley and Jimmy are
doing the appendectomy.
Gill and Levine will be
another couple hours
with the knife wound.
They pulled Ed and his intern
off the floor to do the
lady with the small bowel.
Where's the vascular team?
They're in Minneapolis,
that conference.
Right, okay, where's Baker?
Baker's in the
Bahamas, with his family.
Well, this guy could die
any minute. We can't wait.
I know, but there's
no one to do him.
Okay, okay. Um, call Morgenstern
tell him to get over
here right away.
I'm starting a
ruptured aneurysm.
Peter, you can't.
You're just a resident.
What do you want to
do? You want to wait?
This guy could die while
we're out here discussing this.
I know that, but...
I'm just trying
to keep him alive until
Morgenstern shows up.
That's all, okay?
Now call the OR, get me a team
and tell them
to set up for a
laparotomy... please.
Yes, this is Dr. Lewis.
Get me Morgenstern.
Well, find him.
We have a blown aortic
aneurysm, and Dr. Benton's starting.
He'd like some help.
Yes, that's right.
Dr. Benton's starting.
What's on?
Ruptured abdominal aneurysm.
Who's doing it?
Dr. Benton.
Dr. Benton?
I'm doing anesthesia
for you, Peter.
Great. Listen, get
down to the blood bank.
Make sure they send up 20 units.
We need at least 20.
And get the nurses jumping.
Patient's on his way.
You, uh... you sure
you're okay about this?
Ed, I'm scared as hell
but the guy's already ruptured.
His belly's puffed
up like a balloon
and he's bleeding
to death internally.
I got to do him.
I'm his only chance.
Good evening, gentlemen.
Just wanted to let you know
I'll going to be starting
a ruptured abdominal
aortic aneurysm in Room Two
and I'd appreciate a hand
when you have a minute.
What did he say?
He said he's doing an aneurysm.
Now, that's a joke, isn't it?
Cheryl, go make
sure he's joking.
Dr. Ashley, he's doing it.
You're kidding.
Jim, break and help him.
I'll finish here and get
there as soon as I can.
Okay, boys and girls, let's go.
This isn't a picnic.
This is the late, late show.
Prep, please.
Prep, please. Come
on. Quit staring at me.
Look, I'm just trying to keep
the poor guy alive, okay?
All right, plastic.
Jimmy's coming in to help.
Oh, great.
The only guy in the hospital
that knows less about
vascular surgery than I do.
Okay, is Mr. Harvey happy?
He isn't complaining.
All right, then let's do this.
Knife, please. Thank you.
Mark the start of the
operation at 2:13 A.M.
Let's see how long it's going
to take the Chief to get off
of his girlfriend and
into his work clothes.
Ah, yes, nice and smooth.
Started without you, Jimmy.
There you go, sir.
Okay, now listen up.
We're going straight down
the linea alba... nothing fancy.
The guy's got
a 50% mortality anyway.
All right. Suction.
Let's get that.
Thank you for all
the good it will do.
Pick up. Pick up.
Come on, Jimmy. Work with me.
Pick up.
There's a lot of
blood in there, Peter.
That's precisely his problem.
Okay. Here we go.
Wish me luck.
Knife.
Whoa!
Systolic's holding at 100.
Mother. Okay, now.
I can't find it.
Damn it!
There... no.
No.
Jimmy, get your hand in there
and push away
the small intestine.
Come on, little
leak, where are you?
How bad's his pressure?
You won't like it.
I won't like it? Uh-uh.
Think about him.
Carol, hang six more
units packed cells
and a unit of fresh-frozen
plasma and platelets.
Wait a minute.
It's too much to hope, huh?
I got it. Yeah, yeah.
I got it.
Time down. Call
it out in minutes.
Let's suck this field clean
so we can see what
the hell we're doing.
I got it.
Dr. Benton, the Chief
Resident is on his way.
Well, suck that field clean.
We got the Chief coming.
We don't want him
to think we don't know
what we're doing here, huh?
Pressure?
100/70 and falling.
Okay, I'm not
going to sweat that.
Let's just keep
that blood going in.
Jimmy, what's the matter?
Your hands are trembling.
I can't imagine why.
Yeah, well, me neither.
Everything's cool here.
All we have to
do is sit and wait.
Dr. Benton, Dr. Ashley will
be with you as soon as he can.
All of the sudden, I got
all the help I want, huh?
Okay.
Start a nitroglycerine drip...
50 in 250 D5W,
80 of lasix, IV push.
Get a CBC, 'lytes,
cardiac enzyme
chest x ray and a 12-lead EKG.
Do you take digitalis, dear?
Have you taken any today?
No.
This morning?
Add a dig level.
Meanwhile, three milligrams
of morphine, IV Push.
I can't give this up.
No, no, no, not
you. You're fine.
Dr. Greene, your wife on 2204.
Yeah, I'll have
to call her back.
Sure taking a long time
getting in here, huh?
They've been out there
scrubbing for the last month.
You know, it's times like these
when I get into
a reflective mood
and I pause and think
of how wonderful...
Good morning, Peter.
Give it to me quick.
57-year-old white
male in good health
previously seen at this
hospital eight weeks ago
when he was found to have
a pulsatile abdominal mass
with aortic
calcification on x ray.
Elective surgery was
scheduled for next month,
but this evening
he was complaining of
severe intermittent pain
in the mid-back.
By the time he
got to the hospital,
he had a distended
abdomen, peritoneal irritation
and reduced hematocrit.
So, you decided to open him up.
That's one of the
ugliest incisions
I've seen in a long time.
A good veterinarian
would do a better
skin cut than that.
All right, hold on,
hold on, hold on.
Okay.
Mm-hmm.
Got it.
What's his pressure?
90/65, and he's gotten 12 units.
Okay, we'll take over from here,
try to make something out of it.
Hey, humor me, will you?
Have some dopamine standing by.
Hoover that, will you?
Proximal, then, uh, secondary?
Sounds like a plan.
Good. Give me a little
more room in there.
Thank you, ma'am. Thank you.
Whoo-hoo-hoo!
Look at that. Mm-hmm.
Peter?
You did a good job.
You were lucky as hell
but you were right
to open him up.
Good work.
Clear it out a little bit.
Let me see if I can...
pull it up for a second.
That's what we want right there.
That's right. Pull this up.
Shh, shh, shh.
Why is he still crying?
Why haven't you
given him something?
Look, he's still crying.
Why aren't you
giving him something?
I can't give him anything
until I know the
extent of his injuries.
He's been to x ray
so we know he
has a skull fracture.
A skull fracture?
The baby-sitter.
I never trusted her...
Ma'am, your child has multiple
contusions that are at least
12 hours old.
He has a skull fracture.
He also has several
old healed fractures.
He's a battered child.
I'm not even going
to respond to that.
You think I'd harm my child?
Happens all the time.
Look, if you're not going to
treat him, I'm taking him home.
No, you're not. Do you
have anything to say?
He's my date.
Look, um... I can assure
you, whoever you are...
Ross, Dr. Ross.
Well, Dr. Ross, let me tell you
your concerns are
unfounded, okay?
How did he burn his legs?
What?
These marks right
here on his legs?
Those. Those are
healed burn scars.
How did that happen?
He... I...
I don't know anything
about burns on the legs.
I'm beginning to think
you're making this up
is what I'm thinking.
Ma'am, you may
want to call an attorney.
I am an attorney.
Well, then I'm sure you'll know
how the Department of
Child Services will handle this.
How dare you speak...
How dare you treat
your child like this!
He's a little kid.
I try to be
understanding in my job
but, lady, this just stinks.
Did you find the chart
on the patient in six?
I don't know where it is.
Well, find it.
Well, I don't know where it is.
Do you think that I am deaf?
I heard you. Now
find me the chart!
I told you I don't
know where it is!
Is it okay?
You can go home now.
You did the right thing.
I mean, is the baby okay?
He will be.
Oh, man...
So how's Hathaway?
It doesn't look good.
They contact her family?
Yeah. They found them.
So, how'd your
aortic aneurysm go?
Morgenstern showed.
Dr. Benton to Trauma One.
Well, no rest for the wicked.
Gary, Perez, let's go.
What's the problem?
We picked him up in Old Town.
Orderly.
He was standing,
blocking traffic.
But he's got that smell,
so I thought I'd check.
Yeah, you did the right thing.
We got a diabetic ketoacidosis.
Let's go.
You probably saved his life.
What do you want, a medal?
Give him ten units
regular insulin, IV push.
Start a drip, ten
units per hour.
I want him hydrated
as soon as possible
with normal saline.
You want KCL?
Not on your life or his.
Get a CBC and 'lytes.
Call me with the potassium
and get a blood gas too.
Mark, did you get the
message your wife called?
No.
I'll call her in the morning.
Hello, Mrs. Harvey.
Okay, let's have a look here.
He seems to be
doing just fine, ma'am.
Oh, I'm so grateful.
Dr. Morgenstern came so quickly.
He saved his life.
Yes. Uh... well, Dr. Morgenstern
is a wonderful surgeon, ma'am.
He said you did a lot too.
Well, actually, I just helped
out a little bit, that's all.
I'll, uh, I'll check
on you later, okay?
I'm sorry I yelled at you.
You want some coffee?
Sure.
Hey, I wouldn't
kid you about that.
I had a few.
Maybe more than a few.
Uh-huh.
Hell of a party, though.
Okay, Mr. Murphy, you are done.
Already?
Oh, yeah?
I didn't feel a thing.
No, I didn't.
I still don't.
$24,000... more than
$24,000... that's what it cost
and I want to know
where doctors get off
charging money like that.
Medical costs
certainly are on the rise.
That's why we're going to
have national health insurance.
Well, I think it's a scandal.
I think doctors should be
ashamed of themselves.
Many of them are, I'm sure.
Let's hear what you
folks out there think.
You know the number. Call us.
This is Paul Barker
on Nightlines.
We'll be back in just a minute.
That's it? Anybody else?
Well, actually, I
got a little problem.
My throat's acting up.
You need to see a doctor.
Which room?
Five and six are open.
Five.
So is that it?
Well, if you could
take a look at my throat.
I've got a little soreness...
I'll be down in room
eight. You got a pen?
Wake me at 6:30.
That gives you almost
an hour and a
half. You're lucky.
6:30, Dr. Greene.
Wow.
Captioning sponsored
by WARNER BROS.