.
- Sometimes you gotta choose
between being respected
and being liked.
- You told her to stick
her neck out.
- You continue to prove
you can't stay in your lane.
- 'Cause you've been running
this joint
like a drive-through car wash
since I got here.
We supposed to
be helping people.
- You had a fair amount
of experience with
bureaucracy in your old job?
- Some years ago
stray bullet hit
a 14-year-old boy.
By some miracle, he survived.
It's what drew me to medicine.
- You been taking your meds?
- I can take care of myself.
- But Mom...please, we've got
to get you off the streets.
- Dr. Cooper has gotten
some very fat perks
since he started
boosting the Vascon.
- The more devices the hospital
buys, the bigger his kickback.
So I make him think
I'd do anything for money.
- It's great.
It's beautiful.
I mean, the beaches are...
I mean, they just go
on forever.
The water is so blue.
- Morning, Matt.
- Will, my good man!
Thank you.
- Little upgrade there?
- Oh, yeah.
Man.
That is sweet.
- Thanks.
Did you catch that Bears game?
- No, I missed it.
- Oh, oh, you missed...
- Yeah?
- So good.
- I was at
a buddy's poker night.
Big mistake.
- You hungover?
- No, worse.
Man, I lost my shirt.
Bought in way beyond my means.
- It happens.
- Yeah, it's just the last
thing I need right now.
You know, I'm still
paying back college,
med school, credit cards...
- Yeah, yeah.
Yeah, I've been there.
- Not in quite a while.
- Yeah, I'm doing all right
in the moment.
- Yeah, I'd say.
Any tips?
'Cause I'm about ready to start
picking up the graveyard shift.
- You're desperate, huh?
- Well, how could you tell?
- Wow.
Okay, let me think about it.
Hey, listen, I gotta run
to make my 7:00,
but I'll see you, Will, okay?
- Yeah, see you.
♪
- If you're not going
to order something,
you're gonna have to leave.
I need the booth.
- Why don't we try that again?
But this time let's start
with a "Good morning!
What can I get you?"
And throw in a smile,
just to really sell it.
Gosh, I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to--
- Two coffees.
Black.
And bring back a couple menus.
Hi.
I brought you a three-month
supply of your meds.
I know you don't like taking
them, but you need to, Mom.
- How about...we make
a little deal?
I'll take them
if you loan me $1,200.
For the van,
so I can get it running again.
I'd rather give you the money
for rent.
- Don't start with that again.
- You need a roof
over your head.
Heat, running water.
- Maybe you need all that,
but I don't.
Survived plenty of winters
in the van.
If you don't want to spot me
the cash--
- No, it's--it's not
that I don't want to.
- You just wanna
call the shots.
Tell me how to use it.
Just forget it.
- No, Mom, wait!
What about breakfast?
♪
- I don't want to stay
anywhere I'm not wanted.
♪
- How's it going?
- Yeah.
There you go.
There he is.
What's up, Dylan?
- Hey, what up, Kev?
- Uh-huh.
- You show up late
to surgery too...Doc?
- And good morning to you, sis.
What we playing, man?
- Oh, we playing 21.
- Ay, don't look at me.
I'm not getting in the middle
of that Scott sibling beef.
- Anyway...
you sure you want to dirty
those pretty fingernails, D?
Gotta keep them clean, case
you gotta cut someone open.
- Smart-ass.
- So back to the bust.
Simultaneous breaches.
Three houses, same block.
Bam! We knock the door
off the hinges.
So we coming through, right?
- Yo, that was gunfire.
- Damn right that was gunfire.
- Third floor, Kev.
- I'll call it in.
- All right.
- 911,
this is Officer Kevin Atwater.
Badge number 52784.
Shots fired on the inside of
the southwest corner building
on Damen and Pershing.
Roll some cars this way.
You ready?
Let's go.
♪
- Nah, man.
No way you're coming in.
You're not even armed.
- I'll be all right.
- You need to stand down.
You are not the police anymore.
♪
- Chicago PD, big guy.
You okay?
Huh?
Everything all right?
Hey!
♪
- Hold tight, we're gonna get
you some help, okay?
- Zora?
Zora?
- D, over here!
We're gonna get you some help,
all right?
You're doing good,
you're doing good, okay?
Tender age male victim,
GSW to abdomen,
smaller caliber round.
- We're on the third floor.
- Oh, hey, little man.
You mind moving your hand
so I can take a look?
I'm a doctor.
Oh.
♪
- Ow!
- I know it hurts, I know.
What happened here?
- We were just playing around.
He wouldn't really mean
to shoot me.
He was being a super villain.
The bullets were gonna bounce
right off me.
- Hey.
Hey, hey!
Stay with me--uh-uh.
Open your eyes, come on.
There you go, huh?
What's your name?
- Michael.
- Okay, Michael.
I know it's hard, Michael.
Hey, Michael!
Michael, I know it's hard,
but you gotta stay with me.
You gotta stay awake.
Zora, how long
on that ambulance?
- He said ten minutes.
♪
- Come on.
Hey, stay with me.
Come on.
Hey, hey.
Oh, God.
Stay with me.
♪
.
- Ow!
- No retained bullets.
- Dr. Scott, the trauma
attending is still in surgery.
He'll meet the team
up in the OR
after they get Michael prepped.
- Finish this unit of blood
and get him on
the transport monitor.
- Mommy...
- Hey, your parents
are on the way right now,
champ, all right?
We'll take you up
for a little operation.
- No, no, no.
- Hey, relax.
You're gonna be asleep
the whole time.
You won't feel a thing.
- Asleep?
- Yeah.
The surgeon's gonna look
inside your belly
and fix what's broken.
And, if there's time,
I'm gonna tell him
to put some superpowers
inside of you
before they stitch you back up.
Okay.
All right.
All right, come on.
Let's go.
♪
See you later, sis.
- Yeah, course, do your thing.
Ay, good work, D.
- Good morning, everybody.
By now, you all should've
received emails
with your credentials
for the new online portal,
Patients Pro, okay?
If it's not in your inbox,
check your spam.
If it's not in your spam,
I guess...I don't know,
assume you've been fired.
You will be using this system
to log how much time you spend
with each patient from now on.
Special Forces has a slogan...
"Slow is smooth
and smooth is fast."
In other words, we need
to be deliberate and tactical
in our approach to medicine.
The more patients we're able
to see, the more lives we save.
Oh, and as an added bonus,
whoever ends the month
with the highest turnover rate,
will enjoy an executive suite
at the United Center,
watching the Blackhawks game
of their choosing.
Not bad, huh?
All right, let's get going.
Thank you.
- Not a Blackhawks fan,
Dr. Charles?
- Oh, huge Hawks fan.
Not a big fan
of incentive-based medicine.
- I mean, fast is slow,
but smooth--sorry, I don't know
what that means.
- I don't.
- Hey, can I ask you something?
- Hey, Maggie?
- Yep.
- Can I tempt you away
from your brick?
- Yeah.
- Ah, Dr. Hammer,
you too, as well.
Listen, Elaine Foster
is on her way here.
She suffered a minor fall
at her home.
And her husband, Jim,
is driving her here.
- Elaine and Jim Foster--
big-time moneybags.
- No, no, they are two
of our most generous funders.
I've mingled over the years
with the Fosters
at donor events.
They're really good people.
Very down-to-earth.
Anyway, I'd like the two of you
to look out for them
while they're in the ED.
And I'll stop in to see Elaine
once she's settled in.
Thank you.
- VIPs aren't your cup of tea,
I take it?
- I like them--
just from a distance.
- Didn't you rub elbows all the
time with the rich and fabulous
over in Grosse Pointe?
- Yeah, hence my reluctance.
- Well, heads-up,
'cause here they are.
Mr. and Mrs. Foster,
we're going to treatment six.
- All right.
- How did the fall happen,
Mrs. Foster?
- Oh, Elaine, please.
I got home and smelled
something burning--ow!
- Sorry.
- Uh-oh.
- It's okay.
I'm just being a big baby.
Anyway, I hightailed it
to the kitchen.
And tripped over
my own two feet.
- Happens to me almost daily.
- Well, it turns out Jim here
was heating up
some leftover pizza.
He didn't even smell
that the house was about
to burn down.
He must've had COVID.
Isn't that one
of the long-term side effects?
- I never had COVID.
It's not my fault
you're a klutz.
- Honey, I wasn't blaming you.
♪
So what do you think,
Dr. Hammer?
Am I going to keep the leg?
- Prognosis is good.
I don't think that it's broken,
but we're gonna get an x-ray
to check it out.
- I'm peckish.
We've donated a small fortune
to this hospital.
It'd be nice if you could
offer us a snack.
- Jim, why don't you go grab
something from the cafeteria?
- Fine.
Honey, you want anything?
- No, thanks.
♪
I'm sorry about him.
He's been a bit
out of sorts lately.
- That's okay.
Don't worry about it.
- We'll be back shortly
to take you for that x-ray.
♪
- That was odd.
Goodwin's usually an excellent
judge of character.
I mean, maybe
it's like Elaine said;
maybe he's just having
a bad day.
- Or maybe he's on his best
behavior at donor events,
but around us mere mortals--
- Mere mortals?
Speak for yourself.
- We're going to Baghdad.
- Candace Mason.
31-year-old female.
Pedestrian struck at low speed.
No loss of consciousness.
C-spine cleared in the field.
Vitals are stable.
And pain confined to
her left elbow.
- Hi, I'm Dr. Halstead.
And this here is Dr. Scott.
- I swear, I looked both ways
before I crossed the street.
I'm sure I did.
I don't know how I didn't see
that car coming at me.
- That's okay.
We gotcha.
All right, transfer on three.
Ready?
One, two, three.
- Oh, my God.
Candace Mason?
I have to tell you,
your website saved my life.
Reading about your journey
with Lupus...
it finally inspired me
to see a doctor.
Are--are you okay?
I read on the newsletter
you were having a flare-up?
- Ah, yes, I am,
but that's not why I'm here.
I was in a minor accident.
- Take good care of her.
She's an angel.
- So you're having
a Lupus flare-up.
What medications
are you taking?
- I'm not taking
any medications.
- But if you're in a flare-up--
- Right, um...
anything I tell you
in regards to my health
is protected by
patient confidentiality, right?
- Yes, that's right.
- I'm not in the middle
of a flare-up.
I know what I said
to that woman,
but my Lupus
isn't currently active.
Truth is I've been
in remission...
for almost five years.
♪
- Okay, Dr. Taylor, shoot.
Ask me anything.
- I was hoping you'd give me
feedback on my ten-year plan.
- I'm sorry, did you just say
"ten-year plan"?
As in a full-on decade
of planning?
Oh, wow.
You wrote it out.
Binder and everything.
- You think I'd cut corners?
- You always been
so future-oriented?
- No, actually.
Kind of the opposite.
I spent a lot of my early years
looking backwards.
- Backwards?
- Oh, well, um...
I'm adopted.
So I just had a lot
of questions in regards
to my origins, I guess.
I didn't know anything
about my birth parents.
But once I accepted I wasn't
going to get any answers,
I decided to focus all
of my energy ahead instead.
- Oh.
Yeah, I get that.
Makes sense.
Me, I tend to ride the wave.
See where life takes me,
you know?
- I can't say I've ever let
life take the lead.
- Oh, well, whether you let it
or not, it's gonna throw you
some curveballs.
And in my experience...
planning leads to expectations.
And expectations, they can, uh,
lead to disappointments.
Yeah?
- Dr. Marcel, could you take
a look at the patient
in treatment 3?
- What's the problem?
- I don't know.
I didn't intake her.
Just know she's refusing
to speak with anyone
until she sees a doctor.
- Yeah, okay.
I'll be right there.
Sorry, I gotta cut it short.
- Actually, if you don't mind,
I would love to tag along.
- No, not at all.
- Cool.
- Hey there, Ms. Hawley.
I'm Dr. Marcel.
This is Dr. Taylor.
How can we help?
- Hi, it's Gina.
- You can take
the scarf off now.
- I'll close the curtain.
- She didn't wanna come in.
I practically had to drag her
to my car.
- You're her...
- Best friend.
I left Chicago at the height
of the pandemic
and just got back last week.
If I had known
what was going on...
- Liza, I feel fine, really.
- You are not fine.
You have to show them.
- Well, listen, Gina,
if it's any comfort,
we've seen every wart, boil,
cyst known to man.
So you've got nothing to be
embarrassed about here.
♪
Uh-huh.
.
- Remember when I said Cooper
was getting consulting fees
from Vasik and various
other companies?
Well, I started looking
at those other companies.
And I found some peculiar
things like stock photos
on their websites, contact
numbers that are connected
to overseas call centers.
So I got in touch
with one of my friends
who's a wealth manager.
Asked him to do some digging.
And it turns out
they're shell companies.
- So Vasik set them up
as a cover.
- Anyway, how'd it go
this morning?
- I cried broke, but I'm not
sure Cooper took the bait.
Hey, we're gonna nail him,
Ms. Goodwin.
- Come in.
- Oh, I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to interrupt.
- I gotta get back
to the ED anyway.
- All right.
Thank you for stopping by,
Dr. Halstead.
- Yep.
- So where are you guys
at with this thing?
You got enough evidence yet
to go to the authorities?
- Unfortunately, no.
What I told you about
the shell companies--
well, there's no way to prove
that Vasik was behind them
without being able to look
at their books.
- Look, Sharon, I know
how important this is to you.
I do.
But much more importantly,
I'm worried about
your stress levels.
I mean, it's not like you don't
have other things going on
in your life, you know?
- I'm really taking care
of myself.
- Really?
What's your latest A1C?
- Daniel, I'm fine.
Look, I even got myself one
of those continuous
glucose monitors.
And my blood sugar
is under control.
- I'm very glad to hear that.
- Thank you.
- Just got Candace's labs back.
Other than a slightly elevated
WBC, everything looks good.
- Good.
This is unreal.
- What's that?
- So according
to Candace's chart,
her Lupus hasn't been active
since 2016.
You wouldn't know it
by her website though.
It says she's been
in a flare-up the past month.
Can't eat,
can't get out of bed.
She's also soliciting
donations.
Claims they're going
to Lupus research but...
- You think she's pocketing
the money?
- I don't know.
You'd be surprised the lengths
people go to make a buck.
- Yeah, anything's possible,
I guess.
Anyway, I'm gonna go check
and see if the two-view
of Candace's elbow is back.
♪
- Elaine, they're ready
for you in radiology.
Maggie's gonna bring you up.
- Ugh, nothing makes you
feel your age
like being helped
into a wheelchair.
- Nonsense.
- You're still young.
- Young at heart at least.
- Would you like to accompany
your wife?
- No, I'll wait here.
How long is it gonna take?
I was planning to make
a paella tonight,
and I still need to take
the chicken out of the freezer.
- Let the rads resident
know we need a fast read.
- Right.
♪
- Hey, so good news...
the fine needle biopsy
came back and it's benign.
- So that means
it's not cancer, right?
- Correct.
- Oh, thank God.
- However, the tumor does
extend into your upper chest.
And it's enveloping several
of the major blood vessels
that are coming off your heart,
so you will need
a neck dissection--
possible sternotomy--
to remove it.
- The surgeon will make
an incision along your neck
to excise the mass.
Ideally, it'll come out
in one piece.
But if not, the surgeon may
also need to open your chest.
- Just so you know, we see a
high volume of both procedures
here at Med
with excellent outcomes.
- I read online that sometimes
these tumors are treated
with medicine?
- They are, yes.
Radioactive iodine.
But I'm afraid
it's long past that point.
The tumor's already too close
to your big blood vessels--
- I've been okay so far.
- Gina, I think you should
listen to the doctor.
- I'd like to at least start
with medicine.
- I'm not sure you're grasping
how serious this is.
- I get it.
- You know what, Gina,
this is a big decision.
So why don't you take some time
to think about it
and we'll check back later.
Okay?
All right.
♪
- Radioactive iodine isn't
going to work fast enough.
This thing's
a ticking time bomb.
- Yeah, but we need
to tread lightly.
I'm gonna go grab Dr. Charles.
See if he can make
some headway.
- So your white blood cell
count is slightly elevated.
But that's pretty normal
following a trauma.
It's likely from the stress.
- And your elbow x-ray
was negative.
You'll just wanna ice it
for a few days.
- I feel like I should explain.
- You don't have to explain
anything to us.
- Well, I launched this website
a few months after
I was diagnosed with Lupus.
- "When Life Gives You Lupus"?
- Oh, you saw it?
Well, the only reason I haven't
advertised my remission
is because...I mean, you saw
that woman who approached me.
The website is a lifeline
for so many and I felt that,
you know, bragging about
my remission--
it would kind of dilute
the message.
- And messaging is key, right?
Especially when it comes
to fundraising.
- Any questions for us,
Candace?
- No, I don't think so.
Oh, my God.
- You okay?
- You sure you didn't
lose consciousness?
- Yeah, I'm pretty sure.
It all happened so fast though.
- Yep, let's get a head CT
just to be safe.
- Mm-hmm.
- Mr. Foster,
I just wanted to let you know
your wife will be down shortly.
- Oh, how's Elaine's ankle?
Is it broken?
- No, it's not; it's
just a sprain, fortunately.
- Oh, good.
You're a runner, aren't you?
- Sorry?
- It's not a trick question.
- Uh, yes, I run.
- Mm-hmm, knew it.
See, women of a certain age--
how old are you?
- I don't think that's any
of your business.
- 32, 33?
That's when women start to get
a little extra padding
around the middle,
except runners.
Good for you.
- Excuse me.
- It's just a compliment.
- Get your hand off me, please.
- I'm not gonna bite.
- I said let go.
- Would you--
- Now!
- Just relax.
♪
- What the hell are you doing?
Jim, are you okay?
♪
.
- Okay, so...
where did he touch you?
- What difference
does that make?
- I'm--I'm just trying to get
all the facts straight.
- My forearm.
- Was he aware
that this made you
uncomfortable?
- I asked him repeatedly
to remove his hands.
So yeah, I think that
should've clued him in.
- Of course, but do you think
there's a chance that--
- Peter.
Enough.
Dr. Hammer, I'm sorry and,
quite frankly, I'm at a loss.
In all of the years
that I have known Jim Foster,
I have never seen him behave
in a predatory manner.
If I had, I never would have
put you and Maggie
in this position.
But please be assured
that you will be supported
in whatever course of action
you wish to pursue.
And should you decide
to press charges--
- Oh, okay, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Now let's not get ahead
of ourselves here.
Okay, I think that our best bet
for all the parties involved--
most importantly Dr. Hammer--
to spare her
any further discomfort,
would be to settle this without
involving law enforcement.
- Peter, we are not going
to sweep this under the rug
because Jim Foster is a donor.
- Ms. Goodwin,
I appreciate the support.
I do...but I'm not interested
in pressing charges anyway.
- Well, that's your decision
to make, Dr. Hammer.
But, with your permission, I'd
like to have a word with Jim.
- Sharon, would you let...
♪
- Hey, Nancy, any word on--
- The kid, Michael?
No.
And the OR asked me to please
stop calling for updates.
I'll let you know the minute he
gets out of surgery, Dr. Scott.
- Hey, regarding Candace--
- Yeah, the techs just took her
up to CT.
- Oh, good, great.
Listen, I've been thinking...
let's say Candace
is pocketing donations--
- Oh, so you have evidence?
- No, not yet.
But if we call the charities
listed on her website,
and they don't support
her claims--
- No, man, I don't want
anything to do with this.
- I would've thought you'd
at least be curious--as a cop.
- I'm a doctor, not a cop.
And neither are you.
Though you sure seem to get off
on acting like one, man.
♪
- Psychiatry?
Is this about the surgery?
If you're here to tell me
that I'm not in my right mind
or to try to force me to get--
- No, not at all.
Not at all, Gina.
It's very clear that you have
decisional capacity,
so nobody's gonna
try and make you do something
you don't want to do.
- Oh.
Okay.
♪
I'm not saying that I won't
have the surgery...ever.
I just...
I just wanna wait.
- That's fine.
We can talk about surgery later
if you want, but I just wanted
to ask you when--when did you
first notice
the growth on your neck?
- A few months into COVID.
- Right.
- That's why I didn't come in
for an appointment right away.
It wasn't that big and...
we were being told
to avoid hospitals
unless it was an emergency.
- Certainly, I understand that.
But later, you know,
when things opened up a bit...
I mean, it started
to get a little bigger, right?
- I just sort of hoped
that it would...
go away on its own.
And I...
I realize how insane
that sounds.
- Mm, sounds hopeful.
Nothing insane about hope.
- I was so afraid of...
what it could be
that I just...
I just found it easier to...
- Not think about it at all.
Oh, yes.
It's very human.
♪
- Oh.
Dr. Marcel, coughing up
a little blood here.
- I'm on it.
Dr. Taylor, get her on oxygen.
Ten liters please.
Trini, two of Morphine
and get me a basin.
- What a load of BS.
I paid her a compliment,
which apparently men aren't
allowed to do anymore
without getting shoved
to the ground.
- Listen, Jim, she said
you grabbed her by the arm--
- She assaulted me.
I should be pressing charges
against her.
Can you believe this?
Well, I've had enough.
If this is how you treat
your benefactors--
- Jim, we are incredibly
grateful for your support; ho--
- Yeah, yeah, you can consider
that well all dried up.
In fact, find someone else
to fund your hematology wing.
- Jim.
- We are withdrawing
our pledge.
Elaine, I'm getting the car.
I'll meet you out front.
- Jim.
Elaine?
- A couple weeks ago,
a female grad student
accused Jim of making a pass.
I thought it had
to be a misunderstanding.
He has never been accused
of misconduct.
Is this some kind of a,
I don't know,
midlife crisis?
♪
- Your head CT was clean.
No signs of a bleed.
It was likely just a migraine--
not uncommon
following a trauma.
The nurse will be in shortly
with your discharge paperwork.
- I'm not one of those people
who pretends to be sick to,
like, feed their ego
or scam people out of money,
I swear.
- I believe you.
I can usually tell when
someone's shooting straight
with me, and I think you are.
- Thanks.
- But I will say...
your fear that your message
will lose its impact
if it's not delivered
from the trenches?
I don't know if that's true.
If anything,
you give people hope.
- I've considered that, but if
I'm being completely honest,
it's not just about
the messaging.
Before I was diagnosed
with Lupus,
I was pretty much a loner,
but...
this disease, it gave me
a community for the first time
in my life, and...
if they know
that I'm in remission...
- You'll feel like an outsider.
Yeah, I get it.
♪
But, you know...
walking a path
that isn't yours?
There's a steep price
to that too.
- I know.
I hate lying
to all these people.
- Yeah, just--
- Dr. Scott?
Just wanted to let you know
your patient's out of surgery.
- Oh, thank you.
- No, go ahead, I'm fine.
- You sure?
- Yeah.
Thank you, Dr. Scott,
for everything.
- You got it.
Take care, Candace.
- Hey, Nancy!
How'd Michael do?
The nurse didn't say.
Sorry.
♪
- Just a moment, please.
- Is everything all right,
Elaine?
- I just want to speak
to Dr. Hammer.
- Dr. Hammer.
Over here.
♪
- I'm sorry, Dr. Hammer.
I'm not making excuses for him.
I have none.
But I just...want you to know
he has never been like this.
I...
I don't know what happened
to the man I married.
♪
I'm ready.
- I'll be in touch, Elaine.
♪
Dr. Hammer?
- When they first got here,
Elaine said that he'd been
out of sorts.
- Jim?
- And that he'd lost
his sense of smell.
And when I pushed him away,
he couldn't seem
to find his balance.
Oh, my God.
We can't let them leave.
- What? Why?
What is it?
- We have to get them back here
right now, please.
- Okay.
.
- Hey, Michael.
- I remember you.
- Mm-hmm.
- Surgery went very well.
- Hey, Michael, we're gonna
move you over to the PICU.
Your mom and dad are
waiting to see you.
- Am I in trouble?
- I think they're just happy
that you're okay.
- But, hey, maybe you learned
something about guns today?
- Not toys.
- Right.
I mean, besides, what superhero
do you know that has a gun?
We don't need 'em.
- You know, if you hadn't been
there on the scene...
kid would have bled out,
no question.
You saved his life, Dr. Scott.
- Back shortly, okay?
- She still wants to wait
on the surgery.
- If nearly drowning in her own
blood didn't convince her...
- How does someone let it get
to this point?
- You know, the mind can have
this mysterious
and profound ability
to convince us
to put off almost anything.
- Yeah.
- Why is that?
- One line of thinking is that
we have this bizarre tendency
to disassociate
from our future selves.
There's this really interesting
experiment at Princeton
where two groups of students
were recruited to drink what
was described to them as
this disgusting,
foul-smelling liquid.
Now they were given a choice
about how much
they could drink.
And the group that was told
they had to drink it that day
agreed to drink very little.
But the group that was told
to come back
in a couple of months
and drink it
agreed to drink much more.
- Right.
So they can kick the can down
the road.
- Right.
Okay, so how do we
solve the disconnect?
- You gotta find a way to make
her future self feel...
more tangible to her.
More real.
- There it is.
An olfactory groove meningioma.
- Hmm.
I had a patient early on
in my nursing days
with this type of tumor.
Caused a total personality
change.
- It has a profound
disinhibition effect
on the brain.
And its proximity to
the olfactory nerve, that--
- Explains Jim's loss of smell.
- I'll page neurosurgery
for a consult.
- Do you want to deliver
the news?
- I think maybe it's better
coming from a friend.
- Ah, copy that.
♪
- Gina.
We wanna show you something.
♪
- Is that me?
What--
Where did you get that picture?
- Your friend Liza sent it
to us.
My daughter she just--she loves
these aging filters and--
- What does this
have to do with?
- Well, we wanted you to take
a look at this photo...
and think about a future
version of yourself.
You know, what...
what is her life like?
Who does she care about?
What does she love?
I don't want to.
- What is it, Gina?
- I haven't thought about
the future...
in a really long time.
- Why do you think that is?
- Because what if...
what if I don't have one?
- What if you do?
What would you want it
to look like?
- I guess...
I see myself with a kid.
Maybe two.
Living someplace warm.
I have this dream.
I've always wanted to open up
an outdoor bookshop.
It's impractical in Chicago,
I know, but...
- Not if you're living
someplace warmer.
♪
- Hey, Gina.
Look, I know you're scared.
I get it.
But if you continue
to postpone surgery,
you're denying yourself
a shot at what sounds like
a really great future.
♪
- We're gonna give you
a little time, okay?
You wanna hold onto this
for a bit?
♪
- Wait.
- Gina?
- I'll have the surgery.
♪
- Okay.
- Did Candace leave already?
- Yeah, discharged her.
Ay, come take a look at this.
She came clean
to her followers.
♪
- Unfortunately, she's wrong.
Her Lupus is active again.
She's no longer in remission.
♪
.
- My Lupus is active again?
- Unfortunately, yes.
I ran another set of labs
which confirmed it.
- How did you know?
- So you told us this morning
you did not see the car
before it hit you, right?
So that got me wondering
if peripheral vision loss
could be to blame.
Combined with your elevated
white blood count
and head pain...if your Lupus
had become active again
and was attacking your brain--
- But I thought my head CT
was negative.
- It was.
But swelling wouldn't be
visible on a CT.
- That's right.
We're gonna send you for an MRI
to see exactly what's going on,
but all signs point
to brain inflammation
and optic neuritis
due to underlying Lupus.
- I guess this is what I
deserve for crying wolf
all these years.
God, you should see
the comments under my post.
They're so hurt and angry.
And now if I tell them
it's active again,
nobody's gonna care.
Nobody's gonna believe me.
- Listen, I know you feel like
you lost your tribe right now.
But understanding?
It's a process.
You did your part.
Laying out your truth.
Now give them a chance
to get there.
Those who you want
in the trenches with you,
they'll come around.
♪
- Good luck, Gina.
- Oh, hey, Daniel.
Glad I caught you.
I noticed that you didn't log
any patients
into the new portal today.
If you're having trouble
navigating the platform,
I'd be happy to get somebody
from IT to walk you through it.
- Oh, you know,
I really appreciate that,
but it's not gonna
be necessary.
I'm not gonna be using it.
- Oh, yeah.
I know it's a pain, but, uh...
- Well, not that it's a pain.
It just-- it just doesn't make
a whole lot of sense
for psychiatry.
- Uh-huh.
- We can't just do
a three-minute evaluation
and, like, fire off a script,
you know?
Gotta spend more time
with the patients.
Not really any way around it.
- Yeah.
- This young woman I was
working with today--
I mean honestly, if I hadn't
taken the time to understand
and then address the root cause
of her issue,
she probably wouldn't be
heading off to undergo,
you know, surgery--probably
gonna save her life, so...
- Hey, listen, I hear you.
I think you're right.
- Okay.
Well, terrific.
- Given the necessity
for speed in the ED,
maybe psychiatry
just doesn't belong here.
You think?
You go ahead and run that up
the flag pole, buddy.
- Neurosurgery started Jim
on steroids to reduce the edema
in his brain.
You should also know that
he finally owned up
to what he did.
And asked me to pass along
his apology.
- I'll admit my guard was up
from the minute you said
they were donors.
I've just seen too many people
use their money
as leverage over others,
you know?
- Well, my condolences
to anyone who ever tries that
with you again.
- Hey, Maggie?
- Yeah.
- Mind if I take off
a little early today?
I need to take care
of some personal business.
- No, go ahead.
- Thank you.
- All right.
- I'll see you tomorrow.
♪
- Hey.
- Wait, is that you,
Dr. Marcel?
- In 30 or so years, yeah.
I guess.
- I thought you weren't into
thinking about the future.
"Planning leads
to expectations,
which can lead
to disappointments."
- Oh, you were
paying attention, huh?
Yeah, but I don't know.
Maybe you're onto something.
Maybe it's not
such a bad idea...
giving some thought as to...
where I might want to end up.
Right?
- Right.
♪
- Dr. Halstead, hi.
I'm, uh, Jessa Rinaldi.
I'm a device rep at Vasik Labs.
- Oh, hi.
Nice to meet you.
- Dr. Cooper called my boss
today singing your praises.
And a good word from Matt
goes a long way at Vasik.
- I am honored.
- I would love to talk to you
about one of our products,
the Vas-COM.
It measures cardiac function--
uh...output.
It measures cardiac output
by, um...by...
Well, it--it tells doctors when
patients need additional...
medicine?
I'm sorry,
that's not right either.
- It's okay.
I'm familiar with the Vas-COM.
- You are? Okay, great.
Bottom line, we at Vasik
want to make the Vas-COM
the new standard of care,
and we could really use
your help promoting it
across departments?
Doctor Cooper said that you
could be a real asset...
in that regard...
if you're sold on the device.
And Vasik would, of course,
compensate you
for your time and your effort.
All above board, of course.
♪
- I am definitely interested.
- You are?
Okay, great.
Um, here,
let me give you my card.
♪
- Hey, Mom?
It's me.
♪
It's 1,200.
- Hey.
Stevie!
Stevie, wait.
You're okay with me using it
on the van?
- I'd prefer--you already know
what I'd prefer.
But it's yours.
No strings.
Do what you want with it, Mom.
♪
- Thank you.
- Yeah.
♪
Can we get dinner somewhere?
We don't have to go
to a restaurant or anything.
We could just get take-out
and bring it back here?
♪
- Yeah.
All right.
♪
Let me grab my backpack.
.
♪