So there's this bird,
some sort of swallow, I think.
Where are we with Avery?
Holding offers from USC,
Penn, Tulane, and Emory.
Tulane and Emory are in
love. They want him bad.
Every September,
thousands of 'em
ditch rainy Seattle
to winter in Mexico.
Grey?
These birds aren't dumb.
Uh... Still between
Boston and Seattle.
If I'm gonna lose one
of my talented residents
and my top neurosurgeon,
I'd love a decision
sooner than later.
You and me both, Hunt.
Yang?
She didn't tell you?
Stanford and Columbia
are playing hardball,
but I'm confident that
we're still in the mix.
And every year, crowds of
people gather around Seattle
to drink beer and
watch the flocks take off.
Lee, Steinman, and Renaldo?
Offer from Rice.
Leaning toward Wash U.
Baylor and San Diego
are both after him.
They call it "The
Great Migration."
Well, Karev is staying.
If we are out this many surgeons,
I'm gonna need to hire now,
so let's get answers
from our people
as soon as possible. Thank you.
And let's not forget that we've
agreed to assist Boise Memorial
with their conjoined
twin surgery,
so make sure your teams are
ready to leave from the lobby
no later than 10:00
tomorrow night.
You should be proud.
You trained these kids well.
You trained 'em.
Yeah. I sure did.
We did it!
We passed our boards!
We killed the boards!
I just think it's weird that
we're not even talking about it.
You know, things
are unresolved here.
We're still friends.
It's all good, Jackman.
I love this song!
Whoo! Excuse me!
Kepner's wasted. That's a first.
Yeah, well, lately, she's
been all about firsts.
Yeah!
Wait, wait, wait.
This is Dr. Yang.
Mmm-hmm.
Well, that does certainly
give me a lot to think about.
Thank you so much for calling.
Mayo wants to give
me a research lab.
Guess who's back in the running!
Yeah, Cristina!
April!
So that's what rock
bottom looks like.
Music. Music.
Hello? Yes, this is she.
Uh-huh...
Okay.
Well, yes, thank you. Thank you.
Thank you so much
for the opportunity.
UVA wants a board-certified
surgeon, so they pulled my offer.
Come on. Music!
Come on. Come on.
Music! Come on!
Yes!
Cristina?
What are you doing?
I don't know.
Are you drunk? I don't know.
We got one whole day.
Tuck's with his dad. I think
we should make the most of it.
Sargent exhibit at the
museum, Pike Place,
maybe watch the
sunset over the water.
Twelve whole hours
to get to know the city
that you have lived in
for the past 10 years,
but still have yet to...
No. No, no, no, no, no. You
are supposed to be naked.
Okay, well, the
hospital just called.
A stomach perf with intestinal
obstruction and an enlarged liver.
They don't know
what's causing it.
Uh...
Could be fun. You want to come?
So, how much longer do I have?
Don't tiptoe around.
Just give it to me straight.
Jake, you're not dying.
He can be a little neurotic.
We're hoping we'll be able to
figure out more during your surgery.
Well, do you think it's
something that I picked up abroad,
like Ebola or something? We
were just on our honeymoon.
You two just got married?
You seem like you've
been together a while.
It's our third in 12
years. Honeymoon.
We went to Kauai the first time.
Oh, beautiful.
Yeah, then we got divorced.
Then we went to Fiji the
next time. The beaches.
Yeah, and then we got divorced.
This time, my bride,
she insisted on Thailand.
We just can't seem to
stay away from each other.
Congratulations. Yeah.
So, this patch
here is your tumor.
It's invading the wall
of your right ventricle.
What we'll do is,
we'll resect the tumor,
then repair the ventricle,
and replace the tricuspid valve.
Dr. Yang is the
best that we have.
You couldn't be in better hands.
Come on.
Where is she?
Arizona? She's... Um...
Patients. So many patients.
So, basically,
you all want to chop up my
heart into a jigsaw puzzle.
It may give me a
few more months,
most of which, I'll be
spending in a hospital bed,
while my best
friend in the world
does everything
possible to avoid me?
Or, I spend the
rest of my short life
lying on a sandy
beach in Belize.
Nick, you need this surgery.
Tell Scottsdale I said goodbye.
Looks like I won't
get the chance.
Hunt needs to know
where we are on Boston,
and I gotta let Harvard know
what I'm doing by the end of the day.
We're not going. Anything
else you need to know?
I may have told you, I have
family on the East Coast.
A couple of times.
And I may have replied
that my sister lives here,
and if Cristina chooses
Stanford, it's a two-hour plane ride.
But if she chooses Columbia,
it's only a two-hour train ride.
We're not going.
They want me to run the
neurosurgery department at Harvard.
Webber loves me,
and Bailey loves me.
I will be teaching the
best fellows in the world.
We are staying. We're leaving.
Here you go, Apes.
I was thinking I could
take the trauma rooms,
and we could split the beds.
I can handle trauma,
Alex. It was one phone call.
It doesn't mean I
can't practice medicine.
I still have three great
hospitals who want me.
Of course they do, Apes.
Don't call me "Apes."
Karev, come here.
You're gonna get a
phone call in a few minutes,
and not just any phone call.
It's from Keith Collier. I
don't know any Keith Colliers.
He was one of your
examiners at the boards.
Oh, crap. I failed, didn't I?
They changed their
minds. Son of a...
Karev, Karev, Keith is
a good friend of mine.
Now whatever you told him at
the boards really impressed him.
I mean, really impressed him.
He wants to offer you a peds
surgery fellowship at Hopkins.
Hopkins has the best
program in the country.
They've already chosen
their fellows for next year.
Which is what makes
this so extraordinary.
They're adding a
position just for Karev.
Oh.
This is you playing some
kind of practical joke,
then at the end,
you're gonna tell me
I learned something
when I really haven't.
I am not joking. I have
no skin in this game.
Hopkins is the dream.
I know.
It's really not cool to screw
with somebody's head like this.
You know that. I know.
Make sure your ringer's on.
He's full of crap.
I don't think so.
I'm over this.
Cristina, I made a
decision. You have?
You're going to Stanford.
Oh, you've made my decision.
There's no way you're
going to Columbia.
And Mayo's in Minnesota. Please.
And since we're staying here,
Stanford's only a couple of hours away.
You'll come up.
I'll bring Zola down.
We can get drunk
on the weekends.
Okay, maybe I
shouldn't bring Zola.
Hey! There you are.
Is there anything you want to
go over on the conjoined twins
before you head out to Boise?
No. I'm good. You sure?
'Cause you're gonna be the
sole cardiothoracic surgeon
representing Seattle Grace.
Which, you know,
is kind of unheard of
for an attending to
allow her fellow to do.
But that's just the kind
of faith I have in you.
Technically, I'm
not a fellow yet.
I know. Right?
I mean, so just think
about all the things
that you're gonna be
able to do when you are.
Tip of the iceberg,
Yang. I'm proud of you.
You haven't even
told her you're leaving?
I haven't decided yet
where I'm going. You just did.
Stanford. ALEX: Hopkins!
Hopkins is not in the running.
Not for you.
For me. Hopkins.
Hopkins wants me.
Hopkins wants me!
Johns Hopkins, the
hospital? Alex, how?
Not Hopkins
Refrigeration School?
I kind of bitched out their
chief of surgery at my boards,
and I guess he was impressed.
So they know you're a jerk?
They totally know, and they
want me. Hopkins wants me.
I'm not surprised at all.
I am 100% surprised.
Hey.
Nice work, evil spawn.
Whoo!
Yes! Hopkins!
The stomach's
adhered to the bowel,
and look at the
size of this liver.
You know, this is one
for the record book.
We should be taking
pictures. We really should.
Sure. Let's take a break.
Maybe someone
could find a camera.
We got all the
time in the world.
We do have all the time in the
world. This is my only case today.
Because it's your day off.
I'll have another day off.
I made a lunch reservation. I
even brought the crossword.
We could skip the
crossword for one week.
Oh, that's not right.
What in the name of
chickens is going on here?
Is it Crohn's Disease?
Maybe it's just a mystery.
Maybe Lee Harvey Oswald's
magic bullet's been dancing around
in Mr. Steiner's
intestines for 50 years.
Sometimes we just
never figure it out.
You marvel at the wonder
of it all while you sew 'em up,
and you go eat lunch.
Is it a metabolic syndrome?
Mmm-mmm.
Oh, maybe it's autoimmune.
What did you tell Keith?
- Uh... Finish up.
- Yes, sir.
I told him I needed a
day or two to think about it.
But, I made a
commitment to Robbins.
I don't know what I'm
doing here. I'm freaking out.
What's Hopkins
giving salary-wise?
It's competitive.
They throw in a loan-repayment
package, moving expenses?
You did the whole Africa thing.
Tell me you at least asked
for an international rotation.
Oh, Karev. Look, it's not
like I have any leverage.
And these are two of the
best programs in the country.
Who both want you.
And now's the time
to shake 'em down.
I mean, pit 'em
against each other.
You call Hopkins back
and tell 'em what you want,
and then get Hunt's ass down here
and give him the same demands.
What if he doesn't
want to play ball?
If he doesn't have
the money, he doesn't.
He has the money.
And when he lies and says
that he doesn't have the money,
and he will lie...
You're not doing your job
as the chief if you don't lie.
You tell him you know about
his incidentals and overhead fund.
Incidentals and overhead fund.
Exactly.
You say those four
little words, and I promise
the kingdom will be yours.
How's Julia? You
impregnate her yet?
No, I was all ready
to, but then Lexie...
Oh, she told me she
was in love with me.
Ooh. What did you say?
I said, "Thank you
for your candor."
"Thank you for your candor"?
What was I supposed to do?
Oh, I don't know. Kiss her.
Julia's away on a
conference. I'm not a cheater.
Usually. Mmm.
Look, I owe it to
the both of them to...
I don't want to mess
this one up, okay?
Julia wants to give
me everything I want.
But I'm in love with Lexie, who
doesn't want anything I want.
Dr. Shepherd. Dr. Sloan.
Lexie, come on in.
Plenty of room. Oh. Uh...
Actually, I was just gonna update
you on the Boise doctors' bios,
but since you're both here,
I'm just gonna give it to you,
and then that way, I can leave.
Oh, no. You guys
go. I'm gonna stay.
Hey, Lexie, about
that other thing,
don't think I forgot
what you said.
I just need to ruminate on that.
You know? Run it
up the old flagpole?
Okay.
You know, it's too bad Meredith
and I are moving to Boston.
I'm gonna miss this.
Hey, you got a second?
'Cause I cannot figure out
what to do about Tulane,
and there's this whole other
thing that happened at the boards.
I mean, it's all kind of
thrown me for a loop.
Aww. Look at that. She's cute.
Must be nice in here with
all these cute little babies.
Yeah.
Is she dying, like, right now?
'Cause Nick is.
Remember Nick, your
brother's best friend,
your rock, who is
right now packing up
and bailing on a surgery
that he needs to live
because you can't get your
stubborn head out of your ass
and let go of the fact that
he didn't come to you sooner?
Callie, I... No, I don't get it.
You watch babies die every day.
When things looked bad for
me, you didn't leave my side.
And now your best
friend's asking for you.
Look, you need to get your
crap together before he leaves,
because if he goes
now, he is gone.
She's not actually
dying, is she?
No.
Okay, good.
You said you'd know
more once you got in there.
We hoped we'd know more.
Unfortunately, we weren't
able to find the cause.
But the good news is,
we were able to repair all
the damage to your abdomen.
What's the point if you
don't know what's doing it?
Something is eating my insides.
Maybe it's stress, you know?
You're so worried about
the worst-case scenario,
you finally made it happen.
Okay, coral can poison
you. That's a known fact.
And look at you. I told you
not to pet those monkeys.
What? It's a rash. It's
not from the monkeys.
Please take a look at her
arm? It's been there for weeks.
Where did you say you
honeymooned again?
Thailand.
Where pigs walk
around inside restaurants.
It's called local color.
It's unsanitary.
Life is unsanitary. That's what
makes it fun, for God sakes.
Mrs. Steiner, please hold still.
What is this here?
Is that... Right there.
That's
a worm.
Good news.
I think we found what's
eating your insides.
Whoa.
That's a nasty
critter. Raw fish?
Sushi in Thailand
from a train station.
I'm looking for more
damage. Want to help?
No. I'm gonna cancel
our lunch reservation.
Are you really still
moping about lunch?
I had a plan. We had a day!
Ben, there is a gnathostoma
worm in this man's body.
These things eat through the
viscera, migrate through the tissue.
This is a
once-in-a-lifetime parasite.
I'm sorry if I find it a little
more interesting right now
than the crossword
and garden salad.
The patient is
on antiparasitics.
The worm is going to die.
What...
There's nothing else you can do
right now, other
than go to lunch.
This is not like
one of your movies
where the larvae
gestate in the brain,
leaving the poor host
a hollowed-out zombie
whose bite will now infect the
whole populace on the base.
What movie is that? What?
No, that sounds
good. I haven't seen it.
I made it up.
Oh, man!
Okay, let's see now. There's...
Ooh.
Oh, man.
You made a commitment.
Technically, that was
a verbal agreement.
I never signed a contract.
I would like to think that your
word is as good as a contract.
Normally, yeah,
but this is Hopkins.
I just think you should know
what they're offering me.
Oh, really, like what?
Like moving expenses.
You live here. True.
But this is the extra dough
that Hopkins was willing to offer.
I'm just asking you to add
that on to my new salary.
Karev, even if I
wanted to, I couldn't.
That budget is already set.
We don't have the dough. Okay?
Maybe you should
recheck that budget.
You know, see what
you got lying around
in your incidentals
and overhead fund.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Oh, I think you do.
We can add Spaghetti Wednesday
to the list of things I'm not
gonna miss about this place.
Are you kidding?
Best deal in town.
I've watched Alex go
through six bowls already.
True that.
Hey, I hear Stanford
has a farm-to-table chef.
You can text your
order right from the OR.
I'll factor that in. I still
haven't made my decision.
Well, it's gotta be Stanford.
Where else would you go?
I don't know. I might stay.
Everything's on the table.
She like-a the spaghetti, too.
Tulane's got crawfish. I
mean, that's a selling point.
USC, I mean, what
do they eat in LA?
Souls.
2-1-2. It's New
York. Mount Sinai.
Answer it.
Bad news is only bad news
if you pick up the phone.
April Kepner speaking. Cristina.
Oh, really? Okay.
Okay.
Oh, my gosh. Okay.
No, no, no, no. No, thank you.
They didn't pull my
offer? Oh, no. They did.
I just figured that's
what you'd sound like
in the face of rejection.
Hey, you want my fries, Apes?
Not if they're pity fries.
They taste the same.
No, you still got Case
Western and Seattle, right?
You're gonna be fine.
So what does Sloan
think about Tulane?
He hasn't weighed in
one way or the other.
There's something
wrong with him.
I think he's disturbed
or something.
Then again, I've been pretty
disturbed myself these days.
2-1-6. Cleveland.
Maybe Case Western's
offering loan assistance.
This is Kepner.
Oh, yeah? Well, you know
what? I am an awesome surgeon.
And I would've rocked your stupid
little program, so it is your loss.
Go to hell!
Where are you going?
Belize.
You're going to
have the surgery.
Why, so I can get a few more
months of pain and suffering?
So you can live, and
then you'll have radiation,
or we'll get you
in a clinical trial.
Now you have an opinion, Doctor,
after you've been
MIA for three days?
I've been a little busy, Nick.
Look, I get that
this is scary for you.
I really do.
But it kind of
sucks for me, too.
They're telling me
I'm riddled with cancer,
and I'm completely alone.
Where's your sister?
Did you call your sister?
You're the one that's
supposed to be here!
You're the one who's supposed
to have my back through all this.
And you're nowhere! You're gone!
I have your back! Then have it!
Please?
Please have the surgery.
It'll work. And I'll be here.
I'll be here. I promise.
Damn, Phoenix.
Things a guy has to
do to get your attention.
I love the fireplace,
the stonework.
You hated it a month ago.
And the windows.
These views are
amazing. You are a genius.
I will build you a
dream house in Boston.
What will we do with
this one? Mark will buy it.
His dreams have
always been my dreams.
Harvard is offering me a
$10 million endowment.
They're setting me up with
an entire research team.
I'm gonna cure Alzheimer's,
Meredith. That's my dream.
Not this house.
You're making this
choice with Cristina.
She's not the only
factor. I'm your husband.
You should make it with me.
So I didn't see
any further damage
from the parasite on your scans.
That's great, but you can't just
leave a worm
inside of him forever.
This thing has teeth. You
have to get it out of me, please.
I have a worm inside of me, too,
but you don't hear
me crying about it.
Yours is in your arm, and
they're taking it out today.
Mine could be anywhere.
Oh, my God. My penis.
It's not gonna get to your...
It doesn't do that, does it?
My legs.
Okay, which is it?
Your legs or your penis?
No, I'm serious. I can't
feel my legs or my arms.
It's weird. It's all going numb.
What?
Can you move your toes?
Uh-uh.
No? What about your fingers?
No. Shoot.
Okay.
Can you feel that? Barely.
What's wrong? What's
happening to him?
Page Shepherd.
Right away, Doctor.
Well, the thing's gnawed
through all the discs.
C3 to C5 are all inflamed.
So it's in there.
The worm's in his cervical
spine, nesting, waiting.
So there's a
chance of paralysis.
Complete paralysis. I
need to get in there quick.
Otherwise, he's gonna
be a quadriplegic.
No. I'm going in with
you. I'm on your six.
I'll get him prepped.
Lock and load, people.
She's on your what?
I have no idea.
Okay, dealer's choice.
Do you want to do the
ventriculoplasty, or resect the tumor,
or...
Do you want to be
primary surgeon?
Fine. Fine?
Okay, what is going on?
Are you staying? Are you going?
'Cause it... It's driving
me crazy. I don't...
If it has to do with
Owen, whatever it is,
I am sure the two
of you can fix it.
I'll take all of it.
What? All of it.
The ventriculoplasty
and as much of the
tumor as you'll let me do.
Thank you. It's very generous.
I'll see you in there.
Okay, Marion,
the ultrasound shows the worm
went deeper into your tissue
but we should still be able
to get that nasty thing out.
Jake could die
or he could be in a
wheelchair for the rest of his life.
I'm the one that insisted
we go to Thailand.
I keep trying to turn
him into somebody else.
Maybe we made a mistake.
What do you mean exactly?
How do you know it was a mistake?
I don't know why we keep
coming back to each other.
We're the same people, but we
keep expecting a different outcome.
Isn't that the
definition of insanity?
Or love. If there's a
spark, there's a spark.
Or maybe you
think there's a spark,
but it just happened once,
so you can't really tell,
and there's no time to
actually figure that out
because you're probably
moving halfway across the country.
Are we gonna get this
worm out any time soon?
Yeah. Get the irrigation ready.
On it.
C3 and C4 are just a mess.
I'm gonna have to go
further in here than I expected.
You might as well
go all the way to C5.
I mean, from the
look of this lesion,
that's where the
bastard set up his hive.
I don't want it to be any
more invasive than it has to be.
Don't argue with her. She's
starring in her own sci-fi movie.
You mess with
her, she'll pull out
her ray gun and
atomize your ass.
And he's still pouting.
You're a physician.
Is this really the first time you
missed a lunch and the crossword
because of a
surgery? Here we go.
It was important to me.
This parasite's important to me.
Yeah, I can see that.
You know what? Fine.
Let's do it right now.
Give me the damn
crossword. Just forget it.
Oh, no. Nobody's ever gonna
forget it. Where is Dr. Warren's bag?
Miranda... MIRANDA:
Oh, there it is.
And this is why you don't
work with your girlfriend.
I warned them.
Here we go. Oh, this
is gonna be so great.
It's way better than a
once-in-a-lifetime bone-eating parasite.
Let's see. One down.
Dr. Bailey... Oh, no, no, no.
No help from you. I'm too
excited. This is what I live for.
Let's see, "Peruvian
mountain range."
Oh, Andes. Five. Uh-huh...
"Planet with water, four
letters." Oh, Mars. Duh.
Uh... "Fancy sauce"? Fancy...
Ooh.
Remoulade. Stop.
What? No, no. I'm
on a roll. Come on.
Hey, this can't be the Sunday,
'cause this is way too easy.
Oh, hey, this one, 21 across.
"My question to you." Hmm.
I'm asking you to put it away.
He's asking you
nicely, Dr. Bailey.
Oh, no, no, no. When
he doesn't get his way,
he holds on to it in his
cheek like a squirrel with a nut.
We are doing the crossword.
What is, "My question to you"?
It's a bunch of letters.
Oh, maybe it's a phrase.
"My question to you," anybody?
How many letters?
Uh... Two, nine, 13.
It's 13 letters? Fourteen.
No, I'm looking at it. It's 13.
No, it's 14. Count again.
I just counted.
What, do you have x-ray
vision from across the room?
"Will you marry me?"
is my question to you.
And the reason why it's so easy
is because I made the crossword.
Took me two damn months
not to mention getting a mockup
made of The New York Times.
The phrase has 14 letters.
"Will," four, "you," seven,
"marry," 12, "me," 14.
Got it.
It was in C4.
All right, temp's
down to 30 degrees.
Cross-clamping the aorta.
All right.
Let's see what
we're working with.
Damn it. This
wasn't in the scans.
The tumor's infiltrated much
deeper into the ventricle.
Reconstructive
ventriculoplasty isn't gonna cut it.
We could do a Fontan?
Directly sew the right atrium
to the pulmonary artery.
We could patch whatever's left.
That would help with blood flow,
but the hole in the
resection would...
Yeah. He'd arrest
right on the table.
We could do an
RV to a PA conduit...
No, the thing would
calcify. It would kill him.
A cadaver homograft?
The hole would be way too big.
It's instant heart failure.
They don't know what to
do, Callie. They have no idea.
No, it's Altman and Yang,
okay? They'll figure something out.
They're gonna
figure something out.
Come on, guys. Come on.
Hey.
Sedona.
How's my ticker?
Cancer free?
The tumor had
taken over your heart,
and there was no
good way to get it out,
so they had to close up.
But I thought...
You said it was my best shot.
It was.
So...
I guess I'm going to Belize.
Yeah.
Stupid.
I'm so freaking...
Why didn't I come sooner?
Why didn't I come...
Oh, my God.
I'm so stupid.
No. No.
I'm so stupid. I'm so stupid.
Hey. Hey.
I think we're gonna lose Yang.
Owen, what happened?
Please tell me.
'Cause I have tried everything
short of offering her my own job.
I mean, I've sang,
I've danced, I've...
I slept with someone else.
So,
there's nothing that
you could've done.
She's not leaving you.
She's leaving me.
I'm sorry.
Hopkins didn't pull
the offer, did they?
They gave me the international
rotation and the moving expenses,
and they took
care of all my loans.
College, med school.
Yes.
They're even throwing
in a mortgage allowance.
I could buy a house.
Good.
They gave me
everything I asked for.
So did Hunt.
Then why the hell
aren't you celebrating?
No one's ever
wanted me like this.
You just don't recognize
the view, Karev.
The crowd going wild,
people taking pictures,
the snap of the
tape as you break it.
What are you talking about?
What it looks like
when you finish first.
Chief, you paged?
Yeah.
I can't hire you
next year, Kepner.
I...
I'm taking my boards again.
You know, I'll pass this time.
You don't have to
worry about that.
It's not just about the boards.
I've had to do some last-minute
rejiggering of my budget,
and I just don't have the money.
This is a top-ranking hospital.
There's always money.
I can help you find it. I'm
really good with budgets.
Chief,
I have nothing left.
Seattle Grace
was my last option.
You're not the best
candidate for the job anymore.
I am sorry.
They're conjoined at the
sternum and the diaphragm.
It's tricky.
I can handle it.
So Seattle's still in the
mix. That's a surprise.
Because of Owen?
Cristina, he should be with
someone who wants a baby.
And you should be with
someone who wants you.
You know what? You and
everyone else needs to just...
Shut up about it.
It's a huge decision.
And I don't want you
doing the wrong thing.
It is not your decision to make.
I am your person.
We're not married.
You're not my...
He's my person.
Hey. I just checked in on
him. His vitals are stable.
He's sleeping.
Don't ever leave.
What?
Promise me that right now.
I'm not going
anywhere. I promise.
After my brother, I thought,
I can't do this ever again.
I won't do this again.
And now, here I am.
Okay, whatever you
can't do, I will. I'm here.
And that's how this works, okay?
Come here.
So, what's it gonna be?
Columbia, Stanford?
I hear that Mayo
is back in the mix.
You know, really, you can't
go wrong with any of them, so...
What are you doing?
Propose to me again.
Baby, you should sit down.
Wow. I mean, you look...
Wow.
Miranda, I would love
nothing more than that,
but I'm telling
you, you should...
For the love of
God, man, I'm sorry
I messed up your
proposal, but...
I'm wearing a thong, and
this is as sorry as I get.
So, come on. Ask
me to marry you.
Okay, look, there was
the shooting, right?
And then you and I broke up,
and I just, I wanted
to get out of here,
to do something different,
something inspiring.
I just
didn't think it would
actually happen.
I got a call,
and I've been accepted
as a surgical intern at UCLA.
An intern, Miranda.
I'll be working seven days
a week, 1,000 miles away.
Everything's different now.
What?
I'm happy.
I know this
doesn't fix anything.
But I'm just happy.
I'm leaving.
You got that? Is it
too heavy for you?
No, I'm fine, but thank you.
No, thank you.
You son of a bitch. I
had to hear it from Hunt?
What, you couldn't even be
man enough to tell me yourself?
Sweetie. She's had a
horrible day. I'm so...
You ungrateful crap dog!
It's Hopkins. You went there.
You of all people should know.
You are a miserable,
miserable bastard.
Robbins, they want me. All
right? They really want me.
Oh, well, you...
You're actually going?
Can we talk about
this when I get back?
No!
What are you doing?
No, you are not going to Boise,
because you no longer
represent this hospital!
Give me a break...
Look at Alex, showing us
all up by going to Hopkins.
If Robbins lets
him live that long.
Fine. You know what?
Forget the charts!
Go see if they need
help in the clinic.
I'm going to Boston.
I told Hunt.
I've been prepping for
this surgery for days!
I'm going to Mayo.
This is crap!
I don't know how
those birds do it.
Travel thousands of
miles without getting lost,
banging into windows,
being eaten by cats...
All right, let's get you
some water, okay?
Let's get you some water.
You know, I'm so sick of
everyone being so damn nice to me.
You just feel guilty...
April... for having
sex with me...
No, come on. That is
not... and then I failed...
I am messed up right now.
And now no one wants me.
What?
Oh, crap. Even Seattle?
I don't want your pity, okay?
Can you just leave me alone?
Can you do that? I'm
fine. I'm fine! Okay.
I'm gonna be fine,
Jackson... All right.
I'm gonna...
April, April...
Come...
but every spring,
they're always here.
I guess they come
back to what they know.
People say it's pretty
cool watching them go.
They say you can
actually see the moment
when, at some mysterious signal,
all at once,
the birds decide to leave.
So maybe I've been missing out.
Whatever.
There's always next year.