Previously, on The Resident...
Medical error is the third
leading cause of death.
But you still show up here.
'Cause it's personal to me.
Lily, you're gonna be all right.
Her chart only goes back as
far as this current admission.
I'm gonna go get it myself.
- Where you going?
- Lane's clinic.
Dr. Hunter doesn't want
to turn patients away.
We squeeze in as
many as possible.
You and Nic, that still a thing?
- I think she's worth fighting for.
- Game on.
My approach to this
complex procedure will die
with me if it isn't passed
on to the next generation.
- What about benzodiazepines?
- Last resort, try 'em,
but the side effects are...
Aggression and
cognitive impairment.
I guess it just depends
how desperate the guy is.
As I said, it was
my responsibility.
It was my decision.
I understand,
but what was the
cause, Dr. Okafor?
I broke protocol,
things happened.
♪ ♪
This is a mortality and
morbidity conference,
Dr. Okafor.
To ensure that
an event like this...
A horrific and
preventable medical error...
Doesn't happen again.
The surgeries on
these three patients
took place
concurrently, correct?
Concurrent surgeries are
not against hospital policy.
The critical portions
were staggered,
so the attending
could be present.
Dr. Bell.
Could you explain how
this catastrophe occurred?
Dr. Bell, you were the architect
of these concurrent surgeries.
So I'll ask again:
How did this error happen?
I woke her up at 3:00 a.m.
to tell her that I'm 85% sure
I have cancer.
And then... yeah,
and then refused
to make an appointment
for six weeks.
Kind of backwards, right, Doc?
I hoped the pain would go away.
The number of people
who walk in here
thinking they have cancer
versus the number of
people who actually do...
Not cancer.
Oh, thank God.
Bike accident did more
damage than you thought.
You have an atrophied testicle.
Uh, well, that
doesn't sound good.
Will it just heal by itself?
With this degree of atrophy
and your continued pain,
the recommended treatment
is, um, removal.
Chopping my ball off?
Oh, come on, come on,
guys. Are you serious?
Calm down, I'm sure
there are options.
Will we... still be
able to have kids?
Absolutely.
You only need one
healthy guy for that.
See? That's great news.
No more pain and
lots of kids, eventually.
One nut.
What does that even look like?
Well, can't be
worse than the pair.
They're hideous.
- Maybe less is more.
- But it doesn't have to be.
Dr. Pravesh will show you
some excellent prosthetic options.
You'll be as good as new
in no time. Right, Doctor?
- Great.
- Absolutely. Yeah.
Gonna get you a
bright, shiny new ball.
Ugh.
- It'll be super fast, really.
- Then I'll come after work.
Ma, you know you won't, please.
When I get fired from
my job, who pays the rent?
You? You, Dr. Feldman?
Just let him make
sure you're okay.
- That's all.
- Trevor,
pretending to be
sick to get me here
was the last thing
I needed today.
- Now I'm already pissed. Don't push it.
- Christine?
How the hell do
you know my name?
- I called her.
- Why?
Who is this lady?
Only the best
nurse in this hospital.
Dr. Feldman asked
me to come down.
And drag me to a hospital
room? We're leaving.
- Hey, hey.
- Christine, who's gonna pay the bills
if you have a stroke?
What the hell did
you just say to me?
Or a heart attack.
You-you smoke, right?
Probably spend a lot
of time on your feet?
- Who do you think you are?
- Look,
Dr. Feldman is
worried about you,
which means that I
am worried about you.
I was around his age
when my mother died.
So please stay.
I'll get you the best
doctors, I promise.
Mom. Please.
Okay.
- Great.
- Okay.
Nic! Irving!
Hey, guys.
Hey, York.
I'm back.
- Page Conrad.
- Yep.
♪ ♪
What I'm saying is our
ORs are rarely at capacity,
save Orthopedics
led by Dr. Simich,
which has been practicing
concurrent surgeries
with incredible results. I
would like all departments
to do the same.
That would mean splitting focus.
Welcoming chaos.
I find multiple
surgeries irresponsible.
I've never had a problem,
and we do them all the time.
- You haven't had a single error or complication?
- Relax.
We're not reinventing the wheel.
It goes on in hospitals
all around the country,
it's an excellent
training ground
for residents to practice,
it's perfectly legal,
and if it's well planned,
the surgeries can be
as safe as any other.
Dr. Bell, is there a reason
you have stopped
practicing multiple surgeries?
If I'm not mistaken,
it's been over a year.
I've billed over $35 million
in the last 14 months; you
finding yourself underwhelmed
with my performance?
Dr. Simich and his team have
just set the bar unusually high.
I would like everyone
to rise to the bar,
if not exceed it.
♪ Something about ♪
♪ The way you move is rude ♪
♪ Don't know what it do ♪
♪ Tell me why I ♪
♪ I can't keep my eyes ♪
♪ Off you ♪
♪ I think, oh, I, I, I. ♪
Do me a favor, get
excited, Pravesh.
One of my favorite
patients just landed,
and it's a case
that will inspire you,
it will touch you and
make you believe again.
York.
- Hey!
- My man.
Thanks for that latest Yelp
review, I might get it framed.
Oh, sorry.
That's okay. Honest mistake.
See my review?
My mom cried like a
baby when she read it.
Guys, it's the
least that I can do
after your astute medical care.
It... Oh! Who do we have
here? A fresh new intern.
Dr. Pravesh.
Welcome to Chastain,
Dr. Pravesh. You are fortunate
to be working with this
medical mastermind.
Yes, I am.
So, York, what
brings you in today?
Mm. Slow the
roll. Pull the file.
Okay.
We're just catching
up like gentlemen.
- So, how are things at the university?
- Good, yeah,
sharp crop of
students this semester,
always appreciated.
Not always the case.
Whoa.
This... this can't be right.
So, York, what did you shove
up your rectum this time?
How is that even possible?
- Is that...?
- The princess of pancakes?
I'd recognize her anywhere.
You must admit, on
some level, it's impressive.
Now that's a keeper.
This happens all
over the country.
There are entire Web
sites dedicated to it.
- Well, it's horrifying.
- Irving,
sign up our young intern here
- for your anal objects updates.
- No. -
It's time to educate him
on both the frequency
and creative nature
of these situations.
Yeah, that's a "no,
thanks" from me.
Too late.
- Isn't it your day off?
- Bell paged.
- What's in the garment bag?
- Something of mine.
Mina, just a heads-up,
I think you might be
surgically removing
- a syrup bottle from someone's...
- York's rectum?
Oh, so you know him, too?
He gave her the only
good Yelp review she has.
- Very well-written.
- Are you trying to hand York off?
No, no, no, no, no. Not so fast
turfing this one.
You'll be trying several
non-surgical
methods first, Doctor.
There is no way that thing
is coming out without surgery.
It's family-size.
That's what we thought when
York got frisky with a bottle of...
Steak sauce.
So, go spend some quality
time with our friendly professor
and don't forget to
show Ed his new balls.
20 bucks says you can't
figure out what that is.
It was the only way I could
think of getting her here.
I mean, when I'm
sick, she cares.
And when she's
sick, she doesn't.
- Socks off, please.
- Oh, come on.
- What the hell for?
- Mom.
Stop fighting everything,
and this'll go a lot faster.
When he's right, he's right.
Which is most of the time.
I thought you said I
was gonna get the best.
- He...
- Is the best, yes.
- How long has it been cold?
- I don't know.
- A couple days. Sometimes my feet are cold.
- Both?
- Or just the left one?
- Just the left one.
So what?
You have high blood
pressure and abnormal
pulsation in your abdomen.
So, is she gonna be okay?
Yeah. Just ordering a CT
scan to see what's going on.
Come here, baby.
Did you see him
touching my feet?
I hope it's not
what I think it is.
- What do you think it is?
- Abdominal aortic aneurysm.
Could be.
- Really didn't want to hear that.
- She should be fine.
As long as it's not
increasing in size,
and she doesn't
escape before it ruptures.
I need a minute.
I really don't want
to get stuck in a room
with my pants down again.
I'm willing to risk it.
- No, is that all you're willing to risk?
- Nic.
- I'm trying.
- This was never our problem.
- Then what was?
- Not here, not now.
Okay.
I took this at Lane's clinic.
Look at these dosages,
they are extremely high.
That's not just dose
intensification protocol.
I mean, there's
something else going on.
Cary Michaels, 2015, diagnosed
with stage IV liver cancer,
three months to live.
Still alive today thanks to
Lane's high dosage protocol.
I don't get your
obsession with this.
Well, I do get that
you're loyal to her,
but we both know
oncologists make a huge profit
from the drugs they prescribe.
More chemo, more money.
That's an awful accusation,
and it'll never stand
up to her outcomes.
I'm worried about Lily.
Technology is making
everything easier
and yet, valuable traditions
are being abandoned.
The Bell 2.0 is...
the perfect marriage.
Is there such a thing?
This tool will prove invaluable
in all forms of
surgery, even neuro.
Now, in terms of...
In terms of...
In terms of market potential...
Dr. Bell, I don't want to waste
any more of your time or mine.
Perhaps this tool will
be a great legacy for you.
Legacy is not my objective.
Improving surgical
conditions is.
It's too risky of an
improvement for my tastes.
Oh, surely you
know the biggest risk
- is not taking any.
- You can talk to me
- about risk when it's your money on the line.
- Right.
What do I know about
risk? I'm a surgeon.
The good news is
that we have a number
of hospital wings that
could bear your name.
Well, vanity investments
aren't as attractive to me
as judicious ones.
Cancer.
Tell me about it.
A group of diseases involving
abnormal cell
growth with the ability
to invade or spread to
other parts of the body.
I'm quite sure he
knows what cancer is,
but did you know it was our
number one revenue stream?
I'm listening.
I'll contact Dr. Lane
Hunter, Head of Oncology,
and have her give you
a tour of our new facility
and tell you more.
Best of luck with
your tool, Dr. Bell.
I hope cancer treats
you well, Marshall.
Impressive, right?
It has a thin silicone
elastomer shell.
- Groovy.
- So, Doctor,
will Ed's package
look the same or...?
Exactly the same.
- Well, not if I choose this one here.
- Oh, God.
Happy Easter.
It might actually throw off
your anatomical balance.
- So...
- It's kind of like bad wheel alignment.
You'd be drifting to the left.
You know, I have an idea.
Why don't I just get,
like, a triple "D" implant,
but only in my right
boob. That way,
we'd always be moving
towards each other.
Sort of like...
Okay, now that hurts.
We got this.
Of course we got this.
Doc, how'd I get so lucky?
Everything okay, Doctor?
Yeah. Yes. Yes.
I don't care what Dr. Hawkins
says, I want a second opinion!
I understand that surgery's
scary, but your CT scan confirms
- Dr. Hawkins' diagnosis.
- A seven centimeter
aortic aneurysm
needs surgical repair.
Hey, Ma, Ma, you're
gonna be okay.
Okay?! Okay how?!
Calm down. Calm down.
Oh, baby, I'm sorry.
I am.
I'm gonna be fine. I
just, I don't know how
I'm gonna afford
a freaking surgery.
We'll figure it out.
We always do.
Christine, let me walk you
through everything, okay?
Okay.
Hey, I've got an idea.
You want to come up and
see the medevac helicopter?
You have one of those?
Yep. And you can see it,
if it's okay with your mom.
Yes. Baby, go.
Go ahead.
My kids need me.
I know.
You know, I thought
about going into medicine.
Mm-hmm.
Ear, nose and throat... or feet.
Tops and tails are
sort of my thing.
Oh... 'kay. Okay.
And then I found Aristotle
and I just never looked back.
Tell me, did you
always want to be a doc?
Yes, York.
Yes.
You know, I feel like you're
not really present, Dr. Pravesh.
Like your mind is elsewhere.
Exhale, please.
Ex...? Okay.
Ooh-ee.
- York?
- That's my name.
Did the syrup
queen start her day
with or without her crown?
With.
Free at last. Hello.
Finally get to go home, Bradley?
Finally, yes.
I can't wait to get home
and take a long hot shower
and then sleep.
Followed by, you
know, more sleep.
- You're not driving, are you?
- Oh, hell no.
Bradley, I'll need you
in one of my surgeries
later this afternoon.
Whoa, wait, he just completed
a 30-hour shift.
I'm sorry.
Bradley, do you need
to go home and rest?
No. No, sir, Dr. Bell.
- I, uh...
- Okay.
So, that happened.
Sorry.
Bell's doing Christina and
Ed's surgeries at the same time?
Not if I have
anything to do with it.
Are you kidding, Doc?
I couldn't be prouder.
Mike's in the 82nd Airborne.
1st Brigade Combat Team.
- Paratroopers, right?
- Uh-huh.
And this is a kid who was
scared of heights growing up.
Hey, uh, do you have a minute?
Yeah. I'll see you
inside, okay, Gus?
Sure thing, Doc.
What's going on?
Do you have time
for a triple "A" repair?
Bell scheduled my patient
concurrently with another.
I don't know; I'm
pretty jammed up today.
How urgent is it?
Nic, I already told you, we
transfer Christine to St. Joe's.
I reached out to Dr. Reyes.
He has an opening, no
HODAD, everybody wins.
You can't make
crazy moves like that.
You send a patient
to another hospital
and Claire will swallow
your medical career whole.
No one needs to know;
my plan is bulletproof.
Unless you get shot
down in the process.
You're getting awfully
cautious these days, brother.
reckless, brother.
A little reminder, we'll all
on the same team here.
Look, it sounds like
Christine's stable,
so I'll do her
surgery after Gus.
It'll be tight, but it's doable.
She's gonna need
to request a switch
- or Bell will come for my head.
- Of course.
All right, sounds good?
- Yeah, thanks.
- No. "Tight" sounds like
- a disaster waiting to happen.
- Well, I wasn't asking you.
Well, I'm telling you
that making medical
choices for the wrong reasons
isn't very smart, Silva.
And what exactly
does that mean, huh?
Conrad, it's the right call.
He's just trying to help.
I'll see Christine in surgery.
Thanks.
What's going on with you?
This is incredible.
All funded by cancer patients?
And an early investment
in a groundbreaking
drug for lymphoma.
I love breaking ground.
Well, that's encouraging.
As I tell all investors,
you need to be driven by
the desire to care for patients
as well as for the return,
since most of these drugs
never really make it to market.
Dr. Lane, I don't
like many people,
but I like you.
So I'll be brutally honest.
I'm driven by one thing:
betting on the right horse.
It requires my full focus
and a lot of personal sacrifice.
Just ask my ex-wife and son.
Success comes with a price.
And sometimes,
that price is family.
But, Doctor, you have
my undivided attention.
It doesn't happen often.
What do you have to offer?
I'm happy to give
you a breakdown
of all the drugs we
have in development.
Company?
I'm sorry about earlier.
I just... I got a
lot going on and...
but now I'm all good.
Really? 'Cause
about an hour ago,
you looked like you were
gonna punch Jude in the face.
Oh, I just was trying to do
the best thing for Christine
and you and Jude,
you weren't into it,
- so I let it go.
- You know it's okay to talk
about things other than
patients and medicine.
We can talk about our lives.
Not a sign of weakness.
You get that, right?
Okay, okay.
Go ahead.
Fire away.
Tell me about your mom.
- Nic.
- Mom or Dad, you pick,
because, honestly,
after all this time,
I still don't know much
about either of them.
My parents split. My
dad kept me from my mom
and then she passed
away. You know that.
Dad, well...
I hate him.
You would, too.
Why?
Because he's the last guy
anyone would want as a
father in every conceivable...
But why?
You know I'm not a kid.
I don't need you to hold my hand
and talk me through
all my feelings
about all the bad stuff, okay?
Not everyone needs that.
Okay.
How you doing today, Lily?
Awful.
I feel like a girl trapped
in an old woman's body.
Have you ever thought
about getting a second opinion?
You know, Dr. Hunter
caught my cancer
when other doctors missed it.
She's the only
person that I trust.
Nic, I need your help
smoothing things over with York.
I think he blames me for
needing surgery, which is insane.
I mean, am I the one who
put a syrup bottle up
his butt? No, I'm not.
I just...
Nic, is everything okay?
Nurse Nevin, a word.
- I'll leave you guys to it.
- Uh, no, stay.
This concerns you, too.
Christine, abdominal
aortic aneurysm,
specifically requested
Dr. Jude Silva.
Apparently, he's done quite
a few of these surgeries.
But perhaps you're intimately
aware of those details.
Well, I'm aware that Dr. Silva
has an impeccable track
record with these surgeries, yes.
Come on.
Sorry.
Someone put...
it's not important.
Well, here's something
that is important:
I have an opening in my schedule
which will be filled
by York Evans.
And you, Dr. Pravesh,
will present the case to
me. It better be flawless.
So now, Bell's doing
Ed and York's surgeries.
So everything is not okay.
- Ooh...
- Mr. Evans, please meet Dr. Bell.
As distinguished
in person as in print.
A pleasure to finally
meet you, Dr. Bell.
Well, thank you. I'll be running
your procedure
today, but, uh, first...
Dr. Pravesh will
review the facts for us.
The CT scan confirms
that the foreign body
is approximately
four centimeters
above the rectosigmoid junction,
uh, with surrounding free air,
and has damaged the intestine.
And run us through
the particulars
of how this occurred.
Bu...
Well, well, he...
Put the thing...
He left it in there.
Thank you, Dr. Pravesh.
I'll get it out.
I know you will.
Okay.
Yeah, that would be great.
Her teacher is Mrs. Ashford.
No, I already cleared
it with the school.
That won't be a problem.
Oh... Jenna will be
happy to see you.
I'll just, I'll just come get
her when I leave here.
Thanks, Maggie.
Is Jenna your sister?
Yeah.
You're a good brother.
And you?
What do you need?
"An aortic aneurysm
repair can be complicated
"by a leak and
cause life-threatening
internal bleeding."
I need that not to
happen with my mom.
She's in good hands.
You made sure of that.
If there's a mistake
during surgery,
if the aneurysm
ruptures, will she die?
I'm not gonna
lie to you, Trevor.
With surgery,
there's always a risk.
But no matter what, I
want you to remember
that you're stronger
than you think, okay?
Thank you.
So once timeout has concluded
and surgery begins in
OR One, you'll take over,
- and I'll return to Two.
- Great.
Sorry, Bradley, am I boring you?
No, of course not.
I was just wondering
what the plan is
in the event of complications.
Well, I'll be there to ensure
everything goes smoothly.
You okay, Dr. Bell?
Yeah, I'm fine.
Wake up.
Yes, sir.
"Some might acquire
fancy Ivy League degrees,
"but if they don't have
the inherent instincts,
they may not be cut out
for a life in medicine..."
Dude, stop sending
me these pictures.
What's... what is that?
Someone got his
first York review.
Even Mina got four stars.
"Inept? Unfocused?"
Seriously, York?
"Not to mention
easily distracted."
"Is it the collective attention
deficit of a generation,
or is it one Harvard
grad who..."
I will confess. I was nervous.
It was the first time that...
That you had extracted
an object from the
colon of an adult male?
Yes.
Yes, York.
- That.
- Well...
Next time, I hope
you'll be more careful,
conversational and considerate.
Does there really
have to be a next time?
I'm hearing whispers
that York is unhappy
with your performance.
The one patient
that loves everyone
else hates me.
A lot of this review is
nonsense. I'm having it removed.
It's a stupid review.
If you're looking for
approval, you chose
the wrong path
in life. Do your job,
you do it well, and that's it.
Uh, what's going on?
Lily is my patient.
Not anymore.
I think we should talk.
I'm gonna make this short
and just as sweet as you.
Turns out, I don't
have an appetite
for a nurse snooping
around my clinics,
harassing my personnel,
questioning my methods,
making my vulnerable
patients paranoid.
I think that's a little extreme.
I didn't ask what you thought.
As of this moment,
you are no longer
going to be assigned
to any of my patients.
And if you don't
watch how you tread,
you won't be anyone's nurse.
And that's not a warning.
It's not a threat.
It's a promise.
- Hello, Zoe.
- Hi.
- You look beautiful today.
- Well, thanks.
Edward Brooks.
Date of birth, 8/13/82.
- Agree.
- Attending, Dr. Randolph Bell.
- Yes.
- Here for a left orchiectomy.
No known allergies.
- Everyone agree?
- Correct.
Timeout has concluded.
Dr. Okafor, you may proceed.
Change this damn music.
♪ True, true, all her
friends with it, true, true ♪
You pick this because I'm black?
Picked it because it's awesome.
♪ ...boys do it, true,
true, got 'em saying... ♪
Good work, Bradley.
Thank you, sir.
Hold that steady.
There you go.
♪ ♪
Love the choice of
music, by the way.
Very soothing.
Well, thank you.
I want you to know,
I never just randomly
select residents
for my surgeries.
They're handpicked.
I have a specific
criteria for...
Oh, son of a bitch!
- Oh, my God.
- Sharon, get Dr. Okafor.
- Yes, Doctor.
- Just keep 'em coming... more lap.
Get some suction in
there, for crying out loud.
Can't see a damn thing.
Where the hell's Mina?!
♪ For my money and riches,
she opened up the door... ♪
Bradley's passed
out. York's crashing.
Bell needs you.
His vitals are stable. Go.
- He hit the...
- Left colic.
Yeah.
Switch out.
Grab that suction.
So the pool's a little
lower. Go a little lower.
There you go.
That's good.
Glad she's feeling
better so soon.
Yeah, her grandma's a tough one.
A lot tougher than me.
- There you go... yeah, thank you.
- Mm-hmm.
Okay. Take it away, Cheryl.
Gus Spinelli.
10/28/1965.
- Agree.
- Surgeon Jude Silva.
Agree.
More laps.
Suction.
2-0 silk tie. Now.
Ed's blood pressure
is running low.
I'm not sure how much
more anesthesia he can take.
There's a junior resident
on his way to assist.
This bleeding's under control.
Get back to the testicle.
And check in when you're done.
Bradley's okay.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
- Dr. Bell!
- Just get him out of here!
- I am so... I am so sorry!
- Out!
Out!
What's happening to her?
Trevor, I'm gonna need you
to stay here, sweetie, okay?
- No! What's happening?
- Listen to me. I'm gonna be
- right back. They're gonna take care of your mom.
- No.
Adrian, will you look after
Trevor? I'll be right back.
- Nic!
- I promise.
Where are you taking her?! Nic!
Ma!
- Talk to me.
- Her pressure tanked.
Didn't respond to fluids.
She went unconscious when
her systolic dropped below 80.
Her aneurysm burst. She's
bleeding into her abdomen.
- Is Jude out of surgery?
- No. Complications.
He's not available.
So plan B: Mina.
Scalpel.
They're bringing
Christine into OR Three.
- Now?
- Aneurysm burst.
Go with Dr. Bell. Go.
Go, go!
- Christine's crashing here in OR Three.
- You're kidding.
- I don't do that.
- Well, go!
Start getting control,
and page Jude, stat!
Um... there we go.
I've got control of the
bleeding until we can repair it.
Watch this, and if
hemorrhaging resumes,
call overhead.
- Status?
- His pressure's low.
I'm worried there's
a bleed we can't see.
Okay, I think I can see it.
Status of the aortic aneurysm?
She's stable. Waiting on Jude.
- Where the hell is he?
- Still in surgery.
Shall I extubate Ed?
- Is he stable?
- Yes.
Well, he's not priority.
Put more quarters
in the gas machine.
Have them put a Foley in.
Then get back
there with Christine.
Okay, that's tight.
What about the colon?
I need about 30 minutes to
make headway with Christine.
Place a Foley for Ed,
and re-prep in about 20.
Once Bell or Jude comes in,
I'll scrub out and finish here.
♪ ♪
Christine's bleeding again.
Systolic is dropping.
I need Bell.
Mina needs Bell...
Christine's systolic is dropping.
York's colon perforation's
not under control.
- Bell can't leave.
- There's no time to wait for Jude.
You know what to
do. Prep for a graft.
Dr. Okafor?
You've got this.
♪ ♪
Gus Spinelli, time
of death: 4:23 p.m.
Has Ed been re-prepped?
Yes, right after
the Foley went in.
- Should we do another timeout?
- No.
He's been under too long.
Let's get this over with.
15 blade.
♪ ♪
Christine's pressure dropped,
and we can't get it back up,
even with the blood transfusion.
♪ ♪
I don't think I'd mind it so
much. You know what I mean?
Hey.
You know? I don't think
I'll ever be hungry
for pancakes again.
Until I, um...
♪ ♪
Hey. -Hey.
A patient in his early 30s
scheduled for a routine surgery,
the removal of an
atrophied testicle,
only to have the
healthy one excised.
♪ ♪
How do we explain this?
- I should have double-checked...
- No.
It was my responsibility.
I asked Nurse Moore
to re-prep the surgical field.
When she sanitized
the surgical area...
the incision mark
was removed.
When I returned to OR One,
Nurse Moore asked if we
should do another timeout.
I...
said no.
He'd been under too long.
Dr. Bell, you were the architect
- of these concurrent surgeries, correct?
- Tell me, Stacy...
It's Dr. Leonard.
You like Mozart?
I'm sorry, what?
Mozart. Are you a fan?
- It's okay if you're not.
- I think we're all very aware
- of just how serious this...
- The legendary composer
was unrefined, undisciplined
until along came Joseph Haydn.
And Haydn challenged Mozart,
whom he knew to
possess a brilliant mind.
He pushed him to
the brink of madness
before pulling him back,
masterfully guiding
his young protégé to greatness.
I do the same thing...
in the name of saving lives.
Why?
Because it's my duty to train
the next generation
of elite surgeons.
And on this day,
the one in question,
I pushed Dr. Okafor to
exceed my expectations.
And, sadly, on this day,
she simply wasn't ready.
Complications are something
we all try strenuously to foresee,
but on those rare days
when Murphy's Law brings
its full weight to bear,
tragedies do occur.
This series of events
simply could not
have been predicted.
I guarantee you Chastain
will do the right thing.
You always do the
right thing, Dr. Bell.
Grace, Ed.
We just want to be left alone.
Of course.
I...
I want to say to both of you...
that there was no excuse...
for the mistake we made.
I...
I'm simply here
to say I'm sorry.
♪ ♪
So?
I offered my
sincerest apologies.
And how was it received?
I recall you saying
that families settle
for 45 to 55% less
after a formal apology is made.
Give or take.
Well, I'm confident
we'll be at the higher end
of those estimates.
The M and M conference...
I heard it was pretty tense.
Yeah.
When a doctor
questions the practices
of this hospital
and its physicians
to the extent that
Dr. Leonard is doing...
it has a detrimental effect.
Wouldn't you agree?
Consider it handled.
And Dr. Okafor?
One of the most
gifted surgical residents
I've ever seen.
She is invaluable.
Onward.
It's a multistep process.
Yeah, just unsubscribe me.
But you're still in
your free trial period.
I'm gonna block
you from my phone.
I'll circumnavigate.
Mina.
Sorry about Bell.
Dick move.
First question...
You only get one.
Where are you going?
To unwind.
Does Devon get a question?
Uh, will you ask her if
she's going to unwind alone?
With a boyfriend? Just a
friend? Does she have friends?
Good night.
Mina.
You look absolutely stunning.
♪ ♪
♪ Your eyes, they
did flutter again ♪
♪ And my mouth,
it did hang wide ♪
♪ When you told me
every little thing's ♪
- ♪ Gonna be all right... ♪
- Hey. -Hey.
Look, my apologies
for not coming through.
Gus had a, uh, bleeding
disorder we didn't know about.
I know.
You know, it's strange.
They give us all this training
on how to do our job,
and do it well...
but nothing...
on how to cope with
the loss of a patient.
And it never gets easier.
♪ All that I, all that I want ♪
♪ 'Cause you're all
that I, all that I want ♪
♪ ♪
♪ While I beat
your cold windows ♪
♪ Break the locks on the gate ♪
♪ While I try to forget ♪
♪ I used to be something great ♪
What are you doing here?
I came to see you.
You look good, son.
♪ 'Cause you're all
that I, all that I want. ♪
Captioned by Media
Access Group at WGBH