Good explosion!
Drive it, drive it, drive it!
You watching 77?
I'm watching everybody.
You don't need to watch
everybody, you need to watch 77.
You his agent?
Just an objective mom.
His explosion is impressive.
It's not just burst,
he can pull, too.
You know, the only reason
he went to a double A school,
he was a bit of a late bloomer,
but he's a big man now.
You should be his agent.
Nice pancake, Seven Seven.
You're moving up
those draft boards.
Thank you, sir.
01, 01, ready? PLAYERS: Break!
Set!
Blue 90. Hike.
Good job! Second level, nice!
Get off my quarterback!
Play's over! The play is over!
Save the aggression
for between the whistles!
Daryl!
All right, back to work!
Daryl, stop!
What are you doing?
Canoeing, but I seem
to be taking on water.
This is not okay. Use
your own bathroom.
No canoe in my bathroom.
My leg hurts, soaking
makes it feel better.
You were the one who
had to have this condo.
Maybe next time you
should consider amenities,
like two full baths, instead of
just the joy of outbidding Cuddy.
The guy who signs the loan
gets to pick the bedrooms.
Stay out of mine.
Well, then you owe me 35 bucks
for the grab rail I installed.
Hit the kill screen,
boss is here.
It's not porn, it's
our new patient.
Bummer.
Twenty-two-year-old
male, 6'7", 310 pounds.
Clearly has brain involvement.
The guy has no recollection
of this entire incident.
Football player.
Those are the ones that
get hit in the head a lot, right?
ER CTed him.
No concussion, no stroke,
no cortical degeneration.
And he had a full psych
evaluation. He's not crazy.
So it's roid rage.
You don't think they grow
them that big naturally?
ER also tested for
steroids, he's clean.
Only proving that our guy
got his hands on the good stuff.
The negative test at least
means steroids is less likely.
We should discuss
other possibilities.
Why?
He injects his sore ankles
with lidocaine every game,
you think he's above
injecting steroids?
Repeated head trauma could
damage the base of the brain,
leading to a pituitary
adenoma, which leaks GnRH.
Pituitary damage wouldn't
be visible on a CT scan.
Could cause the excess
hormones that could cause the rage
and would elude
the ER's steroid test.
Fine. Bilateral venous sampling
to find the elevated GnRH,
MRI to find the
pituitary damage.
Unless, of course, there
is no pituitary damage,
in which case, our guy got
his hands on the good stuff.
Foreman. Let the peasants
handle the peasantry.
Your brother needs to get
picked up this afternoon.
From prison.
Your older brother, in case
your confusion is related...
How do you know about that?
He left a message.
He said he couldn't get
you on your cell or at home.
I get it, you're busy,
you'll pick him up
the next time he
comes out of prison.
Is that all?
You're officially
unbusy. Family is family.
Take the rest of the
day, go see your brother.
I have work to do.
Do you feel any pain
that's deep and persistent?
Not just muscles or joints.
Everything hurts all
the time. That's football.
It might not be just football.
We're going to test for
damage to your pituitary.
If there is, it could
create excess hormones,
which could be
causing your pain.
It would also explain
your rage attack.
And if my pituitary is damaged,
how long would it take to treat?
I don't want to get
ahead of ourselves
and start promising deadlines.
I'm sorry, Doctor,
but he's playing in
front of pro scouts,
coaches and GMs this Saturday.
This is the job interview
for the rest of his life.
If we do find something wrong,
we can go in through the nose
and repair the damage,
nothing too invasive.
You'll need a couple
of days of recovery,
and then we can have
you back by game time.
Thank you, Doctor.
There's nothing
wrong with your eyes.
Well, then, your gizmo's
broken. I'm seeing spots.
Or you enlisted, you got the cool
haircut and the awesome pants,
then you realized
that your plane ticket
to the Middle East was coach,
and you decided to
rethink your promise.
No. I've already been there.
Three deployments. Now
they want me to go again.
But my wife's pregnant.
So our Homeland should be unsafe
because your Private was unsafe?
Look, my wife and I
planned this perfect.
My enlistment was
supposed to be over last week,
so we got pregnant
six months ago.
Now they tell me I'm
getting stop-lossed.
Army speak for they don't care
about the fact that I've
finished my contract.
I don't care about the
fact that they don't care.
Hey, come on, I waited an extra
hour just to make sure I got you.
Why?
I saw you limping out there.
Vietnam?
Viet...
How old do you think I am?
I don't know. Vietnam age?
Well, back in my day
the real dodgers had the
stones to run off to Canada
or shoot themselves in the foot.
They didn't come to free
clinics whining for doctors' notes.
Go hug your wife, tell
her to get a babysitter,
and you'll be back in time
to video the kid's first steps.
Yeah, I don't need
to see the scan.
I can tell from your little puppy
dog eyes that his pituitary's fine.
Are you gonna
say it, or should I?
You were right
about the steroids.
You're a genius.
Next time, with feeling.
Put the cheater on a
somatostatin analogue
to clear it out of his system,
send him back to
his football game.
I've never done steroids.
Well, somehow your
GnRH got elevated.
This will help get it back down.
Mom, I swear!
Who's gonna draft you, Daryl?
You're stupid
enough to try that stuff,
especially the week you
know you're getting tested?
You guys must have
mixed up your labs
or got somebody else's blood,
because I never...
Okay, what is that?
Tachycardia. Lay
back down, Daryl.
Why's my heart
beating like this?
It's not steroids.
I need some adenosine, and
get that crash cart over here.
House, next time...
Marcus.
Oh, right. You two
know each other.
What are you doing here?
Interviewing.
Oh.
Who are we kidding?
Interview's over, you got the job.
What job?
My new assistant.
Part of his parole,
he needs a job.
Just trying to do my part.
You were wrong
about the steroids.
Patient had a
paroxysmal tachycardia.
We cardioverted him
back to sinus rhythm.
We're going to get a
EKG and a sestamibi scan.
Marcus, let's talk outside.
Family is family.
Hey, good to see you, too.
Did you have a hard stretch?
Not bad, I hardly
got raped at all.
You can't work here.
But your boss says I can.
I'm not playing.
Lighten up. I mean,
this could be fun.
I get to see your world. You
get me access to the pharmacy.
I am playing. Come
on, man. You look good.
I'd already know that, if you
came to visit every once in a while,
but whatever,
I get it. It's cool.
You don't wanna see me,
you don't wanna pick me up.
It's all justified.
I'll just have to
win you back over.
Let me explain something. This
man who's offering you the job?
He's not a philanthropist.
He seems more helpful than you.
He doesn't want to help you,
he only wants to use
you to screw with me.
You know how you
can screw with him?
Act like your brother getting
a job doesn't screw with you.
Trust me, it'll be better for
both of us if you go back in there
and tell him you
can't take the job.
I'm not a person who has
the luxury of turning down jobs.
Well, figure something out
because you cannot work here.
House!
Okay...
We spent all night, used
all the fancy machines.
Patient's heart looks fine.
Well, if it was fine,
it wouldn't go aflutter
just because you
walked into the room.
Light whip, two extra shots.
Thank you, sir.
Judging by the
look on your face,
I assume you're
upset that big bro
didn't take your
advice and skip town.
You told him about
our conversation?
He bought me breakfast.
It was fun. Put lunch in
the books, just you and me.
Our patient could have a PFO.
Well, naturally you jump
right to a urinary issue.
PFO's not urinary,
it's a heart issue.
It is? Oh.
Well, naturally you think
it's not a urinary issue
because you're so embarrassed
about your own
past urinary issues,
you don't dare
broach the subject.
Oh, come on.
You spending the night
over at Bobby Samson's?
I did not wet the
bed, I spilled a drink.
We're not buying it,
Eric. We never bought it.
Why are you telling
him these things?
What's the big deal?
It was 25 years ago.
Oxygenated and
de-oxygenated blood mix,
the rough flow causes a clot,
explains the heart and head.
Like that power forward from
Loyola Marymount when he...
Hank Gathers? That's
not what happened to him.
Whoa, let your brother speak.
What happened to Hank Gathers?
Conference tournament.
Alley-oop dunk, jams it home,
then he runs up
the court and splat.
He dropped dead of a heart
thing right there on the court.
I remember that. On
autopsy they found
he had a hypertrophic
cardiomyopathy.
Rage and tachycardia
are warning signs.
Seriously?
Because my brother
remembers a basketball game?
Hey, I don't care where
an idea comes from,
as long as it makes sense
and embarrasses someone.
Are you out of your mind?
As a former psychiatric patient,
I take offense at
that terminology.
All I did was ban
you from my tub.
Whatever happened to
proportional response?
coherent conversation?
That thing broke tiles, gashed
the walls, and pooped everywhere.
Expect a bill for
repairs. And payback.
What was that?
I have no idea.
Everybody else thinks hypertrophic
cardiomyopathy makes sense?
Good, stick the
patient on a treadmill.
Stress his heart until it stops.
You want to induce
cardiac arrest?
The only real treatment is for the
patient never to stress his heart again,
which means we have to tell him
to retire at the ripe old age of 21.
Stopping his heart speaks
louder than words. Go.
Maybe it's a good thing. He gave
your brother a job, responsibility.
I'm not arguing that
he shouldn't have a job,
I just don't want
him having one here.
I understand that House
did this to annoy you,
but why is he succeeding?
You know what my brother did
the last time he
got out of prison?
He stole money from
my parents to buy drugs.
He robbed a liquor store, then he
moved on to jacking luxury cars...
Last time.
Every time.
I've known my brother
for over 30 years.
You haven't even
known him a day.
I'm sorry.
The exterminator charged 250
to get the opossum out of there,
and the contractor estimates
1,500 to fix the bathroom.
And why are you
jerking Foreman around?
Because it's fun.
Maybe you should give
those bills to the guy
who left his own
bathroom window open.
Your motives always run
deeper than simple fun.
I want to learn more
about one of my employees
so that I can manipulate him
and destroy him if and when I
choose. Information is power.
Not buying it.
Okay.
Why don't you tell
me my real evil plan?
I don't think there
is an evil plan.
You regret not having a
relationship with your own family,
and you don't want to see
Foreman go down that same path.
I think you're
actually being nice.
Oh, shut up.
You can't accuse me
of an opossum attack
and underhanded
kindness in the same visit.
Then I'll come back.
Treadmill test was a bust.
The guy's in unbelievable shape,
we couldn't get his
heart rate above 150.
Your boss is secretly
a very nice man.
I know.
If we can't recreate
the cardiac event,
we can't prove
hypertrophic cardiomyopathy.
Either we find a
bigger treadmill, or...
Did I miss the memo
about you being released?
I'm feeling fine. I
can't keep laying here
in this bed, missing practices.
All excellent points.
Give me your arm.
What's in the shot?
It's a vasodilator.
Since we can't exercise your
son's heart on the treadmill,
we're gonna have
to do it chemically.
What's wrong?
You're turning white.
What does that mean?
It means he doesn't need
football to get a good job anymore.
Raynaud's Phenomenon.
Vasospasms cut off the
blood supply to his fingers,
could be early onset
rheumatoid arthritis.
His rheumatoid
factor is negative.
Arterial plaque throwing clots
would explain the
fingers, head, heart.
You really think a
guy with stenosis
could've aced
that treadmill test?
You're kidding me.
You got him a desk?
And a nameplate. Man's got to
have a place he can call his own.
What about Takayasu's arteritis?
Lymphoma's a better fit.
We should remove his spleen.
Bold move to skip
straight to surgery.
His big game's coming up,
we don't have time to biopsy,
wait for the pathology
report, and resect.
Right. We should remove
his spleen without confirmation
so he won't miss the big game.
Hang an ethanol drip.
That won't treat for either
lymphoma or Takayasu's.
If it's lymphoma, the
ethanol will make him itchy,
and Foreman can
remove his spleen.
If it's Takayasu's, he'll
lose his radial pulse,
and Chase can
start him on steroids.
Marcus!
What are you doing here?
My new assignment is to
shadow you into enemy territory
and document your
every word to the patient.
Just don't say anything stupid.
You're not an
idiot. Don't do this.
Come on, man. I'm
a new person now.
No more drugs, no more lying.
And if I can't get my own family
to give me an
opportunity to prove that,
then what's the point?
Mom and Dad gave you a chance.
And a second. And a third.
I'm not about to
give you a 54th.
Why isn't your minion
fetching your lunch?
He's busy spying
on his little brother.
What?
That's very demeaning.
You obviously have a theory as to
why demeaning is not demeaning.
You're escalating to prove I
was wrong about you being nice.
Which you would
only do if I was right.
Do you even listen to yourself?
Twenty-three-year-old just
came in to the ER, asked for you.
What's her cup size?
I don't think his cup size
is relevant to his condition.
He accidentally shot
himself in the foot.
Oh, for...
Seriously?
I give you a choice
between moving to Canada
and shooting
yourself in the foot,
and you choose the bullet?
I didn't want to be a fugitive.
You think this is gonna
get you discharged?
We'll patch it up and
send you right back.
Well, don't patch it up.
Look, you got screwed over
by your own government
and that sucks.
But all you're going
to get out of this
is a five-day vacation
and a band-aid.
When I signed
up, I was just a guy.
Now I'm about to be a dad.
I go back over, there's a chance
my kid grows up
without a father.
You got a girl pregnant.
You're still just a guy.
How much longer we have to wait?
We have to keep going until
you start feeling something.
Might help if you told me
what I'm supposed to feel.
I do that, that's all
you'll be thinking about.
Then you'll be telling me
that's what you're feeling.
Power of suggestion.
The other black dude who was
in here earlier, he your brother?
What gave it away?
The way you looked at him.
I have two older brothers, and
we always want to kill each other.
Something wrong?
Not really. Just feels itchy.
Is that what you
were waiting for?
Means lymphoma's most likely.
But that's actually good news.
How can that be good news?
Because it's treatable,
we can remove your spleen
tonight laparoscopically.
Will I be up and
around by Saturday?
We can get to the
radiation in the off-season.
Hey, Ma. Wake up.
Ma, wake up. I'm itchy.
Means I can play.
What are you doing in the dark?
Lying in wait.
Jeez, what happened
to your face?
Right, play innocent.
Like you weren't
looking for revenge
for the prank
that I didn't pull.
It's karmic justice,
but I didn't do it.
Of course you
realize, this means war.
Isolating the
gastroepiploic artery.
Nearly there.
Foreman, come and
take a look at this.
Liver's inflamed.
So the itching wasn't
caused by his spleen.
It's not lymphoma.
What happened to your face?
Wilson annexed the Sudetenland.
No abnormal T-cells or B-cells,
it's definitely not lymphoma.
Liver biopsy only revealed
non-specific inflammation.
Kind of like the time
you took your mom's
birth control pills on a dare
and ended up with
swollen nipples.
That never happened. Right.
And your nickname all the way
up through high school wasn't Erica.
It wasn't.
Okay, I may have
made that one up.
With the understanding that my
brother still had his sense of humor
and would figure
out to play along.
Polymyositis would
explain the head,
liver, heart, even
the white fingers.
Would also be accompanied by a
significant decrease in muscle power.
Marcus, chance
to redeem yourself.
Does our patient
look strong to you?
Sorry, Eric. Big brother
disagrees with your diagnosis.
Felty syndrome?
You said the liver was
inflamed, not the spleen.
Can you believe they let
this guy perform surgery?
What are you doing?
Requesting permission
to share my idea
without being belittled in
front of your new assistant.
Permission denied. Continue.
Our patient has cartilage
damage in both ankles,
he gets lidocaine shots before
every game to mask the pain.
Team doctor uses the same
needle twice by accident?
Viral hepatitis.
Do you think he's
an idiot, Marcus?
I don't think he's an idiot.
Okay. Go test his blood.
Come on. We have
a lunch scheduled.
So you jerked me around.
Your allegiance lies with
your brother. I get it. Admirable.
But here's the problem. I
hired you to tell me the truth.
If you don't do that,
you no longer have a job.
I don't know what secret
you're looking to uncover,
but my brother is a decent guy.
He was arrested
for grand theft auto.
You're gonna be disappointed.
Try me.
He tell you I was with him?
Was it your idea?
We did everything together,
I don't know whose idea it was.
I was 16, he was only 14.
Little punk couldn't even
see over the steering wheel,
but he was quicker with
a flathead screwdriver
than most people with a key.
Sorry to interrupt my character
assassination with boring medical stuff,
but when we drew
the patient's blood
it clotted right there
in the vacutainer.
So the problem is not in
his blood, it's the blood itself.
He's been working out in
the cold, doing two-a-days,
it's got to be cryoglobulinemia.
I usually love breaking
bad news, but in this case...
Start the patient on warfarin.
I am so sorry about
that. You were saying?
We drove for about 10 minutes
before we got
caught and that was it.
When mom came
down to the station,
she didn't say a word
the whole ride home.
She came to the
driveway, turned off the car.
We're sitting in
there in silence.
And then, without
turning around,
she said, "I'll pray for you."
Then she got out of the car.
Wow. You got off easy.
Easy for you, easy for
me. Not easy for Eric.
His life mission became to never
disappoint our mother like that again.
Because he is a good guy.
Thought he would tell
that story at the eulogy,
but I heard he didn't give one.
Your mother's dead?
If he didn't tell you, I'm
sure he had a reason.
Look, you can mock him all
you want about peeing the bed,
but please don't
bring up our mother.
Your blood contains an abnormally
high volume of certain proteins,
called cryoglobulins.
They become thick
when it gets cold outside.
It's like a car trying to run
after the oil's turned to sludge.
We think that's what's been
causing all your problems.
So I just need a quick oil
change and I'm good to go.
This oil change isn't so quick.
We have to put you on blood
thinners and other medications.
The process will take
two to three weeks,
but after that, you should be
able to play without a problem.
After that, it's
not gonna matter.
Doctor, if Daryl doesn't
play in front of the scouts
on Saturday, he
won't get drafted.
Can't you wait
until after the game?
If we wait and let him play,
there's a good chance
he dies right on the field.
I had an epiphany.
Usually that precedes you
walking away with purpose, so...
Flathead screwdriver.
And then I say...
It's not a game, it's proof
that you didn't rig the
grab rail and make me fall.
I already have proof of that.
The fact that I didn't do it.
I can't go on that.
But I can go on the fact
that I had to borrow a
flathead screwdriver from Nora
to install the thing because
we only had a Phillips head.
Then, of course, I
returned it late that night
in a completely successful
effort to see her braless.
Whoa! Wait. Wait a
minute. Wait a minute.
Which means that you didn't have
the tool to sabotage the grab rail.
Braless? Under, like,
a sweater? Or, like, a...
Now I also have proof that I'm
not responsible for the opossum
because I'm absolving you of
responsibility instead of escalating,
which you know
is not in my nature.
So someone is breaking into
our place just to screw with us?
The opossum was meant for me.
I'm so tired. It was exciting
until about 2:00 a.m.
Now it's just torture.
Did you even go to college?
This is the
escalation, isn't it?
Keeping me up all night.
Nothing happens, then you keep
me up all night again tomorrow.
This is your retaliation.
You see, that's just illogical,
'cause I'm staying up, too.
Maybe you napped all day.
I gave you empirical proof
that I did not prank you.
No. No, you did not. You
created empirical proof
that I didn't prank you,
selling me on the notion
that you didn't prank me.
Maybe you self-pranked.
I don't masterprank.
Is that cut on your
cheek even real?
See? This is exactly what our
nemesis wants. Divide and conquer.
Can't you see that?
Okay. I'm going to bed.
I'm telling you,
if we sleep now,
we're going to wake up
next to severed horse heads.
Or worse, the rest of it.
Oh!
House!
The flatscreen!
You would never
sacrifice the flatscreen.
Oh, this guy's good.
Is there a reason for this?
There is a reason for
everything, mes amis.
I am troubled to report that
we have a criminal in our midst.
Guilty of what, exactly?
Last night the fire sprinklers
flooded our apartment.
And before that, I found
an opossum in my bathtub.
You each had motive,
you each had opportunity.
This is the emergency
you paged me about?
Not so fast, Mademoiselle Cuddy.
No one leaves here
until they can account
for their whereabouts
the evening last.
Bye.
Okay. No one who
is employed by me
leaves here until they account
for their whereabouts
the evening last.
What about you, Professor Chase?
Why would I?
Because you hold me responsible
for breaking up your marriage.
I was here all
night with Thirteen
monitoring our patient's
IV blood thinners.
Can either of you prove that?
The patient's alive
and improving.
Is that proof enough?
For now.
What about you, Colonel Taub?
I was out to
dinner with my wife.
Really? Your wife?
Yes, really.
Good enough. 'Cause I
had you pegged all along.
You certainly had all
the motive in the world.
First of all, I'm
not interested.
Second, I don't even
know where you guys live.
Yesterday, I confirmed
that you are a liar.
What are you talking about?
Well, at least a
liar by omission.
House!
Don't.
Get this, class.
Foreman's mom died.
He ever tell any of you?
House, I think you're
getting off topic here.
Is he serious? Did
your mom pass away?
About three months ago.
I'm so sorry.
Why didn't you tell anybody?
And to top it off,
he refused to say anything
nice about her at the funeral.
I didn't talk because it
isn't anyone's business.
Stop. You don't have to
explain yourself to this guy.
You want to hit me, don't you?
Marcus, don't.
I quit.
You should stop
him. He needs this job.
Our patient needs a fresh IV.
I don't need two to three weeks.
See? Got my color back.
It means you're getting
better, but it doesn't...
Means I am better. My coach
had the team doctor come by.
He cleared me to play.
Did your team doctor realize
you're on blood thinners?
I'm off them now.
You're still sick.
You're not ready
to go off your meds.
Daryl, listen to him. It
is not worth the risk...
I'll come back on Sunday, Mom.
You guys can give me
all the meds I need then.
The treatment
doesn't work that way.
Please, go with him.
The antibiotics aren't working.
We're going to switch
you to different ones,
but you're going
to lose your toe.
Outstanding, soldier!
As a general rule, before you
celebrate, do a little research.
The Army's Medical
Evaluation Board
is perfectly fine with
nine-toed infantrymen,
as long as they
can walk and run.
So I lost a toe for nothing?
Afraid so.
Unless you want me to
keep you on the old antibiotics.
We can let the infection spread,
then we can amputate
more than just a toe.
Why are you risking
your life for this?
Your mom doesn't want you to.
My mom sacrificed
everything for me.
Her telling me not to come here
is just another example of that.
I do good out there,
I could take care of her
for the rest of her life.
Who am I if I don't sacrifice
for her? That's family.
You okay?
Everything's blurry.
I can't see.
Take me back to the hospital.
The blindness means
we were wrong about...
Actually, I'm
responsible for that.
I spiked his water bottle with
nitrates. Dropped his blood pressure,
robbed oxygen rich blood
from his brain, making him blind.
I figured a temporarily
blind patient
is better than a
permanently dead one.
His vision was
already coming back
by the time I dropped
him off at the hospital.
Well played. If only we could
combine your medical chicanery
with your brother's
ability to fetch me mochas,
you'd be the perfect Foreman.
Where are you?
I'm busy.
Great, so we don't
have a new symptom.
Means we should just stick
him back on his blood thinners,
and he should be okay
to leave in a couple weeks.
Actually, we do
have a new symptom.
Any of you take a look
at his readmittance chart?
Between the time he checked in
and the time he re-checked in,
our patient lost a single pound.
Patient like that would
usually shed over 10 pounds.
The obvious answer
would be steroids,
but since we've
already ruled them out...
So he's not injecting, but he
could be getting them naturally.
Paraneoplastic syndrome,
the body produces
antibodies which battle cancer,
which could also act
like growth hormone.
We've eliminated lymphoma. What
other cancers mimic growth hormone?
Lung, pancreatic,
renal, breast...
It was a rhetorical
question, I don't really care.
Go test him for all of them.
What are you doing here?
You need a job.
Maybe I can talk to House,
see if I can get your job back.
As soon as he knows you're
okay with me being there,
he won't want me back.
Maybe I can help you
figure out something else.
I promise I won't let you down.
Don't do that.
Let's just see how it goes.
So do they mandate you to
stay here at the halfway house,
or can you come
stay with family?
It's Foreman.
Well, it should stop
now that Marcus left.
Well, that's the whole point.
Oh, I'm sorry. Was
my leg sticking out?
I'm so distracted lately, trying
to think of something funnier
than fire sprinklers going off
in the middle of the
night. Any ideas?
Whoa. Easy there, tiger. I know
where you live. You know how I know?
'Cause my girlfriend and I,
we tried to buy that
very same condo.
Why don't you
leave me out of this?
Wilson was the one
who bought the place.
And you're living there.
You deserve to suffer equally.
Actually, I've suffered more
now that you just tripped me.
Hey, hey. I'm...
His suffering will equal out
because he actually feels remorse.
Why would you out yourself?
You can't even
imagine the retribution.
There won't be any. I'm
ceasing all offensive operations.
I've both made my point and
established my superiority.
And if you even get to the
planning stages of retaliation,
I will tell Cuddy that she lost
her dream place to you two.
See, she's under
this odd impression
that you guys are her friends.
There's no cancer.
We scanned him head to toe,
we checked blood
smears for leukemia,
we even ultrasounded his
chest looking for breast cancer.
Maybe I was wrong
about the weight loss.
You weren't wrong. We
found blood in his catheter bag.
His kidneys are failing.
So it has to be cancer.
Paraneoplastic
syndrome is the only thing
that can link kidney,
heart and liver,
even the rage.
Then why can't we find it?
We've looked
everywhere inside this guy.
What if it's not inside?
You know why you're black?
'Cause God loves me
more than he loves you.
Hmm. What I was going for
was melanin. You got lots of it.
Makes your skin dark,
protects you from the
sun's harmful UV rays.
What are you doing?
Unfortunately, it also prevents
even those with
advanced medical degrees
from considering melanoma
as a diagnosis. Other hand.
On the rare occasion that
black people do get skin cancer,
they usually get it
on their white parts,
like the palms and
soles of the feet.
But your hands and feet are
so smashed up from football
that my team would
likely have written off
any skin blemish as a bruise.
But now that I know that
melanoma is the only thing that fits...
Come take a look at this, Mom.
There's the thorn in the panther's
paw. Paraneoplastic syndrome.
Your body forms
antibodies to fight the tumor.
Those tiny little proteins travel
through your blood and wreak havoc.
We remove the cancerous
mole, everything should be fine.
I'll tell Dr. Chase to
schedule the surgery.
Why bother? I missed my shot.
What kind of life am
I gonna lead now?
Did you study
really, really hard?
Then the same crappy life
that the rest of the guys you'll be
graduating with are going to lead,
minus the student loans.
Hey, you ready?
Almost.
And done.
I heard House and Wilson are
getting pranked by someone.
You wouldn't know anything
about that, would you?
No.
And why should I believe you?
You said I had a trusting face.
I still don't understand why you
wouldn't let me retaliate, though.
They stole your dream.
Well, that's overstating
it. It's just a condo.
It's not because you feel
guilty about hurting House?
Or guilty for being with me?
We'll buy another one.
I just don't see the need
to make a war out of it.
Well, I think
you're rationalizing,
which a less confident
man than myself
might take as a sign that
you're second guessing...
Okay. You know what?
Forget that last part.
I heard Foreman and his brother
are trying to work things out.
That's nice for them.
It's nice of you.
You didn't provoke Marcus to
quit so the pranks would stop.
You were becoming the common
enemy they could bond over.
You are the diabolical, yet
benevolent puppetmaster.
I provoked Marcus to quit because
he was no longer useful to me.
I hired him to get
information, I got information.
Uh-huh.
And how are we going
to get back at Lucas?
We're not.
I win.