Previously on ER:
- You won't tell me how you feel.
- It's fine.
See a couples therapist. Can't
do that, work separate shifts.
This is our niece, Shelley.
I just found out they were here.
We're waiting on Social
Services to come down here.
It was my father's.
I want you to have it.
It suits you.
Surveying your kingdom?
I was just wondering, what
do they do with all the dirt?
When is it supposed to open?
A year from September.
Hey, congratulations,
by the way.
Tenure.
Thank you.
What? That's not a good thing?
No, it's good.
It's great.
So you got about two weeks
left on your internship, huh?
You ready to be an R2?
Do I have a choice?
Can't believe it went so fast.
- I don't hear many interns say that.
- Hmm.
Who's Joshua?
- Family member.
- Yes, I got that from the "Carter" part.
Joshua's what Kem and I
were gonna name the baby.
It's a good thing
you're doing here, John.
If Surgery's mad some guy went
up without a central line, they scream.
GI's pissed some ulcerative
colitis went home without follow-up...
- who do they yell at?
- Me.
You got it.
You also have office hours for
the med students and Residents...
to stop by if they have
any problems or questions.
I get an office?
Well, other chiefs
haven't really used it.
Where is it?
Morris, "office hours" is
just a figure of speech.
Just make yourself
available at Admit.
You're the new head cheerleader.
Organize parties, treats for Residents
working holidays, host happy hours.
- Do I get a budget for that?
- Yeah. It's called your ATM card.
Next year's Resident contracts.
Sign them and have them in
my box by the end of the week.
Dr. Barnett, we need to
find time to talk about yours.
- So you two work together?
- Yeah. In the ER at County.
I'm a nurse.
Luka's a doctor.
Must be challenging.
Can be.
Place is an insane asylum.
How long have you been together?
About a year, on
and off. Mostly on.
Have you sought therapy before?
No.
So, what brings you to me today?
I don't think Luka and
I should be together.
Another four of MS
along with two of Versed?
Was that a statement
or a question?
- Four of MS, two of Versed!
- Want Ativan?
Oh, God! It hurts! NEELA: No.
It has too long a half-life
for pre-op assessment.
- Calm down.
- What's all the ruckus?
Mr. Lillion was checking radiator
leaks while his engine was running.
- I caught my hair in the damn belt!
- Avulsed his whole scalp.
- Okay.
- Then he tried to pull his hair...
- out of the moving fan with his hands.
- Ouch.
Open fracture of third
and fourth metacarpals.
- And extensor-tendon lacs.
- You want antibiotics?
- A gram of Ancef IV piggyback.
- Anything else?
A hundred of
gentamicin. Why gent?
Because open fractures are
susceptible to Gram-negative organisms.
Pratt. Some guy out front
says he's a friend of yours.
- What's his complaint?
- Nothing he'll tell me.
Says he knows you from high school.
- Go. I got this.
Aargh!
- Darnell.
- Greg, how are you doing?
- What's up, man?
- My boy.
- Remember K.J., right?
- Yeah.
- What's up, little man?
- Get up and say hello to Dr. Pratt.
- Where's the love at?
- Right?
- Getting big.
- Tell me about it.
- What's up?
- Somewhere we can talk?
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
- All right. Be right back.
- I'm happy.
- No, you're not.
- I'm not.
- Nobody is happy all the time.
He's like a sphinx. I never
know what he's thinking.
We talk.
We don't talk. I talk.
You sit there and smile.
Occasionally, you nod.
And then I get mad. I'm
always the one getting angry.
- I'm always the one yelling.
- You want me to get angry?
Yeah. That would be nice.
Could you break a dish or scream
at the top of your lungs? Something.
That's what I'm talking about.
What are you feeling, Luka?
Tsk.
I'm happy.
I'm happy and Sam's not.
I don't know why. We're healthy.
We enjoy each other, our work.
We have a good life.
How does that
make you feel, Sam?
Like hitting him over
the head with a hammer.
Was there a particular
event or series of events...
that led to your decision
to come here today?
Uh... Yeah. I thought
that I might be pregnant.
- And are you?
- No. Thank God.
That's a pretty
unequivocal answer.
Yeah.
It's how I feel about it.
Is that how you
feel about it, Luka?
What is that?
Hey! What the hell is that?
What's what, Billy?
That up there coming out of the
damn ceiling. It smells like crap.
- It is crap.
- Okay.
Bad enough I'm stuck in here, you
gotta let the building crap on me?
I think it's just your DTs
kicking in, Mr. Seiger.
Hey! Hey! Unless they're
passing out ponchos...
better get him back in the
ambulance and over to Mercy, pronto!
- Jake's in Philadelphia?
- Tulane.
- He was in San Francisco.
- Couple weeks ago.
Something disgusting is leaking
out of the ceiling. Call Maintenance.
That or a HAZMAT unit.
So Carter gets tenure
and Dr. Lewis doesn't?
- Yeah.
- How do you explain that?
Lewis has more
seniority. She runs ER.
Bada-bing. Show me the green.
Hey, anybody seen Carter?
He's got African love on
the overseas line again.
He took the avulsed scalp.
Sorry, Kem. Can
I take a message?
So you get tenure based on
how much money you have?
He's building a wing for the hospital.
She's pushing paper and banana bags.
Highly-qualified woman,
well-liked man. Who do you think?
Oh, put your bra back
on, Gloria Steinem.
Carter's been here 10 years.
Lewis split and then came back.
It's a level playing field
now. Haven't you heard?
Ix-nay on the Lewis-nay.
Dr. Barnett, do you
have a minute for me?
Sure.
Oooh.
- So he interested in medicine?
- No.
But he's got to do his
community-service hours somewhere.
- What did he get busted for?
- Tagging.
Had some weed on him too.
Hey, we did a lot worse,
just never got caught.
Yeah, speak for yourself.
- Heh. It ain't my fault I ran faster.
- Heh.
All right, look, on the real...
I'm just a hired hand around here.
It's not really my decision to make.
But you'll ask?
- Yeah, man.
- My man.
- I'll ask.
- My man, 50 grand.
Because I don't think
it would be fair to Alex.
Alex is...?
My son.
He doesn't have enough problems without
feeling he's getting elbowed by a baby.
I think Alex would like a
brother or a sister. A family.
- He has a family.
- Okay, hang on.
Hang on. Time-out.
Luka, issues revolving
around having children...
can be complicated when one person
in the relationship already has a child.
God, Luka. I didn't wanna
have a kid the first time.
Alex was unplanned?
Yeah, you could say that.
- I was 15.
- Well, you're not 15 anymore.
After what happened
to your wife and kids...
you really want to bring
another baby into this world?
You had a family before?
He says he's happy, and
he can't even talk about it.
I had two children and a wife.
They were killed years ago.
How does it help us for me
to talk about these things?
It's a huge part of who you
are, and you won't let me in.
How come every kid named Destiny,
Miracle or Faith ends up with leukemia?
Hmm. Alkalinize her fluids
and give Oncology a heads-up.
That scalp guy went to the O.R.
Oh, you got another call
from your Kenyan love nest.
It's the Congo, Frank.
And I know that you
know it's the Congo.
Kenya, Congo. It's all mosquitoes
the size of flying toasters to me.
She sounded kind of upset.
You're all set.
Gonna leave that bucket
in the middle of the floor?
Shut off the toilet in O.R.
Soon as it drains, we'll snake it.
So how long we gonna have
raw sewage seeping out?
Another hour or two at the most.
Okay, great. So
when the bucket's full...
just toss it into the street
like we do chamber pots.
Kem Likasu, please.
Is this Charles?
Hey, Charles. It's John Carter.
Good, good. Is she around?
I found the Chief Resident's office,
but there's boxes I need you to move.
- She what?
- I look like Beakins to you?
Get a couple of your
interns, lean on them.
- See, but they're busy and you're not.
- What happened?
Ray, honestly, what
are you doing here?
This is a great program.
You were lucky to get into it.
- And you're just taking up space.
- You don't think I'm a good doctor?
I think you could be a very
good doctor, but you know what?
You watch the clock all
day just waiting to punch out.
You have two weeks
left on your internship.
Take your degree and go work at
a doc-in-a-box or do air transport.
If you're doing this to make a
living, you don't need a specialty.
You make more than enough
money right now to support your music.
Don't sign this contract unless you
are sure this is what you want to do.
Did something happen to Kem?
No. It's her mother.
She's in the hospital.
- In Africa?
- No. Her mother lives in Paris.
- Did she say what happened?
- Didn't talk to her.
She'd already
left for the airport.
Hey, Frank. I don't
know where Susan is.
- Would you please tell her I had to go?
- Go where?
Just tell her that I'll call
her from O'Hare, okay?
Gotta go by the bank on
the way back if that's okay.
Do you need anything
from Home Depot?
- I thought I'd swing by before work.
- Home Depot?
Yeah. I need to get some anchors
to fix that towel bar Alex pulled down.
- Where are you going?
- Leave me alone, Luka.
Are you gonna walk?
It's gotta be five miles.
Towel bars?
Sam!
- What's he doing in Paris?
- Kem's mother is sick.
Meningitis. She's immunosuppressed
from chemotherapy.
So with Carter AWOL, you
and me pick up the slack.
Five night shifts in a row?
- What?
- The new schedule. Morris?
If that's what it says.
A swing shift and a
day shift back-to-back?
And Ray gets every weekend off.
- What?
- Cubbies-Braves, right?
- Got you covered.
All right. ABBY: Oh, I see.
- So he bribed you for a good schedule.
- Of course not. That would be unethical.
Oh, I hear U2 tickets are hard to
get. It's a shame. I really wanted to go.
- Heh.
- Dr. Lewis...?
He is the chief.
Any way we can make
Abby Chief Resident?
Morris isn't the sharpest shovel in
the shed. But he's a paperwork hound.
Besides, keeps him from seeing
patients. Think of it as community service.
- CT call on Werntz yet?
- I'll call them again.
- Flowers usually work.
- Hey, Jerry, I want you to meet K.J.
- He's our new volunteer.
- Volunteen, welcome.
Jerry will be telling
you what to do.
Jerry, just have him run
specimens up to the lab or whatever.
- Specimens?
- Yeah. Blood, urine...
- Piss?
- Heh.
Nasal swabs, wound cultures,
stool samples, the whole enchilada.
Hey, Pratt, 47's pulling
in with a septic newborn.
Hey, you don't like
it, the door's that way.
Stool sample is
what I think it is?
Mm-hm.
- Septic newborn?
- So they say.
Hey, study your
antibiotics last night?
The gentamicin for the open fracture.
You should know this stuff cold by now.
Gonna be an R2 in a couple
weeks supervising new interns.
- Gotta start stepping it up.
- Eight-day-old female, febrile to 104.
Grunting, severe retractions.
Can't get a pulse ox.
- Tachy to 192. Resps, 80.
- Started this morning.
- I thought it was a cold.
- Access?
I had a 23 gauge in
the hand but it blew.
- No.
- No?
Fabienne Elmont?
John?
Hey.
What are you doing here?
I got your message
about your mom.
You should have told
me you were coming.
Well, I called your cell.
- No. It doesn't work in Paris.
- Oh.
How's she doing?
I can't tell what antibiotics
they're giving her from the IV.
Oh, she's not on antibiotics.
They're not giving her
antibiotics for meningitis?
Viral meningitis?
Oh.
- Who told you she had meningitis?
- I called the clinic.
Charles said you flew to Paris. With
all the chemo, I just assumed that...
- So she's okay?
- She had a fever, the doctor got worried.
So he admitted her.
- But she's much better now.
- Good.
Oh.
John, this is an old friend
of mine, Michel Timbaud.
- BP's 58/29.
- She needs volume.
You're hurting her!
Can't help unless we
give her fluids, medicine.
I'm in. Portable x-ray.
Call RT for a vent.
- Good chest rise.
- All right.
Airway and access.
Neela, what's your plan?
Normal saline, CBC, blood
culture, amp and cefotax.
- Good.
- Hodgkin guy's pressure...
- dropped after antibiotics.
- Run a liter.
- He's trying to pull out his broviac.
- Give the bolus. I'll be back.
- Hundred cc's MS through the IO.
- Please tell me what's going on.
We suspect your daughter has
an infection. Giving her antibiotics.
Fluids elevate her blood pressure.
Tube is helping her breathe.
- IO's infiltrated. Won't flush.
- How old is she again?
- Eight days. NEELA:
Umbilical stump is still attached.
- Is that bad?
- No. That's... That's good.
Umbilical-line kit. Five French.
Sterile sixes and 10 blade.
Hey, Jerry, Hodgkin's
guy needs a Med bed.
Let NICU know
they got a customer.
Your volunteen kid doesn't
seem very interested.
- Yeah. Well, he's not.
- So why has he volunteered?
- He has to work off his probation.
- What did he do?
- Second-degree murder, I think.
- Really?
He got caught
tagging a police car.
- He tried to spray-paint a cop car?
- Yeah. With the cop still in it.
- Ho-ho. The kid's got guts.
- Either that or he's an idiot.
Small-bowel obstruction
secondary to a popcorn overdose.
A 6-year-old ate a huge
tub of popcorn all by himself.
- Yeah, and...?
- Call Surgery, get a CT.
Think they'll be ready to
supervise interns in two weeks?
Not a chance.
John.
That was awkward.
Where are you going?
Back to the airport, I guess.
You just got here.
Well, you were right.
I should have called first.
Michel and I went
to school together.
And he's fond of my mother.
- You two a couple?
- We were.
Does he know about
the past-tense part?
Are you jealous?
- Yeah.
- Heh.
Hey, don't do that.
Don't laugh at me.
Okay. Okay.
Are you sleeping together?
No. Do not answer that.
Well, you haven't been dating?
Is there someplace around here
I can catch a taxi to the airport?
- Don't be so dramatic.
- Okay, look. I'm sorry.
Okay? I'm tired.
And I shouldn't have just barged in
on you. And I feel completely ridiculous.
Actually, it was very sweet.
Yeah.
Okay. Look, I'm really
glad that your mom's okay.
Why don't you call
me when you get home.
John.
Just stay. Just for the night.
- Flushes easily.
- Hook up the transducer.
- Sats, 93. Systolic's up to 78.
- Good. That's good.
How we doing in here?
- What are you doing?
- Umbilical lines.
- You what?
I heard you. Why?
- IO infiltrated. We needed access.
- Why not just put in another IO?
She still has an umbilical stump. UAC
and UVC allow for frequent blood draws.
Gases...
Did she do something wrong?
Hotel La Pavillon.
I'll come by in the morning.
We'll have some breakfast.
Michel coming too?
- He has to work.
- Those his real teeth?
- They're a little too straight.
- Get some sleep.
- I'm gonna come and pick you up early.
- Yeah. You get some sleep too.
You can't be placing
umbilical lines by yourself.
Do you know the things
could've gone wrong?
Thromboembolism, vascular
injuries, arrhythmias...
- I thought arterial monitoring...
- You're an intern.
You can't play neonatologist
whenever you feel like it.
I did a bunch of these...
- when we rotated through the...
- Really? When, two years ago?
Have you done one,
even seen one since then?
- You told me to take more initiative.
- Initiative?
What about common sense, Neela?
What's next,
neurosurgery in the lounge?
You need to know
when to ask for help.
Wha...? W-what the hell is
this? What, you're gonna cry now?
All right, look, you got lucky
this time. She's stabilizing.
But you have to
start using your head.
Now go on. Get out of here. Go.
I'll deal with the NICU guy.
Bonjour... Hello?
I'm sleeping.
It's dark outside.
All right, I'm up.
All right, I'm up,
I'm up, I'm up.
How's Michel gonna get
to work if we have his car?
Who said it's his car?
- Come on. I wanna show you something.
- Does it involve coffee?
Heh-heh-heh. Everything
in Paris involves coffee.
Hurry. We're gonna
miss it. Ha-ha.
- Where are we going?
- Nowhere. We're here.
You got me up at 5 in
the morning to ride a train?
Will you be patient
for once in your life?
Bonjour.
She spent the night at her
dying husband's bedside.
He was a member
of the Resistance...
fought bravely against
the Occupation...
while she smuggled
messages for the Free French...
through Nazi lines
on her bicycle.
He still loves her.
She's not so sure
after all these years.
He is an accountant.
She is a waitress,
longed to be a singer.
She had a mad, secret,
tempestuous affair...
with her sister's fiancé.
What about them?
It's a sad story.
She only has a few
months to live. Cancer.
They love each other desperately,
spend every moment together.
What about us?
You have a story for us?
Quick. Close your eyes.
Quickly, quickly,
quickly. Come on.
Close your eyes.
Wait, wait, wait.
Now.
What are you doing out here?
Deciding if I'm
sick. Pratt's on.
Ah.
- Hey, Neela.
- Hey.
Got you a bear claw. They
don't have the apple fritters.
- What are we doing?
- Neela's trying to decide...
- if she should go to work.
- We get to decide?
She put in umbilical lines
in a newborn yesterday.
Really? Cool.
Unsupervised. Pratt
became unglued.
Wow. I miss all the good stuff.
Well, gotta go.
I'm gonna be late.
Gotta get back on that horse.
Nothing fancy. Just
primer and a couple coats.
- The lichen...
- I'm not painting your office.
- Hospital does it. Need a purchase order.
- Yeah, that comes out of my ER budget.
Hey, Pratt. Stabbing victim in
Trauma 1. Back up the interns, please.
Paramedics are two minutes
out with an MVA, a 9-year-old kid.
Okay. Luka, can you get that?
I've got an extubation in C2.
- We don't have to do the trim.
- No, Morris.
MVA coming in.
Trauma panel. Type
and cross for four.
Pulse ox to 78. RAY:
Taking down neck dressing.
- Shouldn't we tube her first?
- Be my guest.
Maybe there's
something we can tie off.
Etomidate and sux.
- Got the jugular, spared the carotid.
- Can't breathe.
You're just going to sleep.
We breathe for you. Prep
for subclavian on the right.
- 8.0 ET tube.
- Is this the penetrating neck?
Single stab wound.
Hypotensive, no sub-Q air.
- Two of O-neg on peripheral IV.
- Pressure's up to 90 palp.
- I'm in. Bag her.
- Got a flash.
We'll have a central
line for the next 2 units.
Good breath sounds.
Excellent. Maybe there's
hope for you two after all.
Professor Carter.
It's associate
professor, actually.
Heh. Well, I'm proud of you.
Susan didn't get tenure.
- Susan Lewis? Really?
She's pretty pissed about it
too. She's not talking to me.
Now, this is what I really miss
in Africa. Baked goods. Heh.
What?
- You have a lot of jam on your face.
- Well, help me.
Hello.
Au revoir. WOMAN: Au revoir.
- Hey, hey, got a minute?
- Not really. What's up?
I gotta finish my
rankings for my match.
- I could use a little advice.
- Excuse me?
There's something
leaking from the ceiling.
Oh.
Okay. We're gonna move you...
right over here.
And Christian's gonna
take care of you. Thank you.
- Is that what I think it is?
- Yup.
Susan, code brown dripping
from the ceiling again.
Damn it, that is it.
Jerry, call the AOD.
Tell them we are closed to
trauma until someone comes down...
and deals with the raw
sewage leaking from the ceiling.
Is this the
respiratory distress?
- Jerry, what's open?
- There's a bed in Curtain 3.
Arnold Brixton,
65, short of breath.
Sats, 83 on room air,
91 on a non-rebreather.
Tachy at 115, afebrile, good BP.
On theophylline for emphysema.
- Don't say it.
- Say what?
I stopped smoking
five years ago.
- Good for you.
- Come on.
So I was thinking I might
rank County as my first choice.
You want to stay in Chicago?
Yeah. I mean, my friends
are here, all my family.
He needs a monitor and continuous
albuterol with 500 of Atrovent.
What about San Francisco?
UCSF has a great program,
but County has a lot to offer too.
Those sisters are back.
Okay, 60 of pred
and a portable chest.
- And do you wanna talk about this later?
- Sure.
- Rebecca? Birdy? You okay?
- You know them?
They've been in a
couple times before.
Circumferential ecchymosis.
Neela wants to get a telemetry bed.
What happened?
Rebecca almost got
strangled to death.
I tried to tell you guys it's too dangerous
for you to be out there on the streets.
I'd be dead if Birdy
hadn't stabbed her.
You stabbed the attacker?
Well, I had to.
Is she gonna be all right?
Yeah. I mean, she
seems stable for now.
- We might have to...
- No. Not Rebecca.
Shelley. Our niece.
They're working on her
in that room over there.
I grew up playing here, when we
weren't in Kinshasa with my dad.
My mom would save the old bread so I
could feed the ducks on the weekends.
There was thousands
of them in the summer.
Sounds idyllic.
Yeah. Yeah, it was.
So why did you leave?
It was different
when I was little.
We were a novelty then.
My very white mother, my black
father, with their little brown girl. Heh.
It wasn't easy for them.
You know that Joshua
would be a year old now?
I'm gonna head back to the
hospital, see my mother, okay?
What are we doing?
I still love you, and I
know you still love me.
We talk to each other every day.
We talk for hours on the phone.
We tell each other absolutely
everything about our lives.
I make you happy.
I make you laugh.
I tried living in Chicago
and it wasn't for me.
- We don't have to live in Chicago.
- You have your life there...
- your career, everything.
- I would give it up for you.
I don't want you to.
Kem, we had a baby and he died.
It's a tragedy that happens to
people and it happened to us.
But that doesn't
have to define us.
It doesn't. We're stronger
than that. Aren't we?
- I can't...
- We can have another baby.
Stop this. Stop doing this.
I'm sorry.
Are you gonna come
to the hospital? Hmm?
Because Fabienne's
gonna want to say goodbye.
Tidal volume's 700.
AC 14 on 100 percent.
- Units three and four on board.
- Did you follow up with Social Services...
- on home visit for the
Chadwicks? RAY: I'm... Who?
The two old ladies that
panhandle on the south.
You sent them
home with their niece.
From a few weeks ago? - Yeah.
- Down 60 systolic.
- Check for tracheal shift.
Get four of type specific.
This is the niece, Shelley.
Birdy stabbed Shelley.
- She was trying to strangle Rebecca.
- She what?
You sent them home with Shelley.
Did you forget about the follow-up...
- or not want to deal with it?
- I called. But what do I do?
- Make sure they do their job?
- People...
- can we focus on the patient?
- V-fib. Starting compressions.
- Ambu-bag.
- Charge at 200.
- Cardiac history?
- I don't know, Ray.
You're the only one
that's met her. Clear.
Oh, we're being rude.
No.
I'm hungry. Will you get
me something, mon ange?
Thank you for the
beautiful flowers.
He's a very handsome young man.
- Who?
- Michel.
Well, yeah, I guess.
Also something of a fool.
- When are you going home?
- There's a flight tonight at 9.
You're giving up
awfully easily, aren't you?
I was rather firmly discouraged
from continuing to try.
You know what life is?
Joy and grief, hand in hand.
You can't know real happiness until
you've had sorrow to contrast it with.
Hmm.
She hasn't learned that yet.
Leave him alone, Mother.
We were just catching up.
- Rib spreader.
- Abby, get the suction.
I don't get it.
Stab is in the neck.
Yeah. The knife must have
angled down, bagged the subclavian.
Stand back. This is
gonna be pretty bloody.
- Dry as a bone.
- Starting internal compressions.
We put in six units.
Where's it all going?
Whoa. Hold compressions.
- Fine V-fib. Internal paddles.
- Oh, man. Son of a bitch.
All right, stop bagging.
Eighteen-gauge needle.
Coronary artery's full of air.
- An air embolus?
All right. That's
it. We're done.
Time of death, 11:47.
How did she get that
much air in her heart?
I don't know. She had
an open neck wound.
The negative pressure
sucked air into her jugular.
I don't see how that's possible.
She has an occlusive dressing.
I... I took it down
to explore the neck.
Was it before or
after the intubation?
This was before.
You took down a patient's
dressing before she was intubated?
Excuse me. Dr. Lockhart?
Your emphysema guy is coding.
But it was only for a
few breaths. I didn't...
Damn right, we're gonna stay
closed as long as I've got crap...
I don't mean figuratively.
- -literal crap pouring out of my ceiling.
I came to check his neb. He was down.
- Mr. Brixton? Mr. Brixton?
- PVCs.
- All right, a mac-two and an 8.0.
You should have got
me if he was tiring out.
- No, no. He was holding his own.
- Systolic's 77.
- Okay. NS, wide open. Start second line.
- Run of six.
- All right. What now?
- Acute emphysema flare.
He went apneic
on continuous nebs.
- V-tach.
- No pulse.
Start compressions
and mark the time.
Let's get an ABG and
a capnograph now.
- How's she doing?
- Good sats, no stridor.
Got a repeat EKG and neck films.
You're doing good, Rebecca.
I didn't mean to hurt her.
I just wanted her to
leave Rebecca alone.
Did she suffer?
No. We put her to sleep to work
on her. She didn't suffer any pain.
I didn't mean to kill her.
We loved her.
Two hundred. Clear.
- Back in sinus. Got a pulse.
- Okay. What do you got?
Emphysema flare. Abby had
him on continuous albuterol.
He was wheezing.
Given the acute setting...
Chuny, correlate the capnograph
to the ABG. Set the rate at 40.
- Abby, what's the end tidal CO2?
- Ninety-six.
Can you tell me why?
He was apneic. LEWIS: Why?
- He wasn't ventilating?
- That's not an answer.
- He has emphysema?
- Wrong.
- Tired out.
- No.
- Basic respiratory physiology.
- He was hypoxic.
- ABG's back, pH 7.1.
- Think about it.
Emphysemics
chronically retain CO2.
- They rely on relative hypoxia...
- To trigger their respiratory drive.
I put him on nebs, oxygen, and
took away his impulse to breathe.
Leading to hypercapnia, acidosis, V-tach.
- Yeah.
- Sorry.
- Don't apologize to us.
He'll be okay once
you blow off some CO2.
It's a classic intern mistake.
You won't make it again.
Get up.
- What? What's going on?
- Tell them.
That poor woman in there thinks
she murdered her own niece.
Now, Ray.
Hey.
If it's any consolation, that was
a great teaching case for me.
I'm glad my public humiliation
can further your educational goals.
The guy is fine, Abby.
It's not your fault he smoked
two packs a day for decades.
So I was thinking...
that I might rank County as
my first choice for internship.
What about UCSF?
I don't want to go to UCSF.
I want to stay right here.
Don't do that for me.
Whew. Now, this was
a seriously crappy day.
Who wants to get drunk and pick a
bar fight with a bunch of law clerks, huh?
I still have an hour of charting to
do. How are Birdy and Rebecca?
- They're gonna be fine.
- Did you find out what happened?
Turns out the niece had them
panhandling to support her crack habit...
hit them when they
didn't bring home enough.
Well, well. If it isn't
the three amigos.
Let me see. Failure to recall
basic respiratory principles...
unsupervised umbilical
lines in an infant, eesh...
and a fatal air embolus.
Wow. Hey, when do
the new interns start?
A week from Monday.
Man, oh, man. God help
your patients. Ha-ha-ha.
Wait up, dude.
I don't know about you,
but I feel really inspired now.
So I think I'll go and
throw myself under a train.
Don't go away mad, Jake.
But do go away.
I'm moving back to Africa.
And we can start over.
We can do everything
that we didn't do before.
You take as much time as you
need. Take a month. Take a year.
You can take 10
years. I don't care.
And I'm not leaving without
you, and I'm not living without you.
I love you.