When my mother's
Alzheimer's got bad,
I was going through her
bills and I found a notepad.
Written on it were the words,
"Important. Tell
Meredith not to..."
And that was it. She never
finished that sentence.
Tell Meredith not to what?
Not to drink too much?
Not to pet strange dogs?
Not to give her heart away?
Not to leave the sprinklers on?
We didn't exactly
talk a lot in those days.
I regret that.
I wish we had.
I thought you and Dr. Cohen had
clean margins in the mastectomy.
Yeah, we did, but
then a spot showed up
on the latest scans,
alongside the chest wall here.
- So you didn't.
- It could be nothing.
Or it could be leftover cells that
weren't taken out, and kept growing.
- Maggie.
- I'm sorry, I...
- Keep going.
- We don't know
what it is, really,
- until we get in there.
- I'll do a wide local excision,
explore the area,
remove anything I find.
We may need to
do a muscle flap just
- to cover the defect,
but simple.
- Tomorrow?
Ah, we're thinking next week.
No. It has to be tomorrow.
The next day at the latest.
We should let her
get stronger first.
She is strong. And we don't want it
to spread past what it already has.
Of course we don't,
but it's a big surgery,
- so I'd like...
- I can handle it.
I'm fine. I want the next
surgery as soon as you can do it.
- How'd it go?
- Thank you.
Okay, I think...
Her radiation caused some fibrosis,
which made things a little tricky.
You know, I would have
preferred to wait another week.
I wanted to wait, too.
Hmm.
I'm sorry, I haven't followed
up on the... the thing.
Dinner.
It's not because I don't
want to. It's just that I...
Sure. I mean, you know...
- there's a lot going on.
- There is a lot going on.
It'll happen... sometime.
Sometime.
I'd better get in there.
- Boo.
- Oh, God.
- You can't sleep?
- Wide awake all hours.
This chair's the only place
my stomach and back
can get comfortable, so...
- What are you doing up?
- I have three kids. I don't sleep.
Motherhood.
I always wanted more kids.
So Maggie could have
a sister or a brother.
I was worried when she
wanted to move out here.
She was happy in Boston, but...
I'm really glad she found you.
You said your stomach
is bothering you?
Damn it.
Richard?
What are you gonna say?
You're sure it's a met?
It's right where the bile
drains from your liver, so
that would explain your pain.
- You're saying
I have another tumor?
- No, no, she's saying that cells
from the original tumor have
traveled and grown in another place.
In my liver?
- Yes.
- Maybe.
So, I know this
is a lot to take in...
so why don't the
two of you, um...
take the night and we can
meet again in the morning
- and discuss it further, okay?
- We're here now.
- But I just meant that...
- Can you
remove it laparoscopically?
- What? Well, that
would be better than
an open procedure
at this point, right?
Then we wouldn't have
to stop her chemo regimen.
Unless you have a
different surgical plan?
Would you like to
discuss this outside?
No, no, we're discussing
my mother's treatment.
We can discuss it with her.
Okay, Diane, typically,
with aggressive cancers,
we only operate where
the original tumor began.
In this case, it
was your breast.
Once the cancer spreads beyond
that, surgery is not curative...
But it could prevent further
pain and complications,
which there will be if the met keeps
growing or spreads even further.
And we would work to
prevent that using other options.
Sure, pump her with more chemo.
Well, a second ago, you were
worried about stopping her chemo.
- Just take out the met.
- You're asking me
to perform a procedure...
You can barely
see it on the scan.
That'll not only cause
her pain, but put her at risk
- for many complications.
- It's my mom.
I'm asking you to think beyond
the standard and typical...
And I'm asking you to listen
to yourself as a surgeon,
- who should know better.
- Oh, good God, enough!
Both of you, I can't
even hear myself think.
- Mom, we just... We need one...
- Are you saying
that you can't do the surgery
- to remove the, um...
- The met.
- Can you do it?
- I can, but I'm saying
that I won't.
Because in my professional
opinion, I think it's a terrible idea.
Meredith, if you won't do
the surgery, you should go.
We'll find another
surgeon who will.
- No, it's not...
- No.
Maggie, this is not
your decision to make!
Meredith, dear...
I'm firing you.
You're no longer
one of my doctors.
Dr. Wagner to Radiology.
Thank you for meeting
with me this morning.
I found something that, um...
It is called the BXP protocol,
and it started at Gillman.
They're experimenting
with humanized antibodies
for late-stage cancer
immunotherapy.
Um...
- Clinical trial.
- Is this successful?
The trial's next phase
was rushed into approval
due to favorable outcomes.
And your mom meets the criteria?
Once we remove that met
that's obstructing her bile duct,
her liver enzymes will
go down. Then she's in.
Um, Meredith doesn't
feel that surgery is wise.
Meredith is no
longer on the case.
And now that I
know about this trial,
there's even more
reason to do the surgery,
and I'd like one
of you to do it.
Oh.
You know, um...
I think we should
read up on the trial
- and then come up with a plan.
- Yeah.
- Does that sound good to you?
- Yeah, yeah, thanks.
- Anyone think
this is a good idea?
- No.
- Not at all.
- All right,
so we're together on that.
So I'll bring up Diane's
chart, we'll pull together
some other research
and get together,
see what we can
come up with, huh?
You know, I'd
prefer to work alone.
Me too.
No, no, no, no, guys,
that's not a good idea.
Great.
A biliary bypass wouldn't work
given the location and size of the met.
Are you actually
going to resect it?
The met? I'm not
going near that thing.
No one would.
Right now, I'm just trying to
figure out how to lower her LFTs
to get her into this trial.
- Did you consider stenting her?
- That's still surgery.
I mean, with her condition...
But if it's done percutaneously,
under minimal sedation.
Yeah. It could give
more long-term relief,
hopefully, avoiding
re-intervention.
And get her LFTs
down. I like it.
Well, it's better than
a complete bypass.
That's true.
Okay. Good. I was never here.
How are her LFTs
post-op? Any change?
Well, the procedure worked.
I relieved the obstruction,
a hundred percent.
And her LFTs are
trending down, yes.
- So she'll qualify
for the trial?
- Yes.
- She qualifies for the trial.
- Really?
Oh, my God. That
is amazing news!
Ah! Thank you, Dr. Bailey,
for doing the procedure!
Oh! I gotta call my
contacts at Gillman. I...
I gotta go! All
right, thank you!
- Damn it.
- Yup.
No one wanted to mention
that we think that the trial
- is a completely terrible idea?
- You need to sit her down
- and let her know
what's going on!
- Me? I'm not doing that!
- You're her friend.
- Who kept her mom's cancer
a secret
from her. No, you're
her dad. You do it.
- You're Diane's surgeon.
- So was Avery.
Oh, come on! You led the
procedure that brought her LFTs down
and got her the
trial in the first place.
A trial I never believed in.
- Yeah, well, you're the chief.
- Well, who's head of the board?
- Now you care about that?
- Never mind! I'll do it.
She's awake.
Don't want to bother you.
Oh, come in, come in!
Maggie went to get me
some tea or something.
Oh, that's fine. You
know... I wanted to chat.
- Well?
- About the clinical trial.
- Did I get in?
- Well, yes, you... you will, but...
Listen, there's
some things that...
Maggie will be
so excited. She...
She wants to start right
away the, um... the thingy.
- Protocol.
Will you be doing the protocol?
I want to make sure you
have a complete picture.
- The trial is very aggressive.
- That's what we want, right?
Yes, but, um...
the toll it's gonna
take on your body...
it will be difficult,
extremely difficult.
I know.
But...
- Maggie says it's a good idea.
- Diane...
there's a reason
we don't let doctors...
treat members of
their own family.
Sometimes, the need to
help someone you love can...
cloud your judgment.
She wouldn't do anything
to make me worse.
- She's my daughter.
- Here we go. Hi!
Hi.
- What's the matter? What's wrong?
- Oh, nothing.
Everything's great, sweetie.
Uh, you know what? I'm
gonna let you get some rest,
and, um... we'll talk tomorrow.
I appreciate that. See you then.
- Here you go, Mrs. Pierce.
- Oh, well, no need
for special treatment.
I'm happy in the other
chemo room, the regular one.
Right, Mom, it's a clinical
trial, so they have to be able
to control everything
in your environment.
The room temperature,
your temperature, everything.
Oh.
I was going to ask Aurora if
Lee finally passed his driver's test.
- Who?
- Aurora, my chemo nurse.
Her son, Lee, has failed it
twice, and he was supposed to go
to the DMV today.
Maggie, you work with these
people. How do you not know this?
Um...
- How we doing in here?
- They're making a fuss.
Um, we will need you
to sign these forms.
- All of these?
- Yeah.
The thing with
clinical trials is...
they can list a million
ways your body might react.
But the truth is,
they just don't know.
That's why it's a trial.
You need to be
prepared for anything.
You... Here, let me... let me
walk you through this, um...
Um...
So, what this says is
you may experience
some nausea and vomiting.
There's, uh,
dehydration, weakness,
dizziness. There's fatigue.
Night sweats.
And chills.
Skin irritation.
Wound infections.
Extreme fluid build-up.
In short, it will get bad...
then really bad.
And then... if it starts
to work, hopefully,
you'll start to
get a little better.
This treatment is killing
her faster than the cancer.
- It's what Diane wants.
- You mean what Maggie wants.
Mom?
- Why aren't you resting?
- Oh, I woke up hours ago.
Feeling great.
So I watched the
news, did a little laundry.
Then I noticed that the
pantry was a little cluttered,
- so I reorganized it.
- Mom, you don't have to do that.
Well, I did. And you got
up at the perfect time.
- It's lasagna time.
- Lasagna?
You're going to make my lasagna.
Oh, no, Mom. I don't...
I... that's your thing. I
don't know how to make it.
Well, you need to learn.
No. Stop it.
I don't want you passing
things down. That's not...
- I... I don't like that.
- Oh, that's not why.
It's just that I have decided I
don't have to do this anymore.
I am a woman of a certain
age, and I have earned the right
to sit down, put my feet
up and let you cook for me.
- Mom.
- You're not gonna like it
when I'm gone and
you're missing my lasagna.
Invite your
friends. It'll be fun.
Okay. I just need to
go, um... take a shower.
Uh-huh. I don't think so!
- Grab that flour.
- We're doing this now.
Okay... That's awesome.
- Hi! Why are you
all here at once?
- Hi!
We carpooled. We
thought it'd be fun.
- Yeah, Webber drove us.
- And we have wine.
You guys, she made me
make the noodles from scratch.
You know you can buy
noodles in a box, right?
- Wait, hold on. You were two?
- Two years old!
And when I say she was
reading, it was reading.
Maggie was not sounding
out words or anything.
- Okay, Mom.
- And you didn't teach her?
Oh, nobody could teach
her. My baby was a genius.
- That brain of hers.
- Okay, thanks, Mom.
I've you to thank
for that, I guess.
Well, I don't know about that.
Oh, and your mother.
I'd like to pay my
respects to Ellis.
I'm here, I'm
staying in her house.
I mean, it's the
right thing to do.
Well, that's very nice, but
you don't need to do that.
Oh, but I want to.
Where is she buried?
Um...
- A place that she loved...
- We dumped her ashes
- in a scrub sink in O.R. Two.
- By the water.
- Oh, my God!
- Well, it was her favorite O.R
and it seemed like the
right thing at the time.
We're terrible people.
I love it! I love it!
Oh, no.
It's okay, it's okay, it's okay,
I just heard. An
esophageal tear?
Yeah. Hopefully, it's contained
and I don't have
to open her chest.
- What are you doing?
- I should do the EGD.
You're too close. Go
take care of Maggie.
Let me do this for you.
Don't pretend you're
doing this for me.
You've made it very clear for
some time that my well-being
is the lowest of your priorities
Hey, I'm just trying to help.
If I needed help...
you'd be the last
person I'd call.
- You had to do a thoracotomy?
Yeah, the tear was full of thickness.
Conservative management
wasn't the way to go here, Maggie.
No, you're right. Thank you.
So, we'll start
her on tube feeds?
Um, we're... we're...
we're not there yet, uh...
She's on TPN for now, and
I'm also concerned about sepsis,
so we've started her on
broad-spectrum antibiotics.
She's still sedated for the pain,
and we'll keep her on PCA, okay?
Keep her comfortable.
Do you need anything from home?
Do you want us to get you anything?
We need to get her
on her feet A.S.A.P.
If she misses any of her
infusions, she'll lose her position
- in the study.
- Maggie...
I'd like to get Diane
through the next 24 hours.
Okay? And then we'll see
where we are from there.
Maggie?
I really don't need you trying to
talk me out of anything right now.
This protocol is
making Diane so sick
- that her esophagus tore.
- That could just be
from the cancer.
But you can't wait to get
her to her next infusion.
Because my mom wants to live.
And this clinical trial
could give that to her.
She wanted to do it.
She could have said no.
How? How can she say no when
her daughter, who is a surgeon,
is standing right there,
pushing it on her?
There have been
favorable outcomes.
We just need to get her
to the end of the treatment.
She won't make it to
the end of the treatment!
She's already dying.
And now she's suffering
- because of it.
- At least I'm doing something.
At least I'm not just
giving up and saying no.
We are only doing her harm.
You don't get it! You wouldn't.
Meredith, I love my mother
enough not to say "screw it,"
and throw her down a damn drain.
What do you need? What can I do?
- Where's Maggie?
- Diane...
you don't have to keep
putting yourself through this.
Not if you don't want to.
I was born in a two-room
shack with an outhouse.
Six brothers.
Not a lot of food...
or love, or anything.
Getting out of there was...
When that social worker
put this little baby in my arms,
when I looked
down at my Maggie...
Maggie...
is the universe
giving me a gift.
She is...
a happy person.
She's... cheerful.
Maggie is rare, she's special.
This...
This will give her darkness.
How could I do that to
the most special person
in the whole world?
When I die...
she needs to know
that she did everything
that she could.
Diane, she has.
Maggie's done
everything there is to do.
I can't stop. I... I
can't do that to her.
Well, she can take
it. You may not see it
because you knew her
since she was a little girl.
I mean, I didn't. I only
know the woman you raised.
And that woman is smart...
and strong as iron.
Especially for the
people she loves.
Now...
Well...
Now I see where she gets it.
I don't want to die.
Hey.
So I'm gonna put out a couple
of calls to some old professors
from Boston. Do you
remember Dr. Luckett?
- He specializes
in radioactive...
- Maggie!
Don't you dare quit on me now.
You can't... You
can't quit on me.
We can beat this. You
have to fight. I'll help you.
Sweetie...
Sit down and let me talk to you.
- You all right?
- No.
- Do you want to sit down?
I just wish my dad was here.
Maggie.
- Meredith doesn't get it.
- She's just worried about you.
I just got started!
My mom has been sick for
months without me knowing.
Months!
I feel like I left the
house with the oven on
and went about my business
and came back to find
the whole house
engulfed in flames.
And no one will let me in.
No matter what I
do, I can't get inside.
I can't save anything!
I could've stopped
it if I had known.
So, I can't give up. I
can't give up, not now.
- Hey.
- What are you doing? What?
Come here.
Thank you.
She's gonna go
and I'm not ready.
Not ready.
You're never ready.
You just do it.
Listen to her.
Talk about whatever
she wants to talk about,
and record her voice in your
mind. And memorize everything.
Just keep sitting there.
- Orgasms.
- No.
- It's not a dirty word.
- No, no.
I'm dying.
- I have to impart wisdom.
- This wisdom? Right now?
You've got time. You don't
have to go there right now.
Hmm.
- I've had orgasms.
- Oh, well, good.
They are not a
gift. It's your right.
Don't let anyone
tell you otherwise.
And this is important,
at least once a day.
Sometimes I like to wait
- until right before bedtime,
but...
- No! God, no, Mom! Stop.
You are too intense.
Have some fun.
I have plenty of
fun. Which color?
- The darker.
- Okay.
Oh, and did you call
about my eyelashes?
You know I want to die
with my eyelashes on.
Eyelashes are tomorrow.
Good...
You were always so good.
What do you mean?
Incredible grades,
a clean room, and
you never talked back.
And you never messed
around with the boys.
- Most parents
would appreciate that.
- Oh, I did...
Then. But now?
You need to
shake it up a little.
Um...
Be a little lazy
or a little slutty.
- Make a mistake.
- I have a job.
Well, you're never
gonna look back and say,
- "I wish I'd been more uptight."
- Okay, Mom, you have to
be still or else I
can't finish this.
And stop always saying
what everyone wants to hear.
Tell someone off.
It's good for 'em,
and better for you.
Especially if it's a
car sales person.
- Do you like the color? Okay.
- I do.
- And don't forget the...
- The top coat, I know, I know.
You want some water?
Want me to keep going?
I brought my
engagement ring to Seattle.
It's at the house,
in my jewelry bag.
I want you to have it.
- Mom...
- Your father gave it to me.
He'd want you to
have it, too. So, please.
Okay.
Thank you.
I want you to fall in love.
And it has to be
somebody who's worthy.
Find a decent man
who loves you just a little
more than you love him.
Well, equally as
much. How about that?
No, he needs to think
he is lucky to have you,
- and not the other way around.
- Other hand.
Never make yourself
small for anyone.
Be your own person.
And try wearing
a little lipstick.
You know, Mom, if you
keep going at this rate,
you're gonna run out of
advice before tomorrow.
Mm. Oof.
- This polish smells.
- Want me to open a window?
That would be nice.
It stopped raining.
Okay, I'm not going to leave it
open too long or you'll catch a chill.
Typical.
Bring you to a hospital,
help you catch a cold.
Mom?
Mommy?
Listen, I... I... I
know the flight...
the helicopter had to
be expensive, and so...
- I'll write you a check.
- No... no need, no.
This is family.
Thank you.
Daddy, Daddy.
Hey.
- Hey, how's Pierce?
- Not great.
Yeah, sorry to hear about Diane.
She's gonna need me now.
For how long, I don't know.
Yeah, I know.
Our timing's just off, I guess.
I think about my
mom's note all the time.
"Tell Meredith not to..."
Not to cave? Not to care?
Not to give up so easily?
Not to fall in love?
Not to have children?
Not to tell a lie?
She left me wondering.
What to do.
What not to do.
Damn it.
What?
She left me knowing
everything was up to me.
And me alone.
Ellis never forgave me.
She went to her grave
without forgiving me.
It robbed me of so many things.
So many things.
Let's not do that to each other.
And she left me
with no one to ask...
so I would decide
what she meant to write.
"Tell Meredith
not to be afraid."
Goodbye, Mom.