The surgical scalpel
is made of sterilized,
carbonized stainless steel.
This is a vast improvement
over the first scalpel,
which was pretty
much a sharp stick.
Medicine is constantly
reinventing itself.
That means surgeons have to
keep reinventing themselves, too.
I can't believe
we're doing this.
It's Valentine's Day.
We don't do Valentine's Day.
- More to life
than the hospital.
- No, there isn't.
- It's romantic.
- No, it isn't.
There's constant pressure
to adapt to changes.
- Ambulance!
- It can be a painful process.
- Eyes front, ladies.
- But without it...
- OK, that seemed big.
- If it's big, they'll page us.
- It's big.
- Yes!
You'll find yourself moving
backwards, instead of forwards.
- What's going on?
- Grandinetti's roof collapsed.
We'll be getting more than a dozen.
All scheduled procedures are pushed.
On Valentine's Day? Grandinetti's
must have been packed.
Well, tonight's out. I told
you this would happen.
That's why we went to dinner
at four, and exchanged gifts.
Just special. Original.
Magical. Squeals of joy.
- Wow, Scrooge!
- Scrooge is Christmas.
- That's a holiday.
- Dr. Bailey.
My hemicolectomy is
pushed. It's a shame.
I was really looking
forward to that.
Well, that's... You know...
Maybe we could make
up for it. Dinner tomorrow?
No! I...
Just... I'm busy.
I have surgeries most
nights. I always have surgery.
Right. Well, um...
Maybe see you in the OR, then.
Oh, my God. She likes him.
Oh!
- You like him?
- You should totally
go out with him.
- You have to say yes!
- It's Valentine's Day! You have to!
OK, see? This, right
here, what's happening,
with the giggling, the
girl talk, the OMGs...
OK, it has to stop. I am busy.
Hey, Torres.
Do you know anything
about putting together cribs?
- You bought a crib?
- Sloan's coming home tonight.
And I got it put together,
but it wobbles. It can't wobble.
Will you take a look at it?
You're like a sweet, nerdy dad,
now. I don't even recognize you.
- Who's the blonde?
- I don't know.
I may be a dad, but
I am a single dad.
Excuse me.
OK, now I recognize you.
It must, uh, suck to
work on Valentine's Day.
I don't believe we've met.
Aah!
- What did you do to your hair?!
- I changed it.
I colored it. I just...
Wait, you thought I
was someone else.
You didn't know it was me,
and you were hitting on me?
No, I pretty much thought
you were some blonde.
You are pathetic.
And hypocritical.
- And slutty.
- And you are no blonde.
You can't pull that off. Blondes
are either bad-ass or fun.
And you're... you're a brunette.
- Damn!
- Shut up!
Quit staring. I'm probably
gonna change it back anyway.
No, I get it. You get
dumped by your boyfriend,
and you go for the extreme
makeover. Chicks always do that.
I didn't get dumped. I
did not do this for Mark.
I just... It's Valentine's Day,
and I wanted to change
something, and I could change...
I wanted to do something
for me. OK? This was for me.
How is that different
than what I just said?
I'm changing it back.
Watch that rock, please.
This is medic 16...
Restaurant roof collapse.
So far a penetrating abdominal
injury, a sucking chest wound
- and a massive head wound.
- To the left!
- There's an open
fracture on the way.
- You're still here.
If you're here, I'm here. An OSHA
investigator is waiting in the lobby
and also two TV crews
are asking for a statement.
- I told them to wait for you.
- We cleared the OR board.
Also, I paged Bailey, Nelson,
Altman, Hagan and Sloan.
- I'll get...
- Stop! Who do I see first?
- Skull fracture, trauma one.
- The OSHA guy.
- Chart, please.
- - Get as many people as possible
off the backboard, clear C-spines
clinically but if you're not sure,
wait for X-ray, no matter
how backed up they are.
- Hold the elevator!
- I got it!
Trauma four is open.
- Bring the chart, please.
- Right away.
- Where are they
taking my husband?
- He's going into surgery.
His doctors will let us know more
soon. Take a deep breath for me?
- What do we have, Grey?
- Decreased breath sounds
on the left,
- possibly a pneumothorax.
- Put in a chest tube
if you need to.
Evaluate and page
me if it's surgical.
- Sorry.
- I'm sorry.
OK, let me see the chart.
Looks like a pretty bad break.
You're gonna have
to have that reset.
I wonder if there's any chance
you could put me in
a bed next to that lady.
Yeah, sorry, it
doesn't work like that.
Of course. Forgive me.
I've been a head
waiter for 25 years.
I know how it works.
I'll see what I can do.
Depressed skull fracture
with a subdural hematoma.
All right? Book an OR.
- Chief.
- Yeah.
Reassign some anesthesiologists.
You're being cupid for Bailey.
I don't do that. I did that
once, she yelled at me.
I'll be cupid. You
just be the chief.
- I am not cupid.
- Sign.
Dr. Shepherd, the reporters
are waiting for a statement.
- I have surgery.
- Actually, Dr. Nelson said
he can take your skull fracture.
You've got the trustees' breakfast in
the morning, and when the trustees
turn on the 11:00 news, it's
your face they'll want to see.
- Clear the hallway!
- Will do.
- Watch it, coming through!
- I've got the arm.
What do you got?
Traumatic amputation
through the left distal humerus,
bleeding controlled with
pressure. Got ten of morphine
- and vital signs are stable.
- Get him in Trauma Three.
Put him on a monitor,
push two of O neg!
- Grey, Avery, you're with me.
- Chief Shepherd?
Shepherd!
What about the
fact that this...?
Can she have some water, please?
I'm afraid she can't.
Emile, stop.
My husband and I have
been going to Grandinetti's
for 15 years.
Every Friday night.
And sometimes Tuesdays.
Emile always takes
very good care of us.
But now it's time to
look after yourself.
I just thought you'd
want someone with you,
until you find out that
Mr. Banks was OK.
Thank you.
My patient's
stalking your patient.
He's being a good waiter. And
apparently, we're his busboys.
Dude gave me 50 bucks to put him
next to her. He's got the hots for her.
Her husband is in
surgery. She's married.
You're saying that 'cause
you think you're married.
His 50 bucks says he
makes a move. You in or out?
I'm in. And I am married.
- Mrs. Shepherd?
- Huh?
- I'm not Mrs. Shepherd.
- You're not?
- I'm Dr. Grey.
- Right. Right.
Um, Chief Shepherd wanted me to
ask you about the trustees' breakfast.
You Shepherd's flunky? Is
that why he hired you back?
I'm on his service this week.
And during this transition,
he needed a little more help
on the administrative side.
I'm not his flunky.
So will you be going with him to
the breakfast or meeting him there?
I, um... am not sure I'm going.
Well...
You have to. You're his wife.
Sloan? When did you get in?
- Does Mark know you're here?
- No. My flight
got in a little early.
And I took a cab over.
I didn't want to bug him.
Somebody said that you
guys have a free clinic.
- Do you know where that is?
- Is everything OK?
Yeah, I just want someone to check
me out after the surgery and everything.
- Maybe give me an ultrasound.
- The clinic closed an hour ago.
Come on, I have a second.
I'll take a peek for you.
I need another four-by-four.
Dress him, I'm gonna take
another look at the arm.
His wound's completely
macerated and contaminated.
Why wasn't this
guy brought in first?
He was lying in dirty dishwater
for a while before they found him.
- They forgot I was back there.
- No.
It's all right.
I'm not...
I'm not too big on
talking to people.
And nobody talks to
me much back there.
They just, you know,
bring me the dishes.
I lost my arm.
I don't wanna have one arm.
I don't want to be a freak.
I don't like people
staring at me.
- We're gonna do
everything we can.
- Please.
OK, Frankie, I'm gonna
take you up to surgery now.
We're gonna try and
reattach the arm, OK?
Do we have an open OR? I'll
prep him. Work on the stump.
You debride the arm, tag the vessels,
get it up to me as soon as you can.
Wow. Trauma Room Barbie.
Irrigation here and
suction, please?
So Grandinetti's is gone.
A Seattle institution.
- Dr. Warren,
you ever been there?
- Couple times. Good scampi.
Yeah, place is so romantic.
Perfectly lit, intimate.
Those cozy little
booths in back.
Three-oh silk tie, please.
A little too intense
for a first date, though.
Bailey, where would
you go on a first date?
Isn't there a dying
child somewhere?
Nope. I had some time.
And I wanted to observe one...
one of these.
Aw!
- Baby looks perfect.
- Awesome.
- Um, can I, like,
get that in writing?
- Oh.
Even better.
- Here is a souvenir.
- Oh... Um...
Don't you have some
kind of official form or...
a hospital document
you can give me?
Why do you need
an official form?
Well, it's none
of your business.
If you want your
official form, it is, Sloan.
What's going on?
It's for the adoption
attorney, OK?
They need, like, a clean bill of
health from me or something.
There's this great
couple in San Francisco.
- And they have
these two big dogs.
- An adoption attorney?
Yeah, I'm not ready to be a mom.
I'm just not ready yet.
- Have you told Mark?
- No.
And you're my doctor, right?
I mean, don't you guys have some kind
of rule that says you can't say anything?
I'm not gonna tell him.
And neither are you.
Do you think she
needs an extra blanket?
She gets chilled easily.
She must be one
hell of a tipper.
- Sorry?
- I see why she
comes in every week.
I bet you take better care
of her than her own husband.
When she first
started coming in,
before they met,
we had a little game.
She would try
anything we served.
She was adventurous. Fearless.
When she'd gone through the
menu, I would challenge the chefs
to come up with something new.
It became, she became,
my favorite part of the week.
Then one night,
she came in with him.
She felt like this was a
safe place for a first date.
That ring on her finger...
The night he proposed to her,
I placed it in the creme
brulee for her to find.
I watched her say yes
from the kitchen window.
And they never
stopped coming in.
But now he orders for her,
same thing every time.
For 15 years, I've watched
their conversations grow shorter
and shorter.
Until now, all they do is eat.
She has no children.
If he dies,
she'll be...
She'll be all alone.
She's so afraid, I can see.
And all I want to do is take
her hand in mine and tell her
she'll be all right.
She'll never have to be alone,
if she doesn't want to be.
You'll let me know when you have
good news about Mr. Banks, yes?
Yeah, right. Of course.
You can't leave
without telling him.
Yes, I can. I can do whatever...
- Sloan!
- Crap.
When did you get here? I
thought you were gonna call first.
Look!
Oh, my God. Would
you look at that?
That's the Sloan
nose. Can you see it?
Can you see it?
It's my dad's. He
has my dad's nose.
That's the Sloan nose.
Damn it. Will you wait for
me? I wanna take you home.
I got a surprise for you.
Could I see this again?
The Sloan nose.
You win. He's been staring at
her from his kitchen for 15 years.
- He's not gonna tell her now.
- He just did.
She was awake the whole time. She
heard everything. She has to say something.
She's not. Her
husband's in surgery.
So? They're clearly miserable.
Did you hear the whole
creme brulee thing?
Fifty bucks says she tells
him she loves him, too.
- You're on.
- Hi.
- I've got your keys.
- What?
Dr. Shepherd told me you might
not make it home before the breakfast,
so I should ask you what you need
from your closet and I'll grab it for you.
You are not going in my closet.
Aren't you supposed to be a surgeon?
He really needs you by
his side at that breakfast.
I am a surgeon. You tell the
chief that I will be in surgery.
So I'll just pick
something out for you.
So Yang's with Hunt.
Grey's with Shepherd.
Torres is with Robbins.
And you were with Sloan,
until he dumped you.
It's a wonder you
guys got any work done.
He didn't dump me.
He forgot about me.
He decided that we were
going to start a family,
and didn't ask me.
He forgot I was even there.
He just left me lying
in dirty dishwater.
What?
Nothing.
I'm pretty.
- What?
- In my family. I'm the pretty one.
You know, um, my eyes and...
my smile and my body.
You should see me without a
shirt on. It's kind of ridiculous.
But my family is smart, driven,
crazy overachievers.
And they look like they're
smart. They don't look like me.
Which has its perks,
except that my family
treated me like I'm pretty.
They expected nothing from me.
Ever. They never pushed
me. Never thought to.
So I had to push myself. Hard.
I didn't even tell them I was taking
the MCATs till after I'd aced them.
My point is that you
can't just change your hair.
You want to be unforgettable,
you want to not be mousy?
You can't just change your hair.
You have to actually change.
Just saying.
OK. I'm removing the glass
very slowly...
OK, take this. Bovie.
Nice work, Dr. Bailey.
Dr. Warren, can
you believe Dr. Bailey
almost left general surgery for
Peds surgery? Did you know that?
- I did not.
- She almost said no
to general surgery. But
then she thought about it,
and she changed her mind.
She wasn't afraid to
rethink her decision.
She just needed
to be asked again.
I see. Clearly.
- You have my report thing?
- No.
He took you in.
He's given you money,
he flew you to LA.
He deserves to know. So if
you're not gonna tell him, I will.
You paged me?
- What's going on?
- You paged him?
What's the matter?
- Mark, she's...
- I'm giving the
baby up for adoption.
I'm not a mom. I'm not ready.
And I want him to have good
parents and a good home.
No, don't. Don't do this.
Don't give this baby away.
They'll love him. They'll
love him more than I will.
Give him to me.
I'll take him.
I'll adopt him.
I understand. I understand
you're not ready, but I am.
And I know I don't have
the best track record.
And I should have been
there for you, and I wasn't.
But I will be there
for this baby. Please.
I want him to
have a family and...
You've been really nice to
me the past couple of months,
but you're not a
family. You're just a guy.
- Sloan, please.
- I'll help.
Uh...
I'm right across the hall.
And we're a family, sort of.
And we're doctors.
And we're best friends.
And... And we're good people.
We'll... We'll take
care of the baby.
Together.
We'll love him.
Really will.
Just think about it.
Go home, we'll talk about it.
Can we talk about it?
Yes. Yes, we can.
We can talk about it.
- Thank God. Where'd you get those?
- Patient room.
Guy's in a coma, he's not gonna
miss them. Anything happen?
He's still asleep. She
wants to say something.
Oh! Oh, my God, I'm starving!
- Ooh. These are all half-eaten.
- So you can see what they are.
What are we doing?
Her boring husband's in surgery.
This dude's been in
love with her for 15 years.
She just found out.
We're waiting to see
if she says something.
- Or if her husband croaks.
- It's OK if he does
because they're miserable. I mean,
is this what marriage turns into?
Running out of things to say
and changing who you are?
- Probably.
- Yeah.
Well, I didn't marry Derek to be
the chief's arm candy. I'm a surgeon.
Yeah, you married him
for the great surgeries.
I didn't do that either.
- Right.
- You should have.
Shh! She's gonna say something.
She's gonna wake him up.
Oh! What's she saying?
She can't breathe!
Get a crash cart!
She's got a big air
leak in her chest tube.
- What's happening?
- Keep her on 100 percent O2.
Get a bronchoscopy. Grey, see
if an OR's available just in case.
She's having trouble breathing. We'll
let you know more as soon as we do.
We saved the arm. We
saved it. We're ready.
- It's gonna have to be an amputation.
- - What?
There's too much devascularized
tissue, too much contamination.
We could push antibiotics and let
the stump heal, but by that time...
The arm will be dead.
Page me when he's awake.
I'll tell him.
They...
They can't just leave it behind.
We could move it somewhere
else. Attach it to a healthy zone.
- Don't tell me, mouse.
- I'm just saying they could...
Temporary ectopic replantation!
You have to keep the arm
alive until the stump heals.
Yes, but in cases
involving the elbow...
It's extreme. He'll lose
range of motion, grip failure.
He'll keep his arm! He
deserves extreme measures!
If the arm is still viable,
you can't just let it die.
Has it ever been done
before, above the elbow?
I don't know. It could be done.
You could implant it onto the
epigastric and the venae commitante.
Give you a few days
for the stump to heal.
- I've never done one.
- Neither have I.
So? After today, you
can't say that anymore.
Come on! I told him that we
would do everything we could,
do everything that we can!
I'll call Shepherd and let
him know. Grey, Avery,
get ready to scrub in.
We're gonna be a while.
OK, that?
Not mousy.
You're going into surgery now?
- There's this breakfast.
- I know. I know about the breakfast.
Because there's some
resident I don't know
- rooting through
my closet right now.
- Sorry. She's over-eager.
I have surgery. I can't
really give up the surgery.
- No, I wouldn't want you to.
- Just to smile
and stand at a podium
for the suits? It's...
No, you shouldn't come.
You know, my patient,
she's somebody's wife, too.
And I'm her doctor, and...
- OK?
- OK.
OK.
- Hey.
I got a tracheobronchial tear.
Transitory ectopic implantation.
Wow. Nice.
I rented a house. It's amazing.
It's right on the water, a little
cottage. And there are deer.
Like Bambi deer and
singing birds, it's incredible.
I found this little secret coffee
place down the street from here.
And, uh, oh, I was
thinking of getting a puppy.
But, you know, you have
to be home with a puppy
and I'm always here. So
I went down to the pound,
'cause I... I wanted to
get it out of my system.
You know, the puppy love.
And I held all of these
incredibly sweet dogs,
and you would
have been really...
really proud of me, Owen.
I didn't take one home.
I went out and
got a fish instead.
Let me see. What else? Oh, I got
a bikini wax. Yeah, an actual wax.
I haven't had one those since,
remember I tried to wax myself...
- What is your point?!
- You were my best friend!
My best friend who I
could tell everything to.
And now you won't
even look at me.
'Cause you said you loved me.
You said you loved
me, too. And then...
- And then you chose Yang.
- You chose her, too.
You chose her, too.
I feel like I'm cheating on her.
When I talk to you, I feel like
I'm cheating on her. So I'm sorry.
I miss my best friend, too.
Don't you have
something else to do?
This is the closest I've been to
the inside of an OR in a week.
Last week, I would have
been paged in to help.
Now, I'm paged about
fundraising brunches.
I'm adopting Sloan's baby.
It's the right thing to do.
- I think I can.
- Mm-hmm.
I certainly want to.
Callie said she'd help.
- I'm having a baby.
- Congratulations.
- I'm happy for you.
- I'm happy for you, too, chief.
It's what you always
wanted, right?
Yep.
It's what I've always wanted.
How is he, Dr. Bailey? It
looks like you're nearly done.
And it's just in
time for dinner.
And maybe even some dancing.
- If the patient looks good...
- He'll be just fine.
He won't be dancing
anytime soon,
but when the time comes
and he wants to go out dancing,
he will be perfectly capable of
making that determination himself,
without any help from anyone.
And I don't need any help here,
so if you are through
helping me, you can go.
- I just...
- Now.
- She's nice. Chatty.
- Stop talking.
To be fair, I never said a
word about dancing, although...
Shh! What is all this bleeding?
Ah! Splenic artery's torn.
He's gonna lose this spleen.
Lap pads!
Where's my patient?
No idea. He must have left.
I need help in here!
There you are. I've got your
wife's clothes for the breakfast
and I made note cards for
your speech for this morning.
- Good. Go home.
- If you're here, I'm here.
Honestly, I'm happy
to help with this.
You wanna be an
executive assistant?
You should want to do
surgery. That's all I want to do.
I'm not sure I can.
I... Look, I'm grateful
that you hired me back.
It's just been easier to
help out with this stuff.
It's easier coming back as that,
rather than coming back as the doctor
who made a mistake and killed
someone. Killed someone's mom.
And I'm not sure I can be that person.
So if you're not sure you need me,
then maybe I shouldn't be here.
Dr. Shepherd? I have a
patient with an epidural bleed.
Come with me.
- You couldn't do it?
- Actually, we could. Um...
You need to prepare yourself. We needed
to take some extraordinary measures.
Your arm needed a blood supply to
keep it alive until we could reattach it.
So we had to relocate it
to where we could get one.
Is that my arm?!
What did you do?
Why would you do this to me?
- What did you do to me?!
- It's only temporary.
OK, just for a few days.
Frankie, this is what you wanted.
- You wanted your arm.
- In the right place!
I said I didn't want to be a freak!
You should have left me like I was!
Oh, come on. Did you
even tell him you're leaving?
Look, I just wanted
a place to stay.
And some money. I didn't know
he was gonna care this much.
He bought a crib.
He's a good man.
And he'll be very
good to your baby.
You could know the baby, if Mark
raised him. You could come back and visit.
I don't want to know
where to come back to.
If I give him to you
guys, it's still my baby.
And I need him to
be somebody else's.
I mean, my dad got a
clean break from me.
And look at him now.
Don't I deserve that?
Prenatal vitamins are
not a joke. Take them.
And do not skip any
doctor's appointments.
And if you get into any trouble,
or you have a
problem with anything...
call us.
Just... take care of yourself.
Thanks.
- Mrs. Banks?
- How is my husband?
There's been some complications,
but Dr. Bailey's working very hard.
And I'll let you know
more as soon as I do.
Is... Is Emile still here?
Emile is in surgery.
There's been some
bleeding in his brain.
Oh, my God.
Oh, God.
He never said a word.
For 15 years.
Did you know?
Why do you think I
kept going back there?
But then I met Bob,
and Emile never...
I made a choice.
- But you kept going back.
- I did.
Because Bob liked it.
And I love Bob.
It became our place.
And, yes, he orders for me.
Because he knows what I like.
And it may seem like
we have nothing
left to talk about,
but sometimes it's
nice not to have to talk.
Fifteen years ago,
I made a choice.
And I keep making it every day.
That's what marriage is.
That's a lot of damage to his pancreas.
I can't get this bleeding under control.
OK. More suction! More!
The middle meningeal
artery's completely severed.
What did I miss? I've been
literally watching this guy all night.
- How could I miss...?
- - You didn't miss anything.
First CT was negative, there
were no neurological symptoms.
The kind of bleed you never
know about until it's too late.
- Is it too late?
- I don't know yet. Bipolars.
- BP's 80 over 60, falling!
- - Push another atropine!
Damn it. Come on!
Damn it, come on!
Stay with me! Come on!
Stay with me!
Come on! Stay with me!
Stay with me. Come on.
Come on.
The dude waited on tables and
watched his life happen without him.
He's probably better off.
I can't... I can't do this.
I can't just... I can't
just watch people die!
I... I shouldn't have come back.
Listen.
I made a mistake last year.
I almost walked away.
If you don't feel the losses...
if they don't hurt
you and humble you,
that's when you know you're
not cut out for this kind of work.
You can be a good
surgeon, Kepner.
It's why I brought you back.
Congratulations. I
thought we'd lost him,
- but you managed to...
- I can't talk to you.
Right. Um... Look, I'm sorry.
- I thought you and I might...
- I can't talk to you.
You make me nervous.
I forget what I...
And I say things I
don't want to say.
And I can't...
I just go stupid.
I... I like you.
That's all. There.
- All right.
- And so if you
want to go to dinner,
fine. We'll show
up and try to talk.
- How's tomorrow night?
- Fine. I might have surgery.
I might join you.
You can tell your patient
her husband's gonna be OK.
- What about Emile?
- Shepherd said there was no way
to know it was detectable
until it was too late. Here.
- I think this means you win.
- I know. I don't want it.
I don't want it either. You
would have won anyway.
- You think?
- Of course.
- That's her husband.
- Grey, you ready to scrub in?
I have a valve replacement.
You know, I...
Yang is still here.
Can she do it?
We have to keep
reinventing ourselves,
almost every minute.
Because the world can
change in an instant.
Hello, Mrs. Banks.
How's Emile doing?
I'm sorry.
We did everything we could, but the
bleeding in his brain was too severe.
I'm very sorry.
Thank you.
And there's no time
for looking back.
All those people out there.
They just want to stare at me.
They do.
The doctors want to see you,
they want to ask you questions.
Because you're very rare.
And special.
There might be press.
And there's a personal injury
lawyer floating around somewhere
that thinks that restaurant
might owe you a lot of money.
How much money?
Sometimes, change
is good, right?
I don't believe you.
You don't have to do that.
I wanted to before you got home.
And you don't have to
do what you offered to do.
I'm not gonna hold you to that.
- Mark...
- But thank you
so much for offering.
And, uh...
it could be kind
of great, right?
Sometimes, the
changes are forced on us.
What are you doing?
Sit down.
Sometimes, they
happen by accident.
Oh, get used to
it. I'm keeping it.
You should. You're moving on.
I didn't mean that
was a bad thing.
It's what you should do.
- I hate Valentine's Day.
- Me, too.
And we make the most of them.
Hey, Owen. Hey.
- Hi. Do you have a minute?
- I'll wait in the car.
No, stay. It's fine if you stay.
I said that I love
you and it's out there
and I know that I
can't un-ring the bell,
but I'm un-ringing
the bell. I take it back.
- I'm gonna go...
- No, stay.
I miss my friend, Owen.
More than anything,
I miss my friend.
The rest I can deal with.
I can deal with it. It's...
I have a job that I love,
and an amazing student to teach,
and I've got a
cottage with deer,
and a fish and various
waxed body parts.
I'm gonna be fine!
You and I are gonna be friends.
And you're doing a valve
replacement with me in ten.
- Really?
- Go prep 2219.
OK.
I'll see you at home.
We have to constantly come
up with new ways to fix ourselves.
You can't un-ring the bell.
I know.
But I am gonna try like hell.
So we change.
We adapt.
Congratulations.
- Good to see you, chief.
- Good to see you, too.
- Hey!
- Hi.
- You didn't have to come.
- I know I didn't. I chose to.
- Shall we go in?
- Yes.
We create new
versions of ourselves.
- Mrs. Shepherd?!
- I know.
- Mrs. Shepherd?
I don't do brunches. I
don't miss surgeries.
And I don't do Valentine's Day.
We just need to be sure
that this one is an
improvement over the last.
You're gonna have to make
this up to me with a lot of sex.
Yes, dear.