NARRATOR Previously on ER:
- Are you loving motherhood?
- Yeah.
- I hope this isn't awkward.
- What? That you and I are equals now?
Dr. Crenshaw is our new
chief Resident. Neela Rasgotra.
Two years in ER, then defected.
Took that long to figure
you were wasting time?
- I'm your daddy.
- What's up?
How's the new intern?
- She's very, uh, devoted.
- Thank you, Jesus.
Were you the best one there?
How many people did you save?
Did you rock?
Next time you don't
do what I tell you to
do or any other
Attending tells you to do...
you're gonna find yourself getting
rushed right out of this program.
You don't appreciate that I
took the time and the money...
to buy you some new clothes.
I didn't ask you to do that.
No, because you'd rather go to
school dressed like a bag lady.
Would you rather I dress like a slut?
Because that's how the other girls dress.
I'd rather you dressed like someone
that has a mother that cares about her.
- Tony, would you please say something?
- Good morning.
What's wrong with
the way I dress?
She won't even try
on the clothes I bought.
Those are nice.
They're ugly.
And I refuse to conform to some
anorexic, media-fueled ideal of beauty.
That's fine, but you're not
leaving the house dressed like that.
Tony?
I hate living here!
We never resolved
the nanny issue.
Do you really want someone
else raising our child?
Well, I'm just talking
about a few hours a week...
so I can get some
stuff done around here.
I thought we had agreed
to stagger our shifts.
Well, and what,
never see each other?
I mean, even if
that was practical...
after your first day alone, you'd
be begging for help, trust me.
Mm. I think I can handle it.
Well, if you can handle it so well,
help me get Joe in the car, will you?
We're late for our first
mommy-and-baby class.
What?
Nothing.
What? I thought it
would be fun for... What?
I didn't say anything. What?
I'm late for work. Bye.
I'll call you later.
Don't forget his frog.
I know. Come here. Oh.
Can you say,
"Daddy is a butthead"?
Hm?
Why is your daddy
a butthead? Shhh.
I look like a dork.
- No, you don't.
This is not my style,
and this is not me.
If you didn't like what
your mom bought...
ask to go shopping again
and buy something together.
What are you doing?
Damage control.
- Sarah.
- What?
- This is not cool.
- Do you mind? I'm changing.
I hope your mother
doesn't find out about this.
She won't.
And besides, you don't know what
it's like for girls my age these days.
Hmm.
- There is a lot of pressure at school.
- Oh.
What you wear, what
you eat, what you don't eat.
- What's his name?
- Who?
This is obviously about a guy.
- No, it's not.
- Yes, it is.
Maybe I should
dress like a hussy.
Maybe we should
get you a plaid jacket...
and we'll just tell
everyone you're a lesbian.
- Adam.
- Huh?
Adam Horner. He
doesn't even look at me.
Well, good. I don't want some
guy named "Horn Dog" near you.
It's Horner.
Listen, most guys are jerks,
but if you want this guy...
Okay, wait a
minute. You're a guy.
Exactly. If you want
this guy to notice you...
forget about your
clothes and ignore him.
- That's your advice?
- Yup.
- Ignore him?
- Yeah, that's right.
Wow, you really suck at this.
Most guys want
what they can't have.
You ignore him, that guy
will come running to you.
Try not to kill anyone today.
Bye.
He's out. PRATT: All right.
Hope, you're gonna take a deep
breath and you're gonna hold it.
Now, if you don't get the tube
in by the time you run out of air...
we're gonna stop and bag.
Okay? Are you ready?
With you and Jesus
guiding my hand, I am.
Right.
Okay, sweep the tongue to the side
and advance until you're in the vallecula.
Elevate the scope
at a 45-degree angle.
- See the cords?
- Uh-uh.
I'll give you some cricoid
pressure. How's that?
- Uh-uh.
- All the cords should be there.
He's a young guy. Pull up more,
but do not rock back against the teeth.
Aim the end of the handle to
where the wall meets the ceiling.
Can you see the
aryepiglottic folds? Hello?
Sats are dropping. Pratt.
All right, pull out.
You bag. You breathe.
I'm sorry. I ran...
If you were doing what I told you, you
should've been able to pass the tube.
- Maybe you should sit down.
- Yeah.
- Okay.
- I don't feel so good.
All right, I'm in.
- Here, this should keep it from swelling.
- Oh, bless you, Sam.
- What happened to her?
- Nothing.
- It's only the morning test.
- What are you doing with the beeper?
I gave that to Jane.
I don't think she
wanted it, so I offered.
You can't monopolize the beeper.
Residents need the experience.
- She gets airsick.
- What's with your rhabdomyolysis guy?
- He's stable, making urine.
- What about his creatinine?
- I have to check the chart.
- Peak CPK?
- Medicine team's all over it.
- You gotta be all over it.
You cannot let the
internal med docs take over.
- I can't?
- Hey, I'm serious, man.
You've got critical patients,
stay on top of the labs.
But the guy was
ready to hand off...
- And what?
- And it was a good talk.
What's going on with
the PACS system?
Down. They said they should
have it running in an hour.
They've been saying
that since yesterday.
So is it true?
Rumor is you killed an intern.
Yeah, I wish.
Everything in this place is
crap. The equipment sucks.
The students are incompetent.
The interns can't finish a chart.
The Residents, they don't
give a damn about their patient.
Yeah, okay, okay, Kovac.
I see what you're gonna say,
that I was the same way. I wasn't.
- I didn't say anything.
- I could chart, clear beds.
I never passed
out tubing a patient.
I know, you were
really, really special.
You need to go through in-service
exam results with your Residents.
Have you seen these? See, this
is exactly what I'm talking about.
They don't know jack
about emergency medicine.
Soloman's an idiot. Hope is
annoying and incompetent.
Gates should've stayed
a paramedic, and Jane...
- What's wrong with Jane? She's good.
- No, Jane is creepy. I'm serious.
Always sneaking up on me,
like those twins in The Shining.
Look, in-service shows their strengths
and weaknesses. So focus on that.
They all have their own learning
process, so you need to adjust accordingly.
If the Residents fail, it may be
because you're a bad teacher.
One, two, up on three.
And mommies let go. Okay, good.
Everyone pick up their babies.
Hi.
I'm sorry I'm late. I'm
Abby and, uh, this is Joe.
Hi.
Um, am I in the right place? Is
this the mommy-and-baby class?
Yes. Yes, it is.
Good. Well, uh, I'm a
mommy and, uh, this is a baby.
Yeah, being
suspended by his crotch.
Excuse me?
You're carrying your
child in a device...
that can cause hip
luxation and spinal injury.
He should be in a sling.
Oh, well, you know,
I'm a doctor, um, and...
Then you'd think
she'd know better.
She's sitting right here.
Well, um, then you should know
that, um, a happy, healthy baby...
is always carried in a sling.
Well, I do know that if
you dress your baby...
like some sort of
designer accessory...
you're headed for problems.
But don't worry, I
work in the ER...
so I'll be there to take care of
her when she comes in, 14...
pregnant with a drug overdose...
Maybe this isn't the
best class for you.
Thank you so much
for the lunch tray, Archie.
I particularly enjoyed
the bread pudding.
You're welcome, Emma.
That's one of my favorites too.
Ah. The return of Goat Boy.
I heard one of the doctors made a charm
bracelet from all they took from his belly.
Here's what we got:
stable CHF, going to Tele.
Seventy-six-year-old lady
with pyelo, had Levaquin.
Incomplete miscarriage.
Do a repeat pelvic, see if...
- Wait a minute. What the hell are these?
- Pass-ons.
Her BP's low. Like 90, systolic. It's
up with 2 liters and her crit was 24.
- Did you type and cross for transfusion?
- No. That's a good idea. Do that.
Two-year-old with possible meningitis.
Ceftriaxone onboard, currently at CT.
Needs an LP when he gets back.
- Morris, we do not sign out spinal taps.
- Since when?
Wait a minute. Hold on.
These aren't pass-ons.
They're train wrecks.
I'm not taking them.
I can't. Max has a soccer
game. I promised I'd be there.
- Who?
- My son. It's a family thing.
Yeah, his family even
know about you yet?
No, we're keeping that
on the low-low for now.
You know what I'm saying?
Exactly. Thanks, dog.
Did you just see that?
Yup, he's your dog boy.
He's not my dog
and he's not my boy.
And we don't use
the two together.
I know.
You gonna take one of these?
Nope, I have a trauma coming in.
And you're not always gonna have
another Attending on shift with you.
You need to learn how to
handle these things on your own.
Mr. Jennings is on his way up to
Ortho and Lundquist is out of here.
Nice job, Ray. Here's four more.
Are you kidding me? Is this
about the transport beeper?
And we wrap...
We try to keep it tight
enough to immobilize...
but not to the
point of discomfort.
You don't wanna
cut off circulation.
Soloman, you know,
you didn't do so hot...
on the ortho section
of the in-service.
What's the difference between
a Jones and a dancer fracture?
Dancer's a proximal avulsion,
does great with conservative therapy.
Jones is transverse, a little more
distal. There's a good chance of nonunion.
Let me guess, you
had a patient like that.
No.
Right. Come on.
- Who's got somebody in Curtain 2?
- Uh, me, sir.
Forty-eight-year-old, PSVT,
uh, resolved with adenosine...
Excuse me, is
your boss still here?
- Excuse me?
- I need to speak with Archie.
Dr. Morris is not my boss, and
I'm afraid he's gone for the day.
Is there something I
could help you with?
No.
Jane, you need to
focus on cardiology.
What are the options with
a hemodynamically-stable...
wide-complex tachyarrhythmia?
Lidocaine, if you think V-tach.
What else?
Amiodarone.
Okay, I'm guessing amiodarone.
Well, procainamide and
amio can do the trick...
but you wanna stay away
from beta and calcium blockers...
because you'll end up with a V-fib
if you have a bypass tract, right?
So how'd you manage to fail every
subsection of the in-service exam?
I guess I just don't test well.
Yeah, well, you
better start. Come on.
- Have you got something to present?
- No, I started with Dr. Kovac...
- Where are your charts?
- I'm still working on them.
Keep them current.
Do them as you go.
What part of this concept
don't you understand?
Five-year-old with
crush injury to abdomen.
He and grandpa were
chopping down a tree.
Grandfather with
chain saw injuries.
Got it. Keep working up your
patients and grab more charts.
He needs O-neg, a
second line. Page Surgery.
- Where are you going?
- Saw injuries can be gnarly.
You need to finish with the patients
you've got before you do anything else.
- Dr. Rasgotra?
- Yeah?
- Hi, I'm Katey Evans. Medical student.
- Hey.
Dr. Crenshaw told me
to shadow you today.
- He did?
- I got the feeling I was on his nerves.
- He gives that impression to everyone.
- See you, Katey.
- Friend of yours?
- Hardly.
We went out a couple
times. It didn't work out.
Oh, that's too bad. He's cute.
Cute, but he's way too into himself,
and to be honest, he's orally challenged.
Oh, bad breath?
Not exactly. He won't
go south of 14th Street.
- You know, he refuses to dine at the Y?
- Oh.
Oh, I'm sorry.
This is what I'm talking about,
making friends and saving lives.
Does it get any
better than this, ladies?
No, it does not.
So Mrs. Draper is back for her
27th hospital admission status.
- Post-pancreatic pseudocyst.
- Twenty-seven?
Yes. Tell her the hospital
stopped giving frequent-flier miles.
Oh, and she's a
chronic rectal discomfort.
And you two get to work her
up and review her old charts.
All 27?
No, why don't you just forget
all about visit six, 13 and, uh...
What do you think, 21?
Yeah, that should keep it interesting.
It'll be like playing patient roulette.
Be prepared to present
her at afternoon rounds.
Smiles all around.
Maybe he should
use his surgical skills...
to remove that bug from his ass.
Saved. We've been paged.
I'm glad I'm not doing an ER
rotation. I've heard horror stories.
Oh, it's not so bad. Once
you get used to the smell.
- Line is good to go.
- Pressure's 85 after the bolus.
- How much O-neg?
- Forty per kilo, 800 cc's.
Chest and pelvis films are back.
- Let me see.
Sam, your son's school called.
He never showed up for homeroom.
What? I dropped
him off this morning.
Type and cross four units.
He's losing a ton of blood.
- Crush injury?
- Yeah, unstable pelvis.
Open-book fracture
with complete...
SI-joint disruption and
lateral displacement.
- I got the T-POD.
- How's the belly?
Spleen is okay.
Looks like a liver lac.
So he goes to Angio first?
Immobilization.
Hypotension, pelvic fracture...
- Fifty percent mortality.
- Blood in the meatus.
- Tore his urethra, that'll have to wait.
- Along with his liver.
If they can stop pelvic bleeders in
Angio, he might make it to the O.R.
Okay, bring blood, FFP, and
get him on a portable monitor.
It wasn't a very big tree. It was
only about 8 inches in diameter.
I was just finishing the cut
when the chain saw broke...
- Aah!
- Sorry, about that, Mr. King.
We're gonna get you
numbed up right now.
Another five of lido to me.
- How are we doing?
- He's lucky.
Most of these wounds look superficial.
I'm just gonna clean and close.
How's my grandson?
Uh, his injuries are serious.
He's bleeding internally,
but he's hanging in there.
- Can I see him?
- Not right now.
We're taking him upstairs and we're
gonna try to stop the bleeding, okay?
You good down here if I
go up to Angio with him?
Yeah.
I'm good. Go.
Okay.
I was being so careful.
I thought he was safe.
Don't worry. We're doing
everything we can to help him.
- Are you almost finished in here?
- No, why?
- I could use your help in Curtain 2.
- You gotta be more specific, Ray.
Morris' little old UTI lady...
the one waiting for a
ride, has a systolic of 55.
Damn it, Morris. All
right, here, keep irrigating.
- Set up another suture kit.
I'll be back. MARQUEZ: Got it.
Seventy-six-year-old, fever and
gram-negative rods on the UA.
Morris said she was tucked,
nothing to do. Guess he lied.
Tachy after 2 liters. He
should've seen this coming.
- Access?
- PIV. We're working on...
Pratt!
Rennie Stevens,
welding-tank explosion.
Second and third-degree
burns over chest, face and arms.
- Vitals?
- Tachy, BP, 138/90, sat 82.
- Other one's more stable.
- Other one?
Luis Escobar, 23, shrapnel
to neck and left chest.
Vitals stable. Good
breath sounds.
- I'll page an Attending.
- I'm an Attending. Put him in Trauma 2.
Jane, you're with Haleh.
Soloman, you're with
me. Trauma 1. Let's go.
Titrate dopamine and mix up Levophed
if she doesn't respond to 10 mics.
- All right.
- All right?
Alex, where are you?
No, you're not. Don't lie to me.
The school called the hospital.
Well, you got 10
minutes to get back...
Soloman, help Sam
make some room.
Give me something for the pain.
Another five of morphine.
Hang tough, we're
gonna help you.
Start a second line. Two
liters of LR, wide open.
- Full thickness over the entire chest.
- I'll alert the Burn Unit.
- Sats down to 83.
- Listen to me, Mr. Stevens.
We need to put a tube
in to help you breathe.
Eight-O and an intubation
tray. I'll be right back.
Talk to me.
Blunt and penetrating
trauma. Thrown against a wall.
Looks like shrapnel to
the upper torso and neck.
- Hey, what's your name, man?
- Luis. Luis Escobar.
How's Rennie?
We're working on
him, now it's your turn.
- Tell me where it hurts.
- My chest.
- BP, 95/65.
- Yup, he's decreased on the left.
- Sats, 92 percent.
- Any pain here?
All right, CBC, chemistry,
coags, type and cross for two...
liter of Ringer's,
C-spine chest and pelvis.
Page Surgery. I'll be back.
Doing good, Mr. Escobar.
That's it, Max.
That's it. Hustle!
- Go, Stuart. Stay with it.
- Come on, Max. Come on, take this guy.
If you can't go around
him, go through him!
- Hey, come on, man.
- What?
You're not setting
a good example.
Come on.
Nice, nice, buddy. You're
killing them out there.
Who's that with your son?
I don't know.
Excuse me, coach?
Who's Max talking to?
Uh, not sure. Said
he was a friend.
Chest x-ray on Escobar.
Pneumothorax on the left. Send
him for a chest tube. I'll be right over.
- Hard time finding a line. JANE:
Dr. Pratt, he's bradying down.
Hold on. Try a saphenous. If
that doesn't work, go central.
- Right.
- Heart rate's in the 40s.
I need to put a tube in your
chest to re-expand your lung.
- Need any help?
- Push 50 mics of fentanyl.
- What's going on with Morris' patient?
- Uh, I think she's okay.
- I handed her off to Gates.
- Gates.
- You left her with Gates?
- Yeah, he's all over it.
All right, you're gonna feel
some pressure here, okay?
Gates is an intern, Ray.
Who's supervising him?
I guess, officially, you are.
Jane, find out what's
going on with Gates.
- I'm not having any luck with the ABG.
- Angle the needle at 45 degrees.
I can't see. My
glasses keep fogging.
Next time you should leave
the HAZMAT uniform at home.
- Feel for the pulse. See that?
- Yo, doc.
Your sheet-metal guy in
Exam 3 lost his foot pulse.
Nurses can't get his leg out.
Tell them to give him 5 more morphine
and grab me a Doppler. I'll be there.
Someone grab me a central line kit.
This young lady needs a CVP monitor.
You're putting it
in a central line?
Early goal-directed therapy for
sepsis. All the kids are doing it.
- Are we gonna get in trouble?
- No, this lady is in trouble.
We're trying to save
her. That's what we do.
God, please give us the strength and
the knowledge to save this sweet woman.
Hallelujah to that, sister.
Good embolization...
of the superior gluteals
and pudendal arteries.
That ought to buy
you a little time.
- Pressure's back down to 60.
- Another 400 of PRBCs.
Crenshaw's standing
by in the O.R.
Looks like the
liver lac opened up.
His heart rate's dropping.
- Damn it.
Yeah, let's transfer
him. One, two, three.
Mic of atropine and
squeeze in the blood.
- Want me to continue bagging?
- No, see what they need in the ER.
I've got this.
Hi, it's me.
Mommy-and-baby was a freak show.
Um, so we're headed to the
park and I thought maybe...
if you had a couple minutes...
you might wanna
come by and say "hi."
I'm gonna look for some normal
moms, so we'll be here for a while. Bye.
- Hi.
- Hey.
- Can I sit here?
- Sure.
- Is everything okay?
- She thinks she's pregnant.
Oh, congratulations.
- Oh, no.
- No?
No, the father is the husband
of the woman she works for.
Oh, wow, that's...
- What's she gonna do?
- I told her to have an abortion.
That's what I did.
You got pregnant with the husband
of the woman you work for too?
It happens.
Uh-huh.
What'd she say?
The only husbands that don't
fantasize about banging their nannies...
- Are the ones who are already doing it.
- It's our nanny motto.
- Oh, you're all nannies?
- Yeah. Aren't you?
Yes.
Yes, I am.
- Tube's in position. No pneumo.
- Vent pressure's almost 50.
The chest wall's
restricting lung expansion.
He needs an
escharotomy. 10 blade?
Sats down to 84.
All right, put the vent rate up to 25
and the tidal volume down to 500.
Soloman, I need room, man.
Okay, Mr. King. We're gonna
find you a new parking spot.
Mr. King?
Mr. King, can you hear me?
- Son of a bitch.
Pratt. The little head
lac's not so little.
Keep pressure on it. He
must've hit something arterial.
Re-check the crit and
type and cross for two.
Okay, okay, sats are coming up.
- Thank you. HALEH: We
need an Attending in here.
Pratt, take a look at this.
Fluid in the spleen?
Looks like a hematoma.
- Where's Surgery?
- Paged them three times.
- Anything in the abdomen?
- Nothing.
- Vitals stable?
- Tachy, but pressure's okay.
Second hematocrit's 38.
- Entrance, exit lateral to the midline.
- Doesn't penetrate platysma.
Burn Unit on two.
IV blew. Can we get
a second line in here?
- Grandpa's crit is down to 29.
- I'll be right there.
- What's going on with Gates?
- Uh, he's asking for a rib spreader.
What the hell would he be
doing with a rib spreader?
I'm not really sure.
Pratt, what do you want me to do?
- Just a sec.
- What's going on out there?
- We were stuck upstairs.
- What do you need?
- Burn Unit is holding.
- Page Kovac.
- Don't bother.
We left him with the pelvic
trauma. The boy crumped in Angio.
All right, Neela, get this guy up to
CT. Ray will fill you in on the way.
Haleh, transfer the
Burn Unit call next door.
- Jam it into overdrive. Go.
- Stay with him.
Come on, ref, that's a foul.
Come on, this is
soccer, not water ballet.
Way to go, buddy. Dig
deep. Work that ball.
Hey, sorry I'm late. I
got hung up at work.
- How are they doing?
- Winning 2-1.
- Go, Stuart, go.
- Come on, Max.
You stay with him, buddy.
Come on, Maxi. Kick in
the afterburners, baby.
Do you know that guy?
No, who is he?
Apparently he's
a friend of Max's.
Never seen him before.
Okay, don't get
fancy, don't get fancy.
Just put it in the
net. Put it in the net.
Goal!
Yes, baby.
That was a rocket, huh?
That's gotta hurt, right?
Yes. All right.
- See that?
- Yeah, that was beautiful.
You were giving them a
taste of Max-imum destruction.
Yeah!
Hey. What the hell do
you think you're doing?
- Did you touch my kid?
- What?
- You touched my kid.
- Wait. He's not your kid?
- Well...
- No, I don't know who this creep is.
Is this how you get your
jollies, touching boys?
- Whoa. You're making a big mistake here.
- No, you made the mistake.
- You freaking pervert.
- Hey. Back off.
- What am I, too big for you?
- Yeah, you...
Sir, are you okay?
Wake up, sir.
- Call 911. Get an ambulance.
- Yeah, and the cops.
No, there's no need
to panic. It's all good.
I'm an ER doctor. Okay,
everybody just back up.
Let me do what I have
to do, and give me some...
They spent about a million dollars
on fertility drugs to have this kid.
Look at her. That's
not a million-dollar baby.
Right. Like, take
the hint, lady.
Maybe there's a reason
why Mother Nature...
doesn't want you
having kids of your own.
The woman she
works for is a bitch.
She felt sorry for her
husband. He seemed so lonely.
She was always going away with
her friends and all she did was shop.
My boss has closets full
of clothes she never wears.
Which is good for me.
So you wear her clothes?
- You don't?
- No.
- You fool around with her husband?
- He's ugly?
- No. Oh, no, he's...
He's hot. He's a doctor.
I worked for some doctors.
They wanted the kid safe,
so they let me drive the Lexus.
And they went away a lot, so I
could always use their apartment.
Which they didn't know about.
Of course not.
How are you feeling?
I was a little woozy there for a
bit, but I feel better after my nap.
Bacitracin and gauze dressing.
These need to come out in seven days.
- I could probably take those out myself.
- No.
You need to come
in for a wound check.
Hey, make sure that guy's x-ray
goes up with him to the Burn Unit.
He's had 3 liters of fluid and
needs 7 more in the first eight hours.
Is there any chance I
can be with my grandson?
I don't think so, but we can
get an update on his condition.
CT's back on Escobar.
Grade 3 splenic lac.
Good. Consent for
Surgery. He's all yours.
My chief wants to
observe him down here.
- You told me he tore his spleen.
- With no free blood and stable crits.
His belly's tender, he's
tachycardic, he'll have fluid losses.
The O.R.'s full. We
can't take him anyway.
Well, we can't
keep him down here.
We're getting slammed and
he's tying up a trauma room.
Put him in ICU.
Crenshaw says we can't
use our last bed in ICU.
Hey, that's not Crenshaw's call.
- What do you want me to do?
- I want you to get rid of him.
If his crits are stable for six
hours, he can go to Telemetry.
Neela...
Luis Escobar's
girlfriend is here.
I gotta go find Gates
before he kills somebody.
Hey, when I get back,
that guy better not be here.
Systolic pressure in the 70s after
aggressive fluid resuscitation...
but responded well to a dopamine
infusion at 10 mics per kilo per minute.
- What have you been doing?
- Excuse me.
Central venous oxygen saturation
is in target range at 88 percent.
At this time, patient remains guarded
but stable for Critical Care Service.
- What is that?
- I'm dictating my notes.
And you're kidding me, right?
There's no time to send
stuff to a transcription service.
I need your notes now.
It's so inefficient to
write everything down.
Well, that's how we all do
it, so you better figure it out.
What were you doing
with a rib spreader?
One of your victims
from the explosion...
came in with metal
wrapped around his leg.
It was occluding
blood flow to the foot.
I used the rib spreader
to pull the metal off.
It seemed safer than
a blow torch, right?
Yeah, right.
Okay, hold on, hold on.
One second, one second.
I get it, okay? You're the cool guy,
the paramedic who became a doctor.
I'm sure that all the
Residents are eating up...
your war stories and
tales from the streets.
- I don't tell war stories.
- But this is the ER.
We have a curriculum for
shaping young doctors, even you.
Oh. Is that what this is? You
feel the need to shape me?
Why don't you teach
me? I like the shape I'm in.
I can't teach somebody who
thinks they know everything.
What are you talking about?
You running around here
unsupervised, putting in central lines.
You were busy in a trauma. I
saved some woman and a guy's foot.
- What would happen if you messed up?
- I don't know.
Who would've been
responsible for that? Not you, me.
It would've been my ass on the
line. So do we have to go through this?
I don't know. You gonna
ride my ass every shift?
You're missing the point
here. I didn't mess up.
That's not the point,
and that's your problem.
Who's got the urosepsis case?
- Dr. Gates at your service.
- Maya Tennyson, Critical Care.
- Excuse me, but we're in the middle...
- She's still on dopa at 10?
She's holding her
pressure like a champ.
Hm. Nice work with the
early goal-directed therapy.
By the way, I love the dictation. I
can never read anyone's writing here.
Bluetooth. You speak in this
machine and it prints up at the desk.
I like it. This ER needed an
Attending with some initiative.
I'm the Attending.
He's an intern.
Well, actually, the
Bluetooth was Dr. Pratt's idea.
I wanna see the rest
of your charts now.
I'll bet you do.
Timmy, do they still
put people's names...
on hats and stuff like
that in the gift shop?
I think so. But If you wanna write
your name on your underwear...
a Sharpie works well.
No, I just need to get
a gift for somebody.
- What happened to you?
- I was attacked by ninjas.
What's it look like?
- Who's this?
- Obnoxious soccer dad.
Blunt head trauma with LOC.
Breathing on his own,
normal vitals. What's open?
- Talk to me.
- Nothing to talk about.
Guy came at me, I defended
myself, I'm patching him up.
Why did he come at you?
Have you ever been to a kids'
soccer game? Parents are crazy.
I would never do anything
to hurt my grandson, Irene.
It was an accident.
What were you thinking?
He's only 5 years old. He shouldn't
be anywhere near a chain saw.
He wasn't.
Then why is he in surgery?
Hey, I'm Dr. Pratt.
Uh, Dennis King.
This is my wife, Irene.
I can't believe this.
We only leave our son
with family just to be safe...
and this is how we're rewarded.
We're doing everything
we can for Thomas.
Why don't I have a
nurse take you up...
so you can be with him
when he gets out of surgery?
Dennis, Dennis.
I'm sorry. You know I am.
I know, Dad. I know.
I raised my two boys by myself.
Wasn't easy being a
single dad back then. I...
I don't think I was
very good at it.
I thought I could make up for it
by being a terrific grandfather.
Looks like I blew that too.
Pratt, you got a sec?
Yeah. I'll be right
back, Mr. King.
Thanks.
What's going on?
The police are here for Morris
in connection with some assault.
And there are two moms with the cops
saying that Morris is a child molester.
What?
I got a feeling the white
mom's got a fracture.
What is Morris' problem?
Brain damage is the first
thing that comes to mind.
Dr. Pratt, Escobar's
losing his airway.
Why didn't you intubate
prophylactically?
He didn't seem like he
had respiratory issues.
- He's already got too much swelling.
- Page Crenshaw.
Get someone from ENT down here.
- Sats down to 76.
- Somebody get me a smaller tube.
- A 7-5, a 7-0.
- It's too late for that.
- He might need an open trach.
- Heart rate is dropping.
Please help him. He
was just talking to me.
- Seven-0 won't pass.
- He needs a trach.
ENT's in O.R. 2 doing a neck
dissection. They can't come down.
- ENT needs to be here.
- They're not. This guy needs an airway.
- You sure you can do this?
- I think so.
- How many have you done?
- I've assisted on several.
All right, O.R. girl, please
do not make me regret this.
Katey, Betadine
and sterile sixes.
Without electrocautery,
this could be messy.
- Haleh, take Tina to the family room.
- Sure.
- No, I wanna stay with
him. No. HALEH: Come on.
We'll come get you as soon
as we make him comfortable.
Okay, 15 blade to me.
Neela.
I was hoping there
would be a reasonable...
explanation for your
incessant paging...
but you know
what, this is not it.
I had to do a tracheostomy tube.
Really? And who told you to
do that? Because I sure didn't.
Nobody did. My chief
didn't answer his pages.
- You did this without any supervision?
- Dr. Pratt was here.
Oh, great, that
is such a relief.
Unfortunately, your little ER
forest friends don't count anymore.
You wanna be a surgeon,
huh? Wanna be a big-girl doctor?
This isn't Barbie's
Dream Doll Hospital.
I'm an ER Attending. Dr. Rasgotra
was only following my orders.
Oh, I'm sorry,
hello. Dr. Pratt, is it?
I took your silence
for subservience.
You know, not a lot of ER
Attendings have the skills to do a trach.
Very impressive.
Well, you just, uh, take care of
my girl here and we'll call it even.
You don't need
to worry about that.
Dr. Rasgotra gets
plenty of my attention.
Oh, I think I can
manage this from here.
Why don't you girls,
uh, finish up down here?
You've done more than
enough. Believe me.
Wow, you're so lucky.
- He seems like a great guy.
- Yeah, right.
I'm gonna find the girlfriend,
tell her what's happening.
Hey.
You did good, man.
Thanks.
Must be quiet if you
have time to stand around.
How's the kid?
He's gonna pull through.
How's the grandfather?
Uh, he's worried,
but he'll be okay.
You make out okay here? I
heard you had two more traumas.
Nothing I couldn't deal with.
If it's that quiet, maybe I'll
leave a little early tonight.
Abby could probably use
some help with the baby.
I bet. Go for it.
- Sure?
- Yeah.
I got it all dialed in. This
place practically runs itself.
Can one of you guys look
at a suspected hand fracture?
- Who ordered the films?
- I did.
Everybody was busy.
I'll take it.
Did you find Alex?
Oh, yes, he was ditching
school with a friend at the mall.
Well, I guess I have all
that to look forward to, huh?
Yep.
You saved that guy.
That was so cool.
You mean terrifying.
Dude, you rocked. Did you
see the look on Crenshaw's face?
The one that suggested he was
gonna punish me for what I just did?
You spanked him. And deep
down, I think he probably likes it.
It's always those type-A guys who
are so wound up that they go home...
and put on a diaper or wanna
be led around by a leash.
- You're mad.
- Hey. Hey, Neela.
Hey.
Uh, Ray Barnett. I don't
think we've officially met.
- Katey.
- Hey.
Um, I'm still getting
some of your mail.
Oh, I'm sorry. I'll try to
change everything over.
I don't mind. I just figured
you might need some of these.
- Thank you.
- Okay.
Okay. I'll see you guys
around. It was nice meeting you.
- You two lived together?
- Oh, we were roommates.
I hope you had benefits.
It wasn't like that.
We were just friends.
Why? That guy is smoking hot.
Why? Does he have a girlfriend?
Uh, not that I know of.
Just remembered something.
Um, I'll catch up with you later, okay?
Sure.
Witnesses confirm that
the other guy started...
and you just pushed him away.
I told you that.
But that doesn't
explain touching the kid.
I wasn't touching him.
My relationship to the boy is
complicated. It's, uh, sort of a secret.
No, no, not like that.
Well, your hand isn't
broken. It's just sprained.
Would've been worth a fracture if
I would've knocked out his teeth.
What's gonna happen to him?
He's going to jail.
What do you think
about that, Max?
Wait, wait, wait.
Don't arrest my dad.
What did he say?
Max, what's going on?
This is where I leave.
Good luck with that, Pops.
Mom, Mom, this is my
dad, Dr. Archie Morris.
What's up?
Timmy, did you get it? - Yeah.
- But I didn't get a chance to wrap it.
- Yes. No, it's all good.
Gates, just the man I was looking
for. Here, I got a present for you.
- What's this for?
- It's so, uh, people know who you are.
- Hey, you didn't have to do this.
- Yeah, I did.
Let's see.
What the hell is this?
Students wear short coats.
It helps remind everyone, including
you, that you are still learning.
- You feel better now?
- I feel great, man. Yeah.
Gates.
- Hey.
- Hi.
- How long has he been crying?
- Like 10 minutes.
I think he'll settle down.
How was your shift?
Uh, the usual. I had a
5-year-old kid crushed by the tree.
I don't wanna hear stories about
bad things happening to children.
He survived, okay?
How about your day?
It was divine.
Hmm.
I've been thinking.
Maybe you're right.
Maybe we should get
somebody like a nanny...
No, thanks.
- But I thought you wanted...
- I changed my mind.
No nannies.
Just us.
Doesn't sound like
he's settling down, huh?
I'll get him.
Ah.
Hey, hey, hey.
What's all that crying?
Should I stay Or
should I go now?
If I stay it will be trouble
If I go it will be double
That good?
- I should have stayed a paramedic.
- No.
Doctors are much more sexy.
- Mm.
- Uh-huh.
- Rough day?
- Yeah.
One of my Attendings
has it out for me.
Either that or he's in love
with me. I can't tell which.
How was your temp gig?
Same thing, different people.
Nobody knows you.
Nobody really talks to you.
It's like being
the office ghost.
Do you want a drink?
No, I have to study.
Knock, knock.
You decent?
I'm in my thong.
Guess what.
I take it your homework's done?
Yeah.
I've got some stuff from
school you need to sign.
I left them on the table.
All right.
There's lasagna in the
fridge if you get hungry later.
Thanks.
- Well, you were right about Adam Horner.
- Uh-huh.
I ignored him all day, even when he
was looking at me, and tonight he IM'd me.
The Horn Dog comes through.
- It's Horner.
- Watch it. I bruise easy.
Did you save anyone today?
Yes, actually, I separated
a pair of Siamese twins.
Must be gross seeing
all that blood, huh?
No, I saw more blood
when I was a paramedic.
Besides, I'm half
vampire, so I kind of dig it.
Do you want me
to help you study?
No. I want you to work
things out with your mother.
I'd rather shave my head.
Oh, good, I have a
razor in the bathroom.
We can shave it into
a nice little Mohawk.
Okay, I'm just kidding.
I'll talk to her.
Sometime.
- Tonight?
- Yeah.
All right, hey.
Good night, baby girl.
Night, doc.
For the next hour,
we're gonna be talking...
about abdominal pain
in the elderly patient.
What an important
disease this is.
No pass-ons, no
major tragedy, no death.
- Gates still here?
- You just missed him.
- What about his charts?
- They're over there.
Hey, from what I've
seen, cat's a good doctor.
He's all right. Plenty of
room for improvement.
Dr. Morris, I heard some guy
attacked you. Are you okay?
Oh, yes. Yeah, I
turned the other cheek.
You know what Jesus said.
You know, when those guys...
who trespassed against him, as
those who trespassed against us...
Can I get an amen? - Amen.
Amen.
I have a patient waiting, so...
Good night, Dr. Morris.
God bless you.
God bless all of us.
Hey, you wanna grab a bite
with me and Max and his moms?
- You worked things out?
- Yeah, they're pretty cool.
And if everything goes well at Ike's,
we may really work things out tonight...
if you know what I'm saying.
- I think you do.
- You do know they're a couple?
Yeah, a couple of lesbians
in desperate need...
of a Morris sandwich. Unh.
- You know you're sick, right?
- What?
Good night, Archie.
Could you help me
with a two-layer closure?
Nope. Nope, not now, I'm off.
Weaver should be
here any minute now.
All right, wait, wait.
First off, you never wanna
inject directly into the wound.
It distorts the
anatomy for your repair.
He needs regional anesthesia.
Have you ever done
an infraorbital block?
Not really.
Okay, well, it's pretty easy
once you, uh, know the tricks.
Now, first, what you wanna
do is use your left index finger...
to palpate the
infraorbital ridge.
- Got it.
- Good.
Now you're gonna inject 1
centimeter lateral to the ala...
and advance upward until
you're 5 millimeters from the ridge.
Good, good. Very good.