♪ Just hear those
Sleigh bells jingling ♪
♪ Ring-ting-tingling too ♪
♪ Come on It's lovely weather ♪
Hello.
Hi, Mom.
No. I'm making the
nakypliak right now.
Yeah.
I know it's after 6, but...
But the day just got
away from me, you know?
Yeah.
Uh-huh.
No, I don't... Oh, damn it!
Mommy didn't mean that. No.
No. Everything's fine.
Kate's just a little cranky.
Yeah.
No. I'm feeling better.
Yep. The incision's healed.
Okay, sweetie. Okay.
Shh, shh, shh, shh, shh.
Oh, my God.
♪ There's a birthday party ♪
♪ At the home of Farmer Gray ♪
♪ It'll be the perfect ending ♪
Oh!
♪ Of a perfect day ♪
♪ We'll be singing the
songs We love to sing ♪
♪ Without a single stop ♪
♪ At the fireplace while We
watch the chestnuts pop ♪
When did the pain start?
Few minutes ago. He was
having difficulty breathing.
Get an EKG.
Mr. Rollins...
where does it hurt?
You better watch out. What?
You better not cry.
Let go of my hand.
♪ You better not pout
I'm telling you why ♪
Never mind, Kit.
♪ Santa Claus is
comin' To town ♪
Unless you have a
medical problem...
I do. What?
I'm bored.
Yeah.
Well, at least
you're still alive.
Oh. You mean,
unlike that poor woman
they say I raped and murdered?
We both know
the truth, don't we?
Mm-mm. I'm innocent...
until proven guilty.
And the DA can't prove jack.
Thanks to you.
If I could do things
again, believe me...
I would.
Uh, you would've let me die?
Where'd you get it?
Patient gave it to
me for Christmas.
Pretty. Yeah.
Lucy. Got a good case here.
Valerie Page, 24,
dilated cardiomyopathy
recent progression of symptoms.
Palpitations.
Difficulty breathing.
Cardiologist changed her
medication two days ago.
Throwing PVCs, six
to nine per minute.
And lift. Gently.
I'm on the heart
transplant list.
Okay, how shall we proceed?
Call Transplant Services.
One-oh-five.
Lucy, multifocal PVCs.
What should we do?
Get the vitals.
BP's 95/60. Heart rate's 110.
BP's stable. She's
not hypotensive.
So treat with
lidocaine? Right. Do it.
- She's in V-tach!
- Get the paddles!
No, no, no, no.
Check the vitals again.
BP's 95/60. Heart rate's 160.
Lucy? I don't know.
75 of lidocaine. Two mg drip.
With normal mentation,
and vital signs,
lidocaine is still
your first line of treatment.
It's not a good idea to
shock a patient
who's wide awake.
She's back to normal signs.
You feeling better?
Yeah.
I wasn't planning
on this for Christmas.
We'll alter your medications,
and maybe get you home in
time to open presents, okay?
Lucy?
Lily, draw the cardiac
labs. Chuny, order an echo.
Call me back with the results.
- Okay.
You do not know
enough about this case
to make those kind of promises.
Her meds were off, right?
Truth is, that young
lady will be lucky
if she makes it
through the night.
I didn't realize.
As a fourth year,
you've accumulated
a lot of medical knowledge.
Now you have to apply it.
Go back in there
and get a thorough
history, and find out
what you can do
for your patient.
Hey. What's wrong?
Nothing.
Thanks for covering
the transplant service.
Ah. Happy to.
When it means I spend
Christmas morning with Reece.
Well, at least someone
will be enjoying the holiday.
What about you? No plans?
Just work. Mark's in San
Diego helping his father move.
But with Romano
scarce till the millennium,
it seems like a
holiday, doesn't it?
Yeah, you're right. It does.
Dr. Corday, Detective
Cruson is on the phone for you.
I've got a consult in the ER.
Call me when that appy's ready.
Mm-hm.
Hello, this is Corday.
Yes. Yes, I just
saw Mr. Rollins.
I see.
I discharged the
otitis in Exam 3.
One down, 30 to go.
Whoa... Gee. These
lights are a fire hazard.
Is it always this busy
on Christmas Eve?
Like the malls the
day after Thanksgiving.
I need a break, Dr. Weaver.
We all need a break, Amira...
It's Ramadan. I gotta pray.
Okay. Yosh, cover
for her, please.
What's in your bag, Santa?
Secret Santa gifts,
if you've been good.
Hey, have I gotten yours yet?
It's in my suitcase. I'll
give it to you before I leave.
All right.
Oh. Thanks for organizing this.
Anything to help make
working Christmas Eve
a little less painful.
Did I mention I
wanted a Gameboy?
Yes!
You know, Dr. Weaver,
it's not too late to get
in on this gift exchange.
You know what, John, actually,
there's nothing
that I really need.
Excuse me.
Yes. Uh, gentlemen,
how can I help you?
Oh, no.
Oh.
Now you need some scrubs.
The cardiomyopathy was diagnosed
three years ago,
right after she got the
flu on her 21st birthday.
Some birthday present.
There's dilation
of all chambers,
and an LV ejection
fraction of 10 percent.
Her previous ejection
fraction was 20.
Doesn't that meet the criteria
to upgrade her for transplant?
I'll call UNOS and tell them
to move her status to level one.
Dr. Benton, they're
ready for you in the O.R.
All right. Tell 'em
I'll be right there.
Go over everything with her.
Call Cardiology. See if
they have a bed, okay?
Level one?
That means I'm a shoo-in, right?
Well, there's no guarantee
when a new heart
will become available.
A girl can dream.
You know... I almost
went to med school.
What changed your mind?
Hospitals smell.
I hear you.
I opted for a master's
in fine arts instead.
I'm supposed to
graduate in June.
Really? Me too.
I'm gonna die, aren't I?
If you don't get a
new heart... yeah.
We went to Marty's
for some eggnog,
and I haven't
stopped puking since.
Hasn't anyone ever warned you
about the hazards of raw eggs?
At least we got to
finish our deliveries.
You guys work for a charity?
No. Just a bunch of
Wall Street sharks.
Lawyers, stock traders.
We take gifts to homeless
shelters every year
to keep us human.
Oh, yeah. We could
use a Mrs. Claus
to round out the group.
Well, I could use a glass
of wine and a hot bath.
Dr. Weaver as Mrs. Claus?
Hold it, Carter.
Compazine rectal
suppositories for all the Santas.
And rehydrate until
symptoms subside.
Bah humbug.
If you don't mind me
saying, you look like hell.
Yup. I'm midway
through a double shift.
Drew the short end of the stick?
No, I volunteered. I
figured I'd let people
spend some time
with their families.
Chad?
Chad, wha...? Wha...? Chad.
Get off of me.
Take it easy. Hey, Chad.
Chad, it's Dr. Finch.
We're going to help
you. What happened?
He took a nasty
header down the stairs.
Whoa, watch... Watch
his neck. Watch his neck.
I think he got his foot
caught in the banister.
Did he ever lose consciousness?
Uh, I-I don't know. Maybe.
He's pretty messed up.
On what? On what?
I gotta go. Wait!
Hang in there, dude.
No, Tony!
Chad, do you have any neck pain?
Does your neck hurt?
I'm fine. I'm fine.
Get a C-spine just in case.
Pupils equal...
reactive to light.
No midline tenderness.
BP's 140/90. Pulse 68.
Talus shifted
laterally and rotated.
I need to reduce the deformity.
Okay, I need right-ankle films
and a non-contrast
CT to rule out a bleed.
Also, get a B.A.L.
and tox screen.
I got it.
And call the mom.
Name's Kottmeier.
Phone number should
be in the old chart.
You're hurting me.
Stop hurting me.
It's okay, Chad.
You're gonna be okay.
Ouch.
That is a very
delicate injury, indeed.
We were at the mall
waiting on line to see Santa,
and Tommy really had to go.
I always tell him look
down before you zip up...
but he was in a hurry.
I want to see Santa.
I'm afraid that we're
gonna have to cut it off.
What?
The zipper. I meant the zipper.
I'll get the IND train.
I wanna go back to
the mall! Okay, Tommy.
I have to clean the area first.
This may sting a little bit.
Ow! Whoa.
Hold onto him. Tight.
All right. Pickup and Metz.
Go away!
I can't watch.
Okay, Tommy,
this is gonna pinch.
Ouch!
Ow! Ow!
All done.
I-is he gonna be, you know,
okay down there?
Yeah, once the injury heals,
he's gonna be as good as new.
Okay. Tommy, it's all over.
So brave.
Excuse me, Dr. Benton?
I'm in the middle of an appy.
I can see that. But I've
been doing some research
on Valerie Page's condition.
Watch the sterile field.
And I ran across some articles
on an LVAD: Left
Ventricular Assist Device.
Sponge stick. What about it?
An implanted device could
keep the blood pumping
through her body until
she can get a transplant.
Hm. Not an option.
Why not?
No device.
County isn't using
that yet. Driver.
But we're about to.
A clinical trial starts
as of January 1st.
Yeah, but that's one week away.
I doubt that her heart
will hold out that long.
We can transfer her to Rush.
Their program's
already up and running.
Okay, try and arrange
it. Let me know.
Thanks, Dr. Benton.
Hey, doc. Taking me on a trip?
You could say that.
What's he doing here?
You're being transferred
to the jail ward.
This is a joke, right?
What, are you...? You're
getting back at me?
It's no joke. The police
have found evidence
linking you to another murder.
Wait a minute. Look, stop.
I said stop!
Put him in restraints!
Bitch! Look...
Uh! You cannot do this to me!
Oh, yes, I can!
Screw you.
S... Ow. Ow.
Okay. Spare me the theatrics.
Oh, my leg. My
leg, it's cramped.
Yeah, and I'm the
queen of England. Ow!
Goodbye, Mr. Rollins.
Oh. Damn it, it hurts!
Dr. Corday, wait.
His right leg is a little dusky.
Oh, God. It's like somebody's
jabbing me with needles.
How long have you had this?
It just started.
Can't feel a pedal pulse.
There's no popliteal
pulse either.
Want to get an angiogram?
I suppose so.
Would you hurry
up? It's killing me.
Oh, shut up!
Excuse me.
Fill out a form, take a seat.
Actually, I work
here. I'm Carol.
Ooh. It's about time you
brought those little bundles of joy
around for a visit.
Hi, Haleh.
It's Auntie Haleh. Yes, it is.
I'm... I'm actually
not visiting.
Look at them. Carol,
they're adorable.
You know... Oh, and look at you.
You're almost back to your...
Hold it. Guys.
Kate's not feeling well,
and I just wanna
have her checked out.
Is there an Attending free?
Let's find out.
We'll take good care
of her. Don't worry.
I-I... I'm not worried. LUCY:
It's the season of giving.
But she may not make
it through the night.
Yeah. Me too.
Rush turned you down?
They can't take her
until tomorrow morning.
No cardiac beds.
Christmas morning. Bummer.
Chuny, wait. Is it possible
to get surgical equipment
transferred from
other hospitals?
Sure. We do it between
ERs all the time.
What do you have to do?
Well, get a transfer form
and a doctor's signature.
The mall's closed now.
It's not fair!
One more pin should do it.
Ho, ho, ho!
Merry Christmas!
Santa!
Ugh. Oh. Careful down
there, little Tommy.
Come on up here.
Santa's so sorry that he
missed you at the mall.
But he hears that you've
been a very good boy.
You're not Santa. Oh.
Sure he is, sweetheart.
The Santa at the mall
was fat and wore glasses.
This is Santa's younger brother.
Go away! Tommy, stop it.
Well, Santa's got a toy
in here for you, Tommy.
It's... Oh-ho!
I want the real Santa!
The one at the mall.
Okay, Tommy!
Santa's gotta go now.
But he wants to wish you
a very merry Christmas!
Uh. What do we got?
Yo, Santa.
Carter, Taylor Sparks, 15.
GSW to the left shoulder
during a drive-by.
Vitals stable, BP's
140/90, pulse 100.
Hey, dog, get that
stuff out of my face.
Abdomen's benign.
You remember how
many shots were fired?
Punk-ass Lohman
emptied a clip at me.
All right, let's roll him.
See if there are
any other entry sites.
Trauma panel.
Chest and left shoulder.
Back looks clear.
Whoa!
Ho, ho, ho.
Malik?
Not exactly the
present I had in mind.
Hey, fool, that's mine.
All right. Order
a Doppler study.
If the vessels are intact,
we'll leave the bullet in.
Hey, give me back my piece.
Whatever happened
to "peace on earth,
goodwill towards men, "huh?
You tell us, Santa.
Hey.
You're being a
very, very good girl.
Temperature's 100.1.
It was 99.8 when
I took it earlier.
Mm. When was that?
Two and a half hours ago.
You wouldn't believe
how long it takes us
to get us out of the house.
She could be a little warm
from being all bundled up.
You think I'm
being crazy, right?
No. It's good you
brought her in.
I... I'm sure it's nothing.
But, uh, a fever
in a four-week-old
can be cause for concern.
Exactly. I mean,
it's like I know
all the things that
can go wrong, so...
Uh, if you'd like, uh, we
can do a septic work-up.
Is that necessary?
Probably not. But, uh...
you are the one who
needs to make that decision
for her own peace of mind.
Well, as a nurse I would say no.
And as a mother?
Um. Just wanna make
sure everything's okay.
How about we get
a urine and CBC,
but hold off on an LP till
we get the labs back, huh?
I can live with that.
I want you to draw her blood.
You're the best stick in the ER.
I'll be nice and gentle.
Okay.
How're you feeling?
My mom here?
Not yet.
Chad, is your father around?
Sure. Saw him yesterday.
Christmas photo of
him and his new family
vacationing in Florida.
I'd like to call him. Let
him know what's going on.
He doesn't care.
Me and Mom are better
off without him, anyways.
When can I go home?
We're still waiting
on some test results.
Come on. It's Christmas.
Cleo?
Oh, Dr. Finch. How is he?
Chad has a fractured
dislocation of the right ankle.
And we're waiting on a CT
to rule out any head trauma.
Oh, my God.
I-I don't know
how this happened.
I thought he was upstairs
playing video games.
You were home?
I had some people over.
A small holiday party.
Did you hear Chad fall?
There was music
playing, people talking.
Mrs. Kottmeier, your son
has a blood
alcohol level of 0.26.
Were you aware he was drinking?
No.
All right, I... I let
him have a beer.
One beer, that's it.
It's Christmas Eve,
he's on vacation.
He's had more than one beer.
Well, maybe he took
something from the bar
when I wasn't looking.
I get it.
You think this is my fault.
No, I'm not trying
to place blame...
No, you're right.
I... I should've known
what was going on.
I mean, what kind
of a mother am I?
Why don't you go in to see him?
All right, what do we got?
Howard Waller, 71, MVA,
on his way to midnight mass.
I hit Mary. BENTON: Mary?
As in the Virgin Mother.
He lost control of his car,
accelerated into a nativity.
I think I passed out.
Complaining of back
and abdominal pain,
slightly hypotensive.
BP is 100/60, pulse 90.
Alert and oriented at the scene.
Okay, people. Here we go.
Nice and easy. On my count.
One, two, three.
Trauma panel, C-spine.
Chest films. Spin a crit.
Uh, okay, Mr. Waller,
can you tell me exactly
where the pain is?
It's... It's around my belt.
I only wear this
suit once a year.
It doesn't fit me anymore.
Pulse ox is 95.
Let's get an ultrasound in here.
Find something? Yeah.
Ten centimeter pulsatile mass
on the left side below the ribs.
Could be an aneurysm.
Mr. Waller.
There's a good chance
you'll need surgery
to repair a leak in your aorta.
Is there anyone that
you'd like us to contact?
No, there's no one.
Conni, call the O.R. Tell them
to prep a room now, please.
There's a blockage in
your left femoral artery.
A clot has formed,
preventing blood
flowing to your leg.
This is a potentially
life-threatening condition
that requires immediate surgery.
I'm not letting you fix me up...
so they can put me on trial
for some bogus charges.
If the charges are bogus,
you'll be set free.
Without surgery, you could die.
Yeah? Well, I'll
take my chances.
Besides, you
know, I like it here.
Good drugs.
Food's not half bad.
And I get off just
looking at you.
You know, every night...
after the lights
go out, I lie back...
and think about you.
Mm.
So your answer's no to surgery?
That's right.
Well, you'll need to
sign a refusal of consent.
Well, bring it on.
Merry Christmas, Dr. Benton.
Mm, what's that?
Since I couldn't get
Valerie Page
transferred to Rush,
I had an LVAD transferred here.
That's a $50,000 device.
Don't be mad, but
I... signed your name
as the authorizing physician.
You did what?
You were in the
middle of surgery.
You should've interrupted me.
But there was no time.
Uh... Uh, I can't do it.
What do you mean,
you can't do it right now?
No. I mean, I can't do it.
I'm not qualified to do
an LVAD implantation.
Dr. Romano is the only one.
And he's home for the holidays.
But this could save her life.
I know. Lucy, I'm not
qualified. I'm sorry.
What? Nothing.
He's in V-tach!
Grab the paddles!
Charge to 100.
And clear!
Two hundred! Come on, come on!
Not charged yet.
And clear!
♪ We wish you A
merry Christmas... ♪
Crank it to 360!
And clear!
♪ Good tidings to you
Wherever you are ♪
He's back.
I saw her.
What?
Edith. My wife. I saw her.
She's not here.
I know, I know. She's dead.
But I saw her.
I saw her.
Heard about your
Santa performance.
Ha-ha. First and last.
It's Malik's Gameboy.
Didn't wanna hear his
griping if he didn't get it.
You're a good woman, Haleh.
No, Mom. There's no need
to ruin your Christmas too.
I gotta go, okay?
Bye.
Luka. Any word on Kate's labs?
Yeah, I was just
looking for you.
Her urine is negative,
and white count
is basically normal.
"Basically." What
does that mean?
Uh, the differential
shows five bands.
But that's still within the
normal range for her age.
Well... can't the
lab repeat them?
Yeah, but that would
mean sticking Kate again.
Can we do a manual diff?
You know, I will call
the lab supervisor
to see if he can squeeze one in.
Thanks.
How are you holding up?
In all honesty,
I'm... exhausted.
I'm not surprised.
Yeah, well, you know, I can
handle 40 patients in one shift,
I can't handle two infants.
Welcome to parenthood.
Maybe he's out of
town. Or fast asleep.
Dr. Romano. This
is, uh, Lucy Knight.
Fourth-year medical student.
Eh... Yes, I realize that
it's almost midnight, but...
No, it's about a patient.
It's Christmas Eve!
Y-yes, sir. I
understand that. But...
calling the chief
of staff at home!
Oh, okay. If I could
just exp... Hello?
I want my piece back.
Your gun is now the
property of the Chicago Police.
That's whack. It was a
Christmas present for my little bro.
You were gonna give him a gun?
Yeah, doc. Cost me
some serious dollars.
How much?
Forty. Now give it back.
Hey, I gave it to the police.
So, what am I supposed
to give my little brother?
Here. It's a Gameboy.
Worth at least twice that much.
Your brother will love it.
Yeah, whatever.
Merry Christmas!
I appreciate your coming in.
I feel caught between a
rock and a hard place on this.
Well, how so?
It's obvious Mrs. Kottmeier
cares about her son.
But he needs more than that.
Listen, she's an
alcoholic herself...
Still her alcoholism only
factors in if it interferes
with her ability to provide
for Chad's basic needs.
What if she buys his
alcohol and drinks with him?
Did he say that to you?
No, she did, in so many words.
Peter, did you
consent Mr. Waller?
Yeah, why?
Better get in here.
Please. No surgery.
Mr. Waller, you have a
life-threatening condition.
I'm not afraid to die.
I saw Edith.
His dead wife.
She's waiting for me.
I saw her at the
end of a long tunnel.
And there was this
brilliant white light?
Yeah. It was so peaceful.
What you experienced
was a hallucination due to
an endorphin release while
under severe physical stress.
No. It was real.
If this isn't happening,
I have a pain consult to do.
Sir, if you don't
have surgery...
you probably won't
live through the night.
Ahhh...
That means Edith and I can
spend Christmas together.
Yeah.
I'm sorry.
I really tried. I know.
Trust me, if there
was anything else
I could do, I would
do it... Don't worry.
I plan on beating this thing.
With or without
some... stupid device.
Okay. Get some rest.
Keep your strength up.
Hey.
Merry Christmas.
Merry Christmas, Valerie.
Oh.
Breast-feeding was
so difficult at first.
I felt like this cow with
these huge udders.
You look like a natural to me.
Yeah, well...
being that I do it
every three hours.
When do you sleep, girl?
Oh. Sorry.
No, that's okay. The
kitchen is now closed.
And Auntie Haleh
should get back to work.
May I?
Thanks for the chair.
Oh, OB won't miss it.
Okay.
The manual diff came back.
Kate's white count is normal.
Oh. That's great.
Do you hear that, sweet pea?
You're gonna be okay.
Probably just a virus.
Not too surprising
this time of year.
I'm sorry if I've been...
What, a good parent?
No, I was gonna say
difficult. Yeah, same thing.
Ugh...
I can't believe it's 2 a.m.
Yeah. It's Christmas.
That's right. It's Christmas.
I admitted him to ICU.
Donald, I saw your
name on the board.
What are you doing
here this time of night?
Well, I had a gastroenteritis
turn into an ischemic
bowel on me.
Merry Christmas.
So, Peter,
shall we include Elizabeth
in on your dilemma?
I've got a triple-A patient
who refuses to have surgery,
because he believes
he saw his dead wife
waiting for him
on the other side.
That's funny.
I have a patient
refusing surgery as well,
except mine's
the devil incarnate.
Dean Rollins?
As far as I'm concerned,
good riddance.
And who made you judge and jury?
Ugh. Donald, you have no
idea how despicable this man is.
Oh, I'm sure I don't.
But being a doctor isn't
about your personal feelings.
So let's get back
to your patient.
Well, I tried talking
to him. He won't listen.
But did you listen?
You know, this man
is probably frightened,
and thinking that
he saw his dead wife
makes him feel less so.
If he thought that
you understood that,
maybe he'd be more receptive
to what you have to say.
But ultimately it's
the patient's choice.
Of course.
But we must offer to
do everything we can
to keep them alive.
Okay, Gretel!
Okay, you can stop now!
You've got my attention!
Before you say anything...
I've thought of at least
a dozen reasons why I
shouldn't be doing this.
Uh, not the least of
which is ruining my career.
I'd love to hear others,
but since the police
are on their way...
I have a patient, Valerie
Page, 24 years old,
dying of cardiomyopathy.
She's on the UNOS list.
But an LVAD could
buy her valuable time.
What makes you
think I give a rat's ass?
I'm sorry.
What was I thinking,
coming to you,
a seasoned doctor who supposedly
has dedicated his entire life
to helping people?
While I'm just a
puny medical student
who was stupid enough
to think that she could...
Miss Knight.
What do you want?
I want you to help my patient.
I want you to help me.
Looking for the fat
dude in the red suit.
There's a lot of 'em
around here. Which one?
The one givin' out the Gameboys.
Ah, Chuny. I got this. Hi.
We heard you was givin'
up Gameboys for gats.
Ah.
Uh... well, that's
not exactly true.
I mean, it happened once,
but that was sort of
a... unique situation.
We out of here.
Well, wait. Uh, does it
have to be Gameboys?
Hey, Vivian.
I'm looking for my triple-A.
The guy who saw his dead wife.
Howard Waller? Mm-hm?
Over there.
He died?
Coded less than an hour ago.
You miss me?
I'm curious about something.
Me too. Are you
a natural redhead?
I'd like to see for myself.
I find it fascinating
you're willing to end up
a vegetable for the rest
of your miserable life...
just to win a pissing contest.
Well, that's one contest
with you I'm sure I can win.
If you don't have surgery,
the flesh on your
leg will begin to rot
and become painfully
infected, probably gangrenous.
Ooh. You're scaring
me, doc. Next,
you'll go into septic shock.
Which will drop your
blood pressure so low,
you will have a massive stroke.
You'll wind up
drooling in your food,
wearing diapers.
Rather like that pathetic
creature over there.
Except, of course,
you'll only have one leg,
because they'll be
forced to amputate.
But you'll have
won, Dean Rollins.
Now... is that really
the best you can do?
I'm telling you the truth.
If you choose not to believe me,
then you'll have no one
to blame but yourself.
You do care about me.
Don't you?
As your doctor, I do.
No. Not as a doctor.
As a woman.
Say it.
I care.
Then let's do it.
Crappy generator.
I'm gonna give that Amish
salesman a piece of my mind.
What do you need
a generator for?
T.E.O.T.W.A.W.K.I.
The End Of The
World As We Know It.
Ah, Y2K.
Damn computers rule our lives.
It doesn't take a genius
to realize we're doomed.
Okay. Come with me
for aftercare instructions.
You wanna change
that dressing in 24 hours.
Haven't they fixed
most of the Y2K glitches?
Only takes one pebble to send
ripples across an entire pond.
And you can bet this
place will be a deathtrap.
Okay, I assure you, Mr. Thorpe,
the hospital's mainframe
has been thoroughly
Y2K-inspected.
And they checked the interface
with your front-end terminals?
I... I don't know.
Come on. I'm gonna show you
how well you've been inspected.
Chad, your CT
came back negative,
which means no
injury to your brain.
Thank God. So I can go home now?
I'm afraid not.
I've made arrangements
for you to be placed
in an alcohol-treatment program,
here in the hospital.
You did what?
You can't make me stay here.
As your doctor, it's my duty
to look out for your
well-being and safety.
Mom?
Please, Dr. Finch,
don't do this to us.
I'll try harder, really.
Chad was lucky this
time. What about the next?
I won't get drunk again.
I know you don't believe me,
but this is for your own good.
I just wanna go home.
Please. Dr. Finch.
I'm begging you.
Don't take him away from me.
It's Christmas, for God's sakes.
Which puts Chad at
an even greater risk.
He's out of school, he's
partying with friends.
I promise I won't drink again.
I promise.
Please.
It's all right,
sweetheart. It's all right.
It's all right.
Now, go to the month pull-down.
And change it to January 2000.
Hit "apply." And then "okay."
Done.
Okay. Now try to
retrieve my medical chart.
Okay, Mr. Thorpe. I'm
sure we will convince you
that we run a tight
ship here at County...
"No records found for
December 25, 1900."
1900? What did...?
What did you do?
Tight ship. That's what
they said about the Titanic.
Amira, get Tech
Support down here.
I'm getting out of
here while I can.
What do you mean,
you gave it away?
It was for a good cause.
That was my Secret Santa gift.
So I'll get you another one.
I'm already getting
Cleo a Discman
and Conni a blender.
These guys are
taking you for a ride...
Hey, there's four less
guns on the street.
They can take me
for any ride they want.
There's a horde of troublemakers
in chairs asking for you.
Something about gifts
for guns. Thanks, Haleh.
You're still here.
Where's her mom?
Try Exam 2.
Thanks.
Conni? Keep Exam 2
clear for a while, okay?
Sure thing. Thanks.
Ugh, I can't
believe this hospital
doesn't have
24-hour tech support.
Romano's definitely
getting a memo about this...
It's Christmas, Kerry.
Yeah, which means that
Y2K is seven days away.
All the more reason
they should be here.
Computer problems?
The damn thing crashed on me.
I-I-I-I can't get labs, I
can't get medical records...
You know, I got my
start in Tech Support.
Mind if I take a look?
No. Here you are.
That's how I got into
trouble in the first place.
Well, the... terminal
looks current.
Uh, it's a software problem.
I could download a Y2K patch.
That ought to do the trick.
I guess you can't
make things any worse.
Mm.
I feel the catheter sliding.
There's some minor resistance.
I'll give you suction.
It'd be so easy
for me to just slip.
Oh. At least he's
gonna have to stand trial.
Okay, I've got the clot.
Shirley, check the foot.
911 page to O.R. 3?
What the hell is
Romano doing here?
I feel a pulse.
Good. Let's get
an angio of the leg,
check there are no tears.
Can you finish here?
I've come this far. Go.
How do we check for
ventricular decompression
once the device is activated?
With a transesophageal echo,
you should see the
bowing of the septum.
Fourth-year, huh? Not bad.
Well, it's nice to see that when
the cat's away, the
mouse still jumps.
What's going on?
I'm just teaching Ms. Knight
the finer points of an
LVAD implantation.
You know, from now on, I
think I'm only gonna do favors
for people who come
begging at my doorstep.
Which leads me to ask, Peter,
why wasn't it you?
I never even considered it.
Ah. O ye of little
faith. Dr. Romano,
I again just wanna
tell you how much
I appreciate you doing this...
That's enough
sucking up. Cut, please.
Well, that'll be all, Peter.
I'd like to scrub in.
I'm sorry, Peter, you
didn't earn this one.
Yeah, but I'd
still like to help.
Ms. Knight, what do you think?
I think Valerie can use
all the help she can get.
You heard her, Peter. Scrub in.
The '60s were from 1961 to 1970.
What about 1960?
That was the last
year in the '50s.
Which means the new
millennium really starts in 2001.
Then why am I spending
half my paycheck
on New Year's Eve plans?
You and the rest of the world.
Hey, Sleeping Beauty.
Wow. God, that felt great.
How long was I out?
About four hours.
It felt like days.
Where are the kids?
Asleep in the Pedes
room. Yosh is on duty.
Oh, God. I so appreciate
you guys helping me out.
Hey, what are friends for?
Christmas cookie?
Yeah. I'm famished.
Carol, I heard about
Kate. Is she okay?
Oh, she's fine. Thanks.
Where you off to?
Indianapolis to see the family.
Did they take the
Kottmeier boy upstairs?
Few minutes ago. Okay.
Merry Christmas,
Kwanzaa, all that.
Bye! Safe travel.
I'm sorry I can't put you
and the girls in my two-seater.
Oh, Haleh, don't worry about it.
You have done
enough for us already.
Carol, I can give you a ride.
Since when do you own a car?
Since I sold my boat.
Oh. Well, thank you, but no.
The girls are
asleep, I'd hate...
Look who's up. Come on.
Oh. Come here,
sweetheart. I know.
All right. I'm gonna
go get our stuff.
Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes.
Quite an arsenal.
Yep. After I gave away
all the Secret Santa gifts,
I started writing checks.
Well, call the
police department.
Have an officer come
by to pick them up.
I already did.
Double trauma at the back door.
17-year old drive-by victim.
Single GSW to the thigh.
BP is 130/90. Pulse 110.
Name is Hank Lohman.
You say Lohman?
Carter, take the next one.
Scoop and run, 7-year-old.
GSW to the chest and abdomen.
Had a pulse in the
field, lost it en route.
Get ET tube placement.
What happened?
Kid was opening up his present,
took a bullet aimed
at his neighbor,
guy they just brought in.
Son of a bitch.
Let's hang two units of
O-neg on the rapid infuser
and prep for a thoracotomy.
He's in fine V-fib.
Some sterile gloves.
Pupils are fixed and dilated.
All right, let's prep his chest.
Oh, my God. Where's
the blood coming from?
They shot him in the head.
How you doing?
Full traumatic arrest.
Thoracotomy tray is ready.
Chest is prepped.
There's gray matter
all over this backboard.
He's dead.
Okay. The pump is de-aired.
Decrease bypass flow
to two liters per minute.
Start the LVAD.
Uh, fixed mode, 20
cycles per minute.
The moment of truth.
It works.
You're surprised?
It's so loud. How's she
gonna sleep at night?
Uh, she'll get used to it.
Just like hearing the
beating of your own heart.
Okay. Pump is filling nicely.
Oh, Peter, isn't that
your munchkin out there?
Oh, yeah. Uh... you
mind if I scrub out?
Oh. First you want
in, then you want out.
Yeah, yeah, I
know, it's Christmas.
Go ahead. Get the hell out.
Thanks.
Miss Knight, care
to help me close?
Sure.
If you feel you're up to it.
Absolutely.
Hey. Look, I know I was
supposed to pick him up earlier,
but this surgery came up.
Hey.
Save it, Peter.
It's nothing I
haven't heard before.
Carla, you know
it is the holidays.
We could at
least try to be civil.
You want civil? Fine.
Thank you very much
for ruining my life.
What is that supposed to mean?
Roger and I aren't moving
to Germany anymore.
What?
When Roger asked for
time off for custody trial,
his boss decided he wasn't
promotion material after all.
Um... I...
Look, Carla, I don't
know what to say.
I'm sure you don't.
Look. Okay.
I'm sorry about Roger's job.
But no, I'm not sorry that
Reece gets to stay here
with both his parents.
Whatever, Peter.
You won. Merry Christmas.
Hey.
Look.
Hey, Amira? Mm-hm?
I'm expecting an
officer to stop by.
How about, uh... that one?
Hey, what happened?
Yeah, one punk
shot another punk,
took out a little
kid in the process.
Caught this coward
fleeing the scene.
He's got a nasty
cut on his head.
It's you?
What?
You thought I couldn't
score another piece?
You want a gun?
Here, I got guns. Why
don't you take your pick?
You like this one? How
about this one here, huh?
You just pull the
trigger and bang!
A 7-year-old's brains get
splattered all over the wall.
Carter! Hey! What do you
think you're doing, John?
Merry Christmas!
See how long this lasts.
They had quite a night.
Their first Christmas ever.
It's hard to believe.
It only happens once. Enjoy it.
Hm... Luka, wait. Hm?
Do you have any Christmas plans?
Uh, like those two
over there. Sleep.
Why don't you stay
for some eggnog?
It's the least I can
do, for all you've done.
And what?
And end up like those
Santas? I don't think so.
Come on. It's tradition.
Oh. What's in that
eggnog exactly?
Eggs, sugar... milk, rum... Rum?
You know what? I... I... I
suppose I can risk it, eh?
Okay.
Next few days, a bland diet.
Clear fluids, rice, bread.
Hey uh... Your
computer running okay?
Oh, yes. And thank you.
Thank you so much for your help.
I appreciate it.
Santa always
aims to please. Heh.
Say, you wouldn't know a place
to get bland food around here?
Ah. Well, Doc Magoo's
is right across the street.
And, uh, you can't get
much blander than that.
They're open on Christmas?
Yep. Always open. Just like us.
Well... Sounds
perfect. Thanks. Hm.
Dr. Weaver.
Hm? Care to join us?
Ooh. Ah... My treat.
Um... Free bland food.
Sure.
Great.
So you, uh, work
with computers, huh?
Yeah. I, uh, own my
own software company.
Just went public.
Really?
I'm always looking for
investment opportunities.
Oh.
Since we split the breastbone,
your chest will hurt
for quite a few weeks.
That's a small price to pay.
So... how's our lovely patient?
She's doing great.
Pressure's up, kidney
function's improving.
Good. Well, carry on. I'm
going back from whence I came.
Oh, by the way, Miss Knight.
You're going to have to
come by my office sometime
next week to discuss
suitable disciplinary action.
Nothing personal, but I do
have a reputation to maintain.
♪ So this is Christmas ♪
What was that all about?
Nothing. ♪ And what
have you done? ♪
I cannot thank you
enough, Dr. Knight.
♪ Another year over ♪
I'm not a doctor yet.
♪ And a new one just begun ♪
You are to me.
Mm. ♪ And so this is Christmas ♪
God, I am so tired now.
♪ I hope you have fun ♪
♪ The near and the dear ones ♪
♪ The old and the young ♪
♪ A very merry Christmas ♪
♪ And a happy new year ♪
♪ Let's hope it's a good one ♪
♪ Without any fear ♪