That cancer's
a heavy lift,
but there's strength
in community.
Once I let 'em in,
that was a real comfort.
The truth is,
she chose Phillip.
Right, that night in my car,
she was coming
to show me her ring.
I don't know
what she was
gonna say to you,
but I do know
she wasn't gonna
show you any ring.
He slipped the ring
on your finger when
you were unconscious.
He's lying to you.
It doesn't matter,
because it's over.
I'm sorry.
I should've done
something.
No!
Said something.
Get out of my life.
I know we said
someday, but...
You'd make
the best mom ever.
Mmm. Smells so good.
Frittata with
chicken sausage,
Swiss chard,
and Gruyere.
Too bad
I have to go...
Early shift.
I know, I remembered.
I'm prepping yours to go.
You are too good to me.
Protein, iron, vitamin B
from the dark leafy greens.
Mediterranean
diet breakfast.
Shown to...
Help ovarian health?
Exactly.
Is this what
I think it is?
Uh, fertility chart.
Tracking your
ovulation schedule,
like we talked about.
And good news,
we are in
your fertile window.
Oh, my God, Ethan...
I just...
I thought we'd take
a little more of
a laissez-faire approach.
If our goal
is having a baby,
then we should definitely
be having sex.
Especially when
you're ovulating.
Thank you
for breakfast.
I also put some
folic acid in there,
you know, to prevent...
Birth defects? I know.
Yeah. I know you know.
Are you
ever gonna tell me
where we're going
to dinner tonight?
I'm not telling.
Come on, spill
the beans, please.
I'm not telling you.
Oh, come on.
I like this.
I got us a reservation
at Alinea.
Alinea?
Alinea.
It takes three months
to get a table there.
How'd you swing that?
I might've told them
that I'm dying.
Are you serious?
No, come on,
I didn't do that.
Jesus.
Come on, you know
your wife's
a rock star.
That, I knew already.
Matter of fact, I have
all your albums.
You do.
Alinea.
Hey, you going
to Crockett's crawfish
boil tonight?
Maybe, I don't know.
Well, you should.
You know, with Crockett,
the food and booze
will be great.
Heads up.
Treatment 3.
Tom Lyons, 25,
collapsed in
the stairwell
of his building.
GCS 15, BP's low
at 88 over 55 even
after a liter of NS.
Heart rate's 97
and sats 100%.
Hi, Tom,
I'm Dr. Halstead.
What's going on?
I fell.
Oh, yeah?
Isn't this
all a bit much?
We're just gonna
check you out,
make sure you're okay.
On three.
One, two, three.
Thanks, guys.
Lungs are clear.
CBC, CMP, trops,
and an EKG.
Also, a chest X-ray
and stick him for glucose.
On it.
Really, I'm good.
Not sure why
his pressure is so soft.
Let's fast his belly.
Okay.
Yeah.
It's okay.
Get it out.
Tom, you with me?
Give him two units
of blood now, and get
GI down here to scope him.
What's up with his fangs?
Can't be natural, can they?
I don't think so.
It's odd.
Let me know as soon
as his labs
and EKG come back.
Yeah.
Hey.
Takes a while to
mend a broken heart.
Yes, I'm familiar.
Hmm.
Okay, Maggie.
Hundred pounds
of crawfish
delivered to my place.
I'm fixin' to boil.
Tell me you're still good
for the jambalaya.
Crockett, I've set aside
this afternoon to cook,
cleared my schedule.
You're gonna get
your jambalaya.
Okay, how are we
on the guest list?
Everybody, huddle up.
Get over here.
As you know,
Dr. Marcel and I
are hosting a crawfish
boil tonight,
and you're all coming,
no excuses.
Uh, some of us have
shelf exams coming up.
Attendance
is mandatory, Elsa.
Mandatory party?
MAGGIE AND MARCEL:
Mmm-hmm.
I'm sorry, you guys,
I'm not gonna be
able to make it.
The move back into
my house has been
really hard on Owen
and I'm still
unpacking.
Okay.
Okay, you
get a pass.
But everybody else,
you're coming.
No excuses.
If I can swing it after
a day of chemo,
you can, too.
True that.
Natalie, I have
an MVC coming in.
You're going to Trauma 1.
All right.
Elsa, with me.
Desmond,
what do we got?
Kayla Patten,
seven-year-old
unrestrained passenger,
head injury
with scalp lacs,
GCS 13.
Mom's in the
ambo behind.
All right, let's transfer
on my count. Ready?
One, two, three.
Airways cleared.
Breath sounds bilaterally.
All right, let's get
a chest and pelvis X-ray.
Sats 92%.
BP, 100 over 65.
Pupils are equal, round,
and reactive to light.
All right,
let's take down
that dressing
and see where
all that blood's
coming from.
I'm not seeing any other
major external traumas.
Not sure if there's active
bleeding or not.
Well, grab some saline
and flush it out.
What size syringe
should I use?
Forget that,
give it to me.
Squeeze hard.
Okay, I can visualize
the full wound.
It's a deep lac.
Galea muscle's intact.
Still a little bit of bleeding
from the skin edge.
All right, put some
pressure back on it
and let's get her X-ray
and then send her up to CT
for a pan scan.
We'll stitch
her up later.
Let's move.
Isn't it a bad sign
that she's so groggy?
Hopefully, it's just
a concussion.
Mom is here.
June Patten.
Stable, Baghdad.
All right.
Hi, June,
I'm Dr. Manning.
This is Ms. Curry.
She's a fourth year
medical student.
Where's Kayla?
She's stable.
She's up getting some X-rays
to make sure there's
no internal injuries.
I swear her
seatbelt was on
when I started the car.
Can I look at her arm?
Yeah, go ahead.
There's a deformity
at the elbow,
but neurovascular intact.
Let's get some X-rays.
I would've pulled over
if I'd known
she'd taken it off.
I need to see Kayla.
No. June, please.
We need to get
these X-rays,
okay?
You can see Kayla as soon
as she's back from
radiology. All right?
Thank you.
Step back.
Shooting.
Looks like a simple posterior
elbow dislocation.
We need to reduce it
to preserve blood supply.
50 mics of fentanyl,
one of versed.
All right, Elsa?
Supinate while
applying traction.
All right,
you almost got it.
A little further.
Okay,
I felt it go in.
All right, let's do
a repeat X-ray to confirm
and get her an immobilizer.
You'll be able to see Kayla
as soon as she's back.
It still hurts.
Some soreness is
to be expected,
but if you
need anything,
you let them know
and they'll page
me directly.
Hey, CeCe.
Hey, Maggie.
Come here.
There you go.
How you doing, girl?
Ready to get
off my feet
for a few hours.
Come on. Pull up
a chair and stay a while.
Morning.
Piper's got you.
I'll never get
used to this.
Kind of feels like you
volunteered to get your ass
kicked, doesn't it?
Sounds about right.
It gets better.
Mmm.
They juice yours up
with steroids yet?
Mmm-mmm.
Today's my first day.
You're gonna love it.
Yeah?
It's like getting a jolt
of rocket fuel
right when you need it.
Oh!
I could use that.
You look pretty
good to me.
I'm sorry.
I'm Ben.
Maggie... Lockwood.
Nice to meet
you, Maggie.
And I'll be right here
in case you need
any more silver linings.
Glad I know
where to find you, Ben.
Gina Todd?
Hi, I'm Dr. Choi.
I recognize
that jacket.
Army, huh?
That's right.
He's in the Navy.
It's kind
of his thing.
I get it. Wear it
loud and proud.
So, what's
going on, Gina?
I have this infection
in my arm
where my prosthesis
is connected.
I'm getting treatment
at Walter Reed,
but this is killing me.
I've never seen
a prosthetic
device like this.
Most move
at just one joint,
but this looks
so much
more complex.
One-of-a-kind,
I think.
Tons of R&D went
into this thing.
Looks like something
from the future.
Yeah, check this out.
How are you
able to do that?
Three years of interfacing
the arm with my nerves.
So, it's wired
to your
nervous system?
You're controlling that
with your brain?
Let's take a look
at this infection,
all right?
I'm feeling
much better.
Good.
I think I'm ready
to go home.
Is this necessary?
We haven't met.
I'm Dr. Halstead.
Kirsten.
And you are...
She's my girlfriend.
I see.
So, Tom...
Unfortunately, your test
results show you're in
acute liver failure,
which is causing
bleeding
in your stomach.
Can we go now?
No, Tom needs
to be treated.
If not, he could
wind up in
end-stage liver failure.
End-stage?
Be quiet.
Treated? What exactly
does that entail?
For starters, I need
to run some more tests
to find out
what's causing
the liver failure.
No, unhook him
from all of this.
We're going.
Whoa...
Wait a minute.
Tom, what
do you want?
Get up. We'll go.
I wanna leave.
I strongly
advise you not to.
Let's go, Tom. Get up.
Hold on,
before you can leave,
you have to sign
an AMA form.
Then get it.
It took me three months
just to tap my finger.
It's a frustrating
process.
For a while there,
it felt like
I'd signed up
for a billion-dollar
backscratcher.
You seem pretty
well-acclimated now.
Yeah, now.
Sucks getting trapped
under an exploded Humvee,
but it's pretty cool
I get to be
the Bionic Woman.
Let's start Gina
on IV clindamycin,
600 milligrams.
My doc had me
on Augmentin.
Let's try something
a little different.
Let's get
a CT scan, too,
see if the infection
has spread into any
deep spaces.
Okay.
What if it has?
Could require
surgery to clean it out.
Who's your doctor
at Walter Reed?
I need to loop them in.
It's Dr. Flanagan.
Um...
But the thing is,
I flew in this weekend
for my sister's wedding.
I wasn't really
supposed to travel.
The Army doesn't
like their toys
taken out of the box.
So, they don't even
know you're here.
You're AWOL.
I know how it sounds,
but it's my little
sister's wedding
and I'm her
maid of honor.
I'll be back in Bethesda
first thing Monday.
I'd really appreciate if we
could keep the military
out of this if possible.
We'll respect
your privacy.
It's like I tell all
my students at the start
of each year.
"It won't always be easy,
but it will be worth it
in the end."
And does that
work on them?
Not really. Ten-year-olds
have a hard time
seeing past recess.
But I say it anyway,
just to remind myself
as the school
year rolls on.
Excuse me, I'm sorry.
Can I get either
of you anything?
No, thanks.
I'm good, CeCe.
Okay, we have some
really good cookies.
We have chocolate chip,
we have macadamia...
I think I'll take
one of those.
Okay, right over there.
Yeah, maybe
I'll stretch my legs.
All right.
I cannot believe
you're not breaking
a sweat.
Why?
I'm having a hot flash
just watching y'all two.
Oh, CeCe...
Did you ask him out yet?
I'm not gonna hit on
some guy getting
chemotherapy next to me.
Technically, you've been
hitting on him
the entire time.
CeCe, this is
not the place
to meet somebody.
Okay, so, if you met him
in a Starbucks, would you
ask him out then?
CeCe, please.
Look, I'm not telling you
your business,
but that man
is fine as hell.
Ask him out.
What are you
waiting for?
I couldn't decide on
which one to get,
so, I thought maybe,
if you'd be willing
to share, we could
both live like kings.
What do you say?
Mmm.
Thank you.
You know, I should
probably eat an
actual lunch after this.
But
problem is...
What's the problem?
I don't like to eat alone.
What are you up to?
Stop...
Something's wrong! Help!
Someone,
please get in here!
Sats are
down to 84.
Kayla?
Kayla? Her GCS is worse.
She's not protecting
her airway.
All right, bag her
while I get
an intubation kit.
What does that mean?
What's happening?
She's not breathing
on her own
and she needs help.
Ms. Patten, why don't
you come with me?
I'm not
leaving her.
Please, let's
give the doctors
some room.
Hyperventilate her.
Sats are going back up.
All right, good.
Why don't you intubate?
Etomidate and sux.
Are you ready?
Yep.
Pressing and lifting.
Okay, you see
the cords?
No...
Get the tube.
I'll hold down.
All right, go nice and slow,
okay? We've got time.
Don't worry.
Push a little.
Over there, yeah.
Okay, I'm in.
All right.
Bag her.
Why are her sats dropping?
Probably in the stomach.
I'll do it.
All right.
Take off the bag.
Yep, I'm in. Bag.
Eighty-eight,
92, we're good.
All right, get her on a vent
and get Mom back in here.
Look, it was your first time
intubating a child.
It happens.
Don't beat yourself up.
I'm not.
I am a medical student.
This is supposed to be
a learning experience.
Doc, could I curbside
you for a minute?
What's up?
So, I've got this guy
with liver failure
and hematemesis.
Then his girlfriend
shows up
and insists he leave
without getting
treatment.
That's his choice,
not hers, right?
But he's going
along with it.
She's very
"controlling",
is, I think,
the word you'd use.
Okay, well, I mean,
if he wants to leave,
there's not really
a whole lot we can
do about it, right?
No, you're right,
but there's something
odd going on
with these two.
They have
these pointy teeth,
like really sharp.
Implants
or something.
Okay, well,
now I'm interested.
Gina's CT scans.
It's an abscess
where the tissue
meets the prosthetic.
It'll require
surgical drainage.
Yeah, but let's hold off
before scheduling anything.
Why?
I called her doctor
at Walter Reed. He's coming
out to take a look.
Ethan, what?
She asked us to keep
the military out of this.
It's not about that.
She's AWOL.
Look, April,
I didn't wanna make
the call.
But Gina's health
has to take priority.
Her prosthetic is such
a specialized piece,
I need her doctor's input
before having it operated on.
But you violated
her HIPAA rights.
Actually, HIPAA makes an
allowance for situations
just like this.
We would contact the
manufacturer of a prosthetic
in any other scenario.
But in this case, the
manufacturer just so
happens to be the military.
What's that
supposed to mean?
Maybe you can get a little
overzealous when it comes
to the military.
I'm just trying to keep
Gina from losing
her arm a second time.
What's the worst
that could happen?
I die?
If you leave,
it's a very
real possibility.
Look, shut up, Tom.
Get up, we're going.
Whoa, hey.
Tom!
If your liver fails,
your brain
will deteriorate.
Your entire body
will swell up
and you will most likely
bleed into your
stomach again.
And that will kill you.
But I'm already dead.
Tom, don't.
I'm a vampire!
Okay, hold on.
Get out of our way!
I can't do that.
I gotta keep you
at the hospital.
I'm putting you
on an involuntary
psychiatric...
Hey!
Let me see it.
Go get them.
Security, stop them!
Hey, hey,
come back here!
Whoa, stay right there!
Whoa. Get him
out of the sun!
I'd treat it
with Silvadene.
Yeah.
This is why I wear a hood.
Vampires can't be
out in the sun.
Tom, there are
medical explanations
for why this is
happening to you
and I can figure this out,
if you just let me take
another blood sample.
So you can
experiment on me?
This is exactly
what Kirsten
said you'd do.
What did she
tell you, Tom?
That you'd parade me
out in the news,
claiming to be the doctors
who discovered
and cured a vampire.
No, we're not gonna
do that. We just
want you to get better.
As a vampire,
I get to live
like a god.
Long after you
become worm food,
Kirsten and I will
just be starting
our next chapter together.
Look, Tom...
Will, could I get
a minute?
What is with this kid?
Look, he's submissive.
He's impressionable.
She's essentially
brainwashed him.
As far as he's concerned,
he's a vampire.
Trying to reason with him,
it's a waste of time.
Could even be
counterproductive.
Fine, but he's
on a psych hold.
Can't you medicate him?
Not unless he becomes
acutely dangerous,
or we got a court order.
He vomited
a pint of blood
this morning.
He's going to bleed again
and it will kill him.
I never thought
I would ever eat
at the Rainforest Cafe.
Since I got
diagnosed,
I've been trying
to live more
like my fourth graders.
Not a care
in the world.
All they wanna do
is have fun.
Yeah.
But I should quit
taking restaurant
tips from them.
Maybe.
Well, this is me.
I had a lot of fun
today, Maggie.
Yeah.
Me, too.
Listen, um, I'm throwing
a party with a friend
from the hospital tonight.
A crawfish boil.
You should come.
If you're feeling
up to it.
Are you kidding me?
With this rocket
fuel in my veins.
It does feel pretty good.
You know,
I appreciate
the offer, Maggie,
but I really don't
wanna impose.
No, please.
I want you to come.
Okay.
I'd like that.
Actually, I'm supposed
to make some jambalaya
for the party.
I could use
an extra set of hands.
I got hands.
Okay, then.
Come on in.
I'm Dr. Choi.
I called about
Sergeant Gina Todd.
Dr. Choi,
I'm Captain Sims.
This is Officer Miller
and Officer Campo,
Military Police.
Military Police?
I thought you said
you called a doctor.
I was expecting
Dr. Flanagan.
I don't know
anything about that.
We just came straight
from Fort McCoy.
Our orders are to
transport Sergeant Todd
back to Walter Reed.
As Gina's doctor,
I need to know the
plan for her treatment.
Any decisions pertaining to
Todd's care are classified.
Dr. Choi,
Treatment 5
needs you.
Excuse us.
She's hypotensive.
And her fever is spiking.
She's in septic shock.
Bolus a liter of saline.
Not getting a good flow.
Her IV's blown.
Do you want
to put a central line in?
No, I'm gonna drill
an IO in her leg.
It'll be faster.
Okay.
Okay, open up the fluids.
Mmm-hmm.
Okay, much better.
All right, she's stable,
but she's septic.
Give her a second liter
and hang Levophed.
I'm transferring Gina
up to one of our
operating rooms.
Her abscess needs
to be drained
immediately.
Sorry, Dr. Choi,
but Sergeant Todd is headed
back to Walter Reed with us.
Helicopter's already
on the way.
And how long will it take
to get there? Three hours?
It's too risky.
Gina has an infection
in her blood.
She needs surgery now.
We'll let the doctors
at Walter Reed decide that.
I assure you,
they would agree.
This patient
is not going anywhere.
I have orders.
I intend to follow them.
I'm getting Ms. Goodwin.
So,
after hitting the front
and back of her head,
she has what
we call a coup
contrecoup injury.
The foci are small,
but they're cumulative.
I don't understand.
Kayla has multiple
small bruises
in her brain,
but none of them
are big enough for me
to drill and evacuate.
So, what can be done?
Nothing.
Hopefully, with time,
they'll resolve
on their own.
I'm sorry
I don't have anything
else to offer.
You know,
there are some things
we can try
to stop the bleeding
from causing problems.
We can raise the head
of Kayla's bed
and give her mannitol
to decrease
intracranial pressure.
Do you think
it will work?
Statistically, it has
maybe a 25% chance
of changing her outcome.
Oh, God.
Hey, I have seen
this treatment work before.
Ms. Curry?
Why would you
say that to her?
Because it's the truth.
She asked.
No, what she was
asking for is hope,
not grim statistics.
How do you know that?
Trust me,
that's what she
was asking for.
Our job is to look out
for the best interests
of our patients.
I'm sorry
you had to come
all the way down here.
You shouldn't
even be here.
Look, Sergeant Todd
isn't just another one
of your hospital patients.
She's part of
a special DARPA project.
They've invested
a lot of time
and taxpayer dollars
into Gina and her arm.
Unfortunately,
Captain, this isn't
a military base.
You don't have
jurisdiction here.
And if you want
to move this patient,
you'll need a judge's
court order and the
local police to do it.
We'll have all our ducks
in a row by the time
our chopper arrives.
Until then,
out of consideration
of our other patients,
do you mind stepping
into the waiting room?
Thank you.
Ms. Goodwin, we cannot
let them take her.
She's septic.
Well, what can be
done right now?
If we can drain her abscess,
we can remove the source
of her infection.
But I will need
a surgeon to do it.
I can take her up
to the surgical floor
in the meantime.
Well, move fast,
because if they get
that court order,
there's nothing
that any of us
can do to stop them.
Hey, I'm worried about this.
I'm gonna be fine.
Took a bunch of
antibiotics, you know,
a fistful of ibuprofen.
I can't feel a thing.
I get the feeling
it's gonna be
a late night.
Maybe we should
cancel our reservation.
No way. Alinea,
are you kidding me?
We could get another
dinner reservation,
but who knows when
you're gonna get another
vampire in the ED?
If only I could figure out
how to talk to this guy,
how to get through to him.
You can talk to anybody.
That's why I love you
so much. Even vampires.
What?
Keep the reservation.
First of all, Tom,
I would like to apologize.
Clearly,
you are a vampire.
It's just that
we've never
treated one before,
and so, it's our mistake.
And I'm sorry.
You must be
getting hungry.
Would you like me
to contact
the blood bank or...
You're messing with me.
It's just
like Kirsten said.
Doctors can't
be trusted.
Yeah, Kirsten.
Where's Kirsten?
Is she out in
the waiting room?
No.
She left.
Tom, do you mind me
asking how long have
you two been together?
Eight, nine months.
I'm just curious
because, well,
I mean,
if you'll forgive me,
it seems like she
kind of abandoned you.
She had to.
But to the very
people who she said
were so dangerous?
You chased her away!
She'll come back for me.
Tonight.
Well, hopefully,
but I mean,
even if she does,
doesn't it bother
you a bit that,
I don't know,
that she put
herself first?
I think you
deserve someone
who puts you first.
You know? I mean,
someone who loves you.
Because if Kirsten did...
I mean, I don't know.
Why isn't she here?
Give us a chance
to help you.
Let me run some tests.
I just pulled
a 14-hour shift.
Can't someone
from ortho do it?
Already tried,
but they say
it's a soft tissue
general surgery case.
Crockett, please.
We are one court order away
from losing this patient
to the Military Police.
We have minutes,
not hours.
Us versus them, huh?
Will you assist?
All right, then.
Let's go.
Game on.
Now, what's
happening?
Blood pressure's
200 over 70,
heart rate's 40s.
She's going to arrest.
Call a code.
Code Blue!
Please, do something.
Help her!
Ms. Patten...
No, I won't go!
It's okay.
She's bradying.
Swelling must be
causing increased
intracranial pressure.
Take her off the vent
and bag her.
Cushing reflex?
Yep.
Do something!
We're doing
everything we can.
I can't find a pulse.
She's asystole on the monitor.
I'm starting compressions.
Milligram of epi.
I can't believe
this is happening!
Please, Kayla,
please.
Hold compressions.
Come on, baby.
Still no pulse.
Continue compressions.
Another milligram of epi.
Baby, please.
Come on...
Kayla, please, please.
No... Please...
Pupils are blown.
Stop compressions.
What?
Don't stop!
Why are you stopping?
She's still asystole.
Her brain has herniated.
I am so sorry, June.
No!
Time of death, 16:08.
No! No!
I'm so sorry.
No!
No, no, no!
I've received word
Captain Sims
got her court order.
A military helicopter
is touching down
on the helipad now.
Thanks for the heads up.
All right.
Hey.
Yeah?
MPs are moments away
from pulling the plug.
How far off are you?
I gotta finish scrubbing,
gown, and glove up.
I'd say five minutes.
I'll try to
buy you some time.
Captain!
Here's a court
order, Dr. Choi.
Sorry, you and your
crew have to wait.
Sergeant Todd
is already in surgery.
Then we'll get
her out.
The procedure
won't take long.
You'll be on your
way in a little over
an hour, tops.
Your role in this
is over. Step aside.
You interrupt that surgery
and you'll be putting
Gina's life at risk.
I have my orders to
bring her back ASAP.
Are your orders
to bring her
back dead?
Because that's exactly
what you'll be doing.
We'll see what
DOD says.
Thank you for
sticking around
to do this.
I can refuse
you nothing,
Nurse Sexton.
Irrigation.
You're not really
here because of me.
Well... I do love
a good race.
You ever had
a Sazerac, Sexton?
What is that?
My favorite cocktail.
New Orleans special.
I'll make you
one tonight.
Hey, Tom?
What can I do for you?
I'm not feeling good.
I'm sick.
Yes, you are.
And I can help,
but only if
you'll let me.
I've been texting Kirsten.
She's not answering.
When I call, it goes
straight to voicemail.
I think she blocked me.
She's not coming
back, is she?
I'm sorry.
I never felt more alive
than when I was with her.
Imagine the most exciting
woman you ever met
choosing you
to go with her on an
extraordinary trip
that lasts forever.
Must have felt
pretty special.
She could've
picked anyone,
but she picked me.
And now...
This is probably hard
for you to understand.
Actually, Tom,
I know exactly where
you're coming from.
Was it all a lie?
I feel so stupid.
How about we focus
on getting you
feeling better?
Okay.
So, the abscess
was drained. No damage
to the prosthetic,
and hopefully not
the patient's
implanted nerve endings.
Thank you, Dr. Marcel.
Captain Sims and her team
will be transporting
Sergeant Todd to
Walter Reed via
helicopter immediately.
Okay, just make sure
the patient receives
the proper post-op fluids
and meds in transit, okay?
All right.
That poor woman.
She's gonna pull through.
Yeah, but we have
no idea what the
Army will do to her.
It didn't have
to go down
like this, Ethan.
If you had
just listened.
Elsa?
You okay?
People make assumptions
about me.
Okay, but they're wrong.
I mean, I'm not
some kind of a robot.
I have feelings.
Okay, well,
that's a good thing.
No, you don't understand.
They're so powerful,
I feel like if I didn't
hold them all in,
I have no idea what
would happen.
You're afraid of
being overwhelmed?
Yes, yes. I couldn't stand
watching that mother
lose her daughter today.
I do understand, Elsa.
But those feelings
that seem so frightening,
ultimately,
they will become
one of your
greatest assets
as a doctor.
I don't know.
What have you
got going on tonight?
CeCe got reservations
at Alinea. I think I might
just make it, too.
Any luck?
Tom has hepatitis C.
You got him
to take the test?
He needed a little
more time to think
about what you said.
Huh.
Is this your vampire?
Does that explain
why he blistered
in the sun?
Yes. Liver
failure combined
with hepatitis can
cause porphyria
cutanea tarda.
Makes it so
sun exposure causes
painful skin lesions.
And since hepatitis
is transmitted
through bodily fluids,
probably got it
from having sex
with his girlfriend.
Or from sucking
her blood. Yikes.
Wait, didn't that
woman bite you?
Yeah, Dr. Charles,
you need to get tested.
First thing
in the morning.
Given the risk
of transmission,
you should have your
blood drawn ASAP.
You mean
like right now?
Now.
You're kidding me.
Dr. Halstead,
anything else?
No, I'm gonna get
Tom started
on antivirals.
Come and get 'em!
Don't be afraid to get
your hands dirty now!
So sorry. Yeah.
Oh!
April, this is Ben,
my date.
Hello, Ben.
Nice to meet you.
Oh! Maggie,
where's the
jambalaya?
Sorry,
there isn't any,
but I brought
rotisserie chicken
already cooked.
You realize that
supermarket chicken
is not generally served
at a crawfish boil?
All right, well,
glad I made extra
red beans and rice.
Put 'em in
the kitchen.
Let's go.
I got them.
Thank you.
After all the grief
you gave us this morning,
you show up late?
Got a little busy
this afternoon.
Oh!
Not that busy.
Maybe that busy.
Hi, Elsa.
Dr. Halstead.
Oh, come on.
I think you can
call me Will.
Okay.
So, how you doing?
You don't have to
be nice to me.
I know.
So, I've never been
to a crawfish
boil before.
I'm a little
out of my element.
Um...
I can show you
how to do it.
Okay, so, as far
as I understand it,
you pull off the head
and then you
squeeze the tail
to get the meat out.
Wow...
I take it you've
been to a few of these.
It's all on YouTube.
Good to know.
I knew crawfish was spicy,
but my mouth is on fire.
A little bit of Sazerac
should help.
Absinthe rinse,
rye, bitters, sugar.
Ain't nothing to it.
So, how is it?
It's good.
It doesn't taste strong.
I assure you, it is.
Mmm.
Okay, my lips
are still tingling.
Ethan.
Hey.
Can I talk to you?
April, I'm sorry
about today.
You know I can be kind
of a hardass sometimes.
And when I think I know
what should be done,
I have trouble
stepping back.
Okay.
What I'm saying is...
I love you.
And I need to
respect your wishes.
So, no more
ovulation chart
or schedules.
Let's just see
what happens.
Forgive me?
Yes.