How long has your daughter
had trouble breathing?
About a week now.
The best dads wait two or more.
Yeah, no. It's not
like it's serious.
I checked online and
it's asthma or something.
"Or something" is
the number one killer
of teens with no medical degree.
When was the last time
he took you to see a doctor?
Uh... Like five months ago.
We went to a clinic in
Trenton. I had strep throat.
Remember the antibiotic
they gave you? Is it neomycin?
Amoxicillin.
So, about the inhaler
for my asthma, I was...
Sorry.
Hospital policy
specifically prohibits me
from giving meds to
unrelated homeless people
pretending to be
father and daughter.
Your pants are a size too short,
so either you grew
several of inches
or you grabbed the closest
size in the thrift store.
And only you have
dimples, which are adorable,
but they're also an X-linked
dominant genetic trait.
Which actually
doesn't prove anything.
The fact that she didn't
burst into tears tells me
that you never thought
he was your dad.
Let's get out of here.
Since you're the brains of the
operation, you might want to stick around.
What, so I can get
busted by Social Services?
No. So you can stop
bleeding out of your ear.
It's usually a sign
of a skull fracture.
Someone been using
your head as a soccer ball?
No. As much as I'd like
to take your word for it,
I have no interest in
taking your word for it.
No tenderness. No pain.
Right. Looks like you're telling
the truth about something.
The ear canal is fine.
And you don't have a fever.
Pay the man. He's
late for a trashcan fire.
Would you tell me what's
going on? What's wrong with me?
I have no idea.
Why did you ask to meet us
30 miles away from the hospital?
Because I can.
Also, Chris Christie's blog says
the pancakes here are the best.
So, what do we got
on this 18-year-old
with the ear bleed and
the breathing problems?
CT confirms no skull fracture. And
looking at her confirms she's not 18.
Yes, she is.
Says so in the file.
We can't treat an underage
patient without a guardian.
We need to call Social Services.
I cut a deal with the patient.
We don't call, she doesn't bolt.
Whatever age, living on the street
makes her vulnerable to malnutrition,
drug use, HIV...
All things which could
explain her symptoms.
No sign of malnutrition, tox screen's
clear, STD panel was negative
and is that Foreman?
Oh, my goodness, it is.
Hi, Dean Foreman!
Are you not gonna introduce
us because we're married?
No, wait, that's her.
She's a pharmaceutical rep,
and this is a working breakfast.
In a restaurant that's nowhere
near your home or the hospital?
Chris Christie
recommends the pancakes.
Squamous cell middle ear tumor
could've caused the ear bleed,
paraneoplastic reaction
caused the breathing problems.
Middle ear looks
completely normal.
But there is thickening in the
lining of the wall of the third ventricle.
Could be a sign of
cerebral infection.
It would explain
the lack of fever.
Pneumococcus is pretty common
among the homeless population.
We should find out if
she's been vaccinated.
Sure. Ask her and when she
refuses to tell you anything,
start her on ceftriaxone
for pneumococcus.
And if she says she
has been vaccinated?
Then don't believe her and start
her on ceftriaxone for pneumococcus.
How about we don't believe she's
gonna bolt and we call Social Services.
While I'm in the
little boys' room,
you can pretend I'm
seriously considering that idea.
The bathroom's that way.
Pretty sure there's
one in the hospital.
When I was your age, I ran away.
Lived on my own.
At the time, it seemed...
Let me guess,
life with mom and dad was kind
of a drag so you just ran away,
lived with friends
and partied with guys
that you knew your
parents would hate,
and then when you got tired of
being a rebel, you just went home.
Being homeless
isn't a vacation for me,
and I'm not acting out.
My life at home sucked,
so I got the hell out of there.
There are other options
besides living on the streets.
Right. Like group homes,
where you're packed in
with as many messed-up,
delinquent kids as possible,
foster parents, who only take
you in because you're a meal ticket.
I can think of easier ways
to make 175 bucks a week.
No, you're right. I
really should roll the dice
and hope for a pair that don't
ruin my life the way that my mom...
Get your hands off my stuff!
This stuff might tell us
more about why you're sick.
A history textbook?
You go to school?
I don't plan on being
homeless forever.
Hello, good sir.
My brother the general here
gots the green apple quick step.
One of us is in the
wrong time zone.
And if it's me, I need
to talk to a stockbroker
and anyone from the
Kennedy family. In that order.
He got the runs
and we do need him
up and at 'em for
battle tomorrow.
It's hardly authentic,
coming to a newfangled clinic,
especially with a Yankee doctor.
Sir, are you
questioning my resolve?
Yes. And your sanity.
I'm multi-tasking.
General, do not light out.
We swore that we would
see the elephant together.
Far be it from me to come between
two nut jobs and their elephant.
I could add some mercury if you
want to make it more authentic.
The Confederacy thanks you, Doc.
I got House's phone, deleted
all photos of you and Anita.
I owe you.
An affair? Never knew
you were such a tramp.
Neither did I.
Anita, she's fun, smart,
not looking for anything
serious. It's pretty perfect.
Except for the gnawing
guilt about the husband,
the lies she must
be telling him.
But not guilty enough
to stop seeing her.
She's smoking hot. And it's not
his job to protect her marriage.
Aren't you supposed
to be pointing a finger
at your own life as
a cautionary tale?
If not for cheating, I
might still have a wife
but I wouldn't have
Sophie and Sophia.
Which means I wouldn't be
preparing for their visit this week
by child-locking all my
cabinets, padding table corners
and getting rid of
every single magazine.
You could probably just hide
the porn in your underwear drawer.
The magazines go away
so I won't ignore my children.
I know I have to
pay attention to them,
I want to pay attention to them.
But they're just so
boring.
Did you learn anything
at Jane Doe's school?
They did a bunch of vaccinations,
including pneumococcus.
Take her off the ceftriaxone.
So we're back to square none.
Not exactly.
The name she registered
under seems to be fake,
but the address is
a foreclosed house.
We'll let you know what we find.
Plenty of food, water.
And beer.
She eats well, goes to
school, makes good grades.
She's a homeless girl who's
captain of the volleyball team.
How can you be okay with this?
Your mom sends you
to work with snacks.
I want and need parents.
Jane Doe is
flourishing without them.
Maybe.
But this mold definitely is.
You went to my school?
Now that they know
they'll report me.
I can't go back there.
You may have a fungal
infection, you need that medicine.
Fluconazole, right?
I'll get it at a clinic.
I can't feel my legs!
Is that the infection?
I don't think so.
So, what causes an ear bleed,
breathing problems
and our runaway's
inability to run away?
Fungal infection's
off the table.
What about transverse myelitis?
Not with normal
posterior column function.
I've been waiting to
do this for months. Pull!
Sights seem to be off on this.
We didn't call Social
Services before
because we didn't want
the patient to take off.
Now she can't. There's
no reason for us not to call.
How about the reason that there's
no reason. This is working fine for me.
Pull!
That one clearly
took evasive action.
You want to protect
her, because you think
she's fine on her own,
outside the system...
Does anyone have a position
on our patient's medical condition?
Could be endocarditis
with septic emboli.
Pull!
I'd turn around and shoot
you, but apparently I'd miss.
There's no murmurs,
no Osler nodes.
You've never done
this before, have you?
No, I have not.
But all the time I had my ankle
monitor on, I was furious that I couldn't.
Vasculitis fits.
Start treatment with steroids.
If she's lucky, she'll
be free to flee again.
Not once I call Social Services.
I'm not giving up.
You wanna bet?
One shot, one birdie.
You hit, you make the call.
You miss, never mention it again.
No. Why would I agree?
Because your only other
option is you call and I fire you.
Pull!
She responding
to corticosteroids?
Looks like it.
And Social Services.
I thought for sure there'd
be some yelling or profanity,
possible bloodletting.
She's tired of living
on the streets after all.
I'll bet House regrets...
Could he know I'm
good with a gun?
I don't know how, but...
Hiring a hooker to pretend
to be a social worker?
She took a bet that
she knew she'd win.
Frankly, I feel violated.
What happened to the
social worker I called?
Apparently someone identifying
themselves as Dr. Pujols called
and said the patient ran off.
Come on, Poo-holes.
I've informed Social
Services of the mistake
and given Jane Doe's
description to the cops.
They'll track down the parents.
Thank you.
I'll leave you and
Dr. Pujols alone.
You should have told me you were
treating an underage clinic patient.
I was giving you
the gift of deniability.
Now I'm giving you the
gift of additional clinic hours.
No, you're not.
You've got nothing on me.
Check your phone.
My phone?
Right, I guess I did have
some pictures on that.
But I also have these.
Here's the two of you
kissing over dinner.
Busting a move at a nightclub.
Is that your hand near
her nether regions?
Thanks again for taking
out the ankle bracelet.
I'm not gonna let you
blackmail me, House.
Of course not. There's no way
your selling out your integrity
would let me compromise
your job in any major way
over some tawdry bit of gossip.
But what about
compromising it in a minor way,
reduced clinic hours,
unlimited Internet porn budget.
That makes much more sense than
the nuclear option of
ruining both our lives.
You can keep
these. I got copies.
God, how I've missed the sweet
smell of sticking it to the man.
Adams is right. You're
protecting this girl.
Oh, no, I was wrong.
That's the stench of moralizing.
I'm protecting myself from
meddling bureaucrats and parents.
You admire this girl.
She had a horrible home life
so she went out on her own.
She's your road not taken.
I've always dreamed of living in
an abandoned house with mold.
House, all I'm accusing you of is
having a connection with a patient.
This is a good thing.
It's not a good thing,
'cause it's not a thing.
It is a thing, which you'll prove
when her parents show up,
and you start
protecting her from them.
The sound I make is "moo."
And the sound I make is "quack."
Moo!
The sound is quack.
Quack, quack.
Quack, quack, quack.
I'm an ass.
On the plus side, I can now
program my DVR from my phone.
They are kind of boring.
All kids. Not just yours.
Very helpful.
You need to log more hours.
Eventually you'll pass
boredom, get to bonding.
Like Stockholm syndrome.
I heard the nurses talking. You
called Social Services for real.
Because you shouldn't
be living on your own.
Right. Better my mom should
use me as a punching bag.
If your mom abused
you, Social Services
won't let you go home with her.
Have I mentioned I
don't trust the system?
We don't know if you're better
yet. You can't just take off.
Uh... Can we help you?
I'm Adele Brown from
Social Services, and this...
I'm Ellen Rogers,
Callie's mother.
You haven't been
that for two years.
I promise, things
are different...
Wow, two sentences in and
you're already making promises.
Okay. Maybe we need to take a
minute here and give Callie some space.
No, I don't need a minute.
I need her out of my life.
Is she okay? I will
be once you just...
Oh, my God!
We need help in here!
Go!
You bet 100 bucks
on a turtle race?
I paid Mr. Chips 5
bucks to take a dive.
The bleeding stopped on its own.
She got worse after being on
steroids, so autoimmune is out.
Diagnosis depends on whether
the blood was coming from
the sinuses, lungs or her guts.
Mr. Chips looks
like he wants it.
100 bucks says he'll
make soup out of Franklin.
You're on.
How'd the mom seem to you?
If you're asking if she looks like
someone who beat her kid, you're a moron.
Move your ass, Mr. Chips!
You should have seen her
face when mom walked in.
Callie hates her. I
don't think she's lying.
Because people never
lie about people they hate.
Big sinus bleed could be
sinusitis and a bleeding disorder.
She didn't complain
about a headache.
If the bleeding is in her gut,
could be Zollinger-Ellison.
Acid reflux causes asthma, and the acid
erodes the stomach, causing the bleeding.
Yes!
Franklin rules.
Mr. Chips drools.
Mr. Chips' owner only feeds
him on apples and bananas.
Nowhere near enough
Vitamin A. Pay up.
Do an upper endoscopy
to confirm Zollinger-Ellison.
After mommy dearest
has given her permission.
Ellen shouldn't have consent
if she beat her daughter.
Doesn't matter if she
beat her daughter.
Only matters if Social Services
says she beat her daughter.
Good thing you
made it all official.
Will the endoscopy be painful?
Is that an issue?
It's a medical procedure,
there will be some discomfort.
I never meant to
hurt my daughter.
And yet, you hit her.
She told you that?
And now you're
gonna tell me you didn't.
I'm a drug addict.
And I've been a lousy mom.
Especially since
my husband died.
He was closer to Callie than I
was, and I missed him so much.
And it was too hard,
and taking oxy just
made things easier.
Right up until it made
me lose my daughter.
I hurt Callie a lot.
But one of the only things that I can
feel okay about is that I never hit her.
Didn't peg you as the midday fun
kind of guy. So glad I was wrong.
Mmm...
Unfortunately, that's
not why we're here.
Remember that guy from
the restaurant yesterday?
Mmm-hmm.
He's got pictures of us. He's
threatening to show your husband.
I thought you said that guy
was one of your best doctors.
Yeah. Not one of my best people.
We've got to stop
seeing each other.
Not necessarily.
I told my husband about you.
What? Why?
He was saying
that things had been
better lately between him and I,
that I was happier.
I said that I was, and
that you were the reason.
And he was okay with that?
Not initially. It was a
pretty tough conversation.
Neither of us is ready to
give up on the marriage,
and I am not ready
to give up this.
You don't have to
feel so guilty anymore.
You didn't need
to shoot yourself.
I could have given
you a Section 8.
We've hit the
drills pretty hard,
and by the fourth round, my
hand went numb. The gun slipped.
And I only had
blanks in it but...
It's funny how nearly shooting your
toe off cured that speech impediment.
Ha! Yeah. Sorry about
that. Sheldon's a progressive.
Compared to who? Rupert Murdoch?
Progressives are reenactors
who strive for complete authenticity.
They never drop
character while in uniform.
Whereas you just
dabble in crazy?
Sheldon and I had a
big falling out years ago.
We only really started talking
again because of the reenactments.
They gave me my brother back.
That's a very moving story.
Be a lot more affecting
if you hadn't bonded
over something so
completely idiotic.
Your mom didn't
hit you, did she?
No.
Then why did you lie about it?
Because I wanted
to get out of here.
People understand getting hit
more than what my mom does.
Tell me, maybe I'll understand.
I was the mom.
She couldn't keep a job,
spent all her money on pills.
I had to get a job.
Double shifts just to keep the
power on, keep food in the house.
I couldn't tell you how
many times she nearly OD'd
and I had to clean her
up and put her in bed.
So I decided if I was
gonna be the grown-up,
I'd rather do it
on my own terms.
Your mom knows she messed up.
She's determined
not to do it again.
Yeah.
And she'll feel that way
right up until
things get too tough
and she has to
start using again.
Do you think people can change?
No.
But I don't think that's gonna change
your opinion because people don't change.
Stop.
Is that an ulcer? Yeah, it is.
But we haven't
reached the stomach yet,
I'm still high in the esophagus.
Means it's not
Zollinger-Ellison.
Ulcer's bleeding.
We need to lavage before
she drowns in her own blood.
We cauterized the ulcer,
stopped the bleeding.
Compromised immune
system from living on the street
could make her
susceptible to HPV.
HPV was covered on the
STD panel, she's negative.
What if she didn't get
this from being homeless?
What if she got it from her mom?
I'm assuming you're thinking
something genetic because...
I'm thinking addiction.
Alcohol-induced esophagitis.
Explains esophageal ulcers
and her other symptoms.
If only it would explain
why we've never
seen her drunk,
drinking or detoxing.
Her blood pressure's been
elevated. Could be the DTs.
It's been mildly elevated.
Mildly elevated BP could put
her at risk for a berry aneurysm.
Weak blood vessel in the brain
gets pounded on by elevated BP,
causes it to
expand and contract,
causes the symptoms
to come and go.
CT didn't show any
signs of an aneurysm.
Did I mention come and go?
As much as your
presence may cause
objects to become
engorged with blood,
sometimes aneurysms
just aren't in the mood.
Alcoholism and berry
aneurysm are both valid theories.
I think we should discuss this
with the patient and her mom.
Why? We've
discussed it right here.
Tell them she needs a cerebral
angiogram to locate the aneurysm,
surgery to repair.
Brain surgery? When?
We've booked the OR
for an hour from now.
And Dr. House is sure
that's what she has?
He's confident in the diagnosis.
It's consistent with
all of her symptoms.
But you don't buy it.
No.
I think your symptoms are
the result of alcohol abuse.
But I'm not an alcoholic.
You came to the hospital
with beer in your pocket,
we found more
alcohol at your house...
Yeah, I use booze as payment.
I have an occasional
beer with my friends.
That doesn't mean
I have a problem.
I want the surgery.
Actually, it's your
mom's decision.
I'm not an addict.
That's what I always said to
you, Callie, but I had a problem.
I'm nothing like you.
Tell them to do the surgery.
I need a few minutes to think.
The patient asked
me what I thought.
I pay you to think
inside this room.
Outside this room,
I pay you to parrot.
It's her choice. She
has the right to know.
It's a medical choice
that you turned into
an extension of your
baggage and hers.
You told the mom
something you want to believe
because you don't
want to believe that
this girl might be
doing fine parent-free.
Which also happens to be
what the mom wants to believe...
You think she wants to feel
responsible for her daughter's illness?
That woman sees everything
to do with her daughter
through guilt-colored glasses.
It's all her fault.
House,
don't bully her, she's
overwhelmed enough.
It's nothing compared
to how she's gonna feel
when her daughter dies from the
aneurysm she decided not to treat.
You must be Dr. House.
I save my appearances
for when parents are on the brink
of doing something incredibly stupid.
Your daughter has a berry
aneurysm, she needs surgery.
What she does not need is you
making this or any other decision.
I can't just leave
this up to her.
Then leave it up to me.
And just leave.
I'm not gonna
abandon my daughter.
She hates you.
It's actually not
such a big deal.
Plenty of kids
hate their parents.
What makes it a big deal
is that she should hate you.
Playing the biology card doesn't
change anything except where she lives.
Your daughter's
better off without you,
so let her be better
off without you.
I'm gonna do the surgery.
I'll take the fallout
from Social Services.
Dr. House.
My daughter's care is my choice.
And so is this.
Treat her for alcoholism.
Peek-a-boo!
Why would Anita tell her
husband about our affair?
Probably just got sick of lying.
Look at it this way, now the sex
is both commitment and guilt-free.
And men love
commitment-free sex.
Yes, they do. Oh, yes, they do.
They're gonna
find out eventually.
Peek-a-boo.
How do you keep doing
the same thing over and over
with the same
level of enthusiasm?
First off, be a decent,
empathetic person.
This is what you
said you wanted,
but you're actually more upset
now that the husband knows.
Because I'm hurting
him. You always were.
But he didn't know that. Which
means he wasn't really hurt.
Yeah, I know it's
a rationalization,
but it went a long way to making me
feel a little less guilty about seeing her.
Looks like you're gonna
need a bigger rationalization.
Peek-a-boo. Peek-a-boo.
Social Services report
came in on your mom.
Let me guess, she
passed with flying colors.
She always does.
I think she might
make it this time.
House left a bottle of
Vicodin to see if she'd steal it.
She gave it back.
You could at least let
her sleep in the room.
She could have listened
to me about my drinking.
Even if you are right about it,
why take your word over mine?
I'm her daughter.
Because she's your mom.
And for the first time
she's acting like it.
It's a little late for that.
Good night.
Morning.
I heard you went
head-to-head with the mom.
Not for your reasons.
You're protecting the girl.
I'm protecting my diagnosis.
And you tested her, to see if
you could get her back on drugs
and out of her daughter's life.
That was to show Adams that
mommy dearest hadn't changed.
I'm taking a principled
stand against idealism.
Your patient's stable?
Maybe Adams was right.
The illness is alcohol related.
I hope so considering that's
what we're treating her for.
You hope you're wrong
for the sake of the patient.
I hope that I'm right, but the
aneurysm bursts without killing her.
Call me a softie.
Or the mom agrees to an
autopsy so I can prove it.
Your patients love you
because you're empathetic.
I also have kind eyes.
Why are you here?
But you don't love
all of your patients.
Of course not.
I'll bet some of them bore you.
Dull people get cancer
too. Why are you here?
But you fake an interest in
them because you need to, right?
And if you do it long
enough, it becomes real?
Well, no, because
the interest isn't fake.
Really?
Because you realize
they're not dull,
it was just your
misinterpretation of them.
I just haven't found a way
to make them interesting yet.
It's all about common ground. You
find one thing you both like or hate.
John Woo movies,
romance novels, kale.
Sometimes the best way
to connect with someone
is stop thinking about
them and focus on yourself.
What is this about?
Not everything has an agenda.
See ya.
I told him because it
was the right thing to do.
Right.
This doesn't change
anything between us.
It sort of does for me.
You want to stop
seeing each other?
No.
But I was thinking, maybe you
could tell your husband that we did.
And then go back to sneaking
around behind his back?
Yes.
Why would you want to do that?
I don't know.
This just feels wrong.
I think I'm gonna go.
Oh, God!
We thought it
was the salt pork...
But all the menfolk
been eating it
and we're the
only ones that sick.
Which one of you is
the cheap bastard?
Your uniforms are not wool.
They're polyester, cheap polyester.
Which gets processed with a
heavy metal called antimony.
You wear badly
processed polyester
all day and night
for days and nights,
and you get antimony poisoning
which causes your diarrhea
and your numbness in your hands
and your collective vomiting.
Polyester uniforms?
I was being authentic.
With polyester uniforms?
Confederacy gave men $21
every six months for
uniforms... You poisoned us both.
At least I have principles.
Because they
don't cost anything.
Brother against brother.
Now that is authentic.
I know you don't want me here,
but they had banana
muffins downstairs.
Reminded me of
our St. Pete's trip.
Remember?
We used to walk and get some
every morning at that bakery.
I guess.
Were you high on that trip?
Not when we were together.
I used to wait until
you went to bed.
You can stay,
if you want.
Okay.
Mmm. It's not bad.
What's happening?
Is this from the
alcohol treatment?
I was wrong. The berry
aneurysm must have just burst.
Temporal lobes are
clear. Parietal clear.
Get me a micro-vascular clip
tray as well as the occlusion.
Check the ventricles.
Ventricles are clear, too.
Aneurysm must've
leaked instead of burst.
Inject the dye.
Posterior cerebral clear. Vertebral
clear. Circle of Willis also clear.
She doesn't have
a berry aneurysm.
Her BP is dropping.
Start her on pressors.
Get her BP up before her
organs start shutting down.
Adams. With me.
The pressors will only
give us a couple hours, max.
What causes breathing issues,
bleeding issues, paralysis,
loss of consciousness?
What are we missing?
That's everything bad that's
happened. What about the good stuff?
You mean, like, we
should be more optimistic?
She got a little better
when we put her on steroids,
which can attack tumor cells.
Maybe she has cancer.
No hypercalcaemia, no
elevated blood proteins.
She and her mom mentioned a trip
they took to Florida a couple of years ago.
What about dengue
fever? Cholera?
Great ideas. If dengue
fever or cholera laid
in wait for two years
before suddenly...
Did your biological daughter
go swimming in Florida?
In a lake, or a pond,
or an everglade?
Yeah, there's a canal
near my mother's house.
Do you know what's
wrong with her?
Family vacations kill.
Come with me. Don't
want to explain this twice.
You're letting in the flies.
And she needs an LVAD.
No, she doesn't.
Your daughter has ascariasis.
It's a disease caused by a
parasitic worm found in feces.
Animals used the
canal as a potty,
and the eggs from the feces
ended up in Callie's intestine
when she went swimming.
Where they hung out, quietly and
asymptomatically biding their time.
Until somewhere along the
way, they got knocked loose,
maybe a dive in
volleyball practice,
or maybe she slipped on
her way into a soup kitchen.
But once they hatched, the
worms got to work on her lungs,
her ear, and the
nerves in her legs.
The worms got agitated
by the steroids we gave her,
which started them on their
journey to the esophagus.
And, ultimately, to the heart.
A few pills of mebendazole,
and she'll be fine.
She's feeling much
better, walking on her own.
Getting along with her mother?
As long as I keep
bringing her muffins.
Did someone come
take her for a test?
Callie agrees with you.
That people don't change.
She said when her mom slips
again, she didn't want to be there.
She'd rather remember
her like she is now.
Smart girl.
You got the ending you wanted.
Because I was only looking to
solve the case, not their lives.
I don't care if the people who
work for me are screwed up,
in fact I even encourage it,
but absolution, do
that on your own time.
Or not at all.
'Cause clearly you suck at it.
This is Aaron Rodgers.
Wow, 127 quarterback rating.
Do you know what sound he makes?
Okay. Oy!
Um...
This is Terrell Owens.
People call him T.O.
Do you know what sound he makes?
This is Mark Sanchez.
Do you know what sound
people make about him?
Working late?
Husband have her tonight?
And every night.
She broke it off.
It's for the best.
I'm not really an
affair guy after all.
Sure you are, buddy.
You just lost interest once
it stopped being an affair.
That's why you're relieved.
But don't worry, it's
not gonna end here.
You'll just have to get your
adrenaline fix somewhere else.
When that doesn't do it anymore,
you'll just escalate
things somehow.
At least that's
what I've been told.
I'm not like you, House.
True. No limp.