Previously on ER:
You do you and I'll do me and
we'll just go our separate ways.
- What about in vitro?
- Approaching zero.
But not actually zero.
You have an infection in your
gallbladder and you need IV antibiotics.
- You got another text.
- From Ray?
From Australia.
And, girl, he's cute too.
You'll wake up next to me and you're
gonna wonder how this happened.
And I'm gonna smile and
remind you that I predicted it.
The toughest thing about being
a doctor isn't the terrible hours.
It isn't the loneliness, the isolation,
or the knowledge that one day...
we all lose out to the relentless
decay of the human body.
No, it's something else.
Ray. It's 5 a.m.
Yes, I know, but sometimes we
do actually get to sleep on call.
Good. You should be. You know I
have those stupid interviews later today.
No. I didn't forget.
Happy birthday.
Of course I was gonna call. It's
5 a.m., man, give me a chance.
It's my intern, I better
answer. I'll call you later, okay?
Bye.
Hey, Ana. You
having a party in here?
Something like that.
Tachy all night and
then the BP took a dive.
Crackles bilaterally.
I left mine in the ER.
Sensitivities come back
on the blood culture?
Vanco-resistant enterococcus.
That's what you were
worried about, right?
Yeah. Let the PICU
know we're coming.
Pick a color and a number
between one and 10.
Blue and three.
- B-L-U-E. One, two, three.
- Hey, at this point...
removing the source of
infection is our best option.
You mean taking out my gall bladder.
- Yeah.
Let's finally get
you better okay?
Hurry up, I'm getting
sick of you people.
I'm gonna go call your mom.
Hang in there, I'll check
on you in a little while.
Don't you want to
hear your fortune?
I'll be back soon, I promise.
Lucien, are you sure about this?
No, but the conservative approach
doesn't seem to be working out.
She's bacteremic
and if we go in now...
The toughest thing is making
the right call when it counts.
- Forget it. No, it's fine.
- What?
You're gonna be an attending
soon, better assert yourself.
No, you're probably right...
You know, these decisions
are the hardest part of our job.
Consider the alternatives, follow
through in your mind, make a choice.
Can't control what
happens after that.
O.R. in 10 minutes.
I'll meet you there.
Yeah, that's totally gonna
make the elevator come faster.
Sorry, I...
Found it.
Dr. Rasgotra, perfect timing.
Page the intern,
I'm not really here.
Nick Vasquez, 28, fell
through a second story window.
- A closed window, unfortunately.
- How did you fall?
I was, uh, bailing
out of a plane.
In my dream. Uh, I'm a dream runner.
- Dream runner?
Most people are
paralyzed during REM...
they don't do what
they dream about.
My brain chemistry's off, so that
paralysis thing doesn't work right.
So you act things out?
Big-wave surfing, car
chases, dragon slaying.
- I've done it all.
- On my count. One, two, three.
All right, vitals stable en route,
complaining about abdominal pain.
- Well, that's understandable.
- Tib-fib displaced.
I'm gonna get a Stryker probe.
- What? Why?
Missed a compartment syndrome,
doesn't wanna get burned.
It's a good pedal
pulse, no swelling.
- I doubt it's compartment syndrome.
- I'll be right back.
Hey.
- Here.
- What's this?
Those Blackhawk tickets
that we got. It's, uh, this week.
You take them, Sam. Take Alex.
No, no, no. It was your idea. You
might wanna take someone else?
Gates, you have six
patients on the board...
including a fresh
trauma so cut the chatter.
Dr. Morris, four of your
patients bounced back tonight.
It would be okay if you did.
- If I did what?
- Take someone else.
Sam, will you stop it? There's
no one else I wanna take.
Here.
Gates, get plain films, then
remove shards and then irrigate.
We could use you too,
poor guy's IV keeps blowing.
- Check crit q 30 and...
- What was that?
- What was what?
- Banfield, man.
One minute she's kind of loose and cool
then snap, she's back to piranha queen.
She was annoyed
at me for being short.
She made Frank take off
his tie and throw it in the trash.
Dr. Morris, come
with me. It's important.
- Uh, good luck with the interview thing.
- Oh, right.
- Okay, you ready?
- Uh-huh.
Ta-da.
I got under the mud flaps
and matched the original color.
You are kidding.
I rebuilt the engine, threw away the
amels and installed Mikuni carburetors.
My... My dad showed up on
this for his first date with my mom.
Yeah, she was mortified,
made them walk to the movies.
A month later she
was riding on the back...
wearing nothing
but a macramé bikini.
Yeah, these have
that effect on people.
Okay. Go ahead.
Try out your new bike.
No, my new...? No, no Jerry. I
said... I said you could have it.
No way. This belongs with you.
Fire it up.
Keep the shiny side up.
Take breaths, when you
wake up we'll be done.
Dr. Rasgotra? You're gonna
be here the whole time, right?
The whole time. Did
you remember the music?
Sure did.
That's nice.
"Suite for Solo
Cello Number 1 in G."
Dr. Rasgotra, you rock.
Okay, let's get started.
Neela needs to get out of
here to work on her future.
It's okay. I canceled
my appointments.
- What? Why?
- First liter's up.
I'm post-call and exhausted.
I called in some favors to
get you those interviews.
- You feel bad about me not having a job.
- Who told you that?
You've been acting like you'd never
let me leave, but I get it, things change.
Where's this coming from?
You... You and I have never had...
a serious conversation
about of you staying.
- Exactly. Eleven blade.
- Trocar.
Ooh. It's hot in
here. Is it hot in here?
No, check this out.
- It's fine.
- Except for the pelvic fracture, right?
Uh, grade two, non-displaced.
Somebody's here to see you.
Hey, honey.
Find someone to take Oliver?
Yeah, your mom came
over. Thank God you're okay.
- Give us some room.
- You know, we've tried everything.
Sleeping bags, mitts,
hand-cuffing him to the bed.
Hey, now.
But every few months he has a crazy
dream and ends up back in the hospital.
- Oliver's your son?
- Yeah. Just turned 1.
Crit dropped another two points.
Oh, dilutional, most likely.
We'll check another
hemacue in a half-hour.
What, and meanwhile we
just let it keep dropping?
- I thought you said it was dilutional.
- Recheck it now, Sam.
I already signed out to
Suri, I'll have her know.
- What? You're leaving?
- My shift's over.
- They're waiting for me.
- Shifts and breaks...
such a nursey concept,
I've always hated them.
Bye, Mr. Vasquez.
Damn, I think I nicked
the common bile duct.
You think you did
or you did? You did.
So much inflamed
tissue, I couldn't see.
You had no business cutting.
Ten blade, we're converting to open.
Systolic's 86. Everyone knows
Samantha Taggart from the ER?
Starting clinicals for my
nurse anesthetist program.
Sponge.
Record vitals q five
minutes. I'm going next door.
- You're leaving?
- Precepting a trainee. I'll be in and out.
Bovie. SAM: Something matter?
- Not the best teach.
- Countertraction.
Thanks. NEELA:
Don't take it personally.
It's a teaching hospital.
- I'm aware.
Operating on her was
dicey to begin with.
That's your call. NEELA:
We should have our A team.
A team? Why don't you focus
on your job and let me do mine.
- Oh, my God.
- Aah!
I dialed the halothane down
when her pressure got dicey.
- I forgot to tell you to turn it back up.
- You forgot?
- I'm so sorry.
- Tell it to the girl.
Okay, let's clean this
mess up and move on.
Run a six, giving lido.
Forty milligram bolus.
Right. Then
point-five per minute.
It's the ER. They need
a surgeon down there.
Surgery's got an unstable kid
on the table, gonna be a while.
Great. Cordis in.
That wasn't so bad.
He's got a high
tolerance for pain.
- Hang a unit of type specific.
- How's it going?
He's tachy and
crit's down to 29.
All right, let's pack him
up, and get him to angio.
Angio? You mean CT, right?
No, I mean angio. He
has a pelvic fracture.
Fracture's non-displaced,
unlikely to bleed.
The ultrasound was negative.
Could be retroperitoneal.
If the angiogram is
normal we'll explore that.
Right now the pelvis
is where the money is.
In all these dreams...
you're always there.
You are always the girl.
- Nick?
- Mac three and an eight-oh.
- What's happening?
- Five thousand units heparin.
Protein C first? Not standard,
there have been good outcomes...
- for DIC or sepsis.
- Go ahead.
Thing is you have to give it before
you give the heparin or it won't work.
- Something that came up in a class.
- Okay, protein C, and then the heparin.
V-tach.
- I can't believe this.
- Point four of epi.
Going in.
Clear!
- No change.
- Again. Clear.
Hey? What happened?
What'd the angio show?
Lost his pulse before
we could do the study.
Charged to 360.
Clear.
- No change.
- Give the amiodarone.
Sorry to belabor, but you don't drop
crit 10 points from non-displaced pelvis.
If you'd scanned him you might
have seen what I'm seeing in time.
Go find an O.R. The
belly's full of blood.
- You know where it's coming from?
- Go!
Fourth epi's in.
Someone needs to
update the mother.
I should have fought you.
- You should have.
Dream runner's
bleeding out in angio.
- Okay, go.
- I promised I'd stay.
Hold compressions.
- V-fib.
- Switch out.
Go, Neela.
Go.
Ray. I'll call later.
Hold compressions.
Still asystole.
This is over.
13:43.
Please know that we
did everything we could.
Excuse me.
This can't really be happening.
I'm so sorry.
This feels like a dream.
We can't see the future.
Sometimes we can, actually. With
this handy new technology called the CT.
You heard of it?
Fine. Do I wish I could
do it over? Yeah, I do.
- There was no way to know...
- Gates was begging to get the scan.
Gates is a resident.
Don't make this about
hierarchy. If any of us...
refuse to hear another
opinion, the system breaks down.
What system? You
guys don't have a system.
- All I see here is chaos and disorder.
- Maybe that's the problem.
Maybe that's why after five months
you still don't get it, still don't fit in.
- Fit in? This isn't junior high.
- We are a team. We work together.
But you think that you're
so much better than all of us.
So much smarter. You'll
never let yourself be part of it.
If you wanna be a queen
go into private practice...
back to Indonesia,
leave medicine altogether.
But don't torture us here.
Dr. Banfield.
Jerry, turn this in to human resources.
- What are you doing?
Going home.
This isn't your fault.
- If I'd come down sooner I...
- It's not about you.
What's really going on? Are
you sick? I mean, this morning...
- the injection.
- Please. Leave me alone.
Hello?
Yes. I'll sign the
death certificate.
Well, now, what did the
phone do to deserve that?
Hi, Simon, great to see you.
How was Australia? Good. Heh.
You okay?
It's just been an
unbelievably horrible day.
You know what you need?
A didgeridoo.
Banfield just quit and I
just helped kill two patients.
Oh. Uh, Neela, I'm sorry.
Neela.
The care of every
patient is a twisty maze...
that leads to an infinite
number of potential outcomes.
We hope that knowledge
and experience guide us...
but sometimes it becomes
obvious a wrong turn was made.
Ray. It's 5 a.m.
I know, but sometimes we
do actually get to sleep on call.
Pick a color and a number
between one and 10.
Blue and three.
- B-L-U-E. One, two, three.
- Hey, at this point...
removing the source of
infection is our best option.
- You mean taking out my gall bladder.
- Let's finally get you better.
Hurry up, I'm getting
sick of you people.
I'm gonna go call your mom.
Hang in there Ana, I'll
check on you in a little while.
Don't you wanna
hear your fortune?
I'll be back soon, I promise.
If only it were possible to apply
the wisdom of our mistakes...
go back to the fork in the
road and this time be assertive.
Choose the road we think we should
take. Not the path of least resistance.
Forget it.
No, wait. Don't forget it.
She could die on the table.
She could die if we do nothing. These
decisions are the hardest part of our job.
Wait one more day. We'll move her to
PICU, I'll get ID to approve the synercid.
There's no improvement, we'll
take her to the O.R. tomorrow.
- Okay.
- Okay?
Yeah, you're almost an attending,
I need to start listening to you.
Meet me in the
unit for rounds in 10.
Yeah, that's totally gonna
make the elevator come faster.
What are you, like,
in seventh grade?
I look young, I know.
Of course I realize that
pressing a button 10 times...
is not gonna make it faster...
but sometimes when you're powerless
in a situation, you gotta do something.
That's why you're a surgeon,
right? You like to cut, fix, do.
I suppose.
Ah, but to choose inaction is
in and of itself action, isn't it?
- Who are you?
- Ned Roth.
Patient transport specialist.
Buddhist. Omnivore.
- Neela Ras...
- Rasgotra.
Yes, I know.
Have a nice day, doctor.
What are you doing?
And don't say it's none of
my business, because it is.
It is?
- How's that?
- If you're doing drugs, we need to know.
And if you wanted to keep it a secret
you wouldn't be in the break room.
It's 5:30 in the morning. I didn't
think anyone would be in here.
It's recombinant FSH hormone.
We're trying to have a baby.
Oh, wow.
We're giving in vitro a try.
Well, that's exciting.
Well, we better all hope
it works the first time.
I tell you, these drugs and
doctoring is a dangerous mix.
Why do you say that?
I'm erratic, indecisive and I've
been a real bitch to the staff.
Really?
Even more than I usually am.
Everyone and everything
just seems to get on my nerves.
I don't know,
maybe I should quit.
Oh, no. Don't be silly.
- Neela? This conversation?
- It never happened.
Dr. Rasgotra, perfect timing.
Page the intern,
I'm not really here.
A guy fell out of a second-story
window, they need a surgeon in Trauma 1.
All right. Page Dubenko
and let him know, okay?
I hear you're interviewing for attending
positions at trauma conference today.
- You did?
- Yeah.
Lucien's whining about
losing you to another institution.
He was?
Don't look shocked, you know he's
grooming you for a faculty position.
He's the one who set
up all the interviews.
- That's the game.
- What do you mean?
My brain chemistry's off, that
paralysis thing doesn't work right.
So you act things out?
Big-wave surfing, car
chases, dragon slaying.
- I've done it all.
- On my count. One, two, three.
Mr. Vasquez, please meet our
esteemed surgical colleague...
- Dr. Neela Rasgotra.
- Hello.
- Am I going to need surgery?
- I hope not.
Oh. These seem superficial,
but let's get an x-ray to be sure.
- Ultrasound?
- Just called for the machine.
Tib-fib displaced, I'm
gonna get a Stryker probe.
Good pedal pulse, no swelling. He
doesn't have compartment syndrome.
Gates missed a compartment
syndrome last week, he's got PTSD.
- That's ridiculous.
- Five minutes.
Can't let a bad case derail your
focus on the patient in front of you.
Someone ate their
Wheaties this morning.
- You guys looking for this?
- Yeah.
Can we lower the table, please?
- Hey. I haven't seen you all week.
- I know.
- It's weird.
- Yeah, really.
Sam, we need a
second line over here.
I have something that I
wanna give you later, okay?
I'm not getting a good look at the
spleen, but the belly looks clear.
No sign of internal injuries.
- I'll stay here, you run the board.
- I'm already in on this.
I am in no mood to move the meat. I
have the authority to do what I want.
Drunks, drug seekers, hysterical
parents. They're all yours. Shoo.
- Okay.
- I gotta run rounds in the PICU.
Hi. How's the new digs?
Okay, except for no TV.
Well, at least you have
your own room up here, right?
Her, uh, oxygen
level's still a bit low.
So, what now?
We wait. And hope her own
immune system conquers the infection.
She can do it. She's tough.
I need you to get better so you can help
me download Scrabble on my cell. Okay.
Hey. How's she doing?
Twenty of dopamine, sats hanging
around 90, lactate's on the edge.
Well, next 24 hours
will give us our answer.
- You off to interviews?
- I was thinking of canceling.
Are you crazy?
I should see this through.
No, go. I'll take care of it. I'll
call you if anything changes.
Trauma programs will
be fighting over you.
All right, then.
- You know, um, I don't get it.
- Get what?
You seem to be
dying to get rid of me...
you keep mumbling about
the hiring freeze at County...
pushing me to do
interviews all over.
- But then I keep hearing other things.
- What other things?
If you want me to stay,
how come you never asked?
We can't have this discussion until
you've seen what else is out there.
I'm serious. Just
go. Get out of here.
Wow. Look at you.
How's our dream
walker guy doing?
Runner. Dream runner.
He's stable, waiting for ortho.
Good.
I should be on the El right now,
rushing to this interview thing...
but instead I'm here
obsessing over cheese or ranch.
You know what else
I'm thinking about?
- Twinkies?
- Sam.
I think I always sort
of underestimated her.
I feel bad about that.
You know, you two should
never have broken up.
It's sort of complicated and I
think it's best if I lay low right now.
Well, inaction is in
and of itself action.
- What?
- Don't listen to me.
I'm post-call and
you know how I get.
Daria.
Hey, stranger.
- Hey, when did you get back?
- Last night.
Sorry, I, uh, haven't
eaten in, like, 24 hours.
Do you wanna go
and get a proper lunch?
Uh, no, I can't. I've got a
bunch of attending interviews.
- Cool.
- Is it?
I'm not so sure.
I'm supposed to know
things, have goals, and...
How can I have gotten this far in my life,
have no idea what I want from my life?
Sorry. I'm rambling.
And self-absorbed.
How was your trip?
Don't have to know where you're
going, you just gotta keep moving forward.
That is the key to
happiness, really.
Well, you've got it all
figured out, don't you?
See you later, Simon.
- Hello, I'm...
- Neela Rasgotra.
I'm so glad you're here.
I thought you were
in London all this time.
It was great for a while...
but I'd been gone too long...
and England just didn't
feel like my home anymore.
Believe me, I know
what you mean.
And then I got
the call from Duke.
- How's Ella doing?
- Amazing.
Eight, if you can believe it.
Oh, wow.
- She's beautiful.
- Ha, ha.
Durham's a great
place to raise a kid.
I thought I was gonna
miss the city, but I don't.
So, uh, when I left County you
were still doing emergency medicine.
Yeah, well, I saw the light.
Are you looking mainly at academic
positions or community hospitals?
- Uh, I... I don't know. Uh, both, I guess.
- Mm-hm.
And are you hoping to
focus on trauma surgery...
or are you open to
elective cases as well?
I'm open.
And, uh, do you have
any research areas?
I haven't really figured
any of that out yet.
Not really the sort of thing
one says at a job interview.
No, but I appreciate
the honesty.
So is Lucien helping you?
Helping me with what?
Figure things out.
Uh, sort of. Not really.
I don't think County's
really in my future.
County's an amazing place.
What I learned there...
It was a very intense
period in my life.
But it made me the doctor that I
am now, the person that I am now.
Did you ever
consider coming back?
Yes, briefly.
There is something to
be said for getting away...
- from the place where you trained.
- Oh?
They've known you
since you were a student.
And at some level, the faculty
will always see you as little Neela.
You go somewhere new,
you'll be taken seriously...
in a way that will not
happen if you stay.
You know, you really should
turn that off during interviews.
- Oh. I've gotta get back to the hospital.
- You don't have someone covering?
I'm so sorry.
- Let's just finish up, we're almost done.
- Thank you so much.
Maybe you should come by
and visit County sometime.
Yeah. Maybe sometime I will.
Sam, there's a bunch of
stuff I need to say to you.
Me too.
- I miss how...
- These are yours.
Gates, Morris is intubating
your sleepwalker guy.
- What happened?
- Suction.
- Crit dropped, he got altered.
- I'm in, bag him.
Call angio, tell them
we're on the way.
- Angio?
Crit drop, pelvic
fracture, he needs angio.
- What's angio?
- Run of v-tach.
Three hundred amiodarone,
two units on rapid infuser.
- Somebody please explain?
- Bleeding internally.
- We have to find out where fast.
- Can I talk to you outside for a minute?
All right, pack him up.
Let's get ready to move.
Hey, Ray. I'll call
you back later, okay?
We can't wait any longer.
Please. I want Neela here.
- Sat's 87. DUBENKO:
I'm sorry, honey.
We have to do this now.
Ana, honey, you can do this.
You've been through worse.
Oh. Mommy, the music.
I love you, sweetie.
Push the etomidate.
He's bleeding from the belly,
not the pelvis. He needs a CT.
The angio's
negative, he'll get one.
He's about to code. There's
not enough time for two studies.
We gotta make the right
decision now, the clock is ticking.
Neela, dropping crit status
post abdominal trauma...
and a non-displaced pelvic
fracture. CT or angiogram?
This our dream runner
guy? I'd get a CT.
All right, take him
to the scanner.
- Epi's in.
- What happened?
Acute chest, sepsis, she
started third-spacing everywhere.
Still PEA. Code team page.
Ana, honey, please. I know
you hear me. Don't do this, okay?
- This is my fault.
- Infection's fault.
You wanted to take her to
O.R. I knew this was wrong.
Could've been screwed either way.
Made a choice. Can't control what happens.
I'll be there. Full arrest in the scanner.
Some guy jumped through a window.
Ana, stay with us, okay? Please.
Get me the transcutaneous pacer.
Hold compressions.
This is over.
For some patients, there
is no road to recovery.
Nothing we do as doctors
will alter the outcome.
At least that's what
we tell ourselves.
Ray. It's 5 a.m.
- B-L-U-E. One, two, three.
- Hey, at this point...
removing the source of
infection is our best option.
You mean taking out
my gall bladder, right?
Let's finally get
you better, okay?
Hurry up, I'm getting
sick of you people.
I'm gonna go call your mom.
Hang in there Ana, I'll
check on you in a little while.
Don't you want to
hear your fortune?
I'll be back soon, I promise.
When their way doesn't work
and your way doesn't work...
you've got to accept
defeat or find another way.
What about
percutaneous drainage?
Maybe the pus reaccumulated
or she developed an abscess.
- Not likely.
- Less anesthesia, lower risk...
might still allow us to
remove the nidus of infection.
Okay, then what?
- Switch to synercid, watch in the PICU...
- Set it up. I'll meet you in PICU in 10.
You're almost an attending, I
need to start listening to you.
Ray. Happy birthday.
No, I didn't forget.
Jeez, man. I've never heard of
someone being so psyched to turn 30.
I'll call you back later, okay?
Big-wave surfing, car
chases, dragon slaying.
I've done it all.
Dr. Dubenko says hurry,
he's in IR with your girl.
I'm not getting a good look at the
spleen. Will you hand me a DPL kit?
Are you serious? We
don't do DPLs anymore.
It'll give us a fast answer
and spare him the radiation.
- 10-blade, betadine, and lido, come on.
- I'll give you a hand with that. Here.
- Thanks. GATES:
Hey, listen, um...
- Those Hawks tickets that we bought.
- Yeah, what about them?
Game's coming up, I was thinking I
could take Alex if you were cool with that.
- I don't know.
- Well, he loves hockey.
And it could give us a little guy
time and give you the night off.
I'll think about it.
- Fluid's pink.
- What's that mean?
You have internal bleeding and
you're gonna need an operation.
- Wow.
- We're gonna be able to fix everything up.
Morris, let the O.R. know,
okay? Dubenko's waiting for me.
- NPO and check the crit q 30.
- What the hell was that?
- What was what?
- Gates.
Following Sam around
like a puppy in there.
Guy does not know
how to play it cool.
Uh, Dr. Morris...
uh, come with
me, it's important.
Sorry, Ana, I got
stuck in the ER.
There, that's the liver. Good.
Aspirating.
Sats up to 92.
- Wow.
- What?
A lot of purulent material here.
I don't want you to
be late for interviews.
I can't leave in the middle.
Be hours before
we know anything.
Go, mingle, all the top
trauma programs will be there.
Flush. NEELA: If you say so.
And when you've
weighed all your options...
- I hope you'll decide to stay.
- What?
Assistant professor,
full benefits...
research and admin time.
You'll get an official
offer letter in a few weeks.
- Lucien. DUBENKO:
Whatever happens...
you've got a back-up plan here.
- I... I don't know what to say.
- Shut up and go.
Wow. Where are you going?
- Job interviews. I'm late.
- Good luck.
Hey, um, did our dream runner
guy make it to the O.R. yet?
- He's next.
- Do me a favor.
Repeat the ultrasound,
stay ahead of the blood loss.
- Yeah.
- Okay.
Whoa.
- Hello, Neela.
- You're back.
I'm, uh, so sorry.
I'm late for these interviews
and I have to get the train.
- I can't believe this.
- I had the guy replace all the chrome.
Install Mikuni carburetors.
Do you mind if we
borrow your bike?
Well, you know, surfing,
barbecues, all the usual January stuff.
Bastard.
Still, I missed this dark,
cold, miserable place.
Every day.
Really? And what
exactly did you miss?
I don't know.
It wasn't the weather
or, uh, my apartment.
It wasn't even the
job, really. Although...
there's this certain surgeon...
Am I, uh... Am I boring you?
I...
I couldn't seem to
get her out of my head.
You, doctor...
need to go.
I do?
Oh, I do.
You are gonna kick ass
in there, Neela, I know it.
Simon. I missed you too.
A little.
O.R.'s gonna be another hour at
least. You just did that 10 minutes ago.
I know, but I promised
Neela I'd check again.
Yeah, I don't feel so good.
He looks pale. Don't
you think he looks pale?
All right. Hang two units
on the rapid infuser...
and please call the O.R. again.
What? What is it?
The next thing, you need
to come visit Durham.
Can you really see
me living down south?
It's a lovely city, it's much
more cultured than you think.
- Simon?
- How'd it go?
Uh, very well, I'd say.
Uh, Simon, this is Elizabeth Corday,
Chief of Trauma Surgery at Duke.
And Simon is an ER
attending at County.
Nice to meet you.
Give me a call when
you've thought about things...
and we'll talk details.
Take her out for some champagne.
Well, that sounds
like you killed it.
You spend all these years...
scrambling for the privilege
of becoming a doctor.
- It feels crazy to be, you know, wanted.
- Well, get used to it.
What's this?
- Second unit's up.
- I'm in, call for a vent.
Introducer. Forty-five
minutes till they give us an O.R.
- That's too long.
- We'll never keep up.
What choice do we have? Get
a second infuser, hang an IJ.
No, I've got the subclavian.
Dump in blood and the
FFP until the room is ready.
Nick, hang on, okay? I need you.
Oliver needs you.
- V-tach.
- No pulse.
- You're charged.
- Mig of epi.
All right. MORRIS: Clear!
- Units 11 and 12 are up.
- Clear.
No change. Resume compressions.
Please, baby. Don't do this.
- Again.
Okay, enough.
Sterile sevens and
a thoracotomy tray.
I cannot bear another
one of these right now.
- Another what?
- What are you doing?
A room shortage is
a stupid reason to die.
I'll clamp the aorta and
fix this myself if I have to.
Well, all right.
Where are you going?
I have to go to the hospital
and check on a patient.
You are kidding. Have
one of the interns do it.
Just stay here, I'll
be back in an hour.
And don't say it.
Say what?
You know what.
I told you so.
- Ah, it keeps slipping.
- Try a bigger clamp.
Heart's barely filling.
I got it. All right, run in another
liter and shock him again.
All right.
- Clear.
- Sounds like you could use a surgeon.
- Back in sinus.
- Hallelujah.
Thank you.
After I ran into you, I came back
and checked. He was bleeding out.
- Could have gone the other way.
- Now, this isn't a done deal.
Okay, well, let's get him
upstairs while he's still got a pulse.
Hey, Tony.
I'm sure Alex would love to
go to that Hawks game with you.
Thank you.
Anytime.
Get some sleep, Ana.
No more 2 a.m. "Guitar
Hero" with the clerks.
I'll see you in the morning.
Don't you want to
hear your fortune?
It can wait, honey.
- She's been awake for two days.
- Yeah, go home already.
"Your actions are
the seeds of fate."
Not exactly a fortune, more
of a theory, really, but I'll take it.
Hey, you never did my fortune.
Pick a color and a number
between one and 10.
- Goodnight, guys.
- Okay. Rounds are at 7.
Okay. Green and six.
G-R-E-E-N. One, two,
three, four, five, six.