It's cold.
Good. Thank you.
There's a new girl at
the ice cream store.
She doesn't seem too fond
of buttoning her top button.
Let's go check her out.
What are we
supposed to be doing?
It's almost 4:00.
You got somewhere to be?
We know he likes
to manipulate people.
He's probably testing us.
To find out what?
How long we can look stupid for?
He said he'd be here by 3:00.
He's obviously not coming.
I'm going home.
Nobody follow her.
She Pied Pipered nine people
right out of a job last week.
Would you mind holding
my metaphor for a second?
New patient, 37-year-old male.
Suffers from severe
ascending muscle weakness.
Why are you late? To
see who'd put up with it.
So, if we'd have left, we
would have been fired?
I was going to fire
whoever stuck around,
but since everyone
stuck around...
28% curvature of the spine
has caused reduced lung capacity
and he has reduced
the bone mineral density.
The patient has spinal
muscular atrophy.
It's genetic, incurable.
This is not a
diagnostic mystery.
You have just given the
state secrets to the enemy.
What enemy? New
patient, new rules.
Today, you're going to split
yourselves into two teams.
The first to figure out what's
threatening to deprive the patient
of the 20 or so miserable
years he's got left
with SMA gets
to keep their jobs.
Take off your numbers.
You look stupid.
And I think I know
who you are by now.
Wait, how do you
want us to split up?
Good question, Overly
Excited Former Foster Kid.
There's 10 of you.
I was thinking six
against six? No, wait.
How about women versus men?
Excellent suggestion, Fat Twin.
More interesting than
evens versus odds.
Less interesting than
shirts against skins.
If your sex organs dangle,
you're the Confederates.
If your sex organs are aesthetically
pleasing, you're the Yanks.
Dr. House? I'd like to
be on the men's team.
Do your sex organs
dangle, Cutthroat Bitch?
Not yet. You've never hired more
than one female
on your team before.
If you're going to
purge an entire gender
it isn't going to
be the danglers.
Sounds logical, if you don't think
about it for more than three seconds.
I just told you that if the
danglers lose, they're out.
So, I can only assume
you're hiding the real reason.
You don't think the women
will be aggressive enough,
will be good enough at
science. They'll be too emotional.
Can I switch teams?
If the danglers
are okay, I'm okay.
We're not okay. I get it.
You don't like me because
maybe I'm a little bit competitive.
Manipulative.
"Cutthroat Bitch"
is your official title.
It's a game. You can either
play for fun or play to win.
If you want to win,
you want "Cutthroat".
No, thank you.
First thing we have to
do is get inside his head.
It's not psychological.
I'm not talking about the
patient, I'm talking about House.
He's insane, but
he's not irresponsible.
He wouldn't be playing this game if
he didn't already know the answer.
The first thing we do is
gang-bang the sucker.
There's five of us. We
can run dozens of tests.
We don't need a theory.
We just need brute force.
What about the assist dog?
Picks bacteria-infested things
up with its bacteria-infested mouth,
hands them over to the guy...
It's not the dog,
wouldn't be fair.
To who? Whom.
The men. House
knows I used to be a vet.
If the dog's the answer,
they'd be at a handicap.
What about the dog?
Assist dogs put
everything in their mouth.
Money, doorknobs...
Great. That's not what I said.
Why do you think a
low sodium... I don't.
Patient took a trip to
Thailand two weeks ago.
Hey, write bigger and angle
the board more so they can see it.
This is wrong.
It's only wrong if
they cheat off us.
And if they cheat
off us, they're wrong.
They're not cheating,
but one of them is moving.
Hey. Stop playing with your
sutures or I'll have to re-do them.
Why do you guys keep a D-cell
battery in a urine specimen cup?
Because we pulled it
from a patient's intestine.
Why would somebody
swallow a battery?
Why do you assume
it was swallowed?
Bed five needs a
bag of Ringer's lactate.
Would have been worse
if he'd used a nine-volt.
Who said it was a "he"?
False assumptions. You're good.
You're trying to get
me to think like him.
And you're trying to kiss my
ass. Why are you talking to me?
Because House is turning patient
care into a game. It's dangerous.
The patient's going
to suffer. Maybe die.
Wow! You really need a shave.
See what I did there?
Whoa.
Interesting.
I need a crash cart in here!
I didn't do it.
When a person faints,
it's because they're
not getting enough
blood to their brain.
The act of falling
corrects the problem.
You faint again strapped into that
power chair where you can't fall,
you might not wake up.
Killed by an assistive device?
At least my death
would be ironic.
I think when you
went to Thailand,
you picked up a threadworm
called strongyloides.
They usually go
up through your feet.
I didn't do a lot of
walking on the beach.
But I assume you did have
someone lay you down in the sand.
Bare back, bare legs increases
exposure tenfold over bare feet.
Two pills. You'll be all better.
Can I have some
water for those, please?
Hey, take a number!
House didn't say
anything about taking turns.
What's she testing you for?
Don't. They'll spend all
day obsessing over my idea
instead of coming up
with one of their own.
And, hey, I might be wrong.
Seriously. I'm worried
that if we don't know
what she's given you,
there could be conflicts.
No, you're not.
House told me he's
keeping track of all that.
Ten doctors. I should
be getting ten cures.
We need blood, hair, and stool.
You poop and then
you use the wooden
sticks to collect
the fecal matter,
then rub it on the green box.
Hand it to my dog.
Only one of those things
I can do on my own.
And the last couple of days,
I haven't been doing that.
Is it all right with you if we
carry you into the bathroom?
If you want me there, that's the
way you're going to have to do it.
Okay.
Ready? Mmm-hmm.
One, two, three.
Can I get a little
head support, please?
Thank you.
Why are you here?
My offices are being
used by my teams.
Teams?
Which means this is the only
place where you can yell at me.
You have "teams"?
Two of them.
I wanted to deal
with the yelling today
because I noticed
what you were wearing,
and I wouldn't have
to listen all that closely.
You can't make a
competition out of patient care.
Without competition, we'd
still be single cell organisms.
Can I go now? Not
until after the yelling.
What's wrong with him?
I have seven of the
finest minds on it.
Along with three very special...
You wouldn't be doing this
unless you already knew.
I tell you, you tell
them. Game's over.
If you know, you are
obligated to treat...
Well, then, in that
case, I don't know.
Why would a guy
voluntarily shove
a metal object into
an electrical socket?
I'm getting closer and
closer to knowing the answer.
What would happen if
I shut down this game?
I'd fire them all, hire 40
new fellowship applicants
and start the
game all over again.
You do know what's
wrong with him, right?
It would be pretty irresponsible
if I didn't, wouldn't it?
Antibiotics aren't working.
Legionella could explain
the lungs, the fever.
If she had Legionella,
she'd have low sodium.
What can you tell me about her?
She likes body surfing.
Maybe picked up a virus
swimming off Jones Beach.
But she doesn't even have the
energy to finish her crossword anymore.
Her boyfriend said...
That's it.
What is? Blurry vision.
How do you get blurry
vision from not being...
You don't stop a daily ritual that
cures boredom because you're bored.
She stopped doing
her crossword puzzle
because she's having
a hard time reading it.
What causes fever, boggy
lungs, and blurry vision?
Fungal. Aspergillus
would explain
the pneumonia, which
explains the fever.
Start her on amphotericin.
Hey, guys. Great job.
If you were going to try to take
yourself out, why choose electricity?
You eat a bullet,
jump off a building...
I love the team
thing, by the way.
Bury yourself alive
in Cuddy's cleavage.
Teamwork, collaboration,
all for the greater good...
It could have been
a suicidal gesture
as opposed to an actual attempt.
Interestingly, the
rain in Spain doesn't
actually fall in the
plain all that much.
But who puts their
internal organs
on a skillet just
to get attention?
Go ask him.
That would be cheating.
Got a diagnosis yet?
Get out of here.
Got a stool sample yet?
How could you know?
Oh, I talked to a nurse.
Pretty brilliant, huh?
I give you a move House will love
straight from one of his former fellows
and you let me join your team.
You're too late. We
already have our diagnosis.
He's lying because he
wants you to go away.
So do I.
How do we know you're
not a double agent?
Find out what we're thinking
then go back to the women.
Because I don't care
what you're thinking.
You want to know why I
want to be on your team?
Because you're idiots.
If I can get the women out
of the competition, I'm in.
And so are two of you.
So what's the big move?
It's called xenodiagnosis.
We let these bugs bite you, then
we test their feces for parasites.
Why can't you test my feces?
Because you've been chugging
milk of magnesia for the past hour.
You've got a lot going in
and nothing coming out.
Testing the bugs' feces is actually
more accurate than testing yours.
Smaller haystack,
easier to find the needle.
You okay? Get the bugs off him.
Get the bugs off him!
The test isn't done.
He's choking!
Patchy infiltrates on
the X-ray, but patient
improved with chest
PT and oxygen,
consistent with aspiration.
So, now we have another
symptom to explain.
Why does his throat think
his lungs are his stomach?
And why are your
throats closing up?
Shouldn't we be
in separate rooms?
You think I'm going to run two
differentials at this time in the morning?
Grumpy, you're first.
I'm not grumpy.
Well, why would I call
you that if you weren't?
It's an unusual combination.
Unusual equals
exotic equals foreign.
It has to be connected
to his trip to Thailand.
You practice medicine overseas?
I was with Doctors Without
Borders for eight years.
Ta-da! It's in my file.
David Blaine hides the
six of hearts in a beer bottle.
It's still impressive.
You like exotic.
Why are you here?
I want this job.
Parent sick? No. I... I just...
This is not the job you want.
This is the job in the
zip code you want.
You engaged?
Yes.
Ta-da!
Am I not allowed to grow
up and change my priorities?
You're allowed to.
People usually don't.
This is not a new symptom.
Our patient has spinal
muscular atrophy.
He has documented
trouble swallowing.
The choking is not new.
So, if it's nothing new,
what caused the old?
Strongyloides worms
explain the fainting.
We already treated...
So, he's all better,
woman who... Thirteen.
He hasn't gotten any worse.
That's a pretty passive approach
for the daughter
of an alcoholic.
Wrong again.
We could stress his
system, put him on a tilt table.
If he stays conscious,
it means we made the
right diagnosis and we win.
Then, why haven't you?
Six against four.
One of the men is going to
have to join the women's team.
On the other hand,
one of the men isn't
an actual doctor, so
I guess it's pretty fair.
Men, you're in the penalty box.
Who's not the doctor?
Glad you asked about that.
The reason I'm penalizing
you is time management.
In diagnostics, you're always
working against the clock.
The women came up with a
theory and they treated the patient.
You guys just sat
around in a lab,
hoping a series of blind
tests would give you a theory.
You wasted the patient's time.
Now, I'm going to waste yours.
Her gums are turning yellow.
Whatever it is,
it's in her liver now.
Fungal fit perfectly.
We were wrong.
And we're going to keep
being wrong until we're right.
Or until she dies.
Yeah. That was very helpful.
Need a team to tell
me we're mortals.
Look. I'm sorry. You're right.
Doesn't hurt to be reminded that
we're dealing with real stakes, here.
Liver failure is a bad
thing, but it's also a clue.
What does it tell us?
I can't let you leave if I
think you're still suicidal.
I wasn't trying to off myself.
No, that's right, you were
just trying to kill the wall.
I check this box, and
your next roommates
are going to be Jesus
and Crazy McLoonybin.
That guy never had a chance.
It's going to sound stupid.
Suddenly, you're shy?
You pooped your
pants in front of me.
It's one of the nasty
side effects of dying.
Last Saturday I
got in a car crash.
A drunk driver came over
the line and hit me, head on.
It was like slow motion.
I saw these headlights,
then,
I saw...
Paramedics said I was
technically dead for 97 seconds.
It was the best 97
seconds of my life.
Okay, here's what happened.
Your oxygen-deprived
brain was shutting down.
A flood of endorphins and
serotonin was released.
That's what gave
you the visions.
No. Believe me. It
wasn't chemicals.
I've done every
hallucinogenic there is.
This was way bigger than that.
There's something out there.
Something more.
Hey, can I have my knife back?
Nope.
Who the hell isn't a doctor?
House said we can't talk.
He meant we can't
talk about the case.
House is just jerking us around.
That's what he does.
You're not curious.
Only one reason you
wouldn't be curious.
We should talk about the case.
He's punishing
us for wasting time.
Maybe we shouldn't
be wasting this time.
Close that door.
You're going to
get us all fired.
We need to find a link between
fainting and trouble swallowing.
We need to know if it's
dysphagia or full-blown achalasia.
Paraganglioma.
How would a neo-plastic
growth in his abdomen explain...
Not his abdomen. In his neck.
A carotid body tumor
causes trouble swallowing.
Food presses against the vagus
nerve and causes the fainting.
So, if this guy has cancer,
we get to keep our jobs.
If he's healthy, we're fired.
We need a CT to prove it.
And we need the women not to
figure it out while we're sitting here.
And does House's computer
have a built-in microphone?
There is a potential toxicity
with an experimental treatment.
I was never here.
Blood pressure is remaining
stable through 60 degrees.
No pauses on his EKG, no nausea.
Our treatment worked.
I need our patient.
Syncope's cured,
Amber. It's over.
You obviously haven't
stressed his system hard enough.
You crank it up high
enough, anyone will pass out.
This is incredible!
This is the most I've
moved in 20 years.
The tilt table test showed
that the patient's EKG,
BP and pulse remained
normal, despite...
Who are you, Thirteen?
My name's in the file.
The fact that you won't
answer my questions
tells me more about
you than answers could.
No, it doesn't.
We turned the thing
up to 95 degrees...
You don't think that
non-answers tell me anything?
Sure. Just not as
much as actual answers.
That's why they're
called answers.
They tell me you're
hiding something.
Tells you I'm hiding everything.
Tells me you've got
something worth hiding.
Was it Turkish prison? Gay porn?
You killed a man just 'cause he
was asking too many questions?
Can I finish reporting
on the patient?
No need.
See you in an hour or so.
Got to set some stuff up.
Thank you all for
coming to tribal council.
A man of your integrity, I
feel I can trust, Big Love.
And I don't call you that
'cause you're a Mormon.
Where's your team's sixth man?
She went rogue. Broke the rules.
You also sinned. You have
no right to cast the first stone.
And atheists have no
right to quote scripture.
The rules said, "No talking."
I told them not to talk.
Out loud.
We were trying to
save a man's life.
Key word being "trying".
Tilt table test confirmed
that you guys were wrong.
You're fired.
The prodigal son returneth.
You're also fired.
We thought there was a tumor
on the patient's esophagus.
We were right about the area,
wrong about the diagnosis.
Turns out the esophagus is just
straightening. It's scleroderma.
Explains the syncope
and the choking.
He needs steroids.
You did a CT scan? Obviously.
After you were
already proven wrong?
Good for you.
It's too bad you're wrong.
Straightening indicates
weakening, not hardening.
SMA explains the weakening.
Strongyloides infection
explains everything else.
You ladies have the honor to
give the patient a feeding tube.
Discharge him. Show
up for work tomorrow.
The rest of you...
You're a disappointment.
You make me want
to stop dangling.
It was the best two
weeks of my life.
I think I will miss you most
of all, Ridiculously Old Fraud.
Do you think House
could be wrong?
I thought he fired you.
No. He fired the men.
I don't think he's wrong.
If he is, how would I prove it?
I just said I don't think he is.
Well, thinking
isn't good enough.
You have to run a blood test
for anticentromere antibodies.
Would you mind running the labs?
You can't.
Well, I can, but...
No, I was making a statement.
You've been fired.
So, you no longer
have lab privileges.
You weren't coming
here for advice.
You were coming here to
con a favor to save your job.
Sorry. I'm not working
for him anymore,
but he can still make
my life miserable.
And you have a chance
to make his life miserable.
I'm insulted.
You conned Cameron by
appealing to her humanity...
I told her what
she wanted to hear.
And you told me what you
thought I wanted to hear.
If it's any consolation, I think
your motives are more interesting.
I cannot believe he fired you.
Go draw his blood.
I'll meet you in the lab
when I'm done here.
Guess you didn't
find your tumor.
The other doctors tell
you that you were fine?
Yeah, in the sense it's just
my disease getting worse.
You come to terms
with this disease.
You know it's there.
You know it's waiting.
And every now and again
it takes something away.
Took my walking.
Took my modesty.
Now, it's taking one
of my last pleasures.
Well, there's an outside shot
that something
other than the SMA
is causing your eating problems.
And if it is, we can
fix it, remove that tube.
Is that my blood? It's green.
What does that mean?
It means I'm not fired.
Is he a Vulcan?
If no, what makes
Nimoy bleed green?
Are we officially un-fired?
How do we know she
didn't fake the green blood?
'Cause that would be stupid.
And while she may be
manipulative, borderline evil, shallow...
They get it. I'm not stupid.
What contrast did
you use for the CT?
ICM.
His kidneys aren't working.
They didn't filter the contrast,
which, in ICM, is green.
Ten points.
Okay, let's add kidney
failure to our list of symptoms.
What are these points? Is that
how you're deciding who to fire?
I'm going to fire the next person
who asks me who I'm going to fire.
Now we're on the point system?
What happened to
men against women?
Forget the game.
What do you mean,
forget the game?
I mean, forget the damn game!
This guy's kidneys are failing.
We need to diagnose exactly...
I thought we were diagnosing.
You were diagnosing.
Now, I am, too.
I thought that Thirteen was
right about the strongyloides.
I was obviously wrong.
Okay, kidney failure,
aspiration, fainting. Go.
Kidney failure could be the
result of a gram negative bacteria.
Our patient wears
a catheter full-time.
It virtually guarantees
bacterial infection.
Which could have
migrated up to his kidneys.
Infection stresses his already
weakened system, makes his SMA worse.
That explains the
choking and fainting.
Put him on an IV amp and gent.
Our team's scleroderma
diagnosis still holds.
The test could have
been negative because
the blood was tainted
with the contrast.
Do a skin biopsy.
Get a side of lymph
node to confirm.
I could have you fired.
You already had me fired.
Just proves that I can.
Were the men wrong?
No.
That doesn't change the fact...
Why are you yelling at me?
Because performing
tests for someone
who is not a doctor
in this hospital...
You're frustrated. You
want help, I'm here.
If you just need to
vent, leave a message.
I like him better
like this. You?
Patient developed pneumonia.
His lungs are filling fast.
We started him on antibiotics.
Nothing. We were wrong.
And you're here to say?
We were wrong, too.
He doesn't have scleroderma.
Biopsy revealed
no fibrotic changes.
Cervical lymph
node has black flecks.
Just small areas of
necrosis. It's nothing.
You say, "Nothing,"
I say, "Cancer."
It's a bit of a stretch
to jump right to cancer.
I'm not jumping.
Broad specs haven't
worked, so it's not bacterial.
Failing liver despite treatment
suggests it's not fungal.
And her high lactic
acidosis points towards
anaplastic large cell lymphoma.
Also suggests infection, which
is a lot easier and safer to treat.
Large cell lymphoma
is incredibly aggressive.
She'll be dead in a week
if we follow the textbooks.
Unless it's infection, in
which case you irradiate her,
and she'll be dead in a day.
And I know you have
some experience with that.
I've seen doctors
do this before.
Go back to the
scene of the crime,
if you're right this time, you
purge yourself of past ghosts.
I know it's
contrary to protocol.
But I think it's more likely...
Ghosts are there for a reason.
So you don't make
the same mistake twice.
Switch her over to
third-generation cephalosporin.
You want to remove his eye?
Who told you?
You booked the OR.
Good.
You can't beat
me in a foot race.
I thought we were dancing.
Cervical lymph node
is a garbage dump.
A very small one.
Just one truck comes and it
only comes from one home.
Al Gore would be
appalled. The home...
The home is the
right eye. I get it.
Do a biopsy.
On my way.
You're not doing a biopsy.
You ordered an
orbital exenteration.
Right. Because I don't want
to remove a little, tiny piece,
sit in the lab and confirm
what I already know,
while my patient
drowns in his own fluid.
But if you want me
to, I absolutely will.
How advanced is the pneumonia?
It's taking college courses.
Hey, Wilson!
I'm going to cut
some cripple's eye out!
Want to come watch?
Good times.
We good to go?
I thought melanoma
was skin cancer.
Technically, it's cancer
of the pigment cells.
The same cells that
give your iris its color.
Cancer?
Why not? What else
can God throw at me?
Hail, locusts, smiting
of the first born...
All depends on
how evil you've been.
House.
If it's cancer, it's spread
everywhere, right?
That's what's in my
lungs? My kidneys?
There is a chance, by removing
the eye, to get the primary tumor,
and three courses of radiation,
that could...
Could what? A few months? Years?
More likely months.
Any of your other doctors
have any cheerier diagnoses?
If they do, they're
wrong. This is the answer.
It's the only way to help you.
I already can't
walk. I can't eat.
You're telling me
that the rest of my life
is in this bed, puking and pain?
We can manage the pain.
I'd rather just
get this over with.
I've been trapped in this
useless body long enough.
It'd be nice to finally get out.
Get out and go where?
I mean, you think you're
going to sprout wings
and start flying around
with the other angels?
Don't be an idiot.
There is no "after".
There's just this.
House!
You can't let a dying man
take solace in his beliefs?
His beliefs are stupid.
Everybody lies.
Some for good
reasons, some for bad.
This would have been
a fantastic reason to lie.
Hi. Greg House.
Why can't you just let
him have his fairy tale?
If it gives him comfort
to imagine beaches
and loved ones and life
outside a wheelchair...
Are there 72 virgins, too?
It's over.
He's got days, maybe hours left.
What pain does it cause you if he
spends that time with a peaceful smile?
What sick pleasure
do you get in making
damn sure he's filled
with fear and dread?
He shouldn't be making
a decision based on a lie.
Misery is better than nothing.
You don't know there's
nothing. You haven't been there.
Oh, God, I am tired
of that argument.
I don't have to go to
Detroit to know that it smells.
Yes. Detroit, the
afterlife, same thing.
You're not getting
enough oxygen,
so we're inserting a tube
directly into your lungs.
It should help us drain
some of this excess fluid.
Should make you a
little more comfortable.
SATs are still dropping.
The fluid's clear.
If this was cancer,
there should be blood.
Call House.
He just paged me.
Dr. House!
Maybe it was
just an accident.
It wasn't an accident.
Think his nihilism got the best
of him and he tried to kill himself?
He paged me. He paged you?
Why you? I assume because...
Don't assume anything.
Don't fall into that trap.
Is he okay?
Burned his hand pretty good.
His heart stopped
for nearly a minute.
But your cohort
managed to restart it.
But he has not
regained consciousness.
So, since I have you all here,
we should probably talk
about your actual patient.
Clear fluid from the lungs
indicates that it's probably not cancer.
So it would be nice if we
could come up with a new idea.
You're an idiot. You
nearly killed yourself.
That was the whole idea.
You wanted to kill yourself?
I wanted to nearly kill myself.
Is he better?
No.
But he doesn't have cancer.
We think it might be
eosinophilic pneumonia.
Maybe you didn't want to die,
but you didn't care if you lived.
You insisted that I
needed to see for myself.
Was he discharged?
No. He's dying.
You've already had two
near-death experiences.
Not that guy, the guy
in the car accident.
With the knife.
I need to talk to him.
He died almost an hour ago.
Apparently, it's bad
to electrocute yourself
within days of suffering
massive internal injuries.
Why did you need to talk to him?
Did you see something?
Eosinophilic pneumonia.
House? What did you see?
Nothing.
Whose idea was that?
Brennan.
"Nothing," you don't want to
talk about it, or, "Nothing..."
Which one's Brennan?
Is he the ridiculously old guy?
House, you've got
to talk about this.
If it's aggressive enough it might
have gotten past the steroids.
Start him on cyclophosphamide.
I already did.
Just looking at you hurts.
I'm gonna order up
some extra pain meds.
I love you.
How fast will this work?
New meds should start helping
in minutes, okay? Hang in there.
Vacutainer's full. I
need to replace it.
I don't think it's working.
Try and relax.
You must be wrong.
Stop talking.
Hurry up and get the
chest tube working.
Okay. I got it.
Can you get Hoover?
I can't...
Can you put my
hand
on his head?
It's okay. Don't worry.
I'm not scared.
Oh, God.
Time of death...
You're looking better.
Stark's dead.
What are you doing?
Going to see our patient.
He's dead.
"Dead" is not a diagnosis.
You really shouldn't be...
Shut up and give me my cane.
I assume we're all fired.
Should I fire myself, too?
I thought it was strongyloides,
then I thought it was cancer.
A little help, here?
Ready? One, two...
Why did you call me?
Because if I pooped
myself in front of Wilson,
I'd never hear the end of it.
But why not one of the others?
You always have that
phone in your hand.
We all have cell phones,
that's not the reason. What is?
If I died, you'd
never get the job.
I knew you wouldn't
let that happen.
You don't think anybody
else has any reason to care?
I think this is starting
to come back to me.
It's right, left, then repeat.
Yeah. That works.
What did we miss?
If we knew, he wouldn't be dead.
So, that's it? You're
just gonna give up?
No. We were defeated. It's over.
Patient presented with syncope.
We thought it was thread
worms, gave him ivermectin.
Thank you.
The patient seemed better
until his blood turned green.
Can we at least
remove the body before
launching into a purely
academic exercise?
The patient didn't respond
to antibiotics or steroids.
You okay, boy?
What's wrong with the dog?
He's dead.
There are only a
handful of viruses
that can cross between
dogs and humans.
But they may not
be connected at all.
The dog was old.
I've seen it before.
They hang on way past
their normal life expectancy
to take care of their masters.
Did you watch
him take the pills?
The ivermectin. Did
you watch the patient
put them in his mouth
and swallow them?
I don't know. I think so.
What kind of dog is that?
English Shepherd.
That's in the
collie family, right?
Not really.
But they share the MDR-1 gene?
Yeah.
What happens when you give a
dog with the MDR-1 gene ivermectin?
They don't.
I mean, it's used to treat
heartworms in most dogs,
but it would be fatal if they...
Look familiar?
I think the last
time you saw it,
it didn't have that dead
dog's teeth marks on it.
I just put it on the bed
tray to get him some water.
When I asked you if you watched
the patient swallow the pills,
the right answer was, "No."
Take his body
down to the morgue.
If you hadn't treated this patient
as a game, he wouldn't be dead.
Feeling much better, thank you.
I'm supposed to
show you sympathy?
He died while his attending
was lying on a hospital bed
because he stuck a
knife in a wall socket.
He died because a
doctor made a mistake.
She was an idiot.
You employed her.
You're responsible.
Dr. Foreman.
How's she doing?
Fever's gone. AST and ALT
are back within normal range.
She should be out
of here in a few days.
Gutsy call.
Thanks.
It wasn't a compliment.
If you were wrong,
she'd be dead.
I was sure...
No, you weren't.
You couldn't be.
There's a reason we have rules.
If every doctor did whatever
his gut told him was right,
we'd have a lot more
dead bodies to deal with.
It won't happen again.
Yes, it will.
Because you confuse saving
her life with doing the right thing.
I'm sorry, Dr. Foreman,
you're fired.
As soon as the pathologist
cut into the lungs,
we saw the threadworms.
Do you think
it's fair that I fired
all the other
members of your team
when you guys actually came
up with the right diagnosis?
I keep replaying it in my mind.
Did I drop the pills when I
put them on the bed tray?
Did I knock them over
when I turned to leave?
You know, he'd be alive.
His dog would be alive.
I know.
You forced us to act
on a false assumption.
I know.
Everything we built
from that step on,
every test, every
theory, every treatment...
I know. Forget the
lecture and fire me already.
If I was gonna fire you, I
wouldn't be giving you the lecture.
I know you're not gonna let
anything like this ever happen again.
I'll see you tomorrow.
I'm sorry to say,
I told you so.