The longest surgery on
record lasted for four day straight.
A team of surgeons
rotated in and out,
holding scalpels for sometimes
18 hours at a stretch.
♪ I've got, got,
got to let it out ♪
♪ Oohhh, oohhh ♪
♪ I've got, got,
got to let it out ♪
♪ Let it out, let it out,
let it out ♪
♪ Oohhh, oohhh ♪
Try holding anything
in your hand for 18 hours...
♪♪
♪ Didn't think it would hurt ♪
♪ I'll make sure to say it
like I mean it ♪
Now imagine you're also holding
a human life.
Okay, if my LVAD
batteries cost $500 apiece
and I need 25 of them,
how much is that?
12,500.
Very good.
- Do you think that will be enough?
- Definitely.
Are you sure?
Because if the te...
I need an adult now.
I'm trying to figure out
how much money to allocate
toward my test materials.
It's very stressful.
Please.
You have $100,000.
I have a 90-year-old Spanish
doctor I have to convince
to give me his patent
on his cross-polymer
so April Kepner doesn't
find out that I'm a fraud
and a disgrace to medicine.
You're not a disgrace.
A fraud, yes.
Try having zero dollars and
a 12-year-old with a brain tumor
you promised to get rid of.
Sorry.
We'll stop now.
Auntie Amelia is so grumpy
when she loses.
♪ ...need to let it out ♪
♪ Let it out, let it out,
let it out ♪
♪ Oohhh, oohhh ♪
♪ Let it out, let it out,
let it out ♪
Limited test subject
availability.
Kepner didn't believe
we'd get the kids' parents
to let us try this
on them.
Who's Kepner to judge?
Besides, you know,
being the judge.
You're not giving up
on Kimmie though, right?
Hell no.
I'm not giving up.
But she kinda looks like
she might be.
Hey, ladybug!
Come here. Hello.
Hey, I just wanted to say "hi"
before I had to go to work.
Come here, ladybug.
Oh!
- What is, uh, all this?
- Hello.
- Are you sick?
- Oh, I'm just a little
ung-hay over-ay.
Partied a bit too hard
last night, so...
I'm rehydrating.
Banana bag
works like magic.
- Partied?
- Yes, yes, yes.
- All right.
- How are you, my ladybug?
You're so squishy.
You smell like soap.
Yum.
Okay, sweetheart.
Bye, Daddy.
- I'll see you later.
- Say "bye-bye."
Hi, booboo.
Hi.
But my device
will enable
a smoother entry
for colonoscopies,
and then you won't have to
back it out and back it in
to get around the corners.
That is very cool.
Oh, uh,
good morning, Chief.
Uh, I-I didn't see your car
in the lot.
Oh, I'm taking
the train now.
Well, it's your first day
back on the job
and you're already
pushing yourself?
No, I'm...
finding a way to fit exercise
into my day.
It is 2,004 steps
to the train.
If I'd done this
a year ago,
maybe I'd have never
had a heart attack.
But you're gonna
take it easy today?
Not at all.
I've been trapped in my bed.
I've binged every
reality show ever made,
and I can physically feel
my IQ lowering.
I'm getting back
in the OR.
Pierce cleared me.
I did.
She's cleared.
I cleared her.
She's cleared,
and I'm not taking it back
no matter how sternly
you stare at me.
I had things to do today.
Now I've got to spend my day
following her.
Or you could just trust
my professional assessment.
No?
Okay.
Repeat it back to me
so I know you both know.
Okay. Dr. Cerone will be
calling from Madrid
at some point
this morning
to discuss the patent
on his cross-polymer.
They're calling on my phone,
which is fully charged
and on the loudest ring
possible.
And no matter where you are
or what you're doing
when the call comes in,
we find you.
And what are you
not going to do?
Not find you.
Or?
- Mention this to Kepner.
Correct.
Secret club!
Oh, my God.
What do you got,
Warren?
14-year-old male,
blunt abdominal trauma
and a penetrating injury
in his upper thigh.
Bleeding
from a scalp lac.
I pulled him and his brother
out of a house fire...
Chemistry experiment
gone wrong.
Did I kill
my little brother?
Please.
He's gonna be okay, right?
Mom's gonna be so mad.
Lungs are clear,
vitals are stable,
saturating 95
in the mask.
He's been coming in and out
of consciousness.
I was just trying
to teach him chemistry.
Can you tell my mom?
That I wasn't doing
anything wrong?
- Okay, I got him.
- Trauma one?
Yeah. No, Kepner,
you and Grey,
you need to meet
the other rig.
His younger brother
got thrown by the blast.
He was bleeding out
from the abdomen,
and, well,
one of our team,
she just shoved her hand
in there.
Uh, 10-year-old male
with a penetrating...
Why is your hand
inside him?
- Because he was bleeding a lot.
- Take it out of him!
You look 12. Can you find
a grown-up to tell me that?
- Do not move your hand!
- Don't let go!
See that?
Grown-ups.
Nobody move.
Can you feel a pulse?
Yeah.
What do you think she's
got in her hand, Schmitt?
His abdominal aorta?
Yep.
Don't take your hand out!
What's your name?
Herrera.
Andy Herrera.
Okay, Herrera, we got to
get him up to the OR.
And I'm sure you're
very clear about this,
but you cannot move
your hand.
Can you hold pressure while
we bring the gurney down?
My hand, arm, and shoulder
are already numb,
but... I'm going with yes.
♪♪
*Grey's Anatomy*
Season 14   Episode 13
Title : "You Really Got a Hold On Me"
- Tell me you have good news.
- I have good news.
The models are holding up
to the ultrasound?
Nope.
I just melted three more.
What? You found a way
to dissipate the heat?
Not yet,
which explains the melting.
Okay, you found the right
resonant frequency?
That's the hardest part,
so no.
So what's the good news?
I called in reinforcements.
Shepherd.
How's it going, bae?
This is the good news?
Tom, thanks for coming.
How's the head?
May I?
Oh. Seamless.
Literally.
I'm so good.
Tom, this is Alex Karev,
my partner on this project.
- Yeah, we've met before.
- Did we?
H-How do you fit
into this? Neuro?
Uh, interventional radiology?
No, peds surgery.
My patient, uh,
inspired this study.
Oh. When Shepherd said,
"on the team,"
I figured that meant
you were a player.
But, hey,
mascots are important.
Those T-shirt guns
don't fire themselves.
Tom has done
incredible work,
uh, in developing navigation
systems
- for brain surgeries.
- Blah, blah, I'm amazing.
We should, uh,
get a bite or something.
- Y-You and me.
- No, we should get back to work, maybe.
We could, uh, catch up.
You can bring me up to speed.
Uh, the data's
already here.
I just wanted you
to hit the ground running.
Oh, noses to the grindstone.
Such a tease, Shepherd.
Okay, careful, everybody.
If she moves her hand
even just a little bit,
- he's dead in seconds.
- Got it.
Keep a healthy distance.
Bump into her,
and I'll kill you.
Also got it.
♪♪
- Slow and steady.
- Careful. Careful.
Uh, that's my phone.
I figured.
Really, Helm?
Ever heard of vibrate?
It's for you, Dr. Grey.
Yeah, I can't
take it right now.
- But you said...
- I know what I said.
Just deal with it.
Hello? Uh,
Dr. Grey is unavailable, can...
Halfway there.
They do not sound happy.
I mean, it's in another
language, but a very angry...
Deal with it, Hellmouth.
Hellmouth?
She's a rookie, huh?
Yeah.
We're good.
I'm good.
His pulse feels weak.
Can we move faster?
I'm not killing a kid today.
Hey, I'm gonna run ahead
and clear a path.
Come on, come on!
If you could
just jump up there.
- Now can we go?
- Now we can go.
Is Zach okay?
We were watching
this YouTube video.
He added the peroxide
just like they said.
Ow.
We'll check on your brother,
Tyler,
a-and Dr. Hunt will give you
some more medicine
for your pain, okay?
And, uh... You were gonna
do that, right?
Yeah, I was.
Warren, don't you have
fires to put out?
Like, literal fires?
The whole thing exploded
and he wasn't saying anything.
He just laid there.
I didn't mean to...
I was just trying
to teach him science.
Listen. It's okay.
Okay, just relax.
We're gonna take care
of you both, okay?
- Should I dress these burns?
- That can wait.
Just cover the burns
with a saline-soaked gauze.
He needs a head CT, stat.
And we need to find out how deep
that metal is penetrating...
- Okay.
- ..before we remove it.
Yeah, I know that,
and you know that.
It's Dr. Qadri's job
to learn that.
Warren, I'm gonna need you
to leave so I can teach her.
Uh... right.
Right. Um...
♪♪
I'll check on your brother,
Tyler.
♪♪
Careful
around this corner.
So, w-what was
that phone call about?
I could
use a distraction.
Take my mind off the fact that
I can't feel my arm anymore
and I'm one fingertip away
from this kid dying.
Oh, there's this medical
innovation contest,
and, uh, my project is...
Picture you have a fire hose
that isn't working, right?
Okay.
Except my fire hose
is a liver.
- Okay.
- So, my idea is I want to replace it
with a sprinkler system,
except my sprinkler system
is many livers
all throughout the body.
Sounds like
science fiction.
'Cause it kind of is.
So I need a polymer,
and there's this old guy
in Madrid who has the patent.
All right,
we're turning him around.
Uh, okay, so why didn't
you take his phone call?
Because Kepner is
heading up the contest,
and I don't want her to know
that I don't have the patent.
So you're kinda screwed.
Yep, kinda.
Ease him on in.
Slow.
Uh, a
little bumpy here.
Here you go. Easy.
Easy.
What are you doing here?
The kid's brother's
freaking out,
and I-I just wanted to see
if you needed my help.
- Okay, sure. I need your help.
- Great. What can I do?
Get your ass back to the station
where it belongs.
I just want to make sure these
kids get through this okay.
Except your job is
to get to the station
so you can answer other calls
for other people
who need you to make sure
that they're okay.
♪♪
Okay. Easy.
Rookies, huh?
Oh, yeah.
♪♪
All set?
What?
Did you calculate
the expected heat energy, Bello?
Yes. Wait.
Uh...
15 centimeters.
Yes, Dr. Shepherd.
Love a good laser show.
Should we dim the lights?
Put on some Floyd?
Technically this laser
is just for aiming.
And you knew that.
So that was a joke.
Pity laughter.
My favorite.
So, turning our attention back
to the model here,
uh, when I used 400 kilohertz
frequency,
the heat produced
shattered the glass.
Which doesn't bode well
for the human skull.
Your hair has grown back
very nicely, by the way.
I meant to say that
earlier.
Can you flirt after
we've figured this out?
You're a terrible wingman,
Alvin.
Let's, uh... Let's try
focusing the beam
from a greater distance.
Got it.
♪♪
He said greater distance.
As in, move the beam away.
Yeah.
No, of course.
Sorry.
She's nervous.
You're one of her idols.
Why would you say that?
It's true.
Aw, no, I'm flattered.
And you're smoking.
- Oh! Aah!
- Oh!
Oh, God! Aah!
All right.
I can't believe this project
hasn't been funded.
Pop quiz, Qadri.
What are the most important
CT findings
in the trauma setting?
Uh, rule out
intracranial bleeding
and active
thoracoabdominal injury
that would require immediate
operative intervention.
Great. Page me when
the images are up.
Oh, uh, h-hi.
Hi. I'm taking you
to CT now.
What about my brother?
Uh, we don't have an update
on him yet.
My leg hurts.
What's this?
No! No! Dr. Hunt!
- Whoa, that's a lot of... Dr. Hunt!
- Uh, I need a tourniquet.
Dr. Hunt!
- What happened?
- Uh, he pulled the metal out, and...
And he's bleeding out of what
I think is his femoral...
And I-I didn't want
to leave him
and I didn't know what else
to do, s-so I...
You did good, Qadri.
Let's get him straight up
to the OR right now.
Let's go.
♪♪
- Hey.
What is the deal
with April?
Uh, what do you mean?
She's super hungover.
She's using the word "party"
as a verb.
She's just having fun.
You know she had a rough time.
And I think she's just...
She's coming out of it.
I mean, should I be worried?
She's walking
the halls
with a banana bag.
I mean, that's not...
That's not April.
It's not who April was
with you.
I mean, she may be...
She may be someone else
without you.
I mean,
I know that I had...
I had no fun at all watching
Callie fall in love
after we broke up.
Hold on, what?
Falling in love?
Who's...
April's falling in love?
- No, no, no. No, me.
- You...
- No, I, me. It was no fun for me
- Oh, yeah. Totally.
Watching Callie fall in love
after we broke up,
but she...
She was happy.
April, I think is...
I think she's having fun.
I think... she's trying to find
her happy without you,
so maybe you just...
You try and be happy for her.
Look...
He's not speeding us up.
He's slowing us down.
He just got here.
What are we whispering
so loudly about?
She brought in Koracick.
- Oh, God. The worst.
- Total ass.
And he's only here
to have sex with her.
He is not.
- It's a booty call.
- Is it a booty call?
You did have sex with him
the last time he was here.
I never should have
told you guys that.
It was a
shame-based confession.
Okay, and you don't get
to talk about booty calls.
You are bringing booty
into our home.
Clive is not just booty.
I genuinely like Clive.
Yes, we've all heard
how much you like him.
All night long
we hear it.
I'm gonna walk away now.
Unashamed.
- Send him home.
- No.
We didn't make it
into the contest.
We have no funding.
As much as you want
to help Kimmie,
you can't help me
with the physics
of high-energy ultrasound.
Koracick may be a tool,
but he is the kind of tool
that we need right now.
See how I did that?
Tool/tool?
He doesn't go anywhere
near Kimmie.
He doesn't even get
to meet her.
Oh, God, no.
Kimmie's got enough problems.
That was fast thinking
back there.
Thank you, Dr. Hunt.
I'm surprised you just
took your hijab off like that.
Well, I mean,
it's a symbol of my faith,
but my faith is about
service and compassion,
and he was bleeding
really fast.
I'll help drape.
I got your page.
What do we got?
Uh, kid from the fire,
needs an ex lap to take care of
some intra-abdominal bleeding
and a femoral artery repair.
And what do we got,
Dr. Hunt?
Did you page
Dr. Webber as well?
I did not.
A little extra help
never killed anyone.
Dr. Hunt, he's crashing!
Gown and glove me, quick.
- I am fine.
- I'm just helping!
Never seen
this part before.
Your gear is so light.
How heavy is your gear?
It depends.
Am I carrying my axe?
So hard-core.
Okay,
let's fly in that FFP
and hang it
from the rapid infuser.
I need to just get in here
and clamp the aorta,
and then I'll get you
out of here, okay?
Pressure's getting soft.
All right,
we gotta move fast.
Scalpel, Bohkee.
Blue towel
and retractor, please.
A Satinsky.
I can't access
this aorta.
Oh, we got to hurry.
Herrera, take this clamp.
Huh? Me?
No, no, no.
This isn't even
my dominant hand.
You run into fires.
You can do this.
Well, because my dad's
a fire chief.
I mean, he taught me how to run
a hose when I was seven.
I spent my 7th birthday
up in that gallery
watching my mother
do this.
I will walk you
through this.
Take the clamp.
Okay, open and
close it for me?
Okay, good.
I'm gonna support
your free hand.
Now you're gonna slide it in and
clamp just above your fingers.
- You got it?
- Mm-hmm.
What if I miss?
I would prefer it
if you didn't.
♪♪
Okay, is it above your fingers?
I th... I think so, yes.
Okay.
So now... can you feel it
pulsating?
There! I feel it.
I-I clamped it, I think.
- Okay.
- You can take your hand out.
Herrera,
take your hand out.
You told me that if
I took my hand away,
he'd bleed out in seconds.
Yeah, that was before
you clamped him.
Yeah, I don't know
if I clamped it.
- I'm not a doctor.
- Will you just trust me?
Let go of the clamp.
Move!
- Clamp.
- Need some suction.
Great. Bovie.
You did it, Herrera.
He's still alive.
Let's hang two more units.
Sponge stick, Bohkee.
♪♪
Hey, there's scut that's
not gonna do itself, Bello.
And by do itself, I mean,
I'm not gonna do it for you.
Sorry, I'm...
Sorry.
You can page me if you need me,
Dr. Koracick.
Count on it, Dr. Bello.
Geez.
She's hot.
Dancer body. Ass for days.
She single?
Gross.
Um, she's a doctor,
so unless she's
some kind of a savant,
she's of age,
which makes her fair game.
Why so judgy, DeLukes?
Can we just focus
on the project?
There is no project.
There aren't enough variables.
We're talking thermal ablation
of targets
with micromillimeter
precision.
She'll never get there
with just heat versus time.
Why is Shepherd
still barking up that tree?
- I think it's the time frame.
- What time frame?
Rome wasn't built
in a time frame.
- What's the rush?
- Kimmie. Kimmie is the rush.
What in God's name
is a Kimmie?
That.
That's Kimmie.
Oh.
Hmm.
This kid
won't stop bleeding.
Oh, there it is.
Hey, he transected his
superior mesenteric artery.
- Can we fix that?
- We can fix that.
We will do
a reverse saphenous graft.
Oh, that'll take hours.
Why don't you and I
swap out, Bailey?
I'm sure the paperwork's
piled up after your vacation.
Uh, no, I managed
to stay caught up.
I'm fine.
Here, why don't you
harvest the graft
since
you're already there?
I just thought maybe
you'd want to ease back in.
What is a vacation for,
if not to recuperate
so that one can return to work
at full strength?
Um, more suction here,
Qadri.
His ischemia time's
getting up there.
I'm aware.
You know, some vacations
are so strenuous
that you need a vacation
from your vacation.
Ben Warren,
as handsome as you look
in your uniform
and as grateful as I am that
you are still alive today,
you do not belong
in there.
Get out.
I brought your patient in.
I just wanted to see
how he was doing.
And how you're doing,
since it's your first day back
from vacation.
Okay,
my vacation is over.
I went on it,
and I am back.
It was glorious,
but like all experiences,
it now lives on in
the cherished memories
that I share
with no one but myself.
So stop talking about
my vacation!
- Hey, where'd you go?
- None of your business!
Warren, um, she's right.
You don't belong in here.
Uh, I've got my eye
on everything in here.
Now his bowel is
getting dusky.
This kid's gonna wind up
with a stool bag.
Oh, no, sir.
Not on my watch.
Not on my first day back
he's not.
Where's Koracick?
I sent him
to see Kimmie.
- You did what?
- Damn it.
What? Why?
Was that wrong?
♪♪
Oh, God.
Of course that was wrong.
I'm just calling it
the way I see it,
and the sooner
you face the truth...
You're full of crap
and you know it!
"Hamilton" only made
your top three
because it's new and shiny.
And you only left it off
your list because you're bitter
that you couldn't score tickets
for the original cast.
It goes "Cabaret,"
"Hamilton," "Rent."
So... no Sondheim?
Stephen Sondheim.
- Damn it. Sondheim.
- Yeah, can't count him out.
Count of three. Best Sondheim.
One, two, three.
- "Into The Woods." Oh.
- "Sweeney Todd." Gross.
No, he wielded
a hell of a scalpel.
They've been at this
for 20 minutes straight.
Happiest I've seen her
in days.
"Into the Woods," a quarter
of the Broadway audience
left that show
at intermission.
'Cause they want
an easy, happy ending.
But, hello, that's why
it's brilliant.
Doctors. Second opinion.
Weigh in.
Uh...
Ah,
love me a good weirdo.
I can see why you're trying
to rush the process.
Good. Now we can make
some headway.
Oh, I have no doubt
we're gonna make
this ultrasound our bitch
and save a lot of lives.
But let's not, uh, delude
ourselves into thinking
Kimmie's
will be one of them.
There is no easy,
happy ending here.
She's
got a few months to live,
you know,
if she's lucky.
New Guy.
I know.
I shouldn't be here.
I just placed a clamp.
On an aorta.
- You did?
- Yes!
Damn. I... I gotta admit
I'm kinda jealous.
It was amazing.
And awful, because
as soon as I placed it,
the whole OR erupted,
and then...
It's hard having
a front-row seat,
and then getting kicked out,
ya know?
I do.
I just hope he makes it.
You... You wanna see
for yourself?
Look, I-I can't get you
front row,
but... I can get you
pretty close.
Come on.
The patient's mother's
here.
She's looking
for an update.
Okay,
the graft is ready.
Dr. Qadri, can you go out
and update...
Oh, no,
Dr. Qadri cannot.
She cannot go and update this
patient's mother by herself
because she's an intern.
An intern who has yet to update
any patient's family
about anything.
And she's not going to start
by facing that mom alone
to tell her her two boys
might not make it
out of this alive.
Oh, for the love of...
Mm.
I had a heart attack!
Hmm.
That's what Dr. Webber has gone
out of his way not to say.
He's gone out of his way
all damn day
to not reveal my secret,
to not let me do my job,
and to make sure that I'm not
putting any extra stress
and strain on my body,
and it's not okay.
I know better than
to show up
to this hospital
before I'm ready,
I know better than to put
a child's life
in my hands
before I am ready,
and I am ready
to do my job.
Now, I would appreciate everyone
doing their own jobs, too.
Focusing on the field,
until the awkward goes away.
5-0 prolene, please.
Dr. Bailey, look,
all we're...
Babysitters get paid
$10 an hour.
You want to get paid
$10 an hour?
I can arrange for that.
Go.
Come on.
Clive's nice.
He's cute.
He's funny.
Aww.
And the sex?
Wow, you're just getting
straight to it, huh?
Well, Carina is...
Is only getting better.
There's, like, no slump.
It's the opposite
of a slump.
It's a boom.
It's a sex boom.
Ladies, what are
we laughing about?
- Sex.
- Nothing.
Sex? Really?
I was expecting
maternal mortality
or rechargeable hearts
or something.
But, no, that's...
I can talk sex.
Well, you know, the thing about
rechargeable hearts...
Maggie's got a date
with Clive.
- Is Clive still around?
- Mm-hmm.
- Look at that. That's adorable.
I got a date tonight,
too.
- Oh.
- Uh, Priya is her name.
Oh.
Yeah.
- Who? - Priya.
- Did you make that up?
Very cool, brilliant,
- actually. - Oh.
- Mm.
Very attractive.
Human rights attorney, so...
- Well, that's hot.
- That's hot.
- Pretty impressive, yeah.
- Yeah, that is... That's hot.
Interesting.
Um, you know,
I think I'm gonna...
vending machine.
- Really?
- Yeah.
- Oh.
- Huh.
I'm gonna start
double gloving.
My hands smelled like bedpan
when I was eating
- last night.
- Oh.
I scrubbed in on
a bowel resection yesterday.
Being on The Party's good
side has benefits.
I almost called her Dr. Party
this morning
instead of Dr. Kepner.
Is that
a fireable offense?
You're just gonna be
really happy for her.
- No, super happy, overjoyed.
- Okay. Yep.
I never would've pegged myself
as a guy who's into moms,
but moms make you do things
till you get 'em right.
Nope.
- Dr. Roy.
- Hey, buddy.
Um, I've got a patient,
Mr. Wilkins, in 1413,
with a large, super infected
abscess in his groin
that you're gonna
drain for me.
- Um...
- Now.
- Yes, I-I tried.
- Maybe you should try harder.
She's the mother of my kid,
- and this...
- Harder, harder.
Kepner, Grey, I'm about
to update his mother.
What can you tell me?
He had an injury
to his abdominal aorta
- that we're trying to repair.
- Ah, damn.
It's a mess.
We're still trying to evaluate
the extent of the injury.
Can I get a towel?
All right.
Okay, we're good.
So, you're a rule breaker?
Uh, n-no.
Only at places
I no longer work.
Mm-hmm.
Both your boys sustained
serious injuries
and are in surgery.
We'll let you know more
as soon as we can.
Both of them?
Are they okay?
They're in surgery,
but they'll be okay, right?
We're fighting for them.
We're doing everything we can.
I have a job.
I have to work.
I need to feed them
because they are 14 and 10
and they eat everything
that isn't nailed down.
I cannot hold onto them
every minute of the day.
I have to go to work.
They're 14 and 10.
I mean, they should be able to
be home for a morning
while I go to work
without...
Oh, my God.
Tyler is 14,
and Zach is 10.
They have to be okay.
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God!
- I can't believe you used to do this.
- What?
This. That.
Y-Y-You did that.
And you were good at it?
Um, yeah.
- Thanks for the vote of confidence.
- I'm... I'm just saying.
Y-You did this
incredibly cool thing
that probably pays a hell of
a lot more than what we do,
you did it well,
but you walked away from it?
Why?
To do more.
I mean, yes,
I used to do that down there,
with the patients in the OR
where you're trying to fix them,
but I, you know...
I also cut open a guy
with a clipboard.
I mean, y-y-you know the metal
part of a clipboard?
- Mm-hmm.
- Yeah, I broke it off
and used it as a scalpel.
Cracked his chest because
we were nowhere near an OR
and I... I did
what I had to do.
And I saved his life,
but I... got into trouble.
A lot of trouble.
You know, but I-I never felt
anything but proud.
So now I'm doing a job where
I'm the first one on the scene
and I get to do whatever
it takes to save that life.
And that's only
a good thing.
I was just looking for a
"because fire" kind of answer,
but okay.
Can we listen to what's
going on down there?
- Only if you don't let me talk anymore.
- Mm-hmm.
Hey!
What's going on?
Amelia called Koracick,
and I hate him.
Like, I want put him in
an old-fashioned choke hold
and throw him down the stairs
hate him.
Okay.
You hate him because...
What? I need a reason?
Have you met the guy?
Did something happen?
With Kimmie?
It's just... some kids
get under your skin.
You're dropping out?
Really?
I'm not dropping out,
but I'm not gonna rush
developing this thing over
an unrealistic deadline.
- You don't agree.
- No, I don't.
You think I don't know that
this girl is dying?
You should have seen her
when we first met her.
She is a fraction
of who she was.
But she is still alive,
and she is still full of hope,
and that means we don't
get to say, "I give up."
If doctors said,
"I give up,"
we would all be dead
of cholera right now.
We don't get to give up.
We don't get to write her off.
We don't quit.
Yeah, I know
you think you're right,
but you're used to
Brain Tumor Shepherd,
so you don't hear it
when nonsense
comes out of your mouth.
I am not being crazy.
Then stop being naive.
Stop being a ridiculous
Pollyanna
and please, please
stop diminishing
this little girl's life
by barking things at me that
belong on a refrigerator magnet.
It's beneath you.
She is going to die,
and any effort that you spend
that doesn't go toward
preventing that
is a supreme disservice
to her.
And this...
This is not gonna save her.
This is the only thing
that might save her.
She's not gonna have
much of a life
with an exploded,
flaming skull.
- Well, then, we reduce the heat.
- And you leave the tumor!
You do nothing!
God, you're... Then we attack
it from another angle!
We do something else entirely!
Maybe it's not ultrasound.
Maybe it's some kind of
radiation...
- Sh-Shut up.
- You shut up!
We attack it
from another angle.
I just said that.
And then
we reduce the heat.
Yeah, I said that, too.
Why are you...
No. Mnh-mnh.
With more beams,
we control the amount
of heat generated.
This way we have
more variables.
So two beams?
Or... Or... Or seven.
Or 27, or a thousand
that we run for
shorter periods of time.
So when they enter the skull,
they don't heat it.
And where the beams
come together...
The reinforced waves
are intense enough
that they heat and kill
just the tumor!
I mean, it's...
It's brilliant.
I mean...
I'm brilliant.
Bailey, it's been five minutes
and the bowel hasn't pinked up
and I don't hear any flow.
We're gonna have to consider
resecting this bowel.
Ju... Hold on.
Sometimes it takes a while.
Was it severe?
The MI?
Severely scary.
- A stent?
- CABG.
God, Bailey. I'm sorry.
I just wish that I'd...
Wait, wait.
That was your vacation!
There you go,
Dr. Sherlock.
Uh, can I get the
fluorescein dye, please?
Thank you.
All right.
Okay. Can I get
the lights off, please?
Dr. Qadri,
you want to run the UV?
All right.
It's beautiful.
The dye is flowing
with the blood
and clearly perfusing
the bowel.
This boy will not need
a colostomy.
Vacation is over.
What is that?
W-Why is he...
I don't know.
Hit the lights.
He's tachy and his pressure's
dropping.
He's developing hives.
He must be allergic to the dye.
It's anaphylaxis.
Epi .5 and
run saline wide open.
Push 125
of solumedrol now.
Wow.
Yeah.
- Hi.
- Sorry, uh,
there is a call
coming through from Madrid.
- Madrid?
- Yeah.
Uh, I can scrub in
so that you can step away.
I can't step away
right now.
♪♪
Uh...
Sorry, that's for me, actually.
Yeah, I can take that up here.
Now, Hellmouth.
¿Te dijo este es el proyecto
más importante, no?
Por favor escuchame bien.
No, no, no.
Would it kill them
to turn off the intercom? Geez.
♪♪
Uh-oh.
Warren, what are you doing
in the gallery?
Well,
H-Herrera saved that kid,
and she just wanted to see
how he was doing, so...
Waiting room is for
first responders to wait
and to make calls.
I know, but...
You brought that kid
out of the fire.
You brought him to us.
The rest isn't up to you
anymore.
You made your choice,
Warren.
It was a tough choice,
but you made it.
So go back to work.
Or wait in the waiting room.
♪♪
I'm not sure that went
as well as we had hoped.
♪♪
Mrs. Richardson?
I can't stand up.
I'm Dr. Grey.
I was in with your son Zach.
He made it through surgery.
He's in recovery.
And... And Tyler?
I don't know about Tyler, but
I can get an update for you.
♪♪
Uh, h-he made it.
Oh.
It was touch and go.
He had an allergic reaction
in surgery,
but Tyler made it.
Oh, my God.
Thank you so much.
Thank you.
♪♪
What's going on?
Sh-Shh. Pipe down.
You'll scare the tumor.
♪♪
- ♪ Let your heart speak ♪
- Yes! Yes!
Burn, baby, burn.
Amazing.
- I am, right?
- Yes.
Uh, y-you... y-yeah.
- ♪ When I fell, you felt it, too ♪
- Come on.
Come on, come on.
Look at that.
♪ You rattle my bones ♪
Well, it's a...
It's a start.
That's the longest
a beaker's ever lasted.
Glad you're on board,
Adam.
- It's Alex.
- Yeah, either way.
♪ Oh, you're the wildest ride
I know ♪
♪ You're my, ♪
I'm gonna see if I can dig up
- ♪ you're my ♪
- a Game Boy for you, okay?
- ♪ stix and stones ♪
- Okay.
Herrera.
You did so great
in there today.
If you ever consider
a new line of work,
we could really
use you around here.
Thought Hellmouth
might want her phone back.
- Thank you for trying.
- I didn't just try.
Dr. Cerone is gonna be
in the States next week
and has agreed
to come hear your pitch.
What?!
You're kidding.
Wait.
What did you say?
I just said they're standing
between the hose
and the flames right now,
by holding onto that patent.
I mean,
and I should know.
I was literally holding on
to something today
that I couldn't
let go of, either, but...
And then the time came
to step away
and let you take over,
and if there's anyone
he can trust to take over,
- it's you.
- Thank you.
Also I tried to explain
the whole sprinkler thing,
but I don't think
it translated.
Yeah, it really just sounded
like you were screaming at him.
Ah, Romance languages
are passionate.
We don't have to hug now, do we?
I'm not really a hugger.
- Oh, God, no.
- Okay, good.
I had a good time today.
It was nice to meet you,
Dr. Grey.
You too.
I gotta go find my rookie.
- Okay.
- All right.
- Good night.
- See ya.
You home tonight?
Shift ends at 9:00.
W-When I started training,
you... you pushed against it.
I mean, and I get it,
because, you know,
my keeping it from you
and you were thrown.
But still, you...
You pushed.
So I pushed back.
I was so busy pushing
that... I never stopped
to really think about
what I'd be giving up.
Oh, you thought
about it plenty.
But you never stopped
to feel it.
Go on, sit there.
Let yourself feel it.
Then get up...
do what you do.
What are you gonna do?
I... am gonna feel my day,
too.
♪♪
♪ I could fight in a war ♪
Hey.
How you doing?
Fine. Why?
I just noticed
some of the interns
have nicknamed you
"The Party," so...
Yeah. I'm pretty sure
they mean that
as a compliment.
Well, some of the things
they were saying
weren't exactly
complimentary.
Well, you should hear
what they say about you.
Okay.
All right, maybe you can
tell me about that
over coffee or something.
We could actually speak
to each other, catch up.
Well, uh, you've got Harriet
tonight, and I got plans.
Yes, April.
Look, I'm just...
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh-ooh ♪
I'm worried about you.
You're Harriet's dad.
You're not mine, okay?
Night.
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh-ooh,
ooh-ooh-ooh ♪
- ♪ A subtle change in the wind ♪
- Dr. Qadri?
I, uh, thought
you might want this.
- ♪ I know something's going to move ♪
- I had them clean it.
- ♪ Something I could never blame on you ♪
- Thank you.
You did
incredible work today.
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh ♪
I don't...
I don't know if I could've
handled it if he didn't live.
You could have.
I'm glad
you didn't have to.
♪ And no one's quite like you,
it's true ♪
♪ A line in the sand ♪
♪ Show them what you mean ♪
♪ To show them what you see ♪
♪ A line in the sand ♪
♪ To show them what you need ♪
Ready to go?
♪ A line in the sand ♪
Yeah.
Yeah, I'm good to go.
So, uh,
you want to call a rig?
Mm, nah, I thought
we'd hitchhike.
♪ A line in the sand ♪
♪ Show them what you mean ♪
♪ To show them what you need ♪
♪ Give it all away
and find the words tonight ♪
♪ 'Cause I'm trying, darling ♪
♪ I'm trying not to fight ♪
♪♪
Oh, my God.
Cheers!
When you hold on to
anything for too long,
your muscles conform
to the position you're holding.
That applies to the heart and
the mind, as well as the hand.
♪ Oh, Danny Boy, the pipes,
the pipes are calling ♪
♪ From glen to glen,
and down the mountain side ♪
You're flat.
Wait, let me try it again.
Wait. O-Oh, wait.
The rest of it goes...
Hold on. Um...
♪ The summer's gone,
and all the roses falling ♪
♪ It's you, it's you must go, ♪
♪ and I'll abide ♪
Huh? Not bad.
Good, good.
The pain you know is coming
is what makes it easier
to just keep holding on.
♪♪
Sync corrections  by  srjanapala