- ♪ It goes on and on
- The human body has three
systems of communication...
The nervous, endocrine,
and immune systems.
- ♪ It goes on and on
♪ Get away from me, yeah
♪ What we do for the people
♪ Trying to save
you from your ego ♪
♪ This world never stops
♪ Till you're [inaudible]
free to find the [inaudible] ♪
♪ Said you needed a hero
- When any of these systems
experience a malfunction,
it can wreak havoc on the body.
- ♪ Try to copy me
♪ Try to steal my flair
♪ I go for love
♪ It's time to let it rain
- Effective communication
between surgeons in the OR
is just as essential.
- Guess who took the red eye?
- Guess who took
the whole day off?
- ♪ We're gonna get higher
♪ Tiptoe through fire
♪ We're gonna get high
♪ Till we find our way
♪ It goes on and on
- When a life is at stake,
there's no time or
space for body language
or carefully chosen words.
- ♪ It goes on and on
- You're saying I should
crawl into a hole and hide?
- No, I'm saying changing
your phone number
and email address
isn't the worst idea.
- I'm not gonna let them win.
- It's just a cell phone number.
- Just a cell phone number?
It's the only one I've ever had.
I've known that number
longer than I've known you.
- I've been reading...
I've been reading up on other
doctors who've been doxxed,
and it only gets
worse from here.
Calls at all hours of the
night, email inboxes flooded,
people showing up at your door.
- You want to move.
- Look, we'll find an Airbnb.
It'll just be six months, tops.
- Six months!
- Like a vacation...
- Oh, no.
No, this will blow over.
They'll get bored
or find someone
else to be outraged
about.
- Mm-hmm, mm-hmm.
- Look, I'll have an
intern babysit my phone.
- But no matter how hard we try,
there's always a risk
of being misunderstood.
Or simply unheard.
- You look like crap.
- Yeah, I worked the
closing shift at Joe's.
What's your excuse?
- Do we still have
that thing tonight?
Yes, cake tasting at 7:00.
- Oh.
Can't wait to see what
you do with floral
arrangements, Adams.
- Remember when you
fainted in the OR?
- So this is Pierce's last day?
- Oh, God, I hate that.
- Apparently Ndugu's staying.
I work at a bar.
I hear things.
- Good for her.
- You don't like Ndugu?
- Don't like marriage.
- What's wrong with marriage?
- It's a distraction.
- From what?
- Meaningful career,
making an impactful
contribution to the world,
fully-realized
individual potential.
- Ready.
- Are you sure?
Sorry.
Are you going to get off
work on time tonight?
Because I made us
this reservation
at that pizza place
you keep talking about.
- Pizzageddon?
- Mm-hmm.
- It's impossible to get into.
- Well, I have an
in with the manager.
I delivered his baby.
- Did I forget?
Is it my birthday?
Is it your birthday?
- No, I just...
I figured that we
deserved a night out.
- Yeah.
- Yeah!
- All right.
- OK.
- Those two need to get a room.
- What, Link and Wilson?
- Yeah, they basically just
had sex in front of us.
You remember
what sex is, right?
- I'm just saying. Messy.
- I don't know.
Hey, you remember when you
and me used to be like that?
- Nope.
- Do you smell margaritas?
- It's me.
Joe's had a two-for-one
special last night.
- Oh, maybe you should
try soap next time.
- Oh, maybe you should try
being the maid of honor
for someone you have
feelings for who's
marrying someone
else... Oh, wait.
Mission accomplished.
- We're just friends.
- Don't care.
Oh, but can you bring leftovers
from the cake tasting?
- Ow. Ow!
- What do we got?
- William Hudson, 32.
GCS 14.
Left upper extremity deformity
and abdominal contusion.
Systolic's in the low 100s.
- Trauma three.
- OK. What happened?
- Am I bleeding?
- He, uh, tried to mail himself
to his girlfriend in Florida.
- Excuse me?
- It's her birthday tomorrow.
- Says he was trying
to surprise her.
- Wait, you put
yourself in a box?
- Ow!
- And the box fell
from the conveyor belt
while they were loading
it into the plane.
- Yeah, maybe for the best.
He could have died
in the cargo hold.
- He could still die here.
- What?
- I'll go page Hunt.
- You guys still use pagers?
- Excuse me, excuse me.
Hi, are you doctors?
- Uh, yes, we are.
How can we help you?
- We're here to speak
to Dr. Margaret Pierce.
- Do you have an appointment?
- Viv, this was not a good idea.
- Can you just call Dr. Pierce?
- Uh, her... Her
schedule is very busy.
But if you, um, give me
your information, I can...
- No, no, no, no. We
just drove 400 miles
in my 1994 roadie van,
without air conditioning,
so that my friend here
could be seen for
the giant tumor
that is crushing her heart.
So can you two baby doctors
just pick up the phone
and call Dr. Margaret Pierce?
Because we are not
leaving until you do.
- You packing up?
- Yeah.
I'm at that point where I'm
just throwing everything
into a bag because I don't
have time to decide whether
I want to keep it or not.
I know this is all
happening really fast.
Um, it's actually happening
a little quickly for me, too.
But this is just such
a huge opportunity.
- I guess I thought this
place meant more to you
than just a stepping stone
for something bigger.
- Richard, of course it does.
- I mean, we just revived
the residency program.
We just lost Meredith.
- I know.
And I told Teddy when I gave her
my resignation that I would
help interview new candidates
over video chat.
- In my day, you accepted a
job after your fellowship,
then you worked there
until you retired.
They taught you that
loyalty mattered.
- So out of loyalty, I should
not pursue research that would
save thousands of patients?
- You've already started
doing that here with Winston.
- I hate that you're upset, but
I'm not going to apologize...
- Dr. Margaret Pierce,
can you please come
to the nurses' station
on the first floor, please?
- I guess, um...
- Dr. Margaret Pierce...
- We'll talk later.
- Can you please come
to the nurses' station
on the first floor.
- Ma'am, you are not allowed...
- Dr. Margaret
Pierce, can you please
come to the nurses' station...
- Security is on their way,
and the longer we do this,
the longer it will...
- Oh, my God. I'm here.
- Second floor please!
- Why am I being paged
on repeat by someone
who doesn't even work here?
- We're so sorry, Dr. Pierce.
- She grabbed the phone.
- And we called security.
- Dr. Pierce!
Um, big fan.
This is Nola.
She has mediastinal
mass syndrome
due to the large
thymoma which has
completely taken over her heart.
- Uh, Dr. Griffith,
uh, get them upstairs in a room,
so I can do a proper
consult, but do not ever
come into a hospital
that way again,
or you'll be quickly
escorted out.
- Uh, I thought
you were leaving.
I'm going
to push my flight.
Next time, try listening
to the patients
before you call
security on them.
- I'm sorry.
I know it's uncomfortable.
- Uncomfortable?
It hurts like hell.
- Can't you give him
anything for the pain?
- We need to complete
the initial exam first.
- Can I just get back
to playing "Minecraft"?
- What mode are you playing?
- Survival.
- Mm.
- Just nailed an
enchanting table,
then you came in and
started trying to kill me.
Ow!
- Sorry.
- David.
Oh hey, Daisy.
- Dr. Webber.
- Well, look who we have here.
Dr. Kwan?
- Grayson Friedman, 13.
History of ulcerative colitis,
which has previously
been in clinical...
- He knows already.
He's my doctor.
- Hey. Sorry.
Dr. Webber diagnosed
Grayson when he was eight.
We've been managing his
condition with meds.
But this morning, the pain
was so bad he collapsed
on the floor in the bathroom.
- Do you think he needs surgery?
- No.
- Last time you mentioned
an ostomy.
- No, I know what that is.
It's not that bad. Don't
do surgery, please.
- We won't do anything until
we find out what's going on.
We'll run some tests,
and then we'll get you
something for your pain.
- Thank you.
- I don't want surgery.
I don't even think I need it.
- Order a CBC, CMP,
inflammatory markers with a CT.
Then put him on an IV steroid
with a PRN of morphine
to make him comfortable,
and page me when
you get the scans.
- Uh, Dr. Webber?
Do you think that maybe we
could find some time to talk?
- Seems like we're
doing that now, Schmitt.
- Well, I don't have
my notes with me.
Right.
I've been thinking
about fellowships
and attending positions,
and I would love to
pick your brain...
- You haven't applied
for your fellowships yet?
I submitted my recommendations
for most candidates months ago.
- I've been exploring options,
and I would love
your suggestions.
- You're a fourth-year
resident, Schmitt.
My suggestion would be,
get your act together
sooner than later.
- Nola, we're really here.
You're... you're
really being examined
by Dr. Margaret Pierce.
I mean, the
Dr. Margaret Pierce!
Meeting you in
person, it's like...
- That time we met Stevie Nicks.
- I'm digging this more.
- I am flattered.
Oh, keep her elevated.
If she's flat, the
tumor could further
compress the vasculature, which
could lead to more swelling.
Griffith?
- Uh, Nola Marquez, 42.
Developed a mediastinal mass
with a tissue
diagnosis of a thymoma.
The tumor grew
alongside her heart,
putting pressure on it
and the vasculature,
causing SVC syndrome.
Symptoms include
shortness of breath
and mental acuity issues.
- It's not that bad.
- No one believes you.
- Sisters?
- Close.
We're, uh, friends
since elementary school.
We met in chorus, and been
rocking together ever since.
- You're in a band?
- We are a band.
Double Helix.
- Ever since Nola got diagnosed
she hasn't touched her guitar.
- I can barely sleep,
let alone perform.
Viv has dragged me to
every heart surgeon
in the Pacific Northwest.
No one will operate.
They all say it's too risky.
- Bunch of cowards. But
now we have the best.
Dr. Pierce, she's... she's not
pop rock, she's Led Zeppelin.
Double Helix is back.
- All right, well,
first things first.
Let's get some scans,
see where we are.
Griffith, Millin.
- Uh, she's been fasting, and
we've both been visualizing.
So she's ready for surgery
the minute you are.
- Why didn't you
show up with flowers?
That was all I'm saying.
- It was supposed to be
a grand romantic gesture.
- I surprised you in Germany.
- Yeah, but you came on a plane.
- Yeah, like a
regular human person.
- We need to check his upper
left extremity for a fracture.
Order some AP and lateral films.
- OK.
- What's the lesson here?
Romance can be fatal.
Wouldn't
be the first time.
- Or it can save lives and heal.
- Oh, please.
You're just trying
to prove me wrong
because you didn't even know
that Jo and Link were an item.
- No. No, Jo and I are...
We're just friends.
- Friends who have
slept together.
- Wait, you guys slept together?
- How do you know that?
- You know what?
Just, uh, page me when
the scans come in.
- How much longer do
I have to be in here?
- Not long.
Just think like you
have a health bar
that needs replenishing.
It's a video game reference.
- I'm aware.
How do you not know if you're
doing general or subspecialty?
It's a fellowship reference.
- Wow.
You're really begging
for a pile of scut, Kwan.
- No, I'm genuinely asking
how you got into your
fourth year of residency
without a clear direction.
- Well, let's see.
Maybe it was the worldwide
pandemic that happened
in the middle of my residency,
or the program being
shut down last year.
Take your pick.
- Well, I like to
track each subspecialty
I'm interested in
with a spreadsheet
and monitor trends in each area.
- I'm hot.
And it's really
dark in here, guys.
I really want to get out.
- Grayson, just, um,
hum a song or sing.
- Like what?
- Anything inside your head.
- You studying for
your bar mitzvah?
- Yeah. I sound terrible.
I've been practicing for
over 300 days in a row,
and I still sound awful, right?
- Yes.
- Keep chanting.
- It's acute severe colitis.
- That smells delicious.
- I was thinking after we
eat, we can go on a walk.
Um, I wanted to talk...
Hey, what's wrong?
- With Mer gone
and Maggie leaving,
there's not going to
be any Sunday dinners.
- Mm.
- On Sundays, Maggie cooks,
and she puts enough
leftovers in my fridge
to get me to Wednesday.
- So maybe it's time
to learn how to cook.
- I have a history of
spiraling when people leave me,
and a good old-fashioned
spiral does not leave
much time for cooking lessons.
- What does it leave time for?
- All kinds of fun things.
Uh, pulling away
from people you love,
starting fights, lack of sleep,
spilling your worst instincts
to someone who just flew
halfway across the
country to cook for you.
- You love your sisters.
This is a big change.
Anybody would be sad, Amelia.
- How could I be
sad with you here?
- Yasuda, I have a job for you.
- Oh, Dr. Bailey, thank you.
At your service.
- Hey, I need you
to hold on to this.
That is my lifeline, and
I'm entrusting it to you.
Do not answer it
unless caller ID says
it's my husband Ben Warren,
or a hospital number.
- Got it.
So Grey Sloan, your
husband, or Ben Warren?
- My husband is Ben Warren.
Do I need to entrust
this to someone else?
- Nope. I got this.
Entrust me.
- Hey, if you don't screw it up,
maybe she'll entrust you
to babysit her tablet next.
- Do I need to get surgery?
- We should really
wait for your parents.
- I can't get surgery.
My bar mitzvah's
to be in 36 hours.
- You haven't been
taking your medication.
- What?
No, I have. Every day.
My parents set this,
um, annoying alarm.
Um...
- Grayson, I have
your urine results.
The labs don't lie, but
sometimes patients do.
- Yeah, OK, I... I stopped.
But just for a little bit.
I've been in these
Hebrew classes,
and the pills and
infusions, they made me...
They made me really
tired, so tired that I...
I fainted one day,
and everyone saw.
And then the... the medications,
they dried my eyes out.
And then the eye
drops, they burned.
And I got this gross-looking
rash on my neck
that Eloise Schurmann saw...
- Do you know how worried
your parents have been?
- Dr. Webber...
- How much money they've
spent on your treatments?
Now you need surgery.
- No. No surgery.
It doesn't even hurt that badly.
Just... just give me some
steroids or infusions.
The Torah portion
is only 25 minutes.
I can make 25 minutes.
- No, you can't.
- Please.
- If you don't get
the surgery immediately, the
inflammation in your intestine
will get worse, spread further,
and lead to an incredibly
serious infection.
You would be in excruciating
pain, and you would die.
- Kwan!
- You know what?
Dr. Kwan is right.
Grayson, you're not an adult,
and you're not a doctor.
I'm talking to your
parents, because clearly
you aren't mature enough
to understand how much
we care about you,
and how much harm
you could have done to yourself.
- OK, Hudson's X-rays are in.
Uh, sorry. One sec.
It's Jo.
Um, it looks like a simple
mildly displaced
humeral fracture.
- Yeah, and a shattered spleen
with decreasing responses
to fluids.
Teddy and I can take him
up for an ex-lap now.
- And I will set and reduce
the fracture when you're done.
Mm-hmm.
I know what you're thinking...
That I should tell Jo I
have feelings for her.
But listen, we built a
home together as friends.
Our kids are
practically siblings.
If I make a move and she
doesn't feel the same way,
it's over.
Saying something
is not a good idea.
- That is not at all
what I was thinking.
- So you think it's a good idea?
- I have no opinion.
Plus, the last person I talked
to about their relationship
was Ndugu, and his wife is
moving to another state.
- Not to mention him and Altman.
- What was that, Yasuda?
- Do you and Altman need
us to prep him for surgery?
- Yes.
And type and cross
two units of blood.
- And deep breath.
- My parents toured with
the band for a minute.
They were called Blessed Wolf.
- Well, I tried to name us
after our third grade teacher,
Mrs. Hatmaker, but
Nola here nixed it.
- Two women in a
folk rock duo called
the Hatmakers might as well
sew up their vaginas forever.
- Is Viv your only
emergency contact?
- My ride or die, since day one.
- And you repay me
by trying to die.
- Think about all
the songs you'll be
able to write about my death.
- Oh, you're better off.
I mean, who needs a spouse
when you have a bandmate?
- Well, we prefer the
term platonic soulmate.
- Another excellent band name.
- We're going to
talk to Dr. Pierce,
and we'll be back to update you.
Thank you.
OK, what is your problem?
- With what?
- You're hating on marriage
to anyone who will listen,
when I'm about to get married.
- Or I'm doing my job and
connecting with our patients.
- Yeah, but you don't know Trey.
You don't know our relationship.
- I know.
Get married, don't get
married. I don't care.
- But it's not a distraction.
I've been singularly focused
on becoming a surgeon
since I was eight.
- Griffith, I've already
said I don't care.
Who are you trying to convince?
- Doctors? It's Nola.
Something happened.
We were
talking and she gasped.
And then, um, this
machine started going off.
I don't know.
- Grab a crash cart.
How's her airway?
- Airway's patent
and she's breathing.
- She has JVD.
- OK, we need to get her
oxygen, and page Dr. Pierce!
- O2.
- What happened?
- Her BP dropped.
JVD, muffled heart sounds.
- What does it mean?
- Cardiac tamponade.
- Someone tell me
what that means.
- Nola's tumor has caused
fluid to accumulate
around her heart.
We need to relieve the
pressure by draining it,
by doing what's called
a pericardiocentesis.
18-gauge spinal needle.
Griffith?
Find your landmarks.
Find one centimeter inferior
to the left xiphocostal angle.
- Yep.
- Insert the needle
at a 30-degree angle.
Good.
And slowly advance it
toward the left shoulder,
while aspirating.
And you should
start to see fluid.
Good, there it is. Good.
She's stable, but we
don't have much time.
- Until what?
- Until the fluid
builds up again.
Let's get her to the CCU,
and page Dr. Ndugu right now.
- Do you hear something?
- Don't worry about it, William.
- Maybe it's Rose.
- Who's Rose?
- Oh, she's my girlfriend.
She's so pretty and smart.
Except for her teeth.
- Don't worry about it, William.
It's not Rose.
- Oh, my God.
- It's not my fault.
Stop calling, asshat!
You're not harassing
Dr. Bailey.
You are harassing me!
A poor, overworked,
tired intern who would really
appreciate it if you could...
Hello?
Hi.
Sorry.
I'll... I'll tell her.
That was Dr. Bailey's
optometrist.
Tuck's glasses are ready.
- Do you need me to hold
the phone for a while?
- No, thank you.
- Do you need me to hold
the phone for a while?
You in the Nether worlds now?
Do you play with friends, or...
- Do you think Dr. Webber will
still want to be my
doctor after this?
- Of course he will.
- I disappointed him.
- Well, if it makes you
feel any better, so have I.
- Kids at school
call me a defect,
because I'm always in the
nurse's office taking my meds.
I just wanted to be
normal, you know?
- You know, I tried
for a really long time
to be what I thought was normal,
and then I decided to see what
would happen if I stopped.
- What happened?
- I liked myself a lot more.
- OK.
I'm ready.
- You paged?
- I wasn't sure you'd answer it.
- You're still my boss
till the end of the day.
- Pushed my flight
till tomorrow.
Looks like a large thymoma
in the mediastinum.
It's already
starting to tamponade
with sympathetic fluid, so
I don't have a lot of time.
- Tumor is shaped like a heart.
You didn't notice?
- No.
I was more concerned
with how close it was
to the heart, not its shape.
- Have you considered doing
a reconstruction of the SVC?
- Yes.
But I'm concerned that
the tumor involves
the innominate artery.
- OK, what if you take the
entire SVC and left subclavian?
You'd have to
resect the sternum,
the SVC, and all
the pericardium,
but you'd get the entire tumor.
- That's if she doesn't
decompensate first.
If I go into the
wrong dissecting plane
even a tiny bit, she
bleeds out and dies.
- She'll die if she continues
to have fluid buildup.
- What if we use a
bovine pericardial patch
for the reconstruction?
- Maybe that would allow
us to have clear margins.
- No interns. There's
no margin for error.
Just you and me.
- Just you and me.
I'm sorry.
- It's OK.
- We hardly get
to see each other,
and I'm sitting here
crying like somebody died.
Even though I'm scaring you,
I'm so glad that you're here.
- Oh, it takes a lot
for this one to scare.
- I've hidden parts of
myself in every relationship
I've ever had,
except for this one.
It feels so freeing.
I just can be myself,
queen of spirals.
- You can't be the queen of
something that's only, like,
a tiny part of who you are.
You are sweet and kind.
But I also think that
you are underestimating
my ability to fall
off the deep end.
- I'm not
underestimating anything.
The Amelia I know is
a badass neurosurgeon,
an amazing mom.
She works hard on her sobriety.
She's a loving sister,
a devoted friend.
The Amelia I know is inspiring.
She is not the queen of spirals.
She is just a queen.
- Dr. Bailey,
Dr. Altman, Dr. Fox.
All married surgeons
with stellar careers.
- Careful.
The tissue is very friable.
- I'm aware, Dr. Pierce.
All right.
Specimen's coming out.
- Her blood pressure's soaring.
Uh, why aren't you
doing anything?
- Pressure is stabilized.
- Pseudo tamponade effect.
The heart isn't used to all
that space without the tumor.
Now it's alone and happy.
- Let's start the
reconstruction.
Put her on bypass.
- Dr. Hunt and I were able
to perform your splenectomy
without any complications.
You should heal nicely.
- Same with your shoulder.
You're going to need a couple
of months of rehabilitation,
but then you should be able
to regain normal function.
- Great.
Thanks.
- Mm-hmm.
- William, this
is all good news.
- Yeah. No, sorry.
Um, Rose heard what I
did, and she dumped me.
You know...
I fell for her the
second I saw her
in line for Space Mountain.
Company retreat in Orlando.
I thought she was
the love of my life.
How could I have been so wrong?
- Listen, me and my wife,
we were friends for years
before we became a couple.
We met when we were
army surgeons together.
- So just to get this
right, are you judging me
for meeting Rose
at a theme park,
or for believing in
love at first sight?
Neither.
Listen, even though it took us
years to get together, I knew.
I knew from the
moment that I saw her
emerging from a surgical
tent in 100 degrees heat,
having just repaired
an aortic dissection
and saving a soldier's life.
I knew I wanted her in my life.
- Then what took you so long?
- Well, I was...
I was engaged, and then I
was married for a while,
and she was married.
Our timing was just
never quite right.
But those relationships,
they came and went.
And our friendship
outlasted them all,
even after she moved
out of the country.
Then one day, I...
I just realized that
she was the one person
that I wanted to talk to
at the end of a long day,
or a great day.
When I was reading a book or
watching a movie, I'd think,
man, she would love
this, you know?
She just kept... she would
constantly pop into my mind
until finally, I just...
I got on that plane
to Germany, and I...
I just told her.
So if you feel that
way about Rose,
if you know you want
her in your life,
you should just try again.
- Yeah.
I don't think Rose is it.
- Excuse me.
I got to be somewhere.
- Mm-hmm.
- I mean, I did mail myself
in a box, but she's not it.
Thank you for that story.
- Oh, look all of this
inflammation and necrosis.
I mean, this is almost
the entire colon.
- How long had Grayson's
symptoms been under control?
- Oh, years.
The medication protocol
worked wonders.
- And now he's completely
turned that around.
- Foolish to the
point of stupid.
- Dr. Kwan, do
you even remember
what being 13 is like?
Because I do.
It was really, really hard.
You think Grayson
doesn't already know
that he disappointed
everyone around him?
You think he doesn't
already feel stupid?
Believe me, he does.
Did you even hear him when
he was trying to tell us
that the medications
made him feel terrible,
worse than it already
feels to be 13?
Did you listen to your patient?
- Of course I did. But...
- Grayson has spent an entire
year working his butt off
on becoming a man, so
maybe stop chastising him
like a toddler and freaking
him out that he could die.
Sometimes being a good
doctor, or a parent,
or even a good mentor,
means listening to what
the other person needs.
Suction, Kwan.
- All right.
What is it?
- There's no back wall left
for the reconstruction.
I don't think the
patch is going to work.
- ♪ Everything's alive
and wild and dying ♪
- What if we access the jugulars
and use reverse cryoartery,
and drain into the right atrium?
Two incisions, end to
end, on the two jugulars.
- Yes.
- You think we can pull it off?
- I think we're
Nola's only option.
- All right, let's
do it. Right angle.
- Vessel loop.
- ♪ Since I was a child
♪ I've been fighting
♪ I am an animal
♪ My wild's undeniable
♪ A miracle, a mess
♪ Ethereal, blood and flesh
♪ I am an animal
♪ The animal is in all of us
- I'm not saying I'm going
to throw it in the toilet.
But if you throw it in the
toilet, I would cover for you.
- Just shut it up.
- I can't.
What are you doing?
- Oh, my God!
- What on Earth do you
think you're doing?
- Respectfully, Dr. Bailey,
have you considered
just turning it off?
- Uh, have you
considered being a wife,
a mother, and a
high-level professional?
Give me the phone.
OK.
- No.
No, no, no, no, no, no.
- Oh, no. No, no, Viv.
- I can't.
- She's OK, Viv.
Viv, she's alive.
She's in the ICU.
We were able to successfully
remove the mass.
- Wait, what... what?
- The tumor is gone.
She has a long recovery,
but she's stable.
I thought she was
dead. I just...
Your faces, those were not
"I just saved a life
against all odds" faces.
- Yeah. We have
a lot going on.
- Thank you.
Dr. Pierce, I knew
you were the person.
Thank you.
- It was teamwork.
I could not have done
it without Dr. Ndugu.
- Oh, thank you, thank you.
- ♪ Carry you through when
there's no other way ♪
♪ Hold you in my arms
♪ Like I know what to do
- ♪ Hold you in my arms
- How long?
How long do I have
the ostomy for?
- Well, a few months.
Your... your parents went
to get something to eat,
but they've been with
you the whole time.
- I didn't mean to worry
them or to make you mad.
I just didn't think
it'd be such a big deal.
- You know, I remember
your diagnosis
like it was yesterday.
- It was a while ago.
I was in, uh, kindergarten.
- And you were very
worried about missing
your end-of-class party.
- Yeah.
I was worried about
missing the ice cream cake.
I've known
you for a long time, son.
And I look forward to
seeing what's next for you.
I mean, your bar mitzvah,
high school graduation,
college.
And when you make a decision
that puts your future at risk,
well, it's... it's frustrating.
But I'm not mad at you.
And if it came
off that way, I...
I'm sorry.
- I'm sorry, too.
- Good.
Now that we've got
that out the way,
I want you to do me a favor.
Now, when you heal
up from the surgery,
I'm going to give
you a prescription
for a new medication.
- You want me to
promise to take it?
- I want you to tell me if
it gives you any problems,
if something's off, and we'll...
We'll find a solution together.
- OK.
All right, let's
check that ticker.
- ♪ Carry you through
- Hey.
- ♪ When there's
no other way ♪
♪ Hold you in my arms
I have to hand it to
you, you really went for
your two favorite
things in that speech...
Proving me wrong
and getting laid.
- I was just trying to make
our patient feel better.
- Uh-huh.
- Mm-hmm.
Did it work?
- Didn't you see Link?
I meant the other thing.
- ♪ And I'll carry
you through ♪
- Your mom's watching
the kids for the night.
- Dr. Mary Edwards Walker,
first female surgeon
in the United States,
the second female
to graduate from medical school.
Married.
Started a practice
with her husband.
- Wow, you're still worried
about what I think of you?
- The marriage
isn't a distraction.
It's the damn wedding.
It's a pain in my ass.
It's the menu, and
the seating chart,
and the dress shop
is harassing me
because they want me
to come get measured.
But I am here from
sunrise till sundown,
because I'm trying to
prove I'm just as good
as the rest of you.
Also, bridal shops are open,
like, three hours a day
or something, and I can't
ask Adams to measure me
because we all know why, and
my sister won't text me back.
So I'm not going
to get measured,
so I'm not going to get married,
so I'm not going
to have a dress...
- OK, OK, OK. Lift your arms.
- What?
- Lift.
- What are you doing?
- Well, we can't let
Adams near your inseam.
And again.
- Thank you.
- You owe me a drink.
- Jo, you are...
donuts in human form.
OK.
No, no. All right.
You are... you are twinkle
lights and yellow roses,
and although I hate most of
humanity, I do not hate you.
That... oh, um.
Uh, in fact, you
are the only person
I want to come home to for
the rest of my... why...
Why didn't I write a song?
Should have written a song.
Hey, Jo.
I canceled the...
- Whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa. What happened?
- It's Luna.
Something's wrong.
- Wait, wait,
whoa. What's wrong?
- The daycare think that...
That there's a problem
with her hearing.
I... I need...
I need to get her checked out.
- I'll be right there.
- No, no, no.
We're gonna... we're
gonna come straight home,
so you stay there, OK?
- OK.
- When we don't feel
heard or validated,
it can be very easy to forget
that we aren't actually alone.
- ♪ Wait
♪ Let the colors flow
♪ The changing of the season
♪ Ain't enough to
bring you home ♪
Hey, there are my girls.
Hey, you ready to
go home?
- Uh, we're not going
home. I got us a rental.
- What is this?
- It's a picture
of Tuck in school.
- I know it's a picture of
Tuck, but who sent it to you?
- One of the numbers who's
called my phone over 40 times.
I know.
I just changed the number,
changed the emails.
We're taking the kids out
of school for a few days.
- And that there is a difference
between being alone,
and just feeling lonely.
Sometimes, being
alone is the only way
we can hear our own hearts
trying to communicate
what it is that we
actually want...
- I smell cake.
- What we need, and who we love.
- Oh, no fork.
- So we can move
through this world
with better communication
when we actually have
something important to say...
- Hey.
Hell of a way to go out today.
- I could not have done
that surgery without you.
- You would have figured it out.
- No, I wouldn't have.
I wouldn't have figured out
a lot of things without you.
You push me to be better.
You challenge me.
You inspire me to never give
in on a challenging case.
And the way that you accessed
that jugular today, it was...
- It was what?
- ♪ So come on,
bring the rain ♪
♪ Like a tidal wave when
you're tired of waking up ♪
♪ Oh, come on,
bring the rain ♪
- And to be crystal
clear when we do.
- I had a great day.
- Me too.
Don't go back to Minnesota.
- I'm not.
Um,
the team wants me to
open up a lab in London.
I'd run it.
Triple the size,
triple the staff.
I wanted to tell you earlier,
but you were already so sad.
- You want to go?
- Amelia, I accepted.
I am going.
Fantastic.