I mean...
What's so funny?
Come on, April. Tell him.
It's a nurse thing.
You wouldn't get it.
Come on.
Our shift's about
to start. Sorry.
I don't know why I'm
so tired this morning.
Really, you don't know?
Maybe I have some idea.
I'm just happy you're back
home and the whole gun
thing is behind us.
Excuse me,
Dr. Halstead.
Hey, Earl. What's up?
Sorry to interrupt,
but it's about your car.
Seems they pried
the latch open.
Oh, my God, he literally
just parked. What was it,
like 10 minutes ago?
My guess is whoever
did this cased out
Dr. Halstead specifically.
Knew his schedule, what he
might leave in the car.
Mine was the only
car broken into?
Yeah, seems so.
Oh, my God, Will.
I can't believe you left
this back here.
Your laptop's inside.
I'm surprised
they didn't take it.
They must have gotten scared
off before they found it.
See anything missing,
Dr. Halstead?
No, it doesn't look like it.
Well, you must have
got lucky then.
Here you go, Top Gun. You're
going to Treatment Five.
And take Terry with you.
It seems like he needs
something to do.
Come on.
Good morning, Mr. Kaminsky.
Hi, I'm Dr. Choi and this is
Student Doctor McNeal.
Hi.
I understand you're
experiencing some
palpitations in your chest?
How about you unbutton your
shirt so I can take a listen.
Sure.
I see we already took
your blood pressure.
226 over 117.
That's high, isn't it?
A lot higher than
I'd like to see it, yes.
All right,
take a deep breath for me.
And exhale.
Then another.
Exhale.
All right. Bilateral crackles
with mild rhonchi.
That didn't sound good.
Not time to panic yet,
but it's good you came in.
I want to run a few tests
and give you something
to bring down
that blood pressure.
Excuse me.
Hey, Hank. Start an IV
and give 20 labetalol, please.
Absolutely.
Let's get a CBC,
CMP, troponins,
and set him up with
an EKG and renal ultrasound.
Okay.
Hey, Hank.
Everything all right?
Where are you going?
Is he okay?
I'm sure it's nothing.
Terry, clean this up,
and let's get that IV started.
All right.
It's okay. It's okay.
It's okay.
Hey, what's going on?
Hey, what happened to Hank?
He's not feeling well.
Does he know
that patient, Kaminsky?
April, what's going on?
Sorry.
Hey, hey, hey,
come on. It's me.
You always read me in.
Not this time.
Maggie?
Yep?
Patient in Two's got a small
splenic crack without a blush.
Let's send her upstairs
for observation.
I'm on it.
Thanks.
Morning.
That's really all
you're going to say?
Um, what else do you
want me to say?
"I'm sorry," would be a start.
Yeah, I'm sorry things
turned out this way.
Turned out?
Things didn't turn out.
You accused me of sleeping
with your detestable father.
I'm not going to keep
rehashing this, Ava.
Oh, you poor thing.
Connor, incoming.
You're going to Baghdad.
What do we got?
Bode Isiah, 23,
motorcycle versus car, GCS 12,
BP 110 over 70,
heart rate 120,
O2 sats 98%.
He's obviously
in a lot of pain,
seems to have taken
most of the trauma
to the torso.
All right, let's get a chest
X-ray in here now.
All right, on my count.
One, two, three.
All right, Bode,
we're going to take care
of that pain, okay?
Give me 50 of fentanyl.
Yeah.
I'm HIV-positive.
It's good to know,
but we're prepared
for that, okay?
Just let us take care of you.
All right, Bode.
Can you move your head
up and down for me?
There we go, very good.
Now how about
left and right, okay?
All right, C-spine's clear.
Let's roll him
and get a board out.
One, two, three.
Hey, what's the hold-up on
the fentanyl I asked for?
I already gave it to him.
All right, let's get
the X-ray in. Come on.
Whoa. All right, Bode.
You've got a bunch of broken
and displaced ribs.
In order to stop the pain
we're going to have
to surgically
put them back into alignment
with metal plates.
Is that okay?
Okay.
All right, tell CT
we're on our way up.
Let's get him ready to move.
All right? Let's go.
There are my two lovebirds.
I got a tough one in
Treatment Four. Colon cancer.
Who wants it?
I'll take it.
Thanks.
Yeah. Can you take my stuff?
Sure.
You all right?
Yeah.
See you.
Damn it.
Yeah, I need to report
a stolen firearm.
You know what?
Let me call you back.
Dr. Halstead.
Good morning.
You're a hard man to pin down.
What do you mean?
Buddy, I heard you been
skipping your sessions.
Therapy?
Yeah, well, kinda busy saving
lives down here.
Listen, for what
it's worth,
in my experience,
this kind of trauma, you gotta
take the treatment seriously
or it'll bite you in the ass.
I mean, the stories I could
tell you. Drugs, alcohol,
family issues.
Hey, why don't you
just say it?
All right, Natalie told you
I bought a gun.
Well, it's gone.
It's not an issue anymore.
Okay, we done?
Will, let me remind you
your therapy
is not elective.
Goodwin mandated it.
Come on, man.
I don't want to see
you lose your job.
Appreciate it.
I'm not seeing any signs
of concussion.
Are you sure it was a seizure
that made you collapse?
That's what my manager
at the food co-op said,
but it was more
of a dizzy spell.
Thinking it was a reaction
to the chemo.
All right, well, I'm seeing
in your chart that
you're battling colon cancer.
I'd like to send you
for a set of scans
just to see what's going on.
Scans?
No, I don't want to blow
my insurance up any more
than I already have.
Plus, my oncologist
scanned me
just last week.
Well, in that case
I will contact
your oncologist directly
so I can access your records.
I just need your
written consent.
No, I don't want
to bother her.
I'm feeling better.
I'll make an appointment
for the day after tomorrow.
Jared! Oh, baby.
What are you doing here?
I thought you were
at the airport.
I was until Jason
called me in a panic.
He overreacted, all right?
You should be on your way
to Phoenix.
That conference is important.
You are more important.
No way I can stay away for
a week with you like this.
This is my girlfriend, Lucy.
How is he?
We're trying
to figure that out.
I'm telling you,
it's a reaction
to the chemo, all right?
This isn't my first rodeo.
Chemo? I thought
your last cycle
ended three weeks ago.
Three weeks?
Something like that.
That seems unlikely that
would still be affecting you.
Do you mind if I take a look
at your chemo port?
I opted not to get one.
Nurses say my veins
are easy to access.
So what's the plan?
Well, since you don't want
any scans, please just let us
run some labs.
No.
Jared, please.
This is serious.
Okay.
But just the blood tests.
Okay, I'll be back shortly.
Hey, can we get a CBC, CMP,
magnesium and phosphates
for Mr. Bray?
No scans?
He won't let me.
Huh?
Yeah, weird, right?
Yeah.
Speaking of,
did you hear about what
happened to Will's car?
Yeah, it got
broken into, right?
Yeah, but nothing was stolen.
Not even a bag
with his computer in it.
That's strange.
Sounds like Will got lucky.
That's exactly what Earl said.
Mmm.
Dr. Choi, I just checked in
on Mr. Kaminsky.
Yeah.
Nurses still haven't
drawn blood or sent him
up for scans.
What are they waiting for?
Don't know.
Can't get a straight answer.
Want me to do it?
No, I'll handle this.
Hey. Why is nobody filling the
orders for my patient in Five?
Got busy.
I need that workup now.
Will you do it, please?
Sorry, gotta give stat nitro
to Treatment Two.
April.
Doris, I need you
to draw blood in Five.
I'm sorry, I'm on a break,
I gotta clock out.
Draw Mr. Kaminsky's blood
first or don't bother
clocking back in.
Mags.
Yep?
You gotta rein in
your nurses.
They're dropping the ball
on my patient in Five.
Dr. Choi,
we're down a nurse.
We'll get to him.
Ow!
What's wrong?
She's hurting me.
His veins are impossible
and he keeps moving.
Stay still.
Ow! Stop stabbing me.
Doris.
There we go.
All done.
Suddenly don't know your way
around a rolling vein?
It was a hard stick.
I gotta run this to the lab.
Mo, talk to me.
What happened with Hank today?
Nothing. He wasn't
feeling good.
Monique.
You have to ask April.
I'm asking you.
We're talking about patient
care, here. This is serious,
all right?
Monique.
Your patient's
a child molester.
What?
He was Hank's piano teacher.
He raped him when
he was a little boy.
Dr. Lanik is wondering
when his chest tube in T-Two
is getting set up.
You want me to do that
before or after this MVC
that just came in?
How about both
at the same time?
Yeah.
Someone named Sydney Hawkins
is asking for you out
in the waiting room.
Said she's a friend of yours?
Doesn't ring a bell.
I can tell her
you're too busy.
No, I'll come out.
Okay. Hello, Sydney?
I'm Maggie Lockwood.
How can I help you?
You don't remember me,
do you?
I'm Naomi's cousin.
From down round
41st and Langley?
She was a year behind you
at Wendell Phillips?
Well, that was
a bit ago, yeah?
But I do remember Naomi.
Well, she said if I ever need
anything at Med I should ask
for you.
Okay, so what can I
do for you?
Well, just so you know,
I'm not the kind of person
that gets sick a lot.
Mmm-hmm.
But I got this body pain
that I just can't seem
to shake.
If I had a regular doctor
I'd go see 'em,
but if you could hook
a girl up that'd be cool.
Okay, listen, this is an ED.
We need to prioritize
our emergencies.
Yeah, okay, well,
if it's too hectic here,
I mean,
you could just give me
something for the pain.
Okay, no one here is going
to be able to do that for you
until you are
formally examined.
So why don't you come
and take a seat over here.
Go ahead.
Yeah.
And we'll do our best
to get to you, okay?
All right.
Thank you for stepping out
to see me.
Of course. Mmm-hmm.
I appreciate it.
Okay.
Give my hand back,
Sydney. Okay.
Did you take her temperature?
99.6. Just a bit elevated.
I can bump her up the triage
list if you want.
Not necessary.
Please tell me
this wasn't your idea.
What?
You know how unethical it is
denying a patient care.
Treat him like
a pin cushion?
I should write you all up
for what you've been doing.
Do you know
what that guy did to Hank?
He molested him,
Ethan. Regularly.
During their piano lessons.
It's terrible.
I know. But it's not up to us
to dole out justice.
Hank should call PD.
Press charges.
He did already, but it was
Hank's word against Kaminsky's
and the judge dismissed
the whole thing before
it even went to trial.
Yeah, and since Kaminsky
wasn't even convicted,
he's not registered
as a sex offender.
For all we know,
he's still doing this
to other little boys.
Look, I get why
this upsets you.
It upsets me too.
But regardless of how awful
this patient might be,
we have an ethical obligation
to treat him as
we would anyone else.
Fine, but there's nothing
that says we have to make
his stay a vacation.
He will get the bare minimum
from me.
Look, if that's how you feel,
maybe it's better
you keep away altogether.
No problem.
Mr. Kaminsky's EKG
and scans are done.
Your labs came back negative.
I'm not seeing any tumors
or lesions.
That's good, right?
Can I go home, now?
You'll need a follow-up
with a primary care physician,
but it looks like you're
responding to the labetalol
we gave you
so, hopefully,
we can discharge you soon.
Thank you.
One last thing.
I didn't ask you earlier,
but hypertension can often
be made worse
by things like
work-related stress.
That wouldn't apply to me
because I've always
loved my job.
And what's that?
I teach piano at my house.
For over 30 years now.
You have a lot of students?
Enough to keep me occupied.
What are you doing up here?
Trauma patient with severely
displaced rib fractures.
And you didn't page me?
Dr. Latham's held up
in surgery, but he wanted me
to let your know
that he reviewed
your patient's chart
and doesn't think Mr. Isiah's
a good candidate for surgery.
The patient's HIV puts him
at too high of a risk
for infection.
Plating his ribs
is the only way
to treat his pain.
Dr. Latham says you're welcome
to seek another opinion.
Well, that's just great.
Hey.
What about you?
You're asking
for my opinion now?
Look, I know that
I am the last person
that you want to help,
but we shouldn't be afraid
of surgery just because
the patient has HIV.
May I?
Here.
I'm thinking
three KLS titanium
plates per side,
maybe four hours max.
Okay.
I'll clear my schedule
and do the surgery.
Really? Hey. Thank you.
I'm not doing it for you,
I'm doing it for your patient.
Dr. Halstead?
Yeah?
I was waiting
for you outside.
Sorry, I was
with a patient.
Let's go.
Mr. Bray's labs are back.
Thank you.
So, Jared, your liver enzymes
were a little higher
than expected,
given when you had
your last chemo treatment,
but everything else looks
surprisingly good.
So he's out of the woods?
Well, I still don't know
what caused his seizure,
but, for now,
your vital signs seem stable.
Listen, if I leave now,
I can get to my first
presentation in time.
I might just
be able to make it.
You're going to leave
this late? You'll have
to catch a red-eye.
That's okay.
I'm gonna go see
if I can reschedule my flight.
Okay.
Dr. Manning, could you pass me
my bag, please?
It's right over there.
Sure.
Here you go.
Thank you.
No problem. I'll be back to
check on you soon.
Pressure drop.
No pulse, he's in v-fib.
Terry, start compressions.
Doesn't make any sense.
He was fine five minutes ago.
Thought you were staying away
from this patient.
He pushed the call button.
No one else was around.
Charge to 200.
Charged.
Clear.
Still in v-fib.
Push 1 milligram of epi.
Charging 200 again.
Charged.
Clear!
He's asystole.
I think he's gone.
Dr. Choi?
Time of death, 14:42.
Not sure what
I'm missing here,
Dr. Choi.
The patient responded
to the labetalol,
so how'd he have a massive
cardiac event out of the blue?
I'm not sure.
I know they're pretty rare,
but at first I thought maybe
a pheochromocytoma
was responsible for spiking
his BP, but I don't see
any tumors on these scans.
There must have
been some other
factor at play, right?
How many doses of epi did we
give Kaminsky when he died?
According to the case notes,
one, before he went asystolic.
Why?
There's four empty
amps in the trash.
Really? How could that be?
Follow the body down to the
morgue, find Dr. Shore,
and ask her
if she could tell me
how much epinephrine
Kaminsky had in his system
when he died.
Okay.
And ask her
to keep it off the books.
Off the books?
Just do it.
All right, that does
it for this side.
Let's close him up
and reposition him,
re-prep and re-drip.
You got it.
His splintering was
much more extensive
than I thought from the scans,
so you made the right call.
Well, so far so good.
So a patient of mine
sent over a bottle
of Yamazaki 12
as a thank-you
for a triple bypass.
Perhaps after we're done
we could put a dent in it?
Look, Ava...
One drink.
Connor, what are you
so afraid of?
Why did you agree
to do this surgery?
You trying to fix things
between us?
So what if I was?
Then this is not the time
or the place.
I still have feelings
for you, Connor.
Let me know when the team's
ready to restart.
You know what I find most
bewildering about all this?
You've somehow
convinced yourself that
you're the victim here.
Dr. Manning, Dr. Manning,
come quick.
I was just about to leave
when this happened.
Jared, can you talk to me?
Push 2 of Ativan, stat!
What's going on?
He's having a seizure.
Ativan's in.
Jared, can you take
a deep breath?
Baby, can you hear me?
What happened?
You just had
your second seizure today.
Jared, you need to get
a CAT scan immediately.
No, no, I'm fine.
Jared.
I'm fine, really.
Don't... Don't let this stop
you catching your flight.
You should go.
Are you crazy?
I'm not leaving you now.
What about your job?
None of that
matters right now.
I'm not leaving your side
until you're better.
Hey, how's your patient doing?
I'm not sure yet.
Hey, where'd you go?
I was looking for you,
I couldn't find you.
Well, I had to call
the insurance company.
But I saw you
talking with a cop.
Well, yeah,
that was part of it.
I had to file
a whole police report
for the insurance claim.
Why would you file
a police report?
Was something stolen?
Natalie, for the last time,
nothing was stolen.
Hey, I just planted a patient
in Treatment Three for you.
Sydney, right?
I was just about
to head in there.
All right.
Did I hear something about her
being a friend of yours?
She's not a friend of mine.
Okay.
Hey, sorry.
It's just I know
something about Sydney.
She has a reputation of being
a bit of a grifter.
Heard she got arrested for
solicitation last year.
I have sympathy for the girl,
but quite possibly
she's just here
to score some pills.
Yeah, good to know.
I'll proceed accordingly.
Yeah.
So you think Jared's
lying to you?
Yes.
Wow. That's a pretty
serious accusation.
His story just
doesn't add up.
He won't show me his scans,
he doesn't have a chemo port,
and both his seizures today
timed out perfectly
to stop his girlfriend
from going on
her business trip.
Faking a cancer diagnosis for
two years would take
unbelievable commitment,
and then also, how do you
explain the hair loss
and other physical symptoms?
Well, I saw a Ziploc full
of green pellets in his bag.
They looked just like
the rat poison that my
handyman uses in the basement.
If Jared is ingesting a small
dose of a toxin like arsenic,
it could easily mimic
the side effects of chemo.
Huh.
I think he's harming himself
and he needs to be evaluated.
Okay. I will talk to him.
Thank you.
And
another here.
One last fracture here.
20 ccs quarter-percent
Marcaine to me.
Make that to me, Beth.
What, you want to do
everything yourself?
I have the better angle.
Not for the incision.
Okay, fine. Give me
the Marcaine.
Knife to me.
Ow!
She's cut.
The patient's HIV-positive.
Ava?
It just nicked me.
It barely broke the skin.
I doused it with Betadine.
Doesn't matter.
Hospital protocol.
She's being sidelined?
Because the patient is
HIV-positive you need
to be seen
in the infectious disease
clinic, and start taking
antiretrovirals immediately.
Now the medication
can cause extreme nausea
so I want you off surgical
rotation, just for a few days,
until you acclimate.
And if I end up
contracting the virus,
what happens to my career?
There is such a small chance
of that happening,
you saw the patient's chart,
he has a low viral load.
Let's not get ahead
of ourselves.
Just start taking
the meds right away
and hopefully there won't be
anything to worry about, okay?
Ava, I am so sorry.
I don't even know what to say.
It's not your fault.
I was the one who reached
for the tray like
some idiot resident.
Well, let me at least
take a look at your hand.
No, it's okay.
I'll be fine, Connor.
Ethan, it's freezing.
Why'd you bring me up here?
I got a preliminary report
back from pathology
and there was evidence
Paul Kaminsky had high levels
of epinephrine
in his blood when he died.
So?
So I'm not sure he died
purely of natural causes,
and I need you to help me
understand what happened.
Understand? What...
Are you accusing me
of something?
We pushed one amp of epi
when he coded, right?
April, I found four
empty amps altogether,
in the trash afterwards.
I can't seem to account
for the other three.
Maybe another patient
coded in that room
right before Kaminsky.
Nothing was logged.
Maybe they forgot to log it.
I don't see what this has
to do with me.
You were in Kaminsky's room
just before he crashed.
You think I killed him?
I'm just trying to understand
how so much epinephrine
got into his system.
I don't believe this.
April, please.
Just tell me what
you were doing in that room.
He was dehydrated.
I gave him
a glass of water.
So suddenly
you're Florence Nightingale
to this guy?
I think we're done.
April, April, please, just...
You gotta be straight with me.
I'm trying to protect you from
getting in any trouble here.
Really?
'Cause that's not
what it feels like
you're trying to do.
So?
It's hard to say.
I mean, if we're seriously
thinking Munchausen's here,
it's a diagnosis of exclusion,
and I would just need
a lot more time to eliminate
the entire differential.
Well, we don't have more time.
He wants to be discharged now.
Nat, I understand.
He needs to be put
on a psych hold.
Not only is he
poisoning himself,
but he is controlling
every aspect of his
girlfriend's life.
Possibly, but he also could
be a very sick guy
clinging to his girlfriend
during a traumatic period
in his life.
It all comes down to whether
we're willing to risk
locking up a legitimately ill
cancer patient on a hunch.
And I'm just not there yet.
But...
I'm sorry, Nat.
At this point we just don't
have enough information to do
anything but let him go.
One and Two,
you take this one.
Maggie?
Yup?
Dr. Halstead needs you
to page renal, stat.
Got it. Where to?
Treatment Three,
Sydney Hawkins.
Sydney?
Bolus, another liter
of saline.
What's going on?
She's in septic shock.
Wait, wait, she was fine
a minute ago.
Temp spiked
out of nowhere,
BP went in the tank.
What?
Systolic's down to 89.
You can start an external
jugular, stat.
Here's a kit.
Maggie.
You gotta step back.
Did we get the infection
in time?
I don't know.
Lucy? You okay?
What's wrong?
My boss just fired me.
What? Why?
Because I missed
that conference.
They said they can no longer
handle the unpredictability
of my personal life.
And this is the second job
I've lost in a year.
I'm so sorry.
It's not fair.
It's really hard
trying to take care
of a loved one
going through
something like this.
I can imagine that going to
the chemo treatments alone
is like a full-time job.
He actually doesn't let me
go to chemo with him.
Really? Why?
Probably just trying
to protect me.
Maybe he thinks
it'll stress me out too much.
Hey, Dr. Manning.
When can I get out of here?
I'm sorry, Jared, but I can't
officially discharge you
without a CAT scan.
Then I'll sign out
against medical advice.
If that's what you wanna do,
but you're still
pretty dehydrated,
so I would like to hang
one more liter of fluid,
and then we will get you
on your way.
Sorry.
What are you doing?
Uh...
Here you go.
We'll get you discharged soon.
You wanted proof?
Here are the pellets.
Don't tell me you just took
those right out
of Jared's bag.
Given the circumstances
I felt that I had to.
Dr. Manning, I don't need to
tell you that that's a very
serious transgression.
His girlfriend deserves
to know the truth.
I'm going to the lab
to have these analyzed.
Have a seat, please.
The lab tested
the pellets you took.
They came back positive,
didn't they?
Yes.
For high levels of spirulina.
What?
It's a vitamin supplement.
Not arsenic.
Jared realized
you were suspicious
so he gave us permission
to access his medical records.
His oncologist at East Mercy
just emailed this over.
All of Jared's
appointments, prescriptions,
chemo treatments,
it's all there,
including scans of
the stage III malignant
tumor in his colon.
You were absolutely
right about one thing,
he was hiding something.
The severity of his cancer.
His prognosis is not good.
I don't know what to say.
This is awful.
You're an excellent physician,
Dr. Manning.
I realize you've been through
a lot lately,
and against
my better judgment,
I'm going to bat
for you on this,
but it can't happen again.
This is so insane,
Dr. Charles.
I don't know
what I was thinking.
When I ask myself
that question,
the answer usually ends up
having something
to do with me,
you know, something
going on in my life.
Could you have been
projecting onto Lucy something
that might be true for you?
I don't know.
What I suspected. Sepsis.
Yeah, from the little history
I got from her, I'm guessing
this started as a kidney
or urinary tract infection.
I should have known
it was serious.
I could have bumped
Sydney up the list.
Oh, come on, Maggie. No way
you could have anticipated
her being septic.
What's your prognosis?
She gonna have
a full recovery?
She's in acute renal failure.
We'll take her up to the ICU
and start her on dialysis
right away,
but there's a good chance
her kidneys are shot
and she'll need a transplant.
Yeah.
Oh...
Maggie.
Sydney.
How are you doing?
Can I get you anything?
I thought I just had the flu.
Sydney, I need you to know
how sorry I am.
No, no.
I can't stop thinking about
how if I wouldn't have come in
today, I would've been dead.
I'm grateful for you, Maggie.
Least I know
I'm in good hands.
Connor?
I thought that you would want
to know that Bode's surgery
was successful.
He's already up and pain-free.
Good, I'm glad. Come in.
I also wanted
to bring you this.
Yamazaki 18?
I figured the least I could do
was help you numb the pain.
Thank you. Sadly, can't have
any with my meds, Doctor.
Right, yeah.
Well, maybe we can celebrate
when you get the "all clear."
Well, you can
have some, right?
You take it neat?
I'm afraid
I'm still on call.
Actually, I have
to get back to Med.
Oh.
Sure.
Good night.
Heads up, Choi.
We're reviewing the Kaminsky
case for tomorrow's M&M.
Okay.
I see you didn't put down
a cause of death, yet.
Something holding that up
or is that just an oversight?
Sorry, I just need
to check something first.
I need your John Hancock
before the end of the shift.
You'll have it.
Well, if something caused
this guy's epinephrine levels
to spike, it's going to be
on the adrenals,
but I'm not seeing anything.
Could you give them
a closer look?
Something's gotta be there,
I know it.
I'm not supposed to be doing
this without a formal inquiry.
I know, believe me.
You're doing me
a huge favor, Nina.
You're gonna owe me
for this one.
All right, let's see.
Well, I'll be darned.
Huh. Look.
I can't
see anything.
There's your culprit.
Looks like a pheochromocytoma.
It's too small
to show up on the scans.
Must have been what caused
the high levels of epinephrine
in this guy's system.
So he died purely
of natural causes.
Sure did.
Thank you.
You're the best.
Dr. Rhodes, hey,
how's Dr. Bekker?
Hey.
She's hanging in there.
I still can't believe it.
She's usually
the most careful
surgeon at Med.
Just not like her.
Not at all.
Anyway, good night.
Yeah, good night.
What's this?
This is what killed
Paul Kaminsky.
An adrenal tumor.
Okay.
I am so sorry, April.
That was wrong of me.
No kidding.
If I'm being honest
with myself,
I think I was hurt that
you didn't trust me enough
to read me in.
And then I started
to mistrust you as well.
Well, maybe I shouldn't
have cut you out.
It's not easy working
so closely with someone
you've been involved with.
But I'd like to think
we can get past that
and still be friends.
I don't know, Ethan.
You thought
I could kill a patient.
Is that someone
I really want as a friend?
I heard about
what happened. You okay?
What was stolen
from your car today?
Tell me the truth.
Natalie, I don't know
what you're talking about.
All day I have been feeling
like everything is a lie.
It's the same feeling I had
on our wedding day.
Just tell me the truth.
What was stolen
from your car today?
My gun.
Your gun?
You swore to me it was gone.
I wanted to turn it in. I did.
I just needed more time.
Unbelievable.
I didn't know
how to tell you.
I trusted you.
You have every right
to be angry with me.
No, I don't want to hear
any more lies.
Natalie.
It's over.
You don't mean that.
I do.
Goodbye, Will.