Chicago Med, we're inbound
with a 24-year-old female,
Cheryl Martin.
High-speed
collision on Route 30.
T-boned on the
passenger side.
Thirty-four weeks pregnant.
Chest and belly pain.
Heart rate 124,
BP 102 over 80.
Got it. We'll be waiting.
Dr. Halstead.
Maggie.
Incoming helo,
10 minutes out.
Double cappuccino.
What are you
doing with my phone?
I'm posting.
Oh.
My little girl...
Please...
Baghdad.
Page OB.
Got it!
Maggie.
Yup!
Dad?
I'm here, honey.
Need an assist?
Sure.
Coming through!
Need X-rays.
Chest and pelvis.
Got it. Sir, what
is your name?
Ray.
Why don't you come with me
and let the doctors
do their work? Okay?
No, Dad. Dad, please.
This way.
Stay right here.
He'll be right here, sweetie.
On my count.
One, two, three.
I need the ultrasound.
Should I start
a femoral line?
I'll do that.
Okay, get
a triple lumen and blood.
Excuse me.
Lungs are wet.
Belly's soft but tender.
Get a CBC, type and screen,
KB and coags.
If she's Rh-negative,
give RhoGAM.
Got good heart tones
and fetal movement.
Baby and placenta look okay.
I'm in. Clear.
Natalie.
Left hemothorax.
She's bleeding.
Put in a chest tube
and give her back all
the blood you get out.
We're gonna put
a tube in your chest, okay?
My baby...
Won't hurt the baby.
Betadyne and lidocaine.
I got it.
I'm in.
Secure the tube and
let's get her over to CT.
We're taking your daughter up
for a CAT scan. You can come.
Okay.
Dr. Rhodes.
Welcome to CT Surgery.
Dr. Latham. Thank you.
I'll be supervising
your fellowship.
I look forward to it.
Dr. Downey thought
very highly of you.
I'm curious.
There are rumors.
Did you kill him?
I'm sorry?
Did you?
Well, yes. I killed him
and several other
patients as well.
You're being sarcastic.
Yes, Dr. Latham.
I am being sarcastic.
I can see why
you might have found
that inappropriate.
Oh, I should tell you.
You weren't my first choice
for this fellowship.
I preferred a young woman
from Groote Schuur,
but I was out-voted.
Such is life.
That being said,
I hope we will
work well together.
Sputum test
was negative.
Chest is clear.
Night sweats?
No.
Good. TB's still latent.
For now.
No reason it
shouldn't stay
that way.
Anything I need to know?
I worry about
Tate and his son.
They've been tested, April.
They're negative.
And you're not contagious.
I know. I know. But...
What?
I just don't feel
clean.
New residents settling in?
Yeah. I just gotta keep 'em
from killing people.
July first is not a good day
to need a hospital.
And how are you doing?
Cleaned out Bert's
desk this morning.
Thought it would
make me feel better.
It didn't.
Mmm.
Good morning.
Dr. Choi.
Our new Chief Resident
will need this.
ED staff contact list.
Thank you.
Oh, and one more thing.
I know I got
the Chief Resident's
gavel here somewhere.
Funny.
By the way, Maggie,
I've got some ideas
to improve patient flow.
Oh! Can't wait
to hear about them.
I hate killing their dreams.
No, you like to let
them hang themselves.
Morning.
Hey.
Here are
my scheduling sheets.
Last Chief Res
gave them to me.
Thanks, but I've got
my own system.
How we ran sick bay
on the carrier.
Hey, Dr. Choi,
I'm taking off.
I texted you
I'm switching shifts
with Elise Baker.
Right, yeah.
And she also,
she called,
she said she's going
to be a little late.
She has to take
her kid in for shots.
No problem, thanks.
Sure you don't
want these sheets?
No, I got it.
Dr. Choi, we need you.
Chout, talk to me.
Emmie Miles,
15-year-old girl.
Found unconscious,
suspected opioid overdose.
She appeared to have
smoked a fentanyl patch.
Okay, we're going
to Treatment...
Six.
I got it, Maggie.
All right.
You give her Narcan?
Five times.
She responded in the ambo,
just slid back into overdose.
All right,
let's move her.
On my count. Ready?
One, two, three.
April, let's give her
another two milligrams
Narcan and hang a drip.
Got it.
Bring her down slowly.
Don't want to
precipitate withdrawal.
Chout. Fentanyl patch.
This girl try to kill herself?
No idea, Doc.
Grande, quad, half-caf,
nonfat, no whip mocha?
Not half-caf.
Three shots regular,
one shot decaf.
Okay.
So, what happened
to your knee?
I'm embarrassed to say
I tripped over a suitcase.
Missed my conference
in Lyon.
At least I got
to practice French
with an orthopedic
nurse from Montreal.
So, Dr. Reese,
reason I'm here...
Uh, aside from the coffee,
of course,
is that Med
has a residency opening
for you.
I'll take it.
On my service.
Psychiatry? Okay.
Enough foam, enough foam.
Um...
Dr. Charles, thank you,
but I've never
considered psychiatry.
I don't think
I'm equipped.
I think you have
all the tools.
You're a problem solver.
You pay attention.
And look at how beautiful
you're making my coffee
despite
all my meddling.
But... I don't know
how to talk to people.
It's actually
more about listening
than talking.
Grande, quad,
three-quarters caf,
nonfat, no whip mocha.
I'll tell you what.
How about you come
and spend the day with me,
and then see what you think.
She has a contained
rupture of the aorta.
Pseudoaneurysm.
That's how we read it.
It's leaking.
Let's get her up to
the cath lab, fix it.
Cheryl's 34 weeks pregnant.
Wouldn't that
irradiate the baby?
Well, it's not ideal,
but it's very
little radiation.
What about surgery?
That's the other option.
We'd have to
put her on bypass.
We can't protect
the baby's heart rate.
So, let's give her
a C-section.
Take the baby out
of the equation.
No. She could still
carry this baby to term.
Natalie, you are very
concerned about the baby,
but what about the mother?
She is lying there
with an aortic injury.
Honey.
Dad.
Your daughter
has some damage
to her aorta.
It's what we call
a pseudoaneurysm.
And it caused a leak
in the vessel wall.
Sometimes a leak like this
will stop on its own.
If that's the case,
then Cheryl will be able
to carry the baby to term.
So at this point,
we're just going
to wait and watch.
We're gonna take
her up to the ICU
where we can keep
a close eye on her.
Whatever you think
is best.
Oh, my chest.
Mr. Buckner?
Daddy?
He's having an MI.
Dad?
Daddy,
what's happening?
No pulse. Code Blue.
Radiology hallway.
We need a crash cart.
Yes.
Daddy!
We're gonna take care
of him. Just lie still.
Bringing
the cart and monitor.
Just stay here.
Nat, get a quick look.
He's in v-fib.
Charge to 200.
Hold compressions. Clear.
Clear.
Still in v-fib. Clear!
Daddy.
Sinus rhythm.
We got a pulse.
He's back.
Let's get him up
to the cath lab now.
On my count.
One, two three.
Daddy. Daddy!
Daddy!
All right, let's go.
Huge ST changes.
Yeah,
it's a bad one.
Morning, Dr. Choi.
Morning.
This your
fentanyl OD?
Yes.
Sarah. Are you back?
I've invited Dr. Reese
to become a psych resident.
That's great.
You think so?
Absolutely.
I'm a great believer
in psychiatry.
Hmm. Interesting.
Dr. Charles, this is the
patient's mother, Mrs. Miles.
Hey.
Nice to meet you,
Mrs. Miles.
This is my colleague,
Dr. Reese.
I don't understand this.
Emmie doesn't use drugs.
A fentanyl patch
is a very high dose
of a very strong opioid.
This is a difficult question,
but I have to ask it.
Do you think
there's any chance
that your daughter
could have been trying
to take her own life?
No, absolutely not.
She's very popular.
She has hundreds of friends.
She has no reason
to kill herself.
Do you have any idea
how she might have gotten
hold of the patch?
My mother has cancer.
She's prescribed
fentanyl patches
for pain.
I suppose she could...
Would you mind if we
talk with her for a bit?
Please. Go ahead.
Thank you.
Honey, I'll be back
in a couple minutes, hmm?
Hi, Emmie,
how are you feeling?
I'm Dr. Charles.
And I'm Dr. Reese.
Can you tell us
what happened today?
Leave me alone.
We're concerned
about you, Emmie,
and we need to
understand what happened
so that we can
take care of you.
We just want to help.
You know what?
Why don't we
come back later?
And maybe you'll
feel like talking then.
You know who the most unhappy
people in the world are?
Hmm?
Fifteen-year-old girls.
I remember.
Mom said Emmie had
hundreds of friends.
Hyperbole?
Maybe not.
She could have
hundreds of friends.
Oh, like that.
Girls her age
share everything.
They judge everything.
Maybe Emmie was shamed,
and that led to
a suicide attempt.
Let me know
what you find.
Mmm-hmm.
Nice bunch of newbies.
Maybe even the Ice Princess
will finally find somebody.
The Ice Princess?
Yeah, Dr. Manning,
who else?
Just a princess?
Why not the Ice Queen?
It was a joke.
Dr. Halstead.
HR informed me
that you still
haven't supplied them
with current
malpractice insurance.
Oh, I'm trying to find
a carrier that'll
write me a policy.
I'm guessing that's
because of the lawsuit.
Doesn't make sense.
The suit was dropped.
But to an insurance company,
you still look
like a bad risk.
Attending physicians
must provide
their own
malpractice insurance.
Now, the hospital can give you
a grace period of two weeks,
but after that...
I understand.
Look, I know you and I
have had our ups and downs,
but I don't want to lose you.
So I'll make a few calls.
Thank you.
You may not want to thank me.
I guarantee, your insurance
will not come cheap.
Courtney?
Thirty-three-year-old male,
peds vs. auto. GCS 15.
Bruising to the right orbit,
no loss of consciousness.
All right.
Wait a second. Dr. Choi.
Got a GSW in Baghdad.
Where's Baker?
Took her kid in
for shots, remember?
I'll take it.
What room,
Dr. Choi?
Trauma Three.
You heard your Chief Resident.
Let's go.
It's... It's occupied.
Dr. Choi.
Go to Trauma Two. Rotate.
Patient told me
he's HIV-positive.
That's right, be careful.
No problem.
On my count.
One, two, three.
Get it out.
Can you tell me
your name, sir?
Greg Allen.
Can you tell me
how this happened?
Crossing the street.
Wasn't looking.
Will somebody
please call my wife?
The number's in my wallet.
I will.
Lungs are clear.
I'll take it from here.
I got it.
I'll take it.
Thank you.
I'm HIV-positive.
Okay. Follow my finger.
All right,
retractor's in.
Looks good.
Let's harvest.
Check the LIMA pulse.
The LIMA looks small.
How about the saphenous vein?
No. The left
internal mammary artery
is always the first
and best option.
I understand.
It's just...
Dr. Downey preferred
the saphenous vein
to a small LIMA.
LIMA pulse is good,
let's start freeing it up.
If you're sure.
I know what I'm doing,
and I don't like
to be contradicted
by a fellow
while I am operating!
Give me the Bovie.
And Emmie does have
hundreds of friends,
623 to be exact.
She's on a lot of
social media platforms.
Six hundred and
twenty-three friends?
Yikes.
Who do you invite to
the birthday party?
Mmm-hmm. And she isn't
always very nice
to the other girls.
Not very nice?
She wasn't shamed.
She's the shamer.
Interesting.
Well, so what do you think?
Maybe Emmie realized
she really hurt someone
and she felt guilty.
Guilty enough
to kill herself?
Mmm, I don't know.
You know what?
We got to get
Emmie to open up.
Next time Mom takes a break,
jump in there,
give it another shot.
Uh, Dr. Charles, wait.
Where are you going?
Well, I just thought
Emmie might be
more comfortable
talking to a woman.
And somebody her own age.
But I don't know what
to say or what to ask.
I think that once
you get in there,
you'll discover that you do.
Thank you.
It's just...
I hate standing around.
I mean, I've had
a lot of experience,
and this guy won't
let me do anything.
I know he's your friend
and I'm sure he's a
really good doctor, but...
Mmm-hmm.
I don't know.
Jeff, can I...
Can I ask you something?
Yeah.
Do I seem like a...
An Ice Princess?
A what?
A nurse called me
that today.
Uh, do I come across
as rigid or uptight?
Really? Come on.
Do you remember back
when the four of us
were hanging out?
You were the one who always
kept the party going.
Do you remember that one time
we were at a Greek restaurant?
There was
a wedding party next to us,
and they were breaking plates.
So you got us to
start breaking plates...
And the next thing you know,
you're standing on the table,
and you're waving your arms
and you were yelling,
like, "Opa! Opa!"
You were crazy.
Oh, my God, yes.
The bouzouki player
wanted me to join the band.
That's right.
That was great.
Mmm-hmm.
Yeah. Yeah,
it really was.
See, I told you.
Everything's gonna be okay.
I still have to
be on antibiotics
for another five months.
Hey, we... We'll be
all clear by New Year's.
So, tonight,
you're gonna come over.
I'll cook dinner.
I'll see how
I feel after work.
Okay.
You're not contagious, honey.
Doesn't hurt to be careful.
Okay.
Hey.
How are you feeling?
Your, uh...
Your blood pressure
looks good.
And your heart rate...
Are you a shrink?
Uh, no.
I'm barely a doctor.
I just graduated
medical school.
I was, uh, checking out
your Instagram photos.
And you look
really beautiful.
I always hate
the way I look
in photos.
Mmm...
You need to take a lot.
You do?
I took about 100
to get that one.
Oh...
I have to look perfect
or I won't send it.
You've been
reading my tweets too?
Mmm-hmm.
You must think
I'm a horrible person.
Why would I think that?
'Cause of what
I say about other girls.
No.
No, I, um...
I just think you're
under a lot of pressure
to be perfect.
Oh, God.
Emmie?
I'm not...
I'm not perfect.
Emmie, nobody is.
You don't understand.
Look.
It's vitiligo.
I googled it.
You can't cure it.
It's gonna spread
all over my body.
Every... Everybody's
gonna make fun of me.
My life is ruined.
Emmie, did you try
to kill yourself?
I don't know.
You don't know?
I just...
I just wanted it all
to go away.
I'm gonna take a skin
scraping. Is that okay?
He extubated easily,
and the graft is in.
You were right
about using the LIMA.
True, but he's hemolyzing.
His urine output is
marginal and pink.
Neither's uncommon
after being on pump.
Nothing to suggest
he won't make a full recovery.
There's also nothing
to suggest he will.
Dr. Latham.
Um...
I realize, like every
doctor who teaches here,
you have your own methods.
But, I assume,
if I have an opinion,
you'd like to hear it.
Well, of course. Why?
Well, it's just that
you seemed very upset
in the OR.
Did I?
Yes.
I'm not upset.
I can't see! Help me!
Mr. Allen?
I can't see out
of my right eye.
Dr. Wheeler!
I can't see out
of my right eye!
The CT showed a hematoma.
Check the
intraocular pressure.
Where's my wife?
She's on her way.
Pressure's high.
He's got
a retrobulbar hemorrhage.
He needs a lateral canthotomy.
Patient is HIV-positive.
Now, or he'll lose the eye.
Help me.
Clamp.
Here.
Surgical scissors.
Your vision will
return in a little while.
Thank you. Thank you.
Did Dr. Wheeler tell you
to perform that procedure?
It was an emergency.
The patient could have
gone blind in that eye.
Then why didn't
Dr. Wheeler perform it?
You'll have to ask
Dr. Wheeler.
You're a medical student.
You're not allowed to do
an invasive procedure
unless ordered to
do so by a doctor.
I've done
a lateral canthotomy.
Third-year on optho.
You're not on optho.
You're in the ED,
and there are rules.
And unless you
figure that out,
you're gonna get yourself
kicked out of here
and med school.
You understand?
I hear you.
Do you want me
to write him up?
No.
It's for his own good.
I know what happens
when you don't
follow protocol.
It's not personal.
Why didn't you tell me
that you were
coming back to Med?
I didn't know
until this morning.
So you'll be back
in the ED?
Uh, not exactly.
Dr. Charles wants me
to be a psych resident.
You?
Is that such a shock?
I just didn't realize
that you had
an interest in that.
I didn't.
I don't. I...
I don't know.
What do you see?
I wish people
wouldn't diagnose
themselves.
They always screw it up.
Hmm.
Your patient
doesn't have vitiligo.
She has tinea versicolor.
A yeast infection?
Yeah.
That's wonderful.
You know, I'm going to miss
the smell of coffee on you.
It's a little
early to tell,
but my initial assessment
is that your father
is doing well post-op.
Thank you.
Mmm-hmm.
Dr. Rhodes.
Excuse us.
You can see.
The leak from
her pseudoaneurysm
is increasing.
I still think we
should watch it.
Natalie,
if she goes into labor,
it could rupture
and kill her.
We gotta take
care of this now.
We'll take Cheryl
to the hybrid room.
I'll shield the baby
with a lead blanket
and stent her.
We'll have OB standing by.
If anything goes wrong,
they can perform
an emergency C-section.
Nat, we've got to
deal with this.
I'll page OB.
Doctor?
I was with his daughter
when he crashed.
How is he?
Mr. Buckner is in and out
of non-sustained v-tach.
Heart rate spikes to 180.
How long has it
been going on?
Fifteen minutes.
We've started
an amiodarone infusion.
That should suppress
his arrhythmia.
Your lips to God's ear.
Ready to cannulate.
Seeing decels on the fetal
heart rate down to 110.
In position
to place the stent.
Dr. Manning's right.
I don't like that tracing.
Just
a little bit longer.
Heart rate's
down to 100.
Ninety-six.
No time.
The baby's in distress.
We have to get her out now.
Okay.
OB DOCTOR 1:
Sponges on the field.
Yes.
OB DOCTOR 1:
All right. Get ready for flushes of suction.
Last heart rate was 85.
Cut the cord.
Dr. Manning.
She's all yours,
Dr. Rhodes.
Okay, fluoro on.
Let's go.
I'm not hearing
anything. How's the baby?
First APGAR,
six, but already improving.
How's Mom?
Hanging in there.
Placing the stent now.
And deploy.
It's in. Well-seated.
His creatinine levels
hit 2.5.
Is he responding
to diuretics?
No.
I'm not sure why his
kidneys aren't working.
Possibly post CPR
and pump.
Call renal, see what
the nephrologists suggest.
Yes, Dr. Latham.
Your little girl
is doing just fine.
Oh, thank you.
Cheryl.
I'm afraid your father
is not doing very well.
What do you mean?
I'm gonna go check on him.
I'll let you know.
Please take me to him.
Cheryl, you just had
an emergency C-section.
Take me and my baby.
I can't do that.
Please.
My dad.
Pressure's dropping.
No pulse.
Call a code.
Will, start compressions.
Yep.
Epi,
one milligram.
One milligram IV push.
Here you go.
Code Blue.
Charge to 200.
All right, hold compressions.
Clear.
Fine v-fib.
Two hundred again.
Charging 200.
Hold. Clear.
Clear.
Let me do it.
He's asystole.
He's gone, Connor.
Vasopressin 40. Now.
Dr. Rhodes,
the patient is dead.
Time of death, 15:20.
Connor.
Daddy.
Look.
It's your granddaughter.
Daddy?
No.
I've never seen
anything like that.
No.
Dr. Reese,
how's our patient?
I gave her
ketoconazole cream.
Her fungal infection
should be gone in a week.
Excellent.
Mmm-hmm.
Dr. Charles, I've decided
I will take that residency
in psychiatry.
I see now that by combining
my clinical knowledge
with psychology,
maybe I really
can help people.
I am so glad
to hear that.
You're not talking about
Emmie though, are you?
Um...
Listen, you very
skillfully treated
a superficial
skin infection.
Unfortunately,
neither of us
have done anything
to address
the profound underlying
psychological issues
that she suffers from.
I'm just saying, you know,
our patient has
a long way to go.
Oh.
Yes.
Anybody ever tell
you the etymology
of the word "psychiatry"?
The medical treatment
of the soul.
Isn't that marvelous?
So, worry not,
Dr. Reese.
We all... All of us
have a long way to go
in healing our souls.
Dr. Choi.
Yes?
My patient waited
two and a half hours
for a treatment room,
but I understand Treatment One
has been free all day.
Yeah.
Wonderful.
I'd sure like to know
where Noah Sexton
disappeared to.
Thirty-five grand
a year.
What my malpractice
is going to cost.
And that's on top
of my student loans,
which now,
because I'm an attending,
I have to start paying off.
How's your "sick bay"
system working?
I will take those
scheduling sheets after all.
You can have them.
Well, you know,
the thing I learned early on,
the nurses,
they run everything anyway.
Yeah.
You know,
I saw a dead man
come back to life today.
Makes all this other stuff
seem kind of small.
Do you think she's on
Pre-exposure Prophylaxis?
Pretty standard
with HIV. Why?
Doesn't look like he's
afraid he'll infect her.
Well, there's very
little risk, April.
Learn to deal
with things, April.
Life's not perfect.
But it is pretty great.
Hey, Dad.
Hi, sweetie.
Let me check your phone.
I want to see how
many likes we got.
"Likes"?
The selfie we took.
Twenty-two.
Hey, you know
what we should do?
What?
We should take one
in front of Dylan's Candy Bar.
That'll make
everybody jealous.
Yeah, you know
what we should do?
We should go live in a cave
with no electricity
until you're
about 35 years old.
That's what we should do.
Daddy!
What?
April!
Hey.
So... So how are we
feeling after work?
Good.
Then dinner tonight?
You like my raviolis, right?
I tolerate your ravioli.
Are you sure
you're okay
with everything?
Me, the whole package?
Baby, I'm sure.
I'll make the garlic bread.
Come on.
Oh...
Mmm.
I got these.
Thanks.
I'll get them next time.
Okay.
You know, I didn't
expect to see you here.
My mother-in-law
insisted on taking Owen
for the night.
She says I need a life.
Ah...
My car is, um,
is over there.
Okay, I'll walk
you to it.
No, no.
You don't have to do that.
Okay.
My apartment
is just around
the block anyway, so...
Okay.
Well... Good night.
You want to come by
for a night cap?
Yeah.
Yeah, I do.