I want to reassure you.
Your child can have a
completely normal life.
How can a baby have
male and female DNA?
It's a condition called
genetic mosaicism.
The ambiguous genitalia
can be surgically repaired.
Repaired?
Made to look more typical.
More typical?
But you haven't even told
us if the baby's a boy or a girl.
That's a choice
you have to make.
Nice job, Jackson.
Take it.
He had the shot.
He lost his nerve.
Honey, it's okay.
He's doing great.
Three.
No fear that time.
Melanie. What?
Oh, my God. Jackson!
Black heels or the boots?
You know I'm a
fan of those heels.
Boots it is.
For all we know, House knows
you're a fan of those heels.
You think House
is going to figure out
we faked our break-up
because of your shoes?
Go with the boots.
You gonna eat that?
Have at it.
Did you just ask my permission
before you took my food?
Yes, we can.
Adolescent genetic mosaic,
collapsed during a basketball game,
presenting with
persistent pelvic pain.
Fun.
The parents haven't told their son
that he could have been their daughter.
They want assurance
that you won't either.
Less fun. But still.
That was easy.
Our new patient.
Part girl, part boy,
all Thirteen's dream date.
Severe pelvic pain started during a
basketball game. Could be dehydration.
ER gave him fluids
when he came in.
Still, if it was chronic...
We got a kid who could mate
with himself, and we're thinking
he didn't have enough to drink?
There are dozens
of intersex disorders.
Persistent pelvic pain could mean
congenital adrenal hyperplasia, PMDS.
Those conditions
occur in intersex kids
who are chromosomally
XX or XY, not XX and XY.
Parents recently started him on
testosterone, maybe there's something...
Vitamins wouldn't
cause pelvic pain.
There's a note in here.
We're supposed to refer to his
testosterone shots as vitamins.
His parents aren't just liars.
They want us to be liars, too.
I won't do it. You
guys will, though.
He's a kid. Parents don't
think he's ready to deal with it.
My dad was the same way about
me maybe having Huntington's. It's...
Well, if that was
your experience,
it must surely apply
in this situation.
Pain could be caused by a blind
uterus hidden in his abdomen.
He needs an MRI.
Right. Boy with girl genes.
I'm sure you're the first doctor
brilliant enough to check for a uterus.
He could have complications
from the surgeries on his penis.
That can cause pelvic pain.
Way to multi-task.
Impress your boss
and humiliate your ex.
MRI is a waste of time.
But to continue the humiliation,
go put a camera up his penis.
You're Dr. House, aren't you?
What do you think is
wrong with our son?
These people were
just coming to tell you.
This is better.
Don't have to worry about
them losing their way.
We think that he has a blind
uterus. He should have an MRI.
Did you send them a text?
Over the past 13 years,
we've educated ourselves.
Who needs med school
when you've got Wi-Fi?
Go schedule their son for an
MRI with contrast right away.
Thank you. Thanks.
You just said an MRI
was a waste of time.
So is arguing with them.
Contrast's in.
Jackson, we're going to
get started, so try to lie still.
How long do you think the post-break-up
awkwardness is going to last?
Foreman and I are
both professionals.
Stomach and liver are clear.
If by "professional" you mean he's a
T-1000 built by Cyberdyne Systems.
I never understood
what you saw in him.
He's not really your type, huh?
Moving down through
the pelvic floor.
Here's my impression of Foreman
on the happiest day of his life.
Now, the saddest
day of his life.
We just broke up. I'm not
quite ready to mock him yet.
House was a jerk
to split you two up,
but bottom line,
he did you a favor.
Area around the
intestinal tract is clear.
No blind uterus.
I think there's something
wrong with House.
Who's he making miserable now?
Actually, no one.
He okayed an MRI just because the
parents wanted to look for a blind uterus.
There was no fighting, no
arguing, he just went along.
It's a valid medical theory.
He doesn't think it is.
House decided to
humor these parents.
Maybe he had a
great cup of coffee,
or a tremendous bowel movement.
Bottom line is, your
boss is in a good mood.
Stop analyzing it
and just enjoy it.
We're going to use this scope
to fill your bladder with saline,
then examine your urethra
for any narrow spots.
Why would there
be a narrow spot?
Sometimes it just happens.
Can my parents come in?
Sure.
I thought it'd be awkward
for you having them here.
I have this feeling they've
seen me naked before.
Now, take a breath,
just try to relax.
Mom.
It's okay, honey. It's okay.
Hey, remember those sprints
they made you run in practice?
Those were so hard,
but you pulled through.
You can do this, too.
I'm to the bladder.
Start the saline.
I'm going to look around
and pull back on the scope.
Feels tight. THIRTEEN:
That pressure's normal.
Just try to hold on for
a few more minutes.
It's not down there.
It's my chest.
I can't breathe.
Can't... Can't breathe.
Is he okay?
Muffled heart sounds.
Jugular's distended.
Pericardial effusion.
We need a 10
gauge and a syringe.
What's happening?
His heart is filling
with exudate.
If we don't drain
it, it'll stop beating.
We drained the fluid
from his pericardial space.
His heart rate is
back to normal.
Pelvis plus heart
doesn't fit with any of the
syndromes associated with mosaicism.
It could be drugs,
toxins, an infection.
You're okay with this?
With what?
That we're considering a diagnosis
unrelated to this kid being a she-male.
Assuming a coincidence like
that would usually torture you,
but you're completely unfazed.
Completely unfazed? You think
I'm totally lacking in any fazing?
The idea that I'm anything less than
half-fazed, I actually find offensive.
It greatly fazes me.
He started testosterone...
Vitamins.
A few months ago. That can
cause autoimmune diseases
like polyarteritis and SLE, which can
cause pericardial effusion and pelvic pain.
So, it is related.
Now I'm unfazed.
Start him on corticosteroids
for the autoimmune,
finasteride to
block the vitamins.
You slept with House.
He asked permission
before taking my bagel,
took the case without a fight,
honored the parents'
request for an MRI.
Yes, those were my
terms for sleeping with him.
He's in a good mood.
Sex with me would explain that,
but it doesn't explain why I'm not
curled up in a ball, weeping in shame.
I did not have sex with House.
If you two aren't keeping
something from me,
that means he's keeping
something from both of us.
That can't be good. Or
he's just in a good mood.
This is not a crisis.
Maybe you can get back some
of that money he owes you.
Hmm.
Testosterone blocker?
Does that mean if Jackson has
SLE, or whatever that other thing was,
that he'd have to
go off the hormones?
Probably.
Then Jackson will
stop developing,
he'll never go through puberty.
Maybe this isn't
what's wrong with him,
maybe the testosterone
didn't cause it.
Yeah. But if it is, then
he'll never be a man.
Did we make the wrong choice?
You'll need to tell him the
testosterone blocker is something else.
Or maybe this is a good
opportunity to tell him the truth.
It might make it
simpler for all of you.
You want us to tell a sick adolescent
boy that he's really not an adolescent boy?
That doesn't seem simpler to me.
No. Just
give him the meds.
So, you have pain in one
arm and both your legs.
Does it hurt right now?
No.
It's when I, like, put
pressure on them.
See, it hurts when I do this.
Ow!
And this.
What about this?
Ow!
Did you give House the
moron with the broken finger?
They've been in Room
2 about 10 minutes.
The patient should've been screaming
for another doctor seven minutes ago.
Thanks, bro.
If I have this IV, why
do I need a shot, too?
Just some extra
medicine, just to be safe.
I hear you're quite
the basketball player.
What position? Point guard.
Small forward. How's
your crossover dribble?
It's okay. I'm not really
that into basketball.
Gonna feel a little pinch, okay?
So, if you're not that into
it, why'd you join the team?
My mom kind of made me do it.
My parents were the same way,
always pushing
me to try new things.
It was more like what
she didn't want me to try.
I wanted to take dance,
but she flipped out,
and made me choose
between basketball and hockey.
What does your dad say?
He seemed okay with it, then
he just caved in to my mom.
Your palm is red.
What does that mean?
That we still don't know
what's wrong with you.
You were right, he
is in a good mood.
Bummer it didn't work
out with you and Thirteen.
It happens.
You guys seemed happy together.
It's probably for the best, you
know, the bisexual thing and all.
That was never an issue.
No, it never is. Until it is.
This is Thirteen. Before
you guys got together,
she was hooking up with
a different girl every night.
Long term, you really think
you could compete with that?
House, wake up. We have to talk.
Stop pretending to be
asleep, we're not leaving.
House.
What's going on?
House?
He's not breathing.
Can you get a pulse?
Barely. Call a code.
Get an Ambu bag
from the nurse's station.
Heart's still working, means
synapses are still firing.
We just need to get a
message through to him.
You stopped breathing.
What the hell is going on?
I think my penis stopped
breathing. Do you know CPR?
Looks like your brain is okay.
Pupils are equal,
round and reactive.
I'm fine, other than the fact
that my nurple is now purple.
No wonder you broke up with him.
I'm surprised yours
are still attached.
By the way, I could
see that from here.
I assume those are
our patient's lab results.
The patient can wait.
You could have died.
The only reason you'd ignore a
near-death experience is you don't care,
or you already know
why it happened.
It's called Vicodin.
I took too many.
Can I please get some
information about our patient?
The patient's palms are red. Lab test
confirmed liver and kidney dysfunction.
I don't remember you
taking any Vicodin today.
I don't remember
hiring my mother.
And what causes the enzymes in
little Boy George's existing
heart problem and pelvic pain?
You didn't take any
yesterday at breakfast, either.
I don't remember having
breakfast with my mother.
Amyloidosis with
systemic involvement.
Protein levels are normal.
This kid's depressed.
If he's self-medicating
with drugs and alcohol,
that'd explain his symptoms.
Search the school.
Search the home.
Seriously? Or are
you just deflecting?
Both.
Where are you going? Nowhere.
I'm staying right here, so
we can properly discuss this.
He's on heroin. How can you...
Number one, he's happy,
which means he's high.
Number two, when he moved his bad
leg, he didn't use his hands to support it.
Whatever he's taking,
it's stronger than Vicodin.
What are we gonna do?
You really think House
took too many Vicodin?
Guy pops them like candy. I'm
surprised it hasn't happened before.
Do you miss sleeping with women?
Excuse me?
Simple question.
Yes. It's a simple answer.
I'll check under the bed.
I also miss sleeping
with other men,
and I'm sure you miss
sleeping with other women.
Monogamy is like saying
you're never going to have
any other ice cream
flavor besides Rocky Road.
So, you're saying if you don't
have pink bubblegum for a while,
that one day you're gonna
chase down the ice cream truck?
No, Rocky Road is great.
It's a very delicious
and complicated flavor.
I also know that if I
have other flavors,
then Rocky Road is gonna be left in
the freezer where anyone can just dip in.
Can we please drop the metaphor?
Why is this coming up now?
Kutner said the
silver lining of our
break-up was I wouldn't
be dumped for a girl.
There's nothing in here, either.
Seems like you're wrong about
this kid having drug or alcohol...
When did he bring that up?
Earlier today, right before...
This morning, Taub
called you a robot.
Hmm.
Either it's a big coincidence
or they're jerking us
around, they know.
And if they know, House knows.
This is bad.
No, this is good.
House only has two ways
to handle us still going out.
He jerks us around
or he fires us.
He chose option A. This is good.
But this is bad.
"I stand alone, my soul and me,
beneath the mask that others see"
His chest is still rising.
He's just screwing with me
'cause Cuddy made me baby-sit.
"A pain that tears and
bites and will not bend
"Only when I sleep will it end."
Downer. And
medically irrelevant.
You sure his chest is moving?
House.
If he's faking, you think he's going to
come clean because you said his name?
Back off. Only Thirteen gets
to grab my nipples this time.
You know, recreating the moment
when you made us crap our
pants isn't actually all that funny.
That is sweet that you're
worried about House.
Unless the next stanza reads,
"Hoping to fry my brain to death I
smoked some primo crystal meth,"
I'm not interested.
You can't deny that
this kid may be suicidal.
We're not here to make him
happy, we're here to diagnose him.
It's an infection.
Swab of the kid's water
bottle turned up toxoplasmosis.
I'll start him on pyrimethamine.
I had no idea he felt this way.
Is there a therapist here
that you can recommend?
It might help more
if you talked to him.
He's not ready.
If telling him the truth would
help him stop feeling like this.
If I knew that it'd make
him less confused,
I'd tell him right now.
But if she's wrong, we'd
only make things worse.
He obviously
senses he's different.
He's looking for answers.
Every teenager feels different.
He's sick. This isn't the
time to spring this on him.
Okay.
When you give
Jackson the antibiotics,
will you please re-start
the testosterone?
Sure.
I get House wanting to jerk me
and Thirteen around, but you guys?
Told you they
were still together.
How'd he know?
He noticed you smell like
Thirteen's soap every morning.
You figured it out?
Yes, I'm a little slow.
Maybe someone should let me
know when I should be insulted.
Then House doesn't know.
Probably does now
that you felt her up
during that last differential.
You noticed this,
but House didn't?
Yes, I get it. He's
generally smarter than me.
Can we please move on?
He's not generally
smarter than you,
he's always smarter than you.
Unless...
Hello?
House is on heroin.
Well, that's certainly
an interesting notion.
It's why his lungs stopped,
it's why he okayed the MRI,
it's why he missed things
he wouldn't ordinarily miss.
We'll run some tests,
and I'll let you know.
He's there, isn't he?
Well, that would certainly explain
the inappropriate responses.
I got to go. Okay.
Sorry. Consult.
When did you order these?
When you were in the bathroom.
I thought a celebration
was in order.
To cheating death.
You off bourbon? Can I
get you something else?
I came here expecting a burger.
Figured I'd have to endure
a little lecture on moderation.
You never listen, so why...
But instead, I get a drink.
A nice little serving of
respiratory depressant
on the day that my
lungs stopped working.
You seem fine now.
You don't believe
that I OD'd on Vicodin.
You figure I'm on
something stronger.
And because you can
never, ever assume anything
but the most screwed-up
scenario as far as I'm concerned...
Funny how I'm usually right.
You think that I'm on heroin.
This is your version of a tox
screen. Because if I am on heroin,
I can't drink that without risking
another bout of not breathing.
Well?
Good night.
Another shot?
I'm afraid so.
That looks like the
vitamins my parents give me.
Same red top.
These aren't vitamins.
What is it?
I can't tell you that. You
should ask your parents.
You idiot.
Okay, I admit
it. I have bulimia.
I look good though, don't I?
Heroin. Heroin!
House, of all the stupid...
I'm not on heroin.
I just caught you with your
fingers down your throat.
I'm on methadone.
Stupid product,
heroin without the high.
Yeah, and twice
the risk of death.
But no risk of arrest.
You nearly died.
Today was a fluke, I nodded off.
Right, you're safe as long
as you never sleep again.
Mis-time your dose, you
die, couple of drinks, you die,
mix it with the
wrong drugs, you die.
You want to detox from Vicodin,
pick something
that won't kill you.
I'm not detoxing.
If you're looking for something
to help with your pain.
It doesn't help my
pain. It eliminates it.
My leg doesn't hurt anymore.
She completely
disregarded our instructions.
He asked a question.
I was tired of lying.
I didn't tell him anything
about his genetic condition.
I want her removed
from our son's case.
I'm sorry for the position Dr. Hadley
put you in, but I can't do that.
She's a valuable part of
Dr. House's diagnostic team.
If he stays on the
case, so does she.
We have to deal with Jackson.
These questions
aren't going to go away.
He's not ready for this.
Let's hope you're wrong.
I'm sorry. I'll stay
away from their son.
No, you won't.
In about 15 minutes, you're the
only person that kid's gonna trust.
If he needs a hand to hold,
make sure yours is available.
So, what, am I a boy or a girl?
Some of your cells are
male, and some are female.
So, basically, I'm a freak.
No, no, buddy.
You're just a little different.
You've known this since I was
born and you never told me?
We didn't want
you to be confused.
So, you lied to me.
Oh, please, sweetie, we
were just trying to protect you.
Don't.
Just leave me alone.
Get out.
Let's go.
You still breathing in there?
Because if not, I'm
sending in janitorial.
I'm not breathing, but
it's strictly voluntary.
You should've seen the guy
who was in here before me.
I know about the methadone.
It's legal. I have
a prescription.
Whatever doctor you
conned into writing it
clearly had no idea about your
addiction issues, your lack of...
He knows I'm in pain. What I
put in my body is my business.
If you keep taking
this, you could die.
If he'd said that if I keep
doing this, you could die,
then it'd be your business.
I can't sit by and
watch you kill yourself.
As long as you're in my
hospital, you can't do methadone.
I'll send someone for my stuff.
That's it? You're quitting?
You're choosing
methadone over this job?
I'm choosing lack
of pain over this job.
Eventually you have to
talk to your parents again.
No, I don't.
I have this one friend on
my basketball team, Will.
We hang out a
lot. I really like him.
Now I'm worried that I,
you know, like him.
Maybe I'm supposed to.
Because if I'm really a girl...
Do you feel like a girl?
I like dancing more
than basketball.
Is that what that means?
Jackson,
as hard as it is right now,
at least it's out in the open.
You don't have to
hide behind a mask.
I found the poem you
wrote in your room.
No matter how bad things get,
killing yourself is
never the answer.
This was an English assignment.
We were supposed to write a poem
in the style of Sylvia Plath.
You don't feel this way?
I'm sad sometimes.
But I don't want to die.
At least, I didn't.
Are these antibiotics supposed
to make you nauseous?
Yeah, they can.
We're on our own. Is he okay?
He's fine. He's just not here.
Did he quit? Did
she suspend him?
She didn't say. Just
told me I was in charge
until further notice.
So, if we add bloody vomit
to our patient's
list of symptoms...
Surgeon reports the bleeding
was caused by a gastric fistula
caused by necrotizing
pancreatitis.
She must have
told you something.
Nothing that would
help us with this patient.
Heart, liver, kidneys
and pancreas.
Obviously, whatever this kid's
got, it's something systemic.
Zollinger-Ellison.
Or systemic scleroderma.
Zollinger-Ellison fits better.
Why?
Can we at least call House?
We can, I have,
he's not answering.
Put the patient on
proton pump inhibitors.
If he gets better, it's Zollinger-Ellison.
If not, it's scleroderma.
Zollinger-Ellison
doesn't fit better.
You don't want it
to be scleroderma
because that means
he's going to die.
Patients die all the time.
Not the ones whose
families you've ruined.
I don't think that, you do.
It's not your fault.
He was no more confused
than any other teenager,
then I started a fire
and threw gas on it.
You were trying to help.
Hi, is House here?
He's getting dressed.
I'll be back around
10:00 tonight.
Go on in.
Okay.
Who is she?
I hired her to watch me sleep,
make sure I don't
stop breathing.
Home nurses usually wear scrubs.
She's not a nurse.
You hired a hooker to watch
you sleep? That just can't...
Surprisingly,
hookers are cheaper.
They don't sue for sexual
harassment. Which one?
You shaved!
The red one then.
You have two ties?
Meeting at St.
Sebastian's today.
I'm going to try
and talk them into
starting up a
diagnostics department.
That sounds great.
I just came by to check up on
you, see how you were doing.
I'm fine.
I guess you are.
He hasn't responded
to the medication at all?
I'm afraid not.
So, that means he's
got the other thing?
I'm so sorry. We'll start
him on anti-inflammatories.
If we're lucky, that will
slow down the progression.
My son has a death sentence,
and I can't go in there and
be with him because of you.
I'm sorry.
You find a homework assignment
and decide he's suicidal,
make it your own
personal mission.
I let my feelings...
Oh, don't you dare apologize.
Like it could absolve you
of what you've done
to me, my family.
He was fine.
I understand why you're angry.
But this isn't where
you belong right now.
He won't let us in the room.
He's a teenager,
you're his mother.
This is not the time
to start listening to him.
Go be with him.
Thank you.
I didn't do it for you.
We made a mistake.
No, we didn't.
The methadone is good for him.
The methadone is gonna kill him.
He shaved. He was wearing a tie.
He has a meeting
at St. Sebastian.
If he buys a new pair of shoes,
should we let him smoke crack?
Cuddy, he's happy.
House doesn't do
happy, pain or no pain.
Okay, maybe.
But he's our friend,
and this is his one
chance to not be miserable.
The heels, very nice.
No reason not to wear
them now that House is gone.
You okay?
Yeah. Just tired.
Got some good news.
The patient's scleroderma is
responding to the anti-inflammatory meds.
His AST level has dropped a bit.
So, he's dying slightly
less quickly than we thought.
That's great news.
I'm not okay.
Next time, just say that.
What's his AST?
185, I think.
That's a pretty fast drop.
Are we sure it's from
the anti-inflammatories?
What else could it be from? He's
been off the antibiotics for a while.
Proton pump
inhibitors wouldn't...
He's back on testosterone.
Testosterone wouldn't
help his liver function.
But it could improve
his kidney function,
which would also lower his AST.
But not in kidneys
damaged by scleroderma.
Which means it's
not scleroderma.
I have an interview
in two hours.
Wow.
Hand over my letter
of recommendation.
Sorry, I haven't done it yet.
You have no right to sabotage...
I was busy with this.
It's a list of requirements
for your methadone treatment.
Weekly drug tests, supervised doses
administered on a precise schedule,
by me or one of the nurses.
Seems weird,
getting my meds here,
when I'm working somewhere else.
Yes.
I'm offering you your job back.
I want a raise.
No.
And a bigger office,
but in the same spot.
No.
We both know this
is where you belong.
Okay.
Welcome back.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
You okay?
I have issues with
authority. You?
We thought you were gone.
Cuddy missed me.
And what happened to your cane?
She asked to borrow
it for some reason.
Patient dead, or do I
need to do anything?
He's got scleroderma.
It's not scleroderma.
Wow, two days and you've
already got two separate theories.
You're back. Good.
We noticed a drop in AST levels.
It's not from the
anti-inflammatory.
It's because his kidneys got
better from the testosterone.
Which rules out scleroderma.
When did you two
come up with this?
We ran into each
other in the lobby.
So, what'd we miss?
When I say "we," I mean
you, since I wasn't here.
We've ruled out
Zollinger-Ellison.
That was a dumb idea.
Why? Because it was wrong.
Also Toxoplasmosis, dehydration,
SLE, various intersex disorders.
Oh, crap.
Does this kid like
energy drinks?
I saw some empty bottles
in the team's locker room.
But energy drinks
don't explain...
Nice work.
So, we're okay?
Why wouldn't we be?
Nice heels.
This is all your parents' fault.
Excuse me?
You chug a lot of energy drinks
before, during and after practice?
Your son came in here
with simple dehydration.
That's why he collapsed
during the game.
The ER treated him for
that. It didn't help the pain.
That's where the
energy drinks came in.
They put a strain
on his kidneys,
so he needed more time to
rebound from the initial dehydration.
Then why isn't he better?
That's where your
idiocy came in.
Before we could give
him another glass of water,
you two insisted I do an MRI.
So, I go down a blind alley,
looking for a blind uterus,
and my team injects
him with contrast material.
If his kidneys had been healthy,
he would've filtered out the
contrast in a couple of hours.
Since they weren't, it
went around and around,
eventually getting absorbed by
his heart, his liver and his pancreas,
getting in trouble
everywhere it went.
Your son was fine
when he got here.
It was your freaked-out
over-protectiveness that nearly killed him.
Nearly?
He's young. A few weeks
of dialysis, he should be fine.
You gave birth to
a freak of nature,
doesn't mean it's a good
idea to treat him like one.
How are you feeling?
A little bit better.
I saw you talking to your
parents earlier, that's good.
My mom asked if I wanted
to take dance lessons.
That's great.
I'm actually worried I
might miss basketball.
I was starting to get good.
No reason you can't do both.
Starting tomorrow, you'll
come to my office for your fix.
I'm done with the methadone.
I screwed up.
The kid's parents
wanted that MRI.
I knew he didn't
need it. I did it anyway.
That's what got him sick.
You just solved a case
that no one else could solve.
I created a case.
I played nice because I was in a
good mood because it didn't hurt.
You don't need your
pain to be a good doctor.
I'm not interested in good.
You're afraid to be happy.
Why do you care if I'm happy?
You're afraid of change. The
one thing you have is your intellect.
You think if that's
compromised, you have nothing.
Just take it.
No.
Don't do this.
It's already done.
This is the only me you get.