- Previously on The Resident...
- This new neurosurgeon,
- Dr. Cain.
- Do you know how much he bills?
$80 million a year.
Dr. Voss bills $2 million.
Stick with me, and
we will rise together.
Sky's the limit for men like us.
Looked up my birth parents.
- Where are they now?
- Right here in Atlanta.
Three grown-ass kids. The
ones they didn't give away.
I want to start talking
about moving in.
Let me do this at my own pace.
I just only have one request.
I really want those chickens.
No chickens.
♪ We got the same blood ♪
♪ The same blood ♪
♪ Stay by your
side, it's ride or die ♪
♪ We've got the same blood ♪
♪ It's ride or
die, we've got... ♪
Good morning.
I'm Dr. Bell.
We spoke on the phone.
I thought you said
there would be cameras.
There will be.
But I'm-I'm just here today
to go over the surgery.
Okay.
Come on in.
Dale, Reggie, we are so excited
that you're entrusting Chastain
with this life-changing
separation surgery.
We've always been
joined at the hip.
Side by side every
day of our lives.
To be honest, the idea
of not having my brother
right next to me is a little...
scary.
I don't know what
it would be like
-to sleep without
this jerk - this jerk
- snoring in my ear.
- Snoring in my ear.
After surgery, you can decide
how much togetherness you want.
How dangerous is it?
- For Reggie and Dale?
- June,
he already said
the risk is minor.
This is true.
Because the connection
is relatively superficial.
I love you.
Reggie, Dale,
the two of you are
the loves of my life.
And you are my everything.
My whole heart.
Boys, we can figure this all out
after the surgery.
You both can have
your own girlfriend.
Isn't that right, Dr. Bell?
If that's what they want.
You don't seem happy about this.
We want to know
what you really think.
- Talk to us.
If you two want this surgery,
I'll be there for you.
But to be totally honest,
I think our love is like
a three-legged stool.
Remove a leg, and I'm afraid
we're gonna tip right over.
Uh, this is a bigger decision
- than just one girl.
- Would you like to speak
to some separated twins?
No, thank you.
We're sorry for wasting your
time, but the surgery is off.
- Permanently.
What are you thinking about?
I'm ready. Let's
move in together.
Mmm. Absolutely.
Mmm, mmm, as soon as possible.
Mwah.
I just wish we could get that
house that you showed me
when you first
started talking about it.
- It was so right for us.
- Mm, in this market,
somebody probably
already took it.
- Yeah.
- But we both have
great places now.
I could move into yours or
you could move into mine.
- Are those our only options?
- No, they're just the quickest.
This place is rent-controlled.
And I've clearly nailed
the urban chic look.
It's just not very private.
Mm, a short walk to work.
Yeah. How's the ankle?
I don't think you're gonna be
walking to work anytime soon.
Is that your way of saying
we should live at your place?
No, actually...
After everything...
- It's been a rough year.
- Yeah.
I just think it might be
nice to have a fresh start.
You know? Something
that's ours together.
Boarding Flight 416...
Now, Dawn, your doctor told you
you have cancer of the appendix,
which is a very rare,
aggressive form of cancer.
So he basically said just
go home and give up hope.
Yeah, he did.
But I can't do that.
I have seven beautiful kids.
I want you all to take
a look at these pictures.
- Take a look.
- Aw.
Dawn is a single
mom of seven kids
that she adopted through
the foster care program.
My kids need me.
So, I did my research,
and it turns out,
there is something
- that could buy me
precious time.
- And what's that?
They call it "the
Mother of All Surgeries."
No doctor will do it.
12 hospitals
turned her down. 12.
They say the odds are too lon.
But I am ready to fight, Montel.
I just need a surgeon
brave enough to help me.
Yeah, you can see we
all want this for you, Dawn.
- Right?
- Yes.
- We want this for your family.
- Thank you.
And that's why today
you're gonna meet a surgeon
who not only has the
courage but also has the skills
to do the Mother
of All Surgeries.
Ladies and gentlemen, from
Chastain Memorial Hospital,
please welcome
Dr. Barrett Cain to the show.
Dawn, will you let me
fight this cancer with you?
You're the answer to my prayers.
Dr. Damn He's Hot can
operate on me any day.
Mmm, mmm-mmm-mmm.
♪ ♪
- What's this?
- Cool hundred if you make
the next one in.
Save it for Augusta.
Yeah, that's where
the big money is.
Just hang onto it and
let me, uh, put it toward
a healthier wager
on a real course.
I'm sure word must
have gotten to you by now
that I've brought in the Mother
of All Surgeries to Chastain.
Yeah, about that, um...
typically the chief of surgery
decides whether to take on
a high-risk, low-reward
surgery like that one.
Typically, I'm not used to
having someone vet my choices.
This one's
newsworthy, it's splashy.
This would be great
publicity for Chastain.
Greater than separating
conjoined twins.
Not if Chastain turns those
seven adorable foster children
- into orphans.
- I guarantee
that will not happen.
That is not a guarantee
you should make.
This surgery is
hardly that simple.
It's a brutal procedure.
It's like ten abdominal
surgeries rolled into one.
You're worrying too much.
The cancer has already
infiltrated her spine.
So, even if the
cancer is in end-stage,
the woman can die in a
week, even without the surgery.
Now, on the off chance
she gains no more time...
Or she dies on the table...
We gave a mother and
her seven kids hope.
We took a moon shot that
no other hospital would.
So, regardless of the
outcome, we're heroes.
Which is actually why I
came to see you today.
I am assembling a
team of the very best.
Which means you,
as my cocaptain...
we share in the
publicity and in the glory.
- Or the blame.
- You know, Randolph,
I actually took you
for a gambling man.
The PR payout on
this is off the charts.
What's the problem?
Stakes too high for you?
If we do this, we
could be fired.
If we don't, then I'm quitting.
Is this the breaking and
entering stage of grief?
Maybe.
- You backing out?
- No.
They say it's better
to ask for forgiveness...
Than permission.
Hey. Give me a
shot of cortisone.
What's wrong? Physical
therapy isn't helping?
No, it's helping, but
it's just a long process.
I need a little help
getting through today.
Hmm. No.
As in N-O, not a chance in hell.
Pain is the body's
warning system.
Mask it and what happens?
You can push yourself too
hard and hurt yourself again.
But I'm a doctor,
so I won't do that.
Here's my answer:
acetaminophen, ice, elevation.
Now, come on, I'll walk
you down to PT... ignore that.
Sorry.
I will find you, Conrad.
I know where you work.
- Traitor.
- It's a rotation
in the oncology service.
Everyone does rotations.
Yeah, but it's breaking
my heart to think of you
in anything but
eye-catching green scrubs.
Ow. ♪ Babe magnet. ♪
He's leaving us to roll in chemo
cash. That is not attractive.
It's, you know,
it's, it's betrayal.
Tumor biology has fascinated me
since my publication
in JAMA Oncology.
- You know that.
- Yeah, yeah, well, try
to remember us little people
down here saving lives
without kickbacks from pharma.
- Thank you.
- Thanks.
I'm so glad you could
make it for lunch.
Adaku, it's been ages.
The photos you've been
posting look amazing,
but it's impossible to keep
track of where you've been.
Kyoto, New Zealand, Norway.
Okay, please don't tell me
that this trip was
some sort of bucket list.
I'm not dying.
I've never felt more alive.
I beat breast cancer.
Thank goodness.
I was on a... babymoon.
I'm pregnant.
Aren't you gonna say something?
What do you want me to say?
"I'm happy for you, Adaku.
You've wanted to be a
mother your entire life"?
- What did your oncologist say?
- "Congratulations"?
This is not a joke, Adaku.
Have you been
following her advice?
Completely.
She told me to extract
eggs before chemo, so I did.
She told me to wait
until after chemo
until we knew that I was
cancer-free to get pregnant.
And you did all of this without
telling me? Your best friend?
I didn't want to tell you,
because I knew
you'd say don't do it.
Have my ovaries and
tubes removed. It's safer.
BRCA1 mutation is definitely
linked to ovarian cancer.
Is it so awful that
I want you safe?
I am safe. I am healthy.
I am fit as a fiddle.
They said you were
free of breast cancer
before you got pregnant, right?
That was also before your
trip, so months ago now.
I have a friend in oncology
who can check to make
sure there's nothing worrisome
on your ovaries either.
Will you just go with
me for a quick test?
To... put my troubled
mind at ease?
Yes, dear Mina,
I can do that.
Yes, yes, yes.
We get this once a month.
It's me and you, baby.
Doughnut holes
are my preference.
Baker's dozen.
Glazed, chocolate, jelly.
Finish with the powder.
I like to get my hands dirty
in my work and my baked goods,
but I do not dunk.
That's me.
Speaking of me, I am...
I know who you are.
There were photos of you
in the files e-mailed to me
by the adoption agency.
You are my egg
donor's sperm donor.
"Biological father"
works just as well.
Ah, the word "father"
in any capacity
is reserved for the
man who raised me.
Come on, dawg.
I-I-In what world did ambushing
me like this make sense?
I have my reasons.
Now, you can either hear me out
or do your damnedest
to chase me off.
Don't push my buttons,
or I will push back and I
will decimate your buttons.
You gonna play
fair, I can take it.
But you cross a
line, I will defend
with a tongue just
as keen as yours.
We are grown-ass men now.
And I am here to talk to you
about grown-ass men things.
Half your genes come from me,
and I'm dying.
Make an appointment.
It's hereditary.
Which means you
might be dying, too.
If you're experiencing
immediate pain,
come to the front.
Otherwise, take a seat
and we'll be right with you.
Everett Dobb.
Executive director of
the transformation team.
- Transformation team?
- I facilitate
a smooth operational shift
between the old and new regimes,
Chastain and Red Rock, by
managing the golden triangle
of patient safety, access,
- and cost.
- Well, that's a mouthful.
We did a cost-benefit
analysis and closed this clinic.
I'm not clear what
you're doing here,
- but you're trespassing.
- Well, Chastain
has an obligation to provide
health care for those in need.
We are a nonprofit
hospital and tax-exempt,
so it's a legal requirement.
An obligation we fulfill
by treating the
uninsured in our ER.
I'm not sure it's considered
charity when you're turning them
into collections and docking
paychecks when they can't pay.
All of which is in alignment
with our core value
of fiscal responsibility
and... I might point
out... Is totally legal.
You, on the other
hand, broke the law.
I can have you arrested
for breaking and entering.
If you close the clinic,
Chastain could very well
lose its nonprofit status,
ending the tax break
and saddling the hospital
with a bill for
millions of dollars.
We won't be
audited for two years.
Empty this place and vacate now,
or I will call the police.
I know you already know this,
but Dr. Grisham is going to
do a transvaginal ultrasound.
It'll allow us to check
your reproductive organs
for any signs of cancer.
Remember, don't get
distracted by the fetus.
Just make sure her
ovaries look normal.
I love her, but she's bossy.
I love her because she's bossy.
Never say that again.
Okay, guys, we're
ready to start.
I'll be outside if you need me.
Grisham's the best
and always busy.
Thanks for getting us in.
No worries.
She's lucky to have you.
But, Mina, don't
scare her off too much.
Let her enjoy being pregnant.
I've watched too many women,
particularly women of color,
be harmed because no
one was looking out for them.
You know that as well as anyone.
I hear you.
But Adaku's getting great care,
and she's done everything right.
Her dream of becoming
a mother is coming true.
Except the pregnancy hormones
might bring her cancer back
or increase the risk
of ovarian cancer.
I'm afraid of losing her.
I know.
Triple negative
breast cancer is scary.
But we understand
more about it every day.
And now we can analyze tumor DNA
and know that
Adaku is less likely
to respond to
pregnancy hormones.
It won't increase her
risk of reoccurrence.
Your fear is understandable
but groundless.
I promise.
I got to go.
Keep me posted, okay?
Thank you.
Lamar gave me full access
to his medical
file, and it indicates
his emphysema's in early stages.
So he's not dying?
No.
He does have the alpha-1
antitrypsin deficiency.
Which can lead to end-stage
lung disease over time
but nothing imminent.
Exactly.
So now I'm gonna draw some blood
and see if you have
the deficiency as well.
Why would he show
up and lie like that?
I don't know, to
get the attention
of the child he gave away?
Yeah, but why?
I think there's more to
the story than you know.
You think?
Initial diagnosis.
Biology's a huge bitch, man.
I mean, Lamar rolls up on me
with my walk, my talk.
I never met the man, but
it's obvious we share DNA.
Yeah, well, I struggled to
give my dad a second chance
for a lot of reasons.
But then, when I
decided to let him in a bit,
I discovered some things,
some good things about him
I wouldn't have known
if I'd just shut him out.
Well, you and your dad were
estranged, but he raised you.
You had a foundation.
This man gave me away.
He married my biological
mom, had three more kids,
full siblings to me,
and none of 'em
cared to look me up.
Until now.
I am very excited to consult
on the Mother of All Surgeries.
The cancer has spread from
her appendix to her colon,
ovaries, gall bladder,
kidneys, and peritoneum.
It's hard to believe
it's even operable.
- It isn't.
- One opinion.
I'll remove any visible
tumor I see, meticulously,
even if it means
taking the entire organ.
Then the cavity will be filled
with hot chemo;
we'll bathe them.
Scalding-hot chemo.
107 degrees.
Enough to burn or destroy
any microscopic
cells that remain.
But still won't touch
the lesion wrapped
around her spinal column,
with a pathological fracture.
Which is why you're an
essential part of the surgery.
I'm assuming you'll be
taking the anterior approach
to the spinal lesions?
I won't be doing a damn thing.
The cancer is too
widespread and too aggressive.
The only acceptable
approach here is hospice.
This is a high-profile case.
There's a family counting on us.
And we will fail them.
If so much as a cell, one
cell of tumor is missed,
which we know will happen,
the cancer will grow back
before the patient even recovers
from this barbaric surgery.
I'm gonna make sure this
poor woman understands that.
Malia, Malia, Malia,
Malia, grab him.
- Oh.
- Hello, darling.
You don't want to go out there.
It's much nicer in
here with Mummy.
So, guys, hey, listen up.
These are the doctors
that are gonna be helping
Dr. Cain save Mom.
- Can you say hey?
- You're gonna save Mom?
Oh.
Yeah. Hey, you know, I
heard that the cafeteria's having
kind of a special on ice
cream sundaes today.
Maybe you could go down
there and tell them Dr. Bell said
to have a treat on him.
Ice cream! Yay!
Shh!
Quiet, bunnies.
All right.
Hop, hop, hop.
Hop, hop, hop,
hop, hop, hop, hop,
hop, hop, hop, hop.
They're quite the handful.
Malia should be
in college right now.
I have to get better so
I can take over again.
Dawn, would you mind
telling me what you understand
about your prognosis?
I understand everything.
In the best-case
scenario, this isn't a cure.
There is only a slim hope
this will buy you more time.
I'll take it.
And do you also understand
that it's far more likely
that you'll have less
time with your children?
This surgery is so dangerous,
y-you may not survive.
I'm dying anyway.
The odds may be long
that this will help, but
I want to beat them.
And I want to help you, but...
No buts.
I will do anything,
against any odds,
to stay with my kids
as long as I can.
I can't give up.
I still don't think there's
a chance that surgery
is going to give that
poor woman more time.
I have spoken to her at length,
and she understands that.
Yeah, she seems
perfectly aware of the lunacy
that is the Mother
of All Surgeries.
And in the end,
it's her decision.
Well, exactly, and she is
gonna have this surgery
with or without Chastain.
After her last TV appearance,
other hospitals tried
to poach her case.
They're less qualified,
and they don't have you.
Don't worry, I'm in.
But not because I agree.
But because I'm gonna
make good and damn well sure
that Dawn makes
it off that table alive
and wakes up to have
as many days as possible
with her children.
The clinic costs Chastain
money, end of story.
I have graphs and charts that
show it actually saves money
by diverting the uninsured...
Your charts don't include
infrastructure costs.
And besides, what
matters most is income.
With surgeons who
bill $80 million a year
and do TV interviews.
What benefits the bottom
line benefits everyone.
So now it's profit and
publicity over patients.
You forget yourself. I
care as much as you do
about our patients.
Everything I do,
including publicity,
is for profits and patients,
because you can't have
one without the other.
And by the way, I don't
owe you an explanation.
These are all 3-D printed
exact replicas of
Dawn's anatomy.
I downloaded all the data
from Dawn's 2-D scans
and images into the computer,
then the brain machine combines
all that information
and prints it out.
And these tiny little
bumps on the kidneys...
Are tumors.
I only see three or so,
but I feel at least seven more.
It's part of the reason this
surgery is so complicated.
We'll wear gloves and
feel for tumors, inch by inch,
through the entire
abdominal cavity.
It'll take hours and
there is no room for error.
Which is why you're practicing.
Over and over.
This is my third go and I still
haven't managed to remove
the vertebral body
without compromising
the iliac artery, which is
plastered to it by the tumor.
"Fake Dawn" has
bled out every time.
Come on, Pravesh.
Spread the cavity.
If the corpectomy
is causing problems, should
we get Cain in here to rehearse?
He thinks it's unnecessary.
Bell didn't RSVP either.
And believe me, this is not a
surgery that can be improvised.
You like that car?
It's hideous.
I designed it.
Frame-off restoration
built with these hands.
It's my passion.
It's what keeps me honest.
Does it?
That's funny,
because you certainly
didn't keep it honest with me.
You knew you weren't
dying, neither am I.
There is no alpha-1
deficiency here, so I'm good, yo.
Well, that's what you
wanted to hear, right?
You wanted to know if I
was perfectly healthy, right?
Well, yes, of course,
but I thought...
You thought what, Lamar?
If you are my son...
that the odds were you
would carry the gene.
If?
Wow, you don't know.
That's why you came.
What, you thought maybe Bio-Mom
was sleeping around
when she got pregnant?
Is that why you gave me away?
Because you thought I
wasn't yours to begin with?
I may not have raised you,
but I'm not gonna stand here
and have you disrespect me.
Well, then you
sit your ass down,
or you get the hell out of here.
This is my house,
Lamar. You do not dictate
to me how I speak to
someone I have no respect for.
We were young. It was the '70s.
And yes, there is a
possibility that you aren't mine.
It sickens me to say
that all I have to do
is look at you...
and know who my father is.
A proper DNA test will prove it.
I can't change what we did.
And apologizing
- is not gonna make any...
- When did you apologize?!
Let me speak!
I wish we could go back
and make things right.
It's something that eats at
your mother and me every day.
That's why my
marriage is in shambles.
- And my life is on the verge
of imploding.
- Your life?
Man, think about who
you're talking to right now.
Do you think I give a rat's
ass about your struggles?
Is that what you really want
to talk to me about right now?
- You want to speak? Answer me!
- I can't...
S-Something ain't right.
Hey, hey! I need
some help over here!
Watch his head.
Put him down gently.
Let him down gently.
I'll get a gurney.
Good news.
No sign of cancer
on your ovaries.
- I wasn't worried.
- I was.
And I know I worry too
much, but it's only because...
You love me. I get it.
But I'm okay.
You can relax now.
Especially knowing
that there is a silver lining
to all of this.
Since you implanted
your embryos,
you were able to test them
for the BRCA gene mutation
and select one without it.
You did... select an embryo
that didn't carry the mutation?
Oh, no. Please...
Uh, what I've done
is my decision, Mina.
This is my life.
It's not only yours, Adaku.
It's also the life
of your child.
This awful disease killed
your mother and your sisters.
With one test, you could have
protected your child from it.
I will not play God.
God answered my
prayers. He delivered me
- from breast cancer.
- I got you through
breast cancer.
I brought my mother from Nigeria
to come and operate on you.
And I am so grateful.
But I also see
God's hand in that.
Then why not see his
hand in genetic testing?
Science froze your embryos,
medicine got you pregnant.
Without doctors, you
would have no baby.
You wanted me to
get an oophorectomy.
If I followed your
advice, I'd have no baby.
And now, all you're doing is,
is judging me,
trying to control me.
I am doing all of
this to help you.
Can't you see I don't
want your help, Mina.
I have to go.
It's an emergency. Somebody
who does need my help.
We will pick this up later.
I think it's better if we don't.
This is all...
it's too much for me, Mina.
Goodbye.
What's this?
Oh, this is Dawn's
spinal column,
with the tumor adhesions
that make it impossible
to remove the cancer
without killing the patient.
Something you would know
had you bothered to attend
even one of my rehearsals.
Your energy and your tone aside,
I admire you, Dr. Voss.
Your compulsive
need to practice,
it speaks to an obsession
with the precise
anatomy of the disease.
And I get it. I get it,
because the better
you know your enemy
before you meet
face-to-face on the battlefield...
the better chance
you have of victory.
Oh, you do realize her
seven children are out there
praying to God that
this surgery works,
having no idea that there
is zero chance for victory.
This surgery will kill her.
I used to be just like
you before I realized that
all plans go out the
window when the war begins.
Sounds like an
excuse not to prepare.
I get my head right with
my own pre-op ritual,
in which you... are
currently interrupting.
So if you'll excuse yourself,
I'd like to get back to it,
because Malia, Timmy, Dani,
Tunde, Katie, Rosa and Arjun
are all counting on me...
Not God, but me...
To bring my A game and
save their mother's life.
♪ ♪
Hey.
Verdict on your bio-father?
Recent cath showed
triple vessel disease.
And now he has diffuse
ischemic changes.
Who's doing the bypass?
Sieve and Schoneveld
are available.
They're Red Rock guys.
Do we know anything about them?
So far, none of the
new hires are up to snuff.
Forget these Red Rock surgeons.
You should do the surgery.
Lamar is his biological father.
Even more reason to
give him the best surgeon.
Who is one without baggage.
You've told me if I had
an emotional
attachment to a patient,
not to operate. Are
you a hypocrite?
Regardless of
emotional attachments,
you are his best
chance at survival.
I got to get my
head on straight.
Get all the emotion out of this.
You got bad news
written all over your face.
Now what could be worse
than three clogged arteries?
The decision I have to
make in the next ten minutes.
I am the right surgeon
to fix your heart,
but you are not
just any patient.
Who you are and what transpired
between us plays in my mind
and very well could
infect these hands.
I am an overachiever.
Gifted with a competitive
nature and a need to excel
from as young as I can remember.
I collected academic awards
like other kids
collected baseball cards.
Spelling bee, debate
team, Eagle Scout, aikido...
You name it, I mastered it.
I had an addiction.
This deep-rooted
need to conquer all.
You see, there's this tiny voice
deep inside of me
that cannot be silenced,
who always thought, "Maybe...
"maybe if they knew
you were special,
"that... that maybe...
Mom and Dad would come
knocking on that front door."
Realize what they gave away.
And that I was something
worth fighting to get back.
You most certainly are.
♪ ♪
I'll see you in the OR.
It's been over eight hours.
Whose playlist is up next?
Sound of the drill works for me.
Once we're finished,
Cain can work.
Then we still have
to do the chemo bath.
If she's under anesthesia
too much longer,
she'll never wake up.
This tumor's eroded
through the bone entirely.
I've dissected as much as I can
off the iliac and
lumbosacral plexus,
but the arterial wall
has been compromised.
Time to pull.
Slow and steady.
One moment.
Got it.
Deep breath worked the magic?
Picturing her kids watching
me, hopeful. That's the magic.
You ready for me yet?
- All yours, Dr. Cain.
- It's about time.
Get the microscope in place.
I need somatosensory and
motor EPs on the screen.
Foot and a half from
lead position. Eye level.
A little room.
We're gonna double-check
everything in the abdomen
once you've finished to
make sure we've got it.
How much longer?
- Two more hours?
- Nope. Won't take that long.
I need some curettes,
couple of sutures,
and some Megadeth
on the jukebox.
Spine surgeries beg
for headbanging tunes.
Is that irony?
Dissecting the tumor
off the dural sac.
Gonna need you to
put some pressure
right there, Dr. Voss.
I know heavy equipment
is Ortho's thing,
but you're here on the
delicate side, so be gentle.
♪ ♪
♪ She had to know... ♪
That's it. Onc intern,
get that chemo bath ready.
You're gonna need it a lot
sooner than these guys thought.
♪ ♪
- So how did it go?
- I'm fine, yo.
I don't believe you.
Well, I'm fine enough
to do the surgery.
But even if I'm wrong,
you'll be there,
and I know I can
always count on you,
my partner.
I know everyone at Chastain
did everything they could to
give my mom every chance,
and I just want
to thank you guys.
Can you tell us how Dawn
is doing after surgery?
Well, the hours that
we spent preparing
for the surgery
have paid dividends.
Still, Dawn has endured
17 hours of surgery.
Her body is
struggling to recover.
She hasn't regained
consciousness and as yet,
isn't able to
breathe on her own.
When is she gonna wake up?
While we don't know for
certain, we're very optimistic.
And, Dr. Cain, I just want
to thank you for giving
my family hope when
no one else would.
We may be witnessing a
medical miracle in progress.
Let's all pray for Dawn
and give our gratitude to
this amazing team of doctors
still fighting to save her.
We'll be following
Dawn and Malia's story
over the next few weeks.
It's families like this,
bonding together in crisis,
that inspire us all.
You crashed here last night?
Yeah. Surgery was long.
My "Mother of All Surgeries"
patient was just on TV,
and I wanted to catch
it before heading home.
Barely made it out of surgery.
They're calling it a success.
Well, family's still together.
Maybe that's enough, right?
I don't know, man.
You know, my first
day at Chastain,
I was planning on
going into oncology.
Mm, but then the infamous
Lane Hunter came along.
Well, she was an anomaly.
Criminal, psychopath.
I mean, the majority
of oncologists
are caring people
dedicated to saving lives.
When the treatment cures
the patient, that's one thing,
but what may help one patient
will harm or even kill another,
often without any benefit.
It's impossible to know
where your patient will fall
on that spectrum before
you start treating them.
That's why, sometimes,
I miss being a medic
with the patrol units
downrange. That job was clear.
We could be proud of what
we did every day. No gray areas.
But...
all this
corporatized medicine,
profit over patients,
I guess I just look at it as a
different kind of battlefield.
One where we need
to keep showing up,
keep fighting, keep
making a difference.
No matter what the
odds are against us.
Yeah.
Big-time oncologist
just couldn't stay away, huh?
My toe! Oh, my
God, I need a doctor!
Looks like things got
out of control without me.
Bed 4, perfect for you.
You'll want a wardrobe
change and some gloves.
What's the bullet?
Patient's been
stopped up for weeks.
Disimpaction time.
I'm on it.
Watch out, she's a biter.
I can never thank you
enough. Thank you.
Oh, you're more than welcome.
Seriously, people
need to know about it.
- Just excuse me for a second.
- Yeah.
I am so impressed with
what you guys are doing here.
I'm telling you, the world
needs to know about this.
Well, thank you so
much. I appreciate it.
Especially at a time
right now where...
Dr. Bell.
Nurse Nevin has been
telling me about the clinic.
I was just saying
how invested you are
in our service to the uninsured.
How you care about
all of our patients,
not just the big
newsworthy cases.
I'm telling you, Dr. Bell,
- he's one of the good ones.
- Well, as a nonprofit,
charity work is an essential
part of Chastain's mission.
You know, I can
see the segment now:
"World-renowned surgeon
makes time for the disadvantaged."
You in?
- Just say when.
- Come on now.
Thank you, sir.
- And thank you.
- Thank you.
Yes, ma'am.
Let's go.
Neat trick.
It won't work again.
I made this for the baby.
Is this your apology?
I can't apologize for wishing
you'd done genetic testing,
but it is your choice,
and I am sorry I
did not respect that.
Thank you.
Come in. I'm filling
out my baby registry.
Do you think I need
a baby bouncy?
I have no idea what that is.
Me either, but we can
figure it out together, yes?
Sounds awful, but I can't think
of anything else I'd rather do.
Aw.
On three. One, two,
three.
What?
How did you get this place?
Dumb luck or karma. It just
came back on the market.
Whatever it is, I'm so
happy we're here now.
Ah.
When you brought
me here the first time,
it's just I had so much
going on, you know?
And you still do,
but we will get
through it all together.
I know.
♪ It's a shakedown... ♪
Are you sure right now is the
right time to make this move?
I've never been so sure.
♪ All my blood keeps me up ♪
- I love you.
- I love you, too.
And I love this house.
Well, get ready to love it more.
♪ I'm believing
in the change... ♪
Ta-da!
Oh, my God!
- We have chickens.
- Oh!
Wow!
♪ Ooh-ooh, ooh-ooh ♪
♪ Ooh... ♪
Engine still purring
like a '69 Firebird?
Incision is healing well.
Your heart function
and rhythm sounds
within normal range.
Your cardiologist can
manage your recovery.
- Good luck.
- Wait.
♪ I'll be your safe
and sound... ♪
Don't go. Please.
My mind and mouth
move at the same time.
I act before I think
things through all the way.
Character flaw.
I'm working on it.
I did what I did
and I want to do better.
If you can't forgive, I
have to live with that.
But my wife, your mother,
is better than me in every way.
She never would've messed
things up the way I did.
♪ Dark clouds, it's
a shakedown... ♪
I wouldn't know.
My hope is that
you'll reach out to her,
when you're ready.
She's truly special,
like you.
Goodbye, Lamar.
♪ Ooh, ooh. ♪
Captioned by Media
Access Group at WGBH