♪ Ohhh ohhh ohhh ♪
Cooper, get out.
Oh, you look incredible.
You're not supposed
to see me yet.
I think...
I-I think it's a mistake
for us to do this.
Hey. You okay?
What's going on?
Are you
worried about something?
Are you getting
pre-wedding jitters?
You gonna jilt Cooper
at the altar?
Because I will drive
the getaway vehicle,
no questions asked.
I am not jilting, Coop.
It's just, weddings mean family,
and our families...
Look, my mama is
a straight-up southern belle,
which means
she's charming, judgmental,
and not afraid
to self-medicate.
Imagining her
with the freedmans...
And if they're anything like
their son,
they'll want to hug her
and kiss her
and whine about how there aren't
any good delis in Los Angeles.
You know, sometimes
when you have those
"worlds collide" situations,
they actually turn out okay.
And sometimes they end
with a giant fireball
that consumes
everything around 'em.
Well, how much time do they
have to spend together
before the wedding?
Cooper and I thought
we could limit it to a dinner.
Is there anything
I can do to help?
Plan the dinner.
Oh. Okay. Uh, I was really
just asking to be polite,
but you really want me
to do it?
I just figured, if you're
gonna be my maid of honor...
Wait. What? Really? Me?
We're junkies together. That
makes us b.F.F.S in my book.
And Cooper has Violet
as his best man.
He keeps saying I need someone
to stand up with me,
so I would very much like you
to be my maid of honor.
Just don't forget to bring
your fire extinguisher.
Can I help you?
I'm Dr. Violet Turner.
I was told you were the medical
investigator on my case.
Did we have an appointment
for today?
No. No, I just... I thought
we could take a few moments
to talk about Katie Kent.
Dr. Turner--
I mean, this whole thing has
been blown out of proportion,
and I-I wanted to tell my side
of the story, and you'll see--
I-I think we can avoid
wasting everyone's time
on any kind
of formal investigation.
We have a protocol,
and I'm obligated to follow it.
Please hear me out.
As long as you understand
that whatever you tell me
will in no way
limit the investigation
we've already opened
into your case
and can also be used
as the basis
for further inquiries.
Ready when you are.
Hey.
I didn't know
you were back.
Uh, how was Africa?
It was good.
It was really good.
Yeah? You look amazing.
Are you--
i'm--i'm--I'm late
for a meeting. Hi.
Hey. Welcome back,
na--
yeah.
Omi.
She hates me.
Well, she's not too crazy
about me, either.
So, uh...
Are we still agreed?
You don't have to
keep asking me that.
Well, I just don't want
things to be awkward
for Charlotte and Cooper.
It's not gonna be,
all right?
We're not gonna tell anybody
we're broken up.
We're gonna go
to the wedding together,
and then afterwards, we're
gonna tell everybody that--
we're still friends. Okay.
You're gonna get a call
from the medical board
investigating Violet.
I can't believe
it's this serious.
Well, believe.
They're gonna interview you.
Me?
You and I are the only other
doctors who treated Katie,
and I just got my call, so...
You really think
there's a chance
she could lose her license?
Yes.
But if we can help explain
what happened...
Just be very careful
when you answer their questions.
I know you're not asking me
to lie.
I'm asking you
to protect Violet.
I don't need
to be protected.
All the therapy
I did with Katie,
the--the attack, the trial,
the book--
I have nothing to hide,
and neither do you.
Miss me?
Gabriel,
what are you--
I heard your speech,
but I am confident
that eventually, you will
see the error of your ways,
and when you do,
I'll be here, waiting.
Where are you going?
I have a patient
in assisted living.
I'm making a house call.
There are laws
against stalking.
Oh, prison doesn't scare me.
Marion?
Hi. Did I forget
to tell you that I was coming?
Oh, I'm sure you didn't.
Uh, this is Dr. Fife.
He's a colleague of mine.
Why don't we give Marion
a-a minute?
I've never seen her
in anything other than a dress
with her hair and nails done,
which means she's being polite.
Wouldn't have mattered.
Is this you?
Yes, and my husband Jerome.
How long were you married?
Jerome died just before
our 51st anniversary.
Well, bet you can still
fit in that dress.
Marion, your glucose
is really high.
Have you been taking
your Insulin?
Oh, careful.
Is there something wrong?
Oh.
You're not yourself today,
Marion. Did something happen?
If you want to talk,
Dr. Fife can leave and--
oh, it doesn't matter.
You know, Marion,
there is a therapist
here on staff.
And I have two in my office.
You want me to talk
to so-some stranger
half my age,
tell 'em I'm sad,
and then listen to him
try to put things
in a perspective
he doesn't have?
I-I-It's just, that if
you're really sad, then--
we can zap the sadness out.
There's a procedure called
an anterior cingulotomy.
The neurosurgeon uses
a gamma knife
to destroy the parts of
the brain that cause depression.
Gabriel.
Oh. Listen, thank you both
for coming here.
I'll try to remember
the Insulin.
But I don't need shrinks
and I don't need knives.
I just need to be left alone.
Oh.
Hey, Cooper,
uh, this is, uh,
this is my lawyer,
Richard huvane.
Hello.
You went to speak with
Neal chaplin without me present?
What were you thinking?
I was thinking that if Katie
has dropped the lawsuit,
there's no reason for
the medical board to pursue it.
But they are pursuing it.
And now that they've opened
an investigation,
it doesn't matter
what she does.
Well, I...
I-I-I didn't say anything.
As soon as he brought out
the recorder, I left.
I'm gonna catch up
to you later, okay?
Look, I-I was just thinking
that if I could...
I talked to Pete
about it--
Pete is now a witness
in this investigation.
Are--are you saying
I need to be cautious
around my own husband?
You need to be cautious
around everyone.
It's your license
that's on the line.
The woman is probably just
depressed, and fife suggests
destroying part of her brain.
Well, if you invited him,
you should've known.
I did not invite him.
It's part of my strategy.
I did an anterior cingulotomy
back at Hopkins.
Pre-op, the man would not
even get out of bed.
Post-op, he was cooking dinner
for the entire neighborhood.
We gave him his life back.
So there.
But any surgery
on someone Marion's age
is gonna be rife
with potential complications,
including a stroke--
well, you have to be
brave enough to take that risk.
Actually, you're asking
the patient to take that risk,
which I'm not sure
makes you brave at all.
More importantly, Marion has
already made it clear
that she does not want
this surgery.
That's the depression talking.
It's clouding her judgment
and making her incapable
of an informed decision.
Depression doesn't necessarily
make someone incompetent.
Unless it does,
which makes this
kind of a catch-22.
I mean, we can't treat
her depression
if her depression is preventing
her from seeking treatment.
Marion shouldn't be
included in this.
What?
The disease determines
the cure, not the patient.
Listening to your patient,
working with them,
that's essential
to good doctoring.
Healing is essential
Amelia uses the gamma knife,
Marion will feel better.
It's a win-win.
No one is doing
any kind of cutting
until we determine
just how bad off Marion is.
Will you please
talk to her?
Sure.
Thank you.
What a lovely place
to work.
And, uh, saving the best
for last--
this is the office
of Dr. Charlotte king.
Violet,
you are funny as ever.
Oh.
Whoo-hoo.
Mom, what are you doing here?
Ooh.
Hi.
You told us to wait,
but you know your mother.
We were too excited,
so we came on over.
And then we saw Violet
in the elevator...
- Who has this amazing figure, even after having a baby.
- Yeah, yeah.
Yeah, I was just coming
to find you.
Uh, mom, dad,
um, this is Charlotte,
and this is her mother,
Augusta king.
It's a pleasure.
Hello.
Nice to meet you.
Well, isn't this great,
everybody finally meeting?
Hey, maybe I'll just show mama
around the rest of the office.
Oh, great idea. Um, why don't
you guys come with us? Go with--
actually, you know, your mother
and I are kind of hungry.
Oh, well, it's--
it's lunch time right about now.
Why don't you all go
to the promenade
and have lunch first?
That's a great idea.
And you'll be joining us, right?
Oh, well, i'm--I'm really
kind of busy.
Of course she's coming
with us.
Charlotte, I'd love to see
your office. Now.
Oh, but let's, uh...
Uh, lunch?
Another time.
Enjoy.
Well, I'm thinking deli,
but, uh,
I could be persuaded to try
something a little more risque.
Hey.
I keep running into fife
in the halls.
Is he, uh, working here
again or--
no, he just--he says he won't go
away until I agree to date him.
Wow.
I give him a 10
for perseverance.
So what do you rate him
for style?
You know what?
I have a bunch of research
I have to do, so...
Oh. Okay.
Okay.
Hey, Sam and I broke up.
I, uh...
I just thought
you should know.
Why?
Well, he wouldn't commit
to having a child with me
and I didn't want to wait--
no, I meant why--why are you
telling me this?
I mean, y--
you and I,
we're not exactly...
Look, Nai, there's been
this wall up between you and me
since Sam and I got together,
and I don't
want it there anymore.
I want my best friend back.
That's it?
You're not gonna say anything?
I hope it was worth it.
I told you, you should've
ordered the brisket.
I'm sorry. It's just,
um, just kind of a bad day.
But you know what?
I-I think I should go.
What, so soon?
Dad, enough. Let her go.
Well, the three of you
need time to catch up,
and, um, yeah, I'll see you
back at the office.
Fine.
Is everything okay
with Violet?
I swear, she didn't smile once
the whole meal.
She is... going through
a rough patch right now.
She'll be okay.
Well, I hope so.
She is such a good girl.
Is there anything
that we can do to help?
Yeah, how about worrying
a little less about Violet
and asking me
about my future wife?
Well, we introduced ourselves,
and then she and her mother
were gone.
Are you really surprised?
I mean, you completely shut down
when I introduced you.
Well, the mother
was pleasant enough.
But I did find Charlotte
to be a bit... cold.
Charlotte is not cold. It takes
a while to get to know her.
We know enough.
Oh, yeah? What's that
supposed to mean?
Cooper,
for the last few years,
your father and I
have listened to you--
every phone call,
every e-mail.
And do you know how many
of those were you being upset
about something Charlotte did?
Come on. Wait a minute.
That is not fair.
No, she's right, Coop. We went
through all of that with you--
the lying to the ex-husband,
sleeping with that Arthur--
- Archer.
- Oh, it doesn't matter.
The point is, she's hurt you,
more than once.
And we--we understand that
you're going to marry her, but--
but you can understand
why we can't exactly
open our arms to her and pretend
that nothing happened.
You're--you're my parents.
I was giving you one side
of the story.
There's lots of good stuff
about Charlotte
that I didn't tell you.
Well, I'm sure that's true,
but we love you, Cooper,
more than anything.
So anyone who hurts you...
Mm.
The chuppah
will be over here.
Uh, that's just
a little gazebo.
I know what a chuppah is,
darling.
It's the one concession
Cooper asked for.
It's important
for his parents.
Oh, his parents.
You know, Charlotte,
the freedmans
aren't those huggy, kissy,
in-your-face kind of people
you warned me about.
In fact,
they're a little cold.
You're right.
They were cold.
And the way they fawned
over that other doctor--
what's her name?
Violet.
You would think she was
the one marrying Cooper.
Cooper and Violet
are best friends.
His parents have known her
for a long time.
Best friends?
I suggest you do as I do
and try not to let that
get under your skin.
You listen, baby girl,
as your mother, I have to
tell you how it is,
and his parents
do not like you.
They barely know me.
Honey, they're not looking
to know you.
Mama.
No, look...
I bet they're out there
right now with Cooper
telling him that you are not
his kind of girl.
I highly doubt that.
I'm not saying
Cooper's gonna listen.
I'm just saying, you marry
a boy, you marry his family.
Just consider it a warning.
I can't
talk about this anymore.
I have to get
to my final dress fitting.
Oh, I can't wait
to see it on you.
I'm not doing anything.
Look, mama, you can come
to the fitting,
but the dress... it's not
gonna make you happy.
Did something happen to it
in the mail?
No, it arrived just fine,
but... I'm not wearing
the family dress.
Charlotte...
For a hundred years,
the women in our family
have worn that dress
when they took their vows.
Is this because of Cooper?
Has he talked you out
of wearing that dress?
Cooper doesn't know anything
about the dress.
Now listen to me, mama.
I wore the dress
when I married Billy,
and look where that got me.
That can't possibly be
the dress' fault.
Now I know you don't want
to do this,
but it's what big daddy
would've wanted.
And I know you don't want
to let him down.
Dr. Bennett
should leave well enough alone.
Well, Dr. Bennett doesn't feel
you are well enough.
That's why she asked me
to talk to you.
She's concerned
that you might be depressed.
She said she offered you
several treatment options,
but you didn't seem
to have any interest.
Well, that's my right,
isn't it?
Yes, but our goal
is to make you feel better.
And it's possible
that your illness
is standing in the way
of your ability to discern
what's best for you.
Dr. Wallace,
one day you'll be old.
You'll be old and then
eventually you'll be sick.
And then you'll be sad...
And lonely.
And sometimes, you won't want
to get out of bed
or be with people.
When that happens, I hope nobody
treats you like a child,
because it only makes you
feel worse.
You know,
if you want to avoid me,
you should know better
than to come in here
when I'm having
my pre-dinner breakfast.
Oh. I'm not trying
to avoid you.
I'm not.
I just, uh...
It's just, the reentry
gets harder every time.
You know, I miss Maya and Olivia
so much when I'm gone.
But when I'm traveling
for the foundation,
I just--i-i have a purpose.
You know, the work we do,
it's changing lives,
and I see it.
I see it every day.
Then I come back here
to all the... petty drama.
We're pretty
well-stocked in that.
Yeah. I'm sorry.
I-I didn't mean to downplay
what happened
with you and Addison.
She told you.
Unbelievable.
What, was I not supposed
to know?
Well, we, uh, we had agreed
not to tell anybody
until after the wedding,
but still,
she goes running to you.
You know, that's just...
That's who she is.
It's who she's always been.
Well, how do you--
how do you get past that?
I don't think you can.
So you treated Ms. Kent
for pain?
Not just pain. She had nausea
associated with her pregnancy.
Did you
prescribe her anything?
I took a holistic approach--
acupuncture, acupressure.
Were you at all concerned
about how she was responding?
Specifically,
do you feel like Ms. Kent
was getting better or worse?
After she miscarried, I needed
to perform an emergency d&amp;C.
Did you
perform it immediately?
No, not immediately.
Why not?
Answer the question, please.
Violet, uh...
Dr. Turner
felt it was important
that Katie fully comprehend
the loss of her baby
before the procedure.
And what happened
as a result of the delay?
Katie went into septic shock.
But she came through
just fine.
And you believe it was medically
appropriate to have waited?
Yes, Katie was--
I... um,
Violet calmed her down,
and then I did the d&amp;C.
And how did Dr. Turner
calm her down?
She related the experiences
of her own pregnancy.
It was a way of bonding,
and it worked.
And how exactly do you know
what was said
during Katie's therapy session
with Dr. Turner?
Uh, I don't know specifics,
but our practice
is cooperative.
Doctors often discuss
their cases with each other.
Including matters not relevant
to their specific areas
of responsibility
to those patients?
Is that really the ethic
of your practice?
Well, now you're making us
sound like gossips.
Then let me clarify
my question.
Does Dr. Turner ever share
the personal details
of her patients with you,
even when
you're not treating them?
Only when it's therapeutically
beneficial to the patient.
Can you please list the names
of all other patients
with whom Dr. Turner shared
such personal information?
So you got nowhere?
On the contrary.
An hour in the lobby
was very informative.
It's like a college dorm
for septuagenarians.
Everyone into everyone
else's business.
Not unlike this practice.
I asked around. Marion
had a good friend named Walter.
He died of a heart attack
a few weeks ago.
Well, so maybe that's it.
That's why she's been giving up
and not taking care of herself.
She's just grieving.
Mm-hmm. She is.
But when you get to her age,
loss is
a much more common occurrence.
And I think the best way
to deal with it is therapy.
Mm. Most elderly patients
are resistant
to the standard treatment
of meds and talk therapy.
And frankly, at Marion's age,
she doesn't have the luxury
of spending five years
on your couch,
especially when all her pain
can be eradicated
with one procedure.
Well, congratulations
on your psychiatric degree.
Where--where'd you get that?
Oh, snark away.
Pretty soon, you'll be able
to get one out of a cereal box.
With the advent
of psychosurgeries
and new
psycopharmaceuticals,
your degree
is becoming obsolete.
Why are you here?
You don't even work
for the practice anymore.
Oh, I'm here for her.
Okay, th-this
is not productive.
No, it isn't,
but you're being myopic.
The best thing for Marion
is the gamma knife surgery.
Well, she doesn't agree,
and neither do I.
♪ kicking a bottle ♪
♪ down an empty street ♪
♪ where the trees grow tall ♪
♪ and the old folks sleep ♪
♪ we walked long
when we were young ♪
It can't be that bad.
I'm not
showing it to you.
Come on. You look amazing
in everything.
Ugh. Not this.
♪ ...a sunny day ♪
♪ you can be done with it
and walk away ♪
Wh--
oh. Whoa.
See? It's awful.
It was awful
the first time around.
It's awful now.
How can she expect me
to wear this thing again?
Why don't you
just tell her no?
'Cause in my family,
we're not rude.
♪ Counting our blessings ♪
What's that
supposed to mean?
You described your parents
as these unbelievably warm,
caring people.
It was all they could do
to shake my hand.
Well, yeah,
they were a little, uh...
They're sensitive
to our history.
Our history?
Come on, Charlotte.
You hurt me a few times,
and I-I-I talked to them--
I see you huddlin'
in the bedroom on the phone,
and I know who you're
talking to, but I just assumed
you weren't sharing the intimate
details of our relationship.
You're a grown-ass man.
I'm sorry I don't have
an emotionally stunted parent
to take after.
Just because we don't vomit
our emotions all over each other
every two seconds doesn't mean
we're any less feeling.
No? Well, you know what
it does mean?
♪ You can be done with it ♪
Let's stop this.
Too late.
You know what?
You should wear that dress.
It looks great on you.
Screw you.
♪ ...on your arm ♪
I talked to
the medical investigator.
It didn't go well.
I mean, I answered everything
as well as I could,
but I don't know. Maybe--
maybe I said too much.
Well, that wouldn't be
a first.
What does that mean?
You told Naomi about us.
The same day we decided
to keep our split a secret,
you went and told her.
She had
a right to know, Sam.
No, this didn't involve her.
Well, she's your ex-wife
and my best friend,
so it did involve her.
Please. You just wanted
to be let off the hook.
What did you think,
that if you told her first,
she'd forgive you
for everything that happened?
That's not fair, Sam.
No, but it's true.
Maya, Naomi, and I
adjusted our lives to
accommodate this relationship,
and you can't see that.
You can't acknowledge
the toll that took.
It took
a toll on me, too, Sam.
I mean, I sacrificed
my best friend
for a man I was sure I was
gonna raise a family with.
You think I'm being selfish?
Take a look at yourself.
You've wanted me
since med school, okay?
So don't flatter yourself
that any pain that this
has caused is all my fault.
This relationship didn't
just happen. You went after it.
♪ Pull me through ♪
You're right.
But you know what,
Addison?
Maybe we can't be friends.
♪ Lately I ♪
♪ and lately I ♪
Ding, ding.
Wedding update.
You will be excited to know
that in between arranging
what is going to be
a ridiculously delicious spread
for your dinner,
I have also purchased
an amazing dress
for the wedding.
But it's not white
and it's not Vera wang.
I promise, everyone
will be focused on you.
I'm happy for you
about the dress.
Then why the look?
♪ Using words as ammunition ♪
Cooper's parents
don't like me.
They just met you.
He poisoned them.
What? Why?
I don't think he meant to,
but apparently,
he tells them everything,
including every mistake
I've ever made.
They can barely look at me.
Well, have you confronted them
about it?
What am I gonna say,
"sorry I did all these
terrible things to your son,
but please accept me,
love me"?
Well, can't Cooper
convince them?
I think Cooper's done
enough damage.
So what are you gonna do?
Hope we make it
to the altar
before they
convince him otherwise.
♪ Pull me through ♪
No, you can't.
Ladies,
please step aside.
You're not taking
our files.
We're not taking them.
We're only copying them.
What's going on?
They're trying to take
our patient files.
They're relevant
to our investigation.
We have consent
from the patients involved
to review them, so--
I'll call our lawyers.
It's not gonna matter.
I can deal with this.
Unfortunately, this
isn't just about you anymore.
We cannot let them
walk all over Violet.
Well, they're already
standing on her neck,
and they seem hell-bent
on making the rest of us
lay down, too.
That's why we need
to mitigate the damages.
Mitigate?
Well, maybe if Violet
were to take
a voluntary leave of absence
until the investigation
is complete...
That's your idea
of doing something?
Well, he's right.
Sorry I'm late.
Where's Violet?
We asked her not to come.
Is that fair?
Right now fair is not
our biggest problem.
Maybe if we show them
that we are cooperating--
no, it's not fair,
and we are cooperating.
If Violet steps back,
it makes it
look like she knows
that she did something wrong.
Or it makes it look like
she's taking it seriously.
Our primary concern right now
has to be
protecting the practice. I mean,
they're copying our files,
they're dragging us down
for interviews.
This investigation
is only gonna get bigger.
Let them see
whatever they want to see.
We're not an organized
crime family. We're doctors.
No offense, but how long have
you been here, like a week?
She's not supposed
to take offense to that?
Look--
listen, we all
talk about our patients,
not just Violet.
Exactly,
which is why we don't want
the medical board investigating
anyone else,
so we--
this doesn't feel right.
One of our own
is being attacked.
We need to stand by her.
Isn't that what this place
is supposed to be about?
The only people Violet tries
to help more than her patients
are all of us,
and if we can't...
If this is all it takes for us
to turn our back on her,
then I...
♪♪♪
Why did you keep a file
on Pete?
Well, technically,
he was my patient.
For two minutes.
Yeah, it was--it was
a long time ago.
We had a few sessions, then he
came to work for the practice.
And you slept together?
Why is this relevant?
Well, now he's my husband.
We have a child.
The fact that you're married
helps, but I have to be honest,
the situation looks bad.
Privilege really doesn't seem
to be a serious matter at o.W.G.
Okay, look, we are not
gonna apologize
for the way
we practice medicine.
We know how to help people,
we're good at it.
I'm sure you are,
but that doesn't
give you the right
to sit down over coffee
and discuss specific details
of patients you're treating
with other doctors
just because it's interesting.
Well, it's not gonna change.
I'm--I'm sorry, but the idea
that we are suddenly gonna act
like a bunch of disconnected
doc-in-the-boxes
who simply share space--no.
I don't care who sues me
or what's at stake.
We can't do that.
Oh. I prefer
you not be here.
There's something
I'd like to know first.
I'm, uh...
Having trouble understanding
why you wouldn't want
to improve
your quality of life.
The other doctors
at the practice
seem to think your depression
stems from grief
over the loss
of your friend Walter.
Oh, and you know better?
I have that way about me,
do I?
Jerome had
the same brash confidence.
Wh-when you lost him--
I can't imagine spending
half a century with someone
and then having to go on,
but you did, for years.
And according to Dr. Bennett,
you thrived,
which leads me to believe that
if you can get over Jerome,
you can get over Walter, too.
I noticed the words
on the game haven't changed
since the last time
I was here.
Who was it you were playing with
before you stopped?
Walter.
He was my friend.
Oh, we talked...
About our spouses,
about our lives.
We both loved to play scrabble,
almost every day.
That sounds nice.
Oh, it was more than nice.
It was wonderful.
After all those years
without Jerome,
to have someone
I connected with...
That's okay, Marion.
But I-I couldn't.
I couldn't do that to Jerome.
I just couldn't.
You couldn't do what?
We were in the middle
of the game, that game,
and he turned to me
and smiled and he...
He told me he loved me.
Well, what did you do?
I was so embarrassed.
I... I told him
to get out.
A week later, he...
He was dead.
But you did love him.
Oh, how could I tell him?
It was like
I was cheating on Jerome.
And now
Walter will never know.
He'll never know
I loved him.
He sat across that board
from you for a lot of hours.
Right?
So he knows.
Whether you said it
or not,
I'm sure he knows.
We are going to be so late
to Cooper's dinner.
Um... why aren't you dressed?
Maybe Sam and Naomi
are right.
Maybe I am putting
the practice at risk.
No, they're not right.
Well, I could--
I could step away.
I mean, if that's what people
want, which I don't know,
'cause I wasn't invited
to the meeting,
but if that's what it takes--
no, look,
your book was all about
exposing yourself
to help other people.
You've stood up to everything
that's been thrown at you,
and you've come out
the other side still standing.
I don't see how tomorrow's
meeting with the board
is gonna be any different.
Win/lose, right/wrong,
you're gonna
come through this stronger.
The only mistake I can see
is not standing up at all.
Come on. Go get dressed.
I can't.
Violet,
it's a dinner for Cooper.
He's your best friend.
He's getting married tomorrow.
Don't make me feel any worse
than I already do.
I ju--
the idea of facing
those people, I...
I texted Cooper,
and--and--and when
you see him,
just tell him I love him
and I'm sorry.
(William Fitzsimmons'
"the winter from her leaving"
playing)
♪ Shove me out to see ♪
♪ the sea ♪
The one maid of honor duty
Charlotte gave me,
and nobody
is having a good time.
Yeah, well,
the meeting this afternoon
didn't exactly leave people
in a festive mood.
I'm telling you, if the party
wasn't at my house,
I wouldn't be here.
♪♪♪
Hey.
Where's Violet?
She didn't want to come.
And I don't really blame her.
Look, I get, of course, you
didn't want to lie for Violet,
but the way you were talking
in that meeting--
Pete, it wasn't personal.
Yeah, exactly. It was
so cold and emotionless.
But she wrote the book,
okay, and whether you want
to believe it or not,
now we have a really serious
situation on our hands,
which isn't gonna go away.
So what, you just want
to abandon Violet?
No, of course not, but...
Look, if that's what
you want to believe--
look, if everybody in this damn
practice wants to be mad at me,
fine. I am still gonna do
what I think is right.
♪♪♪
First off, this does not count
as stalking.
Uh-huh.
Charlotte invited me.
And about the Marion thing--
♪♪♪
What was that for?
You're a good man.
You just never know.
You know, you think
you hit it off with someone,
that maybe they're the one--
I mean, you know, the one--
and then there's...
There's just so many ways
to screw it up.
But you--you know what?
Better sooner than later.
Right? Because if it's not
meant to be,
then you're just
setting up yourself
and everyone around you
for a whole lot of heartache.
Am I making any sense?
Actually, a lot.
♪ This peace ♪
You guys must be
so excited about tomorrow.
Very.
Should be a lovely day.
Look, I can spend all night
trying to back in
to this conversation,
but the truth is, you guys
are wrong about Charlotte.
I-If you got to know her,
if you just gave her a chance...
She deserves that,
doesn't she?
♪♪♪
This is fun.
Exactly the way I dreamed it
when I was a little girl.
All right,
this is ridiculous.
Let's find my parents,
get your mom.
The five of us will sit down,
and we'll talk this out.
Cooper.
No, don't argue with me.
I mean, we have to resolve this
so that tomorrow,
everyone can be happy
and relaxed.
Stop talking and turn around.
My father is nodding his head.
So's my mama.
Well, hey.
Good to see you
finally talking.
Oh, look,
we're all parents here.
Yes, and we do have
things in common.
Mama.
Well, we don't want
our kids to be unhappy.
So... we agree.
You have
different religions...
And you come from
different cultures...
And your personalities...
And all of these differences
don't make for a happy future.
I think what the mothers
are trying to say is,
you two
shouldn't get married tomorrow.
♪♪♪
Well, the joke is that, uh,
doctors make the worst patients.
Uh, but--but for me,
uh, after I started to heal,
it wasn't like I saw
an opportunity or anything.
I just, uh, I started writing,
and what came out...
It wasn't just the story
of me getting through.
I realized that I was writing,
uh, how I got through--
what really worked,
what didn't and why.
It's--it's not a road map,
but, um, this book is about
making the link,
not just between
doctor and patient,
but person to person.
And it's intended to be, um,
uh, proof, I guess,
that if you really commit
to helping yourself,
no matter
what you've been through,
then you can come out
the other side,
stronger and... healthier.
Does that make any sense?
I'm going to ask you
the question again.
Did you consider whether,
given the news coverage
of your attack,
Ms. Kent would be easily
identifiable in your book?
Um... honestly, no.
Does the issue of
doctor-patient confidentiality
concern you generally?
Come on, Neal.
Of course it does.
An investigation is one thing,
but to imply a complete lack of
professionalism by Dr. Turner--
we're concerned about
a lack of professionalism
at oceanside wellness
generally.
And it may extend
beyond Dr. Turner.
But for the time being,
we're concentrating
on Dr. Turner,
specifically the sharing
of potentially
privileged information--
it sounds like you've already
drawn your conclusions--
I never intended to do
anything but help people
with that book.
Both of you, please.
I think we have
enough information
to make a decision here.
The board will be in touch.
I think...
I-I think it's a mistake
for us to do this.
Everyone out there,
they're miserable.
Our parents don't think
it's gonna work,
the practice is falling apart,
everyone is fighting,
and I don't care what anybody
thinks or how they feel,
not today.
I don't understand.
All that matters
is you and me.
And the rest of 'em?
They don't have to agree
or like it or like each other,
because this is not for them
or about them.
I agree, only out there,
it's not just you and me.
I know how to make this
feel right.
♪♪♪
♪ What's your definition
of it? ♪
♪ How's it make you feel? ♪
♪ Tell me what you say ♪
♪ that truly makes it real ♪
♪ kings and queens,
philosophers ♪
♪ have tried so hard to find ♪
♪ tell me
what it means to you, dear ♪
♪ never mind ♪
♪ love is kind
when the world is cold ♪
♪ love stays strong
when the fight gets old ♪
♪ love's a shoulder to lean on ♪
♪ love is you ♪
♪ love's like the water
when the well runs dry ♪
♪ quench my thirst,
keep me alive ♪
♪ just need one sip, baby ♪
♪ love is you ♪
Wait. So what did
the text say again?
"Gone to Vegas.
Enjoy the food.
Don't wait up."
So they're gonna
get married without us.
Do you blame them?
I need a drink.
We're coming with you.
Uh, I may bow out as well.
I'm with you.
Wait, wait. Uh,
before everybody leaves,
I, um...
I just want to say,
I'm sorry.
I-i--you have to know
that I didn't mean
to make this hard
on any of you.
And I just--i had no idea.
So just so you know, I-I spoke
to the medical board today
and, uh, answered
all their questions.
Um, but I didn't apologize
for what I wrote,
because what I wrote reflects
who we are and the kind
of practice that we have.
We are friends and colleagues
who rely on each other
to help our patients,
and I am proud of us.
So they said they'd, uh,
get back to me with a decision,
but they didn't say when,
so... there you have it.
Okay.
Well, we're all here.
We might as well celebrate.
I, uh, I ordered champagne
for everybody.
♪ Love is you ♪
♪ love is you ♪
Which one's
the ginger ale?
Thanks.
So...
To Charlotte and Cooper.
The smartest two people
I know, right?
♪ You're the one I cling to ♪
You okay?
Yeah.
Um...
That's not ginger ale.
It's no biggie.
♪ I'm so glad I found ♪
♪ that love is you ♪
♪ Much as I've tried
to clarify ♪
♪ love's quite simple,
he's just my guy ♪
♪ a perfect definition ♪
♪ love is you ♪
♪ oh, oh ♪
♪ is you ♪