Meredith: At the height
of the Great Depression,
Harvard scientists
started tracking students
in hopes of discovering the
key to a long and happy life.
Luna's waking up so
early these days,
we should get some sleep.
Yeah, we should.
They looked at participants'
mental and physical health
over 75 years.
It is the longest study
of happiness to date.
♪ It's all good ♪
Mika: Oh, yeah. Oh!
75 years.
And all they did was
confirm what we've known
since the beginning of time...
♪ It's all good ♪
The most powerful predictor
of health and happiness
is the quality of
our relationships.
Are you still awake?
Strong relationships
protect us...
Don't give me that
look, Grandpaw.
Loneliness, on the other hand...
I'm talking to a cat.
Can be deadly.
♪ Everything is clearer, I'm
right where I need to be ♪
♪ Ain't no need to be stressed,
I'm just doing my best ♪
♪ Ain't no doubt that
I'm blessed, yes ♪
It smells like old feet.
Atheromatosis.
Uh, you... No, you go.
Right.
Thanks.
You didn't get
any sleep, either?
Mnh. Nope. Should
we change the locks?
You want to lock out one
of the chief residents?
Yasuda has the van.
We're already not
allowed in the OR.
What's Helm gonna do?
Hey, are we good?
You said you needed a minute.
It's been a week.
Yeah. Just working
some things out.
I can't really put
a timeline on it.
Okay, but if you
want to talk...
Oh, finally.
Someone had fun last night.
Hey, what happened
to your ground rules
and needing three
full REM cycles?
Karma sucks, doesn't it?
Let's go. I can't be late.
I've got a liver biopsy.
Say it louder.
I didn't mean that. I... Okay.
Hey, uh, please don't
put me on rectals.
Ben: You getting nervous? Huh?
The interns should be nervous.
I know this job.
I made this job.
Yeah, but times have changed.
This generation, they
ain't afraid to push back.
I'd like to see
them try with me.
I'm just saying that
you should be prepared
for this class to be different.
They're baby surgeons.
Baby surgeons don't change.
They need structure,
limitations, and tough love.
Right, Pru? Who's the boss?
You're the boss! See? She knows.
Why you make that
girl do that?
Here you go. Thanks.
Did that guy just wink at you?
Um, probably.
20 years later, it never ends.
What do you mean?
What do you mean,
"What do I mean?"
That's how we met.
Your first shift at Jimmy's.
The guy who looked
like Father Time.
He was hitting on
you. I bailed you out.
Sorry I don't have an
encyclopedic memory
of every guy who hits on me.
Well, how about an
encyclopedic memory
of meeting the man you love?
Who?
I'm kidding.
Now that I know that
you're not into the
whole monogamy thing...
Don't finish that sentence.
Have you ever been
in a throuple?
Do you remember when
we were just colleagues
and didn't know anything
about each other?
Can we please go back to that?
Mm. Millin was in a
throuple. I didn't say that.
Hey, love who you want to love.
20 bucks says that you're loving
a new job before the year's up.
50 says it's
Griffith. What? Why?
High risk, high reward.
I need gas money.
Millin, you in?
Can we all just shut up and
focus on our jobs, please?
Yeah.
Bailey: You're late.
I stopped to get
you the Mean Green.
Suck up. Number I rule broken.
Get out of my space.
I don't know what their deal is.
Your days as surgical
cowboys are over.
Our patients deserve
well-trained surgeons,
which you decidedly are not.
You're going back to basics.
No more dodging protocols,
no cutting corners.
If you want to operate
again, you will earn it.
Procedure logs.
You will complete every
procedure to perfection
and get an attending
to sign off.
Until those cards are complete,
you will not so much
as look at an OR.
10 IVs, 15 chest tubes?
10 central lines?
Dr. Bailey,
we appreciate what
you're doing. Suck up.
But we're already cramming
for the ABSITE exam.
Oh. Well, if it's
too much for you,
feel free to choose
another career.
I hear that dermatology is nice.
Want to be a
dermatologist, Dr. Kwan?
Didn't think so.
Schmitt and Helm have
your assignments.
Okay. Kwan, Adams,
Millin, take the pit.
Yasuda, you're with Ndugu.
Griffith, you're with Schmitt.
Any chance we're going somewhere
with a lot of procedures?
We get what we get and
we don't get upset.
Did your class ever have
to do surgical bingo?
My class didn't screw
up like your class.
Alright, I put an order in
for a repeat chest X-ray.
How are you feeling?
Great.
Honestly, I am more concerned
about Ms. Acharya
and Mr. Jenkins.
Well, her biopsy was benign,
and his ECHO got pushed to noon.
So your patients are covered.
Just focus on recovery.
Yeah. Doctor's orders. Okay?
Oh, it's...
Oh, it's the ER. I'll,
uh, check in later, okay?
Okay. Yeah. I just... Can I...
I'm here and ready to help.
I can remove chest tubes or...
Never mind.
Let me guess.
Dr. Bailey's new program?
Well...
Listen.
No procedures on the chief.
And no trolling for
them on my service.
So finish rounding,
then come find me.
Yasuda. I could use your help.
Yeah. Of course.
Tuggle, Futrell...
Are they specific
techniques? They're patients.
I want you to check on
them and report back.
Are you sure you
should be working?
It's only been a
week, and I've got...
A procedure log. I know.
Okay, Mr. Tuggle is going to
need his pacing wires removed.
And Mr. Futrell, he's always
pulling out his A-line, so...
Oh, procedures. Okay. Mm.
And when you're done with
those, I have others.
Just use discretion.
Discretion is my middle name.
Actually, it's Elaine.
I-I'm on it.
All my life... All my life,
I've wanted to be a champion.
And what happens? I get...
Millin: If we could all
just talk one at a time.
Please.
Okay, this sounds
counter intuitive.
But this is going
to go a lot faster
if one person speaks at a time.
Our family softball game
turned into a bit
of a bloodbath.
I cut my leg, and Allie
and Billy need some help.
Yeah, I... I can't
straighten my arm.
That's not normal, right?
No. Not really. What about you?
I don't know.
It feels like I broke my back.
Make her the priority.
She's carrying my grandbaby.
How about my broken nose?
Charlotte fouled a
ball into my face.
Who is Charlotte? Me!
She's my other son's daughter.
She's going to be
this year's MVP.
Oh, when pigs fly.
Okay, Millin, let's get
the Best family settled
while I do their intake, okay?
Alright, let's go.
Alright, who actually
needs medical attention?
Come with me.
The rest of you can wait
in the waiting room.
Paramedic: Coming through.
Oh, oh, wait.
Everybody move back.
Move back, please.
Right, let's get
him to trauma three.
John Doe, looks
to be in his 20s,
found unconscious by
Fisherman's Terminal.
No witnesses, multiple
gunshot wounds
to his chest and abdomen.
Systolic has been
stable in the low 100s.
Received 2 liters of fluid
and 200 mics of fentanyl
on the way here.
Alrighty. On my
count, everybody.
Ready? One, two, and three.
Whoa. Smells like
Pike Place Market.
Order a type and screen.
I can't get through.
Whoo! That's a whole
lot of Benjamins.
Richard: Dr. Griffith,
will you please present?
Dante Collier, 33.
He's had right
upper quadrant pain
on and off for two weeks.
Presented to the
ER this morning.
His lab showed
elevated transaminases
with normal alc, phos, and bili.
Ultrasound confirmed
cholecystitis.
He is scheduled
for surgery today.
Soup to nuts, how long
is this gonna take?
I need to feed my
pumpernickel starter.
What's a pumpernickel
starter eat?
Sorry. I am a surgical resident.
I keep textbooks in my oven.
Richard: I'm afraid we're
going to have to keep you here.
Dante is a baker.
He owns Bread for
This, the bakery.
Oh, their cinnamon
rolls changed my life.
That's my baby.
You should come by
sometime, on the house.
I'll tell the staff to look
out for the handsome surgeon
who keeps textbooks
in his oven.
You know, my wife
makes a mean cornbread.
Sweet or savory?
Oh. You kidding? Sweet.
We'll try and get
you back to work
as soon as we can.
Dr. Schmitt will be
your lead surgeon.
I'll be assisting.
You will?
Uh, he will. Because I
am your lead surgeon.
Griffith, go check
on his labs, please.
Do you want me to stop
and see if Mrs. Fairey
needs her wound vac changed?
Just the labs.
Uh, okay. Get some rest.
We'll be back soon.
Looking forward to it.
How far along are you?
29 weeks.
And, yes, I know I had no
business playing softball.
Not the way your family plays.
They're my in-laws.
This is what happens
when you take a bunch
of highly competitive,
wildly unathletic people
and give them bats.
I've suggested Wiffle
ball or badminton,
literally, anything else, but...
Babe, those aren't real games.
Well, I paged OB.
But I'm also going
to get you an ortho
and a neuro consult.
That doesn't sound too good.
Well, I just want
them to check you out.
So you just stay right here
and don't go chasing
after any fly balls.
Couldn't if I tried.
D-Did he rob a bank?
This must be
thousands of dollars.
Or maybe he was trying
not to get robbed.
Winston: He has three wounds
in the front, two in back.
One bullet must be inside still.
We're ready for films.
I could buy six vans with that.
Yasuda, what do you need?
Mr. Tuggle's post-op, day two.
Should I remove
his pacing wires?
No. And it's not
the time to ask.
Let's hang another unit.
X-rays up. Kwan?
Bilateral hemopneumothoraces.
He needs a chest tube.
Mm-hmm.
Both: I could do it.
Adams, take that
money down to security
and have them lock it up
until the police arrive.
Here, Kwan.
Oh. Pressure's tanking.
He's coding. Let's
prep for a thoracotomy.
Scalpel.
Have you seen the pie episode
of the "Great Bakeoff"?
It's dope.
I don't have a lot
of time for TV.
Before surgery, we
need to make sure
we have all your
medications noted.
I already told the ER doctor.
Are you taking any
medication for HIV?
Excuse me?
I didn't see any
meds listed for HIV.
I figured it was a mistake.
Just wanted to make sure.
I don't have HIV.
I'm so sorry.
Hold on.
Our labs indicate a
positive HIV result.
It's right here.
Well, it's wrong.
I mean, when was I tested?
Standard screening for our ER.
I want one of the other doctors.
Oh, Dante, I would never...
No, you've made a mistake,
and clearly you don't
know what you're doing.
So...
Get me another doctor.
Okay.
Hello, Allie.
I'm Dr. Lincoln.
This is Dr. Shepherd.
Hey, Allie. Tell me,
have you experienced
any back pain
during your pregnancy?
Maybe a little. Mm-hmm.
This is sharper. Stabbier.
And my groin area
is a little numb.
Herb should be MVP. He's 81.
He's still pitching strikeouts.
Everyone gets unlimited pitches.
You're really going to
deprive a dying man?
Who says he's dying?
Look at him!
If anyone deserves
MVP, it's Allie.
I don't want MVP...
Gah! Ah! Ah. Ah.
Okay. Hang on. Ooh, ah, ah.
Wait. I think my water broke.
What's happening? Is she okay?
Uh, Allie, I-I don't
think it's amniotic fluid.
It's urine.
I peed myself in
front of my in-laws?
Don't worry, sweetheart.
We're family.
She needs an MRI. This
could be a spinal injury.
And if we don't move now,
she could end up paralyzed.
Trash duty suits you.
Security's busy on
the psych floor.
I'm stuck with this guy's money
until they get back.
It's been 20 minutes.
No cardiac response.
Okay. Injecting another epi.
Hang more blood.
Heart's not starting.
Resuming cardiac massage.
Come on, man, come on.
Is there any ID on
this kid, Adams?
Uh, no, nothing.
Still nothing. Damn it!
Time of death...
Before you declare him,
can I take over cardiac massage?
He's dead.
Exactly. Good practice.
Yeah, fine, Kwan. Step in.
Careful, now. One hand on top,
one hand underneath,
and squeeze up from the apex.
Yeah.
It's beating. It...
Is it beating?
What?
Oh, congratulations. Now move.
Let's get him up to the OR ASAP.
Can I scrub in?
It's not up to me.
Ask your residency director.
Is your procedure log completed?
We just got it this morning.
Then, no. Let's go.
You just happened to
get your hand in there
at the right time.
You're walking
around with $40,000
in a trash bag.
Dante, we repeated
your lab test twice,
and they both came
back positive for HIV.
Now, I know this is
a lot to take in,
so we'll give you some time.
We can postpone your surgery
for a couple of hours
and provide you
with some counseling
and a referral to a specialist.
Schmitt? I'll put
in the consult now.
Hey, careful. You'll
pull out your IV.
I need to get out of here.
You can get some air,
but we need to keep
the IV antibiotics
going until surgery.
Surgery is the last thing
on my mind right now.
I need to go.
HIV can be treated
with minimal changes
to your life.
But if we don't treat your
gallbladder infection,
your health will
drastically decline.
Where are my clothes?
Dante, please let us help you.
I'll sign whatever
you need me to sign,
but please let me go!
Uncle Bo: Herb's been
playing for 60 years.
Just because she's 5
doesn't mean she
can't add value.
How's a busted nose added value?
Ohh. What do you
think, Dr. Millin?
I think that I am
done with your leg.
Give me a sec. Okay?
You're a sore loser.
Because you cheat.
Oh.
Dr. Hunt,
I finished the, uh, leg lac.
Could you please sign
my procedure log?
Uh, could you please put
me on a different patient?
This family is... a lot.
Dislocated finger in
bed seven, Millin.
Okay? Yes.
Allie: Is it almost over?
First time all day I
can hear myself think,
and now all my thoughts
are terrifying.
Should just be a
few more minutes.
I grew up an only
child, and I hated it.
I wanted noise and
sibling rivalry
and someone who also
despised my mom.
Then I married Billy
and his giant family.
But if anything were to happen
to my baby because of
this stupid game...
Try to take a few deep breaths.
Hey, uh, no more cake.
So your options are
chocolate, sugar, and glazed.
Second breakfast?
First. First.
Scans are up.
There, severe disc herniation
at L5 and S1 levels.
The disc is protruding
and pressing into
the nerve root.
This is cauda equina syndrome.
I'll book her an OR for
emergent decompression.
Mm-hmm. You can't
go in posteriorly.
If we go in anteriorly,
we'll have to deliver the baby.
She's only 29 weeks.
We can't position her laterally.
It increases her
chance of bleeding.
You're not leaving
us many options.
I think I have one.
Teddy: What's happening?
Mr. Jenkins is
prepped for his CABG.
No change on Mr. Futrell,
but I think he has a
crush on Dr. Beckman.
Which is relevant because...?
When he pulls out his A-line,
he only wants Dr. Beckman
to put it back in.
Here, answers to
your other questions.
Good.
Actually, I need
to finish rounding
on Ndugu's patients.
That's got a possible
central line.
Are you sure you
don't need help?
Yes, with my patients. Go.
Oh.
Those are the AMA forms to sign.
I arranged an appointment
with our clinic
so you can talk to them
about your treatment options.
I already know the spiel
a pill a day
and then passing on the virus
is basically a non-issue.
There's also an
inject able option
if you're not into pills.
When I saw you walk into
the room this morning,
my first thought was,
how was I going to ask the
hot surgeon out on a date?
Now I'll always remember
your face as one of the ones
who told me my dating
life had changed forever.
Hey, y-you will still date.
When and how you disclose
your status is up to you.
And then they'll run.
Or they'll be like me and
they'll already be on PrEP.
So they'll have the freedom
to date whoever they're into.
Even guys who
feed their pumpernickel.
Hey, hey, hey. You okay?
I think it's getting worse.
You're getting clammy, too.
Dante, you need this surgery.
Hey, if you walk out of here,
you could become septic and die.
Okay. Okay.
Okay? Yeah.
That... That's it? Yeah.
Because I don't
think I can walk.
Can I get a hand in here?
We still don't know
who this kid is.
As a parent, I... I
just can't imagine.
Um, if you have something
to say to me, go ahead.
Lap pad.
You learn how to be a surgeon
in the operating room.
Full stop.
Suspending the interns
is stunting their education.
And what's worse,
it's impeding my work.
They should be in the OR,
pushing past their mistakes
and learning from them.
Growing, Bailey. Suction.
I won a Catherine
Fox award. I'm aware.
Most people think it
is because of my work
in reproductive care,
but really, it's for
teaching reproductive care.
Okay, this bullet
shattered the spleen
and hit the small
and large bowels.
I'm afraid the SMA is involved.
He might never eat
normally again.
If he lives.
Looks like the bullet injured
the hilum of his lung.
Think I can feel it. Oh, yeah.
There it is. Gotcha.
Whoa!
Adams.
Take the bullet to pathology.
As in now.
His pressure's tanking.
Whoever you are
stay with us.
The table is shaped
like a donut?
No. We add supports
to the iliac crest
to create a hole in the
center like a donut.
That way, you can lie face down
without putting
pressure on your belly.
And we go in and
remove the discs
pressing on your nerves.
And you've done this before.
Well, it's an unusual situation.
That sounds like no.
Is this safe for the baby?
I think it's the best choice.
And I will be in there
to monitor both of you.
I should have
let that ball go.
I didn't want to
disappoint anyone,
but now the baby...
I-I-I should have...
Hey, hey. Hey, it'll be okay.
No matter what happens,
we will all be there for
you when you wake up.
Everyone?
I will tell whoever
you want to leave.
I love you.
As soon as we have an update,
we'll let you know.
You're here.
That must mean Mr. Wallace
is out of surgery.
I passed that case to Dr. Boyle
because I have a lap chole.
Why? Is someone asking?
I plead the Fifth.
Yasuda, you want to tell me
what's really going on here?
I plead the Fifth again.
This doesn't concern
me, so I'm gonna...
Chief Altman said
I might get some
procedures for my log
if I checked on
her patients. Mm.
Don't worry. Joke's on me.
I haven't done a
single procedure,
and I'm behind on
Ndugu's patients, so...
Also, I know it's not my place,
but maybe she's pushing it
just a little bit too...
What are you doing?
Well...
Yeah. You did these.
On my wife.
You helped save
her life, Yasuda.
I won't forget that. Okay?
Now, I need your help
getting her to rest.
Save her from herself.
And don't tell her it's
coming from me, okay?
Use discretion.
I'll see what I can
do. Owen: Thank you.
Amelia: Finished
the decompression.
Screwdriver.
Art. Father Time's name was Art.
Are we still talking about this?
It's important.
Well, maybe you
should have warned me.
There'd be a quiz
about the day we met
20 years later.
Almost done
stabilizing the spine.
No, no, no, no, no.
I'm seeing deep decels.
The baby's heart rate is
dropping into the 60s.
Okay, we need five minutes.
We might not have that.
Her spine is not stable.
If we move her, we
could paralyze her.
Okay, I might be able
to manipulate the baby.
If the cord is compressed,
I might be able to
reposition the baby
to take the pressure off.
Okay, I need the
other screwdriver.
Jo?
No change. Let me just
try one more thing.
Damn it! It's not working.
We need to get the baby out.
I haven't confirmed placement...
We need to flip her now!
Alright, we've
got enough screws.
We can finish after
we save the baby.
Let's do this. Wet lap pads.
Page the NICU team and OB.
Let them know we're doing
an emergency C-section.
Everyone here, drop what you're
doing and help us flip her.
Hey.
I got your text. What happened?
Just gave someone the biggest
diagnosis of their life
as casually as ordering
a freakin' coffee.
And then he almost
canceled his lap chole.
He could've died 'cause of me.
That really sucks.
I'm sorry.
Are you sure you want this?
I want to feel better.
Uh.
Is there a problem?
Look, I want to. You're upset.
And...
Well, maybe we should talk.
Yeah, don't worry about it.
Wait, look... Simone, I...
Hey, Simone.
We successfully
stabilized Allie's spine,
and it'll take a little while,
but we are expecting
a full recovery.
That's great.
And, uh, what about our baby?
Is she going to be okay?
Well, her lungs aren't
fully developed,
so she'll need a little
time on a ventilator.
But for her age,
she is strong.
Yeah.
Hi.
Welcome to the team,
little slugger.
So, we are loud and
we're opinionated,
and we're not the
best athletes, okay?
But we are the Best family.
Yes, we are.
We'll give you a moment.
He can be sentimental.
Well, he is a new father.
I was talking about Link.
I mean, he remembers everything.
Birthdays and anniversaries,
good and bad.
Well, you've known him longer.
You know how sensitive he is,
how much he cares.
And I think
it's even more intense
with people that he loves.
He told you about us?
He didn't have to.
We were already family anyway.
Hm. Mm.
How is Dante?
His gallbladder
was very inflamed,
so we had to convert
to an open procedure.
But Schmitt handled it well.
He'll brief you on
the post-op orders.
Mm-hmm.
He'll be okay.
My instincts... I've
always trusted them.
Lately...
I don't know.
It's a terrifying
feeling, isn't it?
No one has a perfect record.
I mismanaged more than
a few things in my life.
How long did it
take you before you
stopped?
I'll let you know when I do.
What do you have for me, Yasuda?
Lemon, orange, and cherry.
It's Jell-O.
I don't want Jell-O.
I used to hate it.
My mom could serve
nine kids from one box.
So we had it all the time.
A-And I mean literally
every Sunday afternoon.
But then I went to college,
and I found myself grabbing
it at the dining hall.
It... It became a
little taste of home.
You know who wants
a taste of home?
Ms. Granados.
Was she discharged?
Chief.
What about...
What about focusing on rest?
I don't know if
it was my husband
or my surgeon who
put you up to this,
but either way...
I'm fine.
You are not fine.
And that is not coming
from Dr. Hunt or Ndugu.
That is fact.
I know because I was
standing next to you
when you collapsed in the OR.
We pounded on your
heart to keep you alive.
It was... It was
traumatic and awful.
And I'm still not over it,
but... but here you are,
acting like business as
usual when you almost died!
Chief Altman.
Oh. I... I should go.
Okay.
Please don't tell
anyone this happened.
Discretion. Total discretion.
It doesn't matter. She shouldn't leave
if she's pregnant. I understand that.
Excuse me.
Excuse me!
Billy is with Allie.
The baby is fine.
Now, all of you who needed
help have been seen.
So you are all free to go.
Oh, thank you so much, Doctor.
Thank you. You're welcome.
Alright, what about the MVP?
What? Oh, what about Nowell?
What about him?
An MVP is supposed
to inspire people.
Okay? Make them want to
rise up and do better.
Nowell's played left
field for 25 years.
Hasn't caught so much as a cold.
Oh, at least he didn't
set the cabin on fire
with illegal fireworks.
Those weren't mine!
Really? That's why your
eyebrows were singed off?!
Stop!
Stop it! This is a hospital.
There are people who are
sick and injured here.
Some are in pain.
Some will never leave.
You should all be grateful
that you have a family
that wants to spend
time together,
that plays games together,
that has family traditions.
And instead you have all
been arguing all day,
making it next to impossible for
me to do my job and help you.
So I hope that you
all remember this
when you are all
back here next year.
MVP.
Please.
Family: MVP.
No. Family: MVP.
- MVP!
- Whoo!
MVP!
Family: MVP! MVP! MVP!
If I ask you something,
will you just not
be you for a second?
I need to know the
question first.
Have you seen the bag of cash?
I think "idiot"
might be too generous
in this situation.
Help me find the bag.
You're on all the butt stuff
for the next two weeks.
Fine. I don't care.
Just help me find it.
You left it in the on
call room, dumb-ass.
You're lucky I'm the
one who found it.
Ooh, oops.
Bailey: Hand me that bag
before I hand you
something else.
The police put out a
missing persons report.
Hopefully someone will
recognize our John Doe.
Dr. Bailey, is this a good time
to sign my procedure log?
No.
So I don't get credit
for the cardiac massage?
You didn't do that for credit.
You did it to learn
to save a life.
What?
This...
Look, this man is a human being.
He's someone's son,
maybe someone's brother.
He's just like you, at the
beginning of his adult life.
And then he was
shot multiple times
and might not live.
Yet, the only thing the
two of you seem to see
is blank boxes to be checked.
This exercise is not a game.
It is to determine whether
or not you will ever
regain the privilege
of operating
inside someone's living body.
And if I hear that you put
procedures over patients again,
I will make sure
that you never do.
Surgery went well,
but you will have
a longer recovery
since we weren't able to
go in laparoscopically.
You'll have to be here
a couple days, okay?
Griffith, now is
not a good time...
I just want to apologize
if that's okay.
Okay.
Thank you.
Dante, I am so sorry.
I should have been more tactful.
It's no excuse, but I was
racing through my work,
and I-I screwed up.
Sorry. Been there.
I missed a couple of calls
from the health department
a few months ago.
Huge red flag, I know.
But we had just
launched mobile orders.
The kitchen was slammed.
I didn't have any symptoms,
and I wasn't seeing anyone.
So I put it off.
I never expected to have HIV.
I had to find out at
some point, right?
See you in the morning.
Thank you.
Got any dinner
plans, Dr. Schmitt?
I hear the pudding's good.
No dinner plans.
But I-I do have other patients.
Right.
But I could spare
maybe 20 minutes.
Have you ever seen
the "Great Bakeoff"?
It's my favorite.
It's good. Right?
Hi, I'm Dr. Kwan.
You two responded to the
missing person notice.
Our son... he was on
break from grad school.
And he got work on
a fishing barge.
Andres: They docked yesterday,
but we never heard from him.
And we saw that there
was a... a robbery
in the... in the
area in the news,
and the... the police
directed us here.
Oh. You have a
photo of your son?
♪ ...all the money
lying on her bed ♪
Uh.
♪ My brother lied,
told me I was brave ♪
Please take a seat.
♪ He said... ♪
Your son is here.
Dorian... his name is Dorian.
Dorian is here in the ICU.
He was shot three times.
We did aggressive resuscitation,
and his heart stopped,
but we got him back.
He's stable, but in
critical condition.
The bullets caused
extensive damage.
I can take you to go see him,
but I have to warn you,
it will be difficult.
♪ Maybe it's best to
never see the light ♪
♪ Dug the fields with
our hands 'til... ♪
Hey.
Yasuda told you that I cried.
No. But you just did.
♪ ...'til he was satisfied ♪
Hey.
I'm a mess.
♪ ...of the men we'd
like to become ♪
You're alive.
♪ Dreamed about the day... ♪
I just...
♪ ...we'd find all
the strength to run ♪
I can't get the image of Sam
lying on that OR
table out of my head.
I was supposed to save him.
But you didn't, and now
you're trying to
save everyone else.
Mm? Maybe.
Teddy, what happened to
Sam was not your fault.
It was out of your control.
And I promise you, you
will be back to work soon.
But you need to recover.
♪ One day, okay, alright ♪
And that is something that
you can control. Okay?
♪ 'Til then it ain't alright ♪
You're right.
Okay. No more work.
Alright, take this.
Okay, give me. I got
it. I got it. Okay.
Good.
Thank you for looking after me.
♪ Maybe it's best... ♪
Of course.
♪ ...to never see the light ♪
Mm. Mm. What? Wait...
What? No. Do I feel...?
No, no.
Teddy, is this another tablet?
It's... Really?
Please, can I... Okay.
I love you.
Winston. Hi.
I got a cat.
Are you talking to me?
I miss my family,
I miss Meredith,
I miss Maggie, I-I miss Kai,
so, uh, I got a cat.
Oh.
I know things have
been rocky between us,
but I consider you family,
and I would love it
if we were the kind of family
that could fight
and still eat meals together.
Would you be interested
in a burger at Joe's?
I could go to Joe's. Yeah.
You know it would
be with me, right?
Yeah. Come on.
Okay.
Oh.
Oh. Oh, uh, Pru convinced Tuck
to set up the camping tent.
So now they're singing
campfire songs.
Is everything okay?
Yeah, we had a John
Doe in his 20s.
He came in full of bullets.
Turns out to be a fisherman
who had, uh, just
gotten his big payday
when someone stuck
a gun in his face.
Just senseless.
It's the worst part of the job.
Now, I'm different.
The interns, right,
they're just like
any other class
clumsy, competitive.
Their hearts are sometimes
in the right place.
But...
I've changed.
I've seen too much.
I've felt too much.
But isn't that a good thing?
No.
Doctor Ndugu openly
questioned my methods today.
And, um...
Well, maybe he's right.
Maybe
it's a sign that.
I... I shouldn't do this again.
Um... Hold on. Hold on.
You remember how long it took me
to figure out
Pru's Diaper Genie?
Or how frustrated I got when
she would only eat orange foods?
As long as it's food, who cares?
Exactly.
See, you, y-you're sailing
through parenting Pru
because you've done it before.
You know what works
and what doesn't.
You know when to get mad
and when to hold a hand.
So, yes.
You've changed,
but for the better.
I scored four
procedures on my card,
and I won a trophy.
I think victory
looks good on me.
Anyone else?
I got two procedures,
I saw an attending
cry, and I'm exhausted.
Oh, who cried?
Doesn't matter.
How many did you get checked?
Also two. Come on,
you're not gloating?
Not in the mood.
Ready?
Yes.
Over the course of our lives,
our relationships ebb and flow.
MVP. MVP.
We get together, break up,
move away or fall out of touch.
♪ The less it makes
sense the more we try ♪
When did you have time to, uh,
prepare for a famine?
Okay. Do you remember
the first year.
Jimmy's did
All-You-Can-Eat Crab Day?
Oh, when they didn't
limit the time,
and everyone who came for
lunch stayed through dinner
and we made almost no tips?
Yes.
And my tuition was due,
and I was totally miserable.
I remember.
Okay. Well, after
that awful shift,
you and I sat in the back booth
eating oyster crackers.
And you told me that someday
I'd become a doctor
and make enough to afford
everything on the menu.
You made it all better.
Just like you've done
so many times
since we first met.
Mm. Also known as the day
I rescued you from Father Time.
Allegedly.
But I know this isn't
Jimmy's Crab Shack,
but this is
everything on the menu
from the Fisherman's Lure.
Mm.
You know what I love
even more than donuts?
Me?
I was going to
say lobster rolls.
It's prolonged periods of
loneliness and toxicity
that wreak havoc on our
health, our brain function,
and our longevity.
♪ This is the place
we're all hiding ♪
Sometimes being alone
can be so terrifying
that we trap ourselves
in harmful relationships.
♪ The one we all long to be ♪
Um...
♪ The why it's so
hard to sleep ♪
I avoid hard truths.
I avoid them till they are
staring me in the face.
Ran from Baltimore. I
ran from my wedding.
After everything with
Sam, I ran from you.
And I think it's because
I am too scared to admit that...
Right now's not a good time for
us.
I'm not sleeping.
I'm slipping up.
I'm hurting people.
I'm hurting myself.
And I need to put me first.
I need to put my
career first.
When haven't you?
♪ Fire ♪
You accepted a marriage proposal
right after kissing
me in your room.
Then you asked me
to be your best man.
And then you say you need a
minute to sort things out,
but that's over right
when you need me
to help you feel better.
No. You put yourself first.
Don't worry.
Lucas, all of that was...
From now on
we're roommates.
You and I are done.
But in order to really thrive,
you've got to be
willing to cut and run.
Your life just
might depend on it.
♪ When we are known ♪
Captions by VITAC...