Previously, on
The Good Doctor...
How hard can it be to just
act like a normal human being?
No!
Will you stop petting
that stupid rabbit?
We're never going home again. We
have each other, and that's all we need.
Your fiancé sure
can handle a knife.
He's got a serious deficit.
So, are you proud
or disappointed?
Marcus, stop making
everything so personal.
You've wanted his job since day
one. Everyone in this room knows that.
How did you...
It's my department, it's
my job to know everything.
Since I work for you, doesn't that
make all this actually your fault?
I'm sorry. I stopped
listening after "I work for you."
A surgeon needs to communicate.
Can Dr. Murphy do that?
Can he do that under stress?
Can he do that knowing that a
human life literally hangs in the balance?
So, I'm in the
middle of Uncharted
and I'm dead. Can I borrow
some triple-As? I'm your neighbor.
Hello.
Thirty-four.
I moved in last
week. Thirty-three.
Yeah, I know.
I work at a hospital.
That's cool.
Yes.
Triple-As, por favor?
Batteries.
Right. Do you have any?
Triple-A batteries.
Thank you. Piece of
advice? Don't feed the cat.
What cat?
Feed it once, and it'll
never leave you alone.
Thank you for the
batteries, neighbor.
You're welcome.
Environmental cardiac seven.
Surgical. Well, you're in
luck, because I'm not a nurse,
I'm a surgical resident.
How can I help you?
We got a liver for Chuck.
- Where?
- SF Municipal Hospital.
And how long do we have,
body-to-body, on a liver transplant?
Eight hours.
You don't know the
longevity of a liver?
This is a teaching
hospital, and I'm the teacher.
You and Murphy,
you're on organ pick-up.
Check the health and bring
the liver back from SFM.
I was at Chuck's intake.
I'd really like to be...
Now you're gonna be at
the intake for his new liver.
Jared, get Chuck down
here and get him prepped.
We've got eight hours on this
thing and the clock starts ticking now.
I'm not interrupting
your pregame, am I?
I think this is my 400th
breast reconstruction.
The board should
give me a plaque.
What's up?
Your 4:00 p.m. The
VIP. Wannamaker.
Yes. The free-flap. He's
checked into the penthouse suite,
resting comfortably, I'm sure.
I have been working on him
for a while now, and he's close.
He's real close to making
the Foundation his tax relief.
That's good to hear.
I want aces on this.
Everything perfect.
That's good to know. I
was gonna phone it in.
Dr. Montego to the ICU.
Dr. Montego to the ICU, stat.
Is this the chairman's
version of a pep talk?
I'm looking for a fail-safe
outcome on the procedure.
I want you to use
Dr. Melendez as your second.
That's your fail-safe? Melendez?
I'm your chief of surgery.
It's just a precaution. To
guarantee a perfect outcome.
Are you doubting my abilities?
Wannamaker is important.
Everything has to be perfect.
You said that already. I'm
your fail-safe. The VIP'll be fine.
How you doing?
I know these sounds and
everything might be a lot for you.
It's hard for anyone.
I like helicopters.
I didn't know you'd
been on a helicopter.
I haven't.
Fifteen minutes to San
Francisco Municipal Hospital.
Should be a smooth ride.
You do know what this is,
right? I'll tell you what it is,
it's scut work.
Jared gets the golden ticket
and we get pizza delivery.
The rotors just go round and
round, Shaun. They don't change.
How do I talk to you?
So, Chuck, any chest
pain, shortness of breath?
No.
- Any alcohol in the last six months?
- No.
Just a quick pinch.
Any swelling in your limbs?
It's like Walmart on
Black Friday in here.
Things speed way up when
you're having a transplant.
I like it. It's good energy.
So that's a "no"
on the swelling?
No. I feel lousy all
the time, pretty much.
But I've got a second chance,
you know, with this liver?
Sure.
Excuse me. It's my daughter.
I already spoke to Mom.
And Uncle Tommy, too.
Yeah, I need to see your face.
All right. I love
you. All right.
She just graduated from law
school at Cal. I told you that.
No. Congratulations.
Must've told Dr. Browne,
then. Where is Dr. Browne?
Here's your liver. I'm
gonna need you to sign for it.
Standard operating
procedure is to leave the liver
in the safety of
the body cavity.
I'm aware of the procedure.
We had a John Doe at the top
of the registry, but that John
Doe died before we could plant.
- How long ago did you take it out?
- Three hours.
We just lost three hours.
Technically, three
hours and five minutes.
The true clock is on the cooler.
Can't go below 39 degrees,
or above 47 degrees.
You wanna sign for it?
Tissue looks healthy.
What are you doing?
What are you looking for?
- What's he doing?
- I'm not sure.
Shaun, what are you
looking for, masses? Cysts?
They're clean. Think
we'd miss a tumor?
There's nothing there.
I know. There's nothing there.
Okay, the liver needs to go back
into cold storage and we gotta go.
Then I'll release the vascular
clamp and let your blood
- perfuse the new donor liver.
- That's it?
Connect the bile ducts,
sew you up, and then we wait.
Huh. Does the new
one always take?
Over 70% of the time.
Well, I can live
with those odds.
You get some
rest. See you later.
He looks at something, I
don't know what he's looking at.
Is he... You know, is he curious? Is
he concerned? He won't answer me.
You're having trouble communicating
with him? It's a weekday,
it's Shaun... Let's see,
that seems about right.
He seemed different
at the hospital.
You know, I could
kind of talk to him.
Yeah, well, he knows what
to expect in the hospital.
Outside, everything's different,
everything's new. New stimuli.
So, what do I do? I don't
know what he's thinking.
Claire, you're not gonna
figure out what he's thinking,
so don't even try. In fact, if
he's thinking about something
in his own mind,
just let him be.
I'd appreciate it if people
gave me the same courtesy.
I thought with your history...
Claire, if you wanna
connect with him,
you're gonna have to
figure out your own way in.
How's Chuck?
Chuck? Chuck's fine. He's waiting
for a liver. So, come home, please.
Okay.
- Doctor?
- What's up?
I just wanted to thank you.
But I haven't done anything yet.
You have. You've
given my dad hope.
You know, Chuck
was my first patient.
Six months ago, first
day at Saint Bonaventure,
I get a liver failure. One of
the nicest guys in the world.
I wanted to be the one
to give him the good news.
We're not leaving.
You said you liked helicopters.
We made it here safe.
Yes. We're not leaving.
We're not leaving.
Fog's rolling in too quick.
Does that mean
it rolls out quick?
Could be an hour, could
be three. Don't know.
Okay, uh... We're
gonna need a new ride.
Excuse me, I need an
ambulance to Saint Bonaventure.
Sorry, I just don't have the
EMS. I've got a pile-up on I80,
and four other
vehicles out on call.
Not one ambulance?
Let me be clear. This is
emergent. It's time-sensitive.
Honey, this ain't Hertz.
What about a police escort?
That can be arranged.
Of course. Why didn't you?
Don't wanna
ruin the festivities,
but if I could just get a few
minutes with my patient alone.
Mr. Wannamaker. Dr. Andrews.
How we doing today?
Incomplete.
Let's see what we can
do about that. Look here.
Well, looking not too bad,
considering we cut out a tumor
less than two weeks ago.
Yeah, I've been walking
around with a hole in my mouth.
You ever drink Scotch with a hole in
your mouth? Waste of good Scotch.
We needed to
give it time to heal.
Yeah, yeah, you told me.
Have you continued to smoke?
It constricts the vessels,
slows the healing.
I'm not a quitter.
We are going to graft
some skin from your leg,
and fix that cheek
up better than new.
I'm a real estate guy.
There's an old saying,
"You can have it fast,
you can have it good,
"you can have it
cheap. Pick two."
It's not gonna be cheap.
Yeah, I like doctors like
you. You're good. You know it.
Yes. It was harvested
before we got there.
We're waiting
for transportation.
The itinerary and life
clock have changed.
- Yeah, four hours and 14 minutes.
- Excuse me.
Are you talking to the hospital?
Have someone tell Dr. Glassman
that I might be late for our lunch.
Yeah. Okay.
So, how'd you know
about the weather?
Is it some kind of gift?
Come on, I gotta know.
What, Shaun Murphy is Zeus?
I watch The Weather Channel.
You my doctors?
Shaun? Shaun, we gotta go.
You're home.
Your dad and mom have had a
tough night with your brother and all.
Come on, let's go.
No.
No. No. He... He promised me!
He promised. He promised me!
He promised me! He promised me!
I think we'll get there much
quicker if we drive, Shaun.
Could you turn off
the flashers, please?
What's the patient's name?
- I told you, it's Chuck.
- No.
- No?
- No, the, the donor. What's his name?
What, the liver? Oliver?
Oliver.
Hey, you got a second?
What's up?
Just waiting on the liver.
Transplant. Everyone wants in.
They'd trade their
liver to do the liver.
Hey, look, you, you want some help
on this free-flap... What's his name?
- Wannamaker.
- Right.
You got the transplant, that
should keep any attending busy.
Well, I can make time.
Aoki come to you about this?
Look, I get it,
you're the chief...
That's right.
Look, this isn't a coup.
What is it?
It's about making
sure this hospital is first
on Wannamaker's donation list.
I'm aware of the stakes.
Thanks for coming by.
You know, it doesn't make
you any less of a surgeon
having me in there
as your second.
I'm the chief,
you're my attending.
Can't argue with that.
And we both know what your
presence in my OR will say.
That's not my intention.
It's the impact. Intention doesn't
matter. Thanks, but I'm good.
These can't be right.
Whatever it is, it's right.
Chuck's labs. It's got to be
a false flag, or a bad reading.
- For what?
- Medications? Foods? I don't know.
Look, if this is right,
we lose our transplant.
I'm sorry, that doesn't
change the results.
There's alcohol in his system.
He drank. The blood doesn't lie.
Run the lab again.
ETA to Saint Bonaventure?
Seventy minutes.
What are you looking
for? What do you see?
I have a girl neighbor.
Okay. Is she nice?
What does she do? Does
she have a boyfriend?
Do you know her name?
What the hell are you
looking for on the scans?
What... The
temperature is going up.
Officer, we need to find
a place with ice, like, now.
I tested it, Chuck,
and re-tested it.
Talk to me. You know
the six-month rule.
- Was it a craving, or...
- It was three days ago.
My daughter's graduation.
Nobody in my family
had ever gone to college.
There she was,
my little girl,
wearing the robes...
And for just that day, I...
I wanted to be normal.
So I had a glass of champagne.
You're out of ice?
It's broken. Supermarket's
about three miles down.
We don't have time. Right, okay.
The temperature's
already at 47 degrees.
We can't let it go any higher.
Are you gonna help me?
It's sweet. You'll like it.
What should I do with him?
Child Services are
down in Cheyenne.
That's 150 miles,
and they'll just turn me around
and send me back to the parents.
Parents don't want him?
I don't know. He
doesn't seem to want
the parents, that's for sure.
Could take him to the
hospital. Social worker there.
That won't work.
How do you know? Shaun?
You're right, it's
not working. Why?
Shaun! Are you
even listening to me?
Just one drink?
That's what he said.
Should I inform the registry?
How long ago did
Chuck have the drink?
Three days ago.
Give me a marker.
Units. Estimated
blood alcohol content...
What type of alcohol?
Champagne.
What percentage
of alcohol is that?
- I don't know. What's the difference?
- Take out your phone and look it up.
I don't know why
it's not working.
It needs to be
submerged to cool.
Hey! Every five
seconds is an XL.
Why did you answer me
last time? But not before?
Was it because I was angry?
Was it random? Why can't
you answer my questions?
This better work.
It will work.
You answer when I don't ask.
You don't like questions.
I don't.
I didn't do well in calculus.
This is algebra.
With his severe cirrhosis,
his alcohol clearance rate is
one milligram per deciliter per hour.
One drink, say, eight ounces...
It's champagne.
Six ounces, tops.
Play conservative.
Eight ounces results in
a blood alcohol level of
39 milligrams per deciliter.
One standard drink.
Well, the purpose of abstinence,
at least according to
the transplant registry, is?
Patients who kill their liver
due to excessive drinking
prove they can be sober.
Let me see that report.
Zero-point-zero-two.
Chuck was telling the truth.
He did just have the one drink.
He didn't fall off the wagon.
Corporate loves its data.
I'm not sure it'll actually
make a difference, but it
does give us an argument.
You're a genius.
You don't like
the cafeteria food?
They only make one thing well.
What does it say when the staff
sees the president of the hospital
not eating their cafeteria food?
Well, it says the
president of the hospital
isn't allowed in the kitchen.
You sat down. What
can I do for you?
I'd like your advice.
Really? Where's
Aoki? Did she die?
This was a mistake.
That's insulting. Sit down. At
least hear what I have to say,
and then decide
it's bad advice. Sit.
Aoki is pushing Melendez
on me for the VIP.
Ah. You didn't get the email
blast. Rich people aren't allowed
to die in this hospital.
You're not the young
star anymore, Melendez is.
I know that.
And you're upset
about the "why"?
"Why does Aoki think that?"
You should be asking, "Who?"
"Who?" I know who. Melendez.
"Who" are you? Are you a chief
who wants to be top surgeon,
or are you a chief who
wants to be president?
Because if it's the
latter, take your ego,
shove it in a cupboard somewhere,
and start acting presidential.
Dr. Kravitz, you have a
visitor in the main lobby.
Dr. Kravitz, a visitor
in the main lobby.
Dr. Melendez is going to argue
to the board that you get this liver.
I think it's a pretty
good argument.
Do I deserve it?
Um, I'm not sure
that's relevant.
You know, when you're dying,
and I've been
dying for a long time,
you start to think
about your life.
I haven't led a great one.
I could have been a
better dad, a better man.
Newsflash.
I drank too much.
You know, I also have a son.
Yeah. First marriage.
I haven't seen
him in three years.
Getting a liver's not
a second chance.
And it's not a reward
for being perfect.
It's just what we can do.
Maybe. But on the registry,
all of us wait in line together.
And I see these...
These people here, waiting.
I know their faces,
even their names.
They all have stories.
We're in it together.
And I...
I broke the...
Chuck? Chuck! Chuck!
Code blue! Chuck,
can you hear me?
We're in.
Yeah, he's got blood
in his esophagus.
He's got a variceal bleed.
All right. Saline wide open.
Type and cross four units.
I'm gonna band the vein.
Pressure's coming up.
- Chuck had a variceal bleed.
- I was in there.
Portal hypertension,
decompensated...
Are you finished? He's got
three months to live, maybe.
You have to be six months alcohol
free before you're registry-eligible.
And you said you
weren't good at math.
He gets this one or he dies.
Do you know what this
thing looks like at 8:00 a.m.?
I need a police escort
to work every morning.
280 South. Where all roads meet.
No, they don't.
What's wrong with him?
He's autistic, Officer.
What's that mean? Does
he need to be in a hospital?
The last place he
should be is a hospital.
What are you doing? Shaun?
What are you thinking?
Okay, this isn't a
question, I just...
I don't know what
you're looking for, Shaun.
Yes. I can feel it, it's firmer.
And? I don't know
what that means.
There must be a clot.
But there isn't a clot,
the scans show no clot.
That's because the scans were
taken before they harvested the liver.
Prior to the liver being flushed
with UW solution. It's dying.
To preserve the liver,
they replace all its blood
with a solution to protect
it from the cold storage.
But they must have left some
blood behind, which clotted.
- How long to Saint Bonaventure?
- Less than 30 minutes.
Can't wait. We have to
immediately remove the clot
and flush the left lobe to
protect it from the ice bath.
- Hey, we need to stop the car.
- Here?
Yes. Yes. We need to
operate, right here, right now.
Flushes from the
right. So, the left lobe,
starting at the
middle hepatic vein.
A less intrusive cut would
be along the falciform ligament
to allow access to Segment 3.
When you locate the blockage,
I'm gonna have to remove it.
I need a straw to
cannulate the vein, please.
There's a straw in my cup.
UW solution will
stabilize the cell walls...
And preserve the
integrity of the organ.
This is better than
having a baby in my car.
How are you feeling?
Like I'm writing a blank check.
You're gonna be fine.
You're the best.
This bleed, these varices...
This isn't good news.
It tells us that your liver failure
has progressed considerably.
How much?
You have two to three months.
We're getting the liver
today, in an hour. I don't get it.
You didn't tell them?
What?
Your father had a drink.
He had one glass.
Transplant registry doesn't
quantify things like that.
So he doesn't get the liver?
I'm gonna try
and get it for him.
What are you, a car salesman?
What, are you gonna try?
The final decision
is out of my hands.
And if you fail?
I'm gonna do
everything that I can.
I am meeting with the
committee in 10 minutes.
Excuse me.
I handed my dad the drink.
It doesn't matter
how it happened.
He didn't want it, he just
wanted to make me happy.
If you let him die, I will
have killed my father.
It was a glass. A glass of champagne
at his daughter's graduation.
I have the labs to prove it.
Chuck didn't fall off the wagon,
he had one drink.
He never went back.
The transplant registry guidelines
don't play in the gray for a reason.
Those guidelines are so arbitrary.
Have one drink and you die.
A couple pills of
ecstasy, no problem.
Hepatitis B from careless sexual
practice, no, nothing at all about that.
So, what do you want us
to do? Throw out the rules?
I want us not to hide behind
them. We do have a responsibility.
Without the rules, we're
playing God. We need the rules.
Does that help you
sleep better at night?
Yes, it does. We
have one liver today,
and 800 people
in this state need it.
I don't wanna be
haunted by the other 799.
Your guy hasn't earned it.
He knew the rules. And this...
It's a technicality.
No, the drink is a technicality.
Jessica, what's the
legal burden here?
Significant. If we move
forward with this transplant,
we could lose
privileges on the registry.
If it was discovered.
"If it were discovered"? How
narrow can you be about this?
Dr. Glassman,
where are you on this?
I can make a good
argument either way.
Go ahead. Please.
Better to remove the
arguments altogether.
What the hell is
he talking about?
The hell I'm talking about is that
we have a patient in this hospital
who needs a liver.
We also just happen to have
a liver that needs a patient.
It's not that simple.
It is that simple, if you consider
the patient. Rules are secondary.
But is saving this
patient worth the risk
of not being able to
save hundreds of others?
I don't have hundreds of
patients right now, I have one.
His name is Chuck.
Blood pressure steady.
Donor vessel to the facial artery,
and we're ready to close him up.
10-0 polypropylene
and vascular forceps.
Nice work, Dr. Andrews.
What do we have here?
A hematoma?
I can see that.
Let's find its source.
- Sponge, stick, and probe.
It's not my recipient artery.
Heart rate is dropping.
Whatever it is,
it's compressing his carotid.
I can't get deep enough
here. I need better access.
We'll move through zone
three from the outside.
Zone three's a minefield.
I'm aware, but
we need to do this.
Whatever you're
gonna do, do it quick.
It's strangling him
from the inside.
Get me Melendez.
We made it. Yeah. We're
here. Downstairs. Coming up.
No, no, no, no. Jared,
you're not gonna believe.
What... Yeah...
Got it.
Um...
Chuck's been moved
to the bottom of the list.
San Jose Presbyterian
are coming to get the liver.
- Oxygen sats tanking.
- Up him to 100% O2.
You have to go through
the mandible from the inside
while I probe for the
source. It's the only way.
Loupes.
We have to be
careful in there...
Or he'll get a stroke.
We'll just have
to be careful, then.
Give Dr. Melendez a
mandibular channel retractor
and Number 5 bone-cutter.
Number 5 bone-cutter.
Twenty-nine
minutes. It's a lifetime.
Thank you. This is amazing.
Gotta go, the whole team is waiting.
His name is Oliver.
It was a good day.
We saved a life...
Just not Chuck's.
You can still see
where the water was
In a line at the top
Of the chimney bricks
It's not your fault.
I want to believe that.
So we saved a few
things That were spared
- Hi.
And brought it to the ground
'Cause you always build it
better The second time around
Hi.
Hello.
Are you a lab guy or something?
- I'm a surgeon.
- That's insane.
May I have my batteries back?
The ones you borrowed.
Yep.
You can still see
where the water was
There you go.
In a line at the top
Of the chimney bricks
What's your name?
I'm Lea.
I'm Dr. Shaun Murphy.
Nice to meet you.
So we saved a few
things That were spared
And brought it to the ground
Cause you always build it
better The second time around
I drove past the place
Where we used to live
Where you said you
never wanted kids
Sometimes, something so
broken Can never be fixed
You'll stay with me tonight.
And tomorrow, we'll
figure out the rest.
You always build it better
The second time around