Previously on The Good Doctor...
Dr. Coyle. He's
a little too friendly.
I'm sure he's just trying
to establish a rapport.
I give great massages.
And I'll make a killer
omelette in the morning.
That's really
inappropriate. I said no.
You're approaching
insubordination.
You have to file a
complaint with HR.
They will shift the blame
onto me. Like you did.
I've just been fired for physically
assaulting an employee.
So, why do I need to quit
my job to have a family?
Agreed. She can be a great
lawyer and a great mom.
I don't wanna have kids.
I don't need a therapist.
I want to make my own decisions.
I am done talking. Now let's go.
Okay. No. I don't want help!
Where would he go? Is there
a place he likes to hang out?
No. He's not at the hospital.
And there used to be a picture
here. It means he's not coming back.
Hi. Good morning. I'm Aaron
Glassman, Dr. Glassman.
I work with Shaun.
Hi. Nice to meet you.
It's nice to meet you, too.
May I speak with him, please?
Uh, Shaun isn't here.
I know you've been helping
Shaun, and I appreciate that.
But I really need to speak
with him immediately.
I'll definitely let him
know when I see him next.
- I'm sorry.
- What the hell are you doing?
Come on, I know you're in
here. I just wanna talk. Please.
You are way out of line.
Shaun, you have responsibilities.
We've gotta sort this out.
I'll give you five seconds
to get the hell out of here...
- Shaun?
- Or I'm calling the police.
Shaun, I just want...
Five...
Shaun?
Shaun, she's calling the police.
- Is that what you want?
- Four, three...
- Two, one...
- Okay, okay.
Okay, okay, I'm leaving.
It's just that Shaun has a
tendency to run away from conflict.
And in Casper and medical school
people will give you a
little bit of slack, but he...
Now he's in a very hard-to-get job
in a very competitive environment
where people do not
give you a second chance.
Still. Not cool.
If you speak with him,
will you call me, please?
Out.
Yeah.
So, what's your plan now?
I don't know.
I gotta say, he seems
like a nebby old jerk.
And a bully.
What's "nebby"?
Nosy. It's a Pittsburgh thing.
I mean, you're a grown man.
If you don't wanna talk to
him, it's none of his business.
San Jose is too big.
I get not liking San Jose.
I'm not the biggest
fan myself, but...
I don't wanna see a therapist.
So, don't.
I should go back to Casper.
I have a rule.
Never make an important decision
while you are angry, upset, high,
or right before, or after having sex.
Okay? You are overworked,
stressed out and
pissed off at your boss.
Now is not the time to
be making a big decision.
You need to take a
break, clear your head.
You need a vacation.
I have to work five more
months before I earn a vacation.
So, call in sick.
I'm not sick.
You're so adorable.
You don't have to
be sick to call in sick.
I have so much to
teach you, Grasshopper.
And I'm gonna start with a
good old-fashioned road trip.
It's the perfect way
to get your mojo back.
And when we return,
you're gonna know exactly
what to do about San Jose,
therapy, and Glassy the Grouch.
And all you have to do to attain
this superior wisdom and knowledge
is to call
in sick.
Okay. Okay, I will.
Dr. Melendez.
Got a case for you.
My schedule's
pretty packed today.
It's a patient of mine. She
needs a kidney transplant.
You have a donor?
Her identical twin. A
perfect DNA match.
Why is she a patient of yours?
I put balloon tissue expanders
under both girls' scalps
to prepare them for
the separation surgery.
Separation surgery?
It's in six months, after they
recover from the transplant.
Of course, if you're too busy...
No, I'm in.
Where's Murphy?
He's not here yet.
Wrong day to be late.
We're already short-handed.
Actually, I wanted
to talk to you about...
I did not fire Kalu.
If you have a problem
with it, talk to Andrews.
Although if you want my advice,
don't have a problem with it.
Andrews is waiting to
brief us on a new case.
It's a kidney transplant
on craniopagus twins.
Conjoined?
They're connected at the skull,
their entire renal-vascular
systems are interdependent.
Cool.
Hey. Have either of
you talked to Shaun?
No. DR. MELENDEZ: No.
Which isn't unusual.
Is anything wrong?
No, no, not with Shaun.
It's a family emergency.
He's gonna be
out for a few days.
He's supposed to get approval
for any personal days
from his attending.
Right. Which is
why I'm checking in.
I think he thought it was
enough just to notify me.
You call in sick?
I'm ready to go.
No, you're not.
You're gonna need more than
a family photo and a toothbrush.
- Go pack.
- Where are we going?
- Wherever the car takes us.
- I don't like the beach.
Okay, I will let the car know.
Even with your
cardiovascular issues,
a kidney transplant is a
relatively safe procedure,
especially since,
with identical twins,
there's no chance
for organ rejection.
Just make sure you keep
straight which one's which.
The charming, pretty
one has the good kidneys.
Don't worry, we
always triple-confirm.
And we put
everything in writing.
- And you're both charming and pretty.
- Mmm-hmm.
It was a joke, Mom.
And smart. They're gonna
be Ivy Leaguers in the fall.
- Yale and Harvard.
- Wow.
Mom, you don't have to tell everyone
you meet where we're going to college.
- Yes, I do.
- That's awesome. Congratulations.
So, who's going where?
What do you think?
She's totally obnoxious
and thinks she's way
funnier than she is.
- Definitely Harvard.
- Mmm-hmm.
Hey. Don't make me
start mocking your tattoo.
I thought you would have your
entire apartment strapped to your back.
- It takes me a long time to pack.
- That's good.
An anal-retentive packer
is the exact type of person
I'd want operating on me.
Lea, this is your car.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. We're
gonna take my other one.
Okay. What do you do at work?
Do you really care what I do?
Or do you just wanna
know how someone
with such a crappy
apartment can afford two cars?
I just wanna know how
you can afford two cars.
Hmm.
Yeah, I can't.
My Grandpa Rod died last year
and he left me his
most prized possession.
It's the Striped Tomato.
Oh, my God. You like
Starsky and Hutch?
It's okay.
A meticulous packer and
a Starsky and Hutch fan.
Grandpa Rod would've loved you.
Okay, this is it. The road.
You sure you wanna do this?
Speak now or forever
hold your peace.
I'm sure.
Let's go, Lea.
Here we go!
I hear Murphy's AWOL.
He's taking a few personal days.
- Unapproved personal days.
- I approved them.
It's not your job
to approve them.
Or to say you approved
them to cover up the fact
that Murphy's frequent tardiness
has escalated to absences.
What do you want me
to do? Take a polygraph?
How about we jump into
enhanced interrogation?
Here, how about this? Do
you want me to turn this on?
When the Board was
reconsidering your hiring of Murphy,
you assured us that if he was
anything less than excellent,
he'd be dismissed
and you would resign.
I trust you remember that.
I wouldn't have your movers
pack up your office just yet.
You can't protect
Murphy forever.
At some point, he needs to
succeed or fail on his own.
Okay, that's three hours
on the warm ischemia clock
of the transplanted kidney.
Ureter is attached
to the bladder.
How's the kidney's
placement in the iliac fossa?
No kinking or twisting
of the renal vessel.
Good.
You ready to close?
Yes.
Your best bet is a
continuous suture
along the fascial layer.
Suture.
Donor's pressure's dropping.
Okay, up the oxygen.
Jenny must be
bleeding internally.
We're gonna have to open
her back up. Staple-remover.
I like trees.
Yeah? What else do you like?
Besides reading medical journals
and watching reruns of old cop shows.
I like you.
Well, who wouldn't?
I'm very likeable.
Why don't you like San Jose?
Everyone's so competitive here.
You know, if you didn't make a
million by 30, you're a total loser.
I don't need a million dollars.
I don't even think I
need 90,000, but...
You know what we both
need are some tunes.
What's your preferred
driving music?
Music? No. I don't
like music. No...
What? No, no. Not okay.
Okay, I will give you a
pass on not liking the beach
because you're cute
and I might need you
to do brain surgery
on me someday,
but not liking
music, unacceptable.
- I won't have it.
- Are you being sarcastic?
No, I am being...
I actually don't
know the word for it,
but my point stands.
Music is amazing.
You know, I remember
every important thing
that has ever happened to me
based on what song I
was listening to at the time.
I remember smells.
Like our parking garage
smells like fabric-softener.
And when my brother died,
it smelled like burnt food.
Oh, my God. I'm so
sorry. I had no idea.
How did he...
If you don't mind me asking?
My father was mean.
He killed my pet, so my
brother and I, we ran away.
Then he fell off a train
we were playing on,
hit his head and died.
I never went back home.
Dr. Glassman has watched
out for me ever since.
Okay, so, maybe he's not
that much of a nebby jerk.
What are you smelling right now?
Pine trees.
I'm never gonna forget
that when you told me
about your brother and your
dad, it smelled like pine trees.
But I don't want
you to ever forget
that right after you told
me, we were listening to...
No. Do not remember that.
- Or that.
- No, thank you.
Nope. Not feeling it.
Ooh.
So good.
This is the one
you will not forget.
- Do not forget this.
- Okay.
I drank the whole moon dry
Because all my friends are metalheads
Swear they'd never catch us dead
Split up when the police come
Yeah, running
used to get me high
Now I only feel tired
Jenny had a post-op
renal vein rupture.
We were able to repair it
before she lost too much blood.
But both your vitals
are stable now.
And Katie's new kidney
is functioning well.
Thank God.
Will her ruptured vein have any
effect on our separation surgery?
It better not.
Katie, I love you, but if I have
to spend one minute more
than I have to watching you
practicing some Mozart song...
They're not songs,
they're concertos.
Don't worry, six
months is still the plan.
Look, what I did was
incredibly unprofessional
and just inexcusable.
But I'm guessing you're
gonna give one anyway.
No.
No, just an explanation,
and a request.
It could help me to convince
Andrews I deserve a second chance.
Okay.
Let's hear the explanation.
Dr. Browne and I
are seeing each other.
Look, if you could just
put yourself in my shoes.
A woman I care about
tells me a guy harassed her.
And even worse, she tells me
it's my fault because I was too...
Too stupidly insensitive to
understand what she was going through.
I felt like crap.
And like an idiot,
I tried to make it up to her.
All I'm asking for is just
a little understanding.
Wouldn't you have
done the same thing?
Not my problem.
- Yeah?
- Jenny's bradycardic and hypotensive.
- What's happening?
- She was fine a minute ago.
We were talking and then she
started to have trouble breathing.
Jenny's heart is failing.
No pulse.
She's in V-tach. Grab
the cart. Page Melendez.
Jenny's stable. I have her on
beta blockers and vasodilators.
It's not gonna be enough.
The renal vein rupture
must've caused her
already weak
heart to deteriorate.
She's in end-stage failure.
I'll get her on the
transplant registry.
What are we talking,
months? Weeks?
Days.
We're not gonna find a
donor heart in a few days.
We could disconnect
her from the other body
her heart is partially
oxygenating the blood for.
It was already
pushing the envelope
to do the separation surgery six
months after a kidney transplant.
You really think they can
handle it one day after?
It may be our only choice.
Yeah.
His calls are an even
bigger buzzkill than this rain.
And defeating the
whole purpose of this trip.
Okay.
Residents are not supposed
to turn off their phones.
How about we make a deal?
If you turn off your
phone, I'll let you drive.
I don't have a driver's license.
I know.
I've always wanted
to learn to drive.
- I know.
- Dr. Glassman,
- he never wanted me to.
- I know.
Actually, I didn't know that,
but that definitely
sounds like Glassy.
- Okay.
- Yeah.
You're doing awesome.
You're a natural.
Thank you. I think so, too.
Blinker.
All right. Now,
make this left turn.
Okay, don't circle this time.
Just keep going straight.
- What are you stopping for?
- You want me to go out on the street?
It's where the car wants to go.
Come on. What's the worst
thing that could happen?
I could run over
someone and kill them.
You have autism, you're not
blind. And I'll be right here with you.
Mmm-hmm.
Half Dome, here we come.
Can I turn on the radio?
- No. No, thank you.
- Okay. Okay.
We believe moving up
the separation surgery
will lighten the load
on Jenny's heart,
maybe allow it to recover a bit
so a transplant won't even
be necessary in the future.
It is higher risk for Katie now,
given that her new kidney
is still not fully functional.
What do you think we should do?
It's your bodies, your decision.
- Mom, stop it.
- No, I'm serious.
I raised you both to be
strong and independent.
And you are.
So, whatever you
decide, I'll support.
Let's do it.
Go ahead, chop us in half.
Katie?
We obviously need
both your consent.
Okay.
You sure? You wanna talk
more? Have any questions?
No. I'm good, let's do it.
- I want a car.
- So, get one.
You've been driving a half-hour
and you're already better than
half the people in San Jose.
I get distracted when I'm alone.
That's why I miss
my bus sometimes.
Dr. Glassman thinks I'd
do the same thing driving.
He's probably right.
Wanna have some fun?
I'm already having fun.
- Stop the car.
- Why?
Just do it.
Thank you.
Don't worry, we're the only
car on the road right now.
Put your left foot on the brake.
- Okay.
- There we go.
Hold it all the way
down. There you go.
Okay, now floor the
gas with your right foot.
- No, I don't know about this.
- No, it's okay, it's okay.
Now slowly ease your
left foot off the brake.
Until you hear this.
I smell smoke.
Yeah, that's the point,
Shaun. It's burning rubber.
Do it again.
Okay.
Now, this is fun.
Okay, that's enough.
We need some rubber
left to get us home.
I am burning rubber.
- Okay, Shaun, it's time to stop.
- Okay.
Shaun, take your
other foot off the gas!
Shaun, look out!
It's the other foot! Other...
It's the other foot!
Dr. Ko and I have
been working for months
to map the structure of
Jenny and Katie's brain.
Don't you mean brains?
Actually, while different regions
operate independently for each sister,
there is a single brain mass.
That's why all their
previous neurosurgeons
insisted separation
was impossible.
The real problem won't
be dividing their brains,
but dividing their veins.
They share a single
sagittal sinus vein.
Which we'll give to Jenny.
Then we'll create a new one for
Katie using a grafted vein from her leg.
Nice. You've gotten
them up to speed fast.
Well, with six months
of prep to do in 12 hours,
it was our only choice.
So, let's get started.
- I crashed.
- We didn't.
Yes, I crashed. I hit something.
I hit something. I
did. I hit something.
- I know I did. I felt it. I crashed.
- Shaun, you didn't crash,
- you just drove off the road.
- No.
- No, you're wrong.
- And it was totally my fault.
- I hit something.
- No, you didn't.
- I felt it. I crashed. I crashed.
- Look at me. Calm down.
- Okay. Okay.
- Calm. Look at me. Look at me.
Breathe. Whatever
happened, whatever you felt,
you did nothing wrong.
It was all my fault. Okay?
Okay. Dr. Glassman,
he was right.
I should not be
allowed to drive.
No, no.
Shaun?
No, I'm not going
to drive, thank you.
Yeah, I know. No one is.
'Cause you were right,
we did hit something.
Everything is
still looking good.
If you need anything
during the night,
just press your call button.
- Is Jenny asleep?
- Yeah.
Where's Dr. Andrews?
He is with Dr. Ko
and Dr. Melendez.
They're working to finalize the
surgical protocol for tomorrow.
I need to talk to him.
Is there anything I can do?
I changed my mind.
I don't wanna do the
separation surgery.
I'll go find him right away.
I understand she's scared,
but without this surgery,
there is a good
chance both of them die.
- Have you talked to the mother?
- She refuses to weigh in,
insists it's their decision.
Let me try and talk to her.
I don't think
that's a good idea.
You invented the technique
you're gonna use to separate them.
So?
So, she's not even
close to objective.
Okay, now is not the time
to be worrying about lawsuits.
That's my job.
And our job is saving
these girls' lives.
Okay. Take it easy. We're
all on the same team here.
- I'll talk to her.
- You've already talked to her.
I will try again.
Browne should do it.
Me?
We need someone that
an 18-year-old girl trusts.
She's also the best
communicator out of all of us.
Okay.
We'll give Katie the
night to think it over.
Browne, you'll talk
to her in the morning,
get her to consent
to this surgery.
And if I'm not able to do that?
It's not a big deal.
Cars break. That's why
God makes mechanics.
And booze.
- Two shots of tequila, please.
- You got it.
I'm not thirsty.
You don't drink tequila
because you're thirsty.
Have you ever been drunk?
Never?
Eight years of college
and not one frat party?
Tailgating?
Your roommate's 21st birthday?
What is your job?
Now you're interested in my job?
Yes.
I'm an automotive engineer.
I work for a start-up that's
developing new designs
for self-driving cars.
Do you like it?
No.
I like to build things.
Not sit in endless meetings
talking about building things.
Thank you.
Perfect timing.
We are supposed to
be forgetting about work.
For living happy, because
you're a long time dead.
It's good.
Oh, my God.
You have to be the
first person in history
to actually like their
first tequila shot.
It's good.
- Do you want another?
- Okay.
Tequila. Stat.
Yes.
What?
Sorry, I just zoned out.
We should break this off.
There's only so much
studying you can do.
Do you want kids?
Sorry, that's none
of my business.
No, it's...
It's just not a question
I was expecting.
Jessica just told
me she doesn't.
Ever.
- Wow.
- It doesn't make any sense.
She would be such
an amazing mother.
I guess she's lucky she
realized before it's too late.
Some women don't.
My mom was
definitely one of those.
- Sorry, I didn't mean to...
- No. It's okay.
Water under the bridge
that nearly drowned me.
It was a long time ago.
I don't know what to do.
I can't imagine
my life without her.
But I also can't
imagine a life without...
I'm sorry.
Again, this is not your problem.
- It's okay.
- Go. Goodbye.
Finding someone you
can't imagine a life without,
it's hard.
I know it's a
cliché, but it is true.
Good night.
Islands in the stream
That is what we are
No one in between
How can we be wrong?
Sail away with me
To another world
And we rely on each other
From one lover to another
I can't live without you
I love you.
I love you, too.
So, I will volunteer
with foster kids,
coach youth sports.
There are other ways
that I can be a father figure
without actually being a father.
In one day, I taught you
how to play hooky from work,
how to drive, how to drink
and how to totally rock
the house in karaoke.
No. You did not teach
me to drive very well at all.
- At all. I crashed.
- Oh! How dare you?
No, you didn't crash. You hit a
rock that should not have been there.
The whole point of a road
shoulder is to provide a buffer zone.
Who the hell designs a buffer zone
with a huge rock in it? You know?
They should be fired.
Okay. Hold it
right there, partner.
I got one more
thing to teach you.
- What is it?
- The proper way to end a date.
Tell me you hope I
had a good time tonight.
Go ahead.
I hope you had a
good time tonight.
I did. I had a very
nice time tonight.
You're really fun
to sing karaoke with.
Now tell me I'm really fun, too,
and that you hope we
can do it again soon.
You're really fun, too.
- Thank you.
- I hope that we can do it again soon.
Now open the door for me.
Now, if I just walk in,
don't bother trying
for a second date.
It's a swing and a miss. Not a
big deal. Happens to everyone.
But if I don't walk in,
if I just stand
there in front of you
like I don't really
want to go inside,
like I'm doing right now,
then you have to kiss me.
Kiss me, Shaun.
Have you ever done that before?
No. No, no, no.
Well, you're pretty good at
it. You wanna do it again?
Yes, but...
But what?
I know it's frightening. You've
already been through so much.
I'm not scared. I just think,
what if this is how
we're meant to be?
Maybe we're better as one.
I grew up in a trailer,
with my mom telling me every
day that I was no better than her,
and that I would never do
anything, I'd never be anyone.
And I...
I hated being there.
But when I finally left,
walking out of the dirty,
disgusting double-wide
was the hardest
thing I've ever done.
Wait, so am I the awful mom
or the disgusting
trailer in this story?
Um...
It's amazing what you've
accomplished so far. It really is.
But you can be so much more.
And with the freedom
to just finally be yourself.
Just yourself.
I've never seen it that way.
Katie's back on board.
Told you.
She's very persuasive.
Shaun?
I feel disgusting.
You're just hungover.
You are never gonna want
me to kiss you ever again.
If I had brushed my teeth
before I rushed out here,
I'd ask you to do
it again, right now.
Why are you so hard on yourself?
I'm sure you got made fun
of a lot when you were a kid.
And that leaves a mark, I know.
But you gotta shake it
off. Rub some dirt on it.
You're never gonna be happy
if you constantly live in fear.
- We need to talk.
- Look, I have nothing to say to you.
Well, then you can just listen.
You are not a victim.
Not even close.
But you will be unless you
convince Andrews to reinstate Jared.
Are you threatening me?
No, I'm just informing
you that there is no way
that I am the only resident
that you tried to intimidate
into having sex with you.
And I will make it my mission
in life to find every single one
and get them to file a
complaint against you,
unless Jared gets his job back.
And what makes you so sure
Andrews cares what I have to say?
I'm not. But either
Jared's career gets saved
or yours gets destroyed.
Either way is a win for me.
Fifteen blade.
Removing the first
balloon tissue expander.
One down. Five to go.
Hi, Shaun.
It's me again. Um...
You know, Dr. Andrews has
never really been in your corner
and your absence is
causing a real problem.
Please call me
before it's too late.
Or at least call me and
let me know where you are,
'cause I'm worried.
The Cavitron allows us to use
a low-frequency sound wave
to separate them,
so we don't damage the
healthy tissue in the process.
I still can't tell where Katie
starts and Jenny ends.
Imaging is a huge help,
but once a patient is opened,
it's kind of like backcountry skiing.
It's never the same on top.
What you want to focus on
is the terrain you
know is underneath.
Here, here we are
And all we got, we
had from the start
So get up, get up,
get up and go on...
Cut.
Okay. Grafted
sagittal is in place.
Let's remove the clamps.
Hey.
Looks good. No leaks.
Now the moment of truth.
Scissors.
Dr. Ko, would you
like to do the honors?
Definitely.
So get up, get up,
get up and go on
Can we get a little more room?
Coming right up.
Just a little belief to
shake off the doubt
And then there were two.
It's building up
It's been building
up for so long
Thanks for taking
me on a road trip.
I feel a lot better.
I think I'm ready to
talk to Dr. Glassman.
Yeah. I feel much better, too.
And ready to talk to my boss.
What do you have to
talk to your boss about?
He offered me a promotion.
Will you be making
a million dollars?
Very funny.
I make 70,000 now, and
the new position pays 90,
but I'm not gonna take it.
Why not? It pays $20,000 more.
Yeah, I get the math,
Shaun. But just taking this trip,
and you, have inspired
me to do something
that I've been thinking
about for a really long time,
but I've just been
too scared to do it.
I'm gonna quit my job.
You're so silly. What would
you do during the day?
Rebuild old cars.
No more conference calls. No
more never-ending meetings.
The only thing I'm not
looking forward to is moving.
Why would you move?
Because that's where the
shop that I'm gonna work at is.
I got the Striped Tomato,
my brother Donny got
Grandpa Rod's shop
in Hershey, Pennsylvania.
It's been over a year, but
every time I drive his car,
I keep thinking,
you know, I don't need a more
impressive title or a million dollars.
He would take me fishing
in Alaska every summer,
skiing every winter break.
I haven't taken more than one day
off in four years because I always work.
It never stops.
And just taking
this trip with you
made me realize I...
I want to enjoy my life,
you know?
Okay, what? Say something.
You're...
- Hello?
- Jared,
this is Dr. Andrews.
Do you have a moment?
Yeah, of course.
Dr. Coyle approached me today.
He told me that he feels awful
about the way he treated Dr. Browne
and how it came to affect you.
And he asked me to
reconsider your termination.
You should also know that Dr. Melendez
spoke in support of you as well.
Thank you for letting me know.
I was impressed by the
integrity you demonstrated
by taking full responsibility
for your actions.
And I'm certainly
willing to make that clear
to any administrators
at another hospital
if you'd need me as a reference.
But I won't reinstate you.
Physical assault is a line
I'm just not willing
to let anyone cross.
I understand.
I'm sorry.
Take care.
When will they wake up?
They should've already.
Shaun?
Shaun.
Our sharp teeth
are the only light
I drank the whole moon dry
Because all my friends are metalheads
Swear they'd never catch us dead
Split up when the police come
Yeah, running
used to get me high
Now I only feel tired