Every cell in the human body
regenerates, on average,
every seven years.
Like snakes...
in our own way,
we shed our skin.
Biologically, we're
brand-new people.
Are you visiting
Seattle for the first time?
Oh, no, no. I live in Seattle.
I just went home for a month.
I took my son to see my parents.
Oh. What do you do in Seattle?
Uh, I'm a surgeon.
Uh, uh, did you know
any of those doctors...
from that shooting?
We may look the
same. We probably do.
The change isn't visible...
at least not in most of us.
But we're all changed...
completely...
forever.
But that's normal.
I mean, it's a biological
imperative, change.
So the shooting
changed me. I'm changed.
But I'm also ready
to get back to work.
I mean, as ready
as any of us are.
Sitting around the house,
waiting...
I just spend my time worrying.
Your husband was shot.
That's a lot to worry about.
I'm worried about Cristina.
She's getting married,
and that's just...
Well, I had to cut her out
of her last wedding dress
with scissors, so...
You watched your
husband get shot.
He's fine. He's coming
back to work today, actually.
We're all fine.
Uh, ex... Excuse me.
Is everything OK, Dr. Grey?
Yes. Yes. Everything's fine.
Opening two.
It doesn't look too bad.
You just gotta
keep an eye on it,
make sure it doesn't
get any bigger.
But if it changes color,
you should see a doctor.
Dr. Shepherd.
Your lady looks pissed.
Again, Derek?
Whew.
What?
Nothin'. Just... you're awesome.
Chief.
Oh, Dr. Bailey. Welcome back.
- Thank you, sir.
- We missed you here.
The place isn't the... same.
Did you get cleared for surgery?
What do you mean, "cleared for
surgery"? Who has to clear me?
Well, the next time,
I'll leave you there.
- You said that already.
- Oh, Derek got arrested again.
- Meredith...
- Reckless endangerment.
- Please.
- Did he lose his license yet?
Oh, no, because they don't charge
him, because the cops worship him.
Because I saved
some of their lives.
What are we picking?
Dress color. I'm
not wearing white.
It's sexist and...
vaguely racist.
No white, no veil, no rice.
Well, what will your mother say?
No mother.
I didn't get
cleared for surgery,
and I'm pretty
sure it's your fault.
- Meredith, I am the chief. I can overrule the counselor.
- You can?
- Yes.
- I love the blue.
- Chief Shepherd, you're back.
- Good morning.
I found a giant skull
base chordoma.
- Biggest one I've ever seen.
- Really?
- Kid came in to the E.R. with trouble breathing.
- You got cleared for surgery?
- I did.
- Bitch.
- I like the brown, too.
- I know it looks inoperable.
I mean, I would've
said it was inoperable,
- but you're back
and you're you.
- Right.
Hey, uh, yes, good morning.
Thank you. Thank you very much.
Good. Thank you.
Thank you very much.
It's, uh, it's great to
be back. First of all,
I'd like to thank Dr. Webber for
stepping up in my absence. Thank you.
I'm grateful for all of
you, for all of your support
during my recovery. Thank you.
Uh, it's just, uh, so
great to be back as chief.
I'm grateful for the, uh...
I'm sorry. That's a lie.
That's what people say,
and, uh, the truth is...
I hate being chief. I hate it.
Chief Webber...
Chief Webber is our chief.
Um...
and I'm sorry, but this giant...
Sorry, I gotta go
look at this chordoma.
I, um, I'm sorry, but...
I quit.
- Let's go, Kepner. Come on.
- Oh, sorry. OK.
He just quit.
He was supposed to
clear me for surgery.
Yeah.
The bullet's at the surface.
That's good. I
can take it out now.
Nah. I mean, if it's not
infected, I'm gonna keep it.
It's my war wound.
Besides... chicks dig that crap.
Oh, my God.
- Mm-hmm.
- Wow. You weren't kidding.
The last surgeon broke the dura,
which enabled the tumor
to mushroom into the brain
- and down into the spine.
- It's wrapped around
his brain stem.
Whatever we do, we
need to do it quickly.
The size of this thing...
Normally, I open up the
sinuses or the hard palate.
Well, now you have
to open up both.
You want me to split
his whole face open?
Sinuses, hard
palate, tongue, jaw...
A broken jaw is excruciating,
let alone the rest of it.
Does this kid know
what he's in for?
He wants to live. I don't think
he's concerned about the pain.
Well, but you don't know
how enmeshed the tumor is.
- You don't even know
if you can get it all.
- Thank you, Dr. Grey.
You want to try this thing, Torres
and I are gonna need to coordinate.
What are we thinking, a week?
No later.
I'll clear my schedule.
- Welcome back, Dr. Shepherd.
- Thank you, Dr. Torres.
You're not even
cleared for surgery yet.
I'll get cleared.
Hey, hey, hey.
Uh, Dr. Grey.
Chief Webber.
Yeah, a little...
little exercise.
OK.
Mm. Something I can do for you?
Yeah. Um, that stupid
counselor Perkins,
he won't clear me for surgery.
- So I was just wondering...
- No.
- But he cleared...
- I'm... I'm sorry. I am.
But we brought in the best,
and when Andrew Perkins
says you're not cleared,
then it's him you
need to talk to.
Yeah, yeah.
Did you hear that Dr. Yang
and Dr. Hunt are getting married?
- I did.
- It's pretty great, huh?
It's almost like
a silver lining.
You know, I... I've
read a lot about trauma
and how, uh, sometimes people
just up and change their lives.
They say that the trauma
was the best thing that
could've happened to them.
You know, like
Dr. Shepherd this morning.
Did you hear that
he's not chief anymore?
And how have you been, Dr. Grey?
You've been through a
lot since I last saw you.
Does, uh, anyone
have anything to say?
I know that, uh, a lot of you
are only here because
this has been mandated.
So let's talk.
Anything at all?
I ate a really good taco
from one of those trucks
by the side of the road.
- When?
- Last night. You were asleep.
- Which truck? The one on 7th?
- I want to go. I like tacos.
- Me, too.
- I read a book...
about the history of
mass murders in the U.S.
That's... that's the actual
name of what happened to us.
It was a mass murder. You
can't call it a terrorist attack,
because the murders
weren't political in nature.
And we weren't the
victims of a serial killer,
because Mr. Clark would've
had to murder several people
over a period longer than
30 days in order to qualify
as a serial killer. We
could call it a spree killing...
which is defined as killings
at two or more locations
with no break or
pause in between,
because Mr. Clark shot that
guy in his car before he got here.
But I'm not sure that that
counts as a true second location
since it was so
close to the hospital,
which means that we
were a mass murder,
because it happened at
one place, by one person,
and more than four
people were killed.
Oh, that was quite
a show this morning.
I didn't plan it.
Made it better. Any regrets?
No. Any regrets about
proposing to Cristina?
None.
Getting shot turns out to
not be the worst thing after all.
I need a best man.
I... I know...
I know we're not
that close, but...
I don't know. You being
married to the other twisted sister,
I... I just thought it...
It kinda made us like
brothers or something.
- I'd be honored. It's an honor.
- Thank you.
- You need a bachelor party?
- No, no, no.
Even better.
On the, uh, day of the shooting,
I understand that you had
a particularly difficult day.
On the day I gave
birth to my son,
my husband had a car crash,
and he needed a craniotomy,
and he almost died on
Derek Shepherd's table.
Now that was a
particularly difficult day.
And at the end of that
day, my son was born,
and my husband lived.
But at the end of this day...
the, uh...
Unh!
No! No!
Um... this day
was the worst day of my life.
Miranda.
I'm sorry. I didn't mean to...
No, you... you don't just
sneak up on people. OK?
- You don't...
- I got these.
I was, um, I was playing golf.
My phone was off, and I'm...
You know, 18 people got
shot, 11 died, one in my arms.
A boy died in my arms,
and you were playing golf.
- OK.
- Bailey...
We gotta go.
Well, where... where you going?
Home, uh, to my mom. Right?
Yeah? We're gonna
go see Grandma?
Yeah, Tuck. Here you go.
When you coming back?
OK, here, here. Here's your car.
Miranda... when are
you coming back?
OK, OK, OK, OK.
OK, Tuck.
No. No.
M... mom.
You're talking about
slicing his face in half,
breaking his jaw,
cutting his tongue.
It's just... It just
sounds crazy.
I know.
I wish I could offer some
comfort, but honestly,
there's no comfort that can
be offered in this situation.
Let me just say that...
every medical advancement
started with the statement,
"That sounds crazy."
Let me try.
Donna, let me help.
OK. Let's try.
Let's... OK.
Good. OK.
He could not wake up.
He could... wake up...
and never be able to move again.
He could go blind.
He could lose his
ability to speak or to eat.
He could require
around-the-clock care
for the rest of his life.
He could be in a
tremendous amount of pain
for the rest of his life.
He could die on the table.
If that doesn't happen, if
none of those things happen,
he's still facing months
of excruciatingly painful
recovery from this surgery.
And before you make a decision,
you need to
understand the risks.
You're driving awfully
fast, Dr. Shepherd.
The least you could
do is wear a seat belt.
You've been working.
In the clinic, in the pit.
We haven't been
allowed to operate,
which makes zero
sense if you ask me.
I'd like to, uh, talk to you
about the incident last week.
She's not my responsibility.
- She was your girlfriend.
- Well, she's not anymore.
Karev, give me another suture.
My patient didn't
bring her meds.
She doesn't even
know their names.
I... if I give her albuterol
and she's on propanolol,
then she'll stop breathing.
If... if I give her warfarin
and she's on ibuprofen, then
she'll... then she'll bleed out.
If I give her diphenhydramine and
she's on doxepin, then she'll die.
- So do... do... do
you think she wants to die?
- Is she kidding?
- Karev, what's going on
over there?
- I think that she wants to die.
I think she wants
me to kill her.
Do... do you... do you...
do you want me to kill you?
Because you... you
could just get a gun,
- and it would be a lot faster.
- Karev, get her outta here.
You know what? So why
doesn't somebody find a gun...
- and we'll bring her a gun
and just shoot her...
- Karev, help her.
I can't step away.
Get her out of here!
- Help! Somebody find her a gun
'cause she wants to die!
- I got my own stuff to do.
Somebody find something!
Why did you walk away?
Look, life is too short.
I almost died trying
to stop that guy.
Besides, I mean...
you know how much
tail you get offered
when you're carrying a
bullet around in your chest?
It's like I'm a legend.
Are you, uh...
always this crass,
or is that a defense mechanism?
I've had too much
crazy for one lifetime.
You cleared Lexie
Grey for surgery?
Dr. Sloan, I'm
in... I'm in session.
I had to check her
into psych last week.
I had to commit
her against her will!
And you just clear
her for surgery?
What the hell kind
of doctor are you?
It's OK. You can talk to him.
- I'll come back.
- Yeah, walk away.
You're good at that.
She got snowed.
Psych put her on heavy doses
of antipsychotics and benzos.
And then she slept for
almost 50 hours straight.
When she woke up,
she was no longer a
risk to herself or others.
I mean, she has
P.T.S.D. Most of you do.
For her, it caused
severe sleep deprivation
and led to a breakdown.
All she needed was sleep.
So protocol is that
she goes back to work.
See?
I'm OK.
Really. I'm back.
Clamp.
So how are you? I
hear there's a guy.
Yeah, there's a guy.
Mm. That good?
Shut up.
I need another clamp.
So... you're getting married.
I am. I am getting married.
I'm happy for you.
I am, really.
- Really?
- Yeah.
- Thank you.
- Good.
I dig weddings. I do a
mean chicken dance.
Oh, there will be
no chicken dance.
And if you start a conga line,
I will physically throw you out.
I just went to the cafeteria,
and some nurse called me Reed
and then said, "I
thought you died."
Yeah, you don't go to
the cafeteria for lunch.
- They just point and stare.
- Is that why you
dyed your hair?
They stare because
we should've died.
Pack a lunch. Keep
it in your locker.
You are kidding me.
-  You got cleared?
- It's down
to you and Yang.
- That is not funny.
- - Well, Perkins is no dummy.
He can see the crazy right
under the Meredith Grey surface.
Again, Cristina, it's not
funny because you're not
gonna get cleared
either, and the two of us
are gonna be serving
slushies at the multiplex.
Really? I'd choose
dermatology over multiplex.
No, I'd go gynecology
over dermatology.
Oh, of course you would. Perv.
I think I'd go with psych.
That was a joke.
That was good.
- Ha ha.
- That was good.
Anyway, I don't know what
Perkins' problem is with me.
Maybe he saw your file.
- Maybe he knew your mother.
- Maybe he heard how you told
the shooter to shoot you.
Not funny.
Not a joke.
- Dr. Bailey.
- Welcome back.
You OK?
I'm happy to see you all.
Karev, there's a
patient in 23-04
that needs an endoscopy.
Grey and Yang, surely your
paycheck covers more than
stuffing your face
in the basement.
Get to the clinic now.
And, you two...
I'm awful sorry about
the loss of your friends.
Thank you.
So are we.
22-13 has a bowel impaction,
and I'm sure as hell not about
to stick my hands in there.
You, uh, quit your
job this morning.
Should I be worried
about impulsivity?
I didn't quit my job.
Being chief wasn't my job.
I'm a surgeon.
That's what I do.
That is who I am.
But before you got shot...
Oh, I wanted to quit that job
every day before I got shot,
I just didn't have
the guts to do it.
After I got shot, I, uh...
Life is short.
So now I think less and...
just do.
So... for you, the
shooting was clarifying?
A... a lot of people
died in that shooting.
I'm saying, in your life today.
A lot of people died.
Oh.
Um...
Meredith went to
get something to eat.
She should be back soon.
Um...
I'm sorry I got you shot.
By coming out of the office I
didn't listen, and then you got shot.
I... I got you shot,
- and I just need to say,
I am so...
- April...
So sorry.
Gary Clark came here for me.
I gave the order to
pull the plug on his wife.
I got everyone shot.
So... Oh!
Is this what I need
to do to get cleared?
Dr. Grey, you're early.
I'll, uh, I'll call you later.
Yes, please.
Uh...
That was creepy
and inappropriate.
I want a new counselor.
Teddy was never
a... a patient of mine.
She was cleared for
surgery before I got here.
We just met in the cafeteria.
I'm not interested
in your love life.
I don't care how love
blooms over day-old hot dogs.
My husband is about to remove
the largest chordoma on record.
You cleared Lexie
Grey last week.
You cleared Alex
Karev, who insists on
running around the hospital
with a bullet in his chest.
I know who I've cleared.
So then why don't you tell
me what you want me to say,
and I'll say it.
Dr. Grey, I don't think
that you're being honest...
with me or yourself.
And I think that's a
potentially dangerous situation.
So what is it that
you're not saying?
Who's with Derek?
Uh, when I left, um,
Mark Sloan was with him.
- And where's Owen?
- Um, I don't know.
I... I... I think he's still
talking to the police.
OK, not a word of this to Derek.
You have to tell Owen
because he knows.
- Not a word.
- OK.
And April Kepner.
She knows, too.
OK.
Well, go... go tell them.
Go... go back to the hospital
and tell them right now.
Don't you want
me to stay for this?
No, I want you to go.
Go and... and make sure
no one says a word to Derek.
OK. OK.
Your friend left?
- You want me to wait or...
- No, just do it.
The D&C's pretty
straightforward.
The fetus was only
at about 5 weeks.
You'll feel some cramping
after, but it shouldn't be too bad.
Andrew and I just got
busted by Meredith Grey.
- Callie's watching me sleep.
- What?
She's watching me sleep.
And she only watches me
sleep when something is up,
and I'm afraid that
she's gonna propose
or... start talking about
making babies again,
which I'm... I'm
open to, honestly,
just not right now, you know?
And I can feel her watching
me, and it is such hard work
to keep my eyes closed,
but I know that if I open them,
that something loaded is gonna
come out of her beautiful mouth
and pop the pretty pink bubble
that we've been floating in.
- You want to pop the bubble.
- I don't, though.
Believe me. I've been
living in that bubble for years.
Oh, no. Owen and I?
We're just friends, really.
Finally knowing the
truth? I don't regret that.
My bubble is so
pink and so... pretty.
Pop the bubble.
I heard you were looking for me.
The board officially
reinstated me this morning.
- No more "interim chief."
- Well, I'm glad to hear that.
You sure? No seller's remorse?
Oh, have you seen
the tumor I'm chasing?
No, no seller's remorse.
You feel good
about this surgery?
That sounds like
a loaded question.
Look, I know Perkins
cleared you for surgery.
And I know better than to
question your judgment, but...
I still have nightmares, and I
go to two AA meetings a day.
I'm not all the way back,
and I didn't get shot.
That's what I mean when I
say, do you feel good about it?
I feel adrenaline.
And, yeah...
the adrenaline feels good.
I can't believe I'm
not down there.
Palate's divided.
Torres.
Yeah. OK. We're good.
Here we go.
You ever see anything like this?
I've seen mortar fire that
didn't do this much damage.
All right, let's bring
that microscope in
and get you started.
Everybody ready?
- Let's do it.
- Yeah.
OK.
There's the tumor.
We're there.
Microdissectors, please.
Get up.
No.
Ow! Ow! Ow!
Let's go.
Sorry, sorry.
What is wrong with you?
Everything is wrong.
Derek is decapitating
a teenager,
and April Kepner is assisting,
and you're sitting reading
about lilies of the freakin' valley.
Well, you prefer peonies?
We are not better.
Cristina, a psychiatrist,
given several opportunities,
has deemed me
unfit to do my job.
Well, he'll get over it.
Just go back in
a couple of days.
- You are not better.
- Well, in a couple of days,
I'll be better, too.
In a couple of days,
you'll be married.
Are you trying to
talk me out of this?
Look at me and
tell me you're sure.
OK, you know what? No.
You don't get to do this.
OK? All you get to do
is help me break the tie
between the lilies of the valley
and the... and the peonies.
- That's it.
- No, I do get to do this.
I mean, Derek's the love of
my life, but you're my soul mate.
I do get to do this. I mean,
why can't it wait six months?
- Please don't. Don't.
- Your flowers aren't
going anywhere.
You broke up with him
because he couldn't choose you.
Don't... don't... don't do this.
- Just why does it
have to be right now?
- You know what I think?
- I think you should tell Derek
about the miscarriage.
- We're talking about you.
We're talking about
us not being "better."
- Then you need to tell him.
- He's not ready. He's... he's not OK.
Well, you're not OK.
You should tell him.
Well, Dr. Yang, if you don't
feel ready, there's no pressure.
The hospital is prepared to
work with you in whatever way...
What... I'm sorry. I... I'm
getting special treatment?
'Cause I'm the girl who
operated with a gun to her head?
If you don't want to
clear me, don't clear me.
Well, you didn't show up for
your appointment last week.
You were very late today.
I'm getting married.
I heard that. Congratulations.
Can I go now?
When you think about
going into an O.R.,
how does that make you feel?
God, the women in
these magazines...
Some of them are
actually brides, you know?
They're not all models.
All smiling.
It's like the only thing
in the world that matters
is that they find
the perfect shoe
to match that dress.
God, you know, I
knew these girls.
I... I went to school with them.
It's funny.
I used to feel sorry for them.
They're simple girls.
They just want to find the guy
and get married, you know...
and live.
I don't know.
I think you're
either born simple
or you're born...
me.
I want to be the person
who gets happy over
finding the perfect dress.
I want to be simple.
'Cause no one holds a gun
to the head of a simple girl.
- Stop fixing him!
- Owen, help.
Who is it?
I... It's me. It's Owen.
Hey.
You're late.
I'm sorry.
Hey.
It's not OK.
Cristina, what is this?
I don't want to be alone.
You don't ever have
to be alone again.
I'm not going
anywhere, Cristina.
I won't ever leave
again. You hear me?
I am not going
anywhere, Cristina...
if you let me stay.
Thank you.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry I was late.
Uh...
Miranda, look, um...
Look, um...
I... I was playing golf.
And I... I can't
apologize for it
because it wasn't
anything I did on purpose.
I... I was just...
I was playing golf.
I missed you, and I just...
You're... you're a good man.
You are handsome...
and kind... and smart
and... good.
I mean, you're perfect.
But, um...
I'm... busy
holding myself together
with tape and glue.
And a piece of me wishes that
you hadn't played
golf, because...
then you'd be all
taped and glued, too.
And maybe you'd be where I am.
- Shh.
- I...
You're...
You're too much
for me right now,
'cause I'm busy with
the tape and the glue.
Shh. Shh. All right, all right.
All right.
You take care of yourself.
You, too.
You were amazing in there.
Let's make a baby.
What?
Mm-hmm. Come on.
Let's just pull the goalie.
Let's do it. Let's
start right now.
Oh, God.
It's Greg. Damn it.
I... I already gave
him 10 of morphine.
He's in too much pain. I'm
gonna start him on propofol.
- Greg.
- I never should've
let you do this.
- I never should've let you.
- All right, Greg. It's Dr. Shepherd.
You have to listen
to me. Greg. Greg.
Greg, this is the
fight. This is the fight.
It's gonna stop.
We're gonna help you.
But until it does,
this is your fight.
The tumor's not driving
anymore. You are.
You're in the driver's seat.
The life that's in your
head, you get if you fight.
You got it?
Good. Good.
Look, this...
- This pain?
- Yeah.
It's not a dying pain.
It's a healing pain.
- This is a victory pain.
- OK.
You won.
We won.
Hey.
What? What? I went
out to get some ice.
Oh, don't be mad.
We'll make the wedding.
I'll make the wedding.
Just wanted to see you
were alive for myself.
Meredith.
You look hot.
The whole, uh, "crazy
eyes, tight dress" thing,
it's, uh, it's working for you,
for whatever it's worth.
You think that you are so
badass 'cause you lived.
I'm the reason that you lived.
And while you were dying,
you were crying out
for the wife who left you.
So that's the
opposite of badass,
for whatever it's worth.
I'm jealous.
I think I'm jealous
of Hunt and Yang.
You know Derek's
gonna be the best man?
We hardly even know the guy.
I'm gonna do it.
- You're drunk.
- That's why I'm gonna do it.
Lame surgery ran long.
Sorry. What'd I miss?
- I have something... to ask you.
- Oh, no.
I want you to move
in with me. I love you,
and you have a drawer
and a toothbrush,
and I want you to
have a whole dresser
and a whole... blow-dryer
or something... more
romantic than that or...
something.
You're doing
great. Push through.
OK.
Unless you're just
totally hating the idea,
which...
would be OK.
- Is that it?
- Is what it?
You just want me to move in
to a place that I
basically already live?
Mm-hmm.
- Thank God.
- Yes, yes.
Calliope, yes. I would
love to have a dresser
and a blow-dryer or
something more romantic.
Oh. How are you doing? You OK?
Yeah. I'm OK. Uh, Derek?
Uh, I'm sorry. He's not coming.
- Um...
- He's my best man.
I know. Do you want
to pick a new one?
- Mark looks great in a suit.
- Derek had the ring.
- I have it.
- Oh, OK.
OK. Are you still good?
- Yeah.
- OK.
She is gonna come
down those stairs, right?
I never gave you any
crap about your Post-it.
You look beautiful.
I know.
How's Owen? Is he good?
Owen's perfect.
He's perfect.
Thank you.
When we say things like,
"People don't change,"
it drives scientists crazy...
because change is literally
the only constant
in all of science.
Thank you.
Energy.
Matter.
It's always changing...
morphing...
merging...
growing...
dying.
It's the way people try not
to change that's unnatural.
The way we cling
to what things were
instead of letting
them be what they are.
The way we cling to old memories
instead of forming new ones.
The way we insist
on believing...
despite every
scientific indication...
that anything in this
lifetime is permanent.
Change is constant.
How we experience change...
that's up to us.
It can feel like death...
or it can feel like a
second chance at life.
If we open our fingers,
loosen our grips,
go with it...
it can feel like
pure adrenaline.
Like at any moment...
we can have
another chance at life.
Like at any moment...
I do.
We can be born all over again.