Am I going to be late again?
No... and starting today
we are both going to be on time.
Who's picking me up?
Tina's mom.
You're going to play over there
and then I'll pick you
up right after dinner.
I hate Tina.
Don't say that... she likes you.
No, she doesn't.
Her mom's just doing you
a favor.
That's not true.
I'm sure the bell just rang.
I hate going in late.
I'm sorry, sweetheart.
This is the last time, I swear.
I can't wait till
Mommy gets back.
Have a nice day.
Can I help you?
Yeah, I'm looking
for Carla Reese.
She went home last night.
Thank you.
What are you doing?
Oh, um... I was,
um, just going over
Carla Reese's discharge summary.
That's confidential.
Yeah, I know.
Dr. Coburn, um...
I'm the child's father.
She told me.
It's still confidential,
and you know it.
Why did you order a
glucose tolerance test?
I'm not going to
answer that question.
Does she have
gestational diabetes?
Good-bye, Doctor.
Gestational diabetes
can put the fetus at risk
of heart problems,
metabolic problems.
Look, Dr. Coburn, I think
I have a right to know.
If you want to know
what's going on with your child,
then I suggest
you ask the mother.
Aha, thought I'd find you here.
Here I am.
Hey, it's supposed
to be a great weekend.
They say it'll
get up in the 70s.
Oh, yeah...
Damn it.
You're in a good mood.
I was doing fine
until the clinic called
with my blood test results.
Oh?
My viral load's up to 1,000.
A thousand is not significant.
It is to me.
Perfect timing.
What do you mean?
Today is Al and my anniversary.
It would have been nine years.
Talk about the gift
that keeps on giving.
Jeanie, you had
the flu last week.
That's why your
viral load went up.
Give it two weeks.
It'll be back to undetectable.
Think so?
Yeah... and I'm the expert.
I also think we should
rechristen this date in history.
What do you mean?
I propose April 17
be the anniversary of our first
weekend getaway.
Keep talking.
All right.
How does a suite at
Indian Lake resort sound?
They have great restaurants,
massages in the room.
We can leave tonight,
come back Sunday.
Sounds nice.
It will be, I promise.
Hey...
Stop worrying, okay?
Aw, come on, don't lie.
You did not buy this car.
Boxster, dude... I'm leasing it.
How? To afford
those kind of wheels
man, you got to be
making some doctor ducats.
Well, then just call
me Dr. Markovic.
Okay, Doc.
Jerry, did that attending
meeting start on time?
Yeah, and Anspaugh was
looking for you, but don't bother.
I think it ended about
five minutes ago.
Catwoman?
Yeah, Rachel left it in my car.
I should call the school
to make sure they're
going to feed her...
Mark, we need to talk.
Sorry about the meeting.
No, don't worry about it.
Listen, the search committee
received your application
for the teaching position
along with Kerry Weaver's.
I thought Kerry was going
for the research position.
She is... the teaching
job is just her fall-back.
Now, between us, you're
the better candidate.
Now, Kerry's
intellect is superior,
but she doesn't have
your people skills.
Thanks.
The hitch is, you
haven't published.
Whereas Kerry, she's
written seven articles...
Two in the Annals.
Seven?
Exactly, which
means you have to find
an interesting
case and write it up.
Show the committee
you're not illiterate.
A case?
And soon.
I went out on a
limb to back you.
Don't make me
look like an idiot.
Damn it.
Damn it, damn it.
Carol?
What are you
doing? What is this?
You're reading... is it
Harrison's Internal Medicine?
What are you doing?
I'm checking the rate
of oxidated metabolism
in hypothyroidism.
This is important to you?
It was on the
medical board exam.
I put "above normal."
The answer is "below normal."
Every day I think of
another test question
and when I go to look it
up, I find out I got it wrong.
I'm sure you did fine.
No, Doug.
I've looked up
maybe 30 questions,
all of which I missed.
I did not do fine, okay?
Okay, all right, you're right.
But you do things for people
that doctors don't
even think about doing.
Carol?
This guy in the hall
needs a clean-up.
He just did a major code brown.
You're right.
I wipe butts
and take orders from
25-year-old interns.
Who's the jockey on Goosebumps?
Is that turf or dirt? Uh-huh.
And what's the
conditions at the track?
Easy.
Well, listen, put me
down for a double pop...
Goosebumps to win.
Either of you want any action?
I got the lowdown on a miler.
You're a gambler, huh?
Investor... if I want to gamble,
I'll play the stock market.
This is scientific.
What about it?
No, thanks.
Your loss.
Doc?
Uh, sure.
Put me down for five bucks.
Five bucks?
A high-roller.
I see you've been
vomiting... since yesterday?
Yeah, I think I caught
the flu from my cat.
Okay, we're going
to run a few tests,
and let's get an X ray
of his abdomen as well.
Can I keep my hat on?
Sure... why?
It's my thing.
Once I make a bet, I keep
the hat on till the payoff.
Oh, scientific, huh?
Hey, Einstein wore
brown socks for luck.
Now, who am I to
argue with that, huh?
Hey, Jeanie, some guy
dropped this off for you.
Who?
I think it was your ex-husband.
When?
He just left.
Al.
Hi, I see you got the flowers.
What's this about?
Uh, nothing.
Just it's our anniversary,
and I was thinking of
you, like it says on the card.
It's inappropriate.
Jeanie, it's no big deal.
I don't want to celebrate a
marriage that was a disaster
from beginning to end.
I didn't mean to upset you.
Well, here... just... here.
No... keep them.
Give them to a
patient or something.
Oh, God!
Ida Blinnder, 55,
acute abdominal pain.
It's like my stomach
is exploding.
BP 100/70, pulse 90.
I need surgery.
All right, draw the usual labs.
Add an amylase, some LFTs
and call a surgical consult.
Oh, good Lord, it looks
like a railroad yard.
Mrs. Blinnder, I see you're
no stranger to surgery.
I've had five operations.
They never find anything.
You've had all these
for the same problem?
It comes back.
Mrs. Blinnder,
do you ever suffer
the loss of sensation
in your arms and legs?
Yes... yes, I do.
Cancel the surgeon.
Why?
What's going on?
There's a rare condition
called porphyria.
It's often misdiagnosed
as surgical.
It's really a metabolic disease.
You mean this poor thing
had five operations
she didn't need?
It's possible.
This could be the perfect case
to write up for the Journal.
Let's get a CBC and lytes.
What's happening?
Don't worry, Mrs. Blinnder.
We're going to get
to the bottom of this.
Excuse me.
A little help?
Malik, get a gurney.
Found her in a car
outside of Grayson Cemetery
just sitting there
bleeding to death.
These your belts?
Yeah, that's all we
had for tourniquets.
How much blood has she lost?
It's hard to tell.
The car had dark upholstery.
Get the belts off.
See if she has
an arterial bleed.
No spurting on this side.
Can I get a pulse below the cut?
Must have used a dull knife.
Guys, something
ugly is going on.
Well, get the suction.
Think she swallowed something?
Did you see any containers,
poisons, insecticides?
We didn't look...
Just scooped and ran.
What's her name?
No ID.
Go back and check her car.
Give me an Ewal tube
and activated charcoal.
We got to pump her out.
Jeanie, could you hold her head?
Yeah.
Here it is.
Oh, the pain!
"Unexplained abdominal crisis.
Symptoms include
absence of fever."
What's her temp?
Normal.
Good.
"Porphobilinogen in the urine."
Let's get a UA.
You going to write this up
for the Annals of
Emergency Medicine?
And the New England Journal,
maybe the New York Times.
Yeah, who knows how
many needless surgeries
are done in cases like this?
"Porphyria: the hidden tragedy."
Am I going to get an operation?
Absolutely not.
But I want an operation.
Mrs. Blinnder, you
don't understand.
don't need surgery.
What you have is porphyria.
No, she doesn't.
What? She's psych.
She enjoys having
surgery done on her.
"Enjoys"?
Mm-hmm.
She's convinced five
different doctors to cut her.
It's a lie... I do need surgery.
Mrs. Blinnder...
Oh, God, the pain!
Call psych... tell them
to bring down the net.
And cancel the New York Times.
Hey, Carla, it's Peter.
Are you there?
All right, listen.
When you get
this, do me a favor.
Give me a call either at
the hospital or at home,
or page me... 555-0197, okay?
I hope you get this,
and I hope you call.
All right, bye.
Hey, what is it, Carter?
I got a 68-year-old guy
with diffuse abdominal
pain, no focal tenderness
some bowel edema,
but no acute obstruction.
Well, he's got a history of
peripheral vascular disease
so I was thinking about
getting an angiogram.
You know what? Hand it off
to Dixon, because you and I
are supposed to be covering
the wards two minutes ago.
I'd rather stick with him.
His temp's up, he's looking gray
and I just don't want him
to get lost in the
shuffle, you know?
All right, stick with him.
If he needs surgery,
Anspaugh's on call.
Heart rate is 40.
Give two more of atropine, and
get the contents of her stomach
to the lab for analysis.
The cops found empty
pill vials in her car.
What kind of pills?
Three-TC, Retinovir, AZT.
She OD'd on her AIDS pills?
There's more... Valium,
Desipramine, Prozac.
Plus they found a jar with some
kind of mixtures... smells like sterno.
I guess she wanted to make
sure she got the job done.
What's the name
on the prescriptions?
"Suzanne Alner."
See if she has a chart.
Tube is coming out.
Washcloth, please?
Let's start with bicarb
for the tricyclics,
Romazicon for the benzos,
Narcan to cover the narcotics,
and if she's positive
for methanol,
we need to dialyze her.
What about the AIDS pills?
I have no idea.
Greg Fischer would know.
Good, I'll call him.
Why would you want
to hurt yourself like this?
We're talking 200 horses,
zero to 60 in 6.1 seconds.
ER.
Who?
Yeah, I'll let you drive it.
Jerry, someone from Cryo-Gen Lab
is calling for a Dr. Markovic?
Uh, let me call you back.
Hello?
Yeah, speaking.
Um...
Uh, Monday at 4:30
would be fine.
Uh, thank you.
Jerry, isn't Cryo-Gen
Lab that sperm bank?
Uh, yeah.
Don't tell me you're
representing yourself
as a doctor and trying
to sell your sperm?
Shh, just keep it down.
Ah, that is reprehensible.
What's in a title?
The fact of the matter is, women
are paying top dollar for the seed
of a tall man with an IQ of 150.
Who took the test for you?
I took it.
Oh, you're IQ's not 150.
Mine's only 145.
What am I supposed to do...
Apologize because
I'm smarter than you?
What?
I'm going to get an
IQ test from psych
and if you don't score 150,
I'm going to blow the
whistle on you, Dr. Markovic.
Ted brought these down.
She was positive for methanol?
Yeah, dialysis is on the way.
Pumped her stomach
and given her charcoal.
That's all you can
do for the HIV pills.
Cops found two
pictures in her car,
both of a little girl.
Her daughter?
Pharmacy who gave her the pills
has her living in a motel.
I called... They
say she lived alone.
She's got a wedding ring.
Did we find an old
chart? Nothing came up.
This kid looks familiar to
me; what's the last name?
Patient's last name is Alner.
Suzanne.
Where am I?
You're in the hospital.
Oh, no.
Do you want us to call
someone? Your husband?
No.
We found these pictures
in your car.
Is she your daughter?
Mm-hmm.
Where is she?
I killed her.
How you feeling, Mr. Bartok?
Bad, like after I had
my second heart attack.
Well, what you're having
is a lot like a heart
attack, except to your gut.
See, this is an artery
that brings blood
down into your small intestine.
As you can see right there,
it's completely blocked off.
Sounds serious.
It's very serious.
Can you fix it?
Yeah, but we need to get
you into surgery right away.
What if we don't?
You'll be dead in 72 hours.
Cripes.
Listen, I don't
want you to worry.
The chief of staff is on
call, and you're going to get
the best care in Chicago.
So why don't we take
Mr. Bartok down to pre-op
and stat-page Dr. Anspaugh.
Where's my phone?
Hmm, it's around here somewhere.
I don't think this is
the best time for you
to be calling your bookie.
I want to talk to my daughter.
Yeah, sure.
Mr. Gearhart, the doctor
ordered a painkiller injection.
Take your best shot.
Marine, huh?
Master Gunnery
Sergeant, 22 years.
Well, this might sting a little.
I think I can handle it.
Uh, Carol, what are you doing?
You ordered 30
migs of Ketorolac.
He needs it I.V.
You didn't say that.
He's got kidney stones and COPD.
He needs to be hydrated.
Okay, I'll start an I.V.
Sorry, Sergeant, we
got to stick you again.
Well, what's another needle?
Back at Fort Bragg,
my drill instructor
hammered my air-assault
wings into my chest.
I heard about that
stuff on the news.
Sounds awful.
Proudest day of my life.
Weak-tit journalists
kept their noses out
of my marine corps,
we'd all be a lot better off.
Aah! Caught me off
guard there, Cookie.
Ooh, peanut butter and jelly
and a plain doughnut.
Rachel forgot her lunch.
Maybe she left it on purpose.
Hey, you know, I'm new at this.
How's it going?
It's great, I mean, I love
having Rachel around.
We haven't quite got
the routines down yet,
but, you know, she seems happy.
Mmm, So I hear you have
a psych case for me.
Yeah, uh, curtain area three.
This lady has a
predilection for operations.
She's had five surgeries.
They've all been
completely unnecessary.
Not Ida Blinnder.
Yeah... she a patient of yours?
Total fruitcake.
You didn't leave
her alone, did you?
Why?
Whenever she's
rejected from surgery,
she likes to force the issue.
What do you mean?
She eats things:
batteries, paper clips, pens.
Then they have to
be surgically removed.
Ida, what have you been doing?
Oh, no. What?
Haleh, did you take
all the instruments
off this tray?
Uh-uh.
Okay, this was full when I left.
Ida, did you swallow anything?
Oh...
Excuse me.
Uh, is Dr. Coburn around?
She's at the clinic.
Want to leave a message?
No, no.
You know what... Actually
maybe you can help me.
I need to see the ultrasound
tape for Carla Reese.
We only keep them a week or so
before they get recycled.
Let's see.
Ah, you're in luck.
You're a surgeon, right?
Uh-huh.
Is she a surgical patient?
How's she doing?
BP's down.
Breathing's labored.
She's not responding
to anything.
Guess what I found...
Chart on the little
girl, Katy Alner.
Father: Roger. Mother: Suzanne.
The girl in the picture?
Yeah... father brought
her to the clinic last year
for recurrent ear
infections and the flu.
I ran a CD-4.
Turned out she had AIDS.
From her mother?
Yep.
Girl died last month...
AIDS-related pneumonia.
So that's what she meant.
Yeah.
So sad.
I just talked to her ex-husband.
He's on his way in.
Soon, I hope.
His celiac is shot.
Mm-hmm.
White count is 18,000?
Mm-hmm, correct.
He's had two MI's,
peripheral vascular disease?
Co2, 14; fever, 102;
BP's down to 90?
Yeah, that's why I called you.
I thought we should get
him up to the OR right away.
He's going into shock.
We open him up, he
won't get off the table.
Turf him to ICU.
Wait, wait, wait.
You're not going to take him?
He's septic, and
he's grossly unstable.
He's septic because
he's infarcting his bowel.
He's not going to get
any better in the ICU.
Probably not, but
it's his only shot.
Oh, come on, don't you
think he's got a better shot
if he has the operation?
Carter, there's nothing
we can do for this man.
We operate, all we get
is a mortality statistic.
I'm a surgeon,
not an executioner.
Let's go, Doc.
I'm dying here.
Uh, Mr. Bartok,
Dr. Anspaugh feels
that you won't
survive the surgery.
What's that mean?
It means that we're
going to move you.
We're going to move
you up to the ICU...
The Intensive Care Unit.
I don't understand.
You said if I don't get the
surgery right away, I'm through.
That's true.
So? What?
You writing me off?
You just going
to send me someplace to die
like some animal?
I'm sorry.
You're sorry?
What the hell's that?
You told me I was going to get
the best care in the city,
for God's sakes.
Should I call Transpo
to come get him?
You gave me
your word.
No, keep him here.
Give him dopamine, uh,
ten micrograms per minute.
Let me have that, uh...
Yeah, I'll be right back.
Holy cow!
Sorry.
Mother!
Damn it! I'm sorry.
What are you doing?
Trying to get a blood gas.
He's a hard stick.
I'll take that as a compliment.
I'll go get one
of the attendings.
No, I got it.
Kerry?
You might want to help Doyle.
She's using one of the
patients as a pincushion.
Judas Priest!
Sorry.
Got to learn sometime.
I don't see why nurses
can't do blood gases...
As if we wouldn't do
a better job than that.
Sounds like she's got it.
Holy Shih Tzu!
I'd say his chances of
surviving an anastomosis
are slim to none.
Oh, you never know.
His collaterals may still
be perfusing his bowel.
I doubt it.
His BP is up.
He's not a good risk.
Dr. Hicks... Listen,
Mr. Bartok knows
that he might not
wake up from this.
I think he still wants
everything done,
and I think we should at
least try to save his life.
If we get in and
out of there quickly,
he may have a chance.
That's all he wants.
All right, let's take him.
I'll bring him up.
Good news, Mr. Bartok.
You're going to surgery.
Thanks.
Ah, my pen.
I was wondering where I left it.
Scissors, tweezers.
She should be in a circus.
Nothing's left the stomach.
With a rat's tooth on a scope
I can grab all that stuff.
Well, looks like she's
back to being an ER case.
Yeah, "Woman swallows
medical instruments."
The journals would love this.
I didn't know you
were into publishing.
Yeah, life in the fast
track... publish or perish.
She's throwing PVCs.
Probably the tricyclics.
They're cardiotoxic.
Who's talking?
My name's Jeanie.
Where are you?
Can't you see me?
No.
You're experiencing blindness
because of the
methanol you ingested.
Papilledema?
Yeah.
Suzanne?
Huh?
Roger's on his way.
My Roger?
Yeah.
No, God.
Oh, God, what will I say?
I don't know.
Is there anything
you'd want to tell him?
That I'm sorry.
Then that's what you should say.
Psst... Dr. Ross.
Jerry, it's a test,
not a survey.
Doug, got a minute?
These kids were on
their way to the prom
when she had a gallstone attack.
It's no big deal, I've
had them for years.
You guys are starting
early... it's barely 2:00.
We had a pre-prom party.
Betsy's folks are out of town.
Why would you tell him that?
He's a doctor.
I just need some antibiotics.
Well, why don't you let
me check you out first.
Let's go to, uh, yeah,
let's go to Exam 1.
From now on, let
me do the talking.
Excuse me, Mr. Alner?
Yes.
Do you want to see her?
I can see her.
She's dying.
Yes.
Is she in pain?
Some.
Good.
She... cheated on me, got
herself infected with AIDS
and gave it to our baby.
I've been waiting for
this for a long time.
Retract the omentum.
Let's see what we've got.
Ooh!
Oh, is that gangrene?
All the way from
the proximal jejunum
to the transverse colon.
If we go forward,
we'll be here for hours.
And this guy won't
have any small bowel left.
I think it's worth a shot.
What is it, Carter...
He owes you money?
All right, let's go.
Hemostat and a couple
of scudders for the bowel.
What the hell is
going on in here?!
Why? What's the problem?
I rejected this patient
as a poor surgical risk.
But didn't Dr. Carter tell you?
No, he didn't.
I got a 23-year
jump on you, kid.
You trying to outflank me?
No, sir.
What makes you think
your judgment is
superior to mine?
I don't, I don't, I just
thought that the patient...
This has nothing to
do with the patient.
This is about the
practice of medicine.
Interns do not make end
runs on the chief of staff.
I want you in my
office at 5:00 sharp
to discuss your
future as a surgeon.
If you have any hope of
continuing in this program
you will explain your actions
with the appropriate degree
of contrition and respect
and the assurance
that nothing like this
will ever happen again.
Dr. Hicks...
Scrub out, Carter.
All right, Mrs.
Blinnder, sign here
so the doctor can
get back our property.
No, I want surgery.
Mrs. Blinnder, have you ever
had an endoscopy before?
No.
I don't think you know
what you're missing.
Endoscopy is an
extremely traumatic
and invasive procedure.
See, I have to stick
this tube with a camera
down your throat, root around
and grab the items
that you've swallowed
and yank them back
up through your gullet.
And the best thing is
you'll be conscious
the whole time.
You mean... I can watch?
In living color.
Mark, you got a call
from Rachel's school.
They want you to come
pick her up right away.
Someone else was supposed to.
Apparently they didn't.
Ah, geez.
They're holding.
You want to talk to them?
Uh, no... I'll, uh...
Tell them I'm on my way.
Look, I'll be back
in 45 minutes.
Don't leave her alone,
and don't let anybody
else do the endoscopy.
Who's your wife's doctor again?
Janet Coburn.
So why are you coming to see me?
You're the expert
on fetal anomalies.
Since we discovered Carla
has gestational diabetes
I wanted you to take a look.
Well, I can tell you right now
he looks fine.
No cardiac abnormalities?
Nah.
Macrosomia?
Nope.
How's Janet managing your wife?
Uh...
Through diet or
insulin injections?
I'm not sure.
You don't know how your wife
is being managed?
Actually, we're not married.
But you talk to her,
one would hope.
Well, we had a
little falling out.
Uh-huh.
You know, I don't
really know you,
and I'm getting the feeling
I'm doing something
I shouldn't be
and I'm starting to resent it.
Bad news, Betsy.
Your gallbladder is going to
have to come out right away.
You mean first thing tomorrow?
No, I mean right away.
No way.
I paid $400 for that dress.
Well, I'm sorry, but
you're in real trouble here.
Listen to him, Bets.
Shut up, Jeffrey.
I'll come back
right after the prom.
No, you'll get septic and
die by the end of the night.
I'm willing to risk it.
Bets!
Give me the antibiotics.
Betsy, no! You're
going to surgery.
Oh, no... I'm 18 years old.
I know my rights.
I'm walking out of here
and you can't do squat.
Jeffrey, my dress.
Can you be back by 10:00?
No, they crown the
king and queen at 10:00.
10:30, then.
We could leave at 10:30.
Where's the prom?
The Drake.
Okay, the Drake's
halfway across town.
You leave by 10:00.
Forget it.
Jeffrey, zip me.
All right.
Let's go.
Okay, hang on, wait, wait.
I got an idea.
Mr. Greene?
Hi, sorry about the mix-up.
It happens.
Where's Rach?
She went down to the library.
If you have a minute, I
would like to talk to you.
Uh, sure.
I just want to know
if there's anything
we need to be careful
about with Rachel these days.
Such as?
Restricted physical
activities, diet.
Why?
Because of her leukemia.
Leukemia? Rachel
doesn't have leukemia.
Where'd you get that?
Rachel.
She told some of her
classmates that she's sick
and not expected to live.
Why would she say
something like that?
Well, Rachel's been
having some trouble socially.
I'm sure you heard
about the fight.
No.
It was with one of
the more popular girls,
and since then, Rachel often
winds up playing by herself.
Feigning an illness
I'm sure was just a way
to get some attention.
Hey, Rach, you ready to go?
Are we going home?
I wish, but we got to
get back to the hospital.
You can do your math homework.
Big whoop.
Hey, Rachel, that is no way
to talk to Mrs. Hilderbrand.
We'll see you tomorrow.
Say good-bye.
Bye.
Bye-bye.
What's the story?
Old guy was playing cards with
his pals when he keeled over.
Must've gotten a bad hand.
One, two, three.
BP's 80/50, heart
rate's up to 130.
You didn't start an I.V.?
Blew two on the ride.
His veins are shot.
I'll try a stick on the hand.
I'm hearing rales.
Three-plus pitting edema.
He's got congestive
heart failure.
Yep, prep Lasix and dopamine.
We need to get the fluid
off his lungs.
How's that I.V. coming?
Forget it... His
skin's like paper.
I'll do a central
line; grab me a kit.
Any attendings around?
Greene left the hospital
and Weaver's in radiology.
Betadyne, please.
All right, I want you to page
Weaver and call surgery.
Have them help us
put in the central line.
Cancel that, I got it.
Give me an eighth French.
Surgeons put in
lines all the time.
I said I got it.
BP's down to 60.
Standing by with dopamine.
How long is it going to be?
If you're looking
for something to do,
why don't you grab
the guy a pillow.
I'm calling surgery.
Line's in... run the
dopamine 400 in 250.
Titrate the BP to 90.
Hold the Lasix till
his pressure's back.
Here's the deal.
The ambulance will
take you to the dance
and pick you up at 10:00 sharp.
Take that.
10:15!
10:00.
No dancing around.
Keep that I.V. in;
nothing too wild.
Don't worry, I won't.
For her, nothing to eat.
No alcohol, no smoking.
Make sure she's
back here by 10:30,
not a minute later.
Okay, Dr. Ross.
You can count on me.
Bye-bye, have fun.
Be good.
Close the door.
I have never seen as
devious, underhanded
and ultimately
self-destructive a maneuver
as you pulled today.
What the hell were you thinking?
I thought the patient
deserved a chance
and I had reservations about
Dr. Anspaugh's assessment
that the patient was
unstable for surgery.
I know that if I was the patient
I would have liked
a second opinion.
You led me to believe that mine
was the only opinion.
If I'd known otherwise,
it's unlikely I would
have proceeded,
certainly not without
consulting Dr. Anspaugh first.
Before Dr. Hicks and I decide
whether or not to
terminate your residency,
is there anything
you'd like to say?
Yes... I apologize
for not being
more forceful in making my
case to you when I spoke to you.
And I apologize to you,
Dr. Hicks, for not telling you
about Dr. Anspaugh's assessment.
But I still believe that
we owed this patient
a chance in saving his life.
I'm glad we gave it to him.
Anything else?
I have a question.
What?
Did Mr. Bartok
survive the surgery?
Yes, he did.
Labs are back.
BUN's 45, creatinine is 3.5
He's in renal failure.
Anyone page Weaver?
I did.
BP's down to 50.
We got to increase his output.
Prep some Vasotec.
You can't give ace inhibitors
to someone in renal failure.
We got to get his heart pumping.
Malik, give him 1.25.
It'll shut his kidneys down.
If we can improve
his cardiac output
it will help his renal failure.
Believe me, give the Vasotec.
Do you want me to read
the contraindications?
I can read as well as you can,
but if we don't get his
heart pumping, he'll croak.
It's a mistake.
Load the Vasotec.
What's going on?
Patient is in
congestive heart failure
and renal failure.
BP is crashing.
I have ordered 1.25 of Vasotec
but I can't convince
the nurses to carry it out.
Give him the Vasotec.
We got to get his heart going.
What about his kidneys?
Got to get the
heart going first.
Where is she?
Why didn't you tell me?
Still hanging on?
She's delirious.
From what?
The organophosphates,
methanol, tricyclics...
Take your pick.
BP's falling, she's
getting shocky.
Better get Kerry.
Looks like impending
respiratory failure.
You may need to intubate.
Roger, is that you?
She's blind from the methanol.
Roger.
Roger, I'm sorry.
She thinks you're her husband.
For-forgive me.
Roger's not here.
Please... please,
Roger, please forgive me.
Please... Roger,
please forgive me.
Just say it.
What?
Tell her you forgive her.
Please.
It's not my place.
Just say it.
Greg, say it.
Say you forgive her.
Please.
It's okay, it's okay.
What's her rate?
140.
Okay, let's tube her.
Roger!
Hold her.
Shh, shh, shh.
It's okay, sweetheart.
It's okay.
It's okay, it's okay.
Seeing as the test
was multiple choice
with a possible five answers
you could guess randomly
and expect to score 20%.
You got 15.
Fifteen?
Your days as a sperm
donor are over, Jerry.
But... but I was...
I was nervous.
I mean, I don't
perform under pressure.
You want to call or should I?
Kerry, I'm back on.
Hey, Rachel.
Oh, Mark.
One of your patients, Mrs.
Blinnder, was complaining
of abdominal pains.
I had to scope out her stomach.
I believe this is yours.
Thank you.
I was thinking we could
co-author an article
about her and send
it out to the journals.
I've even got a title...
"The woman who ate the ER."
Great.
57, 58, 59, 60, 61, 62...
What's your problem?
Excuse me?
The attitude?
I don't know what
you're talking about.
You second-guess me,
you give me a hard time.
What is going on?
Nothing's going on.
Whatever you say, but
don't ever disregard my orders
like you did in that trauma.
I may be younger than
you, but I am the doctor
and you are the nurse.
Keep that straight.
Sweetheart, you've
got to do your homework
before you watch TV.
I don't want to.
Well, those are the rules.
Can you help me?
I got to help some sick people.
You're always taking
care of sick people.
Rach... Mrs. Hilderbrand told me
that you told some of
your friends at school
that you were sick.
Is that true?
They're not my friends.
You wanted them
to be nice to you?
Dr. Greene, quality
assurance wants you to finish
these charts by 6:00.
Just leave them.
People aren't going to like
you because you're sick.
You help people who are sick.
You don't have to be
sick for me to love you.
And I love you more
than anything in the world.
You know that, don't you?
Dr. Greene... Dr. Anspaugh
is on the phone for you.
Yeah, I'll call him back.
Wait, I got to take this.
Please, Daddy.
Rachel, I have to do this, okay?
We'll talk more when
we get home, okay?
I'm sorry.
I wasn't comfortable
pretending to be her husband.
You don't have to apologize.
It's getting late.
You still want
to go to the lake?
We're going to
need to leave soon.
I don't think so.
Because of what
happened with her?
No.
I don't know.
I guess I'm... I'm not ready.
Okay.
No problem.
If, uh...
Call me...
if you want to get
together this weekend.
How did it go?
Not bad.
We removed most
of your small intestine.
I'm afraid you're
not going to be able
to eat solid food again.
Can I drink?
Yeah, actually.
Smoke?
If you must.
I'll be fine.
Your daughter
is flying in tonight.
Goosebumps.
You want me to
get you a blanket?
No.
Goosebumps, our horse.
How did she do?
Oh, oh, well...
I don't know.
Never mind.
Jerry, would you call the morgue
to pick up Suzanne Alner?
I already did.
Who put those here?
I did.
Somebody threw
them in the trash.
They're perfectly fine.
Yeah, this is
Dr. McGrath speaking.
Yeah, Tuesday at
3:00 will be splendid.
Go for it, dude.
Who's there?
Hey, it's me, Peter.
Peter who?
Ha-ha-ha... very funny, Carla.
What do you want, Peter?
I want to know how you
and the baby are doing.
We're fine... see you.
Carla...
I know things haven't
been right between us,
but I'm here and I'm
trying to do the right thing.
I want to support you
through this, Carla.
I want to be a father
to my kid, you know?
Carla...
Oh, excuse me.
Can you hold that door, please?
Thank you.
Come by Saturday morning.
I could use some
help around the house.
All right, I'll be here.
Hey.
You know what I hate?
Uh, Maggie Doyle.
No, I don't hate her.
I just hate that she's right.
About what?
She's younger than me.
Yes, you're right,
she's younger than you.
We grew up in the
same neighborhood
and now she's a
doctor, I'm a nurse
and I got to take orders
from her all day long.
You're a very competitive
person; you know that.
I can't help it... Every
time I look at her
I'm just reminded that she
got through medical school.
I can't even get
through the door.
You can get through my door.
Anything in a bra can
get through your door.
No, no, I've reformed.
Ask anyone.
All right, kids, right on time.
She wanted to stay
for the best dressed contest,
but I said, "No, Bets.
Your surgery is more important."
You're a good man, Jeffrey.
Thank you, Dr. Ross.
This was the best
night of my life.
Me, too.
I got to go.
Good night.
Which means if you
live close to a river,
you need to keep
a close eye on this...
Rach? Rach, come on.
It's time to go home.
I'm tired.
I know, sweetheart.
It's late.
Can you carry me?
Yeah, yeah, sure... grab on.
There we go.
Mark, I've got a
great case here...
A guy with Takayasu's arteritis
on a dual-chamber pacemaker.
Make a good article.
Tell Kerry to take it, okay?
I'm going home.
Carter... you're on probation,
but you're still in the program.
Thank you.
Thank Dr. Anspaugh.
I wanted you kicked out.
John Carter is not
a law unto himself.
I hope you've learned that.
You won't get another chance.
Hi.
Can I come in?
Sure... come in.
I was just finishing dinner.
You hungry?
No, thanks.
So...
You haven't been here.
What do you think?
Well, uh, honestly,
I'm glad I got the house.
Look, I'm sorry
about this morning.
No, you did a nice thing.
I was rude.
I'm the one who
should apologize.
It's okay.
You don't... really think
that our marriage was a disaster
from start to finish, do you?
We had a good beginning.
The middle wasn't bad.
Yeah, you're right.
We had a pretty good middle.
The end was my fault.
And when I think about it,
I don't blame you for hating me.
I don't hate you.
I don't want to be
angry anymore.
that kind of person.
I never meant to hurt you.
Hey.
Hey, come on.
No tears, okay?
Because I'll start going...
I've missed you.
I miss you.