One of the hardest
lessons as a doctor
is learning to prioritize.
Truck.
Cabin.
Spoon.
Truck.
Cabin.
- Spoon.
- Very good.
We're trained to do all we
can to save life and limb,
but if cutting off a limb means
saving a life we learn to do it,
- without hesitation.
- Several moments ago,
I asked you to remember three
words. Can you tell me what they were?
Truck, cabin, spoon.
The three words I asked you
to remember, what were they?
It's not an easy lesson to learn. And
it always comes down to one question:
What are the stakes?
Truck.
Cabin?
And the third word?
What do we stand
to gain or lose?
At the end of the day we're just
gamblers, trying not to bet the farm.
- Spoon.
- Excellent.
Chief, you paged.
- Hey.
- How's it going?
Well, the word "spoon" has
ceased to have any meaning for me,
but I'm through the first test set. I
have a few more consults today, but...
- What's up?
- Meredith,
I would like to
initiate a clinical trial,
one that would be the next
major advancement in the fight
- to cure Type 1 diabetes.
- Wow.
And I'd like you to participate.
But I am on Derek's
Alzheimer's trial.
- So I don't think
I can do both.
- Just listen.
The basis of this trial was
something that I found in here.
- In my mother's journals?
- Yes.
She was working on islet cell
transplantation when she became ill.
Trying to eliminate the need
for anti-rejection meds altogether.
With her notes, drugs
and new technology,
there's no way we can't take this
the rest of the way down the field.
- "We?"
- Well, it's your mother's work.
I wouldn't feel right moving
forward if you weren't a part of it.
You should look at them
both. Just think about it.
It's your decision.
It's your birthright, Meredith.
It's your mother's legacy to you.
- What is it?
- It's a kale
and apple juice smoothie.
It's time to think less
about your cravings
and more about filling that baby
with nutrients, which that has.
It also has chunks. I don't
drink chunks. I want my coffee.
Mark, tell the woman. I'm allowed
to drink one cup of regular coffee.
- Sure, you are.
- Mark, are you aware
that there are studies that
link caffeine with pre-term labor,
low-birth weight,
other birth defects?
That goo looks great. I
say you stick with the goo.
You two can't just dictate what
I'm allowed to eat and drink.
Nobody's dictating anything,
but you're pregnant now,
so things have to be different.
You're gonna have to eat
better and take it easier at work.
If it helps, we'll
give up caffeine, too.
- That helps no one.
- How about we put it to a vote?
All in favor of Callie drinking
coffee, raise your hand.
All in favor of the goo?
Goo, it is.
- It's horrible.
- It's the opposite of horrible.
- Alzheimer's or diabetes?
- If you continue
to whine about how
you can't decide which
ground-breaking medical advancement
to put your name on, I
will punch you in the ear.
Well, my name's already on
one of them, according to the chief.
- I mean, diabetes...
- Affects 240 million
people worldwide.
- And Alzheimer's is...
- The seventh leading
cause of death.
- It's Sophie's Choice.
- I've never seen that movie.
- You should. It's really funny.
Greys. How long has your father
been having abdominal pain?
- Abdominal pain?
- It sounds like abdominal pain.
Thatcher Grey is not an easy
man to get information from.
- Our father's
here in the hospital?
- I admitted him an hour ago.
- You didn't know he was coming?
- What's wrong?
Could it be related
to the liver transplant?
Of course, he's rejecting
it because it's my liver.
OK, look, just do me a favor,
go take a blood sample and try to
get some more information out of him.
- I need someone
who speaks "Grey".
- Yeah.
Hey, stranger.
Meredith has two ground-breaking
clinical trials, and I don't have any.
OK, but you have a
husband that loves you.
- Well, so does she.
- Then... Then I guess you're
screwed.
Hello? NICU.
I thought I knew all
the nurses on this floor.
- How did I miss you?
- Guess I'm just lucky that way.
- I'm Alex Karev.
- Neat.
- And you are...?
- Not telling you my name.
- Any reason why not?
- Because I don't want to.
OK. Then how about you
pass me one of those charts?
I hear there's a turnip
in the cabbage patch.
- Turnip?
- Gorked. Brain-dead.
Dr. Robbins and I have a baby
with a hypoplastic left heart.
- The transplant coordinator...
- Suggested the... turnip
- as a potential donor.
- Yeah.
Uh-huh.
Well, now you do get to know
my name. I'm Dr. Lucy Fields.
I delivered that gorked baby.
So thanks for the heads-up.
I'll talk to the transplant coordinator.
But now you need to leave.
Come on. That's no
reason to overreact.
Really? Well, now you're barred from
the NICU. How's that for overreacting?
- You can't do that.
- Wanna find out?
- What do we have here?
- You really don't want to know.
Let me get that for you,
Dr. Torres. OK, Randy Shouse, 23,
multiple injuries after slamming
into a brick wall? How did...?
Idiot and his idiot buddies
built a human slingshot.
I wasn't supposed to hit the wall. I
was supposed to fly over the house
- and land in the pool.
- But why would you do that?
So they could film it,
put it on the Internet
and show the world just
how stupid they actually are.
Dude!
Did you get that?
Yeah, buddy!
- But why?
- Because it's hilarious,
that's why.
OK, Randy. That must've been
some kind of awesome slingshot
because it looks like
you've dislocated both hips.
- I'm gonna need to get
some X-rays.
- I'm on it!
- Wow, she's perky.
- Better than stupid
with a death wish.
You're sick enough that you
need to come into the hospital,
- and you don't even call me?
- The pain comes and goes.
- I didn't want to...
- So you thought you'd
just sneak in
and quietly reject Meredith's
liver? Not even make a fuss?
- Please, calm down. Please?
- I am calm.
I'm so calm. I'm,
like, the calmest one.
OK, good. Because there's
something else I should've told you.
- I go to AA a couple
of times a week.
- Yes, that I know.
No, I know you
know. But sometimes,
you have to get up in front of
the group and you say your piece.
And then people sometimes
come up to you afterwards
and say that they liked what you
said. Then maybe you go to coffee
- with them afterward.
- Like a sponsor?
No, not a sponsor. How do I...?
There you are! Sorry, I got turned
around and ended up back in the lobby.
No, no, no!
- No, no, no!
- Oh, God, what? Sorry. Are you in pain?
Yeah. Not a sponsor.
I'm so sorry, this was not the
way that I wanted to meet you.
I didn't even know
there was a you to meet.
I know. I'm sorry, but...
OK, Mr. Grey. Oh, hello.
- Dr. Bailey, this is Danielle.
- Dani. Hi.
Yes, Dani. It's my father's girlfriend,
whom I've just met, just now.
Oh, I see. Nice
to meet you, Dani.
I just have a few questions,
and then I will let you get back to...
- all of this.
- Do you really think I could be
rejecting this liver? Because
Dani has been amazing
helping me take care of myself.
And I'm constantly taking pills.
His anti-rejection meds.
Not, like, speed or anything.
'Cause that would
be inappropriate.
- When did the pain start?
- Twelve days ago.
- She's good with the details.
- Any fevers
or changes in
your urine or stool?
No fevers. But there was a...
pain incident last
week. Thursday.
Actually, you might not
want to hear this part.
I'm a doctor.
All right. Well, we
were being intimate.
- Oh, no...
- And I was on top...
OK.
Go on.
Dr. Avery, it's about time
I had you on my service.
Thank you,
Dr. Sloan. I gotta say,
I really think I have
the hands for plastics.
Forget about your hands.
Look at those cheekbones.
- Sir?
- You're genetically blessed.
Don't think I haven't noticed.
Speaking from personal experience,
I can say that that'll only
help you in plastics. That face?
Better than a hundred
billboards, my man.
All right, Dr. Sloan, I...
really don't feel comfortable being
judged or praised based on my looks.
Oh, poor Mr. Green Eyes.
Let's not pretend being
beautiful's a burden.
Now, come on. Mrs. Johnson's
nose isn't gonna fix itself.
How about a little sparkle?
There it is.
Hip dislocation, fractures of his
femur, radius, ribs and metacarpals.
OK. Should we just go
ahead and reduce those hips?
Kepner, I need you
to speak differently.
- I'm sorry?
- Your voice. It's a little...
Just speak differently.
- Like with an accent?
- Never mind. You know,
how about you get me a
muffin from the cafeteria?
Get me the sugary-est kind
you can find. And some coffee.
Wait. No. Damn it.
- No coffee.
- OK.
No, you know what? Yes. Coffee.
- Please.
- Great.
Crap! No. No coffee.
- You're sure?
- No. No coffee. Just...
- Just go.
- OK.
- Did you still want the muffin?
- Yes.
Yes, I know I'm not Dr. Bailey, but
he's my father and I need his lab results.
- Sorry, I can't do it.
- OK. Well, then maybe
I'll just let your supervisor know
that I've been highly unsatisfied
- with your service today.
- This isn't the mall.
- We don't have comment cards.
- Well, maybe you should!
- Hey. You OK? Need me to talk to him?
- Mark, no.
My day has been too messed
up to have you in it, too.
Son of a bitch.
We know, without a doubt,
that this heart is a viable option.
How? How do we know
that this a good match?
Babies under a year haven't
developed an immune system
that will reject the new organ.
It makes matching a lot easier.
But we're still four weeks
away from the due date.
Our OB isn't even
in town right now.
I'm covering for Dr. Napolitano.
I've got her blessing to go
ahead and do the C-section today.
Today?
- That's really...
- Colin, time's an issue here.
We need to inform the transplant
board as soon as possible
if you want this heart. Otherwise
it's gonna go to another family.
OK. You know what?
There are a lot of doctors
in the room right now,
so why don't we give
the Cookes some space?
You can have one of the nurses
page us when you've made a decision.
What's going on? Why
didn't you page me?
- Turnip, Karev?
- You tattled on me?
- You are so off this case.
- Seriously?
- I have said way
worse stuff than that.
- Yeah, not helping.
Are you kidding me?
Avery, you want to give
the osteotomies a shot?
Yes, sir. Mallet, please.
You live with Lexie
Grey now, right?
- How's she doing these days?
- OK, I guess.
OK? She hasn't seemed upset?
I mean, she kind of cries
sometimes. But she seems OK.
Now, are you gonna strip
the lateral cartilage here?
- Crying seems fine?
- She's a girl. Girls cry.
But you don't know what
she's been upset about?
Not really any of my business.
- Yeah... What's next?
- Next, I finish up here
while you go find out
what's up with Lexie.
- I'm sorry?
- She's upset.
And you're gonna find out why. You
want to be on my service? Then serve.
- Use that Avery sparkle.
- Dr. Sloan...
I'm gonna do a couple more rhinoplasties
this afternoon. You do me this solid,
and I just might be persuaded
to let you take the lead on one.
OK.
Oh.
What're you doing?
Uh...
I looked it up. And
those caffeine studies
showed birth defects in
rats. And I'm not a rat, so...
- Tell her I'm not a rat.
- Let her have...
- We took a vote.
- Yeah, well,
I have to fix multiple fractures,
Arizona. That's major surgery.
OK, so that totally changes
the situation completely.
And Mark's not here, so it's your
vote against mine... I need caffeine.
OK. You want caffeine
that badly, Calliope, fine.
You're a grownup. You can
make your own decisions.
That's right. So...
Damn it! That is not
fair. You're not fair.
For someone who has a history of
ambivalence towards motherhood,
you got the whole
guilt thing down cold.
I'm entitled to an opinion.
I've been left out of too much
of the conversation already.
And I sure as hell did not
choose Mark Sloan to be the father.
So if I'm gonna do this, then, you
know what? I'm gonna have a voice.
Oh, God, that's good.
Holy crap! Your mom was smart.
Truck. Cabin. Spoon.
Three for three!
- Crap! This is so good!
- Is it better than this?
'Cause seriously, Mer, you'd have
to have died of Alzheimer's to fail this.
- I don't even know
if I'm doing it yet.
- You have to.
"Mother/daughter
surgeons cure leading killer."
I'm so jealous, and I'm doing
a heart transplant on a baby
- that hasn't even
been born yet.
- Will you shut up about that?
You're the one who needs to keep
his mouth shut, Cabbage Patch.
Screw this. I've been on this case
for a month. I'm not just gonna sit here.
- Meredith, you
have to come see Dad.
- Does he want more organs?
He wouldn't say, he was too busy
lovin'-up on a tattooed 20-year-old.
Is that upsetting you?
- You wanna talk about it?
- No!
No worries. I have
a surgery to get to.
- Meredith?
- I can't deal with my dad.
- I'm too busy with my mom.
- Let's go.
I wanna see your dad making
out with his tatted up fiancée.
- They're not engaged.
- Are you sure?
- Meredith, please.
- Fine.
You're doing great, Sarah.
- I didn't hear her cry.
- Her lungs were junky.
- We had to intubate.
- She deteriorated fast.
- I'll call for an X-ray
and ultrasound.
- Already ordered it.
What's her pH?
You'll need an ABG...
- Karev, we got it.
- Dr. Robbins, she's my patient.
Not anymore.
- You got something for me,
Avery?
- I do, actually.
Her dad's here. He
might be rejecting his liver.
And he brought his
20-year-old girlfriend.
Yeah, that'll do it. Lexie's
probably going crazy.
Meredith's no help when
it comes to their father.
I'm not gonna be lead
surgeon on a rhinoplasty, am I?
- She just needs someone
to talk to.
- We are not close.
- That is not something we do.
- Peanut butter cups.
- What?
- She's a stress eater.
You get her eating,
you get her talking.
- She loves peanut butter cups.
- That's ridiculous.
Tomorrow, I'm doing a
series of cleft-palate surgeries
for the Nightingales
Foundation. Pro bono.
That sort of thing might
look fantastic on the resume
of someone who's in the
running for chief resident.
- Might?
- Get some results... we'll talk.
- Get in there.
- And do what?
- Make it stop!
- There's no way she's 20.
- She's gotta be, like, 26, 27.
- I'm 27.
Oh.
Gross.
Tiny-baby-heart time. Careful
when you go in there, Mer.
You tangle with one Hells Angel,
you tangle with the whole gang.
- OK. You coming?
- I'm not going in there again.
- Seriously, Lexie?
- I can't.
- Well, then I'm going
back to work.
- Meredith!
- All right, hey. Move, please.
- I'm gonna page Bailey.
- This is what
happened last time.
- Dad, is it the same pain?
- Where does it hurt?
- I'm telling you,
- I have seen this before.
- Will you please let him talk?
- He can't talk.
- It's here.
- All right, just back up.
- Baby, it's gonna be OK.
- Back up.
- I need to do something. Tell me...
Back the hell up right now!
All right, all right, Dad.
The blood tests indicate
that your liver's fine.
Is there anything at
all that you've left out?
It's when he pees.
Just now. And then,
last Thursday, we had Mexican
food, and he drank all this water
because it was spicy and he went to
the bathroom as soon as we got home.
I was so freaked out when he
screamed later during the sex,
- I didn't even connect it.
- All right. Good, that helps.
- So what do you
think it could be?
- It could be kidney stones.
- Or your prostate.
- Prostate? Are...?
You're saying he could have
cancer. He can't have cancer.
That's what happens when
your boyfriend's an old man.
- Old men get cancer.
- Lexie...
But see, if you were
a doctor, like we are,
you'd realize that when
we use the word "prostate",
- it doesn't necessarily
mean cancer.
- Dr. Grey.
No, see, freaking out and jumping
to conclusions like a little child
- isn't gonna do him any good.
- I am scared, OK?!
I am terrified over here,
and I've got questions.
You're terrified?
We're his family.
- I'm his family, too!
- No, you're not his family!
- You're his midlife crisis!
- Lexie, Lexie!
That's enough.
You're out of line.
- Fine.
- Lexie.
Cancer is one of a
hundred things it could be.
Dr. Bailey will run some
more tests just to rule it out.
It's far more likely there's
another explanation for this.
Are you the daughter
that gave him the liver?
- I am.
- Thank you.
- Say it again for the camera.
- No, no I don't think I will.
Kepner, talk to the camera
so we can get to the OR.
In my normal voice, or...?
Randy has multiple fractures.
The most pressing problems
are his hip dislocations.
So we are going to reduce
them as soon as possible
- before they lose blood flow.
- Reduce?
- Pop 'em back into place.
- Oh, man!
Hold on, let me get up on
this chair for the wide angle.
Yeah. We're not doing it here.
He has to be sedated and
we have to fix his femur.
So we're just gonna
do everything in the OR.
What if we did the hips
here, while I'm awake?
And I can give the
thumbs-up to the camera.
You're really not grasping
how much this'll hurt.
- It's for the art, Dr. Torres.
- You know what?
That is a great idea.
- Dr. Hunt, I think that it's...
- Dr. Torres, it is for the art.
Oh.
OK. OK. OK, yeah.
Marcus, hop on that chair.
Kepner, spot him. All right. Sure.
OK, you guys ready?
OK.
Please stop! Stop!
Stop! Turn the camera off!
Marcus, turn the camera off!
- That totally cheered me up.
- Art has that effect.
Listen, I'm sorry
about the turnip thing.
I shouldn't have said
it. But doctor to doctor,
you over-reacted.
That's my patient.
I deserve to be in there.
You deserve it? Huh.
You know, I have a patient, too.
You wanna know what
happened to my patient?
- Look, I'm sure it's tough...
- She had a 40-hour labor.
And then the baby was stuck
on an angle, wouldn't drop.
So my patient just had to push
and push and push.
And you want to know what you say
to a woman who's in that kind of pain?
You say, "One more, Jackie.
One more and you're
gonna see that baby.
One more and you're gonna
have a beautiful baby boy.
I know it hurts, I know it does,
but give me one more, Jackie,
and you get a baby".
That's how you get a woman
to tear her own body apart.
You promise her a baby.
You make a promise and she
hurts herself because she trusts you,
and then when the baby
comes out and he's not...
he's not...
You're the one that's
gotta tell her that you were...
mistaken.
Makes me kind of lose
interest in what you deserve,
Mr. Where's The Cabbage Patch.
Hey, Dad's got a kidney stone.
Dr. Bailey's taking him up to the OR now.
Well, she didn't just give him
a strainer? It's gotta be huge.
Well, he deserves it.
I never really got it before,
but this is how he operates.
He starts up new families,
stops talking to the old ones.
He'll go off and marry
Dani, The Tattooed Lady,
have six little mid-life crisis babies,
and I'll never hear from him again.
It's exactly what he did to you.
It is not exactly
what he did to me.
- Of course it is.
- Lexie, my mother
had an affair,
and then took his
kid across the country.
Your mother died
and he was miserable.
And he started drinking
and he destroyed his liver.
This isn't about you. He found
someone who makes him happy.
Just give him your
blessing. Let him be happy.
What're you talking
about? Don't defend him.
- You hate him! Hate him with me!
- Lexie, I love you,
but you have to grow up.
We've got a strong heartbeat.
I think she likes her new heart.
Of course she
does. It's delightful.
All right. Let's take off
the clamp, Dr. Yang.
Why is her blood
pressure so low?
There's a low arterial
pressure wave.
All right, let's check it. Maybe
there's a kink in the art line somewhere.
Damn it! Turn up the flow.
That aorta needs a long
diagonal anastomosis.
- That'll take at least
45 minutes.
- We don't have that.
We've gotta do it in 30, otherwise
we're gonna lose her. Scalpel!
Clamp it. Start the clock.
Son of a bitch.
I hate this. I hate this.
Come on... Come on...
- What time do you have, Yang?
- Twenty-seven minutes.
OK, I'm ready.
Clamp off.
We got this.
Robbins, Altman, they got this.
Yeah? Then why do you look sick?
- Pressure wave's coming back.
- Systolic's 57.
Sixty.
Sixty-four.
- Eighty-two.
- That's it! Yes!
- Yes!
Chief, I'm with a patient.
Did you get a chance to
look over the materials?
- I did. It's amazing.
- The next step is getting
the funding
in place, and I can make two phone
calls and have that by midweek.
- So you're waiting for...
- You.
You have to sign on as co-investigator
so we can start moving forward.
- Chief, it's an amazing offer.
- It's not an offer, Meredith.
I can't offer something
that doesn't belong to me.
It was your mother's work, and
it's only right that you continue it.
- So you think that I
owe it to her?
- Honestly?
I think she owes it to you.
She didn't give you a lot of
love, but she gave you her talent.
And her name.
And this.
This gift could change
the course of your career.
- I have to get back inside.
- Meredith.
It might change the
way you think about her.
It could be the greatest
thing the both of you ever did.
How did it get to this? How
did four seconds of Internet fame
become worth breaking
yourself into a million pieces?
He did it... because
he thinks it's funny.
That's bull. You just don't
put yourself at that kind of risk.
- Well, it's his decision.
- His decision?
Idiots like this shouldn't
be allowed to make any...
It is his body, OK! And you don't get
to say what he can and can't do with it!
He is a person, he gets to
make his own damn choices!
I am going through the worst
caffeine withdrawal of my life
because someone thinks
that being pregnant means
- I'm no longer of sound
frickin' mind!
- You're pregnant?
Shut up! I'm not endangering my
baby. I just want one damn cup of coffee!
OK. Kepner, go get
Dr. Torres a cup of coffee.
- OK.
- Run!
- Thank you.
- Congratulations.
Whatever. Just come around
here and help me with this hip!
Ready, one, two, three.
She doesn't seem so bad.
Candy?
Screw you and your candy.
- She's terrible.
- All right.
Ever notice how
my sister's a jerk?
- I...
- "Give him your blessing."
What a bunch of crap. Let
him be happy? What about me?
You know, everybody's
making these huge life decisions,
and they're not even considering
how it'll affect me. How I'll feel.
You know, I'm supposed to
be such a big part of their lives,
and yet they're leaving me out
of the conversation completely.
Starting up new families and springing
it on me when it's already a done deal.
"Hey, Lexie, guess what?
I found a tatted up skank to be
your new mommy. "" Hey, Lexie,
I'm gonna have a baby and you're
just gonna have to be OK with that!"
Wait a second. Your
dad's having a baby?
No, not my dad. Mark.
Mark is having a baby, and
he didn't even ask my opinion.
He just clobbered
me with it. Again.
And he's leaving
me behind... again.
So we're done, you
know? We have to be.
But I miss him.
Crap.
My dad's tatted up
skank isn't the bitch.
I am.
Probably a good start would be to
stop calling her a tatted up skank.
Right.
Thanks.
For listening.
Anytime.
Hey.
I banned him from
the NICU this morning.
Kinda want to go in
there and kick him out.
Yeah, punishing Karev is one
of my favorite pastimes, too.
He's harsh sometimes.
But he's also the guy
that gets thrown off a case
and then sits in the gallery
and watches an entire surgery
just to make sure his patient's OK.
I'll teach him to be less of an ass, but
I don't have to teach him how to care.
Do you even have the authority
to ban someone from the NICU?
I don't know.
Just in time, Avery.
Scrub in and take the lead.
That's OK. I just came by to
tell you that you were wrong.
Those peanut butter
cups got me nowhere.
- You're kidding.
- Guess you overestimated
that Avery sparkle, huh?
- Where are you going? Scrub in.
- Really?
- I... I assumed
no results, no surgery.
- I'm not a total bastard.
You gave it your
best shot. Scrub in.
OK.
- I don't know.
- It's OK. Take your time.
Truck.
Cabin.
Remember the third word, Mom?
We should have come earlier.
- She has a harder time
in the evenings.
- She's doing fine.
We're just running some tests.
It's "spoon", Mom.
Remember, "spoon"?
I don't know why we're here.
Why are we here?
- It's such a little word.
- Can we go home now?
OK, Mom. OK.
He's gonna be sore for a while.
You'll need to make sure
he drinks plenty of water.
- Dr. Grey?
- Is he OK?
He's fine.
Lexie?
Will you please just make
sure that he calls me?
- Yes. Of course.
- Thank you.
I'm almost five years sober.
We support each other and...
I'm good for him.
And he is really,
really good for me.
That a hooker on your shoulder?
I was drunk.
OK.
There he is. How
you feelin', buddy?
I can't straighten it
out any more than that.
There's the surgeon! You're
the man, Dr. Hunt! How'd he do?
OK, Randy. Since there was
a tear in your joint capsule,
we needed to open up the hip to
reduce it. We put a rod and screws in
to the other femur to fix
that and reduce the other hip.
And this piece of hardware is
keeping your wrist fracture together.
That's intense. Is that, like,
some sort of record or something?
Like the worst case
you've ever seen?
No. No, the worst
case I ever saw
was a guy who had an ex
fix on his arm like this one,
but he also had a gaping hole with
exposed bone that needed to be covered.
He also had a matching hole
that ripped through his back
and tore his stomach apart. We did 11
surgeries to reconstruct his abdomen.
- He survived all that?
- No. No, he didn't.
But you know, come to think of it,
your situation, it is actually worse.
- How?
- That guy, he threw himself
in front of a grenade to
save six other soldiers.
He didn't launch himself into a brick
wall so the Internet could laugh at him.
Turn the camera off, Marcus.
Chief.
I'd forgotten this about your
mother. She wrote everything down.
She didn't have a thought
or a fragment of a thought
that didn't get scribbled in some
journal. She was compulsive.
- Lucky for you that she did.
- Lucky for both of us.
No, for you.
You knew the woman who wrote
them. That's why I gave them to you.
I was happy to read them
and to understand her better,
but the woman I
knew was different.
But I am starting to realize
how scared she must have been.
That had to be why she
was writing everything down.
- She must have been so scared.
- Meredith...
So, please, go ahead.
I think it's right that
you continue her work.
But I really just want
to cure her disease.
Good night, chief.
Good night.
So, what's your plan?
Sleep.
My plan for tonight is sleep.
I was gonna hit Joe's
before heading home.
- Want to come?
- I just need to crash.
Yeah. No, I get that.
Maybe tomorrow?
For sure, yeah.
- Sorry about your patient.
- Thanks. I'm happy for yours.
- Hey, you want to get a...?
- No.
Right.
- We made dinner... for you!
- What is it?
Grilled chicken breast and
some brown rice and broccoli.
- And... Is that coffee?
- Yes.
It is. And here's the thing.
I get that things are
gonna be different now.
And that's why I'm
gonna eat that chicken,
even though the only thing I want
right now is a peanut butter sandwich.
- Great...
- Oh, I'm not done.
If we're gonna do this whole
"everybody gets a vote" thing,
there's gonna be a new system.
We'll still each get one vote.
But, also, the baby gets a vote.
As I house the baby, I'll be
speaking for him-slash-her.
And since I'll be pushing this baby
out of a very small hole in my body,
I'll also get an
extra-special vagina vote.
So, that's three votes for
us, two votes for you guys.
Oh, we get the final say.
Now, I'll be using my many votes
to say that, once a day, I will
have one cup of regular coffee.
Which is perfectly fine according
to the studies that I've read.
At least until I begin breast-feeding.
Now, anybody want to argue
with my extra-special
vagina vote?
- No.
- No, thank you.
Great.
Oh, we also vote that
Mark gives me a foot rub.
I'll go get the lotion.
OK, well, I guess that a peanut
butter sandwich is doable,
- if you eat the broccoli.
- Deal.
Surgery is a high-stakes game.
Did you decide?
I did.
- I choose you.
- I'm glad.
I've been going over the
data you collected today.
And so far, it is 100 percent
consistent with the pre-trial phase.
- Which means what?
- It means that it's not
not-working.
Oh, that's great news.
You wanna know what
else is great news?
- What?
- The kids aren't gonna be home
for another 20 minutes.
But no matter how high
the stakes, sooner or later
you're just gonna
have to go with your gut.
And maybe, just maybe,
that'll take you right where you
were meant to be in the first place.