A month ago, you were in med
school being taught by doctors.
Today...
You are the doctors.
The seven years you spend
here as a surgical resident
will be the best and
worst of your life.
You will be pushed
to the breaking point.
Eight of you will switch
to an easier specialty.
Five of you will crack
under the pressure.
Two of you will
be asked to leave.
This is your starting line.
This is your arena.
How well you play,
that's up to you.
Mer?
Meredith! Meredith!
Get up! You have to get up now!
Meredith! Get up!
Oh, God.
I...
Oh.
How long was I
out? I don't... I...
I don't know. I lost my...
I lost my shoe.
Where's... Where's
Derek and Lexie?
I don't... I don't
know. I lost a shoe.
What happened?
The plane crashed,
that's what happened.
We were in a plane, and
it crashed. Plane crash.
Where is Derek?
Cristina, where is Derek?
He was sucked out the side
when we hit the trees,
and then the back
of the plane came off.
It came... It came off.
Lexie was in the
back of the plane.
I looked to the back, and all
I could see was freakin' sky.
Where is she? I don't
know! I only have one shoe!
I'm bleeding.
Shut up! Shut up! Shut up!
Do you hear... Do
you hear that sound?
Where is that sound coming from?
There.
It's coming from over there.
Derek!
Lexie!
Derek! Lexie!
Lexie.
Oh.
Is somebody there? I can't...
I'm... I'm here. I'm here.
I can't...
I'm... I'm stuck in here.
Don't do that. Don't do that.
I have to help. Stop. Stop.
I can't get outta here.
What's your name?
Jerry. Jerry, I'm Arizona.
I don't want you to move, okay?
'Cause you could... You
could injure yourself more.
The controls just... I...
I think one of the engines quit.
I... Is anybody else alive?
Um...
Yeah.
Yeah, we're all
alive. Well, I...
I think we're all alive.
You're all surgeons.
What's funny?
I am... I'm married to
an orthopedic surgeon
and I'm staring at my bone.
And it's not... It's not funny.
I think I'm in a
little bit of shock.
Okay.
But really, I'm fine.
It's okay.
If I could just get
myself to stop laughing.
Arizona?
Yeah? Yeah?
I can't feel my legs.
Yeah, I knew that was bad.
Lexie. Lexie.
I knew you'd show up.
How is she?
She's awake and responsive.
How you doing in there?
I'm... I'm great.
Yeah? Good girl. We're
gonna get you outta here, okay?
Okay.
She's tachycardic
and short of breath.
We have to find Derek.
Okay, you know
what? We've got Lexie.
So go. Go find him.
Go, go. Go try and find him.
We gotta get her outta there.
Oh...
Pop it back in.
Wait. Wait. Wait.
Okay, do it.
Oh, God!
Derek! Derek!
Derek!
Meredith?
Meredith.
Derek!
Sir. Have you seen Dr. Altman?
No, but, um, sir, you
have a few messages.
Is anybody dying? No.
Is it Dr. Yang? No.
Then send all
calls to voice mail.
I have multiple
traumas coming in.
I don't have time.
And find me Altman.
All right. Where do
you want me, Chief?
Incoming. Building collapsed
on a bunch of firefighter recruits.
Last day of their training.
Happy graduation.
Okay, well, you
have me till 7:00.
I've got a dinner with the
last group of residents tonight.
I do not understand why
you're spending your week
taking the residents
out to dinner.
Oh, come on, Hunt. It's a tradition.
We're celebrating a milestone.
You're welcome
to join. I'll pass.
I'm telling you, it's an
evening you won't forget,
and the kids, they just love it.
Could someone
please mercy kill me,
so I don't have
to go to this thing?
You do me, I'll do you.
Better leave me a bullet.
Hell if I'm going alone.
Yang and Grey skipped
town at the perfect time.
Oh, no, they will be
back in time for the dinner.
Because I had to pick up
their stupid dry cleaning,
and dig through
their stupid closets
for their stupid heels,
all the while babysitting
Mer's stupid kid.
She's not stupid.
She's actually adorable.
Hey, you decide on Tulane yet?
No, I'm still
weighing my options.
Lot of factors involved.
At least you have options.
Hey, want to hear mine?
When I go back to Moline,
do I work at the Tastee Freez
or milk cows on the farm?
Tastee Freez. No-brainer.
You're still a doctor.
Just go to Tulane already.
It's a thing.
People are together,
but they live apart.
"Live-a-partners."
It's common enough
to have a name.
Syphilis is common
enough to have a name.
Doesn't mean I want it.
Who doesn't want what?
Somebody has gotten themselves
a surgical internship
in Los Angeles.
I'm branching out.
Congratulations.
Or not?
We wouldn't be the first
commuter marriage on the planet.
You're getting married?
Oh, that's fantastic.
Okay, you should probably
leave while you can.
I'm going. Because my love is
strong enough to handle the space.
Long-distance relationship?
Not the end of the world.
You gonna give
me some crap about
"absence makes the
heart grow fonder"?
No. Absence makes
the sex grow hotter.
Arizona's only been
gone for one night,
and already, she's inspired
a totally hot "I miss you" thing
when she gets back. Mmm-hmm.
I have lingerie and
flavored body paint...
There is a God.
Okay, ready? On
my count. One, two...
Three.
Again.
One, two, three.
Damn it!
Lexie, run it down for me.
My legs and my
pelvis are crushed.
And I can't feel my other arm,
so I'm not sure it's
even there anymore.
And, my chest feels
like it's gonna explode,
so it's probably a
massive hemothorax.
We... We gotta... We gotta get
the oxygen from the plane. Okay?
And fluids. Fluids. She
needs water bottles.
And the tubes, the oxygen tubes.
We can get her fluids.
We can get her fluids,
okay? Go get 'em.
Go. Go get 'em. Go get 'em.
Why aren't you doing anything?
She... She knows it won't help.
No.
You are gonna be fine.
Stop. You're gonna be fine.
Go! Get 'em!
I'm gonna be right back.
I've got a lot of free fluid
in the upper right quadrant.
- Somebody call CT.
- Right away, Doctor.
Open femur in two.
Strong pulse. He's good.
I need those chest films, please.
- Right away.
What's up? I just got a call
from Rita Simon this morning.
Really? I haven't heard
from Rita since Baghdad.
Yeah, I was surprised, too,
especially when she asked me
if I knew if you were taking
the Chief job at MEDCOM.
I was gonna tell you.
But you didn't.
I've already lost the
head of neuro to Harvard,
and now I have to find
a new head of cardio
on top of everyone else?
I'm not taking the job.
I just haven't had
time to tell MEDCOM.
What... What do
you mean, you're...
Let's get him ready for CT.
I'm gonna try and splint this.
No, I can do it. I can do it.
Jerry needs
C-spine stabilization.
Who's Jerry?
How are you doing there, Jerry?
I give us four hours
tops before they find us.
There's a transmitter
in the plane
that lets out a squawk that
should lead 'em right to us.
Oh!
Did you find Derek?
Uh, not yet. Jerry,
do you have any tape?
Uh, yeah. Uh, in the bulkhead.
In the cabinet to your left.
There's a flare gun
in there, too. Yes.
You hear a chopper,
you fire it straight up.
And Lexie? Not good.
Oh, great. Great,
great, great, great, great.
Aah!
Okay, keep your
head very still. Yeah.
Good, good. Okay.
Jerry...
Is there a first aid kit?
A... Yeah, a big one.
In the cabinet on your
right, behind the cockpit.
There's no cabinet there.
Just tell her to hang on
for another four hours.
Great.
Hey, hey, wait. Don't leave!
I can't feel my legs.
That's because
I'm trapped, right?
I mean, I'm gonna
be okay, right?
I'm not paralyzed.
I'm gonna walk again.
I'm gonna be okay, right?
I'm sorry.
Cristina.
I can't find him. I
looked everywhere.
I can't find him.
Maybe he's fine.
Maybe he went for help.
Maybe, but I gotta...
I gotta keep looking.
No, Meredith.
You should come... Help Lexie.
You're doing good.
Mark... Cristina's...
Cristina's gonna
be back any minute.
Mark... She's gonna be back,
and we're gonna
get you stabilized,
and you're gonna be fine, okay?
Mark... Just a few
minutes, okay?
She'll be back
any minute. Mark...
I'm... I'm dying.
What? No, you're not.
I am.
Please... Tell...
Tell Meredith
that I love her.
And that she's a good sister.
Please tell my dad...
You're not dying.
You're gonna be fine.
Hold my hand.
I'm not holding your hand,
because you're not dying.
Hold my hand.
No. You're not dying.
Do you hear me?
You don't die today.
I love you.
You don't have to say it
just because I said
it. I do. I love you.
I love you. I've always
been in love with you.
I will always be
in love with you.
Yeah? Yeah.
Which is why you
have to stay alive.
We... We... We're
gonna get married.
And you're gonna make
an amazing surgeon.
And we're gonna
have two or three kids.
So Sofia
can have siblings.
Yeah. A sister and two brothers.
And... That's nice.
We're gonna be happy, Lex...
You and me.
We're gonna have the
best life, Lexie, you and me.
We're gonna be so happy.
So you can't die, okay?
You can't die...
Because we're supposed
to end up together.
We're meant to be.
Meant to be.
I love you.
I love you. I love
you. I love you.
I love you.
Lexie.
Your wife is bonkers.
Yeah, but she's cute.
No, she pulled me off
every single peds case
before she left.
She's punishing me
for choosing Hopkins.
Ouch.
You know what? I don't
care. I'm calling her right now.
Hey, Karev, no.
Put that phone away.
No good's gonna come
out of that. I'm pissed.
Yeah, well, so is she.
You know why? 'Cause she
loves you. She'll get over it.
The best thing you can
do is just leave it alone.
Wait 'till she comes back.
Talk to her tomorrow, when
you've both calmed down.
If you got nothing to
do, scrub in with me.
I've got an open femur.
Oh! There you are.
Why tomorrow? I thought
she was coming back tonight.
Uh, tonight I've
got things planned
that don't include her
screaming your name.
Mmm.
Will you at least tell
me why? Why what?
Why you turned down
the job at MEDCOM.
No. Hunt. Altman.
Tell me. No.
Somebody want to tell
me what MEDCOM is?
It would make this a
whole lot more fun for me.
Army medical command.
They oversee every
medical operation
in the US and in Europe.
Fancy. Very.
She'd be instructing,
innovating surgical
field techniques,
and they're interested in
funding her stem cell research.
Sounds like a good fit.
It is a once-in-a-lifetime
opportunity,
so I just don't understand...
So what, now you're
pissed that I'm not leaving?
Where's your loyalty?
You're being asked
to serve your country.
Do you know where
we are right now, Hunt?
This is the room
where my husband died.
Right here on this table.
And no matter how many
wonderful and amazing
and miraculous things
happen in this room,
it will always be the room
where my husband died.
And the south elevator
will always be the place
where I met him, and...
And the cafeteria will
always be the place
where he bought my lunch.
I would love to leave
here and never look back.
But you are as beaten
and broken as I
have ever seen you.
And after everything that
I have put you through,
the tolerance and kindness
and friendship that
you have shown me,
I am not going to leave you
because of my loyalty.
I am not going to leave here
for MEDCOM or anywhere else.
This isn't holding.
3-0 Prolene, please.
Derek!
I don't understand how
this keeps happening.
Cristina, we have to find him.
I'm serious.
I do not understand how
this keeps happening.
We have to find him because
I don't think he went for help.
We keep dying. We're
in a plane crash, Mer.
Like... Like, right now.
If he went for help, if
Derek had gone for help,
he would've sent a
message or something.
I mean, we have to find
him. Something is wrong.
I can tell you one thing.
When we get out of here,
I am getting the hell away
from Seattle Grace-Mercy death,
and I'm never looking back!
Cristina...
I think Derek is dead.
He would've come for us by now.
He definitely would've
come for us by now.
I think he's dead.
And Lexie's dead.
My husband and
sister are both dead!
And we are gonna
die out here, too!
We are gonna die out here...
Keep it together.
No, you keep it
together! I'm trying!
I know. Keep... Keep
it together anyway.
Keep it together anyway.
My sister is dead.
Do you think Derek is dead?
I don't know. Maybe.
But I've got PTSD, so
you know I'm not reliable.
Cristina...
You are still my person,
even if I'm not yours.
Meredith, Meredith.
Meredith.
I heard your voice.
I thought I... I thought
I was dreaming.
Oh, my God.
Oh, I found it!
The first aid box?
My shoe.
Is she gonna be okay?
She's not barefoot anymore.
Well, I guess that's something.
Son of a... Damn it.
MEREDITH: I know.
Son of a... I know.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Okay. Where's Lexie?
Clothes. No?
Oh.
Okay.
Okay, let's just keep
it together, okay?
Okay.
Clothes.
Loosen the
tourniquet a little bit.
You'll bleed to death.
I need to save my hand.
Well, I'm trying
to save your life.
Oh, safety pin. Safety pin.
Bring that.
Do you have a
T-shirt or a bandana?
Got it. Got it.
Okay, we have to
close the wound.
Use the safety pin.
Weave your way inside and out
and then put the
bandana on top of it
and tape it.
And what's the...
What's the T-shirt for?
Put it in my mouth. I'm
probably gonna scream a lot,
and I'm gonna... I'm
gonna... I'm gonna pass out.
Okay.
Good. Okay.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Please pass out.
You'll have to close up for me.
I have to preorder our duck...
Slow-roasted, it takes
six hours, falls off the bone.
Oh, the residency
dinner. Can I come?
You've had your
turn. Now it's theirs.
You kids jazzed
about dinner? Yes, sir.
Oh, very jazzed.
Yum.
Well, call me Miles
Davis, 'cause I'm jazzed.
I'll give you 10 bucks to
stab me in the face right now.
Hey.
Now I know why you were
trying so hard to keep her here.
If Cristina were staying,
you'd be taking that job.
I'll be fine.
No, no, Owen, you won't.
You are losing
the love of your life.
Yeah.
Everywhere I look,
I expect to see her.
She's not even gone,
and I miss her already.
I wish I could tell
you that will go away,
but it won't.
Matches. Yes, God. Finally.
Fire. We can build a fire.
We Should. They'll see a fire.
Let's get a fire started.
Yeah, Mark. We need...
We need to start a fire.
Mark. Mark.
You have to help.
I'll figure out how
to get it started.
No. You know what?
He doesn't get to do this.
He doesn't get to stop helping.
I'm sorry he lost Lexie,
but she was your sister,
and you're still helping.
He has to help because
the sky is falling, Mark.
Cristina.
No, no, no.
You know, if there's
one thing that I've learned
with all the... The bombs
and the guns to my head and...
And the buses running
down my friends
is that I am not
interested in dying.
I want to get out of here,
and I want to go home.
And everyone has to help.
Mark, get up. Get
up and help, Mark.
Get up.
Mark? Mark? Mark?
Mark. Please. Please be okay.
Mark.
Oh!
Oh, crap.
Mer!
What happened?
When I rechecked him, he had
muffled heart sounds and JVD.
Delayed tamponade?
It's a cardiac tamponade.
Are you sure? 75%.
70%. 70% sure.
That's not very sure.
Well, if you want me to be
sure, get me an ultrasound.
Will you man the
ultrasound? Mmm-hmm.
Thank you.
Looks like the
pericardium's about to burst.
We have to drain his pericardial
sac and relieve the pressure, or...
- Or his heart will stop.
- With what?
We don't even have
an 18-gauge spinal
needle. I don't know.
All right. 18 gauge.
Okay, I got it. Okay.
Hold this. Take the top off.
Okay. Why?
Use that right there.
Use the tube.
Brilliant. Brilliant.
All right, sure.
Okay, this will work.
Sanitize that.
Is the tubing long enough?
I'm going in, um, subxiphoid.
Knife.
Okay, needle.
Here. Here you go, Mer.
Try not to move, Mark.
Try not to move.
Easy, Mark. It's okay. Don't
move. It's gonna be okay.
Aim for his left shoulder.
Wait. Don't puncture his
heart. I know, I know, I know.
Careful. Don't
puncture the heart.
I know.
Okay.
Deeper!
Good. Excellent. That's
it. That's it. That's it. Great.
Very good. It's gonna be okay.
That's good. That's
it. That's exactly it.
You did it. Just let
it drain into here.
You did it. You got it.
I got it. I got the
bag. You got it.
There.
Wanna go for lunch?
Hey! What the
hell are you doing?
Eating. No. No. You
have a dinner tonight.
The... The biggest
dinner of your lives.
Here's the thing,
I can't eat duck.
I had a duck on the
farm. It lived in the house.
So order the steak.
Here's the thing, I had a cow...
Look, no one really
wants to go tonight.
He's preordering the duck.
Come on. Where's... Where's
your sense of occasion?
Mmm. In Baltimore at Hopkins.
Webber and I have issues.
He knows what he did.
I failed my boards. I
have nothing to celebrate.
Oh, boo-hoo. Oh, poor
April didn't pass her test.
Big whoop, okay?
I got fired from Chief Resident,
then I got fired
from this hospital.
Oh, my husband cheated on me.
You were married to a man?
And then he died.
So I didn't think I was
gonna ever be happy again.
But now my life is
pretty damn great.
So you're having a
rough time. It's nothing.
It's a blip.
And in the meantime,
you're missing your moment.
You survived residency.
Stop and celebrate that.
'Cause life... Changes in
an instant. It turns on a dime.
One minute you're miserable,
and then the next...
You've met the most
amazing woman in the world
and are in love.
This moment, your moment,
it only happens once.
Oh. And the duck
is freakin' amazing.
Hey.
Mark?
What happened? Tamponade.
Mer did a pericardiocentesis.
Oh, my God.
He's holding on for now.
Where's Lexie?
Lexie's dead.
So we should get a fire started.
Oh, I've got... I've
got the matches.
We have five left.
Make it big so they see.
What happened to
the four hours, Jerry?
It's been more than four hours.
Shh. Listen. What
does that mean?
I mean, does that mean
that they're not coming for us?
I mean, you said four hours.
You said four hours tops.
Chopper!
Oh, my God. It's
a helicopter! Hey!
Help! MEREDITH: Help!
Where is it?
I don't see it. I don't see it.
Help!
Get the flare gun!
The flare gun! In
the bag! In the bag!
Oh, God, shoot it!
- We're down here!
Come back!
Why isn't it working?
Shoot it again! Shoot it again!
Give it to me.
Help!
Oh, my God, no!
Oh, my God. No, no! Come back!
No, no, no!
I chose Tulane.
Good.
That's good for you.
Yeah.
I feel sick, by the way.
Sick to leave here,
to leave you.
But, um...
But I'm glad... I'm glad you're
so friggin' happy about it.
I'm not.
I'm not happy with any of it.
I'm not happy that
everything I thought I was
turns out not to be true.
Um, I'm not a
board-certified surgeon.
I'm not a virgin. I'm
not a good Christian.
I don't know what I am,
but I know I'm not happy.
I loved having sex with you.
You made me feel things...
You changed me, Jackson.
And I loved that.
But I hate that I'm not a virgin
for the man I'm gonna marry.
I'm not freakin'
happy about that.
And I'm really not happy
that you feel bad about it,
'cause you're my best friend.
But you know what?
Torres is right.
My problems will still
be my problems tomorrow
and the day after that
and the day after that.
And in a few weeks,
my best friend
will be at Tulane,
and I may never
see him again, so...
For one night, I'm just
gonna forget all about that.
And I'm gonna try.
I'm gonna try to be happy.
I'm happy tonight.
I am gonna be happy, Jackson,
'cause this is a happy time,
and we should be
celebrating, okay?
So can you please just wipe
that freakin' frown off your face
and be happy with me?
You look really nice.
So do you.
This is Dr. Robbins.
Leave your name and
number, and I'll get back to you.
Thanks.
Hey, it's Alex.
Listen, um...
Look, the only reason
Hopkins wants me
is because you
made me something.
All right, you made me,
and I still don't know why.
You said one time that
you saw something in me,
and most of me
thinks you're nuts, but...
I gotta go to Hopkins
'cause I gotta see
if I'm something
when you're not there,
holding my hand, you know?
I guess I'm saying
thanks or whatever.
I don't know.
If you want to be
pissed about it,
then be pissed about it.
Bye.
Hey, they don't
know where we are.
They don't know where we are.
It's because the transmitter's
probably been damaged
in the crash.
If the transmitter's damaged...
We could be here for days.
Yeah.
Zola.
Owen has got to have
figured out we're missing.
I know he sent someone.
Mark?
I shoulda said it earlier...
That I loved her. I
shoulda said it earlier.
She...
She knew.
I think she knew.
She didn't know.
Mark...
Mark, hold on.
Okay, I need you... I
need you to hold on.
You'll be okay.
You don't need me.
You take care of our girls.
No. Shut up.
Shut up. Do you
hear me? Shut up.
Lexie's waiting for me.
I'll be okay.
No! Mark Sloan, no!
Hey! No.
No. Sofia's waiting for you,
and Callie is waiting for you,
and I am waiting for you.
We're gonna go
home together, okay?
Okay.
Thank you.
Hey. You were looking for me?
We need to talk. No.
We don't. I am happy to stay.
It'll be fun. It'll
be like old times.
Like you and me back
in Iraq. You're fired.
That's good.
Effective immediately.
Hunt... I wish
it were different,
but this is just the way
things are shaking out.
Now I know you have
other opportunities,
so if you need to make
those phone calls, then...
Owen, stop it. Stop it.
You can't just do this.
You can't... You can't just...
I can and I did.
You can't just... I already
e-mailed the board.
You're already...
You can't just tell me
when to go and when to stay!
I don't want you here anymore!
You shoulda seen this coming.
For months, for months, you
have been disruptive in the OR,
you have been hostile
and insubordinate...
Oh, my God. To
me in front of staff
and in front of students.
I can't have that.
I am the Chief of Surgery.
Owen, I was... I was... I was...
We're past all of that.
We are, because you're fired.
It's a done deal.
Pack your stuff.
You son of a bitch.
You son of a bitch!
Damn it.
You don't lose her.
You fight. You fight
for her. You hear me?
You go.
And you be great.
You don't get to make
decisions on your own
without a heads-up anymore.
You don't say, "Uh, oh, maybe
"I'll apply to be an intern,
"we'll see how it goes.
"I'll bring it up with Miranda
if anything comes of it,
"but for now, it's
my little secret
"between me and me."
That's not your life anymore.
When you are sharing
your life with a person,
you talk to them,
you think with them,
you make decisions with them,
you are loyal to them.
You are not a free agent
anymore. Do you understand me?
Does this mean we're
still getting married?
Well, what do you...
I proposed to you!
In a trench coat and a thong,
proving once again that no
good can ever come from a thong,
but here I am, proposing again.
What, you want a skywriter?
It was clear with the
coat and the thong.
You know what? You put
a piece of string in your tail
and see if you
want to do it twice.
You know, this may be the most
romantic conversation of my life.
Well, I'm not proposing
romance, mister.
I'm proposing marriage,
and if you're not prepared to...
You love me, don't you?
I am very angry with you.
So pissed, you're just gonna
marry me, just to spite me.
Yes. Exactly.
Tell me it's gonna be okay.
It's gonna be wonderful.
Good morning, Dr. Hunt.
This is Dr. Sheehan
over at Boise Memorial.
I just wanted to double-check
what time your surgeons
were set to arrive today.
Okay.
Dr. Hunt, Dr. Sheehan again.
Still no word from
your surgeons.
I'm gonna check
in with the airport
to see if the
weather held 'em up.
Uh, any word from Yang or Grey?
No. Plane should've landed
an hour ago. They'll show.
Well, you know...
There's a little bit of advice
I like to give at these
dinners every year.
It's a secret that
will help all of you
get through the
challenges that lie ahead.
You know, um...
We should wait
for the rest of them.
This is Dr. Sheehan again.
We're starting to get
a bit concerned here.
I'm hungry.
Think of something else.
I have a stick of gum.
I don't want gum. I want food.
Oh. Shoot.
Great. We have one match left.
Hey. No sleeping.
Yeah. You have to stay awake.
Okay.
Derek. Derek. Mmm.
You, too. I want
everyone conscious!
Mer, light the match.
Careful. It's our last one.
Okay.
The years we spend
as surgical residents
will be the best
and worst of our lives.
We will be pushed
to our breaking point.
This is the starting line.
This is our arena.
How well we play,
that's up to us.