- Previously on The Resident...
- If I hadn't gotten injured,
they might not have
caught my cancer in time.
- Your supplements
have potential.
- You killed my pitch.
You said Chastain
doesn't take chances.
They don't.
- I do.
- So what's your plan
if Adaku's baby becomes
your responsibility?
- I don't have one.
- Hawkins is
a whistle-blower. He's
a threat to the hospital.
I'll handle it.
Dr. Hawkins, you lied
to the transplant board.
You're fired. Give
me your pager.
Thank you.
We're a high-volume outfit.
A lot of kitchen mishaps
and food poisoning.
Waiting room's packed 24/7,
- so ten minutes per patient.
- And if the diagnosis
isn't obvious, and it
takes over ten minutes?
We also take pride in
customer satisfaction.
Your bonuses are tied to it.
So... flexible prescribing,
if you know what I mean.
Patients hate being told "no."
Yeah. Isn't that
what contributed
to the opioid crisis?
And why did you say you're
not at Chastain anymore?
If it were easy, everyone
would be a doctor,
because this is the best job in
the world, despite everything.
Because of everything.
How you feeling?
Pain-free. First time
in over a decade.
The transplant team
has been called in.
I will be with you
every step of the way.
I spent half my
life without a father.
We're gonna fix that.
These patients need you,
and I think this hospital
needs doctors like both of us.
God, I love when
you believe in me.
I never stopped
believing in you.
They're firing Conrad.
Security will escort you out.
Screaming won't
make this go any faster.
Or maybe it will.
Okay.
Yeah.
♪ ♪
Good morning, everyone.
I'm Dr. Garrison,
your chief resident.
Welcome, second-year residents.
You'll be getting interns
of your own today.
You will be their
mentors, their teachers.
Do not hesitate to work
them like pack mules.
The hospital relies
on their cheap labor.
No questions. There
are only two rules...
No one quits, no one dies.
Uh, Dr. Pravesh?
Ezra Dreyfuss, your intern.
Hey, Ezra. Welcome.
- And I'm Eline.
- Oh.
You didn't have to come.
Your son's in good hands.
Oh, she's not my mother.
I am also your intern.
Sorry. I-I wasn't expecting...
- You thought I'd be older?
- No, no, no. I... Of course not.
I-I meant...
There are two of you.
Eline, Ezra.
I'm thrilled to welcome
you to Chastain.
You know, on my
first day as a doctor...
Before you go all William
Wallace on us, I am highly
allergic to any
form of nut or dairy.
If I come into contact
with either, I will drop dead.
Sorry. Please continue.
Got it.
Today will set you on the
course for the rest of your lives.
So, when there are tough times,
just remember why you
decided to be a doctor.
Eline?
You ever met an intern
who watched a loved one
die of an incurable disease,
quit work to become a caregiver,
drew inspiration from
the medical professionals
they met throughout the disease,
enrolled in medical school
and became a doctor?
If that person is you,
then... then, yes, I have.
That person is not me.
- Oh.
- I was teaching math
to a bunch of third-grade
terrorists, and I was deeply
- inspired
to get the hell out of there.
- Wow.
- That's hilarious. Okay, my turn.
- Pravesh,
need you and your
children in Bay 3.
Thank you.
Odel. Dr. Pravesh.
If it's okay with you, I'd like
to have my interns observe.
Of course.
So, uh, I've had this
cough for a few weeks now.
- Okay. Just the cough?
- Just the cough.
It's called an emergency room.
I know, but I'm going to
Cambodia tomorrow, so I thought
I'd have it checked out,
and I didn't want to end up
in some remote village
clinic if it got worse.
Okay. Let me take
a look. Deep breath.
I backpacked through
Cambodia in college.
- You are gonna love it.
- Yeah?
I have been to England
once with the symphony,
and that's about it.
- Atlanta Symphony?
- Yeah. I play cello.
You ever play with
Gianni Balissa?
- He taught me everything I know.
- Me, too.
I was honorary recipient of the
Sousa Band Award for the violin.
Let me guess. You're
a musical genius.
Uh... yeah. Yeah.
Dr. Pravesh!
Scooter versus fire
hydrant, we need you.
Beethoven, you're with me.
Eline, I want you
to finish doing
a full physical exam on Odel,
and report back to
me when you're done.
- You have got to be kidding me.
- I don't think he is.
More than half of
hospitals pay doctors
based on relative value
units instead of set salaries.
Think of it as capitalism.
The more procedures,
biopsies, test diagnostic surgeries
you do, the more money
you'll make; it's that simple.
So, what, are we
car salesmen now?
Commission-based pay systems
lead to rampant overtreatment.
- I've seen it myself.
- You concerned we'll all see
how you really
measure up, Dr. Austin?
Maybe you're not as valuable
to the hospital as
you think you are.
Well, depending on your values,
you might be right, Dr. Cain.
This isn't a discussion, it's
Red Rock policy from now on.
You'll be paid for the
volume of work you do.
And quality is irrelevant.
Nobody said that.
Neither of you had to.
Don't worry, Dr. B.
You won't be out here with
the minnows for too long.
I can feel it in my heart space.
Ooh, sorry. Sorry,
it's for my new boss.
What's the meeting about?
Just boring pay stuff.
Nothing like what's
arranged for you tonight.
Grayson, you don't run
my schedule anymore.
Well, my dad
hasn't caught on yet,
and he called me to tell you...
Now, don't hug the messenger...
But, Dr. B., you're
about to present 3B Life
to the U.S. of A.
So suit up and get camera-ready,
'cause you're gonna be on TV.
Oh, he got the spot on Montel?
Better. STV, baby.
Shopping Television?
I mean, this is incredible.
This could make our...
Our supplement line
an industry player.
It all depends on you,
though, so get that face ready
for the small screen.
There she is. Nurse
among nurses.
It's so good to see you, Finn.
Oh... How's the book coming?
Published. Yeah, and
not self-published, either.
Real published. Smell the ink.
That's amazing. Congrats.
I hear you and Hawkins
live together now.
Sounds like Dr. Feldman
gave you an update.
- I hope he's a tidy roommate.
- Mm, getting there.
- Yeah.
- Wow.
All the details
of the life of Finn.
Flip to page three.
I'm pretty sure
you're responsible
for beating the odds.
Uh, where's Conrad? I've
got a copy for him, too, so...
He's not here anymore.
No, he practically lives here.
Well, I'm covering for him.
Which means I
have your test results.
I wish I had better news.
I've reached my final chapter.
My lung function's
deteriorating,
which means I'll be on a
breathing machine soon,
and then will go the way of
all my friends with Duchenne.
I am so sorry.
Well, bad news is no stranger
when you have a body like mine.
I know where I am.
Which is why I'm here.
I want to do something crazy
with the little
time I have left.
What are you planning, Finn?
- Hey.
One of your favorite
patients is here. Finn Niver.
- How is he?
- As feisty as ever.
But, um...
This is the end, isn't it?
Yeah.
I need to see him.
Well, that can be arranged.
You know I can't
set foot inside there.
Well, not at Chastain.
There's something
that Finn wants to do,
and he needs a
doctor to do it with him.
I'm listening.
How do you feel
about space travel?
You eat, sleep, and
breathe this place,
and the day I need you most,
I find out you don't
work here anymore?
What happened?
Ah, it's a long story, Finn.
Someone was a bit
cagey on the phone
about why I'm needed, so...
All I said was it's a
beautiful day to ditch gravity.
Good one. Nice work, Nevin.
What are we talking
about? Skydiving?
Hell no. I have
been tied to this chair
since I was five
years old; I want out.
I want to fly. I want to
float like I own the place.
In zero-g.
Zero gravity?
I sent a pandering
letter to the company
that does zero-g flights,
and they gifted tickets for me
and a doctor of my choosing.
So, you in?
Guys...
it is definitely crazy.
Which is exactly why I'm in!
Yes! Oh, let's do it.
I know this is as much
for me as it is for Finn,
and... I appreciate it.
I had nothing to do with
it. It was all Finn's idea.
Have fun.
Mom calls them brain
damage on wheels.
In her ICU in Boston,
a quarter of the beds
are always filled
with scooter patients.
- So I got off easy?
- Because you were
wearing a helmet.
So, how's it going with Odel?
He really wanted answers,
so I called Pulmonology
for a consult.
Dr. Langford recommended
a bronchoscopy
- just to be sure.
- He has a cough
with clear lungs and
a normal chest X-ray.
He didn't need a
Pulmonology consult.
The patient wanted one.
And he's about to travel.
I was in Nairobi once,
- caught this nasty parasite
and, um...
- Both of you, follow me.
Okay.
Well, guess we're too late.
Can I help you with
something, Dr. Pravesh?
This procedure is unnecessary.
Step out, please.
This is now my patient.
O2 sat is dropping.
He's aspirating.
Turn up the suction.
Get him on 100% O2
and abort the bronch.
- Wh-What's happening?
- He's choking on his own vomit.
No invasive procedure
is completely safe.
You have to weigh the
danger of a simple cough
against an unintended
consequence like this one.
Yikes.
He's stable.
- That's something.
- But he has to be admitted.
He's on supplemental oxygen
and will need
antibiotics to treat
the aspiration pneumonia caused
by an unnecessary bronchoscopy.
He wanted answers. I consulted
an experienced pulmonologist
who suggested the bronchoscopy.
Which is a relatively
benign procedure
- with good diagnostic yield.
- Stop.
It's simple.
You made a mistake.
You need to
accept responsibility,
learn and move on.
You read Annie Diamonte's chart?
Yes. I recommend
you start with the good
news and finish with the bad.
Well, I prefer to
close on the positive.
- Hey.
You know, we really have
to stop meeting like this.
You know, as much as I enjoy
seeing you, Annie, I agree.
I was really hoping
that last chest tube
would have taken care of it,
but your CT scan
shows that you still have
what's called an empyema,
an infection between
your lung and your chest,
which is what's
causing your fevers.
But there's good news.
We saw your scan...
and no sign of cancer.
The immunotherapy is working.
What?
My cancer's gone?
Yeah.
Well, you know, you really
should have led with that.
I was gonna
tell you to stop the
drugs and let me go.
So... so what's the plan?
I mean, another chest
tube? New antibiotic?
Well, we are actually
here to talk to you
about another
option. A decortication.
We open your chest,
then we clear the infection,
and we scrape off the peel
that's trapping your lung,
which is what's making
it hard for you to breathe.
What could go wrong?
Plenty.
This is a very
high-risk surgery.
There's a high likelihood
of bleeding, which
could be catastrophic,
particularly given the trauma
you've already been
through from the explosion.
And even if Dr. Austin
is able to do the
surgery successfully,
your lung may never reexpand.
What are my alternatives?
I mean, I live my
life in and out of here,
sick and in limbo,
buy my time till I die?
I can't do that.
And if my cancer's in remission,
I have a shot at
getting my life back.
You do understand
the risks of surgery?
Yeah. Well, whatever they are,
I'll take my chances.
Oh, wow.
For yourself or
for someone else,
- this is something...
- I'm gone
a matter of weeks,
you're in the
servants' quarters,
and my son, one of the best
doctors at Chastain, is fired?
I'm not responsible for that.
Obviously.
Conrad is dodging my calls.
His way of asking
me to stand down.
- Hmm. Well, stand down.
- My lawyers are submitting
a whistleblower suit.
You know how many
are filed every year?
Whistleblower protection
is a joke in Georgia.
I'll tell you what'll happen.
Red Rock will sue you
for libel, and they may win.
So I'm taking advice from
a guy who's lost two jobs
- in two weeks?
- Yeah.
Being demoted by
these people is an honor.
How do we fight back?
Well, you got a slingshot?
Look, all due respect, don't
go down that path until you have
- a bulletproof strategy.
- Oh, I've got one.
Well, if you're hell-bent
on moving forward,
then I suggest...
you have a look at Logan Kim.
Thanks.
Dr. Austin.
Watch the coat. It's custom.
I don't like wrinkles.
Well, here's one. I'm
reviewing mortality outcomes
of all surgeons,
and you're an outlier.
Your stats aren't up to par.
And as chief, your outcomes
are now my outcomes.
Come on, bruh. Everybody knows
that my outcomes are excellent
for the kind of cases I take.
My patients are the
sickest. My surgeries, risky.
Which is precisely my
point. Annie Diamonte's
upcoming surgery is
too much of a long shot.
- You need to reassess.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Hold up.
You don't want me to do a
highly profitable procedure?
- The crème de la crème of RVUs?
- I'm only suggesting
that you have a plan B.
An escape hatch, so to speak.
Oh. So if something
catastrophic were to happen,
you want me to keep
her alive at all costs,
not let her die on my table,
- just to pad my stats.
- What I'm saying to you,
Dr. Austin, is
that your statistics
don't meet what I
expect from my surgeons.
So, yes, you keep
her alive at all costs
and don't mention a
DNR to your patient.
As the plane descends,
we'll vary the flight profiles
so you can feel the
weightlessness of both martian
and lunar gravity.
So this isn't a free fall.
That's Kimmy.
She makes these crazy
videos in the best way.
She may be a living emoji.
- Shh.
- You'll also experience...
And that's Reggie Perez.
Retired Atlanta United defender,
- 2015 to 2017.
- Hey, you're
in good company, Finn,
but they got nothing on you.
You're the real badass here.
Don't ever forget that.
You'll experience 15 simulations
in total in increments of
about 30 seconds a pop.
Most people think that
zero-g is only experienced
- when the plane is in a dive.
- Hey, Reggie.
Yeah.
I was MVP of the Golden Kickers
till my career
ended at age five.
But mini-me could have
taken mini-you down.
I don't doubt it
for a second, bud.
Well, once we're weightless,
it's an even playing field,
and I am coming for you.
And I'm scared.
I'll see you out there.
He said he's scared.
Does he look scared?
No.
Of Course all the
rush and excitement
come with perils, like nausea.
It's called vomit
comet for a reason.
But there are also other
risks, including dizziness,
fluctuating blood pressure.
There are very rare but
very real complications
aside from the vomit
issue, of course...
Are you scared?
You can change your mind.
It's totally fine if you are.
It's not, really.
'Cause then I'm gonna
spend the rest of my life
wondering "what if."
Means my final weeks would
be torture, and I can't do that.
We'll take those
signed waivers now,
because it's time
for zero-g, people.
One thing, though, doc.
I know you've been
through a lot lately,
and I don't want
to make it worse.
Listen, if things
go south up there...
Like really south...
don't blame yourself, okay?
I mean, the worst that
happens up there is I die.
And is zero-g really
the worst way to go?
No, it isn't.
We obviously want the
surgery to be a success.
But it's risky. So
we have to ask
have you thought about
what you want if
things don't go well?
I've thought about it a lot
since the cancer diagnosis.
You know, I-I love the outdoors
and the physical challenges.
A life hooked up to a
machine is no life at all for me.
So if that is my only choice,
I want you to let me go.
Okay.
Well, then let's fill out a
Do Not Resuscitate order,
specifying your wishes
so that everyone follows them.
Before I sign that,
can I have a minute?
Sure.
Hey. Nic filled me in. I'm
really sorry I'm not there.
Yeah. I heard hints as to
why that is, and I don't like it.
- Conrad, are you okay?
- Right now, yeah.
How are you? I hear cancer-free.
- Yeah.
- That's amazing.
It is.
Look, I know you're
not gonna sugarcoat this.
That's why I called you, Conrad.
I'm not sure I can do this.
Yeah, it's risky, and
I'm scared as hell.
I know that.
I also know it takes a
special kind of superpower
to run into a fire
to save a hospital
and kick cancer's ass
all in the same year.
So if anyone's got this,
it's you.
Thanks, Conrad. I
really needed to hear that.
Bye.
What's going on?
He was midway through
the cefepime when he started
to get wheezy. Now
he can't breathe.
- Sounds like anaphylaxis.
- A reaction to the antibiotics.
Push 0.5 of epinephrine I.M.
now and prepare an epi drip.
- And call the code team.
- Help me.
We got you, buddy.
Hang in there.
- Pressure's dropping.
Let's go, let's go, let's go.
Let's get the pads on him. now.
Come on.
Run the code.
What? No, I-I ca-I can't.
We lost his pulse.
Starting compressions.
This is your patient.
You made the call.
Run the code.
What's the first question
you ask in a code?
What was the rhythm
before he arrested?
- It was PEA.
- What's the differential
for a PEA arrest?
- Eline!
- I can't.
Step aside.
Hold compressions.
He's still in PEA.
Restart compressions.
Push 1 of epi.
Let's move. I'll intubate.
- I'll get the printout.
- He looks better.
Epi usually works
quickly when you give it,
but his blood
pressure's still low.
- Is that real?
- Maybe.
But the monitor's just a tool.
I'll need an EKG
to know for sure.
I mean, what happened
back there? You just froze up.
Call a Code STEMI.
Get him to the cath lab now.
He's having a heart attack.
- What just happened?
- It's called a clinical cascade.
When one unnecessary procedure
leads to many more,
increasing the risk of harm
- from complications.
- Which I put into motion.
You couldn't have known
he'd be allergic to the antibiotics.
- That's not her fault.
- From the time a patient
comes in
to the time he is discharged,
he is in your hands.
This man came in
with a cough, and now
- he might die of a heart attack.
- I will no longer be a doctor.
Not exactly. You're
cheap labor and Red Rock
- will be very forgiving.
- Uh, Dr. Pravesh?
Do you have allergies too?
Your neck.
- Ah.
- Slow down, Turbo.
Oh, I'm very close
to injecting caffeine
directly into my veins.
When do humans
figure out the difference
between night and day?
Because Adaku's baby hasn't.
She was fully awake
from 2:00 to 7:00 a.m.,
just staring at me.
Until I tried to put her down.
Then she wails like a banshee.
And she's supposed
to eat every two hours,
but what does she do
almost every single time?
Chucks it up.
Have you tried cuddling?
- What?
- Eating, bathing, sleeping...
It's all secondary
to the snuggle.
It affects babies
on a molecular level.
Literally changing
their DNA for the better.
It improves their neural
development, their IQ...
I got it. Fine. I'll snuggle.
See you in there.
Logan Kim. Marshall Winthrop.
I know who you are.
We both know why my son Conrad
was kicked out of Chastain.
He tried to do the right thing,
so you set out to ruin him.
I'm sorry.
- Who are you?
- I believe
we've already covered that.
No, I mean, who
are you, really...
The good guy you're
now pretending to be,
or the world heavyweight
champion of hypocrites?
I'm here to talk about my son.
Take your grievance
elsewhere. You think
you can muscle me with
your power and fortune,
but I know how you
made that fortune,
and it wasn't through
random acts of kindness.
To get on your high
horse, it was kill or be killed.
This isn't about me.
I'm making it about you.
James Willebrand.
COO of one of
your first companies.
FCC came sniffing around.
But you made sure he paid
dearly for ratting you out.
See, I know where
the bodies are buried.
And I will dig them up
to stink in the light of day
and bring you to
your aging knees
if you ever challenge me again.
Don't tempt me.
♪ ♪
Climbing to 20 degrees.
This is seriously weird.
- Thirty.
- Pretty sure it's about
to get weirder.
Forty.
Zero gravity.
♪ ♪
Oh, hello freedom.
♪ Out here in the fields ♪
♪ I fight for my meals ♪
Yeah!
♪ I get my back into my living ♪
♪ I don't need to fight ♪
♪ To prove I'm right ♪
♪ I don't need to be forgiven ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
Hey, Reggie.
Yeah?
Bet you can't do this.
I'll bet you're right.
Oh...
I'm messing with you, Hawkins.
- Aw...
- I'm sorry.
I-I've been planning
that one all day,
but you should've
seen your face.
You got me.
- You got me.
- He got you good.
Aw, you got me!
See you sometime.
Scalpel.
I-I can't see where
to start cutting.
All right. Let's
turn the lung over
- and go to the other side.
- Agreed.
Now, Mina, grab the
peel with a hemostat.
Make sure you use the
blunt end of the forceps.
Okay. I got it. I see
healthy lung underneath.
You know, Cain was
breathing down my neck
about my stats earlier.
He told me to keep
Annie alive at all costs.
Must be an open
bed at the vent farm.
- What's that?
- Atlanta Promised Care.
That's where he
sends all his... "saves."
Oh, so that's how
he keeps his stats up
and the money flowing.
His escape hatch.
- That's one point of view.
- Is there another?
Well, for every ten
patients we send to APC,
maybe one might make it home.
Those aren't great numbers,
but it's a chance, right?
But for Cain, that's not what
it's about and you know it.
- Ah!
- Damn it.
- A bleeder.
- Hey, Chu,
you get to work on
her pressure, man.
And order up some more
blood. We're gonna need it.
There's too much
bleeding. I can't see.
- Chu, hang another unit, please.
- I've already used everything
we have up here, another
cooler's on the way.
Suction.
Should we inflate
the lung again?
No, it's not gonna help.
If-if she codes...
You let her go.
To hell with Cain.
- But that's not gonna happen
because... You have a plan.
Of course I have a plan.
There's too much
damage to the lung.
We need to remove
the whole lobe.
Is that gonna leave her
with enough lung function?
It better. Let's get to work.
- Pressure's stable.
- Good deal.
All right, Dr. Okafor.
It's all you.
- Show me what you got.
- With pleasure.
Oh, yeah!
Ooh, nice one, Hawkins.
You okay, man?
Reggie, can you hear me?
Tell the pilot to level out.
Reggie's in cardiac arrest.
We need a defibrillator.
Captain, we have...
Flip upside down and put
your feet up on the wall.
Over here!
We need a defibrillator.
Let's hold him down.
Here we go.
Returning to
Earth's gravity now.
Conrad.
Clear.
You're good. You're good.
He's back.
We did it.
- Deploying the stent.
- Odel's clogged artery
is about to be opened,
and this cascade
will transform into
more of a trickle.
If he'd gone to a
Cambodian doctor in a village,
they would've given him a
tea and sent him on his way.
Instead he came
here with a cough
and I gave him a heart attack.
And that is what's gonna
make you a good doctor.
Giving patients heart attacks?
Humility.
Acceptance.
Those are the main
ingredients in being one.
He might have coronary artery
disease that was undiagnosed
and exacerbated during zero-g.
Tell Dr. Feldman to give
cardiology a heads-up
- that a V fib arrest
with ROSC is coming in.
- Copy that.
Reggie's gonna be okay, right?
I believe so.
'Cause, you know, I'd feel weird
talking about how
insanely awesome
that zero-g experience
was, right, if...
He's in great
hands. It's not weird.
Oh, dude, how
freaking cool was that?!
I believed you when
you said we'd be floating,
but I guess I didn't
really believe you,
because when we
started to rise up...
You-you almost peed yourself?
- Yeah. Yeah.
- Yeah, me too!
Except for me wouldn't be
the first time, so no biggie,
but that was incredible.
Yeah. Yeah, it was. Thank you
for dragging me out there.
I really needed this badly.
Oh.
Hey. You okay, man?
I mean, really.
I was so happy.
I had my work and the
most amazing woman
in my life.
They gave me purpose.
I don't know who I am right now.
Or who I'll be if I can't
be a doctor anymore.
I do know
whatever that version of me
looks like, there's no
way Nic deserves that.
No.
No?
No, you cannot let them win.
Medicine is money,
and money breeds jerks.
But you...
You got to knuckle up
and get your job back.
Hey, if not for yourself,
then do it for the patients
who are relying on you.
Get mad.
Go kick some Red Rock ass.
'Cause we are the
Zero-G Brothers,
and nobody... and
I mean nobody...
Can keep us down.
All right?
Zero-G Brothers?
Yeah.
For life.
You know what?
Guys like us...
find a way to beat the odds.
Don't get too excited.
She'll be off that vent shortly.
So you'll have to
find another patient
to fill your open bed.
What's an empty bed cost you...
Another overpriced painting?
I remind you that
I am the chief.
And with your stats,
you're expendable.
Well, I'd like to remind
you of something
you've apparently forgotten.
The sacred contract between
a surgeon and a patient.
That which distinguishes
us from all other physicians.
We cut people open.
We inflict wounds
to make them better.
They trust us with their lives.
And I don't cut for
the sake of cutting.
I don't do it for the
prestige or the cash
or the stats or the RVUs.
I do it for the patients.
I do it for people like her.
You must have
been different once.
What happened to you, Barrett?
I was born the man I am
today, and I'm proud of it.
No. No, I... I
think you're lying.
You encouraged this
woman to sign a DNR
when I explicitly
told you not to.
You will not disobey me again.
Or what?
You'll have me
fired, like Hawkins?
Demoted, like Bell?
What's the endgame, Barrett?
You cut all your adversaries,
surround yourself
with bootlickers
and those who toe the line.
Yeah, it'll work
for a hot minute,
but I guarantee you it
will breed resentment,
corruption.
And eventually
Chastain will implode,
and you right along with it.
I told him going to the
ER was a crazy idea.
It's a good thing
he didn't listen.
It's just lucky it happened
here at Chastain,
where we have a
world-class cardiac team.
That is lucky.
Honey...
Did the bronchoscopy explain
why I have this damn cough?
Postnasal drip.
Which is what I saw when I
first examined you in the ER.
But we needed the
test to confirm that.
Did we?
Antihistamines are the
first line of treatment.
If it's still bothering
you, I'd say
talk to your
primary care doctor.
But there's nothing
to worry about.
- See?
- That's good news.
Thank you...
for the great care.
Our pleasure.
Why didn't you say anything?
He wasn't lucky to
have a heart attack here.
I gave it to him.
It is also my
instinct to be truthful,
and I am, most of the time.
- So why not now?
- Because if we tell the truth,
you'll be fired for
whistleblowing,
and another conscientious
doctor will no longer
be helping patients.
The lesson to learn is
the best and hardest
thing in medicine
is often to do nothing.
We care for our
patients knowing full well
this is also a business.
The trick is not to get
caught between the two.
My first day was
also a disaster.
And by the end of it, I
was questioning whether...
I worked way too
hard to get here.
I have no intention of quitting.
Good.
No one died, no one quit.
My job here is done.
Oh, and you're not
the only one to blame
for Odel's bronchoscopy.
The new RVU system is, too.
Radical virus...
- Relative value units.
- Oh.
That's why Dr. Langford
was so quick to suggest it.
Right.
Well, today is the day
we introduce 3B Life
to the American public,
and I'll be damned if you
two handsome bastards
aren't just perfect for the job.
Just, you know, stick
to the teleprompter
and gold we shall be.
As they say on the
boards of Broadway,
hatsloche un broche.
Break a leg.
3B Life, you're
up in one minute.
We have Dr. Randolph Bell
and Andrea Braydon...
- Ready to make history?
- You bet.
Hey, how's the big first day?
Mm, practicing medicine is hard,
but teaching it is a
whole other beast.
That's the truth.
There's something else. I
need to schedule some lab work.
- Yeah? For who?
- Me.
What's wrong?
I've just got some
pain under my ribs.
Stomach ache, and this rash.
And my fingers are...
Hmm, headache?
Increased heart rate?
Yeah.
I think you have RAS.
Resident anxiety syndrome.
Conrad had it, too.
It's the anxiety of being
a second-year resident
responsible for others.
Can't say it ever goes away,
but you do learn
to live with it.
- I hope you're right.
- I think I am.
Get some rest, Pravesh.
Forget about your
interns till tomorrow.
Mm.
Yeah! 3B For Life,
people. I mean,
- we rocked America.
Well, Andrea took the lead,
- I just... I followed.
- Mm-hmm.
- Yeah, what happened?
No, it was great, really.
We had a weight-loss story
and a heroic tale.
Couldn't have planned it better.
Which is hardly
a surprise, I'd say.
Hey, what's going on?
You know, Grayson
told me about your day,
so I said I had to come by
and congratulate you in person.
Dr. Barrett Cain.
Chief of Surgery.
- Um...
- Yes, I know. I know,
this is a hard act to follow,
but I'm doing my best.
Andrea Braydon.
Would you, um, like s...
Oh. Looks like we're running
- a little low. Well, we'll have
to get some more. Oh, great.
- Thank you very much.
That's-that's what I'm talking about.
Uh, Dr. Bell. Word, please?
- Well, cheers, guys.
- Amazing.
- Mazel tov.
Yeah.
You know, it's only
a matter of time
before the board realizes
that you swiped an opportunity
from underneath them.
You rejected
Andrea's pitch to them
so you could have the
investment all to yourself.
That's hardly what happened.
And it's a high-risk investment,
and one that Chastain
would never make.
Hmm.
Well, that's not how
I'm gonna spin it.
So what do you want?
I don't know.
A healthy percentage of our
growing supplement business.
And in return I'll just smooth
things over with the board.
Look, I have partners.
- Right.
- It's hardly my decision
to make.
Yes, and I'm sure
they will be thrilled
to add another prestigious
physician with the product.
And if anybody can
convince 'em, it's you.
Ain't that right, partner?
He's bringing it.
Yeah. More bubbly.
♪ Three blind mice ♪
♪ See how they run ♪
♪ ♪
The answer is yes, I have
been dodging your calls.
I am well aware.
Guessing you heard I was fired.
You know, the truth is
I figured it would
happen one day.
You're a rule breaker.
I've decided I'm not gonna
let them win so easily.
Son, I've gone toe-to-toe
with a lot of titans in my time.
These Red Rock people...
You're gonna have to bring
more than a
slingshot to this fight.
It's gonna get ugly.
For all of us.
I just want to make
sure you know
what we're up against.
I hear you, Dad. Thank you.
- Hey.
Missed you today.
I missed you, too.
It was a good day?
Zero-g with Finn is
just what I needed.
- Oh, yeah?
- Mm.
Red Rock came for me.
Now I'm coming for them.
Captioned by Media
Access Group at WGBH