We begin life with
few obligations.
Good morning, Seattle.
Welcome to this fine morning...
We pledge
allegiance to the flag.
We swear to return
our library books.
But as we get
older, we take vows,
we make promises, we get
burdened by commitments.
To do no harm.
To tell the truth
and nothing but.
To love and cherish
till death do us part.
So we just keep
running up the tab
until we owe
everything to everybody
and suddenly think...
What the...?
Sure it was not a deer? There
are a lot of deer. Bucks can get big.
I think I know the difference
between a bear and a deer!
- Rest, ice and elevate, OK?
- You know how I got to the car?
I had to throw a raw
steak and run for my life.
That was a ten-ounce filet. I've
been marinating it for three days.
- We have to move!
- Where?
We barely make 30 grand a year.
Who knows if we'll have
a job after the merger.
- We could move back
to Meredith's.
- You did not say that.
- Why not?!
- Because we're married now.
This is how it's supposed to
be, you and me, out in the world,
making a life for ourselves.
Besides, don't you enjoy waking
up to the fresh air and birds chirping?
You know what I
enjoy? I enjoy plumbing.
I enjoy plumbing so much!
It's not that I don't love
it at Mer's. I do. It's just...
I can't move backwards, Alex.
Not after everything that's...
I just need to keep
moving forward, OK?
- Thank you.
- I know it hasn't
exactly been easy
around here the past few weeks.
And I know you want answers.
But I'm afraid I
don't have them.
Not just yet.
He brought us here to
make himself feel good.
At least he sprung
for good Danish.
Know how many
got fired for that?
The Mercy West staff
will arrive in three days.
When they do, more
cutbacks and more layoffs,
and I need each and every one
of you to step up and be leaders.
And when I can answer
your questions, I will.
Will we be losing
more scrub nurses?
If you'd like to make an appointment
to talk about your concerns, we can.
What about my burn center?
You were right.
Excellent Danish.
What about robotics...?
- Anything?
- Nope.
There was a papillary
muscle rupture in the CCU,
but he died before
they got him to OR.
Crap! I need surgeries now.
I barely hit 100 hours
in the OR this month.
And you know they're gonna keep
the residents with the most hours.
- What do ya got?
- Um, diabetic ulcer.
- Down to the bone?
- No.
I'm done. Finished.
Expired meat.
- You're freaking out.
- You haven't been kicked off
two services in a month. I couldn't
get into an OR if I was bleeding to death.
- You got anything good?
- I'm scrubbing in
on an optic glioma later on
with Derek. I've never seen one.
What are you doing?
Just making sure everything's
running smoothly here.
And... it is.
- Kudos.
- No, no, no. Uh-uh. Ho! No.
I am on Hunt's service. Anything
that turns surgical here is mine.
You don't need hours. You
spent six months in the OR.
- Unconscious on a table doesn't count.
- - Meredith?
Hey. His neighbor said
he wasn't getting his mail.
Meredith...
I heard... you got
married on a sticker.
- That's great.
- We should go,
- so you can have family time.
- I don't know what's wrong.
Did you pick him up off the floor
of a bar? That might be a clue.
Meredith... I'm not...
I haven't been
drinking. I swear...
Now that could be surgical.
OK. Make sure his fluids
are running wide open,
let's get that blood hung.
- Got FFP here.
- What about factor seven?
- Check his INR?
- Hang 50 mikes of octreotide.
- Got it.
- Shouldn't we check for renal failure?
- Move. I need to lavage him.
- I need to put this up.
OK, hey! Pause! Way
too many people here.
Karev, get that orogastric
tube in. The rest of you, out.
No, wait a minute.
I'm in emergency!
This is emergent!
He made amends. He's not drunk.
All right, Irving, I'm taking off the
growth. Let me know if you feel pain.
He gets so many of these.
Have the nursing home
examine him when they bathe him.
- I bathe myself.
- Of course you do, Irving.
He could fall in the tub.
Why don't you two go
get me a cup of coffee?
You already had a cup, Dad.
Too much isn't
good for your ticker.
He can have decaf, Tommy.
We'll go get you a
nice cup of decaf.
Thank you, sweetie.
You know, I'm not
demented. I'm just old.
Come on.
- All right, uh,
Mr. Waller, all done.
- All done.
There might be a little redness,
but it should heal up nicely. Got it?
I've had those skin things
for 30 years. I'm not worried.
What I'm really
here for is AMS 700.
- The... penile implant?
- Yeah.
Usually, the first step in treating
erectile dysfunction is drug therapy.
If you're having symptoms, I
can write you a prescription.
No, no. I took
those pills years ago.
They never even
gave me a lift-off.
And then my wife
died and I gave up.
But I'm seeing this new
gal from the east wing.
She's a younger woman,
and I don't want to disappoint.
I understand. But it is
a surgical procedure,
so there is a question
of safety, given your age.
My age? It's always my age.
Ah, the golden years.
Let me tell you about
the golden years, Doc.
There's just got
to be more to life
than eating pudding
and watching CSI.
Come on. Can you give an
old man a working Johnson?
Did I tell you how
great your hair looks?
It's all just short and...
- edgy.
- You are really tweaking out.
How long has it
been since you've cut?
- Over a week.
- Ooh.
I have something,
if you're interested.
Well, I'm interested.
An MVC came in a while back.
During his work-up, I found
an abdominal sarcoma.
I've been following
his recurrences.
He came back today
with his third one.
Wondered if you could
scrub in, if you feel ready.
- I'm ready.
He's in pre-op.
- You know I need a surgery.
- I don't play favorites.
People are afraid to work with
Stevens, like she's gonna break.
It's not right. She's
a good surgeon.
She has a way with patients.
- A light touch.
- You want nice?
- I can be nice to a dying husk.
- Yeah.
Not a light touch.
My dad's dead.
At first I thought he was drunk,
then he started puking blood.
Puking blood and
disorientation usually means...
- End-stage liver failure.
- He's probably dead by now.
Or he needs a transplant. I
hope he's not a candidate.
That means he'd be in
the hospital for months.
Uh, Mer?
- He needs a transplant,
doesn't he?
- Yeah.
You've got end-stage cirrhosis.
We can treat the symptoms,
but the only thing that can
save your life is a transplant.
- How did it happen this fast?
- He bathed it in gin.
- Alex.
- Your friend's right.
Except for the gin. I
was a Scotch man.
What's the next step here?
Do I get on a list?
Um, Thatcher, the transplant
board has a rule here.
An alcoholic has to
be sober at least a year
before he qualifies
for a donor liver.
I'm only 90 days.
I'll do it.
I'll do it today. I'll go
get tested right now.
- Lexie...
- They just take a piece.
My liver will regenerate.
I can't ask you to do
something like that. It's...
- It's major surgery.
- You're not asking.
You're my dad.
You want a kidney? I'll
throw in one of those, too.
One more time. You be the
chief, cranky and in a bad mood,
- and I'm Callie
asking for her job.
- You are Callie.
- Right, so it works.
- You said that yesterday.
And the day before. And
the day before the day before.
- Are you gonna do this?
- It's not easy to ask
for your job back
after you told your boss to go
screw himself. It's humiliating.
- You're not gonna do it.
- What is the point?
He fired me once. He's not gonna
hire me back now because of the merger.
Whatever. Maybe being
a surgeon's overrated.
I'd be happy
doing lots of things.
I could open a day-care.
Babies are cute.
Ew.
- That one spit.
- Calliope, I don't want you
to have to move to
Cleveland to be a surgeon.
OK. I'm gonna do it.
Oh.
Later? I will come back later.
My girlfriend's moving
to Cleveland. Yep. Yep.
Look at you, coming
in on your day off.
- Trying to get into the OR?
- Yeah.
I'm giving my dad a piece of
my liver. End-stage liver disease.
- Needs my liver,
giving him some.
- Whoa, wait a minute.
- What is your problem?
- My problem is you don't jump
into this without
thinking about it.
Take a couple
of days. We'll talk.
- What is there to talk about?
- Major, life-threatening
surgery.
- My dad needs
a transplant, Mark.
- I get that, but...
No, I don't think
you get it at all.
You know what I don't get?
We're together.
We live together.
We need to decide
these things together.
You can't go under the
knife and leave me a note.
- I would've paged you.
- I am your boyfriend, Grey.
He's my dad!
OK, little pinch.
I cannot get this
stupid thing to work.
Try knocking it on something.
- Excuse me...
- Insider trick.
What other tricks do you know?
Stay away from the lime Jell-O.
If you want good meds, tell them
you have a headache, not stomach.
If your arm hurts
from needle pokes,
tell them you want
anesthetic cream. It numbs it.
- You've done this before.
- Stage four melanoma.
Mrs. Helsby, I'm gonna
have to give him a rectal exam.
- You may want
to leave the room.
- No, I'm not his wife.
What's that saying,
they won't buy the cow
if you give 'em
the milk for free?
We're working on
eight years of free milk.
I was gonna propose last
year, but I got distracted
by this little thing
called cancer.
You got the best
excuse in the book.
Nice.
The ring's at home in
the mouthguard container.
I'm just waiting for
the right moment.
What we'd do is we'd surgically
place the silicone implant into the penis,
and when the pump is
squeezed before intercourse...
- Where does the pump go?
- In the scrotum.
So to pump it up, I
squeeze the jewels?
Dad, Dad... This...
It's ridiculous!
You're 82 years old!
So? I shouldn't have a sex life?
Go on, Doc. You're just
getting to the good part.
No, listen to me. This is major
surgery. They have to cut your...
They cut you open,
Dad. You could bleed or...
You wanna die? Over an erection?
Wars have been fought
over an erection, son.
Irving, I'm sure
that a thing like this
isn't covered by Medicare.
You don't want to
use your savings.
You want to help
Janey pay for college.
Sweetheart, I love Janey,
but let's stop pretending
she's going to college.
She's pretty, but
she's not too sharp.
- Dad!
- Tom, this is my money.
This is the way I
want to spend it!
Your mother and I
saved our entire lives
for what she called a rainy day.
And then she died before
we could spend one cent.
Your mother would be proud I'm
finally doing something nice for myself.
Mom would be proud
you're getting a penis pump?!
OK, we have to run some tests.
We might not know if
the surgery's an option.
So why don't we
all just calm down.
Start from there.
- Hey. What you looking for?
- Excuse me?
I couldn't help but notice
you have no resident on your
decompressive laminectomy.
Today's your lucky
day 'cause I'm available.
Yang, right? I heard you
were hardcore into cardio.
I can be hardcore
into anything you want.
Are you whoring
yourself out for surgeries?
Oh, shut up. You
forced me into it.
Biology? It's crap. Utter crap.
DNA, RNA, it doesn't
make someone your family.
- It does, actually.
- He needs a liver transplant.
Lexie volunteered, like
she got asked for a dollar bill.
I left the room.
He's not my father.
Your dad needs a transplant?
Maybe not. Maybe
he's dead this time.
Damn it. It's worse
than I thought.
The scarring's completely
fused his organs together.
God, looks like somebody
poured a bottle of glue down there.
How do we fix it?
We don't.
If we could get to the
cancer, we get clean margins.
With this many adhesions, the
risk of tumor rupture, it's too high.
We cut into him again, we're
doing more harm than good.
Maybe if we...
We have to know
when to say when.
I'm saying when.
- Is he dead?
- No.
Oh.
Look, we rushed Dr. Grey's
labs. She wasn't a match.
Oh!
OK. Um...
What about Holly?
- Molly? Our sister?
- Yeah.
She lives on an Army base
with her husband in Bahrain.
Plus, she has a history of
DVT. So she can't be a donor.
Oh.
Meredith, we didn't
call you here to...
We thought you should know before
we go in and tell him, just in case.
Right. Right, no, thank you
for keeping me in
the loop. Thank you.
I, um, have to go prep
for my surgery now. OK.
Why are we eating lunch in a
room full of diseased organs?
We are hiding from
Lexie and her big, sad,
"I love my daddy" eyes.
Because I can't take it anymore.
Is Little Grey not a match? Oh,
damn! There goes my transplant.
Nice try. It was my transplant.
Are you gonna get tested?
No, I barely know the guy.
Might as well get tested.
You could regret
it if you don't.
He's a deadbeat, but he
gave you the ultimate gift.
- The gift of life.
- You guys are sick.
You really are sick.
Don't listen to them, Mer.
- They just want a surgery.
- Mama needs to cut.
Babe, you got some dirt
on your neck. Right there.
That's not dirt. That's a tick.
Ew.
- Get it off me.
- Is that a tick?
- It is a tick.
- A tick.
- It's swollen.
- Get if off me.
- It's having lunch, too.
- Get it off me! Get it off me
now!
Tick, tick!
Somebody, take it off!
The kids think
this is all vanity.
But I really need
this surgery, Doc.
If she loves you, she'll
understand if you can't...
perform. Cuddling is nice, too.
You're just a kid, Doc.
You won't understand.
But one day you're
gonna wake up,
and all the big stuff,
all the milestones you
been looking forward to,
graduations, weddings,
having kids, your grandkids,
it's all behind you.
It's all over.
All you got is a
bunch of yesterdays,
and very few tomorrows.
I haven't wanted to
make love with a woman
since Sylvie died 20 years ago.
And then one night,
one night they sat me
down at the bingo table
- with Marion.
- And you just knew?
She's my tomorrow.
- He's still sleeping.
- Good. He needs his rest.
Dr. Bailey, I...
I was wondering
if you could... lie.
If you could lie to
the transplant board
and tell them he's
been sober for a year.
They trust you,
they'll listen to you.
- Maybe he can
get on the list...
- Dr. Grey,
I have 15 other patients all
waiting for liver transplants.
Fifteen people in an
untenable situation,
none of whom drank
themselves into it.
So, no, I will not lie. Not
for you. Not for anyone.
Do you have any other
questions I can answer?
How would you like it?
Things crawling all over you,
stupid squirrels having a
party all night on your roof.
What the hell are
they doing up there?
- Applying betadine to the area.
- I don't know how to deal.
I don't camp! My parents
were lounge lizards.
I was raised in a bar.
Extracting the arachnid.
And there's no plumbing.
I mean, the toilet empties into
a bucket underneath the trailer.
A crap bucket! And Izzie's
all, "Marriage is an adventure,
just the two of us,
exploring the wild."
I married freaking
Lewis & Clark!
- I guess I'm done.
- That's it.
I'm telling her. We're moving
back to Meredith's. I'm done.
- You can't do that.
- Why not?
Because that's not how it works.
She's just been through
hell. She's not OK yet.
Just give her one, Alex.
Since when did you become
a marriage counselor?
I guess when you
save someone's life,
you kind of want it not to suck.
I hate when people who don't
live here say Seattle weather sucks.
- Those people suck.
- Ooh, I wanted to
show you something.
- I made a list.
- Hm? You made a list?
Yeah, to read to the chief.
Fifty reasons why he should
hire me as an attending. OK.
Number one: I built a man's
bones out of titanium rods.
Two: what I lack in experience,
I make up for in raw talent.
Three: I can go seven hours in
the OR without taking a pee break.
- Four... What are you doing?
- I'm going back to the
hospital.
Uh, this is important!
I lost my favorite scrub
nurse yesterday, Anne.
She's a single mother,
supporting three kids,
and now she's out of a job.
This morning, a
ten-month-old hemorrhaged
while I was in her chest
and I didn't have my
favorite scrub nurse.
I had to actually look up
and ask for a mesh wrap
because the new
nurse didn't know me.
Anne knew all my moves
before I even made them.
And it felt terrible to be
in the OR without her.
I was looking forward to 30
minutes in the park with my girlfriend.
'Cause this merger thing?
It's important to all of us.
Sorry. I've been...
Just...
Sorry.
He'll say yes or he'll say no.
And then we'll know.
OK.
- This is our optic glioma guy?
- Mm-hmm.
You sure you're up for this?
There'll be others, I promise.
Yeah, you know, everyone is
looking at me like I owe him something.
- But he's still
the bad guy here.
- You don't owe him anything.
I...
So I'm gonna be fired.
I've done a lot of really
dumb things today,
including pulling
your medical files.
- Lexie...
- Just listen.
I didn't want to do this.
I didn't want to have to
come to you for anything.
So I thought if I looked
up your blood type
and it was the wrong
one, then that would be it.
Then I could just
stop thinking about it.
But I can't, because
you have his blood.
I know that he's not your dad.
I know that he was
never there for you,
and I would never ask
you to give him anything.
He doesn't deserve a
thing from you. He doesn't.
But he's...
He's gonna die, Meredith.
And so I'm asking you
to give something to me.
I'm asking...
I'm asking you to
give me my dad.
Because as crappy
as he was to you,
he was wonderful to me.
He never missed a
single dance recital.
He was there at my
fifth grade graduation.
And what is that?
That's not even real.
I know he's not
your dad. I know that.
But somehow...
you have his blood and I don't.
So I'm asking you,
give me my dad.
Meredith.
We found a match.
- What?
- We found a match. A donor liver.
So we're gonna schedule
the surgery for tonight.
Uh, that's terrific.
But I thought I wasn't
eligible for the transplant list.
It's not from the list, it's me.
I got tested, and my
crossmatch was negative,
which means we're
an ideal match.
So I'm gonna go get admitted
- and we'll do this.
- Mer...
I'm a drunk, Meredith.
I did this. I put
myself in this bed.
I broke me.
I can't... I won't let you
put me back together.
I put you through enough.
It's a generous offer. I can't.
I can't accept it.
I'm sorry, but there's gotta
be something else you can do.
He's 31. We just
bought a condo together.
- We just rescued a puppy!
- Ange, it's gonna be OK.
No, it's not! They're just
sending you home to...
What kind of doctors are you?!
You're supposed to do something!
They're doing
everything they can.
Dr. Hunt's given us extra time,
time that we never would've had.
Dr. Hunt, can I...?
Excuse me.
- Try cytoreductive surgery.
- It won't work.
We have to be able to remove the
tumor and with these adhesions, you can't.
Ball-tipped electrosurgery
helps get around the adhesions.
His cancer's incurable. I'm not gonna
put him through another painful surgery.
- His survival rate's
13 percent.
- I had five.
- Stevens...
- I had a five percent chance
of survival. I have incurable
cancer, but I am living with it.
The reason I am, the
reason I'm standing here
is because no one ever
said, "We've done everything".
I'm alive right now because
people fought for me.
Cristina fought for me.
He deserves the chance to fight.
If he doesn't want it, I will shut up.
But he deserves a chance!
You know what? I'm
good. I'm off the hook.
I did what I was supposed to do.
I offered. Mother
Teresa would be proud.
- You gotta go back in there.
- And do what?
- Cry and call him Daddy?
- He's the sick one, OK?
He's sick, you're not. Go
back in. Say what you gotta say
- to make him take it.
- Alex, I tried.
Try again.
His BP is normal, his
bloodwork is pristine.
He appears to have the
heart of a 50-year-old.
- So, what does that mean?
- It means he's cleared
for surgery.
You're gonna go
through with this?
You bet I am, champ.
Well, it's your money.
We can't stop you.
But Irene and I have talked it
over. We've decided if you do this,
we're taking you out of the home
and moving you back in with us.
I don't want to move in with
you. I'm happy where I am.
That place is causing you
to make irrational decisions:
going after a younger woman,
sneaking into her room at night.
It's not appropriate
for a man your age.
Now there's an extra
twin in Janey's room.
She'll be thrilled to spend
more time with Grandpa.
Come on!
- It's just an erection!
- Excuse me?
All the guy wants is a woody!
God forbid you get to be his age
and your kids won't
let you have one.
He's your father. He's taken
care of you your entire lives,
given you everything, and
now he needs something
and you throw that in his face?
Know how many people
would jump at the chance
to give back to their parents,
who would sacrifice everything
without blinking?
There's nothing wrong with
dating a younger woman.
It keeps you young. That's
my professional opinion.
Does the chief always...
pay such attention
to his patients,
or just the ones whose
wives he had an affair with?
Sorry.
How did I do this to myself?
How did I end up here?
You woke up every morning
and you promised
yourself that last night
would be your last drink.
And you made it...
till 9:00am.
Or noon.
Some days, till cocktail hour.
And you were so
pleased with yourself
that you rewarded
yourself... with a drink.
You convinced yourself again
that it would be the only one.
You have a disease, Thatcher.
When you're in
it, you can't stop.
You can't undo what you did.
But Meredith is offering
you a second chance, man.
You need that liver.
You need it now.
If you want to live.
I took her childhood.
I can't take any more from her.
You...
You better take
care of my girls.
You owe me at least that.
Hey. My stromal cancer patient?
We're going for the surgery.
We're gonna do
it. Hunt listened.
- That's great.
- I'm gonna go scrub in.
Hey, are you OK?
I'm sorry about
the whole tick thing.
I'm fine. It's... It's a small
price to pay for fresh air.
OK.
You're welcome.
You used to pour my
cereal in the morning.
That's it. That's all I
remember about you.
You're not my father. You're just
the guy who used to pour my cereal.
And if you die, it probably
won't change my life that much.
But it will change hers.
If you die, it will break her.
And I'm not gonna
let you do that.
I don't know what it's
like to have a father.
But I do know what it's like
to have a sister. And it's good.
And if we can get through
this, the door will be open for us
to get to know each other.
The door's open.
So before intercourse, he
squeezes the pump in his scrotum.
- Ooh!
- And...
- Oh. Oh.
- Oh.
His age doesn't
make it high-risk?
Well, there's
always risk involved,
but this is the most advanced
solution to his problem.
What's high-risk? Does someone
have a risky high-tech surgery?
Cristina, I don't
think you wanna...
I think this would be a
real challenge for Dr. Yang.
- Do you think
she can handle it?
- Oh, I can handle it.
- I don't think
she can handle it.
- I can handle it.
Pre-op's in 2083.
Thank you, Dr. Sloan.
I'm gonna pay for that later.
But it was kind of worth it.
Beat it. Sloan wants me on this.
OK, Mr. Waller. I'm Dr. Yang.
I'll be taking over your pre-operative
care this evening for your
penile implant surgery.
- You're getting
a penile implant?
- Yes, ma'am.
That fellow, he was
just gonna shave me.
Terrific.
- You wanted a surgery.
- Putting a bicycle pump
in some old man's junk is
not surgery, it's punishment.
At least you don't have to be
laid up in bed for the next month.
You better tell me all the
gossip about Mercy West.
- I want all the gory details.
- Yeah, yeah.
- Am I stupid for doing this?
- No.
Really?
You get to save
your dad's life tonight.
Hey. What are you doing here?
You didn't think I'd let
you do this by yourself?
This is not how this works.
Do I need to find
you something to do?
No, I have a penis.
I'm gonna sit by her
head. I won't say a word.
- Shepherd, this is my OR.
- I respect that.
But this is my wife
that you're cutting into.
I haven't just been waiting for
the right moment to propose.
- You've been waiting
for remission.
- Yeah.
I didn't want to saddle her
down with a sick husband.
But now it looks like that just
might be part of the package.
So, what the hell. I'm not
gonna waste another moment.
You shouldn't.
- Ready when you are.
- Ready?
I had five interns. Four of
you have been on this table.
One of you has
cancer, one of you died.
You better not pull
anything funny on me, Grey.
Let's see what we got here.
Dr. Yang, the senior resident...
should test the apparatus.
I understand if you pass.
I don't pass, Dr. Sloan. This
might be a joke to all of you,
but I do my job.
Squeezing the scrotum.
- Nice!
- Awesome.
Liver's here.
Make sure you keep
the bowel covered.
I need more wet laps.
- Uh...
- He's got some
collateral bleeding.
I need the argon beamer.
- Hang more FFPs.
- BP's dropping out!
Sir, we can't kill this guy.
I'm aware of that, Karev!
If it's bad news, I
don't want to wake her.
Wake her.
Hey.
They had a couple of months
and we just took that away.
- I'm sorry. It's my fault.
- It's my fault!
It was my call, and it was
the wrong call. I was wrong.
I should have known
better. I should have...
I should have taught better.
You see a one in a million,
and you want to believe.
I was wrong to do the
surgery, to put you on this case.
You weren't ready to be
here. You beat the odds.
You were that one in a million. But you
cannot be a doctor and a patient here.
You have to choose.
How'd it go, Doc?
I don't think you'll
be disappointed.
Well, well, well.
Dr. Sloan, I'd...
I'd like you to meet my
Marion. Hello, sweets!
- Sir.
- Now is not the time, Yang.
I have good hands.
They are fast, dexterous,
they were made to throw ties
and do complex procedures.
These hands were
made for surgery.
They should have been
deep in a heart, saving a life.
Instead, they removed a
tick and pumped a penis!
- What's your point?
- My point?
You should cut me.
- What?
- From the program.
You have to make more
cuts, and I should go.
If you can't give me a brilliant
cardiothoracic attending
who is willing to teach me,
then I can't get what I
need from this hospital.
Everyone is scared of
losing their job, and so am I.
But if I can't learn,
if I can't use my gift,
then I...
I guess that scares me more.
That's my point, sir.
The thing about being a surgeon,
everybody wants a piece of you.
We take one little oath...
The case where he kept his
mouthguard, you should open it.
I'm very sorry for your loss.
And suddenly, we're
drowning in obligations.
To our patients,
to our colleagues,
to medicine itself.
Chief?
Are you OK?
I have responsibilities.
To make this hospital the
best medical facility it could be.
To repair what I've broken,
even if it was 20 years ago.
If I am now the bad guy,
if I am now the villain here,
well...
so be it.
This must be so hard for you.
Thanks, Torres.
I was gonna... I was...
But I'm gonna go, so...
- You take care, OK?
- Torres.
Sir?
Go see HR tomorrow.
Tell them you're an attending surgeon at
Seattle Grace and you want a new badge.
And take some of
these Danish home.
They'll just go to waste.
So we do what any
sane person would do.
We run like hell
from our promises,
hoping they'll be forgotten.
Oh, God!
- A deer?
- We have to move.
But sooner or later,
they always catch up.
Hey. You're awake.
How's your pain?
Is your mouth dry?
There's water. Are you thirsty?
Have you been
sleeping on me all night?
Yeah, I was moving
between you and Dad.
- Who's doing good.
- Good. That's good.
And sometimes, you find the
obligation you dread the most...
- Lexie.
- Yeah?
- You're on my IV.
- Oh, sorry. OK.
Isn't worth running from at all.