You're late. I know.
She's worried.
Well, I'm here now.
In trauma,
we're concerned with
one overriding question...
How did this happen?
I didn't want you to see me yet.
I know.
Tatiana, you look...
So beautiful.
What was the
mechanism of injury?
How do we see past the mess
and confusion of the trauma
to figure out what the
damage actually is?
Infinite possibilities put the
patient on the table in front of you.
Now you have to
figure out will they live?
Will you be able to save them?
Or are they a lost cause?
No shared assets, no children,
and, of course, there's a solid
post-nuptial agreement in place.
With nothing to contest, it's
just about signing the papers.
The places to initial and
sign are all clearly marked.
Red tabs for initials,
blue tabs for signatures.
Every part of a trauma tells
a different piece of the story.
This is one of the simpler
divorces I've seen, actually.
And until you look at
each and every injury...
So, what are you gonna do?
You gonna sign the papers?
We have to push,
and we have to fight.
I'm not sure we are
worth fighting for.
You can't see what went wrong.
At work? That's where
you decide to do this?
You want to lower your voice?
What does it matter
how loud my voice is
when 35 people just
saw me get served
with divorce papers
in the middle of the
emergency room?
I am sorry about
that, all right?
That was not supposed to happen.
He was supposed to talk to you
after you were done with work.
It's only been four weeks.
Four, Jackson.
Is that... That's
all the counseling
you could handle before bailing?
You said you wanted to try!
We did try.
It didn't work. It didn't
get us anywhere.
We have the same exact fight
over and over again,
around in circles.
I'm telling you,
it's not working.
Then why are we even
bothering with counseling?
What is the point of counseling
if you're just gonna suddenly,
without even talking about it, just...
Oh, come on. All
we do is talk, April.
So, what? You just, you
just serve me papers?
Just like that?
Do you have any idea what
a slap in the face this is?
How long?
How long have I been sitting on
a couch discussing my marriage
with someone who has
already checked out?
That's not what I was doing.
No, I just want to
know when it happened.
When did you decide
that you were done?
She didn't say
that. Yeah, she did.
When did she say that?
She's been saying it
for three weeks now.
We shouldn't be having sex.
I hardly think our
sex life is our problem.
I don't think it's a problem.
It just... It gets in the way.
In the way of what?
You're just hearing
what you want to hear.
I'm hearing what our therapist
is telling us, and you're not.
It's like we're sitting in on two
completely different sessions.
That's just offensive.
What's offensive is you
keep choosing to ignore...
I'm not ignoring anything!
See? You can't ever
take responsibility.
You never apologize
for anything.
I apologize
all the time.
Not for the things that matter.
What do I have to
apologize for, Jackson?
I am here, and I'm trying.
I want to make this work.
Stop! Will you just...
Don't touch it.
Sorry.
Now, remember, once we
remove these bandages,
there's gonna be some...
Some redness, some swelling.
So, did you talk
to April last night?
I did.
And? How'd it go?
Not, uh... Not
exactly as I expected.
Oh, God. She took it that hard?
Or she didn't because...
You didn't ask her, did you?
Tatiana. You're kidding me.
It's really not that
simple. Sure, it is.
You just say, "This isn't
working for me anymore.
"I'm not happy. I
want a divorce."
Knock, knock! Hey.
Oh. Well, you ready
for the unveiling?
Four years' hard work, Avery.
Well, I'm just the surgeon.
Tatiana's had the hardest job.
This guy. Always sweet-talking.
Forty-three
surgeries, four years,
three months, one
week, and four days.
Can't believe this is the last
time you'll be unwrapping my face.
Okay. Let's do it.
Wait. I'm...
I don't think I'll
be able to look.
Hey, what kind of
hack do you think I am?
You are going to
want to see this.
Trust me.
How's Meredith?
She's good, considering
it's her first week of recovery.
Good.
What are you up to?
You're just...
Mmm-hmm... You're so...
Remember how our therapist
said that we should be more direct
with what we want? Oh.
Maybe you should be more
direct with what you want.
I have an hour
until my I&D case.
I'm heading to the on-call room.
Take a little nap.
Oh, yeah? Yeah.
Too bad you won't
be getting any sleep.
I don't want to talk,
because you know what?
I know what you're gonna say!
You're gonna say
you love me but...
You don't know
what I'm going to say!
I'm pretty sure I do.
It doesn't matter!
You don't! Fine!
Fine, then just go ahead.
Come... Say it.
Uh...
Oh, my God, Jackson!
God, please, would
you just say it?
You're right. I was.
I was gonna ask you for a
divorce when we went for dinner,
and then again when
we stayed in for dinner...
Yeah. And then things happened.
Yeah, well, we had sex, Jackson.
That's what
happened. We had sex.
I was clear about this.
My mind was made up.
I knew what was best for me,
moving forward, no matter how hard.
I knew there were things
that we couldn't repair.
I knew what I had to do.
And it's not clear
for me anymore.
This... When I look at
you and I stop thinking...
When I let myself
just be with you...
All I'm saying is, I don't think
that I want what I
wanted anymore.
And what I want...
What?
I want you.
Me too.
You guys had sex. Yeah.
We did, too. It's messy.
Stop running away from me.
Callie... You and Arizona,
before you guys split,
you did the
counseling thing, right?
I mean, an hour
wait for a table?
It's ridiculous. I'm hungry now.
This was such a better idea.
Place looks nice.
Changed some things around, huh?
Some new pillows.
I like those.
No, you don't. You
hate throw pillows.
I really do. Yeah, I know.
I'm sorry. You want
something to drink?
Yeah.
Oh, my God. They gave
us so many fortune cookies.
I love fortune cookies!
I know. I asked for extra.
I'm sorry again about
last night getting cut short.
I get it. It's okay. It's fine.
Yeah, I know.
And...
Look at that.
Amen.
Thank you for waiting.
Mmm-hmm.
You want to know
what I was praying for?
No, that's all right.
Throw pillows.
Thousands of them
just raining from the sky.
I do not understand
their purpose.
They have so many purposes.
They don't. They're
like a pop of color.
They just get in the way. I
just don't understand what the...
You, like, prop up
your arms and your feet.
Moving them around the
house. Plus, it looks nice.
You're funny.
It's good, right?
It's really good.
Told you you'd like this place.
I can't believe I
never noticed it.
I probably ordered takeout
every night while you were gone.
And I didn't realize this place
was right around the corner.
Wow. Okay.
What?
We just sat down to eat.
I thought we were
having a nice time. We are.
So why are you gonna
ruin it by picking a fight?
No, I'm not.
I wasn't picking a fight. I
was just talking Chinese food.
And Jordan. And takeout.
I am not the one
getting defensive.
And I am? Look...
I did not come
here to fight tonight.
Okay. Okay?
Okay.
So, why did you come here?
Throw pillows, obviously.
I saw you had a nasal
septum reconstruction
up on the board today.
Is that for Tatiana?
Yeah. Her final surgery.
She's come such a long
way. You should be so proud.
I am.
I mean, I will be once it
all kind of comes together.
Mmm-hmm.
I've performed so many
surgeries on her, you know,
that her face is just
this road map, you know,
of an incredible journey
that we've been on together.
I'm rambling. I'll stop.
We really should talk, though.
We are talking.
Yeah, I mean...
Really talk.
About us.
Mmm-hmm.
Obviously it's not
easy, you know?
I do think it's right.
If you're struggling this much,
maybe that should
tell you something.
Maybe you should stop
before you say whatever it is...
We need to talk
about getting a divorce.
April...
Okay.
Come on. Don't...
We're not even living together.
Okay, this is the first
substantial conversation
we've had in, what, months?
Well, that is your choice and
not mine, 'cause I've been here.
I've been willing to
have any conversation.
Don't do that.
Don't blame me.
I'm not blaming you.
It's not blame. It's just fact.
I want to talk to you,
but we're having two
different conversations
'cause I want to work on things
and you just want to end them.
I'm not being flip
about any of this.
You actually believe
that I'm taking this lightly?
It just seems like you
are looking for an excuse
to walk away instead of
putting in any of the work...
You left me!
You walked away! You...
You ran halfway across
the world! How co...
'Cause I was dying, Jackson!
Samuel died, and I died!
Until Jordan, until I was
able go over there and...
And what?
You think I was somehow
just fine after Samuel?
You don't think
I was dying, too?
No. No, okay?
You weren't. Not like me.
You were coping.
You... You were okay.
I couldn't even...
And then I found something.
I found something over there
that I needed so badly!
And I thought that
you understood that!
I wasn't coping.
I was covering.
For you. I was...
To take care of you.
And now you're
punishing me over and over
because I dared to take
things into my own hands
because I recognized
the spiral I was falling into,
and I went and did
something about it?
I was putting you first.
That's what you
do in a marriage!
Or I guess that's not
what you do. I don't...
I took care of myself
so that I would survive!
And all that does
is make you angry.
Look at you. What...
What is it, Jackson?
What... What pisses
you off so much,
that I chose to go after the
thing that I needed to heal
or that the thing I
needed wasn't you?
The thing that I needed was you!
I survived.
You survived.
But I do not think
we can survive this.
No, I'm not getting
divorced, Jackson, okay?
No one in my family
has ever been divorced.
Everyone in my family has.
Sometimes marriages
just don't work out.
It's not just the harder
thing sometimes.
Maybe sometimes it's healthier.
I'm not giving up on us.
I won't. You already did.
Oh, my God! Stop saying that!
You take for granted that
I'm just gonna wait for you,
and wait and wait,
no matter what!
But divorce is not some
dirty word, April, not for me.
In fact, right now, it's a light
at the end of a
really dark tunnel.
What are you doing? Really?
That's what this
has been to you?
I'm so sorry I kept you locked
away in this prison camp!
Hey! You just want to end it?
Huh? Is that what you're
saying? That's not what I said.
You just want to pretend like
this... Well, what are you saying?
You would know if you
would listen! I am listening!
What are you doing?
I'm throwing cookies!
Why? Because!
Because why? I don't know!
You're being
ridiculous! Stop! I know!
Stop. I know!
What...
What is happening to us?
I don't know.
How did we get to this?
How do we make it stop?
Wait.
Wait. What?
We should probably not do this.
Probably not a good idea.
No. Yeah, absolutely.
It's not a good idea. All right.
Yeah, yeah. Okay.
You know what they
call that? Divorce.
And it wasn't an ultimatum.
I gave you a choice.
Where's my
maxillofacial consult?
On the way. GCS is 9.
Pupils are asymmetric. We
need to establish an airway.
What do you got?
He fell 20 feet.
C6-7 unstable fracture.
He's breathing on his own,
but he needs a secure airway.
Okay. Laryngoscope, please.
Wait. Why are you here?
Airway. You paged me.
I thought you were going to the
airport, flying to Jordan with April.
Yeah. No. Um...
Yeah, I decided
not to go, actually.
Uh, scope, please.
Is this flight 2703 to Jordan?
I need to get on that
plane. I'm sorry, sir,
but once the doors are
officially closed, there's really...
Please, okay? My
wife's on that flight.
I just need to get to my
wife, so if you could just...
Oh, my God. That is so sweet.
So you'll open the doors? No.
Are you kidding me right now?
I'm sorry. There's
nothing I can do.
Your plane's leaving. What?
What the hell do you mean that
Owen's not gonna be there with you?
I'm not gonna be there alone.
There's a whole unit of us.
We work together. We're friends.
I mean, we're more than
that. We're like family.
We have each other's
backs. We get each other.
Mmm-mmm. Like I
don't get you, right?
Come with me. Come
on. It's not too late.
I can make a couple
phone calls. No.
We always need more
surgeons over there.
April, no. My answer
hasn't changed.
If you could just see what it's
like over there, the work we do.
It's important.
It's immediate. It's
essential. There's no filter.
There's no time to even...
So often around here,
we, like, walk through life
and get caught
up with all this stuff.
There's no stuff over there. Every
day, every patient has purpose.
It has meaning.
I want you to know it
the way that I know it.
And I can't just pick up
and go. I have commitments.
I have people. Who? Who?
What people do you have here
that would prevent you from
coming overseas with me?
Patients.
I mean, I'm not willing to just
abandon people
that depend on me.
And I am?
Kind of.
Kind of, yeah.
I'm still getting
a lot of necrosis.
I'm afraid that...
The stupid paramedian
forehead flap is dying again.
This is the second one.
I do not know why
this is happening.
I harvested two
blood vessels this time
just to make sure
that it wouldn't...
I was so careful to avoid
clotting, but it's still just...
I'm sorry. We'll
figure this out.
This isn't your fault, you know.
Maybe my face just
doesn't like forehead flaps.
Hey.
You will figure this
out. You always do.
It's not like we haven't
had setbacks before.
Yeah. I know. It's just...
Just crappy 'cause
this one's happening
right before Christmas
when your wife's off being some
kind of superhero in a desert.
And, I mean...
I was around for what
happened this time last year...
When you lost Samuel.
And I know, well...
Things have to be
tough for you right now.
Come on! Just give
me a signal! Just...
Damn it!
Come on, come on, come
on, come on, come on.
Come on!
Do you need more anesthetic?
No, I'm okay.
I heard you were down here.
What happened, baby?
It's nothing. It was just
an accident at home.
Have you heard from
April? Did she call you today?
She's busy over there, you know.
I mean, she probably doesn't
even realize what day it is.
How can I help you?
What do you need?
You know, I could use
more lidocaine with epi,
if you wouldn't mind.
I'll find some.
God! Oh!
It is so good to be back.
April. I'm-I'm not working.
I'm-I'm just... I'm
not ready to work yet.
Hey. I'm gonna head in to work.
You have breakfast?
You know, you haven't
been to church in a while.
What do you say we go together?
Huh?
Hey.
Look at me, sweetheart.
Hmm?
What if we...
Try again?
Mmm-hmm?
Let's try for another baby.
Why would you say that?
No, I just want...
What?
What do you want?
April... Screw you.
Screw you for even
suggesting that.
Screw you.
Okay.
All right.
I'll go.
I'll just go in to work.
Get off of me! Okay,
just calm down. I know.
Get off! Warren!
I was just marking
her face for surgery.
That marker reeks!
All right, guys... I don't
want it near my face!
She keeps trying to
take off her bandages.
I'm not doing this
anymore! I can't! I'm done!
All right, Warren,
Wilson, give us a minute.
Hey, Tatiana, what is going on?
What is it? I had
a life before this!
I had a life!
Then I was in the wrong
place at the wrong time,
and now my face is
melted off of my face!
It's been a year and a half,
and there's so much more to go.
So many more surgeries!
And with each
one, you get better.
This is my life now...
These walls, this bed, you!
I want it back.
I want to go back
to who I was before.
I know.
Go back. I know.
Hey. Good morning. Hey, morning.
Morning, sir. Yeah.
Mmm-hmm.
Oh! Hey. What you doing?
Oh! Um... Uh...
We're dancing.
Dance. Right on.
Right on.
Oh!
Hi. APRIL: Hi.
Well, who died?
What? Nobody.
We're just dancing.
I only dance it out
when something bad happens.
No. JACKSON: Not today.
Did someone...
Did I leave my...
Well, all right!
Mmm-hmm. Hey.
No.
What the hell?
Oh!
Hey!
Oh! All right. All right.
We celebrating the new baby?
What? Wait. What?
What did she say? Torres?
What did you say?
Ah, well...
I'm so sorry.
We are actually
celebrating a baby.
I am pregnant.
Oh, my God!
Holy crap. JACKSON: Yeah, yeah.
- Congratulations.
- Thank you!
Congratulations!
Yeah!
Hey, hey.
Thank you! Thank you!
Work it out.
No, I don't think so.
I'll just sprain my ankle.
It's one small concession.
It's not small.
Look, we are about
to tell my parents
that we got married, eloped.
They wanted to be at my wedding.
They thought they
were at my wedding.
I'm just not comfortable
with it. I mean, you know that.
I know that you're
not religious.
So why are you asking me
to lead your family in prayer?
Because they're
predisposed to not like you.
You're marrying a rich,
handsome surgeon.
Stop it. I know.
We embarrassed them.
And we will apologize for that.
Sincerely, okay?
But I'm not gonna
change who I am
just to get your parents
to like me. No, no, no.
No, I don't want you
to change who you are.
You want me to lie. No. Come on.
It's... It's a gesture
of good faith.
My gesture of good faith
is being a wonderful husband
to their beautiful daughter.
It's one day.
One prayer.
Not like I'm asking
you to go get baptized.
I'm not.
Their first real
impression of me.
What happens
after, at the holidays
when I'm suddenly not praying?
Well...
Are you kidding me? You...
Attention, ladies
and gentlemen...
You want this to go
on for how long exactly?
No, I just... I just want them
to like you and accept us.
Well, if you respect
me, they will.
Jackson. Please. I...
You know what? No.
April, this conversation's over.
Excuse me?
You knew who I was
when we got married.
Okay? We talked about this.
We negotiated our
whole wedding around it.
I thought that we
agreed that we would
respect each
other's differences.
So, yeah, for me,
this conversation's over.
Just over? Yeah.
I'm done with it.
Maybe I didn't...
Maybe I didn't know
who I was marrying.
Really? Okay. Yeah,
because you know what?
The way that you're
speaking to me right now,
the way that you're
acting, is not who I married.
Yet I could say the same thing.
You're right, because
you know what?
We thought about it
for all of, like, 18 hours.
What are you saying? You
wish we hadn't got married?
No.
Ladies and gentlemen,
may I have your attention?
We are now beginning
our initial descent
into Port Columbus
International Airport.
Please raise your tray tables
and place your seats
in the upright position.
My parents are picking us up.
You want the rest of my peanuts?
I'm allergic to peanuts.
It looks like a lovely wedding.
Congratulations again.
She's a really beautiful bride.
Hey, what's wrong?
Are you feeling pain?
No. No. I'm not.
It's just...
Look at me. I'm hideous.
No. Do not say that.
No one will ever look at me
the way you're looking
at April in these pictures.
Tatiana, you're wrong.
Please. Okay?
I look at you, and I see
such incredible strength.
I see bravery.
I see humor and persistence...
Beauty.
Now, these surgeries, they're
gonna give you back a face,
but don't you dare
for a single moment
think that you're
not already beautiful.
Oh, I can't believe
we're doing this.
I can.
You may now kiss.
I know you think it's silly.
Well, I didn't say that.
But I'm serious, okay?
No premarital sex.
How serious? Like
"absolutely not" serious
or "I could be
convinced" serious?
We will survive one more night.
Ah! Speak for yourself.
If we wait... Mmm-hmm.
Our wedding night
will be so amazing.
And tonight could also be
so amazing.
Okay. Mmm-hmm.
You...
What's that?
Good night, Jackson.
I'm gonna go now.
You put the chain on?
I'll see you in the morning.
All right.
Forget something?
What time? SALES
CLERK: What about this one?
I really have my heart set
on getting married in white.
The wedding dress
you're wearing is gorgeous.
I know a cleaner who
can get that stain out.
Yeah, thank you, but
I need a new dress.
I'll see what I
have in the back.
Thank you. JACKSON: Thank you.
Yes, thank you. Bye.
All right.
We've got ourselves
a justice of the peace.
Tomorrow afternoon,
he will marry us.
A justice of the peace?
Okay, so, uh...
Our wedding will be...
Legal. Yeah.
He's got a license.
He's not an Elvis or a pirate
or a cartoon character.
I... I had just
really hoped that
we'd find a minister.
Someone
nondenominational, obviously,
but, you know, just someone
who's at least been ordained.
April, I'm not religious.
No, I know, I know.
Just having someone
with some sort of
relationship with God marry us
is kind of important to me.
I mean, even finding this guy
wasn't easy on such short notice.
I mean, having a wedding
without a lot of God talk
is kind of important to me.
I always had such,
like, a clear idea
of what my wedding
would look like.
Want me to bring you back
to the barn, or were you...
No! Stop it, Jackson. No.
I just want God at my wedding.
I want him there for the
most important day of my life.
Well, you know that
after we get married,
I'm not gonna turn into
this churchgoing guy.
You know, I watch
football on Sundays.
You are not
changing who you are,
and I do not want you to.
But you can't expect me
to change who I am, either.
How's this one?
Right idea, wrong color.
Okay. Yeah?
I'll make some phone calls, and
we'll find an ordained minister.
Thank you. Mmm-hmm.
Did you see what
we just did there?
We disagreed. We discussed.
We compromised.
We are pretty amazing
at this marriage thing.
- We are.
- This one?
Oh, my gosh! Oh, my gosh!
No, no, no, no, no! Don't
look! It's bad luck! It's bad luck!
Yes, yes, yes!
No, no, wait. You
can't steal all my fries.
Sure, I can. What's mine is
yours. What's yours is mine.
We're not married yet.
Crap. Sorry. Crap, crap, crap.
Oh, no! Ah!
You know what?
No more fries for you.
It was an accident.
No, no more.
Hey.
Where are we gonna live? After?
Well, I was thinking...
What about my place?
Absolutely.
Really? Yeah. It's way nicer.
It's bigger. It's
perfect. Great.
But I'm not changing my name.
What? Avery's a great name.
So is Kepner.
You want to take it?
Sure. Really?
No. No, I'm not
changing my name.
Okay.
I didn't expect you to, either.
That's not really
a thing for me.
It's not? No, definitely not.
What?
Holy crap. We did this!
We are doing this.
We're doing this.
I love you. I always have.
Even the things
I don't like, I love.
You're getting married.
Unless you can give
me a reason not to?
Look, we're not doing
this anymore, okay?
No more screwing in closets.
No more screwing anywhere.
I told you, last time
was the last time.
Hey. What's wrong?
I am supposed to do a
facial reanimation surgery.
A procedure Sloan practically
invented my third year.
Done it with him like
a handful of times.
I mean, I never...
There's no way I can
do this on my own.
Of course you can. No,
you haven't seen him do it.
He's brilliant, okay,
and so precise.
I just needed more time.
You can do this, Jackson.
April, what if I can't?
What if I make her worse?
This woman's counting on me,
and I promised that I could help.
Then you will. You will.
I know you will.
You are not a person who
makes promises he doesn't keep.
Okay, let's push 10
of morphine. Yeah.
What do we got?
Tatiana Flauto, 30s.
Some psycho threw
acid on her face.
Police got him, though.
A good Samaritan gave
her a towel with ice in it
before the paramedics got there.
And it adhered to the burns.
We haven't been
able to see underneath.
Right. All right, let's start
with a bottle of saline, please.
No. Thank you.
Hi. Tatiana, is it?
My name is Dr. Avery.
I'd like to wet this
towel with saline
so it'll come off easier, okay?
Will you let me do that?
I'm scared, I'm scared! Okay.
I know. I know. It's
okay. It's all right.
You're safe now,
okay? You're safe here.
I just need you to keep still
so that I can get a
look at what's going on.
All right? No, no, no!
I know. It's okay. You're okay.
No, no, no! You're
okay. I'm gonna help you.
Here comes the saline.
Okay. Here we
go. No, no, no, no.
All right, it's
okay. No! No! No!
Okay. Okay. RICHARD: Okay.
- No, no, no!
- Really good.
Now we got to remove
this towel, okay?
We're gonna get
started. It's gonna hurt.
So I need you to take a
deep breath for me, okay?
Deep breath.
Here we go. All right. Okay.
No! No!
It's okay.
You're doing great. Okay.
All done. You did great.
You did great.
We need to get Sloan
down here immediately.
Sloan is on a plane
to Idaho right now.
Can you handle this?
Breathe. What is
it? What's wrong?
It's too bad! You can't
fix my face! No, no.
No, no, no, no. No, no, no!
No, Tatiana, hey. I know
that we just met, all right?
But what you don't know is that
you and I, we are a team now.
It's gonna be you and me.
We're gonna get through
this together, all right?
I'm not gonna lie. It's
not gonna be easy,
and it's not gonna be quick,
but I'm gonna be right
here the entire time, okay?
I will not leave your side.
I promise you.
Okay?
All right.
Let's get Mepitel and
Xeroform, please. Oh!
Jackson, hey.
It's okay. Really.
I lost some friends that day.
I hate Sloan.
Even when I'm perfect, he
talks to me like I'm an idiot.
Well, try spending a day in the
ER with Dr. Major Owen Hunt.
That man is dark.
He is a dark,
pig-stabbing, scary man.
What?
What's the matter?
This is where Reed was shot...
Where I found her. I slipped
in her blood right there.
I haven't been back here since.
There's an elevator upstairs
near where Charles died.
I never use it.
Hey.
You okay? Hey.
Oh, okay.
I know. I know.
Okay? We're here. We're okay.
I had a gun pointed at me.
I know. I know.
My life flashed before my eyes.
It... It... It really
did. Shh... Okay.
And it was so...
Boring!
I just kept thinking, "I
don't want to die a virgin."
Oh.
You can fix that.
Was that a proposition?
No, I meant... Oh, oh!
No! No, no, no,
no. I didn't mean...
No, I... No. I was...
I... It was a joke. Yeah.
I was making a
totally stupid joke.
Yeah, it wasn't good. Yeah.
Okay. I'm...
What? Good luck with Sloan.
Mmm. Mmm-hmm.
Well, that girl is weird.
I'm a virgin. Yes. So what?
It's not something
I talk about, okay?
We all have things
we don't talk about.
She thinks your
husband walks on water.
Cincinnati, Ohio. Pediatrics.
Thank you. Who's next?
Uh, I'll go.
Charles Percy,
Brookings, South Dakota.
I want to be a trauma surgeon.
Or maybe vascular.
Or, like, uh...
I don't know, actually.
All right, well, you've got a lot
of time to figure that one out.
Who's next?
Right here. Jackson Avery,
originally from Boston...
Hold on. What?
Like "Harper Avery" Avery?
Uh...
Yeah, actually. Anyway...
So you're, like,
born to the throne.
You know what? I wouldn't...
Do you know a Catherine
Avery, the urologist?
I do, actually.
Are you writing this down?
She's just, like, amazing. Are
you going into urology, too?
No. Cardiothoracic all the way.
Can I be done now?
I'll go!
Hi. I'm April Kepner.
I'm from Ohio, and I'm super
excited to be near the ocean,
although I don't really know
how I feel about the rain yet.
As far as specialty goes,
I'm looking for
something with set hours
so that I can raise
kids eventually...
Two boys and a girl.
So I'm thinking plastics,
urology, proctology.
We talk about the
mechanism of injury...
About where it all started.
But the truth is,
it's sort of a myth.
We can't boil every injury
down to one single blow.
This is one of the simpler
divorces I've seen, actually.
You want this?
Do you really want this?
Okay.
What hurts us is cumulative.
It happens over time.
We absorb blow after blow,
shock after shock,
painful hit after hit.
Is there anything else?
Uh. That's it. No.
Okay, then.
But even then,
even if we know
exactly how we got here,
it doesn't mean we can fix it.
Too late to back out?
Are you kidding me?
Ugh. Timothy and I had
a huge fight this morning.
It was probably my fault.
Well, yeah, with that
mouth, probably was.
Look, you guys are
gonna fight, okay?
You'll probably have that
same fight for 50 years.
But you just can't let it become
bigger than the two of you.
So, in other words,
marriage is hard,
but not as hard as getting
acid thrown in your face?
Yes. This mouth. You
see? Four years of this.
And yet you still agreed
to walk me down the aisle.
You kept every
promise you made to me.
Thank you.
Mmm-hmm.
I'm sorry about you and April.
No.
Today's about you, okay?
Let's get you married. Hmm?
For you.
You can't heal every wound.
And that's okay.
I have to believe it's okay.
Hey!
Oh, I wasn't sure what you
would be in the mood for,
so I kind of got everything.
Champagne,
tequila, pinot noir...
Pick your poison.
No, thanks.
Ah! What's happening?
Did you already start
drinking? Are you drunk?
What? I'm...
Hungry, maybe. What?
You just signed divorce papers,
and you don't want a drink?
What are you... What
are you, pregnant?
What?
Oh!
April.
I have to believe that
even if something seems
like it cannot be fixed...
According to the test
I took this morning,
yeah, actually.
I think I am.
It doesn't mean it's broken.