We cover up injuries
with tape and gauze...
Um, have you seen Dr. Avery?
Upstairs in the lab.
To protect the injury,
to prevent infection,
to save the patient
from further suffering.
The hard part comes when
you have to rip the bandage off
because that can hurt like hell.
Hey, how's it going?
Uh, pretty good.
What's up? Nothing.
Have you talked to April?
No.
Why?
Nothing.
Um, I just wanted to see
how you guys were doing.
Have a good night. She knows.
Knows?
April knows.
What? Doesn't she?
Who told her, Karev?
I'm not sure...
Well, she told Karev.
Um, or he figured it out.
No, I mean, I told Karev.
I just asked him to
keep it to himself.
What, keep it to himself?
What are you talking about?
That I'm seeing
people. That I'm dating.
That I went on a date.
So, April knows, huh?
Uh, that you're
seeing other people.
Does April know? No!
She doesn't. She doesn't
know anything about that.
So then what are
you talking about?
Nothing.
I was... I was... Nothing.
All this is just so
weird and new.
I mean, I just really don't want April
to get her feelings hurt here, okay?
So just do me a favor.
Keep it to yourself.
That'd be great.
April's pregnant.
Yeah.
Why are you telling me this?
Jackson, can we...
Why is she telling me this?
Um, did she happen to
say where we were eating?
Uh, I think it's a steakhouse.
Yeah, unless you're
not... If you don't.
No, no. Fine.
Love a good T-bone. Yeah.
Yes.
Maybe... Maybe
we should call her.
Oh, it's Mag... Uh, Dr. Pierce.
"Have to cancel...
Called into big transplant.
"Really sorry, but you
two should still go."
Smiley face.
You know, truth be
told, um, I'm a little tired.
Me too.
Rain check? Rain check.
Okay. Okay.
Good. Okay.
So, what do you say?
Dr. Grey, would you
like to go out with me?
I have said "no" to nicer faces.
Great, then this should
be easy. Yeah, it should.
Good, you're still here.
We've got a transplant on deck.
Uh, Karev was...
Sorry. It's fine.
Hi. Will Thorpe.
You're Thorpe.
I mean, um, hello.
Maggie Pierce.
Hi. Hi.
Tell Alex I'll be right there.
Okay. All right,
I'll see you later.
Bye. Or not.
Okay. All right. Bye.
So you've been talking about me.
That's not necessarily
a good thing.
You haven't given me an answer.
Drinks. Tomorrow.
Unless, of course,
I change my mind.
When were you gonna tell me?
Now. Right now.
I was coming up to tell you now.
I'm supposed to
believe that? Yes!
I can't believe that
Arizona would say...
When did you know? How
far along are you, April?
I'm 12 weeks. Twelve weeks.
I was coming to tell you...
When did you know?
Did you know before the divorce?
Did you know before
we signed those papers?
April? Uh... I... Yes. I...
Yes, I did. I knew before.
Why? Why would you do that?
I have to... I have
to go. No, you don't.
I am being paged to the ER.
Go give it to Grey or
Hunt or literally anybody,
but you're not gonna walk
away from this right now.
I want to talk
about this, Jackson.
I know we need to talk about
it, but now is not a good time.
Don't you walk away. Okay?
I cannot talk about
this right now.
You should get a dog.
You seem like a dog guy.
I live in a trailer.
Yeah, that's something
we can talk about.
You don't like my trailer?
No, sure, I also like
grown-up houses.
Listen, I was thinking we
could have dinner tomorrow?
It's my birthday, and I
can't think of anyone else
I'd rather celebrate with, so...
Tomorrow's your birthday?
No, no. It's next week,
so you still have
time to buy my gift,
but I was thinking
we could, you know,
kick things off with dinner.
Do you like lobster?
Love lobster.
You know how to cook lobster?
Sure, you just boil
a pot of water and...
Yeah, see. You're
already losing me.
Crap. Incoming.
Tomorrow night, then. Lobster.
Birthday lobster,
which you are cooking.
That's become obvious.
We'll start with Kelsey's
double lung transplant first,
and then, assuming
the procedure goes well,
we'll go ahead and do
the liver and pancreas.
And it has to be all at once?
Her CF has compromised
her lungs, liver, and pancreas.
Replace any one
of those organs now,
and the others are
just gonna break down.
I know it seems overwhelming.
The surgery's
long and extensive,
but this is our best shot.
I don't want to do it.
Sweetie, please.
Kelsey, you know
how important this is.
I don't care. I
don't want to do it.
I hear you. It's a
bummer, though.
This donor is a perfect
match... One in a million.
You know, if we do this now,
you can make your spring formal.
Didn't you say what's
his name asked you?
Sam? Or Steve? Or...
Parker.
Well, I guess Parker
can find someone else.
I don't want to go if I can only
sit and watch and be pitied.
What, are you kidding
me? With these lungs?
They're gonna have to
drag you off that dance floor.
Really?
Really.
So, Dr. Karev, how
do we proceed?
What's the first step?
Is that the kid Alex
paged us about?
Yep. Triple organ transplant.
Lungs, liver,
pancreas... The trifecta.
It's gonna be a long night.
I better text the sitter.
So, not that it's any
of my business...
It's not. Mmm-hmm.
He asked me out.
It's not a big deal.
So you said no?
You said yes?
Kind of.
Maybe.
It's drinks.
Good. You're free. You awake?
Yeah, I'm good.
This is good.
Can we not?
You're ready.
I thought I wasn't
ready with DeLuca,
but now that it's out
in the open, it's good.
What's good?
Thorpe, the military doctor.
He asked Mer out. She said yes.
She said yes to buy time.
She'll blow him off
later. She'll cancel.
You didn't see this
guy. I don't have to.
I know Mer. I know Mer, too.
I am Mer. Mer's right here.
I said yes. I'm going.
This is good.
Blake, activate the MTP.
We're gonna need
blood, lots of it. On it.
All right, patient's 10 minutes
out, people. Let's move.
April, I'm sorry. I'm so, so
sorry. I thought that I was...
I really don't give a
crap what you thought.
Listen, I was with you before.
I lived through that
with you, with Jackson,
and I just was trying
to help somehow
so that maybe this
time it could be different.
Sorry, you were there?
You lived through that?
Um, no. No, Arizona.
That was me and
that was Jackson.
We lived that nightmare,
and I refuse to live it again.
And you know what?
It is different this time,
because this time I am
choosing to have faith
in a good outcome for this baby
until God himself
tells me otherwise,
and Jackson... Keps.
I will deal with this myself,
the way I want
to, when I want to.
I know. I'm sorry,
April. I thought...
Don't. Don't think about me.
Don't talk to me. Don't
even look at me, okay?
And I believe in this stuff, so
understand how much I mean it
when I tell you go to hell.
What, you didn't tell him?
Come on. Keps, what
were you thinking?
Shut up. Well, of course
he had a right to know.
Shut up. I'm just saying...
Hey, I'm just saying
he's justified. All right?
I'd be pissed, too.
I'd be really pissed.
Twenty-eight-year-old female,
fell over 100 feet
while rock climbing.
GCS 12, intubated,
multiple extremity fractures.
Vitals are... Tess. Tess.
Her name is Tess.
You want to watch him,
too. Mild signs of dehydration.
I'm okay. Just
help Tess, please.
All right, Tess.
We got you, okay?
You stay with us, all
right? Stay with us.
Volumes and total lung
capacity are perfect.
Replantation is technically
easier on the right,
so we will do that side first.
Thank you for coming back in.
You really think I'd miss out
on a triple organ transplant?
Hey.
Oh, sorry.
Um, can you make sure that
they have bypass on standby,
and, um, tell the blood
bank to have six units on hold.
Okay.
Why aren't you at
dinner? We postponed.
It was really
weird. It's not weird.
Dinner for two with
Webber? It's weird.
It's what you wanted.
Out in the open.
If I'm gonna have dinner with
your dad, you should be there, too.
I know. I'm sorry. I
just got pulled into this.
You know, it's actually
gonna be really cool.
Do you want to scrub in? Yeah.
I've got Wilson and
Cross scrubbing in now,
but I could switch things up.
No, no, no. See, don't do that.
We haven't even started yet.
If Cross is your
intern, let him do it.
I'll... I'll see you tomorrow.
No, no, no. I can
get you both in there.
You can take turns holding
retractors or something.
I mean, don't you
want to see this?
Why? Got to wake up.
Just got called into a
triple organ transplant.
Whoa. Long night.
Callie? CALLIE: Mmm-hmm?
I have a thing...
Tomorrow night.
Uh, more, please.
Drinks with a guy.
Oh. You're getting back
on the horse! That's...
Ooh, is it the... Is it
the Thorpe horse?
Please tell me it's
the Thorpe horse,
because that is a hot horse.
That is... That is Secretariat.
No one's getting on a horse.
It is gonna be weird.
Well, at first it'll
be a little weird,
but not bad weird,
and, Mer, it's good.
Just getting back
out there, it's...
It will be good.
Thanks.
Mmm-hmm.
If it's bad, it's still
good, you know?
I mean, it's like trying to
remember how to ice skate.
A couple minutes, you're
like, "Whoa, oh, crap.
"What... What am I doing?"
But then... Then you
remember how it works
and then it's like, "Oh,
yeah. Yeah, I can do this.
"Oh, I like this.
"Ooh, ooh, I'm good at this."
Ooh, ooh. It's skating
time, my friend.
Push and glide. Push and glide.
I wouldn't mind. You
know what I'm saying?
I'm more of a
roller girl, myself.
She's hypoxic on 100%.
Okay, she's gonna need
another tube on the right.
It's all right, Tess.
I'm right here.
Blake, can you get that? On it.
Sir, Michael, you
need to leave the room.
We need room to work.
Don't worry, baby. I'm
not gonna leave you, okay?
I love you. I love you.
I love you so much.
BP's dropping. What's happening?
Free fluid in the belly
and she's still hypotensive
after multiple units of blood
and plasma. We got to get her up.
Blake, when you're done there, we
need to get her ready for transport.
No, no, no. I can't leave her.
Your daughter suffered
severe injuries from the fall.
We're doing everything we can.
Is that her? Oh, my God. Tess.
Another set of
hands up in the OR?
I'll be right there.
I love you, Tess. I
love you so much.
Michael. We told you.
We told you not to take
her on that mountain.
Why are you always taking
her on those damn mountains?
Uh, Is there a place, uh, where I
can wait for her during surgery?
We all want to wait.
I'll take you all
somewhere more private.
All right. None of us knew
this was happening tonight,
and we're all tired,
so let's be smart.
We have three
organs from the donor
being transplanted
into the recipient.
There'll be long stretches
where not everyone is needed.
Take that time to
nap, eat, hydrate.
Don't come into my
OR at less than 100%.
Kelsey is prepped and ready.
All right. Start time, 23:58.
Ten blade.
So we'll be up next, Cross.
Where's he taking
you? Did he say?
Let it go.
You still haven't
canceled that yet?
What part of "let it go"
is confusing? Lap pads.
I guess there's still time.
This is gonna be
a very long night
if you two keep
hounding me about this.
Wilson, don't you have
anything to talk about?
Oh, um...
Her engagement ring is still in
the drawer in her bedside table.
Engagement ring?
Steph, when was the
last time you had sex?
All right. ALEX: If you're
gonna ditch the guy,
you better do it soon.
God, will you
shut it? You shut it.
Both of you shut it. Balfour.
And I have three children at
home, so don't think for a second
I don't know you two are
making faces right now.
Settle in.
So, is there no
directive in place?
Her fiance knows what she wants.
They spend their spare
time dangling from cliffs.
Of course they talked about it.
But he doesn't have
any rights, legally.
He's not her husband.
Just hoping to
call it an early day
if we don't have
to save this girl?
Guys. Malleable.
It'd be nice to know
what the patient wants.
Well, we don't, so maybe
we don't just give up yet.
I never said anything
about giving up.
Guys, come on.
- Right angle.
- There you go.
Another.
Where are we?
Should we scrub in?
We just started the first lung.
You're early. Way early.
I'd say she still has a
few more hours, right?
Plenty of time for you
to go take a shower,
get a change of clothes,
take a disco nap, groom.
Cancel plans that
aren't gonna happen.
Or stay.
I mean, this is a
triple organ transplant.
I wouldn't nap through this.
Exactly. I'm here. I
might as well jump in.
Go on. Scoot. You
take some "me" time.
We will page you when you're up.
You are being ridiculous.
Okay, would you stop? What?
She needs this. This is good.
I know that.
So stop being the
harbinger of doom about it.
Stop being all
"whoo-yay" about it.
What are we talking about?
You just stop.
Alex, I have to be
positive, because if I'm not,
you're gonna make
her change her mind.
No, you are. Trust me.
If she feels trapped,
she's gonna bolt.
Don't make a big
deal out of this.
It's a big enough deal
already. I know it is.
You got to make her feel
like she has an escape hatch
or she's gonna run for the hills.
- Yeah.
She will, if you don't
shut your dumb mouth.
You're dumb.
Go update Kelsey's parents.
We figure five
hours for the lungs,
seven hours for the
liver and the pancreas,
so there's time.
For?
Edwards, where do
we keep the razor kits?
Oh.
You know we have
a shower, right?
Yeah. I'm on a clock.
Oh.
This is an emergency leg shave.
It's not a big deal.
It's just drinks.
What are you gonna wear?
Uh, sports bra and
granny panties, apparently,
or whatever is in my
locker from yesterday.
Why am I even doing
this? This is just... It's stupid.
You know, I brought
a top with me today.
It's that one that you like.
It's the... It's kind of
see-through, and some heels.
Actually, they're your
heels that I stole from you.
Sorry.
You stole my shoes?
The black ones you said were
too slutty for a mother of three.
Plus, they pinch a little,
but they are so
worth it. So worth it.
I'll leave everything
out for you.
Thank you.
You didn't have to do that.
I know.
Hey, there you are.
Um, I got a message
from Kayla's mom
about a sleepover
with Sofia next week?
Sure. Yeah. It's fine with me.
Okay, great. Mmm-hmm.
Is there something else?
Uh...
No.
No. You sure?
I, um...
I did something bad, I think...
When I was trying so
hard to do something good.
I thought that I was...
I was being a good friend
and, I swear, I was.
I was... I was right.
What was right?
April's pregnant.
And she refused to tell Jackson.
So... Hmm.
So I did.
What?
And she's so angry
with me right now.
Well... I mean, I did
the right thing, right?
No, honey. No.
But he's the other parent.
If April's keeping
things from him...
Still. Still, no.
About the baby.
About the baby's future
and the baby's health.
Doesn't matter. Without him.
No, it still doesn't matter.
Yes, it does. No, Arizona!
No. Just no.
Okay, so...
What if it had been us?
I mean, what if
we'd been trying,
and then suddenly I was
pregnant right when we split up.
And then wouldn't you...
Wouldn't you want to know that?
Well, yes. Yes, of course.
But from you. Not
from someone else.
I'm sorry. You screwed
this one up big time.
Why aren't you down there?
I was on the procurement.
Don't you have an
all-access OR pass now?
Chief of cardio?
So smart.
But a guy who looks
like you can get anyone.
There's no way I'm
gonna land an attending.
A resident, maybe.
I mean, Wilson is like...
But she's with Karev.
Blake likes ladies.
Edwards maybe, she's hot
and she's tight with Shepherd,
so that wouldn't hurt either.
Do you think I have
a chance there?
No. No.
Well, I got to hand
it to you, dude.
You should go.
'Cause I'm about
to nut punch you.
Small intestine and
right colon excised.
Bring this to path, please.
She's gonna need a TPN
when she's more stable.
Dr. Kepner. Dr. Avery's
wondering how long you'll be.
Tell him as long as I need to.
Everything all right? I...
It's fine. Medium clips.
April. She said it was fine.
Pressure's dropping again.
Pupils are dilated.
Non-responsive. Damn it.
Crap. Global ischemia
from the hypotension?
Traumatic brain injury?
What difference does it make?
Her brain's been
deprived of oxygen.
There's no coming
back from this point.
Cabbage patch. OWEN: Damn it.
Blake, step in and finish
creating the colostomy.
You comfortable with doing one?
Uh, yeah. Sure.
Then I'd like you to close up
the fascia with running PDS.
Me? Okay. Why are you leaving?
'Cause there's
nothing left to do.
Patient is too far gone.
But it's not every day you
get to practice on living flesh,
so perfect your
colostomy technique.
I'll call Shepherd
for a neuro-eval.
Yeah, but she's not
getting off that vent.
So wrong. It's not fair.
I'll let you know when
Shepherd's done,
then we can go talk
to Tess' family. Okay.
Robbins?
You told Robbins
and you didn't tell me?
I don't... I don't have time
for this right now, okay?
You've taken more than
enough time, don't you think?
The time was before I signed
the friggin' divorce papers.
What's going on there?
Jackson, I'm not doing this.
Not here. Not now.
Well, excuse me.
Is there a more convenient time
for me to catch you lying to me?
Jackson! You don't
think a pregnancy
would have factored
into my decision
to move forward
with the divorce?
I knew it would,
but you didn't want
to stay with me.
You think I want you
to stay for my baby...
Our baby.
And have you hating
me for the rest of my life?
Well, you got a pretty good
jump on that, didn't you?
Wow, that... Yeah. That
didn't take any time at all.
All right. That's enough.
No, you know what?
It's fine. Screw this.
You want to play
the martyr here?
You want to pretend
you're doing this alone?
Go for it.
Knock yourself out.
It's your deal, April. You win.
I'm out. I'm done.
I said enough.
What are you doing here?
I told you I would page you.
There's still a ton of time
before you need to be here.
I'm here. Let me help.
Fine. Jump in. No. No.
Not fine. No jumping.
Maggie, you got to let it go.
I can't let it go.
You told me your train
had stopped running,
and tonight, one is
coming into the station,
and that is a big deal.
I can't pretend like it's not.
Wilson. Yes.
Go to the attendings
lounge, get my phone,
go into my contacts,
find William Thorpe,
please text him and let him know
that tonight's plans
have been canceled.
Meredith, no! Wait, Meredith...
My passcode is 1-0-0-8.
Now it's really
over. So let it go.
Pickups.
See what you did?
This is your fault.
Um, please, I just...
I... I just need a minute, okay?
Why didn't you tell me?
Because, um, I didn't
want to tell anyone...
Especially you. I
didn't want you to...
I feel like I'm just... I'm
screwing everything up,
and all I'm trying to do is
protect this baby and it's...
It's all screwed up.
Every... Everything
is all screwed up.
April, April.
April, you're having a baby.
Yeah. It's not screwed up.
It's...
It's a miracle.
Yes, it is.
Yes.
Thank you.
Bailey?
Can I ask you something?
You just did.
Well, um, I...
I did something, and I don't...
Yeah, I heard.
Oh. Well, great.
Yeah, you shared
confidential medical information
without permission,
breaking multiple state
and federal privacy laws.
You did it to a fellow doctor,
under this roof, in my hospital.
Speaking as your boss,
that's a firing offense.
And speaking to me as my friend?
I mean, I can see
where you thought
you were doing what was right.
Yes! Yes, I was.
That doesn't make it right.
Yeah, I'm fresh out of
words of wisdom for you.
Okay.
I got all day.
I told you it's not
your business.
Well, it is when you brawl
on the OR floor of my hospital.
I don't need your
help! All right?
Stop telling yourself that
I need your help. I don't.
You're not my father.
I know I'm not.
But who is?
I don't see him
around here, do you?
That the man you want to be?
You're having a child.
Maybe it's not the
way you wanted.
Maybe it's not when.
All right, so you
found out late.
I found out decades late.
What's important
is now you know.
It's happening...
And you need to step up.
That's what matters.
Unfortunately, in surgery,
we discovered your daughter's
injuries were more catastrophic
than we realized
and her brain function
has virtually ceased.
Your daughter has
virtually no brain activity.
I am so sorry.
Oh, my God. But I saw her.
Her heart is pumping.
She's still breathing.
She's alive.
The ventilator is
breathing for her.
She can't breathe on her own or
feed herself or use the bathroom.
She's using catheters
and ostomies
and will likely need
those indefinitely.
From this point on,
she will require round-the-clock
professional care,
probably for the
rest of her life.
Or until she gets better.
I'm sorry?
She'll need the care
until she gets better,
until she wakes up and
she can leave the hospital.
Do we know when that might be?
When Tess could leave here?
Eventually, she would be moved
to a long-term acute care facility
where she would live
for the rest of her...
Well, we can... We can
get you some brochures
if that's what you decide.
Or if you decide
to withdraw care.
Oh, Tess.
I understand
that this is difficult,
and you should take
some time to talk this over.
That won't be necessary. We
understand the circumstances.
We want you to do
everything that you can
to save our daughter.
No! This is not what she'd want.
She could wake up.
I mean, people wake up
from comas all the time.
I'm sorry, but in Tess'
case, that's highly unlikely.
She told me what she
wants. More than once.
Please, she would
not want to live like this.
What is wrong with you?
This isn't your decision
to make, Michael.
If this had happened two
months from now, it would be.
We would've been married.
Will you get him out of here?
Lines are out.
Almost done?
Anastomoses look
terrific on both sides.
No bleeding or leaks.
Sats look great.
Yeah, nice work.
Well, uh, that does it for me,
unless you need
me to stay and help...
In any way. I'll close.
You can go.
Scalpel.
So, what's wrong
with the guy? Huh?
Thorpe. What's his deal?
Nothing. He's fine.
Callie said he was a
jerk that night at Bauer.
That's not true.
Said he almost
killed the surgery.
Scissors.
Ten blade.
He was just trying
to protect his patient.
Oh. So he was throwing
a tantrum like a toddler.
Shut up.
He's nice... And he's funny.
Mmm, so he's just butt-ugly.
Yes. He is butt-ugly.
Yeah, well.
It's hard first time out
after somebody important.
First girl after Izzie
left? It was pretty messy.
You feel like you
belong to somebody else,
like you're cheating, you know?
I mean, you're not, but
man, sure feels that way.
I never had a wife die, but...
I've had a few "first
time afters," Mer.
There's always
something after...
Eventually.
We lose people and
then we find new ones.
It's how it works.
- I guess.
- Oh, I know.
Look, if you're not
into him, who cares?
But if you are, it's okay.
Okay?
Okay.
Plus, it's gonna be
weird no matter what,
so you might as
well get it over with.
Suction.
Yeah, she should be awake soon.
Looks like she's gonna
make that big dance.
No more coughing and wheezing?
Well, the new organs
don't carry the CF gene.
Once she's off the vent,
chances are good you'll
never see her on one again.
Thank you.
She's gonna stay
on that ventilator...
Forever?
Unless something changes, yes.
Her parents will hate me forever
for taking her up that mountain.
She'll hate me for
bringing her back down.
This place looks nice.
Lovely views.
And who knows?
She could be up and walking
again this time next year.
You never know.
Don't give up hope, right?
God bless you, Dr. Riggs.
"Don't give up hope," huh?
Well, that's all they
have now, right?
You changed your tune.
You wanted to give up all day.
No, I did not. I wanted to
do what the patient wanted.
Owen, you got to let
this go. Oh, what's that?
If you're still feeling
guilty after all this time,
that's your deal.
Stop taking it out on me.
Guilty? What have I
got to feel guilty about?
Oh, you think it's all
my fault, but I never quit.
You did.
You let Megan go.
You stopped looking.
I didn't. I stayed
behind. I stayed. I looked.
I searched, and I prayed.
Because you got her killed!
We don't know
that. You decided it.
You made a decision
that she was dead.
You came back
here, you started over,
and you forgot about her.
You shut your mouth. That's
why you hate that I'm here,
'cause I remind you of what
you did, that you gave up on her.
I swear to God...
People here don't even
know you had a sister.
That's sick, mate.
You need to hate someone?
Look in a mirror.
You had a tough day.
You heard, too?
I think everybody's
heard by now.
Right.
I don't know what to do.
I want to make it right.
I mean, I have to
make it right somehow,
but I don't know what to do.
I don't... I don't
know how to fix it.
You did something indefensible.
Right.
So maybe, um...
Maybe I go to her
again and apologize.
The only thing that
you can do right now
is accept what
you did was wrong.
And the only thing
you can do to fix it is...
To wait.
Just give it time
and maybe April
will forgive you.
Maybe she won't...
But you...
That is not up to you.
Hey. DELUCA: Hey.
How's the, uh... How's
the transplant going?
Huge success. Come
on. I'll tell you all about it.
Actually, um, I think I'm
gonna stay here tonight.
I got early rounds in the morning
and kind of want to just study.
Come over. I'll help you
study. I don't want help.
Okay.
I don't want special treatment,
and I don't want to
miss out on things,
but that's already happening.
And I don't want to make
awkward small talk with Dr. Webber.
You are the one who
wanted us to go public.
I know.
I'm just gonna study, all right?
Okay.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Hey.
Hey. I'm glad you
called me back.
Well, I shouldn't have.
I'm way too tired for drinks.
I just got out of a
17-hour surgery.
I probably shouldn't even drive home
until I've crashed here for a while, so...
So how about I take you home?
Um, you're skipping a bunch
of steps, don't you think?
Yeah, how about I
give you a ride home
so that you can
crash in your own bed?
I don't mind.
Look, I know what 17
hours straight feels like.
I'm not worried
about the drinks.
I'll take you out
some other time.
Hey! Happy birthday!
Owen! Come on.
I'm holding a box of
creepy, squirming lobsters.
You gonna let me in?
Just a sec.
Hey.
Am I early?
Uh, no, no, no. We're all good.
I was just gonna... Uh, come in.
Come on.
Looks like you already
started the party.
No, no. I might've
screwed up a little.
I forgot that we were...
I'll just put these in
the fridge, I guess.
Yes, I... I... I can
put some water on.
It'll just take a
minute to boil.
I had a long day,
and Riggs is...
Riggs is what?
Nothing, it's just...
Don't listen to him.
Um...
Let's try this another time.
No, no, no. No.
No, let's do it. No,
let's not, Owen.
Amelia. I'm just...
I'm gonna go.
It's fine. I'm fine.
Amelia, don't go. I'm sorry.
I just had a couple of beers.
Who is it?
It's me.
Hey, I just wanted to apologize.
I reacted badly today, and...
We're having a baby...
Who does not deserve
to have us arguing over it.
That's what I was
trying to avoid.
I get that.
Sort of. I mean, I'm...
I'm trying to get that.
We can figure this out.
All right?
Yeah.
Look, I just... I
honestly... I didn't...
I waited to tell you
because last time...
Last time tore us apart.
Literally.
Neither one of us
could help the other
and everyone got hurt,
and I just didn't want that.
For you or me.
I just... I wanted
to wait until I knew
that everything was okay,
and I'm... I am...
I am really sorry.
Okay? I'm sorry.
You wanted to wait
until it was too late?
Right? Until you were too far
along to do anything about it.
I'm sorry. Do what, exactly?
I don't know... Not put
us through this again,
or a baby, for that matter.
I mean, I'd have to
hold him while he dies.
Maybe have some options.
Um, that is not an option
for me and you know that.
What about me?
Hmm?
What about my option...
You don't count here.
I don't... I'm the father.
Yes, you are. Yes.
You're the father
when there's a baby.
But right now, you
have no choice in this.
It's my body, my baby.
April. You are not my husband.
You have no rights here.
It hurts to tear
that bandage off.
We don't want to see
what's underneath.
But maybe it's not the fear
of the pain that holds us back.
I was worried about the
duodenal segment getting ischemic.
Mmm. Yeah, what'd you do?
Mmm, I placed stents at the
SMA and the celiac anastomoses,
just to be on the safe side.
Smart.
Ketchup?
More ketchup? I love my ketchup.
I did a portal
reconstruction once...
Good guy, had no idea
he drank a fifth a day
until I tried to
cut into his liver.
You know, it's
shoe leather. Ugh.
That makes it so hard.
Yeah.
Napkin.
I almost stopped
drinking right then.
Almost.
Yeah.
I don't want to see my liver.
I don't want to see it, either.
Maybe we're really afraid
to see if the wound
underneath is still open...
I should go up.
Yeah.
Yeah, okay.
You know what I did
do that was funny?
I used an interposition
aortic conduit
to supply the pancreatic graft.
How did... How did you do that?
Or if it might
actually be healing.