What can I tell you?
I'm short-staffed, okay?
I can't go on a transport.
Conni, can you
clear this TIA in 6?
She's waiting for her daughter.
That's what Chairs are for.
And give a gram of
Unasyn to the dog bite in 4.
Mark, they need you at the MICN.
Why don't you try Mercy Air?
Maybe they can
pick him up. Mark.
What? Paramedics have
a guy with chest pain.
Won't get in the ambulance.
Well, explain the risks and
make sure he signs out AMA.
What are his vitals?
He's refusing to sign the form.
Mark, you gave
my patient cefoxitin?
Who? Bovard. Uh, appy.
Hold on. Uh, yeah. Listen,
uh, he needed antibiotics.
Yeah. Cefotetan's a better
drug. Peter, I'm a little busy.
I know. That's not my problem.
You should have called me.
Did you get through? No
answer at his hotel room.
I stat-paged him twice.
Well, try his cell phone.
Any response to Lasix?
Mark, the AMA.
Well, get him on the radio
and try and convince him.
What about a nitro drip?
I need you to buff up a, uh,
recurrent bowel obstruction
I have on the way.
What are we? Jiffy Lube?
I need a sugar-tong splint
in 3. Kovac still MIA? Uh-huh.
Kovac missed his shift?
I'm sure he's on his way.
Where's, uh, Kerry?
It's her day off.
She's at a chrysanthemum show.
Great, the one day I need her
she's playing Martha Stewart.
Hold on. Just a sec. I'm sorry.
'Cause I've got a
helicopter transport.
We're gonna have
to call in backup.
Uh, why don't you wait
till 8:30? He's never late.
Peter, what's this?
Hot appy. O.R.'s ready.
Great. I'll take him. Dr. Greene
needs your help here.
Trauma coming in?
Nah, you're gonna
cover the whole ER.
What? Yep. This'll
get you started.
Diarrhea, ear pain and
weak and dizzy all over.
Whoa, wait a minute.
"Weak and dizzy"
wasn't a part of our
per-diem agreement.
Sure it is. Per diem
means "per my discretion."
Okay. I'm on my way.
I haven't done primary
care since med school.
Don't worry, Peter.
You just gotta cover
until Kovac gets here.
When's that?
I hope soon. Andrazak in
4, check his lytes in an hour.
Oh, and look at a post-reduction
shoulder film on Quintano.
Uh, how long's your
flight? I don't know.
Where you going?
Grass Creek, Indiana.
The wedding coordinator's
coming at noon.
I know.
Mark, we canceled
her once already.
Well, go ahead and talk
to her. You can handle it.
I don't wanna handle
it. I want you to share
in what kinds of
invitations, menus, flowers...
I know. I'm stuck. I'm sorry.
Well, at least try
to get back on time.
I'll call you.
Have a safe flight! What?
Nothing!
Lifeguard Five-Seven-David.
Landing-pad zone is clear. Over.
All right, I've got the earache.
That's a Pedes case.
Yeah. Well, Romano has
me seeing everything today.
And that's a complete
waste of your brilliance.
I've apologized. If
you can't accept it,
let's at least call a truce
so we can work together.
You are amazing.
First, you dump me.
Then you expect me...
Whoa, whoa. I did not dump
you. Then what do you call it?
You were going to
move to Philadelphia
without saying a word to me.
Yeah, but I didn't, did I?
I stayed here and took
this damn per diem job.
And I'm supposed to
believe you did that for me?
That's what I thought.
Hi. I'm Dr. Benton.
So, uh, Jason...
How long has he been sick?
It started last week
with an earache.
And then he had a fever.
Okay. Now he's coughing.
Well, let's take a look here.
You don't think
he's got pneumonia?
One thing at a time.
Get away from me!
Jason. Be nice. The
doctor wants to help you.
- Ow! Hey, whoa.
- I said, be nice.
All right, Jason. Look,
this isn't gonna hurt, okay?
Just, uh...
Just be still. Here we
go. No! I wanna go home!
Okay. It's okay. It's
not gonna hurt. Jason.
That's right, Jason.
Go to Mommy.
Uh-huh.
Why don't you
put him on your lap
and give him a nice big hug?
And if Jason's real still,
I'm going to give him a sticker.
Sats? MAN: Up to 98.
His ejection fraction's
less than 10%.
Mr. Coggins?
Call me Tom. I'm Mark Greene.
We're gonna lie you down
to load you on the chopper.
My first helicopter ride,
I'm gonna miss the scenery.
What's his BP? 90/70.
It's always that low. There's
not much heart muscle.
Can you keep trying
Janet? Sure, Tom.
That's my fiancée.
She's flying in
from Montreal today.
Let me know if you feel dizzy
or have any shortness of breath.
I'm okay as long as I lie still.
Bright side is, I get bumped
up on the transplant list, right?
Gordon, how are we for
oxygen? Four E cylinders, all full.
Ready? Let's go.
One, two, three.
Get a full trauma panel.
Type and cross for eight.
Get the bypass team
on standby. Move.
Oh, somebody stabbed him?
No. He tripped near
a pencil sharpener.
Our manager wanted to pull
it out. But I wouldn't let him.
Decreased breath sounds.
Set me up with a chest tube.
I'll do it. No, I'll do it.
Excuse me. This is
a teaching hospital.
Exactly. Go find another
patient to learn on.
Pulse ox down to 91.
Okay. Let's get
one percent with epi.
Peter, heard you had a good
one. Oh, and indeed you do.
He needs a CT. Let
me get a 10 blade.
Oh, no, don't bother.
I'll, uh, throw the tube in
and take him
right up to the O.R.
Don't worry, you are
in excellent hands.
It's okay. I've got this. No,
no, this is a surgical case.
You are an ER doc today.
Remember? There's a guy puking
out in the hall. See
what you can do.
Excuse me.
I need a 32 French tube,
some 0 silk and Xeroforms...
Sir, are you okay?
Ah, whoa, whoa!
What does it look like? Can
we get some Compazine here?
Sir, you're gonna have
to aim for the basin.
I heard it. But I
didn't believe it.
Carter, get me some gloves.
Dr. Peter Benton, ER Attending.
It's got kind of
a nice ring to it.
You want this? Oh, no. No, no.
Looks like you're
doing just fine.
Trent? Yeah.
I'm Dr. Carter. What
happened to your hand?
Aw, I have this
stupid art class.
We were carving some duck decoy.
Huh. The most exciting
thing that we ever did,
I think, was macramé.
How many stitches do you
think? How many do you want?
Enough to get
me out of art class.
Well, ten oughta do it.
Dr. Carter, can you
step out for a second?
Yeah, after I suture this.
No. It's important.
I'll be right back.
Don't pick your nose.
What? The boy's grandmother,
she wants to talk with you.
Just bring her in. She
asked to see you alone.
Hello. I'm Dr. Carter.
Oh, I'm sorry. I came
as soon as I could.
Is Trent all right?
Oh, just a few stitches.
He'll be good as new. Ah. Um...
Doctor, there's something
you need to know.
Trent's mother died of
AIDS when he was 2.
He tested HIV-positive.
You need to be careful.
He didn't say anything.
He doesn't know. We
never told him. What?
We just wanted him to
be normal like other kids.
Well, what about
the medications?
He thinks he has a
vitamin deficiency.
And your doctor
plays along with that?
Well, he understands.
Trent needs to know.
Yes. When he's older. When
he can better understand.
Your grandson could be
sexually active right now.
He's not. I've asked him.
Are you sure that he's
telling you the truth?
Doctor, I know my
grandson. You don't.
Mrs. Larson, I
have a legal right
to tell Trent that
he's HIV-positive.
You have no right to
interfere in our lives.
HIV is a sexually
transmitted disease.
And if he's having
unprotected sex,
he could be putting
others at risk.
Well, I think we better leave.
Well, he can't leave.
Let me by. Chris?
Let me by. Could you please
escort Mrs. Larson
to Chairs. Let me by.
This way, ma'am. Don't touch me.
Don't do this.
Pulse ox 94 on two liters.
What's your hurry?
Huh?
You keep checking your
watch every 10 seconds.
I'm just charting.
I don't think so.
You're late for something.
I'm supposed to meet my fiancée.
You got a lunch date?
Well, we're meeting
the wedding planner.
You're taking the plunge.
It's a great feeling.
Yeah.
What's your
fiancée's name again?
Janet.
I'm calling the ER.
See if they can get ahold of
her and she can meet us there.
That'd be great. RANDI: ER.
Hi, Randi? Yeah.
It's Mark Greene up in the
helicopter. Who's around?
Dr. Corday's right
here. It's Dr. Greene.
I don't care, I need to
speak to him right away.
Mark, is everything
all right? Dr. Dietrich?
This is Dr. Carter
at County General.
I just repaired a laceration
on your patient, Trent Larson.
I'll try and get ahold
of her. No, yeah,
he's a great kid, uh...
Listen, if I was to
get a needle-stick,
is there anything I should know?
Did you get in
touch with that hotel?
There's still no
answer in his room.
Could you call the
manager's office
and see if they could
send somebody up there?
Detective?
Oh. You keep coming by,
I'm gonna have to get you
a badge and a gun.
So, uh, is there anything...?
Oh, Dr. Kovac, now, you know
the minute there's anything
new, I'm gonna call you.
We take photos for
the medical record.
I thought it might help.
His... His morgue photo's
already on the police bulletin.
Maybe you could go back to
where it happened, show this around?
We've done our interviews, doc.
No one knows him.
What about fingerprints?
Have a seat.
Have a seat, doc.
Look... I understand
how you feel, okay?
But the fact is,
you're probably better
off if no one IDs this guy.
No family member's gonna
come crawling out of the woodwork
with some wrongful death suit.
I don't care.
I just need to know who he was.
Take my advice, doc.
You were defending yourself.
Dedicate yourself
to believing that.
All right. Keep
that clean and dry.
All right. Cool.
Hey, Dr. Carter, is my
grandmother here yet?
Um... yeah.
But first we need to talk.
Why? It's just a cut.
Uh, yeah, actually,
I need to ask you something.
All right.
It's about your mother.
Uh, how much do you
remember about her?
Nothing.
You sure?
Yeah. She's... She's
dead. She was a loser.
A heroin addict.
She died of AIDS.
And she had the virus when
she was pregnant with you.
And the virus can pass
from the mother
to the baby.
Wait a second. So...
I have AIDS? No. You have HIV.
And you're healthy
because you've been
taking medication.
Oh, no, no. See, I...
I just take a bunch
of vitamins. That's it.
No. You've been
taking medication
to combat the virus.
No. No, they're
just vitamins, man.
No. Your grandmother
told me, and I confirmed it
with your doctor.
Why wouldn't she tell me?
I think she wanted
to protect you.
And, um...
But you need to know.
So my whole life
everybody's lied to me.
I'm not lying to you.
How much longer do you think?
Gordon, what's our ETA?
Well, there's the
Kankakee River.
About 20 minutes.
You all right?
It's all right. Just
a little chest pain.
I'll be okay.
Nitro spray.
Open your mouth,
under your tongue.
On a scale of one to
10, how bad is the pain?
Big-time ST elevation
on the monitor.
Find the tenecteplase.
I'll do the heparin.
Uh, wh-what's going on?
You're having a heart attack.
But we're giving you
clot-busting medicine.
Pulse ox down to 82.
Do you wanna intubate?
Not if I don't have to.
Let's get him on
a mask. 15 liters.
Maybe we should land.
No. Dr. Greene...
Dr. Greene...
you'll get me there, right?
Yeah. I'll get you there.
Do you have a girlfriend?
Because if you've
slept with anybody,
they'll have to be tested.
It's important, Trent.
You have to use condoms.
Yeah.
Can I go now?
Yep, your grandmother's waiting.
So a case manager's
gonna phone you tomorrow,
sort of see how you're doing.
And you've got an appointment
with the teen HIV center.
And you can always
reach me here.
The ER always knows
where to find me.
All right. All right?
Trent?
Thank you, doctor.
Hog Butcher for the World,
Tool Maker, Stacker of Wheat,
Player with Railroads...
City of the Big Shoulders.
You know Sandburg's poetry.
Just that one.
After teaching English for
10 years, I know them all.
Looks like you're
feeling better.
ST segments are back down.
Hello?
Yeah, we're about
five minutes out.
Well, that's good. Hold
on. Janet's on her way in.
Thank you. We're gonna
need a gurney and...
What the hell's that?
The main rotor.
I got metal fragments
in the gearbox.
What's wrong? CORDAY: Mark.
Mark, are you there? Mark?
Mayday, mayday.
This is Lifeguard
Nine-Seven-Kilo
on emergency descent.
Cinch him in tight.
I'm gonna shut down
for auto rotation. Mark?
No, no. We're gonna make it.
Mark? Can you hear me?
What's going on? I don't know.
There were horns, shouting.
Now there's nothing. Mark!
VFR position.
Industrial area.
A scrap yard near
95th and Commercial.
Now, when I get
enough rotor speed,
I'm gonna pull on the pitch,
that should cushion our landing.
We're falling.
Hang in there, Tom.
Here we go.
Okay. Everybody out.
Get out now!
Take the monitor. Got
it. Pumps are down.
Let's go. Move away. Airway kit.
Gordon, you get the feet?
- All set.
Let's go together. All
right. We gotta move.
How far? Just keep going.
I'll tell you when. Argh!
You all right? Got it.
Yeah, yeah. Let's go. Come on!
Tom, how are you doing?
Sats are down to 78.
All right. I gotta tube him.
All right. This is far enough.
This will shield us if
the fuel tank blows.
Give me four of Versed,
100 of sux.
All right. Tom...
We gotta stick a tube down
your throat, help you breathe.
Do they know where we
are? Yeah, I called it in.
They'll find us.
I'm giving some medicine
to relax you, Tom.
Got it. Do they know anything?
ATC's got a mayday
call with location.
EMS and Fire are rolling.
Any injuries? They didn't say.
Well, call them back, damn it.
- What's going on?
Mark's chopper went down. What?
They crashed? It was
an emergency landing.
We don't know that.
We don't know anything.
Call Dispatch. They
don't know anything more.
I don't care! BENTON:
Whoa, whoa, hey, hey.
Look, I can't have
this place fall apart.
Get on and stay on with
CDO and keep us posted.
Randi, how are we doing?
We've got 19 patients waiting.
All right, Malucci,
grab some charts.
Abby, draw labs, start some
IVs for anyone who needs one.
Get Carter to order
x-rays from triage.
All right, let's
move, people. Now.
- Where the hell is Kovac?
- We're still trying.
Very nice. Appreciate it.
You play here a lot?
Yeah. I work here
and the Navy pier.
What about at night?
Yeah, sometimes for
the after-dinner crowd.
Have you...
ever seen this man?
No. I would remember
a guy like that.
You don't seem like a cop.
Um, I'm a doctor.
Try the tour-boat ticket
guy. He's here all the time.
I did. Thanks.
Sorry I can't help you.
Good breath sounds.
Keep him on high-flow oxygen.
Fifteen more minutes
and the tank's dry.
Where's EMS? Sound close.
Yeah, but they can't see us.
They'll have to call
in a police chopper.
We can't wait. You
have any flares?
I have a Verry
pistol in the chopper.
But I can barely
walk. I'll get it.
Left side, behind
the pilot seat.
Luka, it's Abby.
Um, could you call me
when you get this message?
'Cause I've been trying to,
uh, reach you everywhere.
I'm getting a little worried.
Abby? Okay, c-call me.
Miss Skye here complains
of abdominal pain.
Well, it's not
really my abdomen.
I can't believe I'm
actually embarrassed.
Well, we see everything here.
Okay.
I got a roll of
money stuck up my...
birth canal.
Look, could you hurry up?
I got a cab waiting with
the meter running. Okay?
Dr. Benton, we
need you right now.
Six-month baby boy,
respiratory distress.
Abby? Um, just
hold on one second.
Temp's 103. Coarse
crackles bilaterally.
Pulse ox is only 75. All
right. Let's take a look.
Sounds like pneumonia.
Let's get a pediatric intubation
tray. Move now, people.
We got a line. I'll draw
a CBC and blood culture.
Damn. I don't even do pediatric
intubations. Where's Cleo?
She took a kid to PICU.
Get her down here now.
What size tube?
We use two and
a half in Delivery.
No. I think I need
something bigger. Uh...
Uh, three, three and a half?
I don't know.
Got the labs.
Move.
Uh, he's clamped down.
I can't get the blade in.
Paralyze him. BENTON:
What's the dose?
You need his weight.
He's vomiting. Suction.
- Pulse ox is dropping.
- What do we have?
Uh, difficult intubation,
I-I can't dose him
without a weight.
That's what the
Broselow tape is for.
Okay. We're in the red zone.
2.6 of Etomidate, 18 of sux.
Premedicate with .17
of atropine, 14 of lido.
Bag him. Keep
some cricoid pressure.
I couldn't see the cords.
That's because you had
the wrong blade and tube.
Thanks for coming.
Drugs are on board. He's loose.
- Okay. Here we go.
- Dr. Benton?
Hold on. Hold on. FINCH: Okay...
I'm in. Bag him.
Dr. Benton, do you wanna
close to paramedic traffic?
I've got this. Hang
400 of ceftriaxone.
Settings will be
volume at 90 cc's...
No monitor beds, and we're
boarding five ICU patients.
All right. Uh, close
to paramedics.
You sure you wanna do that?
We've been getting a
lot of bad press lately.
What would you do,
Carter? I don't know.
Dr. Benton, South Side
Urgent wants to send a patient.
We're closed to transfers.
It's just a backache. Their
x-ray machine's down.
Fine! Fine! Fine! Send
him! So? Do we close?
And don't ask me. They don't
pay me enough to run this place.
Paramedics found them on
the South Side. No casualties.
Well?
Well? Um...
Thank you.
Trent? Hey.
Uh, they told us to wait
because you were busy.
Is she a friend of yours?
Uh, she's my girlfriend.
Your girlfriend? Thought
you said you didn't have one.
I brought her here.
Think that was easy?
You gotta be honest with me.
Is she the only one?
Yes. The only one.
I've kissed other girls
though. Is...? Is that a problem?
No sex with anyone else? No. No.
And you didn't use condoms?
I love her, man.
All right. Okay.
Let's run some tests.
We'll see where we are.
You want to ride up front?
No. I'm staying with Tom.
Nearest facility's Oakdale,
seven-minute ETA.
No. We're going to
County. That's 20 minutes.
Dispatch doesn't want us
to leave our attachment area.
All right. I'll take
responsibility.
Easy now.
Roy, the doctor
says we go to County.
Can't. County's closed. What?
They just closed. ER saturation.
I'm an Attending there.
They'll take us. Let's go.
Patch me through
to the ambulance?
Dr. Corday, surgical
consult in Exam 4.
I'll be there. Just
give me the number.
Excuse me. I'm
looking for Dr. Corday.
Are you Janet?
Yeah. Elizabeth Corday.
We expect them very
soon. How's Tom doing?
Quite well. Apparently, no
one was hurt in the landing.
What landing?
Just something minor
with the helicopter.
So how long have
you two been engaged?
Almost three years. So
he's not in the helicopter?
No. In an ambulance. Um,
my goodness, three years.
That seems like a long time.
Right after he gave me
the ring, he got the flu.
We thought it was no big deal.
But the virus went to his heart.
We spend a lot of
time in hospitals.
Have you seen the
hernia yet? In a minute.
No, no, no, no, no. Now.
EKG on a new chest-pain
patient. All right, let me see.
I got a guy on a
backboard for two hours.
When are you gonna
clear his neck? When I can.
Want me to call Weaver in? No.
Are you ever gonna sew me up?
We're busy. Just
wait right there.
What's this? A second
board. We're backed up.
Four patients just left
without being seen.
Oh, I know the
solution. We see them,
send off labs and have
them wait in Chairs.
Come on. Are you crazy? We
need monitoring, IVs, medication.
The problem is you doctors
order too many damn tests.
You should be
reviewing their charts,
keeping things moving.
Stroke patient needs
a monitored bed.
We don't have them. Tell
him... We'll put him in the hall.
Peter.
None of my nurses
have even had lunch.
Ambulance dropped off
a stab wound to the belly.
All right, all right,
all right, all right.
That's it. That's it.
Get me the phone.
Heart rate is 40
after two of atropine.
Amp of epi. He
needs a pacemaker.
We should be in a hospital
right now. Any hospital.
Rescue 82. BP
is down to 60 palp.
Open up the
dopamine. It's for you.
Hello. Okay, we're almost there.
No. He can't talk right now.
He's out. I can't feel
a pulse. I gotta go.
Starting chest compressions.
We could have been at
Oakdale 10 minutes ago.
I'm going on record
that you overrode policy.
There's gonna be an
incident report on this.
Shut up.
Get back to work.
Hang in there, Tom.
You're gonna make it.
Janet's there.
She's waiting for you.
How long's he been
down? He never arrested.
Needs help maintaining a
pulse. You look exhausted.
He wouldn't let us
relieve him. I'll take over.
We're coming through
here! What's wrong?
This is Janet Wei, his fiancée.
Tom had a heart attack. We
need to put in a pacemaker.
You can take his hand.
Hey, Tom, it's me. I'm here.
Keep talking to him.
It's Janet. He's
squeezing my hand.
- What's his BP?
- Uh, 70 systolic
on 20 mics of dopamine.
What about an intra-aortic
balloon? Not a bad idea.
We need the room.
Everything's backed up.
We're closed to paramedics.
Get that patient out!
- Wait! The rapid infuser!
- Oh, my God!
Clamp the central line!
- Turn it off!
I'm trying! GREENE:
Get Housekeeping!
We need another
two units of blood.
What the hell's going on?
I just got back from transport.
I left Benton in charge. Benton?
Mortimer goes to X-ray. Put
the rectal bleed in Exam 3.
I got a patient says her
tongue is too smooth.
Tell her to get a life.
Smooth tongue could be a
sign of anemia, iron deficiency.
I can't leave for a day
without this place going to hell.
I've never seen it this
busy. It's like this every day.
I just heard from the Trib. Tell
me we're not closed to trauma.
We're not. As of
now, we're open.
We can't see
another critical patient.
Abby, get me the
nursing supervisor.
I want every remotely stable
patient moved out of the ICU.
I was under the impression
you could manage the ER.
Well, I was the only Attending.
Kovac never showed up.
He didn't show?! He
might have switched a shift.
In 20 years, I have never
been late for surgery.
I guess you work on
a different standard.
Peter, based on your
performance today,
maybe you're not the
guy for the per diem job.
Dr. Carter? CARTER: Yeah?
Lab results on Emma Miller.
Oh, man. That's tough.
Fifteen years old.
Pacer is capturing well.
Setting the rate at 80.
- I got your transducer here.
- How are you doing?
Passing a 40-cc balloon.
I need to check
position with fluoro.
Janet, why don't you
come talk to me outside?
Ahem. This pump should
bring his blood pressure up.
Will he live long enough
to get the heart transplant?
I don't know.
I wanna marry him.
I don't know if
he's gonna be able
to leave the hospital.
Can we do it here?
We could try and arrange it.
I think if we got married
it might help.
What if they made a mistake?
I wouldn't tell you
if I wasn't certain.
But I don't feel sick.
You should do the test again.
Emma, if you start taking
medication right now,
you could stay healthy.
No. I know what
happens. Everybody dies.
That's not true. That's not...
Look at Trent. He's had HIV
his whole life. Look at him.
I wish we'd never had sex.
Emma, I didn't know. I swear.
Dr. Carter, tell her. Please.
This is a lot.
This is a lot for you to handle.
And you're both
gonna need some help.
So before you go, I would like
you both
to talk to a counselor.
Hold on, you two. Hold on.
I'll leave you two
alone for a little while.
But before you do anything,
talk it over.
Definitely. Thanks.
Hey. Hey. Come on...
Why is Mr. Chang still here?
He's waiting for a second CBC.
Okay. Do another HemoCue.
If it's over 11, send him home.
Torelli's cardiac enzymes.
Great. All right.
She's outta here.
Clears up another monitored bed.
You know, Romano
was out of line.
Heh-heh! When isn't he?
It's wrong to throw
you into the deep end
and expect you to swim.
Nobody masters ER
management on their first day.
What's this? Back
pain. Collapsed at triage.
Both trauma rooms are full.
Let's take him to Curtain 2. Go!
I need a central line
kit now! BP's 60 palp.
Could be a ruptured aneurysm.
CBC, coags, type and cross
for eight, four units of O-neg.
Let's prep the neck. Move.
I feel a pulsatile mass.
Hey, Malik, is there
any history on this guy?
I need a trauma kit.
This is a triple-lumen CVP.
"History of hypertension
and high cholesterol."
He needs an NG and a
Foley. I need the SonoSite.
Dr. Benton accepted this
patient from an urgent-care center.
What? And he's been
waiting in Chairs?
For two hours.
I can't find the subclavian.
Put him in Trendelenburg.
Look, they said it
was just a back sprain.
The doctor told you that?
Well, I-I, uh... I didn't
exactly talk to the doctor.
Oh, great. And now
he's bleeding out.
Take a deep breath.
M.A.P. is 78 with a pump.
Is that good or bad?
Took you out of heart failure
and got you off
your breathing tube.
Sats are up to 99.
Okay, let's get him on
five liters, nasal cannula.
Conni, why don't you
grab a blood-gas kit?
Where's Janet?
She's trying to get
a clerk from city hall
to come issue a
marriage license.
That's crazy.
People in love do crazy things.
I wanted to wait
for a transplant
so I could chase
her down the aisle.
I didn't want her to
marry a cardiac cripple.
You get a heart, she won't.
If one's available,
if the tissues match,
how long can I
last on this pump?
Couple weeks.
Pretty lousy odds.
They were worse when you
were having a heart attack
and the chopper was going down.
You see any Zephiran?
Yeah. Top shelf.
Hey, I heard about
your teenagers.
They're so young.
It's pretty rough.
Are you okay? Yeah. I think so.
Do you wanna take a break?
I'm gonna plug in two new
patients. I'll come find you.
Talk to Kovac? Not yet.
Dr. Kovac?
Yeah?
We finished the autopsy.
I can review some of
the pertinent findings.
Mm-hm.
There were multiple
contusions to the occipital cortex
with herniation through
the foramen magnum.
And if you'll take a look here,
you'll see numerous fractures
consistent with
repetitive blunt trauma.
I know how he died.
Well, I can tell you
that he was a smoker
based on the lung findings.
Also, he probably once
lived in central California.
There were foci of
pulmonary fibrosis
consistent with coccidiomycosis.
It's endemic to the
San Joaquin Valley.
Eh, that's an agricultural area.
Maybe he grew up on a farm.
Well, I don't know.
There's grease
under the fingernails
and a biker-club tattoo.
He could be just a drifter.
But we'll probably never know.
Happens all the time.
Not such a smart
idea to take your Razor
down a flight of stairs, huh?
Were you wearing a helmet?
Yeah. What do you
think I am? Stupid?
Ooh. Well, we'll
see after the x-ray.
Right wrist film, something
for the pain. A half a...
It happened so fast.
We were having a fight.
He ran into the street
and a car hit him.
They're doing
everything they can.
Dr. Carter? WEAVER:
What's the rhythm?
V-fib. Charge to 360.
Trent. Oh, God. Trent.
What's our down time?
Twenty minutes.
Never had a pulse.
Clear.
Don't let him die.
Still V-fib.
Hey, doc. Hey, thanks
for coming down.
Sure. What do you need?
Thirty-one-year-old patient,
end-stage heart failure.
He may not make
it to transplant.
What denomination? I don't know.
Can he speak? For last
rites, I really need to know that.
No, no. He and his fiancée,
they wanna get married.
Tonight? He's sick.
We can't move him.
We gotta do it here.
Were you able to get a license?
Oh, I tried. But
city hall's closing.
You don't have a
marriage license?
Can you do it anyway?
I'm sorry, but a marriage
isn't legally binding
without a license.
How about tomorrow?
Okay.
He may not make
it till tomorrow.
Can't you help these people?
They want your blessing.
They have very little time.
As long as everyone understands
it won't hold up in court.
Are you ready to
tie the knot? Heh.
Come on. Let's go talk to Tom.
Dr. Kovac, did you
trade your shift?
No.
Hey. Where have you been?
I heard they couldn't reach
you. You didn't answer your page.
What's...? What's the problem?
That I had to come in
today and cover for you.
I thought I was on tonight.
No. You were on today.
Then... Then I'm sorry. There
must have been some mistake.
There was no one with
enough experience to cover you.
We almost lost two patients.
Luka, this is
grounds for dismissal.
Fine, Kerry. Fire me.
I know that you've
been through a lot.
If you need to take some
time off, you should tell me.
But you can't miss
any more shifts.
I can work tonight.
We don't need you tonight.
You should go home.
Go on. Go.
Luka, wait. What?
Wait a minute. Don't walk away.
Where have you
been? Abby, please.
I j... I wanna help.
Just talk to me.
There's nothing to say, okay?
To have and to hold,
to love and to cherish
as long as you both shall live.
"The union of husband and
wife in heart, body and mind
"is intended by God
for their mutual joy.
"For the health and
comfort given one another
"in prosperity and adversity.
"And when it is God's will,
for the procreation
of children."
You can stay as long
as you want, okay?
Emma, I am so sorry.
Get out of here.
Emma... It's your fault.
By the power vested in me,
I pronounce you
husband and wife.
Go ahead and kiss
your bride, Tom.
Congratulations.
I'm gonna break all the rules
and allow you to have
one sip of champagne.
Thanks.
Well, since this is
the honeymoon suite,
you're entitled to a
little privacy. Ha, ha!
We're very grateful.
Thank you. TOM: Yeah.
For everything.
Nice folks.
Tell them to get a license,
and I'll do it again. No charge.
Thanks.
So, what about our
wedding coordinator?
I totally forgot to
call and cancel.
Oh, she'll be furious.
Well, blame it on me. I mean,
it was a medical emergency.
Oh, the hell with
her. Excuse me?
This is all so silly.
I don't want a
rose-entwined arbor
with trained doves.
I don't want champagne
served out of crystal flutes.
I understand.
Who cares about a
bloody ice sculpture?
Not me.
I just want to get married
in a simple ceremony.
I don't know. I was looking
forward to those doves.
So I spoke to the O.R.
The aneurysm
repair's going well.
I'm glad to hear it. Yeah.
I think it's best for now
if you just see patients. Here.
Well, if that's what you want.
Peter, you're an
excellent surgeon.
But ER management is not
the best use of your skills.
Leave that to us.
Hello, Mrs. Barnwell.
I'm Dr. Benton.
So I understand you
have a pain in your hip.
That's right.
And I've been lying
here for three hours.
Oh, well, I'm very
sorry about that.
Pardon me for asking,
but are you an intern?
No, no, no, no, no. I'm
a, uh, faculty physician.
Oh.
Your mother must be very proud.
Yeah, she was.
So how long have
you had this pain?
Before we get much further,
I'd like to say that I
would be more at ease
with another doctor.
Excuse me? You look
like a fine young man.
But, uh, I've always
had white doctors.
I've always felt more
comfortable that way.
So you're saying
that you only wanna
see a white doctor?
If it's all right with you.
That's fine.
You'll just have to wait
another three hours.
What happened to
him? I don't know.
Hey, uh, have you seen Abby?
I saw her punch out.
Hey, Carter. You got a minute?
Actually, I'm on my way out.
Carter, wait.
John, you had a bad
day. We all have bad days.
Look at me.
You have to make tough
choices, do what you think is right
and accept the outcome.
I shouldn't have
told him. You had to.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Hey...
I'm off in 20 minutes. Uh...
You wanna get some dinner?
I-I got an AA meeting
at 9. You'll make it.
Can I join you?
It's a counter, Peter.
You can sit anywhere.
So you survived.
Weaver said I was incompetent.
Really?
Well, that's what she implied.
The per diem job
is just temporary
until you get back into Surgery.
Yeah. But I needed to show
them that I could run the ER.
Why? It has no bearing
on your surgical career.
Yeah. But it reflects
on me, you know? Uh...
I should've been
able to handle it.
You can't be
perfect at everything.
Yeah, but, Cleo,
I can learn a job
if I can do it well.
So do you feel
better having said this
to a sympathetic ear?
Yeah. Yeah, I guess so. Thanks.
You know, I've
had some problems,
and I haven't had
anyone to talk to.
Are you ever going
to be there for me?
Because you sure
as hell haven't been.
Who is it?
It's me.
Can I come in, please?
Sure.
Abby... You don't have to talk.