April.
Cutting board?
Huh?
Uh, corner cabinet
by the Lazy Susan.
Yeah.
And you still haven't weighed
in on the paint choices
that I asked you about.
Uh, what room is that
for again?
The den. Come on, Tate.
I've been working on
this remodel for weeks.
I know. I know.
I'm sorry, babe.
I love that you're making
my house our house.
I love that we set
a date for the wedding.
But I'm driving you crazy.
Yep.
You know what?
Stuck in a house,
on TB leave, I get it.
I mean, I've been
trying to keep busy,
'cause when I'm not,
I can't help but worry.
First ultrasound today?
Yeah.
It's gonna
be perfect.
Are you crazy?
Where's your jacket?
Don't need it.
I love the crisp
winter air.
Yeah, right. I can see
your goose bumps.
Oh, you mean
my pilomotor reflex?
Oh, good God.
Uh, anyway,
this weather is balmy.
Do you remember that
February when you and
Jeff and me and Lisa,
we rented that cabin
at Lake Mendota?
Yes.
And then we got hammered
on that box of wine
we found in the pantry.
Mmm. Which led
to the hot tub.
Which led to you
sneaking a peek.
I did not!
Did you?
No. Of course not.
You're terrible.
Seems like
a lifetime ago.
How'd we lose touch
for so long?
I'm not sure.
Life of a med student.
Lunch will wait.
Ricky Wade, GCS 15,
vitals stable.
You're going
to Treatment Four,
Dr. Choi.
Trauma to
the left ear with hematoma,
multiple dislocated fingers,
expanding hematoma
of the anterior thigh.
Refused the board
and collar.
I'm not a cripple.
I could've walked.
I know. MMA.
Feel no pain, right?
Any loss of
consciousness?
Dizziness?
Hell no. That bitch
barely connected.
Cage doc called the fight.
Said it was
a freakin' bloodbath.
All right.
Let's get an IV in him,
then a gram of Ancef.
The opponent?
Yep.
You're going to
Treatment Three.
Thanks.
Cyrus Hammad.
GCS 15.
Significant swelling
to his left eye
and bruising on
the right flank.
No loss of
consciousness,
but the fight doc
wanted to have him
looked at, anyway.
You're lucky that doc
stopped the fight.
I would've pounded you
into a living...
Hey!
Not in the cage anymore,
huh? Give it a rest.
History and physical
and a detailed neuro exam.
Got it. I'll shout
if I need you.
Yeah.
Excuse me.
Yes?
I'm looking
for my brother,
Cyrus Hammad.
Cheating-ass punks!
What did you do?
Grease some palms?
You know your bro was
getting his ass beat.
I'm gonna need
security in the ED.
Dr. Choi! Stop him!
Come on! Come on!
Come on!
I swear to God!
Chill out!
Walk away.
You okay?
Yeah.
It's swollen.
Let's get some ice on
his thigh and hands.
Had that Arab eating
mat in the first round.
Should've stomped
him into oblivion.
You've got a lot of blood
in your ear, Mr. Wade.
I need to release
the pressure around
the cartilage,
or it will cauliflower.
Skip the Lido.
Last thing I need is
a mile-long hospital bill.
You're gonna feel it.
You sure?
Suit yourself.
Damn it, that hurts
like a mother!
Bastard was all
about cheap shots.
Towelhead!
What do you expect?
Gonna put a dressing
on the ear and get
a CT head and face.
Also some X-rays
of the hands.
What do we got?
Moderate swelling
in his left orbit,
probable fracture.
Inbreds. Always go for
the low-hanging fruit.
Elbow strike?
Hammerfist.
Sounds bad, I know,
but it was a legal shot.
May have a couple
fractured ribs.
CT orbits and
facial bones to start,
chest X-ray for the ribs?
Thanks.
I should hit up Rasheed.
Meet these jackasses
in the parking lot,
show them how
the towelheads do it.
Aamir, let it go.
This is why
you fight, Cyrus.
Not anymore.
"You can't
control ignorance,
only how you react."
Surah Al shura
verse 40.
Scans may take a while.
Moving around's
gonna hurt like hell.
How's a bit of
morphine sound?
Like heaven.
Findings showed
that people with
higher confidence
tend to use open,
expansive postures.
Sure. Hmm,
runner crosses
the finish line,
throw their hands
up in victory.
Exactly. Conversely, those
who are timid or defensive
make themselves small.
They'll slouch in their seats,
cross their arms, their legs,
and actually what
is really cool is...
Oh. Hey.
How you guys doing?
Good, good.
Uh... So far, so good.
You know, just another day.
Um, so, dinner tonight?
Our usual spot?
You got it.
Good.
Bye.
I will catch you guys later.
Crossed arms.
What?
Sorry.
Hey, Daniel?
Oh, listen, I need you
to evaluate a potential
organ recipient
to see if
she's a candidate
for transplant.
Her name's Meghan Scott.
LVAD. Still in SICU.
I know it's delicate, but if
you could get it back to me
by the end of the day?
I will do my very best.
Thank you.
Yeah. For two at 8:00 p.m.
Great. Thank you.
Look at you, all smiles.
Hot date?
Surprise date.
Oh.
I'm taking Nina to
this French restaurant
on Monroe,
Cochon Volant Brasserie.
Nice.
Actually, it's Cochon
Volant Brasserie.
Dr. Stohl.
Personally,
I prefer Alinea.
It's American
molecular gastronomy
at its finest.
Highly ranked on
the S.Pellegrino list.
Didn't realize you were back
from your sabbatical already.
Or that you spoke French.
Oh, enough to get by.
Something I can do
for you, Dr. Stohl?
My sabbatical
was a World Health
Organization assignment.
I advised nongovernmental
emergency medical teams
on how best to respond
and treat SODs.
"Sudden Onset Disasters."
We should sit down
and talk about it.
Sure. Sounds great.
Who is that?
The Troll.
Our beloved Chief of
Emergency Medicine.
Okay.
Talk about
sudden onset disasters.
I've been sober
almost three years.
It's not been easy.
Temptation never
really goes away.
But you've done it, Mom.
Um, you been going
to meetings?
Alcoholics Anonymous?
I tried, but the endless talk
about hitting rock bottom,
I know it's supposed
to be cathartic,
but it just put me in
a worse mental space.
So, no meetings,
no therapy. Um...
Any relapses?
Wow, well, it's remarkable
that you've been able
to stay sober.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
I started meditating,
and, uh, setting small,
achievable goals,
and of course, Bria.
The crew Mom used
to hang with,
I helped her see
they were bad influences.
She dropped them all.
No more bars, nightlife.
She's, uh, a homebody now.
It's senior year.
Must be nice to have
Mom home more.
Is college in the picture?
Yes. But not right away.
We've agreed
I'd take a year off
before applying.
I'm sorry.
A bit parched.
I just... I just want
this to be over.
It's just important that
you understand that
this would be
a life-changing event,
the surgery.
And could really shake up
your and Bria's routine,
so, it's very important that
you have a postsurgical plan
in place.
I plan to keep doing
what I've been doing.
Going solo has worked.
I need to make sure
it keeps working.
What's the status
with the room change, Maggie?
These guys next-door
to each other are like napalm.
I'm working on it,
Dr. Choi.
Thanks.
Hey, man.
Where you headed?
To grab a pop.
Vending machine's in
the waiting room that way.
So, that's how
it's gonna be?
Whatever.
Hey, don't let those
ass-wipes get to you.
Just trying to be tough guys.
No, Jeff.
It goes deeper.
Not many families
with the last name
Choi where I grew up.
Know the type
all too well.
Dr. Manning, you're
going to Trauma Three.
Got it.
Ted Baylor,
21-year-old male.
Friends found him in
his dorm room, hooked up to
the Xbox and unresponsive.
Gave him fluids
and oxygen in the field.
Glucose level?
Blood sugar's 800.
That's sky-high.
I see the train
kept rolling without me.
Yep. Welcome back.
We missed you.
All right. On my count.
One, two, three.
Mr. Baylor? Mr. Baylor?
He's out. Sternal?
Yep.
There he is.
Mr. Baylor,
do you know
where you are?
Hospital.
Okay. He's able to speak
and protect his airway.
Good breath sounds.
Lungs are clear.
Maintaining
oxygen saturation.
All right,
let's keep him on the O2,
bolus another liter of fluid,
and start an insulin drip.
Labs?
What do you think?
Likely diabetic
ketoacidosis,
so, CBC, CMP, VBG, uh,
hemoglobin, A1-C,
and another Accu-Chek.
Uh, for cardiac,
troponin and an EKG.
Nice job.
Help! Help!
Something's wrong!
I got it.
What happened?
He was talking, and then
his eyes rolled back.
I don't know.
Got a pulse,
but he can't protect
his airway.
All right, we need to
intubate. Draw up meds.
Twenty of etomidate,
100 of sux.
Is he gonna be okay?
We'll see.
Hold the meds.
Don't need them.
No gag reflex.
I'm in. Bag him.
Let's get an OG tube down
to decompress his stomach.
His pupil's blown.
He must have a head bleed.
Page neurosurgery.
We need a stat head CT.
Hi.
Dr. Manning, I presume?
I know. Corny.
A little.
But making jokes?
Feeling better?
Compared to before?
I mean, it still feels like
I got hit by a truck.
What happened?
Your body wasn't producing
enough insulin to control
your blood sugar,
so it spiked and
it knocked you out.
Is it diabetes?
Yes.
But the crisis period
is over.
Your blood sugar levels
are improving.
You okay?
It's just a little tender.
Do you mind
if I take a look?
Pain scale,
one to ten?
Twelve.
Okay. How long
has your stomach
been hurting?
A few days. I mean,
it's winter break.
Just more cheap beer
and pizza than usual.
I figured it was
just indigestion.
Is it the diabetes?
No.
Gallstones.
I would like to run some
additional blood tests
and get an MRCP,
a more detailed scan
of your stomach, okay?
Mmm-hmm.
Is there anyone
I can call for you?
No. My dad's on his way.
All right.
He had them.
Gallstones.
They're a fat person's
problem, aren't they?
They are often
tied to obesity.
The diabetes as well.
But, you know, with
lifestyle changes, these
things are manageable.
You mean like
diet and exercise?
You're only 21. It'd be
easier than you think.
I'll be back shortly.
Massive hemorrhaging
in his brain.
Trying to get
the swelling
under control.
Decompressive
craniectomy.
Opening up the skull
should relieve
the pressure.
Yeah, but right before
they put him under,
he had
a Cushing's reflex.
Dropped his heart rate,
and his BP went
through the roof.
Hang in, man.
Mmm-hmm. Yeah.
All right, I'll check.
Sure. Uh-huh.
Everything okay?
Yeah. Why wouldn't it be?
So, uh, Meghan Scott.
I gotta say I have
some reservations.
But she's three years
sober and committed
to staying clean.
Yeah. Without
a plan or strategy
to avoid relapse.
Addiction is
never conquered.
Only managed.
But she's got a support
system in her daughter.
Bria's involved.
Mmm. Maybe too involved.
I mean,
by delaying college,
she is valuating
her mother's life
over her own,
and as admirable
as that may seem,
it just doesn't
tend to last.
Meghan's sick.
It makes sense
that she'd want
to take care of her.
There's
a very fine line between
a healthy support system
and an unhealthy
dependence.
I mean, did you see
during the evaluation,
Meghan needed
her daughter's help to
reach a glass of water
that was literally
right in front of her?
Look, it's a
gut-wrenching process,
and we just have to remember
that we give Meghan a heart,
we could be denying one
to somebody who is just
as deserving,
and might have
a better chance of success.
So, Meghan's a no?
No, I didn't say that.
I just...
I just want
to sit with it
a little longer.
Okay.
That gallbladder's
really inflamed.
It's full of stones.
But it doesn't look like
any have dropped into
the common bile duct.
No, but it's only a matter
of time before one does
and causes
a major obstruction.
Right.
Well, play it safe,
remove the gallbladder?
Yes, except
his latest labs.
Calcium's low.
Amylase, lipase, white cells,
are all through the roof.
Gallstone pancreatitis.
Man.
The swelling
is really bad.
Right now, I think we
should up his IV fluids
and start a course
of IV nutrition.
Should buy him a few days,
give his pancreas time
to cool off. Good idea.
Good.
What does this mean?
His pupils are
nonreactive?
The bleeding in
Cyrus' brain has caused
significant injury.
Despite the surgeon's
best efforts,
Cyrus has slipped
into a persistent
vegetative state.
A coma?
But he can wake up, no?
It's possible?
I'm sorry, but it's more
likely he stays like this
or devolves to brain death.
That referee,
he should've stopped
the fight earlier.
Cyrus was dominant.
The crowd,
they cheered for blood.
They wanted to see
the Muslim boy get killed.
Hey.
Oh!
All bundled up?
You realize your pilomotor
reflex is the first
step towards frostbite?
Yeah. Something
like that.
So, you know,
I've been sitting on
this for a while now,
and, uh,
it might sound silly,
but I believe
if couples are
good travel partners,
then they have what it
takes to have a future.
So, what do you think?
New Orleans?
Drinks, food, music?
I...
"I sometimes imagine, uh,
it was the other way around,
"that Lisa was your wife
and Natalie was mine."
What are you talking about?
I said that to Jeff.
That's why we all lost touch.
He didn't want us to hang out
anymore.
I don't understand.
Right when Lisa and
I started to go sideways,
you and Jeff met me out
at Twin Anchors
for moral support.
Yeah, I remember.
You were up at the bar
ordering a round,
and I was looking at you,
and I just said it.
Why?
'Cause my marriage
was falling apart and
I was a little bit drunk,
and right at that moment,
it was true.
Jeff, of course,
flipped out,
and, uh, I mean,
if you weren't there,
it might've gotten ugly.
And you're just
telling me this now?
I know. I should've
told you this morning
when you asked.
This morning?
How about
when you showed up
as a med student?
Or before we slept
together, or before
I let you into my life?
Unbelievable.
Hi.
Setting up
grocery delivery.
Farewell,
supermarket temptations.
Well, that's
a good first step.
Mmm-hmm.
You know there's
some great apps for
tracking calories, too.
That's way
down the line.
I mean, after I get
a handle on GMOs,
gluten, organic versus
farm-fresh. I...
That's why
I like fast food.
It's simple.
You know what?
Why don't I page
the hospital's nutritionist,
have her come in
for a consult?
You okay?
I've just been feeling
a little bit short
of breath, and...
Just come on now?
A couple minutes ago.
Is it a reaction to
all the meds, or...
No. They're just
sparking your
immune system.
It shouldn't affect
your breathing.
Sit up for me?
Lungs are clear.
Is the extra
oxygen helping?
No, not really.
Will? Will,
I need a hand.
Stat portable
chest X-ray.
What's going on?
Blood sugar's normal.
White cells, amylase,
lipase, they're all down.
Everything's good,
except now he can't breathe.
What's happening?
Your blood pressure
and oxygen levels
keep dropping,
so we're gonna take
a chest X-ray to try
to figure out why.
Mass in the lung.
I'm hearing a rub.
It wasn't there before.
All right.
Let's get an echo.
I can't breathe.
O2 keeps dropping.
Switching to
a full face mask.
Pericardial effusion.
What does that mean?
No, keep this on.
There's fluid built up
around your heart.
It's constricting it
from beating.
Bolus another liter of fluid.
Get 125mg Solu-Medrol IV
and a Levophed drip.
Yes, Doctor.
Page Dr. Rhodes.
We need to tap
the fluid off his heart.
Five minutes ago,
he was getting better,
and now, he's sicker
than when he came in.
Okay.
So, the fluid's from
acute pericarditis.
Stemming from the mass
in his lungs.
Mmm-hmm.
Drain's a temporary fix,
but his heart is
really struggling.
CT chest will show
exactly what
we're dealing with.
He presented
with hyperglycemia and
gallstone pancreatitis.
There was
absolutely no evidence
of a heart problem.
My time with Dr. Downey,
now Dr. Latham,
the one constant,
cardiac events can
strike without warning.
Thought he was
on the mend.
So did I.
Look. About earlier...
Dr. Manning?
Yeah?
Ted's father
has arrived.
I can fill him in.
No. I'll do it.
Hi. Dr. Manning.
Okay. Hard part's done.
Big muscle bleeder down deep.
Stick tying it now.
The Arab,
Cyrus...
You wheeled him out of here,
but he never came back.
What happened?
Turn for the worse.
He knew the risks
when he stepped
inside the cage.
It's the cost of
doing business.
Shower and change
the dressing every day.
It'll take at least two
to three weeks to heal.
Pack the wound.
Get him out of here.
Bulky, swollen lymph nodes
and a clear primary mass
in the right lower lobe
of the lung.
Non-small
cell lung cancer?
The biopsy
results are pending,
but I'm almost certain
they'll confirm it.
I'm gonna talk
to Dr. Latham about
surgical options.
All right.
I'll consult with oncology,
get their opinion as well.
Yeah.
Hey. Sorry, Nat.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Hey, Dr. Charles.
Um...
Speak with you
a second?
What's up?
Yeah, so, my heart
patient Meghan Scott,
I hadn't heard anything.
So, is there something
going on with
the transplant eval?
Well, I know you know
that we're not supposed
to be talking about this,
but unofficially,
her history of addiction
makes her very high risk.
I understand her history,
but we're talking
about her future here.
Well, her future's
precisely the issue.
I'm sorry, Dr. Rhodes,
but the clearance process,
it's unforgiving.
No, no, no, no.
Dr. Charles, you spent, what?
All of an hour with her?
I've known Meghan
and her daughter, Bria,
for months now.
You've known her
within a controlled
environment.
The invasive surgery,
the powerful opiates
for pain management,
the rigorous
medication schedule,
the constant check-ups
to make sure she's
not rejecting the organ.
So, you're gonna
seal her fate with
a checklist then?
She doesn't get a heart,
she dies.
She's looking
at six months,
maybe a year.
Do you honestly think
that I don't know that?
Someone's got to make
the tough decisions here,
Dr. Rhodes.
I'd thank you
to let me do my job.
Amniotic fluid level
looks okay.
Same with
nuchal translucency.
Fetal heart rate is 180,
nice and strong.
Oh, yeah,
that's a boy.
What's up, little man?
Already looking
like a linebacker.
Um, she looks like
a scientist to me.
Dr. Lee? Something wrong?
At 12 weeks,
the optimal crown chin
length is 26 millimeters.
Your fetal measurement is 23.
Is that still within
the normal range?
Yes, but on
the low end.
Something we need
to keep an eye on.
Low measurement,
what does it mean?
The main concern
is anencephaly,
a neural tube defect
that can cause the brain
to develop abnormally.
Is it because of
my TB meds?
Possibly. We can't
really know for sure.
All right.
She said the TB meds
could possibly be
affecting the baby.
That doesn't mean...
I know.
But what if they are?
You can't stop taking them.
So, where does
that leave us?
Look. You're 12 weeks.
If we're considering...
We're not.
April, it's not
what I want either,
but if your health
is in question,
the quality of
life of our baby
is threatened, I...
We need to understand
this gets riskier,
more complicated
after 14 weeks.
Tate, I am Catholic.
April, it's my baby, too.
Don't I at least get
to discuss this?
We are not
terminating
this pregnancy.
So, how long would
I have to do chemo for?
That's up to
the oncologist.
Generally, it's given
in cycles between one
and four weeks long
followed by
a period of rest.
How many cycles?
On average, four to six.
What about side effects?
The Internet lists thousands.
It all depends on
how Ted's body reacts.
But, yes,
the side effects can add up.
And because of
the gallstone pancreatitis,
they may even be exacerbated.
Well, all of this
sounds awful. Um...
What am I looking
at with surgery?
Removal of the mass
via thoracotomy.
I'll open your chest
and peel away the growth
from whatever
it's attached to.
But my pancreatitis,
a few hours ago,
it was too dicey for
gallbladder surgery.
How is it okay
with all of this?
Your cardiac function
is compromised.
Preventing heart failure has
to be our chief concern.
Dad, I don't know
what I'm gonna do.
I feel like if I make
the wrong decision
right now, I'm gonna die.
Do you need
an answer right now?
Ted, look,
I understand this
is all overwhelming,
but you're very sick.
The sooner we start
fighting back...
Emergency radiation.
Yeah, a single dose
intended only to stabilize
the mass in your lung.
It'll give the pancreatitis
a few more days to heal,
and it'll give you
and your dad more time
to decide on a treatment.
And if I still choose
surgery after,
it'll be safer, right?
Theoretically, yes.
When can I do it?
The radiation.
Today. I will set
it up with the
radiation oncologist.
You gonna just
stand there staring,
or are you gonna come in?
I can't get this
frickin' coffee ring
off of...
What's on your mind?
I know
you have reservations,
but I've been reading about
how others have managed
addiction in unorthodox ways.
There's meditation.
Meghan already does that.
Predicting your weak spots.
She's cut off friends
that were bad influences.
The problem with
these techniques is that
they're all solo endeavors.
What Meghan
needs is the support
of a sober community.
But she's been
successful without one.
And she's got Bria,
all the reason in
the world to stay sober.
Won't be enough.
I've been treating
addiction for
over 20 years.
And trust me.
I know of what I speak.
My brother lost
his battle with addiction
about 14 years ago.
I am sorry.
I want Meghan to succeed
just as badly as you do.
But I look at her, and I...
I see my little brother.
He tried to do it solo, too.
It just doesn't work.
And I can't in good
conscience recommend her to
the Transplant Committee
without one good,
solid, clinical reason
that might give her
a chance to succeed.
I've been looking for it.
I just can't find it.
Okay.
Hey. Okay to discharge
the asthmatic
in Treatment Two?
Yeah. Prednisone
and albuterol scripts
are with the clerk.
They've been going for
the last several hours,
trading places.
They believe prayer
can bring him out.
What are you
doing over here?
I just, um...
I'm not sure.
You've been discharged.
Go home.
You're showing
your face around here?
You better suck
in all that!
Is he gonna wake up?
Like you care. You did
this to him. Murderer!
It's not my fault.
We both wanted to win.
Go home, Ricky.
God will punish you.
You will burn in hell!
Aamir!
Enough.
Come. Pray with us.
I'm sorry.
Dr. Halstead,
a moment.
Yeah?
Dr. Manning's patient,
Ted Baylor...
I understand
surgery was proposed,
but that radiation
will be tried first.
As a short-term measure.
Yeah, well,
it's the size of the mass
that's killing him.
Radiation only
stalls its growth.
It doesn't shrink it.
Well, Dr. Manning's
opinion and mine
is that radiation
is the much safer
option right now.
Well, you're the attending.
Keep me posted.
Hey, Daniel, I haven't gotten
your report on Meghan Scott.
How's it going?
Um, still dotting the I's,
crossing the T's.
You know, I know
these evaluations
are difficult,
but if you're looking
for something
and not finding it,
maybe it's not there.
I said I'd have it for you
before the end of the day,
and I will.
Okay.
From now on,
clean nutrition, lots of
cardio, diet and exercise.
My dad, too.
That's the enthusiasm
I was hoping to hear.
I'm getting a second chance.
I'm not wasting a day of it.
Good for you.
Okay, let's do this.
Natalie, hey.
I am so sorry
that I didn't say
something sooner.
I was afraid
I'd lose you.
Say something, please.
I was terrified to
move on from Jeff.
Even more afraid
to get involved with you,
my husband's best friend.
And yet I thought
there is no one
Jeff would approve of me
being in a relationship
with more than you.
And you let me
think that.
He's coding!
I need help!
What happened?
He just dropped.
Take over compressions.
Got it.
I got it. I got it.
No pulse. V-fib.
Charge 200.
Charging.
Hold compressions. Clear.
Resume compressions.
Another milligram epi.
Charge to 300.
Charging.
Hold compressions.
Clear.
Asystole.
You gonna call it?
Time of death, 17:32.
He was dead before
the first alarm
even went off.
COD, tumor
lysis syndrome.
No way.
You know, the radiation
was supposed to
stabilize the mass.
Instead,
it caused it to burst.
I might as well
have just given Ted
a lethal injection,
because that is
essentially
what happened.
Natalie,
this is not on you.
There are no predictors
for tumor lysis syndrome.
It is monumentally rare.
Even more so
in young people.
And the few times
that it does occur,
overwhelmingly,
it's a reaction to
chemo, not radiation.
It still feels like
I missed something.
Well, you didn't.
No doctor sees
gallstone pancreatitis
with diabetes
and thinks volatile
cancerous chest mass.
And yet here it is.
Ted's death is
not your fault.
You just get good news,
or bad news?
My coma patient,
this morning,
he mentioned
a Quran verse,
Surah Al shura 40.
"The recompense
of an evil deed
"can only be
an evil equal to it,
"but whoever pardons
and makes reconciliation,
"their reward
is due from God."
In the psych world,
it's called
complementarity.
You know,
kindness begets kindness.
Hostility, hostility.
Yeah.
An hour ago,
those two hated each other,
but then his father
extends a hand.
Dr. Charles calls it
"flipping the script."
Don't know if
I could've done it.
Yeah.
Not many people can.
Okay, what is with you?
No invitation to sit down?
Usually I can't
sneak past you.
I'm just
a little preoccupied.
I gotta figure
something out fast,
and I'm at a roadblock,
and I can't find
my way around it.
Okay, I will leave you to it.
Hey, uh, if you're going
through hell, keep going.
Isn't that what
you always taught me?
Well, technically,
it was Winston Churchill,
but...
Still, it's never
let me down.
Mmm.
Good.
Mom.
You're recommending Meghan
to the hospital's
Transplant Committee.
Uh-huh.
Well, what happened?
Well, um, if you must know,
a member of my junior staff
drew my attention
to the fact that, um,
I was so focused
on her risk factors,
that I was blind to
the one personality trait that
my late brother did not have.
What?
Grit.
One's ability to persevere
in the face of obstacles,
a clean clinical reason.
I mean, the stressors
are still there,
as are significant
future challenges,
but I like to think
that the determination
that's kept her clean
the past three years
is gonna help her
go the distance.
Mmm-hmm.
Hey, what made you
think of grit?
Fatherhood.
Rough one today, huh?
To say the least.
Well, not to pile on,
but Dr. Stohl just
informed me that he'd
like to use your case
for the next Morbidity
and Mortality Review.
Trace your steps.
An M&M?
Oh, my God.
Well, it's not
an inquisition.
It's just a learning tool
for the medical staff.
You tell Dr. Stohl that?
Okay, good night.
All righty. Good night.
What now?
You can't kick me
out of here, too.
I'm not here to do that.
I was thinking we got off
to a rough start.
Let me make it up to you.
Two beers. My tab.