I always said I'd
be happier alone.
I'd have my work, my friends.
But someone in
your life all the time?
- More trouble than it's worth.
-  OK. Crib goes here.
Apparently, I got over it.
Changing table
will go... right here.
But you can't plan a baby
room before you have a baby.
I mean, you're gonna
jinx the adoption.
The social worker wants to see
where we live. This is like a death-trap.
I'm trying to create a
reasonable distraction.
- Hello?
- Janet! Welcome!
How are you? Thanks for coming
out. Oh, be careful. Watch those nails.
Perfect for a baby, right?
Hm...
I'm gonna stop in the lab. I'll
see you after the intake, OK?
OK. Oh, God. I forgot it
was the Hobarts today.
It always bums me out when we have
an Alzheimer's patient with young kids.
There's no shame in sitting
this one out. I can do the intake.
Stop treating me like I'm your
wife. On the trial, I'm a colleague.
I'm allowed to say, "It bums me out."
It doesn't mean you have to feed me
warm milk and run a
bath. Treat me like a doctor.
Right. Sorry. OK. Go
do the intake, colleague.
Shepherd, you got a minute? I
need to talk to you about your trial.
Oh, um...
I should get Meredith.
I just got a lecture on
the failure to extend professional
courtesy to one's spouse.
I think it's best you
don't get Meredith.
You're in, in very good hands. I still
feel bad that I'm not gonna be here.
For the surgery? I'll be unconscious,
that's not when I'm gonna miss you.
- OK. Then I guess I won't...
- You can feel bad
about all the time that follows.
When I'm not under general
anesthesia, and you're still not here,
you're halfway around
the world... with Arnold.
- Andrew.
- Ah...
- Excuse me?
- He's a rock star.
I kind of feel like the sound of an
adoring crowd should follow his name.
I don't... Is that a
compliment or an insult?
I don't know, I guess it depends
on how you feel about rock stars.
- OK, well,
Andrew's not a rock star...
- Ah...
OK, you know what? Can you stop
that? It's starting to get annoying.
My wife's leaving, I'm
allowed to be annoying.
I'm not a real wife, so that
doesn't buy for a lot of bad behavior.
Well, you're my real best
friend, what does that get me?
- I'm sorry.
- Don't be. Go be happy.
With Andrew. Ah...
You're impossible.
Yeah. You, too.
Meredith, tell me
exactly what you did.
- I can't tell you.
- We can still fix this,
- but I need to know
what you did.
- If I tell you,
- it'll make it worse.
- It's worse already. Meredith...
Listen, I... I love you.
And I'm sorry, but I
can't tell you anything.
You want to be treated like a colleague?
I'm gonna treat you like a colleague.
Alex Karev informed Dr. Hunt that
Dr. Grey tampered with my clinical trial.
She switched around the
placebos and the drugs,
probably invalidating my trial.
- Is this true?
- Nothing
I did has any effect...
- Tell me exactly what happened.
- I can't do that.
Do you have any idea what
you've done? You think the FDA
will get anywhere near
this hospital ever again?
Meredith, look at me.
If this is wrong, if there
is something going on,
if Karev is exaggerating, this is
the part where you have to tell me.
This is the part where you
have to deny the charges.
Kick me off the study.
There's nothing
wrong with the study.
- Nothing I did
changes anything.
- But you're not denying it.
I'm gonna have to investigate
what's going on here,
but it looks to me like
you just lost your job.
So they're probably gonna
fire me. Are you happy?
- Come on, they're not gonna...
- I want your crap
out of my house by
the end of the day.
What the hell was that?
A 757 went down in the Sound.
We're looking at about
200 injured passengers.
We're the designated crisis center.
Families will be instructed to come here
to find their loved ones. We
are activating Surge Protocol.
Dr. Hunt is gonna be running
the show. It's gonna be chaotic.
You need to listen carefully,
you need to stay focused,
do not contribute to the panic.
Get to your stations.
Dr. Bailey, clear
any beds that we can.
- Discharge or transfer.
- OK. Uh, Grey.
All right, Torres, you'll be with
me. Kepner, set up the ER for triage.
Other Grey, I want you
running the family center.
Take over in the
cafeteria. Yang, blood bank.
- We might need a Candyman.
- Dr. Sloan'll be our Candyman.
Let's be liberal with
pain meds for our victims
and sedatives for patients that we're
moving. Avery, you can help him out.
- Let's move, people!
- What happened with Meredith?
- Cristina, I can't...
- Owen!
She tampered with Shepherd's
study, invalidated the results.
She destroyed the whole thing.
There was a plane crash. They're
gonna cancel your procedure
and try to send you home. You
need to tell them that you're a D-1.
You don't need to be in pre-op, but
you want to be moved to a regular room.
That way, when the hospital
starts doing surgery again,
- you'll be first in the queue.
- Don't you have a plane...?
- Wait, did they
shut down the airport?
- No, but we're not leaving
till it's over. They need
surgeons and trauma counselors.
These are your films.
They're gonna schedule your
surgery at Seattle Presbyterian.
Seattle Pres can't take anymore,
- start calling County!
- Avery!
Why'd you give me that guy in
the middle of a mass trauma?
- Avery?
- - The kid quit Webber's study.
What kind of idiot decides
working with the chief of surgery's
too taxing on his schedule?
He didn't quit 'cause he
thinks it's too much hard work.
He quit because he thinks the
chief has a shot at a Harper Avery.
He was worried that if his name was
on it, it would kill Webber's chances.
- Kepner! Discharges.
- Yep.
You know, she's the only one
who ever gave a rat's ass about you.
And now you might
have destroyed her career.
You should find some
skanky intern to love you,
'cause next time you're
in a burning building,
no one is handing
you a glass of water.
Please make sure you give
us a cell phone number...
- Matthew Ruiz? Do you...?
- No one
from the flight has arrived.
- As soon as we get...
- - Do you have a list of people
- they're bringing to the hospital?
- - It can take
Emergency Services quite a long time to move
and identify people in a situation like this.
- Just try to be patient.
- I'm sorry,
my wife was on the plane.
- Can you please just...?
- Sir, at this point we don't
have any information.
Please, just sign the sheets.
I'd like to speak to your supervisor,
somebody that knows what's going on.
Ma'am, my supervisor doesn't have any
information. Nobody has any information.
Please, just sign the sheet.
Dr. Hunt! I had way too many
drinks before I told you that.
- I didn't mean for...
- Not now, Karev.
Look, I told you that because I didn't
think she should be chief resident,
- not that she should be fired.
- If you didn't
think this through,
then you're as dumb as she is.
Hey. You OK?
Yeah, I'm fine. Uh...
The plane was from Baltimore,
where my parents live.
I've taken that flight, uh...
with my son.
You want to come sit
down with me for a minute?
No, no, no. I can't, uh,
there's too much, uh...
OK. Um...
I'm just gonna stand
here for a minute.
Is that all right?
- Are you on any medications?
- - No.
- Ever given blood before?
- Nope.
- Any chance you're pregnant?
- Mm...
- I don't know.
- When was your last period?
I'm not sure.
Uh, what were you doing, um, last
time you had to deal with tampons?
Like, maybe it was
St. Patrick's Day,
and you ate, uh, four
green donuts and thought,
"Wow, that's disgusting,
I must be hormonal."
Oh, my gosh, you're right!
Except it was these gross
cookies with green frosting.
But that was a while ago. Uh, I
guess I had mine again around Easter,
'cause I was all over the
Marshmallow Peeps. It totally works!
Hey! What the hell?!
It looks about six weeks to me.
Ahem. I take it this
wasn't deliberate.
- No.
- OK.
You want to talk about options?
No.
Officials say it's too
early to speculate
on the cause of the crash.
But here's what we do know.
The flight originated this morning in
Baltimore carrying 183 passengers
- and 18 crew members...
- Still nobody?
The families are going
crazy. What is taking so long?
Fishing 200 people out of
the water is slow business.
You want to play Angry Birds?
They'll do triage at the
waterfront. Takes time.
Actually, with it taking this long,
there's gonna be a lot of hypothermia.
- Kepner!
- Yeah. Warm blankets,
heated lamps
- and heated IV fluids. Got it.
- You post chief resident yet?
- No. Not yet.
- What's the hold up?
The suspense ain't killing
me. It's gonna be Grey.
Karev made a great play
for it. A plane full of orphans?
- That's pretty impressive.
- He's already decided,
- you don't have to lobby for your boy.
- - Karev.
I want a written account of
exactly what you saw. Every detail.
- When, where...
- Sir, I don't think...
I don't want to
know what you think.
I need more sedatives. The people we're
transferring are starting to freak out.
You're a good man, Avery.
Lexie's yours. Take
her. Take care of her.
I'll stay out of your way.
I kind of already
have her, but...
- thank you?
- You're welcome.
I need to talk to you.
You know, I think I'm gonna order
pizza. If you want I can get the...
I'm pregnant.
- Cristina.
- I cannot believe
this is happening.
I know.
I know it's complicated. I know it
wasn't supposed to happen like this,
but... Cristina, this
could be something...
What? No.
There is no way we're
doing this. Do you hear me?
- Cristina...
- No, I am not
this beautiful vessel
for all that might be
good about the future.
I am not carrying your
hopes and dreams, no!
I get to talk! I'm here!
There's two of us.
We are a partnership. Can we
just think together? Is that OK?
I know who you are. I know
what you want. I love you.
I don't love the incubating
potential of your womb, I love you.
Why would I want to do something
that would make you miserable?
You think I love you more when you're
miserable? Do you think I want that?
You running off to Meredith? You
think I'm looking for more of that?
- But... I think
there's a way...
- No! No!
I still get to talk. There is
a way to make this work
without it ruining your life
or derailing your career.
I don't want a baby.
Well, you have one.
Are...
- Are you getting
all lifey on me?
- How late are you?
- That does not matter!
- Of course it matters.
OK, fine. You tell me when life begins.
You know, I can't wait to hear this one.
I don't know. Does
it have hands?
- I cannot believe
you're doing this!
- I'm just asking a question.
I don't want one.
I don't hate children.
I respect children.
I think they should have
parents who want them.
I want them.
I want them, and
maybe you could, too.
I believe... your life can
be bigger than you think it is.
I know you can contain
more than you think you can.
I'm not saying we do this.
I'm just saying let's think.
Let's see what kind
of life we can imagine.
Cristina Yang...
I imagine such
a huge life for us.
This is an extremely
serious accusation, Meredith.
- Can't you tell me anything?
- I can't, I'm sorry.
Talk to me.
How many patients are
we talking about here?
- Did this happen
more than once?
- I can't say that either.
- She can't say anything.
- We're gonna
unwind this, Meredith.
Karev is figuring out what cases
he was on when he saw you.
He'll narrow down the dates,
we know which patients...
Nothing I did changed the trial.
- Fire me,
do whatever you have...
- You don't get to choose, OK?
You don't get to decide who
gets the drug or the placebo.
You don't get to decide
what information the trial gets.
Anything I tell you affects the
trial. If you don't know what I did,
- the trial stays blind.
- The trial is over.
You screwed me, you screwed this
hospital and you screwed yourself.
This is your disease
we're trying to cure.
- I could have
picked Parkinson's...
- It was Adele.
- But I I did this for you.
- Derek. It was Adele.
Uh, maybe I should put some IV
fluids in the heater? Warm them up?
- No.
- But if people
have been in the water
- for that long, they'll be...
- April.
But if we just...
No one's coming.
If it's taking this
long, nobody survived.
What are you gonna do?
- I don't know.
- The protocol is fairly clear.
Are you encouraging
him to fire me?
Derek, I basically pressured her
to do it. You'd have to fire us both.
I'm gonna have to suspend
you, so it doesn't look so bad.
The study... I need to turn the
whole mess over to the FDA,
let them figure out what
to do with it. I can't...
- Meredith, I don't
know how to...
- I know.
Emergency Services has
begun identifying bodies.
They've given us a list.
The airline reps are on their
way, we've got social workers here,
and more coming. It's a long list.
Each of you have families to inform.
So, uh, please be outside the
cafeteria in exactly one hour.
You'll call one family at a time,
and you'll be assigned a room
to take them to and deliver the
news. It's gonna be a long day.
That's it.
Dr. Hunt, you gave
chief resident to Kepner?
It was supposed to be me or Grey! You
think anyone's gonna listen to Kepner?
- It's gonna be complete chaos.
- Think anyone's
gonna listen to you?
You just sold out the one universally
liked individual at this hospital.
Everyone is gonna hate you. Chief
resident's supposed to manage peers,
be a resource and
support. After what you did,
do you think anyone is gonna
come to you for anything?
I was planning to give
it to you. But now...
So it's possible that it
won't ever... That we just...
- we just won't
get the treatment?
- It's a possibility. Yes.
Oh, my God. This isn't right.
We're so close. He
needs this! Can you just...?
- Is it killing people?
- No.
- So give it to him anyway!
- I wish we could.
No, don't give me that! You
can, and you're choosing not to!
- Audrey.
- No!
They say there's
nothing they can do?
There's a drug in a box in this
hospital. You were on the schedule!
My children's father is
disappearing! Give him the damn drug!
I could take a leave
for six months or a year.
- No, you couldn't.
- Sure, I could.
They're not gonna fire me.
- No!
- Stop saying no!
I'm telling you, I
want this, I can do this.
This does not have to be your
problem. It'll be my problem.
- You wouldn't even...
- What, notice?
It'll be a baby! I'm not a monster.
If I have a baby, I'll... I'll love it!
That's the problem.
That you'll love it. That's a
problem that we can work with.
- I'm sorry, are you
laughing right now?
- No. No, I'm just...
I'm not. I just...
- I love you.
- What is so...?
- Are you even listening to me?
- Yes.
I'm just trying to figure out
some kind of a compromise.
You know what?
There is no compromise.
You don't have half a
baby! I don't want one!
OK, it isn't about work, this
isn't a scheduling conflict.
- I don't wanna be a mother!
- Cristina, do you love me?
- Of course I do.
- Do you trust me?
- I... Yes!
- You'd be a great mother.
You would. I know you
don't believe me, but it is true.
Just sit with this
for a little while,
this terrible idea that
you might love a baby.
Just, for me, sit with it.
Did you even hear...?
OK. Why would I do that?
Because you love
me. You love me.
That's why.
I have three names. I don't
think I can do this three times.
One foot in front of the other. I've
got something that'll cheer you up.
Sloan gave us his blessing.
Well, that's not really right,
more like he gave you
to me, which was nice.
- Are you serious?
- Yep. I probably
owe him a goat.
- OK.
- All right. Let's do it.
Is the Schoman family
here? Jessica and Maxwell?
Jason Schoman, he's our son.
I'm Dr. Altman. Will
you follow me, please?
They think it's good news.
Elaine Chen.
Ma'am, I'm Dr. Sloan. Why
don't you come with me.
- Gilda and Miguel Ruiz?
- This is a nightmare.
Hi, I'm Dr. Bailey.
Come with me, please.
I can't wait to see her face.
Hey. I brought some pudding.
That's why you're here?
I've got a good nurse, she'll
hook me up with pudding.
I know. It's just...
I just spent the last two hours telling
people their family members were dead.
And I needed to... I
just wanted to say hi.
Or bye. Again. I don't know...
I really tried to be a
gentleman about all this.
But now you need
to get the hell out.
- What are you doing?
- Letting you go
was the worst
thing I've ever done.
It's the most painful
thing I've ever done,
and I'm a guy who's
had 82 surgeries.
My threshold for pain is
pretty high. You need to get out!
I'm not your best bud. I'm
not your security blanket.
I'm a man who's
in love with you,
who waltzed you into the arms
of a damn knight on a horse.
So go to Germany, and have
little spaetzle-eating children,
and please, for God's
sakes, leave me alone.
Cafeteria is pandemonium.
Wailing people everywhere.
You admitting anyone?
We're signing in a few so
we can give 'em sedatives.
That's about it.
ER.
There's a survivor.
- You leaving?
- No. I didn't get fired.
I know that's
disappointing to you.
My trial is about to disappear.
You really want to act
like I'm the bad guy here?
- No, I don't.
- I know the fact
that it is Adele
changes things for
Richard, but it doesn't for me.
- Oh, I understand that.
- You couldn't possibly
understand that.
If you were focused on the
millions of people with Alzheimer's
whose lives could've been different,
would've been better because of this drug,
there's no way in hell you
would've pulled this stunt.
How is it that you don't know the
difference between right and wrong?
Because I don't think that
things are simply right or wrong.
Things are more complicated than
that. This was more complicated than that.
It's complicated that it
was Adele and Richard.
It's complicated that we have a
drug in a box that could help her.
There's nothing
simple about that.
I am very sorry that I
messed everything up.
But I would do it again.
I don't know how to raise a child
with someone who doesn't understand
that there's a... a right
and a wrong in the world.
So now I'm gonna be a bad mother,
that's where we're going with this?
You've been saying it for weeks.
Maybe you're right.
OK.
I just need some time to think.
I just need some space.
Sarah Gordon, GCS at six, head injury
and multiple contusions to mid torso.
- Systolic 70s in the field.
- Unaccompanied minor?
- Yeah,
she was flying alone.
- On my count. One, two, three.
OK, I need X-ray in here. We
need to shoot a C-spine, chest...
- Abdomen's rigid.
- I've got the ultrasound.
Large hematoma on
the left temporal lobe.
- Folks, we've got eyes.
- Sarah, I'm Dr. Shepherd.
You see all these people
around you? They're doctors.
You ever seen this
many doctors before?
Don't worry, we're all here
to take care of you, OK?
Hey, honey. They found his body.
Because his wallet
was still in his pocket.
They said because the impact.
I don't know, maybe it was fast.
Oh, my God, I'm so sorry.
There's no battery. I'm pushing
the button, I don't hear anything.
- Honey, let me try.
- The battery is dead!
- What are you gonna try?
- OK, OK, OK, OK, OK.
Ma'am, can I help you?
We have to call someone,
but the cell phone's not working.
OK, well we have phones
that you can use. Jenny?
I'll do it. I'll do it.
Why don't you take a seat?
Excuse me. Is the
Gordon family here?
The Gordons?
- They found somebody?
- A little girl. Unaccompanied minor.
- They're operating
on her right now.
- Thank you.
We should go home, honey.
A little girl made it. She's
alive. I think we should stay.
She doesn't have anyone.
Her parents aren't here yet.
- I think we should stay.
- Gilda.
If Matthew had been...
I would like to stay.
OK, OK.
We'll stay.
I'll, um... I will let you
know how she's doing.
- Mer.
- The adoption lady's paging me,
Derek's AWOL, he's
not even speaking to me.
Wait. Is it true? What
were you thinking?
I was thinking that the chief's
wife was about to have saline
injected in her brain instead
of a drug that could stop her
from becoming a gorked-out
lump. Derek's head almost exploded.
- Are they gonna fire you?
- I'm suspended.
The chief backed way off
when he found out it was Adele.
- I did what I had to do.
- Meredith...
I couldn't live with myself if
I'd done anything different.
And Karev is
trying to ruin my life!
Mer.
- What did you say to her?
- I didn't say anything.
- Janet, anything he says...
- Can you shut up
for one second?
This isn't about that.
We're granting you
temporary custody of Zola.
Pending the completion of the petition,
at which point, assuming all goes well,
you'll be granted
permanent custody.
And her doctor here
says she's doing great.
So you can take her home.
Today.
Her incisions look fine.
She's tolerating a normal diet.
She'll need neuro follow-ups.
She's still on antibiotics.
Here's a prescription for any
pain meds she might need,
but she's been fine
the last couple of days.
Do you have any
questions about anything?
Meredith, do you
have any questions?
- Hey.
- Hi.
- You done?
- Uh, no, no.
I still have some more families.
Sorry I paged you, I just
wanted to see your face.
I think when something
like this happens, you just...
You want to be with
someone that you love.
So we're booked on
a 9am flight tomorrow.
Let's just spend the
night in some fancy hotel,
just never get out of the bath.
You OK?
Derek, I understand that you don't
want to talk to me, but this is important.
I need to talk to you.
I'm your wife. You
need to call me back.
Does anyone know where there's
a nurse or an information person?
- She should be right back.
- My daughter was in the crash.
They said she had to have
surgery. Are we supposed to...?
- You're Mrs. Gordon.
- Yes. Sarah Gordon is my...
They're still operating. The doctors
have been here every half hour.
- They'll be here any minute.
- Say, would you
like some coffee?
- I'll get it.
- Here, sit down.
- You must have
been driving like crazy.
- I don't under... Are you...?
We heard she was alone.
I thought, as a parent, if
my child was here alone, I...
We all thought that she should
have someone pulling for her.
Thank you. That's incredible.
Diapers. Swaddle blankets.
And formula.
These little bottles are
good for the diaper bag.
- You have a diaper bag?
- No.
We'll get you one, we've
got a few in the NICU closet.
We have all this gear. The parents
come in, the baby doesn't make it,
they don't want to see the
stuff, so they just leave it behind.
Now, here's the pacifiers.
She likes the green ones.
Is your husband putting
the car seat in the car?
I don't have a car seat. I'm
not even sure I have a husband.
Surgeons, right? You probably forget
what he looks like without a mask.
We'll get you one. You're probably
gonna need a portacrib, too.
I'm gonna throw in
some more diaper cream.
She went with her dad
to visit her grandparents.
He had to stay, so he
put her on the plane.
And there was a flight
attendant that watched her,
and was supposed to walk her to
her connecting flight in Vancouver.
You never imagine...
I'm sorry.
I never even asked, you
had someone on the plane.
My son, Matthew.
Is he in surgery, too?
Yes.
- Will he be OK?
- Yes. He will.
Sarah's out of surgery.
You can come see her now.
I'm gonna pray for your son.
Hey.
Can you stand up?
I thought I was
pretty clear, Teddy.
Just shut up and stand
up. I have to do something
and I can't do it while
you're lying in a hospital bed.
I don't want a goodbye hug.
It's gonna make you feel better,
- it's not gonna make me feel...
- Can you just stand up?
You're my husband, and...
and I think I'm falling
in love with you.
Hey. How you doing?
- Not now, Mark.
- Come on, Lexie.
- You've been
in the dead zone all day.
- You have to stop.
You gotta stop talking to
me and checking on me
and talking to my boyfriend.
I love you, and I'm
always gonna love you.
But I don't want to love
you, I want to be happy.
And Jackson makes me happy,
and if you keep pulling at
me, I'm... I'll come back to you.
You're right. I'm sorry.
You got what you wanted.
You wanted a family.
Please, just let me
have what I want.
I said you're right.
I told Avery I
was letting you go.
- Did he tell you that part?
- Yeah, it's
paternalistic and weird.
I'm letting you go, Lexie.
That means you gotta...
walk away.
Chief friggin'
resident. Unbelievable.
- I'm sorry.
- What? Don't be. You deserve it.
I'm happy.
- I have what I want.
- It's been such a crappy year.
I can't believe
we're both happy.
I can't believe they like me
enough to make me chief resident.
They hated me for so long. I can't
believe I actually have friends here.
Well, they're gonna
hate you again.
It's now your job to
boss them around.
You know how
much they love that.
Oh, God. Is that true?
That's true!
OK, so this is the house.
There's another house, where
you're gonna have your own room,
but that, right now, is
just wood and no walls,
so we're gonna stay
here for a while. Derek?
OK. He might be AWOL,
he's had a bad day
and he's a little...
pissed off right now,
but we're gonna be fine.
So we had a big plan
if this ever worked out.
We were gonna have a lullaby from Malawi
to make everything feel homey for you.
To be honest, right now I can't
even think of an American lullaby.
Lexie?
You know, a lot of people live
here. It gets kind of crazy sometimes,
and it's usually not this quiet.
Alex?
OK.
We're gonna be OK.
You and I, we're a team, right?
We're tough. We have that in common.
I am very glad you're here.
I didn't think your first day
was gonna be quite like this.
But I'm gonna get it together,
and we are gonna figure it out.
Tell me how much you love me.
I...
I love you a very great deal.
A lot.
You love me so much. I
want you to remember that.
I made an appointment
to terminate the pregnancy.
- You...
- I'm sorry if this upsets you.
I'm sorry if this isn't
what you wanted, but...
I cannot talk about it anymore.
I... need to lie down. I feel like crap.
This is a marriage.
I tied my life to you.
You don't decide
this without me!
- Do you see me standing here?
- My head is killing me.
You give in a marriage,
you make sacrifices.
I have made many. And I am
asking you to do something for me.
Could you simply consider
doing something for me?
Have a baby? This isn't pizza versus
Thai, you don't give a little on a baby.
- Cristina, I am asking you...
- I'm saying no!
Get out.
Are you...? Because
I'm denying you a baby...
Because you denied
me part of the decision.
me a marriage.
- Oh, how dare you!
- Get out!
- Hi.
- Hey.
I'm gonna go. I just
wanted to say good night.
I wanna come home with you.
N... No, I can't. Um,
Tuck's with me tonight.
I can meet your son. I'm
not gonna bite your son.
No, it's just not
the right time.
- I can't...
- This is a relationship.
Things today were bad. We lean
on each other when things are bad.
That information's not
gonna hurt your child.
And if it does, then this is not
the right relationship for me.
I can control myself in your
house. I'm not gonna touch you.
- OK.
- You can tell
him I'm your friend.
- Tell him whatever you need to.
- OK!
OK.
Oh. I was hoping you were Derek.
Sorry.
Well, he took off, and the
hospital gave me a baby.
She's upstairs sleeping in
some dead kid's portacrib.
Wow. Uh...
I'm getting an abortion and Owen
just kicked me out of my house.
- What? You're...?
- Pregnant.
- And you're...?
- Getting an abortion.
Well... Why didn't you tell me?
You had a busy, busy day.
There's a reason I
said I'd be happy alone.
- Come upstairs. I need help.
- I... I can't.
I've gotta lie down.
It wasn't 'cause I thought
I'd be happy alone.
It was because I thought if I loved
someone, and then it fell apart...
I might not make it.
Tell me not to go to Africa.
Alex.
Go to hell.
It's easier to be alone.
Because what if you
learn that you need love...
and then you don't have it?
What if you like it?
And lean on it?
What if you shape
your life around it,
and then...
it falls apart?
Can you even survive
that kind of pain?
Losing love is
like organ damage.
It's like dying.
The only difference is...
death ends.
This...
it could go on forever.