Whoa.
I don't think I've seen
the ED this quiet since...
I don't think I've ever seen
the ED this quiet.
- Could be the new moon.
- Or because NYU's
on spring break.
- I'd say I hope it stays
like this for you,
but I know you're a masochist.
- Uh, no, not anymore.
I've changed.
- Mm.
- Incoming!
32-year-old woman,
restrained passenger in MVA.
A van hit an embankment.
02 sats in the 80s
and dropping.
- Okay, she may need
to be tubed.
I'll get an airway box.
Casey,
draw up etomidate and sux.
- We got this.
One, two, three.
- Okay,
let's bag her with 100% O-2.
- Looks like
a class two airway.
- Incoming!
- Okay,
use a rapid sequence technique.
Casey, when you finish,
get a 12 lead EKG
and a stat portable chest.
- You got it.
- Restrained passenger in MVA.
- Man, I was good and asleep
and then all of a sudden, boom!
Glass was flying everywhere
and whatnot.
- Let's get her to bay 27.
- God bless...
just trying to get
an early start
back home to Alabama.
- Okay, ma'am.
- We were at this
church convention.
- Ma'am.
- Oh, no, excuse me.
- I am not a ma'am.
I am a Miss.
Miss Verdene.
- Miss Verdene, well,
I am Dr. Bloom,
and this here is
Nurse Brunstetter.
And they're gonna take care
of your lacerations.
- Okay, thank you.
- Okay, let's expose the skin,
irrigate the wounds,
and set up a suture tray.
- Yeah.
- This is Kaye Henry,
restrained driver of the van.
Airbag deployed resulting
in chemical burns
and a bleeding nose.
- We're from Holy Gethsemane
Christian Fellowship.
Everybody from our group
has insurance.
- That's okay.
- No, we can pay.
- Well, today, I am fixing
broken noses for free.
Bay 24.
- 40-year-old woman
in respiratory arrest.
- Seriously?
Let me guess.
Restrained passenger in MVA.
- Please, somebody help her!
Can someone please help
with her leg?
Please, please, someone.
Please, please,
don't let her die.
Mariana?
Mariana, bay 26.
Pneumothorax,
let's place a chest tube.
- Someone, please, please,
help her.
Please don't let her die.
Lottie's got babies at home.
- All right.
All right.
- Why's it so hard?
- Okay, ladies, I need for you
both to breathe for me, okay?
- Turan, compartment syndrome.
Measure lower right extremity
for anterior pressure.
- I'm not getting a good seal.
- Mariana,
angle the tube posteriorly
for better blood evacuation.
- Yes.
- Okay, Nurse Jackson.
- I'm right here.
- Nurse Jackson,
let's get this going.
Where's my cane?
All right, how you feeling,
Kaye?
- Okay.
- Good?
- Yeah.
- Okay,
keep that--that's right.
That's right.
- Chest pressure's equalizing.
- Great.
- Bloom, leg pressure's 40.
- Okay, do a fasciotomy
using the two incision
four compartment technique.
I need my cane.
- Ow, it hurts.
- All right, Kaye.
First time you've broken
a bone?
- Yeah.
- All right.
- This is gonna hurt,
hopefully not too much.
- Okay.
- Auntie Kaye.
- Chante!
That's my niece.
- Kaye.
You need to relax.
- I need to get to her.
- Auntie Kaye, where are you?
- Restrained passenger
in the MVA.
She has chest bruising
from the seatbelt.
- My chest really hurts.
- Okay, we're gonna take a look
at that.
Let's move Chante to a side bay
and get chest x-rays,
both PA and lateral.
- Okay.
- She's been sick
the last few days.
Nausea, vomiting.
- Kaye, I got her.
I promise.
The best way for you
to take care of her right now
is to take care of yourself.
All right?
You need to rest.
- Alfreeda Watson,
54-year-old...
Restrained passenger
in MVA.
- Got it.
- Her leg was trapped
under the seat in front of her.
- Okay, Ms. Watson,
does your--does your leg hurt?
- Well, it ain't childbirth,
but I 'spose it does
ache a touch.
Now, I'm not one to complain,
but I think that New York is
tired of all us ladies
here from Alabama.
- Uh, bay 28.
Let's get some x-rays
and page Kapoor.
Looks like nerve damage.
- Dr. Bloom?
Dr. Bloom.
- Yes?
Yes?
- Your nurse cut
my blouse--brand new blouse
clean off of me.
- And I've apologized
several times.
- Okay, Miss Verdene--
- It was a final call sale.
Now, what are they gonna do
about that?
They're stitching up my face.
They're gonna stitch up
my shirt.
- Uh, Brunstetter,
what have you got?
- Sister Mary Joseph node.
- Good find.
Okay, let's page Sharpe.
- Bloom,
pressure's bottoming out!
- I'm gonna be right back.
- What?
- Someone, I need my cane.
- Restrained passenger,
hit her head during an MVA.
- And this fool done put
an ice pack on it.
- You're in pain.
- But the damn thing leaked.
It's full of all kinds
of fake-ass chemicals.
- Okay,
we're gonna irrigate your head,
make sure all the chemicals
are washed away.
- Irrigate?
Oh, no, ma'am.
This is not wet and wild hair.
- Brunstetter!
- Okay, this is
Nurse Brunstetter,
and they're gonna take
great care of you.
- Bloom.
- Ooh.
I can't wait
to get back home.
- Take a look at this.
She's hemodynamically unstable.
- SVT.
We need to cardiovert her.
Come on.
- She's in defib.
Charged.
- Clear.
- Go again,
increase to 150 joules.
- Charged.
- Clear.
- We have sinus rhythm.
- Back to normal rhythm.
- Blood pressure's rising.
- All right,
vitals are stabilizing.
- Casey, pull up the portable
chest X-ray that you did.
- What are you thinking?
- EKG is showing low voltage
in the lateral leads.
Cardiac tamponade,
probably from that right there
on the chest X-ray.
- What?
- There's a shadow.
- Contusion?
- It's more like a mass.
Let's put Zoll Padz
on her chest
to shock her heart
back to a regular rhythm
next time it goes off
and page Reynolds.
- If one were more
conspiratorially minded,
one might think that you were
actually trying to avoid me.
Uh-uh.
- Rough night?
- You could say that again.
- Well, surely not because
of this adorable munchkin.
- Yeah, well, to her credit,
it does take commitment
to sustain six straight hours
of screaming.
- Well, like her father,
it would appear that
she's only content
inside a hospital.
- Yeah, cruel, cruel irony.
- Let me help.
I mean, after work,
I could take her
for a couple of hours,
give you some me time.
- That's very kind,
but I couldn't ask that of you.
- What if I insisted?
- Yeah, thanks anyways,
but we kind of got
a whole system going.
So we're good...
for the most part.
- You're right,
looks like a mass.
Well, based on the size,
she's had it for a while.
Any of these women know
her health history?
- Not that I can figure out.
- Where'd you want me?
- Sister Mary Joseph node
in bay 29.
- Let's take her up.
- Dr. Bloom, point me.
- Uh, bay 28, nerve damage.
- Okay, Ms. Watson,
I'm Dr. Kapoor.
I realize it might not
look this way now,
but you ladies really were
lucky,
considering that there were
so many of you in the van.
- So because I'm a black woman,
I must be
with all the other black women
you got up in here?
- No, that--not--that's not
what I...
what I meant was--
- Relax, I'm with them.
But you should see your face.
It's like you caught
a spirit or something.
- Is that a bad thing?
- Depends on what you say
about my foot.
- Well,
your foot is not broken,
but the swelling is troubling.
- Yeah, well,
that's nothing new.
As long as I can walk
my fields, I'm fine enough.
- You're a farmer?
- Fourth generation, soybeans,
when the foot isn't giving me
the blues.
- Have you seen a doctor
about this?
- You doctors want
so much out of pocket,
and I make too much
for Medicaid.
So I figure I just ride it out
until I qualify for Medicare.
- Unfortunately, riding it out
is not an option.
I need to ask a colleague
to evaluate it further.
Have a good day.
- I know you.
What's your name?
- Dr. Sharpe.
- No, no, that isn't it.
Dr. Helen.
You come on
after my stories sometimes.
Don't play.
- Okay, yes.
I knew it, Dr. Helen.
Fancy cancer doctor.
Oh, wait.
Are you here
because I got cancer?
- Verdene,
you don't have cancer.
- Miss Verdene.
- Miss Verdene,
you don't have cancer.
- You gonna swear
on them chunky earrings
you love wearing?
- No, they're not that big,
are they?
Miss Verdene, may I?
This reddish lump...
- Mm-hmm.
- Next to your belly button
is rather concerning.
It indicates an infection
in your lymph nodes.
- So what's that mean?
Antibiotics, a cream?
- I'm afraid it's not
that simple.
The infection's being
complicated by your diabetes.
- I got diabetes too?
Talk about buzzard luck.
My father lost a foot to sugar.
- When was your last checkup?
- Well, they closed
the nearest hospital to me.
Take me at least an hour
to get to one.
Now, who got time to drive
to two hours
round trip on top
of an appointment?
- Hmm.
Miss Verdene.
I'm gonna go get my colleague
to come and see you.
- Why?
- I think you just had
a seizure.
Vijay.
- Oh, good.
I have a black female,
54, farmer, dry sense of humor,
presenting asymptomatic
lower extremity edema.
- Black female, 52,
restaurant worker,
cutting fashion sense,
presenting
with petit mal seizures
and untreated diabetes.
- Okay.
- All right, I'm gonna need
a sternotomy tray,
a sternal saw,
and hand me the echo.
- ♪ Feel discouraged
- What is that?
- No idea what she's singing.
- ♪ Should the shadows
- She's induced,
spontaneous respiration.
- ♪ Why should my heart
- Forceps and chest tube,
pass it on the tray.
- Turn up her meds.
- ♪ And long for heaven
♪ And home
♪ When Je...
- You have those suture boots?
- Yeah, X-ray detectable.
- Oh,
she was almost to the bridge.
- You're interested in learning
to become a surgeon today,
Dr. Duke?
- She was singing--
- Get your head in the game.
Ten blade, please.
Thank you.
- We are ecstatic
to be considered
as adoption candidates.
Believe me.
It's just that to come
in--for us to in come tomorrow,
I don't know my--um,
I don't know
my husband's schedule, really,
and I don't wanna spring
anything on him--
on his schedule, I mean.
Oh, I see.
I see.
No.
No, no, no, no.
No, if tomorrow at 4:00 is
the only time you have,
then we will make it work
on our end.
Right.
Yes, thank you.
No, we look forward
to meeting you.
Okay.
Well done, Iggy.
Hi, Chante,
I'm Doctor Frome.
I work here at the hospital.
- Is it finally my X-ray time?
- No, it is not
finally your X-ray time,
because I have one
or two questions
that I'd like to ask you first,
if that's okay with you.
- Where's your white coat?
- The white coat, um,
I don't know.
You know, I haven't worn
that thing in a long time,
because I find that it makes
people feel more comfortable
when I don't wear it.
Plus, if I'm being honest,
I'm a super messy eater.
So lame.
- You're crazy.
- You're definitely not
the first person
to tell me that.
- So when's the X-ray?
- Well, Chante,
um, we can't give you an X-ray,
because you are pregnant.
We give a blood test to women
who don't know
if they're pregnant
before we give them an X-ray.
Because an X-ray can harm
the fetus.
Do you understand what it means
to be pregnant?
- I have a baby in me?
Am I in trouble?
- No, you're not in trouble.
No,
you're not in trouble at all.
Um, did you know
that you were pregnant?
- Maybe.
- Did you plan this?
Um, was the sex consensual?
Did you want to have sex?
- Who doesn't wanna have sex?
I like sex.
Do you like sex?
- Do I like sex?
Um, sure.
- Sex is great.
Wow.
Yeah, okay.
- Okay, yeah.
That's healthy.
There's nothing wrong
with liking sex.
I just need to make sure
that nobody did anything to you
that you didn't want.
- I wanted to,
and my boyfriend was
a scaredy-cat.
He forgot the condom.
- Yeah,
condom's pretty important.
Let me ask you this.
Do you have a plan
with your pregnancy?
- I want an abortion.
- Do you understand
what that means?
- I don't wanna--I don't wanna
have a baby.
- Sorry
for the impromptu music.
My mom used to sing
"His Eye is on the Sparrow",
like, every Sunday.
Yeah, after church, it was
laundry, singing, and folding.
- Angle that light for me.
- She was choir section leader
before she got sick.
The altos, music, church,
it meant a lot to her.
- Dr. Duke, I am fully aware
of the relationship
between black women and church.
They're everywhere
but the pulpit.
My mom doesn't let me
miss a Sunday,
but that's on Sunday.
- Can I have
the cardioplegic solution
sent down?
- Ah, damn it.
- What's wrong?
- The mass causing
the tamponade has grown
through the chamber wall.
Where is the echo I asked for?
- On its way
from Hastings' surgery.
- Get it here now.
- Can you do a resection
to remove it?
- The way it's positioned
posteriorly,
I have to remove the heart
entirely
and then resect the mass.
- And then put the heart
back in?
- Prep the SCS bath
on the back table.
Ms. Henry, I'm Dr. Goodwin.
I just wanted you to know
that everyone in your group
has stabilized except
for Tamala Robeson.
- Her family's so worried.
How is--
- Whoop, you okay?
- I'm fine.
- Why don't we take a seat?
- Why don't we have a seat?
- No, I'm fine, really.
- Tell me about Tamala.
- There was a complication.
During surgery,
we found a tumor,
and it was there
long before the crash,
but it has penetrated
her heart.
So there's a number of things
we can do,
but I need you to understand
that your friend is facing
a very high-risk operation.
- Well, it's covered.
Anything she needs is covered.
I organized our trip.
It's all right here.
Look.
When we rented the van,
we paid for the personal injury
insurance.
I've read the policy,
there's no limit.
So she's entitled to
the best care you can offer.
- Hmm.
- The very best.
And I made everyone pay
the extra $7.50
for the insurance.
They carried on a while, but--
- Well, I'm sure
they're thanking you now.
- Dr. Goodwin, would you be
open to praying with me?
- Um, I'm not really the most
prayerful of guys.
Sure.
- Heavenly father
from whom all blessings flow.
It was your will to work
through this accident.
Bless the hands
of these surgeons
as they do your work.
We are your instruments, Lord,
prayerful or not.
Bless us and show us the way.
Lucky the accident happened
so close to us.
- Mm.
Some are calling it
an act of God.
- What do you think?
- Well, I know is that
half these women came in
with a host
of preexisting conditions,
diabetes, cervical cancer,
hypertension.
And then they crash
right when they need care most.
I don't know.
I'm a cynic.
I mean, maybe it was
divine intervention.
- Yeah.
Maybe there was
an intervention.
I just don't know
if it was divine.
- Is there an update?
- Uh, no update.
I just, uh...do you mind
if I sit?
Um...I met this woman once,
and the amazing thing
about her was that
she loved her friends...
more than anything.
And her friends were
in trouble,
through no fault of their own.
They couldn't get the care
that they needed.
So she decided that she was
gonna help her friends...
No matter what.
So she did something dangerous.
And I would never tell you
her name,
because I don't wanna
get her in trouble.
Because I respect her.
- I expect
she appreciates that.
- But I do have a question
for her.
How did things get so bad
that the only way she saw
to save her friends
was to crash their van?
- Perhaps it's what
this woman saw.
She had a friend who used to
love going for walks.
Now she can't breathe.
One's in and out
of a wheelchair,
another died too early.
This woman sees it all,
sees her friends at church,
praying for the hospitals
to return,
for money to buy medicine,
for deliverance slow to come.
So maybe she prays
for something different,
for the strength to act,
for a sign,
and she gets nothing.
Until a nice young man
at a van rental office
offers to sell her supplemental
injury insurance.
You spend your life wondering
what salvation will cost,
and the answer turns out to be
$7.50.
All I had to do was
one scary thing...
And all our prayers were
answered.
"So do not fear,
for I am with you.
"Do not be dismayed,
for I am your God.
"I will strengthen
and help you.
I will uphold you
with my righteous right hand."
- Meaning God will see you
through?
- Meaning sometimes
you wait for the right hand
of God,
but sometimes the hand is you.
- So me losing my concentration
is me having a seizure?
- In some cases.
Petit mal seizures present
in different ways.
- And this is
from the diabetes too?
- Uncontrolled diabetes
puts you at a high risk
for strokes and other diseases.
You should not drive until
you get this under control.
- Well, if I can't drive,
how am I supposed to get
to a doctor for help?
- A church member
can't drive you?
- An hour each way?
- Perhaps family?
- No one I can rely on.
I'm always bailing them out.
- So what am I dying of?
- Miss Alfreeda,
you're not dying.
- Tell that to your face.
- The swelling in your leg,
we thought that it might be
cancer or a blood disorder,
but it's neither.
It's your kidneys.
They're failing.
- So I am dying.
- Well, your GFR is 16,
which means that the creatinine
isn't clearing
from your kidney,
which means you need
a new kidney.
- Well, it's a good thing
I brought a spare.
- Well, you did bring a vanload
of potential donors.
- You want me to take a kidney
from one of my church members?
- A blood relative
would be better, though.
Do you have any family?
- No, I don't have any family
here.
- Stop telling tales.
I'm her much younger sister.
- Right.
I forgot about her.
- See--you see how she is?
I was gonna do
the Christian thing
and offer up one of my kidneys,
but I ain't doing it now
unless she asks
for once in her life.
- Nobody is asking you
for anything.
- Like, when I helped you keep
Mom and Daddy's farm last year.
Go ahead, tell the truth.
Shame the devil.
- You know what?
That's right, baby sister.
Go on, keep Christ
in your heart and your kidney,
because I don't want nothing
from you.
- We'll have only two hours
for this.
Why is that, Dr. Duke?
- Because we're harvesting
the patient's own heart.
After two hours,
the organ will degrade
beyond viability.
- And the mass?
- Is presenting posterior
as a left atrial mass.
- And I can resect it
with clean margins
in about 45 minutes,
maybe another 45
to restructure
the heart muscle.
- That leaves you
with 30 minutes
to sew it back in
and warm the trunk.
Is there enough time for that?
- Sitting about
4 degrees Celsius.
- Okay.
All right,
ladies and gentlemen,
listen up.
Now this may be
an atypical surgery for us,
but what is typical is
our efficiency
and our precision.
So use them today,
and we may have a chance
to save a life.
Okay?
Let's get after it.
- You're fully on bypass.
- SVC partial dissection
complete.
- Transecting
the ascending aorta.
- Pulmonary artery clamped
and dissected.
- Aortic cross-clamp off.
- Removing the heart.
- Resection tray
right behind you.
- Heart is on the move.
Start the clock.
- Pregnant?
Chante, you pregnant?
- Yes, ma'am.
- Is it Mario?
What'd I tell you
about messing around
with that fast-ass boy?
The baby.
Is the baby okay?
What with the accident...
- The fetus is totally unharmed
as far as we can tell.
Thank you, Jesus.
Okay.
We're gonna figure this out.
- I don't wanna be a mommy.
- Oh, baby.
I know it may seem scary
right now,
but Auntie Kaye will be
right here.
I took care of you, didn't I?
We'll get through this.
- Ms. Henry.
Chante has expressed
more than not wanting
to be a mother.
- Meaning?
- Well, why don't we let Chante
take this opportunity
to share her feelings?
- I want an abortion.
- Did you put her up to this?
- No, but she is
clearly articulating
her choice to end
this pregnancy.
- Then she should have
clearly articulated
that I am her legal guardian,
and I am in charge
of her decisions,
including her medical ones.
- Okay.
I--you need to know
that I'm just here
in support of Chante
and what she wants.
And it seems like
this pregnancy
would be a burden.
- Because you think we couldn't
care for this baby?
- That's not what I'm saying--
- We are more than capable
of taking care of our own.
Every child born
into this family is loved
and extremely well
taken care of.
Chante's child will be
no different.
- But is that what's best
for Chante?
- Based on what,
your 45 minutes of knowing her?
- No.
- Folks always want you
to make a choice,
then look at you funny
when you don't make the choice
they wanted you to make.
One side shakes their heads,
saying you're oppressed,
the other filled
with so called "Christians"
who don't give a damn
as soon as the baby
gets pushed out.
But let's be clear.
This black family right here
ain't being co-opted
for anyone's crusade.
- Oh, Max!
What about if I got you
a food service?
- Don't need it.
- It would take the pressure
off of cooking.
- Luna's still bottle feeding,
so...
- Not for the baby, for you.
- Oh.
- Be my treat.
- Yeah, I'm good.
I eat most of my meals
at the hospital anyway.
Have you tried
the pretzel and hummus combo?
It's very--
- Max.
- I'm good.
- Why won't you let me
help you?
- You know what?
How 'bout this?
When I need your help,
I'll ask for it.
- Speech therapist
to distro four.
Speech therapist
- How's our group?
- Most are recovering,
and we've got aftercare plans
for the noncritical ladies--
- Are you the medical director?
- Is this about
my unpaid parking tickets?
- We're following up
on the accident on the FDR.
I'm Detective Grove.
This is Detective Vasquez.
- Oh, why don't we discuss
this outside?
- We'd like to have
a conversation with the driver,
Kaye Henry.
- Well, she's recovering.
- If she's awake and conscious,
we wanna talk to her.
- And if she isn't, we'll wait.
- Kaye, the police are here
to speak to you.
You understand there will be
repercussions
if they find out the crash
was intentional.
- And the only option is
to tell the truth.
So what are you saying?
- That I don't want you
to go to jail
or your friends to lose
their insurance.
- But they didn't do
anything wrong.
They don't even know
what I did.
- It doesn't matter.
Deliberate actions negate
the policy you purchased.
- For a while there,
I really thought I was doing
God's will.
But this and Chante...
I was all wrong.
Now it's time to do right,
Dr. Goodwin.
This isn't in my hands,
never was.
- Kaye, what are you gonna
tell the police?
- I continue to be thrilled
that I am an only child.
- What do you mean?
- Verdene and Alfreeda letting
decades old personal drama
get in the way of their health.
- Will it kill Alfreeda to ask?
It's a kidney.
- But why offer someone
something
and then make them ask for it?
- Asking isn't such a big deal.
- So it makes perfect sense
that Alfreeda could die
while Verdene keeps
her kidney hostage,
waiting for her to ask for it?
- It's about respect.
Verdene has sacrificed
her own health,
swooping in to help
her entire family,
never getting
a word of praise.
- I'm sure no one ask her
to be their savior.
She's doing it
for the attention.
- That's not true.
- Of course it is.
She's gotta be the bride
at every wedding
and the corpse
at every funeral.
- Come on,
show her some R-E-S-P-E-C-T.
Respect.
- Respect is earned,
not demanded.
- Hi, Chante.
- Hi.
- So Chante, I brought
Dr. Bloom here with me,
because I thought
you might feel more comfortable
speaking with a female doctor.
I also wanted to tell you that
we went around the hospital
and we spoke to some lawyers
here.
- And if you want to have
an abortion, then you can.
- Yeah.
- But Kaye said no.
- Yes, I know,
but as your guardian,
she is there to support you
whenever you can't
make a decision on your own.
But in this case,
I think it's very clear
that you can.
- And as you're
only nine weeks,
it is still legally
your choice to make.
- I don't want Kaye mad at me.
- Chante, you know,
I had to make a choice too
when I was your age.
Doing what was right for me,
it helped me make that choice.
Didn't make it any easier,
but it did make it clearer.
Do you wanna have an abortion?
- Yeah.
- Okay.
Now, look, since you're
under guardianship,
we just need to ask you
a few more questions.
- More questions?
- Just to make sure
that you have
thought everything through.
Like, after the abortion,
what's your plan?
- My plan?
- Your relationship with Kaye,
um...
it may change.
- Like, if she's mad
and doesn't want me
to live with her no more?
- Not living with Kaye is
a possibility.
Something that you have
to think about.
- And I can't lose Kaye.
I can't lose Kaye.
- Which is why we need a plan.
- I don't need a plan.
I don't need a plan.
I need just Kaye.
- Uh, excuse me, Detective,
where you taking her?
- The precinct.
It's none of your concern.
- Uh, you're taking a patient
out of my hospital.
I'm very concerned.
Kaye, what did you say?
- Nothing,
just that she lost her way.
So now we go to the precinct.
- I'm attaching the aorta.
- You have 45 seconds.
- Still have to do
the pulmonary vein.
Duke, I need those hands.
- Target core temp
is 37 Celsius.
- Sir?
- That's the pulmonary vein.
Right there.
Use your 6-0 Prolene stitch.
Don't back wall the vein, stat.
- Give me a 6-0 Prolene
on a stick tie.
- Idle breathing looks good.
- She's normalizing.
- You have five seconds,
but they're flicking by.
- Vitals are stable.
- Ah, the boot should be wider
- Time.
Time, Dr. Reynolds.
- I hear you.
Almost there.
- Full shocks, holding.
Detractor number two.
- Clamps.
Duke.
- Done.
- Charging.
Clear.
Got a heartbeat.
- I got a pulse.
Dr. Reynolds.
- The brainwaves aren't
picking up.
Brain's warming too slowly.
- Does that mean
she has brain damage?
- We won't know
until she wakes up.
- A little help here.
- Get her to bay 24.
What happened?
- We were driving away
and she just started seizing.
- Casey, do a finger stick.
- What's going on?
- We need ten units of insulin.
- Blood glucose at 550.
- I need ten units of insulin,
subq.
- Is she okay?
- Kaye's a brittle diabetic.
- Brittle?
- It's a form of diabetes.
It manifests with dramatic
spiking of blood sugar levels.
- Could that have caused
the accident?
- Very well could have.
- How are you feeling,
Miss Verdene?
- Well, it ain't childbirth.
How long till you know
if I'm a match?
- Could be as soon as tomorrow.
- You can say thank you now.
- I could.
Fine.
Thank you.
- Now, was that so hard?
- Well done, Vijay.
Acting out their ridiculous
feud in front of them.
- Who was acting?
- You weren't really upset,
were you?
- Talk to my hand.
- Um, hi.
- Hi.
- I should learn to accept
a blessing
when it's offered to me, right?
And to be, you know,
less of a jerk.
- Well, it's about time.
Oh, and some other ideas
I've been noodling:
a diaper service.
Or what about a CSA?
Or how would you feel about
your very own car service?
- It all sounds great.
Surprise me.
- Okay.
- Auntie Kaye!
- Chante.
You're about to squeeze me
in half.
- I don't wanna lose you.
- I'm not going anywhere.
- Don't go, don't go.
- I'm right here.
- The court is restoring
Chante's right
to make this medical choice.
And, um...she hasn't made
a decision yet,
because she's a little bit
scared of how
it might affect
your relationship.
- Auntie Kaye,
will you still love me?
- Always.
But you're blocking a blessing,
Chante.
- No, I'm not.
God's with me.
- God is with you?
- I prayed no baby.
God crashed the van here.
The doctor said "no baby," see?
- I crashed the van.
It was me.
God had nothing to do with it.
- God's in you.
- Is God in me?
No.
No, that's not--
I don't know.
I hope so.
- Auntie Kaye.
Auntie Kaye.
- Still no change?
- No.
Tamala kind of reminds me
of my mom too.
It's just we, uh--we haven't
talk much lately.
Family stuff.
- Well, if this was your mom,
what would she want right now?
Couldn't hurt.
- ♪ Why should I feel
♪ Discouraged
♪ Why should the shadows
♪ Come
♪ Why should my heart
♪ Be lonely
♪ And long...
- ♪ Why should I feel
♪ Discouraged
♪ And why
♪ Should the shadows come
♪ His eye
Amen!
- ♪ Is on the sparrow
♪ And I know
♪ He watches me
- Hey, Mama.
No, no, no, nothing's wrong.
I, uh...
I just called to tell you
I love you.
- ♪ And I sing
♪ Because I'm free
- Could you enter this
in the database, please?
- ♪ His eye is on
- Shall we wait
for your husband?
- You know,
he's not gonna make it,
but we are both very excited
about moving forward
with the adoption process.
- Okay, great.
Come on in.
- Thanks.
- Have a seat.
- ♪ His eye is on
♪ The sparrow
- ED's still empty.
How'd the changed woman
enjoy her shift?
- You know,
it was exactly what I needed.
- Tidy Town Cleaners.
Are you...Dr. Goodwin?
- Uh, yeah, but I didn't--
- The bill's covered,
tip included.
A gift from your friend Helen.
- Right.
- May we come in?
- Sure.
Sor--you know what?
Sorry.
Actually, I'm good.
I'm okay.
Thank you.
- Oh, but we've already--
- Thank you.
- Yeah, sorry.
- But we've already--
- No, no, I appreciate it.
Thank you.
Hey.
Hi.
Come here.
Okay.
Hi.
Oh, I got you.
Hi, hi, hi, hi, hi.