NARRATOR:
Previously on Private Practice:
MEG:
I figure we can see what this is.
- I want a divorce.
- Yes, you do.
You've got something
called Wegener's disease.
DOUG: I may not be in love with her,
but I'm staying with my wife.
VIOLET: The construction on the fourth
floor is for a competing medical practice
- that Charlotte is running.
- I'm done.
KEVIN: I got shot.
- Kevin, hey.
[DANCE MUSIC PLAYING ON TV]
Oh, come on.
That is the worst runway walk
I've ever seen.
She's not fierce. Eliminate her.
[PHONE RINGING]
Cooper, I told you,
when the models are walking, do not call.
Doug?
Calm down.
No, no, no. It's okay. It's okay.
It's all right. Don't cry.
It's all right. Yeah, I'm coming over.
VIOLET: Doug?
DOUG: Come upstairs.
- Doug, what's the...?
- Upstairs.
VIOLET:
What's going on?
Where's Karen?
Doug?
- She's in there.
- Karen?
She's been so sick. So sick, and...
Oh, my God.
I didn't know who to call.
You're still my therapist. L...
- I didn't know who to call.
- Okay.
- It's gonna be all right.
Doug?
I killed her.
I killed my wife.
[YELLS]
You did that on purpose.
Oh, come on, man.
If you didn't suck, you wouldn't get hit.
I don't suck. I played on a team, man.
- You suck.
- Oh, say that to my face.
I am saying it to your face. You suck.
- Oh, we need women.
- Word.
I hate racquetball.
Man, Charlotte is working in the building.
I can't get away from her.
Well, Naomi, she's right down the hall,
two doors away. Think that's easy?
- You know, I wish she would just die.
- Whoa.
No, not in a bad way.
Just, like, slightly dead.
Then I wouldn't have to see her face.
She'd just be a memory.
- You ever wish Naomi died?
- Hey, man, that's the mother of my child...
Yes, I do, actually.
When she had sex with that guy,
I wished she was dead.
- Yeah. All right, let's go again.
- I got you. Okay.
[CELL PHONE RINGING]
Hold up.
- What's up, Violet?
- She's calling you?
She wouldn't let me call when the models
are walking. Why is she calling you?
- Traitor.
- Okay, all right.
Okay, I'll be right there.
I'll be right there.
PETE: Just a few more notes to make.
Ten minutes, tops.
Don't worry about it.
Gonna go for another run.
I figure I can get five miles in
before bed.
You ran this morning, and you don't run.
Who are you?
- What have you done with Meg?
- I am bored. I'm out-of-my-head bored.
I'm running bored.
You know what I do all day? Nothing.
And after that, nothing.
And then a little more nothing.
What do people do all day
who don't have jobs or kids?
I can't spend all my time
running around the neighborhood.
My thighs are killing me.
- I'm freaking out here.
- Hey, hey, hey.
I know it's frustrating
being in a new place,
finding out where you fit in,
but don't run. Get a job.
Find the right opportunity.
A job? As in stay?
Yeah. I want you to stay. Now, why
don't we hurt your thighs a little more?
In a non-running way.
- I'm going home.
- You're not going home.
I don't wanna...
Would you stop bathing me
like I'm an invalid?
Well, you got shot.
- You wanna be both shot and dirty?
- I'm serious, all right?
I don't wanna be your responsibility.
I don't wanna be...
- I don't wanna be a burden.
- You're not a burden.
Kevin, look at me.
You're not a burden.
Let me take care of you.
Karen was out of her head
with the pain.
The blood...
She was always spitting up blood.
Her condition was fatal, you know that.
And she was begging me to help her.
So I just...
I did. I helped her.
All right, Karen was sick for months,
and I know that she was dying,
but there were so many other ways
that you could've helped her.
Palliative care, social services,
- pain management.
- She didn't want that.
She was done. She just wanted to go.
- So you shot her in the head?
- Sam, Doug has been through a trauma.
They had a troubled marriage.
He said he was gonna leave her
before I diagnosed her.
Karen was...
- She was helpless.
- It's not like that.
Doug, keep your voice down.
Sam, this is not the time...
- What's gonna happen to me?
FALLON: Time to go.
I was only trying to help her.
You have to tell them. Please.
- So you're his shrink. And who are you?
- Dr. Bennett is... Was Karen's doctor.
Karen was suffering from kidney failure
secondary to Wegener's disease.
She was sick, I get it.
Doug called you,
instead of calling the police?
He panicked, and I called Sam
and I called you.
He ever talk about hurting his wife?
Wanting her dead?
- Well, l...
- Well, whatever he said is privileged.
It's a yes or no question.
VIOLET:
Unless Doug releases me to talk to you,
or I'm subpoenaed,
I'm not gonna say a word.
So you're okay protecting a murderer?
- I'm protecting my patient.
- What about you, Dr. Bennett?
You gonna stay silent, or are you gonna
protect your patient, Karen?
We're leaving. Sam.
I...
The elevator's mine.
You can have the fourth floor,
but the elevator's mine. Take the stairs.
Tell you what.
I'll give you one more day
to calm yourself down,
work through your anger, angst, whatever
it is you're all hot and bothered about,
and then we're gonna get together
and discuss this like grown adults.
I'll tell you what, Charlotte.
Go to hell.
- Oh, my God. He shot her?
- Wait. He "shot her" shot her?
PETE: As in "killed her" shot her.
- Killed who?
Doug Adams murdered his wife
last night.
He did not murder her.
He said she begged him to do it.
Oh, God, that poor man.
- The poor woman.
- Then it was a mercy killing?
- Yes, yes. Dell gets it. It was euthanasia.
- It was a bullet to the brain.
I knew Karen was sick,
but was her condition that bad?
Yeah, it was that bad, but, still,
they were not a happy couple.
Look, I know Doug,
and he is not the type to...
There is no type. Regular, normal people
are driven to murder every day.
Right? Love? Love will do it every time.
Twisted, sick, messed-up love.
Cooper, Charlotte King
is still alive, right?
Yes, I wasn't talking about me.
I'm just saying, the impulse,
we all have it.
- Hey.
- Hey, I didn't know you were coming here.
- Can I talk to you?
- Yeah, sure. Give me one second.
Not you. You.
NAOMl:
Yeah.
What'd I tell you about the elevator? L...
I'm not talking to you.
[KNOCK ON WINDOW]
Charlotte King.
Oh, yay, my day is made.
- I need a favor, Montgomery.
- Oh, that's rich.
You open a practice right underneath us,
and you need a favor.
I wouldn't ask if it wasn't important.
I'm not coming to you
from Pacific Wellcare.
I'm coming to you from my capacity
as chief of staff at St. Ambrose.
As chief of the hospital
where you retain surgical privileges,
I'm hoping we can be civil.
- What is it?
- No, don't engage.
Breathe, Cooper. We can be civil.
What is it?
Pregnant mom
who needs your expertise.
Nice try. Every pregnant mom could use
Addison's expertise.
- This case is special.
- What do you mean, special?
Alena DeGray. Full-term pregnancy.
Eight months ago,
she was in a car accident.
- Doctors did everything they could, but...
ADDISON: She's comatose.
And in early labor.
Okay.
CHARLOTTE:
Sean, this is Dr. Montgomery.
She's an OB/neonatal specialist.
- Would you mind if she examined Alena?
- No. No, please.
Uh, Alena, she just moaned.
That's good, right?
She hasn't done that
since right after the accident.
Moaning is a good sign
that she's starting to respond?
I think it's just a sign of labor.
Sean, the neurologist told you,
she's non-responsive.
I'm so sorry for your loss.
She wants this baby so much.
We found out she was pregnant
the day before the car accident.
I think it was the happiest day
of her life.
Every day I sit here
and remind her about that day
so she has something good
to think about.
ADDISON:
Baby's in a breech position.
- Our OB tried ECV to turn the baby, but...
ADDISON: She's down too low.
I need to do a C-section.
Wanna book an OR?
SEAN:
No.
She needs to go through labor.
She needs to deliver this baby herself.
Sean, she can't.
The breech position
puts the baby at risk for a prolapsed cord,
which would cut off
the baby's oxygen supply.
The head could get trapped,
potentially causing brain injury or worse.
Yeah, woman in Kentucky,
situation just like Alena,
having the baby, it woke her.
Alena needs to deliver this baby naturally,
on her own.
She has to,
or I am never gonna get her back.
Alena is going to wake up.
And we're gonna be a family again.
He's going to kill his own child.
He loves her. He's sat here every day.
He wants her back.
She's not waking up.
"Rip Van Winkle" is a fairy tale.
- Don't tell me you're going sentimental.
- Hardly. Just...
I find him touching.
Great. You wanna comfort him
when he loses them both?
There's really nothing you can do
to help her deliver naturally?
No, and even if she could, the chances
of her coming out of that coma are...
- Almost none.
- I need to do a C-section.
I need to get the baby out now,
or both mom and baby could die.
We can't make him.
We can't force him to let us cut her open.
Look, maybe if you talk to him,
get to know him.
He warms up to you,
and you help him understand...
No, that's your job, Charlotte,
as chief of staff.
My job, as consult,
is to get the baby out.
- I have a practice to get back to.
- So do I.
We have to work together
to help that family.
Yes, we do.
I'll put her on terbutaline
to stop the contractions,
but that'll only get you through the day.
I'll consult Legal,
see if there's any way we can override
the father and do the C without consent.
Okay.
VIOLET: She was dying.
She had Wegener's Disease.
She was dying,
but the pain was under control.
You know as well as I do
that can fluctuate.
I know that he hated her.
And I know that from you.
Then you also know that
he chose to stay in the marriage.
He could've left, and he didn't.
Why now?
She was gonna die in, what, six weeks?
Three months?
You think after years and years and years
of this marriage,
he would shoot her now?
They had a volatile relationship.
All right?
Now, you may have seen his side,
but I saw hers, and she...
She was not suicidal.
- Well, Doug was not homicidal.
- Except for the gun in his hand.
- I don't think it was like that.
- Well,
the cops are gonna want a statement
from both of us.
And I'm gonna tell the truth.
Well, if Doug gives me permission
to talk to them, so am I.
The actual truth,
or the truth that you wanna believe?
NAOMl: No. No. It's...
No, it's fantastic. I'm serious.
- What's going on?
- I like her, Pete.
I went down
to the Venice Family Clinic today
to offer my services.
Turns out they have a huge overflow
of patients, but not enough exam rooms.
But with Naomi's help,
we found some room here.
- Here? At Oceanside Wellness?
- When the clinic has too many patients,
- I'll see them here.
- Addison's always talking about how,
with Charlotte's practice opening,
we need to expand our
community outreach and raise our profile.
Meg is the perfect liaison.
Plus, she's willing to let Dell shadow.
Oceanside Wellness
gets to generate possible future income,
and I get to avoid going stir-crazy.
Everyone wins.
Yay.
What?
Nothing.
It's great. You'll be great here.
- Welcome aboard, Meg.
- Thank you.
You have the face.
- I don't have the face.
- You told me to find an opportunity.
I did. Welcome aboard.
All right, I have to go find Dell
and get set up.
- See you later?
- Yeah.
Sorry.
Is it always this slow?
Only when someone stops it.
We're not moving, are we?
No, we're not.
Are you okay?
You're not claustrophobic, are you?
No, just impatient and in a bad mood.
Anything I can do?
It's an occupational hazard.
I'm a therapist.
And to be honest, I'm a bit nervous.
Interviewing for a new job,
you know, so...
- On the fourth floor?
- Yes. You work there?
- Uh, no. I pushed 5, remember?
- Right.
- Well, if you need to talk, if there's...
- I'm a shrink too.
I think I can handle it.
Oh, I'm Sh...
I'm Sheldon Wallace.
Have a nice day.
This is all yours for the day.
- Is there anything else you need?
- No, this is perfect.
Better than I'm used to.
Can I just say, Dr. Porter, that
I'm very excited to be working with you.
- Meg, please.
- Meg. L...
I was blown away by the work you did
for the women of the Fulani tribe.
I read an article on it.
I just know I'm gonna learn so much
working with you.
Well, I bet you could teach me
a few things too.
- I'm just starting.
- Well, here at Oceanside,
I'm just starting too.
I need someone to clue me in.
- Candy stash under the microwave.
- See? That's critical information.
Well, Dell, it looks like
our first patient together is Renee Olsen.
Okay.
- Renee Olsen?
- Yes.
Hi.
- I'm Dell Parker.
- Hi.
Um, I was referred to Dr. Porter
for, um, termination.
- I'm sorry?
- Termination.
Abortion?
Oh, no, there must be some mistake.
We don't do those here.
Um, but they said... I wrote it down.
- Dr. Meg Porter
for abortion services,
Oceanside Wellness Group.
Am I in the right place?
It's not like I don't want her here.
I just don't...
- Want her here.
- She just did it. She didn't ask me.
Welcome to my world.
I guess it's better than her
going and getting a job with Charlotte.
When you're working with somebody
that you love you gotta be respectful.
You gotta communicate.
That worked so well for you and Naomi
you got divorced?
It's not like she went behind my back.
- She...
- Went behind your back.
- Stop finishing my sentences.
SAM: Okay.
You know, she's a good doctor.
She's gonna be fine.
Hey, did anybody know
Meg was gonna be doing abortions?
- No.
DELL: I know I'm not a partner,
and you might be okay with this.
I wanna go on the record saying I'm not.
- Not okay with what?
- Meg working here.
Oh, yeah. Nai told me.
Pro bono clinic, I think it's great.
- She's doing abortions.
- And?
Oh, wait,
you men have a problem with it?
No, not as men.
- We respect the choice, but...
- I don't.
Um, I'm not commenting.
- We just didn't know.
NAOMl: You didn't know what?
- Meg's doing abortions here.
- She's what?
If only because of the way
this practice is set up...
Women coming in for that having to sit
next to newborns here for a checkup.
- Don't you think we should've
discussed it?
What are we gonna do, tell them no?
Refuse women who ask for them?
Yes.
- Really?
- Ye... Really.
Hey. Nice digs you got
in those exam rooms.
They're palatial compared to grass huts.
- What?
- You should've told us
you were gonna be doing abortions.
Okay, everybody without a vagina,
leave the room.
Unless you wanna fight with me.
- This is a problem?
- No.
I run a fertility clinic. I am in the business
of helping women to get pregnant.
- Whoa, wait.
- Not...
Abortion is legal
in the United States of America, Naomi.
- Are you against choice?
- I am not gonna argue Roe v. Wade.
I am just saying,
they have never been done here.
They should never be done here.
It's a valid medical procedure
for women in need.
Not for me. And not for this practice.
[PAGER BEEPS]
Sorry. Uh, I have to run.
- Addison.
- I don't have a problem with it.
So you're gonna unilaterally
make a decision for all of us?
I'm saying we said she could work here.
She can work here.
- I'm ready for Renee.
- She's gone.
What? Where?
I don't know where.
I just know that she's not coming back.
Well, what happened? Is she okay?
Except for the part about
her planning to kill her baby.
- What did you say to her?
- Gave her my opinion.
- You talked her out of it?
- I just told her what I thought, okay?
I have work to do.
- I want you out of this room.
- Everyone, let's calm down.
I have sat in this room every day
for eight months.
I am not gonna let you come in now
and make decisions...
Sean, I got a message that
you're ready for me to do the C-section?
- I told you no. I meant no.
- We want you to do the C-section.
These are Alena's parents.
Ronald and Jennifer DeGray.
I called them
after I had Legal do some checking.
Turns out
Sean and Alena are not married.
He has no right
to make decisions on her behalf.
We were gonna get married
after we found out about the baby.
I mean, just because we didn't,
I am still family.
I am the only one looking out for her.
Don't you think we want her back?
But she's not waking up.
That's what the neurologist says.
That's what we have to live with.
If you need to do a C-section
to help the baby, then do it.
Please. No.
The parents have the legal authority.
They're right to use it.
The baby's at risk, Alena's in a coma.
To me, there is no choice.
I'm sorry, Sean.
I will schedule a C-section
for this afternoon.
Dell shamed a young woman
for wanting an abortion. Drove her away.
Great standard for patient care
you got going here.
It was unprofessional
and we'll talk to him.
But we need to talk too.
You offered abortions to patients
without consulting anyone else.
I'm a doctor. I don't need
to consult anyone about my medical care.
- In Africa...
- This isn't Africa.
You're a doctor
who's working with six other doctors
who have opinions about cases
and about the reputation of their practice.
Oh, I'm screwing up your reputation?
That's what this is about.
You completely disregarded
everyone else who works here.
So, yes, that does reflect on me.
This is my domain.
Okay, so here it's not about doing
the right thing,
it's about doing what everyone else
thinks you should do.
Your domain feels a little
like a cult, Peter.
No, Meg, it feels like a family
that's just getting back to normal,
and I am not going to stand here
and let you mess it up again.
Fine. I'll go.
I hope you enjoy your family.
It's off.
Baby daddy went to court to get
an injunction as guardian over the baby.
- Not gonna be any surgery. Not today.
- What?
No. The patient is prepped
and ready to go.
If we don't get that baby out, we risk
the chance of it developing hypoxia.
- Damn it.
- I know, I'm sorry,
but there's nothing I can do. Scrub out.
[ADDISON SIGHS]
So, what next?
I'll see if I can convince the judge
to get over here and clear this up.
Yeah. If the baby lives long enough.
- Can I ask you?
- What?
- Cooper.
- You betrayed him, Charlotte.
So how long is he gonna make me pay
for my crime?
He's angry.
I don't see that ending any time soon.
Yeah. Okay. Yeah.
- You're in love with him.
- I am not. L...
I am not.
This doesn't make us friends.
We're not friends, Montgomery.
Don't go getting any ideas.
I have no intention
of being friends with you.
They're saying I murdered her. I didn't.
I helped end her pain.
Sam says...
- He thinks...
- When's the last time Sam saw her?
Two weeks ago?
And for what, maybe half an hour?
He didn't see
how walking up a flight of stairs
got to be more than she could take.
I did.
I had to listen to her moan in pain
when the drugs wore off.
And panic when she didn't cry,
because I thought
maybe she had died from a nosebleed.
That's what we both had to live with.
Nobody else.
The Karen you met
was a strong woman.
But...
But that woman was gone.
The one who took her place
just wanted it to be over.
Well, there were other options, Doug.
Hospice care, a nursing home.
I did what she wanted.
Look...
I know Karen and I
had a lousy marriage.
I don't even know
if I loved her by the end.
But I did care about her.
I just wish you had called me first.
We could've talked about it all.
Your feelings, your marriage,
the decision that you made.
My lawyer says
they're going for first-degree murder.
I can't...
Do you know what it's like in here?
Please.
Please help me.
I waive all privilege.
Whatever it takes.
Just tell them. Tell the police.
Tell them I didn't murder her.
Dr. Turner, you know me.
Do you think I murdered her?
Meg?
- What can I get you guys?
- I will have a tonic water with lime, please.
- I thought the surgery was off.
- For now, but Charlotte's trying to find
a legal way around it, and I have to stay
on my game. I have a patient at home.
- How's Kevin doing?
- I'm driving him crazy.
He hates me taking care of him
and he feels like a burden,
wants to contribute and I'm tired
all the time. But, come on, drink.
- Uh, glass of Pinot.
- Belvedere martini, dry and very dirty.
Oh, I need it. I was in jail all afternoon
talking to Doug.
He wants me to talk to the DA
and explain why they should be lenient.
- Are you gonna do it?
- I don't know. Talk about something else.
I think Charlotte King might be in love
with Cooper.
- Oh.
- Too little, too late.
Her new practice is about to open.
Hey, I ran into one of their docs
this afternoon. The therapist.
- Totally underwhelming.
- You wanna talk underwhelming? Meg.
Is it true that Pete found out Meg was
doing abortions and asked her to leave?
- Not exactly.
- Because if that is true, that is ridiculous.
What, Pete asking her to leave,
or doing the abortions?
Pete. Well, don't tell me you have
a problem with Meg doing abortions?
What, in our office?
Without even asking us?
- Naomi...
- What? I spend all day, every day,
trying to help women make babies,
who stopped believing
that they ever could.
If someone's gonna be in the next room
terminating pregnancies,
don't you think
I should know about that?
Especially as someone who's
not even a member of our practice?
I can't believe
this is such an issue for you.
I wish that I had known a doctor like Meg
or a place like our practice
when I needed an abortion.
I had two.
I had a very misspent youth
and made some mistakes.
- You don't have to tell us.
- I wasn't going to.
- But I'm not ashamed.
- I was.
I had one, and I was embarrassed.
And scared.
I was everything a woman shouldn't be.
Well, I fertilize eggs every day,
and I believe that life begins at conception.
- So, what, it's murder?
- I believe what I believe.
- I believe things aren't so black and white.
- Well, you don't do what I do.
No, I deal with women who
have had children who shouldn't have.
Maybe we should talk
about something else.
What are you doing here?
I just thought
you might be in the mood for a drink
after a hard day at the office.
- No, thanks.
- Cooper...
Get out from the front of my door.
Move.
I'm sorry, okay?
I'm sorry.
I'll do the time.
Whatever you want. I'll do the time.
But I am sorry.
Just go home.
I needed time to think.
So I thought in my hotel room
with the crisp white sheets
and the travel-size toiletries.
- You didn't have to do that.
- I need to know what this is.
What we're doing here, because when
I'm in your bed, everything's fine.
But at your office, I was the enemy.
- You're not the enemy.
- You have two modes.
Off and on.
And when you're off, Peter,
you get cold.
You're closed, you're shut down.
It's like you're punishing me
for something that I didn't do.
You never used to be like this.
The man I knew...
We used to share everything.
So, what happened?
What happened to you
between then and now?
The clinic is good.
What you do for people is good.
I overreacted.
Come back.
You're not the enemy.
Good morning.
So the district attorney's gonna
subpoena Karen's medical records.
Great.
Uh...
I can understand how you wanna believe
Doug acted out of mercy. You treated him.
You're vested in how he behaves,
but sometimes even the best therapists
can't stop somebody
from going down the wrong road.
Hey. You are a great therapist.
If Doug had listened to your advice
and gotten out of that marriage,
we wouldn't be in this situation.
I'm not looking for a free pass, Sam.
Just looking for the truth.
- Good morning.
- Not so good.
- Are you okay?
- I was up all night trying to figure this out.
I cannot get the image of Doug
with that gun in his hand out of my head.
- So then you do think it's possible that...?
- No.
I don't know. No.
L... I wish there was somebody
I could talk to.
Somebody who knows about
this kind of thing. I'm kind of in
uncharted waters here.
I think I know someone you could talk to.
Okay, I have to get to the hospital,
so you two talk. But not too long.
[KEVIN CHUCKLES]
KEVIN:
I'll be good.
[KEVIN SIGHS AND GRUNTS]
Sit down.
Sorry. I don't mean to bother you
while you're recovering.
Oh, please, bother me.
So Doug Adams killed his wife.
You probably don't have a lot of patients
who've done that.
- I deal with murderers every day.
- Well, that's the thing.
How do I know if it's murder
or assisted suicide?
Doug has had no difficulty with impulsivity
or anger control his entire life.
He was submissive to his wife.
I've never found any indication
that he was remotely violent.
In fact, I would be hard-pressed
to concoct a scenario
in which he had the temerity
to strike out against his wife,
unless she instructed him.
- So they didn't have a good marriage?
- He could have divorced her.
We talked about it. He chose to stay
to take care of her.
You don't think he got scared to leave
and took the easy way out?
Killing Karen
would never be the easy way out for him.
I just don't think Doug murdered his wife
in cold blood.
Then you should go with what you know
as a professional.
- Okay.
- Except, um...
What?
In all my years in the force, you know how
many women I've seen kill themselves,
or ask to be killed, with a gun?
None.
That's what I know. As a professional.
What's best for the child
is to have a mother.
- What's best for the child is to be alive.
- I will not hear shouting.
You want me to defer this
to the courtroom?
We can put the attorneys together
and have them drag it out until it's too late.
I wanna hear from you.
The baby's in imminent danger.
If I do nothing,
it could suffer irreversible complications.
And the hospital's position.
Do you support Dr. Montgomery?
We wanna give Alena every chance.
That said, judge,
we don't dispute Dr. Montgomery.
- It is her only chance.
- Sean, Alena is our daughter.
If we thought for one minute
we could have her back...
It's not gonna happen, is it?
That she'd wake up?
No, I'm sorry. It's... It's just not.
You've been here every day, Sean.
And we respect that. We just...
We couldn't do that.
We had to let go.
You have to let go.
JUDGE:
I have two choices, Sean.
I can rule on this,
or you can withdraw your objection.
I'd rather it come from you.
You look like you're in a hurry.
Thanks.
- So we're stuck for a minute, right?
- Yeah.
- Look, I'm sorry about yesterday.
- Ah, we all have bad days.
- Today any better?
- Actually, no.
- I don't suppose you wanna talk about it.
- Yeah, it's complicated.
Transference?
Psychosis?
I'm kidding.
Murder.
Or manslaughter.
Wow. That's big.
- You must be good.
- Yeah.
You'd think.
You know, the best way
to cheer yourself up:
- Cheer someone else up.
- Is...?
Is that your brand of therapy?
What is that, Jung, or Freud,
or fortune cookies?
It's Mark Twain, actually.
You like Twain?
- Yeah, I do.
- You see? There you are.
You've cheered me up.
People who like Twain
always cheer me up.
- Did you get the job?
- I got the job.
VIOLET:
Hey.
[GROWLS]
Ooh, that bad?
[GROANS]
Use your words, sweetie.
Charlotte apologized.
- Did you forgive her?
- No.
Should I? Am I being petty
like a small, petty, little man?
Yesterday I would've said no,
absolutely not, do not forgive her.
She demeans your entire relationship
with that practice downstairs.
But today...
Maybe?
I don't know.
But anger and resentment
can build up until...
Oh, I don't know anything.
Just don't wear an orange jumpsuit
and ask me to testify.
- We need to talk about Renee.
- I'm busy.
This won't take long.
Dell.
You have every right to your own feelings
and opinion about abortion.
If that's the issue, I'm not here
to try to change that.
But if you wanna be a midwife...
We work really hard
to create babies here.
We are in the business
of bringing babies into this world.
Look, I don't know you very well.
I certainly don't know you well enough
to judge you for this.
But you don't know Renee very well,
yet you were quick to judge her.
What, was she raped?
Would it matter if she was?
Would that make it okay?
I mean, does that make her
more or less worthy?
- Ahem.
- We don't get to know why.
That is her business.
That's her choice, Dell.
That woman agonized
over a difficult choice,
made it, and came in here.
I guarantee you she was already worried
about people out there judging her,
only to have you
make her feel ashamed.
But we are medical professionals.
It is part of our job to support her
once she has made
the hardest choice imaginable.
- You're not allowed down here, Sean.
- I know. Look, I just... I can't...
I made her laugh.
I made her laugh,
and she looked away from the road, and...
I caused it.
I was responsible for her coma.
I don't wanna be responsible
for her staying like this.
Please. I know what the judge said.
But...
I need a miracle here.
I'm asking for a miracle.
You were not responsible for this.
This is out of your hands.
You have to stop punishing yourself.
Sean, you didn't make
that accident happen,
and you don't make miracles happen.
But I do.
I'm about to go in there
and deliver your miracle, Sean.
And I know that this isn't the path
that you sought out,
or the one that you and Alena
saw for yourselves.
But this is your baby.
The baby that Alena wanted,
and the one
that she would want you to raise.
So I'm gonna go in that OR,
and I'm gonna bring out that miracle.
Did you talk to the DA? What'd he say?
You know, I didn't talk to him yet.
I wanted to talk to you more.
I was worried about you, here.
Thinking about what you did,
what you had to do.
It must've been awful.
- It was.
- To do that to someone you loved.
And to have her ask for that.
For her to ask you to use a gun.
She was just...
She was in so much pain.
She wanted it to end.
But a gun?
Karen wanted it to be quick.
She was afraid
that something else wouldn't work.
- She was just in so much pain, and...
- I know, I know.
I know all about her pain, Doug.
But what about your pain?
I wanna know about your pain.
NAOMl:
Dell?
[SIGHS]
You're anti-abortion.
I am.
Yeah, unapologetically.
Do you think it makes a difference why
a woman would want to have an abortion?
- Like rape or...
- I think it matters why it bothers you.
- What do you mean?
- Well, if you're against it
for religious beliefs or personal beliefs,
that's one thing.
God or something in your soul
is trying to tell you something.
I refused to even learn
how to perform the procedure
in medical school. I couldn't. I just...
I couldn't.
But if abortion bothers you
for other reasons...
- What?
- Look, I don't wanna be responsible
- for swaying you to the other side.
- What?
Did your child's mother?
Uh, did she consider
having an abortion?
You tried to talk her into getting one.
Yeah.
And now you look
into your daughter's beautiful face,
and you feel guilty.
We went to the clinic,
and she wouldn't get out of the car.
And I yelled at her.
I yelled at her.
And, you know, now I just...
I just can't believe I yelled at her.
Then I think you are not against
a woman's right to choose.
You're just punishing yourself
for the choice you almost made.
Until you let go of your pain,
you're never gonna move past this.
- I've told you everything.
- You released her.
You gave her everything she wanted.
So you should feel
like a weight has been lifted.
But you don't, do you?
It's hard to feel that way
when I'm in here.
It must've been hard.
Her in pain. Yelling at you.
Wanting you to help her.
She made you feel awful
every day of your life.
So you must've thought
that by helping her,
the pain would go away.
But it hasn't.
Because the truth
is still eating away at you.
I couldn't take it anymore.
You need to let it go, Doug.
Just let it go.
She kept yelling at me.
For me to do things for her.
She would say things to hurt me.
She would lie in that bed
and throw things at me,
and call me an idiot and a weakling,
and tell me everything I was doing
was wrong,
when all I wanted to do was help her.
And the more she would yell,
the more she would bleed.
And there was blood everywhere.
And I couldn't take her.
And I couldn't take the blood, and...
And I stopped feeling sorry for her.
And all I thought about
was that I should have left her.
I couldn't leave her now.
I couldn't just walk out the door.
But I couldn't stay.
I couldn't hear her yell anymore.
I couldn't hear it.
So I took the gun,
and I stopped it.
I stopped her.
You murdered her.
- I put her out of her misery.
- No.
You put yourself out of your misery.
- How's it going?
- Ugh. I lectured Dell.
Which I was right to do.
But he has a right to his beliefs.
So now I feel guilty,
and now I need a hug.
RENEE:
Dr. Porter?
- Renee. I tried calling.
- I know. I got your message.
I am so sorry
for the way you were treated.
Dell was out of line, and I apologize.
I'm just glad
you didn't ignore my message.
Yeah, well, I did ignore it.
I mean, I listened to it,
but I wasn't going to come back.
- I don't understand. Why are you...?
- Dell called me.
Oh.
Oceanside Wellness
performs its first abortion.
Wonderful.
DOCTOR: She's throwing multiple PVCs.
ADDISON: Bolus her with a hundred of lido,
and start a 2-milligram-per-minute drip.
- Lap pad.
DOCTOR: Lost her pressure.
V-fib.
ADDISON: She's going into cardiac arrest.
Get a crash cart.
She's thrown an embolus.
Start CPR, epi 0.5.
- Let's go.
DOCTOR: Baby.
ADDISON:
Got her.
[EKG BEEPING RAPIDLY]
ADDISON:
Charge to 200.
Clear.
[DOOR OPENS]
Okay, you ready?
- You ready to see Daddy?
JENNIFER: Ohh.
She's beautiful.
JENNIFER:
She has your nose.
And Alena's eyes.
ADDISON:
I'm so...
So sorry for your loss.
Sean?
I'm afraid you can't.
It's against hospital regulations.
I want her to meet her mother.
And I wanna say goodbye.
This is our daughter.
Look what we made.
Um...
I don't know
if you hear this a lot from us,
but thank you.
I hope you know she made
the best decision she could for herself.
I just always thought
medicine was going to be
about helping people.
It is.
- Naomi.
- Uh...
Dell, I'm proud of you
for doing what you felt was right, but l...
Well, I just can't.
Not now.
SHELDON:
We're on the same time schedule.
Cheered anyone else up?
- Can I ask your professional advice?
- Sure. Step into my office.
Well, let's say you have a client,
and this client has been through hell.
And it's a client that you like.
You really like.
And they've done something wrong.
Or maybe they've done something right
for the wrong reasons.
I'm not making any sense, am I?
Did anyone get hurt?
Yes.
So you have your answer, don't you?
I'm...
I'm Violet.
Violet Turner.
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
You asked what happened to me
between then and now.
I have a dead wife that I hated.
Hated.
Until the moment she was gone.
And if I could
take back the hate...
But I can't.
And it killed a piece of me.
There is a piece of me
that no longer exists because of her.
- So when you feel threatened...?
- There are very few women that I trust.
You trust the women here.
Naomi, Violet, Addison.
- They're family.
- And I'm not?
I'm trying, Meg.
I'm doing the best I can, okay?
Okay.
He's going to prison
for a very, very, very long time.
Yeah.
Poor Karen.
I feel so guilty
that I ever believed in him.
Are you at all religious?
No.
Well,
in church,
when someone dies,
we light a candle to remember them.
What are we doing?
Trying to forgive ourselves.
Can I get in on that?
A baby died today.
Hey, you.
Long day?
Let me make you something to eat.
You must be starving.
Addison, you took care of me.
Now let me take care of you.
I'm fine.
I made a miracle today.