Your primary care doctor was
right. The mass is on the smaller side.
We'll confirm with
the new images
but it should be
manageable with medication.
No surgery needed.
Well, my fiancé
will be so relieved.
He's been worried I'll look
like Frankenstein in our photos.
Also that I might die.
When's the big day?
June.
You've been dealing
with wedding planning
on top of a pituitary tumor?
You deserve a medal.
Our medical record
system on the other hand.
It has you listed as female.
Probably because
of the Pap smears.
Software clearly needs a
trans update. Deep breath.
I'll fix it so everything
is correct going forward.
Please confirm your
gender and pronouns?
Male, he, him, his.
Thanks for asking.
We're the ones with
the messed-up software.
Your scans from this
morning were just uploaded.
In less than two weeks, the
tumor has doubled in size.
♪ You're just too
good to be true ♪
♪ I can't take my eyes off of you
You'd be like Heaven to touch ♪
Thirty-four-year-old female, Zara
Norton. Tachycardic and delirious.
Dr. Guerin, update vitals. Dr. Wolke,
draw bloods for C.B.C. and electrolytes.
♪ Oh, pretty baby Now
that I've found you, stay ♪
Pupils are dilated but reactive.
Ms. Norton, smells like
you've had some marijuana?
Mm-mm. I just unloaded a
shipment at the dispensary.
- Test for THC and a full tox screen.
- I'm a peddler.
♪ Not a user ♪
Run it.
BP's elevated, 180 over 115.
That could explain the delirium.
That sounds high.
I better take my meds, got
'em here, I never miss a...
Oh, no. Wait.
No, that's not it
BP's climbing, 210 over 120.
Enalaprilat, 1.25mg, I.V.
Do you remember the
name of your medication?
You can call me Zara. See
it says right here, on the...
Forget about the meds,
she is not taking any.
This is untreated
chronic hypertension.
What if you're wrong? What
if she's on a loop diuretic
for her pressure? This
could cause renal failure.
She's headed into
hypertensive crisis.
What if we try an angiotensin
receptor blocker? No drug interaction...
Angiotensin receptor
blockers work too slowly.
I'm giving her
the ACE inhibitor.
- BP's going down.
- Yeah.
Nice call.
Latest budget report.
Yeah. The PDF's sitting in
my inbox. I'm trying to ignore it.
And thus...
A sit-down visit?
Just checking in to
see how you're doing.
Okay. You?
Me? I'm... recovering from
the year, like everybody else.
Pandemic, the surge...
You were here for every
minute of every day.
It must have taken a toll.
I mean... Comes
with the territory.
You're not, stressed
or distracted?
I'm... tired.
Okay, well, maybe you
should take some time off?
No.
But thank you. I'm fine.
You don't seem fine.
Are there issues with
my work performance?
- No, you do great work.
- Then I'm not sure
why we're having
this conversation.
Because I'm worried about you.
Because other people
are worried about you.
There's no shame in
struggling a little bit.
You know what would be weird?
Is if you didn't struggle at all.
If you need to see someone,
the hospital will cover the cost.
Great. You'll pay my bills.
And the damage to my
reputation, who takes care of that?
I don't think that
seeing a therapist will...
affect your career.
Says the white guy.
Okay.
Privacy protections
are there for a reason.
No one needs to know.
Thank you for checking in.
How're you feeling?
Good.
Be better when I understand
what landed me up in here.
You had an acute
hypertensive crisis.
I know my blood pressure's high.
I'm already on medication for it.
You probably wanna know what it is.
There's no medication.
We need to do an echocardiogram
to make sure your heart
wasn't damaged in the crisis.
Fine by me.
Here's 10 percent
discount on any purchase
over $50 or more
at Z&B Naturals.
I'm Z, B is my partner Bill.
You're surrounded by
pot all day every day,
- but you never touch the stuff?
- How? Why?
Just never been my thing.
- The name always trips me up.
- Chlorthalidone.
That's for hypertension.
The bottle seems pretty full.
How long have you been on this?
About six months. Just
refilled it, take it every day.
Smile, head tilt.
Now he smiles...
burst of laughter...
Okay.
Yeah. Okay.
Rio Gutiérrez, 29, pituitary
mass went from manageable
with meds to likely surgery.
So talking to the new
radiology resident?
I wanted Dr. D'Souza's opinion
on an intriguing set of scans.
She is very talented.
You're crushing on her.
No. I am not. I love Lea.
Those two things
aren't mutually exclusive.
Mr. Gutiérrez's blood
has high levels of prolactin.
Prolactin is produced
in the pituitary gland.
The tumor could be secreting it.
Or the tumor could be reacting
to the high levels of hormones
being produced
elsewhere in the body.
The patient is a
transgender man.
Do an ultrasound.
Advance the probe until
you see the cardiac chamber.
Maybe Zara has secondary
hypertension due to renal vascular disease.
She doesn't. Her creatinine is
1.2. Her GFR is in normal range.
Well, that would make it
unlikely, but not impossible.
It'd also explain why her
prescribed hypertension meds
weren't working,
and why she got better when
you gave her the ACE inhibitor.
Simpler explanation:
she's not taking her meds.
Valve looks normal.
Should I move on to
the two-chamber view?
Yeah.
We have no reason
to think that she's lying.
She seems to be telling
the truth about her pot usage:
no THC in her blood or urine.
She couldn't possibly be
lying about something else?
The left ventricle is
thickened, which is consistent
with untreated hypertension.
Heart rate is climbing.
Cardiac output is dropping...
- Stroke volume as well.
- She's in cardiogenic shock.
Would you mind if I did an
ultrasound on your abdomen?
For a brain tumor?
This is my fiancé, Eli Simpson.
When I heard about the new
scans, I kind of stormed the castle.
My hero.
Your prolactin levels are very high,
which might be caused by the tumor,
unless another condition
raised your prolactin,
encouraging more growth.
What condition boosts prolactin?
Do you think I'm pregnant?
He can't be. He's
on testosterone.
Except for a few
weeks last month.
I forgot to take my
shot before our trip.
- But there's no way that...
- You're pregnant.
You went into cardiogenic shock
because your heart
wasn't pumping adequately.
We did a minor procedure
and installed an Impella pump,
but it's a short-term solution.
I do feel a little
out of breath.
But that might be just
because of you, Dr. Andrews.
Ms. Norton, I'm a married
man. And your doctor.
You have a rare condition.
Certain parts of your heart muscle
have become abnormally thick.
So, this wall in between the
chambers, that's the septum.
That's a normal one.
This is what yours looks like.
Wow.
It's gonna require surgery.
We're gonna run a few more tests
to determine the best approach.
What? You going to be
my surgeon, Dr. Andrews?
I sure will.
And y'all two gonna be with him?
Yeah.
My lucky day.
Three doctors of
color taking care of me.
Doctors who won't
talk down to me.
Not exactly what I'm used to.
You guys know what I mean.
My mother made me wear a suit and
tie whenever we went to the pediatrician.
Put on your Sunday best just to
get on a scale and touch your toes.
Yeah.
Made me so mad I wound
up becoming a doctor.
The testing confirmed
your tumor is a
hormone-producing prolactinoma.
And the pregnancy is
about six weeks along.
Do you consider yourself gay?
- I don't think that's...
- Yes.
Because I am gay.
But you have vaginal
intercourse with your fiancé.
- That is how he got pregnant...
- Dr. Murphy, that's enough.
Yeah. I... I'm just...
- I think you should leave.
- I just want...
I'm sorry. That was
completely inappropriate.
Our treatment
plan for your tumor
depends on your plan
for your pregnancy.
So...
We've talked about kids,
but I always figured that
was way down the road.
And not this way.
I always assumed we'd adopt.
I'd have to go
off T, and stay off.
If Rio doesn't
continue the pregnancy,
then what happens?
Your hormone levels
would drop quickly,
which would cause
the tumor to shrink.
After that, we'd use medication,
possibly a minor surgery.
I'd like to terminate
the pregnancy.
I looked over all Zara's
labs. All signs point
to her taking her hypertension
medicine regularly.
Her MRIs show significant
ventricular septal thickness,
bad turbulence jet flow.
There's myocardial edema too.
ACE inhibitors were a bad call.
Well, it's eventually sent our
patient into cardiogenic shock.
Why did you ignore
what she was telling us?
I made a medical
diagnosis based on...
pattern processing that
we're taught in med school,
which involves considering, you
know, race, education, occupation, BMI.
Always sounded
like profiling to me.
California, San Jose,
specifically. Yes, we have the rain.
But more impressively, the wind.
That rain's gonna be
coming in sideways.
Just take a look at
how the wind increases
as we progress throughout the day.
So this afternoon, we're talking about
50 mile per hour
gusts possible...
Sorry for crashing.
Radiology doesn't have a TV.
You like The Weather Channel?
I find it soothing.
Would you like to join me?
Now you got the wind picking up.
Now you have your more
intense rainfall coming through.
And that's gonna also
lead to some flood potential
because all of us are
gonna get into the action.
You got the mountains...
Would you mind if I lowered
the volume by four output levels?
A flood potential.
Oh.
That would be perfect.
All the areas around here in
northern California, Modesto,
Stockton, Sacramento...
I find the reflection on
the screen so distracting.
So do I.
Could I...
do this?
Nurse paged me.
Is something wrong?
I've changed my mind.
I want to keep the baby.
Since you're continuing
the pregnancy,
we'll need to surgically
remove the prolactinoma.
So you'll cut into his brain?
Our safest option is to go
in through the nasal cavity
in what's known as a transsphenoidal
surgery, T.S.S. for short.
It's less invasive
than our other option.
That still sounds dangerous.
I've made up my mind.
Do I get any say in this?
I'm all for us having a
family, but I'm not ready to...
No one's ever ready for kids.
Yesterday, you said that you'd
never considered getting pregnant,
and now you're willing
to risk your life for it.
When I was about 7,
I had this one refuge.
I'd hang a quilt
over a couple chairs
and hide out with my two buds...
Foxie the Fox and Fuzz the Lion.
And I'd imagine I was the dad...
and they were
my twin little guys.
Fraternal, obviously.
We were a family.
When I transitioned, I
put that dream aside,
at least as far as
them coming from me.
But now...
Whether we planned it
or not, this is our baby.
How soon can you do the surgery?
I'll order an image-guidance
MRI to get things started.
Based on the cardiac
MRI and catheterization,
there are two treatment
options: myectomy,
basically open heart surgery,
and alcohol septal ablation,
where we use the alcohol
to kill targeted sections
of the heart muscle.
But what would you recommend?
The surgery is more
invasive, tougher recovery,
but better efficacy long-term.
The ablation is less
dangerous, but you're more likely
to need further
medical interventions.
Now you call that
a recommendation?
There are pros and cons to both.
But you'll need to weigh
them. I'll give you some time.
You always want to take
care of people, Dr. Browne?
Pretty much.
Me too.
You run a marijuana dispensary.
It's not all about
getting people high.
No. Maybe not, but I'm
guessing most of your clientele...
My great Aunt Lucy
had pancreatic cancer.
A year, she hung on.
In agony.
Marijuana was the only thing
that helped her eat or sleep.
Doctors didn't give her
anything for the pain?
They suggested ibuprofen.
Now, you know
doctors are 22 percent
less likely to give pain meds to
Black patients than white patients
with the same symptoms.
My point is, you and
I, we're a lot alike.
We're both strong, Black women
finding our way in the world.
But one of us knows more
about medicine than the other.
So,
I'd like to know: what
would you do in my situation?
The open myectomy is a bigger
risk, but offers more long-term benefits.
I made my decision.
I'm with you, Dr. Browne.
Book the myectomy.
Here's the Rio Gutiérrez
imaging for your upcoming T.S.S.
Set that on the table, please.
I, um... I noted the tumor's suprasellar
expansion and surrounding edema
and its splaying of
the Circle of Willis.
That is very helpful.
Bye, Dr. Murphy.
You're safe, Shaun, she's gone.
Not really.
Dr. D'Souza is still in
my brain. I don't like it.
We kissed.
- What?
- When?
I have so many
thoughts about her.
And I have so many
questions I want to ask Rio.
Wouldn't he get
more pleasure from...
Questions you're not supposed to ask.
The kiss, Shaun? When did you kiss?
Last night. In my dream.
If I can't ask questions,
how do I understand?
My... My brain...
My... My brain isn't
behaving the way I want it to.
How do I make it stop?
You're attracted to Dr. D'Souza.
Why does that bother you?
When I was with Carly
and had feelings for Lea,
it meant I was
supposed to be with Lea.
What if this means I'm
supposed to be with Dr. D'Souza?
No. You've loved Lea for
years, this is just... attraction.
But shouldn't loving
Lea make it go away?
Relationships would be a
lot easier if it worked that way.
You're feeling guilty.
I say take Lea out for a nice
dinner, something special.
And tell her about my
crush. I need to let Lea know.
- No. Definitely not.
- No. You do not.
I wanna get your thoughts
on the suprasellar extension
of the tumor for this T...
You remember Sarah Pepper,
runs Nephrology at S.F. Regional?
Always wears a shawl?
So during a staff meeting
last week, she fell apart.
Screaming, crying, in front
of the whole department,
- totally nuts.
- Rough day at the office.
I wonder how you'd approach and
resect without getting a C.S.F. leak.
Yeah.
Place a lumbar drain,
then infuse saline
and do Valsalva maneuver.
Mm.
Apparently Pepper's
meltdown was so over the top,
the hospital forced
her to take a leave.
How long?
Unspecified.
She's always
been a little crazy.
Last I checked,
eccentric and emotional
didn't qualify as crazy.
Thanks for taking a look.
I read that cisgender people
often reduce transgender people
to their genitalia, and
that that is offensive.
Did I do that to you and Rio?
Yes.
I'm sorry.
Rio will be going
into surgery soon.
He's been asking for you.
You haven't been
answering your phone.
Thanks for letting me know.
He is very confusing to me too.
Rio has worked so hard.
He had a bilateral
subcutaneous mastectomy
and takes hormone
replacement therapy,
but now he is choosing
the most female act.
It's not female
if Rio is doing it.
Yes.
And he must have dealt with a
lot of prejudice during his transition.
I dealt with prejudice.
My brother helped me.
Does he have a brother?
His family doesn't talk to him.
And now Rio is
having brain surgery.
He is very brave.
You can stay here.
I have a patient, Zara Norton.
We, uh, we diagnosed
her with H.O.C.M.
I saw the file.
Dr. Guerin expressed some concerns
about my initial handling of the case
in the E.R.
He thinks I stereotyped
her... based on her race.
Do you think you did?
She was crashing,
I had to make a call.
I didn't have a lot to go on.
Glassman came to
see me this morning.
Someone told him I'm
unstable and need help.
Any idea where he heard that?
I asked for help, you can too.
You're a resident, no
one cares if you need help.
I got this job in part
because my main competition,
a man, backed me.
The second anyone thinks
- I can't handle this...
- No one is gonna think that.
They will if you keep
telling them I'm a mess.
You have P.T.S.D. You
shouldn't be ashamed.
Says the woman who just
profiled a Black female patient.
You judged her...
just like people will judge me
and whisper that I've always been
a little intense, so no wonder
I was asked to step down.
Um...
Nobody needs to know.
Exactly.
You tell me that it doesn't matter,
you tell me everyone will understand,
and then you tell me
to keep it to myself.
Should I be ashamed
or shouldn't I be?
All right, Ms. Norton,
time to head to pre-op.
What's in the bag, handsome? I
like to know what goes into my body.
Cefazolin. It's a
prophylactic antibiotic
- we give before surgeries.
- Makes sense.
Hey, what was the meds y'all gave
me when I first got here to the E.R.?
Enalaprilat. It's
an ACE inhibitor.
- Isn't that for hypertension?
- Mm-hm.
But I thought I already told you I
was on meds for my blood pressure.
You did.
So you figured I needed more?
Or did you not believe me?
I'm sorry.
You must be scared.
You shouldn't have
to be scared alone.
I love you.
I love you too.
Eli...
I can't see you.
I'm right here, babe.
Can you follow
this with your eyes?
It keeps disappearing.
You've lost peripheral vision.
The tumor is impinging
on the optic fibers.
We can't perform
the T.S.S. surgery.
With the tumor's
continued growth,
the best remaining option
is the open pterional
craniotomy, but it is higher risk,
with a lengthier recovery,
all of which is on
top of the potential
for gender dysphoria
during pregnancy.
Is that still a concern?
I think back to before
I started taking T,
how terrible that felt.
The thought of feeling
that all over again...
We could go back
to the original plan.
You mean terminate
the pregnancy?
The tumor should
shrink on its own.
After everything you've done
to get where you are in your life,
it's scary to think
about doing something
that would put that at risk.
This is my next step.
I'm ready to take
it, even if I'm scared.
You have to take risks
sometimes, Dr. Lim.
Here.
Shouldn't you be
prepping Zara for surgery?
It's canceled.
She wants to be transferred
to a different hospital.
One where she won't be
"racially profiled into heart failure."
Shaun... you okay?
I'm having thoughts
I don't want to have.
Both Park and Jordan
say I shouldn't tell you.
But you're going to, aren't you?
Yes, I am. I have a work crush.
Also, my patient is a
pregnant trans man...
Wait. One at a time,
Shaun. About this... crush?
Her name is Dr. Cintia D'Souza.
She is a second-year
radiology resident.
Last night, I dreamed we
were in the Residents' Lounge,
watching The Weather Channel
and then we started kissing...
Okay, I got it.
Are you mad?
Park and Jordan were right,
I shouldn't have told you.
No, I'm not mad.
A little surprised,
but that's okay.
I'm still attracted to
other guys sometimes.
No. No. What? Who?
- It doesn't matter.
- Who?
The... Okay, there's this
one physical therapist...
No. No.
No.
What if...
we're attracted to other people
because there's something wrong
with our relationship?
You're not planning on
kissing Dr. D'Souza in real life?
No.
Or working late with her?
Doing some x-rays alone,
where you might end up
leaning over the same lightbox...
We don't use lightboxes anymore.
And I don't plan to
work late with her.
Then I don't think either of us
has anything to be worried about.
I have to go prep for
a pterional craniotomy.
I'm Dr. Glassman, the
president of the hospital.
Unless you're here to
drive me to S.F. Regional,
you can head right back on out.
I apologize for your experience
in the emergency room.
That's mighty white of you.
I don't recommend that
you transfer to S.F. Regional,
or any other nearby
hospital, for that matter.
I'm sure they got the
same fancy equipment,
same shiny sets of
diplomas y'all got here,
and maybe a few
less racist doctors.
Well, apparently, that
doesn't seem to be the case.
I pulled data on comparable
hospitals within 100 miles,
did numbers on surgical
outcomes, and patient satisfaction,
aggregated by race.
Apparently, we're doing
well, comparatively.
Your argument is that your
hospital may be racially biased,
but it's less racially biased
than these other hospitals?
Yeah, pretty much.
Stay at St. Bonaventure,
the president of the hospital
will monitor your care
every step of the way.
For whatever it's worth...
I don't think you can
do better than that.
She's gonna stay
on one condition:
that you're off the team.
Dr. Park, please
open sylvian fissure.
Arachnoid knife and
Rhoton dissector.
The tumor is visible.
What makes someone a man?
I thought it was just
the chromosomes,
but that must not be it,
which makes things confusing
and difficult, and I know Rio
was uncomfortable when...
Life is uncomfortable.
It hits you with tough situations
and you muscle through them.
I see a tiny bleed
in the circular sinus.
Pack it with Floseal.
Someone give me an update.
We got a drop in end-tidal
CO2 and oxygen sat.
See any evidence
of exposed air cells?
No, but waxing bone
edges just to be safe.
But the tumor thinned the
sellar floor and sphenoid wall.
Making it permeable to oxygen.
It's an air embolism.
BP is dropping.
Dr. Lim? What should we do?
Dr. Lim?
Saline gauze.
Tip the table to eliminate the
negative air pressure gradient,
and place a central line.
This'll stop the air leak and
allow us to access the air bubble.
Inserting a Bunegin
air-aspiration cath.
You are two centimeters
from the superior vena cava.
Aspirate the right atrium until
you don't see any more air bubbles.
Nice save, Dr. Lim.
Let's get this tumor out.
Make your transverse aortotomy
with Potts scissors, Dr. Wolke.
Extending the muscular
incision down to the mid-ventricle.
There's the myectomy site.
There is the aberrant
muscle bundle.
Take her off bypass.
See how she does.
How's the cardiac output?
Reduced and insufficient.
Low output could mean we
need to further reduce the septum.
Unless it means that
we reduced it too much.
Damaged the cardiac electrical
conductors that control the heart rate.
She's having
third-degree heart block.
Enrique's right. We
took too much muscle.
Put her back on bypass.
We could augment the
wall with a bovine patch.
Wouldn't insulate
the electrical system.
She'd still be at risk of complete
heart block and cardiac arrest.
We could insert a
dual-chamber pacer.
She won't need the conduction
system in the wall of her heart
to control her heart rate.
Let's go!
How was the craniotomy?
It went well, the
patient is in recovery.
Your text said you
have good news.
And by good news, I mean
bad news for Dr. D'Souza.
Plenty of great stuff
to crush a crush.
First observation,
she smells like cinnamon.
Hmm.
Which is more
puzzling than irritating.
Actually, kind of nice,
which is obviously not helpful.
Oh. Okay, she does this
weird self-grooming gesture,
where she tucks her
hair behind her ear...
and then sort of
massages her ear?
Also not helpful.
Okay, I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Mm-hm.
Okay. At the salad bar,
she used the cucumber tongs
to reach for the cucumbers...
and then the tomatoes...
and the olives...
and the pickles.
- Ugh.
- Mm.
Mm-hm.
Hey.
I can see all of you.
- How...? How'd we do?
- Great.
We got all of the
mass, vision is restored.
You have every reason
to expect a full recovery,
and a healthy pregnancy.
We're gonna be dads.
Are you ready?
I've never been a
pregnant man before.
You'll always be the best
man that I've ever known.
I came to see how you're doing.
Dr. Andrews told me you
was the one who figured out
how to save me.
Still don't change what
went down earlier though.
When I got to med school...
people took one look at me
and thought they
knew exactly who I was.
Black girl on financial aid...
She must not be that smart,
she must have
gotten a lot of breaks...
she'll probably need a lot more.
And I worked...
I worked so hard to
prove them wrong,
that I wasn't who they thought I
was, that I deserved to be there,
that I... I fit in.
When you came into the E.R...
loud and messy...
I saw...
I saw everything
I have tried hard...
not to be.
I don't know, I think
it made me angry.
And I'm ashamed of that.
And I'm really sorry.
I used to be that way.
But I got tired of working that hard
to make white people comfortable.
You two heading
out for the night?
We sure are.
How did the
craniotomy go, Shaun?
Did you guys get all
of the prolactinoma?
Yes.
Is that cafeteria salad?
Are there pickles in there?
Did you want some?
You know, I'm good,
thank you. Shaun, do you...?
- No, thank you.
- Mm-hm.
It does help to focus on her
irresponsible salad-bar practices
and dietary preferences.
I've got a ton of strategies
to manage discomfort.
So do I.
- Hey.
To replenish your supply
and a peace offering.
I wasn't aware we were at war.
Well, it seemed like my gossip
about Pepper kind of landed wrong.
Bad day.
Sorry to crash the party.
Dr. Glassman wanted
me to show this to you two.
I asked Lea to run some
numbers on various metrics by race
and the results are not
great, especially when it comes
to pain management.
We are under-treating
African-American and Latinx patients
by a considerable margin.
I think I need a little
of that peace offering.
Help yourself.
- Anyone else?
- No, thank you.
Me neither.
Started taking Sertraline.
For P.T.S.D.
Sorry to hear that.
You doing okay?
Not really.
But I'm working on it.
Okay.
Dr. Browne, good work.
Thank you.
I apologized to Zara.
She pointed out I
spent med school...
trying to make white
people comfortable.
I mean, she's right.
It wasn't just med school.
Exhausting, isn't it?
But we had to do it, right?
To be here?