Previously on The Good Doctor:
The aneurysm
caused his back pain.
- Dr. Wolke missed it.
- I screwed up.
Compressions?
Dr. Wolke...
He's dead.
Take as much time as you need.
The virus has damaged
your mother's lungs.
We're doing everything
we can to help her.
120 joules.
I've got hydroxychloroquine,
ribavirin...
I'm twice the size of SJ General. I
should have twice the amount of tests.
♪ Over the rainbow
No yellow brick road ♪
♪ Can't seem to find
home Over the rainbow ♪
- I'm a doctor. What happened?
- I don't know. He was running.
And I honked and all of a
sudden, he was in front of my car.
Pedestrian versus
car, GCS five at scene.
Rigid abdomen with active
bleeding. Flail chest with pneumo.
He needs an ex lap. Now.
We've got a massive
hemoperitoneum.
I need two large suctions and
lap pads in all four quadrants.
There's a grade-three liver
laceration in right lateral segments.
Liver stitch, number-1 chromic, and
a blunt needle and a combat gauze.
What were you doing
on your bike at that hour?
Heading into work. Trying to prep
for my budget meeting with Glassman.
Mobilize the liver to check for
any associated diaphragm injury.
It's the other side of town.
I was taking the scenic route.
BP's dropping.
He's got another bleed. Add
more lap pads and run the bowel.
There's a perforation
near the terminal ileum.
Hmm.
Something tore through
the intestinal wall.
It's shrapnel.
From the accident?
The coat's eroded. It looks
like it's been in there a while.
Must have gotten
dislodged in the accident.
How does Asher seem to you?
He seems fine.
Too fine for someone who's
just lost their first patient.
I don't have time to worry
about people being too fine.
He's faking it.
Good. The brain releases
serotonin when you smile
even if you're miserable.
I feel better already.
Denial is not a proven
strategy for psychological health.
Dwelling on things you can't
change doesn't help either.
Twenty-four-year-old
woman came into the ER
complaining of abdominal pain
and headaches and surprise,
she's pregnant.
Apparently not a happy
surprise. She wants an abortion.
Well, what's wrong with her?
I assume you haven't recently
learned the value of sharing,
which makes me think
there's another reason
you're unloading this onto
the surgical department.
She has a congenital IgA deficiency
and a history of severe infections.
She'll need IV antibiotics and
close post-surgical observation.
I figured one of your newbies
may as well learn something.
♪ I guess you'd say ♪
♪ What can make
me feel this way? ♪
♪ My girl... ♪
Lea's birthday is tomorrow.
There are many cute frogs
and many romantic songs.
I can't decide.
It is my first gift
as her boyfriend.
It needs to be... awesome.
Well, then, maybe singing frogs,
however cute, might be a mistake.
Try something more
personal, romantic.
And find a resident who hasn't
done a suction D&C and teach them.
Oh, no. No, I'll do it myself.
I'm not going to teach anymore.
I'm a good surgeon, I'll do surgery.
Dr. Murphy, part of your
job as a surgeon is to teach.
You can't opt out
because it's difficult.
I am opting out
because I'm bad at it.
Well, you can't opt
out for any reason.
But I may have given you too
much responsibility too soon.
So I will supervise your supervision
until you get the hang of it.
Pick someone. Did
you two lose something?
Our patient. Rose Babcock.
She's post-op from repair
of a distal radius fracture.
Sixties. White hair.
Looks at you like she's
staring into your soul.
Does she have a limp?
No.
Well, I think she does now.
Ms. Babcock, did
you fall down again?
Oh, no, I'm fine.
But there's a poor man in
room 318 who's in a lot of pain.
Let's get you back in bed.
Oh.
Yup.
Apply a new Tegaderm,
not antibiotic ointment.
They breathe.
Don't make us handcuff
you to the bed, Rose.
- We charge extra for that.
- Dry the skin more so it'll stick.
Okay.
You're doing just fine, dear.
Heart rate spiking in
the 130s. BP 162 over 95.
Are you feeling any
pressure in your chest?
No, it's just anxiety. Not
mine. It's one of yours.
We're going to pretend, since
it's happening in your chest,
that it's yours. Twenty
milligrams IV labetalol.
I'm fine. I'm an empath.
I can feel what other
people are feeling.
And one of you is
very stressed out.
Olivia, stay where you are.
And one milligram of Ativan.
Keep away from me!
No! Step back.
Sir, you were in an accident.
We're taking care of you.
Stop it. Stop it! No!
Get away from me!
- I need you to hold
him down - Now!
While I administer Haldol.
- Sir, please. Just...
- I'm warning you.
This room is being cleared.
No one is gonna hurt you.
Ben.
You're having a flashback.
You're not in Afghanistan.
You're in the hospital.
Look around.
What do you see?
Zoe?
- Yeah. Yeah, baby, it's me.
- Zoe, I couldn't sleep.
I went for a run and I...
heard an explosion.
I don't... I don't know
what happened after that.
You were hit by a car.
We had to do surgery,
but you're going to be okay.
It's okay.
Take him back to his room. Make
sure he didn't open his wound.
I'm sorry.
Dr. Murphy?
Rose is not your patient.
She was teaching
me about her gift.
She says the basis
of empathy is curiosity,
which I find curious because...
I'm curious about the job
you're supposed to be doing.
Who are you leading
through the D&C?
None of them.
The only one who hasn't done
one does not want to. So I will.
Which resident?
Wanting to is
irrelevant. It's their job.
irrelevant. It's your job.
I'm a Christian.
Performing an abortion
goes against my beliefs.
Okay.
You may encounter
a situation one day
where this procedure
could save a woman's life.
- Then I hope someone else can...
- And it's my job to make sure
you can perform all
surgeries. Including abortions.
So where does that leave us?
I'll do the surgery.
I've only done one. I'm sure
there's a lot I still can learn.
Dr. Murphy, you
have a new student.
Get her started running
pre-surgery assessments.
Thank you, Olivia. That's the
kind of ambition I like to see.
He did three tours.
He came home after
he was injured in some...
kind of explosion. I don't
really know what happened.
Some... He's tried to tell me
about it several times but he just...
- He breaks down.
- When was he diagnosed with PTSD?
Two years ago.
But he hasn't been the
same since he got back.
At first, he was...
moody, irritable.
Little things would set him off.
Then, the insomnia started.
His mind, it's
just never at rest.
The nights are the
worst, you know? He...
He gets these
terrible nightmares,
flashbacks. Just...
We can't sleep in the
same room anymore.
Make sure he stays off his feet.
Would you like us to
arrange a psych consult?
We've been down that road.
Talk therapy, group
therapy, exposure therapy,
endless medications.
Let us know if you
change your mind.
Jillian, I need those
stats on elective surgeries
for my budget
meeting. And a coffee.
Jillian?
She's not there. I
need approval for this.
And this.
You said I couldn't
give her the frogs.
Oh. You can't
give her this either.
You don't know what it is.
I know it would mean more if you
had to leave the building to get it.
I would like to do the
suction D&C surgery.
I assume your religious
convictions haven't changed
in the last few hours.
No. But I believe I was put
in this program for a reason.
So if you think it's important for
me to learn how to do an abortion,
then I should learn.
Take Jordan to the skills
lab, run the surgery steps.
You two will handle
the D&C yourselves.
With you.
How are you going to supervise
my supervision if you're not there?
I will help you prep
and debrief afterwards.
But this patient doesn't
need a gallery of strangers
standing around gawking at
her most private experience.
Sorry to interrupt. Ben
woke up complaining of pain.
- Did you check the incision?
- The pain is in his arm.
Now test external
rotation of the shoulder.
We're almost done.
Can you describe the pain?
We'll call it a ten.
It's been hurting for years. But...
this is... This is something else.
How did you injure
your shoulder before?
I was in a...
I was in a convoy, in Kandahar.
And there was a...
I... I... I dislocated my...
You don't need to
discuss it with us.
What did you find?
Swelling. Sensitivity
to touch. Discoloration.
- Could be CRPS.
- What is that?
Well, it appears the car
accident aggravated a prior injury.
You've developed Complex
Regional Pain Syndrome.
We'll start you on
Gabapentin and Dilaudid.
Opioids make me a little insane.
We could do a
Stellate Ganglion Block.
It's an injection of
anesthetic near the spine
that blocks the pain signals
and could also help the PTSD.
I've been treated
for PTSD for years.
Why haven't I heard about this?
It's experimental.
But promising.
The procedure comes with risks.
Vascular injury,
infection, major hematoma.
Dr. Lim, I've been taking a
risk every time I go to sleep.
I want to do it.
Stellate Block is an accepted
procedure for the treatment of pain.
Which you wouldn't
have suggested
if the patient didn't also
have a mental health condition.
I heard Jordan's
back on the D&C, -
in spite of her
righteous indignation.
Is something chirping?
I think you're being unfair.
Well, if anyone's being unfair,
it's me. I told Jordan to do it.
I told her we make decisions
that are hard to live with
all the time. We
make them anyway.
And I told her
pissing off the chief
was a very bad way
to start your residency.
Glad to hear you're still moonlighting
as Surgical Department Camp Counselor.
But I don't mean you
were being unfair to Jordan.
You're being
unfair to the patient.
She's facing an emotionally
fraught procedure.
She needs the
support of her doctors.
And who she's getting is a rookie
who thinks she's committing murder.
And Shaun.
I have a point.
I'll lead Jordan through the
D&C myself. You're happy.
Dr. Murphy will be happy.
My cup runneth over.
Now get whatever's in that
box out of my department.
Morning sickness. Nurse Ella's.
Rose claims she can
feel her pregnancy.
She was right about the guy in
Room 318. He had a clot in his ankle.
I'm sure she picked up
on some subtle clues,
like the guy moaning
and grasping his ankle.
Get a CT to rule out
abdominal injury from her fall.
We're going to insert a
thin needle into your neck
so we can inject the
anesthetic. It may sting a bit.
Use an in-plane approach
to place the needle
between the C6 tubercle
and carotid artery.
You might feel some discomfort.
- What's wrong?
- Zoe's hurt.
I'm okay.
Get some ice.
Let me take a look.
- What happened?
- I hit her.
Yeah. I was laying next to him.
I know I shouldn't,
but the shot just made his pain
feel so much better, I thought...
Zo, you didn't do
anything wrong.
There was a noise in
the hall. I lashed out...
I know.
I didn't mean to. I'm sorry.
Nothing's broken, but I can get
you something for the swelling.
No. I'm okay. I'm going to
go home, get cleaned up.
I just need some time.
I love you.
I think we can help Ben.
There have been
some promising results
using Vagal Nerve
Stimulation to treat PTSD.
His scarring would make it
impossible to expose and find the nerve
without damaging it.
Those scars are the
reason that we need to try.
Imagine reliving your worst
nightmare over and over again.
Why doesn't anyone around here
want to do the job they were hired for?
What Ben needs is psychological
help. I've ordered a consult.
Leave it to the people
who are trained to do it.
It sets a bad precedent
to force a resident
to do a procedure they're
not comfortable with.
Wow, does anyone around
here not have an opinion
about who should do
that damn abortion?
Jordan had a choice and in my
opinion, she made the right one.
It's not a true choice if you
were coerced by your boss.
I asked her to do her job.
You took an opportunity from
a resident who wants to learn
in favor of one who doesn't.
Is this song and dance about
Jordan doing the procedure
or your niece not doing it?
Neither.
There's a misconception that
Olivia came to St. Bonaventure
because of me.
She's here because
of your reputation.
The great Dr. Lim, a masterclass
in technique, professionalism,
empathy.
Lately, it doesn't seem
like that reputation holds up.
I'm giving you an antibiotic
to prevent infection.
The vacuum aspiration
will take about 15 minutes
and you'll be numbed
with a local anesthetic.
Conscious sedation
is also an option,
but you will need someone
to drive you home afterwards.
Do you have any
questions for me?
I'm scared.
Are you certain you want to
go ahead with the abortion?
Yes.
Then you don't
have to be scared.
You're making the
right decision for you.
Give her another 400
micrograms of misoprostol.
I'll be back for the procedure.
This doesn't work. I need these
numbers in spreadsheet format.
- Sorry. Excuse me.
- Thank you.
Dr. Park?
Rose's CT was normal.
Get an upper GI barium study.
The first quarter supply
costs you requested.
Also, one of your first
years seems upset.
He's been in the
stairwell for a while.
Everything okay in here?
I just needed some quiet.
Surgeons come into the
stairwell for two reasons:
fire drills or doctor trauma.
You having a fire drill?
I just wish we had a more
effective treatment for Ben.
His head's so messed
up and we can't help him.
I don't think this is about Ben.
Have you ever lost a patient
you knew you could've saved?
When COVID was at its worst, we
had to cancel all non-urgent procedures.
A young mom with a
heart condition was...
more urgent than I thought.
And she died waiting for
me to put her on the schedule.
How do you get past that?
You get past it
because that's the job.
You will always remember it,
and you will eventually
stop reliving it.
How can you be so sure?
Because if you don't,
you can't be a surgeon.
And I'm pretty sure
you're a surgeon.
Should get back to work.
Insert the speculum.
Now dilate the cervix.
Begin suction.
Begin gentle
suction in the uterus.
Is anything wrong?
You're okay. Doctor Allen,
I can take it from here.
Don't worry. We're almost
done. You're going to be just fine.
You have no idea what that
woman was going through
- and you made it worse for her.
- I know, I didn't...
You had an opportunity to opt out
before you walked into that room.
But you agreed to
do the procedure,
you took on an obligation to
that patient, and you failed her.
If you ever do
anything like that again,
I will have you removed
from my program.
Maybe you should be
cleaning bedpans for a while.
Hopefully, there's no
moral objection to that.
Why are there adult
toys on my desk?
I've heard good
things about the Llama,
but online reviews
aren't always accurate.
Do you have a favorite?
They're for Lea. Which one
do you like the most, Claire?
Uh...
Evidence suggests that trauma
changes the way the brain works.
An overactive amygdala can
heighten someone's response
to emotional stimuli,
including fear.
I think we should consider
amygdala ablation for Ben.
That's... crazy.
And completely outside the
scope of our care. Where's...
Oh.
We're surgeons. We fix physiological
problems, not mental ones.
It is a physiological problem.
His brain isn't
functioning properly.
If it was a tumor that was
causing these reactions,
- you wouldn't hesitate to remove it.
- But there is no tumor.
You're talking about
inflicting damage on his brain.
He could suffer a stroke,
or come out in a coma,
or not come out at all.
If you use a stereotactic
laser approach
rather than an open craniotomy,
you would greatly reduce the risks.
This is not your case.
You cannot jump into this one
because you don't want to do
the one assigned to
you, which is to teach,
which you've made my problem,
just like you made Lea's
birthday gifts my problem.
You need to grow up and
accept some responsibility.
I was diagnosed
with PTSD last year.
I kept it mainly private.
Melendez really
helped me through it.
It was nice to have
a friend to lean on.
So if you need one...
I feel...
off.
Disconnected.
Like I can't catch my breath.
But...
it comes with the job.
I'll get over it.
It's Ben.
Ben, no one is
going to hurt you.
You're having a flashback.
I know where I am.
Every day since I came home,
I feel like there's a
monster chasing me.
I try to outrun it...
but I end up hurting
the one I love the most.
I'm a threat to
everyone around me.
No, Ben. You just need help.
Nothing helps.
I can't smile. I can't laugh. I
can't feel anything but pain.
I make everyone around me...
suffer.
Ben, there's a
surgery that may help.
I would like to scrub in on
the amygdala ablation surgery.
Rose said you're feeling
overwhelmed and need...
I don't want to hear any more
things that woman has said.
Your job was to
supervise your residents.
Why are you here
instead of doing that?
You said you were going to
supervise my supervision, but you didn't.
You took over my case.
I don't know what I was
supposed to learn, or how.
Scrub in.
Dr. Murphy, walk Asher
through the probe placement
and trajectory to the amygdala.
I will supervise
your supervision.
Okay, insert the probe
perpendicular to the cortical surface.
Stop. You're off course.
On the current trajectory,
you will penetrate a
branch of the choroidal artery
and cause a hemorrhage.
Step away from the probe.
Your job is to
teach, not take over.
Adjust the probe one
millimeter inferiorly.
Avoid the temporal
horn on your right.
I can't see it on
the image guidance.
Tell Asher what you see.
It should point toward
your 6 o'clock on the y-axis.
You have to feel it.
The...
The tissue plane along
the parenchyma is smooth.
It should feel like gliding.
You've reached the amygdala.
Ready to begin
thermal laser ablation.
Rose's upper GI
and labs are normal.
Should we keep her
another day to observe?
No. If she's stable,
let's send her home.
- Okay. I'll have Olivia...
- Open your mouth.
Pardon me?
Open your mouth.
- I can, uh...
- Shut your mouth.
There's this rat...
A mouse. A little, dead
mouse in the garage
and the big strong man
is afraid to get it out.
Not afraid, disgusted.
Neither of us
wants to deal with it,
so we are settling it in
the only responsible way.
- A bet...
- A dare. A series of dares, actually.
Whoever wusses
out first has to...
Take those things
out of your mouth.
I will discharge Rose.
You two go home.
- We were just...
- Being idiots at work,
while people are sick
and dying. Go home.
All of your tests are normal.
We're discharging you.
Right. Because you're psychic.
I'm an empath. Not a psychic.
Whatever the case, I would
suggest you take it easy.
- No drinking, no heavy lifting...
- You have to let it out, dear.
It was you.
You made my heart rate spike.
You're about to implode.
There's nothing
wrong with you... or me.
Code Blue!
Yeah.
Dr. Lim, my behavior yesterday
was inexcusable and unprofessional.
I let you down, I
let the patient down.
I am deeply sorry, and I
promise it will not happen again.
You let your personal judgment
get in the way of doing your job.
You're right, that
is inexcusable.
You said I had no idea what
the patient was going through.
The truth is, I kind of do.
Scared, alone, afraid
of anyone finding out.
I chose my career over
motherhood, over my faith.
But I don't regret it.
And I know God forgave
me because I get to be here,
living my dream
of being a doctor.
But I purposely try
not to think about it.
You're off scut duty.
- That's not why I...
- Take it.
My name is Benjamin Alan Harris.
I'm in Saint Bonaventure
Hospital in San Jose.
Language and memory
appear to be intact.
And your motor
function is normal.
But that doesn't mean
it worked, does it?
No. We'll have to do an fMRl
to see how you respond
to fear-inducing stimuli.
But we'll let you rest for now.
I'm not going to rest
until I know I'm better.
I want you to know
how I got these scars.
No, not now. Just
give yourself time.
I was in a convoy, in Kandahar.
I was in a Husky, a
big vehicle, at the front.
Ben, you don't have to do this.
Ronnie was driving.
He was telling me a story,
something about a goat at the base,
or maybe it was a
chicken, I don't know, but...
we were laughing.
And then the world was on fire.
It's the Husky's job
to spot IEDs.
And I missed one.
I can't see their faces.
Just...
bodies.
Everywhere.
Dying alone,
without their families.
All I could do was
hold their hand.
Are you okay, Ben?
♪ Happy Birthday to you ♪
♪ Happy Birthday, dear Lea ♪
♪ Happy Birthday ♪
Fun day.
♪ To you ♪
What do you mean?
We have a diagnosis.
I thought I felt someone here.
You've had a long day.
You have Prinzmetal's
Angina, Rose.
A heart condition,
but it's very treatable.
It explains all your symptoms.
And it's exacerbated by stress,
which is likely what
caused your heart attack.
You need to stop seeking
out other people's pain.
It's literally killing you.
You're the chief of surgery.
You could have sent
somebody else to tell me this.
Sure. But then I'd miss
my chance to gloat.
You're here because
you're hurting.
And you don't know
where else to go.
Go ahead. Use your magic.
Tell me, what's wrong with me?
How do I stop feeling like this?
It doesn't work that way.
I don't have a magic wand.
I can only hold up a mirror.
Make you slow down and
look at the parts of yourself
that you've been
trying to ignore.
Because you're afraid if you
look too closely, you'll break.
Maybe you will. I don't know.
Maybe breaking is the point.
You can't outrun
your pain, Dr. Lim.
If you keep trying,
it's going to kill you.
Time of death...
Time of death, 7:17...
Time of death, 2100 hours...
- Time of death...
- 7:13.
- 4:26.
- 8:55.
- Time of death...