That was a gift.
From a grateful patient?
Grateful girlfriend.
I have meetings with department heads
later. Otherwise, I would have waited.
Oh, yeah. Of course.
I'll have all this sent to
your home by week's end.
- Dr. Weaver?
- Yeah?
- Maintenance is here.
- Send him in.
What happened to Brenda?
I had to let her go.
She seemed unwilling
to make the transition.
Centered, right above the backs
of the chairs and at museum level.
Oh, museum level.
Always hated the impressionists.
Look, it's a lateral
move, Robert.
All that sugarcoating
of the truth.
Believe me, it wasn't my idea.
Dr. Anspaugh thought it
might be a good interim step.
That's strange, because this power
play smacks of a certain estrogen-based...
- malice I've grown all too familiar with.
- You know...
I wish you'd try to appreciate the fact
that we're trying to do you a favor here.
What you're doing
is bending me over...
and driving it up the chocolate
highway. Let's be honest.
You're a one-handed
surgeon, Robert.
Not to mention a Human
Resources nightmare...
and a lousy administrator who's burned
more bridges than you've ever built.
You're lucky to
have options at all.
- Oh, you're suggesting I have some.
- Yes, you do. You have three. It's this...
it's teaching or it's out.
- Dr. Romano, can I get your address...?
- Bite me, Nancy.
I have some billing givebacks...
- that need to be signed.
- Not my job.
- Cardio admin's on line one.
- Take a message.
What do I tell them?
That I don't work here anymore.
Check the line. NURSE: BP's
dropping. Pulse ox is down.
- What are you doing?
- I'm taking her to X-ray.
That's what orderlies are for. Go
help someone drain an abscess.
- Yeah, but I got...
- You're a med student.
Hey, green card, I want all your
performance evals by day's end.
- Why?
- Something to read on the can.
Why do you think?
You're on my hit list.
- Who supplies the scrubs?
- Allied.
Switch to Lindeman's.
They hug booty better.
The hell are you looking at?
Oh, hey, everybody. Great
news, piñata out in the parking lot.
- They're here for their kid.
- They need to stop having kids.
- Clear them out or you're fired.
- What?
- Let me rephrase that. You're fired.
- You can't fire nurses.
- I just did. Hey, pituitary boy.
- Talking to me?
I lost my arm, not my olfactory nerve. Sic
Security on the bum taking a crap there...
and get a list of every staff
member's salary, including yours.
- What was that all about?
- Meet the new boss.
Get rid of this coffee machine in here!
You losers can pay for your own java.
Oooh, times like this, I
wish I practiced in Florida.
Nah. It's too humid.
Plus, you'd miss me.
- Ha. Well, I wouldn't miss the wind chill.
- Dr. Chen. How many candles?
Hey, I said no cake.
- Happy birthday, Jing-Mei.
- Ha. Like you even knew.
- Yes, I did.
- Uh-huh.
And I got you something.
- Really?
- Mm-hm.
I figured if you aren't busy later, I
would take you over to The Grotto.
- Maybe get some champagne afterwards.
- Ooh.
- You thought this through, didn't you?
- Yes. Why wouldn't I?
How you doing? Jewelry and personal
accessories, all at discount rates.
Uh, no, thanks.
Ladies love stuffed animals.
- Five bucks.
- Don't make me hurt you.
This is America. If you can't
sell crap, we're not a free society.
Come on, get out of my way.
I should be back by 6. She woke up
early, so make sure she takes a nap, okay?
Hey, you like the sign I put up?
Yeah. Yeah, it's, uh, sweet.
Okay, my darling. Bye-bye.
Hey, kids love stuffed animals.
- Five bucks for this little cutie.
- No, thank you.
- It comes in pink. I got dolls too.
- Just go. Go, go.
My foot! My foot!
Told Haleh she was fired,
said it was a management tool.
Always fire someone the first
day. Lets them know who's boss.
He can call himself king
as long as I get severance.
Hey, Abby. Can you park
Mrs. Strohm here in Exam 1?
Uh, no. We lost
another exam room.
We'll park her in the hall.
Weaver never had an office.
He'll take the lounge
if we're not careful.
And put our lockers where?
- Triage?
Oh, that's great. So now our
personal stuff can get stolen too.
Too late. Brand-new leather
gloves, right out of my locker.
Real leather?
- Yeah, why?
- Animals died to make them.
Right. And we should
all wear canvas shoes.
- Oh, God!
- Could use a little help here.
- What happened?
- Corday's nanny ran over his foot.
- With her freaking minivan. I'm crippled.
- How did this become your problem?
Elizabeth decided
it was an ER case.
It's typical. We
got any open beds?
Yeah, if he's a paying customer.
Otherwise, the hall. For anyone late...
- Park him here.
I'm now in charge. Say goodbye to
the warm fuzzies of the Weaver era...
hello to the age of efficiency and cost
effectiveness. Tardiness will result...
in a docked paycheck and/or letter
to file. Once get to work on time...
you will treat, street and do so
quickly. Any questions? Didn't think so.
Medevac, two minutes
out. Auto versus ped.
Kovac and Carter. Keep
dispositions under 20 minutes.
Doctors Lewis, Chen
and Pratt, clear the board.
You get me a breakfast burrito,
extra cheese, hold the salsa.
- "Please"?
- Get your love at home.
Should be interesting.
Romano in charge.
Seen any movies lately?
Nope.
Try that sushi place
at Navy Pier yet?
No.
It's good.
Long time now...
that you've been
together. A year?
Almost.
That's nice.
Josh Rushing, 37. Found down
along old Route 10 outside of Pembroke.
- Long way from County.
- Busy day. We go where they tell us.
Scalp lac, multiple contusions. Probable
hit-and-run. He's suffering from exposure.
Been down a while. Homeless?
After a couple days out, everybody looks
homeless. Is Susan Lewis working today?
Yeah, why?
Jackknifed rig on the Dan Ryan
with an SUV trapped underneath.
Damn it, we gotta go.
Okay, on my count.
One, two, three.
CBC, lytes, BUN and creatin.
Let's get an Accu-Chek.
Wallet says he's from Indiana.
What's he doing walking
the back roads of Illinois?
Got a clavicle
deformity on the left.
Maybe he was exercising.
Eighteen in the right AC with
a liter up. Accu-Chek is, uh, 96.
- Not in loafers.
- Pretty isolated out that way.
- Lucky they found him at all.
- What do we got?
We got a possible car versus
pedestrian. Vitals stable but unresponsive.
This is why I went to school,
to practice veterinary medicine.
- On the monitor. Systolic, 96.
- SonoSite.
- He doesn't need a chest tube.
- I'll be the judge.
Dr. Kovac, a call
for you on line one.
- Not during a trauma.
- Who is it?
It's a collect
person-to-person from Zagreb.
No blood in Morrison's.
- Your dad? ROMANO:
No free fluid, no...
- Someone named Gordana.
- Pericardial effusion. Catch. May I?
Hello. Uh, don't ever
call this number again.
- Why did you do that?
- Hey, you wanna talk to folks at home...
- dial 10-10-Call-the-Third-World.
- Okay. C-spine, chest and pelvis to start.
He needs a rectal.
Oh, um, I took the liberty of checking
the union manual. You can't fire nurses.
They have their own administration.
You lodge a complaint with their manager.
Fine. Tell Hally, or
whatever, that she can stay.
She already went home.
Uh, then have her come back. Make
sure she deducts for the time she was gone.
And give me bullet points on who I
can pink-slip and for what reasons.
There are six unions on the
floor. That's 12 volumes of material.
Fine. Do yours last.
Dr. Lewis. So,
what's the story here?
Sammy got ahold
of Dad's nail gun.
- Who knew he'd use it as a weapon?
- He's 7, everything's a weapon.
This the nail-gun injury?
- Yeah.
Well, Dr. Corday's got this now.
Apparently, Sammy
didn't think it was loaded.
No. I knew.
Well, the puncture appears to
have glanced off the rib. You'll be fine.
- DT and a gram of Ancef?
- Yeah.
And, uh, a Psych consult
for the son, perhaps.
- How's it going down here?
- Wanna hear something scary?
I miss Weaver.
Fresh pot. Enjoy
it while you can.
- How you doing?
- Very well, thanks.
New digs, new challenges,
crappy coffee. Interest you in a cup?
I'll pass.
Smart woman.
Look, I think it's awful,
just to let you know.
A waste, really, of your...
Of your skills, your talent.
But, um, I'm sure
it'll be temporary.
Yeah.
Anything I can to do help?
You could shoot me now.
BP's stable, 120/78.
And the tox screen's back.
No drugs or alcohol
in his system. Crit's 50.
Hemo concentrated.
Neuro exam looks non-focal.
I don't know. On his own, no
car, out in the middle of nowhere...
- Think he was robbed?
- Still had his wallet with him.
Maybe he got dumped.
- I don't know.
- Maybe his wife knows.
He's wearing a wedding
ring. They're trying to find her.
Hundred of
thiamine, just in case.
- Did you know about it?
- What?
- The Romano coup d'état.
- No idea.
- Does it mean anything?
- We're screwed.
Push the admin meeting to 4...
and tell the alderman
I'm out of the office.
- Dr. Weaver.
- John, I have to turn over a number...
of outstanding projects.
Residents time study.
QA of our
portable-ultrasound training.
I'd be really grateful if
you'd see them through.
Sure. WEAVER: Excellent.
So how long is Romano
gonna be down here?
- You think it's not permanent?
- Because whoever runs the department...
needs communication
and clinical skills.
He is, uh...
He's an experienced physician.
His background is entirely surgical.
- John...
you have to be associate professor
before being department head.
I don't want his job, Kerry, I just
don't wanna have to do two of them.
All right. Which one of you
smartasses stole my crutch?
You have any plans for tonight?
Oh, me and this guy named TiVo, we're
gonna curl up in front of the TV. You?
Nah.
Everything okay?
Woman I went to med school with
has a patient who's very sick. Young boy.
Is he terminal?
Post-shunt tetrology
with pulmonary atresia.
- Oh.
- He's outgrowing the shunts.
He needs unifoc
and complete repair.
- That's a pretty specialized procedure.
- Yup. So special it can't be done there.
Nicky Broomer, fell while running.
Shoulder dislocation and rib fractures.
Vitals normal except
for pulse of 120.
- This guy's a runner?
- He's a junkie.
- He gets chased by the cops regularly.
- He fell on the sidewalk. It was wet.
- Are you high now, Nicky?
- No. And he's staying that way.
Mint condition, the entire lot.
The sky's the limit, as far as
markup. It's yours for only 30 bucks.
Hey, I thought you said you
couldn't walk, your foot hurt so bad.
I hopped.
- I'm on the phone here.
- Take two Tylenol every four hours...
and get a real job.
- Hey, it's at 3:00.
- What?
- Cake for Chen.
- Oh, right, right.
- What do you think? Flowers or candy?
- It's gotta be something she can wear.
Let's see who's losing the
dispo race. Why, that would be...
Dr. Pratt, who will now be punished for
his indolent ways. Lower-back pain in 2...
and an unknown intestinal
disturbance in 4. Chop-chop.
In second-to-last place
we have Dr. Lewis.
That's to be expected
from one who ovulates.
She gets the maggot
infestation in 2.
Of course, we have Mr. Gallant, who's
doing Cadillac workups on Yugo patients.
How are you, hon?
Don't tell me. Don't tell me.
It says right here, "My blood
pressure is high." Well, hell, so is mine.
But rather than go to a busy ER, I
stay home and take my medication.
- Have you tried that?
- She's diabetic. Her EKG is...
Is unnecessary. Give her a sublingual
nifedipine and send her to clinic.
- Yeah, but that's not a...
- You filling a special-needs quota here?
Do you need me to say it slowly in your
people's language? Sublingual nifedipine.
When you're done with her, pick up
six more. She's your patient, not mother.
They letting anyone with a
check into med school these days?
- Gallant is one of our best students.
- Doesn't bode well for future medicine.
Maybe when he gets
his license, we'll be dead.
Typically, as Chief Resident, I
assign the med students their cases.
Ah, when? Every other Tuesday?
Any patient here over six hours is your
failure, not mine. Treat, turf or dispo.
You don't have a background in
emergency medicine. It isn't that simple.
- Feast or famine.
- Hey, you're back.
- Another chopper beat us. Susan around?
- Yeah.
Okay. Your screaming isn't
making our job any easier.
This is hard for him.
- Settle down, okay?
- It hurts like a son of a bitch.
It's going to continue to hurt
unless we pull your arm out.
- Please help me.
- Radial pulse is strong.
We should just give
him more Versed or fent.
- Yes, yes!
- We already did. Should be unconscious.
- Why is he still screaming?
- I don't know.
- His ribs are broken.
- That, and he's going through withdrawal.
- I can't take it, baby.
- Hey, Susan.
What?
- I got a guy here says he's your husband.
- What's he look like?
Uh, tall, dark
hair, flight nurse.
Yeah, that's him.
- You were in Vegas for, like, two days.
- And three nights.
We met on the plane on the
way over, hung out all weekend.
Were you sober at any point?
Sunday night, we wanted burgers.
So we took a cab to this drive-through.
Turns out to be a mini-chapel.
Ah, so you figured, "What
the hell. Let's get married."
I know. It was impulsive.
Impulsive?
- Okay, it was really, really stupid.
- Susan.
I'm getting it annulled, anyway.
Haven't seen him since the wedding night.
My flight left the next
morning. He stayed a week.
- He could have married six other women.
- Do you remember his name, at least?
Uh... Chuck... Martin, I think.
Good luck.
Hey, stranger.
- Hey.
- Look, nifedipine is contraindicated.
I'm not bottoming out her
pressure and stroking her out.
I know. He's the one that
needs to be educated about this.
And he wants to hear
that from a med student.
- Obviously, he needs to prove...
- Blah, blah, blah. Go talk to him.
If there's a problem,
I'll take care of it.
- Got a lot of people scared.
- Not you?
- I still need to pay my rent.
- Romano's bark is worse than his bite.
Easy for you to say. You
can walk away if you want to.
- Ah! I can't stand it.
- So Susan got married?
- Can't call her indecisive.
- Can call her crazy.
When are you people
gonna do something?
- So I spoke to an attorney.
- Uh, yeah, me too.
He said annulling it
should be fairly easy.
That's what my guy said.
- I have to admit, I was a little worried.
- Why?
Well, you know...
- it was consummated.
- Oh, yeah. Right.
- A few times, as I remember.
- More than a few times.
- The cabana?
- Right, right.
Right. But since we never lived together,
I figured it shouldn't be a problem.
- Did you tell anyone?
- Like who, my mom? She'd kick my ass...
- if I deprived her of a wedding.
- Same with mine.
- I figured it wasn't anyone's business.
- Exactly.
- And pretty tough to explain too.
- Please, who are you telling?
- You kind of had to have been there.
- Yeah. It made sense at the time.
Guess you have
to get back to work.
Yeah.
- So play hooky.
- Let's go.
Morales, you don't
write, you don't call...
No time to radio.
Twenty-four-year-old female
passed out. No trauma, no seizure.
- What? You were shopping?
- We were registering.
- She's pregnant.
- Don't tell me. You were gonna say that.
- BP's 100/60. Sats are good.
- Do you remember falling, Debra?
I remember feeling weak.
I haven't been eating.
Okay. Start a second line
and put up another liter.
- Morning sickness?
- Oh, bad.
My first wife had three
kids, she never even burped.
Maybe I'm not cut out for this.
- What have we got?
- Debra Strickland. Pregnant, syncope.
- Eighteen weeks.
- Hi, Debra.
- Any cramping or spotting?
- No.
Okay. Let's spin a crit, check
her glucose and dip a urine to start.
- Ow.
- That hurts?
Mm-hm. And my belly.
It never did before.
How about when I do this?
- Ah, ow!
- Yeah.
- Abby, can you see if Linda Woo is here?
- I'll check.
- Finally get a surgical candidate?
- Oh, God. I need an operation?
- Not necessarily.
- Stripe in Morrison's.
- Yup.
Probably blood, judging from her
hypotension. Probe over the kidney.
It is.
Doesn't look like it.
It's not.
- Surgery's here.
- What do you have for me?
An 18-week IUP with hypotension,
intraperitoneal fluid and renal mass.
Obvious ex-lap for tissue
diagnosis and staging.
Who are you?
Dr. Robert Romano, head of surgery
a week ago. Who the hell are you?
This is Dr. Woo.
She started yesterday.
Do you have any medical
problems or allergies?
Are you deaf?
- Um, let me page Corday.
- I'll do it.
BP is dropping, 86/62.
Any moron can see she needs
surgical intervention for hemostasis.
I'm sorry, what's
your position here?
Your practical and intellectual superior
with 20 years of surgical experience...
versus the two years of
ass-wiping you call residency.
- Take her up.
- Done.
He was diagnosed at birth. But access to
any kind of care has been limited at best.
- He's been revised?
- Twice.
The last time, five years ago.
And the surgical team that performed
it in Croatia has disbanded since then.
And there's nothing
else in Europe?
Nothing they can afford.
County's pediatric thoracic group
does unifocalization, free of charge.
Yes. But he's not a citizen.
Neither are we. But we are here.
Even if you get a surgical team to donate
services, who's gonna pick up the tab?
With some PR, charitable
contributions could cover it.
But Kerry would still have to sign off
on it. Are you on good terms with her?
- Uh, not really.
- Well, neither am I.
- Leave it with me. I'll see what I can do.
- Thanks.
- Where's Dr. Woo?
- She left.
You need to teach
them to have thicker skin.
She cried a little.
Pratt's consoling her.
Oh, dear.
Right.
- Uh, intraperitoneal fluid and a mass.
- Pregnant with profound hypotension.
My guess, renal-cell CA.
Necrotic mass obscuring and
deforming the capsule of the kidney.
Bleeding across the peritoneum, more
likely metastases. She'll need surgery.
- Hello.
- I'd like a CT of the abdomen if I can.
And have OB involved
as well. She's stable now.
Why don't we
get a third consult.
Maybe, uh, ask the
janitor what he thinks.
I'm down here less than a day,
already I'm starting to hate surgeons.
Is something
wrong with the baby?
No. The baby's
quite healthy, actually.
- Dr. Romano, you have a minute?
- Less than.
It's about my high-blood-pressure patient.
I should've, uh, pointed it out to you.
Use of sublingual nifedipine is no longer
indicated because of case fatalities.
I never said nifedipine. I said
metropolol. Works fine for hypertension.
You said nifedipine.
You said it more th...
Listen. I'm the
doctor. You're not.
Seems that if it is
your intention to run...
My intention...
is to serve my time without having
affirmative-action imbeciles like you...
make me regret ever having
gone into medicine. Minute's up.
- Hey, where are my bullet points?
- Ah, right.
Well, you can't fire
medical students.
But failing them is bad because
they have to repeat the rotation.
I'd suggest a marginal pass.
- What else?
- You can, however, fire care partners.
- The hell's a care partner?
It's like a non-union orderly.
- Hey, you. What's your name?
- Jim.
Yeah. You pay union dues, Jim?
- No. ROMANO:
Good. You're fired.
- I need something.
- That is putting me on edge.
- Was worse when his girlfriend was here.
- Tell Lewis to gag, sedate or kill him.
- She's on break.
- Is there a prerequisite for working here?
You have to be a know-nothing
drag-ass who doesn't wear a watch?
I suspected Weaver would kill her
mother to get out of here. Now I know why.
Only the chief of emergency medicine
is concerned with clearing the board.
- You gotta help me.
- Hands off, lowlife.
All right, you. Where
are your parents?
I don't have any. They
died in a car crash last year.
- Bummer. What's your problem?
- I need it bad. I need something real bad.
- Let me guess...
- Could you move him to Exam 4?
My pleasure. Come on. - Jerry.
Wait. Just one more paragraph
in the lab-tech union manual.
Make sure that I see all Romano's
patients before anyone gets dispo'd?
- Sure.
- Thank you.
- Doesn't mean you don't work with him.
Okay, where were we?
Um, I reached for the soap, down
I went, landed right on my rump.
Well, that's not good.
Any loss of consciousness?
No. Just loss of dignity.
- I know, I know. I'm late, I'm late.
- I had to move Nicky.
He was driving everybody crazy.
- Ah, thank you.
I sent up labs on your
hyperemesis patient.
- Dispo'd your no-longer-itchy rash guy.
- Was I gone that long?
You take Sandra, we'll call it
even. I gotta check on a patient.
- Done.
- Slip and fall in the shower.
Possible wrist fracture.
Congratulations.
- On what?
- Your newlywed status.
- Ha. Ooh, lucky.
- Excuse me?
Oh. I've been looking for Mr. Right
for 10 years and still haven't found him.
The last time it
happened, they kept me.
You done?
I think so. What
happened to your arm?
Are you incapable of
keeping your mouth shut?
- Were you born that way or something?
- None of your beeswax. Breathe deep.
Hey, what do you do for soft asthma?
A couple of nebs and some prednisone?
You're asking a nurse?
Yeah, what you said.
Only, I take an adult dose now.
What he said, I said. Then
discharge with follow-up. Okay...
that took all of eight minutes.
See, people? It can be done.
What can be done?
Oh, BS'ing your way
through a shift, I suppose.
Listen, I didn't mean
to be nosy before.
I was just making little talk.
- Small talk.
- Dr. Kovac, exposure guy is coming to.
Any word on his wife?
They're still trying
to get ahold of her.
Mr. Rushing? Mr. Rushing,
can you understand me?
- Yeah.
- Do you know what happened to you?
Car...
- crashed.
- Your car?
Where are they?
Who?
My kids.
We were driving...
walked to get help.
- Oh, my God.
- Go get the police.
His kids are still out
there somewhere.
- So how long have you been married?
- Um, two years.
Some people think the age difference
is a problem, but I can't keep up with him.
We're gonna minimize the
exposure to protect the baby.
"Our little accident,"
Bill likes to call him.
- Oh, you're having a boy?
Uh, just a guess. Will
you be able to tell?
- No, not with this.
- Oh, good. I wanna be surprised.
You have to lie very still. And there's
an intercom in case you wanna talk.
CT abdo-pelvis with...
- and without.
- Fine cuts right through the kidney.
When we shoot the rest of
the dye in, you may continue...
- to feel a warm, tingling sensation.
- Okay.
There it is.
Smaller masses in the
abdominal cavity too.
Hey, I'm just the tech.
Hematoma and fluid from
where the main tumor bled.
- She's gonna need a nephrectomy.
- Yeah, like now.
I guess Romano was
right about one thing today.
Is it almost over?
What are their names?
Sally...
and Tim.
Do you know how
badly they were hurt?
It was dark.
I just remember crying.
BP's stable,
128/80. Pulse is 106.
They were so scared.
- Luka?
- Another liter of warm saline.
Do you recall where it happened?
- Do you recall when it happened?
- No.
They're dead, aren't they?
- We're trying to find them.
- I'm gonna start calling some of this in.
- He's near the six-hour mark. Stable?
- Just finishing up a Heimlich.
Which is the cheesy ER way
of dealing with a pneumothorax.
I did it so he could stay here
in case his family is found.
Turf him to Medicine, let
them hold hands and sing there.
- His kids could be seriously hurt.
- But he's not, get him out of the room.
- Look...
- Mandatory therapy making you soft?
Do us both a favor.
Stop seeing your shrink.
I mean, I don't believe in it. And
frankly, if you're that screwed up, quit.
Where the hell have you
been? Get back to work.
Hey, welcome back.
Right. X-ray's backed up and
she's complaining of a headache.
Get her to Curtain 3 and give her
Tylenol. You could use a lunch tray by now.
What I could use is a husband.
Does yours have a brother?
Damn.
Hey, Kippy, my man.
What's happening?
Foot still hurts. I
should sue you clowns.
I'm in a rush. What
you got for ladies?
Stuffed animals.
No, man. I need something
that a lady can wear.
Uh...
Got some handmade jewelry,
some perfume, tie-dyed T-shirt.
- Uh-uh.
- Wait, I got some new items in.
How much?
What's this doing here?
Uh, we have cake
when there's a birthday.
A woman pops a kid out, what
difference does the day make?
No more official or unofficial
birthday recognitions.
Oh, you can't be serious.
Singing, blowing out candles,
eating. By the time it's done...
- everybody's had a break with pay.
- It fosters community.
And lethargy, by the
looks of it. Sandra Haycox.
- What about her?
- Broken wrist.
- Cast her and cast her off. Uh-uh.
- She's complaining of a headache now.
Have her take a number and get
back in line. One complaint per visit.
Hey, who ate my cake?
- Nana, Nana!
- What happened?
Eight-year-old, front-seat passenger
in single-car MVA. Airbag deployed.
- Pretty hard, from the looks of it.
- May have a ruptured globe.
- Why was she sitting in the front seat?
- Ask Grandma.
The tumor outgrew
its blood supply.
Then part of it died, ruptured and
bled. That's why you passed out.
It could rupture again at any moment.
So it's important that we remove it...
and the kidney as
soon as possible.
What kind of a tumor is it?
We don't know. And we won't
know until we get a pathology report.
Do you think it's cancer?
Let's take this
one step at a time.
My mother died of cancer.
And if that's what
this is, I should know.
Debra... I should know.
It appears likely to be
renal-cell carcinoma, yes.
And if it's as aggressive
as it seems, it's possible...
that you would require chemo and
radiation therapy following surgery.
Unfortunately, chemotherapy
is unadvisable while pregnant.
You said it was aggressive.
- Yes, but...
- Take it out.
Take everything.
Are you saying you
wish to terminate as well?
Just... Just do it all at once.
Typically, those procedures
would be done separately.
If you had surgery and
waited until the baby was born...
I want the chemo.
- Honey...
- I want it now.
We're gonna leave
you alone to talk.
I guess she figures she can
try again if she beats the cancer.
Three weeks, the fetus is viable
outside the womb. She could fight it then.
She doesn't wanna take that
chance. She's young. She's scared.
Yeah.
PH is still over nine. Pilar,
how many fingers do I have?
Think the blindness
is temporary?
I've seen alkali keratitis go both
ways, but this doesn't look good.
- How's Grandma?
- She needs an immobilizer for her knee.
Otherwise, she's fine.
What a difference
height makes, huh?
Ugh, why would anyone
put their kid in the front seat?
She begged me to.
She's my only grandchild.
I just wanted to make her happy.
Could you grab a couple of Morgan
Lenses from the eye-exam room?
- Yeah, sure.
- Okay, this isn't going down...
- as one of my better days.
- I think that applies to all of us.
Wait a minute. Why is
it quiet all of a sudden?
- Unbelievable.
- It was too hard to watch.
So you went out and scored?
- You weren't doing anything. I had to.
- You want Narcan?
Put him on a monitor.
At least someone's happy.
Of course, it would be pro bono.
You looked at our budget? Every
time we open our doors we're pro bono.
We're in a deep
deficit, Elizabeth.
I could contact surgeons and specialists,
ask them to donate their services.
Which would account for 25 percent
of the total cost. Forget about Medicaid.
The boy's not even a citizen.
That might interest the media.
Look at the separation of the
Guatemalan conjoined twins.
I don't think a Croatian kid needing a
tet repair is gonna get the same draw.
Kerry, he's 9 years
old. He'll die without it.
And we're just not able
to help right now. I'm sorry.
Kerry, can I ask you something? Are
you as concerned about Robert as I am?
Uh, more precisely,
his mental health.
He seems...
broken by this assignment.
He's a cockroach.
He'll refuse to evolve
and yet survive us all.
- Talk to me about Residents.
- You need documentation.
But you have a more
powerful weapon in scheduling.
They don't pull 16 shifts a month or
work more than three nights in a row...
you can book them for every weekend,
holiday or playoff night you want.
- Good stuff.
- Thank you.
How come the delinquent
hasn't been dispo'd yet?
Uh, that was on my
list of things to do.
You didn't give Eddie enough
prednisone with his albuterol.
Let me get something straight.
You overrode my orders?
Yeah. Before he can leave,
he needs to be able to walk...
and hold normal
sats, which he can't.
- Uh-oh. You screwed up.
- No, I did not.
- Maybe you haven't been listening.
- There's basic medical treatments...
- There's people here who can help...
- You don't question my judgment.
And you sure as hell don't get
too comfortable here, Dr. Carter!
This is my ER now!
That stands for one thing:
Everyone's replaceable!
Even you.
I need to know what
to tell the guy. All right.
- That better be a local call.
- It's a police matter.
- They haven't found the car?
- We checked every road, bridge, river...
- within five miles.
- Why not 10 or 15?
- He can't have walked that far.
- He was getting help for his children.
- He could have walked 100 miles.
- What can I say...
- we already covered a lot of territory.
- Search teams? It's 40 degrees there.
Look, we're doing all we can.
- Luka, where's Dr. Romano?
- I don't know and I don't care.
- Hey, Chuny. How's it going?
- Don't even.
- John. CARTER: I
thought you were long gone.
Yeah. I just wanted to check
and see how Robert was doing.
As expected. He was abysmal.
He has no patient rapport, stunted
interpersonal skills and he's hostile.
- Qualities consistent with surgeons.
- He doesn't know what he's doing.
He almost killed a patient by
prescribing antiquated treatment.
But obviously you
stopped him from doing so.
- I can't stay on top of the guy 24/7.
- We're shifting him to administrative.
- You gonna chain him to his desk?
- The ER may not be the best fit for him...
but it's all the man has. Just make it
work. Or better yet, work around him.
- Okay.
- Excuse me.
I'm Diana Rushing. I got a
message saying my husband's here.
Dr. Kovac. He
treated your husband.
- What is it? CARTER:
It's Rushing's wife.
- I'll take you to him.
- Is he okay? I've been worried sick.
I'm from Indiana.
He's stable, but he's
obviously very upset.
When did you see them last?
He left home four days
ago. Who's "them"?
Your husband and your children.
What children?
He said he was with them
in the car when he crashed.
We don't have children.
Her caretaker says she's
complained of white discharge.
- She have her period yet?
- She says she's a real woman.
- I'm Dr. Lewis. How are you feeling?
- Good.
We're gonna do a test on
your private parts, okay?
Set up for a pelvic. It's probably
a simple yeast infection. Sandra...
how's your headache? Did
the acetaminophen help?
Sandra?
Sandra? I need a crash cart.
She came in with a broken wrist.
- She did.
What happened?
I don't know.
Pulseless and apneic.
V-fib. Charging to 200.
And clear.
Unit number six going up.
Tumor mass has invaded
the renal artery wall...
and sections of the vena cava.
You want me to call?
Won't tell me
anything I don't know.
Stage IVB, by the size and
the spread of it. Take the kidney.
Dr. Corday, call on line one.
If it's Path, put it on speaker.
Pedicle clamp in place.
Metz to divide the vessels.
- Dr. Corday?
Yes, Dr. Meechum.
What are your findings?
Fuhrman grade IV
with a sarcomatoid pattern
and a high mitotic picture. Sorry.
Thank you.
Done. Steel bowl.
It's bad, I take it.
Irresectable.
We'd be doing her a
favor if she bled to death.
Her chance of survival is
less than 2 percent at this point.
Get her husband up here.
I want to speak to him.
Charge again to 360 and clear.
Asystole.
It's been 20 minutes.
Uh, try another amp of epi.
And clear.
No pressure, no pulse.
A headache, a fall, possibly
jogged an aneurysm she already had.
No way you could
have known about it.
No way she could
Yeah, I'm sure she wasn't
planning on dying today.
1827.
He's depressed. That, combined
with aspects of dissociative disorder...
allowed him to create this
weird negative amnesia.
Was it a psychotic break?
Not per se. But he definitely
needs inpatient psych care.
When he talked about them,
he made them sound so real.
To him, they are.
Right now, anyway.
But they won't always be.
With the right meds,
it'll all fade away.
Ow!
Cervical motion tenderness.
PID?
Yup. Mindy, do you
have a boyfriend?
Uh-huh.
You're pretty young
to be having sex...
much less unprotected sex. You
need to tell him to use condoms.
What are those?
That's not a good sign.
Can you tell me his name so we
can make sure he gets checked?
He cleans floors.
He says he loves me.
Four hundred of cefixime
and a gram of azithro.
We're just gonna help
you get dressed, okay?
Oh, man. You want
me to call the facility?
Call the police first. This has been
one of the worst days of my life.
- Careful, don't jinx yourself.
- Goodnight, everyone.
- Happy birthday, Dr. Chen.
- Oh, thanks.
- Hey, my gloves.
- What?
Camel-colored with
lambskin. Are those mine?
- No.
- No, no. Greg just gave them to me.
- They were in my locker this morning.
- So? I bought those out on the street.
You bought these on the street?
- Yeah, from Kippy. But it's a long story.
- Oh, my God!
I'm sorry.
Listen, I'm sorry. I
mean, what do you...?
Ha, I can't believe you bought
my birthday present on the street.
It was a good deal.
They're genuine leather.
If I were you, I'd put
them under a Wood's lamp.
Ha-ha, nice.
- Hey.
- What are you doing here?
- We're not supposed to see each other...
but I figured if your day was as bad
as mine, you could use some company.
Well, 8-year-old blinded by an air
bag, woman keels over of an aneurysm...
junkie shooting up in the ER and a
Down's syndrome girl with the clap.
Hmm. Family of four trapped in a burning
vehicle, one kid survived. 18 months old.
You win. What'd you get?
Oh, the burger and
fries we never got.
Knit one, purl two.
If you take much longer,
you're gonna be sewing scabs.
If I go faster, the
edges don't evert well.
I love watching med students
suture. It reminds me how good I am.
Was.
- What did you say?
- He said, "Was."
Loose stools in Exam
4. Knock yourself out.
Almost there.
Skin stapler will be next.
Cut, please. JACY:
Pressure's steady at 110/68.
He's here.
Mr. Strickland...
I'm afraid we've discovered a highly
malignant and inoperable cancer.
Oh, God.
Stapler ready.
Your wife's
chance of survival...
even with the most aggressive form
of chemotherapy, is extremely poor.
But not impossible?
The one sure thing...
is that she will survive long
enough to deliver your baby...
if she doesn't seek treatment.
But for that to happen, you'd
have to reverse her decision.
- OB's here.
- How close are we?
Almost closed.
Mr. Strickland...
if you wish to overrule her
decision, you need to do it quickly.
The GYN team here is standing
by to perform an abortion.
I want her to live.
Your wife is going to die.
She's gonna fight this.
Do you understand
this baby has a chance?
- I can't, I just can't.
- Dr. Corday?
- Mr. Strickland?
Let's get her draped.
Start with the sterile spec.
Another?
Yeah.
And stop skimping
on the peanuts.
Hey, how about
putting something on...
for those of us in the
room without hairy knuckles.
Something wrong with this show?
Yeah. It only appeals to adults
making less than 20 grand a year.
Thirty grand.
Oh, car wash gave you
a raise. Good for you.
I'm a copier tech.
Well, that explains
the dirty fingernails...
but not why you enjoy watching
half-naked chunky trunks...
pull tractors with their teeth. Must
be a sort of homoerotic thing for you.