SLEEPING AT LAST'S
"ONE" PLAYS....
Time is a strange thing.
♪ Hold on for a minute ♪
When you're waiting for
something good to happen,
it can feel like
time is dragging on.
♪ Over time ♪
But when you want it
to slow down,
it goes by
in the blink of an eye.
♪ Now hold on,
let me finish ♪
♪ Perfect exists
in this life ♪
The odd part is
time isn't real.
♪ If we try ♪
♪ I, I-I, I-I ♪
It's a concept
imagined by scientists
based on the
imperfect movement
of the earth
around the sun.
♪ I'll write
an anthem worth repeating ♪
So why do we put
so much importance
on something
that's just a theory?
♪ I wanna feel the
transformation ♪
♪ A melody
of reformation ♪
Because it's all we have.
Hey, do you two
want to come over
tomorrow morning for presents?
You know, Owen and I are trying
to establish our own traditions
with Leo, just give him
a little bit of normalcy
- while we still can.
- Right.
Before his mother/sister
comes home from rehab?
And his half-sibling arrives, yeah.
Well, kids can make
anything normal,
- so he'll be fine.
- Thanks.
Dr. Grey?
Uh, I start my ICU rotation
tomorrow,
and I was wondering
if you have any advice on... that.
Well, first of all, Schmitt,
don't call them "that."
Sorry, I just mean,
it's so... emotional in there.
Well, it's the ICU,
and she's been here for a month.
She's off the sedatives now.
We don't know
when she'll wake up
or even if she'll wake up.
You know, it's brutal,
and it's depressing.
And it can make you feel like
you're going insane.
Right.
So, I...
You are going to watch
Natasha very closely.
You will examine her
every day.
If there's any change,
any type of change,
you'll page me immediately.
- Okay?
- Okay.
And you should go outside
on your breaks,
because you can feel like
you're losing
all sense of time in here.
- You had the husband?
- Yeah.
Ice skate to the tibia.
You?
Ouch. Wife had
a hell of a concussion.
Most wonderful time
of the year, right?
Hey.
It's snowing.
What are you guys doing for Christmas?
Oh, you know, Leo's too young
to absorb any of it.
But, I think we're gonna
do presents and cocoa
and cinnamon buns,
all that.
Hopefully some of it'll stick.
Yeah, that's sweet.
And Amelia has to go to rehab
to visit Betty. Yeah.
Right. The usual.
Ha. Yeah.
So, we're gonna, um...
We're having Christmas dinner
tomorrow night,
and Amelia wanted me
to invite you.
Oh, no, no. Thanks. No.
I'm... I'm covering for you
in the pit, remember?
Oh, right, right. Yeah.
Of course.
And thank you, again.
Yeah, of course.
We're gonna find
our own traditions, too.
I know.
Merry Christmas, Owen.
It's a unique choice.
I mean, I don't think
we've ever had a chief
give us cured meat before.
I did something nice,
and you're mocking me
- for it.
- Oh, wait! Did you tell her?
We're having
a New Year's Eve party.
Attending and fellows
only. Champagne.
Little snacky things
on crackers.
- Very classy.
- How glamorous.
I know.
You should invite Link.
I mean,
I already invited him,
but y-you should ask him to be your date,
'cause I already told him
that you would.
- Jo...
- Ooh, sorry. Ohh! Oh, my...
- Oh.
- Hey.
Hi. Um, I-I was just leaving,
and it looks like you are, too.
Do you want to take
our hams out
- for a drink?
- Oh, that sounds amazing,
but I have to get home
because it's Christmas Eve.
I have to put the kids to bed
so Santa can come.
- Right.
- Yeah.
- Soon though?
- Yes. Yeah.
Oh, you know, actually,
the Karevs are having
a very classy
New Year's Eve party.
- I'll be there.
- Okay. - No...
..Dark blue scrubs only.
She can have a plus one.
- You're supposed to read my tone.
- Read your what? - Jo,
I'm a big girl.
I can handle
my own love life.
- Thanks for the ham, Chief.
- You're welcome.
Here comes Santa Claus.
This is for you.
Cookies for Santa, in case you
don't feel like baking later.
Link is spending
his Christmas Eve
visiting kids
in the cancer ward.
Seriously?
- Seriously.
You're mocking him
for doing something even nicer.
You should
take a look at that.
We'll see you New Year's Eve.
Bye, Santa.
You are
in a love triangle.
There's no love.
There's no triangle.
Yeah.
Unless, of course, the ham, the
cookies, and I are a triangle.
She's totally
in a love triangle.
Mm-hmm.
Hey.
- Uh, sorry I didn't call first.
- Hey.
Oh, it's okay. Come in.
Uh, I can't stay.
Just, uh... just wanted
to drop these off for Tuck
for in the morning from me.
Oh. Thank you.
Uh... Uh, but I put your name
on all the gifts I got him.
Why would you do that?
Well, 'cause
they're from us.
It's funny.
I-I don't remember us
going shopping together.
I just didn't want him
to think that...
You called a time-out on our marriage?
Okay. I'm sorry.
Uh, thank you
for the gifts.
I'll make sure that
he opens them.
Uh, what are you... Wait.
Where are you gonna be tomorrow?
On call. You know,
Christmas is a big day for us.
Oh, us, too.
Uh, maybe I'll see you in the pit.
Maybe don't sound so hopeful
that somebody gets injured
in a fire on Christmas.
Right.
"We Wish You
a Merry Christmas" plays...
♪♪
Anybody want
to play cards?
I play a mean Gin Rummy.
Oh, you don't want to do that
unless you want to lose.
I am the master of Gin
Rummy
- in this house.
- Oh.
I'm sorry, kids.
I'm just exhausted.
Would I be a party pooper
if I just went to bed?
Of course, Mom.
Get your rest.
Okay.
I'm sorry.
Couldn't even chase Harriet
around that tree this morning.
Thank you so much for taking
care of Christmas dinner.
I've just
been no help at all.
We have Christmas dinner
catered every year, Mom.
There's no reason
to change that.
- Merry Christmas, baby.
- Okay.
- Maggie.
- Merry Christmas.
Can I help you
upstairs?
Oh, no, no.
No, I can make it
to my bed on my own.
She doesn't let me
help her do anything.
She'll get there.
I hope so.
♪♪
It was fine.
A little boring.
I kinda wished
you were there.
At Christmas?
With your family?
Yeah.
Why? Is that weird?
No.
I'll come next year, and I'll
bring some Chanukkah gelt.
It's creepy in here.
I'll protect you.
You are so cheesy.
Hey, uh, Dr. Shepherd asked me
to come check on Natasha.
- Help!
- Can you...
Hello!
Somebody?
Page Dr. Grey.
Oh, my God, it's Natasha.
She's...
She's awake.
Thank you.
Thank you, thank you,
thank you.
I'm saying it a lot
for the both of us.
Schmitt?
Natasha Deon, 45,
hospital day 35.
Neuro... She regained
consciousness overnight.
She is now A&O times three.
Cardio and pulmonary...
She's on a vent
and has an open thoracostomy
for empyema drainage.
MSK... Spine was cleared,
and her pelvis was fixed
internally.
When will she
be able to talk?
We're working on decreasing
her vent settings first.
We also have
to get her nutrition up.
She's weak and has been
through quite a lot.
We can close the
thoracostomy today, though,
since her lungs
are doing so much better.
Natasha, we need you
to get strong for us.
I'm gonna get you up and out
of that bed soon, okay?
Let's make sure
the respiratory therapist
brings that peep down to 5.
Welcome back, Natasha.
You may get
that planetarium wedding yet.
At this point,
I'd settle for a courthouse.
Nice work, Grey.
Love triangle.
When are you gonna stop
stringing him along, huh?
Excuse me?
You heard me.
Link... he likes you, and you
keep giving him false hope.
Who says it's false?
Oh, please.
We both know it is.
Do we?
Speaking Italian...
Andrew.
New Year's Eve.
Is that a date?
Or is that like,
"Oh, come to this party,"
and we'll make eyes
at each other over the punch,
but I'm not really brave enough
to talk to you in public"?
I've been called
a lot of things.
"Not brave enough"
isn't one of them.
Fine.
It's a date.
Dr. Brooks, dial Admitting.
You look good.
Your hair,
it's shinier.
Oh, ew. Please don't
talk about my hair.
Okay.
How's Leo?
He's good.
Yeah, he's teething like crazy,
but he's good.
You miss him?
I mean,
not as much as I miss drugs,
but yeah, a bit.
Well, that's good.
Identifying that.
It's... part
of the process.
No, it's not part
I just miss drugs.
I know they ruined
my life,
but they made me feel
better than anything.
Better than being a mom.
Oh, God.
That's so stupid.
I shouldn't even be a mom.
I'm a kid.
I should just
give you guys Leo
and pretend none
of this ever happened.
Betty...
It's New Year's Eve.
Don't you have
somewhere to be?
Alexi Von Guggenberg's
"Stand Out" plays...
Girl, look at you!
♪ Can't help but stand out ♪
♪ Ooh, can't help myself ♪
♪ I can't help but stand out ♪
Oh, hey, um, weren't you
supposed to be covering the ICU?
Oh, uh,
Natasha was using
the speaking valve
for the first time,
so Dr. Grey said
she wanted to stay.
♪ Ooh, can't help myself ♪
- ♪ Can't help but stand out ♪
- Hey.
Where are you
right now?
- ♪ No limitations ♪
- Sorry,
I'm just...
distracted.
♪ Tell me the rules
so I can break them ♪
Let's get out of here.
♪ I keep slippin' in
their conversations ♪
The ball hasn't
even dropped yet.
The ball can drop
in our bed.
Hmm?
I did not mean that
to sound so graphic.
♪ I ain't doing my job ♪
Do you think
I can ask him over
after his shift,
like, for a toast maybe?
Uh, I mean, my son's with his
father, so I don't know...
Oh, would Ben think
that's a booty call?
He might think
that's a booty call.
Well, maybe that's not
such a bad thing.
Okay, hey, everyone!
It's almost midnight!
Come on.
Hurry, hurry.
- Oh, no, I'll take one.
- Thank you.
Oh, you look... like I should've
joined the Army.
10, 9, 8,
7, 6, 5,
4, 3, 2, 1...
Happy New Year!
- Cheers!
Happy New Year.
Shut up.
Happy New Year, Dr. Karev.
♪ Cuz I'm gonna live
my life free ♪
♪ Can't help but stand out ♪
And may this year be
everything you wish for.
We want to thank you all for...
How are you feeling
off the vent?
And whether all your dreams
came true this year,
or you simply...
Like I haven't
breathed on my own
in two months.
Then you're doing well.
Garrett went to find us
sparkling water
so we could pretend
it's champagne.
- He's a good one, huh?
- He is.
He was by your side
the entire time.
I could hear him.
He talked to me all day about
you and the other doctors.
Shouldn't you be kissing
one of them right now?
Kissing who?
One of the doctors
who likes you.
Garrett calls them
Abercrombie and Stitch.
Yeah!
Come over here!
Oh, dang!
We missed it.
Happy New Year, guys.
- 10...
- 10, 9, 8...
Kiss the one who
turns back time for you.
4, 3, 2, 1...
Happy New Year!
Happy New Year.
Oh!
♪ All right, ohh ♪
Scotch, neat.
Hey, how you doing?
Good, good.
You, uh, been
playing lately?
No.
Been busy.
Same.
♪ Ain't got no regrets ♪
She stand you up, too?
Looks like it.
♪ Till there ain't nothing
left ♪
♪ Feels like my heart will beat
right out of my chest ♪
♪ This is as good as it gets ♪
Natasha Deon, 45,
hospital day 45.
Neuro and cardio unchanged.
Pulmonary... She has tolerated
her speaking valve trials
with intermittent oxygen.
We will remove
the chest tube today.
GI... She's on tube feeds.
PT/OT...
She made it bed to chair.
Well, there has been
a lot of progress.
We're still not out
of the woods yet,
but, um, do you have any
questions for us?
When do I get to eat?
She's been awake for 11 days,
and she's been asking
about tacos for 10 of them.
Tacos are a ways away,
I'm afraid.
But we can...
We can do Jell-O.
The speech and swallow therapist
will try that today.
I'll take it.
Uh, watermelon.
Okay,
you take care.
Hey.
Dr. Grey.
I haven't seen you
in a few days.
- How have you been?
- Stood up.
Sorry.
I don't know if you've
ever been stood up before,
but it feels pretty awful.
- Well, I had a patient.
- You have a phone.
Dr. Rainey to Peds ICU.
Look, it's been fun.
The waiting.
The build up. The game.
But that?
That wasn't fun.
- That was just rude.
- You're right.
I'm a good guy,
Meredith.
But I'm not a doormat.
And if that's what you're after,
then I don't know.
Maybe Link is your guy
after all.
A little more.
A little more!
Good!
There you go!
Please don't talk to me
like I'm a child.
It's perfectly normal
to feel...
How do you know
what "normal" is?
Have you ever had
your spine carved open
and dug around in?
Huh?
Um... Marsha,
can you give us a minute,
please?
Yeah.
Thank you.
Richard, spare me the lecture
about recovery.
- I know that's the pain talking.
- No,
that is me talking,
and I say she's a pain.
You're a pain
in my entire ass!
I asked her to give me
some exercises
so that I could get back
to my sensual self,
and she said
"Don't worry
your little heart
about that"
like
I'm some dried-up old mop.
Well, I'm sure that's
not what she meant.
Then what did she mean?
It's not like
these pain meds
are letting me have any
sexual appetite anyway.
The average
recovery time...
Since when am I average?
Don't talk to me about time.
Don't help me.
Hey, sorry I'm late.
You already started.
This gel is really cold, and I
have to get back to the pit.
You said we were gonna
do these things together.
- You can't just...
- What do you want me to do?
Every time I have to
be a parent, wait for you?
Yeah, but if you say you're gonna
wait, then you can't just...
This baby is gonna be outside
of my body eventually.
Oh, really?
Is that how it works?
Please explain it to me,
Teddy.
Oh, my God.
It's a...
Oh, wow.
We're having a baby girl.
Hey! Ben!
Hey.
MVC out on Elliott.
This... This black ice
is no joke.
- Did you put your snow tires on?
- Uh, I will.
Ben, um, I need to
tell you something...
Or ask you something.
I don't have the words ready,
but my heart is.
I want you to come home,
Ben.
Please.
I mean... it's lonely at
the house when Tuck is gone,
and, uh, the fence,
uh, it...
It blew down after
the windstorm.
I haven't had a chance...
No.
Come home, Ben.
Please.
Come home.
Miranda, I...
I love you.
But you broke my heart.
I'm not coming home just because
now you're lonely
and the fence
needs patching.
Okay.
O-Okay, no, uh,
that's not what I meant.
Uh...
You know I haven't
been myself.
It was my meds.
I was working on
my physical health so much
that I was ignoring
my mental...
My anxieties, again,
they...
I-It wasn't the job,
and it was not your fault.
But I'm...
I'm handling it.
I'm... I'm being treated.
I'm better now.
Structure fire
at Mercer and Fairview.
All nearby units, respond.
W-We have to go.
I'll talk to you later.
Ben?
I'm sorry.
Natasha Deon, 45,
hospital day 62.
Neuro unchanged,
cardio... she was
tachycardic overnight.
Pulmonary... she was placed back
on the ventilator two days ago.
She's been awake
for four weeks.
Why is she
back on the ventilator?
She has pneumonia,
so she's on antibiotics,
but her lungs have taken
a pretty big hit.
GI... Her tube feeds
were held for the O.R. today,
but the CT
from overnight...
My ostomy.
It's been hurting.
Am I...
Are you still gonna...
We won't be able
to reverse your ostomy today.
What? Why?
The CT
that we got back,
it showed fluid collections
in your abdomen,
which may be
the source of your symptoms.
- What does that mean?
- It means that
we will do surgery today,
but it will be to clean out
the fluid collections.
So you're gonna
open her back up?
The wounds she's been working
to heal for the last few weeks?
Unfortunately, yes.
GU... She is
on intermittent dialysis,
and she is going to have
another session today.
Heme... she is
on DVT prophylaxis.
Don't judge me.
I saw a bed.
I laid down on it.
My feet are
very angry with me.
Ah.
I know what you need.
And I know
just who to give it to you.
Mimi at Pink Bunny.
Best mani-pedi
in Seattle.
Why does it make perfect sense
that you have
a favorite nail salon?
Well, you don't want
to dig around somebody's brain
with sloppy cuticles.
You ever want to experience
pure bliss for $29...
Mnh!...
You let me know.
Okay, cut the knot.
Nicely done.
You can do the next tie.
You seem different.
I got contacts.
No, it's...
It's not that.
It's... It's just
you're less...
Glasses.
- Yeah.
- Hmm.
Yeah, and...
And the other day,
when I asked you to change
Natasha's central line,
you didn't mess it up
at all.
Kind of a backhanded compliment,
but thank you?
- I met someone.
- Mm.
And he's hot,
and he's confident,
and he likes me.
And I'm gay.
And he's gay.
And we're... gay
together.
And it's the most me I've
ever felt in my whole life.
Well, I'm happy for you,
Schmitt.
Thank you.
Yeah,
I think it's beautiful.
After all,
what's life for
if not to share it
with somebody, right?
Does that mean
life is not worth living alone?
I think if you meet someone
who lights you up,
you should
fight for them.
Suction.
This fluid looks cloudy.
Oh, no.
She's got dead bowel.
Did we know that?
No, damn it.
G.I.A. stapler.
Oh, God.
That's really bad, right?
Last time I was here,
she was talking about
someone named "Linus"
a lot.
Is that a... like, a boy?
Does she have a boyfriend?
She didn't
call him that, but I think so.
- Hey.
- Hi!
Was that him?
Who?
"Linus"?
Uh, yeah, I guess.
You guess?
I'm doing
the stupid steps.
Um, and I'm on the one
where you apologize for stuff
and tell the truth.
So, I have something
to tell you guys.
- Go ahead.
- Okay.
I've been lying to you guys
since I met you.
My name's not Betty,
and my parents
don't even know I'm here.
But we've been
calling them.
No, you've been talking
to my friend Jerry.
Um, what's
your real name?
Britney.
I'm sorry.
I know I should've told you,
but I was scared
if they found out
about Leo.
Whoa. Hold on.
They don't know about Leo?
I ran away
when I got pregnant,
and they've probably been
looking for me ever since.
Okay. Um, well,
- we have to call them now.
- No.
No, no, no.
You can't.
I'm not ready.
And I'm scared
if they know about Leo,
they're gonna take him.
Natasha Deon, 45,
hospital day 73.
Neuro... I don't understand
what's happening.
It feels like
every step forward she makes,
she takes
two steps back.
It's February 2nd.
Groundhog Day.
That's me.
I feel like
I keep living the same day...
Over and over.
Okay, Bill Murray.
Let the doctors tell us
what's going on.
The reason we think she had
the dead bowel is that she's...
Natasha?
Okay, she's coding!
I'm gonna start compressions!
Crack open the crash cart
and let's push
one of atropine
and one of epi.
Natasha! Schmitt,
get him out of here.
Natasha, please!
I need you!
She probably
threw a PE...
Let's get an echo in here
and start a heparin drip.
Natasha Deon, 45,
hospital day 84.
Overnight,
she continued...
Just tell me.
Please.
Well, when she had her pulmonary
embolism 11 days ago,
it... it... it weakened
her heart and her lungs.
And since then, her kidneys
have worsened, as well.
- I'm sorry.
- Why?
Why?
I just... I...
Garrett, I...
Why is this happening to us?
- I don't have an answer for that...
- Why is this happening to us?
She was getting better.
After all
we went through.
Natasha...
- Garrett?
- Garrett.
Hey, hey, hey.
Garrett.
If she dies, I die.
- Okay.
- If she dies, I die.
Garrett. Listen to me.
Look at me, please.
Look at me.
Look at me. I'm here.
Look at me, please.
Listen to me.
You won't die.
I know it feels like that
right now, but trust me.
You won't die.
You have to fight
for her.
She's in there
fighting for you.
You don't get to give up.
So part of that fight is
you're gonna go take a walk,
you're gonna take a shower,
and you're gonna get a meal.
We will be here,
fighting to keep her alive.
And you are gonna go fight
to keep yourself alive.
Okay?
Come on.
♪ They don't love you
like I love you ♪
♪ Wait ♪
♪ They don't love you
like I love you ♪
♪ Wait ♪
♪ They don't love you
like I love you ♪
♪ Maps ♪
Oh!
Oh, Catherine.
Oh, honey.
I can't do it!
I can't.
No!
I can't...
So, do you think Britney's
spelled with two "T" s or one?
Or maybe they spell it
different,
like with a "Y"
instead of "I", maybe?
Owen,
you have to stop.
We've been having this
conversation for two weeks.
We just need
to find them.
We need to tell them
where their daughter is.
And have you thought about
what you're gonna say to them
if you find them?
"Hi,
we're two strangers."
We took in
your daughter
without going through
the foster system,
and, oh, yeah,
we have her son,
who you don't even
know exists.
"Congrats,
Grandma and Grandpa!"
We at least need to tell
the social worker.
Owen, she... she needs
to make that call herself.
She's not ready.
We can't push her.
Why is she
running our lives?
She's been lying to us, DCHS,
everyone for months,
with no remorse.
She had remorse.
She's an addict.
She's figuring it out.
This is all part
of the disease. Betty is...
Her name
isn't even Betty!
Sorry, I know that, yes, yes,
addiction is a disease,
but since when does its symptoms
include lying
and stealing from people
who are trying to help you?
It just all feels
like an excuse
for justifying
piss poor life choices.
Wait,
where are you going?
To Meredith's.
Why?
I don't know.
Piss poor life choices?
Wait, wait, Amelia.
I'm sorry.
That was way out of line.
You don't even
see the line.
I don't know who I'm gonna be
if they take Leo away.
He's my son.
If they're gonna
take him...
I need to know
sooner than later.
Hey. I have a pitch
for tonight.
You. Me.
Movies. Pizza. Popcorn.
Candy. Sex.
Repeat.
You know
it's Valentine's Day, right?
You hate Valentine's Day.
I know.
I'm trying new things.
Really?
I know you're hurting.
I, um... I don't...
I don't know
how to make it better.
Yeah, neither do I.
I just... I'm trying to do
normal stuff, you know?
I just... feel so...
On the worst day
of my mother's illness,
I wanted to take her IV
and plunge it into my own arm.
I wanted out.
Not just of that day
or that moment.
I wanted
out of this life.
It was a fleeting thought,
but it came, and...
you know, that's how bad
the pain was.
That's how bad
the fear was.
So what'd you do?
I shook. I shook.
My muscles shook in ways
that I did not know
they could move.
And... then I, um...
my eye
started twitching.
Yeah. Yeah, my eye's been
twitching on and off all day.
- Mm.
- And I've got, like,
this shortness-of-breath thing
happening,
where I can't
hold a deep breath.
All day, every day.
- Hey, can I ask you a question?
- Yeah.
How can you stand there and tell
Garrett to fight for love
when you're the one
running away from it?
I have three kids
and a big job.
What?
Nothing, just...
you know,
I used to think you were
so beyond me, but you're not.
You're like a kid
playing hide and seek,
hiding behind
a million excuses.
Happy Valentine's Day.
Hi.
Do you want to go
to dinner tonight?
Are you... asking me out...
on Valentine's Day?
I guess I am.
Uh...
Well, I'm, uh...
I'm not one to usually
bang my head against a wall.
- Is that a no?
- No, no.
I'm banging my head.
It's my new thing,
I guess.
Um...
I'll see you...
tonight?
Okay.
Ben,
you fixing the fence?
You weren't
supposed to see me.
Ah, Ben.
N-No, Miranda,
Miranda, stop.
Okay, it's my turn
to say things now.
You said you wanted me
to be happy,
to follow my bliss,
and I did,
just like you told me to.
And then you turned around
and left me over it.
Now, I may be the one
sleeping somewhere else,
but you left me.
I know.
I'm sorry.
No, you can't leave me
like that again.
Not ever. All right?
You can take all the...
The job sabbaticals you want
and... and change your career
a dozen times,
and I will be with you
every step of the way.
But either we are in this
together or we aren't.
And I never planned
a version where we weren't.
I know...
No, don't say
"I know."
Listen to me.
I should've known
something wasn't right with you.
I-I should've
helped you get help.
I-I should've...
I've seen it before.
I should've
recognized it.
When you had a heart attack,
I promised you
I would build you
a treehouse,
a place for you to go
when you would worry,
when you felt overwhelmed,
when you needed to be alone,
but I never followed through
on that.
For that, I'm sorry.
You're building me
a treehouse?
Now, Miranda, I-I need to know
that this is not something
that you can call "time out" on
ever again.
Never.
No, I-I promise you.
Well, then, yeah,
I-I'm building you a treehouse.
It's, uh... It's not
finished yet, but, uh...
I just figure, you know,
once I move back in,
I can do a little bit of work
on it every morning.
Oh!
Dr. Schmitt said
you had something
you want to discuss
with us?
We've been in this hospital now
for over three months.
Since then,
Natasha's only gotten worse.
And I know you're
the best doctors we could get
because I tried
to find better ones,
but I couldn't.
No offense.
Take me off the vent.
I can't eat.
I can't breathe.
I'm dying.
There are
other options.
There's
home ventilator care.
long-term acute care.
There's skilled
nursing facilities.
They know.
They've been consulting
palliative care doctors.
You all have done
everything you can
to give me
as much time as possible.
We may not have gotten
that wedding
under the stars, but...
You gave us
the rest of our lives together.
Take me off.
Please.
We need you
to give verbal consent
as her power of attorney.
I consent.
So, once I shut
the machine off,
I don't know
how much time you'll have,
so we will give you meds
to keep you comfortable.
Are you ready?
Yeah.
Okay.
Alex has an idea.
Since when
do we do Valentine's?
Since I've been an ass and needed
an excuse to make it up to you.
Ah, that's my cue.
I have a date,
for which I cannot be late.
Hey.
Hi.
Happy Valentine's Day.
Uh, yeah.
Yeah.
Hey.
Hey, are you guys free
to come to the ICU?
What's up?
Just... Just come.
Bring your phones.
♪ When the night has come ♪
Your doctors
wanted to make sure
we got our wedding
under the stars.
♪ And the moon ♪
♪ Is the only ♪
♪ Light we see
Garrett asked me
to read the vows
that you wrote
before the accident.
♪ ...be afraid ♪
♪ No, I won't
be afraid ♪
♪ Just as long... ♪
"Garrett,
the moment I met you,"
I knew I would spend
the rest of my life with you.
Before you,
I never met anyone
"I could be in the same room
with longer than a few hours."
♪ Darlin', stand by me ♪
"I waited my whole life
to meet you.
I gave up thinking
I ever would."
♪ Oh, stand ♪
"But here we are.
Better late than never,
right?"
♪ Stand by me ♪
"Now that I found you,
it all makes sense."
Everything that was once hard
feels easy
now that you are in my life.
"And everything that was
once easy is now sublime."
I'm sorry.
I love you.
I'm sorry
I've been so impossible.
No, no, you do not get to
apologize, sweetheart.
I can't begin to understand
what you're going through.
But I promise
I'll be at your side
while you do it.
Mm.
And...
Catherine Fox.
Easy.
♪ I won't cry ♪
You couldn't be average
if you tried.
♪ No, I won't
shed a tear ♪
♪ Just as long... ♪
Mnh.
W-What's the matter?
Get me
to that bedroom now.
♪ Stand by me ♪
She's back, baby.
♪ Darlin', stand
by me ♪
Do you, Garrett,
take this woman to be your wife?
I do.
And do you, Natasha, take
this man to be your husband?
♪ Stand by me ♪
By the power vested in me,
I now pronounce you
husband and wife.
♪ Stand by me ♪
Don't... Don't...
I know.
♪ Stand by, oh ♪
Thank you.
Thank you for marrying me.
♪ Stand by me ♪
There's never enough time.
Come with me.
Work, kids, life...
death.
Something always
cuts our time short.
I'm supposed to be
on a date.
You already are.
A toast.
To Garrett
and Natasha.
So our best bet is to make
the most of the time we have.
♪ I want to give myself permission ♪
♪ I don't wanna hold it in ♪
Oh, oh, oh.
This is better than sex.
Every pregnant woman I bring
here says the same thing.
What?
You are just so...
I know. I am so.
- ♪ I vow, I vow ♪
- But not as so as you.
Ah, dinner is here.
- Thank you.
- Mmm.
- Do you like?
- Yeah, I like.
- Yeah?
- Mm.
♪ 'Cause this weight
on my chest ♪
Happy Valentine's Day,
my love.
Or make up for lost time.
Did you want to
keep waiting, or...?
Uh... no.
I think
I'm done waiting.
Um, give me
a glass of Lagavulin, neat...
But sometimes,
if we're really lucky...
♪ Say it now ♪
♪ I'll say it, say it,
say it now ♪
♪ Say it, say it, say it now ♪
♪ I'll say it, say it,
say it now ♪
Time stands still.
♪ Say it, say it, say it now ♪
♪ I'll say it now ♪
Sync corrections  by  srjanapala