Previously on ER:
Have you been to Rednofive?
Do you wanna check it out tonight?
Maybe I can move
into your place.
I came in with a cough, and
you sent me out a cripple.
He had a heart murmur.
It was reasonable to believe that
Mr. Ames' numbness could wait.
It'd be good to get you in front of the
press as the doctor found not guilty.
You are very optimistic.
- I'm sorry.
- I don't wanna be alone.
Oh, my God.
Well, I'm coming. I'll
be there in a second.
Who is it? RAY: It's Ray.
- What are you doing here?
- You wanted me to look at your TV?
- It's 6:30.
- Well, you work in an hour.
I brought Krispy Kremes.
- You okay?
- Yeah, I'm just a little out of sorts.
- Look, uh, my cable isn't working.
- Okay, I'll take a look at it.
I'm gonna go and get dressed.
The jury's been out
three days. That's too long.
It's a lot of complicated stuff.
You're gonna be fine.
And remember, we have the
Croatian film festival tonight...
something I know I've
really been looking forward to.
- Maybe it'll take your mind off it.
- That sounds good.
Morning.
- How's the weather, Frank?
- Hurricane Up Yours is about to hit.
- What do you want? I'm filing.
- I'm just making small talk.
- How's it going?
- What, am I being punked?
- You never wonder how I'm doing.
- Course I do. How's the family?
My wife has a goiter.
- My kid has a hard time holding a job...
- Yeah, I gotta run.
Hey, what are you doing
later? You wanna hook up?
- Hook up?
- Yeah, prep for the M and M.
Give you a heads-up
before I kick your ass.
It's an educational
exercise, not Survivor.
- Somebody has her panties in a wad.
- Who's talking about my panties?
- Look, I'll try and find you later.
- Women are weird.
No, Neela's weird. Indian
and Brit? Bad combination.
Channel Five wants a photogenic,
well-spoken ER professional...
to do a health piece.
Anybody interested?
Let's start with "no"
and work from there.
Pretty boy, you in?
- Sorry, bad hair day.
- I'll do it.
You're a newbie.
Put your hand down.
- What about Kovac?
- He's worn out. Gremlin's not sleeping.
- What about you?
- Nobody wants to hear from a nurse.
- Guess it's all you, Morris.
- No, me? No, I couldn't possibly.
I mean, if you guys
are forcing me, I... Okay.
Lou Smith, head injury, altered,
possible blunt abdominal trauma.
BP, 90, tachycardic.
Clipped by an SUV.
Yeah, I almost redlined it.
Abby's got the driver.
Ray, you're with me.
- Got hit on his Harley. ANGELA:
Luka, I need to talk to you.
My wife wanted
me to get a bicycle.
- She's gonna kill me for this.
- Luka, the jury's got a verdict.
C-spine, chest x-ray and trauma
panel. I'm a little busy right now.
Moving all extremities,
but the sats are borderline.
I told the court we'd be there.
- Fifteen liters O2.
- What's the protocol for intubation?
- Etomidate for sedation...
- Trauma 2.
And succinylcholine
as a paralytic.
Kerry can cover for you.
He's got a head injury. Wouldn't
you wanna use lidocaine first?
Yeah, it reduces the ICP
response to the intubation.
Good, good. ANGELA: Luka.
We have two major
trauma patients coming.
- This is important. You need to be there.
- Yeah, one, two, three.
- What are you doing?
- My job.
You gotta talk to Luka.
Knowing Ames' lawyers,
they've already called the press.
Do you know how bad County's
gonna look if he doesn't show up?
Go. I'll make sure he
gets there, I promise.
- Hang a liter of saline.
- Luka, I just talked to Angela.
- You should go.
- Why?
So people who don't
understand what we do here...
can pass judgment on me?
Think about how it reflects on
the department if you don't show up.
- Gram of Ancef.
- I think you already asked for that.
It's hanging.
Let me take over from here.
- What in the hell?
- Chuny, get Maintenance down here.
He's gonna need a portable
monitor for CT anyway.
Hook him up and let's roll.
Hey, Luka, I've
been through this.
Five years ago, I had a
patient with a runny nose...
who I sent home with meningitis.
I was sure the jury was
gonna nail me. They didn't.
Look, I'm telling
you as your friend...
hiding out here is sending
the wrong message.
Is that what you wanna do?
- Open the saline.
I was trying to get to Union
Station to pick up my wife.
Can somebody call her?
Why don't we just concentrate on
getting you better right now, okay?
- You gonna be okay without me?
- We're fine. Just go.
Excuse me. I'm
looking for Dr. Morris.
Mrs. Paik. Hi.
Hi, how's it going?
She's a premed student,
wanted a tour of the hospital.
- Why am I here, Archie?
- Shh.
- Five hundred cc's. PRATT:
Another liter, wide open.
Toss me the Betadine.
Ah. CBC, trauma panel,
type and cross for six.
I'll prime the infuser.
- It says "Helen."
- That's my wife.
Can you put that on speaker?
- Hello? Garrett?
- Mrs. Palsey?
- Who the hell is this?
All right, we need
to start a second line.
- This is Dr. Lockhart.
- Who? Garrett, are you still at work?
Is that why you didn't pick
me up at the train station?
- Honey, I'm in the hospital.
- The what?
Haleh, you do the Foley.
- Mr. Garrett, you'll feel a stick.
- Mrs. Palsey, are you driving?
No, my daughter's driving, thanks
to Mr. Undependable not being here.
All right, call for a portable
C-spine, chest and pelvis.
Mrs. Palsey, your husband's
been in an accident.
You need to get to County
General. He's been seriously injured.
Oh, my God. He's what?
I'll be there as soon as I can.
This is Dawn Archer.
She moved from New
Orleans. Used to work at Charity.
- What's up, Dawn? I'm Ray.
- Katey.
- I'm Neela. I work in Surgery.
- Neela, check this out.
- She's busy.
- There's enough of her to go around.
Let's do a FAST scan and
we'll reassess. All right, what?
Fifteen-year-old, everted ankle.
- Mighty glad to meet you.
- And?
Well, it looks pretty
angulated, don't you think?
- Well, that's terrible, but I'm not Ortho.
- Oh, sorry, I got confused.
Want me to get the SonoSite?
Gates, we're really busy over here.
- I'll get it.
Might I suggest you
start off with an x-ray?
- Brilliant idea. Thank you.
- You guys got it from here?
- We've gotta go.
- I'll call you after the ultrasound.
Can someone wheel
her to X-ray, please?
Dawn, it's all you.
Dawn, meet Josie Weller.
Delightful to meet you. I've been
so looking forward to this day.
We're going to
Radiology, not Disneyland.
Marvelous squared.
Josie goes to Mountain View. It's
a school for kids with special needs.
You know you can take the Red
Line to Roosevelt and hop on the 12?
You have to walk, but the whole
thing should take half an hour...
unless you're a slow walker
and you miss your connection.
- Know why she goes to this school?
- I study French.
I'm just an aide...
but they all have some sort
of developmental disorder.
You have wonderful pecs.
Why do you hide them under
that unflattering white coat?
- Do a tox screen after the film, okay?
- No problem.
Glad you made it.
Are we going to win, Daddy?
So... Of course we're gonna win.
We didn't come this far for nothing.
All right? All right.
Okay.
I'm bagging at a rate of
16. Somebody call for a vent.
- Having trouble getting another
IV. PRATT: Throw in a femoral.
- What about a sternal intraosseous line?
- We don't have those.
We do. We got them three weeks ago.
- Army uses them a lot in Iraq.
Five hundred cc's out.
- You guys have the ultrasound?
- Yeah, but we need it.
- HemoCue's 8.5.
- Okay, bleeding into the chest.
And the cool thing is, Abby's
prepped the chest for me.
- What have you got?
- Still 80 systolic.
- I'm doing a central line here.
- Don't bother. Let me try this.
Wait a minute. Uh, no, no...
Got it. Run the saline.
- Hook up the Thora-Seal.
- I don't think that's the way...
- Nice.
- Very nice.
Wow, ultrasound to Neela.
I'm missing an esophageal
resection to respond to your call.
- I'd appreciate the bullet now.
- Okay.
A 50-year-old driver
versus motorcycle.
Hypotensive with pneumothorax
and fluid in Morrison's.
O-neg's running through a sternal IO.
Chest tube secure and ready for the O.R.
Let's pack up and take him up.
Fine, but then I want you to
get back to the ER for consults.
Yeah, well, I wanna
scrub in on this one.
I'm sorry?
That's at the discretion
of the Chief Resident.
That's me, who, having considered your
request, answers with a resounding no.
I want you to stay here with your
ER buddies and cover ER consults.
Now, bystro, bystro.
- Oh, gosh. Poor Neela.
- Is she why you haven't called me?
What are you talking
about? I've been busy.
It's okay.
A few "who's your daddy's?"
doesn't make us a couple.
No worries. It was
good. Just not that good.
And what in the hell is
that supposed to mean?
You have to move your hips.
You're not touring
with the Grateful Dead.
I move my hips.
Then move them to Admit.
We've got two GSWs and an
antifreeze ingestion coming in.
Look, I can't afford to
close a Trauma room.
- Have you had a problem there before?
- A shootout a few months back.
God knows what
got hit in the walls.
I'm gonna need to check the
panel box and open the wall.
Well, do what you have to do.
- Do it quickly.
- Get down.
- Something going on in here?
- No.
No, Benny got jacked and
passed out. I'm just sewing him up.
And this is funny why?
Uh, he was... He was
talking in his sleep.
Yeah, told a real zinger too.
- Oh.
These two rabbits
walk into a bar and, uh...
Okay, she's gone.
Whoa, whoa. Watch
the cuticles, all right?
Last time, I was bleeding
like a hemorrhoid.
We got a displaced fibular fracture.
Needs reduction under fluoro.
- You gonna sedate her for that?
- Yeah, set up for ketamine and Versed.
You got it.
So how's it going here?
You like everybody?
- Everyone seems really friendly.
- Happy birthday.
Even the patients.
All rise.
- Has the jury reached a verdict?
- Yes, we have, Your Honor.
"In the matter of
Ames v. Kovac...
docket 06CH75255...
we, the jury, find in
favor of the defendant."
Thank you, ladies and
gentlemen, for your service.
The jury may now be excused.
Two units of O-neg,
three of type-specific...
and barely keeping
his systolic above 80.
- HemoCue?
- Dropped from 12 to 8.3.
- We're ready for you, Dr. Dubenko.
- That's my cue.
You need some help?
Isn't there something
you should be doing?
Well, not if you
require my assistance.
All right, then. Scrub in.
Fifteen-year-old female,
twisted her ankle during gym.
Displaced fibular fracture,
post-reduction films look good.
Dispo?
Home after casting with
pain meds and, uh, crutches.
Sounds good.
Follow up with Ortho.
There's one more thing. I just
got off the phone with her school.
- She has Asperger's syndrome.
- And?
And she's a little sexually
forward for her age.
- I'm guessing that that's her.
- Yeah.
You see that sometimes
with Asperger's.
I was thinking about giving her condom
ed. and starting her on Depo-Provera.
Depo? That may be
a little too proactive.
She's a teenager, but
mentally, she's a kid.
- I don't know if she can take hormones.
- I don't need no wheelchair.
- Hospital policy for all our patients.
- Let go, Morris. Stop touching me.
Uh, well, before you start any
form of hormonal birth control...
check an ICON and do a pelvic.
Call me when you're
ready. I'll supervise.
Hey, Kerry. Can you do me
a favor and see my guy in 4?
He's been here 14 hours for
a pre-employment physical.
Doesn't have a primary-care doc?
Classic misuse of the ER.
Dr. Lockhart. Five pages in 45
minutes. I hope someone's dying.
- Stab wound to the right shoulder.
- Get Rasgotra.
I'm scrubbing in on an
esophageal jejunostomy.
Well, hold up. Neela's
in the O.R. with an MVC.
- No, Neela's here, covering consults.
- No, Neela's in the O.R.
- Are you trying to irritate me?
- Well, you make it so easy.
Take a bigger
bite. Don't be shy.
My wife is going to be pissed.
You were hit by a
car. It's not your fault.
The only times I've seen her mad
were the day I brought the Harley home...
and the day we met.
- The day you met?
- Yeah. She's a photographer.
She was in the park shooting
this Chicago Magazine thing...
and I kept getting
in the picture.
- Intentionally?
- No, no.
Not at first, but when I
saw it was getting to her...
I kept doing it.
And I told her I'd stop if
she'd give me her number.
- Well, I guess that worked.
- Yeah.
Six months later, we were
engaged, looking at houses.
That's sweet.
I'm gonna check on my hemophiliac.
Make sure you evert the edges.
- Okay.
- You know, we had some...
We've been through
some tough times...
but she got us through them.
- It's nice to have someone like that.
- Yeah.
Lou Smith, came in as an
MVC. Hit on his motorcycle.
- He should've taken the train.
- Who's taking care of him?
- I wish I was.
- Why the delivery?
We could see this on the PACS.
Come on, it's an
excuse to see me, right?
Uh, wrong. Look at this.
- Oh, man.
- Those are brain mets.
- What's his primary cancer?
- Cancer? He came in as trauma.
Ventricles look good. No midline
shift, no edema. Sounds like...
My husband's Garrett
Palsey. He was brought in.
Hi, I'm Abby Lockhart. I
worked on your husband.
- What does that mean?
- Mom, it means she treated him.
- Let me see if he's still in surgery.
- Please, he needs me there with him.
Another round of platelets
and FFP. More lap pads.
He's oozing around the
packing. Think it's retroperitoneal?
Yeah, probably. Hold
pressure over the portal triad.
Clamp.
- This is the Pringle maneuver, right?
- Yes, but nobody...
No one calls it that anymore.
Dr. Crenshaw.
Was I unclear when I
assigned you to consults?
No? Do I speak too fast?
Or is it that I accidentally lapsed
into Aramaic, as I am prone to do?
- No, I...
- Then explain what you're doing here...
instead of seeing any
of the eight consults...
currently waiting
on you in the ER.
You didn't mention you were
covering the ER, Dr. Rasgotra.
I'm sorry. I was here, he
was unstable, and I thought...
You don't think. You're
years away from thinking.
If I tell you to do consults,
that is not a suggestion.
That is an order.
Do you understand?
- Pulse is dropping, 61.
- Give her a break.
Patient's crashing. I
needed another pair of hands.
I lost an excellent
esophageal jejunostomy...
because I had to
clean up her mess.
Plenty to go around here.
Mobilize the left triangular
ligament for me, will you?
He's still in surgery, but
I can bring you upstairs.
Did they say how he's doing?
I'm sure they'll give
us an update up there.
Frank, page me if my
pediatrician calls again.
Do I look like your girl Friday?
- Hey, you're not in jail.
- Not this time, Frank.
I just got off the phone
with Angela. Congratulations.
- Thanks for the pep talk.
- That's great news, Luka.
Morris owes me 50 bucks.
- He swore you were going down.
- I'm not going anywhere.
I knew you would win. I
prayed on it, Dr. Kovac.
Well, it worked. Thanks.
How are your patients?
Our motorcycle guy, Mr. Smith, is
thirsty. Could I give him some ice chips?
Yup, that's a good idea.
He's gonna need more than
ice chips. Look at his scan.
I called his oncologist at Huntington.
Brain mets from pancreatic cancer.
- Is he in treatment?
- He failed rescue chemotherapy.
From what this scan shows,
he belongs in a hospice.
- What about radiation?
- For metastatic pancreatic cancer?
Hospice can probably help
him enjoy his remaining time.
- Which is just about up.
- Dr. Kovac.
- I'll talk to his family.
- I am the family.
- This is his wife, Mrs. Smith.
- It's spread, hasn't it?
- Uh, can we go over here?
- Has it spread?
- Yes. Yes, I'm afraid so.
- It's in his brain.
Oh, I thought we had a couple
of years, maybe even more.
We were supposed to go
on a bike tour in Provence.
I'm sorry, Mrs. Smith.
Well, I guess, uh, this
was supposed to happen.
Wow. I think that it's
best that it comes from me.
I think that I should
be the one to tell him.
We'll give you some time.
When you're ready, I could
come in and answer any questions.
Mr. Gallagher, your
slit-lamp exam was negative.
There is nothing in your eye.
It still hurts.
Well, maybe because
you keep rubbing it.
Maybe you're missing something.
I'd like to see an eye specialist.
Your eye will be fine.
This doesn't warrant an
Ophthalmology consult.
Doctor, the electrician
is ready to see you.
- Give him a gram of acetaminophen.
- What are you "gramming" about?
I got crap in my eye. I
wanna see the doctor.
We can fix it, but it's
gonna take a week.
How much will
it cost for a rush?
It's not the money. I
gotta wait for parts.
I don't think you understand.
If we shut down the Trauma,
patients get diverted to other ERs...
and there'll be longer
transport times and...
Hey. MAN: Did
someone say Chante?
Just give me a minute.
- Chante.
- Morris, what the hell are you doing?
My eyebrows. The
camera picks up everything.
- Get out.
- Dr. Weaver, please. I just need...
There's a rectal prolapse in Curtain
2 with your name on it. Now go.
Leave me a little
powder. I tend to shine.
Just go.
- So Josie's ankle will be fine?
- A month in a cast and she's good to go.
I told you, dear.
He thought she was gonna
need a wheelchair or something.
- No, none of that.
- Tony's very good for a neophyte.
- May I speak with you a second, please?
- Yeah, sure.
I'd like to talk to you about
your daughter. She's, uh... She...
- How do I say this?
- She got naked again?
- So it wasn't just me?
- Isn't he adorable?
Her condition makes her
act like that. It's no big deal.
This is a big deal. Have
you talked about birth control?
- Why would I do that?
- Because you're her father.
- The school will handle it.
- It's not their job.
Her school's different.
That's why we sent her there.
Look, Mr. Weller, I realize
this is a difficult conversation.
You think birth control's
the answer to...?
- Honey.
- Josie's a pretty girl.
Smart, open. If she takes her
clothes off in front of the wrong guy...
Josie likes Hilary
Duff and MySpace.
I'm sure she does...
but Josie doesn't have the same
ability to say no like other kids.
Thank you, Lucien,
for letting me scrub in.
I wish it ended better,
but I appreciate...
Listen to me.
Dr. Crenshaw is your
chief, and he owns you.
He owns you.
As smart as you think
you are, that guy is smarter.
You'll start
respecting that today.
And if you ever play me like
that again, ever run to Daddy...
when you don't like Mommy's rules,
you will be done here, do you hear me?
This is your only warning.
Now, Mr. Palsey's
family is waiting. Go.
Go.
This is Mr. Palsey's wife and
daughter. This is Dr. Rasgotra.
How's Garrett? Is he all right?
Well, when we opened
your husband's abdomen...
we found it full of blood.
- But you can fix that?
- The accident tore the vena cava.
We tried to repair it for over an
hour, but he was bleeding too fast.
Okay. Okay, so, what
happened to my father?
Mrs. Palsey, he died.
Oh, God.
- Oh, God.
- We made every effort.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Okay. It's all right. I got her, I
got her. Back up. Mrs. Palsey?
Mrs. Palsey?
- Mrs. Palsey? Mrs. Palsey?
- She should be waking up by now.
- Pulse ox only 91. PRATT:
I'll bag her through this.
- She's okay, right? PRATT:
She needs time to come around.
Systolic's down to 88.
Does your mother suffer
from a heart condition?
- No.
- High cholesterol?
- What are you talking about?
- Look at the monitor.
- ST elevation, T wave inversion.
- The leads must be reversed.
Nothing wrong with the
leads. Looks like a massive MI.
- CBC, lytes and troponins.
- MI? I know what that is.
My mother can't be
having a heart attack.
She's 45. No risk factors.
Charging to 360. Clear.
- No change.
- All right, amp of epi.
Neela, pick up the pace.
A hundred per minute.
- Is she on any medications?
- No. What's happening?
Your mom's heart's
in a dangerous rhythm.
Shock again after five cycles.
Okay, have lido ready. Acute LV
dysfunction after a sudden tragic event.
- This is broken-heart syndrome.
- I read about that. Never seen a case.
Stress cardiomyopathy
from the catecholamine surge.
- No cardiac risk factors. It all fits.
- You want the lidocaine?
Yeah, all right, 7-5, MAC
2. Someone call Cardiology.
All right, so we're
gonna give you a shot.
- I don't like shots.
- Josie, it's gonna be fine.
Yeah, it'll pinch a little at
first, but it's gonna protect you.
Did you know the Blue Line goes
from O'Hare to Irving Park Road?
Jump off and take the 80 towards
the lake. It'll drop you at Sheridan.
We're talking about something
very serious now, hon. Pay attention.
So you're gonna have to come
back every three months for a shot.
And I'm gonna give you some
education on condom use.
For when we have sex.
No, not when we have
sex, when you have sex.
That doesn't mean you're
old enough or ready...
but when the time comes, I just
wanna make sure you're prepared, okay?
Can I get a pen and
paper and take notes?
Just no props or diagrams.
- What the hell is Morris doing?
- Not his job, that's for sure.
Here we see firsthand...
the effect of overexuberant
Halloween-candy consumption.
Little Luke here has
a bowel obstruction.
Too much taffy gummed
up the works, right?
We're gonna stick this
tube in his stomach.
- He's not moving air.
- Point-3 epi sub-Q.
Continuous albuterol,
intubation tray. Call RT.
Hey, you guys are in the way.
I'm just warning parents so
people don't abuse the ER system.
Overeating Halloween candy
is not draining the system.
- This is.
- Can you explain the patient's condition?
Asthmatic. He got laid
off. No job, no insurance.
Hey, I got more stuff.
Instead of costing his
insurance company 10 bucks...
taxpayers will spend tens of thousands
of dollars taking care of him in the ER.
You're a proponent of
a national health plan?
If we had one, this guy
would be home with his kids...
instead of
fighting for his life.
That was gold.
- What's her name?
- Dr. Judas.
Three-sixty again. Clear.
- Asystole. NEELA: V-fib.
Another 50 of lidocaine.
- Let's try amiodarone.
- Neela, she's in asystole.
All right, let's try one
more round of epi.
No, please don't stop.
Syndrome causes a
transient ventricular weakness.
It's temporary. It's
reversible. She'll get better.
- We've been flogging her for 20 minutes.
- Epi's in.
- Husband just died.
- Please don't give up.
She's had five rounds.
She's not responding.
All right, hold compressions.
- Oh, God. Mom.
- Neela, stop.
Back in sinus.
You sign them out?
No. Mr. Smith? SMITH: Hey.
You got a great team here, doc.
Do you have any questions
you want me to answer or...?
No, I'm just praying
my Harley still runs.
Dr. Kovac, I'd like to sign those
papers you were talking about.
Yeah, sure. Uh,
right over there.
Give us a second, please.
You didn't tell your husband
about the brain mets?
No, he thinks the chemo
worked. Let's leave it at that.
I don't lie to patients.
Look, when he was first
diagnosed, he shut down.
For the past six months,
he's been living it up.
He's been taking tango
lessons and scuba lessons.
And we are going to
France in December.
He has the right
to know the truth.
- Why spend his last months in fear?
- Dr. Kovac?
I mean, if he just has a little
hope, at least there can be...
- There's still chance for a miracle.
- Ray, put them back in the room, please.
We wouldn't even be here if it
wasn't for that stupid car accident.
Mrs. Smith, I'm giving
you a second chance.
You're gonna tell him now or I'll
tell him when I come back, okay?
- Mr. Ames.
- You were celebrating.
In court today. You
were celebrating.
Mr. Ames, we were just happy
that the case was over, that's all.
You were happy that you got
over. Isn't that what you really mean?
Look, I have patients.
I was a patient.
Don't you remember?
Mr. Ames, you
shouldn't be back here.
Isn't this where the
sick come to get healthy?
- Because I wanna get healthy.
- Hey, do you need some help here?
- Do these people know what you did?
- It's under control. It's okay.
I came in here with a
cough, and I went out like this.
I gave you the best
treatment possible.
While I was having a
stroke, you ignored me.
- Mr. Ames, that's...
- You ignored me.
- You did.
- You should go. You should...
Go where?
- Where am I gonna go?
- Security.
If you had let me go
home in the first place...
then none of this
would've happened in the...
- What do you want me to do?
- I want you to...
I want you to give
me my life back.
- Just give me my life back.
- Come on, get up. Get up.
Give it back.
Give it back to me.
Stop. Get off.
Get him off.
Mr. Ames?
Mr. Ames, wait up.
I just wanted to make
sure you were okay.
You wanna make sure I'm okay?
No, I'm not okay.
I'm not okay at all.
See, when you came in
the court this morning...
I was telling my
kids about justice.
They were looking at
that lady with the scales.
And I said that justice
was gonna be done today.
But I don't think it was.
I know you don't
feel that way, but...
Look, I just wanna
hear it from you...
without the filters of
lawyers or judges, anybody.
Did you give me the
best possible care?
At any given moment, I'm
responsible for 40 acute patients.
We try our best to watch everyone.
It's hard. We're... We're not gods.
So you feel you
paid attention to me?
I followed your progress,
examined you once a shift.
Your wife and I were
in constant contact.
You talked to my wife?
Listen, the stress of something
like this can cause you...
No, no, no, you don't
understand. Don't understand.
After the stroke, I
came home one day...
and all of her stuff was gone.
Same with the kids.
So I called her sister, I
checked the machine.
Finally, I get an e-mail telling
me that this was too much.
This. Me.
Pursuing you, pursuing
this. It was too much.
She thought that, uh...
That nothing was
gonna ever come of this...
and that if I
couldn't move on...
then she was gonna have
to move on without me.
Eighteen years, and she
leaves me in an e-mail.
I figured that I'd just
win this, you know?
I'd win this case and I
would send that e-mail back...
and then she'd come back home.
There are people who
can help you. Groups.
But I don't want any help.
I want things back
the way they were.
I wanna work. And it wasn't
some government check.
- I build things. That's what I do.
- I know.
But I just don't
know how to fix this.
How do I fix this?
I'm sorry, I have to get back.
- No, I got it. I understand.
- Look, if you need anything...
Curtis. My name is Curtis.
Of course. Curtis.
If you need anything,
give me call, okay?
If a laparotomy is indicated to
rule out a life-threatening condition...
the procedure doesn't
become unnecessary...
just because the
condition is ruled out.
You lost me.
Well, the ER keeps accusing us of
performing unnecessary surgery...
but we believed the
guy had a triple A.
- If we waited, he'd die.
- He didn't have a triple A.
Given his symptoms, we would've
been right 90 percent of the time.
- Then surgery would have saved his life.
- Good. Do it like that.
- Okay, your turn.
- I'm fine. I know how to do this.
I'll just pull some articles.
If you're not prepared, the Attendings
are gonna have you on a spit.
- Let me take a look. Give it.
- No, I'll be fine. Hey.
You're gonna see my
secret winning strategy.
My spelling is awful, huh?
- Tony...
- Worse than awful, my...
My syntax and my grammar and...
- Yeah, but how do you...?
- I'm a little dyslexic.
I've learned to work around it,
and most of the time, it's fine.
Hi. NEELA: Hi.
- We're having girls' night out.
- You in?
- I'm busy.
- I'm free.
- Preparing for the M and M.
- Go out with the girls.
- Tony, we...
- We'll talk about this later.
Maybe it's a good thing
that you talked to him.
Yeah, he just feels alone.
Dr. Kovac, we still need to
break the news to Mr. Smith.
- She didn't tell him?
- She's sticking to her guns.
Okay, uh, go ahead and
sign out. I gotta do this.
Wait a minute, though.
We have tickets to Ig...
Yes, in an hour.
Well, we can just do
it some other night.
- You're canceling?
- Oh, my God, you're disappointed.
No, I guess I just have to go
to Ike Ryan's with everybody.
I'll come pick you up.
How's it going?
Hey, I'm ready to get out of
here, doc. How's my CT look?
Well, uh, the good news
is, there is no skull fracture.
- There's no hemorrhage.
- Thank God.
I don't know if
my wife told you...
but three years ago, I was
diagnosed with pancreatic cancer.
I don't have time for
some brain injury too.
- I got trips to take, friends to see.
- Yeah, sounds like fun.
Yeah, my wife and I, we're
going to Provence for the holidays.
Might even go to Paris, eat
some Grand Marnier crepes...
and some of the best
Bordeaux we can find.
Well, I don't wanna stand
in the way of your plans.
Uh...
All you have to do is sign these papers
and I'll start you on new medications.
You can explain them to my
wife. She handles all the medicines.
No problem. Can we talk?
Oh, my God, thank
you. Thank you so much.
He cannot ride the Harley.
- Okay, but what about the trip?
- You better rent a car and do the driving.
He could have
seizures or a stroke.
I wanna make sure I'm not
setting someone up to get hurt.
Okay, I promise.
- Okay. Good luck.
- Thank you.
- Provence is beautiful.
- How's your promotion going?
- I'm hanging in there.
Still got a few knuckleheads
I gotta beat into shape...
but other than
that, it's all right.
- Are they showing you respect?
- You know how it is.
They do what they do.
We keep pushing through it.
To pushing through it.
You'd better get that.
No, no, no, it's probably
a Jehovah's Witness.
- They're very persistent.
- Yeah.
- Save my spot, okay?
- Mm-hm.
All right, hold on.
Ah...
What you doing here?
Now's not a good time.
It's Thursday. You said I
could move in on Thursday.
No, no, I said Friday,
tomorrow, maana.
No, you said I could
move in on Thursday.
- I said Fri... WOMAN:
Hey, what's up?
- Oh. My bad.
- Who's this?
- This is my brother Chaz.
- Hey.
- How you doing?
- Hey. You, uh, moving in?
Yeah, but he's supposed
to move in Friday.
Thursday.
Oh, Greg, you cannot let
him sit out there in the hallway.
- Come on in. Are you hungry?
- I'm 18. I'm always hungry.
- Betina, come on. BETINA:
So, what can I get you?
Okay, okay, okay.
I would shag...
I don't know. I guess
I would shag Pratt.
I knew you had the fever.
And shoot Morris.
Do us all a favor.
I think you're a little
too hard on Dr. Morris.
I mean, he has potential.
Apparently, Morris is in the
process of bringing God into his life.
Dr. Weaver, is that you on TV?
Is not draining the system.
It is.
- Turn it up, turn it up.
Oh, the camera really
does show everything.
- Look at you.
- My hair looks like crap.
Kerry, you look good.
Is that Morris? - Morris?
You okay?
Bad day. And the nights are...
I've been having these dreams.
About Michael?
No, Gates.
Oh. Heh.
- It's stupid. It's my frigging hormones.
- It's not stupid. It's human.
And he's cute and he's nice.
And you can't just
sit and mourn forever.
Yeah, but it's only
been six months.
That's longer than
you were married.
- You always thought I rushed into it.
- Well, Michael was a great guy.
You were just young
and impetuous...
and I don't think he'd want
you to put your life on hold.
I know. You're right.
So, what exactly are
these dreams you're having?
Oh, your average intubation.
- Extubation. Re-intubation.
- Okay, I get it.
- Why don't you call him?
- Oh, God, no.
No, come on. You
better do it quick.
One of these girls is gonna
shag, shoot or marry him.
Well, we are studying
for the M and M together.
Excuse me.
Could you set my friend
up with some tequila?
Well.
Hey. GATES: Hey.
- What are you up to?
- Answering e-mail. What's up?
- Sarah got an A on her English paper.
- That's great.
She had to write an essay on who
she'd most like to have dinner with.
Guess who she picked.
Me, of course.
Gandhi? Madame Curie?
Keith.
- She wants to ask him why he died.
- Let me see that.
Every time I think she's
gotten over losing her father...
- This isn't bad.
- You think?
Yeah, she wants to know
why he fought in that war...
and why did he have to leave
before she got to know him.
These are good questions.
All right, all right, all
right. Call him, call him.
- Who is it?
- It's Ray, isn't it?
Are you mad? It's somebody
I met at a conference.
Then hit those digits, sister.
I miss him, T.
- Me too.
- You do?
Yeah.
Yeah, every day.
Tony, my computer crashed again.
In fact, yesterday I
went by our old school.
I thought about all the
touch football we used to play.
You mean how he used
to burn you all the time?
Yeah. In his dreams.
Well, he did get the girl, huh?
Yeah, he sure did.
- Hello?
- Uh, is Tony there?
I'm sorry, he's a little busy
right now. Can I take a message?
Never mind.
- It's a bung number.
- You wanna try it again?
- No, I'm good.
- Is it Gates?
Wait, wait, wait. Let's
get back to the game.
- Okay, Abby, shag, shoot or...?
- Not me, though.
You just don't wanna talk.