Patients who
undergo an amputation
often feel sensation
where the missing limb was
as if it's still there.
The syndrome is
called "phantom limb."
Hey, what do we got?
Plane crash. Open
fracture of the left femur.
Signs of massive infection.
Ow.
It's as if the body can't accept
that a terrible
trauma has occurred.
The mind is trying to make
the body complete again.
Patients who experience
phantom limb...
What? What's wrong?
Nothing.
Is it hurting again?
No, I'm fine. I'm fine.
Go back to sleep.
Okay.
Report many
different sensations.
But by far, the most common
is pain.
Uh, an acoustic neuroma?
Oh, boy.
A long, difficult surgery
with a stupid-high
post-excision mortality/morbidity?
That's what you want
to start my hand with?
It's my hand.
And thanks for
making it sound so fun.
You can't try something
with a little margin for error?
I was so supposed to
operate on Jimmy months ago,
but then the plane
crashed. It has to be today.
Well, if you can do this,
I guess my hand can do anything.
Still my hand. Mmm-hmm.
Uh...
Okay, folks. Let's just start.
As many of you know,
Seattle Grace-Mercy West
has suffered a financial setback.
The administration
is working hard
to keep the impact of that
setback as small as possible.
To that end,
we're gonna have to initiate
some cost-cutting measures.
The board has hired a
physician advisor to help.
What's a physician advisor?
Well, she consults on
maximizing efficiency,
streamlining processes, assessing
where we can trim our budgets.
Who to fire and
when to fire them?
She's here to
advise and to help.
I was hoping to introduce her in
person, but she seems to be late.
Oh, on her first day?
Not very efficient.
You can expect to see her in
the halls, in your labs, in the OR.
So we're gonna
have an accountant
following us around in the ORs?
She's not an accountant.
She is a trained surgeon.
Frankly, she is
here to try to help us.
Oh, okay.
Thank you for your cooperation.
Hey. Can I get a
minute? It's urgent.
Yeah.
This was urgent?
Yes. It's the stupid
pregnancy hormones.
It makes me want to have
sex all the time, urgently.
I like the stupid hormones.
Oh, no. What?
Oh, I have a consult. What?
I have a consult.
Are you crying?
No.
Yes.
I cry every time I get mad.
You're not... You're mad?
Yes, I'm mad,
because I can't have sex
because I have
this stupid consult.
Dr. Shepherd? Ross?
Sorry to bother you, sir, but I was
hoping to scrub in with you today,
and I'm supposed to
be on Dr. Grey's service.
So I was wondering if maybe
you could talk to your wife for me.
I'm gonna kill him.
No, Ross, he cannot
talk to his wife for you,
because you are with
me, and we have a consult
with a pregnant lady
with abdominal pain.
So go do the workup,
and I will see you there.
I am liking the stupid hormones.
Here you go, Doctor.
Dr. Kepner, um, we're swamped,
and I have a shortness-of-breath
lady who needs a consult,
and you probably
have better things to do,
but I need help, please.
I'm drowning here.
What bed?
One, two, three...
What are you... Stop it.
Edwards, if you're
covering the pit,
it is your job to know
every bed in the pit.
Okay. Put on
your big-girl pants.
You're about to learn
how to run the pit. Let's go.
I apologize for the wait, ma'am.
You're experiencing
shortness of breath?
Luckily, no. Forty-five
minutes in an ER bed
before a doctor pulls
out a stethoscope?
I'd likely be experiencing
shortness of life.
I don't understand.
Alana Cahill. I'm a
physician advisor.
Could you point me
towards Chief Hunt?
I'm afraid you've made
me late for a meeting.
My bad.
It's like a knife
is stabbing me.
You're sure it
isn't early labor?
Because if it is, I'm gonna
need to call my sister
and have her bring
me my makeup bag.
I'm determined to look cuter
than the baby in the pictures.
Heidi.
Sorry, honey.
I babble when I'm nervous.
Brie hates it. She's the quiet one.
Usually.
Okay, well, it's
definitely not labor,
because I'm not
seeing any contractions.
And the baby's
heart rate is good.
Did you hear that,
honey? The baby's fine.
Then what is going on?
There's a few possibilities.
The labs should help clarify.
Ross, did you get that
chem-18 I ordered?
Um, I thought I
checked off that box,
but apparently I checked chem-7.
My mistake,
which I'll quickly fix.
In the meantime, I'll leave
you the lab work I didn't forget.
I guess he babbles
when he's nervous, too.
Ah! Okay, okay.
Ah!
Everyone at Namboze
was so worried when we heard
the program might move
to UCLA, myself included.
You make the kids
feel so at home here.
Well, we were never
gonna let that happen.
No, I was away,
but now I'm back.
And as long as Dr. Karev and I are
here, then the program stays here.
Okay, um, Nyah's
pericarditis is quite severe.
The pericardial sac
around her heart is inflamed
and starting to adhere
to the heart itself.
So I'll perform what's
called pericardial stripping.
So I'll remove the sac,
and her heart will start
beating on its own again.
What shall I tell her?
Oh, tell her we're
gonna fix her heart,
and she'll breathe much better.
Nice program.
Shame to see it go.
Thanks. Wait. What?
We're getting a visit
from the efficiency fairy.
You think she's not gonna
make this disappear?
Look, shut up.
We just got it back.
She's trimming fat.
You're flying kids across the
world for a pro bono surgery.
That's pretty fatty.
Yeah, they're orphans.
Well, now you're
just making my point.
Oh, my God.
Mac 3 and cricoid pressure.
Is she okay? ET tube.
Yeah, start her on 10 mics of
dopamine, and where are the damn labs?
Here. She's in liver failure.
Talk to me, Bailey.
What's going on?
Yeah, Ross is right. Brie's
liver won't last another week.
I just went to the gift shop.
What happened?
Is this because of the baby?
No, no, no. It appears to be
unrelated to the pregnancy.
Brie's liver stopped
filtering out toxins,
so her body's shutting down.
Without a transplant, her
liver may not last 72 hours.
Don't people wait
years for a liver?
Not always. In
emergency cases like this,
patients get moved
to the top of the list.
So we've notified UNOS, and
as soon as they have a liver...
What about the baby?
The baby is
perfectly fine for now.
So now we just wait, okay?
Okay.
Do not...
Say anything.
I am so... So sorry.
Wow!
Is this you not saying anything?
Go away
and do not come
back without a liver.
Um, can I get you a tissue? Go!
Hey, there's my guy. Jimmy.
Hey, Carla. How are you?
Please say you're
not still married.
Ah, afraid so.
Ignore my sister.
No boundaries. Ah.
You think she cares?
Unless she's the wife.
You the wife? Oh,
no. You're in the clear.
Headaches still bad?
He can barely get off
the couch, he's so dizzy.
Meanwhile, I have to wait
on him like he's the boy prince.
Warms your heart, doesn't she?
- Yeah.
Wilson, what are some
of the other symptoms
of an acoustic neuroma?
Hearing loss, increased
intracranial pressure,
tingling in the face...
And being a giant
pain in my ass.
I tried to find another surgeon
when your hand healed.
Turns out, no one will go
anywhere near this thing.
Well, we're gonna run
some scans and some labs
and see if the tumor
has progressed.
You mean, it could be worse?
Well, we'll have a clearer
idea once we see the scans.
See if you can switch with Ross.
Oh.
Did I... No, it's
nothing you did wrong.
It's that Ross knows what I
want before I even ask for it.
I won't have time to
teach you on this one.
Shepherd, this is Alana Cahill.
She is our physician advisor.
Derek Shepherd. Neuro.
I saw you're doing
an acoustic neuroma.
Very exciting. First
thing tomorrow.
Patient's here today.
Are pre-op overnight stays
typical in all departments?
That is a question
for Chief Hunt.
If you'll excuse
me, I have to prep.
Hmm. Well, I'll see
you in the OR tomorrow.
Typically, you
need to be invited.
If things were
running typically,
I wouldn't be here, now would I?
Okay.
Brian Turner, age 55.
Minor head injury.
Vital signs stable.
Fell off the damn ladder
cleaning the damn gutter.
I was gonna say all
that. Fewer damns.
You'll need to know if he
lost consciousness in the field.
Sir, did you lose
consciousness in the field?
I didn't fall in a damn
field. I fell in my damn yard.
Ask the paramedic,
not the patient.
Oh, he was conscious
the whole damn time.
Um, could we just start over?
Uh, no time. Get
him triaged. Go.
Forty-five minutes in an
ER bed before I saw a doctor.
Well, that's not good.
No, it's not.
Alana Cahill?
Uh, Dr. Webber.
Wow.
Alana was a student of mine,
uh, how many years ago now?
Oh, do we really have to say?
She was a great student
and a gifted surgeon.
So what brings you back?
You looking at joining the staff?
She is the physician
advisor that I told you about.
Ah. Um...
Well, we should get a
cup of coffee, catch up.
I'd love to, but
I'm pretty booked.
In fact, we should
get going. Mmm-hmm.
Uh, of course. It was,
uh, great to see you.
Your hero sent me to
trade services with you.
You're welcome. Can't.
I'm waiting for UNOS
to call with a liver.
So go wait in the OR while you
play teacher's pet with Shepherd.
I'm not moving from this spot.
Great cell reception.
See? Five bars.
You know it's not like
ordering a pizza, right?
It could take days.
My patient doesn't have days.
Okay, fine. I'll wait.
And when UNOS calls, I'll
run to Medusa. I promise.
Give me my phone.
If I miss the call,
Grey is gonna kill me.
If I go back to Shepherd and
I'm not you, he's gonna kill me.
Give me my phone.
Oh, my God.
Give me the phone.
Hello?
The pericardium is free.
You should see an increase
in, uh, cardiac function.
It's weird. Heart's floppy.
Still not the way a
kid's heart should look.
Mmm. Could be endocarditis.
I'll do a biopsy.
Biopsy needle, please.
Unless it's...
Oh, my God. It
couldn't, could it?
Could this be
endomyocardial fibrosis?
I've only read about
it. It's rare, subtropical.
Could this be that? Maybe.
Remember we had that kid
with Pentalogy of Cantrell?
This program...
Is a medical freak
show goldmine.
They can't cut it.
Nobody's cutting it. Robbins,
tell her to stop saying that.
I'm sorry. What?
You all right? Uh.
Okay, um, take that
to path. Stat, please.
Oh, you know what? I'll take
it. Alex, you take my place.
The nurse can take it.
No, I'd rather take it myself.
Oh.
Are there pastries and bagels
in every one of your lounges?
No. Well, maybe. I don't know.
Is that the kind of thing
you're gonna be looking at?
I will be looking at
everything, Doctor.
Huh. Um...
Dr. Robbins. This
is Alana Cahill.
Oh.
Uh, are you all right?
Mmm-hmm. I'm
fine. I'm sorry. I...
Could you just give us a minute?
Of course.
That was the
efficiency lady, right?
Yeah, so I probably look
as crazy as a bag of cats.
So it was nice working with you.
It's your phantom limb pain?
Callie said it only
happens at night.
Until now.
I'm going crazy. I...
You're not. You're not crazy.
Phantom limb is
a very real thing.
I just left a surgery
because there was pain in a
part of me that no longer exists.
So I... What are you doing?
We're helping you visualize
a leg that doesn't hurt.
Here we go. Now...
Just look at that.
I... Are you kidding me?
We are rerouting your brain,
reminding it of what happened.
There are many
treatments for phantom limb.
There's heat, there's massage,
there's virtual reality therapy.
I knew a guy in the army
who had to stab his prosthetic
with a screwdriver
as hard as he could.
Oh, great. Well,
that's not crazy.
Well, for him, it was the
only thing that worked.
Now...
Is your pain any better?
It is, a little.
You see? You just need to
figure out what works for you.
Callie knows all this.
What does she say?
I haven't told her.
She's an orthopedic surgeon.
And I have been her
patient for so long.
And I am just starting
to feel like a wife again,
and she needs me
to. I cannot have this.
I am finally getting
my life back together,
and I will not be screwed over
by something that's not even there!
All right.
We're gonna work together.
We're gonna work together,
and I'm gonna help you,
and we are gonna
figure this out.
Okay?
African babies are a godsend.
You don't have to tell me.
Oh, not Zola. Not the cute ones.
The sick ones.
They're exotically diseased
beautiful little train wrecks.
I just found a case of EMF,
and I get to do an endocardial
stripping of the left ventricle.
Do you know how many
other people have done that?
No. Me neither. It's unheard of.
Where are you going? I have
to see a man about a liver.
Dr. Bailey.
Can I please get another intern?
What's wrong with Ross?
A lot.
The kid made a tiny mistake.
Because he's an idiot.
If I have to work with
him one more second,
I'm probably gonna kill him.
Uh, you think I
didn't want to kill you?
You cut LVAD wires,
and yet there you stand.
So... Be merciful
and suck it up.
Cousin Dora sent him
a stupid giant cookie,
but he can't eat before surgery.
So now I'm starving
and I gotta look at this
giant freakin' cookie
that I can't have!
I keep just telling her
to eat the damn thing.
Oh, so you can make fat jokes?
Then throw it away. Jimmy...
Oh, no. What's that
look? What's wrong?
The tumor's progressed.
But you could
still operate, right?
Yes, we can,
but all those risks we
talked about before...
Like me going deaf...
Or half my face being
melted like it was blowtorched,
or me not surviving at all?
Yeah, the chances of those
things happening are much higher.
So... You should take some time
and think about if you
still want to do the surgery.
I've taken time.
I waited for months
for you to get better.
Doc, I can't just sit here and
wait for this thing to kill me.
I'm dying, she
makes it about her.
Hey.
I'm sorry. I can't
let him see me cry.
I'll never hear the
end of it. No, it's okay.
It's a horrible
thing to say, I know,
but when I heard you
were in a plane crash,
part of me was relieved.
It's an awful thing that
happened to you, and I'm so sorry.
But it gave me more
time with my brother.
These past months have
been the best we've had.
I'm ready.
We both are.
Here's the recheck on the
calcium level you asked for.
Ross is gone, sir. I'm sorry.
He and Dr. Grey
went to go get a liver.
I don't want anybody
in the gallery.
I don't need an audience.
You up for this? Mmm-hmm.
I want you to know,
the thing with the labs,
it won't ever happen again.
Okay. Just let it go, okay?
Congrats on the baby.
Thank you.
You must be, what,
three months in?
Baby's the size of a lemon.
So... Second trimester, huh?
The fetus is growing feet...
Discharging urine
into the amniotic fluid.
And you must be feeling
better, less nausea.
But the second trimester's
also known to bring with it
swollen gums, heartburn, gas...
Do you want me to start crying?
And on three. One, two, three.
Last BP was 110 over 70, but there
was significant dashboard damage.
Stop. Dr. Edwards, what injuries
are we most concerned
with in this patient?
We always start with the ABCs...
If you'd been listening to the
paramedic, you'd have your answer.
Can you start over?
There was significant
damage to the dashboard...
What's the basic law
of motion, Edwards?
The basic...
Energy cannot be
created or destroyed,
but can change in
form or be absorbed.
Uh, which means the
impact to the dashboard
was absorbed by the patient.
So the injuries we're
most concerned with are?
Are knee injury,
possible pelvis, c-spine.
Correct. Matthew here
stabilized the pelvis in the field.
It really wasn't
that big of a...
So now you can start your exam.
Mmm-hmm.
So I'll just... See
myself out then.
Okay.
Okay, Ross. There's the knot.
It's a nice one.
Uh, okay.
Yes, thank you. Scissors.
Careful now.
We're just gonna cut the suture
as close to the knot
as possible without...
Oh, no.
Are you serious?
Oh, no, no, no, no, no.
Oh!
You cut the hepatic
artery in the hilum.
You cut the hilum before
I had a chance to say,
"Don't cut the hilum!"
You see what he did?
Don't ever do that.
Clamp.
I don't know. Um, Dr. Robbins.
Hey. Everything,
uh, work out all right?
Yeah, I'm sorry that you had
to see that. It was a personal...
You were having a moment. Yeah.
We all have 'em.
Just sucks when they
happen at work, right?
I was, uh, just telling Dr. Cahill
how well Nyah's surgery went.
Yeah.
And that you let me finish
the surgery on my own.
- Oh, yeah.
- Thanks again.
That's impressive for a fellow.
Oh, well, he's
more than qualified.
Well, I will be observing
Nyah's second surgery tomorrow.
So will that be
you or Dr. Karev?
Oh, no, me, of course.
Yeah. With our
cardio fellow Dr. Yang.
All right. I will see you there.
- Okay.
What's going on?
Nothing. I'm fine.
I'm sorry about this morning.
Are we all set for tomorrow?
Uh... 8:30, OR two.
Great.
Look, if you want to sit it
out, Yang and I can handle it.
Maybe, you know, you
should just take it easy.
It's just that Yang
keeps squawking about
how they're gonna
cut the program,
and I just don't
want anything to...
Yeah. Um, are you finished?
I just want
everything to go well.
Then I'll see you
tomorrow morning.
10-Blade, please.
Did...
Did you see that?
God! Ah!
Ah!
Oh.
Ah! Oh.
Morning.
Oh. You all right in there?
Um, yeah. No, I'm
fine. I'm fine. I was just...
I'm about to take a shower.
Oh, want some company?
Um, yeah, of course I do.
It's just, I'm,
um, running late.
So, uh, how about tonight?
Yeah. How about a movie night?
Yeah. You read my mind.
Okay. All right.
Unfortunately there was
a surgical complication
with the donor liver,
and it is no longer viable.
Oh, God.
Okay. So what happens now?
Well, Brie is back
on the transplant list.
We'll continue supportive
care so her body's ready
if another liver
becomes available
or if we have to
deliver the baby.
A c-section? Can
she handle that?
Any surgery is risky,
and her condition is causing
her blood to stop clotting.
So we need to continue
with the blood transfusions
and buy her some time until
a liver becomes available.
If a new liver
becomes available.
Yes. HEIDI: Oh, God.
The last thing I said to her
is, "You're gonna be fine."
You have to fix her, please.
Yeah. Here.
You can see that she's
still on the respirator.
Her vitals actually...
Uh...
I hope you won't mention my
colossal incompetence to your husband.
He... Still thinks
I'm the golden boy.
No, stop that. You
don't get to do that.
You don't get to
feel sorry for yourself
or make little
self-deprecating remarks.
You destroyed a
perfectly good liver today.
When I look at
you, that is all I see.
A perfectly...
good liver. Hold on a sec.
I'm not done. Put
your phone away.
I'm sorry.
Don't be sorry. Be better.
I think it's UNOS.
Hello.
Can I help you find something?
No. I'm just observing
surgeries today,
and I'm trying to
maximize my time.
Shepherd's acoustic
neuroma is at 8:00,
and that's gonna be a long one.
Just trying to be
everywhere at once.
Actually, Shepherd's
surgery got pushed till later.
Oh, I totally misread that.
That is going to work
so much better for me.
Thank you, Doctor.
Maybe that, uh, gives
us time for coffee.
I'm afraid not.
Just time for me to
see more surgeries.
Well, I always did expect
to see you in the OR.
One way or another, right?
Right.
Okay, now breathe.
Try to calm the waves.
Try to slow them down.
What's the point here?
Well, the idea is,
if you can teach your
mind to calm the waves,
you can teach it
to calm the pain.
But I...
I can't do it. I can't do
it. It's... This is dumb.
This is not dumb.
It is biofeedback.
Look, I can't stop the
stupid make-believe waves.
So... What else you got?
Well, I have a minimally
invasive spinal surgery
that can deaden your nerves.
No, no, I have to operate today.
Then I got make-believe waves,
or I got a
make-believe waterfall,
or a make-believe campfire.
Or I could just find a
screwdriver and stab it in your foot.
Just stab me in the head.
CT results on pelvic fracture.
Thoracentesis if
positive effusion.
Um, musculoaponeurotic grafts?
What are you doing?
What am I... What are you doing?
I thought you were
trying to talk dirty.
I didn't want you to feel
like the only giant nerd.
I was talking out loud?
Yeah.
Though I was
weirdly kind of into it.
Mmm.
Um, I have 60 million
things to do today,
and I'm sure I'm
gonna forget something.
Kepner's running me ragged.
And that's not working
for me anymore.
Um...
You know, if you're too
busy for this, we can, um...
I am not too busy for this.
Mmm.
I am too busy for this.
All right.
Thank you for understanding.
Okay.
Her last AST was 23-42.
INR was 6.
Is it viable?
I think it's a match.
She'd be crying if it wasn't.
She cries when she's angry,
which is whenever she sees me.
Look.
She's looking at me and not
crying. It's gotta be a match.
Thank you so much. Thank you.
We have a match.
You're gonna fly
to Portland, Oregon.
I will fly to Portland, Oregon,
to retrieve a liver for a woman
who I've already
destroyed one liver?
Is that the wisest
use of our resources?
I can't. I can't get on a
plane. You know that.
I know you haven't
been on a plane.
Maybe it's time you try again.
Their procurement team is
going to do all of the work.
You know good and well we
prefer to do the recovery ourselves.
All he has to do is
carry a cooler. Meredith.
If he's been to a picnic,
he can handle this.
Shane, have you
ever been to a picnic?
I've been to a picnic.
Oh, look at that.
He's been to a picnic.
These women deserve
more experience
than a fool who's eaten
a potato salad in a park.
She's right. Maybe I'm
not the best person...
You're an intern. Of course
you're gonna make mistakes.
Bad things happen, but
you have to move past it.
Leave it behind you,
the sooner the better,
or it'll eat away at you and
stop you from moving forward.
So just get over yourself.
Move past it, and get
your butt on that plane.
So... Now I'm confused.
Who's going to Portland?
I can't.
You and I are going to Portland.
Mmm. Okay.
So, Wilson, what do you see?
Cerebellum and
occipital brain tissue.
Mmm-hmm. Healthy,
perfect tissue...
Tissue that needs to be wet.
So every 10 minutes when
you hear that timer ding,
you need to drench the tissue.
Okay.
Okay, good. Now when
I get close to the tumor,
what I'm gonna do is,
I'm gonna ask you to...
Drench the tissue. Got it.
No. I'm going to stimulate
the facial nerve with a probe.
And then I'm gonna ask you to
tell me when Jimmy's face twitches.
As long as we see a twitch,
his facial function is still intact.
Okay. Drench the tissue.
Well, let's go. What
are we waiting for?
I got word to hold a minute.
Okay, you're
right. I can do this.
Get off.
All right. Well, call me when
you get eyes on the liver.
Yeah.
It looks good so far, Bailey.
Now remember, once we get it
out, we're only 50 minutes out.
So you can start prepping her.
Dr. Ross. I, no.
I can't make the cut this time.
Let's stop while we're ahead.
No, I don't want
you to make the cut.
I want you to get the basin so
I can put the liver in the basin.
Can you do that?
Yes. That I can do.
Uh, Dr. Grey...
Is that a mass?
No. It isn't?
No, I mean, it is.
We have to have that biopsied.
And how much does
the Africa program cost?
Less than you'd think.
Admin costs comes
out of an endowment,
and all the surgical
time is donated.
But endowments
don't tend to grow
with the popularity
of these programs,
where, very soon,
you have every sick kid
in Africa banging
down your door.
What happened?
You need me to step in?
No. No.
Robbins?
Try to picture the waves.
I'm trying.
Okay, really, what is happening?
Just calm the waves.
These are tsunami-force
waves, Owen.
What is wrong with this woman?
I mean, is she
having a panic attack?
Should she even be in the OR?
Don't you have another
operation you need to go see?
I mean, Shepherd's doing...
Yeah, an acoustic
neuroma, but that's later.
No, it's now. He
started hours ago.
Look, you should
go. I'll take over.
All right. No one is moving.
I'm stripping the endocardium
from the papillary muscle.
I screw this up, I'll have
to replace the mitral valve,
so don't move.
I can switch
out... Just shut up.
I'm at the beach.
Something's wrong.
They should be back by now.
Something's wrong, isn't it?
Uh, um...
There was a mass on the liver.
We're waiting
for pathology to...
Oh, God. A mass
means cancer. It's cancer.
You got two donor
livers in two days.
There's no chance
we're getting another one.
If this one has cancer, then...
Okay, okay, Heidi, just...
It's not bad news yet.
Okay? So just come on.
Take deep breaths.
Okay?
Oh.
Grey.
Okay. Yeah.
I'll see you in 50 minutes.
Liver's fine.
Oh, thank God.
Okay. Thank you.
All right.
Okay, now we have
to remove the tumor
from the nerve
sheath. Stimulator.
Uh, I don't see any nerve
fibers. It encased the entire nerve?
Yeah, I'm afraid so.
Okay, facial function.
Still twitching.
Syringe.
I was worried I missed the
whole thing. Where are we at?
Where we're at is,
I'm trying to focus.
I mean, how long has
the patient been open?
Counting the minutes I'm
wasting answering your questions?
I'd have fewer questions,
but your intern told me
that the surgery had
been moved to 3:00.
Clearly, it wasn't.
So forgive me if I'm
trying to play catch up.
Intern mistake. I apologize.
Dr. Wilson was under orders
not to allow any visitors...
I'm not a visitor, Dr. Shepherd.
Anyone who is not
surgically necessary
is not welcome in my OR.
All right, cottonoid,
Boki, please.
I have to switch, Alex.
No one is switching.
You're holding the mitral
valve, so don't move.
What's wrong? Are you sick?
Alex, take that scalpel...
What? What are you doing?
And stab me in the foot.
What? What?
My prosthetic. Stab me.
What is wrong with you?
Dr. Karev, I am
the chief of surgery.
This is an order.
Stab Dr. Robbins
in the foot right now.
What?
Alex.
Of course.
Arizona? Alex!
That's better.
Suction.
What happened? Did I...
You didn't do anything.
It's a bleeder. Cautery.
Cottonoid.
Okay.
Got it. How's the
facial function?
I'm sorry. I don't see a twitch.
Come on, Jimmy. Twitch.
Damn it.
What does that mean?
It means we may have cost Jimmy
the ability to
move half his face.
We won't know until he wakes up.
Oh, perfect timing, Grey.
Oh, no. Did I step on your foot?
No. I'm not mad this time.
Oh. So you cry when
you're happy, too?
Apparently.
Eyes on the liver.
Learn something.
Edwards, status report.
Uh, uh...
Your MVC is in bed
one waiting on an angio.
I paged an ortho consult for
bed 2, and drunk guy in bed 3.
And what's in bed 4? New
patient. Patellar dislocation.
And bed 13?
There is no bed 13.
Good job, Edwards. You passed.
And your waiting room
is clear. Nicely done.
Ah, sorry to interrupt.
Do you need something?
Kinda.
I've been watching you for two
days. You don't seem to slow down.
I thought you might need a
break. Maybe grab a cup of coffee?
Probably shouldn't
have started with
the whole "watching
you" thing, huh?
Now you think I'm some
sort of creeper. I'm not.
Unless you're inclined to
have coffee with creepers,
in which case, I totally
creep, like, all the time.
Her heart is, uh,
pumping like a champ.
Thank you, both of you.
What else do you
have over there?
I'm sorry?
Uh... Sick...
Orphan... Children?
Kids with heart problems?
Ah.
She means, she's glad the
program is up and running again.
Both of us are.
Yes.
Look at me. I'm a mess.
I ate a stupid big cookie.
That's what you get when you
keep me worried sick for 22 hours.
Hey, Jimmy, can you
wince like that again?
Answer the man.
Facial expression
looks symmetrical.
Mmm-hmm. Did he...
Can you hear me?
Who could ignore that voice?
All right, welcome.
Welcome, everyone.
Thank you so much for coming.
It has been a privilege
to watch you work,
and I am so impressed
with what I've seen.
Dr. Karev's pediatric
African exchange program...
You cannot cut that program.
I'm sorry, but these children,
these... Little orphans...
We are the only hope they have.
Many of them have rare disorders
that most western doctors
rarely have the opportunity to treat.
And if you stop the program, I
will never get that chance again.
They.
They will never get that
chance, the precious children.
I have no intention
of cutting it.
Super.
It's a no-brainer
from a PR standpoint.
That kind of positive
visibility is gold.
However, there will
have to be some cuts.
And I'm going to suggest one
that is going to seem
surprising at first,
but that addresses
fiduciary concerns
with nominal impact
on the core facility
and the human and
physical resources.
Oh. I'm sorry. What?
Uh, yeah. I'm out.
I am proposing that
we close your ER.
What?
We're a level one trauma center.
We're a hospital.
In the last three days,
your ER went from being in
shambles to peak efficiency.
Well, then why would
you propose cutting it?
This allowed me to
see that in either case,
it's not bringing in the money.
It's bringing in the patients.
Over half of whom are
non-emergent, underinsured,
and belong in a primary
care physician's office.
You have surgical interns
in there doing chest exams.
It's hemorrhaging resources.
Look, I know these cuts
are going to be painful.
But understand that I am trying
to keep your
hospital doors open.
This is ridiculous.
You can't close the ER.
You went to med school.
You have to ask yourself...
Do you have a better idea?
Because the way I see it,
this woman is trying to keep
the hospital from closing,
in which case
there'd be no patients,
we'd have no jobs,
and some of us don't have
a few million to fall back on.
So unless you
have a better idea,
why don't you just sit there and
listen to what she has to say?
All right.
So... The other proposals
include a review of
ICU, step-down closures
with a reorganization
of post-op care...
Alana.
Wow. You've been
here three days.
I've been here for years.
Maybe you judged
us a little harshly.
Maybe we can work together...
Being a harsh judge is a
necessary part of my job, sir.
I can see you're
disappointed in me,
but it was your job to judge
me when you were my teacher.
You're not anymore. No,
that's not the case. I'm...
You said something to
us during my intern year
that I have never forgotten.
You said, "Medicine
is constantly changing.
"You need to be part of
that change or get out."
I'll be making some changes.
You should be proud of me.
By the way,
you logged fewer OR hours
than any other general
surgeon on staff last month.
Good night.
The body can be stubborn
when it comes to
accepting change.
Ugh. This...
This is so stupid.
We're a level 1 trauma
center. This woman's an idiot.
Well, and a little bitchy.
This was supposed
to be a good day.
Shepherd did a 23-hour surgery.
We're supposed to be
popping champagne.
Let's try and go to sleep.
I don't think I
can. I'm so pissed.
The mind holds out hope
that the body can
be whole again.
Do you want to go
to the beach with me?
What?
And the mind will
always fight for hope,
tooth and nail...
Bailey had no business
calling you out like that.
She's nervous.
Everybody's nervous.
Everybody should be nervous.
It's not our fault.
Is it?
It feels like it is.
Hey, congratulations.
For what?
Your acoustic neuroma.
Mmm.
You got your hand
back. You're you again.
We can be happy about that.
Until it finds a way
of understanding
this new reality...
I flew on a plane today.
You did?
I did.
Congratulations.
And accepts that what is gone
is gone forever.
This really kind of works.