Previously, on
"New Amsterdam"...
I'm his son, Your Honour.
I can take care of him.
He can come home with me.
Why don't you answer
your phone?
I've called you, like,
a million times.
- I have not had a second...
- Mom kicked it.
Yeah. Like a date.
♪ They gon' talk about me,
they gon' talk about me ♪
♪ They can't walk around me,
they can't walk around me ♪
♪ I'm rich as, rich as,
I'm rich as, rich as ♪
♪ Them can sick a duck,
you can sick a duck ♪
Hmm.
♪ Like I'm Dan Bilzerian ♪
♪ I get ten Brazilians
like I'm Dan Bilzerian ♪
♪ I'm rich as, rich as,
I'm rich as, rich as ♪
♪ Them can sick a duck,
just sick a duck ♪
Ah, check you out!
What did you do to my sink?
Upgrading it.
Pop! Pop!
This is not an upgrade!
Your water pressure's
terrible.
No, it wasn't!
Now I got to fix this.
What? Man, just look,
I'm soaking wet.
And don't touch anything else.
You want me to fix it or not?
I want you to not trash
my apartment.
I'm not the one
who overpaid for this place.
That's your problem.
I'm over here
doing you a favour.
A favor?
You know what?
I saw the building you manage.
No of fence, but don't do me
no favours, all right?
Just don't upgrade
anything else
until I get off work, please.
You might wanna change first.
Can't sleep.
Still in shock.
Instead of filling
that glass,
can you help me clean a few?
Was that really necessary,
Lauren?
Like, right now?
No.
Sorry.
I mean, are you even
mourning Mom, or...?
What?
Of course I'm mourning her.
Okay, well, you might be able
to completely shut down,
compartmentalise, and run off
to your little job...
Oh, because I have a job,
you think I don't care
that our mother is dead?
Whatever, Lauren,
I'm just saying,
I need time to process this,
all right?
This is, like...
This is, like, a loss.
I mean, Jesus,
I don't even know how this...
I don't even know
how this happened.
Right, yeah,
how could a 63-year-old
pill-popping, raging alcoholic
just fall down and die?
Quite easily, as it turns out.
And the way you adjust, Ness,
is by letting this
be a wake-up call.
Start taking responsibility
for your life.
Oh, my God, you can't
help yourself, can you?
You know, I thought
you weren't supposed to take
people's inventory
in whatever "A" you're in.
Can you just sober up
before we have the meeting
with the lawyer tonight?
And there it is... that is what
this is really about, Lauren,
isn't it?
Put on a united front
so they can crown you
the executor
of Mom's entire estate.
Right, well,
one of us has to be
the responsible one, right?
And I tell you this much,
I'm not going to enable you
the way Mom did.
No more allowance
so you can spend it on drugs.
No more free rent
so you can turn your place
into a crack den.
Nope, that all ends today.
So you can figure
something else out.
Hmm.
Mm.
Please?
Oh, Max, looking for you.
Always nice to see you,
Elizabeth.
You too.
So here.
The patient satisfaction
survey results.
Great.
Clearly you haven't
read them.
I have not,
but these are gonna be
a great distraction.
From what?
From myself.
Patient satisfaction surveys.
Wanna know your PSS scores?
- No.
- 44%.
Okay, you wanna know why
I get bad scores?
I've been compiling a list
over the years.
Last week, a woman complained
because the person next to her
was dying too loudly.
- Hmm.
- Dying too loudly!
- It's a hospital.
- Yeah, it is.
Keep up the great work.
- Floyd, just in time.
- For what?
The, uh, patient
satisfaction scores are in.
Your department received a...
Dr um roll, please...
51%.
Ugh. Sorry, man.
Oh, don't be. It's great.
Nailed it!
39%.
Your department officially has
the lowest score.
All of my patients
have cancer, Max.
Of course my department has
the lowest score.
Yeah, of course, great work.
Thank you.
I'll see you later, okay?
- Hmm. Oh, hey.
- Oh!
Iggy, just the man
I wanted to see.
Do you mind if I talk to you
about your PSS scores?
Oh, oh, all right.
Uh, what are we looking at?
Some high-60s, mid-70s? What?
Actually, it's, um...
It's 91%.
- It's 91%?
- Mm.
- That-that's huge.
That's a new record. Yes!
Up top!
No, no, not up top.
That number is terrible.
Uh, 91% satisfaction
is terrible?
Correct.
Satisfaction is not really
our goal, health is.
I think if we were
selling smoothies or Slinkys,
then these patient
satisfaction surveys
would be a great barometer
of how we were doing that,
but our patients come
to New Amsterdam
on arguably the worst day
of their life,
where we tell them things
they really don't wanna hear.
So I think if they are
"satisfied,"
then that means
we're doing something wrong,
or we're asking
the wrong questions.
- Does it really now?
- Mm-hmm.
"Were you greeted
with a smile?"
Really?
"Did you enjoy the décor?"
Honestly, who cares?
Since my entire department's
grant funding
is directly tied
to these scores...
Which are stellar...
- I care.
- Good!
I'm glad you do. I care too.
That's why I'm changing
the survey.
What? No, no. What? No!
Just to be more accurate.
More honest questions
means more honest answers.
- Max... Max!
- Iggy.
If we're not improving,
we're failing.
You'll thank me later.
Hiya Diallo,
12-year-old female.
Bike accident, head trauma.
LOC on the scene.
Avi Diallo, 17-year-old male.
Elbow contusions,
multiple skin abrasions.
Please help my sister!
A car swerved
into our bike lane.
I tried to help her...
It's okay. It's okay.
We got it.
Both pupils are sluggish.
She needs a head CT stat.
Let's move.
Avi. How you feeling?
How's my sister?
Did she wake up?
She sustained
a significant amount of trauma
to the right side of her brain.
She has what's called
a subdural hematoma,
which means there's bleeding
in her brain from the fall.
She also has paralysis
of the left arm.
Look, she needs surgery
right away
to avoid a brain herniation
that could be fatal.
No, eh, I...
Now, are your parents
at home?
Are they at work?
We need to notify them
right away.
You can't... they're in,
um, Cancun.
Vacationing.
Okay, can we get
their number?
No, no.
- Ah, name of the hotel?
- No.
They-they check in
when they can.
But if they call
when you do the surgery,
I'll update them.
Okay. Uh, thanks, Avi.
I'm gonna go check on Hiya.
And be right back, okay?
Dr. Turan, can you call
Child Protective Services
for me?
Why? What's going on?
Nothing that kid
is telling me is true.
Oh, you trying
to win a sister over
- with sugar now, huh?
- Hey, trying?
I thought I already had.
Uh, although I am sorry for all
the back-and-forth lately.
Ever since my pops moved in,
things have been out of whack.
But maybe, just maybe,
we can make up for lost time.
Or maybe the time we had
was enough.
I'm supposed to be
leaving soon, anyway.
Yeah, you keep saying that.
Excuse me.
Uh, you looking
for the OB department?
Yes, I need to give up
my baby.
Oh, are you, uh, in labor?
Mm-mm.
Do you need to talk
to a hospital social worker
about the adoption process?
No.
I need my baby
to be delivered today.
Otherwise, I'm gonna kill it.
And for you.
- Here you go.
- Thank you.
- Are these the new surveys?
- Sure are. There you go.
And remember,
complete candour is welcome.
And for you.
Hey, hey.
Are you seeing this?
Are you doing the surveys
over the phone?
Max told me to call.
Call who?
Every patient we have.
And there you go.
Hi, Maureen.
I'm ready for you.
Sorry, Iggy,
don't want to bias the results.
- Uh...
- Here we go.
Gladys, you're better
than that.
Fill that out.
One through five.
Just fill whatever feels right.
Go ahead and mark that down.
Uh-huh.
Almost there, Dr. Frome.
Just need to finish
this survey.
Turns out I got a lot to say.
Bob, Louise,
thank you for coming.
Skip the preamble.
Just tell me how long.
Whatever time I have left,
I wanna spend
as little time as possible
in this office.
She'd tell you
if you stop talking.
Okay, so-so I actually,
I have some good news.
I just got your numbers.
And they're what?
They are phenomenal.
Your cancer
has shrunk dramatically.
Uh, now I get
to tell you something
that I don't get to say
often enough.
You're looking
at a full remission.
I told you, Louise.
I told you!
A miracle occurs,
and the first thing you do
is yell at your wife.
Real nice, Bob. Real nice.
Sour grapes?
- Mm...
- I'm relieved, okay?
What the hell's wrong with you?
Uh, a cancer diagnosis
is stressful on everyone.
Even good news
can be hard to accept
after months of chemotherapy.
But that's where
you're wrong.
I haven't had months of chemo
because I've been throwing
your stupid pills
in the garbage.
Straight into the trash.
Against his wife's wishes.
Okay, hold on, you have been
throwing away your chemo pills?
They made me feel sick,
so I stopped taking 'em.
And now? I'm not sick.
You doctors, acting so fancy.
You have no clue.
Just a bunch of puppets
for Big Pharma.
Mr. Levin, Mr. Levin...
Yeah, save it
for the next sucker.
Come on, Louise.
Mm-mm. Rise up!
- Take off the blinders!
- Apologies. Again.
- Get out of the chair!
- He gets crazy.
Bob!
Olivette, I know you
don't want to harm your baby.
Um, you wouldn't be here
if you did.
So you wanna tell us
what's going on?
Olivette, when was
your last prenatal visit?
Uh...
I haven't gone to any.
You're afraid
you'd be judged?
Are you still using?
I stopped once I found out
I was pregnant.
Okay, so you intended
to keep the baby.
Yes.
The baby was gonna be
my new chapter.
I'd be clean.
Like the best mom, you know?
But...
Then you went back out.
About a week ago.
First time in months.
Okay, so what changed?
Didn't need anything
to change.
It's what I do.
Knew it was gonna happen
eventually.
No family, friends?
Any support?
None out here.
Olivette, you slipped.
It happens. That's all.
Nah, that ain't
the end of it.
I'm gonna keep using,
I know it.
And when was the last time
that you felt the baby kick?
Any movement?
I don't know, a few days ago.
Maybe.
I heard 26 weeks is safe
for a baby to be born.
Is that true or not?
Technically, yes, uh,
the baby can survive
at six months.
- But you're not in labor, and...
- I don't care.
It's not safe with me.
I need it out.
Avi.
Hiya's stable.
They're gonna be taking her
for surgery soon.
She is? Thank you.
While they're prepping her,
I need you to come with me.
There's someone who I want you
to talk to, okay?
You called them.
CPS.
Okay, as a doctor,
I am mandated by the state
to report
any suspicious behaviour.
What suspicious behaviour?
Are your parents really
in Cancun?
Is Hiya even your sister?
Yes.
Okay.
That's a start.
Look, I wanna help you, okay?
But you need to come with me.
Sure.
All right.
Just let me get my bag?
Don't...
Avi. Avi, Avi, don't do this.
You said you'd help us!
You lied!
Avi. Avi, come on.
- Open the door.
- I can't.
Look, this isn't helping...
Hiya or you!
We can't be in the system.
They'll separate us!
Master key.
You want me to call security?
No, no.
Look, Avi.
Avi, we're coming in.
Damn it, Avi!
- What's-what's happening?
- Avi. Avi, she's crashing.
We have to get her up
to the OR right now.
No. Turn off the alarm!
I can't do it from out here!
I know you're doing this!
I know it's a trick!
No! This is real!
Look, if you don't
let us in there right now,
then your sister
is going to die!
Get her up to the OR stat!
Hot off the presses
and straight
into a hermetically
sealed envelope.
Are you ready
for your new PSS scores?
It's no the Oscars, Max.
Just open the damn thing.
And the Oscar goes to...
36%.
Th... oh, my God.
No. This can't be happening.
Now you have honest feedback
to make real improvement.
Max, my funding will be cut.
Okay, listen to this.
"My new meds made me feel sick,
and I couldn't get a follow-up
for a month."
"When I'm in crisis,
I don't want to wait a week
for my next appointment."
"I had to wait three months
to get my first appointment."
Now, if you're asking me,
seems like the unifying factor
here is wait time.
Great... so are you
gonna spring
for ten new therapists?
I don't know
if it's a staffing issue.
Seems more like
a scheduling issue.
Okay, sure,
but you know that scheduling
will never be perfect because
it's not like a patient
can predict
a mental health crisis.
You know that, right?
I do,
and I couldn't agree more.
- Good. Really?
- Yeah.
You're saying
that mental health
is inherently unschedule-able,
so why not toss the whole
schedule out the window?
Right, no more appointments,
first come, first serve.
I think that's really smart,
buddy.
Uh, hi, can I have the room
for a second, please?
Max.
No appointments will be
wildly disruptive
- to my department, okay?
- Yeah.
My patients rely heavily
on structure.
Uh-huh.
The predictability
and reliability
of scheduled appointments
is everything...
Routine is the cornerstone
of their mental health.
Iggy, I hear you,
but this isn't me, okay?
This is the survey.
This is what
your patients want.
You know what?
I actually can't even discuss
this with you right now.
Why? Why not?
Because you didn't make
an appointment.
See what I did there? Wouldn't
it be nice if you could just
show up with your problems
and get help when you need it?
That's the beauty
of open access,
and some of these patients
need help today,
Iggy, not in three weeks
on a Tuesday at 4:00 p.m.
So what do you say
we give it a shot?
- What's the worst that could...
- No, don't... don't.
Don't say it.
Okay. That's fair. Yeah.
If I may be candid,
there are parts of Bob
that have definitely
gotten smaller with age.
But I didn't know cancer
worked that way.
Spontaneous remission
is extremely rare,
but yeah, his cancer's
definitely shrunk.
I just gotta figure out how
because either it's a fluke,
or Bob has inadvertently
found a cure for his cancer.
Oh, please don't
tell him that.
That will definitely go
to his head.
Nothing is easy with that man.
Ever.
But I love him,
even in spite of his behaviour.
Finding out you have cancer
is never easy.
Oh, please, I know
several people with cancer
who aren't going
through the same
mortality-induced mania
that Bob's going through.
Can you be more specific?
Trading in our Volvo
for a cherry red Miata, fine.
I expect him to do that
around this age.
And while the spray tans
are unsettling,
I can literally
look the other way.
But spending hundreds
of dollars a month
on vitamins and elixirs
instead of taking the meds
prescribed to him by a doctor
is ridiculous, even for him.
Hang-hang on, what kind
of vitamins and elixirs?
Oh, they all
have crazy names.
Are you ready for this, Ben?
"Horny goat weed."
Tell me that's not a scam.
Can you bring me everything
that Bob has been taking?
Everything?
Yes. Everything.
I waited too long.
Opening the door.
Well,
she's in good hands now.
It was working.
We were doing really good,
you know?
Until today.
Are you gonna tell me
what's going on?
Both our parents died
of COVID.
Two years ago.
I'm really sorry.
We couldn't visit.
We couldn't say goodbye.
They just went to the hospital
and never came home.
What about other family?
Grandparents?
Hiya and I decided
to stay together.
Figured if we go to school,
stay under the radar,
no one would split us up.
I turn 18 in a few months.
Old enough to be her guardian.
What about you?
What about me?
Who's taking care of you,
Avi?
So since this is
your first prenatal exam,
we're just gonna check
the health of the baby
and make sure
we can induce labor.
Is that the heart?
That is the heart.
- Nice and strong.
- Mm.
Can I hear it?
Sure.
Would you like to know
the sex?
Yes. And no.
So hey, how about this?
Write it down for you.
Whenever you're ready.
Or not.
Is there any intrauterine
growth restriction?
- None that I can tell, why?
- What's going on?
The baby seems small.
How far along are you again?
26 weeks.
- Since your last cycle?
- I guess.
Take a femur length
measurement.
That's 23 weeks.
It's off by 3.
So...
so what does that mean?
That would mean
that your-your baby's
too premature for us
to induce labor.
If we were to do it now,
it probably wouldn't even
survive.
You're gonna have to carry
another three to four weeks.
No.
No, that's impossible.
I can't. I know what I am.
- I'm an addict.
- Yeah, I know.
Well, we can get you
into rehab.
I've done more using in rehab
than I do on the streets.
No, you're not listening to me.
I can't do this!
- No, I can't do this!
- Whoa, whoa, whoa!
- Call security!
- Seriously?
- Security? What for?
Floyd, don't do this.
Well, she's not giving us
a choice.
Look, I'm gonna put you
on a psych hold.
You're not gonna be able
to leave the hospital.
No! Why?
Reckless endangerment
of an unborn child.
Call security!
Hey, I have a
scheduled appointment.
- But I was here first.
- I know, I know.
Uh, everybody, that's...
Hey, that's enough!
That is enough!
Please form a line to the right
of the hallway.
Yeah, but what am I supposed
to do with this?
Are you the person
to give the survey to?
Just asking.
Thank you very much.
Have a good day.
Hey, hi, hi.
Do you have a scheduling nurse
that I can borrow
just for a little bit?
I'm drowning up there.
How'd you get so buried?
Uh, Max. How else, you know?
He forced me
to institute open access,
and now my department
is just flipped upside-down,
all because of a stupid survey,
you know?
Love the guy,
but I just wanna...
Wanna strangle him sometimes.
He's just over-asking
and over-promising
and over-everything.
Tell me about it.
Oh, yeah?
Why, what'd he do to you?
You can ask Nurse Colleen.
She's available.
Yes, yes, thank you,
thank you, thank you.
Somebody having
a mid-life crisis down here?
All you're missing
is the toupee.
Thank you. Thanks again.
So you're actually
committing a pregnant woman
like she's a criminal.
I never said
she's a criminal.
Though, by her own admission,
she's a threat to herself
and her unborn child.
Is this Gilead?
Give me a break.
Look, I'm giving the patient
what she wants,
which is... stapler...
A chance for her child.
Then tell me this:
Could a woman in New York,
if need be,
terminate her pregnancy
at 23 weeks?
Yes.
And would she be detained
for it?
Oh, come on,
this isn't a life sentence.
Olivette will only be held
until she reaches 26 weeks.
And what about the baby?
Become a ward of the state?
Because good luck
finding someone
to adopt a 26-week-old preemie.
Okay, I am not
the bad guy here.
But you are stacking the odds
against this baby from day one.
Okay, don't you think I know
all the societal challenges
for babies like hers?
Detaining Olivette
is not ideal,
- but I'm listening to the...
- Are you?
- Are you fully listening?
- Yes.
I'm trying to save a child.
But you're gonna fail if you
can't save the mother first.
Avi.
So we're gonna keep Hiya
for a few more days,
but we are expecting her
to make a full recovery.
Thank you.
Avi...
look, this isn't gonna be easy
for you to hear,
but once she's discharged,
Hiya is gonna become
a ward of the state.
No! She can't.
I-I can do better.
I can take care of her.
I know you can. I know.
That's not what
this is about, okay?
Look, Hiya's injuries
were physical.
We could fix those.
But you have injuries too.
You do, and people might not
be able to see them.
But that doesn't mean
they're not there.
What are you saying?
New Amsterdam Hospital
has a mental health department
which specialises
in child traumatic grief...
No. No. Mm-mm. No.
Wait, just listen to me.
Just listen to me.
Okay?
They can give you the support
that you need.
And eventually,
you can move forward.
And in a couple of months,
when you turn 18,
I really think
you're gonna be better.
I do.
And ready...
Ready to take in Hiya.
And be her guardian.
In the truest sense
of the word.
Come here.
Hey, Max.
I have the, uh, new test score
right here.
5%.
- 5% increase?
- No, no. No. Take a look.
That's a 5% total score.
- Ah.
- Yeah.
That is the single lowest score
in the history
of any department
at this hospital... ever.
The last record-holder
was Rikers.
I am losing out to jail.
But isn't open access better
for the patients?
Better for the patients?
You saw the "last helicopter
out of Saigon" scenario
in my waiting room, right?
You were there?
My staff spent the entire day
just, uh,
careening from one
upset patient to the next.
That's all they had time to do
all day.
Well, isn't it better
to inconvenience a few
- for the greater...
- No. No! It's not, Max.
It's not better for anybody.
I have followed you around
for years,
a cheerleader just watching you
casually knock everything down,
but not anymore.
My department was working.
And it was working well!
And now your insistence
on treating everybody
all at the same time
is working for nobody.
My staff included.
So no, I am not gonna go along
with your little
Quixotic experiment anymore.
All right, why can't you just
leave well enough alone?
We have a good thing going,
Max.
You ruined it.
Why?
You're right.
Do what you have to do.
Thank you.
All right, are you
sure that this is everything
that you've been taking
for your...
- Breakdown?
- Holistic healing journey?
Yes.
What is this,
some kind of shakedown?
Were you taking a drug
known as antoderide?
What's it for?
- For hair loss.
- Why would I take that?
Bob, we can all see
the giant bald spot
on the back of your head.
Ben has a perfect view.
Then fine, I'm taking it.
So what?
I wanted to feel young
for however long I had left.
Sue me.
Dr. Wilder,
is that drug the reason
that his tumour shrank?
Not a lot of people
know this,
but Viagra was first invented
to treat hypertension.
For the record,
I'm not on Viagra.
Yet.
- Louise.
- What?
But when the company realised
that they had a gold mine
for treating
erectile dysfunction,
they rebranded it.
My point here
is that sometimes,
discoveries are made
on accident,
and you... you, Bob,
you're living proof
that antoderide
has this amazing side effect
of treating Gonsalves' tumours.
So my hair medication
will get rebranded?
Will that make it
more expensive?
- Bob!
- What?
It's not all about you.
No. No, no, no, no, no.
Your cancer is so rare,
it just doesn't make a lot
of financial sense,
but there is an organisation
that logs drugs
with unexpected and potentially
lifesaving side effects.
So with your permission,
I would like to share
your numbers with them.
Well, if it'll help humanity
and whatnot, sure.
Glad to help.
- Hey.
Uh...
Just wanted
to officially apologise
for forcing open access on you.
It was, uh, clearly a bust,
and I-I don't blame you
for switching back.
Well, I didn't switch back.
- No?
- No. Kept it.
- You kept it?
- Yeah, we kept it.
Exhibit A,
you just waltzed right in
and started talking,
didn't you?
Uh, yeah, I did, but you...
I thought it was a disaster.
Yeah, it was more like
a train wreck,
but, uh, you know,
once we sorted through
the rather size able backlog
of patients in our system,
um, open access
actually integrated
pretty seamlessly into our
existing scheduling model.
Appointments in the morning,
walk-ins in the afternoon.
Wow, so it's-it's working.
Well, I had a patient today
that had all but given up
on scheduling appointments
altogether.
You know, she works at a few
different restaurants,
picks up shifts,
doesn't know her schedule
till the night before,
and when she found out
that she could just walk in
when she was free,
we had a great session...
One that wouldn't have
been possible yesterday,
so yeah, it's working.
- Thank you.
- Knock knock.
Hot off the presses.
New survey scores.
Oh, my God,
you're killing me.
- Ready for this?
- No.
Here we go.
Okay, buddy.
Survey says...
Oof.
It's 53%.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
53%.
Well, Max, you were right.
Less satisfaction,
but better health.
You know,
I usually pride myself
in listening to my patients,
and what I, uh, heard from you
is that because
of your addiction,
you believe that
you lack the capacity
to safely bring your baby
to term.
And I get it.
You know? That takes courage.
But for nearly six months,
you had it... courage.
Hey, it took courage
just showing up here
and asking for help
in the first place.
But you know what else I heard?
I heard from you
that it's hard,
maintaining this on your own.
So my question for you,
Olivette,
is if you were capable,
if you had the support
that you needed,
would you continue
with your pregnancy?
Oh, no, hey. No, I'm serious.
In your heart, would you want
to carry your baby to term?
Yes.
Okay.
Okay, so instead
of committing you
until you can safely deliver,
I'm gonna make a commitment
to you
so that you can.
Now, you're gonna need
prenatal care,
proper nutrition,
birthing classes,
birthing coach,
and you're also gonna need
to stay clean.
That's most important.
Now, I know none of this
will be easy, Olivette,
so this time,
you're gonna have something
you didn't have before.
A sisterhood.
Because if you need to go
to a meeting or an appointment,
I'm gonna go with you.
And if Gabrielle can't,
I'm there for you.
And if neither of these
wonderful women are available,
we've got nine others
in this hospital
who are pledging to step in.
And not just for you...
For any other pregnant woman
who might be struggling
on their own.
And you still got that little
piece of paper he gave you?
- A girl.
- Ooh.
Looks like
she's gonna be a part
of this sisterhood too.
Hi, I'm home. Hey.
Oh, hey, just in time.
I... oh, I was fading.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Oh, there was a tiff
this evening.
Um, Saleem accused Raffi of,
and I quote,
"Being really extra."
Yeah, that is a lot
coming from Saleem.
Right? Uh, yeah.
But on the plus side,
it exhausted everyone,
and now they're peaceful,
sleeping angels.
Okay.
Chicken quesadillas
in the fridge.
Okay, I think
we've covered all aspects
of the amended trust,
and you are clear on your role
as executor, Lauren?
- I am.
- Good.
Then that just leaves
the distribution of assets.
"As my eldest daughter, Lauren,
"worked tirelessly
to help me in life,
"in death, I, Jean Marie Bloom,
"bequeath my entire estate,
valued at over $7 million,
to my youngest daughter,
Vanessa Pageant Bloom."
Uh...
well.
Don't know about you,
Counsellor, but, um,
I could use a drink.
Dad?
- Hey.
Fixed everything up?
Yeah.
Was nothing I couldn't handle.
Guess I shouldn't have
doubted you.
So what's in the bag?
- What, this bag?
- Yeah.
Oh, just a little
New York Noodletown
sumthin'-sumthin'.
Ooh.
You got the kung pao shrimp?
Is water wet?
That reminds me.
I got a couple things
I wanna do
in that bathroom of yours.
- Oh, don't tell me that.
- Hush.
I just wanna re-caulk
around the sink.
Put in a a new shower head.
Earn my keep around here.
Sounds good, Pop.
All right then.
All right.
All right, just gonna...
Can't we say grace?
Yeah.
♪ You know you left me
standing there... ♪
♪ I don't believe
I would just survive ♪
♪ I could feel you
next to me ♪
♪ An escape
from the world I'm in ♪
Slow down.
I'm sorry.
I didn't get...
all of that.
I didn't...
♪ Oh, I'm lost and found ♪