"Don't be scared."
I have no idea how
many times I've said it.
The intern stands over a patient
with a scalpel or a needle or a clamp,
afraid to make the first move.
Told you it wasn't that far.
Curb, front door. What's
that, 50 feet? It's not that bad.
It's a nice 50 feet.
Mmm-hmm.
So help me out.
Which date was this?
Why?
Well, I need to know
what to put in my diary.
Well, there was one, and
then there was another,
so I'm pretty sure
that makes two.
And what about the car
ride home the other night?
I could barely
keep my eyes open.
Well, we ate. We talked. We
laughed. It was very date-like.
Why does it matter?
Three's my lucky number.
They're scared.
Well, then I guess
you're out of luck.
Mmm.
They know what to do.
But they just need
that little push.
Wait.
You didn't say good night.
Oh. How thoughtless...
Of me.
Good night.
Just hang in there,
okay? Yes, sir.
Thanks.
I have to go to sleep. Aw.
Early rounds.
I know. I know.
Good night. Good night.
I love you.
Thank you.
What, are you
sneaking out on me?
Oh, hey.
Sorry.
Give me a minute. We
can get some coffee.
Actually, I can't.
I'm assisting Bailey on
that Heller myotomy today.
Oh. That's right. That's today.
Well, text me right after. I
want to know all about it.
Okay. Okay. Hello?
Oh.
Get out! Get out! Go!
Get out! Just get out!
Please, just get out!
What is going on?
I don't know. She
just started screaming.
Why are you here?
Why is she screaming?
Get him out of here!
What did you do?
Nothing! God, no, nothing!
We were sleeping. I was
sleeping, and then the screaming. I...
Mer? Mer, are you okay?
What's happening?
Get him out of here. Who's he?
Look, just for the record,
I didn't do anything.
Get him out of here!
My shoes are in there.
Get out!
Mer? Mer, he's gone.
Can you please open the door?
I am worried about you. I
want to know that you're okay.
Is he gone?
Yeah. Yeah, he's gone.
Move the VP shunt till Monday.
Got it. Anything else?
All right, I'll be in touch.
Shepherd not coming in today?
No.
Is she sick or...
I don't know. Uh,
I'll tell her you asked.
Yes. Thank you. That's...
Okay.
Ashley Hughes, 21.
Crush injuries with
bilateral hip dislocation.
Good distal pulses.
How'd it happen? Fell on me.
What? What fell on you? I did.
Whoa. Uh, you okay there?
You're bleeding pretty
bad from that head lac.
Don't worry about me.
Just make sure she's okay.
Let's get her inside.
Somebody page Torres.
So the Rotko kid
looks pretty good,
but I want to monitor
him overnight.
You said we should do something.
We are. We're monitoring
the kid overnight.
About April. It was your idea.
"Something." I
said, "Something."
I didn't say, "Go behind
her back and tell Jackson."
April.
Hi. Uh, good morning.
Um, we're gonna
take the next one.
Oh.
Okay.
Yeah, well, maybe next
time be a little more specific.
You know how long it's
been since I saw your mother?
No idea, sir.
Too long.
Her plane lands any minute.
Yeah, I'm sure that trip's a
complete coincidence, right?
Nothing to do with me
or her or, I don't know,
anything you might
have mentioned.
Um, my wife and I don't have
any secrets between us, Jackson.
I enjoy seeing her, and
she enjoys seeing you.
Now, if you feel otherwise,
that's a damn shame.
Your injuries are not that bad,
but Ashley's are pretty severe.
Can you walk us through
exactly what happened?
I don't really think that's...
I mean, you know,
Ashley, she's a lady.
Mmm-hmm. And you
and the lady were...
Listen, it is easier for
us to treat her properly
if we know how the
injuries happened.
I don't want to kiss and tell.
He's funny, cute, and sweet,
and so I thought, "What if he's big?"
I'm an athlete.
I ran the New York City Marathon
the fastest of anyone in my age group,
and I don't back
down from a challenge.
Maybe you should've
backed down from this one.
Hey, you shouldn't
say things like that.
People make assumptions
based on size all the time.
I mean, so, what, I just shouldn't
date big people just because I'm little?
I really like him.
He's a gentleman.
She asked me over to her place.
I was sort of surprised.
I mean, obviously, the size
difference crossed my mind,
but I am not a quitter.
I was staring at Mount Everest,
and I was ready to climb.
I'm sorry. I'm not really
comfortable talking about this.
So my legs were
on his shoulders.
It was a lovely evening.
And my feet were,
like, way up in the air,
and it took some finessing
at first, but I was determined,
and it was worth it.
Oh, my God, it was
so worth it, until...
I slipped. Boom!
Then her legs snapped.
It was terrible.
It was terrible!
Ooh!
But this is way worse.
Okay, her pain's
still not controlled.
Well, she's maxed out on meds.
We'll have to reduce her under general.
Uh, no, but then we'd
have to intubate her.
Uh, Warren! Warren, I
need your help in here.
Okay, Ashley, I know that you
are really hurting, and I can help that
if you think that you can handle a
lot of pain right now all at once, okay?
We need to get your legs back into
your sockets, the sooner the better.
Now, we can go to the
operating room, or we can...
Might as well get it over with.
It's your call.
Go big or go home, right?
All right.
Edwards, you do the left
leg. I'll do the right. Can you...
We're gonna do
them both at once?
No need to put her
through this twice.
All right, Warren, I'm gonna
need you to hold her in place.
All right. Hang in there.
Almost there. Oh, God!
Oh, God! Oh, God! No!
All right, is everyone
ready? Yep.
Ready. All right, on
the count of three.
One, two, three!
She can't stay locked
away up there all day.
She has to come down sometime.
Do you think she wants food
or just coffee, or not coffee?
What if she wants tea?
Tea is more soothing.
What do we know about this
guy? I mean, not very much.
I mean, she's barely
even dating him. It's... Hi.
How are you?
Um, we made coffee,
but we could make tea.
Are you okay?
Where do we keep the
stuff for the countertops?
What? The blue
stuff, you know, the...
To clean the countertops
that's safe for kids.
Uh. Used to be behind
the paper towels.
Uh, Meredith, what happened?
How can we help you?
I found it.
Meredith.
You are wondering why I'm here.
I crashed here last night.
And the night
before. On the couch.
I thought I'd be out
before you woke up, but...
Can I use this on the stovetop?
Sure.
Thing is probably covered
in 10 years of grease.
Uh...
I'm sorry I didn't ask before.
I just needed a place
to stay for a minute,
but I'm gonna grab my
stuff, and I'm gonna go now.
No, it's Owen. Something
happened with Owen,
and it really
shook her up, so...
Maggie!
Look, you told me and...
Yeah, and now I wish I hadn't.
I'm leaving. No, please stay!
Something happened to you,
and now something has
happened to Meredith,
and I think that we
should all just sit down
and talk about it, all right?
Can I use bleach in here?
There's something
we use under the sink.
I can show you.
Yeah.
We're taking Ashley up to CT
now. Torres would like you to join.
I'll be there in a few minutes.
I almost killed her.
With our sex.
Dr. Blake, I need some help.
I paged Dr. Torres,
but she just ran a trauma
patient up to CT and...
Okay, let me see what you got.
Oh, God.
Uh. Yes, Dr. Torres or
did you try Dr. Robbins?
Dr. Robbins is in surgery.
So I figured since you
and Dr. Torres are...
Oh. Right. Okay.
I've got it.
Hi. She was having a
play date with my daughter,
and they were running around,
and she tripped. Landed on a rock.
I brought her right
in. She's okay, right?
Hi, sweetie. I am Dr. Blake.
I'm Sofia Sloan-Torres.
I know. I work with your mom.
Your moms.
My head hurts.
Okay. Let's take
a look at that cut.
Okay. That doesn't
look bad at all.
It is so cold and sleeting
back east, just dreadful!
So you came to
Seattle for some sun?
I came to Seattle
for my son. Mmm.
How are things going with April?
Why must you
meddle in everything?
I do believe you went
through an entire divorce
without me saying one word.
Oh, Jackson, I just
want to talk to her.
No, absolutely not.
Oh. Come on, honey, let me help.
You won't help, though, Mom.
You'll only make things worse.
Now, I cannot be any
clearer with you about this.
No.
I don't want you
talking to April.
bullying her around.
I don't want you anywhere
near it, actually, okay?
It's my problem, my
business, none of yours.
Understood?
Zola and Bailey are dropped off.
Is Ellis still down?
Sound asleep.
And we are cleaning in here now.
We are done in the kitchen,
so we have moved on.
Okay.
Well, pass the disinfectant.
DeLuca got out of here
in a hurry this morning.
Yeah, he's scrubbing
in on a Heller myotomy.
He's doing the
esophageal dissection.
Where's the wood polish?
Here you go.
I told him to let me know how it
goes, so I'm just waiting for a text.
Owen won't stop
texting and calling.
What are you gonna do?
I have no idea.
Yeah, I wouldn't
know what to do, either.
You know Owen probably
better than any of us.
Do you have any
advice for Amelia?
How long has that
stain been there?
You're keeping
busy. I am hiding.
Catherine Avery is here, apparently,
and I am not in the mood for...
In the ER, I'm a sitting
duck, but in an OR...
Come on, she can't be that bad.
No, she's worse than bad. She
can be terrifying, like a hurricane.
When she hits, you do
not want to be in her wake.
Well, you can't
avoid her forever,
not when she's about to
become Hurricane Granny.
Maybe not, but I
can avoid her for now.
You ready? My first
surgery's with you.
She has a femoral neck
fracture on the right hip.
It didn't show up
on the plain films.
Yeah, I met a puppy once
that was half German Shepherd,
half Teacup Chihuahua,
and all I could think
was, how did you happen?
I once watched this monster truck
crush this two-seater convertible
at an intersection, and the
truck barely had a scratch on it,
but the convertible was totaled.
I mean, logistically, if
the Chihuahua is the dad,
did he just hop up on the
German Shepherd mom?
Ashley was just
out for a joy ride
with her top down,
and then... Bam.
Head-on collision.
Or is the German
Shepherd the dad,
and they give a ladder to
the little Chihuahua mom
so that he can reach her?
Whoa! Whoa, whoa.
Stop, stop, stop!
No, these are
scientific questions.
No, not you. The scanner.
Look at her right leg.
It's pale and cold.
No distal pulse. We
need a gurney in here!
Book an OR. Right away.
What... What's happening?
Ashley, I stopped the scan
because I saw
something concerning.
The blood flow to your
right leg is compromised.
It's not good, so just
hang in there, Ashley.
All right, come on over. On the
count of three. One, two, three!
Let's move.
Looks like the
leg is pinking up.
Oh, caught it just in time.
You know, gosh, it sounds fun,
but you do not want to run into
a German Shepherd in the wild.
Happened to me in college.
Uh, irrigation?
I don't think this conversation
is entirely appropriate.
No, it's not. K-wire, continue.
Yeah, I was at a
party, met a guy,
took him home, and
when his pants came off,
my jaw hit the
floor and so did it.
Oh. That is not okay.
That is what I said. I said,
"Get out of here, and you
take that thing with you."
How big could it have been?
Okay, can we not?
Yeah.
Oh, wow.
- No, no, no.
- That's... Yeah.
Dr. Torres? Yeah.
It's not urgent, but
they're calling from the ER.
Your daughter's down
there with a head lac.
What? I can take over. You go.
Yeah.
When I was pregnant
with Jackson,
a three-hour
surgery felt like 12.
Hi, Catherine. Um...
I actually don't
really have much time
'cause I have another
surgery really soon...
Oh. Baby, please, sit back down.
Come on. I know
you're tired. It's okay.
Come on.
Some nights, my
feet were so swollen,
I was physically unable to
even take my sneakers off.
A few times, I slept
in the damn things.
I... I guess you
talked to Jackson.
Oh. Let's not talk about him.
I want to know about you.
How many weeks is it now?
Uh...
It's okay.
We don't have to talk
about it if you don't want to.
I... I understand. I'll go.
Thirteen.
I'm coming up on 13.
Morning sickness?
Um, no, I've actually been
really lucky with that so far.
You are lucky. I
couldn't stop being sick.
I thought I was coming down
with the stomach flu or something.
Took a whole week for me
to realize I was having a baby.
It was a shock.
Yes, uh, it's
definitely startling.
Yeah, the morning that
the test turned positive,
I couldn't believe I had to turn
around and keep it together that day.
I bet.
I was already so emotional,
but I was not gonna cry
in that lawyer's office, so...
Oh, honey.
You mean, you found out the same
day you signed the divorce papers?
Yeah, it was a rough day.
I just sat there listening
to those lawyers,
but all I could think
about was how I just...
I just... I needed
time to, like, think.
Mmm. Process.
I would've done the
exact same thing.
Sweetheart, no
matter what happens...
Everything looks good here.
All right, let's hope that we don't
come back to the ER for a while, okay?
Thank you for taking
such good care of her.
See you in a bit, okay?
You okay? Okay? Of course.
And, uh, Sofia is okay,
which is what really matters.
Okay.
I mean, it would've been nice to get
a page, um, before you treated her.
Well, I just wanted to make sure
I had all the information
before I pulled you out.
No, right, of course. Or
you could've tried Karev.
He's in peds, or Grey, who
Sofia's grown up knowing.
Grey has the day
off, and Karev just left.
Or Bailey.
You want me to page the
Chief of Surgery for a head lac.
Mmm-hmm.
What's going on?
She's my kid, and she doesn't
know anything about you.
We haven't even
had that conversation.
Oh.
So... Okay.
This is about what I
said last night, isn't it?
The last thing that I wanted
to do is make things weird.
It's Arizona. She's
glad that you helped.
Obviously, she's not mad,
but she's not ready, either.
You and I, it's all happening
so fast, and we're so new and...
Oh, God. No, that's...
What was I thinking?
It's fine. It's fine.
Your heart was in the right
place, and she'll be ready one day.
Okay, absolutely.
I'm sorry.
I can wait.
What vacuum cleaner
is this complicated?
It's a carpet steamer.
And we own it?
Assembly.
"Insert handle into machine
base. Press down firmly."
Okay. Bolts.
And circle thingy.
What happened with Owen?
It's nothing.
Uh. Little circles
or big circles?
Small. You're
lying. Screwdriver.
I showed up at his trailer.
He was drunk, so I left.
Hose. How drunk?
Bad. Slurring, stumbling.
He's tried to call.
I'm not ready.
Where is he?
I'll kill him. Did he
hurt you? Are you hurt?
Go fill this with water. Cold.
What's going on?
There's a stain on the carpet.
You said this was an emergency.
There is. There's a stain.
I canceled my last two surgeries
and left DeLuca in charge
of my post-ops for this?
He's out already? The Heller
myotomy, that was today.
That got canceled.
Okay, I'll do it myself.
Somebody vacuum the stain.
Don't look at me.
Dr. Robbins? Huh?
I'm so sorry. You
are Sofia's mother.
I never would've
interacted with her
if I knew that you would
have a problem with it.
What? What did you do?
I... Callie explained to me
that you weren't comfortable
with me meeting Sofia.
You're not ready, and
I totally understand.
No, wait, stop. Just...
No, I never said that.
Well, however you
phrased it, it's fine.
I just wanted to apologize...
No! The subject
has never come up.
She was lying.
Callie lied to me about you?
It sure seems like that.
So DeLuca probably
just got busy, right?
I mean, he's an intern.
He's probably just been
running around all day.
He just forgot to tell me
his surgery was canceled.
You sure that thing
works? It's brand-new!
Just because you never took it
out of the box doesn't mean it works.
How long has it been
sitting in the closet?
Are we facing
this the right way?
The steam is facing the carpet.
How many other ways are there?
It's been like this
lately, you know?
It's been hard for us to get
our schedules to match up.
It's funny. It was easier
for us to get together
before we went public than now.
So funny.
What?
Why are you all exchanging
looks and not exchanging words?
He's been a little
standoffish and hard to reach
and not entirely upfront
about everything he's doing.
A little, I guess.
What are you saying?
He's giving you the brush-off.
Uh, no. No, he's not
giving me anything.
That's the problem.
Give me that!
You think he's dumping
me? That's ridiculous!
Unless it isn't.
Where are you
going? To the hospital.
No one brushes me off.
I brush. I'm the brusher.
No, no, no. This is a bad idea.
Mer, you want to jump in here?
This stain is not coming out.
Hey.
Whatever's going on
between you and Penny,
leave me out of it.
Okay. She does not waste time.
Um. Look, I said a thing...
I know! I know what you said.
So listen, I mean, we've never
even discussed Penny meeting Sofia,
which I'm fine with, by the way,
but then you go and
throw me under the bus?
I don't even... I know. I
know. I wasn't thinking.
I... I was just... I blurted
it out, and it was so dumb.
Great, so if you have a problem
with your girlfriend, figure it out.
Don't put me in the middle of it
because I'm... I'm done being
stuck in the middle of things.
Hey. Is that Amelia or...
Look, I promise I gave
her your message, Dr. Hunt.
I... I promise. It's
just, this is my mom.
Okay.
What'd you do?
Excuse me?
Look, I know that look.
I get that look whenever
I piss off Miranda.
She ignores my messages, too,
and we live in the same house.
I think this is a
little worse than that.
I, uh, bought Tuck
a pocket knife.
He liked camping, wanted to
whittle, and the thing was beautiful.
It was wooden
handle, steel blade.
It was really nice, but
she didn't see it that way.
What I saw as a survival tool
she saw as an inappropriately
dangerous weapon.
Huh. And she forgave you?
Yeah, eventually,
but, uh, you know,
still comes up
from time to time,
but, you know, it faded.
Well, I thought this was
gonna fade, but hasn't yet.
I mean, it took
some apologizing.
A lot of apologizing. Yeah.
Look, I just I told her I would never
intentionally do anything to hurt him
or her.
You know, and she knows
that because she knows me,
but, um, sometimes you...
You just have to say it.
So I freak her out by
telling her I love her,
and she lies to my
face. Who does that?
She didn't say it back?
Not even close.
Ugh. I did that to Alex.
She'll say it back, right?
I mean, you said it back.
Yeah! A few years later.
A few years?
I can't live like
this for a few years.
You don't really have a choice.
When you date an attending,
they have all the power.
You're an intern at home.
You're an intern at work.
There's no way around
it. No one asked you!
And she's a resident.
DeLuca, a word?
Yeah, of course.
He has a point, though. Pierce
definitely has all the power.
I have to talk to Callie.
You're avoiding me.
What? No, I haven't.
I've called. You
haven't answered.
Just been a really
busy day. Sure.
In a marathon surgery
that got canceled.
Um...
What's really going on here?
Uh...
Okay, look, I'm very busy.
I have many, many
things on my plate.
I just... I don't have
time or patience
to play childish guessing games.
Do you want to
be with me or not?
There's my answer.
Look, it's not like...
You know, you're the one
who wanted this out in the open,
and now that we've done
that for, what, like five minutes,
you can't handle it?
I'm sorry.
You can leave now.
Mer, that closet's
cleaned already.
Well, we're gonna use the top shelf
for beach towels, towels, and rags.
The middle shelf
will be for sheets,
and the bottom shelf
will be for the children
in case they need to reach it.
Okay. Sure.
I counted 19 mini-shampoos
and 11 conditioners.
Trash or...
I'll take them. What?
Works the same as
shampoo in a big bottle.
Mer, what is it?
It's his stupid, stupid blanket.
We're done cleaning.
Run me through what
happened. She coded.
It was a massive
pulmonary embolism.
They're doing a cath
embolectomy right now.
This is my fault.
I reduced both of her
hips in the trauma room.
I should've waited. It's been
problem after problem ever since.
This is a known complication of
femur fractures. You know that.
I shouldn't have
pushed. If I had just...
Torres. Torres, stop.
You did what you had
to do. You made a call.
The wrong one, apparently.
A bold one.
We don't know
that it caused this.
I know you feel responsible, but
there's no place for that right now.
I need to deal with this
clot before she arrests again.
Plate.
Here you go. - Thank you.
Hey.
Um, I just had the most unexpected
conversation with your mother.
Damn it! I told her not
to say anything. Just...
No, no, no. It was fine. Um.
It was really nice, actually.
Maybe we could find a time to talk
sometime soon, just the two of us?
I'd like that.
Great.
Oh, God, she's dead, isn't she?
Ashley's okay.
She suffered a
severe complication,
but we were able
to control it in time,
and she should
make a full recovery.
Whoa, uh...
I'm sorry. I didn't
hurt you, did I?
No. It's fine. I'm fine.
She'll be awake soon?
Yeah, we'll send someone
to come and get you.
Okay. See you.
You okay? Yeah, I think so.
She's at Meredith Grey's house.
She is?
She asked me to send
over some case files,
and so that is where she will be
in case, you know, you
wanted to make a bold move.
Here you go, Sofia's chart.
All clear. Thank you.
And don't worry. I didn't
discharge her myself.
I had Bailey do it.
Chief says she's good.
She must be good.
Look, Penny, I'm sorry. I
should not have lied to you.
If we are not in the same place,
if you aren't ready to be
where I am, that is fine.
You can tell me,
and I will listen.
If you aren't ready for
me to meet Sofia, great.
That is your decision.
But making me feel like crap
about trying to help, lying to me,
that is not okay.
So Amelia went to go pick up
the kids. Should be back soon.
Whoa.
You made a fire.
I mean, it's 70 degrees
outside, but that's cool.
This was Derek's blanket.
I always hated the
stupid thing. It's...
It's not soft. It's not
warm. It's not a great color.
He had it in the trailer.
He brought it here.
Made it to the
dream house with us.
He made a bed in front of
this fireplace for us once.
And now he's gone, and I
still have the damn thing.
I freaked out this morning.
I heard. You okay?
So you brought the guy
here, and it was terrible.
It wasn't terrible.
So why did you freak out?
That's the problem. It
was kind of incredible.
He was going to leave,
and then we fell asleep,
and then when we woke up,
I... He was just
there, and I just...
Everyone said I was ready.
You said I would be okay,
so I thought I should just
do it and get it over with.
But I wasn't ready for it
to be...
You warm enough?
Yeah, I'm fine.
Remember, guys, Mama
made the house really clean,
and we're gonna
keep it that way, okay?
Oh, someone's here.
Hey.
Uh. Okay, Zo, you take your
brother inside and wash your hands.
Okay. Come on, Bailey. Let's go.
Hey.
I just wanted to see you
so I could apologize,
you know, face-to-face.
About the other night, I
am sorry. I was thoughtless.
And I don't know why...
I don't have an excuse.
Amelia, Riggs said some
things to me, and it just...
And...
And I'm really sorry.
I know.
I knew.
Listen, I just got sober again,
so to find myself
in that position...
And it was unfair of
me to put you there.
I know that, and it
will not happen again.
No, I know it won't.
I promise.
I appreciate that,
but I can't count on it.
Right now, I have
to count on myself.
It's not your fault. You're
just not in this with me,
so I can't do this with
you, not right now.
Maybe not at all.
Amelia, you know
me. I would never...
I know that right now
I'd like you to leave.
Okay.
Oh. Your numbers look great.
Thanks.
They, uh, said
you're, uh, awake.
Hi.
Um...
I think he might want to
come in. You all right with that?
Yeah.
Ash, I, uh, don't
know what to say.
Uh...
They said I'll be okay.
I'm so glad.
Listen, Chris, I've
been to the mountaintop,
and it's exhilarating, but I...
But you don't ever want
to see me again, do you?
No one needs to
climb Everest twice.
Oh, hey.
Uh, Sofia's more than okay...
thanks to some
astronaut stickers
and some strawberry
Jell-O. Thank you.
When did you know that Little
Tuck was ready to meet Ben?
Oh. Um...
Well, Tuck was too
young to tie his own shoes,
so I wasn't gonna get
any answers from him.
What I cared about
was, was I ready?
Hmm?
See, I'm ready. I was
ready the day I met her,
but I'm always ready too
early. I got married too early. I...
It was one thing when it
was about me, but now...
You know, say...
Okay, when you see Sofia
kick a ball across the room
and you start to daydream
about 20 years from now
when Sofia scores winning goal
at the Women's World Cup Final
and the whole stadium
is chanting her name.
"Torres! Torres!"
And it's all in slow motion
and you're up in the
stands screaming and crying.
Yes, yes. You do that, too?
So the question is,
who do you want screaming
and cheering beside you?
This looks cozy.
What are we doing?
Enjoying the clean, clean
house. Look at your crumbs.
How's DeLuca?
He's a non-issue now.
How's Hunt?
Also a non-issue.
What am I eating?
I'm gonna need something
way less healthy than this.
- Pizza's coming.
- Mmm.
Mmm.
You're not pizza.
Uh. No, I'm not. I'm...
Is Meredith home? I'm Will.
I know who you are.
Yeah, you should leave.
Look, I've been worried
about her all day. She...
No, really, go.
It's okay. I got it.
Hi.
Who's that?
That's the doctor
who fixed my head!
Yes, she is, and she
is a very special doctor.
You remember her name?
Penny. Her name is Penny.
Hi, Penny!
Hi, Sofia. How's your head?
Good!
We decided that stitches could
only be made better with ice cream.
And I thought maybe you
might want to come with us?
We are in the same place.
I'm in the same place as you.
I've been there
a while. I just...
I would like for you to
come get ice cream with us.
Very much.
And you can say no.
I would understand.
I'm not saying no.
Then what are you saying?
Thank you.
All right. I think we're
going. You ready?
All right, let's go.
All right!
Hey, Jackson, your mother and I
are headed to dinner. Care to join?
You know what? I
can't. Thanks, though.
Ma, can I talk to
you for a second?
Mmm.
Okay.
I told you not to
talk to April, right?
I know.
Yet you did anyway.
I know that, too.
You know, as hard as it
is for me to say this to you,
thank you.
It seems like it was a good
thing, like you were right.
Yes, I was.
I got everything we need.
"Need"? Wha...
What she knew, when she knew
it, whom she spoke to, and when.
I needed to confirm that she
withheld information from you
when she was signing
those divorce papers,
that she legally committed
fraud, and she did.
And now we can go after her.
Don't stop. Don't hesitate.
You can't be scared
of what's next.
I'm so sorry if I, if I did
something to hurt you. I...
It's not... It's not you.
I mean, it is you, but it's
not because you're you. It's...
I'm...
Do not let fear get in your way.
I lost my husband two years ago,
and you are the first person
that I've been with since.
And this would be so much easier
if last night were awful or something.
I just have a lot of stuff.
It's a lot.
And you're great.
And last night was great.
Yeah, I thought so, too.
But there's a "but."
Yeah.
You're not ready.
I guess I'm not. I want to be.
Okay, then. I'll...
I'll back off,
for a little while.
But so you're prepared,
I'm gonna call you again,
and if you ignore me,
I'm gonna show up again, and
we'll go back to sitting in that car,
talking and laughing.
And I'll be waiting
until you're ready
because I'm pretty sure
you're worth waiting for.
Good night.
That's why we
don't operate alone.
There are attendings
and nurses and interns.
Those ORs are full of people.
I'm fine.
Are you sure? Is he gone?
Yes, he's gone. Yes, I am sure.
I am completely
and utterly fine.
I'm gonna go
check on the pizzas.
Laundry's done, dishes are done,
and I made a lunch
for Zola tomorrow.
Thanks.
And I'm gonna go.
So in the cases where
someone actually does get hurt...
You can stay in
your room if you want.
It's clean.
Nobody has to
go through it alone.