.
Apologies I couldn't scrub
in last night.
If you want to shadow me,
consider yourself on call.
I don't like having
my time wasted.
The hospital will
discontinue the Vas-COM
until it can be proven
to be safe.
Hold off on banning
the Vas-COM just yet.
Given my son-in-law
is a consultant for Vasik,
I shouldn't be the one
to deliver this news.
It's time to do
our random drug testing.
I'm not gonna pass this test.
Here.
What's this?
It'll make the last traces
of the drug undetectable.
My niece, Holly,
is singing carols.
I thought you'd want
to come with me.
Yeah.
Let's go cheer Holly on.
all: Six, five, four,
three, two, one!
choir:
♪ Dashing through the snow
♪ In a one-horse open sleigh
That's my niece.
choir: ♪ Laughing all the way,
ha ha ha ♪
♪ Bells on bobtails ring,
making spirits bright ♪
♪ What fun it is
to ride and sing ♪
♪ A sleighing song tonight
After this,
will you be my guinea pig?
I'm testing out a new eggnog
recipe for the family party,
and my place is just
a couple blocks from here.
choir: ♪ Jingle bells,
jingle all the way ♪
Sure.
Okay.
choir: ♪ In a one-horse
open sleigh ♪
♪ Jingle all the way, hey!
Oh, thank you.
Vanessa,
your drug test results.
♪
Negative.
Thank God.
Thank you, Maggie.
Thank you.
♪
I feel like
a lot of this is my fault.
I'm sorry for the stress
that I caused you.
For coming into your life
the way that I did,
for wanting you here,
and just never
telling you the truth.
No, no.
I understand why you did it.
You had--you had a daughter,
and you wanted to meet her.
If ever--if I ever
were in your shoes,
I probably would have done
the same thing.
Okay?
Okay.
Okay, cheers.
Cheers.
Too much vanilla.
No. That's perfect.
We have a winner.
You know,
with Dr. Cooper's situation,
the company is concerned that
they don't have anyone
advocating for the Vas-COM.
And I'm sorry if this
is a little personal,
but I understand that
you have financial worries.
It's no secret.
We can help you. Look...
Will, I wouldn't mention
this if I didn't trust you.
And I hope you feel
you can trust me.
I do, Jessa.
So here's the deal.
Vasik can offer you
the same arrangement
they had with Dr. Cooper.
Arrangement?
I don't understand.
For every Vas-COM catheter
the hospital ordered,
Dr. Cooper
received a percentage.
Really? Wow.
Yeah.
I mean, these catheters are
used once, and then discarded.
If we got enough departments
behind them,
the hospital could go
through thousands.
What do you think?
That sounds great. But...
I mean, isn't this kind
of like kickbacks?
You don't have to worry
about that.
I mean, you're completely safe.
Okay, good.
I mean, but Medicare.
I mean, insurance companies?
They don't ever question
these charges?
You'd be surprised.
I mean, Vas-COM catheter
is a small ticket item.
They hardly notice.
And besides, even if someone
did question it,
then the doctor could always
justify it clinically.
I mean,
that's the beauty part.
Look, you don't have
to give me an answer tonight,
but let me just say I think
you and I would be
a good team.
Oh, my God.
This is a disaster.
We can go to the FBI now.
Yeah, there's no question
these are felonies.
Why didn't you tell me
about this sooner?
I didn't have enough.
And even when I tried
to get the Vas-COM pulled,
the board refused.
You were there.
Yeah.
And Dr. Halstead put himself
in a very difficult position
for months
in order to get that.
All right, look,
we can't blindside the board.
Before we go to the FBI,
I've got to brief them.
Well, do it quickly, because
I'm not sitting on this.
Message received.
But until you hear back
from me,
it is business as usual.
Please, not a word of this
to anyone.
Dr. Halstead?
All right.
Send me a copy
of that recording.
This is a friggin' disaster.
♪
Dr. Halstead?
Lily.
Lily, my baby, she's so sick.
Yeah, something's
really wrong with her.
You're going to Treatment 3.
Okay. I'm Dr. Halstead.
We're gonna take good care
of Lily.
Find Dr. Scott.
You got it.
They said the vomiting
started a few days ago.
We didn't think it was
anything serious.
I mean, babies spit up, right?
But it just kept getting worse.
After she nursed,
she couldn't hold it down.
She's always been so active,
and now she's--
Listless?
Yes.
How often have you been
changing her diaper
because it's wet?
I'm not sure.
Two or three times a day. Why?
Less than six means
a baby's dehydrated.
So we'd like to get Lily
some fluids.
Mm-hmm.
Okay.
30 cc/kg bolus
of normal saline.
You got it.
And a maintenance rate
of 12 cc per hour.
Okay.
What's causing this?
Well, given her symptoms,
it could be a number of things,
but I don't want to speculate
until we run some tests.
Maggie, CBC, CMP, and CRP.
Right.
We'll be back when we get
some results in, okay?
Crockett?
Avery.
What are you doing here?
Stalking you.
Uh-oh.
I had a follow-up
with my orthopedist.
Oh. Is everything good?
Mm.
Humpty Dumpty
is back together again.
Well, that's good.
Avery, stop bothering
Dr. Marcel.
We have a patient to see.
Oh, no bother at all.
Hi, Mom.
It's good to see you too.
Mr. Carmona's in pre-op.
Dr. Marcel?
Yeah.
Bye, Dr. Marcel.
Okay.
Happy day, Reuben.
I couldn't believe it
when I got the call.
We've been waiting
for months.
So long.
Reuben didn't make it easy
to find a liver.
B negative.
It's a very rare blood type.
But we finally got a match,
and its anatomy is excellent
for transplant.
We're so grateful.
Best Christmas ever.
Okay, Reuben, now you're
gonna take a nice long nap
and wake up with a new liver.
I love you, Papi.
Don't cry, mija.
Hey, you're gonna do great.
Sure am.
♪
And shouldn't
have to have surgery.
We got Lily's
test results back.
We looking up her symptoms
on the internet, and it said
that she might have something
called pyloric stenosis.
And she'll need surgery.
No. No, no, no.
She does not have
pyloric stenosis, okay?
No, her labs show
she's low in potassium.
It's a mild
electrolyte imbalance.
We're not sure yet,
but it's most likely
a viral gastritis.
More commonly known
as a stomach flu.
That's all?
We hope so.
We're gonna keep Lily on fluids
and monitor
her condition, okay?
Best-case scenario,
it resolves on its own.
Thank you.
All right.
We'll keep you posted.
Thank you.
Oh, gosh.
Okay, I think that I have
every--
Mr. and Mrs. Bennett,
this is Dr. Hammer.
Hi.
I feel okay.
I really--I don't think
I need to be here.
Honey, you had a seizure.
Mrs. Bennett
was getting ready
for work when it happened.
The seizure resolved on its own
before the paramedics arrived.
She's COVID-negative
but is running a fever of 102.
Okay, any history
of epilepsy, seizures?
No. First time.
But I didn't sleep well.
Could it just be that?
I don't know.
We're gonna take a look.
Dr. Taylor?
Yes.
Do you want me
to call your office,
let them know
you're not coming in?
No, no. I'll be fine.
I'll take care of it.
She's never missed
a day of work.
Stressful job?
A little.
Yeah.
They totally depend on her.
Okay. Lungs are clear.
Heart sounds good.
Pupils are equal
and reactive.
Ow. Ow.
Your liver
is slightly enlarged.
Dr. Taylor,
what do you recommend?
A CBC, BMP,
and a chest X-ray.
Is that all really necessary?
Yeah, I think so.
I'm sorry, but admissions
just informed me
that there's a problem
with your insurance.
It's not going through.
Well, that doesn't
make any sense.
She has great coverage
through her work.
I'll get it sorted out.
Here, in the meantime,
just put any charges
on our credit card.
We'll check back in as soon
as we get those test results.
♪
What do we got?
28-year-old male
Kyle Liddell.
Fell on the pavement,
struck his head.
The guy stepped out
in front of a bus.
Good Samaritan turning off
his car alarm pulled him away.
Caused Liddell to fall
and hit his noggin.
Bystanders say it looked like
he was unconscious
for about a minute.
GCS of 12 now.
Minor hematoma.
No other trauma noted.
Mr. Liddell, can you hear me?
Mr. Liddell? In here.
♪
All right, on my count.
Ready, one, two, three.
All right. All right.
Let's get some ice
for this goose egg here.
Right.
Excuse me.
Does this hurt?
Can you feel this, Mr. Liddell?
Liddell. I'm Liddell.
Okay, he's still
pretty out of it.
All right, let's pan scan him,
but first, routine trauma labs,
and I need X-rays
for chest and pelvis.
X-ray!
So, suicide attempt?
Who else steps out
in front of a bus?
June, let's place him in soft
restraints, just to be safe.
And also, let's place
a psych tech outside his room.
Got it.
And also,
let's call Dr. Charles.
Mm-hmm.
.
Mr. Liddell? Kyle?
How you doing, Kyle?
I'm Dr. Charles.
I'm late. God, I'm late.
Oh, God, I'm late.
You're late?
What are you late for?
What the--what is this? Why?
Well, we were
a little concerned
for your--for your well-being
when you were brought
into the hospital.
The hospital?
Wait, why I am here?
Well, you know, you stepped
into a busy street,
and when you were pulled
out of the traffic,
you hit your head.
You're actually very lucky
you didn't sustain
a much more serious injury.
But no. Uh.
Traffic? I was on campus.
God, I'm late. I have to--
Okay.
Please let me go.
Hold on. Hold on.
Help me understand this.
You said that you
were on campus?
Yeah. I teach.
Okay.
'Cause you were actually in
the middle of downtown Chicago.
No. No.
I--but the--I heard the bells.
The bells?
Are you--are you
sure about that?
Yes.
You know, it says
that the man who--
who pulled you out of traffic
was--was turning
off his car alarm.
Is it possible that
that's what you heard?
Oh, no.
Oh, no. Is it happening again?
Is--is what happening again?
I had it under control.
Oh, no, no, no. Come on.
Tell me what you had
under control.
I, uh, I have schizophrenia.
And--
Okay. Okay.
Oh, God, the voices.
No, no, no.
Have you been
prescribed medication?
Yeah, risperidone.
And I--I have been--
I've been taking it.
That's great.
Who is your doctor?
Who's taking care of you?
Dr. Kallejian. Henry.
Okay.
Look, I know Dr. Kallejian.
Why don't you let me
get in touch with him, okay?
And in the meantime,
gonna give you something
make you feel
a little bit better.
And we will get you
through this, all right?
Nice to meet you, Kyle.
Nice to meet you.
So your patient
is not suicidal.
Oh, yeah?
How do you figure that?
Well, didn't know he was
stepping into traffic.
Ah, okay, so the cars
and the busses
didn't tip him off?
He was having an auditory
hallucination.
Led him to believe he was
on the campus where he teaches.
He--he suffers
from schizophrenia.
Ah, psychotic.
Well, I've treated his
injuries.
Send him upstairs.
You know, he's not a danger
to anybody, Dean,
and clearly been
very responsible
about his treatment.
Something destabilized him,
so I'm just gonna--gonna
keep him down here
till I figure out what.
Well, I'm sure
you know what's best.
But on behalf of all
of our other patients,
the ED is a frightening
enough place as-is,
but when you add
the mentally ill into the mix,
it can only
compound people's fears.
♪
Matt.
Will. My savior.
Man, I was lucky
I was with you, huh?
How you doing?
I'm great.
I wish I had something
to offer you other than JELL-O.
Nah, I'm good. Thanks.
Listen, Matt,
I want to ask you...
Any regrets?
Regrets?
You mean the coke
and the booze.
Yeah, sure.
No, come on, man.
The Vas-COM.
Why would I have
any regrets about that?
Before your heart attack,
that's what it seemed
like you were saying.
I was pretty out of it.
I don't really remember
what I said, but no.
I want you to check
this out, though.
Janie and I are renting
a villa in Montenegro.
Okay, two months on the beach.
I mean, I'm thinking
I come back from here,
I'm gonna start a concierge
practice in Montana,
and it's beautiful.
There's so much money there.
Wouldn't have to work so hard.
Right?
You know, given the degree
of portal hypertension,
we should use
a venovenous bypass
early in the hepatectomy.
Good catch.
Is that aftershave?
Excuse me?
What I'm smelling.
Does that bother you?
No.
As long as it's not verbena.
That's what my ex wears.
What else do you see?
Uh,
yeah, the donated liver
is smaller in size,
so we should oversew.
Right.
Dr. Blake.
Mr. Carmona's crashing.
Reuben, mi amor.
What's going on?
I don't know.
He started talking funny,
not making any sense at all.
And then
he just stopped moving.
Reuben?
Can you open your eyes?
Reuben. Open your eyes.
Oh, God.
Reuben?
All right, GCS 7. Let's go.
We gotta get his CO2 down.
Get an intubation kit ready.
Bag mask.
He needs a CT stat.
And let radiology know
we're coming up.
What's happened to him?
Not sure.
Hopefully we'll know
after the CT.
What about the transplant?
Believe me, we're gonna do
everything we can to make sure
he gets that surgery, okay?
Kate, would you
direct the family
to the waiting center, please?
Ready? Here we go, guys.
Come in.
So you informed the board?
I did.
They're very grateful
you and Dr. Halstead
uncovered this fraud.
Okay.
And they see a way,
going forward,
that will protect
the interests of the hospital.
What is that supposed
to mean?
Dr. Cooper will be fired
immediately, and Chicago Med
will discontinue use
of all Vasik equipment.
And that's it?
What about the FBI?
The board does not feel
that is in the hospital's
best interests.
You've gotta be kidding me.
Sharon, you and I both know
that these things are
best dealt with quietly.
The board doesn't want
the negative publicity.
With good reason.
Look at the ramifications.
Loss of donors,
A-list physicians leaving.
It's devastating.
So I imagine
Dr. Cooper's father-in-law
had his hand in this.
Of course he did.
So Matt Cooper just walks?
And what about all those
other Vasik execs?
The board is just thinking
of the greater good.
Whose greater good?
I understand how you feel,
how you both feel.
But the decision has been made.
There's no appeal, all right?
So I advise that
we keep this to ourselves.
There is no sense
in jeopardizing
our employment, okay?
This is over.
Let's go back to work.
Put this behind us.
♪
Hell, I'll go to the FBI.
You can't go to the FBI.
Sure, I can.
Your whole purpose
in bringing me here
was to get evidence
to take to them.
And you did that.
You validated my suspicions,
and I thank you.
Okay, Matt is planning
to set up shop
in a billionaire enclave
in Montana.
You know, he can
plan anything he wants.
All due respect,
Ms. Goodwin--
Dr. Halstead, you came to me
because you wanted
your job back.
You got it.
Now, this is over.
It's time for you
to focus on medicine.
♪
.
I'm seeing diffuse
brain edema.
Yeah, it's the end-stage
liver failure.
And his transplant surgery?
Well, there's signs
of impending brain herniation.
If we don't correct it,
you can forget transplant.
This man will be dead.
Can we correct it?
How much longer is
the donor liver viable?
Four hours, tops.
It's possible.
I can put a right-front bolt
with a twist drill
to monitor
intracranial pressure
while treating with mannitol
and hypertonic saline,
along with the lactulose
and rifaximin.
And that should bring
the pressure down
so we can operate, right?
Yeah, that's the idea.
Even though you had the good
sense to call me,
I can't guarantee anything.
♪
She's worse.
Terrible headache.
Temperature's 104.
Jaundice.
Ow! Really hurts now.
What--what's wrong with her?
I'm sorry, her tests
weren't conclusive.
Start her on a broad
spectrum antibiotic?
With these symptoms, there's
a multitude of possible causes,
and I don't like
prescribing antibiotics
unless they're
absolutely necessary.
I think we should hold off till
we know what we're treating.
But you--you said her tests
weren't conclusive.
Yeah, I'd like to send her
for a CT
of her chest and her abdomen.
It'll give us a much clearer
picture of what's going on.
How much will that cost?
What difference does
that make?
Yes. Yes. Of course.
Okay, you can do with her.
Thank you.
I need a transporter.
Hey, so we need to send Eve
up to Radiology.
I'm sorry, but admissions
just informed me
that your credit card
was declined.
What?
No, I hardly ever use that.
I can see that your wife
is going up for tests.
We can deal with this later.
Yeah. Thank you.
♪
How you feeling?
Better, yeah. Tired.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Probably the sedation.
You know what?
I don't think
we need these anymore.
Would you?
Wow.
So...
Oh, wow. Thank you.
I talked to Dr. Kallejian.
Uh-huh.
He says that you've been
managing your illness
really well
over the last few years.
Which leads me to wonder--
I mean, any--
any big changes
in your life recently,
like, I don't know, new job?
Loss of a loved one?
I'm not married.
Both my parents are still
alive.
We're close.
That's good.
Yeah.
I've been a doctoral candidate
for the last two years.
Been TA-ing the whole time.
Okay.
Is this gonna keep, like,
happening?
Is this gonna get worse?
Not if I can help it.
Okay.
I mean, my plan
is to figure out what--
what caused your episode
and to address it.
Kyle, any new medications
of any kind?
No.
Okay.
No, no, no. No.
Look, I can't end up back
in the hospital again.
Nobody's talking about that.
Nobody.
No new vitamins or supplements?
No, I take--I take, like,
Vitamin D, fish oil.
Well, those are both good.
Anything--anything else?
Oh, I started drinking this
tea like a month or two ago.
Hmm.
I go to this health
food store near me.
They blend their own.
I drink one called
Mindful Energy.
It's supposed to help you
focus,
you know, keep you sharp.
Can you remember the name
of the health food store?
Yeah, Happy Path.
Okay, well, listen,
I want you to rest some more,
but we are making
progress here, okay?
I'm really glad to see
that you're feeling better.
So what's the deal?
Can we turf Liddell
out of my ED or what?
You know, Dean, I gotta say,
hard not to notice
that you don't have
a whole lot of patience
with mental illness, do you?
You noticed that, have you?
Yeah.
You know Kyle, here,
and you know our patient
Krista, those twins, Neil.
Yeah, you just, you can't
let go of that, can you?
All right, let me give you
my perspective here.
Okay, when you're in combat
and you're dealing
with the wounded, they can say
some pretty crazy things.
You don't listen to them.
You just get them to safety.
And you do everything
you can to save their lives.
I completely get that. I do.
But, I mean,
just for the record,
trauma-induced mania, I mean,
it's temporary.
It's not a mental illness.
Look, you can split hairs
all you want.
What about Liddell?
You know, I still have
some digging to do,
but I have to say I am really
developing a--I don't know,
an admiration for his--
for this courage.
Courage?
Yeah.
You got a couple minutes?
I'd like to show you
what I--what I mean.
Sure.
You know, it's a simulation
that was developed
for psych residents.
Give them a sense of what
some of their patients
were experiencing.
Yeah.
Look, gets too intense, just,
you know, take them off, okay?
No, I'm sure it'll be fine.
All right.
I gotta go back upstairs.
But I'd love to check in
with you later,
see what you thought?
All right.
Okay.
Wow. Huh. Look at that.
You should never have left
your apartment.
They can get you out here.
You have no protection.
Ha.
You're so stupid. Worthless.
Everybody knows it.
Why did you listen?
You're in danger.
Don't look at them.
Don't make eye contact.
They hate you.
Everybody hates you.
She's one of them.
She's getting instructions.
Those are poison.
Don't touch them.
You're evil.
You don't deserve to eat.
Stay back. They'll kill you.
Uh...
You're hopeless. Pathetic.
A waste of time.
You're such a failure.
Look at you. You suck.
You should die.
We'd all be better off.
♪
.
Well?
ICP is down, but still high.
So he's improved.
Marginally.
Well, given what I had
to work with.
I know, Sam.
Okay, but with a new liver,
Reuben's encephalopathy
and edema might well resolve.
Or they could get worse
from the surgery
and lead to a herniation.
If you hold off
on the transplant,
I can do a hemicraniectomy
for the edema.
No, with the donor
liver's window of viability,
we can't wait.
We have to operate now.
Or you find a new liver.
No, Reuben's blood type
is rare.
He'll die before
he gets another match.
I say we go for it.
It's our best option.
Dr. Halstead, Dr. Scott.
Help her! Please!
She was doing so good.
50 mg/kg of phenobarb.
Got it.
Heartrate 130.
Sats are down to 86.
Caprice, bag her.
I'll set her up to intubate.
Intubate?
Lily can't protect her airway
right now.
But intubation
is the safest thing for her.
Oh, my God.
Broselow was in the pink.
Give me 2 mg of etomidate
and 13 mg of sux.
Satting now at 94.
Why is this happening?
I promise we're gonna
find out, okay?
Now, let me know when
those drugs are in.
♪
Okay,
so with your permission,
we'd like to send Lily
for a CT of her head.
Anything. Just make her well.
Scans didn't reveal
any tumors, masses,
or obvious infections.
Any ideas?
One. Kind of a stretch.
Something I saw
when I was homeless.
This couple isn't
experiencing homelessness.
No.
No, there's something going on.
I need to give her
a more thorough physical exam.
♪
Sepsis?
Yeah, possibly.
But she's not running a fever.
Okay, so stroke.
Intracranial hemorrhage?
Yeah, I mean, CT
should tell us something.
Poor little girl.
What'd she ever do
to deserve this?
♪
Just turn your head.
Here. Here, take a look.
What is it?
A scab.
It's from an insect bite.
What does that mean?
I have an idea,
but I'm not sure.
I need to run
one more test.
Western blot analysis?
Yeah.
We should have
an answer very soon.
So I called
your health food store,
and I got the ingredients
to that tea
you've been drinking.
Lot of stuff in there.
I think yerba mate,
spearmint extract.
But the main ingredient
is St. John's wort.
Now, listen, nothing wrong
with St. John's wort,
per se, right?
Actually helpful to--
to some people.
But it has also been known
to increase the metabolism
of certain
antipsychotic medications.
Increase the metabolism?
Yeah.
It speeds up how your
body processes them, right?
Rendering them
considerably less effective.
So I'm gonna be okay?
You switch out that tea,
yeah, I believe you will be.
I mean, look,
you responded really well
to the extra risperidone
I gave you, right?
Half-life of St. John's wort
is, like, 24 hours,
so by this time tomorrow,
you should be feeling
a whole lot better.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
♪
Okay, done clamping.
Initiate VV bypass.
ICP's up in the 70s.
We gotta get that
ICP below 20.
Let me do a hemicraniectomy
now, before he herniates.
No, we need to complete
the transplant first.
With a new liver,
things will correct with time.
Or you'll have a working
liver in a braindead patient.
Treat him medically
while we operate.
Dr. Abrams?
1 g/kg mannitol, increase
propofol to burst suppress,
and replace clotting factors.
Good.
Last one.
Let's get this liver out.
I'm sorry, but we believe
Lily has a genetic condition
called OTC deficiency,
which causes ammonia
to build up in the blood.
We're ordering
a specific lab to confirm.
If it's genetic, why is
she just getting sick now?
The disease can
present anywhere
from a few days after birth
to several months.
How serious is it?
Unfortunately, very.
We need to start
treatment immediately.
Is our little girl gonna die?
We're gonna do
everything we can
to make sure
that doesn't happen.
Let's get Lily up to PICU,
get her on hemodialysis.
♪
Hey.
So we got your test results.
You contracted a disease
called typhus.
Typhus.
In the United States?
It does occur,
and we can treat it.
Doxycycline 500 mg.
How the hell
did she get typhus?
From a flea bite.
That was the scab
that we found.
Most likely it was a flea that
had been on an infected rat.
What does it matter
how I got it?
It matters.
It's a public health issue.
I'm sorry, I have no idea.
Eve, enough.
I want to know what's going on.
What do you mean?
Your health insurance
isn't valid,
our credit cards are maxed out,
and you've come down
with typhus from a rat.
Eve, tell me.
I haven't--
I haven't been going
into the office
for the past three months.
I spend my days
in our storage locker.
Our storage locker?
My company's restructuring.
They fired me.
I've been trying to find
another job, and there's...
There's nothing. Nothing.
Why didn't you just tell me?
Because I couldn't!
Everybody thinks
I'm this huge success.
You think I am.
Honey.
I'm sorry. I'm so ashamed.
No.
I'm sorry.
I'm so--I'm so sorry.
.
I was wondering
where you got to.
It was unsettling, you know?
Yeah.
How does he--
how does Liddell do it?
Everything going on
inside of him like that.
How does he--
how does he hold a job?
How does he get
through the day?
I mean, I think he works
at it, you know?
He stays on top of it.
Goes to therapy.
Takes his meds.
Look, I've known
a lot of individuals
been faced with serious
mental health challenges,
right,
who get the help they need
and go on to lead full,
normal lives.
I'm talking about people
with severe depression,
with PTSD, you know?
I understand
how terrifying it must be.
What?
Well...
For a soldier to ask for help,
right?
For a soldier to think
that they might be one of them.
You know, someone who could
lose it at any second,
fall apart.
Hey, that's--
that's not gonna happen.
It's always been
so mysterious to me.
You know, I think about guys
like you and Ethan over there,
doing your jobs.
You guys are, like,
bravest people I'll ever know.
Mm.
But when it comes to--
to saving yourselves?
All right, listen, it's...
It's not always so bad.
Comes and goes.
Anyway.
I--I get that
it's complicated, okay?
But I just--I just
want you to know,
there's ever anything I can do,
you know I'm around.
♪
Hey, Dan?
Uh...
I'm sorry about Neil.
I could have done better.
And I'm sorry Ethan got shot.
I know you are.
♪
Lily will need
a liver transplant,
but I think
she's out of the woods.
She's responding well
to the medicine
and the dialysis.
I'm hopeful.
Well, at least
that's something.
What's going on with you?
You got a baby, a total
innocent, has to suffer,
while a bunch of crooks
in this world
are getting away
with everything.
I'll see you
at the Christmas party.
Hope the punch is spiked.
♪
Reuben's surgery
was a success.
Oh.
He's doing well.
You'll get to see him
in a couple hours.
Thank you.
So a patient gave me this.
Oh.
What do you say?
Absolutely.
Ooh!
Oh.
Merry Christmas.
Oh, wow, look at that.
Huh.
Mistletoe.
Yeah.
And two vaccinated,
consenting adults.
Indeed.
♪
God, it must have been
so hard to keep that lie up.
I know.
I've done it myself.
I never told anyone
about my mom.
How we lived.
Acted like I had
a perfect little life.
Not easy.
I've been keeping up
a lie too.
Yeah.
And it's costing us too much.
Is there a Carly here?
Who, me?
Yay!
Here you go.
Looks like you've been nice.
What do you say?
Thank you!
You're welcome! Yay!
Mwah! Merry Christmas!
See you later. Okay!
You know, upstairs,
what happened...
Mm-hmm.
That was just for fun.
Yeah.
Mistletoe.
Mistletoe. See you tomorrow.
Okay.
And last but not least,
where's Cody?
Yay!
Merry Christmas.
Um, Santa, can I say
something real quick?
Sure. Okay.
For those of you who
don't know,
and that's most of you, um...
Maggie Lockwood
is my biological mother.
And I am so grateful and
blessed to have her in my life.
♪
Ms. Goodwin?
Yes.
Pursuant to our conversation,
we have warrants
for the following offices
and computers.
Thank you.
Matthew Cooper,
you're under arrest
for violation
of Title 18 for fraud.
Wait, wait, what?
What the hell?
Jessa Rinaldi,
you're under arrest
for violation
of Title 18 for fraud.
Any false statements
you make to the FBI
are punishable for up
to five years in prison.
How could you do this, Will?
How could you do this to me?
Wait, what? Was this you?
♪
You called the FBI?
I did.
But you told me--
I told you to stand down.
This is my responsibility,
not yours.
Any and all fallout
lands on me, not you.
And believe me, Sharon,
there will be fallout.
♪