Previously on The Resident...
Randolph Bell.
Will you marry me? Thank God.
Because I can't return this.
Are you in love with Cade?
All I know is that
whatever I feel
only goes so far, and
then the walls come up.
Maybe you just
need a little push.
It's like
he wants to relive
what happened to Nic
and rewrite the ending.
I wish we could
rewrite our ending.
Your father's here.
Just flew in from Seattle.
Hey, Molly. Look at you,
getting out of here.
Yep. Thanks for all the
fun books, Doc Sullivan.
- How's your daughter?
- On the mend at last.
Morris, what's happening?
Just you, Doc.
Rocking that suit.
Laura, good morning.
- Morning, Doc.
- Has anyone ever told you
you look like Sophia Loren?
- Only you. But that's okay.
- Ah.
I got this twinge
driving me crazy.
I think I pulled a muscle
playing a ferocious
pickleball game.
You think maybe you could
find me a muscle relaxer?
Uh, you know I can't do that.
But I've got some ibuprofen in
my purse if you would like...
Gives me a stomachache.
I'll get a massage later,
tough it out till then.
Good morning, love.
How we feeling today?
Hi, Dad. Conrad's just
finishing up his examination.
- What's the good word, Dr. Hawkins?
- Hey.
CBC and 'lytes are stable,
one low-grade fever
controlled with meds
and you are getting
your color back.
She's doing really well.
Next step, get her out
of bed, up and moving.
She's just being
a little stubborn.
Hmm.
I think I know what
that problem is.
There's no longer a
guard outside the door.
I know they caught the
men who tried to kill me.
I understand, intellectually,
but I just, I don't
want to leave this room.
Totally normal PTSD.
You'll beat it.
I miss that feisty girl with
the chip on her shoulder.
Yeah.
I'd love to see you do a
walk around the unit today.
With a walker, someone by your
side to make you feel safe.
Come on, Cade. You and me.
Once around the unit,
like when you were a kid.
Even better.
Don't get me wrong, I'm
loving the attention,
but who are you again?
I practically raised myself.
This guy was always
at the hospital.
- And now...
- You're his patient.
- Bingo.
- Who doesn't love being psychoanalyzed
by two totally
unqualified people?
A gift. To soothe your belly.
- Banana pudding?
- Mm.
Are you trying to kill me?
I'm allergic.
I almost died when I
was four. Remember?
I thought that was strawberries.
My apology. I'm gonna go
to the cafeteria right
now and I'll be back
with the best chocolate
pudding in the house.
Then we walk.
- Your father, he's...
- He's a mixed blessing.
He's a god to his
patients and himself.
You know who really
loves banana pudding?
Him.
Story of my life.
Marco Anza, 14-year-old
male, syncopal episode.
History of osteogenesis
imperfect a.
Hey, Marco, my
name is Dr. Feldman.
- Can you tell me what happened?
I fell off
my neighbor's bike.
My mom's gonna kill me.
She followed the ambulance.
She'll be here any minute.
All right, we got you,
buddy. On my count.
One, two, three.
I'm not supposed to bike.
I-I got dizzy and
everything went black
and that's when I fell...
He's in V tach.
Go get a crash cart
and Dr. Austin.
Thready pulse.
Prepare to do chest
compressions if he codes.
I'm his mother. Uh, no
CPR. His-his bones break
with the slightest pressure, he
has osteogenesis imperfect a.
- Where's that crash cart?
Right here.
All right, I'll get
these pads on him
and you charge to 200.
Uh, Doctor, please
don't let my baby die.
Please, God, please, please.
All right, clear.
Sinus tach at 110.
All right.
He's okay, Mom. He's stable.
Thank you. Thank you.
That was terrifying.
I don't understand.
Why did his heart stop?
It didn't. It went into
a dangerous rhythm,
and now we have
to figure out why.
Marco.
Honey, it's Mom. Talk to me.
Please, talk to me, honey.
My back really hurts.
What'd he say?
- His back hurts.
Another possible
injury from the fall?
He could have broken anything.
It's exactly why he's never
supposed to be on a bicycle.
Answer box.
Yeah. All right, people.
Let's get this young man
ready for X-ray and CT.
Improved By M_I_S
www.opensubtitles.org
Are you back at work, Albert?
Yeah, just in time
for the midterms,
much to the chagrin
of my students.
I'm sure they are
thrilled to have you back.
Well, they did
make a TikTok video
reciting the periodic
table while twerking.
I suppose that's their version
of a "Get well soon" card.
That is something
that I'd like to see.
And there's something
that I want to show you.
- These are your lungs.
- Mm-hmm.
Do you notice
anything different?
This is what they
looked like before.
No tumors.
- That's right.
If I didn't know you
entered our clinical trial
with advanced lung cancer, I'd
say that these are the lungs
of a completely healthy man.
O-Okay, wait, wait.
Complete remission?
- Yeah, man.
- Oh, my gosh.
- Thank you.
Thank you, Dr. Pravesh.
I know this trial was
brutal, but it worked.
Yeah, yeah... And the science.
The science.
You found answers.
More people will benefit, right?
Now call Grace, and
give her the good news.
Okay, here's my idea.
We got four
marriages between us.
Do we really need a ceremony?
I mean, we could elope.
Just you, me, a
justice of the peace,
followed by a wild honeymoon
at the destination
of your choice.
Um... Whoa, I'm-I'm sorry.
I was told that you
wanted to see me?
Yes, please.
We both do. Please, come in.
Yeah, and congratulations
on your incredibly
successful clinical trial.
And the rabies
protocol with Conrad.
We are so proud of you.
Especially since you
trained here at Chastain.
What she's really saying
is she's terrified.
And we don't want to lose you.
Dare I ask?
Are you being courted by
the great research hospitals
of the world?
Actually, yes.
Baltimore Hospital of Advanced
Sciences is flying me up today.
Wow.
We will match any offer.
Thank you. But there is no
official offer to match,
and money is not
the only factor.
There are... um, issues here.
Personal ones, I imagine.
Yes.
- We're rooting for you and Leela.
- Thank you.
I appreciate that.
Uh, I almost forgot.
Congratulations on your,
on your engagement.
- Thank you.
- Thanks.
Oh, the poor guy.
You know, his career is
accelerating like a Ferrari,
and, you know, all he can think
of is the empty passenger seat.
Thank you. Okay, I better go.
I got a crazy day.
Wow.
There have got to be over
200 healed fractures here.
Mm, it's no wonder his
mother's so protective.
Osteogenesis imperfect
a is a brutal disease.
Every time your kid
stumbles, a bone can break.
And bone pain is terrible.
- You ever broken any?
- Lucky for me, only one.
- Proximal humerus.
- Hmm. How?
Oh, that's a long story
involving a skateboard ramp
and a very dumb teenage AJ.
And a cat.
Don't ask.
Well, there's a new
spinal fracture, T11-T12,
likely from the fall,
but we can fix that.
But what concerns me the most
is the restrictive cardiomyopathy.
With the severity of
his pectus excavatum,
his rib cage is almost
strangling his heart.
- The Ravitch procedure?
- Yeah.
Break the bones of his sternum
and reset them to make room
for his heart to work properly.
It's an incredibly risky
operation for a kid with OI.
Yeah, but if we don't fix it,
Marco could go into lethal
rhythm again and die.
I understand the upside
of the operation,
and the danger for
Marco if we don't do it.
But what about the
surgery itself?
There is a risk of
damage to his heart
and aortic aneurysm once
we saw through the bone.
So, you could damage his heart
while you're trying to repair
the bones that you are afraid
- might strangle the heart?
- And again,
these are bones that caused
him to black out on the bike
when his heart went
into a lethal rhythm.
If we don't do
the surgery, any stress
on his heart could worsen
the strain and kill him.
So there's risks with or without
the surgery... but far less
if I just make sure that-that
he's never alone again.
Never alone?
Mom, are you kidding?
That's crazy.
I-I don't want to
live like that.
I don't want to be
wrapped in Bubble Wrap
and put in a drawer.
I want to do stuff.
Honey, I know you do,
but you have to accept
there's limitations.
You can't do risky things
like go ride a bike.
I-I get that I can't,
like, play football,
but I'm not gonna
stop riding bikes.
Did you know his first
fracture happened
when he was three months old?
I was putting a
onesie over his head
and his collarbone just cracked.
It's been 14 years of this.
But we've managed.
I've managed to
keep my boy safe.
Mom, I-I love you,
and I know that
you've protected me
ever since I was a baby,
but safe isn't enough.
I-I've done a bunch of research,
and I can get better.
I-I want to go to college.
He's right.
In some forms of OI, fractures
decrease after puberty
when rapid bone growth
comes to an end.
This may already be
happening with Marco.
After a fall from a
bike, we'd expect to see
far more fractures
than he has today.
See, if they do the surgery,
I could totally be better.
I'm sorry. This is a
very, very big decision.
I... I have to think about it.
Brave young man.
- We both know we can fix him.
- Very brave.
You know, the mom's
protected him so long,
- she can't let go.
- Well, in medicine,
as in life, no risk, no reward.
Tell me about it.
So he has Behcet's
and he's sick enough
to be in the ICU?
I am thinking pulse
doses of steroids.
Ah, I thought maybe that was
the best course, but obviously,
I had to confirm
with my partner.
Somehow I don't think that's
why you came to find me.
Another spot-on diagnosis.
I heard you've got a job
interview up in Baltimore today.
They're flying me
business class.
Champagne before takeoff, baby.
- Oh, wow.
I remember when you were a
green, starry-eyed intern.
Your first day at Chastain,
I took one look at you
and I thought, "I got to
break this poor guy down
and rebuild him
from the ground up."
You were impossible.
I tried very hard to
find another resident.
And when the sun came up on
that first 37-hour shift...
I was convinced I'd
made so many mistakes
- that I'd never be a doctor.
And you said this
job isn't easy.
That if it were, everyone
would be a doctor
because it is the
best job in the world,
despite everything,
because of everything.
That's still the case.
All right.
Now I'm gonna say
something selfish.
Okay.
Don't break up the team.
I don't want to, trust me.
You can work things out.
She's worth it.
And all your friends and
colleagues are here, you know?
I don't know.
I really don't.
But I do know that I need to
see what else is out there.
I get it.
You've earned this.
- Uh, uh, uh...
Your pudding, darling.
Thanks. Where you been?
I went by the pharmacy to
get some medication for you.
- Medication?
- Yeah, to help
with this PTSD anxiety.
I don't do benzos.
And you're not my
prescribing doctor,
so that's, you know, illegal.
But thanks.
Probably wise.
Maybe an overreaction
on my part.
I just hate to see
you under duress.
I'll take them back.
Well, I promised
Conrad you and I
would do our forced
march an hour ago.
Let's do it. Oh, that's
Kit Voss, isn't it?
- Yeah.
- Just give me a few minutes.
I've been meaning
to introduce myself.
I'll be right back.
Dad.
Ms. Voss, good afternoon.
Oh, are you getting
in that elevator?
You
must be Cade's dad...
Help.
Dr. Sutton, Dr. Austin.
We've decided not
to do the surgery.
Well, I'm sorry to hear that.
Especially since Marco
seemed to be all in.
Well, Marco's 14.
He thinks potato chips
are a food group.
I am his mother and I-I
know what's best for him.
Well, for the
record, our medical opinion
is that surgery is
the best choice.
Because we
believe the risks
of not doing it far
outweigh the risks of...
Please, stop. Just stop.
If something goes
wrong, which may happen,
you two just leave the
outcome here at the hospital.
But my dear,
kind, clever, amazing little boy
will be gone.
I will not go home,
for the first time in 14 years,
to be alone, without my son.
It's about control.
She has controlled every waking
moment of that child's life.
For good reason,
to keep him safe.
But now that he has
a will of his own,
she can't seem to let him go.
Well, there's nothing
we can do, is there?
Unfortunately not. We both
know she's not 100% wrong.
The surgery is risky, Marco
is a minor and it is her call.
The resident is falling
asleep while he's retracting,
I'm about to call the
whole thing, and I find
the little nubbin hiding
behind the kidney.
Well, Seattle Children's must
feel so grateful to have you.
Ah. I like to tell
myself they do.
But I'm thinking of
relocating closer to Cade.
She's my only child.
This has... been a nightmare.
Rearranged all my priorities.
That's understandable.
You know, we're in the market
for a pediatric surgeon.
I don't suppose
you'd consider...
Mm, I'm sorry.
It wasn't my
intention to turn this
- into a job interview.
- No, of course not,
but I'd love to give you
an exclusive CEO
tour of Chastain.
I can reschedule
my next appointment
if you can be available.
Do you have the time?
I have all day.
Great.
Great, thanks for your help.
The patient in 423
needs a PCA pump.
I wrote the order.
How did Cade's first
outing on two feet go?
What outing?
With her father.
Helping her walk
around the hospital?
That didn't happen.
I saw him with Dr. Voss.
Okay.
- What happened?
- I fell.
-  It hurts.
- Laura?
I need a lac tray,
Lidocaine with epi and bandages.
Feels like
my incision opened.
All right, let's
get you back in bed.
Eh, it's a superficial
lac. You're good.
- Where's your dad?
He got a better offer.
Obviously this is complicated.
You don't have to talk about it.
Hurts.
Talking helps take
my mind off of it.
No loss of consciousness?
Nope, I've been painfully
awake this whole time.
- No head CT for me.
Well, I'll be the judge of that.
You just focus on keeping
my guts from spilling out.
Ordering me around again?
It's nice to see
you're on the mend.
Your hands.
Gentle.
You can always tell how much
a doctor cares by their touch.
I'm so pissed your
dad left you here.
You can count on him to
make a big showy entrance
that gets him a
lot of attention,
but after that...
Look, he does the best he can.
From grade school on,
when I got up in the morning,
he'd be gone to work.
So I made my own lunch.
Did what I had to do,
what I wanted to do.
Made me self-reliant.
I'm grateful for that.
You're being too generous.
Well, not everyone can be
the kind of father you are.
Gigi's a lucky girl.
My dad showed up this
week, he gave blood,
he saved my life.
You got to give credit
where credit's due.
Mm-hmm.
He'll stick around for a
couple days, he'll get bored,
go back home to inappropriate
wife number three,
and Seattle Children's,
where he can see
the hero worship in
his patients' eyes.
Not before I have
a word with him.
I was gonna ask
if we could take him home.
- He was doing so much better.
- I can't breathe.
He's desatting fast,
his lungs are flooded.
- He's working too hard.
- We need a crash cart now.
Mrs. Anza, we're gonna
have to intubate.
- No. No, no, no.
- His lungs are drowning.
We have no choice.
Dr. Pravesh, here you will find
our very own
world-class geneticists.
They are making great strides
in the field of hereditary
cancer syndromes,
as well as sequencing
newly discovered
chromosomal disorders.
These are the very
experts in virology.
Is that our rabies protocol?
That's right.
Chastain Rabies Protocol.
Your groundbreaking work.
We're trying to determine
how to trial it in
endemic countries.
Well, you guys
certainly go all out.
We have to.
It's our very center
for rare diseases,
where research will
meet clinical excellence
to cure the most challenging
diseases in the world.
Well, it's a dream setup.
For the, uh, research
scientist, it is.
And we want you to
be a part of it.
Okay, uh, you've got me.
- I'm impressed.
We certainly hope so.
Because it's all yours.
We want to make you the
director of our program.
You're young for a job of
this stature, it's true.
But
we feel that you're
the perfect person
to lead us into a
brighter future.
Wow.
I'm...
I'm honored.
Is that a yes?
I need some time
to think about it,
process it all.
Of course.
But we need to
know by next week.
Next week?
You think this was
my fault, don't you?
'Cause I didn't say yes
to the surgery right away.
No.
We're not here to assign blame.
Marco is stable
on a vent for now.
First his heart, now his lungs?
The truth is, your
son is getting worse.
His chest
deformity almost stopped
his heart this morning.
Now fluid is backing up from
his heart into his lungs.
We might not be
able to extubate him
ever again if we do not move
forward with the surgery.
- Are you sure?
Yes.
We have to operate,
and we have to do it today.
There is no option.
Okay.
It is a beautiful hospital.
How does it compare
to Seattle Children's?
They're
very different.
Seattle Children's
isn't a public hospital,
with all the good
and bad that entails.
The best thing about
Chastain is our staff.
We have a roster of
extraordinary doctors.
Mm.
- Excuse me.
And looks like two
of my best surgeons
are about to perform a Ravitch
procedure on a teenager
with a severe case of OI.
I could get you visitor
operating privileges
if you'd like to scrub in.
I'd be delighted.
Let me just go check
in with Cade first.
Meet me at OR 2.
Right.
Yeah. How's my girl?
Uh
Not great.
- She fell and hit her head.
- What?
- And opened her sutures.
- How?
Because she decided
to walk by herself.
Where were you?
I'll go check in on her now.
Uh, you're a little late.
She's asleep.
She should've waited for me.
She's always done
things on her own,
without support.
Okay.
Look, I feel bad enough.
I don't need a lecture.
And for the record,
do you know where I was?
I don't care.
I was asked to scrub in on
a life-threatening surgery
on a teen, okay?
Chastain has no
pediatric surgeon.
I may be able to
help save a life.
Oh, we have plenty
of great surgeons.
Your daughter needed you.
Why don't you just say it?
I'm in your way.
You want to have
Cade all to yourself.
I'm her doctor.
So, yeah, right now,
you are in my way.
And I'm her father.
Then start acting like it.
You okay?
Good. Good. Just doing
my little pre-op stretch.
- Time to get
changed and scrub in.
I'll show you to
the locker room.
Dr. Austin, Dr. Sutton,
this is Cade's
father, Dr. Sullivan.
He's visiting his
daughter and happens to be
a top pediatric surgeon,
something Chastain lacks.
Just here to watch and learn.
Yeah, well, this is a big one.
It's high-stakes.
Got a life to save.
Happy to
have you scrub in.
Delighted.
All right.
That should give
his heart and lungs
room to breathe.
Very delicately done.
I-I do have one suggestion.
If you're open to it.
I'd recommend
overcorrecting the sternum
just a little bit more.
It may look silly now,
but when you go to secure
the pectoralis muscles
back down, it'll
it'll make sure that the
sternum doesn't dip back
into dangerous territory.
That's actually an
excellent suggestion.
Huh.
I like that.
In fact, I will make that
adjustment right now.
Rongeurs to me.
Take it you've
done a few of these?
Just a few.
Dozen.
BP's plummeting.
He's tachycardic.
And has severe JVD.
Uh, high-output
cardiac failure.
Hang do but a mine.
Five mics per kilo.
He's in V tach.
And he's likely ruptured
the aortic aneurysm.
Laps to me.
We need to get a
bypass in here now.
Dr. Cade's father,
step in. We need your hands.
By all means.
So, the
aneurysm involved
the ascending
aorta and the arch.
And the descending aorta.
Time for the frozen
elephant trunk technique,
wouldn't you say?
I've only done that in adults.
Works in kids, too.
We good?
Hell yeah.
Ah, let's do it.
Wow, he's good.
No kidding.
We do need a peds surgeon.
Yes, we do.
So have you broached the
subject with Sullivan?
I did.
But?
He's very charming,
and he turns it on effortlessly.
Maybe a little too effortlessly.
But those hands would
save a lot of young lives.
I wouldn't worry about it.
Ian Sullivan will
be putty in yours.
Darling, are you all right?
I'm just pushing
myself a bit too hard.
I had a podcast interview
about unaccountable doctors,
then a deposition where I
testified about the cases
that were ignored by
the state medical board.
Then I came back here
and did a lap chole,
which I should have
delegated to Nolan
but I didn't because
I missed the OR
- and...
- Can you go home
- and rest now?
- Uh...
No, I would need somebody to
cover for a bowel resection.
Nolan can do it.
Or Leela. Your health
is our priority.
Now go.
How'd it go?
How'd what go?
The job interview.
So you heard?
- Everyone heard.
Everyone's talking about it.
Everyone's afraid you'll leave.
They offered me a job.
An entire department, actually.
I'd be running their new
center for rare diseases.
It's a dream.
Devon, that's-that's incredible.
You must be really proud.
Thank you.
So are you gonna take it?
Do you think I should?
I can't make that
decision for you.
Is there anything left of us?
That's on you.
You're the one who made it clear
that not having kids
was a deal-breaker.
I think the deal-breaker is
that you didn't even discuss
my feelings about it.
You just laid out your rules.
Your job,
your body, your
eggs, your future.
Mine didn't even factor in.
And that's not what our
relationship was supposed to be.
It was supposed to
be a partnership.
You've already
made up your mind.
And now you're just justifying
your decision by blaming me
for the fact that you're
leaving your friends
and the hospital that made you.
I can't believe you'd do that.
Kincaid, my darling.
I'm so sorry.
Heard you were the
hero of the day.
I guest-starred in
a roller-coaster.
Ravitch procedure with
Drs. Austin and Sutton,
but hardly a hero.
I left you waiting for me,
and you did what you always do
the way you've always
done it: On your own.
There was a kid who needed you.
Work to be done. There's
nothing new to see here.
Yes, there is.
You needed me.
Nothing should have taken
precedence over that.
Dad, we have a long history of
other kids taking precedence.
But I'm over it.
I'm a doctor, too.
I've let hospital drama
suffocate my personal life
more times than I can count.
Remember when you were the
lead in the school play,
and opening night,
I-I sent you roses
- and then didn't show up.
- Yeah, sure.
There's no need to rehash that.
And today I brought
you banana pudding.
People don't change, do they?
I keep making the same
mistakes again and again.
What's going on?
What do you mean?
I sense an agenda.
Humble pie is not your dessert.
Kit Voss offered me a job.
Why would you leave
Seattle Children's?
- Were you fired?
- No.
Look, I saw you
pocket the benzos.
You're not having an
issue with that again?
No, I have this pain in my
back, it wraps around my side,
- keeps me up at night.
- Well, have you seen a doctor?
Of course not. It's
just a muscle pull.
It's nothing, it's fine.
Look, I won't... I won't
make a habit of the pills.
But at my age, you know,
I'm not getting any younger.
Aches and pains
are a common thing.
Dad, you're barely 60.
Hey, hey, 59.
I'm considering
coming to Chastain
so that I can be closer to you.
Oh, my God.
Louisa left you.
No.
Why do you always
think the worst of me?
I left her.
And now you need a whole
new crop of people to charm.
- Ouch.
- So you arrived to save me,
and then you managed to line it
up with an agenda of your own.
: No, no. I
did come to save you.
The "agenda" came
after I realized
that I wanted to be
with you from now on.
I really did drop everything
to come and save you.
And in return, you rip
my heart out.
- I'll come back later.
No, no, it's fine.
I'm leaving.
For good.
You okay?
No.
Bye.
Well, not a bad day overall.
We saved a life,
and the young man
actually has a chance
at a real future.
And he might be one
of the lucky ones
whose OI goes into remission.
That'd be icing on the cake.
There's just one last
hurdle for Marco.
Oh, he'll have his work cut
out for him getting his mom
- to let him grow up.
Hey.
What's going on?
Oh, lately, I've been a
little disappointed in myself.
Really? You?
I'm afraid to do what that
kid was willing to do.
You know, take a big
risk for a larger life.
Listen to me.
After everything you
have been through,
I can honestly say
you are one of the most
courageous women I know.
And you've got nerves
of steel in the OR.
- Well, thank you.
- You're welcome.
But here's the thing.
I haven't been in a
significant relationship in...
I don't know, a long time.
For a lot of reasons.
You know, my past, obviously.
But now I've gone and
fallen for someone
who I won't identify,
and there are huge
potential complications.
Don't tell me you're afraid
the guy's gonna say no.
Because that seems
inconceivable.
I'm as afraid he'll say
yes as I am he'll say no.
Ugh, it's all terrifying.
Yeah. I get it.
You know, honestly?
I'm terrified of
becoming a father.
You know, just the way
it's all happening, right?
And Padma is loosey-goosey
and I am not.
You know what I was thinking?
What if the kid doesn't love me?
There's not a
chance of that, AJ.
Hey.
Conrad and Gigi would
be lucky to have you.
Is it that obvious?
Maybe not to Conrad.
Billie.
Go tell the man how you feel.
You know what? Slight
detour before home.
I have a top secret mission,
should you choose to accept it.
What is it?
Someone I know needs a hug,
and they're right over there.
I'm a really good hugger.
And so is Mr. Waffles.
Then you two are the
perfect people for the job.
All right, follow me.
Hey, there.
Reinforcements are
here to cheer you up.
Hey, cutie-pie.
- Oh, who's your friend?
- This is Mr. Waffles.
What happened to your head?
I got a boo-boo.
Want Mr. Waffles to kiss
it and make it better?
And I could also give you
a kiss if you wanted me to.
Yes, please. Both
would be great.
Mr. Waffles is your
new best friend, huh?
Thank you.
Want to have a puppet chat?
Yeah, you're gonna talk for him?
What's the joke?
Why do the chickens
cross the road?
Why?
Because they want
ice cream pasta.
Ice cream pasta
with chocolate on top.
That sounds delicious.
You want
some of that, too?
How are you feeling?
Would a martini help?
Uh, I'm not so
sure about a drink.
- I have an idea about the wedding.
- Mm-hmm?
Let's put it aside for now.
We can still keep the
date we came up with
and have a big engagement
party for our friends.
Would that be okay?
Darling, what is it?
I-I can't, I can't really see.
All right.
Let's just lie you down.
There you go.
It's likely an MS flare-up
because you pushed
yourself too hard.
- I'll call your doctor.