Let's stay focused, Johnny.
What are you looking at?
Who is she?
That's Miss Cindy,
Zeke's new aide.
What happened to his old aide?
She got married.
So, first, you want to rub the glue
on the paper in any shapes you like.
Why do people get married?
Because they love each other.
Why aren't you married?
I haven't found the person I love yet
because I spend all of my time loving you.
Does that mean
we can get married?
Well, love comes in many types,
and there's lots of it to go around.
My snow is ruined.
It's not ruined.
Oh, it's pretty.
See, look, I like the green.
Who ever heard of green snow?
It's magical.
Come here, we'll get
you cleaned up, okay?
It's okay.
Are you okay?
You gonna pay for that?
Nice of you to offer.
Now I can actually get
some cream cheese.
29-year-old teacher, she works
with special needs children. She...
I love what you're wearing. It
brings out the blue of the case file.
Which means it's not from
the ER. So why are you here?
Because Dr. Cuddy is not here.
She's decided to spend some more
time at home with the baby for a while.
I'm taking over some of her
day-to-day responsibilities,
like babysitting you.
Interesting. You have
your whole life ahead of you,
so why would Cuddy
want you to die so young?
She figured I'd spent three years
working for you, I was inoculated.
Good. Fun.
You get to exercise your newfound
power, I squirm under your thumb,
resent the student becoming the
teacher, and then push comes to shove
and we all get to realize
what our real roles should be.
And then you put out.
That's why I took the job.
29-year-old special ed teacher
coughs up blood all over Corky.
No dyspnea, no weight loss.
Why are you smirking?
Never thought I'd see the day you
were taking orders from Cameron.
Cameron's in charge?
When did that happen?
You're going to
destroy her, aren't you?
I am going to do my job. If that
involves leaving her a rotting pulp...
Cameron's going
to mark her territory.
She'll probably overcompensate
and destroy you. Bleeding ulcer.
Scope of the stomach
and lungs were clean,
yet she continues to spit up blood
from both her stomach and lungs.
Means there's probably something
wrong with the blood itself,
leukemia, von Willebrands.
Thoracic tumor's a better fit.
Erodes into her airway and
esophagus, explains the...
Oh, will you two
stop it already?
Stop what? Disagreeing.
Okay. Which one of us
shouldn't have an opinion?
It's not an opinion,
it's a smoke screen.
You toss out a lame idea instead of
agreeing with Foreman's better idea
because you're
worried that will confirm
that he's boldly gone where
no man has gone before.
You slept with Foreman?
Sorry. You were busy.
Drop it, House.
We're seeing each
other, end of discussion.
Anything else isn't relevant.
It's extremely relevant.
Apparently, it colors everything.
Now I have no idea if
you have differing opinions
because you have
differing opinions
or because you're just trying to
prove that you can think for yourselves.
How about you just judge
our ideas on their own merit?
You don't want me to do that.
Go run a bleeding time test,
confirm our patient's blood is screwy,
then you can come back and
pretend to disagree about why.
Time zero.
I'm impressed, you
didn't even flinch.
I just went to my happy place.
We cannot let House
anywhere near this woman.
Where is your happy place?
My class. With them.
Pass the first mark.
It's a great thing you do.
Not really.
Most kids, typical children, you hand
them a pair of scissors and they cut.
Well, Tony, he's got CP,
and when I gave him scissors,
we went on a journey together,
learning to get his fingers in those
holes, to hold the scissors apart,
to hold the paper.
I mean, when he finally learned
to cut, we both just wept with joy.
If you ever meet our boss,
just yes or no answers, okay?
It's not slowing up.
No sign of clotting.
So there is something
wrong with my blood?
Don't worry, we'll
run some lab tests to
find out which clotting
factor is off and...
I'm not worried.
Must be one hell
of a happy place.
She's beautiful.
I know. I'm lucky.
Absolutely.
What's she like?
She's eight weeks old.
Are you asking me about her
politics or her sense of humor?
My cousin had a kid. They
acted like they knew the thing
from the time it was two
minutes old. I just thought...
She cries, she
eats, and she poops.
What's wrong?
I don't feel anything.
You're tired.
I'm not sleep deprived.
She sleeps fine. I'm
obviously not hormonal.
I know I'm supposed
to feel amazement.
I'm supposed to love her.
I just...
I don't feel anything at all.
Sorry. Maybe I'm just tired.
Thank you for
stopping by. I'm okay.
Lisa,
if you're...
I'm feeding her, I'm changing
her, and I'm burping her.
I'm doing everything I'm
supposed to do. She will be okay.
Please go back to work.
It is the blood, but the clotting
proteins aren't the problem.
It's her platelets. Looked like
they had bite marks in them.
So, now you're agreeing?
Either you folded because I gave
you crap, or you broke up, or...
We disagree, you
blame our relationship.
We agree, you
Don't you see a problem there?
Yes. Don't you?
Could be lymphoma.
Not with a normal LDH.
ITP fits. We should
start her on methotrexate.
Absolutely. And
total body irradiation.
Because she failed
the bleeding time test?
TBI will promote cancers,
kill her digestive tract.
Don't forget, stop her
from bleeding into her brain.
It's premature, reckless,
and potentially lethal.
True. Must be somebody's job to stop
me from being reckless and irresponsible.
Nobody can stop me
from being premature.
I got a patient with ITP. I
want to hit her with radiation.
I'm gonna have to call you back.
Methotrexate. Good point.
On the other hand, if
she bleeds in her brain,
she's gonna need a
special ed class of her own.
Fine.
Really?
Yeah. If you think
it's right, do it.
Hmm.
Some people thought you were
going to be brutal, marking your territory.
Who? Nobody.
Just because I call him
nobody, doesn't make me a racist.
I'm not going to play games.
If you come to me with a request,
and it makes medical sense, I'll say yes.
I need oral sex.
I'm pretty sure biological
imperative qualifies as medical sense.
Can I return my phone call now?
I don't really see how
that's going to be possible.
Patient won't respond to methotrexate,
bleeding time hasn't improved.
You have a medical dilemma
for me, I have one for you.
I need a reason to not
do total body irradiation.
Other than that
Cameron said you can't.
She said I can.
Then why don't we just do it?
Because it's premature,
reckless, and potentially lethal.
Then why don't
we just don't do it?
Because that would let
Cameron in on the fact
that I never intended to do it.
This is gonna be
convoluted, isn't it?
Figured I'd ask for something
really crazy so she'd shoot me down,
and get the whole, "I can control House"
thing out of her perky little system.
So the next time I went back and I
asked for something marginally crazy,
it would seem marginally
reasonable, and she'd say yes.
So, yeah, slightly convoluted.
You're screwed.
Unless we irradiate her.
Without the radiation.
We book the nuclear lab,
we fill out the paperwork,
we bring the patient down there,
we do everything but flip the switch.
Go. Do. Don't flip.
And is there anything
we should be doing,
you know, to actually
help the patient?
Trust me, for the long term,
this will help all our patients.
In the short term, double the dose
of methotrexate and add prednisone.
Cameron's got the
keys to the castle.
This trial I'm running, the
drug really seems to be working.
She's kind of liking the power.
Think I'm kind of
liking her liking it.
I'm not sure what I'm
going to do about Thirteen.
She's sort of
dressing like Cuddy.
She's on the placebo.
You can't possibly know that.
Accidents happen. I found out.
You cannot tell her. You'd
be compromising the trial.
She knows she had a 50-50
chance of not being on the drug.
If you feel like you're
lying to her, too bad.
I don't want to tell her.
I want to put her
on the real drug.
And you want me to
tell you that that's okay?
Her trial results are already
compromised just from the fact that I know.
As long as she's
wasting her time,
why not give her something
that might actually help her?
Valid point, except for the
fact that it's a load of crap.
Don't be an idiot.
So, how long until we
start the procedure?
We already started. Told
you, you wouldn't feel a thing.
You should lie back.
Just stay really still.
I have to pee.
Can we, like, call a timeout for a
minute? Let me go to the bathroom?
Yeah. Sure. We'll just start
up again when you're done.
Thanks.
Sorry. I didn't
realize I had to go.
No problem.
Sarah!
No pulse. Get the paddles.
Clear!
Got a pulse.
It's not ITP. She clearly
doesn't need fake radiation.
No structural
defects in her heart.
What about a calcified valve
or a patent foramen ovale?
Transthoracic echo and
bubble study show nothing.
Her heart's clean.
The patient said
she had to go pee.
Maybe when she got
up, she started to urinate,
increased the vagal tone, caused
arrhythmia and stopped her heart.
Who has to go pee in the
middle of a nuclear procedure?
It wasn't really a
nuclear procedure.
She didn't know that.
People don't die from peeing.
Heavy metal, toxin.
Drugs or alcohol.
Or her own body is making
a toxin. Cold agglutinins.
Abnormal protein gets
activated by cold temperatures.
Like the classroom
with the broken heater
and the cold metal table
in the procedure room.
For God's sake, get a room.
Immerse her in an ice bath. The
cold will activate her cold agglutinins.
Causing her heart to race.
Confirming our diagnosis.
And giving her
another heart attack.
Lucky for me, there's a flaxen-haired
maiden who loves to say yes.
How in the world could you
approve total body irradiation
for a patient with possible ITP?
It was the right call.
There was no medical
justification for that kind of...
Not medically, no. Absolutely
no medical rationalization.
I had to say yes because
House wanted me to say no.
You think he was bluffing?
I'm the new kid,
he had to test me.
Don't get cute,
don't engage him.
Do not play his games
because you will lose.
You hired me to do
this job, let me do it.
Oh! I'm sorry, looks like you guys
are in the middle of a conversation.
I can wait until Cuddy leaves.
You are gonna leave
soon, aren't you?
I mean, the nurses have
got your baby out there.
Not that they're going
to kidnap it or anything,
but I figured that the new
mother brings the baby to work
because she wants to
listen to all the cooing.
If you're gonna wait,
you can wait outside.
Unless the new mother
brings the baby to work
because she wants
to dump the baby,
because she hates the baby
and thinks she made a big mistake.
You can't trust that
Wilson guy with anything.
Lisa, are you...
It's not a big deal, I
was having a bad day.
Is Wilson gonna be in trouble?
For betraying my trust
in a vulnerable time? No.
Why would that bother me?
He was worried, he
made a bad choice.
It's not a big deal.
I know it seems like crap, you
probably feel like crap, but it's not.
Legally, you haven't
adopted her yet.
There's no obligations, no strings.
It could be undone tomorrow.
Emotionally, you'll
feel guilty for a while,
but the kid, she won't
even know you existed.
You saying I should
give her back?
Much better than having a
mother who doesn't give a crap.
Thanks.
I'm just gonna go
drop it off at the pound.
What did you want?
We got a green light. Go
draw the patient's blood.
Why?
To see if it clumps in the cold.
She's making you confirm
your theory before you treat?
She approved the bath.
She just thought we ought
to do a test to confirm.
That's more of a
yellow light, isn't it?
So, she lets you nuke
the patient, no problem,
but makes you jump through
hoops to give her a bath?
Why would she do that?
I think she was playing you.
Go draw the blood.
I didn't realize the nurses
allowed any visitors in here.
They don't.
We'll just do these problems,
and then you have to go. Okay?
Okay. I need to draw some blood.
I had a crush on my teacher
in fourth grade. And fifth.
It's more that... Johnny
was a non-verbal autistic.
Then for Sarah, he talks, makes
eye contact. He's like a regular kid.
Since she got sick, he started
going back away from us.
I had to bring
him in for a visit.
Tell you what,
I'll close the blinds so the
nurses don't ask questions.
You can stay as
long as you want.
We should have the
results in about an hour.
I'll be here.
Good job.
One minute at 39 degrees.
Oh! Damn. Sorry.
You all right?
Don't be paranoid. I feel great.
Didn't expect the meds
to work this quickly.
Let's not get ahead of ourselves,
you might not even be on the real drug.
Several patients have shown improvement.
I know my test results have been better.
I know I have more energy.
You ever hear the
term "placebo effect"?
I guess I do have a
few reasons to feel good.
But let's not get ahead
of ourselves, you're good,
but not "curing
Huntington's" good.
Good.
It's clumped. House
was right, ice bath's on.
You got a sec?
Don't be an idiot.
I know it's hard, but you need
to stay in there for three minutes.
It's okay.
You come to procedures now?
Only the ones that might involve
stopping the patient's heart.
Cameron tell you to be here?
Shut up.
Tell me about Jonathan. How'd
you get him to come out of hiding?
He was extremely
sensitive to touch,
yet he had a tactile
fascination with newspaper.
I mean, he wouldn't read it,
he would just touch it, crinkle it.
I thought maybe that was a
way in. Papier-mâché and...
And it was. He let
me into his world.
Please tell her that
talking will ruin the test.
All the kids, I try to become a part of
them, and have them become a part of me.
How much longer
until the heart attack?
I wanted to be a doctor from
the time I was eight years old,
never wanted to be
a pediatrician though.
Now they're both talking.
Well, I wanted to
be a sociologist.
I was supposed to observe a
class. I was sent to room 214,
but I went to room 241 instead.
It was a special ed
class. And I just...
I just felt at home.
Time. Heart rate's normal.
You can get out now.
It's not cold agglutinins.
I'm not surprised.
She obviously has brain damage.
Seriously.
She screwed up a room
number six years ago,
and you decide she
has brain damage?
Transposed digits.
Classic marker for
number confusion.
It means she has a lesion in
her left parahippocampal region.
I misdialed a phone number this
morning. It must be contagious.
She also forgot to pee
before your fake test.
So she has a small bladder.
Shows an inability
to predict the future.
Also located in the left
hemisphere of the brain.
Close to the
parahippocampal region.
Means the damage is ongoing.
Two subtle clues,
six years apart,
that's hardly
compelling evidence.
I'm compelled.
That's not what this is. Every
time a decent person comes in,
you set out to prove that
they have brain damage.
I never said her deranged
personality was a symptom.
You don't need to. I've
been here five years.
I can hear your thoughts
from my apartment.
Can you hear me now?
Move on to another organ.
I did.
The screwed-up numbers and forgetting
to pee points to her being a human being.
The platelet dysfunction and cardiac
arrest points to a pancreatic tumor.
Or Multiple Sclerosis.
The brain is like the Internet,
packets of information constantly
flowing from one area to another.
Plaques in her brain are like a
bad server, slow down the flow.
If it's in the parahippocampus,
it'll spread to the brain stem,
which means it'll
be the lungs next.
Brain biopsy will
show you the plaques.
Or we could not
cut into her brain.
It's just her pancreas.
We should do an ERCP.
Or we could settle this
with rock, paper, scissors,
but, unfortunately, there are
people who adjudicate these disputes.
A pancreatic tumor is
much more likely to kill her.
Not this week, not next
week, not next month.
The number confusion
was six years ago.
You don't think we
have time for an ERCP?
The heart attack
was six hours ago.
Now, maybe, it's planning to go
into hiding for a couple of years
or maybe it's
gonna hit her lungs.
Stop!
We have to
assume it's the brain.
I'll go fire up
the biopsy drill.
No. We have to assume it's the
brain until we prove otherwise.
Do an MRI, T-2 images.
You want me to do another test?
You should be able
to see the MS plaques.
If they exist, you
can do your biopsy.
No.
You want to say yes, you
know you should say yes.
But you also think that this
job is about standing up to me.
So you're not gonna say yes, you're not
gonna say no. You're just gonna waste time.
And the patient's brain or pancreas,
or whatever is wrong with her,
is not gonna wait for
you to impress your boss.
So, pick one, either him or me.
Do the MRI.
You still here?
The whole point of giving
Cameron the job was so you could...
I don't want to go home.
House told me I
should give her back.
Instead of being offended,
I've been wondering if he's right.
He's not. He never is,
not when it's anything
personal or human or...
No. He's always cold, he's always
an ass, but he's very rarely just wrong.
I've read every bonding
and attachment book there is.
I feel like I'm in prison at
home. I feel like I'm free here.
Parents make sacrifices.
I don't know if I want to.
I'm not proud of
this. I feel terrible.
I feel like a failure.
But she deserves to be loved.
I don't know what to say.
No plaques on
the left hemisphere.
Or the right.
Even magnified images of her
hippocampal region. Nothing.
This is surprising.
So, can we cancel the biopsy?
Go ahead with ERCP.
I need to talk to
you about Remy.
Who?
Thirteen.
What did you call her?
She's on placebo.
And you want to change that?
I'm the last person you'd ever
come to for ethical advice, literally,
which means you've already
asked every other person,
and no one's giving
you the answer you want.
Or I respect your opinion, and I
want to hear what comes to your mind.
She invited any of her lesbian
friends into bed with you?
I was mistaken.
Drug gonna cure her?
It looks promising,
reducing symptoms.
No cure then.
So, the pros are you might
delay the onset of symptoms,
give her an extra year, maybe
three. She's still dead before you're 45.
The question is,
are those few years worth risking
the rest of your life in medicine?
No.
There. That wasn't
so hard, was it?
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Unless you love her.
If you love her, then
you do stupid things.
Common bile duct is clear.
No filling defects
in the biliary tree.
Oh, God. What?
It's her lungs. House was
right. O2 sats down to 89.
Increasing to 100% O2.
Better get out.
Do we have to tell him?
The surgeons were able to
drain the pleural effusions.
The patient's breathing on her
own, but she's still pretty weak.
Lung failure proves
that one of us was right.
Who said "brain"?
Yes, you predicted that her lungs would
fail, but the MRI was negative for MS.
I was right about the
where, but not the what.
A picornavirus could cause
localized demyelination
that the MRI wouldn't pick up.
If we run a nerve conduction
study on the surface of her brain,
we'll see the dead spots.
You're talking about
cutting into her skull?
Actually, I'm talking about cutting
off her skull, exposing her brain.
A pancreatic
tumor could still fit.
It explains the heart,
the blood and her lungs.
ERCP was negative.
And she agrees with me because
she agrees with me. Right, sweetie?
All we need is a more sensitive
test. Endoscopic ultrasound.
Just accept that you've
been proven wrong.
You were also proven wrong.
Why don't I get a second test?
Because if I'm
right about the brain,
then we don't have time
to indulge your wrongness.
Let me know when Cameron says
yes to cutting off our patient's skull.
I'll be doing the
endoscopic ultrasound.
Good news, I don't need your approval
for some crazy, unproven treatment.
I just need to do a test.
You want to remove
your patient's skull.
Remind me to revoke
Kutner's telephone privileges.
I didn't realize that was an
AMA-approved treatment for MS.
Not searching for MS, but what
set it off. Equine encephalitis.
Turned a cool breeze
of MS into a Cat 5 storm.
I didn't realize your
patient was a horse.
There's been human cases.
Not when it's 30 degrees outside.
Transmission is by mosquito.
So, she got bitten
six months ago.
Or it's some other infection.
Whatever it is, it's
running rampant
in the left side of her brain. When I
get in there I'll get you the specifics.
You're asking me to let you cut
off the top of someone's head.
I need more than "I'll
know it when I see it."
So, you want proof before you
let me go looking for the proof?
This is the test.
You have to give me something.
Cuddy's gonna love you. The patient,
on the other hand, is gonna hate you
until the day she
dies next week.
Actually, this idiot will
probably forgive you.
You gonna help or what?
I want kids.
Um...
I think these kids are
already spoken for.
Not now. But since we're dating
I just thought you should know.
I thought, because
of your illness...
So did I.
Even when I didn't
know if I had it or not,
I just assumed I couldn't
take the chance. But now,
even though I know I have
it, it feels like an option.
You really don't have to
keep buying me things.
Just open it.
This is nice.
The picture is
actually your gift.
That's your baby.
I took her picture to one of those places
that does that age enhancement thing.
And according to the
kid who works there,
this is a pretty
good approximation
of what your daughter will
look like 18 years from now.
That's sort of cool.
Right now, she's just
this weird little creature
that sleeps and poops and cries.
But that is who
she's going to be.
You will be teaching
her how to ride a bike,
giving her advice about friends and
school and having her heart broken,
she'll ignore most of it,
but some of it will stick.
You're gonna be there
for her through all of that.
You just have to get
through this part. That's all.
It's very sweet.
I'll pay you back for the photo.
Don't worry about it. That's just
the picture that came with the frame.
You can chuck it.
A kid with a raging
viral syndrome
and three dead mosquitoes.
I'm off to storm the Bastille.
These aren't mosquitoes.
Fruit flies. Close enough.
Acute viral nasopharyngitis?
One of her students
has the common cold?
Team's not what it used to be.
On the other hand, Kutner ran his
endoscopic ultrasound, didn't find peep.
So, disproving it's her
pancreas proves it's her brain?
Yes!
You used to do this job. Remember?
It's what used to pass for evidence.
Now I do this job. You brought me
three dead bugs and a runny nose!
I can't find you the proof you want
because it's trapped inside her head.
The only way I can get at it
is to cut it open and rip it out,
which, apparently, is the
one test you won't let me run.
So, either I do
this or I do nothing.
What do you want me to do?
Say yes just because you're House?
I'd certainly like that, yeah.
Yes.
Cameron actually said yes?
No, I'm just obsessive
about clean cuticles.
Sawing off the top of her skull
and placing electrodes
on her brain is insane.
Right, we should be re-testing
her pancreas for the umpteenth time.
You're skipping steps
because it's Cameron.
You haven't figured her out, you
want to see how far you can push.
I'm skipping steps because
our patient is skipping steps
on the way to being dead.
If you got a better idea...
We should remove her spleen.
Splenic lymphoma explains the
damaged platelets, the heart, the lungs.
If this doesn't work,
spleen is all yours.
Unless I kill her, of course.
Not only will this allow us to
clock your brain's processing speed,
you'll also get free cable
for the first three months.
What's this?
A blue car. Is that
part of the test?
No, my lease is up
next month. You like it?
I'm gonna ask you
a series of questions
designed to stimulate
left-brain function,
logic, reasoning,
problem solving.
Or as my mentor Old Ben
liked to call it, "The dark side."
If we find slow areas, we
know we found damage.
We treat, you go home. Ready?
I'd nod yes, but I
can't move my head.
This pen is red. Its
ink is red. Is all ink red?
No.
Nerve conduction's 12.8 meters
per second, right within range.
Cameron's letting him
cut into our patient's skull
based on nothing but dead bugs
and someone else's runny nose.
There are two pints in a quart.
Four quarts in a gallon. How
many pints in five gallons?
House, step away
from the patient.
Who's that?
That's my old boss. And by
"old," I don't mean "former".
Insulting me is not
gonna make me go away.
You're not here, obviously, I'm
not trying to make you go away.
Hint, the answer is a number.
Um...
40?
12.4 meters per second.
Conduction's still normal.
Dr. Cameron? You're
actually assisting him with this?
Yes, because I'm actually
familiar with this case.
Well, I'm familiar
enough to know
that cutting into this woman's
brain is not necessary.
Is she serious?
She's certainly not funny.
Put the phone down, pick up
the baby. Make us all happy.
Okay, settle down, baby. It's
okay. We'll be done in a minute.
House, I can call
security. I can...
BP's dropping.
Get it back up. I got a
whole stack of these.
Give her 10 cc dopamine.
Already am, thanks. Your baby
needs you a lot more than we do.
You aren't hungry, you aren't
wet, I don't know what it is.
That is so annoying.
Can you make it stop?
Baby's crying is annoying you?
What's her nerve conduction?
14.3. It's actually speeding up.
But her BP's 80 over palp.
We're gonna have to stop.
That doesn't make any sense.
The fact that you're wrong
doesn't make any sense
or the fact that I believed
that you were right?
BP's still dropping.
She's gonna stroke.
I'm giving her 10 more cc,
and I'm putting an end to this.
Okay, Rachel, quiet down.
I need you to be quiet.
Please, turn that phone off.
Why does the baby annoy
you, but no one else does?
I mean, you're
right about her, but...
I don't know what you want. I will
give you anything that you want.
I don't know what it is.
Tell me. Please.
Just help me. Please!
Really?
That worked?
She's stable.
We're finished
here. Close her up.
How long until we can
perform the splenectomy?
Can't dose her with anesthesia
until the last batch completely clears.
How come the baby annoyed her?
We should get her in
there as soon as we can.
Two hours, at least.
Her blood pressure's in the
tank. I hope she lasts two hours.
What was different?
Our patient loves
all things annoying.
She'd love this conversation.
She's an earth mother,
takes in the freaks and rejects of
humanity and tells them they're A-okay.
So, what was different?
Her head was open, you were
asking her questions, a baby was crying.
She had low blood pressure.
According to the
laws of physics,
low blood pressure
causes light-headedness
chest pain, but not annoyance.
Move your feet.
You decided to keep her. Thank
you for telling me. You can go now.
I talked to her. We connected.
You talked at her, you
had a chemical reaction.
Are you trying to annoy me?
I'm trying to explain you.
I know it doesn't make
any sense, but it was real.
It was there.
You want to hold her?
Come here, come say hi.
You think we'll bond?
Is that cute?
A little.
If I threw up on
you, you'd be pissed.
Your puke isn't as cute.
That's 'cause of your hips. If she
would've just gestated a little longer,
her stomach sphincter
would be fully mature.
But, no, we have
to walk upright,
which means that baby's head
is too big for mommy's hips.
And by the way, your hips may
be an evolutionary improvement.
So we've evolved to
find baby puke cute.
'Cause otherwise we'd kill them
all before they became functional.
Bonding's over. I got
to go see another baby.
So, I can just live spleen-free?
Plenty of people live
perfectly normal lives without...
Spleen's fine.
It's not her brain.
Of course it's her brain.
You've looked at her brain, you
took off her skull, you found nothing.
Didn't look in the right part.
Didn't look in the heart part.
In the womb, blood has to bypass
the lungs since they don't work yet.
When we're born, we take our
first big breath, lungs expand,
and the ductus
closes. Yours didn't.
She has a Patent
ductus arteriosus.
When you get stressed,
your blood pressure goes up
forces open the ductus,
blood takes a little detour,
makes it leak from your
nose, your stomach, your lungs,
and more significantly, keeps it
flowing to the right side of your brain
and away from your left.
Which means that when you
get stressed, you get un-stressed.
That's why you're so good
with those annoying kids.
And why, when your
blood pressure dropped,
you were able to identify Cuddy
as an annoying human being.
Good news is we
can fix the heart.
Bad news for the annoying kids.
She's incredible.
Thank you.
Great work today.
I should have trusted your
instincts. I will in the future.
I quit.
I think I just apologized. If you
want, I can get down on my knees.
It's not because of you.
I approved an insane procedure
with no proof, no evidence, no...
You made the right call.
The problem was a brain
problem. Without the procedure,
House never notices the
increased left brain function.
She'd be dead if
you hadn't said yes.
I know.
But
I'll always say yes to House. I
studied under him. He's in my head.
And if you gave anyone else
this job, they would always say no.
Because... Well,
because they should.
House is insane.
Which leaves me.
I'm sorry.
Hey, buddy.
It's okay, buddy, come here.
I missed you so
much. I missed you.
How are you?
Good. Yeah? You
look so handsome.