Infections have a nasty
way of sneaking up on you.
You're feeling pretty good,
you think the infection's gone,
and then it reappears,
out of nowhere,
when your body's still weak,
when you've barely recovered.
Hey.
What's all this?
Sold it. I'm done with it.
With the trailer?
Yep. Don't need it anymore.
Don't you need a place to sleep,
or are you moving into my
house, too, and no one told me?
Better. I just bought
my own house.
Closing it this morning.
Amelia's been
giving me a hard time
about getting a
grown-up house, so...
So, no more trailer.
Bam. You're
infected all over again.
Yeah.
Is this... Should I
have asked you?
I should've asked you. No, no.
You paid for it. It's yours
to do what you want with.
You sure? Yes.
Congratulations
on the new house.
Thanks.
And once the infection spreads,
once it gets into
your bloodstream,
well, then you really
have to watch it.
'Cause that's the
kind of infection
that can kill you.
Catherine's back
in town next week.
Thought it'd be nice to
have some people over.
Well, nothing
fancy, just dinner.
Who's in?
You know, that's a
fine idea, Dr. Webber.
Oh, sorry.
Yes, yes, yes.
Thanks. Absolutely.
Okay. Avery said yes.
Uh, how about you?
Yeah, I'll be there.
Okay. I'm not sure about
Dr. Warren's schedule, though.
Okay. Um, Warren?
Uh, yeah, I'm
in. I'm in. All right.
Uh, what can I bring?
Um, I wouldn't say
no to that artichoke dip
you brought to
the resident mixer.
Well, that's...
That's Miranda's secret recipe.
Okay.
I see.
I'll bring it.
Should be a great party.
Hey, Maggie, did you hear
that Owen bought a house?
Oh, good, now you can
naked snuggle on his sofa.
Wait. Furniture, right. I
need some of that. Suction.
No black recliners, I beg you.
And nothing you have
to assemble yourself.
You got a real house,
get some real furniture,
keep the momentum going.
Hey, maybe you should
come shopping with me,
point me in the right direction.
Then you'll just wind up with
a house full of furniture I like.
I don't see that as a problem.
I want stuff we both can enjoy.
Wait. What? Why?
Is she... Are you
moving in with him?
Duval forceps, please.
Oh, No.
I mean, that's
not... I don't think...
Why not? Just think about it.
It's pretty big.
Nice yard. Good school district.
I'm sorry.
Did you just go from
moving in to having kids?
Boy, you guys move fast.
I couldn't even sleep in
the same bed as my fiance.
We were engaged for a year.
Long engagements, bad idea.
I agree. Better to go straight
to the marriage
part. It's better.
Would you get married again?
I'd consider it, with
the right person.
You would?
I'd strongly consider it, yes.
Me, too.
With the right person.
Okay, then.
Wait. What?
Did you... What just happened?
Are you engaged now?
What? No. No.
Hypotheticals.
We were just...
That was nothing.
We were just talking.
We were just...
Maggie, we were just talking.
Oh, please. How long
you think till you move out?
Who's moving out?
Amelia, when she
marries Owen Hunt
and moves into his big,
new, kid-friendly house.
No, no. Okay, hang on.
It was a hypothetical
conversation.
That is it.
In which you were picking
out hypothetical furniture
for your hypothetical
children's hypothetical playroom.
Wow. It was nothing.
Can we drop it, please? Why?
Gladly.
Gladly? Why gladly?
What's wrong?
Do you see a dilation?
I'm worried about
medullary sponge kidney.
You didn't answer my question.
You didn't answer mine.
You think we're moving too fast?
Is that it?
Amelia, please.
You're the one who
pushed us back together.
You know, you
practically yelled at me
to run back into
his arms, and now...
Thanks for the consult.
I called the landlord,
and he agreed to swap
out our two-bedroom lease
for something smaller, since...
I mean, I figured that
I could save on rent
while I'm at Preminger,
so I can afford to fly back
on weekends to Seattle
to, you know,
visit you and Sofia.
Okay.
Okay? Yeah, sounds good.
I don't want to leave
when we're like this.
We've barely
talked since the trial.
I really don't know what to say.
Neither do I, but I am trying to
say words and to be here and help.
You've helped enough.
Okay.
X-rays came back
clear. No breaks.
We got lucky, Nash.
So listen to your grandma
the next time she tells you not
to climb the bookshelves, okay?
All right.
Thank you, Doctor.
You have been so
good with him today,
so patient, and I
can't help but notice
I don't see a ring
on your finger.
Excuse me?
You should meet my
daughter. Nash's mom.
Not the sharpest
tack, but really sweet,
really pretty.
Ma'am, I appreciate the offer,
but I'm with someone already.
Oh, are you engaged?
Are you getting engaged? Uh, no.
Uh, well, I...
Her number's in that chart.
I'll tell her to
expect your call.
Okay.
Hey.
I think Grandma over there
just arranged my
marriage to her daughter.
Well, there must be
something in the air,
because Amelia and Owen are
talking about getting married, too.
Hey, maybe you guys
could have a double wedding.
Then I would only have
to live through it once.
Help! Please! Someone
help! It's okay, buddy. I got you.
Whoa. Okay, what happened?
He passed out, he came to,
and then he passed out again.
Okay, let's get him down here.
There's another kid outside.
Is this your son, sir? Uh,
no. I'm his driver's ed teacher.
Hey, I got it.
Hey, there. You okay?
Can I... Can I park here?
Quit hovering and just
go in there and talk to him.
He has made it very clear he
doesn't want me anywhere near him.
So, no.
Does she have him on
fluconazole in case it's fungal?
You do realize that
Kyle can see you?
It's not one-way glass.
Thank you.
Kyle?
Oh, God. I'm fine.
Are you okay?
I'm fine. I'm fine. I'm fine.
I'm fine.
Everything just
started spinning.
The... The nausea's probably
because of the antibiotics.
Uh, I'll get Dr. Shepherd
to get you an antiemetic.
Why don't you just go?
Take that.
I don't need any help.
And I definitely don't
want an audience for this.
Then, um, let's pretend that
you're puking for some
other reason, then.
Aah. Like, um, after
a show or something.
Too many whiskey
shots, you know?
Fun puking. You're
not hearing me.
I don't need any help from you.
Look, I understand if you
don't want to deal with me,
but you are gonna need somebody.
Does your friends, do your
family know that you're here?
That's none of your
business, all right?
I'm not your business anymore.
Okay.
But you're gonna need someone.
Dr. Shepherd took
out your implant.
Your tremor is gonna come back.
No kidding.
Kyle, I'm sorry.
I'm gonna puke again, now.
How about you just go?
Go. Go!
I'm...
I'm going.
Dad, Dad, I may have
brushed against the wall, but...
Good news, Arvin. I
see no signs of anything.
You're doing just fine.
And the doctor says I'm fine.
Yeah. The doctor.
Well, it... It was the
wall of a hospital,
but didn't I say that?
Tell him that Rhys had
a medical emergency.
It's strep throat. That's
not an emergency.
Strep throat shouldn't
cause you to faint.
Are you on antibiotics?
Yeah, for two days. I'm fine.
But, still, open up.
You passed out in a car.
You know how dangerous
that is on the road?
I wasn't even
driving! It was Arvin!
Has he passed out
before? I don't know.
His mother would kill me
if I let something
happen to him.
Please don't talk about her.
It looks like Rhys has
a peritonsillar abscess.
I do need to drain it.
Oh, no, no,
you're not sticking that
thing down my throat.
Hey, hey, Rhys,
buddy, it's okay.
I'm here. All right?
It's like I told you, I want
you to think of me as a father.
Why? All my mom ever talks about
is when she's gonna
break up with you.
What? ARVIN: Hold on. Hold on.
Your mom's doing
our driver's ed teacher?
I came as soon as
I got the message.
Rhys, honey, are you
okay? Yeah, I'm fine.
No, he's not okay,
and neither am I.
You told him that you
want to break up with me?
Is that true? You told him?
Ah...
This is way better than
our last driver's ed class.
Ready? Here we go.
Oh.
Be nice. I know.
But, God, she put
me through hell.
I know, and you won.
You can afford to
be magnanimous.
Hey, guys.
Well, I was wondering if, um...
I've had a surgery
come up later this week,
and so I wanted to ask
if I could please have
Sofia Tuesday night
instead of Thursday.
Um...
So if I allow you to
have Sofia on Tuesday,
then in exchange, I
will have her Friday?
Yeah, sure, if
that's what you want.
Great. Okay, then I
will make that work.
Thank you.
She's gone. Hmm?
I'd lose that crazed smile
before you start cramping.
Yeah.
I am concerned about Kyle.
You know, he's still septic.
His cultures are
showing possible fungus.
He's also complaining
of neck stiffness.
Why are you talking
to me about this?
You operated three days ago.
Why isn't he recovering?
No. You are off this case.
You are not on my service today.
Why are you talking
to me about this?
Are you sure the infection
isn't because of the
second lead you placed,
the one you had to
convince us to get?
Him. The one I
convinced him to get
because he is my
patient, not you.
I am just concerned.
And if you were
the patient's family,
I would want to
assuage those concerns,
but you are neither
family nor friend right now.
He developed a complication.
Complications happen, Edwards.
We deal with them every
day. Today is no different.
White count is trending
down, wound is clean,
but his temp is
still a little high.
Hey, Kyle, how you feeling?
I was good until
these two showed up.
It's been nag city
for the last half-hour.
Well, maybe you should
think about that the next time
you're in the hospital for
three days without calling us.
I went through 19 hours of
labor with you, without drugs.
You owe me at least
a text or a "tweep."
Mom, it's a tweet,
for the 10th time.
Are you Dr. Shepherd?
I am, yeah.
Dr. Shepherd recently
removed the infected device
from Kyle's brain, but
you should be aware
that both the surgery
and the antibiotics
aren't working as
well as we expected.
I'm sorry. Who are you?
I'm Dr. Edwards.
I'm one of the surgeons here.
This is her?
This is her.
You can go.
Kyle, if we could just talk...
Why is she even
here? I want her to go.
Mmm-hmm. My son is
not good enough for her.
She's not good enough for us.
My brother's broken
a lot of hearts,
but I've never seen
anyone break his.
And I got to think
he'd be better off
if he'd come in here
sooner instead of
trying to avoid you.
So, please, do my family a favor
and get the hell out of here.
Thank you, Dr. Edwards.
That will be all.
So, it's a basic
decortication procedure,
except there is a
slight abnormality.
Yeah, sorry, I can't take
your decortication procedure
'cause I already took
it. Just did the consult.
You just took my
patient without telling me?
You've been pawning
decortications off
on me since I got here.
You hate them, so
now I just take them,
and you don't have to pawn.
Thank you.
Bacon?
Is that a box of bacon?
Bacon. Mmm-hmm.
A cardiothoracic hand grenade.
You know you're a doctor, right?
Mmm. Mmm-hmm. A heart doctor.
It is good.
Told you. Mmm-hmm.
It's my job, isn't it?
You got the big, fancy job,
and you have no
respect for mine.
Are you trying to
tell me that your life's
ambitions stopped
after driver's ed teacher?
Do you know how many hours
the average American
spends behind the wheel...
Oh, here we go. How
many accidents there are
every day?
I am shaping the
drivers of the future.
I'm saving lives!
I'm a freaking hero!
Okay, Superman. We get it,
okay? Hands at 10:00 and 2:00.
Yeah, except the recommended
placement is 9:00 and 3:00 now.
9:00 and 3:00! See these two?
You and Wilson
are doing it right,
not rushing into things.
"Rushing into things"?
We've been together
a million years.
Dr. Karev? Dr. Grey?
Had to put the screws
to the X-ray tech,
but I got him to
rush Rhys' films.
Is that air around the trachea?
I hope not.
It could be artifact,
but we need a CT.
You're really great.
You're... You're clean, but...
Who's interrupting the happy
couple to let Mom know?
I don't know. I was
thinking right about now.
Yeah, well, maybe
I am, too. Oh, great.
So now you're gonna
break up with me?
This is fantastic.
Have fun.
I never said that.
You've been treating me like...
Jo, look, I need to know
what is going on with Kyle.
Just tell me.
Shepherd would kill me.
His family would kill me.
Jo, please. Come on.
You have, what, four floors
to tell me everything you know.
Please. What is going on?
Okay, his symptoms
aren't getting any better.
He's febrile with some
headaches, a bit lethargic,
and Shepherd ordered a stat CT
that showed evidence of an
abscess in the periventricular area.
Okay. Uh...
So what is Shepherd's plan?
Drainage and
ventricular washout.
No. No. What?
She wouldn't do that.
She knows how
dangerous that can be.
She... She can't.
I'm sorry. I have a ton
of prep before surgery.
Does... Does he know
how dangerous it can be?
Big wedding or small wedding?
Well, not too small.
You want it to be a party.
So, um, kids?
Five.
Whoa, five?
Sure.
Unless the first
few terrorize us.
Then we can have four.
Are we really
talking about this?
Marriage and kids?
No.
I mean, maybe one day, but no.
It was pretty fun watching
Maggie's face in the OR, though.
Yep.
You know, it is fun
being fake married to you.
Well, it's fun being
fake married to you.
Mmm. Mmm-hmm.
I have... I have to
prep for a surgery.
Bye-bye.
Uh, Knox asked
me to cover for him
on that facial implant tomorrow.
Cool with you?
Yeah, of course.
Hey, look, if you
need a place to crash,
I still owe you and
I still have a sofa.
Here you go. Why
would I need your sofa?
Everything okay
between you and Bailey?
Yeah. Fine.
No, you're still living
in the same house,
but you're not talking
to each other, right?
I'm aware.
Counseling?
Well, if we go to counseling,
then we'll have to talk,
and then we'll yell,
so not talking is better.
So, then what are you gonna do?
Do? Well, yeah.
You can't just stay like this.
Oh, I can stay like this.
And I will. I am a
very patient man.
And I am right, which makes me
even more patient
since she is overreacting.
I know it and she knows it, though
she's not ready to admit it yet.
So I am biding my time
until she apologizes,
at which point I
will haul my ass
back into our bedroom
where it belongs.
So... So you're not mad?
Nah, man, I am pissed as hell,
but she's the love
of my life, so...
I mean, you get
it. You got April.
April and I are divorced.
Well, like I said, waiting game.
Stay strong. You'll get there.
You're out of your damn mind.
Yeah, I know.
Oh, hey, Bailey, I need to
talk to you about Warren.
Oh, if this is
about that dinner...
No, it... It isn't. You
know, I'm just concerned.
It's been a couple months now.
We'll be fine. Look,
it's a waiting game.
I'm right, and once he remembers
that's always the
case, we'll be fine.
Well, good.
And then maybe you would
consider reinstating him,
sooner than later, okay?
So when you said
you were concerned,
you meant you were
concerned about you.
Of course not.
Um, sir, after the many years I
served under you as my chief,
you must understand
how difficult it is for me
when you force me
to say, respectfully,
this is not my problem
and, please, go
do your damn job.
I don't think you
found that difficult at all.
I'll probably end up
hosting this wedding.
I hosted Owen's last
wedding. Why not?
What's it matter? Why
do you care so much?
I just wanted Amelia to
keep busy with something.
You know, like a hobby.
'Cause if she's
talking Owen's ear off,
she can't talk off mine.
How does this change that?
This means more talking.
Only now it'll be about
flowers and caterers
and what kind of
dress I'm gonna wear.
Kill me now.
Promise me you won't do this.
What? If Jo ever pulls
that ring out of that drawer,
just go to Vegas.
Elope or something.
Don't put us through it all.
Oh, no.
Air pockets in the
parapharyngeal space.
Necrotizing fasciitis.
God, it's everywhere.
Mediastinum, the heart.
There's no time. If it
spreads any further,
there won't be
anything left to salvage.
I'm gonna take him
up to the OR right now.
I'll page Jackson and cardio
and tell them to meet us up there.
They paged cardio.
You want it?
I don't even know what "it" is.
It's a kid with strep throat
turned into nec fasc in the chest.
Pretty cool. Not for the kid.
No, for the kid, it sucks.
Does sound cool, though.
Flip you for it.
Is one of you gonna
get in here, or what?
Uh, you know what?
You can have it.
I mean, you have seniority.
Yes.
So I don't have to go
in there if I don't want.
Thought you wanted it.
This is an abuse of power.
This is a delegation
of resources.
You're a very valuable resource.
Oh, don't you flatter me now.
I have faith in you.
Where Mer's concerned,
just, you know, give
as good as you get.
I gave you bacon!
You're taking Kyle in
for a ventricular washout?
Hello, resident who is
not on my service today.
There is an 85% mortality rate.
If his abscess ruptures
while he's on the table,
he dies immediately.
Edwards, you are
really underfoot.
Look, he just deserves
all the time he can get,
not some Hail Mary.
I mean, can you answer
me, please, Dr. Shepherd?
Do you have this?
Okay, no, I am
not answering that.
Not simply because
the patient and the family
have expressly asked you
not be involved in this case,
which would be enough,
but more because I
do not answer to you.
This is my surgical plan.
I am confident in
my surgical plan.
End of discussion.
Wilson, what?
I just wanted to let you know
the OR will be ready in 45 minutes.
Thank you.
For an average surgeon,
sure, a ventricular washout
could be a Hail Mary,
but, Edwards, this is me.
Either come in or stay out, but
don't do whatever it is you're doing.
Okay.
I was thinking, uh...
Maybe I can postpone leaving,
for just a little while,
just until things are better,
until you and I
are... Are better.
What's the point?
What? Two days? A week?
We both know how this ends.
No, I don't.
But apparently you do, so
why don't you enlighten me?
All right, look, we'll
drag this out. Sure.
You can wait here and things
will get superficially better,
and then you'll leave,
and then we'll let things taper
off the way things taper off
over long distance,
and then we'll be sorry,
and we'll make
promises that are just lies.
It's all a lie, because I'm
not leaving without Sofia,
and you would never forgive
me if you gave up your grant,
so I'm stuck here, Penny.
I am stuck, and
there's no good solution.
Callie, why won't
you look at me?
Are you breaking up with me?
Is that it?
Maybe instead of
dragging this out...
Maybe we should
just call it now.
Yeah, we should. You should go.
I told you to go.
And I'm really bad
at following directions.
I hurt you.
You sure did.
And I'm so sorry about that.
Boy, my sister really hates you.
Yeah.
Clearly, you told
her all about me.
Well, to be fair, I told
her all the good stuff first.
I've missed you.
Yeah?
Well, relax.
Like, I mean, not
like sad or, like,
you know, love-sick miss you.
I manly miss you.
Like, I'm very tough.
Look, I talked to Dr. Shepherd
about your surgery.
And she's got this.
You're gonna make it
through this. I know it.
That's great, because
I look way hotter
when I'm not in a hospital gown.
Yeah, I remember.
So, what's our plan?
With you and I
after all this is over?
What?
Yeah, when I'm well and
I'm done with this place,
we should go away together.
I can't go somewhere.
Come on. Have fun.
Live a little. Okay. Like where?
I have a bunch of
gigs lined up in Europe.
Mmm-hmm.
Come on tour with
me for, like, a month.
I'm a surgeon, not a groupie.
Come on. You know
you want to see me play.
I do, actually.
But, you know,
I'd probably just embarrass you,
acting a fool, you know,
screaming your
name in the front row.
I'm excited to see that.
No, you think you are.
You have not seen
me act like a fool.
I'd throw my bra on the stage.
Please do that. Shut up.
Listen...
I, um...
I am in this
kind of deep with you,
so just
don't say these things if
you don't mean them, okay?
Okay.
I have to take him to surgery.
Oh, yeah. Okay, it's
invaded the pleural space.
Chest wall's involved.
We'll debride the top layer off.
Go deeper.
Get the pericardium
if you have to.
I don't want to peel
this kid down to nothing.
And I don't want this
kid to have to go through
all this and still be infected.
Go deeper! JACKSON:
Grey, come on.
Sorry. I've had enough
of bad decisions today.
Yeah, well, what did I do?
Relax, mate. It's probably me.
No, she's just pissed that Shepherd
and Hunt are getting married.
Really? JACKSON:
Oh, that's nice, actually.
They're not. They
had a conversation.
All right, so she's pissed about
them getting married someday.
Why's that?
There's a kid on the table
whose flesh is being eaten
alive right in front of us.
Can we please just focus?
Well, someone hand
me a half a cup of Drano,
I'll get it done in a jiffy.
You think that's
funny? Little bit.
I'm trying to say
we're well aware
of who's on the table
and what the stakes are.
We're all working
as fast as we can.
We're all on the
same page, Grey.
You're not more interested
in saving a life
than the rest of us.
Mayo.
Antibiotic irrigation.
What'd you have?
Young kid with
advanced nec fasc.
I just hope I got it all.
I hear you.
I've got a ventricular washout
on a massive brain abscess.
Sounds last-ditch. Sorry.
Well, not necessarily. I
feel pretty good about it.
Okay.
I do.
Well, you feel really good
about a lot of things, so...
What does that mean? Nothing.
Just... Just forget about it.
Is it a problem for
you, Owen and me?
Is that... Is that what
you're talking about?
Let's not. You have surgery.
I can handle it. Can you?
Because it seems
like... Like what?
Like you don't even see it.
You think you're
making all these choices
and building this life when
none of this is actually yours.
That doesn't even make sense.
It does make sense.
You are living in my house,
helping to take care of
my children with my sister.
You are marrying
my best friend's ex.
You are trying to
do my husband's job.
You know, you used to have
humility, even a little anxiety.
And now you even
have his confidence.
But why not?
Because you've taken
over everything else.
What are you saying?
Get your own life.
You have surgery.
Noah, you really
don't have to stay here.
Listen, this may all
be nothing to you,
but it doesn't mean
that I don't care,
okay, about you and the kid.
I didn't say it was nothing.
Oh, right, sorry. Sex.
You were using
me for my stick shift.
Noah, for God's sake,
that is not what I said.
Excuse me. Hi.
We have an update.
Okay. The surgery went well.
We believe we were able to
resect all of the infected tissue.
Rhys was very lucky.
If you hadn't brought
him in when you did,
we probably wouldn't
have been so successful.
Oh, wow. Okay.
Okay. It's okay.
Thank you.
He's gonna be okay.
He's here because of you.
He would've died, and he didn't
because of you. Right?
Yeah, kind of. Um, yeah.
You are a hero.
I mean, I just did what
needed to be done.
No.
Wow.
Okay.
Well, good luck.
See? Happy endings, they happen.
Oh, please. Everyone's
in love in a foxhole.
What?
He saved her kid.
That's like post-traumatic
stress romance.
You know what? Give it a rest.
Just because you
choose to be unhappy
doesn't mean
everybody else has to.
Not true. Not always a choice.
You have chances, you know?
You're hot, you're
smart, you're funny.
Maybe Thorpe didn't work out,
but that doesn't mean
you have to stop trying.
And it sure as hell doesn't mean
you get to crap
on everyone else.
And, yeah, I'm gonna
have a big wedding,
and you're gonna be there
'cause you're gonna
be my best man!
Deal with it!
Doctor.
Hi.
Um...
Is there any way that I
could also have Sofia tonight?
I know we already
moved things around,
and thank you again
so much, by the way.
It's just I really need to...
Could I have her
tonight, please?
It's just... It's
been a tough day.
You're right.
We already did
move things around.
Or rather, I already moved
things around for you.
I know, and I thought that's why
you would be
okay with letting...
With bending the rules
for your convenience?
The rules that only exist
because you put us and all
of our friends through hell?
No. I'm sorry. I just...
You know, you chose this.
You ruined everything.
And yet you still expect me
to leap to fulfill your needs.
I did that. I did
that this morning.
Okay, Arizona, I
get it. You're angry.
I wasn't angry.
I was gracious.
I was nice and I
was accommodating
and I tried to help you,
and yet here you are
again, asking for even more.
I...
I do not have any
more to give you.
You have used
up all of my grace.
Blake, what's wrong?
Oh, Dr. Grey, I, um...
I am gathering my things.
I'm leaving for the fellowship.
Already? Mmm-hmm.
My time line accelerated a bit.
Callie and I broke up.
I came here for her.
I stayed for her.
I...
Thought we were
gonna be together.
Doesn't really
matter what I thought.
We're over.
We don't work anymore.
Sorry. I had no idea.
It's okay.
You'll be okay, Blake.
You will be okay.
You will pick yourself up,
and you will go kick
some fellowship ass.
Right?
Thank you.
For teaching me,
for... For everything.
It's my job.
50 cc syringe.
Another one?
There's more in there. Keep
irrigating until it clears out.
No, no, no, no, no, no.
What?
There's too much fluid
coming out, and it's cloudy.
So the abscess is...
It's ruptured into
his ventricles.
Okay, then we just
need to move faster.
More irrigation!
Keep the syringes coming fast!
Damn it. It is getting harder
to withdraw anything at all now.
His BP's starting to rise.
Come on, Kyle. Come on.
Stop. I need you
to stop irrigating
and run up to the
gallery right now.
What? Why?
I don't want her watching this.
I'm gonna try moving
the catheter around.
He's getting bradycardic.
Come on. Come on.
Sorry.
Steph, you shouldn't
be watching this.
Oh, no.
Time of death, 15:23.
No! No! No!
No. No.
Edwards.
Stephanie, stop.
We tried everything we could.
His brain had already
infarcted from herniation.
It was too far gone.
I'm so sorry.
And she's standing
there with these sad eyes
like she's the victim.
She's not the victim.
Callie caused all this,
she set it all in motion,
and now here we are and
there's not one part of it
that doesn't suck, you know?
Thank you. Yeah, I do.
Good night, Robbins.
Good night.
Jackson, hey.
Uh, I e-mailed you the
video of the 3-D ultrasound.
Did you get it?
You ready?
Ready.
There you are, baby.
I couldn't wait till
next week to see you.
I hope you don't mind.
Thank God. Mmm.
Did you catch the place on fire?
I'm sorry. I was trying
to make us dinner.
Should I order pizza or Thai?
Jo, I'm ready.
I know. I'm sorry.
I'm starving, too.
No, I'm ready to get married.
I have proposed to you twice,
and you still haven't
given me an answer.
I bought you a ring, you
told me not to get rid of it,
so it's just sitting in a
drawer, collecting dust.
I know.
No, I'm ready to be married,
and I need to know
when you will be ready.
It doesn't have to
be today or tomorrow,
but I need to know
it's gonna happen.
I need to know that you're
up for this, 'cause I am.
Look, I'm not scared of
being committed to you.
I want to be married to you.
But I'm done waiting. So I just
need to know, will you marry me?
Oh, God. Okay. Okay.
I...
Alex, I can't.
Of course you can.
Alex... I don't
need a big thing.
I just need you.
I'm so sorry, but...
No.
You know that thing?
That terrible thing you
thought you had laid to rest?
What if you didn't?
Well?
It's great.
Owen, it's really great.
Wait till you see inside.
What's wrong? What's wrong?
My patient died today.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I thought I knew what I
was doing, but he still died.
I thought I knew
what I was doing.
You and I... We're good, right?
I mean, this is real between us.
We know what we're doing.
I think we do.
Why aren't we doing it?
Why aren't we building our life?
I don't want to waste our time
on conversations or some
hypothetical lives someday.
I...
I want a real life...
And I want it with you.
Are you asking me to marry you?
Yes.
We're not talking
about the fake married.
We're talking about
the real married.
Real, Owen.
Completely real.
Will you marry me?
You know that thing you
think you finally figured out?
What if you haven't?
I didn't mean to startle you.
Hell of a save today.
Thank you.
Night. Night.
Hope you feel better.
I feel fine. Yeah, right.
What did you say?
Nothing. Forget it.
You turned that OR
into a minefield today.
Everybody felt it. And?
I mean, I see why you're pissed.
I would be, too, I bet.
She's your sister, right?
Who? Your dead husband.
Don't talk about him.
Amelia Shepherd's his sister,
you had this great thing with him,
now he's gone and she's here,
and she gets to get
all the good stuff, right?
With Hunt, of all people.
Everyone else is
so happy about it,
and all it does is make you
want to punch her in the face.
Am I close?
I can see why Owen hates you.
Hey, I'm trying to be nice
here, empathize a little.
We both lost people.
That doesn't mean we
belong to some club.
Now, that's just mean.
So? So don't be like that.
I should be like you?
Laid-back and cool?
Can anyone ever
get a rise out of you?
People have, yeah.
Like who? Owen?
All right, don't bring him up.
You brought up my dead husband.
Yeah, to be nice.
Well, don't be nice.
Well, don't be mean.
I'll do whatever I want!
Yeah? Well, so will I! Me, too.
Well, what do you want?
When do you know you've
put something to bed?
When is it finally
safe to move on?
Maybe you never know.
Maybe you just
have to test the water.
You have to see how it feels.
Okay, this could
make things a little...
Just shut up.
And if it feels good,
I mean, really good,
then, hell, I say go for it.