DYING CHANGES EVERYTHING.
THERE'S THE EMOTIONAL FALLOUT,
SURE.
BUT THERE'S ALSO
THE PRACTICAL STUFF.
WHO'S GOING TO DO
YOUR JOB?
WHO'S GOING TO TAKE CARE
OF YOUR FAMILY?
THE ONLY GOOD THING
FOR YOU IS,
YOU DON'T
HAVE TO WORRY ABOUT IT.
PEOPLE YOU NEVER KNEW
WILL BE LIVING IN YOUR HOUSE,
WORKING YOUR JOB.
THE WORLD
JUST KEEPS ON GOING...
WITHOUT YOU.
STEPH, I NEED A FAVOR.
I'LL DO YOUR SCUT
FOR A WEEK--
TWO WEEKS--
AND BEFORE YOU SAY NO,
I JUST WANT TO SAY THAT
YOU LOOK REALLY PRETTY TODAY.
AND YOU'RE THE MOST TALENTED
INTERN IN OUR CLASS,
AND I'M IN NO WAY TRYING
TO BUTTER YOU UP
SO YOU DNO.T SAY NO.
YOU DON'T EVEN KNOW
WHAT I'M ASKING YOU YET.
YES, I DO. I'M NOT GOING
ANYWHERE NEAR MEDUSA FOR YOU.
I WANT TO LIVE
SO I WILL SAY IT AGAIN--NO.
NOTHING TO BE SCARED OF.
SHE'S JUST AN ATTENDING.
WE ONLY CALL HER MEDUSA
BECAUSE--
BECAUSE SHE'S A MONSTER
OF MYTHIC PROPORTIONS.
WHAT'S THE PROBLEM?
I HAVE THESE LABS
FOR DR. GREY.
WELL, THEN GIVE THEM
TO HER.
I'VE BEEN WAITING FOR THOSE
FOR OVER AN HOUR.
I HAD TO DO AN ADMISSION--
STOP MAKING EXCUSES.
SORRY.
STOP APOLOGIZING.
OKAY.
STOP TALKING.
HIS LACTIC ACID IS NORMAL.
WHAT DOES THAT TELL US?
YOU CAN TALK NOW.
THAT HE'S PROBABLY
NOT SEPTIC,
SO HE'S GONNA BE FINE.
ALTHOUGH HIS WHITE CELL COUNT
IS ELEVATED
SO I SHOULD PROBABLY
KEEP AN EYE ON THAT.
IN FACT, I WILL KEEP
AN EYE ON THAT
GO TO THE PIT
AND TRY NOT TO KILL ANYBODY.
IMPRESSIVE.
I WOULD'VE EXPECTED THAT LEVEL
OF INTIMIDATION FROM YANG MAYBE.
NOT YOU.
HOW IS YANG, BY THE WAY?
DOES SHE LIKE MINNESOTA?
SHE LOVES IT.
DR. PARKER.
AND THAT WAS BEFORE
I REALIZED...
DR. PARKER.
THAT THERE WAS
A TUMOR
I MEAN, WE HAD SPENT, UH,
THREE HOURS
TRYING TO DEAL
WITH THE VALVE--
OH, DR. YANG.
YOU'VE GOTTA HEAR ABOUT
THIS CASE DR. THOMAS HAD--
MUST BE WHAT,
TEN YEARS AGO?
YEAH.
UM, I LOOKED AT
THE OBERMAN BABY'S SCANS.
UH, I KNOW WE DISCUSSED
DOING A THORACOTOMY,
BUT I THINK A V.A.T.S.
MAKES MORE SENSE.
FANTASTIC.
BUT LET DR. THOMAS TELL YOU
ABOUT THIS STORY FIRST.
YOU'RE NOT GONNA BELIEVE
YOUR EARS.
HOW ABOUT I SCRUB IN
WITH YOU
AND THEN I CAN TELL YOU
THE WHOLE STORY?
WHEN'S YOUR SURGERY?
11:00.
OH, THAT WON'T WORK.
00.
OH.
WHY DON'T YOU MOVE
YOUR SURGERY BACK
AND THEN I CAN JOIN YOU?
UH, THAT'S REALLY
NOT NECESSARY.
AND THEN YOU WILL BE ABLE
00.
IT'S A PORT-CABG.
HAVE YOU EVER SEEN ONE?
I'VE DONE ONE.
THREE IN FACT.
WELL, THEN YOU'LL APPRECIATE
MY APPROACH.
IT'S EVEN BETTER.
WELL, WAIT A MINUTE.
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
MY AMBULANCE ISN'T HERE YET.
I CAN START THE STORY NOW.
THE PATIENT WAS 66.
ALTHOUGH I SUPPOSE
I SHOULD START
WHEN I FIRST MET THE MAN.
JUST WANTED TO LET YOU KNOW,
WE'RE ALL SET FOR TONIGHT.
UNLESS YOU HAD SOME QUESTIONS
OR CONCERNS.
I DON'T.
OKAY. UM...
5:00.
OKAY.
HOW OFTEN SHOULD HER
CALCIUM LEVELS BE MONITORED?
EVERY 12 HOURS.
AND WHAT'S THE PRIMARY CAUSE
OF HYPOCALCEMIA
AFTER PARATHYROID SURGERY?
UM...
REALLY?
ARE YOU TELLING ME
NOT ONE OF YOU KNOWS THAT--
HUNGRY BONE SYNDROME...
WHERE CALCIUM AND PHOSPHORUS
ARE RAPIDLY DEPOSITED
INTO THE BONE.
YOU'RE NOT SUPPOSED
TO BE HERE.
GOT A LAST-MINUTE FLIGHT.
COULDN'T PASS IT UP.
NOT ANYMORE.N CALL TONIGHT?
I SWITCHED SHIFTS.
WHAT'S YOUR TURNAROUND
THIS TIME?
12 HOURS. AND I PLAN TO MAKE USE
OF EVERY SINGLE ONE.
OCCUPIED.
MM. I DON'T WANT YOU
TO GO.
LISTEN... I WISH I COULD
PUT OFF HOPKINS
SO YOU AND I COULD SPEND
MORE TIME TOGETHER,
BUT I'VE ALREADY
POSTPONED THEM ONCE.
MM. I KNOW, BUT IT DOESN'T MEAN
I HAVE TO LIKE IT.
I REALLY HATE GOOD-BYES.
WELL, YOU'LL LIKE THIS ONE.
OKAY, WHAT DID I SAY
ABOUT THE STARING?
I'M FINE, AND EVEN IF
I WEREN'T,
STARING AT ME
WOULDN'T MAKE ME MORE FINE.
I'M SORRY, DR. TORRES.
REALLY, AVERY? YOU TOO?
NO, NOT STARING.
UH, DEFINITELY NOT.
EXCUSE ME.
OKAY, WHAT DO WE GOT?
HEY, YOU TELL ME.
LOOKS LIKE A TRANSVERSE
PROCESS FRACTURE
AT L-3, L-4,
BUT SEE THIS SWELLING?
I CAN'T TELL IF IT'S
UNSTABLE OR NOT.
IT'S UNSTABLE
OKAY.FOR SURE.
BOOK AN O.R.
WE NEED TO GET IN THERE
AND RELIEVE THE PRESSURE
AS SOON AS POSSIBLE.
WAIT. "WE"?
AS IN YOU AND ME?
IT'S NO BIG DEAL.
ACTUALLY, IT IS.
IT'S--IT'S--
IT'S A VERY BIG DEAL.
I'VE BEEN CLEARED FOR SURGERY
FOR WEEKS.
YEAH, I KNOW,
'CAUSE I CLEARED YOU,
BUT YOU SAID
YOU WEREN'T READY S--
WELL, NOW I'M SAYING I AM.
WOW. OKAY.
AGAIN, IT'S NO BIG DEAL.
IT IS A BIG DEAL.
I WILL BE DONE
00.
THAT'S NOT THE POINT.
WHY ARE YOU PUTTING
THIS PRESSURE ON YOURSELF?
I'VE BEEN PRACTICING
FOR WEEKS. I FEEL GOOD.
I JUST CAN'T SIT AROUND
LOOKING AT THE CLOCK.
YOU REALLY NEED
TO DO THIS TODAY?
YEAH, I DO...
ESPECIALLY TODAY.
OKAY.
I MEAN,
HE SAYS HE'S READY.
AND HIS NERVE GRAFT
SEEMS TO BE READY.
SO I GUESS TODAY'S THE DAY
HE'S GONNA OPERATE...
WITH HIS BRAND-NEW HAND.
AND IT IS GONNA WORK.
IT'S DEFINITELY GONNA WORK.
YOU THINK IT'S GONNA WORK,
RIGHT?
I THOUGHT I MIGHT FIND YOU
IN HERE.
I KEEP THINKING
IF I SAY SOMETHING BIG ENOUGH
OR...
SHOCKING ENOUGH,
HE'LL JUST--
HE'LL OPEN HIS EYES.
MM-HMM.
00.
HIS DIRECTIVE
WAS VERY SPECIFIC.
IF, AFTER 30 DAYS, THERE ARE
NO SIGNS OF RECOVERY,
MARK WANTED TO BE LET GO.
THAT'S ALL WE'RE DOING...
HONORING HIS WISH.
I KNOW. I JUST...
OH, GOD.
IT'S SO HOT IN HERE.
I THINK I'M GONNA
TAKE OFF MY SHIRT.
OH, YEAH. THAT'S BETTER.
OH, YEAH, IT'S SO MUCH COOLER
WITH MY BOOBS OUT.
WELL, IF THAT
DIDN'T WAKE HIM,
I DON'T KNOW WHAT WILL.
YEAH.
YOU ALWAYS HAD TO BE
THE FIRST.
YOU ARE A TERRIBLE BEST MAN.
ADDISON'S GREAT,
BUT ONE WOMAN
FOR THE REST OF YOUR LIFE?
IT'S NOT WHAT GOD INTENDED.
ESPECIALLY FOR MEN
WHO LOOK LIKE US.
GOD INTENDED FOR US
MANY, MANY WOMEN,
A STAGGERING NUMBER
OF WOMEN.
I JUST HOPE YOU DIDN'T
FORGET THE RINGS.
DEREK...
YOU'RE LUCKY TO HAVE ME.
YOU WILL NEVER, EVER
FIND ANOTHER FRIEND
AS GOOD AS ME, EVER.
E YOU FILMING THIS?
OKAY, WE'RE NOT DOING THIS,
OKAY?
I'M NOT GONNA BE
IN ONE OF YOUR VIDEOS...
SO YOU CAN PUT IT ON
YOUR CREEPY BOOKCASE
WITH ALL YOUR OTHER
CREEPY VIDEOS.
THERE'S NO BOOKCASE.
AND I'VE NEVER
DONE THIS EITHER,
BUT TRUST ME,
WHAT'S ABOUT TO HAPPEN,
YOU'RE GONNA WANT TO RELIVE
OVER AND OVER.
MM. ONE SECOND.
UH, THE INTERN APPY--
YOU GOT YOUR GUY?
I
AND YOU REALLY WANT
TO DO THIS TODAY?
ESPECIALLY TODAY.
OKAY.
UH, GREY. HEY.
UM, I NEED YOU TO TAKE
00 LAP CHOLE.
OH, I CAN'T.
I HAVE THE INTERN APPY.
OH.
GREY, LIVING UP
TO YOUR NICKNAME.
NICKNAME?
I HAVE A NICKNAME?
UH, THEY CALL YOU MEDUSA...
THE SERPENT-HAIRED MONSTER
WHO TURNS FOLKS TO STONE.
HEY, THIS IS NOT A BAD THING.
YOU WANT TO BE THE ATTENDING
WITH THE SCARY NICKNAME.
IT KEEPS YOUR RESIDENTS
IN LINE.
IT STRIKES FEAR
IN THEIR HEART.
TAKE IT FROM THE NAZI,
IT'S GOOD TO BE FEARED.
YOU RETIRED THE NAZI.
THEY CALL YOU
SOMETHING ELSE NOW.
THEY DO?
THEY DO.
WH--
MM-HMM.
EXCUSE ME, DR. PARKER,
QUICK QUESTION.
OKAY, HANDS UP, EVERYBODY.
ONE, TWO, THREE.
WHAT CAN WE DO FOR YOU,
DR. YANG?
OH, I-I DIDN'T MEAN FOR YOU
TO STOP YOUR PROCEDURE.
YOU CAN JUST KEEP GOING
WHILE I TALK.
WE CAN'T, ACTUALLY.
WE FIND THAT MULTITASKING
LEADS TO ERRORS IN HEARING
AND ERRORS IN HEALING.
OKAY. UH, WELL, UM,
DR. THOMAS INVITED HIMSELF
ONTO MY V.A.T.S.
THIS AFTERNOON--
MM-HMM.RMAN BABY.
I WAS WONDERING IF I COULD DO
THE PROCEDURE ON MY OWN,
WITHOUT HIM.
HOW COME?
UH, WELL... DR. THOMAS
IS A BIG TALKER AND--
OH, MY GOSH.
THAT IS THE TRUTH.
DR. THOMAS CAN CHEW YOUR EAR
RIGHT OFF.
I-I TELL YOU, ONCE HE CORNERED
ME WITH A STORY,
I WAS ON MY WAY
TO THE GENTLEMEN'S ROOM.
I HATE TO INVOKE POTTY HUMOR,
BUT I WASN'T SURE
I WAS GONNA MAKE IT.
THAT'S HOWSTORY WAS.
EXACTLY. SO--
MY ADVICE TO YOU IS,
VISIT THE LADIES ROOM
BEFORE YOU ENTER
YES.Y.
I WILL, BUT ANOTHER SOLUTION
WOULD BE
IF HE JUST DIDN'T SCRUB IN.
YOU'VE GOT A TOUGH ROW
TO HOE THERE, DR. YANG.
NO DOUBT ABOUT IT.
THANKFULLY,
YOU'RE A TOUGH COOKIE.
YOU'RE UP TO THE TASK.
WE SALUTE YOU.
GUESS WHAT.
I HAVE A NICKNAME.
MEDUSA.
I'M MEDUSA GREY.
I HAD TO PUSH
MY FLIGHT TONIGHT.
OH.
IT'S NOT WHAT YOU'RE THINKING.
IT'S NOT LIKE LAST TIME
or the time before that.
My surgery got pushed.
That's it.
I'm on standby
for a later flight.
IT'S OKAY IF YOU'RE
NOT READY TO FLY.
I SAID I'D COME.
I'LL BE THERE.
Well, you won't make it
by 5:00 anyway,
so why push yourself?
I WILL BE THERE, MEDUSA.
OH, SO YOU DID HEAR ME?
I like it.
Snakes in the hair--hot!
Okay, bye.
CRISTINA'S COMING TONIGHT?
00,
BUT SHE SAYS
SHE'S GONNA BE HERE.
HUH.
SHE'S NOT GONNA GET
ON THAT PLANE, IS SHE?
WE'RE WORKING ON IT.
PROBABLY NOT.
YOU REALLY DOING
THE INTERN APPY?
JEALOUS?
HE'S TOO BUSY
JUST DOING THE INTERNS.
ARE YOU GONNA SAY GOOD-BYE TO
YOUR FAN CLUB BEFORE YOU LEAVE?
I'VE BEEN SAYING GOOD-BYE
ALL DAY.
GROSS.
THEY'RE GONNA BE SAD
TO SEE ME GO.
YOU MAY HAVE TO STEP UP,
AVERY. COMFORT THEM A LITTLE.
NO SLOPPY SECONDS FOR ME,
THANK YOU.
YOU'RE A SURGICAL FELLOW.
MIGHT AS WELL
ENJOY THE PERKS.
BESIDES,
YOU NEED TO GET LAID.
YOU HAVEN'T BANGED ANYBODY
SINCE LEXIE.
SORRY, MER.
I-I HAVE...
BANGED PEOPLE.
I'M SCREWED.
AS LONG AS MEDUSA'S
MY ATTENDING,
I WILL NEVER GET TO SEE
THE INSIDE OF AN O.R.
UNLESS YOU'RE THE PATIENT.
OH.
DON'T BE ALARMED,
BUT MEDUSA'S WALKING OVER HERE.
DEPENDING ON HER MOOD,
I MAY HAVE TO PRETEND
I DON'T KNOW YOU.
GOOD AFTERNOON, EVERYONE.
AS YOU ALL PROBABLY ALREADY
KNOW, WE HAVE A TRADITION HERE.
THE HONOR OF PERFORMING
YOUR FIRST SURGERY
IS RESERVED FOR THE INTERN
WHO SHOWS THE MOST PROMISE.
DR. WILSON.
CONGRATULATIONS,
YOU'RE SCRUBBING IN.
YOU GOT SODA
COMING OUT YOUR NOSE.
HE HAS AN UNSTABLE FRACTURE.
I NEED TO DO A FUSE IN HERE
AND HE--
ANY NUMBNESS
OR TINGLING AROUND
THE MEDIAN NERVE?
NOT--
I'M GOOD TO GO, TORRES.
YOU DID A GREAT JOB.
AND YOU'LL NEED
YOUR I.D. CARD
TO ACCESS THE SCAN ROOMS.
HEY.
UH, THIS IS MEL BARNETT.
HE'LL BE JOINING US
FROM MIAMI.
PEDS SURGERY.
I'M THE NEW ATTENDING.
AND YOU ARE?
I'M DEREK SHEPHERD,
UH, NEURO.
NICE MEETING YOU.
CALLIE TORRES, ORTHO.
OH, RIGHT.
UH, I AM SO SORRY,
UH, ABOUT YOUR WIFE.
I MEAN, I HEARD, AND, UH--
THANK YOU.
OKAY, UH...
HOW ABOUT I SHOW YOU
THE NICU?
YEAH.
LET'S NOT MAKE
A BIG DEAL.
LISTEN...
I WISH I COULD PUT THEM OFF
SO YOU AND I COULD
SPEND MORE TIME TOGETHER,
BUT I ALREADY
POSTPONED HOPKINS ONCE.
OH, MY GOD.
JUST GO--GET OUTI'M SORRY.
CALLIE?
I SAID GET OUT.
ARE YOU OKAY?
GET OUT, OKAY?
GET OUT.
YOU'RE GONNA THANK ME
FOR THIS, AVERY,
WHEN YOU'VE REWATCHED IT
FOR THE 500th TIME
TRYING TO FIGURE OUT
HOW TO LINE UP
YOUR VERTICAL MATTRESS SUTURES
AS PERFECTLY AS I CAN.
NOW PAN UP TO MY FACE.
YOU SEE THAT?
NOT A DROP OF SWEAT.
YOU KNOW WHY?
'CAUSE I'M THAT GOOD.
NOW GO GET SCRUBBED.
YOU'RE GONNA FINISH UP HERE.
WAIT. REALLY?
HURRY.
BEFORE I CHANGE MY MIND.
AND I FINISHED
THE RECONSTRUCTION
WE TALKED ABOUT ON
THE YOUNG MASTECTOMY PATIENT,
UH, AND THE RESULT
IS FULL SLOAN.
I MEAN, SHE IS GONNA LOOK
A SCALE HOTTER
THAN GOD INTENDED.
UH, AND GRANDPA'S LABS
CAME BACK.
STABLE. UM, SCARRING IS GONNA
BE A PROBLEM, OBVIOUSLY.
BUT THE RESULT
IS PRETTY GOOD CONSIDERING.
AND YOU THINK
WE CAN DO BETTER.
I DON'T KNOW. RECONSTRUCTION?
THAT'S PRETTY RADICAL
FOR A GUY HIS AGE.
NO, YOU'RE RIGHT.
WE CAN DO BETTER.
HEY, I WISH YOU COULD
SEE THE SURGERY I'M WATCHING.
IT IS A TRAIN WRECK.
So you're not gonna make it
by 5:00.
Do you want
TO FaceTime OR SKYPE
OR SOMETHING?
IT'S KIND OF WEIRD THAT
YOU'RE NOT GONNA BE HERE.
OH, LOOK AT THAT.
HE TURNED A PORT-CABG
Why? A STERNOTOMY.
WHY? BECAUSE THIS SURGEON
IS 103.
BECAUSE EVERYONE IN THIS
FROZEN TUNDRA
IS TOO DAMN POLITE TO SAY,
"HEY, RETIRE, OLD MAN,
BEFORE YOU KILL SOMEONE
WITH YOUR BRITTLE, BONY HANDS."
I'M SORRY. WOULD YOU MIND
TAKING THAT OUTSIDE?
I'M TRYING TO TAKE NOTES.
YEAH, WELL, THERE'S NOTHING
TO LEARN HERE.
HE'S JUST POKING HOLES
in a guy's pericardium.
HE'LL NEVER COME OFF BYPASS.
I just wish
YOU WERE GONNA BE HERE.
Owen e-mailed me today,
WANTED TO MAKE SURE
I HAD PEOPLE AROUND ME TONIGHT.
I don't know why everyone
is so worked up about 5:00.
I mean, Mark is
still gonna be gorked
no matter when my plane lands.
OH, FOR PISS SAKE.
HE'S DOING ANOTHER GRAFT.
TALK ABOUT LIPSTICK ON A PIG.
HEY, WHOEVER THAT IS BETTER HAVE
SOMETHING IMPORTANT FOR ME...
'CAUSE I'M A BUSY WOMAN.
I'M SORRY, DR. BAILEY.
IT'S YOUR INTERN--
SHANE ROSS.
YOU LEFT ME
WITH MRS. COGGINS,
AND HER C.T. SCANS
JUST CAME BACK--
SLIDE IT UNDER THE DOOR.
OH, SHOOT.
HE DID. HOLD ON. HOLD ON.
UH...
YEAH, UH, YEAH, SHE HAS
A SMALL... HEMATOMA.
UM, JUST MONITOR IT CLOSELY.
ONLY YOU
CAN MAKE A SMALL HEMATOMA
SOUND SEXY.
CRAZY. AHH.
I DIDN'T HEAR ANYTHING.
B.C.B.'s
AT IT AGAIN.
WAIT. HOLD ON.
HOLD ON.
BE RIGHT BACK.
OH.
ALEX KAREV. RIGHT.
UH, HUNT MENTIONED THAT
ROBBINS REALLY LIKED YOU.
MEL BARNETT.
HERE FROM MIAMI.
OH, THE NEW PEDS GUY.
YOU'RE HEADED TO?
UH, HOPKINS, FELLOWSHIP.
LEAVING TONIGHT.
THAT'S RIGHT.
SO IS THIS, BY THE WAY.
HUNT'S BEEN FILLING ME IN.
OH, DID HE, UH, TELL YOU ABOUT
OUR EXCHANGE PROGRAM YET?
WE BROUGHT OVER 32 KIDS
FROM 5 DIFFERENT COUNTRIES
IN AFRICA.
HUNT DID MENTION THE PROGRAM,
DR. KAREV.
ADMIRABLE WORK,
BUT I'M AFRAID
IT DOESN'T
FIT WITH MY AGENDA.
WE OPERATE ON SICK ORPHANS.
HOW DOES THAT NOT FIT
YOUR AGENDA?
NOT TO WORRY. I'VE ALREADY
REACHED OUT TO U.C.L.A.
THE PROGRAM WILL CONTINUE,
JUST...
NOT HERE.
IF YOU'LL EXCUSE ME, I'M TRYING
TO CLOSE ON A HOUSE.
WELCOME BACK.
TORRES.
I HAD NOTHING TO DO
WITH THIS.
OKAY. I HAD A LITTLE
TO DO WITH THIS.
WELL, THANK YOU, EVERYONE.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
IT'S REALLY NO BIG DEAL.
WHAT?
YOU HAVE TO SAY IT.
IT'S A BEAUTIFUL DAY
TO SAVE LIVES.
THERE'S NO WAY
SHE PULLS THIS OFF.
SHE MIGHT, AS LONG AS SHE
DOESN'T LOOK UP AT MEDUSA
DURING THE SURGERY.
YEAH, THAT FACE
WILL CALCIFY HER.
DO YOU THINK
MEDUSA'S ALWAYS BEEN MEDUSA?
Probably. I heard
her mom was even worse.
Yeah, but...
that doesn't give her an excuse
to act like a demon
from the depths of hell
itself.
IT'S LIKE SHE CAN HEAR US.
YEAH,
THAT LITTLE RED LIGHT...
MEANS THE INTERCOM
IS ON.
OHH. OH.
Now sit up straight.
I DON'T THINK
THAT YOU'RE A DEMON.
FOCUS ON WHAT YOU'RE DOING.
THERE IT IS.
HUH.
LOOK AT THAT.
GOD, I NEEDED THIS.
IT FEELS SO GOOD
TO FINALLY HAVE MY HANDS
ON A PROBLEM I CAN FIX.
NELSON IS ON STANDBY.
LET'S HAVE HIM COME FINISH.
DEREK, JUST TAKE A SECOND.
JUST--
I'LL MEET YOU IN POST-OP.
I HAD A PATIENT ONCE
WHO TOLD ME ABOUT
HIS WEDDING DAY
AND HOW THEY ASKED
ALL THE MARRIED COUPLES
TO COME TO THE DANCE FLOOR
TO DANCE TOGETHER.
AND THEN THEY ASKED
THE COUPLES
WHO'D BEEN ONLY MARRIED
A YEAR TO SIT DOWN.
AND THEN FIVE YEARS,
THEN TEN YEARS,
20, AND SO ON,
UNTIL THEY GOT TO
THE LAST TWO COUPLES.
UH, TWO SETS
OF GRANDPARENTS.
BEEN TOGETHER 60 YEARS.
60 YEARS
WITH THE LOVE OF THEIR LIFE.
THAT'S GONNA BE YOU TWO
AT OUR
GRANDDAUGHTER'S WEDDING.
CALLIE...
ARIZONA...
CONGRATULATIONS.
I LOVE YOU.
WHAT ABOUT YOU?
WON'T YOU BE DANCING
AT YOUR GRANDDAUGHTER'S WEDDING?
GOTTA HAVE A PARTNER
FOR THAT.
WELL, IF YOU HAD A PARTNER,
WHO WOULD IT BE?
OH, WELL, THAT'S EASY.
LEXIE GREY.
DR. TORRES.
UH, NOT A GOOD TIME.
HEY, LOOK, THE NEW GUY,
UH, BARNETT,
HE'S SHIPPING
THE--THE ORPHAN PROGRAM
OVER TO U.C.L.A.
YEAH, REALLY NOT
A GOOD TIME.
I'M LEAVING,
SO I'M NOT GONNA BE ABLE
TO DO ANYTHING ABOUT IT,
AND I KNOW--I KNOW DR. ROBBINS
WOULDN'TOH, ALEX.S HAPPEN.
NO, WHAT? WHAT?
MAYBE WHAT? JUST WHAT?ALK--
I'M UP TO MY EYEBALLS TRYING
TO SAVE THINGS AROUND HERE,
AND YOUR PEDS PROGRAM
REALLY DOESN'T MEAN
THAT MUCH TO ME, OKAY?
SOMETIMES THINGS DIE, ALEX,
AND THERE'S NOTHING YOU CAN DO
ABOUT IT.
TOLD YOU,
NOT A GOOD TIME.
APPENDIX IS OUT.
YEAH!
ALL RIGHT.
WHOO!!
YOU'RE NOT FINISHED.
I KNOW. NEXT I...
PULL UP
ON THE PURSE STRINGS
AND INVERT THE STUMP
INTO THE CECUM.
OH, NO
Okay, you ripped the cecum
wide open.
WHAUM...EXT?
WILSON, YOU HAVE TO THINK,
QUICKLY.
Come on. What's next?
THINK.
Go in and grab
your purse strings.
B.P. IS DROPPING.
YOUR PATIENT IS IN TROUBLE.
GO.
OKAY, MOVE. CLAMP.
IRRIGATION.
Irrigation.
Suction over here.
I KNOW WHY YOU FAVOR
A LESS-INVASIVE APPROACH.
BUT, YOU KNOW, YOU'RE
A CREATURE OF YOUR GENERATION.
I MEAN, YOU BELIEVE IN
30-SECOND RICE
AND INSTANT OATMEAL
AND THE--THE, UH,
NEWS BRIEF.
WELL, NO.
YOU'RE--YOU'RE LOOKING
FOR THE--FOR THE BULLET,
THE MEMO, THE TEXT.
OKAY. UM, BUT--
LOL. OMG. HA!
OKAY, WELL, AS I SAID,
I WILL OPEN HIM UP,
BUT HE'S A BABY,
SO THERE'S ONLY ROOM
FOR ONE HEADLIGHT.
SO YOU UNDERSTAND?
ONE HEADLIGHT, ONE SURGEON.
OF COURSE I UNDERSTAND.
AND YOU OWE ME ONE,
BECAUSE I'M GIVING
THOSE FINGERS A GOOD...
THREE HOURS OFF.
OH, WAIT, WAIT.
OH, THAT'S NOT WHAT I MEANT.
I'M--I'M SORRY. JUST STOP.
THIS IS MY CASE.
YOU WANT ME TO DITCH
MY ORIGINAL PLAN, FINE.
YOU WANT TO BACKSEAT DRIVE,
ALSO FINE.
YOU'RE THE ATTENDING.
I'M THE FELLOW.
I'LL RESPECT THAT.
BUT YOU'RE NOT STEALING
MY SURGERY.
YOU'RE WELCOME TO ASSIST,
TO OBSERVE,
TO YAMMER ABOUT
THE GOOD OLD DAYS,
BUT THIS IS NOT ONE OF THEM.
THIS IS MY PATIENT,
MY PROCEDURE.
HEADLIGHT. NOW.
YES, DOCTOR.
WE--WE SHOULDN'T HAVE
TRIED THE SURGERY TODAY, OKAY?
IT WAS TOO MUCH.
BEING IN THE O.R.,
THINKINTORRES--MARK--
NO, LOOK, I SHOULDN'T HAVE
BEEN OPERATING EITHER.
LOOK AT US. WE'RE EMOTIONAL.
IT WAS JUST--IT WAS BAD--
MY HAND WENT NUMB
IN THERE.
00.
SO I DISCHARGED
OUR CLEFT BABY.
HE'LL BE BACK
IN ABOUT SIX MONTHS.
OH, AND I...
I DECIDED AGAINST
RECONSTRUCTION... FOR GRANDPA.
I KNOW IT'S NOT
WHAT WE TALKED ABOUT, BUT...
AND DON'T TAKE IT
THE WRONG WAY, ALL RIGHT?
BECAUSE...
YOU'VE TAUGHT ME A LOT.
BUT I THINK, UM...
I REALLY KNOW
WHAT I'M DOING NOW.
SO...
I'M GOOD.
THE PLASTICS POSSE'S...
GONNA LIVE ON...
BECAUSE, UH...
BECAUSE I CAN TAKE IT
FROM HERE.
AFTER I STOP HIS MEDICATION,
I'M GONNA EXTUBATE HIM.
OKAY, WE'RE ALL DOCTORS HERE.
YOU DON'T NEED TO SAY THIS.
I'M NOT SAYING IT BECAUSE
YOU NEED TO KNOW THE PROCEDURE.
I SAY IT BECAUSE EVEN IF
YOU THINK YOU'RE PREPARED
FOR WHAT'S ABOUT TO HAPPEN,
YOU'RE NOT.
YOUR BRAIN CAN'T FULLY ABSORB
WHAT WE'RE ABOUT TO DO.
BUT BY SAYING THIS...
I'M GIVING YOU
A LITTLE TIME TO CATCH UP.
SO...
AFTER I STOP
HIS MEDICATIONS...
I'M GONNA EXTUBATE HIM.
AS INDICATED
IN HIS LIVING WILL,
DR. SLOAN ASKED THAT,
IF LIFE-SUSTAINING PROCEDURES
WOULD ONLY PROLONG
THE MOMENT OF DEATH,
THAT THESE PROCEDURES
BE DISCONTINUED.
SOMEWHERE TO BE,
DR. YANG?
NO. IT'S...
00 IN SEATTLE.
00 A.M. IN MOSCOW...
00 A.M. IN SINGAPORE.
MM.
CLAMP.
DR. SLOAN ASKED THAT IF
HE WERE UNABLE TO MAKE
HIS OWN MEDICAL DECISIONS,
THAT HIS DIRECTIVE BE HONORED
BY HIS CHOSEN PROXY.
HIS FINAL REQUEST WAS THAT
ONLY COMFORT CARE
BE GIVEN TO HIM
IN HIS FINAL MOMENTS.
ONCE SUPPORT IS REMOVED,
HE MAY ONLY HOLD ON
FOR A FEW MINUTES...
OR THE PROCESS
COULD TAKE HOURS.
I'M TURNING THE VENTILATOR OFF.
WE'VE SEDATED HIM
WITH MORPHINE
SO HE'S NOT FEELING
ANY OF THIS.
THANKS.
I'LL GIVE YOU SOME PRIVACY.
WE TRIED SO HARD...
OUT THERE IN THE WOODS.
WE THOUGHT IF WE COULD JUST
GET HIM BACK HERE ALIVE...
I-I CAN'T STAY HERE.
I'M--I'M--TELL DEREK THAT
I WAS HERE AND I HAD TO GO.
I AM, UH...
I'M GOING TO THE AIRPORT.
I'M GONNA GO SEE CRISTINA.
OKAY.
WHAT'S WRONG?
CHIEF, SORRY.
I WAS JUST GOING
SOMEWHERE ELSE, ACTUALLY.
THAT SURGERY WAS DESIGNED
FOR YOU TO FAIL.
THE INTERN APPY--
IT SETS YOU AS THE EXAMPLE.
OKAY?
DON'T LET IT GET TO YOU.
WHY IS SHE SO MEAN?
SHE'S JUST TRYING
TO TEACH YOU.
NO, WHY IS SHE SO MEAN?
IS IT THAT PLANE CRASH?
WHAT?
I HEARD SHE WAS
IN A PLANE CRASH
WITH SOME OTHER DOCTORS.
THEY WERE STRANDED IN THE WOODS
FOR, LIKE, A WEEK.
PEOPLE DIED OR ALMOST DIED
OR SOMETHING.
YEAH, YEAH, PEOPLE DIED
OR ALMOST DIED OR...
SOMETHING.
DR. GREY ISN'T MEAN.
SHE IS STRONG.
AND SHE'S NOT GONNA GO EASY
ON YOU BECAUSE SHE KNOWS THAT
THAT WOULD BE A DISSERVICE
TO YOU.
YOU ARE A SURGEON.
IT IS YOUR JOB TO FIX THINGS
OTHER PEOPLE CAN'T.
NOW IF YOU CAN'T HANDLE THAT,
LEAVE NOW.
IF NOT...
DON'T STAND AROUND
IN HALLWAYS AND CRY.
CRY SOMEWHERE ELSE,
WHERE I WON'T SEE YOU.
YEAH, COME ON IN.
DR. CRISTINA YANG
OF SEATTLE FAME,
FORMERLY OF CALIFORNIA.
SIT.
HOW'D IT GO
WITH DR. THOMAS?
UH, WELL, I'M HAPPY
TO, UH,
TAKE ONE FOR THE TEAM,
UH, BUT I'D APPRECIATE
IF YOU STEERED HIM
IN SOMEBODY ELSE'S DIRECTION.
MM.
I'M NOT SURE
THAT'S GONNA WORK.
SEE, I'VE ASKED HIM
TO HELP YOU OUT,
NAVIGATING THE WATERS
AND ALL.
I FOUND THE CAFETERIA.
YEAH, IT'S...
MORE THAN THAT.
MY WORK HAS BEEN IMPECCABLE.
MY RECORD HERE IS PERFECT.
MM-HMM.
IF ALL YOU LOOK AT
IS OUTCOMES, MAYBE.
BUT ON OUR YARDSTICK,
YOU DON'T
SEEM TO BE THRIVING.
I WANT YOU TO SUCCEED.
BUT THE FACT IS,
WE WORK AS A TEAM HERE.
NO ONE HERE
IS A SUPERSTAR.
OUR HOSPITAL
IS THE SUPERSTAR.
AND OUR PATIENTS...
THEY'RE SUPERSTARS.
WE PRIDE OURSELVES
ON THAT.
NO EGO,
NO PROPRIETARY ATTITUDES,
NO COMPETITION.
ARE YOU SERIOUS?
WE'RE SENSITIVE
TO ALL YOU'VE BEEN THROUGH.
IF YOU WANT TO TALK
TO SOMEONE,
I'M HAPPY
TO GIVE YOU NAMES.
DR. PARKER, THAT WON'T--
LOOK, WHY DON'T YOU
TAKE A FEW DAYS...
SEE THE LAKES,
CHECK OUT
THE MALL OF AMERICA?
YOU KNOW, EVERYBODY SAYS
THEY RIDE THE ROLLER COASTER
FOR THEIR KIDS,
BUT THE ADULTS
EAT IT UP.
GO GET SOME R&R.
HAVE A GOOD TIME.
SOFTEN UP THOSE SHARP
SEATTLE EDGES.
DOCTOR'S ORDERS.
I'M SORRY. IS THIS R&R
A SUGGESTION OR--
IT'S MANDATORY, YANG,
STARTING NOW.
ANYTHING?
NO, NOT YET.
HERE YOU GO,
DOCTOR.
THANK YOU.
D-DOES MY NICKNAME
COMMAND RESPECT?
NO.
STRIKE FEAR IN THE HEARTS
OF RESIDENTS?
NO.
WELL, WHAT IS IT?
MM.
YOU'VE BEEN... HAPPY.
AND THE INTERNS NOTICED
THAT YOUR HAPPINESS
OFTEN COINCIDES
WITH THE ARRIVAL OF--
OF DR. WARREN.
AND THAT'S ALL I'M SAYING.
OH, OH, COME ON NOW.
YOU HAVE TO TELL ME.
NO, I CAN'T.
I AM A GENTLEMAN.
AND ALSO, I DON'T WANNA.
WH--WH--UH...
OH, COME...
OKAY, I'M GONNA TELL YOU THIS
BECAUSE I'M LITERALLY
ABOUT TO WALK OUT
OF THIS HOSPITAL FOREVER.
MNH-MNH. KAREV. KAREV.
YOUR NICKNAME'S B.C.B.
B.C.B.?
BOOTYILEY.
THAT'S WHAT THEY CALL YOU.
THANK YOU.
GOOD-BYE, DR. BAILEY.
YEAH. BYE, KAREV.
HEY. SO THAT'S IT?
I'M NOT EVEN AS GOOD AS ONE OF
YOUR INTERN GIRLS, HUH?
YOU'RE NOT GONNA
SAY GOOD-BYE TO ME?
MER, WHAT--WHAT ARE YOU
DOING HERE?
DON'T CHANGE THE SUBJECT.
DON'T MAKE THIS A THING.
DON'T MAKE THIS A THING?
MARK IS DYING RIGHT NOW.
AND THAT'S IT?
YOU'RE JUST GONNA LEAVE, TOO?
I'M JUST--I'M GONNA BE ON
THE OTHER SIDE OF THE COUNTRY.
IT'S, UH, WE'LL TALK.
IT'S NOT LIKE--
THAT'S WHAT CRISTINA SAID.
IT'S NOT THE SAME.
NOTHING IS THE SAME.
EVERYTHING IS DIFFERENT.
EVERYONE'S LEAVING
AND EVERYONE IS DYING.
DON'T MAKE THIS MY PROBLEM.
I'M FINALLY GETTING
THE HELL OUTTA HERE.
I CAN'T KEEP STANDING AROUND
BEING THE GUY
WHO SHOULD'VE BEEN
ON THE PLANE THAT CRASHED.
I SHOULDN'T BE HERE, MER.
I... I SHOULD'VE LEFT
THIS FREAKIN' PLACE
THREE MONTHS AGO.
GET OFF.
LOOK, I'M NOT GONNA STAY
IN SEATTLE
JUST BECAUSE YOU DON'T WANT
TO BE ALONE.
LOOK,
HOPKINS WON'T WAIT FOREVER.
I GOT A PLANE TO CATCH,
SO BYE.
WATCH IT.
THIS IS
YOUR FINAL BOARDING CALL
FOR ALL PASSENGERS
FOR FLIGHT 3-9-8-4.
HOLD ON, PLEASE.
YOU JUST MADE IT.
YEAH.
THANK YOU.
SHH.
SHH, SHH, SHH, SHH.
ON BEHALF OF THE CAPTAIN
AND OUR ENTIRE CREW,
WELCOME BOARD FLIGHT 5-3-1
WITH NONSTOP SERVICE
FROM SEATTLE...
TO ROCHESTER, MINNESOTA.
AT THIS TIME, PLEASE MAKE
SURE YOUR SEAT BACKS
AND TRAY TABLES
ARE IN THEIR UPRIGHT
AND LOCKED POSITIONS.
THIS AIRCRAFT IS EQUIPPED
WITH SEVERAL...
I HAVE TO GO.
IN THE EVENT OF
AN EMERGENCY LANDING...
I HAVE TO GET UP.
I HAVE TO GO.
FIND THE NEAREST EXIT...
IN THE EVENT
OF AN EMERGENCY...
I'M SORRY, MISS. IF YOU COULD
PLEASE STAY IN YOUR SEAT--
YOU NEED TO RETURN
NO,TO YOUR SEAT.AVE.
NO, NO, I DON'T THINK
YOU'RE HEARING ME.
I'M SORRY. WE'RE ABOUT
I NETO CLOSE THE DOORS--ANE.
OPEN THE DOOR, OR I'LL PULL
WE CAN'T--MISS, I NEED YOU--
GET THE HELL OUT OF MY WAY.
OPEN THAT DAMN DOOR...
AND LET ME THE HELL
OFF THIS PLANE!
I NEED YOU TO CALM--
LET ME OFF THE PLANE!
THEY SAY DEATH
IS HARDEST ON THE LIVING.
I HAD THE BOARDING PASS
IN MY HAND.
I WAS...
STANDING THERE
WATCHING THEM BOARD THE PLANE,
BUT I... COULDN'T MOVE.
NEXT TIME.
We have to get past this.
I KNOW.
What are you doing here?
HEY, WHO IS THAT?
POINT ME.
I'm sorry about before.
You should be.
I'M SORRY, TOO.
I thought you said
he was leaving.
I thought
you said you were leaving.
The guy replacing Robbins
is just gonna
mess the place up.
Besides, I don't even
like Baltimore.
So what are you saying?
I couldn't get
on my plane, okay?
I COULDN'T GO.
YOU'RE SAYING YOU DITCHED
THE FLIGHT
'CAUSE YOU CHICKENED OUT.
WHAT A LOSER.
When Hunt lands,
tell him I'm staying.
What?
I just saw him here
at the airport.
Isn't he coming
to see you?
IT'S TOUGH
TO ACTUALLY SAY GOOD-BYE.
SOMETIMES IT'S IMPOSSIBLE.
AX. SLOP TIME.
JUST ABOUT
TO GET YOU OVER THERE.
YOU'RE JUST GONNA GET--
DR. HUNT?
HEY. UH, YOUR DAD TOLD ME
WHERE I COULD FIND YOU.
WHAT ARE--WHAT ARE YOU
DOING HERE?
MARK SLOAN DIED YESTERDAY.
OH, GOD.
UM... I'M SO SORRY.
I WANT YOU TO COME BACK
AND WORK AT THE HOSPITAL.
WHAT?
NOTHING IS THE SAME
OVER THERE.
IT'S ALL...
I KEEP TRYING...
I KEEP TRYING
TO THINK OF WAYS
I COULD'VE
DONE THINGS DIFFERENTLY,
AND, UH...
IF I'D REALIZED
THEY WERE MISSING SOONER,
IF I'D TOLD CRISTINA
HOW MUCH I...
I KEEP LOOKING
FOR THE DO-OVERS,
AND THERE'S NO DO-OVERS.
THERE'S JUST THE WAY IT IS,
AND I CAN'T FIX THAT,
EXCEPT FOR THIS,
FOWH--U.
I DIDN'T TEACH YOU,
NOT THE WAY THAT I SHOULD HAVE.
I-I SHOULD'VE HELPED YOU
BE STRONG
INSTEAD OF KICKING YOU
WHEN YOU WERE DOWN.
I SHOULD NEVER HAVE TAKEN
YOUR JOB FROM YOU.
YOU DON'T BELONG OUT HERE
ON A...
A FARM.
YOU BELONG IN SEATTLE,
SAVING LIVES.
NOW COME HOME.
UH, I CAN'T KEEP
DOING THIS ALONE, ARIZONA.
I JUST CAN'T.
GET UP.
GET THE HELL OUT OF BED
AND SNAP OUT OF THIS...
IF NOT
FOR ME, THEN FOR SOFIA,
BECAUSE SHE LOST A PARENT
LAST NIGHT.
AND I LOST MY BEST FRIEND.
AND I WILL BE DAMNED
IF I LOSE YOU, TOO.
SNAP OUT OF THIS?
HOW THE HELL AM I
SUPPOSED TO SNAP OUT OF THIS
WHEN YOU CUT OFF MY LEG?
YOU NEVER REALLY STOP
FEELING THE LOSS.
EVERYBODY...
CHEESE!
CHEESE.
NOTHING'S HAPPENING.
OH, COME ON.
I THINK IT'S ON VIDEO.
SHOULD I GO OVER THERE?
NO, JUST GIVE HER
A SECOND.
WELL, NO, IT'S--I'M--
I'M PRESSING THE BUTTON.
IT'S JUST--
IT'S NOT DOING ANYTHING.
WELL...
MAYBE IT'S BROKE AND--
I'M TAOH-- OVER.
NO, NO, NO. OH, NO.
I DON'T NEED YOUR HELP.
I DON'T NEED--
WE HAVE A KID TOGETHER,
SO YOU'RE STUCK WITH ME
IT'S WHAT MAKES THINGS
SO BITTERSWEET.
WE LEAVE LITTLE BITS
OF OURSELVES BEHIND...
LITTLE REMINDERS...
A LIFETIME OF MEMORIES,
PHOTOS, TRINKETS...
HOH.
I GOT IT.
THINGS TO REMEMBER US BY
EVEN WHEN WE'RE GONE.