Again.
It hurts when I breathe.
Could it be my heart?
Something wrong?
Hey.
What?
Is there something
wrong with my heart?
Probably a bruise
to your chest wall.
We'll get an x-ray to make sure.
You were lucky.
We'll probably
be sifting through
the walking wounded
until morning,
but I think we're over the hump.
Carter just brought
up the last critical.
How many came in?
Thirty-seven. Five in surgery.
Only two ER deaths.
That's not too bad, considering.
If you don't count the DOAs.
You did a great job.
You should go home.
We got it from here.
The board's backing up.
We're fine. Go home.
We'll see you tomorrow.
Hey. You leaving?
Uh, no, I thought I'd
check on the bishop.
Another critical come in?
No, no, no. That's it.
Is she stable?
Yeah. After three
rounds of terbutaline.
Good. It was scary, though.
Yeah.
So are you heading home soon?
Um... I don't know.
You okay?
Yeah.
Any change?
He didn't want the
breathing mask.
Has he been awake?
Napping on and off.
What time is it?
Eleven-thirty.
You're here late.
You'll have to be
intubated soon.
On a ventilator?
Your oxygen level is down
to 65 on 100 percent oxygen...
I've seen what happens
after a ventilator.
If it drops below 50...
Thanks. But no thanks.
Anyway, my bags are packed.
Water! I need water.
Mr. Martin!
Ugh, it stings.
Mr. Martin, just
give it a few seconds.
No, it stings.
A few seconds and
the pain will fade.
Need some help?
No. I just put in
a drop of Alcaine.
Mr. Martin fell asleep
under a tanning lamp.
I wasn't tanning.
I was depressed
due to lack of sunlight.
Tell me about it.
Got back from
lunch and it was dark.
UTI in 4 is gone.
Groundhog see its
shadow this year?
Seeing his shadow
has nothing to do
with how much sunlight we get.
Yes, it does. Six
more weeks of winter.
Seven-year-old with
diarrhea and wheezing.
Ordered Solu-Medrol
and breathing treatments.
Any history of asthma?
Nope.
Fever or cough? Nothing.
Carter, want to
figure this one out?
Bring it on.
Okay, that's it.
Weaver's on at 6:00.
Could you tell her that
I'm finished testing tonight
so she can stop avoiding me?
How'd your personality test go?
I scored somewhere
between serial killer
and talk-show host.
I thought they
were memory tests.
Ahem. That was Monday.
What's next,
Rorschach? Spelling bee?
Swimwear competition,
sudden-death Twister.
Who knows? Maybe
a chili cook-off.
The needle goes in,
but you can squeeze on
the owie ball. See that?
What's up? Hold that for me?
Kid freaked out when
I tried to start an IV.
Who's, uh...?
She's a new intern for Pedes.
Huh.
And then it won't
hurt anymore, okay?
Hey, Jason. I'm Dr. Carter.
I understand you're having
some trouble breathing.
You mom? Yes.
Any history of asthma here?
Uh, no.
Mrs. Fabrone works as a
cleaning lady at a church.
She found a bottle of holy
water in the sanctuary and thought
it might help with
Jason's diarrhea.
Holy water, huh?
Only it tasted funny.
When Jason started
coughing, she checked.
It was lamp oil.
He aspirated holy oil?
Guess so.
That's the common
duct. We don't cut that.
What time is it?
Four fifty-five. No, no, no.
Your interview tomorrow.
Oh. Ten a.m.
Get there by 9:30.
Right.
So why do you wanna
be a doctor? What?
It's a common
question in the interview.
Oh, yeah.
Clips.
So, what's the answer?
I wanna help people?
No?
All right.
Now we dissect the
gallbladder from the liver.
What's the right answer?
You tell me.
The money?
I wanna be a role model.
If you're not gonna
take this seriously...
I am. I just don't know.
I guess I always
thought it'd be cool.
Well, at least that's honest.
So I should say that?
Of course not.
Dr. Benton, how much
longer do you have?
Are you timing me, Shirley?
Mass-cas called in.
They need you downstairs.
What happened?
They didn't give details.
All right. Let me get
some more suction.
I'll be maybe 15 minutes.
Okay.
You should hang out.
You never know what you'll see.
Great job, Jason.
I'll stop by and
see you later, okay?
You're admitting him?
Yeah, just for a day.
Keep him on continuous
nebs and monitor his sats.
Where's mom?
She went to go
talk to her priest.
Could've used you, actually.
She got a little
upset after you left.
About her kid or because
she stole from the church?
My friend used to lift
communion wine for us.
He just went to confession.
What about you?
Me? I just got sick.
So you're a heathen.
Protestant.
Is there a difference?
Will you sign this for me?
What is it?
It's for my supervisor.
If you think I did a
good job with the kid.
"Child Life Specialist."
Intern. First day.
Oh, yeah? Hey,
welcome. John Carter.
Rena Trujillo. Nice to meet you.
And you.
Don't forget your voodoo doll.
It's a procedure doll.
They make 'em life-size
for really big kids?
Why, you lonely?
Yeah. I work a lot.
That's too bad.
John, Luka needs you.
Abby, this is Rena.
Hi. A train derailed
by Lakeshore.
They need to set
up a triage center.
Excuse me.
Any passenger
cars? Commuter train.
How many? They don't know.
They're pulling bodies out.
They need docs on-site.
Prep trauma rooms, set up
Curtain 2 and 3 for majors.
And call everybody in.
Carter, let's go.
Chopper already here?
They'll meet us on the roof.
We don't have an Attending.
Kerry's due in 15.
Call me if you have any problem.
Four units of O-neg.
Move all stable
patients into the hall.
Double up the rooms.
Anyone walking waits in Chairs.
Put all surgical teams
on alert and notify the O.R.
Already did. We're low on vents.
Then grab some from the ICU.
Found it.
Randi, call the
nursing supervisor
and float some
nurses from the unit.
They'll need 'em up there.
Get 'em from Med-Surg.
Oh, my God.
Captain Davis,
incident commander.
We were evacuating
the first car when it rolled.
I got a man crushed
underneath. His legs are pinned.
Fourteen DOAs so far,
we're still pulling 'em out.
Two middle cars are the worst.
What happened?
An automobile
stalled on the tracks.
We think the brakes
on the back cars failed
when the train tried to stop.
Blunt chest trauma over
here, dropping his pressure!
I've got it. You
take the crush injury.
What's on the monitor?
Sinus tach. Vitals?
BP, 90/60. Pulse is 120.
I was supposed to fly. My
damn flight was canceled.
Okay. Rales on the left.
My chest. Feels like
something tore inside.
Try a 14-gauge and
bolus a liter of saline.
Mitch! Mitch, I'm sorry, man!
Don't apologize to me.
I didn't know it was
gonna tip over like that.
BP, 85/60. Pulse, 110.
Doc, I need something
more for the pain.
What did you give
him? Ten of morphine.
Held off when he
dropped his pressure.
Give him five more,
but after the liter.
How long till you
can get him out?
We couldn't lift
it with the jacks...
How long?
How long do you have?
Get a jack on this.
That's not gonna hold.
She conscious? Yeah.
I'm Dr. Kovac. What's your name?
I couldn't get out.
Your name? Do you
know your name?
Shannon.
Okay. Does your neck hurt? No.
Hey, Luka!
What?
We may need a surgeon.
Call it in.
We might not be
able to get him out.
I need a surgeon with
a field amputation kit.
He's on stand-by.
No, not on stand-by. Here now.
He's losing a lot of blood.
Ma'am, has someone examined you?
They're looking for my son.
He wanted to go to
the bathroom by himself.
Okay, let's get you out.
I can't move my legs.
Does your neck hurt?
Please, you have to find my son.
Okay, lean forward.
I can't!
Doris!
Are you allergic
to any medicines?
He's wearing a blue sweater.
Doris! In a sec!
I need a line
and a set of vitals!
He's 7.
He wanted to go to
the bathroom by himself.
Saline, wide open.
Nasal O-2, and get
me if she's hypotensive.
Please, you have to find him!
Are you looking
for a little boy?
He's pinned. We
have to cut him free.
Can you get a BP?
No room. Pulse is thready.
How do I get in there?
The roof.
Systolic's 95.
Make it two liters.
Radio the IC.
I need the metal cut
before we transport.
Did they find him?
I think so. Is he okay?
I don't know yet.
What's his name?
Myles.
Where is he? Over here.
Got an airway?
Breathing on his own.
We're waiting on a circular saw.
Myles? Myles, can you hear me?
Pupils, poorly reactive.
Looks like a closed head injury.
We need to get him out.
I told you,
equipment's on its way.
Get it here, now!
She's throwing PVCs.
Do you want us to treat?
What? Ectopic beats.
Can we give lidocaine?
What's the injury?
Train hit her car.
Possible pubic ramus fracture.
Not at her age. Just
get her to County.
Where's the amputation?
Over here.
We've got a crush
injury to the legs.
BP's 90/65 with fluids.
I don't know how much
longer we can keep it that way.
They can't get him out?
They're trying to, but...
You all right?
You okay? Damn it.
I'm fine. I'm fine.
What's his name? Who?
The firefighter. Lorcan.
I had to inflate two BP
cuffs to use as tourniquets.
Watch your step.
Right. You okay?
Yes.
Lorcan, I'm Elizabeth Corday.
I'm a surgeon.
You gonna cut 'em off?
Only if I have to.
Now, listen.
We can't give you
more pain medication
because we need to keep
your blood pressure up.
So I'm going to give
you a nerve block, okay?
Do it fast.
Prep the groin area. Betadine.
How much fluid in?
Three liters saline,
two of O-neg.
20-gauge for the injection.
These cuffs aren't holding.
I'm gonna reinflate
'em and then clamp 'em.
Lorcan, you want
me to call Patty?
No! You sure?
I'm not dying, man.
All right, buddy.
Who's Patty?
Patty's my ex-wife.
Guys and I were going out after
to celebrate my
divorce going through.
Get back. We're gonna
hammer through this.
Just a second!
Come on, let's do this!
Hold on, Lorcan.
Get me out!
Get it?
Done.
Thanks.
That's it!
Okay, on three. One, two, three.
Where's the backboard?
Paramedics are bringing it in.
All right.
Is he still breathing?
Yes. Good air entry.
How many did you
say we could take?
I didn't. They're
transporting all over the city.
We're two docs down
and a surgeon in the field.
You want me to page Dr. Greene?
He's at his competency testing.
Find out how many
they're sending us.
Malucci's on his way
with the first air-evac.
Possible aortic rupture.
Peter, you're up first. Got it.
No, elevator. Call CT.
Have them cancel
all elective cases.
I don't want them
jamming up on us.
Stay close to me.
If you have any questions, ask.
Don't be surprised if the
nurses push you out of the way.
It's their job. Don't
knock anything over.
I don't need to stay?
Only if you want to.
Blunt chest trauma,
asymmetric BPs.
Dropped his pressure en
route. 60 palp. Tachy at 120.
Sir, do you know where you are?
I was taking a plane.
Oriented times one only.
Marked tachypnea. Pulse ox, 88.
Heart sounds muffled.
What's that mean?
Trashed his aorta.
The major artery from the heart.
Neck veins are distended.
He's in tamponade.
Have the O.R. prime bypass.
You our new third-year?
No, I'm just applying.
Come on. Get over here.
Move!
Let's prep for
pericardiocentesis.
Too late. Lost the pulse.
Argh! Thoracotomy tray.
You better put on a gown.
It's gonna get bloody in here.
What do you got?
Abdominal wound.
BP's 120/90.
We're taking her to Lakeshore.
Are you kidding me? She
needs a trauma center.
All right. Reroute to County.
Give her 10 more of MS.
We're supposed
to rotate... Do it!
Doc! Doc! Yeah?
Tracheal shift to the
left. I need to stick him.
What's his pulse ox?
88 on high-flow O-2.
I can't hear anything
with all this noise.
Did you get it?
I don't know.
Are these all ours?
No, it's the damn news.
Okay, he's moving
air. Take him to County.
Not Lakeshore. County.
Tell them he needs a
chest tube, maybe a vent.
Stop! Stop! You okay?
I think I may have
strained my back.
Come on! Keep digging!
We can't. The weight of
the train will shift on you.
That crane coming? From Indiana.
What?!
It's on its way, Lorcan.
What's his pressure?
85 palp. Pulse
110. Four units in.
Can you assist?
Yeah. I can start.
Lorcan, listen to me.
I'm gonna have to proceed
with amputating both your legs.
No! I've had people
trapped for hours
before we got 'em out!
I appreciate that.
But you've lost too much blood.
If I don't amputate and
control the bleeding,
you're going to die.
Okay, then. I'm gonna start.
Do you understand?
I have to start now.
Prep the area.
10 blade.
Can you tell my
fortune with these?
Pick up each card from
your pile and put it under
the card to which it belongs.
Is that the death card?
I'll tell you if you're
right or wrong.
Are you ready to begin?
Hit me.
Begin.
No. No, just try the next card.
No.
Yes.
Third one's a charm.
Yes. Look, two hands.
Yes.
No.
No? No.
Do you ever say anything
besides yes or no?
No.
I've isolated the
femoral artery.
Retract distally.
Got some oozing from the SFA.
Can't do much
about that in the field.
Mitch!
I'm right here, buddy.
I think maybe you
should get Patty.
You got it.
I need to dissect
this vessel out. Metz.
What? What is it?
Carter, quick.
Clamp that. Clamp it.
What, what, what, what?
Medial to the muscle
bed. Clamp it now.
Is it your back?
It's coming and going.
Intermittent pain?
Yes.
How often?
What's her pressure?
Dropping. 80 palp. Myles.
Start her on dopamine.
Titrate to 100.
Save him, please.
How long till you are through?
I don't know. Ten
minutes, maybe.
Pupils are still sluggish.
Okay. 0.3 of atropine.
Do you have any mannitol?
On board. Hang 40 grams.
He's hypertensive
and bradying down.
I know.
He could have a bleed.
You're not coming with us?
Okay, load him.
I'll be right back.
Carter, I have to
take this boy in.
There is a woman back there
impaled, with spinal shock.
And I want you to
stay with... What is it?
She's having
contractions. What?!
contractions at 25 weeks.
I need tocolytics
and a fetal monitor.
I can keep on going if I
can just get them to stop.
Have any terbutaline? No.
In the rig? We don't carry it.
You should fly back with us.
Carter, take the mother.
The woman down there.
What about him? We opened
the interior compartment.
Call another surgeon!
We're out of O-neg.
We have to finish him now.
If we put you on the chopper,
could you monitor this
boy on the flight back?
Yes. But he could
exsanguinate from his left leg.
You were a surgical
resident, yeah?
Interned. For a year.
Trauma panel and get a HemoCue.
Sinus, rate of 95.
Any chest pain? No.
Mild guarding. No rebound.
Set her up for a CT
and put in a Foley.
Is that man from the train?
Yeah.
Is he dying? I don't know.
Abby, could you shut the doors?
Type and cross
for four. Dip a urine.
More O-neg on the infuser.
The heart's not filling.
Unit seven going
up. Got it. Cut.
Okay, you're done.
We gotta shock him.
Hold on. Couple more sutures.
Dr. Benton, Dr. Finch needs you.
Bad leg injury.
Got it.
Clear!
He's all yours. Get a rhythm,
send him up. White, with me.
Still in V-fib.
Another amp of epi.
Stand by with lidocaine. Clear.
Peter, I have a right orbital
trauma with loss of vision.
Set up the slit lamp,
tetracaine and fluorescein.
Dr. Benton, blunt abdominal
trauma. Possible liver injury.
What's the crit?
Thirty-four, but
he's pretty tender.
Do an ultrasound.
If you see fluid...
Chuny, I need
vitals now. Coming!
Traumatic
extrusion of the tibia.
You call Ortho?
Yes, but he's
looking pretty dusky.
Hold on, that's my bone!
All right. All the major
vessels seem intact.
Just try to get him up.
Peter, Carter
needs to talk to you.
Not now!
He's performing a
double amputation.
What?! A guy
pinned under a train.
Don't worry. That
can be reattached.
Give another 20 MS.
Okay, he's on Bravo 3.
Carter, what are you doing?
Left anterior thigh.
I've incised through the
fascia and muscle planes.
I need to isolate the
neurovascular bundle.
I thought Corday went with you.
She did.
Well, what is she doing?
We've got to control his airway.
BP's rocketing, 240/120.
Pulse, down to 30.
Another mig of
atropine and mix Nipride.
He's in respiratory distress.
I'll intubate. 6.5 ET tube.
Should we stay on the ground?
No, let's go.
Fifty of lido, one of
Pavulon, 50 of sux.
You okay?
No.
Using the dull edge of the Metz,
let your finger
continue blunt dissection
of the artery from the
neurovascular bundle.
What?
Blunt dissection...
You're gonna have to
shout. I can barely hear you.
Do you know what you're doing?
Does anybody know
what they're doing?!
What's he down to now?
190/100. Pulse,
44 after two migs.
Try 80 of Lasix.
Let them take him downstairs.
Go! Go straight to CT.
There's a case on the table.
He probably has an epidural.
I'll tell him.
How often you been
having back pain?
Every four or five minutes.
When's the last time
you felt the baby move?
I don't know. I haven't.
Okay.
Got it!
Can you call on the
radio and see how he is?
We'll be there soon.
BP, 95/65. Pulse is 110.
Am I gonna die? Am I?
We'll get you out.
If I die before I get there,
you have to make sure
they take care of Myles.
They will. He's 7.
I know.
His father's in Kansas
City on business.
We were coming
back from visiting him.
I thought it'd be fun for
Myles to take the train.
What about the sciatic nerve?
Pull it down as far as possible,
then apply an Ochsner clamp.
That one. Third to the right.
Okay. I got it. Now what?
Put a second clamp
five millimeters distally.
We're gonna get you
through this, Lorcan.
You're gonna be all right.
Remove the proximal clamp
and ligate the crushed area.
0-Vicryl?
No, no, no. Nonabsorbable.
Peter, this boy's herniating.
Use silk if you've got it.
Okay. Done that. Now what?
We've got to drain the hematoma.
Carter, I've gotta go.
Call me on your cell phone.
I don't have it. In my locker.
Find one. Peter, now.
Keep bagging him.
What do I do about this nerve?
Step off in the
right parietal region.
Dr. Benton? Pulse
ox is dropping.
Dr. Benton?!
What is it?
You have a cell phone? Nope.
Do you? No.
Terbutaline's on board.
Repeat in another hour.
You sure McLucas
hasn't answered?
We just paged her.
Give her a second.
What about Mark?
He's on his way.
Okay. You're about
25 percent effaced.
But dimpled, not dilated.
Okay? We can control that.
You think so?
An OB Resident's on his way.
I don't want a Resident!
You have to calm
down. And focus, okay?
Give the terbutaline
a chance to work.
Mark's on the phone.
What line? Three.
Climbing again, 220/115.
Blown right pupil.
He needs a burr hole.
Where's your perforating drill?
Is 1 open?
Yeah. Malucci's calling it.
Connect the chisel bit.
Let's keep
hyperventilating. Let's move!
Coming through!
I gotta move this guy.
No, no, no. Shove him
up against the wall. Move!
Have somebody shave his
head. Give me 8.5 gloves.
Sit him up to 30 degrees.
Carter's on Line 3.
He needs to talk to you.
White, get over here and
hold the phone up to my ear.
10 blade.
Pressure's through
the roof, 260/140.
Not good. Up the
Nipride to three mics.
Put my glasses
down. All right, Carter.
Talk to me. Where are you?
Sciatic nerve.
All right, good. Cut proximally
and let the muscle retract
into the muscle belly.
Lorcan, they found Patty.
They're gonna send a truck
to take her to the hospital.
No, no. Forget it.
Okay. Cutting now.
Make sure you use a
scalpel instead of scissors.
Otherwise you'll get a neuroma.
She's on her way.
She wants to come.
No! No! Not now!
Would you please
hold him still?!
Okay, now what?
Take two Kellys and clamp
the femoral artery vein.
I don't want her
to see me like this!
Can you give him something?
Whoa! He's seizing!
Five of Ativan.
Five of Valium. Put
the phone right here.
I don't want her to see me!
You gotta hold him
still until it kicks in.
You're almost free.
Is that two clamps
each or altogether?
Two clamps altogether!
Two of Ativan? Five.
Am I clamping the vein
and the artery separately?
Carter, clamp the vessels
as one unit at both ends.
Ativan's on
board. Still seizing.
All right. You know
what? I gotta go in.
Just reparalyze him.
Both proximally...
Don't do it!
And distally or
one proximally...?
Carter, just clamp
the damn vessels! Go!
How many liters in?
Two and a half. Lost a pulse.
She's in V-fib. Charge to 200.
Do you wanna run her inside?
No, here. Paddles.
Charging.
Clear!
Still in V-fib.
Charge to 300. Clear.
Mark, penetrating back injury.
Needs to go straight to the O.R.
All right, I'll tell Randi.
Mark.
You feeling any
more contractions?
I'm sorry. Don't be.
I slipped and fell.
I thought it was just backache.
Did you give her terbutaline?
Ten minutes ago.
Fetal heart tones?
One fifty-five. No decels.
Well, that's good.
They haven't stopped.
You gotta give it
some time to work.
Or maybe we should
try magnesium.
We will if we have to. Okay?
Let's just wait and see.
It's okay. It's okay. It's okay.
Irrigate. More Ativan?
No. Stopped seizing
once he relieved
intercranial pressure.
Suction catheter. Carter,
are you through the tibia yet?
Done. Almost there, Lorcan.
Good. Use the rongeur
to bevel the anterior apex.
Where is that?
Sharp edge at the
end of the bone.
What's his pressure?
Down to 170/60.
They're all sharp! Damn it!
It's the anterior surface.
Dr. Weaver, I need you.
What patient?
Girl whose car got hit.
I'm sorry. What?
The anterior surface.
Get him upstairs.
You're almost there.
When you're done,
use the rongeur
to crack the fibula.
Wait, wait, wait!
Hold on! Hold on!
Dr. Benton!
Good luck.
BP's low. Want me to
put the dopamine back on?
Hold the elevator!
No. This one goes straight up.
Status, post-cardiac arrest.
I just opened up
this kid's head.
Did you evacuate the clot?
There's still active
bleeding at the site.
She's in shock.
Lucky he got her back.
All right, go.
No. Take the boy first.
Call Neurosurg, tell
them we're on our way.
I need two units of
FFP and an ICP monitor.
Eighty-five palp.
Start the dopamine.
What is it?
I wanted to ask you
something. He die?
Who? That man.
They cut open his
chest, but he died.
Yes. He had a fatal injury.
What about the boy?
He went up to surgery.
Is he going to die?
I don't know.
Is there someone
we can call for you?
Your mom or dad?
They won't understand.
Won't understand what?
I thought it would be painless.
The train would hit my car,
I'd just be gone.
Yeah, don't talk to
me about saturated.
You haven't seen saturated.
Chuny, I need a trauma
panel. What's open?
I don't care. I'm
admitting them!
Carter, they're
holding O.R. 6...
I was just there. No surgeon.
Is he stable? Yeah,
but I had to sedate
him with 10 of Valium.
Carter, are you deaf? What?
I keep shouting, you keep
getting on the elevator?
Is this the pre-op amputation?
This is the post-op amputation.
What, in the field?
He was trapped.
What did they use, a chain saw?
Dr. Benton talked me through...
You did this? There
was nobody else...
Well, by all means, let's
get whoever's available.
You try next time.
Maybe if you'd
respond to your page...
I can't wear my
pager in the dojo.
Brenda knew where I was.
Should have
called her. Let's go.
Dr. Weaver, frail chest in 4
just dropped his
pulse ox down to 81.
Carter, can you take this?
Give him another one.
Maybe I should have let him die.
Stop cryin'. I'll clean up.
Good work, Carter. I know.
Really. He was lucky
that you were out there.
Thank you. Carter!
I'm coming!
Kerry? Yeah.
You have a suicidal ideation?
Young girl in Trauma 2.
Does she have a plan?
Parked her car
in front of a train.
Oh, I suppose that qualifies.
She's also in a
major depression.
Flat affect? No real remorse.
About the suicide attempt?
For the train wreck.
Oh, my.
Think you're gonna
get off before 12?
Mm. Probably not.
Okay.
Uh, I'll try to be quiet.
No. Wake me.
Something wrong?
Hey. What?
There something
wrong with my heart?
Probably a bruise
to your chest wall.
We'll get an x-ray to
make sure. You were lucky.
We're still sifting through
the walking wounded,
but we're over the hump.
Carter just took
the last critical.
How many came in?
Thirty-seven.
Five up in surgery.
Only two ER deaths.
That's not bad, considering.
If you don't count the DOAs.
You did great work today.
You should go home. We got it.
Board's backing up.
That's all right. Go home.
Shirley called for you. What?
O.R. nurse. You
asked her to call
when the mom and
son came out of surgery.
Did they? Yeah.
They're in Recovery.
Mom's got sensation in her legs,
and the kid's
neurologically intact.
That's good, right?
Yeah. That's good.
Ah. You still here, huh?
The nurses put me to work,
thought I was a
volunteer or something.
Good. Now you've
got an experience
to talk about in your interview.
I don't know.
It's yours. You
might as well use it.
I mean, I don't
know if I want to.
Want to what?
What I saw tonight...
Most people go their whole
lives without seeing stuff like that.
Drilling into a
little boy's head.
Guys having their legs cut off.
People dying
right in front of you.
You get used to it.
Yeah. That's what I'm afraid of.
But thanks for helping
me find out early.
Go to the interview.
Dr. Benton... Go to it.
You may feel
differently in a few days.
I know, but...
Hey, give yourself options.
Anything?
No contractions
since the third round.
Fetal heart rate looks good.
So it's over.
Aside from bed rest.
How long do you think?
You can catch me up on my soaps.
It'll be okay.
When I felt the
baby move before,
obviously I knew it
was in there, but...
Suddenly this feels
real, you know?
Yes, Mom.
OB's waiting, and
Transpo promises
they'll be down
soon to take you up.
Thanks, Abby.
The monitor stays on
for at least 24 hours.
I'll keep it on
until I give birth.
You just have to slow down.
No more helicopters.
Right.
Hey.
You leaving?
No. I thought I'd
check on the bishop.
Another critical come in?
No. That's it.
Is she stable?
Yeah. After three
rounds of terbutaline.
Good. Yeah. It
was scary, though.
Yeah.
You heading home soon?
Um, I don't know.
Are you okay?
Yeah.
Any change?
He didn't want the
breathing mask.
Has he been awake?
Napping on and off.
What time is it?
Eleven-thirty.
You're here late.
You'll have to be
intubated soon.
On a ventilator?
Your oxygen level is down
to 65 on 100 percent oxygen.
I've seen what happens
after the ventilator.
If it drops below 50...
Thanks, but no thanks.
Anyway...
my bags are packed.
How long do I have?
Maybe hours.
Then I'd better hear it now.
Hear what?
Your confession.
Bishop, I don't think...
That's what you came
up here for, isn't it?
I wanted to check on you.
You're searching for your faith.
You think you lost it,
but you only buried it.
It's never left you.
In the name of the
Father, of the Son
and of the Holy Spirit.
Amen.
May God, who
enlightens every heart,
help you to know your
sins and trust in his mercy.
Father, I can't...
Luka.
Your heart is burdened, Luka.
Talk to me.
Let me take that burden with me.
I don't know. I, uh...
Lost my family.
Danijela, my wife, she, uh...
wanted to move out of Vukovar.
But, um, I had to
finish my internship.
And, uh, soon it was too late.
It wasn't safe to move.
I was gonna get some supplies
and I made them stay behind.
I was just crossing the street
when the mortar shell
hit the apartment building.
Go on.
I ran inside.
There were my neighbors.
Hurt. Bleeding.
Dying. But I passed them by.
I had to get to my family.
Danijela!
Luka.
Luka...
Marko...
Luka! Marko...
A piece of shrapnel had
torn into Danijela's spleen,
and she was bleeding to death.
When I turned
back to my daughter,
she wasn't breathing.
I lost her pulse.
But as long as I,
uh, kept doing CPR
and breathing for my daughter,
I thought she had a chance.
I could only pray that
someone would get there to help.
If I had picked up
Danijela at that moment
and gotten her to the hospital,
she could have had surgery.
You know, she could have lived.
But I couldn't
leave my little girl.
Danijela.
I waited and prayed.
I prayed someone would come.
And no one came.
No one came.
Jasna. Jasna.
I called out for hours
as I stayed there
breathing for her, doing CPR.
I finally had to stop
from exhaustion.
I lost them all.
You couldn't sacrifice
the one to save the other.
Even if you had, you'd
still blame yourself.
These things can't be explained.
Why it happens.
The providence of God
and the mysteries
of life and death
are the very fiber of our faith.
They were gifts
of love and life.
You are a gift of love and life.
Don't turn your back on them.
God,
father of all mercies,
through the death
and resurrection
of your only begotten Son
was reconciled
himself to the world
and sent the Holy
Spirit among us
for the forgiveness of sins.
Through the ministry
of Holy Church,
may God give you
pardon and peace.
And I absolve
you of all your sins
in the name of the
Father and of the Son
and of the Holy Spirit.
Amen.