My neighbor Kenny and
his girlfriend go all the time.
The rides were actually fun,
Claire, even though they hurl you
through the air very quickly
without a proper three-point seat belt.
It was worth the $300 I spent.
What kind of carnival
cost you that much money?
It was not just the carnival.
Kenny's girlfriend wanted to
go to see a movie afterwards.
But I just got the second edition of
Chaikof's Atlas of Vascular Therapy,
so decided not to go.
- And you paid for everyone?
- I had to. I lost the bet.
Rounds will have to wait.
We have a consult come up.
Hunter Denoble, 38. Came
into the ER this morning,
complaining of severe neck
pain. X-rays show anterolisthesis.
A herniated disc? 38, a
little young for that, isn't it?
Unless there's a
history of spinal trauma.
There is. Hunter fractured seven
vertebrae in his neck and back
in a motorcycle
accident 10 years ago.
He was one of my first patients.
Suffered complete paralysis
from the chest down.
A few months back, just gnawing
pain. Ibuprofen usually took the edge off.
Every day?
Ah, yeah, give or take.
It's not that bad.
Last night, things changed.
He couldn't move his neck at all.
And the pain medicine had no
effect. So he wanted to tough it out,
but I dragged him in here.
Yeah, sounds like you.
- Feel that?
- Yeah.
- And that?
- Mmm-hmm.
I made partner at the firm.
I don't like to call in sick.
And let's face it,
I've spent enough nights in
hospital rooms for five lifetimes.
Can't argue with that.
Squeeze my hands?
You have any tingling or
weakness in your arms?
No.
The plain film showed what
looked like a herniated disc,
which would mean...
Artificial disc replacement,
day procedure.
He'd be out by the
morning at the latest.
You married him?
Yes. Three years ago,
in Cancún. It was lovely.
Even though he's
in a wheelchair?
- Shaun...
- No worries. I get this all the time.
Sure, she can never wear
heels, but think of the parking.
- Ah!
- What happened?
Pain shot right down
through my legs.
- Your legs?
- Yeah.
I haven't felt anything
below my chest in 10 years.
What the hell is going on?
When I saw the break of day
I wished that I could fly away
Instead of kneeling in the sand
Catching teardrops in my hand
My heart is drenched in wine
But you'll be on my mind
Forever...
Mom?
Why, there's my girl!
I don't wanna see you.
I haven't seen you in years.
Don't run away from
me. Can we talk?
Since I don't wanna see you,
it follows that I don't
wanna hear from you either.
I just came in to get antibiotics.
My surgeon doesn't work on Fridays.
It feels fine.
Sorry, it's not fine.
This implant is
definitely infected.
Just that one, though, right?
Yes, at this point, your
butt-lift, tummy-tuck, lipo,
and breast augmentation
appear to be healthy.
I need to remove this one and clean
the area before the bacteria spreads.
Well, can you replace it?
Once the infection is resolved
and you have a few months to heal.
I don't wanna walk around with
half of a face for a few months.
Isn't there anything you
can do to save the implant?
I can't make any guarantees,
but if I can replace the implant
without risking reinfection, I will.
Okay, Doctor.
I didn't understand the lyrics,
but I liked your mom's voice.
Is she a professional singer?
She is a lot of things.
A great mom wasn't one of them.
How so?
A lot of people have issues
with their parents. Nothing new.
But, well, everyone's
story is different.
How so?
When I was in high school, I
babysat the kids in my neighborhood.
I wanted to buy a laptop for
school like a lot of my friends had,
so I saved up 1,000 bucks.
I came home one day,
and the money was gone,
and so was my mother.
And three days later,
she came back from Reno with a
designer dress and a guy named Ricky.
I never got the laptop.
My mom made
pancakes. They were good.
Mmm. What is that?
I've never seen
anything like that.
Maybe a spinal column tumor?
Hunter's initial
spinal cord injury
from the motorcycle accident
that caused his paralysis was at T1.
But that part looks almost
completely normal now.
Hunter's phantom pain
is real.
My former mentor, Sonya Kung,
is head of the surgical residency
program at Denver Memorial Hospital.
If you want a meeting,
I'll make a call.
Why?
You're gonna need
a job after this year.
Are you trying to screw with my
head, or are you actually being serious?
The opportunity is real.
I'm trying to be nice. I do
that when it doesn't hurt me.
And this definitely doesn't hurt you,
you getting rid of some competition.
True.
Although you're not
high on my list of threats.
This would be a much
bigger benefit for you.
Look, I fought to stay here.
I'm not going anywhere.
It's very rare, but,
after many years,
with a bruised cord like
yours that isn't severed,
it can start to function again.
So this mass is
causing Hunter's pain?
Yes.
If the cord is healthy, why
aren't I feeling more than pain?
The mass is compressing
the healthy cord,
just letting the pain through.
We still have to do some more
advanced imaging to map the mass,
but I'm fairly confident that if
we removed it, that could change.
You may be able to walk again.
We were able to clean out the
infection and swap in a new implant.
I'm very pleased.
- You think it looks okay?
- I love it.
And you are going to
look great at the beach.
Wailea.
We went there on our
honeymoon. Thank you.
Ooh, well, he's taking you to
Hawaii. You should be hugging him.
I'm so relieved.
Satisfied customers.
This is why cosmetics
is the most fun speciality.
Now, we're gonna
monitor you closely.
There is a risk the infection could
have seeded to other implants.
Keep me posted.
Yes, Chief.
I'll take the early shift.
Once I'm on my feet, I'm
never sitting down again.
I'm gonna take Cora
dancing. She's a great dancer.
Oh, no. I push myself.
No offense. It's my rule.
Right.
If this works, after a considerable
amount of physical therapy,
you may be able to walk,
but that doesn't mean
you'll be a very good dancer.
After years of atrophy
from not moving your legs,
you will likely be very bad.
You know what the worst part is?
It isn't being in a chair. It's
that people see the chair first.
They don't see me. You
know what I'm talking about.
Why would I know what
you're talking about?
My brother-in-law is on the
spectrum. So is my assistant.
I make it a priority of hiring
people with disabilities.
Let me guess. When you
first started working here,
no one believed in you.
They didn't know me.
They didn't know that I was
going to make a good surgeon.
No.
You were different.
I guarantee you,
every other doctor started
with a basic level of respect.
It's implied. They're competent.
We waste our time and energy
trying to prove that we belong.
- I'm fine.
- She's just being thorough, honey.
You've been over
my body three times.
Early infections often mimic
blemishes. It pays to be thorough.
Is this sore?
Maybe a little.
- What's wrong?
- It could be nothing,
or it could be a carbuncle,
an early sign of infection.
Dr. Andrews needs
to have a look at this.
This varicocele is raising
testicular temperature
and causing your
sperm count to be low.
Surgically, I go in,
ligate the varicocele,
and recheck your
numbers in a few weeks.
It's done under a local,
so no anesthesia risks,
minimal blood loss.
There's a risk of low
testosterone and impotence,
but recovery time is
usually a week at most.
So I could have kids. I just
might not be able to make them?
As I said, it's low risk.
I only mention it because
I'm obligated to inform you.
Well, you're obligated to
inform me because it's a risk.
It's an unlikely complication,
but, yes, it happens.
It's outpatient. I do it
right here in the office.
What I see here is a
chance to fix a problem.
And I see a chance
to create a new one.
I'm sorry. I have to
go. I have a patient.
Look, I see a lot of
men with this issue.
Sure, they come in
because they want kids,
but I think what they really
want is to reaffirm themselves,
and that's a good thing.
Thank you.
It's a spinal
arachnoid meningioma.
Have you seen
one of these before?
Much smaller. They
usually don't get this big
because the pain and weakness
brings the patient into the ER fast.
But in this case, no pain,
no ER visit until it got this big.
And it's wrapped around
the spinal cord tightly
and fused with the dura.
Can we get a fibre-optic laser
and take it out in segments?
No, I don't think so.
It's stopped growing
and settled in this position.
But I do think that we can dissect
along the subarachnoid plane
down to the largest segment
at T2 and remove it in one piece.
That's an extension of the mass.
Mmm, no, it's the
medullary pyramids.
No, it's an extension
of the mass.
The pyramids are more
central, and the color is wrong.
Murphy's right.
The extension's tightly
adhered to the brainstem.
- Who caught it?
- Jared did.
Nice work. Most first-year
residents would have missed this.
It's very small on the surface,
but I can feel the
fluctuance under the skin.
What do we need to do to fix it?
We need to remove
all of the implants,
and some of the healthy
underlying tissue as well.
Unfortunately, it will cause
significant permanent scarring.
No, no, no, you can't do that.
I'll look worse than I did before.
I don't get it. You removed the
bad part from her face, and it's fixed.
It looks good.
No more infection.
Let's just do the same
with the rest of them.
It's not that simple.
When we removed the
infection from Emma's cheek,
it was under the pretense
it was a localized issue.
If we just take out the
infection from the new area,
it could jump again.
I won't do it.
When an infection spreads,
it often moves very quickly.
What Dr. Andrews is saying...
I understand what he's saying.
I'm 50 years old.
When I went to drop my
daughter off at Michigan,
we went to that bar
on Liberty Street,
where we first met.
I saw myself sitting
there 25 years ago,
young, confident,
full of potential.
Then you raise a kid,
and look after your
husband, a home,
lose touch with who you were.
You said it was
an infection, right?
Like strep throat or something?
That's what antibiotics are for.
Couldn't we just use them?
We could try strong,
broad-spectrum antibiotics.
But I really don't wanna do
that. You could become septic.
You could die.
It'll work. It has to.
The brainstem is complex.
Even our best imaging can't
provide a complete picture.
So then you would just
leave the cyst in him?
Other than the pain,
it's not harming Hunter.
It's stabilized now
and done growing.
But what about the pain?
An implanted nerve inhibitor
will completely remove the pain.
But I won't be able to walk.
No.
Exactly how risky is removing
the mass from the brainstem?
Everything that keeps
your heart beating
and you breathing
is right there.
The nerve inhibitor
is a day procedure.
You'd sleep in your
bed tonight pain-free.
Give me a percentage
on this thing.
Don't do this to yourself.
I don't like to give
those kinds of numbers.
They're population-based,
and they don't apply to
your exact circumstances.
I understand how
statistics work.
But there's a number,
and it's relevant.
There's a 15% chance
this surgery would kill you.
I remember the moment I
accepted I'd never walk again.
It wasn't when Dr. Melendez
told me after the accident.
A few months later,
I was in rehab, and I was trying
to get up in the standing frame.
I looked out the window,
and there was all these
people just living their lives.
I'm trying to fix something
that I can't change,
and life was going
on without me.
So I started living again.
But now there's
something I can do.
Hunter...
I wanna talk to Dr. Melendez.
- No.
- Please.
Just go get Dr. Melendez.
You curious?
About why I gave you the credit?
I assume you
thought it was a set-up.
That Andrews thought you were
wrong, and you tried to throw it on me.
That's very cynical.
The other alternative is
that you were being kind,
which seems very unlikely.
There is a third possibility.
I'm proving a point.
When you lose their respect,
no matter what you do,
no matter how many wins you
chalk up, you'll never get it back.
The game's already
over. You lost.
Does anyone like you?
I like me.
I've got results.
I know this is her first
cycle of antibiotics,
but I'm not seeing
any improvement.
Her neutrophils
are through the roof.
You'd be under
anesthesia for nine hours.
I'll need to make sure
that your body's healthy
enough to handle the stress.
Will you tell him not
to do this? Please.
You don't care what I think?
I'm the one in the chair. You
have no idea what that's like.
I'm right there with you.
Who carries you up the stairs?
Who pushes you
out through the sand
so you can put your
feet in the water?
Well, this way you won't have
to do those things anymore.
So you just wanna
gamble the life that you have
for the life that you had?
Cora,
we have a great life,
but I wanna walk again.
And I want you to see me walk.
I'm not gonna stand
by and watch you die.
If you wanna selfishly
gamble your life away,
you're doing it on your own.
I'm doing this for us.
No, you're doing this for you.
She'll be back.
Hey. Uh, I got a page.
I'm busy, and I don't like being
tricked into coming down here.
Yeah, I know you hate me...
I don't hate you. But seeing
you is not healthy for me.
Okay, wait. Well, I just needed
to tell you that I was sick.
I am sick.
I know. You've been telling
me that for years. You were right.
I got help.
They have me on
mood stabilizers.
I'm doing better now.
I mean, sometimes, the
meds make me feel flat.
You know, no highs, no fun.
No lows though,
either. It's worth it.
I'd like to try again
to be your mom.
I mean, maybe we could
just talk some more?
I'll think about it.
Well, take these.
They need water,
or they're gonna die.
My number's on the card.
I think I just won
the Tour de France.
It's a long surgery.
It will put a lot of
strain on your heart.
Your cardiovascular
fitness is excellent.
You get it, right?
Get what?
Why I want the surgery so bad.
You'd jump at a cure
for autism, wouldn't you?
There isn't a cure for autism.
Well, last week, I didn't think
there was a surgery to help me.
The surgery isn't
guaranteed to help you walk.
Why would you risk losing a person
who accepts you the way you are?
You may not find another one.
There are a lot of reasons
to marry me, you know.
I'm sure there are a lot
of reasons to marry you.
Yes. I'm organized.
I have excellent
visual-spatial memory.
And Lea says I'm
refreshingly honest and fair.
I suppose Cora loves me
because I'm determined,
and I'm pretty smart.
Committed to helping others.
Most of all, probably,
because I'm patient.
Were you always those things?
Were you those things before
you were in the wheelchair?
Your autism helped
you. That's your point?
You're saying this chair
made me a better person?
The difference is,
losing this chair now
won't make me lose
the lessons it gave me.
The antibiotics aren't working.
I told you if they didn't,
we'd be doing surgery next.
No.
She's going to die
if we don't act now.
Honey,
we need to listen
to the doctors.
I need you to trust me.
I can't go back to
being like it used to be.
You don't have a choice.
She wants a second opinion.
She's going to die.
I told her that.
Sometimes, it's tough to
actually get out of those doors.
When I was kid,
my little sister had an
accident climbing a tree.
A traumatic brain injury.
And I woke up every morning
dreaming that she was better,
but she wasn't.
I took care of her a lot.
Brushed her teeth,
combed her hair, fed her.
Hunter was my first
patient as an attending.
And I had to walk in that room
and tell him that there was
nothing I could do for him,
nothing I could do to fix him.
And now there is?
But there's no guarantee.
There is never a guarantee.
I'm sorry,
but I can't risk losing the
man that I fell in love with.
You're not just afraid that
the surgery will kill him.
You're afraid
that it might work.
You've only known
Hunter in a wheelchair.
Walking would be a
fundamental change in who he is,
a fundamental change in
who you are as a couple.
You're worried that no matter what
happens, you're gonna lose him.
Hunter seems to
have a great life.
I don't know if I'd
risk giving that up.
What if there was an operation
to make you a perfect doctor,
never make a mistake,
but it had a, you know, 5% chance
of killing you? Would you do it?
That's not a fair comparison.
Well, you said Hunter's
doing fine the way he is,
but we're talking about
giving him something more.
What about 2%?
I don't think there's
a number for me.
Of course there's a number.
Every time you get in your car...
Hell, every time you leave your home,
you take a risk something bad
could happen, but you do it anyway,
you know, to make yourself
better, to make the world better,
sometimes just to have fun.
Sometimes to go to a carnival.
Kenny's not your friend.
He's using you.
I don't think so. We have fun.
He's got a rap sheet.
Mostly misdemeanors, but
there's a couple of felony-theft cases
that were bargained down.
Wait. You ran a
background check on Kenny?
Well, you start by talking. I
start by gathering evidence.
I'll forward it to you.
In my experience, there
are only two reasons
why a married person has
this kind of cosmetic surgery.
Either you're halfway
out the door, or she is.
Emma loves me.
That's what I figured.
The antibiotics aren't working,
so your wife is going to die
unless you get in there,
and you convince her that she
doesn't need any of this cosmetic surgery
because you are a
faithful, loving husband.
How's the pain?
You know, I think the adrenaline
of actually doing this is helping.
It's the oxycodone.
That's good.
I'm glad you came back.
I never left.
I don't wanna do
this without you.
anything without you.
If you can walk,
you'll be different.
You won't need me anymore.
You think I married you
'cause I was having trouble
hanging clothes in my closet?
You're my girl.
I will always need
you, even if I can fly.
Who's gonna remind me to
call my mom on her birthday?
Or floss? God, I hate flossing.
Who's gonna remind
me to be a better person?
Who's gonna hold my
hand when I'm scared?
That was nice.
You have to have the surgery.
You were distant before.
But since the surgery,
you can't get enough of me.
It worked. You're
happy. I'm happy.
I love you. I always have
loved you. I always will.
- You stopped loving me.
- No. Never.
If you were in love with me, you
never would have cheated on me.
Barry, please,
no more lies.
You were never
home. We never talked.
You were never there.
There was never another
woman. I was gambling.
A lot.
I did it because I was ashamed
of the man that I'd become.
When we got married, I
promised you the world,
and instead, I gave
you a mediocre life.
When I was up,
it made me feel like a winner.
And I was too embarrassed
to let you see me like that,
- so I hid it from you.
- Barry...
She's gonna do the surgery.
Thank you.
Andrews needs an
OR for Emma Newton.
Hmm.
Claire,
you're beautiful, smart,
and very good at your job.
Thank you, Shaun. That's
a very sweet thing to say.
Would you ever date
someone with a disability?
Yeah, sure.
You could choose
the ideal mate, Claire.
Why would you want
the unnecessary burden?
Everyone is dealing
with something.
We just have to love other
people for who they are,
hope they love us, too.
OR-1 is prepped for Hunter.
I'll join you in a minute.
So, what changed her mind?
Jared did.
Morgan, you're my first assist.
Make the call.
Thanks.
This is as far as you can go.
Nurse Matthews will take
you to the waiting room.
Okay. Can I...
Can I give him a kiss?
Of course.
I can't do this.
Yes, you can.
This is what you do
in a relationship, right?
You take chances together.
- Go.
- Okay.
That's a large tissue
defect in the left breast.
If we'd been in
here six hours ago,
I could have salvaged more
underlying muscle tissue.
I'm noticing a heart rate
jump. You seeing that, JL?
I am now. How's
her surgical sites?
Not seeing any bleeding.
Morgan, what about your side?
Everything looks good here.
Maybe the anesthesia's light?
No. No, something's
definitely happening.
Jared's right.
Suction, Claire.
Give me a 25 on a 130.
All right, Murphy, I want you
to cut right under my forceps.
Very carefully.
Section's cut.
How are the
motor-evoked potentials?
Signal's coming through. Spinal
cord is functioning normally.
The mass has fully
encased the medullary cord.
Give me the ferromagnetic wand.
I can't get the caudal end
clear of the underlying cord.
Had a big drop in potentials.
We're compressing his brainstem.
- What's his pressure?
- Mean arterial pressure's 70.
I got nothing now.
Push IV fluids, keep
that MAP above 90.
Hunter is going into
neurogenic shock.
We need to stop the surgery.
I'm almost there.
Twenty seconds.
Pressure's 60.
Push vasopressors.
The last piece is right there.
It's probably edema. Push
100 of dexamethasone.
Still nothing.
He's dying.
It's one damn
centimeter of tissue!
All clear!
That's her second dose of
amiodarone. She's not responding.
She's thrown a septic
embolism. I'm cracking her chest.
Ten joules. Clear!
Again.
Clear!
Starting cardiac massage.
It's time to call it.
Time of death, 10:23.
Welcome back, Hunter.
The mass was tightly
adhered in some spots,
so we're not exactly sure
what to expect moving forward,
but the cord looked healthy.
We're gonna be bringing in
several specialists to work with you.
The first will be a
neuropsychiatrist...
Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you. I'm
grateful to all of you.
Would you mind if we talked
about the rest of this later?
I just wanna sit with my wife.
- Thank you.
- Yeah.
Hey.
Hey. Hey.
I met a couple today
that lost their way.
They loved each other,
but by the time they remembered
what really mattered, it was too late.
I don't want us to be like them.
I wanna be fully
committed to you.
I love you, too.
There's a surgery I could have
that should make me fertile,
but there's a risk of impotency.
What do you wanna do?
I wanna give you what you
want, what we want, a family.
We are a family.
Yes, I want children.
And there are many ways to do
that, which we'll explore together.
But I draw the line at
anything that risks our sex life.
It's just one night a week,
but I think this could be
my big break, you know?
You always had
a beautiful voice.
Well, everyone's
got one thing, right?
But enough about me,
I wanna hear about you.
Do you have a man?
I did.
Pretty young thing, should
have plenty of choices.
I'm not looking to
complicate my life right now.
Hmm.
Still looking after
everyone else but yourself,
like you did for me.
You know, I brag to everyone,
"My baby, she's a surgeon."
Surgical resident.
Right, sorry.
You like it?
I love it.
Where are you staying?
Are you in town for a while?
Yeah. I'd like to
be closer to you.
I found a place.
You'd like it.
But I just need to
put up first and last.
I'll pay you back.
How much do you need?
$2,500?
Plus I have to get
furniture and all of that.
I thought maybe you could
help me pick that stuff out.
You've always
been so good at that.
I really appreciate
it. I'm good for it.
Okay.
Uh, Celeste isn't coming.
She broke up
with me. I hate her.
But I'm not gonna
let that ruin our night.
That's what friends are for.
They got each other's backs,
rain or shine.
By the by, I found a $20
in your battery drawer,
so I got us Chinese
food. Don't thank me.
I don't like Chinese food.
Aw, come on, now. Trust me,
everybody likes Ma Jong's kung pao.
Here you go.
I'm pretty torn up about that
Celeste thing. She was a real keeper.
You said you hated Celeste.
I do. I hate her 'cause... I
don't know. I kind of love her.
This tastes terrible.
Okay. Then he
hates Chinese food.
More for me. Plain white rice?
I got a gaming console, and I
hooked it up to your bad boy over there.
We could play
some Mortal Kombat.
Come on.
We doing this or what?
Sounds fun.
Yeah, here you
go. This one's you.
That's you, on
the left, right there.
- Okay.
- Yeah.
You got four arms to play with,
but you're naked, so here we go.
I gave you a pneumothorax.
I didn't realize how
bloody this game was.
A fireball. I got you there.
Have you played this before?
That looks like
a spinal fracture.
Yeah, I'd say there's
a huge fracture.
You died.