And easy on the CrossFit
for a while, okay?
Hey.
Thank you.
Just cleared
Treatment Three,
just gotta turn it over.
Sure.
APRIL: Man, we're up
again already?
Looks like it.
What's going on?
Who are they?
Big Brother. Hey.
Oh.
Up.
JCAHO.
SHARON: Yeah.
They're doing
a surprise site survey.
Who's JCAHO?
MAGGIE: The Joint Commission.
They rate
the performance standards
of hospitals
and certify them.
So far, JCAHO's reports
have been positive.
So let's keep it that way.
Stick to protocols
and with big smiles.
(CHUCKLES)
Dr. Choi,
we're gonna need some
of your Navy-inspired
discipline today.
Sorry, I'm with
the Paramedics today,
resident ride-along.
Mmm-hmm.
And "discipline"?
Is that a nice way of
saying I'm a tight-ass?
Oh, yes, tight.
I didn't say that.
(CHUCKLES)
And, uh, getting
those docs in line,
isn't that the Chief
Resident's job anyway?
SHARON: Wonderful.
The guy enforcing the rules
is the one who's
always breaking them.
Yeah. Good luck with that.
WOMAN OVER PA:
Code One team to the ED.
What do we got?
CESAR: Nathan Clay,
58-year-old male,
peds versus auto.
GCS 12, vitals stable,
gross deformity to
the left upper arm.
Right in here.
Complains of
chest and back pains.
Mr. Clay,
can you hear me?
(GROANING)
Mr. Clay?
On my count,
one, two, three.
(GRUNTING)
(BREATHES HEAVILY)
CONNOR: Airway's intact,
breath sounds
clear bilaterally.
Tenderness in the left chest
and thoracic spine.
What happened here?
He was walking with his wife
on Michigan Avenue.
Suddenly flips out and
starts whaling on her.
A couple of Samaritans
jump in to help out.
He takes off
right into traffic.
Score one for karma.
CONNOR: Twelve lead EKGs.
Chest X-rays.
CT of the chest,
abdomen and pelvis,
with recons
of the TLS spine.
On it.
WOMAN: No. Leave me alone.
I'm fine.
Laura Clay,
55-year-old female. GCS 15.
I'm fine.
I need to get to my husband.
CONNOR: Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Ma'am. Ma'am. Ma'am. Okay.
COURTNEY:
Heart rate's tachycardic.
This is all my fault.
Look, I blocked
my fall with my hand,
not my c-spine.
I'm neurologically intact.
Technical. Are you a doctor?
Yes. Yes, I am.
(SOBS) Laura.
MAGGIE: Dr. Rhodes.
Please, no!
Ma'am,
ma'am, stay right there.
Honey, no...
Get away!
I'm right here.
CONNOR: Hold on.
There are
too many of them.
I'm here, my love.
I need restraints,
two of Versed,
five of Haldol.
No, not Haldol.
Quetiapine.
He's not abusive,
he has Lewy Body Dementia.
Wait, scratch the Haldol.
Twenty-five of Quetiapine.
LAURA:
It's all right, my love.
What the hell's
Lewy Body?
Debilitating form
of dementia.
Alzheimer's meets
Parkinson's.
(NATHAN SOBBING)
He took
a pretty good whack.
He's got a chest bruise,
left first rib fracture,
proximal humerus fracture.
How are his labs?
It's all good.
Calcium was elevated.
I suspect he'll develop
a kidney stone down the road,
but it's likely
he's had a few before.
DANIEL: Prior heart surgery?
Says it was
a quadruple bypass,
had it done at Northwestern
five years ago.
He remembers the details?
Yeah, he's lucid, somewhat.
All right, EKG is normal,
but because of
the prior heart surgery,
I'm gonna repeat it
every few hours.
He's all yours.
Mr. Clay?
Mr. Clay, I'm Dr. Charles.
How are you feeling?
My wife, Laura.
Where is she?
She's being
treated right now,
but will be in shortly.
I hurt her again,
didn't I?
(BREATHES HEAVILY)
This isn't
the life she deserves.
Mr. Clay.
Mr. Clay?
Damn. You've got
the online thing down.
There was a time.
Yeah, what's her name?
Easy, she's taken.
Vicki. Doctor at the VA.
Oh, man, there are
so many female paramedics
who're gonna be sorry to hear
you're off the market.
Couple of guys, too.
You let 'em down easy for me?
All right.
You sure you're gonna
be okay back here?
'Cause we can just throw
Desmond in the back.
Ah! Fine.
Ambo's like the Humvee.
You sit where there's room.
Comfort's not a factor.
Well, good. This day's gonna
go by quick then.
FEMALE DISPATCHER: Ambo 61,
40-year-old male,
down in his home.
222 Bromley Avenue,
some kind of
lower-extremity insult.
He's in severe pain,
possibly trapped.
Copy, Main.
Ambo 61 responding.
All right, we're on!
(SIREN WAILING)
It doesn't make any sense.
I've had Boomer
since he was a puppy.
He's super loyal.
I leave the room
for a second,
he's looking for me.
I had a dog like that.
He might nip a little,
but this was
a full-on attack.
In my experience,
dogs can be unpredictable,
even really friendly ones.
Sometimes if a dog's
in pain, though, he...
He wasn't.
We were playing tug-of-war
like we always do.
Dog bites shouldn't
be stitched.
They need to stay open
so the wound
doesn't become infected.
Also I'm gonna give you
a tetanus shot
and an antibiotic.
Boomer's healthy.
He's had all his shots.
It's just a precaution.
(WINCES)
(SIREN WAILING)
(INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER)
MABEL: Paul's in trouble
down there.
BRETT: Did you call 911?
MABEL: Yes, I'm his neighbor.
Paul?
(KNOCKS ON DOOR)
Paramedics.
(EXHALES)
It's ripe.
ETHAN: Man, look at this.
He's a hoarder.
(SIGHS)
What do you think?
You good
going in there?
I'm good.
Okay.
Get the truck company here.
Tell them they're gonna have
to help dig us out,
and grab me a second radio,
and I'm gonna try
and go in
through the back door.
You got it.
Paul!
Everything okay?
(GRUNTS)
Third squad caught
a high-rise fire.
Dispatch is pulling a truck
from up north to help us out.
Gonna be a while
before they get here.
In the beginning,
I wanted to think
it would pass. Any wife would.
But I'm also a neurologist,
and I couldn't
ignore his symptoms.
So you diagnosed
the Lewy Body Dementia?
Yes. But I got
second and third opinions.
And they both
agreed it was LBD
and that was
about four years ago.
Four years? Really?
You know, Nathan expressed
deep regret to me
about the pain
that he's caused you.
That kind of insight
is rare for somebody
who's been battling
LBD for that long.
Well, my husband
was an engineer,
and his brain is
wired to solve problems.
Last year, I retired early.
I wanted to devote more time
to his cognitive therapy.
Well, it's been working.
There's moments
when he's lucid,
but more and more,
it's this.
CONNOR: Mrs. Clay,
Nathan's latest
EKG is still normal.
I wanna do another
one in a few hours.
But if it is good too,
I'll discharge him.
Thank you, Doctor.
Mmm-hmm.
I know that it would be
better and safer
for the both of us
if Nathan went to
a care facility.
But if I do that,
then it's over.
I'm not ready
to give up our Sundays
listening to opera.
I know it's hard to imagine,
but my Nathan
is still in there.
Last week, he made me dinner.
Florentine lasagna.
He can still cook?
Well, meals take longer
to prepare than they used to,
but he does it for me.
He's fighting
just as hard as I am.
Hi, honey.
Everything's gonna be okay.
Everything's okay.
BRETT ON RADIO:
How're you doing, Ethan?
Fine.
Long as I breathe
through my mouth.
Is it as tight in there
as I think it is?
It's worse.
Are you claustrophobic?
Didn't used to be.
And I mean...
And Tate totally snores,
but I don't mind.
Oh! He does this
thing where he shoots
his dirty boxers
into the hamper
like a buzzer beater.
Anyway, it's cute.
Oh, my God,
you're in love.
WILL: Whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa.
What's that?
What's what?
Used gloves go in
the bio bin, not the trash.
Okay. Those were
actually clean, though.
They were on the floor.
Probably just got
stuck to the pair
that came out before them.
Unless you're certain,
it's bio.
Come on, Maggie,
you know the protocol.
MAGGIE: I do.
I've also been
through this circus
about a dozen times.
JCAHO days are
about patient care,
not about a pair
of latex gloves.
Look, I'm already in
the doghouse with Goodwin.
If there's any chance of
getting out, I want it.
So, (INHALES DEEPLY)
by the book.
By the book.
(SIGHS)
LAURA:
Okay, honey, eight across.
It's five letters,
and the clue is
"rental agreement."
And the first letter
is "L".
I'm thinking
the second is "E".
L-E...
Lease?
Good. Good, honey.
All right, next one,
we're gonna do 23 down,
six letters.
(MONITOR BEEPING)
The clue is
"collects" with an "S".
What happened?
I don't know,
his blood pressure tanked.
All right, bag and
hang a liter of bolus.
NURSE: Yes, Doctor.
Sats are dropping. Intubate?
CONNOR: Yep.
APRIL: Grab the bag and
hook it up to the O2.
All right,
20 of Etomidate, 100 of SUX.
Let's bring in the FAST scan.
April, give me some pressure.
Here, Doctor.
And I'm in.
Got it.
Okay.
Scan.
Here you go.
APRIL: Heart rate, 110.
All right, belly's clean.
Poor wall motion of the LV
and a small effusion.
He's bleeding internally?
Dr. Charles.
Mrs. Clay, please.
Sats are back up.
Oxygenation improving.
It's not gonna matter if he
goes into cardiac arrest.
CT of the heart
and great vessels.
Let's get him
ready to go.
Laura,
if we may?
The blunt trauma
from the car accident
displaced one of
Nathan's bypass grafts.
His aorta is
leaking blood.
A pseudoaneurysm.
CONNOR: Mmm-hmm.
How bad?
Right now,
it's just a slow drip.
It hasn't ruptured yet.
So there's still
an opportunity to operate,
repair the suture line,
and plug the hole?
Normally, yes.
Your husband's prior
heart bypass surgery
significantly increases
the difficulty
of the operation.
His odds of surviving
the procedure plummet.
So if surgery isn't
a viable option, what is?
Given the circumstances,
we feel the safest choice
is to make Nathan comfortable.
How long?
Can't be certain,
a day, a week,
maybe a few months
until the aneurysm ruptures.
I'm very sorry.
PAUL: Hello. I can't move.
ETHAN: I'm coming, Paul.
(GRUNTS)
MAN: Don't touch that.
ETHAN: What was that?
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(INHALES AND EXHALES)
(YELLS)
(GROANS)
Ethan? What happened?
Got bit by
the lid of a tin can.
Truck company is almost here,
they're gonna clear a path
to get the stretcher through.
PAUL: Please, hurry.
Hold on, Paul!
Oh, thank God.
I haven't been able to
pee in over 16 hours.
I thought
I was gonna explode.
Brachytherapy for
prostate cancer?
Two days ago.
My urologist said
it was the way to go.
Who's your urologist?
I'll call and tell them
you've experienced
a blockage.
Dr. Mason over
at Advocate South.
Contact info's in my phone,
my pants pocket.
Oh, sorry.
Oh! Whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Everything okay?
Just a little spill.
I got it.
Okay. Hold on, I'll call
Environmental Services
and have them send a janitor.
It's just pee.
I've cleaned it 1,000 times.
Yeah, but not with
JCAHO and RoboCop Halstead
on the prowl.
"By the book," remember?
Oh, man,
I think the seed came out.
It's radioactive, right?
Oh...
Dang.
Okay,
I'll call Urology instead.
Cath lab for
a cardio angiogram?
Should give a better view
of Nathan's pseudoaneurysm
and hopefully help me estimate
a timeline for his wife.
Do you mind grabbing me
an MRI of his head
while you're up there?
A brain scan?
His injuries
don't necessitate it.
Not for him,
it's for me.
Uh, Dr. Charles.
Dr. Rhodes,
his awareness and
gross motor skills
are just too
strong for somebody
who's been battling
LBD as long as he has.
No amount of
cognitive therapy
in the world
is gonna outthink
this disease
to the degree that
he appears to be.
Laura and two
other neurologists
have all agreed on
the Lewy Body diagnosis.
You think they're wrong?
I don't know what to think.
That's why
I need the scan.
I'll need the wife's consent.
Hasn't she been
through enough?
I'm just trying to spare her
some false hope here.
Hello.
Gentlemen.
JCAHO day isn't
exactly the time
to be sneaking in
unauthorized tests.
I don't know
what to tell you.
Okay.
Thanks, pal.
Mmm-hmm.
(SIREN WAILING)
MAN: Yeah. What do we got?
BRETT: Hey, guys,
start clearing out!
(INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER)
MAN: Don't touch that.
Get away.
There's a second person.
I'm hearing another victim.
Ethan, the neighbors
seem sure
it's only Paul in there.
MAN: Don't touch that.
ETHAN:
There's someone else here.
Dr. Perrington.
Got a hemoptysis patient.
Chest X-ray says it's a COPD,
but I think he needs a bronch.
You wanna
take a quick look?
Really?
The esteemed Dr. Halstead
needs my help with a patient.
I'm honored.
Look, I'm sorry about what
happened the other day...
You want a consult,
page my resident.
Okay. No redness.
No inflammation. Looks good.
So I can go?
The nurses are working
on your discharge
paperwork right now,
and your wounds should heal
in about seven days or so.
Until then, irrigate them
and keep them covered.
You all right?
Uh, just itchy
and a little sweaty.
Mind if I take a look?
No rash.
Could be an allergic reaction
to the antibiotics.
You do feel warm, though.
I'll get a temp.
(CELL PHONE CHIMES)
Oh...
My sister checking in.
(SNIFFS)
I left Boomer with her.
She's not
a dog person either.
I get the impression
they're not for you.
I've treated
a lot of dog wounds,
especially on kids.
It's 99.4 and was
normal at intake.
Um... CBC and CMP?
NATALIE: Yeah.
I'm not out of here,
am I?
Sorry. Itching and fever,
even a low one,
could be more than
an allergic reaction.
Someone will be
with you shortly.
Paul, is there
anyone else in the house?
PAUL: No. No, it's just me.
You gotta hurry!
(GRUNTING)
Ethan, what happened?
You okay?
(GRUNTING)
(PANTING)
What's all this?
Well, it's pretty
clear an Attending job
at Med isn't gonna happen.
You don't know that.
Just being realistic.
Perrington's on
the hiring committee.
She hates me.
Not to mention Goodwin.
Really, Miami, Will?
I've seen you sunburn
walking from
the ED to your car.
Hey, gotta go
where the jobs are.
No coffee. JCAHO day.
Right.
LAURA: I don't understand.
There should be atrophy,
heavy degeneration,
tangled cells in
the white matter.
When was this taken?
About an hour ago.
I'm sorry.
I had a hunch, I rushed it.
I really should've...
That is a healthy brain.
There's no disease.
This means that...
Nathan doesn't have
Lewy Body Dementia.
He has the symptoms.
It keeps getting worse,
practically a textbook case.
How?
Take a look at
this cross-section
we took during the MRI.
Notice the adenoma,
benign tumor,
in the parathyroid gland.
So you think this is all
hormonal irregularity?
Elevated parathyroid
hormone is consistent
with increased calcium
and cognitive impairment.
Nathan has both.
Yes, but he also
has hallucinations,
physical aggression.
You don't see that in patients
with hyperparathyroidism.
That's where his
recent bypass surgery
makes him unique, okay?
The beta blocker
he's been taking ever since
causes increased levels
of violent behavior
in a select
amount of patients.
Oh, my God.
A hormonal imbalance
with a medication
side effect.
Why didn't I see that?
The clues were
right in front of me.
Because they
mimic the symptoms
of Lewy Body Dementia
to a tee.
And four years ago,
that adenoma
would've been so small,
no scan
could've caught it.
Look, I'm just
telling you that,
presented with
the same evidence,
I would have done
exactly the same thing,
reached exactly
the same diagnosis.
Anybody would've.
You didn't, I did.
And if I had caught
the PTH four years ago,
Nathan doesn't
run into traffic,
doesn't get hit by a car.
Today never happens.
He's dying and it's
entirely my fault.
(PANTING)
PAUL: Help! Please.
Anybody! I need help!
Ethan? Ethan, talk to me.
Ethan, do you copy?
Let's go.
MAN: Living room's clear.
(EXHALES)
(GRUNTS)
Thank God.
Paul.
Help me, please.
Paul, I'm Dr. Choi.
Hey, your heart's racing.
When's the last time
you had any fluids?
(EXHALES)
My leg, I burned it.
I see that.
Don't touch that.
(EXHALES DEEPLY)
How did this happen?
While I was cooking,
I tripped.
I spilled the frying
pan grease. (GRUNTS)
This didn't just happen.
This burn is thick, leathery.
Twenty-four hours old?
Why didn't you
seek help sooner?
Didn't want anybody
to see how I live.
Okay.
I'm here now.
I'm gonna take care of you.
(GRUNTS)
DR. HARPER:
Brachytherapy seed.
Yep.
Doesn't happen often,
but it can get
expelled in the urine.
So, um, how
radioactive is it?
To us, it's harmless.
Still, don't touch it
with your bare hands.
Oh!
So you're not
gonna dispose of it?
Not on JCAHO day. Sorry.
Call the Radiation
Safety Officer.
Oh, man. Here we go.
LAURA: I get it. You didn't
do Nathan's bypass surgery.
You don't know what
you're walking into.
I can get you
every angio he had.
You will know exactly
where the surgeon
placed every suture.
The bigger issues are
the adhesions and scar tissue
that have formed over
the last five years.
We can expose a healthy heart
in 10 or 15 minutes.
After a quadruple
bypass surgery,
it could take hours.
An infinite number
of complications could arise.
When I decided to
make Nathan comfortable,
I believed he had
a neurological
death sentence.
Now, it's a whole
new world.
The dementia
can be reversed.
I understand, but the fact
that he doesn't have LBD
doesn't make
the surgery any easier.
Nathan's odds of dying
in that operating room
are just as high
as they ever were.
It's still my recommendation
to not operate.
I'm sorry.
I'll do the surgery.
Thank you.
Thank you for
giving us a second chance.
Difficult is
not impossible.
ETHAN:
Brett, how close are you?
Ugh, Ethan, finally.
You okay?
I'm fine, but Paul's got
a serious third-degree burn
that needs to be
released in the ED. ETA?
BRETT: I think we're
almost to the kitchen.
We need more room
for the gear.
PARROT: Don't touch that.
Get away.
Who was that?
The other person
I heard, a parrot.
Look, you still have
the hallway to deal with
and Paul's foot's
still swelling.
No pulse in
the instep or ankle.
BRETT: All right, uh, we're
coming as fast as we can.
But not fast enough?
Okay, Paul,
here's the deal.
Your skin's so burned,
blood can't get in
or out of your foot.
I'm gonna cut into
your leg on both sides
of the burn to
release the pressure.
Here?
I wait any longer,
you're gonna lose
your foot.
But is it going
to hurt?
Already pushed
morphine in your IV.
That'll help.
But I'll feel it?
Focus on me, not my hands.
It'll be over
before you know it, okay?
Deep breath.
(INHALES DEEPLY)
Then exhale.
(EXHALES DEEPLY)
(GROANS)
Keep breathing, Paul.
Keep breathing. Big breath.
(INHALES)
Bigger exhale. (EXHALES)
Done.
Good job, Paul.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Good job.
A high white cell count?
What does that mean?
You probably
have an infection.
From Boomer?
It's possible.
Have you felt
sick recently?
No, not really.
I mean, every now and then
my throat aches a little.
Doesn't really
bother me, though.
Hmm.
The lymph nodes are swollen.
Consistent with an upper
respiratory infection.
Let's get
a rapid strep test.
What kind of dog
is Boomer?
Boxer-bulldog mix,
a rescue.
When I went to the shelter,
all the dogs swarmed me.
But Boomer hung back.
Not because he was shy.
It was a move
so he'd stand out.
He was playing me. (CHUCKLES)
Smart dog.
I'm gonna swab
the back of your throat.
I'll get this to the lab.
(INHALES DEEPLY)
I'm doing what
I think is right.
Nathan's mental impairment
is due to a pea-sized tumor
that is easily removable.
A 45-minute operation
will cure him.
But first, (SIGHS)
he has to survive
this monumentally
difficult surgery.
I'm sorry,
you can't bring your dog
into the hospital.
It's my sister's dog.
She's somewhere
in the back
not answering her texts.
Only service dogs in the ED.
I'm sorry.
Is this Boomer?
How'd you know?
I've been
taking care of Tara.
She said he was
a boxer-bulldog mix.
I thought it was only
gonna be one or two hours.
It's been five.
Is she okay?
She spiked a low fever
and we're testing for strep.
Strep? This is nothing.
Okay, good.
Look, I have
to go to work.
There's no pets
allowed in my building.
He barks one time,
and I can get evicted.
I'm sorry. There's nowhere
else to take him.
Oh. No, no, no.
I can't take this...
I know.
It all happened
really fast.
What do I do?
Get him
out of here, now.
But where do I take...
Reese, I don't care where.
Just out.
(CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY)
EARL: Hey, look at this guy.
Yeah, Earl, this is Boomer,
could you watch him
for a minute?
But don't get too close,
because he...
Come on, fella.
Come on, guy, let's go.
Come on, big boy.
There you go.
Okay. Okay.
When I'm out, the city
will condemn my home.
Won't they?
Fresh start, I guess.
Get away.
Don't touch that.
MAN: There they are.
Hey, guys.
BRETT: Hey, you're okay?
For a second there
it sounded like you...
Little hairy for a while,
that's all.
Escharotomy in the field?
Damn. Nice job.
One across, six letters.
"Bread, milk, eggs."
Thoughts?
Staple.
Nice.
Thank you.
Sure.
All right, guys.
Got it.
MAN: Clear.
Lift him up.
PARROT: Don't touch that.
Dr. Manning, uh,
Tara's rapid strep
came back negative.
(INHALES DEEPLY) Okay,
so we're back at square one.
Mmm-hmm.
You know what?
Let's run a...
(BOOMER BARKING)
EARL: Easy. Easy.
I'm sorry. I am so sorry.
Hey, Earl,
what's going on?
I don't know what happened.
Twenty people
petted this dog,
and this patient
is the only one
he barked at.
Come on, boy. Come on.
Come on, come on.
Come on, bud.
Let's run an infused CT
chest and abdomen on Tara.
Oh, I've heard stories.
Mmm-hmm.
Yeah.
DOWNEY: Easy,
snakes in the grass.
The bypass grafts
are buried in the scar tissue.
Tough to see.
Soften your grip
and go slow.
I see it.
DOWNEY: Mmm-hmm.
Proximal pseudoaneurysm
of the LAD bypass graft.
Let's cannulate and
get him on the pump,
so we can do the repair.
No, I don't need the pump.
It just needs
a single repair stitch,
I can do it
on the beating heart.
80 suture.
NURSE: Suture.
(EKG BEEPING)
DR. VORSPAN:
EKG is ischemic, ST elevation.
Pseudoaneurysm's ruptured.
He's bleeding.
80 suture to me.
I've got the better angle.
Dr. Rhodes.
I pushed for this surgery.
I can't lose him.
DOWNEY: I'll get you
better exposure.
There.
CONNOR: Going to put
a second stitch in now.
DOWNEY:
Don't back-wall the graft.
DR. VORSPAN:
Bleeding has stopped.
EKG's improving.
Pressure's good.
We're out of the woods.
Not yet.
I wanna check his
other bypass grafts.
Something goes wrong
in the future,
no surgeon's
gonna open his chest
a third time.
Lymphoma?
I have cancer?
The next step is a biopsy
to determine exactly
which kind.
But I'm only 26.
I go to the gym every day.
I don't smoke.
I know. It's not fair.
But I don't feel sick.
Well, that's because
it was caught early.
You have time to
get way ahead of this.
Mmm-hmm.
The lymph nodes
are around here, aren't they?
Boomer's been
nipping at me for a month.
Always right there.
Do you think he knew?
Maybe.
It seems some dogs
can smell cancers
even in the very
early stages.
Yeah, he wasn't
attacking you.
He was trying
to protect you.
(CHUCKLES)
Maggie, what's going on
with Treatment Four?
MAGGIE: I know, I know.
We don't have
the space for this...
It's been all day.
Dr. Halstead,
Environmental Services
hasn't shown up yet.
I can't even get an estimate
as to when they will.
(EXHALES) I'll go
see them in person.
I'll drag someone
down here if I have to.
Knock some heads.
I need that room back.
How's he doing?
Well.
Good.
How are you doing?
As a neurologist,
Lewy Body Dementia
was my worst nightmare.
I'd seen so many cases.
And I'm wondering
if it influenced
my diagnosis.
Hmm.
Medicine,
you know,
imperfect science.
Practiced by
human beings, no less.
Four years we could've
been doing CTs.
But I had an answer,
so there was no reason
to continue
radiating his brain.
I robbed Nathan
of his mind,
imprisoned him.
I drained our savings,
squandered our time together,
time that we can
never get back.
How am I gonna
tell him what I've done?
He's never
gonna forgive me.
Your husband's gonna
forgive you, Laura.
Want you to
trust me on that.
Your struggle,
if I may,
is figuring out
how you're gonna
forgive yourself.
Vitals are stable.
EKG looks good.
Cleveland Clinic
has an axiom.
Emergency surgery
on a healthy heart,
yes.
Re-do surgery
for a repaired heart,
yes.
Emergency surgery
for a repaired heart,
no.
Because, overwhelmingly,
those patients
die on the table.
Couldn't do nothing.
I suspect it was ego
more than altruism.
Great surgeons
know the balance.
You're confident,
not arrogant.
I like that, Dr. Rhodes.
Nice job today.
(CHUCKLES)
You're good. You're good.
Good boy. Good boy.
Don't come from above.
Come from the front
so he can see you.
And hold out
the back of your hand first.
Okay.
Come on, buddy.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Hey. There.
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
Did you ever hear
that origin story
about dogs?
In Eden,
humans and animals got along,
even spoke the same language.
But when Adam and Eve sinned
and God drove them out,
a great chasm opened up
between people and animals.
And as the chasm grew wider,
at the very last moment,
a dog leaped
across it to be with us.
SARAH:
That's a great story.
Yeah.
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
Come in.
Ms. Goodwin, can I
talk to you for a moment?
Quickly. I'm on
the homestretch with JCAHO
and I don't wanna let up now.
I know my voice
isn't official,
but I'd like to put in
a good word for Will
regarding the open
ED Attending position.
Really?
It'd be a shame
to lose him.
He's a great doctor.
He cares about this hospital.
Just a few weeks ago,
you asked to be
taken off his shifts.
We don't always
see eye-to-eye,
but his heart is
in the right place.
Well, Dr. Manning,
I'm glad your opinion
of Dr. Halstead has changed.
Okay.
(GRUNTS)
Dr. Halstead,
Environmental Services
are on their way?
Nope.
It turns out every department
in the hospital's calling ES
to handle things
they normally
take care of themselves.
Be tomorrow before
a janitor shows up.
Ah, bureaucracy.
Phew!
Mmm.
Yeah.
There. The room
is yours again.
Against protocol.
I won't tell
if you won't.
Well, guess that means
I get to clean this up now.
The way I wanted to
eight hours ago.
(CHUCKLES)
You know what?
Toss me a pair.
Oh?
You know,
the kind that stick to yours
when you pull 'em out.
You want in?
Heck, yeah.
We've come this far.
And they call you RoboCop.
(CLEARS THROAT)
RoboCop?
(INDISTINCT TALKING)
Katrina.
Reese, come with me.
Uh-oh.
Yeah, I've seen that look.
Dr. Rhodes.
Everyone,
look, we all know
how important JCAHO site
visits are.
Yet, despite what I
said about the rules,
my team ordered
tests on the sly,
brought a dog into the ED,
and handled
radioactive material.
Sharon, you have every right
to be upset, really.
But we can't
really be ignoring
the second law of
thermodynamics here,
now, can we?
How's that?
Well, systems do tend
to degenerate
into evermore
disordered versions
of themselves, right?
I mean, look around you,
all we're doing
here all day long
is battle the universe's
desire to fall apart.
Yeah.
Wish you had seen
the house I was in today.
DANIEL: I'm just saying,
I love rules, we all do.
But in bringing
order to disorder
every now and then
a couple
are gonna get bent.
Nice try, Daniel.
But the good news is
JCAHO didn't catch
any of you.
So we keep our top rating.
I'll see you all tomorrow.
"Second law
of thermodynamics."
Please. (CHUCKLES)