We have a seat opening up
on the board.
Are you familiar
with George Thomas?
I'm not trying to be
a part of your board
so I can be a mouthpiece for
some special interest groups.
I'm all ears.
I think that you got
a lot invested in 2.0.
I'm not gonna gamble
with a patient's life
just so I can show off
my shiny new toy.
The real-time
data's insufficient.
Imaging is inadequate.
What am I supposed
to do here?
The hospital is flying in
workers if we walk out.
They're flying in scabs?
I don't ever tell you
how to do your job.
And I'm not telling you
how to do yours.
I'm telling you
people are scared
'cause they can't afford
to miss a paycheck.
Dignity, respect,
more money in our checks.
more money in our...
Give me a second, okay?
Sharon.
Daniel.
You're striking?
No. I'm just, you know,
showing solidarity,
which I believe I'm allowed
to do on my day off.
You are.
Look, I know that
this whole labor dispute
has been complicated
for us.
It is.
I just want you to know
I support the service workers,
and it's very important
for me to feel
that Liliana feels like
I have her back.
Okay, Daniel.
All right.
Just stay warm
out here.
Thank you.
See you tomorrow.
Okay.
Dignity, respect,
more money in our checks.
It means a lot
to me, Daniel,
and my friends,
you being out here
in the cold with all of us.
Are you kidding me?
We get to hang out
together, and, I mean,
you are very attractive,
which is a bonus.
Oh.
It is.
Hey.
Hi. Sorry I'm late.
There's a little
foot traffic outside.
Hard to navigate.
I noticed.
I already got your coffee.
Oh, thanks.
Thanks for meeting me.
Yeah, of course.
What's going on?
Well, um,
I'm working the steps
in NA with my sponsor,
and I'm up to step nine.
Oh, yeah?
Okay, that's good.
Step nine is making amends
with the people
you've harmed.
Oh, well, you don't
have to do that.
Yes, I do.
Anyway, I'm sorry
for not showing up
to that job interview
you arranged at O'Hare.
Oh, you're going way back,
aren't you?
And for that time I stole
Grandpa's pocket watch
and hocked it for cash.
And, um,
this one
really haunts me, uh...
that time I said
Mom drinks because of you.
Yeah. Water under the bridge.
Have you talked
to her at all?
Do you know where she is?
Well, last I heard, uh,
she quit rehab.
But it's actually later
than I thought,
and, I got to get...
Get to work.
Maybe we can pick this up
another time, all right?
Okay.
Thanks for the coffee.
Going to treatment six.
All the attendees
are occupied,
so you've got me.
David Sullivan, 18 years old.
BP 118/77, heart rate 99.
His parents called 911.
David fainted,
probably 'cause he hasn't
eaten anything in days.
But it's even worse
than that.
He's saying some
pretty horrible stuff.
Okay. Hey, David.
I'm Dr. Asher.
Can you tell me
what's going on?
Go away.
All right, on my count.
One, two, three.
We came in with David
six months ago.
Dr. Charles and Dr. Cuevas
diagnosed him with
schizoaffective disorder.
Are they...
Are they here?
Uh, Dr. Charles
isn't working today,
but Dr. Cuevas is.
Can you call Dr. Cuevas
for me, please?
Leave me alone!
David, we just want
to check you out.
It won't matter.
Nothing matters.
Mr. and Mrs. Sullivan.
Hi.
David, hi.
Do you remember me?
Dr. Cuevas?
I don't need a doctor.
Okay. Can you tell me
why you think that?
I know.
David, are the voices
talking to you?
Maybe if you tell me what
they're saying, we can help.
You can't.
Why is that?
Tell them, David.
Go ahead, honey.
I'm dead.
What do you mean?
You can't help me
because I'm already dead.
In the months since
we were last here,
David has been taking
a combination of risperidone,
aripiprazole, and clozapine.
Yeah. Things were going okay
for a little while there,
but then there was
this new development.
So David, how did you
come to believe
that you're dead?
David?
I could feel it.
And what did it feel like?
Like my organs
stopped working.
And did anything else
besides the feeling
lead you to believe this?
The voices.
The voices in your head?
And why do you think that
they're telling you the truth?
Stop trying to convince me
that I'm wrong.
I'm only trying
to understand.
I remember now.
I remember you.
Yeah. I've treated you
before, more than once.
You were the first one
to make me take medicine.
I was just trying
to help you, David.
You're the reason I'm dead!
Hey, hey, hey, it's okay.
It's okay.
It says here, Walter,
you're a type 1 diabetic?
Yeah. That's why
I'm in the Med more times
than I can count.
Sorry about that.
That's all right.
I mean, it's nice to
have a hospital I trust
for days like this.
And the Tylenol is not helping
with the fever and the chills.
101.5.
All right.
Let's have a listen.
And deep breath for me.
All right, good breath sound.
Glands feel a bit swollen.
You have a sore throat?
A little, I guess.
It's mild.
Okay.
Remove your glasses
for me, please.
How long have you been
feeling this way?
Uh, three days.
I know because it started
just after a trip I took
to Yosemite for hiking.
I hear it's beautiful there.
It is spectacular.
I mean, the only
downside for me was...
Yeah, I guess I should
show you this.
Argh!
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, I slipped and fell
on some rocks.
Sorry.
Yeah. It looks like
it could be infected.
Might explain your fever.
CBC, CMP, Accu-Chek,
hemoglobin A1C
and blood cultures.
Uh, let's swab
for COVID too,
just to rule it out.
And add a tetanus booster
if it's been more
than ten years.
Very thorough. I like it.
It's always been the MO here.
We try, Walter.
Hang in there.
All right. Thanks.
Maggie?
Yep?
Trash in three is
practically overflowing.
It looks like it hasn't
been emptied in days.
Oh, all right.
I'll talk to the guy
who's subbing.
Joe, right?
Did you turn over
treatment three?
Turn over?
Change the sheets,
wipe down the surfaces,
clean the floor,
like we do after a patient
is discharged?
Yeah, I think so.
Then why is
the trashcan full?
I'll empty it.
Uh...
I cannot believe
it's come to this.
Hiring scabs?
Doris.
Look, the strike
has us in a bind.
I need your help in
turning over rooms today.
I thought we had
replacement janitors?
Yeah, but they're
slacking off.
Start with
the empty rooms
and work your way
around the football
as patients are
being discharged.
Please?
That's just great.
Thank you.
Ms. Goodwin?
Yeah?
It's been seven days.
How long is this strike
supposed to go on?
All I know is, the board
and union are working
to come to an agreement.
Well, it's only
a matter of time till
this blows back on us.
I'm aware,
Dr. Halstead.
Your concerns are noted.
Okay, Jack.
I'll make it known.
Talk later.
Sharon Goodwin.
What a delightful way
to start the day.
George.
How are
negotiations going?
They're going.
That's all I can tell you
at this point.
Well, look. I'm not
trying to insinuate myself
into the negotiations,
but I do need to share
my staff's concerns
over how patient care
could be affected
if this strike
drags on much longer.
Hopefully, we're not too far
from an agreement.
Okay, well, I'll keep
my fingers crossed
and hope to hear
good news soon.
I promise you'll
be the first to know.
All right.
Okay.
What've we got?
Abby Hawkins,
eleven years old.
Sustained a pretty bad leg
injury on her family's farm.
BP and heart rate remained
stable the whole way here.
Okay. Hey, Abby.
I'm Dr. Marcel.
You're at Chicago Med.
We're gonna take
good care of you, okay?
Thanks for your help.
Look, I'm not leaving her.
I'm Abby's doctor,
Warren Johnson.
Dr. Charles?
We are essential!
Oh. Give me a sec.
Sorry. I heard
you were out here.
That's okay. What's up?
Do you remember
David Sullivan?
I do, yeah.
Well, his parents
brought him in.
His paranoid delusions
have given way to
something else.
He now believes
that he's dead.
Dead.
Okay.
Crucial that you don't
push back on the delusion.
Well, I tried
reinforcing it
to gain his trust,
but it didn't
get me anywhere.
Okay. I'll be right back.
Liliana, there's a young man
that I've been treating.
He's back in the hospital,
and he's in trouble.
I need to go
check in on him.
Okay.
All right.
I'll be right back,
soon as I can.
We are essential!
Hang in there, Abby.
Maggie?
You're going to Baghdad.
She and her family
are patients at
the clinic where I work.
They brought her in?
Yeah. I gave her 50 mics
of fentanyl for the pain
and put a splint on her leg.
Okay. Here we go.
I got it. Thank you.
You're also a pilot?
Yeah, I used to be a flight
paramedic in the army.
Those skills come in handy
when you're out
in the boonies like us.
Soon as I saw Abby's leg,
I knew I had to
bring her here.
Luckily, the farm co-op
has a chopper.
Where are
her parents now?
Following behind
in their truck.
They'll be a couple of hours,
but they've given consent for
any treatment Abby may need.
Okay.
Oh, man.
How did this happen?
Abby works on her family farm.
Her leg got caught
in the hydraulic bucket
of a skid steer.
What's that?
A machine
used to feed cattle.
My uncle has a farm.
And why was this little girl
allowed anywhere near
dangerous machinery?
Look, her father was
working the skid steer.
Abby was trying
to climb aboard
when her leg slipped.
Okay, um...
get me X-rays of the leg,
chest, and pelvis.
After that, get me a CT
angiogram of the leg, please.
And another 50 mics
of fentanyl, please.
Got it.
Hang in there
for me, Abby.
You're all right.
Seeing a laceration
on the crown.
Um, add a CT head,
abdomen, and pelvis.
You know what,
let's just plan on
going to 2.0. Let's go.
2.0?
Surgical suite.
You still think
you can save her leg?
Well, I'm not sure yet.
We'll see. Come on.
Let's go.
Breath for me, Deanna.
Again.
Okay. Clear on
both sides.
When did you
start throwing up?
Yesterday.
But I've been really nauseous
for a couple of days.
Hmm. You weighed in
today at 112.
You were 131
at your last physical.
That's a pretty significant
decrease at your height.
I didn't realize
I'd lost that much.
I've had very little appetite
the last couple of months.
Oh, yeah?
You want to tell me
why that might be?
Uh, my daughter, Olivia,
she lives with me.
She's been going through
some health issues.
I'm pretty stressed out
about that.
Yeah, kids.
Tell me about it.
I'm gonna be sick.
All right. Basin.
All right. We're gonna
figure this out.
Uh, chest X-ray,
blood cultures,
and, uh,
CT abdomen, pelvis.
Dr. Charles.
Oh. They told us that
you had the day off.
Dr. Cuevas told me
you guys were here,
and so I just...
I thought I'd check in.
Appreciate it.
Thank you.
David, how are you?
What's up? How you, uh...
How you feeling?
I, um...
I took the liberty.
This is your...
your drink of choice,
isn't it?
He's been refusing
to eat or drink anything.
Huh.
Why, uh... Why is that?
There's no point.
You know, Dr. Cuevas
said that you told her
that you were dead.
I'm really sorry
to hear that. Um...
How's that feel?
What's it like?
What do you think
it's like?
Honestly, I have no idea.
That's why I'm asking.
It's like...
Like my insides are rotting.
Wow. That sounds awful.
It is awful. I hate it.
Well, maybe there's
something we can
do about that.
I'm not taking any more pills.
I hate the way they
make me feel.
David, please. We should
listen to Dr. Charles.
I won't do it.
You can't make me.
Hey, um, could we just
step outside for
a quick second?
David, hang in there.
I'll be right back, all right?
Be right back, honey.
You know, I was looking
at David's chart,
and he apparently
just had a birthday,
and that was 18,
which means
he's legally an adult.
If he doesn't want to
take medication,
then he...
He has the right
to refuse it.
How is that possible?
You heard the things
that he was saying in there.
Well, despite
his delusion,
he made it very clear
that he doesn't like the way
the pills make him feel.
Now, look. David can
barely keep it together
with medication.
What's he gonna be like
without it?
Dr. Charles,
he thinks he's dead.
Look, I understand
how frustrating this is.
But patients' rights
in this country
are extraordinarily robust,
even if the patient
happens to be having
a mental health crisis.
So you're saying that there's
absolutely nothing to be done?
What I'm saying is
that we, uh...
We have to reconsider
our tactics.
Okay.
Hey. Got your CT scans
here, Deanna.
Okay. So as you can
see right here,
there's a blockage
of some kind
that's amassed
in your stomach.
Cancer?
From the looks of it,
I would say that
it is not, no.
Oh, thank God.
But, uh, whatever it is,
it does not belong in there,
and needs to come out
immediately.
Does that mean surgery?
Yes, a laparotomy.
We have to open your stomach
to get it out.
It's scary,
but it's a procedure
I've done many times.
I guess if it
has to be done...
It does.
So I will call up to the OR,
make sure they're
ready for us.
And if you need,
I can contact your daughter.
No.
I'll call her myself. Uh...
She has her own
health issues to deal with.
I don't want her
to be alarmed.
No fractures
on the X-rays and CT.
Most of the leg muscles
are still intact.
Yeah.
She might have adequate
motor function. That's okay.
Her sensory function,
that's almost gone.
2.0, show us the CT angiogram.
CT angio.
Sagittal subtraction roadmap.
What was that?
2.0's AI.
Wow. That's amazing.
The SFA and pop
look intact.
Yeah, but I'm not
seeing any blood flow
below the trifurcation.
2.0, can you confirm?
7% percent blood flow
to the foot.
Only 7%?
Afraid so.
So you have to amputate.
Sadly, I'm not seeing
another option.
I'll call the parents.
This never should
have happened.
Dr. Archer,
I got your page.
Dr. Cuevas, are you
familiar with the term bezoar?
Bezoar?
Yes. It's a mass
of foreign material
that accumulates
in the stomach.
Hmm. Very good.
Behold, the bezoar I found
in my patient, Deanna.
It's a giant hairball.
Hair?
Yeah.
Obviously, she's been
snacking on it.
Oh, my God.
The question is, why has
she been eating her hair?
When I'm done here,
you can help figure that out,
'cause it's now a psych case.
Okay.
Hey, Maggie.
How's Abby doing?
Well, Dr. Marcel said
he has to amputate.
Oh, that's awful.
Yeah. I just called her
parents to tell them.
They're still a ways away,
so I'm gonna stick around
and be here for them
when they get here.
That's good.
Maybe it'll help
to see a friendly face.
Yeah.
Hey, you mentioned
your uncle has a farm.
Yeah, in Sheffield.
Oh, yeah.
He raises
chicken and cattle.
When I was growing up,
I'd love spending
the summers
just working alongside
him and my cousins.
Yeah. It's a different world
out there in farm country.
Yeah.
I hate to see what
this is going to do
to Abby and her family.
Look, I can
tell you this.
From what I know
about Abby over
the years I've treated her,
she's got heart.
She'll overcome this.
Leg or no leg, nothing's
gonna keep her down.
Well, that's good.
Madeline?
Uh, DCFS was notified of
a potential child abuse case.
I don't know anything
about that.
Dr. Marcel made the call.
Well, there must be
some sort of confusion.
Where's Dr. Marcel?
He's not here,
but I'll track him down
and get to the bottom of it.
You can go back
to your office,
and I'll call you
when I get something.
Okay. Let me know.
Yeah.
Child abuse?
This wasn't child abuse.
I know.
Why would Dr. Marcel
do that?
I'm gonna find out.
Crockett?
Yeah?
I need to talk to you.
I'm about to
operate, Maggie.
Why did you call DCFS?
Because it's
my legal obligation
as a mandated reporter, okay?
Come on.
It was an accident.
Yeah, well,
there's no reason a child
should have been anywhere
near a machine like that.
You don't know what
it's like on a family farm.
Kids work.
It's part of the culture.
Well, maybe it shouldn't be,
because this little girl
is about to lose her leg
as a result of her parents'
negligence.
Crockett, I know how these
DCFS investigations play out.
If Abby and her parents
get separated,
it could be impossible
to get them back together.
Please. Call off
Madeline Gastern.
Where are we?
Whenever you're
ready, Doctor.
Crockett.
Maggie, I'd appreciate it
if you'd leave.
Okay.
That's odd.
Her foot color looks better.
Yes, it does.
I'm feeling a good pulse.
How's that possible,
given the lack of blood flow
on the CT angiogram?
Maybe the vessels
in her leg
were spasming
due to the shock
of the accident.
2.0, what's your assessment?
Given change in exam,
three-vessel spasm likely.
Then this pulse means
the spasm must have broken.
All right, let's shoot
an on-table angiogram.
Maybe Abby doesn't have
to lose her leg after all.
Walter, what's going on?
Ah, it's my back.
Itches like crazy.
Open that up a little.
Yeah, you've developed
a rash back here.
You've never had an allergic
reaction to antibiotics
before, have you?
No, never.
Let's get a differential
to the CBC, lymphocytes,
and monocytes.
Could infection from
the cut have caused this?
I doubt it.
But, uh, this next set
of tests will tell us.
Go easy on that, okay?
Okay.
Hair?
That is so strange.
Yeah. And quite
a bit of it, too,
which is why I asked
Dr. Cuevas to join us.
Psychiatry?
Yes.
But there's no reason
to be alarmed.
We just want to help.
There is a condition
called trichophagia,
where a person compulsively
eats their hair.
Okay. No. No.
Dr. Archer mentioned
that you've been under
a lot of stress recently.
And I ask because this
compulsion can be triggered
by feelings of anxiety.
I do not eat my hair.
It's actually not
that uncommon.
Over a million people
in the U.S...
Well, I am not
one of them.
I think this
conversation is over.
Deanna...
No.
Please leave.
Okay.
And listen,
my daughter is on her way
in here soon.
I do not want you
mentioning this to her.
Of course.
We will respect
your wishes.
That is the second patient
today I have struck out with.
Hey, you tried.
You mind if I, uh,
run something by you?
Whatever it is,
I won't do it.
That's, uh,
completely up to you.
I'd just appreciate it
if you'd hear me out,
'cause it's...
I don't know,
it's conceivably
something that could...
get you back on track.
I can't be fixed.
Nothing will change
the fact that I'm dead.
No argument there.
What?
Well, look.
My primary concern is your...
Is your well-being,
you know, your...
Your state of mind.
And you made it
very clear that you
did not at all like the way
that this made you feel.
So I'm just wondering if...
I don't know,
there might be something
that could move you on
to the next phase,
you know, to...
To a new life,
a life after death,
if you will,
a different life.
David, have you ever heard
of something called ECT,
or electroconvulsive therapy?
Like, electricity?
Life after death?
What, you mean...
You mean, like Frankenstein?
Well, actually, yeah.
I mean, kind of like
Frankenstein.
I mean,
didn't Dr. Frankenstein
jolt electricity into
his creature to, you know,
to reanimate it?
'Cause frankly,
that's kind of
what I'm hoping ECT
might do for you.
Is that something
that you might...
Might think about?
I'd definitely consider it.
Okay, good.
Excuse me,
I'm all turned around.
How do I get to
the intensive care unit?
My mom just
got out of surgery.
Name's Deanna Brooks.
Oh, hey. No, I got this.
Hi, you must be
her daughter, Olivia.
I'm Dr. Archer.
I treated your mother.
She's doing well.
Oh, I'm so glad
to hear that.
Yeah. She's upstairs
in the ICU,
and the elevator's
just around the corner.
Trini, can you
do me a favor?
Could you please
take Miss Brooks
up to her mother
in the ICU?
Of course.
Right this way.
Thank you.
Sure.
Are you thinking
what I'm thinking?
Yeah.
Dr. Halstead, the lab
just sent Walter Crotty's
latest results.
Thanks, Nancy.
Bad news?
I thought I had my
patient's diagnosis pegged.
But he got this weird rash,
and I can't figure out why.
You know, I created
a diagnostic search engine
optimized to take account
of irregular symptoms.
Why am I not surprised?
You have some time
to help me out?
Sure.
I'll run your patient's
charts and labs
and see what comes up.
Send them to me.
Great. On their way.
Stick around.
Almost there.
Okay.
Tularemia, streptococcus,
lymphadenitis,
cat scratch fever,
tuberculosis,
meningococcemia,
and then there's plague.
Plague? Bubonic plague?
Yes, but the odds are
considerably lower
than for the others.
Wait. Plague is flea-borne.
Walter's red bumps
could be flea bites, but...
when was the last case
of recorded plague?
Actually, just six weeks ago.
Sacramento.
Walter mentioned
he just got back from
a hiking trip in Yosemite.
Which is only a couple
of hours from Sacramento.
I'm going to have
the lab run a Gram stain
on Walter's blood.
I'm gonna reach out
to the CDC,
let them know we might have
an outbreak on our hands.
Dr. Archer, hi.
Hi.
This is my colleague,
Dr. Cuevas.
I got a page that you
wanted to talk to me?
I did.
My mom's still
pretty tired.
Well, that's normal
after surgery.
Right.
Mmm-hmm.
I guess I'm sort of rattled.
She won't say much
about her procedure,
only that you removed
some sort of blockage,
but that's it.
Can you fill me in
on what happened?
Well, I'm sorry,
but it's up to your mother
to share those
details with you.
Every time I ask,
she just changes
the subject.
Turns it back to me.
You know, your mom
mentioned that you have
some health issues.
Do you mind sharing
a little bit about that?
Sure.
I was diagnosed with
breast cancer six months ago.
Just finished
my fifth round of chemo.
The cancer hasn't spread,
and my oncologist
has been very positive
so far, so I'm hopeful.
Sounds like you have
every reason to be.
Thanks.
Sorry to make you
come up here,
go out of your way.
No, not at all.
Thank you.
CDC says until we know
the results of Walter's labs,
we need to cordon him off
and limit contact
with anyone else.
I'll let the nursing
staff know.
Hey, Doris.
Have you seen Maggie?
We need to restrict
all access to
treatment three.
What's going on?
Uh, potential contagion.
I'm waiting on the lab
to confirm it,
but steer clear
for the time being, okay?
Okay. Yeah. Um,
I'll let the nurses know.
You okay?
Something on my neck
is driving me nuts.
Can I take a look?
Yeah.
Grace.
Doris, let's get in the room.
Oh, okay.
It's a rash,
like my patient.
Couldn't be spreading
that quickly.
Let me see.
What is "it"?
And... And what does "it"
have to do with my neck?
Have you been in
treatment three today?
Have you had any interaction
with my patient, Walter?
No. I... I've been turning
over rooms all day
because the replacement
janitors aren't doing squat.
All right.
What's happening to me, Will?
Incubation period
for the bubonic plague
is two days, so...
Bubonic plague?
Uh, no. Can't be.
Yeah, no.
Wait.
What are you doing?
Unbelievable.
No, I know exactly
what this is.
Hey, Sharon.
How great is this,
twice in one day?
I'm sorry, George.
We have a serious problem.
Oh?
Take a look.
Okay. I'm not understanding
what I'm looking at.
Eggs.
Eggs?
Eggs, George,
from bedbugs.
One of my doctors just took
this picture in our ED.
It seems the re...
The replacement janitors
have not been properly
changing sheets, or...
Or sanitizing the rooms.
Oh, no.
A patient
has developed a rash
from a bug bite.
So has a nurse,
and it remains
to be seen who's next.
This strike needs to end.
Jack's not gonna give in
unless he gets more
concessions from the union.
He says we can't afford to.
And what about liability
lawsuits from patients?
Can we afford those?
Yeah.
I hear you.
I'll make sure Jack
understands what's at stake.
Mom's awake
and feeling pretty good,
so I'm getting a coffee.
My daughter just stepped out,
but she won't be long.
We actually
spoke to Olivia.
I asked you not to.
We didn't tell her a thing
about your condition.
However, she did mention
that she's been undergoing
chemotherapy
for the last six months.
It's been
a very difficult time.
I have no doubt,
and I'm very sorry.
But it seems like
around the time
Olivia started losing
her hair from the chemo,
you began having
stomach issues.
Deanna, we believe you
that you haven't been
eating your hair,
but you were eating
your daughter's hair,
weren't you?
Her hair started falling out.
It was on her pillowcase
and her sheets, and...
seeing it there,
my baby's hair...
my heart would pound
in my chest.
My whole body would tremble.
It just... It was unbearable.
And eating her hair
made you feel better?
I put some in my mouth
and chewed it, and I felt...
I felt better.
When I swallowed it,
those awful feelings...
went away.
So as she kept losing it,
I kept eating it.
Mom, what's wrong?
Excuse us.
Mom.
Honey, I need
to tell you something.
So we're going to send
a mild electrical current
through David's brain,
which is going to cause
a brief seizure.
Won't that hurt him?
He'll be under general
anesthetic the whole time.
He won't feel a thing.
Look, we want to do
whatever it takes
to help our son, but...
But shock therapy?
I don't know. I don't know.
It just feels so extreme.
I completely understand
why you feel that way,
because of the way
the procedure has been
portrayed in the media.
You know?
But the truth is
is that modern ECT is
safer than ever before,
and has proven
to be very effective
against certain
treatment-resistant disorders,
schizophrenia among them.
You know, in many patients,
it seems to have the ability
to press a reset button
in the brain.
Anyway, gonna get going,
and I'll check back.
Okay.
All right.
How you doing, pal?
You ready?
Okay. I want you to
count backwards from 10
for me, all right?
Ten, nine,
eight, seven...
Tourniquet looking good.
Keep the paralytic
out of that leg.
Set.
Okay.
Here we go.
Abby!
You okay, pumpkin?
Dr. Marcel says I will be.
Yeah. She'll need more
surgeries in the future,
but, uh...
I'm hopeful Abby
will eventually make
a full recovery.
Thank you for everything.
And thank you,
Dr. Johnson,
for making sure
she got the best care.
Daddy?
What is it?
It's my fault.
What?
No, it...
It was an accident.
You told me
to stay back, but I...
I didn't listen.
You're gonna be okay.
That's all that matters.
But my leg, it's so bad.
I can't help.
Pumpkin, you don't need
to worry about that.
Your mom and I have
got the farm covered.
Honey, you just think
about getting better, okay?
You were supposed to
get back to me, Maggie.
Yeah, I'm sorry.
That was...
That was my fault.
I misjudged the situation.
And how exactly
did that happen?
Well, I didn't have
all the information
when I called.
I really don't like my time
being wasted, Dr. Marcel.
And I'm very sorry
about all that.
You need to get
your act together.
Indeed, we do.
I don't know, I...
I guess I had
blinders on today.
All I could see
was another kid
suffering abuse, you know?
Mmm. Turned out okay.
You saved a leg,
and a family, too.
Thank you.
David, how are you...
How are you doing?
How you feeling?
Um, don't know.
I feel kind of different.
Okay.
Voices? Any...
Any voices?
Actually, I... I can't
really hear them right now.
Huh.
Mom?
I'm just...
I'm so happy, honey.
I'm just really happy.
Hydrocortisone should
relieve some of the itching
and swelling.
Whatever.
Hey, good news,
your white cell
count is down,
and your blood sugar
is back where it should be.
Antibiotics and insulin
did their job.
That's a silver lining,
I guess.
You know,
I used to be so impressed
with this hospital.
Sorry, Walter.
I'll go put in
your discharge paperwork.
Mmm-hmm.
How's it going down here?
Patient's upset,
and I can't say I blame him.
But he'll be okay.
Well, hopefully,
we can put this behind us.
The board and the union
just reached an agreement
on a new contract.
Housekeeping staff will
be back at work tomorrow.
I'm so proud
of each of you. We did it.
Liliana!
Oh, just a minute.
I'm so sorry.
I did not mean to desert you
for the entire day.
I understand.
You do?
He was your patient.
You had to help.
Oh, thank you.
Oh, my...
Congratulations!
New contract!
I'm going with my friends
to celebrate. Come!
Oh, no. Your victory,
your party.
Have a good time.
No. No, Daniel.
You have to come.
You're my boyfriend.
I am?
Yeah.
Oh. Well, when you
put it that way...
I'd show you my room,
but we're not allowed
to have visitors
up there.
Yeah.
This is where we usually
have our meetings.
Yeah. It's, uh...
it's nice.
Thanks for
letting me come by.
It's almost curfew, but...
I think we still have
time to make coffee.
Oh, no, no, no.
It's fine.
It's, uh...
It won't take that long.
Uh, I don't like the way
I left things earlier.
Um, kind of ran out.
Oh, it's no big deal.
Yeah, it is. It is to me.
It... It is.
Uh...
All right. Uh...
Okay, so, uh...
So you mentioned
your mother.
All I ever wanted
when you were a kid
was to get her
to stop drinking.
But she wouldn't.
She couldn't. She couldn't.
And, uh, I didn't know
what to do.
And then, you know,
you started having your...
Your problems, and, uh...
guess I just
sort of checked out.
And, uh...
I wasn't there for you guys.
I just... I wasn't.
And, uh, I...
I should have tried harder.
And instead,
I just got angry,
you know?
And I tried to just
push it all away.
And I ended up pushing you,
my own son, away.
And, uh...
I don't know if
I'll ever be able
to say this to her,
or when.
But, Sean, I wasn't
there for you.
I wasn't there.
Dad,
you're here now.
Am I?