♪♪
Scientists have
published studies
about how
the practice of gratitude
improves
mental and physical health.
♪ It's a new day
♪ In the best way Oh, my.
♪ Take a picture
and we put it in a cool frame ♪
A daily gratitude practice
reduces depression
and increases happiness.
♪ We can see that
♪ We've always been heading
towards the right track ♪
♪ Look at us, look at us,
look at us ♪
♪ Feeling so elated
♪ Look at us, look at us,
look at us ♪
Gratitude enhances empathy,
which helps build
positive relationships.
Okay, I entered
the latest data,
I updated Hamilton,
and I checked the cells
on the columnar injection.
Yeah, I don't think you get
how holidays work.
Name a surgeon who does.
Look, I'm headed up
to the cabin for two whole days,
and it's beautiful
up there.
Fireplace, lot of snow,
zero dead animals on the wall.
It even lowers blood pressure.
You're very --
That's very tempting.
I need to get home
to my kids.
Oh, did you think
I was inviting you?
I was trying to talk my way
out of inviting myself.
♪ We're looking, we're looking
Thanks for the ride.
I mean, are you sure?
There's --
I mean, the weather's
getting bad here.
Happy Thanksgiving.
If giving thanks
is so good for you,
why do so many people
struggle doing it?
♪ Hey, hey, hey
♪♪
♪ There's no one stopping us
♪ We're looking,
we're looking up ♪
Maybe this will help
keep you awake after your shift.
What's after my shift?
I don't know. Just...me.
Webber chose me
to work on Thanksgiving,
which has to be
a precursor
to becoming chief resident,
right?
I mean, I've been crushing
my solo surgeries --
Honey! Levi!
Levi Schmitt?
Am I having a stroke?
Or is my --
Mom?
What are you doing
here?
Bringing Thanksgiving dinner.
Nico, I brought some
for you, too.
Oh, thank you,
Mrs. Schmitt.
Mom, I'm working.
I'm literally going down
to the ER right now.
I'll wait.
I'll set everything up,
and then you can come up here
and eat whenever you're hungry.
I --
What, you think
I'm going to let my son
not eat
Thanksgiving dinner?
Go. Save lives.
I'll be here.
Okay, I'll --
Okay!
I'm not technically
supposed to be working.
I can hang out with her.
No.
She'll never set you free.
Happy Thanksgiving,
Bailey.
Sure.
Oh. I thought you had plans
with your family.
I did.
Then Dean Miller's father
showed up at the station
and took Pru home with him.
Mm.
We don't have enough doctors
on a regular day,
so I'm working.
Oh, me, too.
You're hoping the stupidity
of the human race
on a day filled with
alcohol and cooking
will bring you
a good, bloody surgery.
It's a tradition,
Bailey.
I cut on Thanksgiving.
Just not a turkey.
Dr. Riker to Radiology.
Hey.
What are you doing here?
I wanted to go and check in
on Farouk.
No, no, no, no, no.
We had a plan.
We have a plan. I'm staying here
with Megan and Farouk
and you are going home
to cook Thanksgiving
with your mom and the kids.
B-But my ex-lap just went longer
than I thought,
I took a shower,
and now --You're not following
the plan.
Hey.
Mom's gonna kill you.
Then it'll be
a traditional family affair.
Hey.
So, how are
the lungs sounding today?
Much better. The wound infection
seems to have cleared up.
We'll start weaning him off
the drips today.
So I get to go home
in two days?
Mnh.
Three days?
We need to give your heart
time to adapt, Farouk.
But I've already been here
for three weeks.
Can I at least have
some pie?
Of course you can.
You know what? If you don't
mind, I might even join you.
My kids are down with their aunt
in San Diego.
You know what? We should have
the entire meal right here.
Picnic in peds until
the nurses throw us out.
I'll raid the chemo floor
and see if I can find
some board games.
Bring Monopoly.
Dibs on the dog.
You do understand that you
actually have to cook the meal
to bring it here
for us to eat it?
Okay, your mom is now
texting question marks.
You have to go.
Do you --
Do you hear something?
Hey, do you want to see
if we can find
the Thanksgiving parade?
Yes.
Let's do it. Okay.
There we go.
Okay, now you can go.
What? I --Okay.
No, I want to see the --
Bye!
It's still early, sir.
People have just started
drinking,
deep fryers
haven't exploded yet,
and people have spent more than
a year away from each other.
They'll need a little longer
to start fighting.
You're saying give it time.
They'll come.
My mom did.
Mine!
Wha-- I --
Ma'am! Ma'am! Ma'am!
Ma'am!
You can't park there!
I'm sorry.
I only have about an hour
before I have to get back
and serve my pecan pie,
'cause if my husband cuts it,
there'll be only four slices
for a family of 12,
and I made two.
Here. Southern girl.
I don't go anywhere on
Thanksgiving empty-handed.
Homemade crust.
Okay, but you'll still need
to move the car --
Ohh.
I'm sorry.
If -- If someone could just
check me out really fast
before my kids notice
I'm gone.
Ohh.
If this is surgical,
can I scrub in?
Get a gurney, Schmitt!
And move the damn car!
I am exactly like
my mother.
I'm in a hotel room, missing
the holiday with my family,
and I'm eating
stale nuts for dinner.
From what I've heard, Ellis Grey
wouldn't have made it home
even if it were
blue skies and sunny.
You're not helping.
That's because we're fine.
I will cook.
That sounds dangerous.
Hi, Mom.
Hi, Zola.
I'm so sorry.
It's okay.
You tried to get here.
And Thanksgiving isn't really
a holiday we should celebrate.
There's no actual evidence
Native Americans
were even invited to a feast.
Mm-hmm.
I think they cared more
about being colonized
and having their land stolen
than mashed potatoes.
I'm sorry you're alone
and eating peanuts, though.
Love you!
I love you, Zola.
Love you.
♪♪
Hey.
Happy Thanksgiving.
There's my little turkey.
Hi.
Uh...
Meredith is stuck
in Minnesota.
Snowstorm,
no flights out.
Um, same with Maggie and Winston
in Boston.
Climate whiplash.
Oh. So you're...
In charge of four children
and Thanksgiving dinner, yeah.
Oh, it's fine.
You don't have to
change your plans.
My plans?
What should I do --
reschedule my dinner
at home alone
or my depressing movie
marathon?
You, uh -- You were gonna
spend today alone?
Jo, uh, didn't even realize
it was Thanksgiving,
so she took a shift,
and, uh,
Scout was gonna be here
with you, so...
And I do not want to
become my parents
and make Scout shuffle
between dinner with you
and dessert with me
on the holidays, so...
May as well figure out
how to do this now.
You're also terrified
you're gonna ruin the turkey,
aren't you?
I followed every instruction
in this cookbook,
and it all still feels wrong.
♪♪
What do we got?
Ashley Wright, 40, G-5, P-4,
31 weeks along,
hypotensive,
pulse 138 and thready,
febrile, complains of abdominal
pain and nausea, vomiting.
She collapsed outside
on arrival.
Is my baby okay?
We're checking right now.
How long have you been
having pain for?
Oh, I don't know.
A few days? A week?
Maybe a little more.
Did you see your OB
at any time during this?
I've got four kids
at home already,
my in-laws are in town
on open-ended tickets,
and everyone's always hungry
or out of toilet paper
or unable to
get on the Wi-Fi.
And I thought it was just
heartburn from the pregnancy.
Heartburn can cause pain
but shouldn't cause a fever.
Baby is fine.
Fetal heart rate is stable.
Still no sign
of contractions.
I'm seeing free fluid
in the right upper quadrant.
We're gonna have to
take a closer look to confirm.
Ashley, I don't want to expose
your baby to any radiation
with a CT scan,
but we can do an MRI.
It's safe?
Yes.
Would you like to call anybody?
Your husband?
No, no. Not yet.
I don't want to
interrupt the meal.
I worked
really hard on it.
Okay.
♪♪
Hey.
Hi.
So, I'm driving up to the cabin,
and I'm thinking --
That having Thanksgiving
by yourself is still lonely,
even if you pretend
it's your idea?
Oh, boy.
Someone's gone dark.
They canceled my flight
due to weather.
Wow.
You should have called me.
I did. It went
straight to voicemail.
Yeah, the reception
on this highway's pretty bad.
I'm sorry. You okay?
I am.
My children are taking it
better than I am.
Well, I got two hours
of winding road ahead of me,
if you want to
keep me company.
Okay.
Well, you're not
very good company.
Okay, I will start,
but before I do,
I just have to know,
is there such a thing
as too gross?
I cut people open
for a living.
Hey, look,
everyone's got their thing.
Okay, okay.
Toes.
Toes are off-limits.
Deal. No toes.
Okay.
Okay. So my first Thanksgiving
as a resident,
I'm working the ER when
two drunk brothers come in
after fighting over
who's gonna cut the turkey.
And one of them stabbed
the other one.
Close. Younger brother tried to
grab the knife,
which caused older brother
to completely slice off
his index finger.
Of course.
We asked him if they
brought the finger in
so we could try
re-attaching it,
but they said
they couldn't find it.
Naturally.
So we sewed him up,
we admitted him
for observation,
until a few hours later,
younger brother comes
right back in with the finger.
Oh, no. Where was it?
Gravy bowl.
Ugh!
They found it when Grandpa
ladled it onto his turkey.
No!
No, no, no.
Trauma one, let's go.
Male Patient:
Can someone --
Can someone call my wife?
Her name's Heather.
Okay.
What happened?
Bagger at a grocery store.
Passed out on the job.
Hypoxic and tachypneic.
What -- you know him?
I treated him
a couple months ago.
He's a vet.
Pulmonary fibrosis.
Noah, can you hear me?
Major Hunt.
I need your help.
Please, I need --
I need help.
It's okay, Soldier.
I'm here now, okay?
Let's go.
Ooh, looks like
Park Place, Teddy.
Time to pay up.
I got it.
Here, here, here,
here, here.
The graham crackers --
they got stuck in my throat.
I am fine.
And, Teddy,
you owe Dr. Hayes money.
Oh, I want to play
a different game!
That's just because
I'm winning.
No, it's just because
you're winning --
You forgot the two hotels.
Like that!
Still better than playing
with Owen.
When he was little
and he didn't win,
he would punch the wall.
I'll let you in on
a little secret.
Right after
my boys' mom died,
we used to make Friday night
our weekly games night,
and the winner got to pick
next week's pizza toppings.
Now, my boys love Hawaiian.
I can't stand fruit on a pizza.
That's disgusting.
It is.
It's an abomination.
So I had to develop a pretty
good strategy, you know?
What?
I'm sorry, um --
did you say "games" night?
With an "s"?
Yeah, games night.
You know,
when the family gets together
and play
a bunch of games?
I know what gamenight is.
Game night. Singular.
We played more than
one game.
It's still called
game night.
Respectfully disagree.
Uh-oh.
Hold on, Noah.
I know it hurts, okay?
Do we have the films?
Pneumo.
He's gonna need a chest tube,
breathing treatment,
and steroids.
Noah, I'm here.
Danny and I are here.
We came
as fast as we could.
No. Hey,
Danny shouldn't be here.
Honey, it's okay.
Is he okay?
Um...
His lung collapsed,
so we're gonna need to
insert a chest tube.
I'm also gonna run
some additional tests
to rule out infection.
Danny, I'm sorry.
We'll still make
the apple pie, okay?
I got all the ingredients.
We're almost finished
with his work-up.
If you want to wait in chairs,
we'll come get you.
Yeah.
Okay.
Dr. Hunt?
Yeah?
Can you do something
for me?
Anything.
Take my kid somewhere.
Take his mind off...
all of this, please?
Of course. Of course.
♪♪
How you doin', Ashley?
I'm laying down,
and it's quiet.
I don't remember
the last time.
My husband and I,
we always wanted a big family,
but when three became four
and then four became five...
I'm starting to feel like
I'm repopulating the Earth.
Have you ever considered
birth control?
Every time I think about it,
I'm pushing a baby out.
Always feels weird
asking for it then.
It's more common
than you think.
Ohh!
Ashley?
Oh!
The pain just got a lot worse!
Like, a 12
out of 1 to 10.
Scans are up.
Free fluid and
a possible abscess formation
in the right upper
quadrant.
It's her appendix. See?
Her uterus has pushed it
all the way up to the liver.
Ashley?
Yeah?
Your appendix
most likely perforated
and caused inflammation
in your abdomen.
You're gonna need surgery.
My appendix?
Dr. Schmitt is gonna
take you up to pre-op.
We'll call your husband
on the way.
Okay.
♪♪
Ooh, that is
my basting timer.
My hands are garlicky.
Can you grab that?
Oh, got it.
Okay.
Oh. Sorry.
What?
Nothing.
Link, what?
Is it burning?
No. You'd have to turn on
the oven for it to burn.
I didn't turn
the oven on?!
From the looks of it,
you turned it on,
but then at some point,
you turned it back off.
Oh, my God! And it's
the middle of the afternoon.
I can't start
the turkey now.
It's fine.
We'll order Chinese.
The kids are already bummed
enough that Meredith isn't here.
They need some normalcy.
Us fumbling in the kitchen
was normalcy for them
for months.
Um.
We will serve the traditional
Thanksgiving entrée of...
mac and cheese.
With a side of...
Bagel Bites.
And turkey for dessert.
Thank you.
Yeah.
9 out of 10 Thanksgivings
turn into impromptu
interventions for my sister,
which are about as fun
as you can imagine.
And Charlotte?
Charlotte learned the idea of
Friendsgiving pretty early on.
She saved herself
most of the drama,
which is a good thing.
She's at her roommate's
in Wichita right now.
She likes these big, weird,
loud, happy families.
It's the only time
she gets to experience that.
How close to the cabin
are you?
I'm close.
Close enough I can picture
the fireplace.
You didn't mention
there was a fireplace.
Oh, I did.
You just didn't want to
hear it.
I might be
regretting that decision.
Yeah, it's pretty special.
There's this sound that
comes over the frozen lake,
this cracking noise.
And every so often,
the fire crackles
right along with it.
And you're sitting there
under your blankets
with a whiskey,
watching the snow dance
on the window,
and everything
just feels still...
and right.
♪♪
Oh, that's...
the room service.
Stay right there.
Don't move.
♪♪
Hi.
You said "stay where you are,"
so...
♪♪
You turned around?
Yeah. I turned around.
♪♪
Do you want to come in?
Yes.
♪♪
We'll need to do
an open appendectomy
so that we can be sure
to wash out
as much of that infection
as possible.
I will be in the OR the entire
time to monitor the baby.
If we see
any signs of trouble,
we may need to do
an emergency C-section.
I have to consent
for a hysterectomy?
Unfortunately, if there is
an abnormal amount of bleeding
during the C-section,
it's possible the safest option
is to remove the uterus.
Because...?Richard:
If we're at that point,
we're making that decision
to save your wife's life.
Ashley...
we'll see you in the OR.
Sweetheart,
you're gonna be fine.
How many beers
have you had?
Two.
Minus half of one
I spilled.
Okay.
I want to ask Dr. Wilson...
If you have to deliver,
will you tie my tubes?
What?
A tubal ligation won't stop
the bleeding and --
No, I'm asking you to.
Please, if you don't have to
remove my uterus,
please at least tie my tubes.
Baby...
If we have any more kids,
I might die,
and if I die,
I don't know what the heck
all of you will do.
♪♪
It's just around here, okay?
Hold on.
Um, hey.
Hey, when you all
come back up here,
can you dress Allison
in her pajamas,
just in case
she falls asleep?
I mean, bedtime is gonna be
all over the place tonight.
Sure.
Thanks.
Farouk's in better spirits.
I'm just waiting for
his latest labs.
Mm.
Dr. Odell to...
Owen, are -- are you still
in the hospital?
Listen, Teddy, um...
Noah's back.
Is it bad?
Yeah.
I'll call you later, okay?
Hey, so, um...
do you like video games?
Yeah.
Okay.
You do? Okay.
You wanna play?
Oh, yeah.
You sure?
'Cause I'm good.
We'll see about that.
Let's play!
Okay.
Okay, here we go.
So, if you were at home,
what would you be doing?
I would have
gone grocery shopping,
and then I would be
sitting at my kitchen table
with the kids
while my sisters cook.
Mm.
Maggie likes to cook, so...
Got it.
I like to cook.
Oh, yeah?
Yeah, I do,
when I can take my time
and  --
and put on some music,
crack a beer,
cook outside on the grill.
When it's not
negative 10 degrees?
Yeah, I mean, yeah.
The menu changes
with the weather,
that's for sure.
But, I mean, to me,
cooking's a bit like surgery.
You have to know knife skills
and how to be in the moment.
I'm pretty good at both.
I'm getting better at it.
With your knife skills?
That's good.
It's about time.
No, being in the moment.
Right.
I think it was all those months
in the hospital.
It's strange, isn't it?
How laying in a bed,
staring up at
the fluorescent lights
can just -- phew --
completely change
your thinking.
I mean, when I got out,
Charlotte and surgery,
they were my only priorities.
You're grateful
for them.
I am.
And you?
What are you grateful for?
I'm grateful
that you're here.
And this wine, of course.
I'm grateful for the wine.
Mm.
♪♪
Who's ready
for Thanksgiving Bagel Bites?
I thought there was
a turkey.
There was, but, um...
I pardoned it.
What does "pardon" mean?
It means to forgive,
to let go.
Ellie, I pardon you
for breaking my Buzz Lightyear.
Aww, now, that's the spirit
of Thanksgiving.
What's an AVM?
An arteriovenous
malformation.
What does it do?
Well, it's when
your arteries and veins
get connected
by a tangle of blood vessels,
so it disrupts the normal blood
flow and oxygen circulation,
and it can bleed out
and cause trouble.
What's sex?
♪♪
Zola:
Baby is having
variable decels.
Okay, we'll try to go
as fast as we can. Suction.
Not sure if you're aware,
Dr. Webber,
but I've actually performed
quite a few appys
with hardly any supervision.
Oh, you're not gonna
take the lead, Schmitt.
Because
the patient's pregnant?
No, because
I am a man of tradition.
I don't watch surgery
on Thanksgiving.
I do it.
Wilson, how about you?
Any Thanksgiving
traditions?
Not exactly.Oh, come on.
You've had to
have something. Clamp.
My childhood was
such a trash dump,
I had to write the good things
on little scraps of paper
to remind myself
they even happened.
Then I would shove them into
an old takeout box
and read them on Thanksgiving
between sad chicken nuggets.
Damn it,
baby's lost variability
and is having
prolonged decels.
Heart rate's in the 80s.
He's in distress.
What do you want to do?
Let's get him out.
Prep for a C-section right now.
♪♪
I hope Owen eventually shows up
with some food.
I thought you hated
Thanksgiving.
I do.
I didn't have it for 10 years
and I never missed it.
I don't like turkey,
I hate forced togetherness...Mm.
...and the whole thing
makes me miss my Dad, so...
But Farouk loves the sides.
I'm avoiding your mother.
Because of Leo?
Yeah, just -- I'm worried
how she's gonna react
if he comes out in a dress
or in another one of his
princess costumes again.
Are you sure you don't want
to be home to intervene?
I love my son so much that
I am afraid my intervening
may cost my entire relationship
with your mom.
It doesn't matter.
He's your son.
You have to fight for him,
despite the cost.
Or you can
make Owen do it.
Oh.
He's in V-fib!
Get a crash cart in here.
Oh, my God, Farouk?
Farouk?!
Paddles and epi!
Page Dr. Hayes, now!
Oh, my God, Teddy.
♪♪
Come on. Come on.
Teddy, oh, my God!
Farouk, come on!
Oh, my God!
Come on!
♪♪
♪ Early in the morning
♪ I still get
a little bit nervous ♪
♪♪
♪ Fighting my anxiety
constantly ♪
♪ I try to control it
♪♪
♪ Even when I know
it's been forever ♪
♪ I can still feel the spin
♪♪
♪ Don't know if you get it
♪ 'Cause I can't express
how thankful I am ♪
♪♪
♪ That you were always with me
when it hurts ♪
♪ I know that you'd understand
♪♪
♪ I don't wanna lose control
We can't stop
this bleeding.
♪ I don't wanna lose control
Lap pad.
Clear!
What the hell happened?
He went into V-fib.
His dilated cardiomyopathy's
getting worse.
Charge to 200! Clear!
Okay. I'll take over.
♪ Nothing I can do anymore
We are not stopping.
Push epi again!
We are gonna get him back!
Alright, let me in.
Charge to 200!
Clear!
♪ Spinnin' out in space
pressing on my chest ♪
We're not gonna get
his heart back.
Yes, we will.
His heart is too damaged.
We are not gonna
get it back.
You've been running this code
for half an hour.
He's still in V-fib.
Megan, I think our only chance
is to put him on ECMO.
I'm continuing CPR.
Listen to me.
You are his aunt.
Megan, you are his mother.
I am his doctor.
I am telling you
this is where we are now.
♪ Spinnin' out in space
pressing on my chest ♪
Do it.
Prep him
for ECMO cannulation.
♪ I don't want to lose control
Come on.
Come on, Farouk.
♪♪
Oh. Is Levi coming?
Oh, he's still in surgery,
ma'am.
Oh.
I just thought you shouldn't
have to sit by yourself.
It's Thanksgiving.
Oh, that's nice, dear.
But no need to be so formal,
Nico.
You've slept in my basement.
And with the direction
this relationship is headed...
Um, ma'am --
uh, sorry -- Myrna.
Now, is this what I expected?
A husband for my only son
instead of a wife?
No.
But it is
every Jewish mother's desire
to have their kid
be a doctor.
Second best is for them
to marry a doctor.
And me? I get both!
I'm sorry.
Marry...?
So, will you raise
the children Jewish?
The children?
I know it's not my decision,
but my mother's name
was Beverly.
She went by Bev.
Bev could work for
either a boy or a girl.
It's, uh --
what do they call that?
Androgynous.
Is "Bev" androgynous?
I  --
I don't know.
Well, it's just something
for you to consider.
Now...do you have
any genetic markers
that we need to
be aware of?
Because Levi's great-grandfather
died of colon cancer.
♪♪
Yeah.
Hmm.
♪♪
♪ I'm in the building
and I'm feeling good ♪
What do you say, Ellie?
What do you say?
Come on, keep going.
Keep it going! Keep it going!
Show those moves.
Come on!
Oh, yeah. Whoo!
♪ She off the Richter scale,
she had me shook ♪
Alright, Ellie.
What you got?
♪ Now, I don't wanna come
in between ♪
You got this!
Alright, Bailey, you're up!
What you got, huh?
Keep moving!
Alright. What do you say,
Scout, huh?
Gonna break it down.
♪ Do you want to dance
to the music? ♪
♪ Do you wanna rock
to the beat of the drums? ♪
♪ Singin' sweet melodies
just for you and me ♪
♪ Baby, we should cut a rug
Ahh.
Alright, come on, guys.
What you got?
Old school? Old school?
You should be teaching me!
Mm.
Is it weird to eat burgers
on Thanksgiving?
You like the burger?
Yeah.
Then it's not weird.
If you like it,
you're happy eating it,
and that makes you thankful.
That's what
Thanksgiving's all about.
Doesn't matter what you eat.
Is there medicine
that can help my dad?
It's complicated.
I know my dad hurts
a lot.
He can't play baseball
with me anymore,
doesn't cut the grass,
and he breathes funny,
like
he can't...
And my mom cries a lot
in her closet.
♪♪
Your dad's really sick,
you know?
And that makes it
really tough,
especially for you
and your mom.
♪♪
Is my dad gonna die?
Not today.
I don't
want him to hurt anymore.
♪♪
Chest tube's in.
Noah's all bandaged up,
and someone from palliative care
is in speaking with him now.
Oh. I can also recommend
home nursing aides
that can help change
the dressing,
if it's too much.
Mnh.
Uh, no,
that's not, um...
I'm okay with that.
Okay.
I just --
I should have never let him
take a job.
He was bagging groceries,
on his feet for hours at a time,
lifting things.
He was in no physical shape
to work, but...the bills.
He's...
d-d-dying.
Literally drowning
in his own breath,
and I'm falling apart
in a hallway.
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
No.
No, no, no, no.
Come. Come. Come.
Okay.
Now, fall apart.
What?
Yeah. Cry. Um, scream.
Punch the bed.
I-I'd give you something
to break,
but I don't have anything
on me.
Yes, your husband is dying.
Your son is gonna
lose his father, and it's --
it's unfair.
It's devastating,
and you deserve to feel that.
♪♪
I need to go
back in there.
And you will,
but everyone around you
gets to fall apart.
Take your turn.
♪♪
Thank you.
Uh...
You said "were."
What do you mean?
You said
Charlotte and surgery...
Yeah?
...were
your priorities.
Right.
I mean,
priorities can change.
♪ Oooh, hoo, ooh
♪ Oooh, hoo
♪ Ooh, hoo
♪♪
♪ You know I love
your wounded heart ♪
♪ With all those scars
♪ Where you were torn apart
♪ Torn apart
♪ When those shadows fall
♪ Oh, you stand so tall
♪ You rise above
♪ And you raise me up
♪ Ooh, ooh
♪ Ooh, ooh, you elevate me
♪♪
♪ You elevate me, yeah
♪ Ooh, ooh
♪ Ooh, ooh, you elevate me
♪ You elevate me
♪ Ooh, you elevate me, yeah
♪ Ooh, ooh
♪♪
Okay, so, Nurse Karen just took
Danny to get some ice cream.
They'll be back in a minute.
Thanks.
Listen, about...Roy.
I don't want to
talk about Roy.
I just want to say that
I'm taking up his work.
I started a study.
I'm gonna write all the reports.
I'm gonna go to D.C.
I am all in.
I'm going to figure out
a way to take care of everyone.
How much longer?
For what?
Till this is over.
I-I-I can't do it anymore.
I can't put my family
through this much longer.
Noah, it's okay.
No, it's not.
I ruined my kid's Thanksgiving
and...
I --
I don't want to
ruin Christmas.
Everything hurts,
and the hospital bills...
When is this gonna be over?
Please.
Soon.
It'll be over soon.
♪♪
I just want to go home.
Okay.
♪ Keep on falling,
keep falling ♪
♪ Keep on falling down,
falling down ♪
♪♪
♪ Keep on swinging
♪ Keep swinging
♪ Keep on striking out,
striking out ♪
♪ Deep down, you believe it
♪♪
♪ Deep down, you can see that
♪ You got what it takes
♪ I know what you're made of
♪ Let go of the fear
that haunts you now ♪
♪ Step out from the shadows
♪ There is hope to fight for
♪ You've got what it takes
Your baby boy's
doing great.
He's upstairs in a NICU
for monitoring,
and you can visit him tonight
if you want.
Thank you.
And Ashley?
During the C-section,
we encountered
a lot of bleeding.
We had to do
an emergent hysterectomy.
But she's gonna be okay?
It'll be a longer recovery,
but, yes, she will be okay.
♪♪
Why didn't she tell me?
If she wanted to be done
with having kids...
if it was too much for her,
if she was in pain...
why didn't she tell me?
I want to take care of her.
♪♪
All I've ever wanted to do
is take care of her.
♪♪
Our society doesn't give women
a lot of permission
to talk about what they want,
to talk about what they need,
to ask for help.
Maybe don't wait for her
Maybe just...help.
♪ Step out from the shadows
♪ There is hope to fight for
♪ You've got what it takes
♪♪
So I hear this crash,
and I run into the kitchen,
and Levi is covered in flour
and he says,
"Mom, maybe we should
buy the crust."
Hey. You two have dinner?
Uh, yeah. Your mom's
noodle kugel's delicious.
Well, nothing like
a Thanksgiving kugel.
I saved you a plate,
sweetheart.
You're not gonna eat
with me?
I'm stuffed.
Plus, I made
an extra pumpkin pie
to take
to your Aunt Mimi's.
Hers is always too dry.
Happy Thanksgiving,
sweetheart.
Come by and see me sometime,
okay?
You, too. Anytime.
You don't have to
just come with Levi.
♪♪
So, what did you guys
talk about?
You.
I now know literally everything
about you.
♪♪
Mmm. That's good.
Bailey?
I'm fine.
Miranda?
No. It's Pru.
She's only 2 years old.
2!
And she's already
going through a grief
that I didn't experience
until only a year ago.
It's hard to lose a parent
at any age.
It's a specific pain,
and it sticks with you
for the rest of your life.
I just want to hold her
and tell her everything's
gonna be alright,
but now I don't even know
if that's gonna happen anymore.
And I-I know it's selfish,
which is why I'm crying at work,
which is embarrassing.
♪♪
Come on.
Richard, I don't...
♪♪
Is that pecan pie?
Southern home cooking.
Come with me.
I --
♪♪
Okay, thank you.
What happened?
He coded. Heart failure.
We put him on ECMO,
and I just got off the phone
with the heart transplant
coordinator.
He needs to go on
the transplant list?
It's the only thing
left to do.
I'm sorry.
♪♪
Kids are asleep.
Is that turkey
finally done?
It's all carved
and put away.
And, Amelia...
it's freakin' delicious.
That might be the nicest thing
anyone's ever said to me.
Link, today was...
You are nothing like
your parents.
Mm. Mm.
Mm.
Link, uh...
Nothing has changed
for me.
♪♪
Why do we
only designate
one day a year
to give thanks?
I'm sorry about Seattle.
♪ Soft static
on the TV screen ♪
I'm sorry about the cabin.
You know, when this stuff
clears in the morning,
we could always --
Yes.
♪ Young people
on the livestream ♪
Yeah?
♪♪
Yes.
After everything
we've been through,
why not celebrate the good
every day?
We've been eating it
all day.Yeah.
Hug your loved ones.
You're gonna...
Smile at a stranger.
♪ That watching people
watch people ♪
Oh!
♪ Is the future
of our collective dream ♪
Choose kindness.
Ooh.
That looks so good.
Mm, yes.
So, um...
Even if we're working,
even if we're not
in the mood to celebrate...
♪ Nothing's ever gonna be
the same ♪
...and even if traditions
are not your thing...
...it's important that
we're together.
♪ It's all quiet
on the chain gang ♪
Do you still have
your pieces of paper?
Mm-hmm.
Okay.
Uh, Schmitt,
you want to take the lead?
I am thankful for Nico.
♪ You tried building
the Tower of Babel ♪
I wrote "toast."
I didn't realize we were
being sentimental,
but I am thankful...
...for Levi.
I am thankful for Luna.
Oh, I didn't
even see -- Hi!
♪ It's impossible to miss
Hello. Hi, honey.
Well, I am thankful that,
this year,
we had more saves
than losses,
and I am thankful that...
♪ All the little people...
...well,
that we're still here.
Mm.
♪ ...playing
all their little games ♪
What's the worst
that could happen?
Well, I am thankful
for Richard Webber.
Richard. Richard.
Yeah.
Yes!
And this pie!
Can we eat?
Yes, let's dig in.
I'm starving!
Alrighty.
Yes. Yes. Oh, thank you.
Wow, look at all this.
Man.
My mom made the kugel.
Oh. Okay.
You got to have it.
Made the what?
The kugel, right here.
Have you never had
kugel?
Uh...Here, eat this one.
Okay.
Yes.
♪♪
Someone might do it in return.