Good morning.
That's your third ding.
Good morning. It's Carly.
She has arrived
at her pathology conference.
- Hmm.
Shaun, you need to text her back.
Her text wasn't a question,
it doesn't require a response.
True, but it sucks to be left hanging.
You didn't like how it felt when you
thought Carly was ignoring you.
"I have received your message." Sent.
Mm.
- You made me breakfast?
- Oh, God, no.
I ordered breakfast.
But I managed to keep it warm.
You don't have to do this. I'm fine.
- Did you get any sleep?
- I got enough.
Her death's not your fault.
She knew the risks, she made a choice
to save her baby.
I bet she'd make the same choice again,
even knowing how it would end.
Thank you.
Thanks for breakfast.
We do a complete enucleation
of the right eye,
then replace it
with the temporary implant,
- and in a few weeks...
- Know why blind people don't skydive?
It scares the hell out of the dog.
- Let the doctors finish, okay, bud?
- Yeah, cancer eye out, fake eye in.
Just like last time, I got it.
Check it out.
Moves and everything.
Can't even tell it's fake.
Very cool. Like a bionic superhero.
Yeah, my superpower
is tripping over stuff.
- What time is the surgery?
- Three o'clock.
Which means I've got six hours left
to blast some aliens.
♪ We've got to bring the resources ♪
♪ I wanna play it till the time comes ♪♪
If anyone utters the word "Bubble Girl,"
I will transfer to a different hospital.
When you were his age, would you
have faced going blind with humor,
uh, maturity and acceptance?
I would've burned things down.
He's dealing with it in his own way.
We'll check in while you're
taking care of paperwork.
Make sure Charlie knows there's
people he can talk to.
- Thank you.
Dr. Reznick, take Charlie's blood
to the lab.
Dr. Browne, talk to him,
maybe he'll open up to you.
Heart sounds are normal.
No sign of pericardial effusion.
You are the oldest SCID-patient
I am aware of.
People with your condition
usually die very young.
Yay. I win.
Tara, imaging confirms that you have
infected tissue on your right lung,
that's what's causing
your breathing issues.
We're gonna remove it with
a procedure called decortication...
And use the thorascopic approach
to decrease risk of infection.
I'll be in an enclosed chamber
in the OR. What else?
I assure you, we'll be taking
every precaution to keep you safe.
Dr. Melendez, this building
is a glorified incubator
for every infection on the planet.
Considering I don't come with an
immune system, I don't need assurances.
I need you to tell me
how you're gonna not kill me.
We will administer a course
of broad-spectrum antibiotics.
You will be transported to the OR
under a respiratory hood.
The room will be equipped
with laminar air flow
and kept at a positive pressure
of eight Pascals.
Surgical instruments will be
double-sterilized
- and blood products will be irradiated.
- Thank you, Dr. Murphy.
Visitors will also have to go
through a strict decontamination.
There won't be any.
The less time I spend with people,
the better. Are we done?
How'd your talk with Charlie go?
- He wants to be alone.
- No, you wanna be alone.
- Yet, here we are.
A precocious pre-teen going blind.
That's Claire catnip.
You have to talk to him.
- Did he have any tests scheduled?
- No.
No one's seen, heard, or smelled him.
I'm calling Security.
- Hold on.
- What are you doing?
- Where's Charlie?
- Did something happen? Is he okay?
He's in Imaging.
We'll have him back very soon.
He ordered a ride 15 minutes ago.
- To where?
- It's close.
We could have him back
before anyone knows.
Are you insane?
You're right. It's much better
if we go back
and freak out
two already-freaked-out parents.
And explain to Andrews
you didn't do what he asked.
Which emoji was it?
Just send it to me.
Ah.
You told me I have to respond.
There is no response to:
Okay, I think Carly's saying
she misses you
and wants to know
that you miss her too.
You know all of that
from one fake face?
Just text her back
something flirty, casual.
Say something like,
"I can't stop thinking about you."
I have stopped thinking about her
many times today.
Do not text Carly that.
I have to go...
Okay.
This popcorn is terrible.
We have to get you back
before your parents worry.
We're gonna be three years,
five months too late.
The game is a blowout.
So we leave now...
- What's her name?
- What?
I don't know.
The only words I've ever said to
her are, "Can I have a slushy?"
- I just wanted to see her one last time.
- Go say hi.
- Are you crazy?
- I was asking her that earlier.
Tell her you think she's the most
beautiful girl you've ever laid eyes on,
and with your last few hours of sight,
you wanted to see her face.
- As lovely as this is...
- Don't ruin the moment.
The necrotic debris has
encased the visceral pleura.
Follow with the camera,
I don't wanna spring a leak.
Tissue's fused her lungs to her
chest wall. I need Kaiser forceps.
Damn it. Tissue's too thick
to fit through the ports.
We need to do a thoracotomy.
Can't open her up
in an air-tight chamber.
If we have to cauterize a bleed,
the whole thing could explode.
We have to take our Bubble Girl
out of the bubble.
Hey! Get your ice-cold lemonade!
We've been gone too long.
Calm down. It'll take the kid
15 seconds to chicken out.
Or less.
I'm a wuss.
Most kids wouldn't have
gone over at all. Good for you.
- Can I...
- No.
- I'm just...
- It better be fast.
- What?
We're giving a sad, nearly blind kid
a few more minutes in the sun.
We could get an award for this.
Change gloves every 20 minutes.
We need to be fast but extremely careful.
Knife.
It's a Northern flying squirrel.
They don't fly so much as glide.
- You're lucky it's not infected.
- It's a fascinating species.
They're uncommonly high-strung
for a nocturnal rodent.
- Is the squirrel in the bag?
- Yes.
- Henry comes everywhere with...
- No, no, no.
I don't need to see him.
Has he bitten you before?
It's my fault. I provoke him.
- Henry's a good boy.
- It's not your fault.
You can't take him from me.
He's not allowed to hurt you.
- Hi. It's 12:47.
- Thank you.
- You're late for your 12:30...
- Mrs. Pryce and I need to have a talk.
It's okay. Henry and I are fine.
Who's Henry?
You hesitated before
cutting her open.
We had to work fast
once I made the incision.
I was running through the procedure
in my head.
There's no shame in needing
to process a tough loss.
Talk to someone.
I'd prefer to focus on my current patient
rather than my last one.
- Hey.
- Dr. Browne, where is my patient?
And before you say "Imaging,"
I know that's not true.
He is with me and Morgan,
he just needed to process
some things... Watch out!
What's going on?
Morgan just missed a turn,
she's a terrible driver.
No. We're on our way back now.
- Hurry.
- Okay.
- How long was I out in the open?
- Thirteen minutes.
We got all of the infected tissue.
That's annoying.
It was necessary to save your life.
- No, I meant your phone.
- Oh. It is.
Bet it's your girlfriend.
How did you know?
Only annoying girlfriends
text so much.
I used to text my boyfriend
all the time.
It annoyed him too.
I am supposed to flirt with her
and I don't know how.
Did your boyfriend break up with you
because you were annoying?
No, he died.
That's the downside
of outliving your prognosis.
You outlive everyone else's too.
That is a downside.
Get out your phone.
I'll tell you what to type.
I'm really good at phone sex.
It's the only kind of sex I can have.
We haven't had sex.
- I'll stick to foreplay?
- No, thank you.
Do you text your parents
or are they dead too?
My parents are in Denver.
My dad's job transferred them there.
They always wanted
to live near the snow.
They're outdoorsy
and I'm, you know, not.
I'm not close to my parents either.
I have autism and they don't.
I need to listen to your lungs.
I just got really dizzy.
What's going on?
You have an infection.
Temperature is 103.6.
BP is 80 over 50,
she's showing early signs of sepsis.
Start her on a course
of IV immunoglobulin therapy.
- ADA-enzyme replacement and GM-CSF.
- Okay.
I think we can do more
than treat her.
Gene replacement therapy.
We harvest her stem cells
and use a retroviral vector
to transduce her DNA
with the modified ADA gene.
- If it works, she's cured.
- If it doesn't, she dies.
There's a 50 percent chance her body
will have an acute toxic reaction,
- we're going to treat the infection.
- She'll get another infection.
And another, and another, and
eventually, one of them will kill her.
You don't know that,
she's beaten the odds.
By cutting herself
off from the world.
Traditional treatment is the safer course.
He's blowing off steam,
he's with the doctors, he's safe.
He's scared, overwhelmed, and, obviously,
he felt like he couldn't tell us.
You've been keeping him
under lock and key.
I'm protecting him.
We have to stay strong.
Charlie knows you're strong.
And he knows you love him,
but the moment you all heard
the word "cancer,"
everything in Charlie's life changed.
And I think he needs to know
that at some point,
it's going to start to feel
like his life again.
My mom and dad
used to do these things
called spontaneous
family adventure days,
SFADs.
They were pretty lame,
but they let me skip school.
We got to go to baseball games,
drive around blaring music.
I got to eat food that was inorganic
and genetically modified.
Sometimes I got to stay up
past midnight.
Now we go to doctor's appointments.
And my mom makes lists and cries.
And my dad's quiet.
Just one more quick stop.
- Morgan, Andrews is expecting us to...
- Please, just 20 more minutes.
Fifteen.
Park told me you rejected
his gene therapy idea.
We can't dismiss plausible
treatment options out of fear.
It's not fear.
It's a reasonable degree of caution.
Since when are you cautious?
The benefit of the cure
may be worth the risk.
Let Park take it to her.
No, it's not worth it.
The cure is riskier
in the short term,
but the long-term
upside is much greater.
We can give you the chance
to live a long, healthy, normal life.
No, you can't.
I've been a freak my whole life.
And curing my disease,
letting me take a breath of fresh air
is not gonna make me normal.
Increase the oxygen to 15 liters,
start her on the IVIG.
We need to let her rest.
I'm a freak too.
People have called me that
because I am not neurotypical.
And I used to be alone,
like you.
Sometimes that was easier
because it is hard to be around people
when you're not like them.
But now, I have Dr. Glassman,
and a roommate who is a girl,
and a girlfriend who is only annoying
some of the time,
and I think it is better
than being alone.
If you're cured,
you can be outdoorsy
like your parents
or you can stay inside
and have phone sex.
It will be your choice.
The next time you go over my head
will be the last.
Prep her for the gene replacement.
Nice work, Shaun.
No. No way.
He's going blind. It's his last chance
to see a naked woman.
You're a woman. I bet
under those clothes you're a naked one.
I'm his sister.
I'll slip you 50 bucks.
My budget proposals
for your approval.
Surgical cases for your review
before the board meeting tomorrow night.
Pregnant woman.
How's Neil taking it?
Five minutes, please,
I'm with Dr. Lim.
I see there's a new member
on the clinic team.
- How's that going?
- It's been half a day.
We're working out the kinks.
If it's still smooth sailing
by close of business,
let me know your secret.
I guess that answers
my initial question.
I mean,
he keeps telling me he's fine.
You're the last person he'd tell
if he weren't.
I'd be the second-to-last.
I'm almost done.
You're the president.
He has to listen when you talk,
or pretend to.
The 4-year-old with the ear infection
has been here half an hour,
his mother just pulled
out finger-paints.
You need to go.
Debbie, this is Dr. Lim,
Chief of Surgery.
I know.
It's very impressive. Come back
if you get an ear infection.
- One more.
- No. We're done.
Surgery can't start without me...
Where are we going next?
Yosemite? The Great Wall?
The top of Everest?
It's never gonna be enough.
- Claire, stop.
- You can't pack a lifetime of things
you're gonna miss into one day.
Your situation sucks, and it is unfair,
but you know what?
Life sucks, and it's unfair,
and things end before we're ready.
We are going back now.
No.
I'm not gonna have the surgery.
How long before I know
if I've let you talk me
into something really stupid?
You could have an acute
toxic reaction
and die in the next 24 hours.
But we hope to see some positive sign
your body's responding soon.
Okay, your transfusion is done,
we'll check on you in a half-hour.
Dr. Murphy?
Would you sit with me?
What do you want to know?
Nothing, I...
I just want someone to be here...
in case I croak.
Hmm.
That's probably all
your annoying girlfriend wants too.
Just to know you're there.
Carly's in good health
and unlikely to die soon.
Some girls have all the luck.
Debbie!
You bellowed?
This thing is broken.
Can you call someone from IT
and send them over, please?
Oh, I meant to tell you
I upgraded our software.
- Gonna be faster, more efficient.
- Not if I don't know how to use it.
You can't change my
software system without asking me.
I didn't change it,
I upgraded it. There.
Or kick out my chief of surgery,
or interrupt my appointments.
You'll be here 20 hours a day
if you don't stick to a schedule.
It's my call.
I'm not here to slap on band-aids
or to write prescriptions.
That woman had serious issues
we needed to discuss.
With the rodent in her purse?
Squirrel.
It's a Northern flying squirrel.
You weren't gonna fix whatever issues
she has with an extra five minutes.
It's my clinic, okay?
I decide how it runs!
Okay.
I thought you wanted me
to be a part of it.
You know, to actually help and to...
make changes, have opinions, but...
if that's not what you want,
then I should do what I promised.
I quit.
You're out of sutures.
I'm sorry.
I shouldn't have said any of that.
I lost somebody recently...
and it hurts a lot.
And I took it out on you
and that is unfair.
But if you don't have this surgery,
you won't ever drink another slushy
at a baseball game,
or feel the wind in your hair
when you speed down the road,
or... Or touch a naked woman.
I know this sucks.
It really, really sucks,
but it will get less sucky.
And the part that hurts
so much right now
will start to hurt less.
And life goes on,
and you will have wonderful moments
and you will have sucky moments,
and it will be your life.
It'll be a good life, Charlie.
I suspect it might even be a great life.
Oh, thank God!
Sorry it took a while. Car trouble.
Welcome back.
You had some good people very worried.
I'm really sorry.
You guys can ground me forever
for this, but I just...
I just wanted to have
one last day of fun.
We can be fun too. Again.
I was thinking.
It might be time
to re-introduce the SFADs.
Baseball games,
concerts, staying up late.
That sounds pretty lame.
We're running a little late.
And we need to get you prepped.
Sorry, I need some 5-0 nylon sutures.
And, apparently, we need to talk.
You can report back to the
chief of surgery that I'm fine.
You don't have to talk to me,
you don't have to talk to her,
but you need to talk to someone.
I'm not a med student, Aaron.
I've lost patients before.
But not someone who should've lived.
No one would be fine, I wouldn't be.
You're not fine.
If for no other reason than your boss
doesn't think so.
And the bigger problem is
your girlfriend agrees with her.
We'll be there
as soon as you wake up.
We love you so much.
I love you too.
- We'll take good care of him.
- Thank you.
You ready?
Yeah.
I forgot to take his vitals.
I'm sorry.
Go ahead, I'll bring him out.
- I thought you already took my vi...
- Shut up.
Bringing the patient down now.
Vitals okay?
Temp might be a little up
but he's ready now.
I just need you
to count back from 10.
Ten, nine...
eight, seven...
six, five...
You're right.
I'm not fine.
It's okay not to be fine.
You can't blame yourself.
I was the one holding the knife,
blame lies with me.
But the responsibility is ours.
- Yours and mine?
- Yes.
You're not objective about me
because of our relationship.
If we weren't together, I'm not sure
you'd agree to let me do that surgery.
You honestly believe
I approved a procedure
that I didn't think you could do
- because we're sleeping together?
- No.
You thought I could do it,
that's the problem.
I think your personal feelings
may have led you to overestimate me.
You came to me.
You sold me the surgery,
told me that you could pull it off.
And now, I'm at fault
because I believed that you...
It's not about fault,
it's about being aware,
so that this doesn't happen again.
It will happen again.
I will make decisions,
you will have bad outcomes.
That doesn't mean
either of us was wrong.
My approval had nothing to do
with our relationship.
We can't know that for sure.
If we weren't dating,
that woman might still be alive.
And we both have to live with that.
Mom? Dad?
- We're here, honey.
- We're right here.
- You did so good.
- We're so proud of you, buddy.
Charlie? It's Dr. Reznick.
How are you feeling?
Not awesome.
Are you in any pain?
No. No, I'm okay.
I'll let you rest.
- Wait, Dr. Reznick?
- Yes?
Thank you so much for everything.
You're welcome.
And Dr. Browne.
Dr. Browne, are you here?
T-cell count increased
and your fever dropped to 99.3.
- Your body's fighting the infection.
- So, what does that mean, I'm cured?
It's too early to use
that word exactly.
We'll keep you in isolation
a few weeks,
make sure your immune system
is developing on pace.
And there is still a five-to-seven
percent chance of a toxic reaction.
But, yes, the cure
appears to be working.
You should tell your parents
the good news.
What are they gonna do?
Feed me juice through a straw?
They could just be here.
I'm fine.
Let us know if you need anything.
I'll check on you in the morning.
Thank you...
for not killing me.
You're welcome.
There is still a five-to-seven
percent chance of a...
Shaun, she knows.
♪ Even your going ♪
♪ Let it ♪
♪ Knows you ♪
♪ Rocking you to sleep ♪
♪ From the Otherside ♪♪
Aaron, you...
You do not owe me a gift.
I owe you an apology.
I was out of line today,
I was pushing way too hard.
It's not a gift.
Oh.
Is it punishment?
Nurses swear by them.
The arch supports
are supposed to be spectacular.
I'm not coming back to the clinic.
It was a bad idea, terribly executed.
Two of the smartest women
I know, my wife,
and my new office manager,
think that I need to make some changes.
You wanted to help, you wanted to be
a part of my life, I fought it.
I proposed and then I freaked out.
- We got married...
- You freaked out again.
Yes, I did,
but for a legitimate reason.
There was a gun in the house,
but that's not the point.
The point is,
that in the midst of all of this,
I took on not one but two jobs
at the hospital.
- Yeah, which you love.
- Not more than you.
Hmm.
Come back to the clinic.
Do I get to boss you around?
A little.
Let's go upstairs.
Charlie asked for you.
You connected with him.
I said what I had to,
to get him into surgery.
No.
- You were your old self again.
- My old self...
was always there for everyone.
Just giving away pieces of herself
over and over.
Charlie is still blind.
It was a hell of a day.
The blind kid
didn't get me depressed.
You, on the other hand...
Deal with your crap,
before this is who you really become.
♪ Generator ♪
♪ I've been waiting ♪
♪ Come erase me ♪
♪ Generator ♪
♪ I've been waiting ♪
♪ Come release me ♪
Hey,
this is Audrey. You know what to do.
♪ Release me ♪
♪ Come release me ♪
♪ Generator ♪
♪ I've been waiting ♪
♪ Come release me ♪
♪ Come release me ♪♪