Previously on ER:
- You did it.
- We have a baby.
Will you be home
late again tonight?
I've got the med list.
- Why didn't you have it before?
- Phenelzine?
She'll be a star in internal
medicine or research.
You have to be more decisive.
Shall we try the high-dose epi?
I assessed it, I
ordered it, I pushed it.
- I gave her the order. CARTER:
Until you falsified the chart.
That's a felony.
Nothing I did on this shift can convince
me or anyone else that I belong here.
She's not an ER doc.
We need more wipes.
Where's your mom? She's late.
- Hey, 9 ounces.
- Nice.
Can't say I don't produce.
Better put on your shirt. She
already thinks we're pervs.
Come on, baby. You gonna
be good for your grandma?
Yeah, you're always a
good boy, aren't you?
That's my baby. That's my baby.
I'm sorry. My battery was dead.
- I had to get a jump.
- That's all right.
- Hi, baby.
- Hands. Wait, hands, hands.
- Hi, Ma.
- Hi, hija.
Carlos is going to
buy me a new battery.
Really? What you
need is a new car, Mom.
- Yeah?
- Preferably with an air bag.
Yes, well, you going
to buy it for me?
Yeah, right. My brother's a saint
because he's getting a battery...
but I gotta pick up the
tab for a whole new car.
He didn't sleep
well last night...
so you might wanna put him
down early for his morning nap.
Oh, okay. Poor lindo.
Just like your mother, only
don't be so stubborn, okay?
- You ready to go, babe?
- Yeah.
- Say goodbye to Mama.
- Goodbye, baby.
- And Mommy too.
- Say goodbye.
- Come on, baby.
- Okay.
It's all right, papa. Don't
worry. We'll be back.
- Your son has a set of pipes on him, huh?
- Yeah.
He gets that from
your side of the family.
Oh, yeah?
What are you trying to
say? I got a big mouth?
You want a turkey or
peanut butter sandwich?
- Both.
- You want turkey with peanut butter?
- You used to make it for me, remember?
- No, I didn't.
Well, somebody did. Hey,
what are sodomy laws?
I'll get it.
- What are you doing here?
- Just got off work.
- Thought I'd stop by, say hello.
- Hey.
Guess he misses us or something.
I have to be at work in, like, 40 minutes,
and he has to be at school, like, now.
You know, if he
wants, I could stay.
Nice try. Gina got a ticket for
double-parking last time. Go.
When are you gonna
stop working night shifts?
Soon.
- And what are sodomy laws?
- Out!
You know...
I have a couple of minutes
before I have to leave.
Really?
A lot can happen
in a few minutes.
I'm sorry.
It doesn't have to
be anything fancy.
I'm really tired.
How tired?
Not that tired.
How did you score?
- On your boards?
- Don't know. I can't bring myself to look.
- Any luck, I failed.
- Now, that's a positive attitude.
Part of me is afraid I'll be given a
license to practice medicine one day.
- Isn't that the point?
- If I was good at it, yeah.
Between annoying Attendings,
butting heads with nurses...
and being responsible for a patient's
death because I tried to be aggressive...
writing's on the wall for
me, wouldn't you say?
You're not good until
you've killed someone.
Spoken like someone who hasn't.
So how you doing?
Fine.
And I don't have much
of a poker face, do I?
Abby, pilonidal cyst in Four.
Gallant, shingles in Two.
Neela, vaginal bleeding
in One. Get to work.
Sorry, I'm late. Had a
meeting with Risk Management.
Oh, my God. Are you okay?
My feet are swollen,
my back is killing me...
and apparently, my
waddle's too slow for people.
Got a long day. The
sooner we start, the better.
All right. We're doing interviews
on the phenelzine death.
- I'll need some time off the floor.
- Are we being sued?
Not yet. Need to clarify
the hospital's defense.
All right, Gallant,
you're up last at 11:30.
The Attending's up last since he's
the one who will be named in the suit.
God knows Carter's got assets.
That why he left the country?
All right, we'll start at the bottom
and work our way up. Neela, that's you.
The guy's records fell through the cracks.
It's not like anyone did anything wrong.
What's the matter with
you? This chick is hot.
- A little overweight, but in a good way.
- Not interested.
- Mike, she's your type.
- I'm busy.
- Lieutenant James on line one.
- Tell him I'll call him back.
Busy doing what? Playing
soldier? You need a life.
Dr. Gallant, you treat the
immersion burn in Exam Four?
- Problem?
- I tell you...
- You did excellent with the débridement.
- Magna cum laude.
- Ever thought of switching to surgery?
- I'm pretty well committed.
- If you change your mind...
- She has legs up to here:
- Pratt.
- You're playing games.
Susan's with Risk
Management, so present to me.
- Yeah, okay. You all right?
- Yeah. Why?
- How's your dad doing?
- Oh, he's much better, thanks.
Okay.
We have a homeless John
Doe, approximately 70 years old...
found in a makeshift tent in
Lincoln Park, cold and altered.
His sugar's at 435, so I gave
him 8 units of insulin sub-Q.
- How long has he been outside?
- Rectal temp's 92.3. Overnight?
Diabetic ulcerations
on the feet.
Also has high blood pressure: 180/95.
And evidence of a prior MI on the EKG.
- Pretty bad cataracts too.
- You sure he's homeless?
- Well, he fits the bill, right?
- Nails are groomed.
Check Missing Persons.
Maybe he's a wanderer.
Sir. Sir. Oh, great.
- Here.
- Seems like he's incontinent too.
Kerry. My department's in utter chaos.
Since Robert, there's been no leadership.
Scheduling's a nightmare. And nobody's
representing us at the bargaining table.
- Our salaries have been cut back.
- I know.
- Well, what will you do?
- Have the new department head...
assess the situation and
get back to me about it.
- You selected a chairman?
- Dr. Weaver, Sandy on two.
Chairwoman. Can you
find out if it's urgent?
Unless you prefer to
be gender non-specific...
and simply referred to as chair.
Only dinner. Call her back.
I'm late for a medical
executive committee meeting.
I don't understand.
When was this decided?
Two months ago. Still need final
approval, but that shouldn't be an issue.
Fine, but it would have
been nice to have been asked.
Three months. I don't know.
Something like that. You don't want it?
Maybe. I don't know. It would have been
nice to be given a choice in the matter.
How long has your back
been hurting, Mr. Halpern?
A couple of days now.
Did you fall or strain yourself?
I slipped on the stairs
about a week ago.
Might have triggered something. I
had a slipped disk a few years back.
- You have surgery for it?
- No, no. I couldn't afford it.
It just flares up once in a
while. I usually just take Vicodin.
Let me guess. You're allergic
to Tylenol and ibuprofen...
and Vicodin is the
only thing that works.
Yeah, I don't really like the stuff,
but what am I gonna do, you know?
- Abby?
- T and L spine and get some urine?
Yep. We'll be right back.
Then run a tox screen. Check his
records. Make sure he's not drug-seeking.
You read my mind. So you
think you'll match at County?
Huh. I don't know.
So you basically let a desk clerk get in
the way of your getting a medical history?
I suppose I did.
Did you inform Dr. Gallant that you
didn't have Mr. Sanchez's med list?
- Yes.
- And yet he gave the order for Demerol?
Yes.
- Do you have anything else?
- No, I'm good.
Okay. Thanks, Neela.
I have a friend who's doing a study
on neuroprotective agents in stroke.
They're looking for
students to work in the lab.
Research?
Just check it out.
This is crazy.
If Susan knew she was in
some inquisition all day...
she should've scheduled
another Attending.
Abby: chest pain, scalp
lac, itchy groin rash.
- Already got eight.
- I've got 12. What's your point?
Dr. Chen, old frozen
guy is waking up.
- He asked for some water.
- Oh, hey, Kovac called.
He said next time he's
gonna have a triple latte first.
- That make sense?
- Yeah.
- Aren't you two living together now?
- No.
For what it's worth, I
think Luka's a good guy.
- Oh, wait. You didn't...?
- Sleep with him? No.
I went in a completely
different direction.
Hi, I'm Dr. Chen. Can
you tell me your name, sir?
Jones.
First name is Bob.
Is there any family
we can contact, Bob?
No. I'm homeless.
Mr. Jones, your
hemoglobin A1C suggests...
that your diabetes was
under control until recently.
What happened?
No missing-persons
report that fits.
Well, we'll just have
to call Social Services...
get him placed somewhere.
Yes.
I need somewhere to live.
All right, re-check
d-stick, urine ketone...
You know what,
why am I doing this?
He's Pratt's patient.
So the Klonopin's working?
Okay. No, that's good.
Just give me a call if he
gets agitated again. All right.
What are you doing?
Talking to your father's nurse.
She tried to call, but you were busy.
He tried to fry a steak while
she was stripping his bed.
- What?
- Yeah. Set off all the smoke alarms...
- scared himself, but he's okay now.
- Oh, my God.
I gave her verbal orders for p.r.n.
Klonopin. It has a long half-life.
You might wanna
consider restraints.
Dr. Chen, Rescue 3-8 has two critical and
six serious from a structure-fire collapse.
Give me it. I'll call Resp. Make
sure they have vents ready.
Page Trauma and Burn
Fellows, set up rapid infusers...
and get Lewis out
of that damn meeting!
She discovered he'd had a bad reaction
to morphine and sought out an alternative.
It was smart on her part.
She didn't tell you what
that alternative was?
No. Not specifically.
Did you hear Dr. Gallant give
the order to push Demerol?
No. But to be fair, I had
stepped out of the room briefly.
- What are you guys looking for exactly?
- The truth.
Meaning you think there's
some sort of cover-up?
Excuse me. Dr. Lewis, FD's
are rolling up with criticals.
- What do we got?
- Tommy Mason, 33.
Full-thickness burns to
the face, neck and chest.
Unconscious at the scene. BP's
90 palp, tubed for agonal resps.
- Residential fire? EMT
1: Abandoned warehouse.
- Should've let it burn. Nobody to save.
- Sam, Gallant, you take the next one.
Pratt, you come with me.
- What happened?
- Industrial fire, 17 got hit pretty bad.
- How did your meeting go?
- Fine.
Andy Fash, 22. Smoke inhalation.
Passed out and took a fall.
Dislocated knee. - BP's 132/80.
- Belly pain. SAM:
Good pulse on the foot.
- Pelvis is stable.
- I'm cool. How's Mason?
- We don't know yet.
- I'll get the next one.
- This the second critical?
- Next rig.
Took a while to fish her out.
- Abby, you take this one.
- By myself?
Chen and Pratt, next room.
Gallant, Neela, with me.
29-year-old female, chest, pelvis crush.
Injury on scene with prolonged extrication.
Hi, I'm Dr. Lewis.
- It's Sandy.
- Hey, doc.
Got a flash. Wire. Sandy,
you need to stay still, okay?
BP's 80 palp.
Tell Gemmill to stop trying
to get a look at my boobs.
- Chest is up.
- Rib fractures.
- Pneumothorax. She needs a chest tube.
- I was about to say that.
Pulse ox to 78. How about
doing it instead of talking?
Ten blade.
Tegaderm for the line.
Sandy, how are you doing?
I've been better.
- I remember you.
- How's the baby?
You have carbonaceous
material in both nares.
We need to think about
securing your airway.
You wanna shut me up by
sticking a tube down my throat?
We wanna help
you breathe better.
I want... I wanna
talk to Kerry first.
Okay. Cut in the
fifth intercostal space.
- Mid-axillary line.
- Yeah, I'm aware of that.
Free fluid in both
pericolic gutters.
Sandy, you need the O.R.
We're gonna have to intubate.
- What's taking her so long?
- I paged her.
Okay, I'm in.
Please.
Okay, okay.
Put her on 100-percent non-rebreather.
The minute she's here, I'll intubate you.
- Need another doc.
- Go, Gallant.
- Just a chest tube.
- Not a student. They want a doc.
Neela, have you ever
done a horizontal mattress?
- Yes.
- Dazzle me.
- What do you need?
- Glove up.
Sixty percent surface
area burns with hypoxia.
- This guy needs an escharotomy.
- Wide prep, 10 blades for both of us.
We'll open a square over the
entire chest down to the sub-Q.
BP's down to 70 palp.
Gallant, check the ET for a
leak. May have to re-intubate.
- Yes, ma'am.
- Ready?
Every time.
Anterior axillary line all
the way down to the 10th rib.
Join the top and bottom transversely.
Mike, you should be able to bag him now.
Nope. Sats are dropping.
- Hold up. Eighteen angiocath.
- What?
Tracheal shift. Puncture wound. Tension
pneumo on the left. Gotta needle him.
Hemostat and 4-0 vicryl.
- Pulse is stronger. Sats coming up.
- Nice catch, Gallant.
Hey, Abby needs some
help with a knee reduction.
- Pratt.
- I'm in the middle of tying off a bleeder.
Gallant can take over.
Sterile gloves. - What's up?
Lateral dislocation with
equivocal pedal pulses...
wheezing, maybe
smoke inhalation.
- Is he hanging in there?
- Chest was so bad, he couldn't breathe.
He's intubated and doing better.
Systolic's 120 with 50 on board.
- Lopez?
- We don't know yet.
He's had 250 mics of fentanyl.
I told the old-timers
I'd race them to the top.
All right, this is gonna hurt.
Have to pull on your lower leg
to move it back onto the knee.
Seventeen years between
them. I got eight months.
Come on, stabilize the distal
femur. Let's get ready to pull.
- Tommy got up there first. Then Sandy.
- Enough counter-traction?
Remember thinking
the old guy won.
Yeah. Ready?
- Then I saw them both drop.
- Okay, one, two, three.
- Where's Sandy?
- Trauma One.
- How bad is it?
- She's conscious.
- Excuse me. Sandy?
- Crit's 24 after two units.
Sandy?
- Oh, God.
- Hey, baby.
- What did you go and do?
- Roof collapse.
Bilateral rib fractures,
pneumothorax.
Intra-abdominal bleed,
pubic rami fractures.
We need to get her to the O.R.
- It's a good thing I pumped, huh?
- Chest tube output going down.
Pulse ox, 87.
- She's on 100 percent?
- Yeah.
- Why isn't she intubated?
- She refused until you got here.
I wanted to say, "Hey."
- Type-specific's here.
- It's okay. It's gonna be okay.
Sandy? Sandy? Sandy, you
need to stay awake, sweetie.
Need to stay awake. Sandy!
- Stay awake.
- 20 etomidate, 120 of sux.
- Pressure's drifting.
- Stay awake.
- Number two mac.
- Sandy, I need to do this.
Sats in the 70s. We should bag.
- Kerry...? WEAVER:
Push the drugs.
I need an end-tidal
CO2 detector.
- Etomidate first?
- Kerry...
- No.
- You need to let us do it.
Please. She's my wife.
How long am I gonna be in this?
When you dislocate, you tear
up a bunch of knee ligaments.
Those heal, right?
Even with surgery, there
still could be some instability.
I've wanted to do this
since I was a kid, you know?
There are some new
artificial ligaments.
But if it's really bad, you
may need knee replacement.
Mason says it's a calling.
So, what happens
when you can't answer it?
Good pulses. Check his airway.
I'll see if they need me next door.
- What happened?
- Cardiac injury.
- I lost the pulse. CHEN:
Start compressions.
Thoracotomy tray to Dr. Gallant.
- You're serious?
- Why not? He's earned it.
Ten blade, then Mayo scissors.
Put up a screen. They
don't need to see this.
Okay. Rib spreader.
Open the pericardium
with the Metz.
Stay anterior or you'll
cut the phrenic nerve.
You do remember the
anatomy of the phrenic nerve.
Edema and secretions.
Tube's not advancing.
You asked for an 8-0.
- BP 108/68.
- Come on. Come on, honey.
- Switch to a seven-and-a half?
- Come on. You can do this.
Sats, 83, 82...
- I'm switching to fiber-optic scope.
- Suction and crichoid.
- Eighty-one, 80...
- Kerry?
- I see cords.
- Get a tube.
- Seventy-nine, 78...
- I'm in.
Bag her.
Good yellow on CO2 monitor.
- Pressure's 120 palp.
- Four of Ativan and six of Pavulon.
Are you okay, Dr. Weaver?
- Portable vent?
- Just keep bagging her.
Okay, Mr. Fash, we're gonna
move you to... Are you all right?
- I can't breathe.
- I hear stridor.
Okay, try continuous
albuterol at 20 per hour. Pratt?
- Pratt, I need you in here.
- This guy needs me a little bit more.
I'll start an atrial line.
He needs four units, now!
Okay, we can try a Foley.
- This guy's in respiratory distress.
- Upper-airway burn. Crank up the O2.
Ventricle's starting
to fill. Crank it up.
Abby, does he need intubation?
Just bag him. I'll be
there in a few minutes.
All right. Ambu mask at 100 percent.
- What's happening?
Okay. You need to try to
relax, all right? Just relax.
No reading on the pulse ox.
- He's out.
- All right. Try a jaw thrust.
There's no chest
excursion. I can't bag him.
Twenty cc's for the
balloon. Extend his neck.
- We did!
- Okay, good hemostasis with the Foley.
Another 2 units and
we might save this guy.
- Okay, fine. Etomidate and sux.
- You got it.
Push the drugs, Abby.
One of us will be right there.
- Run of six.
- Heart's still empty.
Where's he losing it?
- Abby, try a 6-0. Take a look.
- Okay, sponge stick and suction.
Clamp the hilar vessels.
What do you see?
Nothing! Larynx is swollen shut.
- His sats are down to 72.
- This is ridiculous.
- I can't ventilate him.
- Just keep bagging.
I'll be right there in a second.
All right. Eleven
blade and a five shiley.
- What?
- You heard me.
- All right.
- Okay, hilum's clamped.
- So is the aorta.
- V-tach.
Internal paddles. Charge to 30.
Clear.
Abby, how're you doing
in there? You okay?
Yep.
Tube and curved Kelly.
Ectopy on the monitor.
- You do this before?
- Nope.
Charged.
- Clear.
- No change.
- Amp of epi.
- Sixty.
- Charged.
- Never mind.
- Why?
- I criked him.
- By yourself?
- Sats are up. He's fine.
- Well, now, that's a med student.
- Okay, going again, 100 of lidocaine.
- Charged.
- Clear.
Still V-fib.
- Asystole.
- Okay, come on. Five of epi.
High dose should give
us a shockable rhythm.
Stop compressions.
Don't bother, man.
Twelve twenty-seven.
- Should we let those guys in?
- After we close the chest.
Oh-silk on a needle driver.
BP's 82/60. Want more blood?
Another two units and
squeeze in the FFP.
Fractured liver, pelvis, ribs...
humerus. God, what's not broken?
- Kerry, do you have the C-spine film?
- It's Sandy.
What?
Oh, God.
Who's operating?
Anspaugh, hopefully, and Dean.
Ignacio's anesthesia.
Shirley's circulating.
- Good. That's good.
- Platelets are here.
Do you want to stay with her?
- What?
- Would you like to observe?
Yes. Yes, I would.
All right. Chest
tube on mortar seal.
You got it.
- The O.R.'s ready.
- All right, let's go then.
I'll say a prayer for
you, Dr. Weaver.
Kerry, she'll pull
through. She's a fighter.
I'm right here. I'm
not going anywhere.
Have the blood bank send four units.
- Already had six.
- How is she?
- Lung collapsed.
We're able to re-inflate
it. She's lacerated
her liver, which we
need to repair now.
- Mija. Oh, my God!
- What happened? Where you taking her?
Try not to be scared.
She needs an operation.
Sandy. Mija.
- Mija?
- She's not conscious, ma'am.
- Where's Henry?
- With my wife.
- Is Sandy gonna be all right?
- Yes.
I will be with her in the O.R.,
but there's a waiting room upstairs.
And I'll call you the minute
that she gets out of surgery.
- Take care of her.
- We will.
- I'll take them up.
- Thanks.
No. No.
I can tell you exactly
what happened.
I mean, we had a very
recent discharge summary...
documenting an adverse
reaction to morphine.
The patient was in pain. I gave
the order to administer Demerol.
I shouldn't have. End of story.
Not exactly.
Luis Sanchez's
chart is incomplete.
No Attending note.
Any idea why that is?
Maybe Carter didn't have a chance to
do it before it was sequestered by Legal.
He was leaving for
Africa that night so...
So he was distracted,
is what you're saying.
No. I'm not saying that at all.
Think he needed time
to get facts straight?
What? No. It was a busy night.
We had a lot of patients.
Is Dr. Carter typically
available to you?
Of course he is.
What are you doing? I
thought you were helping.
I am. By preparing you for the difficult
questioning you may face in a deposition.
Do you feel supported by
Dr. Carter as an Attending?
Yes. He's a great teacher.
One of the finest physicians I've worked
with. I respect his opinion tremendously.
So why didn't you
present to him?
LEWIS It doesn't make sense...
because he was probably
30 feet away the whole time.
Was Dr. Carter informed
of the decisions...
you were making in
your treatment plan?
No.
I wanted to handle it myself.
I thought I was better at
this job than I guess I am.
I'm completely
responsible. Nobody else is.
Will you state if deposed?
Yes.
When is that
supposed to take place?
The deposition? We're not sure.
We haven't heard from the family yet.
- I might not be able to do it for a while.
- Why is that?
The Army called me up.
I'm gonna be deployed to Iraq.
Excuse me.
- I got Halpern's records.
- It'd be nice to see you.
- Gallant?
- It's always nice.
- Halpern, right. Refresh my memory.
- Call back.
- Desperately seeking Vicodin.
- Yeah.
You hear anything
about Sandy Lopez?
- No, you?
- No.
Puts it in perspective, huh?
So Mr. Halpern managed to hit up
every local hospital for Vicodin this year.
- Know what his tox screen showed?
- Narcotics and benzos?
Nope. Nothing. He's
clean. Aspirin and caffeine.
Excuse me.
Could you find out
about my sister?
They told me she's in
surgery and you'd know.
- You're Sandy's brother?
- I'm one of them. Is she okay?
- Uh, let me make a call.
- Thanks.
Falciform ligament's clamped.
- Systolic's in the 90s.
- Two more units going in.
How long have you
two been together?
Three years.
One of which
included a pregnancy.
That gets you bonus
time in the equation.
- Okay, there's lots of blood.
Suction. DEAN: Looks venous.
HemoCue's 8.3.
We met here.
At the hospital?
It was the last place I
expected to find anyone.
Right. Uh, the
spleen looks good.
But...
- there's a grade-four hepatic lac.
- Bovie.
I miss Mark too.
Let's pack off the liver.
Shirley? Shirley, can
you wipe my brow?
Lap pads. I need lots of them.
What's the therapeutic
range of procainamide?
Four to 10 mics per mil.
Measure its active metabolite.
Procain plus NAPA
should be under 40.
- Did you open that envelope yet?
- Yes.
- And let me guess. You passed.
You're not a bit
excited about that?
I'm a little excited about it, I suppose.
Don't have to tell my parents I flunked.
I don't know. I'm not
sure it means anything.
I suppose we should at least
go celebrate passing tonight.
Well, I'm not much
in the mood myself.
Yeah.
Susan, what are you doing?
Please let these
be Braxton Hicks.
- What's wrong?
- You need to isolate the segmental veins.
Trying. ANSPAUGH: Kerry?
- How is she doing?
- Systolic's down to 78.
She must have a
retrohepatic caval injury.
Oh, God. CORDAY: Okay,
clamp the suprarenal IVC.
All right, I'll take over.
- Large-angled Satinsky.
- Come on, baby.
Please don't scare me like this.
IVC clamped. Mark time.
CVP dropped to zero.
Start an epi infusion.
Keep her temp up.
All right, supra-hepatic
cava clamped.
You sure you should be in here?
- She's fine.
Bradycardia.
She's lost her filling pressure.
Can you unclamp?
If we do, she'll bleed out.
- And if we don't...
- her heart stays empty and she arrests.
- Oh, God.
- Systolic's only 60.
- Mig of atropine.
Let's prep the
chest for a Schrock.
- Ten blade.
- Heart rate's down to 58.
Sternal saw.
We have to put in
an atrial-caval shunt.
To do that, we have
to open up the chest.
It'll improve her preload and
get blood back to the heart.
- Kerry!
- Do it.
Nicotine, coffee and aspirin.
You're setting yourself up for an ulcer.
I don't drink coffee.
Okay, soda then.
A lot of caffeine
in your system.
Over-the-counter migraine
tablets. They don't do squat, though.
Nothing works but Imitrex.
That's a pretty
expensive medication.
Especially for someone who doesn't
work much, not insured anywhere.
Yeah, well, thanks
a lot, Uncle Sam.
How long have you
had the headaches?
Ever since I pulled
sand duty in the Gulf.
What branch?
- Army.
- Yeah, me too.
Don't count on the benefits.
Spent a year in the desert.
Came home with migraines.
V.A. says it's not service-related.
Won't give me a dime.
That why you sell the Vicodin?
Pay for the Imitrex?
What unit?
Forty-third Battalion.
Medical Corps.
You gonna turn me in?
No.
But I'm not gonna give
you the Vicodin either.
That's fair enough.
You stay low. Watch your back.
You didn't say how
your meeting went.
It's gonna be fine.
Look, I'm sorry I've been...
I don't know.
Bitchy about this whole thing.
It's just not
comfortable for me.
Lying and having someone
else cover my mistakes.
And it just sort of keeps on
compounding, one on top of the other.
I'm being deployed to Iraq.
I'm headed for Texas
tomorrow morning.
You haven't finished
your residency.
I know. I'm gonna finish up
the last few electives down there.
They called you
up, just like that?
Yeah.
You're a coward.
- What? What?
- A coward and a liar.
I never asked you to do
this for me, but you did.
Now you're leaving. And I'm supposed to
live with the fact that I killed a man...
and that you helped to
lie for me to cover it up?
- Listen, Neela...
- Michael, go to bloody Iraq.
And tell yourself you've
done something noble.
- I had to protect you and Dr. Carter.
- No.
You didn't.
Well, at least the
contractions stopped.
So the sub-Q terb worked?
She's still 1 centimeter dilated and
50 percent effaced. You can sit up now.
So I should just take it
easy, cut back on a few shifts?
You're having
regular contractions.
Your cervix has softened,
shortened and dilated.
- Bed rest, huh? Plain and simple.
- For how long?
Three-to five-weekers do
well, full-terms do better?
Oh, no way. I can't stay
in bed for five weeks!
You can and you will.
Schedule an appointment for
an NST with my office in a week.
This blows.
The whole day blows.
Yeah.
- What else happened?
- Nothing.
- Oh, I failed my boards.
- What?
Need a 182 to pass. I got a 167.
Oh, Abby.
- I'm sorry.
- It's okay.
Well, how were you supposed to
study? You're pulling double shifts.
It's fine.
It's not like a burning building collapsed
on me or anything. I'll take them again.
Atrium's oozing.
Another 2-0, I'll
oversew the purse string.
V-fib.
Charge to 30.
I love you so much.
Come on!
Clear.
- No change.
- Okay. Teflon pledgets.
Oh, there's blood
pouring out of her ET tube.
DIC. More platelets and FFP!
Clear!
Asystole. CORDAY:
Resume cardiac massage.
- Mig of atropine!
- You can stop.
She's gone.
Kerry.
Can you take it out?
- By law, we're not supposed to...
- Please.
Of course.
I'm so sorry.
We wanted more.
I had to twist her
arm to have a baby...
but once Henry was here,
she said, "I can do this.
Eight more and we got a team."
Sandy had a big family.
I only had her... and Henry.
What am I supposed to do now?
Would you like me
to talk to the family?
No.
No, I'll go do it.
Hey, you hiding out
or taking inventory?
Oh, just looking for Reglan.
You leaving?
I've been ordered to sit
on my sofa for five weeks.
Sounds good to me.
Yeah, I bet.
Do people know?
No, not really.
You prefer it that way?
You know...
Look, what you did was stupid...
but there were a lot of circumstances
that conspired to kill Luis Sanchez.
The nursing home should
have put a medic alert on him.
You should have gotten a
full med list, but you didn't.
If it goes to court, the Army
will send me back to testify.
No, I doubt it'll happen.
People don't sue
doctors they like.
And for whatever reason,
Mrs. Sanchez liked you.
Take care of yourself
over there, okay?
Yeah.
You have a healthy,
happy baby, Dr. Lewis.
Hey.
- You get called in early?
- No.
My shift doesn't
start for an hour.
I wanted to see you. Maybe we
can get a coffee or something?
Sandy Lopez died today.
- Who?
- Weaver's Sandy.
Take care of yourself,
Dr. Kovac. Sam.
Ace.
- So how long have you got?
- Here?
- About an hour.
- On your tour of duty?
A year at least. Maybe longer.
So you're just gonna sneak
out in the cover of darkness?
No "Hi," "Bye," "Kiss
my ass." Nothing.
- You know, I'm not much for sendoffs.
- I don't care what you call it.
There's a war going on.
Gonna miss having
you around, man.
- Yeah, right.
- No, I'm serious. You're an honorable guy.
I'm not sure I've ever met one.
Don't go getting
yourself killed.
Alex?
Alex, get out here.
Mom, guess what.
Alex, turn it down, okay? I've had a
crappy day, and I got a major headache.
You look good, though.
Dad's here.
Is there anything I can do?
Need me to watch Henry,
or do you need a ride home?
He's with Sandy's family.
Dr. Weaver.
It's okay.
Dr. Weaver, it's okay.
- Got anything else?
- No, that's about it.
You'll need this.
Rabbit's foot.
It's American for
good luck, isn't it?
Thanks.
You're welcome.
You'd better come back.
You know that, don't you?
Yeah, I will.
You just better be a damn
good doctor when I do.
You ready?
Bye, Michael.
- Hi, Eduardo.
- Hey.
I'm here to get
Henry. Is he awake?
Hey, listen. He's not here. I think
he's with my aunt or something.
No, no. You told
me that Theresa...
It's nothing personal, okay? I
mean, I always really liked you.
Wait a minute. You said that
Theresa was taking care of him.
We're his blood relatives.
What are you talking about? What's
going on here? Where's Henry?
I don't know.
Where is my son?
Sandy's son.
I don't understand
what you're talking about.
I don't understand what you're
talking about. Where is he?
- I hear him.
- No, that's mine.
- No! Let me in. Let me inside.
- No.
- I know my own son...
- No, no, Kerry. He's not...
- No! Let me in! I know my son's voice!
Why won't you let me inside?
- I'm really sorry, okay?
- Please! Please!
- No!
- Why are you doing this?
Why are you doing
this? Let me in!
That is my baby! Give me my son!
Give me back my son!