Hey, can I give you
a hand with that?
Oh, thanks, John.
Paid a fortune for it and
the damn thing's stuck.
No problem, as long as I
can sneak under a corner of it.
I left mine at the
house on my way out.
Ooh, I hate coming in
to work in the morning
when it's still dark.
That doesn't look promising.
Yeah, perfect start to what's
bound to be a perfect day!
We got a 93-year-old
woman with COPD.
Increased wheezing
due to smoke inhalation,
with no evidence
of facial burns.
BP's 134 over 92, pulse 96.
Give her five albuterol,
get her on a pulse ox,
and order chest films.
What's going on?
Oh, there was a fire
in a nursing home.
There weren't enough
people there to get 'em out.
Carter, can you get
this last ambulance?
MAN 1:90-year-old with
tachypnea and altered mental status.
BP's 95 over 60.
No singed nasal hairs.
They're sending us
two more, one critical.
Full thickness burns.
Who's on the desk?
Nobody. Steve's sick,
and Randi left at 6:30.
She didn't wait for
her replacement?
I am not her keeper.
If you wanna
bitch, bitch at her.
Haleh, I need you.
Oh, and Jeanie called.
She's not coming
in today either.
Got basketball practice, or
are you coming straight home?
- I have practice.
- You ready?
Yeah.
Good morning. Morning.
Where's your backpack?
Mm-hm.
It's in the upstairs bathroom
on top of the toilet,
and you dumped
your basketball stuff
on the basement steps.
If you want it to end
up in the washer,
you put it in the basket.
She can hit a
20-foot fading jumper,
but she can't get within
10 yards of the hamper.
Yeesh.
You got a minute? Not really.
Yeah, uh...
Carla told me that
Reece might not be mine.
What are you gonna do?
I don't know.
I don't know that I believe her,
with everything that's going on.
That bitch. What the
hell is the matter with her?
Jackie. Look... No. No.
Everything she's
put you through,
and she isn't even sure?
I'm sorry.
But I don't know what's worse.
That she's always known,
or she's just doing
this to get Reece?
Well, I got a paternity test.
I, uh... I haven't taken it yet.
How long does it take?
I don't know. I don't
know that I'm gonna do it.
You have to.
What if I'm not his father, huh?
What are you gonna do,
wait till he gets older, Peter?
He's bound to find
out. Yeah, I know. I...
Yeah, and then he's gonna know
that you've lied to him.
Hi. Hi.
What do you want?
Well, I called,
but the phone just kept ringing.
I don't always hear
it, it's down the hall.
I gotta get to work.
Are you still working
at the pharmacy?
Yeah. Pay sucks, but
the hours are good.
Well, look, your tests
came back after you left.
You gotta come
back to the hospital
and get treated for
the bladder infection.
A bladder infection
can be very dangerous
when you're pregnant.
I'll come by as soon as I can.
Have you given any more thought
to the detox program?
You know, you really have to.
Yeah, I stopped using
about, uh, five days ago.
Oh, good for you.
Yeah, thanks again.
Yeah, I don't give a damn
how many patients you've got.
Excuse me. Hey, you know what?
We are drowning here,
and I need some
qualified bodies.
Excuse me, I'm, uh... Go away.
I've got 11 fried old folks, you
wanna compare patient loads?
Uh-uh. You need something,
talk to the boss lady.
Hey, you're in a
nasty car accident,
I hope you end up down
here, so that I can personally be
of absolutely no damn
help to you whatsoever!
Twerp. Excuse me.
Hi. Uh, I'm Andrew...
Do you have an M.D.
behind your name?
No, I... Okay, then have a seat.
I'll get to you later.
Uh, Margaret Ramey sent me.
You're a desk clerk?
Yes, ma'am.
Good. Then get back
here now. Come on.
Okay, so you want me to...
You're a clerk. Clerk.
Malik, get on the phone
to anybody who has the day off.
Tell them to get into work today
if they still wanna
work here tomorrow.
Oh, God! Can I help you, ma'am?
Oh, I... I've lost my husband.
Were you in the fire?
Barry's my husband's name
and I was following
him down the hall,
and they went so fast.
Uh-huh. Your husband's
name is Barry? Yes.
Well, let's go see if
we can find him for you.
Oh, why, thank you.
Sir, can you take a
deep breath for me?
Pulse ox 82 on four liters.
Hey, I just found
your patient's wife
wandering in the hall.
Can I bring her in?
Absolutely. You free?
Yeah, I was just heading back
to the desk to grab another one.
Well, I got two. You
can have this one.
No singed nasal hairs.
Barry, I'm right here.
Sir, I need you to lean forward
so I can listen to your back.
- He can't lift himself.
- I...
Wet crackles bilaterally.
Put him on a
non-rebreather mask.
MS, CHF, coronary
artery disease.
All right, S4 gallop.
Let's get a nitro drip.
Titrate to a systolic of 100.
Add another 80 of Lasix,
and four of morphine.
You got it? Yeah. Yeah.
78-year-old woman
with rheumatoid arthritis.
Contusion to the right thigh.
BP's 155 over 88, pulse 96.
Three-centimeter vertical
laceration to the forehead.
Knew I should've had
that third cup of coffee.
What's going on?
Nursing-home fire.
Gabe, check the residents.
Make sure all the
majors are covered.
And, Carol, can you
take over the desk?
They're stacking
up like cordwood.
No physical sign of
the smoke inhalation,
but she's still short
of breath and hypoxic.
Pulse ox is down to 84.
Uh-huh. Crank her up to 10.
All right?
What the hell's going on?
Her chest is clear. I mean...
You wanna get Dr. Greene?
Uh, no. What's her temp?
101.2.
Will you appreciate
the coarse rhonchi
at the right base?
She's got pneumonia.
Not much gets by
you, does it, Dr. Dave?
CBC, blood cultures...
Chest x-ray, ceftriaxone. Sign.
You know, uh,
Andy does imitations.
Ask him.
Imitations, huh?
Oh, I'm better at improv.
You know, Second City.
This is just my day job.
Yo, man, do Keanu Reeves, man.
No. Aw, come on. Do something.
Go ahead.
Whoa! So you're a
little pregnant, huh?
All right.
You picked a name
for the little dude yet?
No. No, I haven't.
Well, how 'bout Leif?
Or Bodhi? Or Keanu?
Keanu is a most excellent name.
That's very good.
Malik, did you get ahold Jeanie?
Yeah, she says she
couldn't make it in.
She hasn't made it in
all week. Call her again.
Tell her to come in here.
If not to work, then to explain
to me why I shouldn't fire her.
Just had a great
pickup. Oh, yeah?
Elderly woman
who was in that fire,
presented with rapid breathing
and altered mental status.
Tachypneic and hypoxic.
You're figuring smoke
inhalation, right?
Your Bunsen burner's still on.
That one sticks,
you gotta jiggle it.
Pulse ox was 84. You with me?
Struggling, but I
think I get the picture.
I was tempted to just
write it up as inhalation,
but I noticed a few
subtle physical findings.
Quiet crackles in
the right middle lobe,
a slight dullness to percussion,
and a low-grade fever.
Pneumonia.
Right.
I figure I'm gonna find
some gram-positive diplococci
in her sputum.
She's lucky she had
you as her physician.
Damn straight.
Haleh told me she heard
the rhonchi on the patient
and told you.
I... I can't understand
what he's saying.
He's not getting enough oxygen.
It can lead to confusion
and disorientation.
His lungs are very sick.
Right now our only option
is to place a tube
down his throat
to help him breathe.
But I don't know that
that will be helpful.
Well, is there a chance
he can get better?
There is a chance. But
in his declining health...
I'm not optimistic.
But he could get better?
Yes, he could.
Then let's try it.
It could also be his heart.
Why don't we run some
more tests, and, um...
Just make sure that we're
doing the right thing first.
Lily, can we get
Cardiology down here?
To, uh, do an echo?
Yeah.
Help me!
How you doing?
Uh, 89-year-old woman.
Agitated, delusional.
Vitals normal. No signs of
smoke inhalation or injury.
What have you done so far?
Gave five of
Haldol, two of Ativan.
I lost my reading
glasses on the way in.
Help me!
Why won't you help me?
Please!
Help me!
These dementia cases are so sad.
Hated my Geriatrics rotation.
One reason I chose Pedes.
Help me! Please! Ma'am.
You're doing fine. Help me!
Help me! Help me! Please!
Help me! Please! Please.
Help me, help me.
How's she doing? Fine.
Excuse me.
Think we're
getting on top of it.
Three have been
admitted to Medicine.
The broken hip
went up to surgery.
One's in CICU,
and five were
treated and released.
You smell gas? Yes, I do.
Malik, smell that?
Yeah.
Okay, I'll call Maintenance.
And, Malik, get
everyone out of this hall.
Definitely stronger in here...
Ah!
Both eardrums are intact.
How's the ringing? Still bad?
Ringing still bad?
What was it?
Fire department thinks
somebody left a Bunsen burner on.
I was doing a stain earlier,
but I'm sure I turned it off.
You want me to set up
an Audiology appointment?
No, I had it worse sitting
too close to the stage
at a Clash concert.
Ah, I just wanna get
out of these wet clothes.
Few scratches, but that's it.
Thanks, Gabe.
Could this day get any worse?
What the hell happened here?
We're not certain yet.
We think a small gas leak
may have ignited next door.
Small? I heard it
up on the 4th floor.
Fortunately, no one
was seriously injured.
Someone may have
left a Bunsen burner on.
Really?
When did the pain start?
Last night before I went to bed.
Had you had anything to eat?
Uh, we shared a
pizza for dinner.
Any vomiting? No.
Any pain?
A little bit around
my bellybutton.
How old are you, Eddie?
12.
Married? Big for your age.
You play football?
Eh, he's not much into sports.
Uh, video games.
That's what kids do now.
Sit up for me, will you?
Any pain back here?
Yeah, a little. Mm-hm.
Carter?
Dr. Kayson's here.
Thanks. I'll be right there.
Okay, nothing's too
serious, Mr. Bernero.
Maybe just a little
touch of the stomach flu.
Why don't you pee in the cup,
give it to Malik.
It's what he lives for.
Mm, pistachio,
almond and peppermint.
Yum, ice cream cake. Peppermint?
Just eat the pistachio then.
Oh, God. Another birthday?
Just leave the decorations
up permanently.
It's Carol Hathaway's
baby shower.
It's a surprise.
Mm. Anybody missing a
pair of reading glasses?
Just found them in the freezer.
May I see those?
I've left mine in some
pretty weird places.
In the dryer one time.
Are they yours?
No, but I think I
know whose they are.
Hey, you got a minute?
Yeah, I wish I had.
We can talk while
I work if you like.
Nice office.
Yeah.
You have to admire the
method to his madness,
no matter how sociopathic.
Who?
Romano. This office.
Sorry.
You wanted to talk?
Slumming amongst
we simple surgical
folk, Dr. Benton?
We were just
discussing a patient.
Oh, nothing that
was taking Peter away
from the electrifying excitement
of trauma medicine, I hope.
Lizzie, I've got a hernia
scheduled for
tomorrow in the a.m.,
and I was gonna be tied
up with a breakfast meeting
with insurance people.
And I was hoping you
could take it for me.
It's a bit early. Six o'clock.
In the morning?
Yeah, early bird
catches the worm.
Seems one of the
more advanced members
of your ER brain-trust
blew up the lab,
and the insurance company
is rightly concerned
about hospital safety.
Did anyone get hurt?
Your boyfriend
got his hair mussed.
Mark?
Yeah. But he bounced right back.
Have to hand it to
him. He is a scrapper.
He's deaf as a post.
I understand that's, uh,
probably temporary. Oh, oh!
Um, Lizzie.
How much would
you pay for my sperm?
I beg your pardon?
Oh, is that sexual harassment?
Oh. Oh, my. Oh.
No, I'm being, um, recruited
by the Marshall/Hillberg
Sperm Bank.
Its, uh... Its donors include
Olympic athletes and
Nobel Prize winners.
It's an elite gene pool.
And they want you?
Yeah. Yeah, it's a little
embarrassing, actually.
Uh, but it's for a good cause.
I mean, who knows
what the mother's side's
gonna bring to the party.
But as for my side
of the genetic divide,
I can guarantee a
significant advantage
over the rest of the
spermic competition.
Can't have too many extra
Romanos running around,
spicing up the
gene pool, can we?
Hey. What have we got?
Shattered femur. Rock climbing.
55-year-old trying to keep up
with his much younger wife.
Wow. What a mess.
Nothing like major
orthopedic surgery
and four months in a wheelchair
to prove your vitality
to the fairer sex.
You still looking for
your reading glasses?
Yeah.
I meant to stop by a drugstore
on the way in to pick up
one of those $10 pairs.
Are these them?
That's great.
Where'd you find 'em?
In the freezer in the lounge.
The freezer?
That's one place I didn't look.
Thanks.
Hey, Cleo. Could you write
me a prescription for Keflex?
I've got a sometime
patient, 8 months pregnant.
She's had no prenatal care,
and has a bladder infection.
Want me to look at her?
Well, she's not in the hospital.
Don't ask. I just...
I thought I'd get
her the prescription
and hope that she fills it.
Thank you.
It's probably the heart failure
that's making him sick. Oh.
Not his lungs.
I think that we need to
accept that the time has come
to let nature take its course.
I don't know what to do.
Barry always made all
the important decisions.
Do you know what a "Do
Not Resuscitate" order is?
Yes.
I think you need to sign
one for your husband.
Will you do that for me?
Yes.
Excuse me.
Dr. Spielman's office?
Yeah. Uh, third floor. Make
a left past the MRI suite.
Dr. Spielman.
Kerry! My God! How are you?
I'm fine, thanks. Oh.
Still sacrificing yourself
at the altar of the indigent
down at County?
Battling windmills
is more like it.
Please. Want some tea?
No, thanks. No, thanks.
So you moved, uh, the
office around a little bit.
Yeah, when we
put in the MRI suite.
What a mess.
So, what brings you
to our humble digs?
Job-hunting, I hope.
Uh, no. Gabe Lawrence.
You let him go a
couple of months ago?
He left the staff, yes.
I heard it was politics.
A... A bit of a palace coup.
With me cast as Iago, I suspect.
I was wondering if that's
what really happened.
Gabe Lawrence
was my closest friend.
My mentor, my teacher,
and the finest doctor I have
had the privilege to work with.
His leaving was the
most trying experience
of my career.
I hired him at County.
I hadn't heard that.
Renee, I need to know.
Should I be concerned
about the safety of my patients
with Dr. Lawrence on my staff?
Hey, have you seen Dr. Lawrence?
Check Trauma 2,
he's in with Malucci.
What have they got?
Stab wound to the chest.
Rib spreader.
Suction.
Still no pulse.
Gabe, do you need a hand?
No, we're fine. You know what
they say about too many cooks.
Heart's still beating.
Notice how little blood
there is in the heart?
Pulseless electrical activity.
All right, we need four
more units of O-neg.
Stab wound to
the left ventricle.
Keep your finger on it.
I'll do internal compressions.
How fast are you at sewing?
Blink and you'll miss it.
We need two needle
drivers with 2-0 silk.
I'm putting him into
ventricular fibrillation.
Serious?
You wanna sew a moving target?
What am I gonna do next,
Kerry? Sauerbruch grip.
Did I ever tell you Dr. Weaver
was the finest student I
ever had? Hands down.
Scary. Knew the answers
before you could ask the questions.
And what is the
Sauerbruch grip, Dr. Weaver?
Occlude the inflow
from the inferior and
superior vena cava.
What'd I tell you? All
right, when he arrests,
you've got 30
seconds to fix this hole.
Go in high, with a
horizontal mattress.
V-fib.
Charge the paddles to 20.
Two more units are in.
Keep 'em coming.
Don't tie that off too tight.
Paddles now.
Last knot.
Don't look at the
monitor, look at the heart.
That, my young friend,
is what normal sinus rhythm
looks like inside the chest.
Damn.
She was the last
one. They're sure?
Nobody else used it.
Are they gonna
fire her for that?
Who's going to get fired?
Dr. Finch. She used
the Bunsen burner last.
You can get fired for that?
If you can be fired for
dress-code violations,
you can be fired for
blowing up a hospital.
They can fire you for
dress-code violations?
Is anything open? I just
need it for a few minutes.
Do Christopher Walken.
Well, you see, you want a room?
The only room that's
available... Exam 1.
Thanks.
Welcome. Have fun
storming the castle.
Alrighty.
Okay.
Here you go.
Sit up.
All right, man. Let's get
this DNA stuff over with.
See?
See how easy that
was? It didn't hurt.
All right. Yeah.
Good man. That's my big man.
Okay.
I'm sorry.
Come here.
Excuse me, is Meg
Corwin working?
Deb, where's Meg?
On break.
She's probably out back.
Past the water fountain
and the bathrooms.
Thank you.
I get paid today, really. Hey.
I'll... I'll catch
you later, okay.
Um, I'm off at 6:30.
Maybe.
What are you doing here?
Brought you your prescription
for your bladder infection.
Thanks. Who was that guy?
Um... Oh, Meg, you're pregnant.
No kidding. I didn't ask to be.
Oh, you weren't there
when it happened?
This is none of your business.
Look, you wanna piss
your life away, fine.
But your kid deserves a chance.
I think you're mixing me up
with someone who gives a damn.
I didn't leave it on. I
was there. I saw you.
I turned it off.
You need to tell
Dr. Weaver it was you.
Why would I be stupid
enough to do that?
Because Dr. Finch
is going to get fired.
Maybe she left it on.
Dr. Dave? Benton's
with your broken arm.
I checked the charts,
her patient came in
an hour before yours.
Dr. Finch was in there
long before we were.
I turned it off, Lucy. Honest.
Hey, Cleo.
I got a 12-year-old boy
whose blood sugar is 278.
Diabetes previously diagnosed?
No, I just got the test back.
He overweight?
Crappy diet? Couch potato?
All of the above.
Kids sit around eating junk food
and play video games
all day, and bingo.
They've got diabetes.
How do I treat it?
Well, you want me to
talk to the family with you?
Got some experience
with it. Sure, that'd be great.
I'd heard that Gabe
had lost a power struggle
with Renee Spielman
over some junior
staff tenure issues.
And you never checked
when you hired him?
Hey, I have known Gabe
Lawrence my entire career.
He trained me. He's the
reason I became an ER doc.
When I heard he was forced out,
I jumped at the
chance to hire him.
You jumped at the
chance to impress him.
Student hires teacher.
Okay.
Spielman suspected
signs of early Alzheimer's,
but when she asked him to
undergo neurological testing,
he... He blew up, and he quit.
He hasn't spoken
to her ever since.
You have to fire him.
No. She wasn't sure.
His inability to
cope with stress.
Wandering around the
halls 'cause he can't...
He's always been scattered.
He could endanger the patients.
Mark, I don't
know if I can do it.
I... I... I mean, I
love him like a father.
I don't know if I can fire him.
Is there a family
history of diabetes?
My mother has it. I...
I thought this was
something only old people get.
This type, primarily yes,
but some children
are susceptible to it.
We need to get your
son into a diabetes clinic.
There's a new drug, Glucophage,
that works well for kids,
but it is expensive.
Does your insurance cover
prescription medications?
I'm not insured right
now. How expensive?
$100 a month, plus he'll
need constant monitoring
and clinic visits.
I can't afford that.
Look, your son
needs to lose weight,
exercise and control his diet.
If he does all those things,
he might not need medication.
I'm starting a
new job next week.
It's got good benefits, but they
don't kick in for three months.
Can this...? Can
it wait till then?
The longer your son walks
around with an elevated blood sugar,
the more likely he is to
develop complications.
This will be a pre-existing
condition, right?
On my new insurance?
If you start treating
him right now,
then that's a pre-existing
addition, they won't cover him.
Uh, I don't know the
specifics of your new plan,
uh, but it's possible.
What about I start him on a
diet and get him working out?
My mother's in an HMO,
she gets diabetes pills for free,
he could take those
for three months.
Your son needs the support
of a physician's supervision.
You can't change him
overnight. He needs a nutritionist,
an exercise specialist,
a diabetic educator.
How much will all that
cost? It's only three months.
I'll stay on him. We
weren't even here, all right?
No, your son needs
medical attention.
This is a very serious disease.
He could suffer kidney
failure, heart disease, go blind.
Hang on... There
could be infections.
He could lose his limbs.
Let me talk to
Dr. Finch for a minute.
I think you're making it worse.
The man's considering
waiting months
to treat his son. Well,
forget three months. If the
insurance won't cover his son,
and he can't afford
the medication,
what will happen over
the next three years?
He can't take his
grandmother's glyburide,
he could drop his blood sugar,
eat more and gain more weight.
So we start him
off on half a pill,
two and half milligrams, the
dad gets him to lose weight.
When the insurance
kicks in, he gets better care.
You asked me to help
'cause you don't know anything
about Type II
diabetes in children.
Sedentary kids don't
change their lifestyles
without professional
supervision.
Dad hasn't been able
to get the kid off the sofa
and away from the pizzas
and potato chips in 12 years.
What makes you think
he could do it now?
Carter, your CHF
guy's in V-tach.
Look, he's your
patient. I'll be right there.
If you let that kid
walk out of here
to accommodate the
father's financial problems,
you're endangering
that boy's life.
But what is it?
It's ventricular tachycardia.
It's an abnormal heart rhythm.
How much longer?
A few minutes.
A few minutes?
Oh.
Dr. Lawrence?
Can I talk to you for a
second? Yeah, what's up?
You told Mrs. Karis
to wait here in Chairs
for a prescription
over four hours ago.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, Mrs. Karis. I, uh...
I got tied up with
other patients,
and I... I... I completely
forgot about it.
I'm very sorry. Uh,
one pill every six hours.
And, uh, elevate your ankle
and ice it three
times a day, okay?
Gabe, can I, uh, talk to
you in the lounge, please?
Yeah.
Thanks, Brenda. That's it?
Yeah, appreciate it.
Wait... Wait a second,
what is she doing?
What is this?
What's going on here? Come on.
What the hell is going
on here? What is this?
Why is she taking
off her ankle wrap?
Dr. Lawrence,
that's Brenda Brewer.
She works up in Accounting.
She doesn't have
an ankle injury,
and you've never
seen her before.
You tricked me?
Please, can we not do this here?
It's been very busy here today!
I had several ankle
injuries. I got them confused.
I went to see Renee Spielman.
Gabe. Gabe!
Time of death is 7:42.
Mrs. Connelly?
Has he gone?
Yes.
Barry, you... You're so sweet.
Yes, you are.
I'll miss you.
I, uh... I need to call my son.
Is there...? Is there a
phone I could use nearby?
I'll show you.
Thank you.
Thank you, doctor.
Sure you wanna
go through with this?
Jail isn't exactly the
best place on the planet
to have a baby.
At least she won't be high.
There he is.
Got him.
5-3-2-0. Got a white male
with a leather
jacket at the alley.
What happens now?
Just wait to see
if it goes down.
Bingo.
Get anything?
Pills, some weed.
What's this, Einstein, crank?
Kid's a regular little
cash-and-carry pharmacy.
You bitch.
How could you do this to me?
You don't have anything to say?
How could you do this to me?!
Lucy, has Dr. Lawrence
come back?
No, not yet.
Uh, Dr. Weaver?
Yeah.
It's a possibility that
I was the last person
using the Bunsen burner
before the explosion this morning.
I understand it's been assumed
that Dr. Finch used it last,
but I used it as well,
maybe after she did.
Probably after she
did. I think I turned it off.
But it... It's
possible that I didn't.
So it could've been my fault.
The fire investigator
said it was the gas line.
They found a ruptured
pipe in the wall.
Oh.
Well, I... I guess it wasn't me.
Dr. Malucci, safety is our
number one priority here.
It's not acceptable
for you to "think"
you left on a potentially
dangerous lab tool.
Are we clear? Yes, ma'am.
This is Dr. Lawrence.
Please leave your name and
number, I'll get back to you.
Gabe, this is Kerry.
I'm at the hospital, and
please call me back.
Dr. Carter, can I come in?
Sure.
Um, this is my
son's record, right?
It was on the end of his bed.
Yes, it is.
It says in here that
Eddie has diabetes.
You put that in here? Yes.
Tear it up, please.
I can't do that.
It's illegal.
I'm not a fool.
I love my son. I wouldn't
do anything to hurt him.
But we're just getting
back on our feet here.
I don't have the kind of money
that other doctor
was talking about
for all those
specialists and things.
I'll have my new
insurance in three months.
And it's good.
I'll get Eddie on a
diet and exercising.
We can use my mom's pills.
And she gets those little
kits that, uh, check her blood.
Glucose levels.
Right, right, right.
We'll get those and
if he's not improving,
I'll bring him back. I'll do
whatever you tell me to do.
But if there's a chance
to do this any other way...
please help us.
What are you doing?
I was doing chart review
in here this morning,
and the sprinklers
soaked everything.
I just did something
and now I'm not so sure
it was the the right
thing. Oh, yeah? Me too.
Really? Yeah, about an hour ago.
What?
I just, uh, destroyed
what little was left
of a good man's career.
What'd you do?
Got a pregnant junkie
arrested for possession
so she could get clean in jail
and give the baby a chance.
Wanna talk about it?
We could drown our sorrows
in a couple of ginger ales.
No, thanks,
the girls are throwing me
a surprise baby shower.
I thought that was
supposed to be a surprise.
I'll look surprised.
I miss Doug.
You call him?
Has he called you?
He leaves messages
on my machine.
I think he calls when
he knows I won't be there
so I don't have to talk
to him if I don't want to.
You don't want to?
I don't know what
else there is to say.
Rain check on that ginger ale?
Sure.
Hey, Malik. Yeah.
Have you seen the T-sheet
on the Bernero kid's chart?
The diabetes kid?
Why is it so hard
to keep them on the charts?
It was there a while ago.
Yeah, I hate this. Now I
gotta fill out a whole new chart.
I don't have time for this crap.
Randi, Bernero kid in
Curtain 3 can go home.
Just a little case
of the stomach flu.
Kick him out of there.
We need the bed.
Randi, have you seen Kerry?
Um, Curtain 2.
Thanks.
Hey. Hi.
How's the baby?
He's doin' great.
We're having a shower for
Carol. You ought to stop by.
Yeah, I'll try. All right.
Okay, hang a banana bag
and try to dress those abrasions.
I think he fell on
his face again.
Kerry, Malik called, said
it was important I come in?
Yeah. You know, I
checked your timecards
and you've worked two
days in the last three weeks.
We depend on you down here.
And when you call
in at the last minute,
it just makes it tough
on everybody else.
I'm not coming back.
I'm sorry, I didn't mean to
make it tough on everybody.
I didn't intend to. I should've
come to talk to you earlier.
Well, is everything all right?
I've never been happier.
I have Reggie and the baby.
And every time I'm at work,
I want to be home with them.
That's great. So...
if you need me to
work a few shifts... No.
No, no, no.
But as the baby gets older
and doesn't need you so much,
call me. There will always
be a job for you here.
Thanks, Kerry.
I'm gonna miss you.
I'm gonna miss you too.
Hey.
Hello, baby.
Oh, Roger was gonna pick
him up at your place later.
Yeah, I know, I know.
Actually, you know what,
I called him and told him I
was going to drop him off.
Roger! ROGER: Yeah?
Reece is here.
Hey, I, um... ROGER: My man.
I got this DNA kit
to test for paternity.
And?
And I'm not gonna use it.
I'm gonna throw it away.
Why?
Carla...
I put my hand on your stomach
when you were pregnant.
And I felt him move.
I was there when he was born
and all those
nights in the NICU.
I wake up in the
morning, that little boy
is the first thing on my mind.
When I go to sleep
at night, he's the last.
I love him.
He's my son.
I don't care about biology.
I don't need some damn
DNA kit to tell me that.
I don't have a whole
lot in my life, Carla.
My career...
Jackie and her
kids and that boy.
He means more to me than
all the rest of them combined.
I'd lay down in front
of a train for him.
That's how I love him.
So I'm asking. I am...
I'm asking you...
Please...
Don't... Don't... Don't
take my son away from me.
Please.
Carol, Weaver
needs you at the desk.
Something about overtime.
Great. Okay.
Surprise!
Oh, my God!
You guys... You didn't
know? I had no idea.
We chipped in on the bassinets.
We have no money anymore.
Aw, they're beautiful.
Dr. Weaver,
Dr. Lawrence is
down in Trauma 2.
You were looking for him, right?
Where have you been?
Out walking by the lake.
I was worried about you.
When despair for
the world Grows in me
I go and lie down
Where the wood drake
Rests in his beauty On the water
And the great heron feeds.
I come into the
peace Of wild things
Who do not tax their lives
With forethought of grief.
I come into the
presence Of still water
And feel above me
The day-blind stars
Waiting with their light
And for a time, I
rest in the peace
Of the world and am free.
How can I remember
a William Blake poem
I memorized over 30 years ago,
and not remember
that I saw a woman
with a sprained
ankle this afternoon?
I started to notice something
was wrong about a year ago.
You know, memory loss
and not being able
to find the right word.
I went to Boston to see
an old classmate of mine,
a neurologist.
He did a PET scan, and it...
It showed bilateral
hypoperfusion
to the parietal areas.
He started me on Aricept.
It's supposed to...
put the brakes on... On...
On the Alzheimer's.
But I guess...
Guess it, uh... It
didn't help enough.
Roz Chow is doing great work
upstairs at the Comprehensive
Dementia Center.
You should go see her.
What for? I have a
progressive neurologic disorder.
They're working with
neurotrophins and antioxidants.
Maybe you could
get into a clinical trial.
I was thinking of
committing suicide.
I don't...
I can't figure out
the best time to do it.
Too early, and I'll miss
what little life I have left.
If I wait too long, I
won't remember to do it.
Please don't say that.
God, I'm gonna
miss this. You know...
You know, medicine
has been my whole life.
No. No, you could stay on
and you could lecture
the medical students
and the residents.
But not see patients, right?
Gabe, you are a brilliant doctor
and you are a wonderful teacher.
Please...
Please don't give
up those gifts.
Look, I saw a
woman this morning.
Dementia. She had...
She had no idea where she
was. She didn't know who she was.
Ten years, that'll be me.
Bedridden...
in diapers... locked
away in some home...
nobody coming to see me.
I'll come and see you.
Yeah, but I won't...
I won't know you're there.