Previously on House.
I don't know how I got here.
I saw a symptom
before the crash.
Why was I taking a bus?
Medical hypnosis can bring
the brain to a Class 2 Theta state.
You're taxing an
already injured brain.
Someone's dying
because I can't remember...
It was Amber.
She was on the bus with me.
She's the one who's dying.
Her heart won't stop racing.
No idea what's causing it.
Sure it wasn't the bus
that landed on her?
It's not trauma.
She was stable post-op. This
didn't start until an hour ago.
My God. HOUSE: Delayed
reaction to the trauma.
She lost both kidneys
in the bus crash,
ripped up her femoral artery.
We fixed the artery, got her
on dialysis for the kidneys.
Whatever's doing this to her
heart, it isn't from the crash.
Check her potassium? Of course.
Why didn't you call me?
She's been under the
whole time. She had no ID.
Pushed adenosine? And verapamil.
And floated a Swan an hour ago.
Coronary angiography?
Three critical
patients ahead of her.
We'll have her
in within the hour.
We're fifteen minutes away from
Princeton-Plainsboro by ambulance.
You want to move her?
Her heart rate is 130.
She's hemodynamically
stable. We're moving her.
You're not her doctor, you
can't make that decision.
Her husband can.
Right?
Move her.
If the trauma didn't
damage her heart...
Why was she on the bus?
I don't know.
If she had any
underlying condition,
the accident could
have exacerbated it.
Why were you with her?
I don't know.
I'm not hiding anything,
I just don't remember.
What else could
damage her heart?
Wilson. Don't get lost.
I'm barely coherent. I
need your help right now.
V-fib.
Charging.
Okay. Okay.
Clear! Wait. Wait! Wait!
Protective hypothermia.
You want to freeze her?
Her heart's not beating.
Her heart's already damaged.
You restart it,
it'll keep racing,
shoot off free radicals
and kill her brain.
We ice her down, put her on
bypass until you've diagnosed her.
This is not a solution. All
you're doing is pressing pause.
It gives you more time
to find the diagnosis.
House. This is Amber.
Please.
Cold saline solution.
Core temperature down to 90.
Bypass circulating.
She's stable.
Why are we doing this?
Bought us time to think.
The trauma must have stimulated
a pre-existing heart condition.
Auto-immune, congenital anomaly,
blood-clotting disorder,
lead poisoning...
Could be anything.
Great. Let's explore that.
Quick, get her on panacea.
We can narrow it down by
looking for arterial blockages.
How? On an echo?
Can't see wall motion
when there's no motion.
EKG? Nope, heart's
in the off position.
Thallium uptake scan?
Useless on a cold heart.
Yeah, we get it. Her
heart's not beating.
It's gonna make it
harder to diagnose.
On the other hand, she's not gonna
die while you're whining about it.
What else?
There is another
way to narrow it down.
If you really did see a symptom
in Amber before the crash,
physostigmine helped
your memory last time.
Why not cyanide? He's a
mess, he needs to sleep.
I had a heart
attack this morning.
I can't do any more
drugs till lunch.
Get her an angiogram. It could
show damage even in a stopped heart.
Rest of you, search
her apartment.
Toxins, heavy metals, drugs...
Anything that might
make her heart race.
I need to know if there's
anything medically relevant
that you couldn't
share publicly.
Is this a Philanderers
Anonymous intervention?
You were obviously
drinking last night.
Maybe you took Amber to a bar?
I left here on my
motorcycle. Alone.
You ended up drunk
on a bus. Together.
Maybe you met Amber in the bar?
I was not having
an affair with her.
You can't really say that
if you don't remember.
I lost four hours,
not four months.
Maybe it was the first time.
If you drank together, any
chance you did any drugs?
I'll run a tox screen.
You coming?
Correspondence.
Letters to patients.
She could have caught
something from one of them.
Copy it to a thumb
drive. Let's get out of here.
Travel. Do you know if she's
been out of the country recently?
It's just video clips. Maybe
she narrates where they are.
And action!
Looks like she
didn't travel very far.
You look beautiful.
You look nervous.
I've never done this before.
I have. Trust
me. You'll love it.
Hey. Not even close to relevant.
As long as we don't
know what's wrong,
we don't know what's relevant.
Yeah, maybe they're having
sex on a pile of asbestos.
Go watch it.
If we were in a
stranger's house,
you'd be watching the video.
You altered your behavior
because you're friends with her.
Are you okay?
We shouldn't be
treating her at all.
I'm gonna search her bathroom.
Are you okay?
Can't really say "yes" when
it's a hallucination asking.
Don't worry, you're
just dreaming.
What symptom did I see in you?
A myoclonic jerk. Boring.
An incredibly rare
neurological symptom is boring?
Am I in someone
else's subconscious?
What did we do last night?
Was I meeting you for a drink?
Is that all it was?
A man thinks a
woman is beautiful,
admires her intelligence,
admires the way she has
to get whatever she wants.
The things he
likes about himself.
And maybe she always
had a little thing for him.
His mind, his blue eyes.
But someone gets between them.
So they decide to meet one night
at an out-of-the-way
little bar...
Does that sound familiar?
Do I feel familiar?
What do you feel?
Electricity.
I know I saw the symptom.
I know the memory is locked in
my brain, now I know how to get it.
No.
You don't even know
what I'm talking about.
You need to rest.
I have yet to hear about any
study linking electricity and rest.
Deep brain stimulation.
It's been proven.
Electrical impulses applied
directly to the hypothalamus
can evoke detailed memories.
My mistake.
Drilling a hole
and shooting lightning bolts into an
already cracked skull is very restful.
It's not fatal at all.
She's right. You need to sleep.
Brain activity spiked.
Amber?
Amber? It's me.
Random spikes are common.
Shut up.
It's gonna be okay.
I'm here with you.
The team has found something.
Can you ask her if
we can be excused?
What?
The coronary angio was negative.
So was the tox screen.
That's what you
found? Negative tests?
I could have told you
she doesn't do drugs.
I found these in her
apartment. Sorry.
Prescription diet pills,
SSRIs, amphetamines.
Diet pills cause structural
damage to the mitral valve,
could explain the tachycardia.
She'd have to be an addict to take enough
for her to damage her heart. I'd know.
Did you know she was
hiding them in her vitamins?
We have to warm her back up, get her
heart beating so we can do a CT to confirm.
No. We've been over this.
Starting her heart could
cause brain damage,
could burn out the heart muscle.
Test her heart
without starting it.
Crack her chest open. Reach a
finger inside the pulmonary vein,
run it across the valve.
That's the safer course?
It is if we're wrong.
When did we start
assuming we're wrong?
If this were any
other patient...
If the valve is calcified,
that's our answer,
that's our cure. Go.
Thirteen.
Who found the diet pills?
Kutner.
You didn't even go in
the bathroom, did you?
You're suddenly mute
in the differentials.
A blow-up doll
would be more useful.
And yes, that's the first time
I've ever implied something
negative about a blow-up doll.
It's Amber. I don't...
Normally, I'd be fascinated.
Today, don't care.
Get over whatever
it is and do your job.
Wait. Look at her eye.
She's jaundiced.
Her liver's not working.
Diet pills don't kill the liver.
Put her back in ICU.
Liver failure means whatever
this thing is, it's spreading.
Despite the fact
that she's frozen.
Hepatic and heart failure could
mean anti-trypsinase deficiency.
We can stick a
needle in her liver.
We see fibrosis, she's right.
Does Amber drink sherry?
Nocardia fits just as well,
but there's no way we can tell,
since we can't take
her temperature.
I had a dream she
was pouring me a glass.
And since I'm a scotch,
beer, gin and rum man...
If we warm her back up, we should
be able to tell if she's got an infection.
Yes, we can get a diagnosis
by letting the disease run
rampant until it kills her.
If it's spreading, we need
to slow this even more.
We've got to cool
her down further.
I know you love her and
you're scared she's going to die.
But just making her colder
and colder isn't a cure.
It's not dealing
with the reality.
Sherry means something.
Amber doesn't even drink sherry.
House, can we get back to...
If she did drink sherry, it would
mean nothing, but since she doesn't,
my subconscious is obviously
trying to make some other point.
There's a Sharrie's Bar on
Third, right off the bus route.
Wilson's right. We
need to make her colder.
Putting more ice on her is
just delaying the diagnosis.
Not on, in. Fill her
lungs with slurry.
Where are you going?
Taking Wilson out for a drink.
Is this the place?
Maybe.
Hey. I assume you
are here for these.
Did you see me here
with a tall, blonde woman?
Yeah, I think she joined you
after scotch number seven.
Did she seem sick?
She sneezed.
I gave her a napkin.
Did you see the
color of the sputum?
I assume sputum means snot.
Look, I see lots of
drunk chicks in here.
I didn't have time to stop and analyze
the color of your girlfriend's boogers.
She's not my girlfriend, genius.
She was hot, you seemed into her
and she bought you drinks.
Last night, she
was your girlfriend.
Blood in her sputum. It could
mean parasites. Any recent travel?
You seemed into her?
If he had a brain, he
wouldn't be tending bar.
Sneezing's a new symptom.
Let's assume the runny
nose means an infection.
What did House have to say?
He told me I was
raised by wolves,
and that's why I use the same
hand for my fork and knife.
Whoa.
Not that one. The slurry tube.
I know this is
different. But it's not.
Everyone dies.
She's not dead.
You're reacting this way
because she might be soon.
Yeah. I am. Why aren't you?
I'm an Indian guy named Kutner.
Ever wonder what
happened to my parents?
I'm sorry, I didn't...
I was six years old.
I used to like helping out in
my parent's store after school.
A guy walks in to rob the place,
ends up shooting them both.
Wasn't fair.
Took years, but I had to
accept that's just the way it was.
So, you gonna help me
fill her lungs up, or not?
Tell me the liver biopsy showed
infiltrates, minor inflammation.
Yeah. How...
Snot on a napkin.
Add the heart,
the infiltrates...
Hep B.
Start her on IV interferon.
I'll go tell Wilson.
Good idea.
And I'll go nap, because I
was concussed last night
and had a heart
attack this morning.
I'll tell Wilson. You go sleep.
Hepatitis B is a lame diagnosis.
Oh, God, I get less
rest when I'm asleep.
I rise from the dead
and that's reaction I get?
I'm sorry. If I had known,
I would have started a
breakaway Jewish sect.
Hep B fits.
Why are you doing that?
Because Hep B doesn't fit.
Turn her over.
We're about to start her
second course of interferon.
Which she might not need
once you turn her over.
The small of her back.
She's bruised. Why
is that significant?
Look closer.
A rash.
How'd you know what was
on the small of her back?
Well, either I'm still asleep,
or I'm starting to remember.
Looks like an influenza rash.
The flu wouldn't be killing
the organs one by one.
Dermatomyositis.
Wouldn't speed up her heart.
Maybe it's an allergic
reaction to the interferon?
Yes, the symptom I saw on the
bus was a rare interferon allergy
that flares up two
days before you take it.
How'd you see the
rash down there?
I don't know. Maybe
she leaned over.
Maybe it's not a rash at
all. Could be an abscess.
Thirteen, stick a
needle in there.
If there's pus, Foreman's right.
Ultrasound is safer.
I'm not asking you to stick a
needle all the way through her.
Taub, you do it.
No. Wait, I can do it.
No, apparently, you can't.
It's not fluctuant.
Clear, it's not pus.
Means it's vesicular.
Rocky Mountain Spotted Fever.
We had dinner with a friend
last week. We walked their dogs.
I guess she
could've gotten a tick.
It's treatable, doxycycline.
Allow eight hours for the
antibiotics to take effect,
then we warm her
up, shock her heart.
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
If we're wrong, restarting
her heart could kill her.
Run blood cultures first.
Fastest way to test is to treat.
If we're wrong, still should give
us time to try something else.
We are not starting her
heart until we're 100% certain.
We're never 100% certain.
Run the blood cultures.
After we get confirmation,
we'll restart her heart.
He's wrong. And
you know he's wrong.
You can't change your mind just
because a family member starts crying.
They're always scared.
I said run the blood cultures.
Sorry. Wide stance.
You're right.
I'm screwing up.
Why are you screwing up?
I didn't even like her.
Did you hate her?
Not enough to want her dead.
So it's not guilt.
That just leaves fear.
A young woman dying.
A young doctor dying, in
fact. That sound familiar?
Yeah, I'm at risk
for Huntington's.
I've dealt with it.
By not getting tested.
Dealing with it by
not dealing with it.
It's clearly
working beautifully.
You're the champion of not
dealing with your problems.
My grandson gave me
a mug that says that.
Okay. Enough hand-holding.
Deal with it, get back in
there, or pack up your stuff.
You're screwing up this
case worse than I am.
House is gonna kill the patient.
What are you...
What are you doing?
She's up to 80 degrees.
We're gonna restart her heart.
No, you're not.
There's still time to undo
this. Cool her back down.
You weren't taking
the safe approach.
We've got to know if the
antibiotics are working.
Her EEG's slowed.
Amber.
Well done.
We still don't know what it is,
but you've just let it
spread to her brain!
This is exactly what I said would
happen. It's in her brain now.
The brain involvement
gives us a new symptom.
That wouldn't be
there if you hadn't...
It's where the
disease was going.
We needed to know that.
This was not your
decision to make!
You went behind my back.
You went behind House's back.
Inside voices.
House wanted to warm her up.
You just guilted him
into changing his mind.
Heart, liver, rash
and now her brain.
Auto-immune fits best.
Crash trauma could've set it off.
Start her on prednisone,
then we'll warm her up again.
House, if this is
some other infection,
the steroids will trash
her immune system.
He's the attending.
You're the family.
Go spend more
time with the patient.
You can't do this.
That's not a good argument.
It's not an argument
at all. I'm sorry.
Cuddy's right. I was
afraid to do anything.
I thought if everything just
stopped, it would be okay.
And it's gonna be.
Taub's starting treatment,
we're doing everything...
Not everything.
Before you warm her up...
You said you wanted to
try deep brain stimulation.
But there's no reason.
We know the symptom.
We know what I saw.
What if it's not the rash?
What if you saw the
rash in the ambulance,
or when we were
putting her on bypass?
What if there is still something
else stuck inside your head?
You think I should risk
my life to save Amber's.
I'm inserting the IPG probe
into your ventral hypothalamus.
Give me 3 volts.
- I can't hear him.
- Can't hear who?
Everything's in black and white.
Who was talking? Is Amber there?
You're supposed to be jolting
my hypothalamus. Not petting it.
We don't want to overload it.
As long as I'm risking my life,
I might as well be
watching a talkie.
Increasing from 3 to 5 volts.
Sending impulse.
You're not getting them back.
Hey! You take my keys, you
gotta give me a phone call.
Who are you calling?
Dial-a-Wilson.
I was on call.
Amber was home.
I told her to find you,
have you pick me up.
I said to find Wilson.
He's working.
And I'm willing to suffer
this indignity on his behalf.
Does she seem sick?
Not yet.
Come on, time to go.
Need another round and a drink for
what passes for a lady around here.
What's your poison?
Nothing. We're leaving.
We're leaving, leaving,
leaving. Cosmos.
I remember Wilson
buying cranberry juice.
I'll have another, and
she'll have a Cosmopolitan.
The obstinate drunk
thing is not flattering.
Come on, you called for a ride.
Drink your drink, or
I'll drink them both.
One, and you leave voluntarily.
Let's go.
Hey! Need another Cosmo, here.
She sneezed.
What color is it?
Thanks.
Looks like snot.
Seems like a cold.
Nothing else?
No.
Where are you going?
You think I paid?
House, what are you
doing? You can barely walk.
Go home. I'll take the bus.
Hey, someone's
gotta pay for this.
Hi.
You forgot something.
Boy, you don't give up, do you?
Yeah, I'm an idiot that way.
You doing this for
me, or for Wilson?
For Wilson.
Well, then, it's even
more impressive.
Damn. Do you have a Kleenex?
I got a sleeve.
I got two, actually.
Gonna need more than
that. I'm getting that nasty flu.
Is that it? The flu? Is there
any rare complication?
No. It'll explain the
rash, but nothing else.
Unless...
What?
Don't do it.
It wasn't the flu.
It's what she did for it. She
has amantadine poisoning.
The crash destroyed her kidneys,
her body couldn't
filter the drugs,
she ODs on amantadine,
explains the heart, the liver...
We just need to start on her
dialysis and flush the drugs out.
What? What's wrong?
Amantadine binds with proteins.
Dialysis can't clear
it out of the blood.
There's nothing we can do.
I'm so sorry.
Amber.
He's seizing. Wilson!
I need help, here.
House suffered a
complex partial seizure.
The violent shaking widened his
skull fracture, causing a brain bleed.
We won't know if there's
any cognitive impairment
until he's out of the coma.
He was right about
the amantadine.
Amber's body
couldn't filter it out.
That's what caused her heart
to beat too fast for too long.
It caused irreparable
structural damage.
Didn't matter if they
shocked her or froze her or...
Her heart was dead once it
stopped in that ambulance.
What about a new
heart? Transplant?
All of her organs are
damaged. She can't qualify.
There's nothing we can do.
Nothing we could have done.
We should call time of death.
Technically, she's still alive.
Could probably survive a
few more hours on bypass.
We could wean her off
anesthesia. Wake her up.
Give you a chance to...
It'd be cruel. Don't...
Wake Amber up. See her again.
Tell her what she means to you.
Wake her up to
tell her that she's...
You are waking her up so that you
can both say goodbye to each other.
She would want it.
Hey.
You're in the hospital.
I'm on bypass.
Yeah.
Do you remember what happened?
I got on the bus.
I shouldn't have
gotten on the bus.
No. No. It's not your fault.
It's not your fault.
How bad?
You had tachycardia, complicated
by complete renal failure.
The tachycardia degenerated
into V-fib, followed by hepatic failure.
The flu pills...
Yeah.
I'm dead.
I love you.
I love you, too.
We should say goodbye.
She didn't even like us.
We liked her.
Did we?
We do now.
What do we say?
We don't need to say anything.
I'm tired.
I think it's time
to go to sleep.
Just a little longer.
We're always gonna
want just a little longer.
I don't think I can do it.
It's okay.
It's not okay.
Why is it okay with you?
Why aren't you angry?
That's not the last feeling
I want to experience.
BP stable.
Still non-responsive.
Pupils are equal,
round and reactive.
Heart rate's normal.
Respiratory rate is...
You're dead.
Everybody dies.
Am I dead?
Not yet.
I should be.
Why?
Because life
shouldn't be random.
Because lonely, misanthropic drug
addicts should die in bus crashes,
and young do-gooders in love who
get dragged out of their apartment
in the middle of the night
should walk away clean.
Self-pity isn't like you.
I'm branching out from
self-loathing and self-destruction.
Wilson is going to hate me.
You kind of deserve it.
He's my best friend.
I know.
What now?
I stay here with you.
Get off the bus.
I can't. Why not?
Because...
Because it doesn't hurt here.
I lied.
I don't want to be in pain and
I don't want to be miserable.
And I don't want him to hate me.
Well... You can't always
get what you want.
Hey. I'm here.
Blink if you can hear me.
No. Don't try to talk.
Just rest.