Many visits
to the doctor start
with taking
your blood pressure.
What are you doing
back there?
It's a vital indicator
of your health.
Ahh!
Oh, baby girl.
I know
all the tricks.
I've done this before.
But within the human body,
there are many
pressurized systems,
and each has its own threshold
and consequence for pressure.
You're late.
Yeah, well, B-shift
was late first.
Mm-hmm.
How are
my favorite ladies?
Oh, well, one of us
slept through the night.
Yay!
And the other one
was jolted out of bed
with a hospital scheduling
nightmare.
Make the residents
pick up the slack.
Minnesota's got
a good program.
Maybe you can poach one
from there.
Too soon?
Dr. Wright
has apologized, twice,
and he hasn't been
on my service since.
♪ Power in all the pain,
yeah, yeah ♪
Since when?
Oh. Oh, since
he planted one on you. Oh.
The coffee's fresh.
Uh, don't let Miss Pru
con you out of her nap.
Oh, you know
what we should do?
We should bring her lunch today.
Oh!
I could wear my turnouts
and my helmet
and my big,
red fireman badge,
and I could strut around
in front of Dr. Romeo
a few times.
Love you!
Too much pressure on the lungs
can cause them to collapse
to 1/10 of their size.
Skulls can only take
so much pressure
before the brain herniates
into the spinal cord.
My case notes, my bag,
my coffee, my keys --
♪ It feels good
No. No.
Not my keys.
Have you seen my keys?
They were just -- just --
Ah!
Keys.
Okay, we're ready.
Exhausted,
but we are ready.
Are you ready?
Oh. You found Ribbit.
Okay, this is Scout's.
We -- We have to
give him back.
Okay. Here.
♪ It feels good to feel good
Don't look at me
like that.
I miss them, too.
Enough pressure on the limbs
can cut off blood flow
and kill them.
Okay.
The person you are trying
to reach is unavailable.
Please leave a message.
Schmitt?
It's Dr. Webber again.
Call me back, please.
♪♪
Are you
still calling that boy?
Every morning,
and I will until he answers
or comes back to work.
♪ It feels good to feel good
You think I should
give up on him?
I think not everyone belongs
in an OR, baby.
♪ It feels good to feel good,
yeah ♪
The amount of pressure
may vary,
but every system
has a breaking point.
♪ It feels good
Ten more seconds.
Oh, man.
If I can do it,
then you can do it.
Yeah, you're 14.
You're a rubber band.
Look, I couldn't even bend
at all after surgery.
But now look.
That's why you can't slack
on physical therapy.
I'm not.
I got two broken bones, okay?
In the same leg.
And a spine injury!
He had
open-heart surgery.
Is this a competition?
Absolutely.
Always.
Okay, it is complete.
Your dining room
is now your gym.
Time for weight-bearing exercises
so we can get you
walking again.
Alright, I've got to
pack the car.
Up you go.
20 leg raises.
I did those an hour ago.
Congratulations.
20 more.
Oh, God.
Post-op assessments
continue to show
no signs of cerebral edema
or midline shift
post cell injection,
and there is no regression
in motor deficits.
"Regression"?
My motor skills
have improved,
but Dr. Grey can't say that
definitively,
because the medical journals
don't like that.
But last night,
it was unbelievable.
My wife and I --
Let's --
Let's stop there.
Oh, get your mind out
of the gutter, Dr. Bartley.
We played chess.
- And my hand didn't shake.
- Hm.
Thanks to Dr. Grey.
Thanks to the whole team.
Led by you.
Just accept the compliment.
And on behalf
of the clinic's leadership,
we hope you will also accept
our offer
for you to join us here
in a permanent position,
as director of the Grey Center
and chief of general surgery.
When can you start?
♪♪
Nonfat latte.
Thank you.
Hey.
I just got in.
My flight got delayed
a couple times.
Noted.
Did you see my e-mail about
the preschool sites for Scout?
Yeah, uh, I still haven't
looked at it, but I will.
Yeah, we should probably get him
on some waiting lists.
There's one school
with a nature program.
They grow
their own snacks.
There's another one
with a music program.
Yeah, well,
I said I'd look at them.
I know.
I just want to get --
I have a patient waiting.
Dr. Bradford
to Labor and Delivery.
Well, it looks like
it's appendicitis.
So tell the resident
to take him up to CT.
Wait, do I have
a resident?
Here.
I'm here. Sorry.
J--
You've already apologized.
No need to keep raising
the incident.
No, I-I meant --
I meant for being late.
I'm on your service.
But if you need me
to be somewhere else,
I will absolutely go.
Um...
Find another resident.
Get a chart.
Help, help!
I-I need help!
Are you doctors?
Uh, yeah.
Y-- Are you hurt?
Uh, not me.
My boyfriend.
He's in the car with Gigi,
and he needs help.
Hurry, please!
I warned him something like this
would happen.
I knew letting Gigi live with us
was a bad idea.
Oh, is Gigi hurt, too?
Is she a family member?
Ivan treats her like one.
Honey, I brought doctors.
Everything's gonna be okay.
♪♪
Oh!
Hi.
Is that a boa constrictor?!
Burmese python.
Gigi.
Give us one minute.
♪♪
Everything's
gonna be okay, okay?
Just look at me.
Just breathe, okay?
It's gonna be fine.
You had to know
an offer was coming.
Why? Did you?
No, but your project
was wildly successful.
Doesn't take a genius to
figure out we'd want you here.
We're really not even done
with the Parkinson's research.
It doesn't matter.
Now they all want to see
what else you can do.
What if I just want to go home
and be with my kids?
Then you should.
You don't have to do
every project yourself.
Hire a great team,
provide strategic direction.
It's still your name
on the door.
Look out.
What could have possibly made
you think
that I would respond well
to you springing this on me
in front of a staff
I do not know?
Well, maybe
you'll respond well to this.
It's the hospital's new budget
on the Grey Center
and your prospective
salary.
I'm sorry you felt ambushed
back there.
This just got approved this
morning, and I got excited.
You pick
what we do with it.
Take the work that we've done
and run with it.
Huntington's disease,
ALS, MS, Alzheimer's --
whatever you want.
And I think Dr. Marsh
might benefit, too.
♪♪
So, win-win, right?
Okay.
Dr. Norico Ohn to Radiology.
Did Bailey say why
she needed to see me outside?
Patient consult.
Well, we typically
see those inside, Helm.
Dr. Perez said Dr. Wright said
Dr. Bailey said --
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
N-Never mind, okay?
♪♪
Excuse me.
Oh!
Now it makes sense.
N-No.
N-No, no, no.
Mnh-mnh.
Nope. Mnh-mnh.
32-year-old male,
bite to
the upper left arm,
constricting injury,
complains of pain
to the arm, chest, and abdomen.
I had questionable pineapple
this morning,
so it could be that.
I'm guessing not.
When are you people gonna
get her off of him?!
Hon, you know I love it when you
get fired up, but I'm okay.
Gigi's just giving me
a hug.
Gigi is killing you!
Burmese pythons
are docile.
Uh. Your situation
suggests otherwise.
I teach second grade, and
my class is studying reptiles,
so I thought a class pet
would be engaging.
I swear, when I got her,
she was only a few feet,
but she just kept
growing and growing.
Mnh-mnh.
So I brought her home.
And she grew
because you fed her too much.
I swear,
she's never done this before.
When I went to feed her
this morning,
she bit my arm
instead of her food.
Once they bite,
they don't let go.
Ohhh! Ohh.
I can't feel my hand.
Is that bad?
Yes!
He has eyes on the back
of his head with his students,
but Gigi's just
one slithering blind spot.
O2 is dropping.
Look, uh, page Neuro
and Cardio a-and Ortho.
No, page everyone.
Until we get that thing
off of him,
we don't know
what's going on.
And where's
Animal Control?
Oh, God.
♪♪
Hey.
Uh, Luna found Ribbit
this morning.
I put him with your stuff
in the lounge.
Oh. I was wondering
where that went.
Are you looking
at preschools?
Amelia says we need
to put him on a wait list.
Do you already have a plan
for Luna?
Yeah, I'm just gonna see
what you do
and then just do that.
Ortho consult
needed outside?
Um...we miss you.
Well, we miss you, too.
Dr. Brooks to Oncology.
For the record...
...I blame Amelia.
How is what happened between us
Amelia's fault?
Ohh.
Well, because I've decided that
everything is Amelia's fault.
She's found a way to ruin
every good thing in my life.
We are not ruined.
We are best friends
who were smart enough
to protect that.
Okay, fine.
But she's ruined
most good things.
I think I like
petty Link.
Petty?
Mm-hmm.
Yeah, okay,
I'm petty now. Great.
She turned me into my father.
I blame her for that, too.
But your father got back
together with your mother.
You're not helping.
♪♪
Want me to run another BNP
on Mr. Walters?
Please and thank you.
I am headed
to see my MVR.
Dr. Pierce! We need Cardio
in the ambulance bay.
There's a snake.
Alright.
And that's code for...?
Snake! There's a giant one
wrapped around a dude's body.
Not it!
You don't like snakes?
No. Do you?
Oh, I love snakes.
I begged my mom for a pet snake
when I was a kid.
I even considered
herpetology.
That's great.
Yeah.
Let's go. Yeah.
I'll be right --
Yeah, yeah.
Who are you?
Hey.
Okay, what do we --
Oh, my God! Wow, wow! Wow! Wow!
Oh! Oh, okay, yeah, no.
I don't --
Everyone here
needs to grow up.
Wright,
get that cannula on him.
Yeah, I-I just don't want
to disturb Gigi.
She's not poisonous,
is she?
No, her species is
very easygoing. Shy, even.
I know you love her,
but she thinks you're food.
How are we supposed to
examine him?
By chopping her head off!
No!
Oh...
Awesome.
A python.
You know they can swallow
their prey whole?
Well, imagine that.
Uh, sir, just try to relax.
Okay? Alright?
Every time you breathe, your
snake is programmed to tighten.
But we're gonna
get her off you, okay?
Alright.
Uh, we need rubbing alcohol.
- Okay.
- Uh, Helm, r--
♪♪
Helm! Alcohol!
Helm!
♪♪
Good morning!
Hi!
Tseng?
Laura Eames, 34, severe
mitral valve insufficiency
and scheduled
for a mitral repair.
And also
22 weeks pregnant.
How are you feeling?
Oh, I'm good.
Todd's a mess.
She's been breathing
even harder on our walks,
and the swelling in her legs
has gotten worse,
and she's gained
another 2.1 pounds.
He keeps a spreadsheet
of my weight,
as if it'll somehow help.
Find me a woman who wants
a spreadsheet of her weight.
I like data.
I'm a --
Don't say "doctor."
PhD.
Environmental science.
He doesn't save lives.
He can save us
from climate change.
Well, speaking of data,
I need to do your echo
before we take you up
to pre-op.
So we'll need
to lower your gown.
Oh, bye.
Oh, no. Uh. You can --
You can stay with your wife.
Oh, ew.Oh, no.
No, no, no, no.Oh, no,
we're not married.
He's my brother.
Oh! Sorry.
It's okay.
But, really, bye.
I left my fidget popper
for Leo.
I'm gonna miss you.
Yeah, I'm not. He beat me
at gin rummy five times.
And that was just
this morning.
Well, come here. Come here.
I love you.
Owen's PT routine. He needs to
be up on his feet yesterday.
I don't need oversight.
If you ever want
to walk again, you do.
And please,
just let people help.
I mean it.
You can't be the only hero.
Even if you're mine.
Farouk, you want to take that
out to the car?
I'll be right behind you.
I feel another lecture
coming on.
I've given you guys a pass
because you've had a full house,
but now we're leaving,
and your kids are at Mom's,
and so it finally gives you
some alone time
to deal with whatever the hell
is happening between you two.
And don't say
that it's nothing.
You two are easier to read
than Leo's Dr. Seuss books.
♪♪
Fix it.
Love you!
Alright, a little bit
of rubbing alcohol
sprayed around Gigi's mouth
will irritate her.
When you --
you say "i-irritate"...Well, s-she'll
unclench her jaw.
But it won't hurt her.
She'll be fine.
Yeah, and --
and then what?
Then we have to
uncoil her.
Uh, but she can't do it
by herself, so...
Wright and Lincoln and I
will remove her,
and then
you can all move Ivan inside.
Yeah, I don't remember
volunteering.
Okay, fine.
Fine.
Alright, alright.
You ready, Dr. Webber?
Uh! Um...
Okay.
♪♪
Oh, for God's sakes.
Huh?
Let's save this man's life!
♪♪
Bailey, be careful.
Oh, my God.
It's working.
Ohh!
- Aah! Aah!
- Ohh!
Oh! I got you.
I got you.
Okay, good.
It's time, guys. It's time.
Oh, here we go.
Here we go.
Alright, go, go, go.
There we go.
Oh, God!
Easy, guys.
Easy.
Ooh, don't bite me.
Don't bite me. Don't bite me.
I hate snakes.
There we go.
Oh, God, oh, God,
oh, God.
Alright,
alright, alright.
Over his head.
Right there.
- Alright. Alright.
- Alright.
Okay. Got him?
- Okay.
- Alright.
Watch his head.
I got you, buddy.
I'm coming.
I'm coming. Ivan.
I'm right here.
I'm right here, okay?
I love you.
I love you, too.
I'll be okay.
Take care of Gigi.
Alright, Trauma 1.
Let's go.
Okay, I got it.
Now, Link, now!
♪♪
Ohh!
Okay, Laura.
Your labs
look reassuring,
and -- and Todd
is grabbing coffee.
He seems pretty worried.
He's the reason
why I'm here.
No. Sorry.
That sounded wrong.
When I decided
to get pregnant,
everybody warned me
against it.
My parents worried
about my heart.
My friends worried about me
raising a kid alone.
Todd immediately
made a spreadsheet.
He's come with her
to all of her appointments.
Oh.
He's been letting me stay
at the other half of his duplex
while I recover.
I've always been pretty
independent, but free rent.
Take it.
Babies are expensive,
and good help
is hard to find.
I'm a single mom, too.
How do you do it?
Do you have help?
A significant other?
On your side.
My job has a, uh, daycare.
Okay. Good.
You know, you seem like
a -- a really kind person.
Oh.
Healthy, well-adjusted,
and you're a doctor.
Are you open to dating?
If -- If the person
liked kids?
Oh...
Well, um,
our hospital policy
prohibits doctors
from dating patients.
Oh, no, I --
I mean my brother.
Todd is great,
but he's really shy.
Oh.
And he's done
so much for me,
I'd love to help him find
somebody --
Laura, I'm gonna interrupt you
right there,
'cause we are all done
with your echo.
Okay.
So I will see you
in the OR, okay?
Okay. Hm.Okay.
Thank you.
Please save me.
Okay, hang on.
I think if we just --
like that?
Yeah.Okay.
Thank you.
I'm a PhD who can't remember
the essentials,
like a portable charger
or potato chips.
I have now mentioned my PhD
twice and you think I'm gross.
Or smart, but I bet I've had
more years of training than you.
Probably true.
Mm-hmm.
So, Laura's surgery
is gonna take a few hours.
Mm.
We can text you
when she's in recovery
if you want to leave --No, no, no.
I'll stay.
She probably doesn't care,
but I do.
Besides, I got a sandwich
and five episodes
of "Ready, Set, Globe!"
I love that show!
I'm rooting for Jasper and
his 75-year-old mom, Vicki.
You think they can still win
after the unicycle accident?
I-I --
Wait, what?
Oh, crap.
Oh, my -- Oh, my God.
Okay, forget
that I said that.
I am going to scrub in
and let you catch up.
Yes, please, before
you tell me something else
I don't need to hear.
Okay, okay.
Oh, oh. But the second-floor
vending machine
has really amazing
salt and vinegar chips.
That I needed.
Dr. Eisenberg, 4673.
Ivan, you may have had
some damage to your lungs.
Your oxygen level's not
where we'd like it to be.
Will you tell Clark
to take care of Gigi?
And make sure he feeds her,
because she gets testy
when she's hungry.
Clearly.
I hate today.
Um, we'll give him the message.
Uh, you need to focus
on you.
Films are up.
Oh, he's got
a big opacity.
It could be blood.
A rib could have punctured
a lung.
Helm, let's put in
a chest tube.
On it.
I think I see
some air-fluid levels.
There's something else
going on here.
Yeah, it's probably
a hemothorax.
His O2's at 92.
Which is why we can
and should scan him first.
Bailey --Unless someone wants
to kill this man.
Helm needs to put
that scalpel down!
CT. Now.
♪♪
Come on, let's go.
Let's go, let's go.
Yeah.
♪♪
These pythons still act hungry
once they've eaten,
so their owners
will just feed them again.
Puts them at risk
for obesity.
What do they eat?
Mice?
Arms.
Well, the whole hospital
is talking
about how you tamed
the snake, Bailey.
You were
Indiana Jones.
Indiana Jones
was afraid of snakes.
Mm.
Whoa.
That, right there,
next to his lung...
is that his liver?
And his stomach
and colon.
The pressure ruptured
his diaphragm,
and his abdominal organs
herniated into the chest cavity.
So if we would have inserted
the chest tube...
It would have gone right through
his liver or bowel.
You're welcome.
I'll book an OR.
♪♪
Do a lot of your patients
try to set you up?
No. But I did get a baby
out of one of them.
Isn't that kind of
your job now?
She's talking about Luna,
Tseng.
I was once hit on
by a patient.
He was 15.
He thought I was
a high school volunteer.
I was 26.
I'm just still trying
not to screw up motherhood
and being an OB resident.
I can't handle dating.
Her BP's dropping fast.
Fetal monitor
is showing decels.
We need to increase
her tilt.
Page an OB attending.
Oh, she's coding.
Let's start CPR.
Let's bag her.
♪♪
It's not working.
Push ephedrine.
I'm gonna try
to reposition the baby,
in case it's aortocaval
compression syndrome
and her uterus is compressing
against her IVC and aorta.
Isn't that why
she's tilted?
Yes, but
it may not be enough.
Okay, on the count of three,
turn her.
One, two, three.
♪♪
Wow.
Well, that's not what I would
call screwing up, Wilson.
Have you ever seen
anything like this?
A man's abdominal cavity
squeezed like toothpaste
up into his chest
by a python?
Nope, and I'm happy
to never see it again.
It's a great
teaching case, though.
You're lucky,
Helm and Wright.
Are we?
Well, we get to watch
a master at work.
Yeah, a good teacher makes
all the difference.Gauze.
You ever had a mentor
during your residency?
Yeah, sure did.
She was a surgical genius.
Also, hot.
Yeah, I was smitten
from day one.
It may not have been the best
reason to choose a specialty.
But that's
what got you here,
and you eventually
got over her, right?
Nope.
I'm married to her.
Dr. Pierce?
Yeah, she was my teacher.
That's how
it all started.
Dr. Webber.
Animal Control
finally arrived.
Boyfriend's trying to decide
what to do about Gigi.
Oh, Damn it.
Colon looks dusky.
♪♪
Oh, do you think
it's salvageable?
Maybe. Here, let's pull down the liver.
Mm-hmm.
BP's dropping.
Hang two units of blood.
Suction.
Help me find
the source.
♪♪
Okay, eight more.
Just 'cause Megan wrote
those numbers on that sheet
doesn't make them necessary.
She's not my doctor.
Well, PT doesn't
just improve mobility.
It also helps prevent
post-surgical complications.
You don't have to sell me
on physical therapy, okay?
Well, then,
just keep going.
I need a break.
You can take a break after
you finish these rounds.
You're not gonna be able
to walk or operate
if you don't push yourself.
Don't hold back.
Don't hold back?
Look at you, Teddy.
You've been tiptoeing
around this house,
pretending like
everything is fine.
But please just stop,
okay?
And look me in the eye,
for God's sake.
Just keep doing
your therapy.
It hurts!
I'm holding back
because I'm in pain!
So am I!
♪♪
I can't look at you because
I don't recognize you anymore.
♪♪
It's the TX2 robot arm.
I read about it
in the hospital newsletter.
It's so precise.
Yeah.
And very strong,
so don't try to arm wrestle it.
I won't.
So, what would you do
with the money,
if you got some
of this funding?
What would I do?
Uh, well,
I'd keep studying
regeneration
stem cell therapies,
expand my research
on xenotransplantation,
stuff like that.
Are you doing all of that?
I mean, I'm always trying to
save more patients
without someone having to die,
but it's -- it's difficult.
And it takes time.
It takes money.
Not everyone gets surprised
with millions
in research funding.
It's not like
I don't appreciate it.
I'm not grateful for it.
You know about my life
and my kids in Seattle,
and it really kind of
seems like
this just got
a little bit more complicated.
I could meet your kids.
You could have a life here.
But Hamilton just implied
that this money could help you.
Wait, I'm sorry.
Did you just change the subject?
No, that's me assessing
how complicated this is.
So you think I'm in
a relationship with you
to get grant funding?
I told you
I have trust issues.
I didn't mention my research
because it's not relevant
to how I feel about you.
I think what we have here
is pretty great.
I'm in this, Meredith.
But it seems like you take
things that are pretty great
and you start looking
for the problems.
You want me to take
the offer.
I want you to do
what you want to do.
♪♪
I got to go check
on a patient,
but...
it's your choice.
It's your life, as much as
I'd like to share it with you.
♪♪
Push bicarb.
He's hemorrhaging
from his liver.
Okay, he's unstable
and in full DIC.
Okay, uh, let's pack him,
leave him open,
and get him to the ICU
to stabilize him.
We'll try again tomorrow.
Let's get more lap pads
and get ready for a wound-vac.
But what
do we tell Clark?
Tell him to meet us
in the ICU.
Oh. Oh, my gosh.
♪♪
Hi, um.
Hey.
Laura and the baby
are both fine,
but the fetus compressed
her major vein,
causing her heart
to briefly stop,
so we will need to reschedule
the procedure.
Oh, uh.
Wow, okay.
But s-she's fine?
She's fine.
She's sleeping.
I can take you
to see her, or...
Do most people usually peek
at their person
while they're sleeping?
I'll let you know
when she wakes up.
Great.
Okay.
Um, h-how far did you get in
"Ready, Set, Globe!"?
Erikk and Tiffany just found
the amulet
in the cave in Thailand.
Oh, yeah.
So...
Right. Um, and you found
the vending machine.
Yeah, I-I couldn't decide
what I wanted,
so I got one of everything.
Right.
Except salt and vinegar chips.
I got two of those.
You hungry?
Actually, starving, yeah.
Thank you.
No, thank you.
A-And just for the record,
we're not weird
"Game of Thrones" siblings.
I just worry about her.
Yeah.
She'll be a great mom.
Mm-hmm.
And I want her to feel
a little less alone.
She deserves more.
Do you want to go
for a drink?
Um, there's this bar
across the street, Joe's.
Not to be confused with me.
Uh-huh.
My name is also Jo, but, um,
I'm "Jo" without an "e."
The bar does have an "e" --
This is a terrible idea.
I'd love a drink.
I --
Okay. Okay, great.
Um...
I just have to finish
my shift.
Yeah, and I have to wait
for my sister.
Right.
But after that,
Joe's with an "e"?
Joe's with an "e."
Yeah.
Okay.
♪♪
For the past 20 years, you have
supported death with dignity.
You don't get to make this
an ethical argument.
You know that I support it.
I've even helped patients
pursue it.
But it's not about me.
You made a choice
that put our family at risk
without even consulting me.
If something happened, I didn't
want you to be implicated.
Oh, so you're fine with me
raising our two kids alone?
I was careful.
Careful?
Was Heather Young careful?
Do you even know the soldiers
that she gave the drugs to,
or the families?
What if a devastated kid
shows up at our door?
What happens if he goes
to the military and tells them
that his father ended his life
with drugs
that a doctor gave him
illegally?!
How do we know that
that won't happen?
We don't.
This will follow us for the rest
of our careers and our lives.
And you made that decision
for me.
And for our kids.
I thought we were a team,
in good times and bad.
Isn't that the promise
that we made?
I was just trying
to protect you.
I don't need protection!
I have never
needed protection!
I need my husband
and the father of my kids
to not go to prison!
Teddy, wait.
Wait, wait.
No, you don't get to
just walk away.
Wait!
Oh, my God, Owen.
♪♪
Owen, you -- you walked.
Huh.
I walked.
♪♪
♪ Cold, bitter hands
♪ Cold, bitter nights
David Hamilton
is a showman,
so it's hard for him
to understand people
who don't respond positively
to public accolade.
But I understand.
And I am so sorry
he handled it the way he did,
and I hope you don't let it
scare you away.
♪ I can feel
a new tide rising ♪
♪ Will it wash me clean?
Thanks.
You're very kind,
and it's unnecessary
for you to apologize for him.
Mm-hmm.
And let me ask you
something --
are you seeing my sister?
We...are getting close,
yes.
But that's not why I hope
you take this job.
Or at least it's not
the main reason why.
He reminds me of my mother.
Because they worked
together?
Because he's exactly
like her --
his wants, his needs,
his demands,
and that personality
is exhausting for anyone.
But for me, it's --
Triggering.
I don't like
that word, but...
How do you deal with him?
Well, for me,
he's the opposite of triggering.
He knew me before I changed
my name and my pronouns,
and when I told him
my new name,
he patted me on the back,
and he called me brave,
and he told me
he was proud of me,
and he never deadnamed me.
He got right on board
with my pronouns
while my parents continued
to insist
that it was an impossible
adjustment to make.
♪ Oh-oh-oh, oh-oh-oh-oh
David can be demanding
and egotistical.
But he respects people
and talent,
and not everyone does.
Plus, he told me
we'd change the world,
and then we just put a big dent
in Parkinson's.
We did do that, didn't we?
We did do that.
♪♪
So he's got
a pretty good track record
for keeping his promises.
♪ Will it wash me clean?
Check his lactic acid
and ABG every hour.
He needs aggressive
fluid resuscitation.
Damn it! V-fib.
Starting compressions.
Should we take him back
to the OR?
Not if we want him
to make it.
- Hold on, Chief.
- Okay.
Let's go.
♪ Oh-oh-oh, oh-oh-oh-oh
Okay. Watch it.
Watch your foot.
Crash cart!
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God! Code Blue. Surgical ICU.
Okay. What's -- What's --
What's happening? Code Blue. Surgical ICU.
What's going on?
Push one of epi!
You have to save him.
Please.
Just do whatever,
just bring him back.
Wright.
I just --
Is he gonna be okay?
- Get the paddles!
- Okay.
Charge to 120.
Clear!
Charge 200!
♪ Mm-mm-mm
Doug Andham to the ICU.
Oh, hey, um...
I saw that Ivan has
a displaced humerus fracture.
I can join
when you do the ORIF,
in case his radial nerve
is severed.
Okay.
I'm not sure how we lived
together that whole time
without discovering
our mutual fear of snakes.
Amelia...
I can't.
I-I-I really --
I can't do small talk with you.
I -- I can't.
You always said
that you didn't want us
to end up
like your parents.
You didn't want that
for Scout.
I don't want that
Can we just decide
to not hate each other?
I need to hate you
for a little while,
right or wrong,
because when
I don't hate you...
I love you.
And we can't have that,
right?
♪♪
♪ Last night,
I went out drinking ♪
♪♪
♪ Wish I had more time
to sleep in ♪
♪♪
♪ Lay with him
till he's awake ♪
♪ I want to stay,
but I'm always leaving ♪
♪♪
♪ Gotta make more money
this Friday ♪
Is he gonna live?
We are gonna do
everything we can.
Mm.
You look like
you could use some rest.
Do you have a ride home?
The man I love
let his pet snake
literally squeeze the life
out of him.
I'm not sure rest
is gonna help me get over that.
I'm standing here,
thinking that I might need
to reassess my entire life.
♪♪
Maybe...hold his hand
for a minute.
Remind yourself
why you love him.
♪♪
Come on.
♪ When the walls
start closing in ♪
♪ Here I go again
♪ Caught in the whirlwind
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh
He sent Gigi
to a rescue organization.
I'm not sure I would be
as forgiving.
Chief,
what you did today...
it was an education
on so many levels.
Dr. Wright...
♪♪
Um, thank you.
I appreciate the vote
of confidence
in how I perform my job,
but before this grows
into a larger problem --
It's -- It's not.
It's not.
And it won't.
I am very sorry
for what I did.I --
It was not appropriate.
No, it wasn't.
But you sent me a signal.
No, I did not.
Yes, you did, too.
I mean, I don't know.
I don't know, maybe you didn't
do it on purpose,
or maybe you didn't think
I'd pick up on it,
because you don't see yourself
that way, but I do.
I see you, and I felt it.
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh
But I amsorry.
And it won't happen again.
Good night, Chief.
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh
♪ It's the never knowing
♪ That keeps me going
You're exactly the person
I wanted to see right now.
Hey.
Is everything okay?
No.
Today was tough,
but you want to go to Joe's
before you pick up Luna?
Oh, um --
Sorry, I told my sister
we were getting a drink,
and she may have raved about you
in a drug-induced haze
for 10 minutes.
You ready?
Um...
Uh, is ev-- You're...?
Go. You have plans.
Okay.
Yeah, ready.
Let's go.
♪ Caught in the whirlwind
♪♪
Okay.
Here you go.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Put this one on there,
too.
Thanks.
Yeah.
I'm exhausted.
Go to bed.
I'll be fine.
I'll probably just fall asleep
on the couch.
No, I mean...
exhausted from this.
Owen, I love you,
and I'm not gonna leave you,
but I -- I need to know
that we come first --
the kids, us, our family.
I-I understand
why you did what you did.
I understand your principles.
I understand your heart.
But, Owen, I swear to God,
don't do something
without talking to me.
Trust me that I-I will figure
out how to support you.
Trust me that
I will be there for you,
or trust me that I will talk you
out of doing something stupid.
But, please, just...
come to me.
I love you, too.
♪♪
I love you.
Shhh!
Oh.
And how many books
tonight?
One, but she, uh --
she made me read it to her
five times.
Oh.
How was your day?
A python tried to eat
a person.
Herniated his abdominal organs
into his chest.
Mm. Dramatic.
Have we been ignoring
a snake?
What?
Well, we're sending mixed
signals to other people.
Oh, oh, no, no.
Ingrid never kissed me.
A woman you rescued
thought you were
inviting her on a date
to Thanksgiving dinner.
Fair.
Mm.
We have stressful jobs.
We hardly see each other.
We
adopted a teenager.
We're doing
a custody battle.
I-I'm worried
that we're feeding a life
that might be squeezing
our marriage to death,
and I don't want to do that,
because
it's too important to me.
You are too important to me
for anyone
to mistakenly think
that we're available.
Yeah.
Miranda Bailey.
I am available to you.
Mm.
♪ I cursed my skin
And only you.
But you're right.
We -- We haven't been spending
much time together.
And we got to fix that.
Yeah.
Also, I don't care how young
and handsome your resident is,
you're never getting rid
of me.
♪ Scared of lonely
C'mere.
♪♪
Don't let go.
Hell no.
When too much pressure
builds within your body,
you might need a surgeon
to relieve it.
We drill burr holes,
place chest tubes,
cut open limbs.Ohh.
Richard.
I thought you were working late
tonight, baby.
I made, um,
a bad call today,
and if a resident
had implemented it,
it could have killed
a man.
♪♪
This morning, you said,
"Not everyone belongs in an OR."
Well, I created
a teaching method,
pressured you and Bailey
to let me implement it,
and it may have ended a very
promising resident's career.
And I might be bringing down
the rest of his class, too,
and I can't,
in good conscience, do that.
What are you suggesting?
I want an assessment.
A physical exam,
a cognitive review,
a fine motor skills test --
I want it all.
And if my judgment
is off...
if I don't belong
in the OR anymore,
then I want to know.
♪ All your beauty
In life, relieving pressure's
not always as easy.
♪ That's all I can see
But it's just as important.
Too much stress takes
a toll
on our mental
and physical health.
♪ When I close my eyes
Hello?
Hey!
Mama!
Hi!
Hey!
How's everybody doing?
I missed you!
Thank you
for picking them up.
Oh, yeah.
No problem.
I got to taste Ellis's
chocolate pudding surprise.
The surprise
is gummy worms!
Are you kidding?
Oh, my goodness!
And I saved you some.
Great.
I'm going to the gym,
because Winston saw
a two-for-one special,
so now I belong to a gym.
Wow.I thought you were
staying for dinner.
You said set
five places.
You know, I brought a guest
home for dinner.
I brought my friend Nick
from Minnesota, Dr. Marsh.
Hello.
♪ So close
You're curing Parkinson's
together?
Uh, no,
I'm a transplant surgeon.
Then how'd you meet?
Uh, well, um...
Your mom saved my life.
♪ Our walls are shaking
Who's hungry?
Me!
Okay.
Do you like
chocolate pudding surprise?
Uh, well, only
if the surprise is gummy worms.
It is!
It is?!
Let's have some, then.
So go for a walk.
Meet up with a friend.
Dance it out.
Wow, okay.
Chocolate pudding surprise.
Let's try it.
♪♪
Mmm!
I love it.
Very good.
Love it.
You know what else I love,
though?
Pizza.
Me, too.
Yes.
Me, three.
Alright.
Seek out the moments of joy
that keep us alive.
♪ Oh, oh, oh
♪ With you
♪♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh
♪ With you
♪ If the world is going up
in flames ♪
♪ I just wanna lay here
with you ♪
♪♪