- Previously on The Resident...
- I had a question for you.
Old friend's developed
a bit of a tremor.
What about benzodiazepines?
Dr. Hunter, if there's
ever an opportunity
to help you with your
research, count me in.
I saw Lily earlier.
She didn't look good.
I went to check Lily's files,
and they were missing.
Dr. Hunter keeps her
patients' records separate
on her own server
at her clinics,
not at the hospital.
The operation came
off without a hitch.
You had a spectacular surgeon.
- Cake.
- Louisa will be taken care of.
But I have to pull two
million dollars out of thin air.
Be prepared to be
woefully understaffed
for the next 12 months.
Hi. Patient in bed six
was triaged as acute.
Uh, he said his pain was a ten.
Ear pain is always rated
the lowest priority: basic.
Certainly not acute, which
means "big deal emergency."
When is Nurse Hundley back?
Oh, she's at St. John's now.
Budget cuts or something.
I got your back.
Tachy, intra-abdominal
bleeding, possible liver lac,
and a right-sided pneumothorax.
- Acute?
- Bus overturned on I-85, multi casualties.
- Ambulances are stacking up outside.
- Page Dr. Hawkins.
We need help down here.
Bilateral femur fractures.
Hypotension, JVD,
and muffled heart sounds
indicate cardiac tamponade.
Both acute... uh, Trauma
Bay Two and, uh, bed eight.
Where is everyone?
It's all blowback
from helping Louisa.
Our budget was cut.
ER staff nearly halved
midnight-to-noon shift.
Right, well, we have
Claire to thank for that.
Nurse Hundley was let go.
Too experienced, too
good, too expensive.
New triage nurse
is a bubblehead.
- All right, let's go.
- Urgent?
Look, I-I don't want to
tell you how to do your job,
but she's awake and breathing.
- Uh... basic. -My hand hurts.
- Yes, ma'am.
Hey.
Hey, I need to see
a doctor, I think.
I wiped out on my skateboard,
I wasn't wearing my helmet.
- Um... Yeah, um...
- My head hurts a little bit.
- Little road rash.
- Okay, a headache, uh, road rash.
Uh, still breathing. Basic.
Please, just, uh, take a seat
in the waiting room.
Charge.
Clear.
Shock.
Still no pulse.
Hair acts as an insulator,
and prevents the shock
from getting to the heart,
which is the point of
the defibrillation, so...
we remove it.
Then we reapply
directly to the skin.
Charge.
Clear.
Shock.
Sinus rhythm.
Where's your ID bracelet?
Didn't get one.
Think I could get an
aspirin? Head's killing me.
Not until you see the doctor.
I'll get you an ID, though.
Hey.
♪ ♪
♪ Push your hand through
the door, pickin' every lock ♪
♪ Make a quick escape... ♪
Brent Carter?
- It's okay.
- Yeah.
Dislocated shoulder.
I've got it.
Good news is we fixed it.
Better?
Yeah.
Here you go.
Excuse me, this isn't mine.
Hey, Irving, bed seven's
in A-fib with RVR, I'm
giving ten of diltiazem.
- Whatever, man. Just do it.
- Excuse me, Doctor.
- Excuse me.
- Yes, we'll be right with you, ma'am.
Doctor, please.
Oh.
Sir?
Hey, sir.
Let's get this
guy to acute, now!
Get his vitals, start an IV.
Let's have the intubation
cart standing by.
He's unresponsive.
Pulse is weak.
Double access, wide open
fluids, peripheral neo for now.
Dr. Okafor, tube him.
On it.
Damn it. Left pupil is blown.
Looks like we have a brain
bleed. Do we have images?
There's no ID bracelet, so
there's no way to know if there
- are tests.
- Is he gonna be okay?
Where is this
patient's ID bracelet?
- Has he even been checked in?
- I-I didn't have time.
- Um...
- What's his name?
Find his name.
Uh, Ian. His name
is Ian Robinson.
- Ian, can you hear me?
- He can't hear you.
My best guess is a
subdural hematoma.
The bleed must be
compressing his brain stem.
Well, is there another
way to relieve the pressure?
- Burr holes?
- Not without scans to know where the bleed is.
I can't just blindly
drill into a brain.
But he's gonna be okay,
right? Because he-he said
he just had a headache.
Please.
Please, no, he...
He can't...
He has no ID bracelet.
You didn't even
admit him properly.
So we have to learn his
name in the middle of a code?
Ian.
His name is Ian.
I found him.
Just lying over
there, unattended,
in basic.
Why didn't you
triage Ian properly?
It's my first day.
Oh, man.
He had a head injury.
That's, at minimum, urgent.
- Always.
- We were so busy...
and he-he seemed okay.
With brain bleeds, there
aren't always symptoms at first.
He had a head injury.
He should be on
concussion protocol...
in urgent.
The patients, they
just... they kept coming.
And I-I didn't want to him to be
marked as urgent
if he was basic.
It's better to be overly
cautious with a head injury.
Now you know what
happens when you aren't.
Next time your
patient won't end up
like Ian, dying alone, in basic.
All right, everyone,
let's get back to work.
Someone is dead
because of her mistake.
Yeah. And she'll always
carry that with her.
He's right.
We need to move on,
and focus on the
patients that we can help.
Abdominal pain.
Bed two.
All you.
Heart rate is 120.
Blood pressure is 110/60.
That's bad.
Well, it just means
your body's working hard
to fight off this infection.
Okay, well, Dr. Hunter just
gave me mega antibiotics,
so it should start working soon.
I'm so sorry you're
going through this, Lily.
Your immune system
was not strong enough
the last time you
left the hospital.
We should've kept you longer.
No, it's not Dr. Hunter's fault.
I mean, she knows
what she's doing.
Of course.
Dr. Hunter has a
great reputation.
Yeah. She's the best
oncologist in Georgia.
Hey, how long have
you had this rash?
Um, just since this morning.
It really itches.
As I remember, you don't have
any allergies to any
medications, right?
Uh, honestly, I-I
can't remember.
Sorry.
The chemo's trashed my memory.
But, i-it should be
in my chart, right?
Well, Dr. Hunter likes to keep
your paperwork at her clinic,
but, um, let me
see what I can do
to get the information
sent over here, okay?
- Okay.
- All right, I'll be back.
Ian's father Paul's here.
We're gonna go talk to him.
You need to learn how to do
one of the hardest things
we have to do as doctors.
Let's go.
Mr. Robinson, I'm
Dr. Conrad Hawkins.
Your son Ian suffered a fall,
and it led to a
subdural hematoma,
which is a massive brain bleed.
This was not a
survivable injury.
Ian's dead?
Yes.
Are you ready?
Yeah.
That...
That-that's not Ian.
That's not my boy.
How's your day going?
Could use a do-over.
Yeah.
We took his picture.
We'll ask everyone who
comes in if they recognize him.
I'll circle back
later in the day.
Let me know if
you find anything.
You bet.
I dropped off the John Doe
report with risk management.
- Now what?
- Go upstairs and see our patients.
Triple-check that anyone
who was admitted from the ER
was properly
diagnosed and treated.
Who knows what mistakes
are coming our way.
I'm counting on you.
What about you?
I'm staying here.
I'll take over triage.
Great.
Show it to all the
patients and everyone
in the waiting area... Ask
if anyone knows who he is.
One thing we know for
sure is he isn't Ian Robinson.
Has the real Ian
Robinson showed up yet?
No. Mr. Robinson isn't even
sure that his son was on that bus.
Right now, we have no idea
how that backpack even got here.
Lily's rash is really
bothering her.
It's probably a
superficial phlebitis.
Change her IV and give her 25
of diphenhydramine.
Of course. Also,
would it be possible
to get her complete chart
sent over from your clinic?
What's wrong with
her record here?
Well, we weren't able to find it
when she was admitted...
It seems to have...
- completely vanished from our system.
- Huh. That's odd.
And since Lily's
multiresistant infection
is so difficult to
treat, I figured
you'd probably be
more comfortable
if we had her
entire history here.
Of course. You're right.
I'll have the clinic
send it right over.
Great. Thank you.
So, how long till Shirley
passes the gallstone?
We're trying to get
out of town for vacation.
Well, it really depends on
how many stones there are.
Any decreased
appetite or weight loss?
Shirley hasn't been eating much.
Have you lost any weight?
Not much. A pound?
More like 15.
Your husband is very attentive.
Howie worries.
But he's not my husband.
He's my boyfriend.
We met six months ago at
an aero-modeling convention.
We were both
building exact replicas
of the Wright brothers' plane.
Yeah. For us, it was love
at first Wright Flyer.
- Okay.
- Please, Doctor,
- please help her.
- Oh, no, my... -Okay.
I'll increase your pain med dose
- and frequency.
- Okay.
As long as you're here,
we'll run a few more tests.
- Thank you.
- I don't want Howie to worry.
Then you better get
these gallstones out quick,
so we can go on
our trip and relax.
Deep breath.
Oh, hey, Dr. Pravesh, I, uh...
I want to touch base with you.
I hope I didn't alarm you
by ordering more tests.
It's probably just gallstones.
Good.
See, we're on our way
to Kitty Hawk and, uh...
I'm gonna propose,
in a big romantic
plane-themed gesture.
- That's great.
- See, when you get to 80
without a wife, you figure
nobody could ever love you.
Then along comes my Shirley.
She... she's my everything.
And if I should propose early,
you let me know.
I'm a practical man, and
I don't want to be morbid,
but...
we're old.
So please take good care of her.
Things seem less chaotic.
Made our way
through the worst of it.
Any word on the identity
- of the John Doe we lost this morning?
- Not yet.
This is a new patient of ours.
Shirley Harris.
Take a look at the ultrasound.
The ER doc diagnosed gallstones.
I'm afraid he missed a mass.
What does the blood work show?
Slight anemia. Weight loss.
Let's get an EUS to better
characterize the mass
and a CT for the
surrounding areas.
And we'll hope for the best.
Yeah. Let's hope.
Kelly.
- What are you doing?
- Preparing for the dissection.
You aren't doing the
dissection; you're a resident.
I do it for Dr. Bell.
Well, he's not here.
When I was a resident,
they wouldn't let me
tie a knot unsupervised.
Give me the Kelly.
Watch and learn.
I have nothing to learn.
You are barely halfway
through training...
There is plenty
for you to learn.
Any action on this? How
much you gonna give me
- if I make the putt?
- Huh. You haven't mentioned money
- since you got a case of the yips.
- How much?
- Hundred.
- You sure?
Downhill, very slippery.
- How about five?
- Easy money.
You haven't even
two-putted in six months.
Thousand?
Fine.
You miss, you donate
a thousand bucks
to my son's school fund-raiser.
Wonderful. For the kids.
I miss the putt, thousand
bucks to your son's school.
I sink it, thousand bucks to...
me.
♪ ♪
Damn it! Man!
I'm back.
She made me hold the
retractors the entire time.
- Like I was... an intern.
- Insanity.
20-something male, John Doe,
fractured left femur,
bruising to the right chest,
- neck injury with possible crushed larynx.
- John Doe?
I thought we had
all the casualties
from the bus accident.
He's the last one... found
him way off in some shrubs.
He must have been
thrown on impact.
Okay, this could be
our guy, Ian Robinson.
Take him to Trauma Two.
Let's hope it's
him... It'd be nice
- to tell Paul we found his son, alive.
- Barely.
He's desatting.
Attending, get a GlideScope.
Airway.
Oh, no. No, no, that's surgery.
You can't do that in the ER.
Not without
attending supervision.
By the time someone gets here,
he'll be brain-dead.
Get the trach kit.
- Are you sure?
- There's no choice.
There is a choice... you
could choose to follow protocol.
- The patient would die.
- I'm not telling that father
his son is dead for
a second time today.
Don't do this.
Stop!
That's normal.
I'll take this photo
up to Paul Robinson
and confirm he's his son.
Not to point out the
obvious here, but you...
are a badass.
Let me see this badass's work.
Surgery performed in the ER
by an arrogant, overconfident,
unsupervised resident.
Flawless technique.
Mm, you know how to cut.
But you don't know when not to.
I'm benching you
for the day. Clear?
Get him up to my OR.
That's unfair... You
saved the patient's life.
Why didn't you say something?
I want to cut tomorrow.
Thank you.
Yeah, we'll work
on both of those.
My office sent over
Lily's file... did you get it?
Not yet.
Are you sure? Did you check?
- Did they e-mail it?
- We don't e-mail
patient files;
they're not secure.
Well, let me check the fax.
No fax.
Is the paper tray empty?
Nope, it's full, just
waitin' for a fax.
Well, my office sent it over.
The problem is on your end.
It's a miracle people make
it out of this place alive.
There's one person
I wish wouldn't.
Yes, that's my son.
Thank you, Dr. Hawkins.
He's in surgery; you can see
him just as soon as he's out.
- Okay.
- We need his medical history.
Is he allergic to anything?
Medications, food allergies?
Any health conditions
I should know about?
- Heart condition, diabetes?
- Let's see,
his doctor said that
he has low calcium.
Too much tension on my
carotid repair. Hold him still.
- Hold him still.
- Baseline is hypocalcemic!
The blood transfusion made
it worse... he needs calcium!
Okay, well, add
calcium to his IV.
What IV? It tore
right out of his arm.
We don't have access.
I'll put in a new
IV. Hold his arm.
- I'll rip his arm out of the socket.
- The seizure won't stop
until we get calcium
into his veins.
Don't let go, no matter what.
I need access now.
There's too much tension...
Almost there. Almost there.
- We're about to have a blowout on our hands.
- I'm in.
Pushing calcium now.
Thank you.
It's gonna help
with your breathing, Lily, okay?
- Page Dr. Hawkins.
- I already paged him.
- Give me the epi.
- Nurses can't administer meds
without orders.
Looks like they can.
Oh, my God.
- Where have you been?
- In a stuffy room
with stuffier administrators
trying to get them to rehire
Nurse Hundley.
Once I pointed out
they could be looking
at a lawsuit, they caved.
She'll be back in the ER
within the hour. She's wheezing.
- What's hanging?
- Saline and imipenem.
I just gave her epi.
Stop the imipenem.
Open the saline wide.
Lily, you're gonna be all
right. I'm gonna sedate you
and put in a breathing tube
- to keep your airway open.
- What's happening?
I'm here, Lily, and I'm
gonna take care of this.
I have to figure out which one
of her meds is
causing the reaction.
- There's... there's so many.
- Well, I don't remember
her having any
sensitivity, so whatever it is,
it's got to be something new.
Her only new med
is the imipenem...
If it is that, we're screwed.
Is she allergic to
any other antibiotics?
- Well...
- Whoa, whoa, wait, wait, wait, hold on.
Her chart only goes back as
far as this current admission.
I know, and I've been
trying to get it sent over
from Dr. Hunter's
clinic since this morning.
They keep insisting they
sent it, but it never arrived.
With Lily's infection, I
don't want to keep her off
the broad-spectrum antibiotic
for long. We need her chart.
Hey, Debbie, can
you cover for me
- for an hour? Can you stay?
- Where you going?
Lane's clinic. We
obviously can't trust them
to get us her chart, so
I'm gonna go get it myself.
Just enhance that a bit more.
- What have you found?
- Shirley Harris's EUS,
CT and supporting lab work
confirm gallbladder cancer.
But the good news
is it's early stage
and confined in the gallbladder.
So there is a real chance
the treatment could
be curative for her?
Well, we can certainly reduce
the chance of recurrence.
The tumor's located
in the neck of the gallbladder.
In order to get clean
margins, some of her liver
- will have to be removed as well.
- It is tricky.
Tricky?
It's a minefield
of blood vessels
and bile ducts,
and she's anemic.
Clip the wrong vessel,
once the bleeding starts,
we might not be able to stop it.
At her advanced age,
there's a real chance
she won't make it through
surgery... why risk it?
I highly recommend
a palliative consult.
Shirley's 80 is a young 80.
More like 60, full of life.
Her boyfriend's about
to propose to her.
She has a lot to live for.
If she makes it off the table.
It has been done
successfully before.
Cancer?
Gallbladder cancer?
Yes. But because
we caught it early,
there's a real chance
for a total cure.
With surgery and radiation.
That sounds simple, but
I'm guessing maybe it isn't.
The surgery itself
is-is complicated.
How complicated?
Could the surgery kill Shirley?
This is a highly
aggressive cancer.
Without the surgery, you
could have less than a year.
But with the surgery, you
can have many more years.
Are you okay?
Shirley, say something.
I might be dying.
And there's only one
thing I want to know.
Howie Green...
will you marry me?
You're not supposed to
ask me that, Shirley Harris.
- I'm gonna ask you.
- Don't be difficult.
- Answer me.
- Yes.
I will marry you,
- only if you marry me.
- Yes!
I will marry you.
So, how do we make sure
this lifesaving surgery
doesn't kill me?
- 'Cause I got a wedding to go to.
- Yeah.
In the hands of
a lesser surgeon,
I wouldn't be as confident,
but you're getting the best.
Dr. Randolph Bell has
the highest success rate.
The man on the billboards?
Yes. He's our chief of surgery.
Are you sure Dr. Bell
is right for this case?
He's done hepatobiliary
surgeries many times.
There's no one else here
who can touch his record.
It's his record
I'm worried about.
His complication rates
have risen dramatically lately.
And I only bring this
up because I know
attendings aren't always
aware of their colleagues.
Every doctor makes mistakes.
Of course, but
this is far beyond.
Conrad, hold on.
I'm gonna speak to you now
as a dear friend and mentor.
You're one of the most
gifted young residents I know.
Don't sabotage a career
that's just beginning.
Doctors must support each
other through good times and bad.
You, of all people,
should know that.
I'm grateful for all you
did for me in the past,
but I have to speak
for my patient.
Shirley's my patient now.
She wants Bell,
who's my choice.
Let's all get on the same
page with this decision.
Shall we?
Excellent.
♪ Money, money ♪
♪ I just can't get enough ♪
♪ Dollar, dollar ♪
♪ I just can't give it up ♪
♪ Brother, brother, I'm
working overtime... ♪
What would it take
to get you unbenched?
The inflammation makes it hard
to get a good view
of the anatomy.
If I were assisting, I
could clear the field
for you to do that.
Dr. Kays benched you.
You're the chief of surgery.
You can unbench me.
I could.
It's a difficult surgery.
What exactly are you implying?
I'm saying your success rate
is better when I'm beside you.
I agree with
Dr. Kays' assessment.
You have gotten a
little full of yourself.
Take the day off.
- Hi.
- How can I make your day better?
- I'm Nic Nevin, from Chastain.
We're still waiting on
Lily Kendall's records.
Yeah, I faxed everything.
Right, um, and I'm sure
the problem's on our end,
but since I'm here,
if you wouldn't mind
- just making me a copy...
- Wait in the lobby.
Sure.
Nurse Hundley. You're back!
You're back! Oh...
As much as I love to
see a man on his knees,
get up, Dr. Feldman.
This place is a mess.
Allie?
Nic?
- I haven't seen you since...
- Nursing school.
Wait, you're not here for...
Oh, no, no, not a patient.
No, I'm just waiting
on some records.
Good. I have to
get back to work.
- We should catch up soon.
- I would love that.
- All right, I'll see you.
- Okay.
Can I help you?
Oh, I was just, uh,
admiring the facility.
That treatment
room is incredible.
You can treat so many
patients at the same time.
Dr. Hunter doesn't want
to turn patients away,
so we squeeze in
as many as possible.
Here's the file.
- All right, let me just make sure it's all here.
- It is.
Okay. Well, thank you.
Bye-bye.
Excuse me, Dr. Hunter.
Dr. Pravesh.
I wrote a paper on
intraoperative
radiation therapy,
so I would love to
observe this afternoon.
Well, you're certainly
welcome to observe,
if there is a procedure.
Medicare hasn't signed off yet.
Let me take that off your plate.
That's industrious. I like that.
Be warned, Medicare
doesn't like to approve
expensive
experimental procedures.
Oh, no worries. I can
be very persuasive.
Please.
Please don't hang up.
They hung up. Unbelievable.
Or believable.
I'm a physician
calling on behalf
of Shirley Harris.
Shirley Harris. H-A-R-R...
I cannot hold again,
okay? Don't you dare...
Hi, yes. I need approval
on an experimental...
Yes, I'll hold.
No, I will not hold!
I have been hung
up on seven times
and on hold for over
an hour and 20 minutes!
There's no code because
it is a new procedure.
Without the tumor resection
and the adjunct
radiation procedure,
the patient will die.
Can you hold on a minute?
You will?
Oh, that's awesome.
Oh, I'm so relieved.
Thank you.
Whoa, whoa. Uh,
where are you going?
Kitty Hawk.
You have surgery this afternoon.
I just got it authorized.
- It took four hours.
- Sorry.
Can't make it.
I'll be standing at the
birthplace of aviation,
marrying the love of my life.
After our honeymoon,
we'll come back
and fight the cancer together.
Right now there
is a window of time
where the cancer is contained
and we can remove it all.
If we wait, the
disease will spread.
Dr. Pravesh...
you don't know that
the cancer will spread
or if the surgery will kill me,
but I know that when I die,
I will be this man's wife.
We're going to Kitty Hawk.
Wait.
Please. What if you
could get married
and have the surgery today?
We want to be
married at Kitty Hawk.
Then I'll bring
Kitty Hawk to you.
How'd you score
the model airplanes?
Howie has hundreds of them.
♪ ♪
So, Irving is a
licensed minister?
And willing to write
a wedding ceremony
filled with airplane puns.
Less surprising.
The photographer?
Publicist.
Renata loves a PR moment.
A hospital story
with a happy ending.
As long as Bell doesn't
kill her on the OR table.
Okay, thank you.
Right, let me know if
anything does turn up.
Still trying to
identify the poor guy
we lost in the ER this morning?
Police are checking
missing persons reports.
I don't know what else
to do to find out who he is.
You understand we can
only save the living ones.
- Right?
- Yeah.
But I can't get his
family out of my head.
What is this thing?
Some sort of lifesaving
playing-card-ectomy?
You should go now.
Mm-hmm.
I'll take it from here, Howie.
To cross this line,
you have to be sterile.
I'm so happy you're
my wife, Mrs. Green.
Well, get used to it.
I'll see you when I
wake up, Mr. Green.
She's in good hands.
Thank you.
♪ ♪
Beautiful incision, Dr. Bell.
Thank you, Jessica. Suction.
Okay.
All set.
So we use the Mobetron
because it allows the electrons
to precisely deliver radiation
and limit the spread
- to non-affected organs.
- Exactly.
We'll give one large
fraction dosage.
Well, don't you need
a radiation oncologist?
I'm double-boarded.
Blood pressure's
dropping, Dr. Bell.
It's fine as a bleeder.
It's nothing I can't handle.
- Do you need assistance?
- No, I need quiet
so I can work.
Vascular clamp.
307.
Run fluids. Wide open.
We're good.
Change the music,
something upbeat.
♪ Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa ♪
All right, we're on.
So, it was a question of anatomy
'cause hers was atypical.
Though it didn't
show up on imaging,
the common hepatic artery
was not in its normal position.
And a less-experienced surgeon
wouldn't have
known to look for that.
They would have tied it off
like a bleeder, not realizing
they're cutting off the entire
blood supply to the liver.
Because I've seen it before,
now I routinely look for it,
and that habitual
extra precaution,
well, that just helped me
avoid a deadly complication.
And now, I believe she
has a honeymoon to go on.
Well, I'm certainly happy
we had you today, Dr. Bell.
♪ Everything I touch ♪
♪ Burns right down ♪
♪ To dust 'cause I'm reckless ♪
♪ Yeah, I'm reckless ♪
♪ And I always seem to fall ♪
♪ On the wrong side of the law ♪
♪ 'Cause I'm reckless ♪
♪ And I can't help ♪
♪ My reckless ways. ♪
I hear you went to my clinic.
I did.
I did. I was impressed.
Beautiful architecture.
Inspiring, really.
Mm. You're very dedicated.
A real gem.
Tumor margins clean.
Clear nodes.
With my hands
and your radiation,
we didn't just buy her
more time, we cured her.
You know, I've
been married twice.
Had my share of affairs,
but I've never really...
had love like that.
But that right there
is why I do this.
Really?
Would you have done the surgery
if Medicare had refused to pay?
No, of course not. I'm
not some gung ho resident.
Would you?
Top Ramen got me
through my residency.
I'm serious.
- It took me years to pay off my student loans.
- Yeah.
Now...
we're the best at what we do.
We save lives.
We deserve to be paid for it.
Amen.
Great to see you back.
It's good to be
seen, Dr. Hawkins.
Don't know what you said
to convince them to rehire
some old ER nurse, but
thanks. I owe you a beer.
Ah, I'd say it's the
other way around.
This place is a
wreck without you.
I heard today was a rough one.
It's a good thing you
were here to take over.
Which reminds me.
A janitor turned this in.
He found it on the floor.
Might belong to your John Doe.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Hello?
This is Dr. Conrad Hawkins
at Chastain Park Memorial.
Is this Erik's mom?
I have some bad news.
Your son came into our ER today
after an accident.
He had a head injury
that was very serious.
We did everything possible,
but unfortunately,
we couldn't save him.
What do you say we get
away together for a few days?
Just us.
That sounds nice.
Where are you thinking?
I don't know.
Kitty Hawk.
If we're gonna
take time off work,
we have to go someplace good.
All right. Wherever
you want to go.
As long as I'm with you.
Kauai.
Just tell me when.
Oh, don't leave.
- Come back here.
- Let me get my computer.
I need to work.
So what are you working on?
This is my own thing.
A group of people not far from
here got some rare sickness.
They think it has something
to do with the drinking water.
Who knows.
Could be the next
Flint, Michigan.
If it is, I'm going
to find the story.
I'm proud of you.
Proud of you.
♪ ♪
♪ And I've walked a
dark and narrow road... ♪
I'm so glad you called.
Well, it's just so nice
to get out for a beer.
And great that you don't have
to work late or do a double.
The hours at the
clinic are great.
I get to help my
kid with homework.
I was gonna ask you, um,
what it's like to
work for Dr. Hunter.
We just had massive budget
cuts at Chastain, so you know,
just checking to see if
there's any greener grass.
I heard. That sucks.
Um, I like working for Hunter.
I mean, the pay is
good, so are the benefits.
She doesn't freak out if
I have to take the day off
'cause my kid's sick.
And it looks like a health spa.
The patients love it.
Well, as much as they can.
Cancer's brutal.
You know, I noticed working
with her patients at Chastain...
- Mm-hmm?
- The chemo dosages she uses are really high.
I'm not a doctor, but I know
she puts a lot of
thought into coming up
with the protocol
for each patient.
Everyone is unique.
That's terrific.
Yeah.
If you do decide you
want to work for Dr. Hunter,
one thing I can tell you is,
she likes everyone who
works for her to be discreet.
Maybe that's why
it was so difficult
to get a patient
file from your office.
I just remembered that my sitter
has to leave
early tonight, so...
Oh, well, maybe another time.
Sure.
♪ Can see our scars ♪
♪ It's what we're made of ♪
♪ It's who we are. ♪
Captioned by Media
Access Group at WGBH