Can I confess something?
'Course you can.
So I picked a coffee shop
for our first date
in case I needed to make
a quick getaway.
In case I was a dud?
Smart.
Very smart.
I get it, trust me.
But I'm going to guess that,
because you're letting me
walk you home,
maybe not a dud?
You guessed right.
Yeah, I've been here
about nine years now.
Oh!
Love Lakeview.
Wrigley's right there.
Britt, what are you
doing out here?
I'm sorry.
I went to the store,
wanted some chocolate milk,
but I forgot my keys.
And your jacket?
This is my daughter, Britt.
Um...
She's supposed to be staying
inside the apartment.
Please, Mom.
Can you just let me in?
Yes, Yes. Come on.
Um, Britt has a problem.
She's been clean a few
weeks now and doing great.
It's just the withdrawal
symptoms are hard.
Oh...
Whoa. Whoa. Whoa. Whoa.
You okay?
My chest, it hurts
when I breathe.
Okay, um, we need to
get her to a hospital.
What? No.
I'll let 'em know
we're coming.
Incoming. Take Baghdad.
Yep.
Cesar?
Gabriel Park, 16,
single GSW to the abdomen.
GCS 15, BP 98/66,
heart rate 118, sats 100%.
I can't move my leg.
Gabriel, I'm Dr. Rhodes.
You hang in there.
What happened?
Gunman held up
the family store.
We were in the back,
stocking the freezer.
And Gabriel was
working the register.
Mr. and Mrs. Park,
why don't you come with me
and let Dr. Rhodes work, okay?
All right.
On my count. One, two, three.
Single bullet hole,
interior abdomen.
Let's get a chest X-ray
and log roll.
On my count, one, two, three.
There we go.
No exit wound. All right, back
down.
Let's find out
where this bullet is.
Everybody clear.
We're gonna take care
of you, Gabe.
X-ray's up.
There it is.
All right, trans abdominal
trajectory.
He needs surgery.
Please, my left leg,
I can't feel it.
Gabriel, I'm going to do
everything I can to fix
your leg,
but right now I need
to look inside your belly
and make sure that
everything is okay.
You understand me? Good.
Call for blood. Let's move him
over to the Hybrid OR.
Page my team. Let's go.
Will.
What's up, Jay?
They just brought that kid in.
He was shot in
a convenience store.
Okay.
So we caught the guy,
and we got the gun
that he used.
Good. Why are you telling me?
CPD ran the serial number
on it, and it's your gun.
The one that was stolen.
Hey. Any word on the boy?
I heard it was your gun.
Don't say it, okay?
The last thing I need
right now is a lecture.
I wasn't going to.
It's not like I put the gun
in the shooter's hand.
It was stolen from me.
I know that.
Look, I know this is
a terrible situation.
I just hope you're talking
to someone.
Your therapist or--
Why do you even care?
You said we were done,
remember?
Hey, any update on
Britt Mills?
Other than learning from
her mom you two were
on your first date?
It had to be awkward
to find her daughter
like that.
Yeah.
Britt's echocardiogram
is showing endocarditis.
It happens sometimes with
intravenous drug users.
I bet bacteria from a needle
worked its way to the heart.
What's cardiology saying?
They advise against surgery.
I think we should treat
with a six-week course
of antibiotics,
so we need to put
in a PICC line.
PICC line? I don't know.
I mean, she's only been
clean a few weeks.
Leaving a catheter in her arm?
That's almost an invitation
to relapse.
But if we don't, she'll have
to come into the hospital
twice a day for infusions.
Got to be another way.
Dr. Rhodes.
Thanks.
Connor, is the kid
gonna be okay?
Yeah, he'll definitely live.
We repaired a bunch of small
bowel where the bullet tore
through,
but it's still lodged in his
spinal canal.
How bad is it?
Too soon to tell,
but when he came in,
he said he lost feeling
in his left leg.
We're sending him up to CT,
get a better idea of what's
going on.
Neurology's gonna
take a look at him.
We got it.
Maggie, female mid-30s,
syncopal episode in the field.
Down maybe 30 seconds
before roused by bystanders.
Sydney?
Hey, Maggie.
Hey.
Dr. Lanik, you're going
to Treatment Three.
Went from GCS 12 to 14
with a sternal rub,
supplemental oxygen,
and 250 mils normal saline.
Monitor showing multiple PVCs.
I fainted.
Yes, and we're going to take
very good care of you.
BP's a little low,
100 over 66,
and heart rate, 78.
But I'm not sure
if she's beta blocked.
Okay, transfer on my count.
One, two, three.
She's got a tunneled cath
in the left upper chest.
That's for dialysis.
She's on the list
for a kidney.
Hey, order a 12-lead EKG.
All right.
Am I gonna be okay?
Yes, you are.
Where's that X-ray?
Okay, clear.
Ms. Curry?
Ooh, mild fluid overload.
So?
Cardiac enzymes,
BMP, CBC, blood cultures
times two.
Yeah, give her a dose of vanc.
25 milligrams per kilogram.
On it.
Repeat her vitals and let me
know when her labs are back.
Okay.
You know this patient?
She grew up near me.
Came in a couple weeks ago
with sepsis.
I should have seen her
immediately.
Feels like somebody's
sitting on my chest
and my back at the same time
ever since we got back
from that cross-country
ski trip two days ago.
I never felt
anything like this.
This isn't like him.
Patrick's always so healthy,
even if he sort of let himself
go the last few years.
Really, Alice?
It's your medical history.
It's relevant, isn't it?
Uh, yeah.
Does the pain extend down
your arm or up to your jaw?
No.
Does this hurt?
Out of 10,
10 being the most painful.
Uh, I guess a five.
Okay, let's get a CBC, CMP,
troponins,
and set Mr. Novak
up for an EKG.
Patrick?
No pulse.
What?
He's not breathing, bag him.
Got it.
But he's got normal sinus
rhythm.
There's no pulse.
He's in PEA. Call a code.
Patrick?
We need help in here!
Need an airway!
Look.
He just opened his eyes.
He's breathing on his own.
Oh, thank God.
Honey, are you okay?
Patrick?
Asystole.
Milligram of epi, now.
Intubate him.
Hold off. Patient's
breathing on his own.
Can someone tell me
what is happening?
Your husband's
in cardiac arrest,
but as long as I'm doing
compressions, he's getting
oxygen to his brain.
We'll keep at it until
his heart takes over.
Honey, Patrick.
I'm right here.
You're saying it's not
just the withdrawal?
I have a heart infection?
Symptoms of endocarditis
usually come on slowly
and they're often mistaken
for heroin withdrawal.
The chest pains you were
feeling this morning.
We can treat endocarditis
with long-term antibiotics,
which normally involve leaving
a catheter in the arm.
A PICC line.
It's okay,
I'm used to needles.
Britt, we really get how
tricky early sobriety can be,
and we just want to put you
in the best possible position
to succeed.
So if we're gonna give you
this PICC line,
there's something else
we'd also like you
to consider.
What?
Well, it's a drug
called naltrexone that blocks
the effects of opioids
on the brain's limbic system,
essentially making it
impossible to get high.
There's a drug that'll stop me
from getting high?
Let's do that.
Listen, naltrexone is by
no means a magic bullet,
and it comes with certain very
real risks.
The thing is, Britt,
you can't take it
unless you've been opioid-free
for at least 14 days.
If there are any opioids
in your system,
the Naltrexone could trigger
severe side effects.
I'm clean.
For over two weeks.
Okay, well, it's also crucial
for you to understand,
if you were to use, it could
very well lead to an overdose.
I'm not going to. Ever.
She's been trying so hard.
Okay, well, we just need
to do a urine test
to be safe and...
And we're set.
Okay.
This is great,
I mean...
Ava.
Hello, Connor.
Um...
How's the hand?
It's much better.
It was my fault.
I should have gotten my hand
out of the way.
Well, maybe I could have
been a little more careful.
Look, I am sorry that
I haven't been able to
come by to check on you.
It's okay.
I know we're not in
the best of places right now.
Yeah.
Dr. Rhodes.
Once again, you are doing
your best to ruin my day.
Maybe I should go.
No, no, you stay, Dr. Bekker.
This concerns you, too.
Two months ago, you operated
on a gunshot victim,
a Shawn Corcoran?
Yeah?
And you assisted?
He died,
and someone is alleging
that you brought him to
the ICU with his abdomen
left open
when you should have
closed him.
And then, you lightened
his anesthesia prematurely
all contributing
to his death.
Who made these allegations?
It was an anonymous complaint.
Unfortunately, the hospital
oversight committee is obliged
to do a root cause analysis
into the case.
You'll both be interviewed.
And then what?
Well, if the committee finds
that the charges have merit,
you, Dr. Rhodes,
will be brought before
a peer review board.
But hopefully,
that does not happen.
Your Hybrid OR has cost
this hospital a fortune,
but it has made
for some good PR.
The last thing I need is
a scandal involving its chief.
Connor, peer review?
You could lose your license.
Yeah.
Mr. Davis, you're back.
Yeah, it's starting
to feel like we live here.
But I'm just a little bit
worried about Sophie.
What's the matter with her?
She's not eating
like she should,
and she's sleeping
more than usual.
All right. Well, why don't you
lay her down right here
and I'll take a look, okay?
Okay. You're okay.
Shh...
Just right here.
Hey...
100.1.
She is running a fever.
Okay.
I'm not seeing anything
unexpected.
Okay.
Don't worry,
we'll figure this out.
Put in an IV and check
the patency of the G-tube.
It could just be she's not
getting her fluids
and nutrition in.
Right.
This have anything to do
with her heart condition?
I don't know yet.
Um, it could just be that,
right now,
she's not getting
the nourishment she needs.
But let's just check
the tube first,
and then we'll go from there,
okay?
Okay.
All right.
Ms. Hawkins,
your tests show potassium 9.2,
chloride 115, BUN 105,
and creatinine 6.
What that mean?
It means your dialysis
hasn't been working.
When was the last time
that you went to the center?
A few days ago. Why?
And did they mention any
problems with your flow rates?
Because your catheter is
clotted.
Maybe told you to come to the
hospital and get it replaced?
Oh, something like that,
maybe, yeah.
But then I got too sick.
That's okay, we'll get it
all fixed up,
and get you emergency
dialysis.
Mmm-hmm. Meanwhile, we need
to lower your potassium.
Let's give her an amp
of bicarbonate,
10 units regular insulin,
an amp of D50,
and then 8.4 grams
of patiromer.
Got it.
All of that?
It's really bad, isn't it?
Mmm-hmm.
You need a new kidney.
I'm gonna see if I can
get you moved up on
the transplant list.
Maggie.
You're taking such
good care of me.
Thank you.
No more ski trips,
I promise.
I know you didn't want to go.
Dr. Halstead, should we
get him on ECMO?
We can't put a patient on ECMO
unless we have a plan to get
him off it.
Then what can we do?
This is it.
There's nothing else.
I'm not gonna stop
until his pulse comes back.
You need a break.
Let me take over for a while.
All right. Switch.
Hey, you good?
I'll be right back.
Based on my experience,
it's definitely the best
course of action.
Okay.
Hey, Sam.
What's the report
on the GSW victim?
Since when is he your patient?
Come on, Sam.
Bullet lodged in his cord
at T12,
hematoma surrounding the cord.
Kid's hemiplegic on his left
side, right leg still works.
Wait, so there's a chance
he'll regain feeling
in his left leg
when you pull the bullet out?
No, we're leaving it in.
Removing the bullet risks
substantial bleeding along
with more potential damage
to the spinal cord,
which could result
in the kid being paraplegic.
Well, isn't that
worth the risk
if it means he might gain
full function back?
Well, I'd rather have one
good leg than two bad ones.
Wait, look, we're talking
about a kid, here.
Okay? With his whole life
ahead of him.
Halstead, no one asked
for your uninformed opinion,
and the family's made their
decision.
Go back to the ED
and put a Band-Aid on someone.
Good news, the urine tox
screen came back clean.
I wasn't worried.
Monique, let's administer
the first dose of naltrexone,
then send her up
to the IR for a PICC line.
Could you turn on your side,
please?
Mmm-hmm.
Honey, are you...
Are you sure about this?
This is a really big step.
Yes, Mom. I'm sure.
Just a little pinch, okay?
That's it.
Thank you, both.
I understand what she does
for a living,
but she's been
responsible with her health.
She's not high risk.
Yes. I understand.
That about Sydney?
Yeah, she's on the bottom
of the transplant list
because she's a sex worker.
When she came in,
I kept her waiting.
I didn't take her seriously.
I didn't realize
that she was septic.
Maybe if I hadn't kept her
waiting, this wouldn't have
happened.
Maggie, you don't know that.
You know, we grew up a couple
blocks from each other.
Huge difference,
those couple blocks.
April?
I want you to do a blood
draw on me.
A blood draw?
Maggie, you cannot be serious.
Treatment Four's open.
Let's go.
She's not breathing.
Sats are down to 60%.
Start bagging.
Sats are coming back up.
88, 93.
Need to intubate.
I'm in. Bag her.
Call for a vent
and get a chest X-ray.
She's stable for now.
What's wrong with her?
I don't know yet, but we're
gonna get to the bottom of it.
Come back, Patrick.
Please?
Just come back.
Dr. Halstead,
it's been 10 minutes.
Stay with me, please, baby.
Excuse me.
Will, I need a word.
Gabriel and his parents
are now saying
they want the surgery
to remove the bullet.
Glad to hear it.
You had no right
interfering with my patient.
Hey, all I did was make sure
they knew their options.
No, you went in there
and advocated for a surgery
that they had decided against.
Connor, this kid shouldn't
have to live
the rest of his life
with only one good leg.
No, he shouldn't,
but what happened happened,
and we can't change that.
Well, maybe we can.
Maybe he can go back to
the way he was.
Will, I get it, man.
It was your gun.
You might have some messed up
idea that this was somehow
your fault,
but pushing for that surgery,
the kid could wind up in a
wheelchair.
Or he could be made whole
again.
I have a patient to attend to.
Help!
Somebody help my daughter!
Excuse me.
Need noodle.
Not noodle...
She's seizing, five milligrams
of Ativan.
Easy...
Meds are in.
Dan, help her! Help her!
Help her!
BP 154 over 94.
Heart rate 118.
Sats 92%.
She's stable.
How did that happen?
Was it the injection?
No, only if Britt had drugs in
her system.
But... But she didn't.
Did she?
Maggie, come with me.
We need the room.
I'm on the transplant
committee.
I am notified
about every HLA match.
Did you really think
I wouldn't find out
that you planned to donate
a kidney?
Well, I hoped you wouldn't,
because I didn't want to have
this discussion with you.
Maggie, undergoing surgery
for a patient,
an irreversible procedure,
is a violation of professional
boundaries.
I'm sorry, but I don't care.
So who are you doing it for?
For her or for you?
For me?
Well, look.
I've gone through Sydney's
records.
She was already in
septic shock
when she came in, Maggie.
We did everything
we could for her.
So if this is coming out
of some misplaced
sense of guilt--
She's at the bottom
of the transplant list.
She's never gonna get
a kidney,
and she's gonna die
if I don't give her mine.
But have you stopped
to consider your own health?
Wha--
Donating puts you at risk,
Maggie, for infection,
hypertension, intestinal
obstruction--
Those are very rare
side effects.
Okay, but what if
your remaining kidney fails?
People who donate kidneys do
just fine, and you know that.
It is still an ethical
violation
and I can't, I just...
I can't let you do this.
Sharon, there's nothing
that you can do
that's gonna stop me.
Actually, there is.
You're out of paid
sick leave days.
You can't take the time off
to recover.
Not without jeopardizing
your employment.
Lose my job?
You would do that?
Maggie...
Yes, I would.
She could have died.
My baby could have died.
I'm just stumped as to how...
How she passed the urine test.
I don't know.
Jackie.
It was mine. It was my urine.
She swore that she was clean,
and then, when you said
she was gonna have to do
a drug test, she told me.
She told me she'd shot up
a week ago.
And you went ahead anyway?
She...
She said that it
wasn't that much.
That it wouldn't matter.
You have to understand,
this has been going on
for such a long time.
I've tried everything.
I got her a therapist.
I got her a job.
I hardly ever leave her alone.
And still, every morning,
I wake up and I find
that she's figured out
some other way to get high.
The naltrexone gave me hope
that it would save her.
Also could've killed her.
Jackie, I cannot even imagine
how brutal this must be.
But I'm gonna be very honest
with you.
As a parent, I understand
the need to protect
your child,
and as long as you
keep doing that,
she's never going to
get better.
The committee's running
a little behind.
Ava, you are blameless
in all of this.
I made every decision
in the OR.
Dr. Bekker,
they're ready for you.
Hi.
Um, Sophie's MRI shows
an abscess.
An area of swelling
in the right frontal lobe
of her brain.
It's an infection.
How... Why...
It can happen in children
with congenital heart disease.
Bacteria originating
from the heart travels
up to their brain.
Mmm-hmm.
So the neurosurgeons
would like to take her
up to the operating room
to have a catheter placed
and the abscess drained.
A catheter in her head?
The good news is that
the abscess is small enough
so that she won't need
a craniotomy. Surgery.
When my wife found out
that she had a brain aneurysm,
the doctors said
it was small enough
that she didn't need
to have surgery,
and then it killed her.
I can't make you any promises,
but I can tell you that
this is an entirely
different situation.
I'm hopeful.
You should be, too.
Okay.
Let me check for a pulse.
Move.
Patrick, come back!
Oh, no.
No, you hang on, Patrick.
Please.
You hang on, Patrick.
Dr. Halstead.
Oh, God.
No...
I'm sorry.
It's my fault.
I did this to him.
Okay, we are ready to start
your dialysis.
Huh?
Sydney?
She's in v-fib.
It's her potassium.
Call a code.
Code Blue! Get Lanik in here.
Start bagging.
Still in v-fib.
Paddles.
Charge to 200.
Charged.
Clear.
Still in v-fib.
Milligram of epi.
Epi's in.
Charge again.
Charged.
Clear.
Back in sinus rhythm.
Another round of insulin,
glucose, and two amps
of bicarb.
Got it.
Sydney, I'm right here.
Sam, don't do the surgery.
Are you on drugs?
You're the one
who pushed for this.
I was wrong.
It wasn't a clinical decision.
It was emotional.
Yeah. Well, it's too late.
Please, talk to the family.
I already have.
You made such
a compelling case for surgery
that they're determined
to go through with it.
Well, tell them you refuse
to do the surgery.
I did.
They said they'd get
another surgeon.
At least if I do it, there's
a decent chance of success.
Come in.
Maggie?
I'm applying for the
Family Medical Leave Act...
To get the time off I'll need
for recovery from surgery.
You're determined to do this
no matter what I say?
Yes.
Why, Maggie?
Why is this patient
so different from any other?
She isn't.
I see so much
suffering every day.
Day after day, and there's
nothing I can do about it.
But this time I can.
This one time, I can.
It's just impossible to think
that I would stand by
and let her do this
to herself.
Well, it's completely
counterintuitive.
I mean, as parents, we're
programmed to fix our
children's problems, right?
Dr. Charles,
did you release Britt?
She's gone.
Britt?
Britt! Britt!
She took her clothes, too.
Where's she gonna go
with a PICC line?
She went to get high.
Let's just hope
she doesn't OD.
Hey.
You were right.
I felt guilty.
Hoped I could
turn back the clock.
Make it like the whole thing
never happened.
Yeah.
If he wakes up
worse than before,
I'll never forgive myself.
Let's just hope for the best.
Connor.
I heard you're facing
the oversight committee.
What's that all about?
I... Old case, pro forma.
It's no big deal.
She's not answering
any of my texts.
I knew I shouldn't have
taken my eyes off of her.
Jackie...
You don't understand.
I'm her mother.
I have to find her.
And how many times
have you done that already?
Dr. Rhodes?
Dr. Rhodes, please.
Dr. Latham, I want it
to be clear that I bear
full responsibility
for Mr. Corcoran's surgery
and its outcome.
Be that as it may,
we didn't call you in
to hear your statement.
We called you in to apologize.
Apologize?
Dr. Bekker made it
eminently clear that
all of your decisions
were sound, both medically
and ethically.
I reviewed Mr. Corcoran's
chart and given the severity
of his injuries,
find no reason to disagree.
I'm not sure that Dr. Bekker
knows the details of the case.
Dr. Rhodes, the committee
has determined that
you are not at fault
for Mr. Corcoran's death.
You may go.
You told them that I did
everything in the patient's
best interest?
Yeah.
You and I both know that
some of my actions were
questionable.
We have no way of knowing
if they had any effect
on the outcome.
Still, the oversight
committee should have heard--
Why, so you can face peer
review and lose your license?
Connor, I did it for you.
I'd do anything for you.
I'll be back to
check on you. Thank you.
Sam?
I was able to remove
the bullet without causing
any more trauma.
So?
He'll be fine.
Thank you.
You know, your behavior
today has been
erratic, irrational, and
impulsive,
hardly qualities one wants
to see in a physician.
You need to get your head
out of your ass.
There's nothing
you can do right now.
We just have to wait and see
how Sophie responds
to the antibiotics.
Why don't you go home
and get some sleep?
Okay.
Come in.
Ms. Goodwin, um...
I'm not entirely
comfortable with
how things were left
with the oversight committee.
I am.
I just don't think
that Mr. Corcoran's case
was accurately presented.
I'm guessing you're talking
about when you lightened
his sedation
so Detective Halstead could
interview him.
Yes.
And wasn't that done
in an attempt to save
Will Halstead's life?
I assume when you made
that decision,
you hoped Mr. Corcoran
would survive.
Ms. Goodwin, lightening
Mr. Corcoran's sedation
might have contributed
to his death.
Might have.
There's no way to know.
He was gravely injured
when he was brought in.
You know,
I was reminded today,
in our effort
to help people that
we sometimes find ourselves
in situations where
what's right and what's wrong
isn't entirely clear.
And we can only hope
that the decisions we do make
are coming from
the right place.
Go home, Dr. Rhodes.
Hey.
Gabriel pulled through.
He's gonna be fine.
Glad to hear it.
For both of you.
Yeah.
Sam Abrams told me
to get my head out of my ass.
He's right.
Don't be too hard on yourself.
It was a tough call. I get it.
I gotta find Nat.
Night.
Congratulations, Connor.
Heard you got a pass.
And I'm sure you thought
I was the snitch.
You know,
the thought crossed my mind.
I wish I could
take credit, but
your patient croaked
in the ICU and I didn't even
know about it,
so I guess the question is,
who was the snitch?
Why now?
Months after the fact.
Got an enemy out there.
So you'll be in tomorrow?
Yeah, I'll see you
in the morning.
Dr. Manning?
You can call me Natalie.
Natalie.
If it weren't for you,
I don't know how
I would get through this.
So thank you.
Yeah.
Have a good night.
You too.
Natalie.
Yeah?
What's going on?
What?
I came to apologize
and tell you
I wanna start taking
therapy seriously.
That's great.
But I find you hugging
this guy.
Will, I--
No, tell me something.
Was it all really about me
having a gun
or was it about another guy
and you just couldn't tell me?
I don't even know
what to say to that.
That man just lost his wife.
His baby could die.
He is all alone.
He needs someone
to be there for him.
So do I, Natalie.
So do I.
What are you doing out here?
Aren't you going home?
I've been thinking
who was in the Hybrid OR
who knew about my decision,
who had the expertise
to judge it?
You think it was Marty?
Or Sofia?
No, if they'd had a problem,
they would have raised it
at the time.
I think it was you.
What?
I... I defended you.
Exactly. You're...
You're like a pyromaniac
that sets a fire just
to put it out.
Uh... Why in God's name
would I do that?
For the same reason
you slept with my father
and put your hand
where you knew I would cut it.
What?
To keep me tied to you.
Risk my health?
Like you said,
you'd do anything, right?
This is insane.
My God, can you hear yourself?
Ava, I think you got a problem
and I think you need to get
some help.
I've done nothing
but support you and help you.
You're the one
with the problem, Connor.
You're the one who
should get some help.