Don't miss the new season of
"The Resident."
First tenet of our
profession, do no harm.
See all-new
episodes Tuesdays.
And check out our
other Fox shows,
"9-1-1," "9-1-1 Lone Star," and
"Prodigal Son," only on Fox.
Previously on
"The Resident"...
Dr. Voss, the CEO job
- is yours if you want it.
- You're damn right I do.
No one has the skill set
for a double hand replacement.
I might have someone.
Dr. Jake Wong,
my former stepson.
Chastain wants you here
permanently.
What do you say?
I'll be looking forward
to working with you again,
Dr. Voss.
My O-1 visa is expiring,
and so I applied way in advance.
Yesterday, I found out
it was denied.
Cain may be down,
but he's definitely not out.
Can't stay here.
Where is he being taken?
There's only one option.
Hey, you're up.
Shh.
You hear that?
I don't hear anything.
Exactly.
Silence.
Once our baby comes,
you can kiss that goodbye.
I think we can handle
whatever she throws at us.
Yeah, sure.
But you know...
feedings, crying, diapers...
That's just the beginning.
- I did two rotations in Peds.
- Oh,
did you have to
deal with nightmares?
"Oh, Mom, Dad, can I come sleep
in the bed with you?"
Then, suddenly, she's a teenager
and she's out
with her friends
till 1:00 in the morning
and you can't sleep
because your heart's pounding
so hard.
I didn't think about that.
All I'm saying is let's just
enjoy the peace
while it lasts.
Technically, you are
a recovering patient.
Maybe I should stay home
with you today.
Mm...
Go.
Mwah.
- Hello?
- Hawkins.
Man, I'm glad you picked up.
Hey, Captain, we still
on for drinks on Friday?
Well, that depends.
You still work with
Search and Rescue, right?
Yeah. What's wrong?
Decided to do
some free-climbing.
Let's just say
it didn't go my way.
Okay, what are we looking at
in terms of injuries?
Remember the shrapnel injury
that Rodriguez took
during the live...
live fire exercise?
- That bad?
- It's worse.
I figured that you could, uh,
get SAR moving
'cause you know 'em personally.
Well, I called
Search and Rescue.
They're trying to track his cell
signal before his battery dies.
Helped him stem the bleeding,
but it sounds like
- he's gonna need an OR.
- And who is this guy?
This is Captain Hill,
my commanding officer
in Afghanistan.
Of all of the stories
you've ever told me,
you never mentioned a Hill.
I know. I haven't spoken to him
in years.
A few weeks ago, he calls me,
says he wants to talk.
What aren't you telling me?
I promise
I'll tell you more later.
Just trust me, please?
Okay.
I love you.
He's in respiratory distress!
All right,
this may be uncomfortable.
Let me breathe!
He's-he's breathing.
*THE RESIDENT*
Season 04  Episode 07
Episode Title: "Hero Moments"
Aired on: March 02, 2021
Hill's cell signal puts him
within 100 meters
from this point here.
It's hilly terrain,
so we split up,
each cover a different sector.
Get Hill out
before the storm hits.
Next few hours are critical.
Hey. Here you go.
Four shots, extra dry cap.
No sweetener.
Not the reaction
I was expecting.
Because you're still thinking
about your immigration status.
My lawyer hasn't called yet.
She will. All right?
Just... just be patient.
Patience is for
kindergarten teachers.
They already denied
my visa renewal,
so this self-petition
is my last shot.
You know,
if only there were a...
a once-in-a-lifetime surgery
happening today
to take your mind off things.
Maybe something like,
I don't know...
a quadruple heart valve
replacement?
- Mm.
- One only done by 20 surgeons
in the entire world and now us.
I have been dreaming of those
40 sutures for weeks.
Oh, I know.
Last night you muttered
the valves in your sleep:
Aortic, pulmonary, tricuspid...
I did not.
- Did I?
- Hmm.
Ms. Williams, I'm Dr. Pravesh.
I see that you're experiencing
- some hip pain from sickle cell.
- Like I told your nurse,
I need Dilaudid.
Two milligrams IV.
It's the only thing that helps.
I see that you've been
to five different ERs
in the past few months.
IV opiates each time.
I'm not drug seeking.
Do you know what
a sickle cell crisis is, Doctor?
Your red blood cells
become misshapen,
like a sickle, not a sphere,
and it blocks blood flow
to your organs and bones.
Yes, you know the science.
But do you know
how it feels?
Sharp, stabbing pain in my back,
my shoulders,
even my cheekbones.
And when they come on,
they're more excruciating
than you can understand.
Ms. Williams,
that is not why I'm not...
I don't want to be here.
And if you're not going
to help me, then...
maybe I should leave. Ah...
Did that little movement
hurt you?
Tell me more about your pain.
My hip feels like it's on fire,
even when I'm still.
It's not like
my usual crisis pain.
And when I move...
it tears through me,
like shards of glass
in my veins.
Here.
Stop.
Stop, stop, stop.
Okay. Tell you what.
I will give you
what you need...
if you let me take
an X-ray of that hip.
And figure out what's going on.
Deal?
Captain Hill!
Found him.
We're a hundred meters northwest
of Many Point Creek.
Roger that.
Hang in there, Captain.
Let's have a look, shall we?
Ah, deep gash
through the abdomen.
Looks like it's gone
through the peritoneum.
How far out are you?
Ten mikes.
That's not soon enough, is it?
You're bleeding internally,
into your abdomen
and likely into your chest.
I'm gonna die out here.
Well, not on my watch, Cap.
We need to buy you
some more time.
No idea what
you're making there,
but am I correct in guessing
- that it's really gonna hurt?
- Yeah,
afraid so.
This is an old trick
I learned back in training.
- You can handle it.
- Yeah.
I'll make a slight incision.
All right. You ready?
Do your worst.
Here we go. One, two, three.
That's better.
Hey, everything all right?
Found him. We're going to
airlift back to Chastain.
Okay, I'll meet you there.
Page Austin for me.
I want him to meet us in the ER.
Keep pushing.
As hard as you can.
Well, Barrett,
you're doing quite well
for someone
who just came off the vent
this morning.
What about
the damage in surgery?
The medial cord
was completely severed.
Partial laceration
of the lateral.
Both primarily repaired.
I'm sorry,
but the chances of you regaining
full function of your hand
are 50% at best.
Will I ever operate again?
I expect your strength
and mobility to return,
but it will take weeks,
maybe months of PT
before you can even think
about operating again.
It will be painful
and strenuous.
I can deal with the pain.
More than pain tolerance,
what this process requires
is patience.
We're done here.
I should get back to Chastain.
Tell the new CEO
I want to talk to him.
You just did.
So, I overheard
some nurses saying
you stole the show
at Waylan's last night.
It was an ambush.
They didn't tell me
it was karaoke night
and I ended up singing
"I Want It That Way"
with half of Radiology.
Well, I'm glad to see
you're making friends.
Thank you, but it's not like
I'm 12 years old,
starting a new school.
♪ Are you okay sleeping
through the silence ♪
♪ Give me space and time ♪
♪ Allow us
to become whole again ♪
♪ We deserve to try ♪
♪ Step beside your body ♪
♪ Got to think about
that somethin' inside ♪
♪ We all need something ♪
♪ A little breakthrough ♪
♪ I won't let you down, no ♪
♪ I don't want to leave you ♪
♪ No matter what comes our way ♪
♪ We gonna make due ♪
♪ When the river runs dry,
I won't give up on you... ♪
Well... this
seems like the perfect day
for a ten-hour
valve replacement.
Ready for bypass.
♪ I won't give up on you ♪
♪ Give up on you. ♪
So every time you have a crisis,
the sickled blood cells
block blood flow
to the hip bone right here.
Over time,
that bone starts to die.
We call it avascular necrosis.
It's why you're in so much pain.
Okay, so we treat the pain,
get me back on my feet,
I go back to PT.
Well, I'm afraid pain management
and PT aren't gonna cut it,
and that's why
I brought in Dr. Voss
- to see you.
- I'm sorry, Rose,
but you're gonna need
a hip replacement.
Sorry, I have to get this.
Let me know what you decide.
I'm not doing the surgery.
The risks are too high.
I know it's scary,
but a hip replacement
- is your best option, Rose.
- Doctors never get it.
You're the ones
with the medical degrees,
but I have to school you
on my disease.
- It's exhausting.
- I know from personal experience
that many patients of color
aren't heard.
Chastain is different.
I'm different.
Help me understand.
Surgery for sickle cell patients
is even riskier.
You could fix my hip
but leave me with other issues.
Tell me I won't have
an anemia crisis
or a cardiac crisis or worse.
I can't imagine the pain
you've endured, and I understand
why you are reluctant
to think more time in a hospital
- would help you. I get it.
- It's more than just that.
It's about how I want
to live my life.
I'm a dancer.
Was a dancer.
When the pain got to be so bad
that I had to stop,
I put all of my savings
into a studio.
Now I teach dance
to high-risk kids.
Tonight they have a recital
to showcase all their hard work.
Those girls, they're my life.
And I want to be there tonight.
I'd rather limp and be alive
than die sooner
because of a surgery.
Your hip is about shot.
I want to do it today because
it's best that we take advantage
of this window
while you're relatively well.
Because during
a sickle cell crisis,
there would be such
a high possibility
of a fatal blood vessel blockage
that a surgery would be
even more dangerous.
So, Rose, let me help you.
We will do everything we can
to keep you safe.
That's a promise.
All right,
first suture's in place.
Threading
through the suture ring.
Slight drop in pressure.
- Blood volume decreasing.
- Keep transfusing.
Some blood loss is not atypical.
The call was for Dr. Austin.
Incoming abdominal trauma
with hemothorax.
Dr. Hawkins is requesting
you personally.
Conrad seldom does this.
Whoever the patient is
must be special.
Which is why I have to go.
But we're fine here.
I'll step out for a minute,
take care of this trauma
and be back the moment I'm done.
Anything goes wrong,
they'll blame the attending.
Mina, you got this.
38-year-old male
with penetrating injuries
to the chest and abdomen.
Initially hypotensive.
O2 sat falling despite
chest tube placed in the field.
It's been a long time since
I felt pain like that.
You're talking,
so airway's intact.
We need to get
two units of O-neg running.
We need a portable
chest X-ray ASAP!
On my count. One, two, three.
- Hemothorax?
- Drained about 750cc's in the left chest.
It was likely a rupture
to his diaphragm.
- Oh...
- That's more blood than we'd like.
I need to get him to the OR.
His vitals are stable.
Stop by CT first?
Yeah. We'll get X-ray
then we'll pack him.
- I'll let OR know we're coming.
- Thank you.
- Hey. You made it.
- Hey.
What's going on?
Uh, he's stable at the moment.
I'm just waiting
on the chest X-ray.
Okay.
I want to see
the tube placement.
- This can't be right.
- Apart from the chest tube
and a few broken ribs,
looks clear to me.
Hey. Talk to me. What's wrong?
Nate's chest,
it shouldn't be clear.
- Why?
- There should be
a bullet
next to his spine and...
there isn't.
Okay, so, the bullet
that you're talking about,
you think it migrated
to another place in his body?
Yeah, and I need
to help them find it
'cause Nate got shot
saving my life.
Nate and I were
approaching a target
in the Sangin Valley.
We got ambushed.
Take cover!
They got us surrounded!
Nate ordered us to pull back.
Flank up!
But...
I thought one of our Marines
who got shot up
on the road ahead
was still alive, so...
Hawkins, stay put!
That's an order!
Fall back! Fall back!
I made my way up the road,
I get there,
and...
he's dead.
I start to head back,
to regroup with my company.
But I get blindsided by an RPG.
I had a dislocated shoulder,
broken knee,
shrapnel in my neck.
Figured this was it.
And then Nate showed up.
Saved my life.
That's when he, that's when he
caught three in his chest.
But he kept going,
made sure we both got to cover.
Doctors got two
of the bullets out,
but the third was lodged
near his spine
and it was too dangerous
to remove.
It wasn't giving him any
trouble, so they left it there.
And now it's gone.
I can't believe you kept this
to yourself all these years.
It wasn't my proudest moment.
I disobeyed an order
and it nearly cost my commander
and friend his life.
I was...
ashamed.
You were just doing your job,
and so was Nate
when he came back for you.
When I was a kid, my mom
used to make me practice needlepoint.
And I would get so annoyed
and I would tell her
that nobody uses that skill
in the real world.
I'm gonna call her tonight
and I'm gonna beg
for her forgiveness.
Well, this is needlepoint
times a thousand.
If all 40 sutures
aren't perfectly placed,
the valve won't fit
or the heart muscle will rip,
and we start over.
Okay.
♪ 'Cause I was dyin' ♪
♪ For this love, this love ♪
♪ Yeah, I was dyin' for
your love, your love... ♪
Ah. Perfect fit.
Now, by the time I'm ready
to insert the next valve,
Austin should be here.
Actually, he won't.
That was Dr. Austin
on the phone.
He took care
of Dr. Hawkins' patient,
but an aortic rupture
just came in.
He wants me to keep going.
- Alone.
- He says to tell you
that you know this heart
just as well,
if not better than him.
You got this.
Then we keep going.
Okay.
Suction.
What's going on?
Get me a liter of normal saline.
Dr. Voss?
She's tachycardic,
hypotensive and hypoxic.
Could she be bleeding?
She was earlier,
but it was minimal
and I gave her a unit of blood.
Let's get her on 100% FIO2
and start norepinephrine.
Come on, Rose.
Come on, come on, come on.
- Good, good. She's settling out.
- Hopefully long enough
for me to finish and for you
to figure out what's going on.
Hey.
Your former CO pulled through.
No complications.
And the bullet I told you about?
It wasn't in the surgical field.
- So, when is the head and neck CT?
- To be determined.
There were no symptoms
indicating that the bullet
- is migrating in Nate's body.
- But there is one.
I specifically remember
hearing the doctors say
there was a bullet
they couldn't remove.
Well, did Nate tell you
the bullet's still there?
No. I haven't spoken to him
in, like, ten years.
I can't justify a CT
on a postop patient
just to look for a bullet
that might not be there.
Since when does my word
not carry weight with you?
Your word always carries
weight, Hawkins.
But the event in question
was a decade ago
and the patient is personal.
My emotions are in check
- and my memory's just fine.
- Hey.
- Austin's just doing his job.
- No.
He's ignoring
important information
that could save
his patient's life.
Nate is
unconscious, it's my call.
We will wait
for the medical records
to confirm what you're saying.
If he codes while
you're dotting your I's
and crossing your t's...
Look, Nate was badly injured
saving Conrad.
- He's carrying a lot of guilt right now.
- I get it.
He gets a pass.
Thanks.
I know what you're gonna say.
Really? Try me.
That guilt can play
with our mind,
but that's not
what's going on here.
Then why don't you tell me
what is going on?
I was there
when the doctors told Nate
they couldn't remove
the last bullet.
I heard them tell
a fifth-generation Marine
that his military career
was over.
He had to retire because of me.
All right. I'll see you at home.
- Okay. Bye.
- Okay?
Hi.
This, uh, this might...
May seem a little strange. Um...
I'm Randolph Bell.
Yeah... I-I know who you are.
- Yeah.
- You must be Jake's husband.
- Gregg, yes.
- Yeah.
I just wanted
to introduce myself, and, um,
you know, if you or Jake need
anything, I'm-I'm here, so...
You want advice
on how to open the door
so you can find a way back
into Jake's life.
Yeah, I... You know, I certainly
wouldn't turn it down.
But I have to stay out of it.
This is between you and Jake.
Okay, yeah. No, I understand.
It was nice to meet you.
For what it's worth,
I'm rooting for you.
How's my new hip?
Ceramic on polyethylene
perfection.
I traded hip pain
for something else, didn't I?
Your body had
a dangerous reaction
to the blood that you received
during surgery.
Because of all the transfusions
I've had throughout my life?
You've developed antibodies that
our labs can't easily test for.
When we gave you blood
in the OR,
your body attacked it
and started to break down
your own blood.
You're severely anemic.
We don't have compatible blood
to give you.
We're working
with the Red Cross.
We'll find blood
your body will accept.
And until then?
Your heart is working
very hard to keep up.
We're giving you
supplemental oxygen.
And if the extra oxygen
isn't enough,
my organs will fail
and I'll die, right?
Please leave.
Glad you're feeling better,
but your career is still
in jeopardy.
As your lawyer,
I have to reiterate that
even if you manage
to recover physically,
you falsified a patient's file.
That's a criminal offense.
You could lose everything.
Because someone at Chastain
told Mullins I lied to him
to get him to the OR,
putting him at risk for COVID.
Exactly. And now that
whistleblower's gonna testify
against you at trial.
Find out who they are.
I want to know
everything about them.
Hey. Just to be clear,
blindsiding my husband?
Totally out of line.
Well, that... look, that was,
that was never my intention.
- I just wanted him to feel welcome.
- Oh, my God.
Do you remember when you said
if I came to Chastain,
it'd be up to me
if we had a relationship?
You told me you'd follow
my lead.
- You said that.
- Y-Yeah.
Of course. I ju... I'm...
Look, I'm here if you need me.
Oh, please. This isn't about me,
it's about you.
It's always about you.
I guess I was hoping
we could turn the page.
The last thing I want to do
is drive you away.
But I... y-yeah.
I overstepped, and I'm sorry.
Okay, um...
I have a family.
And you are not in it.
Yeah, okay.
- That's your contract.
- I know.
- It's unsigned.
- I know that, too.
- Well, do you need a pen?
- No, I need a do-over.
It was a mistake
to take this job.
I can't work under
the same roof as Bell.
- Can I ask why?
- He's trying to erase the past
and I won't let him, and now
he's basically stalking me.
You may not know this,
but Randolph
used to have my job.
How did he lose it?
Did his boss figure out
what a colossal jerk he is?
Quite the opposite.
They asked him
to turn on a fellow doctor.
He refused
and resigned on his own.
Randolph stood up for a good man
because he is also a good man.
And now I'm standing up for him.
I don't know what happened
between you
but I do know people can change.
Maybe you should give him
a second chance.
Who knows, it could be
the right thing for both of you.
At least share
your reservations with him.
He might surprise you.
Great. Thank you.
The Red Cross has
a blood match for Rose.
They're gonna put a rush on it.
You know that's good news,
right?
It wouldn't be necessary
if I hadn't pushed her
to do the surgery.
No. Hey, Pravesh,
this isn't your fault.
She didn't want the surgery.
Okay? She knew there would be
an unexpected complication
and now it's happening.
Dude, if she doesn't make it...
It's Rose. She's unstable.
I'll run the blood up
when it arrives. Hey.
You listened to her
and took her seriously.
Another doctor might not have.
Whatever happens,
you did right by Rose.
Unstable tachycardia.
I need an amio 150
and a code cart.
- I don't feel right.
- Your heart is working overtime
to bring blood to your body,
and it's working too fast.
Hang on, Rose.
Your blood just got to Chastain.
It's on the way up.
My chest. Help me.
Hold on, hold on.
I need to cardiovert.
120 joules.
Rose, this is gonna hurt.
Clear.
I'm so sorry, Rose.
Your heart rate's rising.
- I might need to shock again.
- No. No, not again.
- Please.
- There may not be enough time.
Here it is.
- Lifesaver. I'll hang it.
- It's the closest match
they could find,
but, Devon, it isn't perfect.
- She could hemolyze this, too?
- Mm-hmm.
I'll take the risk.
Hey.
Hey, Captain.
Surgery went well.
Though hold off
on hiking for a while?
Yeah, I can do that.
I have to ask you,
that bullet in your chest,
did they ever get it out?
No. They never did.
I'm gonna call Dr. Austin.
I'll be right back.
Nic, can you fill him in?
We think the
bullet may have migrated
to another part of your body.
- Well, that doesn't sound great.
- Don't worry.
We're all over your case
and we'll find it.
Look, I know what you did
for Conrad.
It's a debt he'll never
be able to repay,
but I know he's trying.
You know, I have some regrets...
...about the way
I've treated Conrad.
He's reached out to me, uh,
over the years, but, uh,
I've just been like a blockade,
you know?
Feel... feel real bad about it.
But I think I'm...
I think I'm ready
to clear the air now.
Sorry, could...
could you turn up the lights?
It's a little dark...
- Nate, are you feeling okay?
- Uh...
- Little light-headed.
- Hey, can you squeeze
- my hand?
- My face...
I can't feel the side
of my face.
I got
to call you right back, okay?
He's showing signs of a stroke.
We need to get him to CT.
All right.
I don't see any foreign bodies
in his neck or brain.
- Just dental cavities.
- Yeah, but-but you see that?
The streak artifact
from Nate's dental work
is distorting the images.
Look outside the distorted area.
You can barely see it.
There's a sharp outline
of something.
It could be the bullet.
Could be.
It's at the carotid bifurcation;
Explains the mini-stroke.
If it shifts position
even just a few millimeters,
it could travel up to his brain.
Blocking the blood supply,
giving him a massive stroke.
Austin needs to get it out
as soon as possible.
Ooh. Yes.
Blood volume
in the circuit is dropping again fast.
There's no
blood loss in the field.
And there's
no blood on the floor.
He must be bleeding somewhere
we can't see.
- Why is he waking up?
- He's been dosed appropriately.
I don't know why
he's not responding to the meds.
Blood volume approaching
critical levels.
Brain perfusion is at risk.
And what are
we looking for, Dr. Okafor?
- You fixed it.
- We fixed it.
The blood must be emptying
into the lung cavity.
Need to make an incision
into the left pleura.
The vena cava has been
punctured by the central line.
Not only has he been bleeding
out into the pleural cavity,
but all of
the anesthesia medication
has been
lost there, too.
Okay, on my mark, slowly
pull back
your central line catheter.
I need a Prolene suture.
Pull back your central line now.
And stop.
Okay. Push meds now.
Volumes are stable.
How are you feeling?
Well, for a guy who just got
a bullet taken out of his neck,
not half bad.
All right, I'll let you rest.
Let's catch up tomorrow.
No.
You should sit.
I need this to sink in, okay?
I'm good.
I asked Dr. Austin
to save it for me.
This thing has been my...
constant companion.
But I realized I wasn't
the only one carrying it around
for all these years.
That's why I called you.
What happened...
The choice that I made...
...is what we do for each other.
You made the exact same choice.
So...
do me a favor.
Throw this away.
'Cause when you toss it,
I want you to toss away
the guilt,
and the shame
and anything else
that you've been holding onto.
Hey, you have got some friends
in high places.
The CEO put in a good word
for you.
Okay.
And you deserve
an explanation.
The reason that I can't
give you a second chance
is because
my husband and I are...
adopting.
Wow. Well...
- that's, that's great.
- Yeah.
I'm gonna be a parent,
one that will never bail
- the way that you did.
- Jake, I...
It...
It's fine.
I'm a grown man.
But the last thing
I'm gonna let happen
is for you to become
some beloved grandpa,
only to pull the same
vanishing act on my kid.
Well, I get that.
I really do.
But I'm not going anywhere.
Thank you, Miguel.
I'm so glad you came.
Let's talk again
next week.
- What's this?
- This is what happens
when you listen to the people.
They're ideas from our staff
on how to turn
this place around.
For example, we'll be starting
an insulin-by-mail service
to decrease wait times
at the pharmacy.
I'll be assembling
a task force to address
post-surgical admission times,
which are far longer
than average.
And most importantly,
tri-tip sandwich day
will be more often
than once a month.
Well, sounds like you had
a great day.
And do I get the feeling
I'm not the only one?
I-I scored a coffee date
with my former stepson.
Here, tomorrow.
And I...
I hear that you might've had
something to do with it.
I may have.
Well... thank you.
You don't have
to thank me,
but you do have to
buy me a drink.
- Oh.
- I'll make it a double.
Where did you get this blood
from, the fountain of youth?
I haven't
felt this good in a year.
Yeah, that's
what I like to hear.
So... where are we going?
Well, Rose, like I told you,
it's a surprise.
Mm, I hate surprises.
Wasn't that in my patient file?
Well, I think you're
gonna like this one, though.
'Cause I looked you up online,
- I made some phone calls.
- Oh.
And...
bam.
No, you didn't.
You couldn't make the recital,
so we brought
the recital to you.
You don't know
how much this means to me.
Thank you.
Ah...
Basking in
your own surgical glory.
- A little bit.
- I don't think
you need to fear
being deported
before becoming
a world-class surgeon.
Because today you have proven
that you already are one.
Not only does today mark
your accession to the upper
echelon of surgeons,
but it also marks
my last day as your mentor.
You really think so?
Yeah, you don't need a copilot.
You are more than capable
of flying solo.
So...
tonight I am preparing
a very special dinner,
among other things.
Hmm.
Does this meal include...
- a chocolate soufflé?
- Mmm.
How'd you guess?
Indeed it does.
Okay, okay, okay.
And the other things?
Ooh, well...
those you will just
have to wait
and see.
Mm...
How was your talk with Nate?
It was good.
It was really good.
I'm glad I got to meet him.
Me, too.
You know, as parents,
we're gonna need
to lean on each other
in all kinds of different ways.
I do.
I wish I would've told you
about what happened
with Nate sooner.
I just...
I couldn't and I'm sorry.
It's okay.
I get it.
- You coming up?
- Yeah, I'll be right there.
Captioning sponsored by
20th CENTURY FOX TELEVISION
and TOYOTA.
Captioned by Media Access
Group at WGBH access.wgbh.org
Sync corrections by srjanapala
Don't miss a new Season of
"The Resident,"
Tuesdays on Fox.