Unless you're paid
to be there,
no one ever wants
to go into an O.R.
It's freezing,
you're naked,
and a stranger
will be cutting into your body
with knives.
♪ I wanna go up, up, and away ♪
This is not it. It's not on here, okay?
But what patients don't know
and what we try to keep them
from knowing is...
Why shouldn't that
be on there?
...sometimes it's just
as terrifying for us.
♪ I just wanna show them
I can make it ♪
♪ On my own ♪
- ♪ I wanna go up, up, and away ♪
- What?
Traumas, heart surgery,
anything to do
with the pancreas.
♪ A-dah-dah-dah... ♪
Any surgeon who says they're
not afraid of those is lying.
♪ 97 more days ♪
♪ Until I'm living out
in the world ♪
You just wrote that.
But no matter how risky
the surgery...
♪ I'll turn my problems
into pearls ♪
...no matter how scared you might be...
♪ ...the stories
how people run back home ♪
...your job is to reassure
your patient...
♪ Up, up, and away ♪
♪ And dah-dah-dah-dah,
dah-dah-dah-dah ♪
...and tell them, "Everything
is going to be okay."
♪ Dah-dah-dah-dah,
dah-dah-dah-dah ♪
Whether you believe it or not.
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh ♪
Uh, hey. Has-Has Richard been
getting the hiccups lately?
I don't know.
Why?
Could be a symptom
of Creutzfeldt-Jakob's disease.
Less than 350 Americans
get it each year.
There's no 1-hertz spikes
on the EEG.
The RT Quick Panel
come back yet?
Um... ugh.
Not sure.
My tablet just died.
Okay.
I'm gonna get another one.
I'll be right back.
Permission slip.
Zola's field trip
to the zoo.
Oh.
Well, that's next week, but...
This is next week.
Oh.
Has DeLuca been sleeping?
I don't know.
You're okay with that?
Are you here to help?
When my mom was sick,
I was so blinded
by my need to cure her
that I couldn't accept the fact
that she was dying.
And instead
of caring for her,
I put her through
all this unnecessary testing,
and I hurt her.
That's what you told me.
Right, but she had
an actual diagnosis.
It's Alzheimer's,
Meredith.
I do not believe
that it is.
Well,
Amelia and Koracick do.
So Catherine's
taking Richard home today.
*GREY'S ANATOMY*
Season 16  Episode 21
Episode Title: "Put On a Happy Face"
Aired on: April 09, 2020
Sync corrections by srjanapala
Oh, hey, Mommy.
Nope.
Unh-unh.
You call me Baby Daddy.
And now I will never
do that again.
Did you already finish up
your arthroscopy?
Yeah.
Cruised through it.
Still have clinic
and some post-ops, but...
how 'bout
an early movie?
Then Angelini's.
Take advantage of still being
a party of two.
I have a DBS, and I'm hoping
to fit in a corpectomy.
You had contractions last week
over an open brain.
So?
So, don't you think it's time
to lighten the load?
I am.
Well, you can return
to surgery
whenever you want
after this baby is born.
My body won't
come back so fast,
so I gotta squeeze in
as much as I can.
Dr. Shepherd,
O.R. 3 is ready.
Alright.
I will be there in a minute.
Might be more like ten.
Shut up!
And let me know
if there's any increase
in Mr. Rojas'
chest tube output.
You got it, Dr. Altman.
And, um, congratulations,
about tonight.
Even though marriage
is an outdated concept,
I still think it's neat.
- I've been busy.
- Thanks.
But it's
a simple request, Tom.
- Y-You need to calm down.
- Calm down?
What the hell is wrong with you?
I should've known.
Known? Known what?
What's... What's wrong?
He said he didn't see the e-mail
requesting time off.
I saw the subject line.
It didn't seem urgent.
Y-You're getting married,
what, in a few months?
It's tonight, Tom.
It's just a... It's a
last-minute thing, you know?
Some family members
for a backyard party.
"Last-minute thing."
Well, that sounds elegant, Hunt.
Well, it's exactly
what Teddy wanted.
So, the time off, please?
Sure.
Whatever you need.
Thank you.
- I'll see you.
- Yeah, okay.
Thanks for the heads-up.
- Tom, I...
- No, no, no.
I'm I couldn't be happier
for you.
Morning, Daya.
How you doing today?
I'd be better
if I had a smiling photo
for this dating app.
His, not mine.
She signed me up
against my will.
And you can see
how happy it makes me.
Oh, right. You can't.
Fun!
Daya Burman, 13,
presents
with Moebius syndrome,
a rare neurological condition
that inhibits
facial expression and
And leaves me with
resting bitch face 24-7.
Not true.
And language.
You'd swear, too, if you could
only express your emotions
through Bitmojis.
Well, fortunately, we're gonna
change all that. Dr. Avery?
Yes, we are,
because today,
we are doing a bilateral
gracilis transfer,
which means we're taking
the muscles and nerves
from your legs...
Mm-hmm.
...implanting them
onto your face.
- Sorry to interrupt...
- Mm-hmm.
...but we know the surgery.
We've bailed on it four times
in the last year.
And by "we," I mean
But I think
he's finally ready,
and I want to get going
before he chickens out again.
Last time, I barely got into
a gown when he changed his mind.
Because you don't need
this surgery.
You're beautiful
just the way you are.
You've been scared of hospitals
since Mom died.
But I start high school
next year,
and I want to have friends.
Friends I can laugh and cry with
and who understand me.
Because right now,
no one understands me.
I do,
and I think
you're perfect.
Now we're talking.
Look out, single ladies.
- Hey, just
- Promise not to chicken out again
and I won't post it.
21-year-old male.
Took a baseball bat to the chest.
- Blunt trauma?
- Not exactly.
Oh, my God.
You should see
the other guy.
He's totally fine.
Okay, you
Look, you don't understand.
Alright? You're making
a huge mistake.
DeLuca, this doesn't
concern you.
Yes, it does concern me, okay?
R-Richard's my friend.
You've had weeks
and have found nothing.
I'm taking
my husband home.
Even if it means
you're gonna kill him?
'Cause that's what you're doing.
You know that, right?
- You
- Andrew!
Take a walk.
I'm sorry, Catherine.
He's exhausted.
We're all exhausted.
This is hard enough
without the accusations.
But But I told him
not to come up here.
Yeah, 'cause he's so great
at following the rules.
Okay, I-I'm not a child!
I-It won't take long.
Just to the exit.
I'm taking you home,
sweetheart, remember?
Look, I want to walk.
Okay. Okay.
- Ooh! Man.
- Ooh.
- Damn it!
- Alright, you just slipped.
My leg fell asleep because
you people keep me in this bed.
Are you okay?
I just need a minute, okay...
Okay.
'Til I can get the feeling
back in my toes.
What do you mean you have
no feeling in your toes?
Your feet have never
fallen asleep?
Humor me.
They're They're numb
and tingly.
Meredith, he just slipped.
Well, what about your fingers?
Are your fingers numb?
Mm.
I'm gonna check your calf,
okay?
Mm!
- Ohh!
- Okay.
Tingling in the extremities
and sensitivity to touch
are not signs
of Alzheimer's.
Definitely should do an EMG
to test his nerves.
You really think
that's warranted, Grey?
I do, because if I'm right,
then it gives us some hope.
And if you're wrong,
then it's torture.
I don't need
any more tests!
Catherine...
I know you don't want to
see him in pain.
I don't want to
But are we really
willing to ignore this?
Do it.
Ugh.
Baby, we have to.
We have to.
Let's type and screen him.
Let's get a chest X-ray
and a CT trauma series.
Schmitt,
let's get the ultrasound
so we can assess
the extent of this damage.
Catcher called for heat.
Next thing I know Boom.
Shards came at me
like a boomerang.
Let's page cardio.
- It's in my heart?
- We don't know.
That's why
we paged cardio, alright?
- I-I can take that for you.
- Yeah.
Cascades, huh?
Yeah.
My dream's to go
to the Mariners.
Seems to be everybody's
dream these days.
Okay,
ultrasound's unclear.
We're gonna get you up to CT,
and let's book an O.R.
- An O.R.?
- Trust me
you do not
want to be awake
when I pull this thing
out of you, okay?
You're gonna be fine.
Okay, let's move.
Let's go.
So, you noticed
sensory deficit
and an increased sensitivity
to pain, which means...
The nervous system
is like an electrical grid.
By sending a small charge
to certain areas,
we can see if all those lines
are connected.
Or if a power line is down.
The shock of this
should send
all ten of his little piggies
squealing.
From one chief to another,
sorry.
Oh! Ohh.
Ohh.
Adding more juice.
- Aah!
- Yeah.
Ohh!
No motor output
going to the legs.
The test confirmed
what we saw with the fall,
which is he has
severe acute onset
motor and sensory
nerve degeneration,
which is inconsistent
with an Alzheimer's diagnosis.
I'd like to hear
from my neurosurgeons.
Grey's right.
It's a fantastic catch.
I'm also withdrawing
my Alzheimer's vote.
I
It's not just his mind
that's failing him.
- It's his body.
- Not Alzheimer's?
Oh, my God.
That... That's fantastic.
Well, what is it?
Where does that leave us?
In neuroscience,
the official term is square one.
We keep hunting.
Right. Then we should start with
a sural nerve biopsy
and re-check his pan-scan
to rule out a
an occult tumor
and just try to determine
what exactly
is destroying his nerves.
Agreed.
Aw, damn it.
Trauma consult.
Please keep me posted.
And thank you, Meredith.
Thank you all.
Okay, I am, uh, clearing
the rest of my schedule today.
I'll meet you
in the O.R., Grey.
Uh, let Koracick
know what you find.
I'm gonna let him
take over.
Oh, you don't have to tell me
I'm better than you, Shepherd.
- I know I am.
- You're not.
But my water just broke.
- Oh. - Oh.
- Oh.
Uh... you want a wheelchair?
You're gonna walk?
You do Richard.
I'm good to walk.
Sorry about the floor.
I'm gonna call Link.
- Oof.
- Good luck!
Are we there yet?
To the line
you can't cross
unless you're a patient
or doctor?
Uh, no. Why?
Wait! Doctors!
That's why.
Just keep going.
He already gave consent.
He's your dad, Daya.
Uh, did you have
a last-minute question?
It's happening again.
Dad, breathe.
Remember?
Please breathe.
Daya, I'm sorry.
I love you.
I can't lose you.
And you're perfect.
You're perfect.
You don't need to change.
I do.
I do need to change.
Dad, I need this change.
Mom wanted this for me.
She wanted me
to be able to smile.
She She wanted to be able
to make me smile.
She wanted this,
and she's gone,
and you're using her death
as a reason
to not let me have what
she and I both wanted for me.
That is just
Okay, you have to breathe.
Do you need
one of those bags?
No, he's okay, right?
Nice and easy.
Just breathe, okay?
Look, Mr. Burman,
we know that her condition
is not life-threatening,
but it is
a very serious challenge.
We all depend on nonverbal
communication every day.
You're doing it right now.
You're not talking,
but we all can see that you are terrified
and you're panicked,
all because
you're scared
for your daughter.
But we have good news.
We know what she has,
and we know exactly
how to fix it.
We just need you to let us
do that for her.
Let us do that for you.
I want to smile, Dad.
I want to be able to smile.
Please.
Okay.
Promise me you'll
swipe right at least once
while I'm in surgery.
Alright.
Daya, you ready?
Are you kidding?
Look at this face.
I am pumped.
Alright.
We got her.
I heard about Richard's EMG.
That's big news.
Yep.
Talk of the hospital.
- Well, that and your spontaneous wedding.
- Tom.
Did my invitation
for tonight
get lost in the mail,
or...?
Let's not make this harder
than it already is.
Oh, you're referring to
your impending nuptials
as "hard."
- That's a good sign.
- I love Owen.
And you love me.
Now you're racing off
to the altar
to try to convince yourself
you can live without me.
Spoiler alert.
You can't.
This wedding is happening.
You know, I've seen a few
shotgun weddings, Teddy,
but usually, it's not
the bride holding the gun.
Everything is looking
Oh. Oh, hey.
What'd I miss?
Just the initial
pelvic exam
that shows that's Amelia's
at five centimeters.
- Huh?
- Already?
- Mm-hmm.
- "Huh"?
You didn't feel
any contractions?
Nope.
Maybe a little.
They started
at 9:00 this morning.
What?
You put yourself on the board
for five surgeries.
Well, I thought they were
still Braxton Hicks.
No, no, no, no.
You're definitely
in active labor.
- Ugh.
- I'm gonna go get the fetal monitor
so we can
check on the baby.
What, are you skipping town?
'Cause now is not
the right time to tell me.
No, that's our go-bag.
I packed Bluetooth speakers,
a deck of cards,
trashy magazines,
peanuts.
- I hate peanuts.
- No, those are for me.
Oh.
Oh, I-I-I'll go get you
some French fries
and and the biggest
chocolate bar
- No. S-Stay. Please?
- I can find.
I'm not going anywhere.
Oh! Ooh!
Ah.
It's not in your chest,
okay?
You don't feel pain
when you see something violent?
Like, all over?
No.
Hey. I'm here.
Sorry. I was with Richard.
Oh. Um, how's he
How's he doing?
We're making
some progress, I think.
I hope.
- Ouch.
- Yeah.
See?
Okay, baseball bat splintered,
went into his chest, obviously.
Yeah, it did.
He has blood
in the pericardial sac,
and that looks dangerously close
to the left atrial appendage.
Uh, you need to put him
on bypass to fix it?
- Unlikely, but I will if it tears.
- Okay.
He's a baseball player?
Pitcher in the minors.
- About to get called up to the majors.
- Yeah.
- Not anytime soon.
Ohh. Gosh.
Again, Schmitt, this is not
happening to you, okay?
He worked his whole life
for this!
Do you think her dad will
swipe right, like she asked?
Maybe.
Is that my only
hope now?
A stupid algorithm
that claims to know
who to pair me with?
I don't even know
what I'd put in my profile.
I hate everything.
Well, except mac and cheese
from a box.
- You know, this looks like
the appropriate size.  - Mm-hmm.
Now we just need
to tether the muscle
to the oral commissures
right here and here.
We'll be able to eliminate
that constant frown.
What about you,
Jackson?
Do you use
a dating app?
Wait, what's your
profile picture?
A shirtless selfie of you
on your yacht or on your jet?
You have a jet?
No.
I mean, my family
The Like, the foundation,
I guess, has a jet.
What about you, Hayes?
Definitely not a jet.
No dating profile,
either.
Right, 'cause you have
your own personal matchmaker.
What's that
supposed to mean?
Ready to close.
Vicryl.
Dr. Goldberg to L&D.
Dr. Rachel Goldberg to L&D.
Any word?
They're still in the O.R.
You know, Tom, I'm
I'm a very proud woman,
but I'm not too proud
to admit
the mistakes I've made
in my life.
And this year oof
this year, I've just
screwed up everything.
Uh...
Uh, I don't know.
Remember that one summer
you came to visit me
at my lake house?
You borrowed my car,
and you forgot to put
the parking brake on. -
As we had dinner,
I had to watch my Saab
99 Turbo...
...roll down the hill and sink
to the bottom of Lake Habeeb.
You said it was the
that was the first time
you'd seen me cry.
Oh, Tommy.
Tommy.
Well, listen, depending on what
we find out from this biopsy...
I might be coming to ask you
to play a bigger role
in the foundation.
- Oh.
- Eh, Jackson's my first choice,
but I just don't want to
pressure him
into doing something
that makes him unhappy.
Kit Cat, the foundation
is your life.
Not as long
as Richard needs me.
Mnh-mnh.
I gave up on him once.
I'm never
doing that again.
Oh.
I already informed pathology
to put a rush on the report.
You okay?
I'd say we should bring in
someone who isn't family...
That person
doesn't exist.
Let's go.
Ten blade.
Hey, hey! Hey, stop!
Wait! Don't cut! Okay?
- Damn it, DeLuca!
- Just stop, okay?
I- I'm sorry,
but I found something.
I was going over
Dr. Webber's history again,
and he got a hip replacement
three years ago in Boston.
Richard Webber
is sedated on the table.
You need to step away
from the sterile field
and wait outside!
And you can tell us about it
when we're finished.
- No, no, no. How about now? Huh?
- Are you
Gonna listen to me now?
That's it.
You're done.
Get out.
- Uh, we need to re-sterilize.
- Bailey.
No, no, no.
B-Bailey, listen to me, okay?
Look, you don't need to do
the biopsy, alright?
His hip replacement
was made out of cobalt.
We did a heavy metals test.
Wh... It came back negative,
right?
Not for cobalt.
That test is mercury,
arsenic, and lead.
We wouldn't see that.
Right.
And if that hip is
deteriorating, Bailey,
cobalt poisoning would explain
the dementia, the depression,
hallucinations, tremors
everything, okay?
And every second
that it stays in his body,
he's
he's getting sicker.
Bailey, please trust me.
Change of plans.
We need to draw some blood.
D...
DeLuca, run this down
to the lab.
Tell them the chief says
move this
to the front of the line.
- Run!
- Okay. Okay.
You really think a hip replacement
- could've caused all this?
- Mm-hmm.
It's a metal-on-metal joint,
which means
it's entirely possible
that the friction caused the hip
to wear away over time.
I-I confirmed it with
the hospital in Boston today.
They used a chromium cobalt
alloy for his surgery.
Cobalt in his blood stream
would explain
the neurotoxic symptoms.
Okay, so,
cobalt level's...
- 200?
- Oh.
The average level in a healthy
adult male is around 8.
That's 25 times
more than it should be.
How permanent
is this damage?
- I-It's not. It shouldn't be.
- You don't know that.
First step is we have to
get that cobalt out of him
and replace it.
Well, go, go!
Get that thing out of him now!
- Right.
- Alright, Taryn, find an empty O.R.
- and prep Dr. Webber.
- Hey, I want to scrub in.
And I want a house in Hawaii.
Go home.
Chief, any resident
who found what I found
would get the privilege
to scrub in. Please.
Y-You can't
discriminate against me
because you think
I have a problem.
Lord, I'm sick of you.
Dr. Bailey...
...he doesn't have to
touch Richard, but he's right.
It's his diagnosis.
It's a career
defining moment.
He should get to
be there.
Not a finger.
Thank you. Scout's honor.
Got to go find
Atticus Lincoln.
Well, he's with Amelia,
and they're having a baby.
Right.
Well, not anymore.
Hey, Mer.
Thank you.
Don't make me
regret this.
- I won't.
- Amazing catch.
Sorry, sorry, sorry, sorry,
sorry, sorry, sorry, sorry.
Ah, doesn't hurt a bit.
Ah.
Actually, you sh...
squeeze harder, actually,
because, uh, because
I'm feeling nothing here.
You're progressing very nicely, Amelia.
Really?
Because it feels epically slow.
D... Oh. Dr. Lincoln,
uh, we need you
in O.R. 1,
explantation and replacement
of a hip prosthesis.
Kind of in the middle
of something here.
It's for Richard.
He tested positive
for cobalt toxicity.
It's his hip.
Webber's got
a cobalt hip?
Yeah, which is leaching
more cobalt into his blood
the longer we speak.
I I would not ask,
but he needs the best we have,
and he needs it now.
Okay. I think
we're almost done here.
No, you're still
only six centimeters.
- You have hours.
- What?
- Still?
- Yeah.
Oh. Okay. Go.
- You sure?
- Yeah. Yeah, it's Richard.
Go. Go.
Mm. Mwah.
Okay, go.
No, w-wait.
Wait, do that again.
Mm.
Mm. Mm.
That really does
help with the pain some.
I told you!
Okay, go, go!
I'm pretty madly
in love with you, you know.
Me, too! Go!
- Bailey!
- Huh?
Huh?
Oh, uh, no, I'm gonna
help prep Richard.
You stole the father of my baby
while I'm in active labor.
Uh
Ha... Uh
Oh.
- Oh!
- What?
- Aah!
No tension.
Perfect coaptation.
Just need to anchor
the muscle proximally
and we get to
close her up.
I saw a survey
that said 98% of women
have been told
to smile more at work.
Why is there so much pressure
to smile all the time?
It's not like it makes us
better at our jobs.
The only people
that smile all the time
are clowns
and sociopaths.
Dr. Avery,
are you almost done?
Why?
You need my O.R.?
No, but thank you.
Chief Bailey wanted me
to tell you
we're taking Dr. Webber
to the O.R.
because he has a hip
made of cobalt,
which has been
slowly poisoning him.
- Wait, what?
- I know.
Dr. DeLuca
figured it out.
DeLuca?
Jackson, go.
We can finish and close.
- Got it?
- Yep.
Score one for DeLuca.
The way he's been acting,
I'm amazed anyone listened
to anything he had to say,
least of all Grey.
You seem very interested
in who Meredith Grey listens to.
Do I?
I hadn't noticed.
Hmm.
Schmitt, bovie.
What are the odds
that that thing
would just shatter like that?
Well, maple bats
splinter easily.
Why are they allowed?
Well, they're trying to
phase them out, go back to ash.
Oh, good.
Schmitt, can you get that,
please?
Oh, but then I wouldn't
be sterile.
I know.
Okay.
Some guy
named Winston says
- that he can't stop thinking about you.
- No, no, no, no. Not that one.
Okay.
Grey texted, too,
and Bailey and Helm.
Well,
what did they say?
Ooh, it's a lot.
I'm reading.
Dr. Webber has cobalt poisoning
from a hip replacement,
and they're rushing him
into surgery to replace it.
They think that it
explains everything
that's wrong with him.
Pierce, we can we can
page Altman if you need to
No. No.
I'm I'm okay.
I just need a second.
Okay. Bovie.
You're the one who paged.
Mm.
I'm driving across
the Key Bridge
in Baltimore
one night, early June,
sunset, weather's gorgeous,
slight breeze,
sailboats on the water.
There was a crimson sky.
- Tom.
- A- And I see this guy,
20-something,
on his phone,
looking distraught,
his face all
tightened up in anguish,
and he's leaning way out
over the railing.
And before I know what
I'm doing, I slam on my brakes,
I run to him
"Don't do it! Don't"
Cars lined up behind mine,
people leaning on their horns,
but I had to stop him.
I- I At least try.
I couldn't let him
throw his life away.
So, what happened?
Did you talk him down?
Oh, no.
It turns out he was just calling
into a radio station
for some
free concert tickets,
and the reception was better
out over the water.
I just wanted to tell a story
to illustrate my point.
Don't throw your life away,
Teddy.
I hate that I have
dragged you into this.
I hate
that I'm hurting you.
Because you love me.
I am marrying Owen.
And I love you, too.
Which means
I'm not giving up on you.
So, tonight,
I'll be in my car.
Lot B, 7:00.
Waiting...
♪ You and I ♪
...to take you
wherever you want to go.
You want to go out
to your place? Hmm?
Explain things to Hunt? Fine.
You want to run away,
go down the coast,
spend a weekend...
figuring things out?
I'll be there. 7:00.
Tom.
♪ Be over before we know it ♪
We can't do this.
Say it.
- I love you, too.
- Mm.
Mm.
♪ Don't even try ♪
♪ Don't look for a reason ♪
♪ This isn't the end ♪
♪ It's only a season ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh ♪
♪ A love like ours
will never die ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh ♪
♪ A love like ours
will never die ♪
They ended your suspension?
Temporarily. Yeah.
Okay, everyone.
We've done this a thousand times.
We know what to do.
♪ A love like ours
will never die ♪
Ten blade.
♪ Never die ♪
What is all that?
Mostly sludge.
I've never seen
this much tissue damage
from a hip replacement
before.
Look at this
gluteus medius tendon.
I can't believe
that was all inside of him.
Not just him.
These hips were the new
standard for a while.
Surgeons used to
beg their hospitals
to invest in them,
but, uh, if this is happening
to other people...
it's gonna be
a game-changer, DeLuca.
Can someone get me
an update on Amelia?
Ooh.
Okay.
Oh.
How are we doing?
Uh, contractions are
less than
three minutes apart.
She's doing great.
- Ooh.
- Good. Can I take a look?
Uh-huh. Ooh!
I feel like my organs
are in a vice.
Aah!
Hey, I know you said
no medications, but
There's fentanyl
in the epidural.
Nobody advertises that,
but Aah!
Women are smart.
We are evolved.
We are critical-thinking.
How did the first woman
ever have a baby
and then decide
to have another one?
Aah!
Or let another woman have one?
Oh.
How do humans exist?
Why do we do this?
You do this because
you're so in love with someone
that the two of you
can't contain it all.
So you make another person
out of that love.
Oh, God.
Bailey... I am so sorry.
I'm awful.
I was not thinking about it.
You can go.
I ju... I deserve to
have this baby on my own.
D... No.
Now, that would go against
the rules of pregnancy club.
The surgery went well,
and the bandages should be
able to come off soon.
Recovery will be slow.
You'll need rehab
and speech therapy.
See, Dad?
Everything was fine.
- I came as fast as I could.
- Hi.
How is she doing?
Um... uh... we're great.
Ms. Scott?
Why are you here?
I I was in
the neighborhood,
and I thought
maybe you might
want to catch up
on your homework.
Oh, my God.
Dad, you're dating
my algebra teacher?
Um... only kind of.
It's just...
We have the same dentist.
She set us up.
I didn't know she was
your teacher at the time.
We didn't want to tell you until
after the school year was over
and you weren't
in my class.
Oh, honey. Please.
Don't be upset.
I'm not upset.
I'm trying to smile.
Okay.
Well, now we know why
the dad never swiped right.
God, I hate set-ups.
But if it makes
them happy...
So, this lack of interest
in dating
it's... it's only in regards
to yourself, right?
I mean,
just because I'm miserable
doesn't mean
everyone else has to be.
Okay.
So, I'm not wrong, then?
'Cause I get the feeling
people are having conversations
about my personal life
that I'm not privy to.
You know,
you should smile more.
Hmm.
- Ohh!
- Okay, it's time to push.
- Okay.
- No, I ca... I can't push anymore!
- I can't! I can't!
- Oh, yes, you can.
No, I can't! I'm done!
I'm dying! I can't!
Okay, okay, but
but think of
all those women you were
talking about,
the women that do this every day.
No, I hate those women!
And they all have drugs
and masturbation and
and then C-sections,
and I don't even have Link!
Ohhh!
Uh, okay.
Okay, here.
Sit up.
- I can't! I can't! I can't do this!
- Okay.
Tucker's father
wasn't with me, either.
- So, move.
- Why? What are you doing?
- Ah. Okay.
- Okay.
Oh, my God.
I can't do this.
- ♪ Every breath ♪
- Okay. Okay.
- Okay.
- Now...
- Alright.
- ...let's have a baby.
- Okay. One, two, three.
- Okay.
Push!
♪ All we have
is here right now ♪
One more, one more,
one more.
♪ Right now we have it all ♪
♪ We ♪
♪ Don't know what's coming ♪
♪ With the sunrise ♪
♪ So, stay ♪
♪ Right where you are ♪
♪ And hold on to the moonlight ♪
♪ All we have
is here right now ♪
♪ Right now we have it all ♪
♪ All we have
is here right now ♪
♪ Right now we have it all ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh ♪
♪ Let's make it last forever ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh ♪
♪ Let's make it last forever ♪
Good.
Alright.
Clip.
This
atrial appendage clip
should contain
the bleeding.
I thought these clips
were only used for a-fib.
Mnh.
Schmitt.
Um...
Oh, Dr. Webber's out.
He's stable.
Yes! Sorry.
Pierce, you can
you can go if you need to.
What? No.
No, I do my best work
when I am...
profoundly relieved.
Now, what about you?
Don't you have a wedding to get to?
Ah, there's plenty of wine
to keep people happy.
Oh, Schmitt, could you...?
Oh. I'm doing yours
now, too?
Great.
Great use
of my medical degree.
A voicemail
from Dr. Altman.
Oh, it's probably
about tonight.
Could you just, uh,
put it on speaker?
- Yep. Thanks.
- Oh.
Mm.
Oh.
Oh, God.
- Schmitt?
- Oh, yes!
- Schmitt.
- Yep. Yep.
Schmitt!
Yep, yep, yeah!
I'm trying, I'm trying,
I'm trying, I'm tr...
Okay.
S-Sorry, everyone.
Clearly,
that was meant for me.
You know, Teddy's idea
of a wedding gift.
Yeah.
Yeah, that's a good one.
- Yeah.
Um... suc... Um
Suction.
Was it another
false alarm?
Where's Carina?
Are you okay?
I'm okay.
Everything's okay.
Atticus Lincoln...
come meet your son.
♪ I'm living in a hazy,
hazy scene ♪
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God. Hi.
Oh.
♪ With my head up
in the sky ♪
Hi.
- ♪ I am free ♪
- Oh, oh.
He's so small.
Don't say that to the person
who just pushed him out.
♪ ...and who I want to be ♪
♪ And who I want to be,
I want to be ♪
♪ I know just what I want to
know, just where I want to go ♪
♪ And who I want to be ♪
♪ I want to be ♪
He's beautiful.
Isn't he?
♪ Cloud chaser ♪
You both are.
♪ Mm, mm ♪
♪ I'm a cloud, cloud chaser ♪
♪ Mm, mm, mm ♪
♪ There's a part of me,
a part of me ♪
Oh. Is he, uh... doing o...
He's stable.
Came off his vents
easily.
We won't know more
'til he wakes up,
but that implant was basically
rotted inside of him.
It was, uh... awful.
♪ Wishing on the brightest,
brightest star ♪ -
♪ But nothing ever really
feels that far ♪
♪ I'm following the burning,
burning sun ♪
♪ Around and around
and here I come ♪
Okay.
When he wakes up,
make sure his pain's controlled
and walk him through
his recovery.
And tell him he missed
his chance at the majors
and his dream is dead.
Schmitt, you're not the one
who's suffering here.
He is.
So put on a game face,
suck up your feelings,
'cause that's what we do.
If you can't do that,
if you can't do your job...
consider a new career.
♪ Cloud, cloud chaser ♪
♪ I know just what I want,
I know just where I want to go ♪
♪ And who I want to be ♪
♪ I want to be ♪
♪ I'm a cloud, cloud chaser ♪
Oh, God.
Oh, yes.
Oh!
God!
Oh.
Mm. Mm.
Oh, God. Oh.
Let's not wait 'til 7:00.
Let's leave now.
No, I can't.
I can't leave with you.
I c...
I'm... I am marrying Owen.
This was...
This was goodbye.
Okay.
Mm. Mm.
How's that?
Ah.
Thank you, Maggie.
It's so nice
to hear you say my name.
Do you know
who this is?
Mm.
You mean, um... Jackson?
Hey, Richard.
Do you know
where you are?
Grey-Sloan Memorial?
If this is a quiz,
you might want to ask
some tougher questions.
Fair enough.
Okay, um, hold out
your hand for me.
Oh, sweetheart.
The nurses
are gonna bring in a bed
so I can stay the night
with you.
It's Catherine.
It's It's Mom.
I know who it is.
What is she doing here?
Sweetheart.
I've been with you
this whole time.
Is your mind
playing tricks on you again?
Did you stand by me
while I was being fired,
you buy my hospital
to humiliate me,
or is that my mind
playing tricks, too?
Richard, calm down.
Get out.
- Richard.
- Okay, Mom, let's go.
Let's give him a little...
- ...little bit of time. Okay?
- Richard.
Sometimes, surgeries
go better than planned.
Grey.
Heard about Webber.
Oh, yeah.
Incredible catch.
Yeah,
it was... not all me.
It was an army
and mainly DeLuca.
Mm-hmm.
Want to grab a drink?
Celebrate?
Yes.
Except
I'm so exhausted.
Will you ask me
another time?
Of course.
See you later.
Bye.
♪ Place to belong ♪
♪ I'm already gone ♪
Hey. Andrew?
♪ We're the lonely hearts club ♪
♪ We're losing in love ♪
♪ We're shaking it... ♪
Andrew, it's over.
Maggie said she'll call us
if there are any changes.
♪ We're the lonely hearts club ♪
I don't I can't, uh...
I don't know
what's going on.
Okay, okay.
Can we just go home?
Let's go home, okay?
Come on.
♪ I was already gone ♪
There's no better gift
you can give someone
than saying you saved
the person they love.
It went okay, I think.
♪ Searching for somebody
and a place to belong ♪
♪ A place to belong ♪
I look forward
to those moments.
♪ We're already gone ♪
Unfortunately, those perfect
outcomes are rare.
♪ We're the lonely hearts club ♪
♪ We're losing in love ♪
You would think it gets easier,
but it doesn't.
♪ ...shaking it,
shaking it off ♪
♪ We're the lonely hearts club ♪
Each one hurts just as much
as the last one.
♪ We're shaking it,
shaking it off ♪
♪ You're the voice in my head ♪
♪ You drive me to bed ♪
♪ You make my decisions ♪
♪ No, you don't listen ♪
♪ You don't listen ♪
So, we hope for the best...
...and prepare for the worst.
Hey, Teddy.
I'm so sorry, honey.
We'll reschedule.
♪ We're the lonely hearts club ♪
Alison just fell asleep,
and I'll get that guy down.
Why are we rescheduling?
Owen got pulled in
for a last-minute surgery.
Said to send everyone home.
He didn't call you?
♪ We're shaking it... ♪
No.
Oh, well, seems he barely
had time to tell me.
I mean, trauma well,
you know better than anyone.
♪ Lonely hearts club ♪
Right.
Because the worst
has a nasty way of finding you.
♪ Lonely hearts club ♪
Sync corrections by srjanapala