Previously on ER:
Look, Luka...
I'm glad we're friends,
but I've got a dad.
- Fingernails, tattoo, the hair?
- It's the whole package.
I'll talk to my band mates,
see if I can't pull it back a little.
- You off?
- Yeah.
If you wait for a second,
I'll walk out with you.
- Okay.
- Ah! Damn it!
Son of a bitch!
- He should be in a nursing home.
- I'd never do that to him.
You wanna stay here for
tonight? Plenty of room.
Actually, you can stay
as long as you like.
Hey. SAM: Hey.
How was your night?
- The usual.
- Anything good?
Guy got his arm caught in
a sausage-making machine.
Nice.
I'm not on till 9.
I can drop Alex off at school,
but can you pick him up at 3?
Sure, after I get some sleep.
Morning.
Mom, I need 10 bucks for the
class field trip to Millennium Park.
Okay.
They've got a giant silver
sculpture shaped like a bean.
If I don't get the money in...
I have to stay behind to do
homework with the fifth graders.
Okay, okay.
What? You've never
seen a kid pee before?
This is gonna bounce.
- Whoa, that's a lot of zeroes.
- Tuition was expensive.
No wonder you're
sleeping on Abby's sofa.
You know you can defer paying
your loans until after residency?
Not this one. This
is for my father.
- What? Your dad's leaning on you?
- It's for my brother's university tuition.
My parents put me through
school, now it's my turn...
They can't wait until
you're making real money?
Is there something
you need, Ray?
How would you like to
work Christmas for me?
I'm already working New Year's.
Look, you do Christmas and
I'll take your New Year's Eve.
You'd work New Year's Eve?
It's important to have us all together
on Christmas. I'll take Ramadan for you.
I'm not Muslim, I'm Sikh.
Great. I'll cover whenever
you wanna take a Sikh day.
- This is unbelievable.
- What? Weaver's got a boyfriend?
Only 39 percent of the staff
has had a flu shot this year.
I don't want massive
absenteeism in January.
- I had mine. NEELA:
I'll get one today.
- How about you, Ray?
- Tomorrow.
My band's to play at Delilah's
tonight. Can't have a sore arm.
Sore arm?
How about 100 percent
compliance by next week?
You've had lame excuses
for the past two months.
- What are you talking about?
- First, you had a cold.
- Oh, yeah, then you were sleep-deprived.
- Police officer shot. ETA, two minutes.
- Where's the wound?
- I couldn't understand.
- All right, clear Trauma 1.
- Neela, Ray, Chuny, you're with me.
Mary, get some extra security
down here to handle the press.
- Do me a favor, give me a flu shot.
- What?
Yeah. Get me when
I'm not expecting it.
Just stick me quick, I
got a thing about needles.
Paramedics
probably have two IVs.
You can go
femoral if we need it.
Eddie Escobar,
caught one in the neck.
- Lost lots of blood.
- This the throw-and-go?
- We were 10 blocks away.
- You're at County General.
- Should've called paramedics.
- We'd still be waiting.
- C-collar.
- Board's ready.
One, two, three.
We're gonna give
oxygen through your nose.
- Thank you. NEELA:
Pulse is thready.
- Take my keys, Gary.
- It's okay, Eddie.
- Try not to move.
- Someone needs to feed my dogs.
- Have intubation tray ready.
- There's a filing cabinet...
in the bedroom
with all my papers.
Forget about that. It's
gonna be okay. Tell him.
Trauma panel, type and cross, six units,
call X-ray, get a portable neck-and-chest.
I threw up all over Amy's
collage. It was so embarrassing.
Oh, that's okay. We see, like,
a hundred puking kids a day.
- Really?
- Mm-hm.
- Mom's here. This is
Dr. Lockhart. ABBY: Hi.
- School nurse called my office.
- They sent her in for vomiting and fever.
- She okay?
- Well, it seems like it's just a flu.
Are you okay, honey?
- I should take her to our doctor.
- She's here now...
- I see how busy you are.
- It's not that. It's...
Do you want to go see Dr. Ben?
Uh... I...
It's probably just
the stomach flu.
Let us run tests. We'll give
her fluid. She'll be good as new.
- How long is that gonna take?
- About an hour.
- Can we move her to a real room?
- I'll work on it.
Sam, this girl needs
a line and Tigan.
You have to ask Malik.
Excuse me! Excuse me.
Sub-Q air. Otherwise okay.
- Excuse me.
Two units O-neg.
Looks like the bullet missed
your spinal cord and trachea.
That's good. SAM: Excuse me.
- That's good news.
- Sats aren't so hot.
- He needs plastic.
- Yeah. I'm all over it.
We're gonna stick a tube down
your throat to give you more oxygen.
Whatever you say, doc.
- You'll go to sleep first.
- Twenty of etomidate, 100 of sux?
- Everyone else okay?
- We're all good, Eddie.
- You get the perp?
- Couple of double taps to the chest.
- He went down.
- Go for it, Ray.
What happened? McWAYNE:
Convenience store holdup.
Chased the guy into an apartment
building, called for backup.
Scumbag starts
shooting out the window.
All right. There's too much blood.
- Pulse ox only 72.
Okay. Pull out and bag him
up. You want me to do it?
No, no, no. I got it.
Give me a straight blade.
- You cut yourself?
- No, that's... It's nothing.
- We should take care of it.
- No, really, it's okay.
One more shot, Ray.
- Ray?
- Just give me some cricoid pressure.
I could get this.
- I still can't see the cords.
- Okay, that's it.
- You want me to try?
- How about you try?
- Crike tray.
- Yeah?
Yeah. Betadine, 11 blade.
No. Third drawer of the
crash cart. Get the trach light.
- The what?
- Are you going fiberoptic?
Not exactly. SAM: Got it.
- Where's the scope?
- It's a blind procedure.
Who's in charge of this ER?
- That would be me.
You can stay here, sir,
but you have to be quiet.
Okay.
Bend the tip to 90 degrees.
Turn the lights off.
Passing the midline,
lift the jaw forward.
Sats are dropping.
Shouldn't we prep the neck?
Through the cords, you'll
see a pre-tracheal glow.
- He needs a crike.
- That's the glow.
Won't see it if you're
in the esophagus.
Okay, that's it. Bag
him. Turn the lights on.
- Very slick.
- How about a subclavian?
Okay, good breath sounds.
Number six gloves, Dr. Barnett?
Seven-and-a-half.
Sterile drape and a
finer needle, please.
I have Mallory. McWAYNE:
This is Eddie's fiancée.
- Okay.
- Oh, my God, Eddie.
I'm Dr. Lewis. He's doing okay.
- He was shot?
- Once, in the neck.
He's sedated with medication, but
you can sit with him, hold his hand.
I was playing around with my
nephew. We were wrestling.
Looks like he kicked
your butt. Is the rib sore?
- Right there, yeah.
- Okay, Mr. Sakabu.
I think it's nothing
but a bruise.
What about my shoulder?
- Any pain when I press?
- It's more on the inside.
It's probably just a strain.
I'll have the nurse bring
your discharge instructions.
Hey, hey. I didn't
know you were in today.
The stupid alarm didn't go off.
- Rough night, huh?
- Yeah.
You okay?
Okay. I got a quick one
for you, ready for discharge.
Give me a couple
of minutes, okay?
Good news. Labs are fine,
white count's not elevated.
- So we can go?
- Mom. Mom.
Are you all right, honey?
- What's wrong?
- It hurts now.
- Where does it hurt?
- Right here.
Here? JOYCE: Ow!
Does it hurt more when
I take my hand away?
Ow!
I'm gonna get you some
medicine for that pain, okay?
I need to run some more tests.
Start with four of MS. Thanks.
I thought she'd
be better by now.
What starts out looking like flu
ends up to be something else.
- Like what?
- Appendicitis.
You said it wasn't serious.
It may not be. I'd like
a surgeon to take...
She needs an operation?
It's a possibility.
Oh, God.
No. No, she's not
having surgery. Not here.
- It's a very simple operation.
- I need to talk to my husband.
There's time. I need to
do another blood test...
You can't do surgery
without my permission, right?
Right. One step at a time, okay?
You call your husband.
I'll get things started.
- Hey, Ray. Is Carter in there?
- Just Lewis.
- How's the cop?
- Stable. What's in your hand?
- A chart.
- Okay. The other hand?
A pen. I didn't say I'd do it.
- Hey, anybody seen Dr. Chen?
- Sorry.
Do you have any plans
for New Year's Eve?
- You're not really my type.
- Funny. My band's got a party gig.
- Can you take the p.m. for me?
- On New Year's Eve?
Well, look at it this way, you won't
have to go to a square dance by yourself.
Or with a date, or whatever.
You give my med-student
lecture for me in January.
- Deal. CRAWFORD:
Suspect's been wounded...
and apprehended. Do we have ETA?
No, I'm sorry. They
haven't called that in yet.
- We'll be with the family.
- Okay.
Ten-year-old girl. Fever, vomiting,
right lower quadrant tenderness.
- Rule out appy. ABBY:
Yeah. CT or ultrasound?
It depends.
What the hell was that?
What?
Jing-Mei?
Oh, sorry.
Coffee was brewing.
You okay to work?
Yeah, sure. What do you got?
Thirty-five-year-old,
strain and sprain...
- chest and shoulder contusion.
- Okay.
- You don't wanna see the patient?
- No. I trust you.
How's your dad doing?
Okay.
I mean, I've got a nurse
for him 16 hours a day.
And then from 11
to 7, it's just me.
- So you're not getting much sleep.
- Hey, Dr. Chen.
Carter's got a baby in status. Needs
you for that suspect in that shooting.
- How soon?
- Right now.
Gunshots to the
chest and abdomen.
- Vitals?
- No pulse in the field.
- Son of a bitch.
- How long down?
Cops had to secure the building.
- How long did that take?
- Made us wait 45 minutes.
It takes 20 minutes
to bleed out.
If there'd been a shooter,
she'd be full of holes.
Two of O-neg on the infuser.
- On my count...
- Hold on. He's cuffed.
- Who's got the key?
- Not me. You got the keys?
- I'll check with Hogan.
- Quickly.
- Start on the paramedic gurney.
Betadine, 32 French.
Thoracotomy's all yours, Neela.
- You gonna assist?
- You'll be fine.
Sterile gloves and 10 blade.
- First unit's up.
I need to lift up his
arms. Where's the key?
- We're working on it.
- Get the bolt cutters.
Take it easy. TOMMY: I got it.
- Can the officers wait outside?
- Suspect's in custody, uncuffed.
- We're waiting here.
- Don't think he's gonna jump off the bed.
Hook up the Thora-Seal.
Give her room to work.
Think he's got a chance?
Why do you think they're
letting me crack his chest?
- That thing's got to wait outside.
- That thing is a service animal.
A service animal with fleas.
Actually, fleas have a
natural aversion to minis.
- Abby, Dilantin level's back...
- Carter, this is Mrs. Gellin...
- and her guide horse, Ruby.
- Who should be outside.
We let Seeing Eye dogs in here.
Our floors are gonna
be covered with crap.
- She's housebroken.
- What if she spooks?
Oh, we've been on the
L, airplanes, elevators...
- She can stay.
- Thank you.
See you later, Ruby.
Dr. Carter, Officer
Escobar's son's here.
Okay. We're... We're
still working on his dad.
The kid's anxious to see him.
- Let me... Let me go check for you.
- Thanks.
- Too close to the skull.
- Can you stop the bleeding?
Direct pressure. SAM: Got it.
Call Angio. Maybe we can
balloon the proximal carotid.
They just picked
up his son at school.
- Arlo's here?
- How old is your son?
Fifteen. I'm not his mother.
Arlo's from Eddie's first marriage.
- Fine. Throw down a fresh drape.
- I'll be next door.
- CVC's in. Need a repeat chest.
- Hey, Arlo. It's not as bad as it looks.
- It's okay. You can come on up here.
- What is she doing here? I want her out.
Excuse me, ma'am...
- Who let her in?
- This the ex-wife?
- You shouldn't be here.
- Mom. Mom.
- Get out!
- Can you just shut up?
Okay, everybody shut up.
Officer, you and Mallory
need to step outside.
- I don't wanna leave him.
- Everyone gets to see him...
- just one at a time.
- Come on.
We're gonna start x-rays on your
father. You can say hello quickly.
- Dad, it's Arlo. I'm here.
- He can't talk with the tube in his mouth.
You're gonna be all right.
Take them to the family room.
Me?
- You're tough, Dad.
- All right, honey, that's enough.
Dr. Barnett will
answer any questions.
Okay. Right this way, guys.
- Sam, check a second HemoCue.
- I think it's next door.
Thanks.
- You got a rhythm?
- Unit five and six are up.
Hold compressions.
- Asystole.
- How's his volume?
- Heart's filling well.
- Too many holes.
We could try high-dose epi.
Penetrating trauma
with no pulse in the field.
Okay.
11:07.
- He's dead?
- Yeah.
You just saved the taxpayers a million
bucks in trial fees and prison costs.
- What happened to your wrist?
- Oh, I don't know.
Neela, you wanna help
Officer McWayne out here?
- I was gonna find family for this patient.
- Get him started in the suture room.
Sorry about the
misunderstanding.
Some people are freaked
out by little animals.
I'm gonna clean your cut out.
I have a cousin who gets
nervous around Chihuahuas.
- Is she wearing sneakers?
- It keeps her from slipping on the floor.
My husband wants
her transferred to Mercy.
- Surgery's on their way to check her out.
- We wanna move her.
You're gonna have to find a
surgeon at Mercy to accept her...
before I can okay a transfer.
Whoa, whoa. Hey, back off, Ruby.
- Doctor, can you come to the phone?
- Yes. One minute. I'll be right back.
Re-prep the wound
and tie up the horse.
It's my husband. He's
driving back from Detroit.
- Hi. This is Dr. Lockhart.
- Are you the doctor?
- Yes, I am.
- You better be damn sure...
- you know what you're doing.
- Mr. Trager...
- If you do anything...
- Mr. Trager, I understand.
We will.
Yes, your wife is working on that
right now. We would never do that, sir.
Got paged about
a patient transfer?
Wendall Meade, Social Services.
Thank God you're here.
Why don't you get here soon, and
we won't make any decisions with...
Nice talking to you too.
Little pin prick
and some burning.
- Ooh.
- Sorry.
Must be a pain having to waste all
that time trying to save a scumbag's life.
- He jacked a mini-mart, doc.
- Looks like a 14-year-old.
Feels like a foreign body.
Something hard. Is it
possible you were shot?
I don't think so. I remember I
scraped my wrist when I fell.
- How about there?
- Mm-mm. That's a loop of bowel.
I left messages for
three surgeons at Mercy.
- They'll call back. JOYCE:
How long can we wait?
Eight to 10 hours.
- I can't find the appendix.
- What does that mean?
Usually if it's enlarged,
it's easy to find.
- She may not have appendicitis?
- It's not a perfect test.
She could still have the disease
even if the ultrasound is normal.
Can't you people give
me a straight answer?
I would say, based on her fever
and tenderness, that it is appendicitis.
She said it was stomach
flu, then changed her mind.
Now you can't find her appendix?
Transfer center from Mercy
wants to talk to the Attending.
- Finally.
- Hang a gram of cefotetan.
Do you think I
need an operation?
- Do I need it soon?
- Yep.
Can I have it here?
Well, you could...
but your parents want you to
have it at a different hospital.
- Won't that take a while?
- Not too long. It'll be okay.
Why can't I decide?
Because when you're a kid, your
parents get to decide what's best.
The only way to stop the bleeding is
by blowing up a balloon in his artery.
This x-ray is gonna
guide us to the right spot.
- How does he get blood to
his brain? NEELA: Dr. Lewis.
Hold on. RAY: That's
a good question.
Two carotid arteries
supply the brain.
Right and left, okay?
If one gets blocked, Mother
Nature has a backup plan.
It is called the
Circle of Willis.
It's a detour.
But it allows the blood from the
right to get over to the left-hand side.
- I understand.
- So he can recover.
Well, priority number
one is to stop the bleeding.
- If you're not wearing lead, leave.
- I'll come get you when we're done.
- Thanks, Dr. Barnett.
- Ray's fine.
Okay, Ray.
- Sam, Dr. Kovac called.
- Did you take a message?
Sounds like your kid got
suspended from school again.
- I may need to leave.
- In a minute.
- Dr. Lewis.
- Have them step outside.
I removed a foreign body
from Officer McWayne's arm.
- What's that?
- Feels like a plastic BB.
Could be what shot your patient.
- That couldn't sever a carotid artery.
- You sure?
Officer Escobar was
shot with this metal slug...
- from a sub-Q, right upper a trapezius.
- Looks like a 9 mm.
- Is that what the suspect used?
- I don't think so.
Nine-millimeter semi-automatic,
standard issue. That's what we carry.
I can pick him up. It's not
a problem. Stay at work.
- Well, what is it about?
- No. The school didn't tell me anything.
They didn't tell you?
What did he do?
They just said to
come in for a meeting.
- Well, is he okay?
- Yeah, yeah. He's fine.
All right. Call me as
soon as you get back.
- I will.
- Okay, thanks.
Tetanus shot for
Officer McWayne.
Being interviewed
about friendly-fire.
Is it for sure now?
They found a pellet
gun at the scene.
So he didn't shoot the cop then.
- Guess not.
Arlo, you should be
in the family room.
Is that the guy who shot my dad?
He was the suspect
they were pursuing.
- Can I go in there?
- Probably not a good idea.
- I wanna see him.
- Arlo.
- He's a kid.
- You don't have to do this...
- Was he on drugs?
- I can't say.
- Did he have a police record?
- I don't know.
Why would he do that?
Why would he shoot my dad?
Arlo, we're not exactly
sure who shot your dad.
He may have been accidentally
shot by a police officer.
- What? But I thought...
- This guy was only carrying a BB gun.
They won't know for sure until
the ballistics tests are completed.
Oh, man.
One of his own guys.
Arlo, can we talk to you?
- Which one of you did it?
- We don't know anything yet.
Why don't we go and sit down?
- We're sorry. ARLO:
It's not your fault.
Comes with the job.
There, balloon is up and
the vessel is occluded.
- Can we have his family in?
- Not yet.
- Entrance wound is dry as a bone.
- Nice.
He's not waking up.
He's still comatose
with a flaccid paralysis...
and an up-going toe.
So much for collateral flow.
- But you can repair the carotid?
- Oh, it'd likely do more harm than good.
It's not a procedure
that I'm comfortable with.
- But if the wife consents...
- His fiancée.
- Not her call then.
- We have an ex-wife.
- Is there a blood relative?
- Yeah, a son, but he's 15.
- Could he be a mature minor?
- A what?
It's when a kid's mature enough
to make medical decisions.
- Could be.
- Okay, I'll talk to him.
Get Wendall in on this.
And find me if you need me.
- Okay.
- Dr. Dubenko, I need you right now.
Keep his crit
above 30. PO-2, 90.
Ten-year-old,
appy, systolic's 60.
- Is she septic?
- Antibiotics are on board.
- We're running in a liter.
- Who saw her from Surgery?
- The family wants her transferred.
- That isn't happening.
Dr. Hong at Mercy accepted her.
- Pressure's up to 70 with 500.
- They're sending an ambulance.
I'm sorry, ma'am. Your
daughter is very sick.
She needs surgery now.
Do we have consent?
- No. She said we could wait.
- In most cases, we could.
This is unusual. The infection
spread to her blood quickly.
Mrs. Trager, we need
consent for surgery.
- My husband will be here.
- We don't have time.
- I need to wait.
- It's life-threatening.
- Okay. We'll double-doctor it.
- What? What?
Two physicians' signatures
can override your consent.
Sign it. Sign it. Let's go.
- This is not what we agreed on.
- I'm sorry.
- You done this before?
- No one gets in trouble...
- acting for the patient.
- Tell that to Dr. Corday.
- Treating your dad...
- Sorry, I was tied up.
Everyone, this is Wendall Meade.
- Hi, Arlo.
- Can he stay?
If it's okay with Arlo.
Yeah?
Okay, so the two
treatment options:
We can use a catheter to
plug up the artery with coils.
Like with a balloon?
Yeah. That would give him a 15
percent chance of getting better...
85 percent chance of
still staying in a coma.
Or we could do surgery to
reconnect the artery. If we do that...
that would give him a 30
percent chance of improving.
- That's a little better.
- Yeah, well, it's risky.
Usually with surgery, half the
time the patient deteriorates or dies.
The surgery sounds too risky.
Do you understand
the choices, Arlo?
They both kind of suck.
- Can you explain them back to me?
- What?
- I need to make sure he understands.
- I'll make sure he does.
Arlo?
Well, if we play it safe...
there's a small
chance he gets better.
If we do the surgery...
there's a bigger chance he'll improve,
but an even bigger risk he'll get sicker.
That's right.
It's your call.
What are you talking about?
We've decided Arlo's mature.
He can make the decision.
By himself? He can't handle this.
- Yes, I can.
- No, you can't. You're 15.
- He's my dad.
In cases like this, the decision has to
be made by a blood relative. It's the law.
How can this be right?
Between you and me,
it's not the end of the world.
The board has a
zero-tolerance approach...
to what they
consider pornographic.
What?
He brought this to school.
He was showing it to the other
kids. That may not be appropriate.
They have lots of cool
electronic gadgets in here.
I don't think they were
looking at the gadgets.
- Is that your name on the mailing label?
- Yeah.
And you're Alex's stepfather?
Not exactly.
I see.
But you take an active
role in the child-rearing?
Yeah, I pick him up from
school. You know, we do sports.
- I took him fishing.
- That's great.
You know, Alex and his mom...
we've been all living together,
and it's really going well.
And how long has that
been the arrangement?
About a week.
Ray, do you have a minute?
Hey. Hot chocolate?
It's my treat.
I'm really sorry about my mom.
She's just looking out for you, okay?
- By freaking out?
My dad's lucky she won't
even talk to him anymore.
Are you okay with
what we talked about?
About your dad?
Last year for the
ninth-grade prom...
- there was this girl Sarah.
- Yeah.
I was too afraid to ask her.
But my dad told me that you got
to take chances or you miss out.
She was going with this
guy from the baseball team.
And two weeks later, she asked
me to go to a concert on the pier.
Sounds like your
dad's a pretty cool guy.
He'd want the surgery.
- Then that's what we'll do.
- But my mom's gonna freak out.
It's your decision.
And I'll back you up.
You will?
Sure thing.
Abdominal pain and
near-syncope from hypotension.
He was here this
morning. Dr. Pratt's patient.
Marina, find Pratt, and
grab the ultrasound.
I thought it was a bruise.
- When did you get dizzy?
- A few hours ago.
- Why didn't you come back?
- Doctor said it wasn't serious.
Pressure's only 80 palp.
Trendelenburg, liter of saline,
CBC, type and cross for force.
- Sir, where does it hurt?
- Sonosite.
- What's up?
- You sent home an unstable patient.
Damn, he lacerated
a spleen. Call Surgery.
Dr. Pratt...
- I signed off on this.
- He was rolling with his nephew.
- You didn't mention belly pain.
- He didn't have any.
Did you even check a crit?
- It would have been normal.
- His shoulder was hurting?
- There was no point...
- Blood irritates the diaphragm...
and gives you pain. You missed
it. You forgot about Kerr's sign.
No, we missed it because you
were too tired to see the patient.
- So, what did the principal say?
- You're busy, we'll talk at home.
Why can't you tell me now?
I don't want to talk
about it over the phone.
- All right. Okay, when I get home.
- Okay.
Arlo's consenting for
surgery. It's taken care of.
- You called it in?
- Vascular's ready for him.
- Okay.
- I'll start the pre-op list.
I have to go pump
before I explode.
Carolyn made it to the O.R.
- Who?
- Appendix girl.
Great.
You were busy today. Declared
a 15-year-old a mature minor...
- overrode parental consent on an appy.
- And took a kid from an abusive parent.
It's the triple crown
of social work.
- When are you off?
- Another hour.
Wanna get some dinner?
Thanks, I have plans already.
- Not with anyone, if you're wondering.
- Not a problem.
You can come along, but I have
to warn you, it's pretty physical.
Oh, yeah? RAY: Dr. Carter...
Neuro's admitting my CVA in 4.
Thanks. Abby,
that's two to sign out.
- It's 7:05.
- I've been here five minutes too long.
Stroke patient, tele-admit and the
cop Dubenko's sending to surgery.
- You've still got three on the board.
- I know. They're all discharged.
- Hey, Ray, you forgot something.
- Abby, what?
- Oh!
- Your flu shot.
You're welcome.
Pressure's good, 122/76.
You feeling better, Mr. Sakabu?
Yes. Thank you very much.
Okay if the nephew comes back?
Yeah, sure. We might be
able to get more history.
- Are you on any medication?
- No.
Any allergies?
Uh-uh. How could this happen?
Well, it's a very
unusual presentation.
You need enough force to break
a rib that cuts into the spleen.
My nephew's a pretty tough kid.
He'd have to be to
cause something like this.
My uncle gonna be okay?
Hey, have you seen Susan?
- She signed out.
- Oh, great.
- No, just page her again for me, please.
- What do you need?
Can't believe Ray
dumped this on me.
I'm supposed to take care of
this cop's kid. What's going on?
- He signed out to you? Why'd he do that?
- I was in his exit path to the door.
Dr. Lockhart, this
is Keith Trager.
- Daughter has appendicitis.
- Right. Hi. We spoke on the phone...
- Where is she?
- Her condition worsened.
- We had to take her.
- You were to transfer her.
- I know. There wasn't time for that, sir.
- Take me to her now.
- One second.
- There's a problem with Arlo?
Ray said it was all
settled, but he's very upset.
- I know the case. Want me to take it?
- Can you? Thank you.
- Excuse me.
- I'm coming.
Arlo?
- Where's Ray?
- He had to leave.
- When's he coming back?
- He left for the night.
- He left?
- I'm sure I can help.
He promised that he would
help me talk to my mom.
I can do that.
Bowel grasper and stapler.
Pressure is 122/76.
Prep the extraction bag.
Peanut swab with
Betadine for the stump.
Oh, my God. NURSE: Got it.
They're doing it through the scope, which
means a smaller scar, shorter recovery.
So she's okay?
It's not a complicated
procedure.
Everything's fine, Keith.
Who is that operating?
That's the chief of surgery.
- He's the best. DUBENKO:
Up on the cautery.
Dr. Dubenko, the
parents are here.
Oh, she's doing great.
We caught it before it burst.
- What's that?
- Pulse ox probe slipped off.
Everything's fine.
You know, I brought my dad
here for back surgery. He never left.
Well, that's not gonna happen.
He died on the table. Some
junior doc botched the job.
I'm sorry to hear that.
I hate this hospital.
- Where's the other doc?
- He isn't available...
He took off.
So, Arlo, have you decided
on which treatment...
you would like us to pursue?
I want him to
have the operation.
It's too risky, honey.
It's what he'd want.
- Isn't it better to
have him around sick...
- than to lose him?
- Does he have to be here?
He's your father's best
friend. McWAYNE: I feel bad.
I don't know why we're still
talking. Ray said it's my decision.
- What, you don't want my opinion?
- No.
Tell her.
Legally, Arlo has the right...
- He's too young to handle it.
- I'm not!
- Don't talk to your mother like that!
- Maybe if I reviewed the risks...
No. I understood
it the first time.
Dad would wanna go for it.
I know that's how
he always talked.
He liked to take chances.
That's what
probably got him shot.
We're not gonna
make any progress...
I want him to
have the operation.
If you approve this surgery...
how are you going
to feel if he dies?
- He's not gonna die.
- He could die.
Are you ready to live with that?
I'm trying to protect you.
I know you think
you're all grown up.
Are you ready to accept
responsibility for your father's death?
- Hello.
- Hey, Marie.
It's Dr. Chen. How's he doing?
- Well.
Okay. Well, go ahead and
push another two of Ativan.
Yeah. Listen, any chance
you can work late tonight?
- Probably.
- Yeah, we're getting slammed.
And I don't think I'm gonna
be able to get home till 2 a.m.
Well, all right.
That would be great. Thank you.
Yeah, thank you so much.
- No problem.
Okay, bye.
- Hey.
- Sorry about Uncle Sumo's spleen.
- Yeah, well, we caught it in time.
Who knew his nephew
was the size of a Hummer?
Didn't mean to
snap at you earlier.
No. No. I was the Attending.
I should have seen him.
So who's the potassium for?
My dad.
- You gotta go easy on that stuff.
- Of course. Forty a day for his diarrhea.
This should last me a few weeks.
- Hey.
- It's a big wall.
- Yep, I'm in training.
For what? Taking down PCPers?
Triathlon.
Wendy. MEADE: Hey, Brett.
This is John. CARTER: Hi.
- First time?
- No.
I did this once
when I was a kid.
All right, thanks. Take good
care of him. See you at the top.
Let's go to the beginner wall.
Is this how this thing
is supposed to go?
Sure, if you want to hang
upside-down by your balls.
What's going on?
The family have decided
not to have the surgery.
The family? We've been
together for three years.
- Don't I get a say in any of this?
- Hello, this is Dr. Rasgotra in the ER.
We are canceling the carotid
surgery on patient Escobar.
Yes, I can hold.
Hey, John. CARTER: Hi.
So you two are dating?
No, we're just friends.
Well, that's how it starts.
We went out for a year or two.
Oh, yeah? Great.
Thought we might
even get married.
One day she tells me she
wants to start seeing other people.
Why do they say that?
You know, if you want to
break up, you should just do it.
Is the rope supposed
to be this loose?
- Better?
- Yeah, thanks.
Hey. SAM: Hey.
- Did you get back to sleep?
- No, not really.
Sorry.
Okay, where's Alex?
Up in his room.
Want a beer?
Do I need one?
He brought this to school.
That's it?
That's such crap.
Where'd he get it?
You subscribe?
- I like the articles.
- Oh, please.
So listen, anyway...
a friend of his had the
magazine in the bathroom...
in the stall...
at school...
You know, the kid was...
Are you kidding me?
Oh, my God.
Do you think that Alex is?
I thought it would be at least a
year or two until I had to deal with this.
Well, I guess I
need to talk to him.
Yep.
So I'm here twice a week,
anytime you want to join me.
- That'd be great.
- Brett could give you another lesson.
He's quite a teacher.
- See you next time.
- Bye.
I got an outfit just like that at
home, but I didn't want to show off.
So are you hungry?
Um, no. No, not really.
You got to eat dinner.
I'm just gonna grab
something at home.
Come on, you've been
a good sport. My treat.
- Okay.
So, what are you
in the mood for?
I don't know.
Indian?
No? Chinese?
Uh...
- Sushi?
- Had it for lunch.
What about deep-dish
pizza? I could go for pizza.
- I know a good pizza place on Monroe.
- Yeah, too many carbs.
Right.
Hey, I have an idea.
Okay, close your eyes,
pick a page and point.
That's where we go.
- What if it's a doughnut shop?
- Are you in this or not?
- There?
- Not there.
- Right there.
- And the winner is...
- Uncle Vito's Mongolian Barbecue.
What's that?
It's Italian. It's Asian.
It's maybe Southern.
All right, close your
eyes and do it again.
No, no. You made the rules.
Mongolian barbecue?
But it's in Downers Grove.
We don't want to go that far.
Are you in this or not?
All right.
I hope they have tofu.
Officer McWayne.
They're moving
him up to the ICU.
Okay.
Thank you.
Arlo!
- Arlo!
- It's okay.
- Where is he going?
- Probably just getting a snack.
- He seems really upset.
- It'll pass.
Well, maybe I
should go talk to him.
No, he's too emotional. You can't
talk to him when he gets this way.
I hope he doesn't feel
like he was forced into this.
You don't want to think
about it some more...
- discuss it after he calms down?
- It won't help.
He's not being realistic. That's
why we had to make the decision.
He's too confused.
I heard him express a
strong opinion more than once.
You and I both know it
was the wrong choice.
He was hoping for something
that's never going to happen.
He loves his father, but I'm
the one who has to set the limits.
Anyway, thanks for
everything you did.
I'm not sure I helped.
Well, when you let us
work it out together...
you did the right thing.
Yeah.
Hey. Can I come in?
Didn't know you liked The Goon.
They didn't have Hellboy.
So look...
about today at school...
Mr. Elmore is such a loser.
Yeah.
What happened with
that kid in the bathroom...
all right, I just wanted to make
sure you didn't have any questions.
About what?
You know, about
what he was doing.
Spanking the monkey?
Yeah.
What about it?
Well, it's... It's normal...
but, you know, it's not the kind
of thing you should do at school.
You think I'm stupid?
No. At your age, it can
be a confusing time.
If you ever want to, you can
always talk to me about these things.
Okay.
Good night.
I heard there was
an after-hours club.
Cool.
Have you seen Kristy?
Yeah, she's pulling
around the side.
Hey, you're late.
- We went on at 9.
- How could you just leave like that?
I'll meet you in the car.
- I'm sorry, what?
- You abandoned that kid.
I signed out my patients
when my shift was ov...
- You should have signed out to me.
- You were busy.
You thought it was
easy. It got complicated.
How did it get complicated? The
kid wanted his dad to have surgery.
- How long you discuss it, two minutes?
- He understood.
His dad's not
having the surgery.
- Why not?
- Because you weren't there.
His mom gave him a hard
time about it, and he gave in.
- Did you at least talk to him?
- Yes.
Well, all he needed was a
little hand-holding, Neela.
- I mean, God, is that so hard for you?
- Don't turn it around, make it about me.
- You promised to help.
- No, I told him...
You know, it's not my job or
anyone else's to keep your promises.
- My shift was over.
- He was counting on you.
- I had a gig.
- Screw your gig!
Medicine isn't a day job!
This coming from a girl who was
selling hot dogs three months ago.
I was off at 7.
Abby was off at 7.
But we were still there
taking care of our patients.
We'd never leave the hospital if we had
to stick around to tuck in every patient!
I'm not talking about every
patient, I'm talking about one kid.
It was the most important
decision of his life.
He trusted you, and you left.