He's a hard worker, he's
strong, he's got a great attitude.
- How's he gonna work with a bad hand?
- It don't hurt.
- The cast will be off in three weeks.
- Cool, G. You said six before.
I've seen you around,
right? You, uh, work upstairs.
Yeah. I'm an ER resident.
All part of the County family.
I hate doctors. Y'all think you're
the queen of the damn Rose Parade.
I'm not a doctor.
Not the sharpest
nail in the box.
Just give him a
chance. You'll see.
Okay, kid. Let's talk. Alone.
All right, look. Listen, listen. I
gotta get back down to the ER.
Make sure you tell him that
you work real hard, okay?
- Okay, G.
- I'll see you at home.
- All right.
I work real hard.
I don't want to be here.
Sand truck rolled
on I-40. Three DOAs.
Jessie Callahan, 35-year-old
restrained passenger.
High-speed T-bone, BP 122/78. Pulse
93, bloody scalp lac, she got a liter.
- Okay. Trauma 1.
- Tom? Where's Tom?
- Jessie, can you tell me where it hurts?
- I left Tom. I left him all alone.
Her husband's still in the car.
Fire department's cutting him out.
Paramedics are working on your
husband. Gonna let us help you?
So just Neosporin
on the abrasion?
And tell him to stop for a while
or he's literally going to jerk it off.
- Lewis. Paramedics pulling in with a fall.
- Okay.
Jerry, call the morons in Engineering
and tell them to get down here.
We're okay. Nobody
panic. Nobody panic.
And call Psych. The sun
goes down, the nuts come out.
Are we ready for him?
- Who?
- The alderman.
Have you been
drinking, alderman?
Hey, back up. You
can't come in here.
All right, keep them back.
- John Bright, 55, 8-foot fall off a stage.
- It was a dais.
BP 124/82, pulse 79. No LOC.
Complains of neck, hip and right knee pain.
Alderman, it's an honor to have
you here. I'm Dr. Kerry Weaver.
- Are you taking any medications, sir?
- No. And call me John.
Gently, people. CBC, chem
panel, type and hold, UA.
- Chest is clear.
All right. Pupils 4
mm and reactive.
- Who you on the phone with?
- Uh, the office.
She's my assistant.
Jennifer, honey, try to breathe.
- Shut that cell phone off in here.
- You can use our phones. Just dial nine.
- Have you been drinking?
- You don't have to answer that.
No, I haven't. I'm on the
program. Just got my two-year chip.
Okay, then. Open wide
and stick out your tongue.
Okay. Don't worry, sir. You're
in the finest hospital in Chicago.
Okay.
The emergency power
will kick on any second.
- Let there be light.
- Shooting.
Thank God something's working.
Get that into Exam 2. Move it.
We're gonna take a scan of your belly to
make sure you're not bleeding internally.
- Is Tom here yet?
- We'll find out.
Come on. Get the lead out.
We got a VIP customer waiting.
- Leon, what are you doing? I work here.
- Me too, G. I got the job.
- Okay, good. That's great.
- It's cool, man.
Hey. Hey, this is
Dr. Weaver in ER.
Get your fat union asses
down here and fix the power.
Got the job! We're
gonna work together!
Pratt, hey, kiss your friend
goodbye and get back to work.
Hello.
- Damn it. Hello? LEON: It's
good. It's gonna work out...
Does anyone have
a carrier pigeon?
- Good.
- I get the overtime...
- Leon. How's it going?
- I got a job.
Glad to hear it. She's stable.
But check another HemoCue
before you send her to CT.
- She may need some blood.
- Okay.
You got nothing to
worry about. This is cool.
After I get off, we'll go to
Mario's, get pizza and celebrate.
No, G. I'm working
tonight on the late shift.
- Tonight?
- I get my own uniform. Isn't that cool?
- And you know where to pick it up?
- I got the address. They wrote it down.
- I can find it by myself.
- All right, good.
- Congratulations.
- Stop worrying, man.
We're gonna be
working together, man.
- We're gonna be working together, ha-ha.
- Shh, shh!
All right, G. I'll
see you later, man.
- All right.
Work on a press release and fax it
over. Somebody get me a fax number.
All right. Engineering is coming
down now to work on the power.
How are you feeling, alderman?
Pampered. I'm sure
you have other patients.
This ER sees about
90,000 a year, doesn't it?
- Hmm. That's why I'm tired all the time.
- More like 110,000.
It's a damn miracle
what you people do.
We have a great team. But we could
do more if we had better resources.
No medial or
lateral instability.
You probably tore a
ligament when you fell.
There goes my dream of being
an Olympic gymnast, ha-ha.
I'll page Dr. Hullverson. He's
our top orthopedist, excellent.
Give the alderman
six of morphine.
We should see
a tox screen first.
What? Who are you?
- Was it cocaine, alderman?
- Oh, my God. Get out.
Ray MacGee, Chicago
Times. I have a right to be here.
Listen, hey. Leave this
man alone. This is a hospital.
You ever heard of
the First Amendment?
Ever heard of an
awake colonoscopy?
Wherever you stole that
scrub top from, I want it back.
Jerry, can you try and
keep out the fake nurses?
So many rules to remember.
- Fake nurses?
- Uh, don't ask.
Don't we have enough
trouble with the real ones?
- Ah, looks busy.
- Lucky you.
I hate nights.
MVA coming in, two minutes.
- Is that from the I-40 pileup?
- That lady's husband.
I'm off. Can you make sure
somebody finds her if it is?
- Sure.
- Good.
Ooh, hot date?
No. I gotta give a check at
this symphony fundraiser thing.
- Lifestyles of the rich and famous, baby.
- Hey!
- Look what the patient fairy brought you.
- Ah, ha-ha, no.
Mrs. Hawkes, 44, fever,
cough times three days.
- I'm juggling 10 patients already.
- I'm just waiting for a chest film.
If it comes back clear, just write her a
little scrip, send her home. Easy dispo.
Okay. Probably just the flu.
Give it to Pratt. He'll hate it.
- Done.
- Ten minutes.
Ah, you two have fun.
- So you sure you wanna go?
- Definitely. Free canapés.
What is a canapé anyway?
- Don't worry. I'll use the right fork.
- Next time we'll do something fun.
Next time we'll do
something that you wanna do.
Oh, you mean like
miniature golf or bowling?
Things my people enjoy doing?
- It's too bad Cats closed.
- I'll just shut up now.
- That's sexual harassment, isn't it?
- You bet.
I'll circulate a petition.
- Excuse me. Dr. Carter, right?
- Yeah.
I'm Sarah Wilson. I
work with Dr. Mac.
Um, you called the clinic,
said he needed to come back.
Oh, yeah. He left before
his chem panel came back.
Oh, he's dizzy. He's dehydrated.
And I'm worried about his diabetes.
Yeah. Well, he really
needs to come in.
There are always patients at
the clinic. He won't leave them.
Uh-huh. And what, there's
nobody to cover for him?
A one-man show, seven days a week.
- Dr. Carter.
Another one from the pileup.
Pulse 110, 20-minute extrication.
Take a deep
breath, Mr. Callahan.
- My wife, Jessie...?
- Mr. Callahan. She's here. She's stable.
We'll let someone know
you're looking for her.
I need you to come down
to the clinic and talk to him.
- What makes you think he's gonna listen?
- Well, he likes you.
- Sure had a good way of hiding it.
- He's going to kill himself.
He won't listen to
me. Stop by, please.
- Carter.
- Just for a minute.
Calling for anesthesiology
backup in Scanner 2.
That's Pratt's patient.
Jessie Callahan. She
crashed on the CT table.
- Excuse me.
- Will you come?
Uh, if you leave the
address at the desk, I'll try.
She might not make it down.
Prep the rapid infuser in Trauma 1.
Pneumonia. Her right
lobe's completely socked in.
So much for an easy
dispo. Did you run labs?
White count is 27,000 with a left
shift. Gram-negative rods in the sputum.
Call ICU.
It's got to be klebsiella
or pseudomonas, right?
Yeah. Not good.
Sats are only 85 on two liters.
Crank her to five
liters, nasal cannula.
Get a gram of cefotaxime,
IV, and 500 of Biaxin.
This is Dr. Lewis.
I've never had flu this bad.
She's coughing a lot. Do you
guys have cough medicine?
We're giving her all the
medicine we can right now.
I need to talk to your
mom for a minute, okay?
Hey, you guys want a soda?
Go on.
- Is our mom really sick?
- Well, she has pneumonia.
It's a serious disease, but we're
doing everything that we can.
- We should call Doug...
- No. Mom would freak.
Call who?
Doug. He's our brother.
- Does he live with you?
- No. He's 20.
He has like 50 earrings.
I just need some sleep. Marten
never should have called 911.
Well, I'm glad he did. This type
of pneumonia's very dangerous.
My kids have homework.
They need dinner.
Mrs. Hawkes, you're too
sick to leave the hospital.
Write me a prescription. I want
to get it filled on the way home.
If we take you off the
medicine, you will probably die.
Is there anyone we can call?
A relative to be here with you?
- Someone to watch your kids?
- My husband died last year.
My Aunt Sara.
She lives in Detroit.
And what about your son Doug?
No. I don't want him here. I
don't want him near my kids.
Is there anyone else
nearby we can call?
No. I'll call Sara. She'll come.
Pratt, Carter needs you now.
Your MVA, she crashed in CT.
Charge to 360.
All right, clear.
- Still in V-fib.
- Another mg of epi, charge to 360.
- What happened?
- Shut up and bag. The second HemoCue?
- Did you check it?
- Yes, I did.
- Coarse V-fib.
- All right and clear.
Let's go.
Sats dropping to 91.
- Push the lido. Ten blade. Say it.
- Ten blade.
- Can you find my wife?
- We will, Mr. Callahan.
Right down to the rib.
Curved Pean clamp next.
Pressure's falling, down to 80.
- Keep the elbow up.
Push harder. Lean with your hip.
Okay, tension pneumo. Line's in.
Let's hook up two units of O-neg.
Okay, pressure's coming up.
Nice work.
Malik, hook up the Thora-Seal. 0
silk on a driver and Vaseline gauze.
- What do you have?
- Tension pneumo, intraperitoneal blood.
Ex-lap. Don't even
bother to scan him.
Come on upstairs, sir,
where the good drugs are.
Mr. Callahan, you are bleeding in
your belly. You need an operation.
Is that Jessie?
The other doctor is taking care of her.
But we need to take you up to surgery.
I just want to see her. I
need to know she's all right.
One minute, okay?
No pressure.
She should never have left.
Got a huge retroperitoneal bleed.
- Carter?
- Not now, Luka.
Mag and bicarb
are in, round four.
- Jessie.
- Can you close that door?
- V-fib. Shock again?
- Yeah. Charge 360, stat.
- Charged.
- All right. Everybody, clear.
- Looks like sinus.
- No pulse. It's P.E.A.
- How long?
- Ten minutes. She's brain dead.
Her heart's barely beating.
He wants to see her before
we take him up to the O.R.
- Shall I bring him in?
- Yeah.
- I'll tell him.
- Thanks.
All right, everybody.
See you tomorrow.
Hey, Jerry, can you call Housekeeping?
Pizza kid with braces puked again in 3.
- Sure. Nacho?
- Oh, thanks. Cheesy.
- Jerry, where's our alderman?
- Um, I think he's still up in X-ray.
Damn it. I asked them to put a
rush on it. Get them on the phone.
Mm. Kerry, we need
to discuss our alderman.
Did you know he's the one who wrote the
bill to finance the spousal abuse shelter?
- He's one of the good guys.
- Mm-hm. Not too good.
When we were checking for pelvic
fractures, I found a sore on his penis.
I think it's syphilis.
- Did you swab it?
- Yeah. We're waiting on labs.
Uh, they just finished with the
alderman. They're bringing him down.
- Thanks, Jerry.
- How should I handle it if he's positive?
You won't have to. I will.
Her heart's still beating.
Her pupils are dilated.
That means her brain was
deprived of oxygen for too long.
Maybe she'll wake up.
No, she won't.
Mr. Callahan, your
bleeding is getting worse.
We have to take
you up to the O.R.
We wanted a family.
We couldn't.
I couldn't.
She didn't like talking
about donors or anything.
She's gone. You're
putting yourself in danger.
I can't just leave
her here to die alone.
Okay, I got a vascular
surgeon, an anesthesiologist...
and three surgical residents in an
O.R. suite that rents $5000 an hour.
- He wants to be with his wife.
- That's touching.
- She's dying.
- If she doesn't die faster, he'll die.
- I explained all that.
- I'm going upstairs.
If he's not up there in 10 minutes,
I'm gonna take out your spleen.
We're the richest
country in the world...
and we can't provide basic
health services for our citizens.
Yes. Not just emergency care.
Prenatal screening, drug
and alcohol treatment.
We do what we can
with limited resources...
Everybody at City Hall
should come down here...
and see what kind of
war you fight every day.
You've been fighting
some big wars yourself.
Don't tell me we can't
find him a private room.
Nice to see you
again. Robert Romano.
Heard you were here.
Getting all the care you need?
- We're waiting on a few tests.
- I don't want a private room.
Lets me experience the kind of service
my constituents get when they come in.
You're in good hands
with Dr. Weaver.
But if you need anything at
all, hope you'll give me a call.
Find him a room.
I was on the committee
that hired that man.
- Oh, he's an excellent surgeon.
- Tragic about his arm.
Lots of people downtown
wish it had been his head.
You haven't broken your knee.
Looks like you have blood in the joint.
- Is that serious?
- No. You'll feel better once we drain it.
That sounds unpleasant.
It sounds worse than it is.
- Could you give us a minute?
- Oh, sure. Espresso's calling.
Girl lives on caffeine
and chocolate.
Alderman...
when Dr. Lewis examined
you, she found a sore.
Yeah. Is it what I think it is?
- We're still waiting for the lab results.
- But you have some idea.
It's probably syphilis.
That wasn't the
diagnosis I was hoping for.
- How many partners this year?
- Only one.
Okay. We'll give you a shot
of antibiotics and you'll be fine.
Good.
But we'll need to report it
to the Health Department.
Any way we can keep it
out of my medical record?
It's automatic once
the labs are done.
But there's no need to worry,
your records are confidential.
No, your health
records are confidential.
Every time there's an
election, I have to release mine.
And syphilis is not a word
the voters love to hear.
- I understand your concerns.
- We'll both get treatment.
You don't think everyone
deserves some privacy?
- Her sats are still falling, down to 83.
- Okay. Call Lewis and put her on a mask.
- Doug!
- Ha. Hey, monkeys.
- You came.
- You making trouble?
- Nice to see you.
- Hey, I'm Dr. Pratt. You must be Doug.
Yeah. Hey.
Hey.
What's he doing here?
He was worried about you.
He doesn't worry about
anyone but himself.
Ah, good to see you too, Mom.
- Did you find Lewis?
- She's coming.
I told you not to call him.
I don't want you near my
kids, Doug. Make him leave.
- What's up?
- Her sats are down to 83.
- Doug, you're high, aren't you?
- No.
Get the hell out of here.
- Who's he?
- Her son.
Mom, please. Let Doug stay.
So you can sit around
and watch him get stoned?
Come on. They live with you,
watch you sit around and get drunk.
Get the hell out
of here. Get out.
Take slow breaths.
- Oh, God.
- Mom?
- Sats are down to 78.
- Up the 0-2. Get them out.
- Come on. Come on. PRATT:
She's not moving any air.
Bag her. Get 20 of etomidate,
100 of sux, set up for an intubation.
You called him?
Aunt's in Detroit. He's
here. I tried to help.
You can help by learning to listen when
the patient asks you not to do something.
Jerry, Dr. Lewis mislabeled a
swab. Can we pull it from the lab tray?
Labs went out an hour ago.
I need you to call and
cancel it. It's under Bright.
- The alderman?
- Yeah.
I can try.
She's oxygenating well. Turn her down to
80 percent and check gas in half an hour.
- ICU is full.
- Call again. She needs a bed.
Listen, sorry about that. I
was trying to do the right thing.
You exacerbated a terrible
situation. I told you to call the aunt.
I did. She's 69 with MS. She
can't take care of those kids.
Well, you think stoner
boy's gonna do any better?
Doug?
Okay, guys. I gotta talk
to the doctors, all right?
- You okay?
- Uh...
Yeah, I smoked a little this afternoon,
you know, but I'm fine now, so...
- Hey, did I kill her?
- No.
We had to put a tube in her
throat to help her breathe.
- Why did she cough up all that blood?
- She has an infection in her lungs.
Hey, look, I'm sorry
I said all that stuff.
It's just... God,
she just gets to me.
Your mom's in
stable condition...
but she's gonna have to
be in ICU for at least a week.
Rachel and Marten
need a place to stay.
Tonight, at least.
Yeah, I guess.
It doesn't look like your mom's
aunt will be able to help out.
Who? Aunt Sara?
She can't even feed herself.
Is there anyone else who
can take care of those kids?
No.
There's nobody.
Packed cells are in.
Tom, listen to me. You
have to go to the O.R.
I won't leave her.
- You could die too if you don't.
- She's not dead.
Malik, can you see if the
next two units are ready?
Yeah.
Remember when we went up to
Lake Louise biking that summer?
Is that it?
Yes.
She's gone.
Time of death: 19:34.
- Mr. Callahan?
- Thank you for letting me be with her.
Okay, let's move him.
I'll call Surgery and catch up
to you at the elevators, Malik.
You got it.
Labs came back on your
alderman. Positive for syphilis.
I asked to pull the
swab. It was mislabeled.
You want labs, can't get them. You
don't want them, they get efficient.
Chuny, I need a repeat
potassium on Mrs. Callahan.
- I'll get it.
- What is she still doing here?
- She's an MVA.
- Kovac pronounced her an hour ago.
She's in and out of V-tach.
But she's got a pulse.
Jerry, I thought I asked you
to pull the alderman's labs.
- I called them. I'll call them again.
- It's all right. I'll take care of it.
Paramedics are pulling
up with a kid. Took a fall.
Don't they call ahead anymore?
Jerry, make sure those TV news
vans are out of the ambulance bay.
Hey, Luka.
Why is Jessie Callahan still in Trauma
1? Because she died an hour ago.
Her husband wouldn't go
to the O.R. until she passed.
So I unhooked her leads
and pronounced her.
Good God.
What happens when he gets back from
surgery and finds out his wife is alive?
- I'll tell him it was a miracle.
- We need a doctor over here.
This isn't funny, Luka. You unhooked
the monitors of a critically injured woman.
Hardly in the best
interest of your patient.
She wasn't my patient, he was.
David Scott, 9 years old. Altered after
a fall from the top bunk of a bunk bed.
Neighbor was babysitting,
heard a crash, called 911.
GCS 235.
- The real one will be bigger.
- I hope so.
- Quiche?
- Oh. Thank you.
Have you tried these?
- They're like perfect little salty things.
- Don't fill up on those.
With any luck, we may get out
early enough to get some real food.
How much are
they trying to raise?
Fifty-eight, I think.
We're throwing in 10.
- Thousand?
- Million.
Right.
So I guess that means
you get great seats forever?
Gamma will.
What do you do with $58 million?
You get architectural
significance.
What's the point of
building a cultural edifice...
if you're not gonna prove
your civic superiority?
Well, that's a lot
of civic superiority.
McNulty's clinic's
not far from here.
What do you think
he'd do with $58 million?
- Hot hors d'oeuvres in his waiting room?
- Hello, John.
Hello, Gamma.
- Hi, Steve.
- John.
I'm Millicent Carter,
John's grandmother.
- Hi. Uh, Abby Lockhart.
- Gamma, you've met Abby before.
Oh, I'm sorry. So many
people in John's life.
Don't you look beautiful.
What exactly are canapés?
I mean, are they
different from appetizers?
I'm not sure, dear.
There's a foundation board
meeting on Thursday, John.
- Can you come?
- No. Thank you.
I'd appreciate it. We're
electing new officers.
Oh, well...
I thought that was a whoever's-in-
the-bathroom-is-president kind of thing.
I'm stepping down. I'd like you to
take your father's place as treasurer.
How did Dad get off so easy?
I've asked your father to
take my place as president.
Don't you think you're
getting a bit long in the tooth...
for the disaffected
youth role, John?
Gamma, thank you. But, no,
thank you. I already have a day job.
David, can you open your eyes?
Looks like a Colles' fracture.
- I'm assessing his mental status.
- He responds to painful stimuli.
David, do you know where you are?
- I don't know.
- All right. Let's get a head
CT. KOVAC: Lots of old bruises.
- Active kid. Hockey, maybe?
- We should do a long-bone survey.
We have to rule out intracranial bleed.
- You guys seen Pratt?
Mrs. Callahan's potassium's 3.2.
- Okay. Add 20 of KCL to her next liter.
- She's a DNR.
And if she arrests we'll let
her go, until then we treat her.
She's dead, Kerry.
Oh, great. Just what I need.
- This is a decision for her husband.
- He's had surgery.
If you'd told him the truth...
he could have given us
instructions on his wife's care.
Now we have to decide.
Give her the K.
What can I do for you?
I'm finished for the day and I
come down to say good night...
and who should I find still
sitting in the middle of the ER?
- We're waiting on tests for the alderman.
- Alderman Bright, that's right.
Five hours later. Did I not tell
you to find him a private room?
- He didn't want a private room.
- You should've given him one anyway.
He should have had two doctors
and five nurses over him every minute.
"Can I get you anything?
More ice for your knee?"
- We only have five nurse...
- I don't give a damn.
Whatever he needs, whatever he
wants, you do it and you do it now.
Here you go.
- That was a little rude.
- Stay out of it.
- Excuse me...
- So was that.
Could I have your attention?
With 200 fewer seats...
larger rehearsal hall and
dressing rooms, world-class...
My grandmother doesn't want
me to be treasurer of the foundation.
- She wants me to quit working.
- She's old.
She's probably looking to
you to take some of her load.
Embrace my familial
responsibilities?
Join the family business?
Which is what exactly?
It's this. It's giving away
money. It's cutting ribbons.
It's waving to the common man.
It's Prince Charles
without the castle.
Don't know about no castle.
Seen your grandmother's house.
Abby, I know that
you mean well...
but don't try to tell me what
to do with my life, okay?
Okay. MILLICENT: John Carter.
CT's ready and he's waking up.
- Where's my dad?
- We called him.
How did you get hurt, David?
I fell off the top bunk.
Okay, we're gonna
take care of you.
This is Chuny. She's taking you
up to get a few more tests, okay?
- You'll find my dad?
- We've already called him, honey.
- He should be here any minute.
- Dr. Kovac, kid's x-rays are back.
Finally. I thought Tuesday
nights were not busy, huh?
Who told you that?
Oh, damn it. JERRY: What?
- Is DCFS still around?
- Excuse me. Um...
They told me my son was
back here. Uh, David Scott.
Ambulance brought him in a
few minutes ago. He fell out of bed.
Mr. Scott? SCOTT: Yeah.
Where is he? Is he okay?
Your son has a broken
wrist and he hit his head.
He gets hurt all the time.
More since his mom left.
- His exams showed some old injuries.
- Yeah. You see, he doesn't pay attention.
The injuries are suspicious.
What?
Are you suggesting
that I hurt my own son?
- Do you?
- No. No, of course not.
We're giving her all
the right antibiotics...
but her sepsis is very advanced.
So, what are her chances?
I'm afraid they're
not very good.
I just need to determine...
what is the best living situation
for your brother and sister.
Yeah.
Do you think living with you
is the best thing for them?
Uh, probably not.
So I should find someplace
else for them to stay?
Wait a minute. You're not
trying to keep them together?
- Is this coming from you?
- I think Doug agrees that foster care...
is the best option for
his brother and sister.
Doug, do you know
what foster care is like?
Most likely, they
won't even be together.
We'll do our best to
keep them together.
- But that doesn't always happen, right?
- We do our best.
Do you know what
that means? Hmm?
That means they're
gonna get split up.
Their mom's dying, and
they're gonna be separated.
Living with strangers,
is that what you want?
- Hey, Doug. Doug.
- Oh, she's right!
Listen, your mom might die.
You need to stay together.
They love you, man.
Ha-ha, right, right. The dumb
stoner who makes them laugh.
- You care about them. That matters.
- Hey, I can't take care of two kids.
You'd be surprised
at what you can do.
No.
Hey, trust me. I know.
You just need to step up.
You never should have called
me. All right? My mom's right.
They're all right.
Make them wrong.
I can't, all right?
Bright to Williams,
right? Got the new label?
Uh, specimen two was mislabeled.
Happens. We don't want the
paperwork guys to strike us dead.
We just need a Dr. Hancock.
Mm-hm.
That's it? CANDI: That's it.
I think Shaw's is open late if you
still wanna get something to eat.
No, I'm not hungry.
Not hungry, or pissed at me?
I'm sorry, but I don't think you have
any right to lecture me about my family.
Was that an apology?
I don't owe you an apology.
- Ticket, sir?
Look, you want me to
end up like my father?
At Gamma's beck and
call, handing out checks...
so the Art Institute gets a de Kooning
or the symphony can have travertine...
Why don't you just get involved with
the foundation and change the priorities?
Give the money to health care, education.
Anything you feel passionate about.
I feel passionate about what I
do. I feel passionate about County.
- Who says you can't do both?
- Ha. I do.
Okay, look, you were
born really, really rich.
- So what? It's nothing to be ashamed of.
- I'm not ashamed of who I am.
No? You drive a Jeep.
You wear a cheap watch. You
rent a two-bedroom apartment.
- What do you want? Me to drive a BMW?
- No. I don't care.
I couldn't care less.
But you care a lot.
You want everybody to think that
you're just like them and you're not.
You just signed a check for $10
million in there. You didn't even blink.
I write a check for over
$100, I get a stomachache.
I give something more
important than money. I give time.
I do it every day to real people
and it makes a difference.
And I think that's
great. I really, really do.
But money makes
a difference too.
You know where my
money comes from?
You know where the money for the
Carter Symphony Hall comes from?
Great-grandfather made a killing in the
Depression cornering the coal market.
In the winter of 1933, a
lot of children froze to death.
And my family
made out like bandits.
That was 70 years ago, Carter.
You can't give the
money back now.
Why not help give it to
people who really need it?
There are still lots of kids
freezing to death every winter.
Black Jeep.
- How's the knee?
- Sore.
Well, swelling's down. Looks
like we can get you started home.
Ah, almost 11. Should be safe.
Right, local news usually packs up
and goes home if they miss the 10:00.
I'll go get the car.
All right. Your thigh will probably
be a little sore from the penicillin shot.
How do we stand on the
medical-records issue?
It's been handled.
Good. Good. Thank
you for your discretion.
I'm glad I could help.
Bright is discharged, Jerry.
- Did we ever get his labs back?
- They're negative.
That lesion was
right out of Netter's.
- We should run it again.
- It's fine.
- He could have untreated syphilis.
- He's fine. Let it go.
Don't touch me.
Yeah. Almost midnight.
Let the shouting begin.
- He's scared. He needs me.
- We can talk here or go to the precinct.
- This is you, right?
- Calm down.
No, I'm okay. But this is
crazy. I have never hurt my son.
I'm gonna call my lawyer.
- What the hell was that about?
- Father abusing his son.
- Where's Social Services?
- They were busy.
So you called the police?
- Kid has multiple old fractures.
- Wait. Did you talk to the child?
Of course I did. He was scared.
Hey.
You got the blue
cast. It's my favorite.
Is my dad coming back?
Well, he had to
talk to some people.
- You get along pretty well with your dad?
- Better since Mom left.
He says we're like
Starsky and Hutch.
That's an old TV show
we watch on Nick at Nite.
- Sounds nice.
- Yeah.
You've been hurt a lot
in the last few months.
I don't pay enough attention.
Did you really fall out
of bed today, David?
I...
I jumped.
Is that the truth, David?
It's okay. You can tell me.
Hello?
McNULTY: We're closed.
- Dr. McNulty? McNULTY:
If you're sick, go to County.
Dr. McNulty, we met the
other day. I'm Dr. Carter.
You left before your
tests came back.
Your blood sugar was 435.
Your diabetes is way out of control.
- I take my Orinase.
- Orinase?
- They still make that?
- Works fine for me.
Not according to your tests.
There are newer, better drugs.
Yeah. Thanks.
Goodbye.
You're not gonna be able to help anybody
down here if you're in a coma or dead.
Actos. Six-month supply.
Hey, hey, you steal those from
County? There are laws against that.
You gotta watch your sugar too.
Sure.
Don't get your tux
dirty on the way out.
Looks like you could use
new equipment around here.
No, no. You're not doing that.
You can get yourself
a cardiac monitor.
Chemistry analyzer.
Twelve-lead. Anything
else you might need.
What's this?
White liberal guilt?
Probably.
Lots of guilt.
No, thanks.
I'm not here to
make you feel better.
There must be
something I can do.
Yeah.
You can sweep.
- Did ICU come for my pneumonia?
- Went up a couple of minutes ago.
DCFS is taking the
kids up to say goodbye.
Hey, she's still alive, right?
- Yeah.
- You came back.
- Well, I never really left.
You know, she said I was
the biggest mistake of her life.
I don't want to let them down...
- but I don't know if I can do it.
- You just do the best that you can.
That'll be enough.
Come on. I'll take
you up to see them.
Stay with her as
long as you want.
Okay.
Go ahead.
Thanks.
- He came back, huh?
- Yeah.
Hey, um, I was
out of line before.
Whatever. I'm an
adult. I can handle it.
You should worry about those two kids.
- Hey, Pratt. Phone call.
Hello. Dr. Pratt.
Hey, Mrs. Knightly.
What?
Oh, man. When?
Okay.
Jerry, I'm off in 15. Tell
Weaver I had to leave.
I'll come in early and
make it up in the morning.
- Was that Pratt leaving again?
- Uh, yeah. He had to go early.
- Go where?
- Didn't say.
Well, guess what? I want to go
too. Maybe I should just leave.
What do you say? Just
leave because I feel like it.
Your child abuser was a case of a
boy wanting to spend time with his father.
- Who? The Scott kid?
- Yes.
The kid hurts himself so Dad will
stay home and watch TV with him.
- Did you page me for a post-op seroma?
- Yeah. Exam 4.
Your Mr. Callahan's
finally in Recovery.
Send your patients up to the O.R. a
bit more promptly in future, all right?
And next time, get DCFS down
here before you call the cops.
Tom's out of surgery.
He's gonna be okay.
You can let go now.
Pratt left again? Man, when I
was an intern, it was a full-time job.
Yeah. It still is.
Ugh. I just want to go
home and get into bed.
What do you think
the odds are...
that Antonio Banderas
will be waiting for me?
Oh, I almost forgot. Here.
I know it's a little early, but I was
in Field's buying a gift for my niece...
and I saw the infant stuff.
I pass those little clothes
and I go into a trance.
- I have to buy something.
- Susan...
Those Onesies and jumpers, they
have control over me. And the little shoes.
I don't know if it's a boy or
girl so I got green, neutral.
If you hate it, I have
the gift receipts...
Uh, I'm not pregnant anymore.
I miscarried.
Oh, uh, God.
Kerry, I'm so sorry.
Embryonic loss rate after implantation
is about 30 percent in IVF. It isn't rare.
- Thank you for the thought.
- Sure.
And when you see Pratt, why don't
you remind him this is a full-time job?
Good night.
They brought him in on a
10-29, possible stolen car.
Car was clean. But they found
a shotgun with a clipped barrel.
The others have criminal
paper, your brother's clear.
Just hanging next to the
wrong car at the wrong time.
This is against like 15 regs...
- so make it fast.
- Thanks.
I ever get shot, I want
to end up at County.
- You guys always take care of us.
- Thank you.
Don't be mad. Don't be mad, G.
Please, it wasn't my fault.
It was Dukey's fault. He's
the one that had the gun.
What were you doing with
those boys? Didn't they hurt you?
I was telling them about
the job you got for me.
While I was telling
them, the cops came.
Okay, okay, listen to me.
Do not talk to anybody in here.
Not the police, no one.
Not until I get you a lawyer.
Tell Mr. Keegan I
won't be late next time.
- Leon...
- Was he mad? Tell him I promise.
Leon, you didn't show up.
You probably lost that job.
No, G. No.
I don't want to stay in here, G.
Come on, please? Can't we go home?
The judge sets bail in the
morning. Then I can take you home.
- In the morning? I...
- Doc, you gotta go.
G, I can't spend the night
here. I don't know these people.
First thing in the morning, okay?
- Doc?
- G.
- First thing.
Don't leave me, G.
G, don't do that, G.
G, come on. G.
G.
Don't leave me here. Come on.