Maggie?
I need to take a minute.
Don't you feel
worn down from your chemo?
If you don't want us
to treat you medically,
then you're getting help.
That Crockett guy,
what's the deal with him?
Not sure he's my speed.
Strikes me as someone
who doesn't take
things seriously.
We told your supervisor
we didn't want you
treating our daughter.
I just need to
check one last thing.
Dr. Manning?
I'm gonna want to
oversee all your cases,
until we know your TBI
isn't adversely affecting
your patients.
You don't have
the authority.
It's for your
own protection.
I'll go
talk to her.
I know, I know, I'm late.
It was hard getting out
of the house this morning.
You sleep okay?
I got a full eight hours.
I had breakfast.
I don't have a headache.
I feel great.
Toddler in
Treatment Six.
Nanny brought him in.
Parents just got here.
A bloody nose?
I'll do the intake
and then pass it
off to Terry.
This has med student
written all over it.
I don't know.
Lanik wants you
to take it.
But I've got pediatric
charts to follow up on
from the night shift.
I'll take care of them.
Are you kidding?
I was late
because traffic sucked,
not because of my TBI.
That's not my decision.
I am fine.
Natalie.
Thank you.
What?
The wink wasn't
exactly natural.
I was trying to
match your sexy.
Just keep being you.
You catch any of that?
You mean you
ogling my sister
like she put
the gris-gris on you?
Yeah.
Yes,
it's now burned
into my retinas.
Sorry.
"Gris-gris"?
It's a voodoo thing,
means you're
under the spell.
At least I think it does.
Dr. Marcel drops a lot
of Cajun nuggets.
You're starting
your surgical
residency with him,
not prepping
for Mardi Gras.
Speaking of,
how's it going?
It's intense.
I mean, one minute
I'm cracking
open a chest,
the next I'm digging
through a belly.
Just remember there's
an actual person
on that table,
not just a body.
Of course.
Dr. Choi.
Good morning to you.
Dr. Sexton,
right on time.
Let's go.
Cool.
Hey, hey there,
Ms. April.
Good morning, Dr. Marcel.
Did Noah say
anything to you
about working
with Dr. Marcel?
Just that
he's keeping him
really busy,
which I figure
is a good thing.
Yeah.
You know, I got
a question for you.
What?
Why are
you so damn sexy?
Stop it! Stop...
How you gonna be
talking nasty in the
middle of the hospital!
I'm not nasty.
She's nasty,
trust me.
Well, you two
look happy.
I'm here with my man.
What's not to
be happy about?
Where are you off to?
You know,
I've been doing that
volunteer upstairs.
So we gonna go
grab a cup of coffee
and then he's gonna
walk me
upstairs afterwards.
Wait a minute.
You should join us.
Honey, I'm so sorry,
it's the ED.
I gotta skip coffee.
Okay.
What, well you do,
but we don't.
Uh, sorry, I have
a staff meeting
in 20 minutes.
Well, then, we gotta
drink fast then, right?
Come on,
give me some.
I love you.
I'll see you later.
I love you, too.
I love you, too,
but in a different way.
Whatever.
So, Carl, how long
has the pain and nausea
been bothering you?
Kind of lost track.
Let's just say, years.
So it comes and goes?
No, it came
and never left.
I've learned
how to cope.
But some days,
I just can't look
the other way.
Yeah... Yeah,
today's one of them.
Actually, this is the
worst it's ever been.
Vitals are normal.
Afebrile.
Is this the first time
you've seen
a doctor for it?
Here in Chicago.
I'm from
Tennessee, though.
I was a regular
at the Westwood
Regional ED.
Pretty sure every
doc there poked,
prodded and scanned me.
I'll have them
forward his records.
Did Westwood Regional
make a diagnosis?
No, they had
a lot of theories.
IBS, IBS-C, ulcer.
One doc thought I had
an eating disorder.
Believe me, I would pile on
the pounds if I could,
but eating sends me
right to the bathroom.
Vomiting?
Most of the time.
I just can't believe
this is what
I've been reduced to.
I'm 26.
I should've
graduated college,
met someone special.
Instead, my life
is making sure
I always know where
the nearest bathroom is.
We'll figure this out.
Mo, let's get a chest X-ray,
KUB, CBC, CMP and a UA.
Mmm-hmm.
I know you've seen
a lot of doctors for this.
I'll do my best
to be the last one.
Here you go...
Good morning,
I'm Dr. Manning.
See?
I'm Kyle. This is
my wife, Janet.
Hi.
And the little
guy is Lucas.
Hey, Lucas...
Hi.
Peekaboo.
Well, he seems happy.
That's a good start.
I see the bloody
nose has stopped.
Can you tell me
what happened?
He was at the park
with his nanny
and it just started gushing.
And she couldn't
reach either of us,
so since they were
around the corner,
she brought him here.
I have a three-year-old
and a nanny, I get it.
All right.
Yeah, the nosebleeds
aren't a new thing.
We've been dealing
with them all summer.
Can I see
your nose?
Turbinates are swollen
and irritated.
Seasonal allergies?
Oh, yeah.
They've been brutal for
all of us this year.
For Lucas, it's nosebleeds
and this rash on his arm.
Oh, yeah, and
that little cough.
Hey, buddy. Can you
open your mouth for me?
Real wide,
like this... Aah!
Good, good, good.
I am seeing evidence
of post nasal drip.
That's likely what's
causing the cough.
Is it worse at night?
It was.
But then we put an atomizer
with eucalyptus oil
by his crib.
It's helped a lot.
Let's take a look.
All right,
let's see.
He's a little wheezy.
Any fever?
Yeah. He felt
a little warm yesterday
morning. He...
He was fussy
at breakfast,
but by lunch,
and ever since then,
he's been a bundle
of energy.
Good.
Is this the rash
you mentioned?
Yes.
Have you been using
a topical hydrocortisone
cream on it?
No. I've been mashing
up a chewable fish oil
tablet in his yogurt.
Oh, okay.
Well, if it's working.
All evidence is pointing
towards allergies and
an overcautious nanny.
But since Lucas may have
had a fever yesterday,
I would like to do
some blood tests.
Is something wrong?
We just have adopted
a naturopathic approach
to our health care.
Look, the thing
with blood tests is,
they will not introduce
anything new into
Lucas' system.
They'll just show us
if something's there
that shouldn't be.
Yeah. Okay.
Go ahead.
Great. I'll send
a nurse in.
Maggie? Doris said
you were looking for me.
Yes. I've got
an appointment
this afternoon.
I need you to take over
for me while I'm gone.
No problem.
What time
will you be back?
I won't.
Okay.
Guess that's all
I need to know.
Monique,
what am I missing?
These last few weeks
Maggie's been
so short with me.
It's not just you.
The other day I saw her
sneak into an open
treatment room and lie down.
So I asked her if she was
feeling okay and she
bit my head off.
Huh.
I'm elbow-deep
in this guy's belly,
and it was a big belly.
Highly doubtful
this fellow ever
skipped a meal.
No, not surgical.
So I go to sew up
a hole in the small
bowel and, bam!
Out pops
this critter.
No lie, this thing
looked straight at me,
dropped back
into the bowel,
disappeared.
What the hell?
What was it?
A tapeworm.
The biggest one
I've ever seen.
Only one I ever seen.
Uh, also, not surgical.
So what did you do?
Went after it.
I stuck ringed forceps
into that bowel and I
yanked that old worm out.
All three feet
of him.
Then I sent him
off to pathology
and finished the case.
If Dr. Marcel's
taking Noah under his wing,
he should teach more
and brag less.
Yeah, his style's
just different
than yours.
That's probably why
you don't like it.
Come on, you buy
that tapeworm story?
Come on,
Dr. Marcel may be
a personality,
but he's a good
surgeon.
Carl's labs and
X-rays are back.
What about his
medical records from
his previous hospital?
Still working on it.
Seems Westwood
Regional went bankrupt.
I've got a call into
the company appointed
to handle patient affairs.
Thanks, Mo.
Mmm-hmm.
Uh-oh.
You look concerned.
Your white cell count
is high.
X-ray showed dilated loops
of bowel and your overall
blood count is low.
Means more
tests, right?
Yeah.
So what's next?
A CT angiogram
of your blood vessels
and a CT with contrast
for your bowel.
Did you ever have
either of these
tests before?
Angiogram...
I don't know,
maybe.
The CT with contrast,
is that the scan you
drink something first?
Ugh. Then I've had
one of them. Didn't like
that drink at all.
Well, unfortunately,
it hasn't gotten
any better.
Sorry, man. I'll go
put in the order.
Thanks.
Hey, so in T Four...
...something worth
looking into.
Mmm-hmm.
Don't forget.
Don't forget legal research
regarding contractor's
negligence for the complaint.
Issue. Rule.
Eunice Kim, 25.
First year associate
at some big time law firm.
Anyway, her roommate
called us
when the ranting and
the pacing started to
annoy the neighbors.
She say anything about
the last time she slept?
Yeah, been
at least two days.
When we showed up,
she was screaming
at herself in the mirror.
We tried to calm
her, but...
Yeah.
She wasn't having
any of that.
Yeah.
Find any drugs
in the apartment?
Nope. Tons of books,
nothing sketchy.
Charges pending?
Figured you could help
more than lock-up.
I appreciate it.
Hey, let's get some
M-tabs for Eunice.
Don't forget.
Don't forget! Don't forget.
Eunice, how you doing?
Get legal research...
I'm Dr. Charles.
...regarding contractor's
negligence.
IRAC. Issue. Rule. IRAC.
Eunice?
IRAC. IRAC.
Eunice!
Hey! How you doing?
I'm Dr. Charles.
You think we could maybe
sit and talk a bit?
Only a moment, I don't have
anything more to spare.
I got it.
A motion to strike
the affirmative defense.
Eunice...
Wait, can't do that
because there is
a genuine issue
of material fact.
Gotta do discovery...
Eunice!
I can see you're under
a whole lot of pressure.
I'd like to give you
some medicine to help
you calm down a bit,
you know, maybe
think more clearly.
Think more clearly.
Yeah.
That might help.
Okay.
I need
to organize.
Yeah.
I don't know where I am.
You're in
a safe place, Eunice.
What's going on?
He's losing it.
I need to get out!
How much longer
till we get the scan?
Twenty seconds.
Two milligrams
of midazolam.
Carl, it's Dr. Choi.
We're almost done.
I'm gonna be sick.
Slow breaths.
Only ten more seconds.
I'm not gonna make it.
Yes, you can.
You can do this, Carl.
Five seconds.
Four, three,
two, one. You good?
Get him out.
You did it, Carl.
Good job, buddy.
It's over.
Good job.
I'm sorry.
It's okay, hey.
It's all right.
Good job, man.
I mean, that's not
a normal calf, right?
Yeah, it's swollen.
And you
didn't injure it?
Nope. Nothing.
I went to bed,
it was fine. Woke up,
thing's a grapefruit.
Press against my hand.
One to ten,
how bad's the pain?
I'd say a seven,
maybe an eight.
That's in line with what
I'm thinking. Blood clot.
It's called a DVT,
deep vein thrombosis.
Seriously? Me?
I exercise a few times
a week. I don't sit
for long periods of time.
Yeah, unfortunately,
not fitting the profile
doesn't mean you
can't develop one.
Beating the odds.
Lucky me.
CBC, BMP, protein C, S
and Factor V Leiden.
Let's get Mr. Bowe a DVT scan
and put him on a heparin drip.
I'll check on you in a bit.
Dr. Halstead,
before you leave,
can you grab my phone?
Front pocket of my jeans.
Sure.
I kept the swollen
calf under wraps
'cause I didn't want
my fiancée to freak out.
But I think we're to the point
where I'd better let her
know what's going on.
Got you.
Oh, man.
That's one
angry belly.
What's going on?
Surgical consult.
I didn't call for one.
It was only
a matter of time.
Good find, Noah.
Dr. Marcel, Dr. Sexton,
can I speak
with you outside?
All this stalking
around the ED,
peeking in on patients.
You hanging outside
Carl's room earlier,
you were sniffing
for surgical cases.
And Noah's your intern.
Best you could
do is show him
how to poach patients?
Whoa. Poaching
implies stealing.
Hardly think that
applies in Carl's case,
seeing as how you were
gonna call us anyway.
Possibly.
Possibly?
Dr. Choi, Carl's belly
was so hot it nearly
burned my hands.
There's an issue
in there that requires
surgical attention.
Or do my hands
deceive me?
No. CT showed a partial
small bowel obstruction
with a likely
transition point.
So it is surgical.
Possibly.
The CT imagery is poor
because Carl was agitated
during the scan.
I'm not comfortable
making any treatment
decisions
before I know
exactly what's causing
the obstruction.
So I'm ordering an MRI.
Pending the results,
I'll let you know
if a surgical consult
is needed.
Okay.
I apologize
for overstepping.
Protocol, etiquette,
they mean something.
I'll do better at
remembering that.
Okay.
Doris, any word from
the lab on Lucas' tests?
Not yet. Word's out your
case screams allergies.
It's probably
last in line.
Maggie?
Yeah.
There are patients
waiting to be seen
and I have absolutely
nothing going on.
Light case load.
Lanik was very clear.
This is ridiculous.
Then talk to Lanik
and stop bugging me.
Because you're giving me
one more headache
that I don't need.
Okay.
Look, I'm sorry.
I've somewhere to be
and I can't be late.
April, I'm leaving.
Eunice, how you doing?
I'm happy
to see that, um,
you seem to be
a little better.
Embarrassed
is more like it.
It's all a blur,
but I know I wasn't
myself.
I understand how...
How scary that can feel.
It can't happen again.
Now on, no matter
how busy I am,
I'll make time for sleep.
I mean, sleep is crucial.
But counseling, medication,
other lifestyle changes
are all things that
we need to talk about.
Little extreme, no?
I mean, I had
a panic attack,
not a nervous breakdown.
It wasn't
a panic attack.
I'm quite sure that
you were experiencing
a manic episode, Eunice,
symptomatic of
bipolar disorder.
No, no, no...
I can't have bipolar.
I have $300,000
in student loans
and my salary doesn't
even make a dent.
I need to make partner.
Takes most lawyers
five years,
I'm on track
to do it in three.
Can't you just give me
more of that medication?
Or something else?
Well, thing is,
bipolar disorder doesn't
really work that way.
Unless you address it
comprehensively,
the manic episodes
will likely return.
They'll increase in intensity
and can even be followed
by cycles of depression...
But I know the signs now.
I can get out in front
of it if I start
to feel off, control it.
I don't think anybody
can control this.
You know,
not even somebody
as determined as you.
But, Eunice,
you can absolutely
learn how to manage it.
Why don't you
let me admit you
and let's start looking
for a stable medication?
No. I'd like
to be discharged.
Today's not
a wash yet.
I can still put in
some face time
at the firm.
Look, I know the criteria
for involuntary commitment.
Legally, you can't
keep me here.
Does the furrow
of your brow
suggest a surgical
consult is now needed?
MRI revealed
a focal solitary mass
in the distal pancreas.
May be a cyst.
I concur.
Gotta assume it's
what's riling Carl's
belly up so fiercely.
He needs a distal
pancreatectomy.
You take out the section
of the pancreas
housing the mass,
no more
chaos downstream.
That is a huge
procedure.
Not to mention, it won't
do a thing for Carl if
the mass isn't the issue.
If the mass
isn't the problem,
then what are
we looking at?
Carl's been
suffering for years.
The mass could have
been there the whole
time, unchanged,
which means it's
likely not a factor.
Or the mass has been
growing over time.
We leave it in,
the inflammation worsens,
the bowel
completely obstructs,
then perforates
and Carl becomes septic.
The first step of that
potentially fatal
catastrophe is a fever,
which, by the
looks of him,
has set in.
100.6.
But holding.
Yeah, for now.
You operate
on his pancreas
and you're wrong,
it does way more
harm than good.
But if I'm correct,
he lives.
And I don't like if's.
Carl will be treated
medicinally until his
previous scans arrive
and I can compare them
against today's MRI.
That's gonna
be a problem.
His medical records from
Westwood Regional are
being held hostage.
This is a mess.
You know, Westwood
Regional's bankruptcy
has created the
legal equivalent
of a battle royale.
MRS. Medical
Record Services.
I'm assuming they control
Westwood's patient charts?
Correct. It's MRS
that have
the files on lockdown,
they're actually
threatening
to destroy them.
My main concern
right now is Carl.
My opinion
is not changed.
His distal pancreas
is wreaking havoc and
it needs to come out.
Without Carl's previous scans,
which it's clear
we're not gonna get,
you can't prove
that's the fix.
No, I cannot.
Then you shouldn't operate.
The pancreas is
the most unforgiving
organ in the body.
The potential for
surgical complications
is through the roof.
True. But God
only gave us
so many heartbeats.
No sense in Carl
running out
of his early.
Excuse me?
Is there something
going on here
that I should
know about?
Nothing
I'm aware of.
Dr. Choi?
Then give me
recommendations.
Let me operate now
before his bowel perforates
and it's too late.
Ms. Goodwin,
it's a risky procedure
that may be unnecessary.
Let me admit Carl
for more tests.
Hon?
Hi.
I'm sorry, the lab took
longer than expected.
So, Lucas' BUN, creatinine
and white cell count
are all elevated.
That suggests
dehydration.
And between
the white cell count,
his persistent cough
and the post nasal drip,
it's likely a bacterial
sinus infection.
Okay. Thanks,
Dr. Manning.
Yeah.
So, what do you think?
We could make popsicles
from coconut water.
That should help
with the dehydration.
Yeah, maybe add an
herbal antihistamine, too.
I can pick up some
powdered quercetin
at the farmer's market.
Great.
I'm sorry, perhaps
a more immediate
treatment...
You mean antibiotics?
No. Not after last time.
Lucas had an ear
infection last year.
The doctor prescribed
amoxicillin.
One dose and
he broke out in
hives everywhere.
I mean,
his recovery
from the antibiotic
was worse than
the ear infection.
And since then,
if there are natural
options without
side effects,
we try those first.
Look, like you two,
my son's health comes
before anything else.
But, you know, sometimes
there's just some things
that a holistic approach
alone won't cure.
We agree. A sinus
infection isn't one
of them, though.
You're right.
Over time, natural remedies
may help his immune system
resolve the infection.
But the dehydration...
Lucas needs
more than popsicles.
At least let me give him
an electrolyte drink.
How much?
Twenty-four ounces
to sip throughout the day.
through a sippy cup,
he won't do it.
Is there another way?
Saline IV.
I know
it's another needle,
but no side effects,
I promise.
Saline, but no
antibiotics.
Understood.
Thank you.
Dr. Halstead,
the blood thinner,
I don't think it's working.
The calf's still huge
and my foot's starting
to swell up, too.
You having
trouble breathing?
More like winded.
I wanna send you for a CT.
I gotta get a better
look at that clot.
This will help you
breathe better.
Get a hold
of your fiancée?
Voicemail.
She's still looking
at dresses.
Pretty sure she's not
checking her phone.
So, when's the big day?
Spring.
Still debating locations.
Well, congratulations.
Techs will be
by in a few.
The surgery,
it's your choice.
Okay. All right.
Thank you.
So, I explained both
of your positions.
Philosophically,
he agrees with you,
Dr. Choi,
preferring
a conservative approach.
But, realistically,
he's in pain
and desperate
to feel better.
So he chose the surgery.
Dr. Marcel, Mr. Harris
is now your patient.
All right,
let's do this.
See you in the OR.
This is huge.
Eunice?
You're right.
I can't control this.
I need help.
Well, you're
gonna get it.
Come on.
How long
will the CT take?
Just a few moments.
You'll be back
before you know it.
Okay, because
I haven't been able
to reach my fiancée
and my phone's at,
like, 4%.
I'll call her.
Thanks.
Yeah.
Her name's Aubrey.
Number's my
emergency contact.
Got it.
Wait, now you think
it's pneumonia?
It's a possibility.
We thought you
were gonna tell us
we could go home.
I mean, Lucas
isn't dehydrated
anymore, right?
Right, but he is still
wheezing and his
temperature has ticked up.
The nurse said
he was 99.3.
Is that even a fever?
He looks fine.
He's up, he's active.
On the outside,
he may look normal,
but on the inside,
pneumonia is notorious
for its slow progression.
Or it is just
a sinus infection,
which you've been
saying all day until,
apparently, right now.
Okay.
How would you
know for sure if
it's pneumonia or not?
A chest X-ray.
You're kidding,
right?
We said no
to antibiotics.
We're definitely
not letting you zap
Lucas full of radiation.
These hospitals.
You scare people
with diagnoses
and then you sell them
on treatments
they don't need
that actually
make them sicker.
Dr. Manning, we'd like
to go home. Okay?
If Lucas doesn't improve,
we'll take him to our doctor.
Your doctor?
An actual MD?
No. He's a holistic healer.
So his answer for
pneumonia's gonna
be what, oil of oregano?
Horseradish with lemon?
Look, you don't agree
with alternative
medicine, fine.
But don't insult us.
I'm not. I'm trying
to inform you.
Dr. Manning?
Yes.
Speak with you
a moment?
Please excuse me.
What's going on?
My boy with the bloody
nose, it may very well
be pneumonia,
but his parents
won't allow me
to do a chest X-ray.
They would rather go home
and take their chances
with herbs and teas.
Let me see the chart.
Yeah, these symptoms,
okay, pneumonia has to
be on the differential.
Yeah.
Let me talk to them.
Okay.
Alone.
I'm the
attending physician.
We don't know.
These tests are the only
way to provide us...
Do what you need to do.
Thank you
for working with us.
Yeah.
They agreed to
the chest X-ray.
This is the second
time this month
that parents
have lost faith
in your judgment.
They may be
upset now,
they won't be
when I'm right.
I gotta tell you,
these labs, they look
like a sinus infection.
So you'd better be right
that it's pneumonia.
Hello, hello, hello.
This is your last week?
Oh, girlie.
You're looking good!
Girlfriend's a champ!
You still walk
around in my sweater.
Thank you.
That's a good catch.
Maggie.
Caroline.
I'm so sorry,
I didn't know.
No one does,
except for Sharon.
And I'd like to keep it
that way, please.
Yeah.
I've been there.
You mind if I sit?
Girl, you got a whole bag
hanging. You ain't going
nowhere no time quick.
Okay.
Come on.
So, where's the badness?
In my breast.
And what's
the prognosis?
Still waiting to see
how I respond
to chemo stage.
I've been there.
Sisters in arms.
So, you know this
keeping a secret thing,
it's not gonna...
It's not gonna be
that easy, right?
I'm managing.
Oh!
That cancer's
a heavy lift and I know
it sounds like a cliché,
but there's strength
in community.
And pity.
Mmm-hmm.
And obligation.
And I don't want
any of that.
I hear you.
And I was afraid to
tell my friends, too.
But once I let 'em in,
I let my friends
be my friends.
That was a real comfort.
It's time to heal
with steel, Dr. Sexton.
Incision is yours.
What's it gonna be?
Midline...
Is that a question
or a statement?
Midline.
Okay. Then what?
Divide and tie off
the falciform ligament.
Keep going.
Eviscerate the patient
and find
the transition point
of the small bowel.
I like
what I'm hearing.
Don't stop now.
We open the lesser sack
and take down
the lienocolic ligament...
Hey, Carl. I'm gonna
take good care of you.
Dr. Marcel?
I'm gonna be by your side
the whole time, Carl.
What are you doing?
Okay?
This isn't
an easy surgery.
I'm just letting Carl know
that we're gonna take
special care of him.
You think he can hear you?
Unsure.
But what the
body can't hear,
perhaps the soul can.
That said, Carl
needs to know exactly
what's gonna happen.
So continue,
Dr. Sexton.
Isolate the spleen,
put a curved eight
around the hilum and
then take the spleen out.
From there we mobilize
the distal pancreas
and put a TA 90
stapler across it.
Okay.
Let's get started.
Hey!
Sorry I'm late.
Patient surprised me.
In a good way.
Hey.
Not always the case.
Mmm.
How you doing?
How's your day going?
You know what?
I am so happy.
You know? I wish everyone
could feel this way.
Nice.
You know what?
Let's make some lasagna.
I wanna make some.
I love your lasagna.
I do.
All right, let's invite
Sharon over. It'd be nice
to hang out with friends.
Done.
I love that.
Come on, lasagna.
Thank you.
Nurse moved me up
to the oxygen mask,
but I still can
hardly breathe.
Yeah.
Your CT shows
a large proximal
pulmonary embolism.
Okay, that means your
blood clot from your leg
has moved to your lungs.
I played
tennis yesterday.
Now, I don't have
the energy to sit up.
Why is this happening,
Dr. Halstead?
Well, we'll figure that out
later. Right now, we need
to deal with that clot.
I'm gonna send you
up to IR to treat it
endoscopically.
Okay? Let's go.
Were you able to get in touch
with my fiancée, Aubrey?
No, and I'm really sorry.
I was about to
and I got pulled away.
I promise I will call her
soon as you're on the move.
Neal?
Neal!
No pulse.
VF on the monitors.
Bag him.
Paddles. Charge to 200.
Charged.
Clear.
Epi. One milligram.
Epi's in.
Okay, here we go.
Clear.
No, no, no.
Another round
of epi.
Come on, Neal!
Clear.
Asystole.
Damn it!
Time of death, 17:48.
Tough one, Halstead.
But don't sweat
the review.
I looked over the chart
and the PE is clearly
the cause of death.
There's nothing
you could've done.
Dr. Halstead,
Neal's fiancée
Aubrey just arrived.
Hello? Mama,
I'm here.
I don't know, they're not
telling me anything.
I don't know
who to find.
Can you please
just come now?
No complications.
Lucky for us, too,
'cause Carl's bowel
was in bad shape.
Dr. Marcel was right
to push for surgery.
Yeah. He was right.
Yeah.
This time.
But Dr. Marcel's style,
the risks he's willing
to take...
Man, Ethan,
can't you even enjoy
the moment, man?
I mean, we won.
We saved his life.
Yeah.
Okay.
Noah. Noah!
I'm sorry.
I should be
celebrating.
If we'd waited
like I wanted,
Carl's bowel would
have perforated.
Well, it turned out okay.
Yeah. Noah...
I want you to succeed,
you know that.
After two years
at Dr. Choi boot camp,
and what I've seen
from Dr. Marcel,
don't know
why I wouldn't.
You ever need anything,
questions, advice,
just wanna talk
something out...
Yeah. I know
where to find you.
I gotta get back
to recovery.
Want to be there
when Carl wakes up.
Go, go.
Or maybe you
can't go to bed.
Why?
Maggie?
You okay?
Maggie,
what's going on?
Honey?
I'm in the kitchen.
Are you sure
that we don't need
any more wine?
It's very easy for me
to just sort of jump back...
Hey, Bert.
Hey! Wine's
covered, Dan.
Got red and white.
I know both go well
with CeCe's lasagna.
Honey? Honey,
dinner's almost ready.
So will you set the table?
The dishes are already
out there, please.
Mmm. Let me.
The least I can do.
Thanks, Bert.
Good to
see you, pal.
Hey, man.
How you doing?
Oh, I'm good.
Good, yeah.
Sharon's gonna
be here, like,
any minute.
Why didn't you tell me
Bert was coming?
Because
if I told, I know you
wouldn't invite her.
And three people
don't exactly make
a couples dinner party.
Couples?
What are you doing?
I do not wanna hear how you
think this is a bad idea.
It is way beyond a bad idea.
It's atrocious.
Okay, yes,
I am meddling.
And I would've preferred
to warm Sharon up
to the idea,
but I happen to be
a little short on time.
You cannot spring this
on them unannounced.
These two people went
through a terrible divorce.
They haven't talked to
each other for a year.
Danny, you and I found
our way back to each other.
That's completely
different.
Who says that
Sharon and Bert
can't do the same thing?
I just want them
to be happy. That's it.
Well, you can't
manipulate people
into doing what you want
if it's not what they want.
Hey.
I remembered that CeCe's
lasagna pairs well with
both red and white, so...
That's right,
it does.
It's good with red
and with white.
And rosé.
Daniel.
Sharon!
Bert.
So, who's hungry?
You said an X-ray
would confirm pneumonia.
I thought it would.
But you still
aren't sure?
And now you wanna
try to pump our son
full of antibiotics again?
To be safe, yes.
No. We have been
here for hours
agreeing to things
we're not
comfortable with.
No more.
We're going home.
I'm sorry, but I won't
approve that discharge.
Then get me
your boss.
Now!
Hey! Hey, I need
to see a supervisor.
We're calling
our lawyer.
Lucas most likely
has pneumonia.
He needs these
antibiotics, now!
No!
You're not hearing me.
Pneumonia for toddlers
can be fatal.
Janet, get Lucas now.
No. You're
endangering his life.
We are taking
our son.
So either get out
of the way or I'll go
through you.
Hey. Hey!
Security!
Open the door!
Are you out
of your mind?
Security!
I won't let you take him.
We need security!
Open the door!
Security!
It's gonna be okay.
Open the door, please!
Hey, open the door!
Now! Lucas,
it's okay. It's okay.
Honey, it's okay.
Come on,
don't you have a key?
Please! Hey!
Look, don't you dare, no!
Please!
Get him out of there!
Lucas, it's okay,
honey. It's okay.
It's okay, buddy.
Everything's gonna
be all right.
Open the door!
You guys
are kidding me!
Open this door!