Previously on The Resident...
You're not wearing a ring.
I haven't made my decision yet.
You love Micah.
You love Conrad.
You're not getting married.
You know why I stay, don't you?
You're here.
We make a great team.
Don't you look dapper?
- I could say the same thing...
- Shall we?
One of my investigators
was able to locate
a former QuoVadis employee
who witnessed
fraud at the company.
Will they come forward?
A special M&M?
Run by Bell.
With the entire board present.
Why?
Man, I wish I brought popcorn.
Maybe we're gonna get
an update on QuoVadis.
There's nothing to update.
QuoVadis is dead.
We killed it.
Gloriously.
Take your seats, please.
I called you here
today because we have
an unusual patient to discuss:
Chastain Park Memorial.
Our speaker will explain
exactly how Chastain fell victim
to an unscrupulous
device company.
Former QuoVadis
device rep, Julian Booth.
Did you know?
I thought she was dead.
Thank you, Dr. Bell,
for having me here.
I look out today
and I see dedicated
doctors and nurses
who come to work each
day to heal their patients.
That was my mission as well.
But, like Chastain, I
was misled by QuoVadis.
The results were harm
and, in some cases...
death.
And the most
frightening thing is
the fraud committed by QuoVadis
was far too easy to accomplish.
And that is why I'm here
today... So that, moving forward,
we can make sure the devices
put into Chastain patients heal
instead of harm.
I can't believe
that you're here.
What happened to you?
Gordon's bodyguards
were following me.
I lost control of the car
and I crashed into the river.
Almost drowned, but managed
to get out and swim to safety.
Yeah, but where have
you been this whole time?
Hiding out in my parents'
house in Savannah.
Why didn't you just let
me know where you were?
I was afraid of what
Gordon would do
if he found out where I was.
And I...
I thought you'd be
in Silicon Valley.
No.
I didn't marry Priya.
I'm sorry.
It was for the best.
Julian, there is something
that we need to talk
about that can't wait.
- Your cat.
- What?
I've been taking care of him.
You have Bailey? Wow.
Uh, thank you.
Uh, so... my shift is over.
If you want to come
by, reunite with Bailey,
and talk some more...
Sure. I'd love to talk.
♪ You shake me
like a tambourine ♪
♪ Like a tambourine,
♪ Yeah, you shake
me like a tambourine ♪
♪ Like a tambourine,
like a tambourine, yeah ♪
♪ Oh, oh-oh-oh, oh-oh ♪
♪ Oh, oh ♪
♪ Oh, oh-oh-oh, oh-oh. ♪
♪ ♪
No ring on your finger.
You still haven't given
Micah your answer?
I make decisions based
on rational thought,
long-term analysis,
and coldhearted
logic. That takes time.
Emotion needs to
factor into that, too.
Talk later.
Come on, you can't
dodge Micah forever.
He deserves an answer.
I'll handle my
situation with Micah
- if you handle yours with Alec.
- What situation?
You're never at the
clinic when he's there.
You're avoiding him. Why?
- Talk later.
- Mm-hmm.
- Am I night owl or
an early bird? Uh-huh.
Well, I guess it
depends on the company.
And how is the company so far?
Let me just say
I'm here for you.
Okay. How do you
feel about co-pays?
Well...
Are you single?
Uh, I think you're
in the wrong place.
This isn't really speed dating.
We're helping
patients find doctors.
Oh, I know. But my
mom's been begging me
to find a nice doctor
to bring home, so...
No. Uh, just...
- No.
- Okay.
Craziest disease
I've ever treated?
The weirdest place
I've practiced medicine.
Valerie, right?
That gymnast training
for the Olympics.
Doctors who listen
and retain information.
It's like Christmas.
Look, uh, my whole life has been
about getting into the Olympics.
I moved away from my
family to train at the best club,
sacrificed having friends,
delayed going to college.
But a few weeks ago, I had
some shortness of breath
and dizziness that
came out of nowhere.
And I sprained my
calf a few days ago,
but it could be because
of the extra training hours.
- Well, to be safe,
we could examine you.
- Hmm.
But which doctor to choose?
Two for the price of one.
Let's see how this shakes
out. So, what's wrong with me?
I didn't hear any
murmurs in your heart
- and your lungs sound clear.
- No signs of edema.
We'll do a CBC
to rule out anemia.
We'll run an EKG to
have a look at your heart.
Valerie, you did good, girl.
Any pain besides the shoulder?
My back has been giving me
the blues, but that's old news.
I want to check your
gait. Let's take a loop.
Ooh, ooh.
I'd know that bum anywhere.
Hello, sweet cheeks.
Mwah.
- First husband.
- You mean best husband.
Well, number two was a bit of a
bore. What are you doing here?
That's between me and my doctor,
not between me, my
doctor and my ex-wife.
We have two children and
a grandchild. I beg to differ.
I bought Josie a scooter,
and I took it for a test
ride and I failed the test.
- Brett...
- Though, to be fair,
that garbage truck
came out of nowhere.
I thought we agreed,
no gifts for Josie
- until her next report card.
- And when did "we" decide that?
When I said, "No gifts for
Josie until her next report card."
Ooh. Careful,
that's a little tender.
Dr. Feldman, what did you feel?
Not 100% sure. I'll grab an
ultrasound, get a thorough look.
I got a call from Jessie's
doctors at her rehab.
She's fatigued and nauseous.
You think this is
residual effects
from the drug trial she was in?
I'm bringing her in
for some bloodwork.
- Let me help you with Jessie.
- Thanks,
- really, but I'm fine.
- Who's picking her up?
- Kyle.
- Kyle?
Jessie reconnected with
him. He offered to help.
Since when does
Kyle offer to help?
♪ Please let me
catch my breath ♪
♪ Let me catch my breath ♪
♪ Let me catch my ♪
♪ Okay, please,
let me catch my... ♪
Ah, come on, bring it in.
You know the drill.
Oh...
Gosh, I missed you, baby girl.
Glad you're doing okay.
- I missed you too, Daddy.
- Hop in. Let's go.
♪ ♪
You broke up with Karen.
How could you
possibly know that?
Your blood pressure's
high, which usually means
you started smoking again,
and since she was the
only thing between you
and your hand-rolled
Cuban cigars...
Damn, she's good.
- Imagine being married to her.
- I liked Karen. What happened?
She wasn't the one.
And once you know
that... why waste time?
A focal dilation in the
aorta about 5.6 centimeters.
Add that to his
abdominal tenderness,
and Brett has an
abdominal aortic aneurysm.
I-It's an enlarged area in
the lower part of the aorta,
the major blood vessel that
supplies blood to the body.
Am I gonna die?
It's treatable.
We'll consult with
our surgeons, the best.
Until then, I'm gonna
put you on a drip to get
your blood pressure down
and admit you to the ICU.
ICU?
Come on, be straight with
me. Do we need to call the girls?
Yes, but don't worry.
I've got you.
That was incredible.
- Unless I'm kidding myself.
- No, you're not.
That was incredible.
- Then why are you making
a run for it?
- Uh, I'm not.
I'm not. I have a-a
meeting later this afternoon,
so I-I, um, I need
to get Bailey home
because he's
clearly pissed at me.
Okay.
Look... I am figuring out
pretty much
everything in my life.
I just don't want you to
get caught up in that mess.
- You deserve better.
- Julian, stay.
Okay? Trust me, I am still
figuring out my own mess.
Maybe we do this together.
This was nice.
But I have to go.
Given the size and-and potential
for rupture with this triple A,
do you think he needs surgery?
Oh, there's no doubt in my mind.
Well, isn't there an alternative
that won't require him
to go under the knife?
He's the father of
your children. I get it.
Go on, get a second opinion.
Just quickly circle back to
mine before your first love
dies waiting.
This all looks good.
You don't have to
run these by me.
Just wanted to make sure.
Look, Nic, you've
been avoiding me
ever since I told you
how I feel about you.
No. Look, I just... I have
- a lot going on.
- Hey.
Hey.
Is that Valerie's blood work?
You guys sharing a patient?
- Yeah.
- Oh.
Cool. Well, I will
let you get back to it.
Valerie's EKG is normal.
So her heart is fine.
What if the intermittent
shortness of breath
and dizziness is a lung
issue... A pulmonary embolism?
Well, Valerie
also has calf pain.
Maybe it's a DVT.
Well, we should get a CT
angio to see what's going on.
No, I-I think a CT is premature.
Years on the road has taught me
that speed and efficiency
in diagnosis is key.
80 million CT scans
are done a year.
Many of them are unnecessary.
All right, fine.
We'll do it your way.
For now.
I agree with Dr. Austin.
Brett's gonna need surgery.
- Well, thank you for
taking a look. Ditto.
It's not every day you get
seen by the hospital CEO.
Happy to do it. Kit's a friend.
When he says "friend,"
does he mean good friend?
- No. Stop it.
- Another F.O.W.?
- I mean, haven't you had
enough of those? F.O.W.?
What am I missing?
Stop worrying about me.
Just this once,
I'll let you worry about me.
All right, I checked upstairs.
They're gonna let me know
when they're ready for
you. How you feeling?
- Tired and just still nauseous.
- Well, if your blood work
- comes back inconclusive, we'll
tag in Conrad. How's he doing?
Things still good
between you two?
Fine. Yeah.
Things are... things are great.
- How was the drive?
- Traffic jam.
We'd still be staring at
bumpers if I hadn't improvised
a well-timed U-turn,
creating my own lane.
Which worked like a charm
until we saw the flashing lights
- behind us.
- Yeah, okay, look.
I'm developing this app to help
the people who keep us safe.
FBI, firefighters, cops.
It's a dream of mine.
So, I get to talking to this
very handsome young officer
who pulls us over.
And I told him about
this passion of mine.
Nic, ask yourself. What if
law enforcement agencies
could share information
ten times faster than
they do right now?
Huh? Game changer.
The cop loved the
pitch, and Dad promised
to drive like a normal person,
so no ticket, no big deal.
I thought your dream job
was at that real estate firm
after you left your
other dream job
reinventing public
transportation.
Fickle markets.
I read the tea leaves,
and thankfully...
You'll need to know a
lot about programming.
Sweetheart, I can hire other
people to dig into the details.
Right.
- They... are ready for you.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Wait, wait, wait. You know what?
What if I converted my app
to help the health
care industry?
What do you think?
That sounds amazing.
Yeah. Yeah, it does.
We should get going.
You have a deep
vein thrombosis...
A blood clot in your leg.
That's why you
were having calf pain.
Yeah, we want to put
you on blood thinners
to treat this clot and
stop it from getting worse.
Valerie...
you will need to suspend
your training for a few months.
A bad fall could
cause internal bleeding.
No. No, if I do that, I won't
be ready for the qualifiers,
and I'll miss out on
joining the Olympic team.
Look, I'm 18.
That's old for my sport.
This is my last shot.
We wouldn't ask this of you
if your life didn't depend on it.
Hey, you know, Valerie,
my sister...
she had the same condition.
And she was torn between
playing professional
basketball...
and taking this treatment.
She chose her
career and lost her life.
I can't watch you
make the same mistake.
Okay.
Give me the blood thinners.
I'm sorry about your sister.
When did she pass?
She lives in Buffalo.
Please tell me you didn't
just lie to our patient.
Well, I could, but
that would be a lie.
We don't coerce patients
into treatments they don't want.
Even if it's for their own good
and they don't understand
what they're choosing?
That's why we take the time
to explain it to them.
Look, when I treated people
in underserved communities,
I didn't have the
luxury of time.
I did what I had to do
to save my patient's life.
Yeah, but you're not out
there anymore, are you?
- You're at Chastain.
- Yeah, and maybe
you've been in
here way too long.
Are you sure you were
a medic in Afghanistan?
Oh, I know who I am.
Question is who are you?
I've been summoned.
Must be important.
Dad, what's going on?
I'm leaving Chastain.
Leaving?
Why? Was there a
shake-up on the board?
No. I resigned.
I came here to
rebuild our relationship
and we've done that.
Yeah, we just got
to a great place.
I know.
And, as a result
of your influence,
I've come to realize
that I want to use
my vast resources
to change the medical
industry for the better.
But you can do that here.
There's still work to be done.
But there's even more
in the device industry.
I'm considering
- righting the QuoVadis ship.
- What?
- Why?
- I am putting that plan
- together as we speak.
- Dad...
I think you are
making a huge mistake.
We should discuss
this over dinner.
It's important to me
that you're on board.
Fine.
Oh, thanks for being here.
I know you have
got a lot on your plate
and more important things to do.
Nothing's more
important than you.
Listen, I'm s-sorry,
I-I just got to ask.
"F.O.W."?
If you don't tell me, it's just
gonna keep me up all night.
Brett knows I write my
dance card in pencil.
He was asking if you were
my current "flavor of the week."
As an ex-husband,
I find it interesting
that Brett cares.
He wants me to be happy.
And in his mind, happiness
includes finding someone
to share my life with.
Which is sweet,
considering I broke his heart
into a million pieces.
I was dedicated to
my career, wanted out.
Didn't have it in me
to end our marriage,
so I gave him a
reason to divorce me.
I cheated on him.
I s-sometimes wonder if I...
should have fought harder to
have a marriage and a career.
One of them would have suffered.
Yeah, see, people
like you and me...
We believe that.
And here we are.
Alone.
Well, it seems appropriate
that we're both here
- in the ruins of QuoVadis.
- How so?
The information that you
gave my investigator...
That QuoVadis made
their devices in China...
Started the chain of
events that led to this.
Thank you for convincing
me to come forward.
- Hmm.
- And for not telling anyone
where I was. What
was the final nail
in the QuoVadis coffin?
It was a study.
Called "SEVER."
20 people were implanted
with a VNS device
and 15 of them died.
Oh, my God.
But my experience here
has shown me that we need
medical device companies
that care about their patients.
So I'm thinking...
about buying, rebranding
and retooling QuoVadis.
Okay.
Uh, but why am I here?
Because I was moved by
your speech at the M&M.
See, I bet on people.
And not the letters
after their name.
I wish I could
share your vision,
but I don't know what
I believe in anymore.
Yes, you do.
You believe that the industry
needs to be changed.
Gordon used
words just like that.
- Yeah, that's not me.
- That remains to be seen.
I have to do my homework on
you before I give you an answer.
Very well.
You'll let me know
what you decide.
Administer the anesthesia.
He's having a
hypertensive crisis.
Despite the meds
we've given him.
Systolic pressure's at
250. If we don't stabilize
- his BP...
- He'll bleed out and die
before we make a single cut.
Phentolamine, now.
This is a temporary fix.
We can't go forward until we
get his hypertension under control.
Till then, we need
to abort the surgery.
She still in there? How
long you think it's gonna be?
Well, these things
can take a while, so,
- if there's somewhere else
you need to be, just go.
- Ouch.
Nic, what's the problem?
Why are you here, Kyle?
I thought you could use
an extra hand with Jessie.
An extra hand? Seriously?
I was going to Jessie's
parent-teacher conferences
when I was 16.
Where were you when I
had to bail her out of jail
on my prom night, or
when she OD'd last year?
Or the year before that?
- Ah, sweetheart, how'd it go?
- Fine. You know.
They won't have the
results till tomorrow.
So, um, see you at home?
Yeah, yeah. Call
if there's anything.
Oh, we'll be fine.
I got this guy to wait
on me hand and foot.
- Yeah, you do.
- We'll make dinner.
- Love you.
I'm thinking lobster thermidor.
I bet you are.
I was a jerk. You were
sweet, and it's not who I am.
Not that that's an
excuse, but can I come in?
We should have started
with this conversation
and not, you know, sex.
But it happened, and
we can't take it back.
- Would you?
- No.
No. That's-that's not the point.
The point is you
were great and kind.
I want to take
you out for dinner.
My treat.
A thank you for
taking care of Bailey.
And time for us to
talk about everything.
You, me, what the hell
we're gonna do with our lives.
Mostly mine.
- Before you say no...
- I wasn't gonna say no.
Good.
How long do you think
he'll be staying with you?
You know Kyle. When
things get tough, he'll bail.
Not too long ago, the same
could have been said about me.
Well, you wanted to
change. He doesn't.
Anyway, enough about my dad.
What about yours?
I heard rumors.
They're true.
He's leaving Chastain
to pursue a new passion.
I don't know. I should be happy.
But part of me
just feels like...
Like he's leaving you again.
Yeah.
I need help!
Valerie, what's going on?
I'm scared. I don't
know what's going on.
She has hemoptysis.
She needs a CT now.
There's a sharp
pain in my stomach.
Add an abdomen pelvis sequence.
Valerie doesn't have a uterus.
Incredible. What's going on?
Her ovaries aren't cystic,
and there's no torsion.
What if they're masses?
They are smaller.
Inflammation caused by
cancer could explain the DVT
and the abdominal pain.
We need to schedule a biopsy.
These are cancerous cells.
Well, that explains the
pelvic pain and DVT.
Wait, I see sertoli cells.
Seminiferous tubules.
Are you saying our female
gymnast has testicular cancer?
Did you get sneaky
and go behind my back?
I was supposed to pay for
dinner. That was the deal.
Okay, the chef remembered me
from the ER on Valentine's Day.
I saved his pinky, which meant
he could cook
dinner for his wife.
He insisted on
covering our meal.
That's romantic-adjacent.
Pretty impressive.
Hey, can I ask you
about your wedding?
I've been secretly
hoping I wasn't the reason
it all blew up.
You know, if I was..
Truly in love with Priya,
I wouldn't have
had feelings for you.
Now, what I don't know is...
I did and I do
have feelings for you.
And now you're back.
With a job offer from
Marshall Winthrop.
I don't know if
I should take it.
To be honest, it
scares me a little.
Wait, that's a good thing.
If it doesn't scare you, it's
probably not worth doing.
It's our job as parents
to push our kids.
You tell your husband
to get on the train,
- but let you drive.
- Oh, yeah.
Oh, I'm so sorry.
You came to see Mr. Winthrop,
and I talked your ear off.
Oh, that's okay.
Is-is he available?
Uh, well, you don't
have an appointment,
and he has a board
meeting soon, so...
Well, good news is I
have another appointment
and a board meeting myself,
so I'll just be five minutes.
Not to mention my
daughter is dating his son.
Mr. Winthrop, I put Mr. Nevin
- on the schedule
for a quick hello.
- Hey, there.
Kyle Nevin. Nic's father.
It's great to finally meet you.
A pleasure.
Your daughter is the best thing
that's ever happened to my son.
Well, what, uh,
what brings you by?
Marshall...
yeah, I've spent
my entire career
building a brand
with little regard
for anyone other than myself.
It's always been
about me. My legacy.
Now I find myself
wanting to give back.
So I'm on the cusp of
revolutionizing the way
doctors communicate
with their patients.
It's a very personal
venture for me.
I'd like to keep
it in the family.
So, I'd love to
explore a partnership...
if you're interested.
Unfortunately, I'm not looking
for new business opportunities.
But I wish you the best of luck.
Ah.
Okay.
Thank you.
Thank you for your time.
Hey, you know where to find me.
We got to figure out
Brett's hypertension pronto.
We had to put him into a
medically-induced coma.
Well, you just rescanned him.
Tell me you learned something.
A mass in his right adrenal.
I think it's a pheochromocytoma.
I mean, it produces hormones
that spike blood pressure.
We paged the lab
to add on plasma
and urine
metanephrines to confirm.
How bad is this?
Well, it's-it's bad.
Look at that. The
aneurysm is dissecting
and blocking flow
to the kidneys,
so if we don't operate,
we risk organ failure
and possibly death.
If they operate on Brett
with an uncontrolled pheo,
he could have a
hypertensive crisis,
leading to a stroke,
a brain bleed or...
rupture of his aneurysm.
This is an impossible choice.
And it's-it's one we
don't get to make.
This is up to his
power of attorney.
Did he list one on his intake?
He did.
You.
My ovaries are
actually testicles?
That never descended.
It's a genetic condition
known as androgen
insensitivity syndrome.
The disorder prevented your
male DNA from processing
testosterone in utero.
And because you could
only process estrogen,
you were born with external
female characteristics.
- But now one of those
testicles has cancer. Yes.
But the good news is
the cancer didn't get far.
Once we remove your testes,
you have a high
chance of full recovery.
And knowing you, cancer's
the underdog in this fight.
What does this all make me?
- Who am I?
- The same person
you've always been.
Did the testosterone
give me an edge?
Then the Olympic committee
could deem me ineligible.
I just traded one
obstacle for another.
Look, we've only been
together a couple days,
all right? But game
recognizes game.
You're like me. You
break down doors.
When one closes, we
climb through windows.
Windows won't open, we
barrel through the ceiling.
We chew up obstacles and
find a way to move forward
no matter what.
None of that changes,
unless you let it.
So what's it gonna be, Valerie?
Let's remove these bad boys.
I have the
Olympics to train for.
What man puts his
life into the hands
of the woman who
broke his heart?
A man capable of forgiveness.
I guess that's true.
I don't know why
he's forgiven me.
What am I supposed
to do, Randolph?
There is no logical choice.
Well, you know, sometimes
logic just goes out the window,
and you have to
trust your instincts.
I know Brett
wouldn't want to wait.
Send him to the OR.
Okay.
Micah, hi.
Wow. I'd nearly given up on you.
I've been considering
your proposal.
We need to talk.
I know.
I assume you have your answer?
Well, your record appears
to be different from the man
you say you are today.
I don't take gambles on men
I don't know. Not anymore.
Well, I'm sorry you
won't be working for me.
That doesn't mean I
won't take your money.
I want to start a nonprofit
that will hold device companies
like QuoVadis and
the FDA accountable.
Something that will become
a solution to this epidemic.
I knew I was right about you.
Hey, w-what's going on?
Why do I need to be in the ER?
Your potassium
levels are elevated.
Okay, well, what does that
mean? Am I gonna be okay?
Um, we just need to try
to normalize your levels.
- Okay.
- Here, why don't you
lie down here.
Hang a liter and let's get
her up on the monitors.
I need to talk to
Kyle for a second.
You pitched your
thing to Marshall.
You used my name and
put my boyfriend's father
in the position to have
to reject your offer.
I mean, do you see how
weird this is for everybody?
- He struck up a conversation.
- You orchestrated this.
- That's why you're at Chastain.
- Don't you do this.
- I am here for Jessie.
- You called me weeks
before Jessie
needed to leave rehab.
You knew that Conrad's father
was chairman of the board,
and when I didn't
return your call,
you just found another way in.
It doesn't mean
I'm not here for her.
Okay, yes, look...
I know I crossed a line.
But I'm telling you,
if this app takes off...
we'll never have to
worry about money again.
I did this for the two of you.
I can't...
It could be my legacy.
You think this app
is gonna change your legacy?
Growing up, our school
didn't have your number
for emergencies, they
had our neighbor's.
Even the nurse
knew that our father
couldn't be trusted to be there.
There isn't one person who
relies on you in a time of need.
That is your legacy.
Look, Jessie needs
stability, okay?
If that's not you, just leave.
Nic...
this time I'm here.
For her, for you.
You're just gonna have to
give me a shot to prove it.
- You mind if I join you?
- Oh, I prefer it.
There aren't enough
bones in this surgery.
I'm bound to get
lost in the weeds.
Well, I can walk you
through it if that's helpful.
It is. And thanks again
for being here for me.
Well, Brett's under, his blood
pressure seems to be holding.
So we're already
off to a great start.
You know what's even
more helpful? Honesty.
Don't sugarcoat this.
Walk me through
it like a surgeon.
So, by manipulating
the pheo, it could release
even more "catecholamine"
hormones into his body,
causing a hypertensive crisis,
resulting in a
stroke or rupture.
That's more like it. Thank you.
Now what's Dr. Austin doing?
He's trying to get
control of the distal
and proximal abdominal
aorta, and this way,
if the aneurysm ruptures, he
can clamp it off immediately
so Brett doesn't bleed out.
Gerald Forceps and
vessel loops for the iliacs.
Right angle to Mina.
Chu, I need you to
max out those drips.
We maxed out two minutes ago.
- Austin, do you have control yet?
- If he can't get control?
He will. These are our
most talented surgeons.
U-Uh, guys, I think
he's gonna stroke out.
- We need to abort. If we
abort now, we'll never get
another shot at this.
It's now or never.
Dr. Austin.
Dr. Okafor.
Aortic clamp.
We now have proximal
and distal control.
I am ready to open
up that aneurysm sac.
Potts Scissors to me.
Nolan, your days of
being a wallflower are over.
Come join the party, brother.
Aortic graft is going in.
BP's normalizing.
Brett's almost there.
God, the nonprofit
sounds awesome, Julian.
And you got Marshall on board?
- Impressive.
- You should know
that a teeny, tiny part
of what you said was helpful.
Oh, yeah?
Which teeny, tiny part?
"If it doesn't scare
you, it isn't worth doing."
I lost my life once as a
dancer and then in a job
that I settled for.
What scares me is living
a life without meaning.
It is inspiring to watch
you dedicate yourself
to moving the
needle in health care.
- And I know you will.
- I'll have to devote everything
to making this project
work, which means
leaving Atlanta and
traveling the world.
I understand.
Now is not our time.
Well, eventually,
I'll have my sea legs.
You'll have your research year.
- And who knows what'll happen?
- True.
And we still have tonight.
And I want to
make the most of it.
So we got Valerie all
set up for her surgery.
A hundred says she
wins a gold medal.
I'll put a grand on seeing her
face on a box of cereal one day.
Ooh. High roller.
No dice.
She's sharp, you're
probably right.
So, listen, about
our disagreement...
Look...
we're just two doctors who
do things differently, right?
Which means we probably
shouldn't work together again.
But if you ever
want to grab a beer...
Yeah.
I know where to find you.
How's Jessie?
Well, we stabilized her,
but her kidneys are failing.
Is the damage reversible?
We don't know yet. There
are still more tests to be done.
Sorry to interrupt.
Conrad.
Kyle.
I was talking to
Jessie. Do you think
her kidney damage is
related to her opioid use?
No. It's most likely
experimental meds she was given
during a drug trial.
Well, I-I know we're
gonna get through this.
The Nevins will do whatever it
takes to help one of their own.
That is, if I'm welcome.
Let's go see her together.
You've died and
gone to hell, darling.
You'll be in critical
condition for the next week
and in physical therapy
for at least six months.
But I'll guide you
through both...
if that's okay with you.
♪ ♪
I care about you, Micah.
More than I ever
thought I could for anyone.
Really? Because I haven't
heard from you in weeks.
Well, I was weighing the
pros and cons of your proposal.
I... I don't like to
make decisions
- based solely on emotions.
- Look, maybe we should just...
But yes.
Yes, I...
will marry you.
♪ You should be with
him, I can't compete... ♪
I love you.
You know that. But Mina,
I need to be with someone
who loves me on the same level.
- I-I do love you.
- I know.
But these past few weeks
have made it very clear.
We're not supposed
to be together.
I'm sorry.
♪ When you got to run ♪
♪ Just hear my voice in you ♪
♪ My voice in you ♪
♪ Shutting me out of you ♪
♪ Shutting me out of you... ♪
I should let you pack.
I should let you sleep.
You have an early shift.
Somehow...
work is not on my mind.
Yeah. Suitcases, neither.
I have an idea that'll
get us out of bed.
One last dance.
I love that idea.
♪ Night around you ♪
♪ Is what night becomes ♪
♪ Lake becomes an ocean... ♪
Well, look at you.
A left foot and a right foot.
Just wait till you
see me next time.
I'll have hips, too.
♪ Please don't ♪
♪ Please don't
make a fool of me ♪
♪ Please don't make... ♪
If you feel like you've
found your next calling,
then I'm happy for you.
Well, thank you,
but I want to do our exit
differently than last time.
Last time, I would've
ushered you right out the door.
Now...
I'm considering
locking you inside.
Son, I-I'm leaving town,
I'm not leaving your life.
I want to see you often.
And I'll be making
many trips to Atlanta.
You know what?
Why wait for that?
Maybe we finally take
that trip to Anguilla.
And you would actually go?
Dad, I told you things
have changed between us.
I'll send you a few dates,
we'll put it in the books.
I'd love that.
Hey, Nic.
Look, I don't mean
to add to your stress,
but we can't just keep
avoiding each other.
Right? I mean, my feelings
aren't just gonna change.
Alec...
Conrad and I have fought long
and hard for our relationship,
and we've been through it.
But I love him.
But if you and Conrad
weren't together?
Look, right now, the work
we're doing at the clinic
should be our only focus.
Let's not complicate things.
Captioned by Media
Access Group at WGBH