So, he's just back? Mmm.
For good? Yeah.
Okay, that face
that you're making,
I don't know you well enough
to know what that means.
You know those very happy,
cheerful people who have everything
and when the fact that they
have everything comes up,
they act very humble, and
they say, "I'm just so blessed."
Those people, you want to
punch those people in the face.
Yes. I do know those people.
Yeah, I'm one of those
people now. Okay.
This morning, I was standing
on my porch of my perfect house
looking in the window at
my amazing, perfect children
and my amazing,
gorgeous husband,
on the way to my amazing job.
And I thought to myself, "I
have everything I've ever wanted.
"I am just so blessed."
I really want to pummel
your face in right now.
Right, I would beat myself up.
Except I'm too tired from...
Were you about to say
that you're so exhausted
from all the great
sex you're having?
I am just so blessed.
I'm gonna walk
away from you now.
Picture the life you
dreamed of living,
the person you
pictured being with.
Picture the job you
dreamed you'd have.
I'm a surgeon
here at Grey Sloan,
but I like to think of
myself first as a teacher.
I train young doctors
to become surgeons.
Are you living the life you
envisioned for yourself?
Are you who you wanted to be...
Okay, guys, let's get
a picture. Come on.
Everybody, eyes over
there. One, two, three.
Cheese!
When you grew up?
I have some loose ends in DC,
so I'll be flying back
and forth for a few weeks.
Tie them up, hand them off,
and then I'll be here for good.
And you want to
come back full-time?
That's the plan. This is great.
Mmm-hmm.
Uh, you realize all this
has to be approved?
By whom? I'm on the
board. I have privileges.
By Amelia.
Of course. I'll ask Amelia.
I am the head of the
department of neurosurgery,
and that means I
operate on brains.
Cool! Awesome!
It's very cool, actually,
because I fix the big,
squishy, slimy computer
that runs your whole body.
If the brain goes,
everything goes.
It is the coolest.
And, uh, this is
Dr. Derek Shepherd,
and he's a member
of our board and, um...
I'm her brother.
I'm also a neurosurgeon.
I work for her.
Your sister is your boss?
My sister is my boss.
Okay, kids, uh,
let's keep it moving.
- Uh, thank you, doctors.
- Mmm-hmm. Mmm-hmm.
Oh, sweet!
How hard was
that for you to say?
Rolls off the tongue.
It's not gonna be
like it was before.
I'm not gonna
angle for your job.
I'm not gonna steal your
patients. I just want to work.
You say that now,
but I know you, Derek.
I know us.
You grew up bossing me around.
I don't know that this can work.
Give me a chance,
and I will show you.
I don't have anything
for you today.
I'm clipping an aneurysm later.
I will let you know.
You're not gonna
make this fun, are you?
It's a lot of fun for me.
No, no, no.
Ew. Super no.
Wait, no, he's cute, I think.
You're going so fast.
He's 32 and wearing a
high-school letterman jacket.
Your glory days are
over, Steve. Give it up.
You are so quick to judge.
It's a skill.
You spend enough
time on this thing,
you can learn everything you
need to know from the first picture.
Will. Cares too much
about his cars. Hmm.
Mike. Too close with those cats.
Theo needs to
learn to wear a shirt.
Okay, okay, Theo is a no-go,
but maybe your
pickiness is keeping you
from going on any real dates.
You need to expand
your horizons.
Ugh.
My horizons haven't been
expanded in a very long time.
Ugh! Gross! I
mean, yes, but gross.
So, I am a plastic surgeon.
I also operate on the
ear, nose, and throat.
This is Dr. Warren. He is
a terrific surgical resident.
And together, we
form the Plastics Posse.
Well, he calls us
that, but I do not.
It's what we're called. It's,
you know, what they call us.
No, see, they don't think
it's cool because it's not.
Well, it's not for
them, Ben. Hmm.
It's for us, okay?
All right, kids, let's
go check out the ER.
All right. Let's go.
Making medicine cool.
Huh? Not familiar with
the high-five. All right.
So, I have a
teleconference all day,
so you can hold
down the fort for me?
But I'm not on
your service today.
You're always on my service.
At least in spirit.
Can I hear it? Once?
You want to say it?
No.
No? Thinking about it? No.
Plastics Posse.
Uh, excuse me. Yeah?
I lost track of my
kids and I... Your kids?
Ten of them, fifth
graders, varying heights.
Oh, the field trip. Yeah.
I went to the restroom, and I
came out, and they'd vanished, so I...
You're a terrible chaperone
is what you're saying.
That's what it looks like, yeah.
I think they're with Dr. Webber
in the emergency room.
You don't, uh, happen to
know where that is, do you?
I do. Follow me.
Okay. Thank you.
A trauma is any kind of injury.
So, if you cut yourself or you
break your leg skateboarding
or wreck your bike, all of
those injuries are called traumas,
and that's what we
are set up here to treat.
Now, for a lot of people,
the emergency room can
be kind of a scary place,
but it's actually...
Cool!
Cool! BOY: A police car!
The police! DAN: I need
some help over here!
Right here, right
here, set him down.
Kids, let's move.
We got two guys down. We
couldn't wait for the medics.
Okay, I need a gurney.
Trauma room is in there.
Let's back up.
Page Grey, Torres.
Let's get Cardio in here.
Brett, they got you now, buddy.
All right, you just relax. You
let them take care of you, okay?
It's okay. Okay, let's go.
Just stick against the wall
and let the doctors through.
To the side.
Where are they going?
Is that policeman gonna die?
All right, everyone stay calm.
Everything's okay, all right?
What's going on?
Multiple gunshot wounds
from a robbery still in progress.
Sounds like a bloodbath. Whoa!
Hi, kids. Sorry.
Uh, I should probably
go with them, right?
Did you get paged?
No. Then no.
We should just take the
kids back to the school.
No, we can't. I can't
reach the bus driver,
and he's not due back till 3:00.
Is there someplace
that we can...
Dr. Webber, you coming?
Yeah, I'll be right there.
Um, kids, let's
go see the babies.
It's nice and peaceful up there.
- Excuse me.
Dr. Edwards will take you.
I will? Yeah, it'll be fine.
Make medicine fun.
Educate, entertain, inspire.
And keep them away
from the scary stuff.
It was a bank robbery.
Three suspects held up
the bank tellers at gunpoint.
Brett and I moved in first,
but as soon as they
saw us, they panicked.
They just started firing, hit me
right through the side of my vest.
Pete, try not to move
your neck, okay?
What are we looking at?
Two gunshot wounds to
the upper left chest cavity.
At least three bullet
holes in his left abdomen.
I'm gonna need access. Here,
I'm gonna start a subclavian line.
Have they brought Brett in yet?
He's being worked
on right next door.
Is he okay?
He took the brunt of it. DAN:
Two of them were armed.
Brett took one of them down,
then he grabbed the other one.
He ended the thing,
even after he was hit.
He's the only reason I'm
standing here right now.
Brett saved it.
Blood's filling his chest
cavity. He'll need bilateral tubes.
Betadine.
Then take him up right
now and start an ex-lap.
Pete, we're gonna
cut into your chest
to place a tube that
will help you breathe.
Even with the pain meds,
it's gonna hurt like hell,
but it's the only way.
All right, C-spine's clear.
I'll get out of your way.
Oh. Whoa!
Uh, hey, you're
bleeding quite a bit there.
I'm fine.
No, you got shot in the leg.
Come on. Let's
get you into a bed.
I need a nurse in here.
I'm right outside,
Pete, all right?
Mmm.
Dr. Hunt, the officer's
mother is here.
Richard, can you?
Yeah, go ahead. We got it.
Pete, you ready?
They said I should
speak to a doctor.
Mrs. Gibson, your son sustained
multiple gunshot wounds.
We're assessing
his injuries now,
and I will update you as
soon as we know more.
Which one?
I'm sorry?
Which one of my
sons? They're both here.
The GSW to the neck
definitely hit the trachea.
And he's got one to the abdomen.
Brett, do not try
to talk. We got you.
I need to crike him
before he loses his airway.
Okay, do it quickly. I
got to get him upstairs
and examine these
abdominal injuries.
OR Two is ready for us whenever
he's stable enough to transport.
Guys, these two
cops are brothers,
and Pete's injuries
are pretty severe.
So let's not let their mother
lose two sons in one day.
Move, please!
Make way, guys.
Doctor coming through.
Excuse me. Excuse
me! Excuse me, guys.
Move, please.
Um, do you think you could
maybe relocate your guys?
I could try, but
they'll never listen.
Is there any update on Brett?
Um, it is too early to say,
but he's in good hands.
All right, now this looks
like a through-and-through.
Whoa!
You're missing a
chunk of muscle,
and you have exposed
bone fragments.
Wow. What?
Uh, no, I just can't
believe what I'm looking at.
That bad, huh? No, no, no.
I just mean I can't believe that
you carried your guy in on this leg.
I didn't have a choice.
No, of course you didn't.
And you know what?
You can tell your guys they
can be wherever they need to.
I'm Dan Pruitt.
Dr. Callie Torres.
There he is!
Coming through!
Is that another gunshot victim?
Oh, hey, hey, hey. No, no, no.
Easy. You got to stay off this leg.
Multiple GSWs to the
right abdomen and chest.
Okay, Trauma Three.
Get him intubated,
put in a central line,
and send a trauma panel. Move!
Is he alive? He's alive, right?
Do you know him?
He's one of the suspects.
He was sitting in the car while
the others were in the bank.
I want to know how he turns out.
Hey, guys, do you see
that one in the back?
Yeah, that's one of mine.
I operated on him
before he was even born.
Now he's two hours
old and cute as a button.
A healthy little Pop-Tart.
Pop-Tart?
Yeah, a fetus that's popped.
A baby that's born
from his mother's womb.
You just ruined
Pop-Tarts for me.
Yes? What's a womb?
Oh, boy.
Um...
You're tanking at this.
I don't understand why 'cause
I'm usually really good with kids.
- I have a question.
- Go ahead.
Is that policeman going to die?
He was shot in the throat.
That's why he was
gurgling blood like that.
And that means he can't breathe,
so isn't he going to die?
How we doing, Pete?
Thinking of going for a run.
This one, always the wise guy.
Does this remind you
of that trip to the ER
when I got hit by the pitch?
You didn't even try
to get out of the way.
Nothing changes, right?
I got to learn to duck.
Mom? Yes?
Remember that potluck
we did a couple years ago?
With all the guys in your
backyard? Mmm-hmm.
When we get out of here,
we got to do that again, okay?
But bigger, more people.
We'll invite these
doctors. Everybody loved it.
Okay. Sure, honey.
We were gonna make it
an annual thing, remember?
We never did.
We got to do that...
Pete?
Peter!
We're gonna take good
care of your boy, ma'am.
We need Pierce back in here!
They've got him, Mrs.
Gibson. Pete's a tough kid.
What are you doing?
There's a trauma.
I didn't page you.
Amelia, I'm here to
help you. Let me help.
You're the boss. I'll
do whatever you need.
You want to help?
Take my aneurysm.
OR Four. Go clip it.
And there it is. That pause.
The one that means, "I don't
want the boring aneurysm.
"I want the big,
exciting neuro trauma."
You don't do second place.
I do now. I'm
clipping an aneurysm.
We have an audience
out there. I know.
Starting cardiac massage.
Hang another unit of
blood on the rapid infuser.
Right away.
Come on.
Come on, Pete.
Give me something.
Give me anything.
I have a heartbeat.
Got a pulse. There he is.
What's the story?
Traumatic arrest.
Down for 14 minutes.
Pupils are fixed.
No.
We lost him?
No corneal reflex, either.
I'll do a formal
exam in six hours,
but someone needs
to prepare the family.
He's most likely
brain dead. I'm sorry.
We lost him.
Pete's body is still strong,
but I'm afraid his brain
has been deprived
of oxygen for too long.
He won't wake up?
No. I'm afraid he's brain dead.
Mrs. Gibson, I am
so sorry for your loss.
And Brett?
He's still in surgery.
And he's gonna be okay?
He's stable now.
We're taking care of
him as best we can.
Who would do this to them?
Okay, blood in the
abdomen. Possible liver injury.
Turn him on three.
One, two, three.
No visible wounds on his back.
Looks like a bullet's
lodged near his spine.
Page Neuro! Tell them
to meet us in the OR.
Bailey, there's a cop
asking about this...
Oh, my God, how old is he, 15?
Too young to be
playing with guns.
This kid was really
shooting at cops?
But he's the driver,
according to the police.
Alleged driver.
Can I tell him anything?
Tell him he's
still alive, for now.
Notify OR Six we're on our
way up with an emergency ex-lap.
Right away.
Whoa!
Awesome!
What did I tell you?
Pretty cool, right?
Questions? Me! Me! Me! I do!
Mmm.
I got a marble stuck
in my nose once.
That's not a question.
Gross.
Are you sure this is okay?
Yeah, it's totally fine.
We got the nail out. "We"?
You pulled that nail
out of a guy's head?
I did.
Wow. So, you're
kind of a badass, huh?
I am. ALEX: Okay, next slide.
And this is a coffee
can in a man's abdomen.
Cool! That's disgusting.
Okay, now that is...
That's definitely
not appropriate.
It's totally fine. We
got the can out, too.
Sure, yeah.
But they're gonna
ask how it got in there.
Okay, guys, bus is
here. Let's roll out.
What is that?
It's a coffee can.
All right. Let's go,
guys. Come on.
Dang, just when we
were starting to have fun.
Bye! Bye.
Hey.
Hey. I thought Amelia...
Uh, I was looking for
the other Dr. Shepherd.
She's busy with a trauma. Ah.
Did you talk to her?
I did. And?
I'm clipping an
aneurysm for her.
Huh.
And you're good with that?
What do you mean?
Well, it's a far cry from mapping
the brain for the president.
She's been talking to you.
A bit.
I'm good with it. Actually,
I'm a little nervous.
You sure you
want to tell me that?
No, I mean, it's a good
nervous, a good, excited.
I just haven't operated
in months, and...
It feels really good to be back.
Well, I'm glad to have you back.
Hey, Hunt. We
should hang out more.
Do you fish?
Never. Never have.
You should. We will.
Okay.
All right. Okay.
The bullet's nicked the bone,
but there's no cord damage.
I'd say leave it. Your call.
This liver's in bad shape.
It's actually avulsed.
The blood supply's
completely gone.
A kid this young
helps commit robbery?
He's not much older than Tuck.
Aw, damn it.
No, there's no
saving this liver.
He's gonna need a
transplant and fast.
Wow. So, someone
doesn't get a liver
because this shooter gets one?
He won't survive without one.
And we don't know if this
boy even had a gun on him.
Please. If he
didn't shoot a cop,
he was an accessory
to someone who did.
He'll be tried as an
adult. Hey, he's a patient.
We don't pay attention
to the backstory.
We don't know
anything about him.
We know we lost a cop today.
And we know he chose
to help his friends hold
people up at gunpoint.
You do that, you pretty
much get the hand you're dealt.
Pack him and
aggressively resuscitate.
Then leave him here
with a scrub nurse.
And you go find his
family. I'll call UNOS.
All right. First things first.
I checked on your partner,
Brett. He's still in surgery.
Minimal internal injury.
They're still working
on the trachea repair,
but it didn't hit any of
the major blood vessels,
which is really great news.
Thank you. That's... Thanks.
Now you.
You aren't going to
need surgery, just a splint,
but it does mean that
you'll need to stay off of it
for at least six
weeks, maybe eight.
You think that means
one week, I can tell.
But it means six.
At least, okay?
After today, you know,
I think I might want to
ride a desk for a while.
After 14 years on the
force, this is the first time
I ever had to fire
my weapon on duty.
First time we were fired at.
Wow.
Well, it sounds like it was a
good run. I'm sorry it ended.
Thank you.
Any word on the kid?
Uh, no. Still in the OR. Okay.
I just need something
good to come out of this day.
Abdominal injuries
are under control.
I'm ready to close. You
about done, Kepner?
Almost. Then I'll
let Wilson close.
Thank you, Dr. Kepner.
Okay, update me
when you're done.
He's de-satting. What is it?
Uh, it's not me. Field is
clear. There's no bleeders.
Nothing here. Tube's
intact. No leaks.
Check his pupils.
No response.
Oh, damn it. Damn
it, damn it, Brett.
Did he throw a clot?
We won't know until
we get him up to CT.
Page Neuro, ask them
to meet us post-op.
Right away. We had him.
We had him.
I'm so sorry, Mrs.
Gibson. Brett's gone.
I knew this could happen.
I'm afraid Brett suffered a
large stroke during surgery.
Unfortunately,
it's not uncommon.
In this case, the
damage was very severe,
and it resulted in brain death.
Mrs. Gibson, there was
nothing anyone could do.
But his hand is
still warm in mine.
His heart's beating.
I can see his breath.
I woke up this morning the
mother of two perfect children.
Happy, proud. And now...
I just don't understand.
Very sorry, Mrs. Gibson.
Oh, God.
Hey, how's he doing?
Pressure's dropping, and
he's oozing from his drains.
Well, UNOS didn't
have anything available.
Neither did any of the
hospitals here or in Oregon.
Did you track down his family?
Oh, he's in the system.
His latest foster
parents haven't seen him
since the night he came
to stay with them, though,
so, they're not exactly
racing down here.
So he's alone? He's just
gonna die here, alone.
How much time do we have?
Well, without a
liver, he's got hours.
Ben, stay with him.
Keep his SBP above 100.
Where you going?
Well, I just can't
go to sleep tonight
knowing I didn't try
absolutely everything.
God, I mean, how
did this happen?
This day started out so great.
"Blessed," I think you said.
Now I have to go ask the
mom for her son's organs.
That sucks. But is
this how it has to be?
If I'm that happy, someone
else has to be that unhappy?
I mean, this poor cops'
mom lost two sons today.
What? Two sons?
Stroke. On the table.
Oh, God!
Uh, ugh.
Okay, you have to tell
their commanding officer.
He's been asking
for good news all day.
Sure, I'll go talk to him as soon
as I'm done asking the mom
if we can cut up her
hero sons for body parts.
Which, what time is it?
Those organs will
be dead soon, too.
Also, the commanding
officer keeps asking
about the kid they brought in.
I think it's 'cause he just
wants to hear that he's dead.
Can you blame him?
Uh...
I showed a bunch of school kids
that x-ray of a coffee can
stuck up some guy's butt.
Riveting. Alex.
Read the room, man.
I was just trying
to cheer you up.
Oh, Grey, um, is your
patient an organ donor?
I'm about to go ask her now.
Oh, when? Now? 'Cause,
you know, there's a window.
I know, Bailey. I know.
And I have a 15-year-old
boy open in the OR
who needs a liver, and
UNOS is coming up empty.
Fifteen-year-old?
You're not talking about...
I checked your patient,
and he's a perfect match.
And we can do it today
if the mother would
consider a directed donation.
Are you serious?
Okay, all I'm asking is
that you bring it up with her.
Just ask. No!
He will not survive
without a new liver.
Bailey, asking for her
sons' organs is hard enough.
Now you want me
to ask her for organs
to give to the kid
that killed her sons?
Okay, take away
the story. Right?
Take away the good
guys and the bad guys.
It's a child who needs an organ
and a patient with one to give.
Bailey, that woman
lost everything today.
I know! Okay, you
don't think I know that?
But ethically, you have to.
Ethically, I'm looking
out for the best interest
of my patient and his family.
Hey, thanks for walking us out.
You know, you
didn't have to do that.
With your sense of
direction, I kind of did.
That's...
That is absolutely true.
I know it's been a drag for you,
but I really appreciate it.
You really did make
it fun, so thank you.
Well, thank you. Where's Julie?
What? I can't find Julie.
She's not on the bus.
Have you seen her? No.
Oh. Wait, Julie
is the one who...
Who was asking about
the policeman. That Julie.
She was just right
here, wasn't she?
Julie?
Hey, don't worry.
We'll find her.
We'll find her, ma'am.
I know this is a difficult time
and it's the last thing
you'd want to think about,
but you do have a
decision to make.
Do you know if your sons
would have considered
becoming organ donors?
They were always helping
people, even as little boys.
That's why they
wanted to be policemen.
Well, Brett did.
Pete, he was always
a little mixed up.
He just followed Brett,
but then he found his way.
I think that that's
what they'd want.
I think they'd want to help.
Okay. There'll be some
paperwork to fill out.
Uh, Mrs. Gibson, it is
possible for you to designate
where you want
your son's liver to go.
Uh, specifically, I
have a young patient,
he's only 15, desperately
in need of a liver.
He's a perfect match
with your son Brett.
Oh, God. So
young. That's terrible.
And you think Brett
could help that boy?
He could. You could.
Fifteen. Mmm. What
happened to him?
Well, he was
injured in the robbery.
Wait, you're not saying...
Okay, Mrs. Gibson, I understand
it's an impossible question,
but we need to ask...
No, he murdered my boys.
You have the
audacity to walk in here
and ask me to give
him my child's body,
my child's blood,
so he can live?
No, he's not getting
anything. He can go to hell.
Grey, well, I had
to try for my...
For your patient, I know.
But now that's dozens
of transplant patients
that you just screwed
out of a chance.
What happened? My
daughter's missing.
I knew we should have
gone home immediately.
Ma'am, just try and
stay calm, okay?
Is she the kind of
kid who wanders off?
No. No. What if
someone took her?
Do you think someone took her?
Now, look, we took a
class picture this morning.
This is her. This is
what she's wearing.
I'll send this out to my guys,
and we'll track her down, okay?
Edwards, have the
paging system call for her.
You know what
the girl looks like.
Start checking the
floors, room by room.
Okay.
Julie Hamilton,
please report to...
And he's so cute and
he's incredible with the kids.
Really? Seems like he
wouldn't have lost one, then.
No, no, you should have seen him
when she actually went missing.
He stepped up and...
Well, he might be a little
young for me, though.
Well, better than too old.
And can I really date a teacher?
Why not?
He gets off work at 3:00
p.m. I get off work at 3:00 a.m.
When will we have time
to... Steph, stop. Stop!
This isn't shirtless
cat guy on the Internet.
Stop looking for reasons
not to like the nice, cute guy.
You're hot for
teacher. Let it happen.
I'm gonna let it happen.
Is there any hope?
I'm afraid not.
We'll observe them
for the next six hours,
but there's no
brain activity at all.
How's their mom?
She is going to need all
the support you can give her.
Thank you. Okay.
What about the kid? Jared?
Listen, Dan, I
know you're angry,
and I know that
you need to know,
but we can't talk about a
suspect's condition, not legally.
I'm not looking to
settle a score, okay?
I knew this kid.
Brett knew this kid.
We put him in juvie. We
got him into the foster system.
We tried.
Jared's one of those kids, you
know. He's smart. He's funny.
He's just susceptible
to bad things,
bad choices, bad kids.
Brett would have
called this his moment.
What's his moment?
He called it... He
called it the moment,
when a kid would back
themselves into a corner.
When it would
hit the fan so bad,
that there's no other
choice but to turn it around,
wind up in lockup, or dead.
Brett would say, "That's
when you can get them, Dan.
"That's when you
can turn them around."
And this would have
been it for Jared.
And Brett would have
been here to help.
So, Derek's back.
Is that a question?
No, it's just...
And I'm glad, I am,
for you and the kids,
and I don't want to
make this all about me.
It's just he says he wants
to come back and just work.
For me.
Still not sure
what you're asking.
Well, I'm asking should I
believe that? Can I believe that?
I do.
You do.
Yeah, he's different.
I don't know how to explain it,
but I think he realizes
what makes him happy,
and he's choosing it.
And that makes me happy.
I think this is his moment.
Grey, what did you call me for?
'Cause if you just want
to yell at me some more...
Nope. I think I just
got that kid his liver.
Jared is prepped and
ready, still in OR Six.
Thank you. And thank
you, Officer Gibson.
Here's your second
chance, Jared.
Okay, first kidney is out.
Julie Hamilton, Julie Hamilton,
please report to any hospital
personnel member immediately.
You see that?
Yeah...
Well, there you are.
Am I in trouble?
You know, you're not really
supposed to be up here.
I saw that man in the
ER. He was bleeding.
Yeah, the doctors worked
really hard to try to save him.
But he died. So they're
taking all his parts out?
Mmm-hmm.
He's a donor,
so his body is
gonna help save lives
of people who
need organs to live.
My grandpa had a
heart transplant once.
Will she give his
heart to someone else?
Yes, she will.
I want to do that.
Be a donor? No.
The doctor. I want to
do what she's doing.
That's my wife. See
the lead surgeon?
And right now she's making
sure that the artery to the kidney
is long enough to
attach to someone else.
How did she learn all that?
She went to school
a lot and practiced.
And she's just really great.
Yeah.
I think that's
what I want to be.
Feels good, doesn't it?
Knowing what you
want to do next.
Thank God, Julie!
Oh!
Hey, baby.
That boy's alive?
He is.
Because of my son?
That boy and the 37 others
that were in the bank today.
Thirty-seven people got to
go home to their families today
because of your sons.
Now, I would have called
that a pretty good day's work.
But, Grey...
This is a list of 100 people
who all got second chances
today because of your sons.
Now, they won't
know who to thank,
so I would like
to say thank you.
They were good boys.
Okay, here we are.
I'll just put on the brakes.
All right.
Okay, ready? One, two, three.
Oh.
Good.
All right, looks good.
Use the crutches.
I know you won't think
you need them, but do it.
It'll heal faster.
Thank you, Dr. Torres.
For everything.
Oh, I'm...
I'm so sorry about your
friends, Officer Pruitt.
Thanks.
Hey, listen, um... Yeah?
Never mind.
No, no, no. What is it?
Well, it's just that if
today weren't today,
if it was any other day,
like, you know, a regular day,
I'd ask you if you'd like
to have dinner with me.
It's like I said, you know,
I just needed something
to come out of this day right.
Um...
Well, I will need to see you
back here in, um, 10 days
for a follow-up on that leg.
Ten days?
Is that all right?
Sounds like a plan.
That is a plan.
All right. See you in 10 days.
Hmm.
Nick. Hey. Dr. Edwards.
Glad I get the chance to say
goodbye. Better make it quick, though.
I'm not letting this kid out of
my sight again. Oh, son of a...
Wait, wait, hang on.
Before you run off.
Uh...
I could be totally off base
here, but you and I maybe had...
Hmm.
Would you like to maybe
hang out sometime?
Wait, really?
Yeah, yeah, I mean,
you'd really want to?
Yeah. I would.
Um...
We could grab a
drink or something.
Oh, I can't drink. I'm...
Oh, okay. Then coffee.
Coffee's great. Yeah,
I'm all about the coffee.
Perfect. Cool.
Well, I'm free Friday night.
I can't. Friday's
the junior prom.
You chaperone
high-school events, too?
No, I go to them.
Seventeen years old?
Could you maybe
not scream it like that?
Oh, my God! I
can't... I can't breathe.
Oh!
I know I told you to expand
your horizons, but oh, my...
It was his little
sister's class.
He said he was doing this
teacher-helper-volunteer thing.
Thought it would look good
on his college applications.
I'm gonna need
many more of these.
Hey. Thanks for
doing this for me.
These two will look as
good as they possibly can
before their mother
sees them one last time.
Though it's taking a little
longer than I expected.
You okay?
Yeah.
Yeah?
Yeah. I'm fine.
This is totally something
Sloan would've done.
Really? Yeah.
You know, he really
did treat me like a son.
Passed everything on.
Got such a charge out
of it, the Plastics Posse.
It got a little goofy
sometimes... Mmm-hmm.
Honestly, but...
I want to do that.
You know, pass it on to someone,
the way he did for me.
Whatever. I don't know
if I'm making any sense.
It makes a lot of sense.
Yeah.
Whew.
It's cold out here.
It's quiet out here.
Mmm.
Ever since you've been back,
you guys have been reconnecting.
Vigorously.
You should have
built thicker walls.
You okay?
What do you mean?
I didn't want to ask you,
and I'm not supposed
to big-brother you.
And you don't need me to.
There was a robbery,
two shootings, and you
declared two men dead.
I kept thinking about Dad.
I wanted to know if you're okay.
I'm happy for you.
That you're back,
you're making it work.
That you're not running.
What do you mean, "running"?
Hey, I am not judging.
We are runners.
I ran from my engagement.
You ran from Addison.
I think, after Dad,
if something scares us,
we sprint, fast as we can.
But you turned around this time.
That's something. I'm inspired.
Open your eyes.
Take a good look around you.
Did mom tell you I
went to go see her?
No.
Wow. How did that go?
She said I was tired and
miserable, which I was.
Told me to get it together.
No sympathy. Oh, no, never.
She said, "Derek, take a
good, hard look at your life.
"If it's not working,
shut up and fix it."
How's the view?
Do you like what you see?
Amy, I've been missing
out on everything in my life.
I mean, I'm watching my
kids grow up on a computer.
I don't want to miss my family.
I don't want to miss
another second.
I want to coach soccer,
go to ballet recitals.
I don't need to
change the world.
Clipping aneurysms,
stopping bleeds,
that's the fun.
That's changing the
world with our hands.
Think back again to
when you were little.
When did that stop being enough?
Saving someone's life?
Are you living the life
you pictured for yourself?
That's more than enough.
I'm glad you're back.
Me too.
I think I'm falling in
love with Owen Hunt.
And I'm really afraid
that it's gonna destroy me.
It wouldn't be
love if it didn't.
Or are you still dreaming
of something even bigger?