We doctors take
pride in the fact
that we can basically
sleep standing up...
anytime, anywhere.
Jackson.
Stop!
Stop! Hey, hey, Jackson!
- What?
- Stop. Stop. I'm sorry.
- But you need
to take something.
- Where's Charles? Charles!
Where's Charles?
Hey. Hey, hey! Stop.
It's Lexie. Wake up.
- It's time for work.
- Yeah, just about.
But it's a false pride
because the truth is...
after about 20
hours without sleep...
you might as well just come
to work drunk, doctor or not.
So it's no wonder that fatal
medical errors increase at night,
when we doctors are,
proudly, sleeping on our feet.
Recently, our communal
pride has been shattered
and our egos have been
wounded by new laws...
- Hey.
- That require - that we sleep all day
- before we work all night.
- Oh! Dr. Shepherd!
There's French toast and
coffee if you want breakfast.
- It's 6pm.
- Right. Uh... Bacon for your dinner?
Thank you, no.
We're not happy about it.
But as someone who may
one day need medical care,
you really should be.
It's Night of the
Living Dead out there.
I'm still sleeping.
A whole day happened
while you were sleeping.
Let's see, I did three
aneurysm surgeries,
I consulted on a massive
spinal tumor, that was neat.
Got the Phillips grant,
and oh, by the way,
the, uh, soup of the day in the
cafeteria was potato-leek soup.
- You got the grant?
- Yeah, I got the grant.
- You got the Alzheimer's grant?
- Yeah, I got it!
Mark is putting together
a little celebration at Joe's.
But I would much rather
celebrate here with you. Mm!
I am late for work.
Gotta love the night shift.
- Proud of you.
- Thank you.
- Nice face.
- At least I can do surgery.
- How's that hand?
- It would be better
if you hadn't run
your face into it.
So he beats the hell out of you
and now you're
laughing about it?
Eh, some of us can move on.
You're sitting on my coat.
And some of us can't.
Did you just yawn?
Was that a yawn?
Don't tell us you're tired
after getting to sleep all day.
- It's not as easy as it sounds.
- Not easy? Not...
When I was a resident, I
actually worked for a living.
I did every other
night call for five years.
There were days I didn't go
home for 72 hours. I loved it.
As you trudged through the snow
while you whittled your own scalpels.
Sorry, I didn't quite
catch that, Karev.
Uh, Karev, I need you to
follow up on my post-ops,
and here, take this research,
divide out all the fistula cases.
Avery and Little Grey, Hunt
is waiting for you in the pit.
All right. Try not to screw
up our patients. Good night.
- And good luck.
- - We'll be over at the bar.
- Try not to need us.
- Dr. Grey. Shepherd's wife.
- You're with me tonight.
- Yes.
Good. I heard you're good.
Listen, I'm late for dinner.
So, um, I made a list of
my patients, their protocols.
Basically, everybody's stable.
Just try and keep them that way.
And if I need to get
in touch with you, sir?
You won't. 'Cause you're good.
Nice to meet you.
Everybody else is stable. Watch ICU
bed 12, he may need to be intubated.
And call me if there are
any major traumas. Avery?
- How you feeling?
- What, my hand? It's fine.
- Just a little bruised.
- I'm not talking
about your hand.
Trauma demands a cool
head. If you're not up to this...
No, I'm good. Thanks. Karev
and I are cool, that's, uh... over.
- Out of my system.
- - You don't have to prove anything here.
- If you need
a couple shifts off...
- I said I'm good, sir.
All right. I'm... I'm not
asking you to talk to me.
I'm telling you,
talk to someone.
You got me?
Have a good night, sir.
There's the man of the
hour. Congratulations.
Thank you very much. Thank you.
First round is on me...
Um, guys...
- There.
- Yeah. No, try again.
You need to tilt the
glass like I said. Tilt...
- I'm tilting it!
- I know...
- Let me try again, OK?
- All right.
Why are you behind the bar?
Uh, Owen told me to
get a job. So I'm working.
What's everyone drinking?
She sat on the sofa for three
days straight watching infomercials
and eating cereal out of the box.
So yeah, I told her to get a job.
But you didn't
specify what kind?
I thought she'd go to a lab
or the morgue. I
didn't expect this.
Tell her you changed your mind.
Tell her she can be a
housewife for all you care.
I think that the only thing she'd
be worse at than bartending
- is housewife-ing.
- What's so bad
about bartending?
- She's not dancing on a pole.
- I give this one night.
And this Cristina Yang of Beverly
Hills? She does not enjoy serving people.
All right!
I call this the Early
Onset Alzheimer's.
Because you won't remember
anything after you drink it.
Mm!
To Shepherd and
his genius brain crap.
- To Shepherd!
Oh! Oh, my God, this is strong.
Ugh!
- Yeah, I'm gonna need a Scotch.
- Make it two.
- Babies.
- - Early Onset Alzheimer's?
You don't think that's
a little distasteful?
- I think it's delicious.
- Cristina...
- Um, you want a beer?
- No, I'm on call. I want to talk.
A bachelor party just
came in. Uh... We'll talk later.
- Hi!
- Yes!
Is someone getting married?
Who's getting married?
- He said, "Any major traumas."
- We are not calling Hunt.
- We don't even know
what this is yet.
- ER's swamped. We had to split
- Trauma Three,
put them both in there.
- Did you call Dr. Hunt?
- We're not calling Hunt.
- On my count. Ready, one, two, three.
- Reilly, you OK?
- Lucas? It hurts.
- It hurts really bad.
- You'll be OK, Ri. All right?
- We'll be OK.
- What've we got?
Car versus train. Two
brothers, 17 and 15,
tried to outrun the Coast
Starlight to Portland. The train won.
I know, it was stupid, it was
so stupid. I'll never do it again.
The driver was inside the car, the
other was thrown out. No seatbelt.
Dr. Avery, come
take a look at this.
Yeah.
Call Hunt.
Mrs. McNeil? I'm Dr. Grey. I'll
be taking over for Dr. Stark tonight.
Drew's in a lot of pain.
OK, well, that's not unusual
for this type of chest surgery.
Abdominal pain is not normal
after pectus excavatum surgery.
And it's been going on for two
hours. I'm a nurse at Seattle Pres.
It's OK, Drew, honey.
Mommy's right here.
His abdomen does
seem a little tender.
I'm concerned about his vitals.
And I know my son.
He's not a complainer.
Something is wrong.
- Can you please call Dr. Stark?
- I will. I'll call him right away.
You're back already? That date
wasn't even like, what, an hour?
- I need a drink.
- Careful...
Hey! That was mine! Now you
have to order me another one.
Oh, God, that's disgusting.
Right. OK. So get this.
His very first question? "So,
what's your favorite food?"
- What'd you say?
- French. But that's not the point.
Why would he ask me
what my favorite food was?
Like he read that's
some good ice-breaker
from some Internet handbook that
was handed out at the loser fair. Ugh!
This is why you don't
meet people on the Internet.
You're married. You
don't get to have an opinion
about my pathetic
forays into Internet dating.
- You do need a drink.
- Thank you.
- Go to Africa.
- What?
Arizona's an idiot.
And she's a fool,
and you need to go there
and tell her that I told you to say
that dating is evil,
and that what the two of you
have is rare and that she's an idiot!
Get on an airplane
and go to Africa
and thank God that you never
have to go on a first date again.
Yeah, I'm not going to Africa.
Well, then you're just
as big an idiot as she is.
- Oh.
- - Torres is a grown woman.
You can't make her do
something she doesn't want to do.
OK, again, Mr. Perfect
Married Guy,
you don't get to
open your mouth...
One, two...
Chug, chug, chug!
Oh, yeah! Oh, yeah!
Who's first?! Oh, groom!
What the hell did I miss?
You guys Super Glued
yourselves together on purpose?
Apparently, my son and girlfriend's
love is so great, they can't hear you.
Yes, they Super Glued their arms
and hands together on purpose.
- Uh, why would they...?
- We're moving
to Wisconsin tomorrow.
No, you're moving, Dad.
I'm staying here with Lauren.
No, you're not. You're
going to Wisconsin with me
and your mom and
the dog and the cat.
No. Not without Lauren, I'm not.
Nobody can tear us
apart, Mr. Nystrom.
I know that, Lauren,
but the doctor here
- is still gonna give it a try.
- - I wish we could glue our lips together forever.
Me, too.
I... I will figure
something out.
Thank you.
Have you ever had the
tiramisu at Gino's Trattoria?
- Excuse me?
- Tiramisu, Gino's Trattoria.
Uh, ladyfingers soaked in rum.
- No, I haven't.
- Neither have I.
Because you felt the need to
drag me away from my dinner
- to examine a kid with gas.
- Gas? I thought...
Uh, when I called you, he was in a lot
of pain and his vitals were borderline.
They're better now because I
gave him a liter bolus of IV fluids
at 20 cc's per
kilo, but his pain...
And yet, what you should have
given him was an anti-flatulent.
Abdominal pain after chest wall surgery
in a patient on narcotic pain killers
is gas or constipation
until proven otherwise.
- But Dr. Stark,
what if his pain...?
- Tiramisu.
- Avery, what do you have?
- Large gaping wound
to the abdomen.
Looks like something sliced
right through him, debris inside.
- We need to get in there.
- Book an OR!
Reilly? Reilly, talk to me!
Reilly can't talk right now, OK,
buddy? He's got a tube in his throat
- to help him breathe.
- Reilly, I'm right here! All right?
Put more pressure on that.
Lean in there. Pack it, pack it!
We were gonna be late,
so I ran it. Funny, right?
We didn't want to get
in trouble with Mom.
So I... I go back to school,
picking him up after band
practice. We're halfway home,
he forgets his stupid saxophone.
Two hundred. Clear.
- He forgets everything!
- Three hundred.
- Everything!
- Clear.
Continue compressions. Push
one of epi and one of atropine.
I know it was stupid.
The guard rails had just come
down. I thought we could make it.
It's my fault. Please.
Please. He's my little brother!
- He's... he's little...
- They're
working on him.
OK? I just need you to take
it easy. All right? Take it easy.
He's gonna be all right, right?
Time of death, 20:48.
Dr. Hunt, we need to intubate
him and get him to the OR now!
- Another Scotch?
- Yeah.
Mm...
- On the house.
- Uh, hey.
If every drink is on the house,
then eventually there'll be no house.
- Right. Uh, six dollars.
- It's actually eight dollars.
- You having fun?
- I am.
Good. That's good.
Keep it.
Thank you.
Hey, here she
comes with our shots!
Bring 'em over!
His pain is getting
worse, his color looks bad,
his vitals haven't stabilized. I've
seen gas, Dr. Grey. This isn't gas.
We have to give the
medicine a little time to work...
We gave it time to work. It didn't
work, which means this is not gas!
I've worked the night
shift. I know what goes on.
I've lived through horror stories of
patients falling through the cracks
because residents are
running around half-asleep
and their attendings
are nowhere to be found.
- I will not let
that happen to my son.
- I won't either. I promise.
And I agree that it's not
gas. So let's run some tests,
- and find out
what's going on. OK?
- Thank you.
It's gonna be OK.
To the groom!
It's rude to ditch out on
your own party, you know.
Yang is bartending. Do you
know how disturbing that is?
It's a phase. She's gonna be
fine. Besides, you won one of
the most prestigious grants out
there. This night's about you, not Yang.
Suit yourself.
How are we letting this
happen? I mean, seriously,
- how are we just OK with it?
- Oh, I'm not OK, I'm jealous.
Cristina gets to live out
the twenties we never got to
'cause we were stuck in med
school. Watch, ten years from now,
we'll all have a midlife crisis
and end up doing the same thing.
Except we'll be in our
forties and won't look as cute.
How many of those have you had?
Hey, my son is with his father.
I am 24 hours child-free.
If Cristina Yang can tend
bar 'cause she wants to,
then I can drink
'cause I want to.
- Double fisting!
- Has she mentioned me?
- What?
- I know she writes to you.
So I'm asking you if
she's mentioned me.
Well, you know,
she's been very, um...
She's, uh... She just sort of
dove right into the medicine.
And she's been... she's been busy.
And just, uh... Does that help at all?
I can't believe this. I honestly... I
can't believe that I am here again.
No, you're not doing this. You're
not going down this rabbit hole.
I have to start all over! All over!
I don't even know how to do that!
I do.
You might need a little
sexual palate cleanser.
A palate cleanser?
Are you serious?
- What? It works.
- Sexual sorbet?
I love it!
See that redhead back there?
She's been eyeing you all night.
Really?
Oh. OK, yeah. OK.
Thank you, Mark. All
right, I'm gonna, um...
- I'm gonna go for it.
- Oh, no.
Oh, oh.
Wish me luck.
All right, liver hemorrhage is
under control. Let's move on.
Uh, there's another
one. No, two.
- What is that?
- Part of the
steering column maybe?
Might have shattered
inside the abdomen.
There's an infrarenal hematoma.
We should expose
the retroperitoneum.
- Good idea.
- I'll get the aorta
- below the mesocolon.
- Slow down, Avery.
We need proximal control first.
You keep looking for
this kid's dashboard
- and I'll take care of that.
- Can I get more
light in here, please?
Dr. Hunt, his parents are here.
They're asking for an update.
- Avery?
- I'm staying.
I'd... I'd like to stay.
- Grey, tell them where we're at.
- - OK.
What are you doing in
the attendings' lounge?
- You could get in trouble.
- Pizza?
I have stupid teenage patients
who Super Glued themselves together
so their parents can't tear them apart.
- Mm! That sounds romantic.
- Yeah, more like moronic.
I have no idea how to get them
apart without taking off half their skin.
- Try acetone.
- Try going away!
- Meredith, any ideas?
- Mm... Acetone?
Thank you.
So, what's the deal with Stark?
A lazy, back-stabbing
weasel. Why?
Because I called him in
to examine this patient...
You called him in? Ha! I
wish I could've seen that.
- You don't call Stark.
- Well, my kid just
had pectus excavatum
surgery and he
was in serious pain.
Yesterday, my
fundoplication patient
was vomiting.
You don't call Stark.
Well, this kid's
mother is a nurse
- at Seattle Pres.
- Let's play a game.
There's one rule:
you don't call Stark.
Alex, I'm serious. Normally,
I would handle this myself,
but I haven't been on Peds in a while.
You know the complications with kids.
- Did you order blood work
and a CT?
- Mm-hm.
I'd add a LDH, a
CRP and a sed rate.
With Stark you have to cover all your
bases, so if you do end up calling him,
he has no excuse but to
get off his ass and come in.
Thank you.
Well, turns out she was eyeing
my new haircut, and not me.
I gave her the hairdresser's
number though, so...
Well, you tried. You
put yourself out there.
- That's what counts.
- Uh... Yeah, no.
Actually, that counts for nothing.
'Cause I put myself out there every day.
You know, I write online profiles,
and I check the boxes that say
- I like hiking and dogs...
- - Is there a box for fistulas?
'Cause that's what I want.
A guy that can talk fistulas.
I want a guy that can direct me
towards a better
scientific understanding
of just why a fistula may occur
in patients that are
healthy one minute
and die the next.
Find a man that's interested
in fistulas and pancreases,
and you'll find a man
that's not Internet dating.
What's wrong with you? You
didn't call Stark again, did you?
No, I'm not calling him
until I get my CT results,
and there's only one CT tech down
there and he's really backed up. So...
Have I mentioned that I hate
the night shift, and I hate Stark.
Hey, chief. What are
you doing here? It's late.
When a screaming mother calls
me at home to tell me my residents
are about to kill her son, time
becomes irrelevant, wouldn't you say?
Dr. Grey, are you
familiar with Mrs. McNeil?
She called you? I did
not give her your number.
She's a nurse. She worked the
system. But what concerns me
is not how she got my number,
it's why she felt the need to call me
in the first place. Now,
what the hell is going on?
I have a plan in place.
I'm just waiting for a CT,
and the guy's just very
backed up down there.
- How long
have you been waiting?
- Two hours.
- Get up.
- Excuse me?
Get on your feet.
I understand you're a
little behind schedule.
Yeah, it's just me tonight,
so we're backed up.
- Why didn't you
call the on-call tech?
- He wasn't feeling so hot.
I thought I'd cut him a break.
He does the same for me.
Listen... Hawk.
We're in the business of saving
lives. Now, I don't care if your friend
is lying in a ditch bleeding,
he will come in tonight.
Now, get him on the phone now.
Hello?
No, this is not your dude.
This is Chief Webber.
What do I need? I need you
to get yourself into this hospital
in the next five minutes or you and
your dude can kiss your jobs goodbye!
Now, that's how you
get things done at night.
I just left Lucas in
surgery. He's critical.
It's very touch-and-go at this
point, but we're still working,
and, um, we'll keep you
updated on his condition.
- Thank you.
- OK. Thanks.
- I'll let you know.
- And Reilly?
Our other son,
Reilly. How's Reilly?
Has... anyone talked to you?
No. We've been waiting.
OK. Um...
OK.
- Mr. and Mrs. Nash,
I'm, uh, afraid...
- No! No!
- I'm sorry to say that...
- - Please don't say that.
- despite our
efforts to save...
- Please don't say that!
- Reilly's life...
- No, no!
His injuries were too severe, and
he died in the emergency room.
Oh, my God!
- My baby! No, my baby!
- I'm so sorry.
No!
Oh, my God! No!
Please tell me he's gonna live.
The parents didn't
know the brother died.
Not to mention how he's
gonna feel when he finds out.
- How do you live with yourself?
- Shut up! Just shut up, please.
- Avery?
- Sorry. Sorry. I just...
This is a really tricky part
right here. There's something...
- What is this?
- More suction
and some laps in here.
- Here.
- Is that a piece
of the turn signal? Come on.
It's right next to the aorta. Can't tell
if it's just kissing it or if it's perfed.
Get me some umbilical tape and
let's pull it so we can get some control.
OK, pulling. Pulling.
- Wait, wait,
don't, don't, don't!
- Clamp.
- Give me the clamp.
- Avery, I'll do this.
Give me the clamp. Give
me the clamp. Here, take this.
- Got it.
- I've got the
bleeder right here.
Nice work.
Nice work, Avery.
So this won't sting, but as
the skin starts to separate,
- you may feel some pain.
- I feel nothing
but pain right now.
Me, too.
It's your mother, Lauren.
This is just gonna take a
few more minutes, right?
Hopefully.
Is it working?
God, I can't look.
Please. If we could just
stay together one more day...
Well, you'll definitely be
together for another hour
because this is not working.
Yes!
Ah! Dr. Bailey! Yes!
Dr. Bailey! I'm so
glad you're here!
I'm not here, you don't see me.
I just need a nap before I go
home. But first I need some food.
This will just take a second.
I got these two 15 year olds.
They Super Glued themselves together.
They're in love, or they think they are.
Anyway, I tried petroleum and
acetone to separate them, but...
- Don't separate them.
- What?
Young people need
love too, Kepner.
We all need love. If
the world had more love,
we could get rid
of wars and fistulas.
Why won't this damn
thing take my money?
Dr. Bailey, are you drunk?
Tipsy. Mm... A little tipsy.
Right. Um, I'm gonna go ahead
and take care of that for you.
- Oh...
- Mm-hm.
Hey, Dr. Altman? Are
you available for a consult?
I'm just waiting on
some CT results.
Uh, well, Joe took my keys,
so I'm pretty sure I shouldn't
be practicing medicine.
- What are you doing here then?
- I'm killing time until Joe
- gives me my keys back.
- Can't you do that at the bar?
Cristina Yang is bartending, so
no. I can't. It's just too depressing.
Cristina's bartending as,
what, some kind of joke?
As some kind of bartender.
Yeah, I know. That
look on your face?
That's how my whole body
feels. And not just 'cause Cristina
makes the world's strongest drink,
but because my aspirational couple
has broken up and they're
living on two separate continents
and 'cause I'm dating men
who still live with their mother,
but they don't admit
that on their profiles.
They wait. They
wait... Thank you.
They wait until I've spent
an hour applying my makeup
and driving across town, and then
they tell me that small, little detail.
Thank you.
Oh. Oh.
And my star student,
my most promising resident
that I have ever seen,
is mixing Irish Car Bombs for a
bachelor party over at Joe's Bar.
I'm not even gonna mention
that she's letting the bachelors
feel her up at will, 'cause
that just adds insult to injury.
- Crap, I'm... I'm really drunk.
- Pictures are up.
All I'm saying is that
that redhead missed out.
If Joe's were a lesbian bar,
you would've been
up to your ears in...
Please. Don't say vagina.
Huh. Now, I don't have to.
God! I hate being drunk.
You think it's gonna make
you feel awesome and happy,
but it just makes you
feel tired and gross.
Yang looked like she
was having fun tonight.
What, the crazy party
girl thing? That's crap.
Every girl who climbs
up on a table thinks she's
the hottest girl in the room, but
really she's just dancing alone.
You OK?
Yeah, I just... I need to sleep.
- I need to sleep.
- All right.
Mm...
Drew's got a perforated ulcer.
And Cristina's working at Joe's.
- What?
- Forget it. It's bleeding.
It must be from the
anti-inflammatories.
- Wait, what about Cristina?
- She's a bartender now.
- I called Stark again,
and no answer.
- Well, big surprise.
- This kid needs surgery.
- I know.
Mrs. McNeil, this is Alex Karev.
He'll be consulting on your son's case.
The CT scan revealed that
your son has a perforated ulcer.
- That's what's
causing his pain.
- So does he need surgery?
- Yes.
- And we've called Dr. Stark
- and he's on his way.
- We can start
prepping him immediately.
Thank you. Thank you.
Hold on. Are we really gonna call in a
whole OR team without an attending?
What if Stark doesn't answer the
page? What if he doesn't come in on time?
What if the kid dies while
we're waiting to find out?
Look, I'm taking this kid to the
OR whether Stark comes or not.
Like the chief said, this is how
you get things done at night.
What if we have to do a truncal
vagotomy or a pyloroplasty?
- Have you ever
done those on your own?
- Not only can I do it,
I can do it better than
Stark. Are you in or out?
Like hell if I'm gonna
let you do it without me.
I'm in.
- OK. Is he under?
- Is he talking? Yeah, he's under.
- No word from Stark yet?
- No.
Call him every five
minutes until he answers.
- And page Dr. Bailey.
- Bailey's not on call tonight.
Just keep calling her.
I thought you said you
could do this better than Stark.
Shut up. All right,
uh, ten blade.
Ooh! It's the OR.
Uh...
Hello? Uh, Dr. Bailey's phone.
No, she is, um... She's
indisposed at the moment.
Page someone else, thank you.
OK, good. That's good.
Now, give me my phone.
- I need to call Ben.
- Who's Ben?
My ex. I dumped him.
Which I now realize
was a big mistake,
so I wanna call him.
I wanna call him and
tell him I have needs.
'Cause he understood how
to take care of my needs
in a way my husband did not.
I want to tell him that. Ha!
So give me my phone.
- Are you sure about that?
- Give me...
- Drunk-dialing
never really ends well.
- You are a virgin.
Wow. Word really
does travel around here.
I'm Bailey. I know everything.
Come... Come here, Kepner.
Come. Closer.
Closer!
Alex Karev is not the boy you want
to take your maiden voyage with.
Oh, God! Oh, God, yes. I know. I
am aware. You don't need to tell me...
You take your maiden voyage
with a nice boy. A kind boy.
A boy who loves you. A
boy that you love so much
you want to Super
Glue yourself to him.
You wait, you hear me?
Keep your knees together.
'Cause believe me, even though
you haven't met
your Ben... yet...
you will meet your Ben.
Not my Ben, but your own Ben.
Who might or might
not be called Ben.
Use soap and warm water.
On... my maiden voyage?
On the Super Glue.
Use soap, water,
and put a little acetone
in it. It works like a charm.
- OK. Yes, ma'am. Thank you.
- Mm-hm.
Mm!
Salt, shot, lime! Here we go!
- Yeah!
- You want some more water?
You know, you could fire
her for drinking on the job.
Are you kidding? I did that
three hours ago. Take her home.
Can't. Not until
she wants to go.
- Why not?
- Because she's
got a lot of people
telling her what to do, and she
doesn't need to hear it from me.
So, what are you gonna do?
I'm gonna sit here
and drink water.
Make sure she doesn't
leave with anybody.
Really? That... That's
your whole plan?
Well, if she's gonna
act like a stripper...
I'm gonna act like a bouncer.
Oh, God.
Dictate the op notes
and monitor his ABG's.
I'm gonna rack out. I
have to be back here in...
- two hours.
- I got it. Go.
All right.
Good work, Avery.
Go talk to the parents.
Give them the good news.
- OK?
- OK.
You can, um... You
can talk to me, you know.
- If you want to talk.
- About what?
I hear you every night.
I'm just saying. I
had sleep problems.
And they turned out
to be real problems.
Yeah, well, I don't
have any problems.
That kid was practically
dead when he got here,
and I pulled half his car
out of him, so he lived.
He's gonna live to be stupid
another day because of me.
His parents aren't gonna
lose everything because of me.
I call that a
pretty great night.
So, what is your problem?
- Any word from Stark?
- No.
There's the perf.
Anterior duodenum.
We could do a Graham patch.
Excellent suggestion,
fellow surgeon.
2-0 silk, please.
Can you believe we called an
entire OR team and they came?
- Amazing.
- We've got balls. Clamp.
You've got balls.
I've got cajones.
You know those are balls, right?
Oh... I was just thirsty.
- I didn't wake you, did I?
- Oh, no. I was...
awake.
Water?
I want...
um...
- sorbet.
- Sweet tooth?
I think I have some cookies
around here somewhere.
Mark.
Oh.
Really?
Really.
OK. I told them about the
surgery and his recovery process.
Do you think I should mention
his high chance for infection, or...?
I don't know, I don't want to
worry them any more than I have to.
No, just tell them he's
gonna feel pretty awful.
That he lived, and
his brother died.
That every time he
feels glad to be alive,
he'll hate himself for it.
Just tell them to
look out for that.
He won't want to talk about
it, but he'll be glad they know.
All right.
Under the cover of darkness...
people do things they'd never
do under the harsh glare of day.
Yeah, nice.
- It's not as bad as it looks.
- It looks pretty bad.
- Yeah.
- Hey. Thank you for calling.
- I appreciate you staying,
Shepherd.
- Yeah.
Cristina?
Oh, my God, it's my boyfriend.
- Husband. I'm your husband.
- Right.
Sorry, dude. She's all yours.
Come on.
Come on. Yep.
All right. Good night.
Oh, good! You're awake!
- Indoor voice, please.
- Of course.
You know, I really appreciate
you opening up to me.
I mean, you always have that,
like, super serious Dr. Bailey face on,
I couldn't even tell if you
liked me. But now, I mean,
I don't know if I'd say
that we're friends exactly,
but sort of, I mean,
don't you think?
- Dr. Kepner?
- Yeah.
This... never happened.
- This never happened. Got it?
- Mm-hm.
Say the words. This...
- Never happened.
Yeah. Yeah. OK.
Decisions feel wiser.
People feel bolder.
What can Stark do?
We had to operate.
He can yell. He will yell.
Doesn't matter. The kid's in
good shape. The mom's happy.
- We did what we
were trained to do.
- Remember the first day?
The chief said only
two of us would make it.
I thought it'd be
me and Cristina.
How are we the
last two standing?
I'm gonna make
your lives a living hell.
And you know what?
I'm gonna enjoy it.
You lied to my patients.
You hijacked an OR.
You performed a surgery that you
had no possible business performing!
And for the life of me, I... I... I
don't know what you were thinking!
Medicine has a
hierarchy for a reason!
If there had been
a complication,
you know whose ass
would've been on the line here?
Mine, not yours! Mine!
You doctors in this residency who
think you can do whatever you want
whenever you want, I
got some news for you!
I am the attending,
you are the residents...
But when the sun rises...
you have to take responsibility
for what you did in the dark...
- I had to use soap and water.
- What?
The acetone didn't
work on the Super Glue
till I mixed it with
soap and water.
I could use a little soap and
water right now. I feel disgusting.
- I can smell you from up here.
- Dibs on the shower!
- I want a beer. Who's up for a beer?
- Oh!
- Where do we get a beer at 6am?
- At home.
And face yourself
under the cold, harsh...
light of day.
Water?
Good morning.
Good night.