Coming through.
Thank you.
Oh, what a day.
E.R.
Yes, I know they're
late, but I can't...
Okay, okay. I'm on my way.
They're on their way up. Ta-da!
Hello.
No, this isn't E.R.
This is Patrick.
¿Habla Espanol?
'Kay. Bye-bye.
Are you the new desk clerk?
Si, senorita.
Yeah, right.
Um... who are you?
Patrick.
Okay, Patrick,
where is everybody?
My dad went to the bathroom.
You need to go sit over here
because you can't sit here.
Patrick...
Patrick, don't turn.
Don't...
Whoa!
Hi. This is John Carter.
I'm calling about your ad about
the one-bedroom apartment.
Got anything to eat?
Thanks.
I'm sorry?
Perfect. Taken.
Okay. Thank you.
I'm starved.
Mr. Carter?
Where did these come from?
Taglieri.
Brought them for
Carol Hathaway, I think.
There's a woman
in the suture room
who needs stitches in her face.
The plastic surgery
boys are there already.
Why don't you bat clean-up.
Give her a really good scar.
Just kidding.
Peter, E.M.T.'s at the back door
with a 20-year-old
stabbing victim.
Doesn't sound good.
All right, notify the O.R.
Call the blood bank.
Tell them I need
eight units O-neg now!
Still doing the total
gastrectomy this afternoon?
I can't. I've got an interview
with Morgenstern and Bradley.
Starzl Fellowship?
Yep.
Did Langworthy say only
third-year residents get it?
In her dreams. Exactly.
Tell Morgenstern to
meet me in Trauma Two.
What have we got?
Stab wounds to the neck.
Pulse 150 and
thready. B.P.'S 50 palp.
Uh-huh. What else?
Couldn't tube him.
Too much blood.
This guy's circling the drain.
That's what I love about you.
You're all optimism.
Let's take the turn.
Let's get him down here.
Let's move it, people.
Get him in Trauma Two.
Let's not lose him.
Here we go. Follow me.
Dust me. Come on.
All right, unstrap him.
Let's move it.
If we don't need
it, let's lose it.
We'll do this like
we always do it.
We're going to do
this on my count.
One, two, three!
All right, let's go to work.
Pulse ox?
It's only 70, and he's cyanotic.
All right. Let's go.
Here we are.
No airway.
Intubation tray. Move.
7½?
Yes.
Cranks.
Come on. Come on.
I can't see anything
in here. Suction!
Come on, I need some suction.
Let's get it in here.
We got a full-out gusher here.
One more minute, he's
going to have brain damage.
Let's do a crike.
You sure?
As the day is long. Let's move.
Doing a surgical airway here.
All right, now give
me the numbers.
Nice and loud, all right?
B.P. still 60/40.
Pulse, 160.
All right. Trach tube.
Thank you, darling.
Syringe.
Come on, honey.
See what we got here.
Uh-huh.
I like the way it sounds.
All right, ladies and gentlemen,
I believe we have
ourselves a breather here.
Welcome back, sir.
Can you ventilate him?
Good morning, Peter.
Breathing easy.
What have you got?
A stab wound to the neck.
Unable to intubate
due to bleeding.
Performed a stat
crichothyrotomy.
Airway established,
good bilateral breath sounds,
and patient is stable.
What do you need me for?
Let's get him up to the O.R.
Peter...
excellent.
Excellent work.
Sound judgment.
A solid execution.
Excellent.
So, I'll see you at
the Starzl interview
this afternoon.
Right.
Pretty cool.
E.R.
Yeah, hold on.
Carter, phone for you.
For me?
Thanks, Jerry.
Hello.
Yes, yes, yes. I did call
about the one-bedroom.
No, really?
What about the studio?
Garage?
No, I don't think I
want a gara... hello?
Hello?
That's good, huh?
Looking for an apartment?
Yeah. I've been living at home,
and my dad thinks
I'm a freeloader.
Mine did, too.
Finally found my own
place about six months ago.
Yeah? Through the paper?
No, no. Through a patient.
85-Year-old guy
has a heart attack.
He crumped, I jumped.
What are you saying, Jerry?
That he died, and...
Dr. Benton?
Dr. Morgenstern called,
and he wanted me to tell you
that your "stertzle"...?
Starzl.
Yeah. The interview's
been pushed to 3:00.
Oh, man... Sh...
Boy with a laceration in One.
Carter's having a light day.
Let him take it.
No. I'd rather you do it.
Carter, see the kid in One.
I've got to get up to
Recovery to see a patient.
Oh, Carter.
96-Year-old stroke victim
in Curtain Area Three.
Might want to check it out.
Check it out?
Yeah. He lives at 1680
North Lake Shore Drive.
Great location.
More sleep.
Say it ain't so, Joe.
It ain't so, Joe.
Oh, God. It's 7:00.
My shift starts
in a half an hour.
You're going to be late.
I am?
Mm-hmm. I called the hospital
and told them you were too busy
having sex with your wife.
And you want me to make
an honest woman of you?
Yes.
Okay, that takes
care of the cut.
I fell off a ladder.
Yeah, I know.
Let's check your elbow.
I fell off a stool, but I
didn't hurt my head.
It stays on.
See?
Go like this.
Oh, knock, knock.
Who's there?
Patrick.
Patrick who?
Me... Patrick.
Okay, I think
it's probably fine.
But, just to be sure,
I'm going to have
someone take an X ray.
X ray?
It's like a picture.
A photograph of your bones.
Ooh. Can... can I keep it?
Sure.
Oh, thank you.
You're welcome, Patrick.
Okay, I'll be back to
check on you, okay?
Take him up to X ray.
Sweet kid.
Yeah. Sometimes I think
I should be going
out with the patients
instead of the doctors.
Doctors... I don't know.
Shrinks aren't so bad.
So the rumors are true.
What rumors?
That you've been
going out with Div Cvetic.
Oh, just now and then.
Oh, geez. For two months.
What? Was it
supposed to be a secret?
You've been having
lunch with him every day.
Malik, did you get
those blood samples
from the lady in Five?
Already at the lab.
Great. Thanks.
So everyone knows? Knows what?
That it's your birthday today,
he's taking you out
for dinner tonight,
and asked you to
wear that black dress?
Oh, my God! What did he
do, put it in the newsletter?
The bulletin board.
Just kidding.
I will kill him.
After dinner.
Jerry, you got anything to eat?
Bagels in the lounge.
Never mind.
Did Linda Farrell come by yet?
Linda Farrell of
the pepperoni pizza,
Armani suit,
Novell Pharmaceuticals?
Yes, Jerry.
Haven't seen her.
I'm a little confused.
Is "Slice" your first name
or your middle name?
"Slice" is his street name.
Right. "Street name."
And how did this happen?
Cops beat me up.
He put his foot
through a window.
Breaking and entering.
Hey, who's the nurse
on the phone out there?
That's Nurse Wright.
Lydia Wright.
She married?
I have no idea.
Okay, this is probably
going to sting a little bit.
What's that?
Oh, that's an EKG caliper.
We use it to measure the
distances on a cardiogram.
What you may not know, of
course, is that a cardiogram measures
the electrical
activity of the heart.
You probably shouldn't
be doing that. Uh...
Carter, can you
grab Lydia and Jerry
and meet me at
the ambulance bay.
You bet.
Radial head looks okay.
No fat pad sign.
I think he's in the clear. You?
E.M.T.'s pulling in right now.
Motorcycle versus semi.
Who's on?
Benton and Ross.
Surprise!
♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
♪ Happy birthday ♪
♪ Dear Susan ♪
♪ Happy birthday to you. ♪
Birthday Jell-O in the lounge.
I hate this.
That's why we did it.
Oh, thank you.
Happy birthday.
Hey, Carol. Carol.
Thank you.
Thought maybe we'd crawl in here
and escape for an hour, huh?
What if they find us in a
compromising position? Then what?
Then how about a
more exotic locale?
I have seven minutes.
Don't know if "exotic"
is the word I would have picked.
I mean, look, we put
the pool in over there,
a little wet bar,
a putting green.
A putting green?
Hey, I'm a doctor.
Golf's an easy game.
I could teach you how
to play this afternoon.
I have to be back
in four minutes.
Maybe there's not
enough time for that.
'Course, if you
moved in with me,
there'd be more
than enough time.
Yeah, you mentioned
something about that.
Yeah, two weeks ago.
The silence of no answer
is getting a little deafening.
Oh, God, Tag... So much
has happened, you know?
I know. We've
gotten through that.
I just... I want to move
slowly, and feel sure.
About us.
About me.
I think we have moved slowly,
and I am sure about it all.
I'm a good guy,
Carol, and I love you.
If you have a problem
with our being together,
I need you to deal with it.
Knock, knock.
Was that Patrick?
Yeah. As a precaution,
Dr. Lewis has asked him
to sit in a wheelchair
until his father gets here.
Some precaution.
Ah. Linda Farrell.
Still haven't seen
her, Dr. Ross.
Jerry, do you like your job?
However, when I do, I
will certainly track you down
no matter where you are.
Well! And a good
late morning to you.
I had car trouble.
Mm-hmm.
I did. I had car trouble.
How is Jennifer, Mark?
She's, uh... she's great.
Yeah, I'll bet.
What's this for?
Later on tonight?
Keep it up.
She's adorable.
Yeah. She's almost 13 now.
Oh, and this
is... this is Ralph.
Have you ever seen
anything so cute?
Miniature schnauzers.
Very cute.
Is Mookie down here?
Carter's stitching him up.
Carter? Where's Benton?
Don't know.
That is one sorry paint job.
Yeah. That's because
the hospital likes
to save the big bucks
for those doctors' salaries.
Actually,
I'm not even
talking about myself
because I'm a resident.
So they don't pay me anything.
You're telling me you're
some kind of freebie?
Carter!
Where's Dr. Benton?
He's supposed to be
stitching up this boy.
Palm me off on the freebie?
Not one word out of
you, Mookie James.
You have done quite
enough for one day.
How do you two...?
Where is Benton?
He had to go to Recovery.
Son of a bitch!
You casually mentioned
our dinner to Doug Ross?
Yeah. Yeah. What's the problem?
He's like Dr. Intercom.
Biggest gossip in the hospital.
The cafeteria workers
probably know.
But you do look great
in that black dress.
This isn't working.
No?
No.
Dr. Cvetic?
The patient I
mentioned earlier...
He's right over here.
Three times, you mentioned him.
Three times, I told you
I didn't have time to see him.
What was your name?
Div...
Malik, why don't I just...?
Malik! That's right. Yeah.
I told you that three
times, too... Div.
Listen, son, you...
Okay, enough. Stop.
What are you guys going
to do now, arm wrestle?
No, of course not.
Look, I've had five
admissions today:
two attempted suicides,
two bipolars who forgot
to take their lithium,
and a 40-year-old
who walks in off the
street claiming to be dead...
All before lunch.
Now, your patient's
simply going to have to wait
for the afternoon shift.
Boat collision out on the lake.
12-year-old caught
in the wreckage.
How long?
E.M.T.'s pulling up now.
Connie, clear Trauma One.
Notify the O.R. now, please.
His parents are with him.
They hurt?
No. Thrown free. But
they came with him.
Oscar, what do you got?
David Adler, 12,
found unconscious.
Please help him.
I'm Dr. Ross. I'm going to
take your son to Trauma.
We'll do everything we can.
He went under so fast,
we couldn't find him.
B.P. 70, pulse 140.
Jerry will tell you
where you can wait.
Can't we stay with him?
We'll do everything we
possibly can, I promise.
Couldn't start
an I.V. or intubate
so we scooped and ran.
G.C.S 2-4-2.
Pupils mid-range and slagging.
Okay, all right, here
we go, get back.
On three. Hit that buckle.
One, two, three.
All right.
Airway?
You got it.
Hold that.
All right, now give me...
Six and a half.
Yeah.
All right, come on, buddy.
Okay.
Uh-huh.
His heart rate's low.
Give him atropine
and epinephrine.
O-negative's here.
You ordered it?
Yep.
Internal jugular?
Have to.
His peripheral
veins have collapsed.
All right, here we go.
Connie, will you move
those people out of the hall?
Perfect.
Yep.
Uh-huh.
Okay, here we go.
Yeah.
All right.
Here it comes.
Put it down.
All right, I think
we got this baby.
O.R.'S prepped.
They can X-ray
his C-spine upstairs.
Let's take him on up.
Paddles.
200?
Yep.
And clear.
Again.
300?
Yeah.
Clear.
Give me 360.
Charging.
And clear.
Okay, he's stabilized.
Let's go.
All right, people,
let's go. Come on.
He's going to need
at least six units.
We got him. Let's go.
Oh, man.
I think we may have
just pulled that one out.
Yes, we did.
That was like clockwork.
I wish they were all like that.
We haven't done a save
like that in a long time.
So smooth. Seven
minutes, door to door.
You were great. You anticipated
every move, every beat.
I mean it. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Yeah?
I do.
Carol, I'm sorry.
I shouldn't have done that.
Uh...
You didn't do it alone.
Listen. I got to go.
All right, Patrick.
You'll be all right.
Going home, Patrick?
Si, senorita.
His father's here.
And you're going to take it easy
for the next few days, right?
Pick a card...
any card.
Oh, pick a card, any card.
Here.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Let's find your dad.
Let's go, Patrick.
Yay! Go home.
Go home?
Where am I going?
Uh... Doug, I've
got a three-year-old
with a fever in two, a
six-month-old in four.
His mother says he's not
keeping anything down.
Mm-hmm. Okay.
I'll be right there.
I'm sorry, Dr. Ross.
I still haven't seen her.
Seen who?
Linda Farrell.
Oh, right, Jerry.
Oh, okay. Thank you.
Michael Carson, age 35, victim
of a five-mile-an-hour
car accident
and not a scratch on him.
No clue why he's comatose.
Results of the C.T.?
Normal. No improvement
with glucose and Narcan.
Well, he's nonsurgical.
He's all yours.
The differential
diagnosis of coma, huh?
Good luck.
You, too... on your interview.
Yeah.
Well, let's see
what we can come up with.
I asked you to take that boy
with the laceration.
Why are you doing in here?
Why didn't you?
Because Carter could handle it.
What's the big problem?
The problem is I
asked you to treat him,
and hoped maybe
you'd talk to him.
I had a patient I had
to go see in Recovery.
Oh, the hell you did.
You just didn't
want to be involved.
Okay, whoa. Wait a minute.
What am I supposed to be,
the Big Brothers
program or something?
I'm supposed to turn every
gang kid that comes in here
into some kind of
Nelson Mandela?
I know you'd never
do that, Peter.
That's why I never
asked you before.
I've known Mookie since he was
four years old, and
he was a sweet kid.
And maybe someone
will get through to him,
and he will be that
again someday!
Probably wouldn't
be half as tough
as getting through to you!
What about metabolic causes...
Hypoglycemia,
diabetic ketoacidosis?
Blood tests rule that out.
It can't be
arrhythmia or an M.I.
Negative C.T. rules out
mass lesion and trauma.
Benton gave him Narcan?
And an amp of D-50.
The blood came back normal
except for a slightly
elevated white count.
Up to 14,500.
Pulse is slowing...
It's down to 50...
And his B.P.'S dropping.
All right. Well,
speed up the I.V.s
and give him 300cc
bolus of saline.
What about atropine?
Yeah. Yeah.
Point five, I.V. push.
Maybe he had a seizure.
Connie, get a temperature.
Mm-hmm. He's
got a slight abrasion
on his tongue,
probably from biting it.
Partially compensated
metabolic acidosis.
You see that with seizures.
101.5.
Meningitis?
Yeah, could be.
We're going to have
to do a lumbar puncture.
You ever done one?
No, but I've seen it done.
Mm-hmm. See one,
do one, teach one.
Okay.
Benton.
Hey, Sarah.
You changed clothes.
Uh... yeah.
Oh.
Who's in there now?
Dalton.
George Dalton?
Mm-hmm.
Guy can't close a door,
much less an incision.
Yeah. I once saw him try
to connect a ureter
to a sigmoid colon.
You think that's bad?
I watched him do a beautiful
right fem-pop bypass
on a femoral artery...
The left femoral artery.
Yeah, so what do you think
he said to the patient, huh?
"Sir, there's some good
news and some bad news."
"Sir, the operation
was a success."
"But it was the wrong leg."
That was terrific.
Thank you, Dr. Dalton.
It was good.
Dr. Benton, you
don't mind if we take
Dr. Langworthy first, do you?
She's scrubbing on
a small bowel at 4:30.
No, not at all.
You ready?
Yeah, sure.
Come on in.
Okay.
Insert it between L4 and L5.
Uh-huh.
Tilt it slightly upward
so it's parallel with the bed.
Okay.
Advance it slowly
between the vertebrae.
Then you'll feel a slight pop
when the tip punctures
the spinal canal.
I felt it.
Okay, you're not done yet.
Now remove the stylet
from the needle
and check for fluid.
Perfect. Bingo.
Perfect on the first shot.
Crystal clear, Mr. Carter.
That's one hell of
a champagne tap.
Champagne tap?
Perfect hit the first time.
Resident owes you a
bottle of champagne.
Not the resident. The nurse.
Dr. Greene, your
wife called and asked
if you could meet
her at Doc's at 4:00.
Okay. Thanks, Jerry.
Hi.
Couldn't wait till tonight?
I wish.
Judge Franklin
called an hour ago.
He said my zoning opinion
wasn't quite what he'd hoped for
from a University
of Chicago graduate.
The guy's nuts.
He's an appellate judge, Mark.
So what?
It's the first thing
you've written.
What did he expect?
Something better, which he's
personally going to lead me in
at tonight's 9:00 meeting.
I called my mom.
She's going to bring
Rachel up in the morning.
I'll have to use the car again.
That's all right.
I'll take the el. It's...
Jen, you'll do fine.
How do you know?
This is a
make-it-or-break-it job, Mark.
I mean, if I blow this chance...
I wanted to spend
the night with you.
Well, you'll be back Monday.
I can't.
Rachel's day care's having
a Halloween party Monday.
What about Tuesday?
I work Tuesday.
Well, maybe you can get off.
Jen, we're going to figure
this all out, okay?
It's just going to
take a little time.
I'll call you when
I get up there.
Okay.
Okay?
Yeah.
Well, I'll see you
in the morning
on that hemicolectomy.
You bet.
Dr. Benton, thank you
so much for waiting.
Mm-hmm. You ready?
Good.
Dr. Benton, this
is Dr. Alex Bradley.
He's in charge of the
Starzl Fellowship this year.
Yes, sir.
Please be seated, Dr. Benton.
Pleasure.
Thank you.
It isn't often we entertain
the candidacy
of a second-year
surgical resident.
Yes, I know. I feel
very appreciative
that you feel my qualifications
are worthy of consideration.
Excellent recommendations.
Obviously solid achievement.
As you know, the,
uh... Starzl Fellowship
allows you to study with
surgical transplant teams.
Have you done research
in that area?
Well, not directly,
but I've done similar...
Any, uh...
extracurricular activities?
Uh... yes.
Uh... I believe it says...
Excuse me... right there.
Uh... the A.O.A. Honor Society.
Right. Back in medical school.
Anything more recent?
No, um...
Peter has shown superior
commitment and leadership.
His students come
out of the rotation
stronger than any I've seen.
Well, that's very good.
That's very good indeed.
Thank you.
Well, thank you
for taking the time
to go through the
qualifying process.
We won't make a decision
for another two weeks,
but you'll hear from us then.
Uh...
Thank you.
Thanks, Peter.
You did great.
Yeah? Yeah.
Hey, Lydia, will you
give this message
to Carter for me, please?
Sure. I didn't know he was
looking for an apartment.
There's two available
in my building.
Yeah? That makes three.
Good night, ladies.
Good night, Jerry.
I hired Mookie
today... That "gang kid."
Mm-hmm.
Citikids intern program.
He does volunteer work,
they suspend his sentence,
and he stays out
of juvenile hall.
Mm-hmm.
He starts next week.
I put you down
as his supervisor.
You sure you don't mind?
It's been a long day.
I could actually use
a quiet night at home.
The lecture's on advances
in cardiomyopathy.
A roomful of cardiologists.
I could hit my quarterly
quota in one night.
Then it's an opportunity
that you shouldn't miss.
I'll make it up to
you this weekend.
After last weekend,
I believe you.
Bye.
What?
Since when are you
so eager to be stood up?
Even I need rest.
This is the Murdoch chart
that I've been looking
for all afternoon.
Call me crazy,
but the black dress
looks better
without the lab coat.
Just shut up, okay?
I can barely sit here
dictating charts like this.
You can in my book.
Happy birthday, Susie-cakes!
♪ Happy birthday ♪
♪ To you ♪
Everybody, come on.
♪ Happy birthday... ♪
♪ You live in a zoo. ♪
Hey, Billy, this is Susie.
All right. Happy birthday.
Hey, how do you do?
Doug, this is my sister, Chloe.
Hi.
Oh, and this is Billy.
And Billy.
Hi, Billy.
Now, we've come to celebrate.
Oh, man.
I know this really cool club.
There's dancing and everything.
You'll love it.
Chloe...
I'm going to go look at these.
Why don't you come with us?
I got to work.
Come on.
Congratulations.
Good night.
Jerry said to give this to you.
And there's a couple
in my building, too.
Wow. It's like the perfect day.
What else are you
guys on, Chloe?
Vodka and what else?
Nothing. I just
wanted to wish you
a happy birthday.
So you showed up drunk
with a guy you probably
met an hour ago?
I did not.
Billy cares about me,
so just leave him out of it.
I think he is already out of it.
Oh, is he staying
at my place, too?
Did he help you steal the TV?
Oh, you shut up.
You just shut up, Susie.
You are just like Mom.
You're just like Dad.
You're just always
hating everything that I do.
That is not true,
and you know it.
Nothing was ever any
different at home for me
than it was for you.
Sure. Sure.
Oh, God. I don't even know
why I'm having
this conversation.
They never thought
I could do anything.
Do you think they thought I
could go to medical school?
Become a doctor?
I had to prove it to them.
Sometimes I still
have to every day.
You don't know
anything about every day!
You don't know.
You don't have to worry
about paying the rent!
about where you're
going to sleep!
You don't have to
worry about getting a job!
Chloe... Chloe... Chloe...
Chloe, Chloe. Okay,
okay. Calm down.
Are you okay?
Take it easy.
You're going to be okay.
All right.
You're safe here, Chloe.
Do you understand?
Dr. Benton's going
to fix your hand.
And then, if you want,
you and I can talk
through all this.
Okay?
You are pathetic.
What are you doing back?
I thought Jennifer
was in town.
So did I.
I thought you had a
date with the drug lady.
She went to a lecture on
cardiomyopathy instead.
Wow, that stings.
Actually, I'm glad.
She might be a
little perky for me.
Perky? I thought
you liked perky.
This is true
but lately, I have
found myself attracted
to sullen and
withdrawn and confused.
Yeah? That's good. You
ought to go out with me.
I am out with you.
Oh my, oh my, oh my.
Come on.
I'm the short guy here.
There's nothing wrong
with a little infantile
schoolyard competition
to kind of boost the spirits.
Oh, no...
All right. Here we go.
A little game of
one-on-one to 21.
A buck a point.
You're on.
All right. Ready?
Mm-hmm.
Through the leg.
They're stitching her up now.
She can sleep it off
tonight in Room Three,
and Benton said he'd find
somewhere to throw Billy.
He ought to find somewhere
to lock him up.
I told you, I don't
like surprises.
I'm sorry.
That's all right.
I'm used to it.
Come on. Let me
get you out of here.
We can still grab some dinner.
No. I don't really feel like it.
I think I'll go up
top, grab some air.
Want some company?
No.
Can I come over later?
Uh... maybe.
I don't know, Div.
I'll call you.
Okay.
So, uh...
you and Doug were great today.
What?
The 12-year-old
kid... Boating accident.
Oh. Thanks.
Yeah. Another ten minutes,
we would have lost him.
I'll see you later.
Doug?
Hey.
Come on in.
Word came down from the O.R.
The little kid from
the boating accident
came through really well.
He's going to be just fine.
That's great news.
Pretty strange day, huh?
You could say that.
I'll tell you,
I could live the whole
thing all over again.
Doug, John asked me
to move back in with him.
I just thought I should tell
you that I told him I would.
And did you decide
this this afternoon?
We've been talking
about it for a while.
But did you decide to
tell him this afternoon,
and you're just telling me now?
It doesn't matter, Doug.
What happened with us
this afternoon...
Does that matter?
What happened
today was an accident.
There are no accidents.
Look, it's great.
I mean... really.
It's great.
Thanks for letting me know.
I can't find anybody
to drink this with me.
Don't know that I'm
the best candidate.
You are the only
one with a birthday.
Oh, please.
However, you're not the only one
with a crazy family.
My dad says you
should never ever do this
with a bottle of champagne.
Now, if that's not crazy...
Okay...
are you ready?
I don't think so, but... okay.
Ooh! Ah!
Thanks.
You know, Carter,
this is a whole side of you
I've never seen before.
What do you mean?
I come up here a lot.
You do?
Well, if you were
Dr. Benton's student,
you'd come up here a lot, to.
However, today
was an excellent day.
I performed my
first lumbar puncture.
How was it?
Really scary.
But Dr. Greene
talked me through it,
the patient did have meningitis,
now he's going to be okay,
so I guess that's
worth a little scare.
You know, Carter,
you can call us
by our first names.
You call me Carter.
Yeah, well...
that's different...
somehow.
So your sister...
She's really stuck
on this guy with
the greasy hair?
I doubt she knows
his last name. Why?
I was going
to ask her out.
Who are you?
I'm just kidding... Susan.
I get it... John.
No. Doesn't sound right.
Okay.
Call me Carter.
Captioning sponsored
by WARNER BROS.