And the only thing wrong—
The only thing wrong
with the American dream...
is people— too many people...
Too many of us telling young
people that the dream is dead.
They told me that when I was
growing up in the slums of Trenton.
And they were wrong.
They told me that
when I decided to run for
senator, with only $58
in my savings account.
And they were wrong.
And they are still
telling me that now— that
I don't have a chance
because I'm black,
because I don't have
the right nose, because
I still only have $58
in my savings account.
With your help, we can
keep that dream alive.
And in closing,
just...
let me say...
Let me say that you should
all donate the legal maximum...
to the next president
of the United States.
Are you okay? Do you need some water or
something? No. I'm fine. I'm fine, really.
Handsome guy like you, I
bet you get 70% of the women.
Well, here's hoping.
Of course, it helps
your wife died of cancer.
I mean, I'm sorry, but the
sympathy vote’s in your pocket.
Yeah, I appreciate your support.
Listen, Senator, my union
has a hell of a war chest.
Um, I've always been
strong on the union.
The thing is, you always go on in
your speeches about the workers...
in Indonesia,
Cambodia, Timbuktu.
Because I think we
have a— A moral...
My union members are hurting.
They don't care about moral this
and moral that. Are you all right?
- Senator?
- Ugh. Hey!
The guys are gonna love that.
Everyone, give him some
room. Give him room to breathe!
Back off, please!
Senator, are you all right?
The senator's suffering from nausea,
headache and mental confusion.
Ah, bad sushi is
so hard to diagnose.
You're being childish.
Look, if his case is
as trivial as you think,
it'll take you three
minutes to diagnose.
Uh-huh. Three minutes that I could spend
sitting on the toilet with the funny pages.
- You're mad at me.
- Nope.
I never liked
Cameron or Foreman.
You know why I'm forcing you
to fire one of them? Because
you need to prove to me
that you're a team player.
Now, if you did that, you wouldn't
need to go through this exercise.
Fine. I'll hold the senator's
hair while he upchucks.
Oh, and, uh, by the way,
I need you to give a speech at the National
Cardiology Conference, um, next week.
I don't do speeches. I'm shy.
Eastbrook Pharmaceuticals has
developed a new A CE inhibitor.
I would like you to extol the virtues
of this breakthrough medication.
Eastbrook Pharmaceuticals?
Wait a second? Don't
I own that company?
Oh, no, that's right. You do.
Viopril is a significant
improvement over the old version.
It's all there in the study.
I know its price tag is
significantly improved.
You can either give one 10-minute
talk and one three-minute diagnosis,
or you can fire
one of your pets.
My understanding was that you
believed in rationality above all else.
Viopril.
I appreciate your
keeping the media away.
We're keeping your staff
away as well. Take it easy now.
- I'm in the middle of a campaign.
- The faster we can get you better,
the faster you can get out of here.
Anyone else at the
fund-raiser get sick?
I don't think so, and I don't think that's
it. I've been under the weather for weeks.
Lots of traveling. I'm supposed
to be in the Sudan next week.
Oh!
Helps me concentrate.
Even better than drugs.
Open your mouth, please.
Ahh.
That's quite a scar.
When I was six, I fell off
the swing and bit my tongue.
Couldn't talk right
for the longest time.
Lots of teasing. It just made me fight
harder, speak up for those who can't.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Tongues heal too fast. Your political
consultants have written you a nice story.
In a tight race, the lispers
alone could put you over the top.
You a Republican, or
you just hate all politicians?
I just find being forced to
sit through drivel annoying.
You find sincerity annoying?
You're a black kid
from the ghetto...
who made it to Yale Law
and the United States Senate.
That's a sufficiently mythical story.
You don't need to lie about your tongue.
Must've missed it.
What's wrong?
What is it? It's not
the food. It's your brain.
Get an M.R.I. and
a lumbar puncture.
Cancel your travel plans.
The senator's L. P.
Showed no sign of
infection, and the
M.R.I. looks fairly clean.
I guess we can tell him he's
fairly healthy and can go home.
Well, there is something
in Broca's area,
but it's small, low intensity.
Most likely just background
noise. Care to bet your job on that?
What was that? What was what?
You got annoyed. That
was clearly an annoyed face.
I get annoyed by glib
remarks about our futures.
Last week you didn't get annoyed.
You made poopie in your pants. It's weird.
It's almost like now you know
you have nothing to worry about.
Chase has nothing
to worry about?
None of you has
anything to worry about.
What happened?
Vogler saw the error of
his ways and repented.
The lesion could be nothing. Also
could be a brain tumor or an infection.
There's only one
way to find out which.
You want to cut into his brain?
Dangerous, I know. Especially since
he's a politician, his brain's all twisted.
But I weighed that against
the risk of him stroking
out before lunch. Call
Surgery. Get it scheduled.
- You're not pregnant.
- Well, I told you that.
There's got to be some
other reason I'm still spotting.
Sure. You were pregnant.
Based on your hormone
levels, you've had a miscarriage.
I haven't even been on a date.
Right. And since it's
physically impossible to
have sex without someone
buying you dinner...
I haven't had sex since I
split up with my husband.
- That was almost a year ago.
- Fine. Have it your way.
Immaculate conception.
- Um, what do I do?
- Well, it's obvious.
Start a religion.
In my office.
Afternoon delight. She
just loves the hard wood.
You're not doing a brain biopsy
based on a spot on an M.R.I.
Where'd you get that?
Not on a United States senator.
Oh, just so I'm clear— If he was a janitor,
that would be okay? Do you have a list?
A brain biopsy can cause
permanent neurological damage.
Uh-huh. Whereas tumors are really good
for brains. Make 'em grow big and strong.
- It's my call.
- No, it's not.
- You're pulling rank on patient care?
- It's not my call either.
- It's up to you.
- Either it's a tumor or it's an infection
that the lumbar puncture didn't pick up.
Either way, unless we treat it
immediately, it could kill you.
Or it could be nothing. Reading
brain M.R.I.'s is not an exact science.
Well, what caused my s-symptoms?
Wow! Excellent question. Many
doctors wouldn't have gone there.
It could be a transient
ischemic attack.
You could make the argument for
watching carefully for the time being.
Hmm, but you’d only
make that argument if
you were an administrator
covering your ass.
That's absurd and
insulting. Insulting, yes.
What would the voters think?
If they find out I've
had a b-brain biopsy?
This could leave you
b-b-b-brain damaged,
and you're worried
about NASCAR dads?
It's not a brain tumor.
It's not a bacterial
infection either.
So you biopsied
his brain for nothing?
If that were true, would Dr. Wilson's
mouth be contorted into that ugly shape?
It's toxoplasmosis.
You sure?
Which means the Great
Black Hope has full-blown AIDS.
They're gonna love
that in Dubuque.
Toxoplasmosis is a fairly
common fungus you can get...
from eating under-cooked
meat or touching cat feces.
In rare cases, the fungi travel up the
bloodstream and latch onto the brain,
causing a lesion
or inflammation.
So, what's the prognosis?
Toxo usually
responds to treatment,
but it only causes a
lesion in your brain if your
immune system is
extremely weak to begin with.
Senator, I'm afraid
you have AIDS.
As I'm sure...
No! As I'm sure you know, people
with H.I.V. can live a long time.
- What else could do this to me?
- Theoretically, certain cancers.
If you have toxo in your
brain, you have AIDS.
I do not have AIDS.
I don't sh—sh—shoot up drugs.
I don't s-sleep with...
This is very bad news. I
get that, and I sympathize.
But we gotta speed through
the denial phase because
you need antiretrovirals
and you need them fast.
But—You haven't even
tested me for H.I.V.!
- We will.
- But the toxo drugs
are gonna piss off your fungi.
And when fungi get pissed...
I am not going
to take the pills.
You're afraid
word will leak out.
Trust me. You're not gonna
be president either way.
They don't call it the White
House because of the paint job.
Here's what you're gonna do.
You're gonna give me
the drugs for the toxo only.
You're going to test me for
H.I.V., under a false name.
You are going to
test me for cancer...
and anything else that
could have done this to me.
If I have cancer,
I will deal with it.
But I do not...
have AIDS.
"Eastbrook Pharmaceuticals
are pleased to announce...
that Dr. Gregory House
will present the latest
research on our exciting
new ACE inhibitor."
You're making that up.
That's Vogler's company.
Press release. "During an address at the
North American Cardiology Conference."
- House never gives speeches.
- But when I really believe in something—
Gosh dang it, I got a chance
to make a difference here.
You made a deal with Vogler?
It's all the rage.
Everybody's doing it.
So, what's the deal? You get to
keep all of us if you flog his products?
One speech. No biggie.
Foreman's doing a bone
marrow biopsy to check for cancer.
Cancer? The senator's got AIDS.
Cancer sounds better
in a press release.
I need you guys to rush
the ELISA test for H.I.V.
Thank you.
For the speech.
When I said rush, I
meant, you know, fast.
- "Stat's" the word you doctors use, right?
- I know it's hard for you.
Double stat?
This may sting a little.
Sorry. It wasn't the shot.
It's, um— My head's killing me.
Senator, we don't
have to do this now.
We can hold off till your
H.I.V. test comes back.
Because you figure it's
gonna come back positive.
In my experience— Patients lie.
Politicians lie more.
Black politicians...
Oh. I don't think black politicians
lie more than white politicians.
- We lie less.
- You figure we're morally superior?
I've got my theories.
No, we— We just
can't get away with it.
No one's gonna g-give
us the benefit of the doubt.
No one's gonna cut
us a second chance.
And when it happens, it's
not just a—a bad politician.
It's—It's a bad role model.
It's a—a dis...
Discredit to the race.
You ready? Yeah.
Yeah.
Take a deep breath.
Dr. House, I just wanted...
You're welcome again. I
want you to know how much...
Got it. You're grateful.
Apparently you seem to think it
will mean a lot to me to know that.
Do you know why
people pray to God?
I thought you didn't
believe in God. I don't.
Well, then you better be
making a very good point.
Do you think they pray
to him and praise him
because they want him
to know how great he is?
God already knows that.
Are you comparing me to God?
I mean, that's great, but just so
you know, I've never made a tree.
I thank you because it
means something to me...
to be grateful
for what I receive.
You are the most naive
atheist I've ever met.
Dr. House, you have
a patient in room one.
Thank God.
People pray so that God
won't crush them like bugs.
I'm not gonna crush you.
"Petechial" bruising? I don't
know if I pronounced that right.
Gosh, the Internet is
such a wonderful tool.
It could be leukemia.
Definitely possible.
The more likely
diagnosis is hickey.
Well, it can't be a hickey.
Why is everybody so
ashamed of sex all of a sudden?
I'm not having sex.
I've barely even thought about
sex since my marriage. Ow!
I say you're having
sex, you say you're not.
Either you're
lying or I'm wrong.
- Or there's some middle ground.
- You mean, like, oral?
I mean, you're having
sex without knowing it.
I'm testing you for
booze, drugs and G.H.B.
I don't drink or—What's G.H.B.?
The date-rape drug.
It's positive.
Your "T" cell count is eight,
which means there's a
good chance you'll die.
I'm telling you this because we
need to contact your sexual partners.
I've only had two girlfriends.
Two. After my wife died.
I used c-condoms.
You know the chances of you getting H. I.
V. from heterosexual sex with a condom?
Yes.
Someday there will
be a black president.
be a gay president.
Maybe there'll even be
a gay, black president.
But one combination I do not see
happening is gay, black and dead.
You need to stop lying to me.
It must be miserable, always
assuming the worst in people.
Cut the crap. You're dying.
And you're clever, you're
witty and you are a coward.
You're scared of taking chances.
I take chances all the time.
It's one of my worst qualities.
On people?
Wanting to believe the best
about people doesn't make it true.
Being afraid to believe
it doesn't make it false.
Well, that's very moving. It's
a shame I don't vote. Hmm.
This is who I am.
I believe in people.
I'm not hiply cynical, and I
don't make easy, snide remarks.
I would rather think that people are
good and be disappointed once and again.
I need to draw some more blood.
Nurse!
The antiretrovirals
aren't working.
That's not surprising.
He's just gonna keep getting
worse. You realize that, right?
Why are you spying on my case?
Why are you giving
that speech next week?
We're both just doing what we have to
do. You don't see a problem with that?
Checking in on a patient?
Yeah, wow. How do I
look myself in the mirror?
You're not the one being asked to
perpetrate a fraud on the American people.
It's a 10-minute speech.
That I've been ordered to give.
Vogler's drug works. Don't care.
Why do you have to make
everything so dramatic?
I'm a very high-strung
little lap dog.
Uh-uh. No pills.
What's going on?
The antiretrovirals
aren't working.
Why not?
Because you don't have AIDS.
The first test was
a false positive.
Happens one time in every 5,000.
You r-ran a second test?
- Yeah.
You're still dying.
The only difference is,
now we don't know why.
He's continuing to lose control
of the muscles on his right side.
- His brain is getting foggier,
and his "T" cells are still in single digits.
- Why are we doing this here?
So Cuddy can't find us.
Unless we figure out
the underlying disease,
this guy's lied to
his last constituent.
- False negative
on the P.C.R. AIDS test?
- Ran it twice.
- Immunoglobulin deficiency?
- No history of respiratory problems.
Idiopathic "T" cell deficiency.
Idiopathic—from the Latin
meaning "we're idiots"
'cause we can't figure
out what's causing it.
Give him a whole body scan.
- You hate whole body scans.
- 'Cause they're useless.
Could probably scan
any one of us and find
five different doodads
that look like cancer.
But when you're fourth down
and a hundred to go, in the snow,
you don't call a running play up
the middle, unless you're the Jets.
I hate sports metaphors.
Why did you order
the second AIDS test?
Standard procedure. Oh, well,
that's you— Mr. Standard Procedure.
You suspected the first
test was a false positive?
I knew he was going
to Africa, and I figured
he was vaccinated
for Hep "A" and "B."
That could cause
a false positive.
- You knew that before you ordered
the first test. What changed?
- I should have ordered both.
You were sure he had AIDS.
Then you talked to him, then
you had doubts. What did he say?
He said he had not
engaged in any risky behavior.
Huh. And you believed him.
He didn't have
any reason to lie.
Everybody lies,
except politicians?
House, I believe
you're a romantic.
You didn't just believe
him, you believed in him!
Do you want to come over tonight
and watch old movies and cry?
Dr. Cameron's getting to you.
Well, I guess you can't be around that
much niceness and not get any on you.
Is that why you haven't
put the moves on her?
What makes you think I
haven't put the moves on her?
Oh! Oh, boy! You're in trouble.
You have restored my
faith in the human race.
- You're lying.
- No. I'm not lying.
Just got your results back.
No G.H.B., no nothing.
It means you're having
sex and you're lying about it.
No. And I have a new symptom.
I have a rash on my butt.
Do you wanna? Yeah.
- What is it?
- It's a carpet burn.
No. It can't be.
Doctor, I love sex.
I miss it. I haven't
had any in over a year.
Well, you managed to keep this appointment,
so you have no short-term memory problem.
Multiple personalities? Do you
find yourself losing chunks of time?
Do you wake up, and
you don't remember falling
asleep? No. I just wake
up really exhausted.
- Something upsetting you?
- No.
My ex lives in the
apartment downstairs.
He's always calling me,
always wanting to get
back together, complaining
about mixed signals.
"Get out of my life." How
much clearer can you get?
We have a sleep
lab in the basement.
If nothing else, it will get you
away from your ex for a night.
Slightly enlarged lymph
node in his left armpit.
How slightly? Quarter mil.
- Lymphoma?
- Sure.
Or he's had a cold
in the last six months.
- What, you got her on speed dial?
- I just follow the scent of arrogance.
Another slightly enlarged node over here.
Two more in his neck and one in his groin.
And there's a cyst in his liver.
It looks complex.
Central necrosis?
Spontaneous
bleeding. It's benign.
I was rooting for a really cool tumor.
Instead we're stuck with this crap.
Doesn't matter. Once you
find 'em, you gotta check 'em.
Knock yourselves out.
I just saw Senator
Wright. He looks like hell.
That sushi must've been a
lot worse than you thought.
Mr. Vogler, would you like
a free whole body scan?
A man of your stature should get himself
checked at least three times a year.
Here's a few key points I want
you to cover during your speech.
Fourteen pages.
The audience will be
comatose by paragraph two.
Throw in a joke.
Dr. Chase, we need to talk.
- How do you see this ending?
- What ending?
I can't fire you, so
you have no reason to
fear me and, therefore,
no reason to lie to me.
You told Cuddy where I was.
You told Vogler what I was doing.
Yeah. So how can
I work with you?
Well, you don't have a choice.
This might hurt a little.
Lie to me.
Okay. It'll feel like
a gentle massage.
House...
is a lousy teacher.
You can't lie for beans.
Have you ever told
any really big ones?
Oh-ho-ho-ho!
I might be messed up,
but I'm not that out of it.
Strap his arm down.
Am I going to be okay?
I hope so.
I am selling my soul.
Just a little piece. And you
are getting something in return.
I said I was selling it. Didn't
say I was giving it away.
That would be
immoral and stupid.
All they've done
is add an antacid.
Does it work?
That's not the point.
Of course it's the point.
He's not asking you to lie.
He's not asking you to do something
illegal. He's not asking me to do anything.
He's not ordering you. He gave
you a choice. You chose your staff.
I know this isn't easy
for you. You'll suffer.
Vicodin sales in
Jersey will triple.
But you are doing a good thing.
Only you could feel like crap
about doing something good.
Kidney and liver cysts are both benign,
and the lymph nodes all came back clean.
His left armpit node has
antibodies for C. D. 1 1.
Not enough to indicate lymphoma.
We never tested for
hairy cell leukemia.
No, but we would have picked it up
somewhere else besides one lymph node.
- And his spleen isn't enlarged.
- Size isn't everything.
The spleen is the
mother lode for hairy cells.
Let's cut it open.
You can't biopsy his
spleen. It'll bleed like stink.
In the senator's condition, a spleen biopsy
could easily cause sepsis and kill him.
Why do you do this to me?
Now if I kill him, I can't tell the judge
I had no idea of the risks involved.
His brain is turning
into mush, and he's at
risk for more infections.
We have to do it.
See? That'll sound
much better in court.
Okay. Go tell our human pincushion
we'll be sticking him one more time.
Cuddy.
Don't you hate doing this?
Yeah.
What's up?
You like me.
Why?
That's kind of a sad question.
I'm just trying to figure
out what makes you tick.
I am not warm and fuzzy, and you are
basically a stuffed animal made by Grandma.
I don't think that's
why you're asking.
- I think this is because of the speech.
- God, don't try and pick me apart.
Then why are you asking?
What do you want to hear?
Hey, Senator. We need to do
one more biopsy—on your spleen.
I'll have to sign lefty.
My fingers aren't working.
Have you been coughing a lot?
Does it hurt?
It's like I can't get air.
Is that from the toxo?
No. This is—This is new.
You don't need to sign.
We can't do the biopsy.
The senator's breathing
is severely impaired.
His O₂ sat levels are at 89.
His silver stain indicates
Pneumocystis carinii pneumonia.
Another killer fungus. It's
consistent with hairy cell leukemia.
But we can't biopsy his
spleen. Respiratory distress.
His platelets are 20 and dropping.
His blood won't clot worth a damn.
There's gotta be another
way to diagnose hairy cell.
No. His bone marrow's indeterminate.
Spleen biopsy's the only way to go.
You know, when the Inuit go
fishing, they don't look for fish.
Why, Dr. House?
They look for the blue heron
because there's no way to see the fish.
But if there's fish, there's
gonna be birds fishing.
Now, if he's got hairy cell, what
else should we see circling overhead?
He should have all
sorts of weird viruses.
H.T.L.V. and A.T.L.V.
We can test for
them. Run the titers.
These were your brain
waves at 2:45 a.m.
Now, here it comes. There's an
abrupt jump from slow-wave sleep.
This indicates
partial sleep arousal.
Most common type is
somnambulism. Sleepwalking.
That would explain why
I'm so tired when I wake up.
Yes. And also why
you were pregnant.
And the hickeys.
And the carpet burn.
I had sex in my sleep?
Sexsomnia is a
documented disorder.
You said your ex lives
downstairs. I'll kill him.
Okay. But he probably didn't
know that you were asleep.
Sexsomniacs can
act pretty normal.
I'm gonna write you a prescription
for a low-dose antidepressant.
It'll let you sleep better.
If you wanna save yourself the $15 co-pay,
you could have sex while you're awake.
- He's my ex. I don't— -
You live in the same building.
You haven't had sex with anyone else for
a year. You sleepwalk right into his arms.
Call me crazy, but I'm
sensing unresolved issues.
Negative for H.T.L.V. 1 and 2.
And negative for A.T.L.V.
and everything else.
It's not hairy cell.
Hey. You really gonna
give that speech?
You got an opinion
too? I'm a little surprised.
Frankly, I thought you were too much
of a self-absorbed ass to do this for us.
You're welcome. He's
positive for Epstein-Barr.
So what?
It doesn't point to
hairy cell. It's irrelevant.
Hey.
You didn't fall off the
swings when you were eight.
S-S-Six.
Ever.
Give that back.
Uh-uh. We have to talk.
You had an epileptic seizure.
That's how you bit your tongue.
I-I haven't had
a seizure since...
What medication did you take?
No s-s-seizure since I was six.
No dr-dr-drugs s-since I was 10.
Yeah, that's it. Don't worry
about what the question is.
Don't worry that you're starting to
feel dizzy. Just stay on message.
My...
My mother used to call it...
"funny-something."
- Phenytoin?
- Yes!
Okay, okay. You're okay.
It's okay.
Everybody lies.
Senator Gary H. Wright of New
Jersey had childhood epilepsy.
He took phenytoin.
That drug, with the
Epstein-Barr virus,
is associated with common
variable immunodeficiency disease.
"T" cells down, "B" cells down. Keeps
you from forming enough antibodies.
See, the antibodies are
basically your defensive line.
And your brain is
like the quarterback.
And then the fungi are like blitzing
linebackers plunging up the middle.
Your lungs are like...
Okay, you got two
quarterbacks. C. V. I. D.?
That's a type of immunoglobulin
deficiency. I said that.
Yeah. Well, it was a
stupid idea when you said it.
Then he got the respiratory problem,
and he tested positive for Epstein-Barr.
That's pretty much
a childhood disease.
That's another reason
why Chase's suggestion
was idiotic. He got
it when he was a kid.
He didn't get any symptoms
until now. It happens.
It gets triggered by
stress— Like public speaking.
So you're basing your
diagnosis on a virus that's
relatively common and a
drug he took 30 years ago.
Start the senator on
I.V. immunoglobulin, stat.
If he gets better, I'm
right. If he dies, you're right.
Dr. House?
You faked that. No.
Say “antiretroviral."
Antiretroviral.
Now, say it three times fast.
We just got your latest blood
results. Your white cells are up.
Your "T" cells are back over a
hundred. That's-That's good, right?
In a week? That's terrific.
You'll need medication for the rest of your
life, but other than that, you're fine.
Am I well enough
to run for president?
- Why not run for pope
while you're at it?
- Oh, come on.
Kennedy had Addison's.
F.D.R. had polio. Two of
the best presidents in
the last hundred years.
If they were running today,
they wouldn't stand a chance.
You figure you'd be surgeon
general if you didn't have the limp?
No. There's things I can't do.
And like you said, I...
have to live with reality.
Well, then I'm running.
Good for you.
Now, don't get excited.
He's right. I, uh—I won't win.
Then why run?
Oh, I see. Your point being, the only way
to make a difference is to win every fight.
But, hey, why listen to me?
I own the company. I'm
certainly not to be trusted, right?
Dr. Greg House, on the
other hand, has a reputation...
for integrity,
among other things.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Dr. Greg House.
Eastbrook Pharmaceuticals' extraordinary
commitment to research excellence...
is exemplified by
their new ACE inhibitor,
a breakthrough medical approach that
will protect millions from heart disease.
That's not a speech.
I thought it was pithy.
You got enough for a press release
anyhow. Foreman or Cameron.
A few things I
forgot to mention.
Ed Vogler is a
brilliant businessman,
a brilliant judge of people...
and a man who
has never lost a fight.
You know how I know that
the new ACE inhibitor is good?
'Cause the old one was good. The new one
is really the same, just more expensive.
A lot more expensive.
You see, that's another
example of Ed's brilliance.
Whenever one of his drugs
is about to lose its patent,
he has his boys and girls alter it
just a tiny bit, patent it all over again,
making not just a
pointless new pill,
but millions and
millions of dollars.
Which is good for
everybody, right?
- Except the patients.
- But— who cares?
They're just so damn sick.
God obviously never
liked them anyway.
All the healthy people in the room, let's
have a big round of applause for Ed Vogler.
I threw in a joke.
♪♪
I'm sorry.
I should've taken an extra couple
of Vicodin and just held my nose.
- I'm guessing you did take
a couple extra Vicodin.
- True.
You don't need to worry
about firing anyone. I'm leaving.
Why?
Is this another noble,
self-sacrificing gesture?
Are you trying to
protect Foreman? No.
So this is just,
"Don't fire me. I quit"?
I'm protecting myself.
You asked me why I like you.
You're abrasive and rude.
But I figured, everything you
do, you do it to help people.
But I was wrong.
You do it because it's right.
There are only two ways
that I can deal with things.
One is in my control.
That's to leave.
Good-bye, House.
That's some bad hat, Harry.