Ready to get started?
Yeah.
Okay, thank you.
Let's step on the scale,
please.
You've got a lot of history
and biology to overcome.
Your ghrelin is out of whack,
and you've got
high leptin resistance
making you feel hungrier
than you actually are.
But then your body is terrible
at signaling
when you're truly full.
Add to that
all the emotional stuff
you're working through,
having a healthy relationship
with food
will be a lifelong battle
for you.
Well, then it's a good thing
I'm halfway done, right?
You'll need someone
to work with you
on your ingrained
emotional assignments to food.
No, no, no.
No, I really like going
to group.
It's great.
I share in there.
- Everyone's really supportive...
- Iggy.
You haven't logged in once.
No, that's not true.
I've...
The system keeps track.
You have to stop lying
and do the work.
There's someone I want you
to talk to.
It's a recovery coach?
What is that, a food monitor?
Food chaperone?
That's not happening.
No, absolutely not.
No.
Can I put my pants on now,
please?
*NEW AMSTERDAM (2018)*
Season 03  Episode 05
Episode Title: " Blood, Sweat & Tears"
Aired on: March 30, 2021
- Dr. Goodwin.
- Yeah?
- Yes, Dr. Kao, what's up?
- You caught me.
- I just wanted to check
- and see, not to rush you.
- Mm-hmm, okay.
- But I was just curious.
- Yeah.
- How are the interviews going?
- Interviews.
For the interim chair
of neurology.
Yes, those interviews
are going great.
Really good.
You haven't started them yet,
have you?
Not in the technical sense,
no, but Agnes,
you are the best interim,
interim chair of neurology
a medical director could
ask for.
I appreciate your confidence
in me,
but Dr. Kapoor is a 30-year
veteran in the field,
and I'm not even an attending.
I am woefully underprepared.
You're not, Dr. Kao,
but if it makes you
feel better,
I will start
those interviews today.
Ah, Max, we've got a problem.
Tomorrow,
but what's one more day?
- How can I help?
- Sorry, Agnes.
- No, Max...
- This way, yep.
Our blood bank supplies have
reached critical lows.
How did that happen?
I've narrowed it down
to vampires
or the global pandemic.
There's a nicer way
to say that.
A third of our blood
donations normally come
from high school
or business blood drives,
but with everyone at home...
Well, what about
hospital employees?
Tapped out.
Everyone's within their
eight-week turnaround window.
But we've got
backup supplies, right?
Um...
most of it went
toward Haven yesterday.
There was a ten-car pileup
on the BQE.
The world's opening up faster
than we can replenish
our stores.
We're one major accident away
from catastrophe.
- Okay, okay.
- Don't worry.
You manage what little
we've got left,
and I will get
the blood flowing.
I love your enthusiasm,
but blood drives
aren't as easy...
I got this.
Oh.
Sandra Fall from billing?
Max Goodwin,
the dark overlord.
- Ouch, when did that happen?
- When I got downsized.
Oh, sorry.
There have been too many cuts.
Well, how am I supposed
to cover my rent
or pay my bills?
I'm gonna have to fight my cat
for food.
Wait, no, you won't
because I just had
a great idea.
You can be
my new executive assistant.
You are rehired.
Where are you going?
To find a nice street corner
where I can beg for change
and recyclables.
Come on.
It's not that bad of a gig.
Oh, no?
What happened to Dora?
- Dora quit.
- Oh, what happened to Adele?
- Adele died...
- What?
Of natural causes.
It had nothing to do
with this job.
Listen, I really need your help
putting together
a hospital blood drive.
It is an emergency situation.
It's got to be fast,
impactful, efficient,
and when I think efficient,
I think of Sandra... ow.
- Okay, just for the day?
- I gotta go.
Please, just for the good
of humanity?
How about for your cat's
nutritional autonomy?
- Fine.
- Really?
- I'll do it for Lilith. Okay?
- Yes, fantastic.
- Thank you...
- Okay, no hugging!
No, no, no.
Six feet apart.
And, surprisingly, I've turned
into a compulsive handwasher,
so if you can't find me,
that's where I'll be.
Right, good.
Great.
My office?
My spy craft is
really on point today.
You sleep okay?
Yeah.
Oh, wow.
Wow, I haven't seen
one of these in ages.
What's on a Leyla playlist?
I have to go.
You sure you don't wanna
leave that here?
Mi casa es su casa,
or a closet in this case.
No one's gonna touch it
or your ancient iPod.
Oh, that's gonna make
a huge difference.
Okay.
Good talk.
Operation Blood Flow is a go.
I should start knocking.
No, no.
I'll leave you guys to it.
Thank you, Dr. Shin.
Yes.
So you have an idea
for this Operation Blood Flow?
Yeah... no, uh...
It j...
Just needs some retooling.
Okay, do you want
to talk it over?
Talk about...
no.
Yeah... no.
Minor tweaks, little stuff.
It's... you know.
Yeah, I got it.
I got this.
As our new
associate trauma surgeon,
your primary job will be
backing up Cassian.
Understood.
You do realize that
that means a lot less surgery
than you're used to, right?
Not a problem.
Just put me to work.
Yeah, the ED is not
like the OR.
I can't just...
Anesthesia's tubing a patient
in bay six,
and we're out of Midazolam.
Midazolam. Midazolam...
What are you... whoa!
Hey!
Careful.
- Aha!
- What the hell?
Pharmacy is always running
out of the drugs that we need,
so we keep a secret stash
in the ceiling.
- Is that legal?
- Don't ask.
Like I was saying, the ED is
not structured like the OR.
It's like jazz.
You gotta go with the flow.
Get in the rhythm.
Improvise.
Okay.
I like jazz.
Elisa Barkley,
16-year-old restrained driver
of a car T-boned
by a speeding taxi.
Tachy, multiple hip fractures,
deep laceration
on the upper thigh.
Lost a large volume of blood
at the scene
and became hypotensive
in the field.
Please, help my daughter.
Ma'am, we're gonna take care
of both of you.
Unstable pelvis.
Book an OR.
I'll need at least two units
of trauma blood.
Two units is all we've got.
Then I guess
I'm taking it all.
- OR 2.
- All right.
Yeah.
We need to divert all
knife fights, GSWs, and MVAs.
And pray no one here has
a massive bleed.
Why?
New Amsterdam is officially
out of blood.
We need blood fast.
We gotta target non-sick people
coming into the hospital,
most of whom are parents
who often have their kids
with them,
and what is the one thing
that parents need right now
more than anything?
Time away from their kids.
So the puppies will babysit
the kids,
and we will give the parents
a quiet moment to come in
and give us
their life-saving blood.
Why not just get
human babysitters?
Because the puppies were
already on rotation
in the pediatric ward.
- Max.
- Yes?
Please tell me
you're done retooling
whatever it was
that you were retooling.
- Yeah.
- Hi, Sandra.
Got a lot done, too.
You were busy doing...
other stuff.
By other stuff, I assume
you mean finding out
that the one major accident
we were away from catastrophe
just came in?
That is not what I meant,
but I told you I got this.
So we probably have people
in every seat
lined up around the block.
Take a look for yourself.
Hmm.
You do know that puppy blood
won't work, right?
Okay, my veterans.
Everyone here tested negative.
Congrats.
Let's all take a seat
and get started.
All right?
Um...
Chance, hi.
Really glad you made it.
Everybody, I'd like
to introduce a new recruit.
This is PFC Chance Becker.
He is a cavalry scout
from the 101st Airborne, yes?
Yeah.
Chance, in our one-on-one's,
expressed a little reluctance
at joining this group,
but I assured him
that there's no safer place
than here with his sisters
and brothers,
and he's coming up
on a really tough anniversary.
I thought maybe he could use
a little support.
So welcome.
Good for you.
Thanks, guys.
Here for you, man.
Yeah, we've all
lost something,
so go ahead.
We were, um...
Our convoy, it was...
heading towards an OP
in Kandahar Province.
And we took direct contact
from an AQ element.
Four of my squad members,
they were in the lead vehicle
when it got slammed by RPGs.
It was...
Our driver kinda ran us
off the road, and...
I jumped out.
We were taking small arms fire,
but I just...
But...
I just ran
towards the wreckage.
All I could think was to...
dig out my brothers
and sisters.
Flames, fuel.
I could barely hold it
together.
I called battalion
for a medevac, but...
They were already gone.
Wow.
- Hey, now. Hey, hey, hey.
- Oh, my God. Rhonda!
- What are you doing?
- This guy's a fobbit!
- He's a what?
- I was there!
Then how'd you call it in?
The medevac.
I used...
I called HQ.
No way
this guy's seen combat.
What... okay,
what are you talking about?
He didn't return
suppressor fire
when they got hit.
And no one calls HQ
for a nine line medevac.
Okay.
There are protocols.
We all follow them,
or people die.
He's a fake.
Nothing has changed.
I... I just woke up blind.
Okay, let's take a look.
What about work?
It's not my job.
Ms. Castillo.
It's really important
that I have
all the information.
If they close the factory,
me and my friends will be
out of work again.
We already lost our jobs
during the shutdowns.
We can't lose this, too.
We're still paying off
our rent deferral.
HIPAA privacy laws prevent us
from disclosing
anything you tell us
without your consent.
Please.
This may help me treat you.
I work in a plastics factory.
Off the books.
It's the only work
I could find.
I think
you may have been exposed
to diboron tetrabromide.
It can trigger vasospasm
in the retinal artery,
which is probably what's
causing your blindness.
Probably?
Well, it's a theory.
Can you fix it?
I think so.
I mean, yes, definitely.
Maybe.
Am I going to look
like Frankenstein now?
Oh, not at all.
These are what you call
subcuticular continuous
sutures, all right?
By the time I'm done,
you won't even have a scar.
Dr. Reynolds.
A word?
Excuse me.
How long have you been
stitching for?
I don't know.
I wasn't keeping track...
Exactly.
Okay, this is not the place
where you can take your time
making sure
every suture is
textbook perfect.
We are a conveyor belt
that never stops moving.
So you want me to do
a less good job on my patients?
No, no, not less good.
Faster.
Jazz.
Look, you wanna talk jazz?
Miles Davis?
Following my own meter,
especially when it comes
to my patients.
Okay, Miles.
Well, look.
Here is what backed up
while you were inching your way
through that superficial
four-centimeter scalp lac.
Go ahead,
follow your own meter.
You should be done
by next Wednesday.
Thank you.
Hey, guys.
What are you doing?
Scheduled maintenance.
There was a backpack in here.
A puke-orange backpack.
Where is it?
Don't know.
Well, it was here
this morning.
I'm sorry.
No, no, no, no, no...
Thank you for letting me
do this.
Not at all.
Family members often donate
for a loved one's surgery.
Actually, you're doing us
a favor.
Blood's in short supply
right now.
Take as much as you need.
Take it all.
I'd do anything for my baby.
I'm sorry.
Elisa always says
I'm being melodramatic.
And teenagers never are.
I just need her to be okay.
What's wrong?
Was, um...
was Elisa adopted?
I was in labor with her
for 31 hours.
Did you use an egg donor?
No, her father and I did it
the old-fashioned way.
What's going on?
Were you able to stretch
the two units of blood?
Just about.
Why? Was her mom not a match?
No.
But it's more than that.
What do you mean?
With their blood types,
there's no way
she's Elisa's biological mum.
This is what we should've
been doing the whole time.
I mean, puppies are
a great incentive for kids,
but this is not
the right incentive for adults.
- What they need is...
- Money?
No, this is about
more than money.
It's about tapping in to what
people have really been missing
during this pandemic, you know?
Something that feeds
every New Yorker's soul.
Complaining
about subway delays?
Ye... no. Restaurants.
Eating out.
Experiencing something new.
Something you can only get
right here in New York.
So we are giving everyone
who donates blood a free meal.
And not just any meal.
A multi-course tasting menu
by a Michelin star chef.
First, we're gonna
bleed them.
- Then we're gonna feed them.
- That's actually good.
- So I called Elena Roca.
- Oh, love her.
Yeah, and she agreed
to donate her staff
and her food.
Who could resist?
Wow.
They seem to be resisting
just fine.
All I did was tell my story.
Okay, that's great.
Let's talk about that.
Sit down.
I have a feeling
that you have been telling
that story for quite some time,
and I think that you would
really like that
to be your story.
- I'm not lying.
- Chance.
I have a buddy at the VA
who told me
that you are not in the system.
You're not in
the Choice Program.
Nothing.
You are trying to fill a void
in you.
You are not alone in that.
But the way you're trying
to fill it...
It's called stolen valor.
It's not real.
You were never in Afghanistan,
were you?
There was no ambush.
There were no burned bodies.
Do you know the smell
of burning flesh?
It's sickening.
Never leaves you.
You smell it everywhere.
A match, a candle,
a grill in the park.
All of it brings it back.
I can't go anywhere
without them following me.
Don't tell me
the flames weren't real.
Push 2 milligrams
Ativan IV.
Pushing 2 milligrams
Diboron tetrabromide exposure
doesn't cause seizures.
I don't know what's wrong
with her.
There's a small anomaly here.
I don't see anything.
Right here.
Guess that could explain
Rose's symptoms.
It's really small.
Well, look, you asked
for my opinion?
This is why the Verapamil
didn't work.
So I should start her
on Phenytoin?
If you want her
to get better.
I don't know.
Dr. Kao?
Yes?
It's what
Dr. Kapoor would do.
Anita, the test results
were incompatible
with parental relation.
What does that even mean?
Are you...
Are... are you saying Elisa is
not my daughter?
I'm hoping it's a mistake
our end.
- A simple DNA test will clear...
- Clear what?
Do you think I hallucinated
giving birth to her?
Do you think I stole her?
No one is saying that.
Then what are you saying?
How could my child not be
my child?
If she was switched at birth.
I honestly wish I didn't have
to bring this up,
but I am duty-bound
not just to you,
but if there is another family
out there...
Elisa's my child.
Emotionally, of course.
If the biological...
truth or whatever's different,
I don't want to know.
I do.
Elisa?
I want the test.
Whatcha looking for?
An orange backpack.
Very heavy,
incredibly important.
- Oh, no.
- What was in it?
I have no idea.
Kevin McGlynn, 65.
Complaining of nausea
and sudden abdominal
and lower back pain.
- Tachy?
- 140 BPM.
Thinking a leaking abdominal
aortic aneurism.
Well, then why'd you
bring him here?
We went on diversion
four hours ago.
You're not the only ones
diverting.
Blood shortage is citywide.
Yeah, that's
a pulsatile mass.
- Grab Reynolds.
- Oh, he took lunch.
He took lunch?
- You probably want me to go...
- Find him now.
With me, Trauma One.
Prepare to intubate.
Insert a Foley
and two large bore IVs.
On it.
Please tell me
you found blood.
No.
We've got to be ready
for open repair.
His AAA could blow
at any minute.
We're gonna do this
without blood?
You got a better idea?
- Nice lunch?
- Yeah.
- I usually take lunch at 1:00.
- Yeah, not anymore.
Here, we eat on the go
when you can if you can.
I don't know, I don't know,
I don't know.
I don't know what to believe.
I know that I've lost the trust
of my vet's group.
I know that,
but now I feel like, um...
I feel like
I've missed something.
You know?
I do know
that Chance is suffering.
You think he's telling
the truth?
I think that he's telling
a truth, yeah.
- Did you Google him?
- Gladys.
I refuse to believe
that that is what
our profession has come to.
Okay?
And yeah, I did, obviously.
I couldn't find anything.
Chance?
No, no, no, no.
No, don't say that.
Listen to me.
No, listen, listen.
Just tell me where you are.
Chance, tell me where you are.
- Chance.
- You did this!
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Wait, no, stop, stop!
- Chance, stop, stop, stop!
- Don't! Don't!
Oh, my God, stop!
- Don't!
- Chance.
Okay.
- Okay, okay, okay!
- Don't! Stay back!
You made me go
to that stupid group.
- I did.
- I know, I know.
I'm sorry.
I shouldn't have done that.
Chance, I shouldn't have
done that, but I'm here.
Please, talk to me.
- Why?
- You don't believe me!
- Yes, I do!
- I believe... I believe...
I believe your burns are real.
I believe your pain
is very real.
Chance, look at me!
I believe you.
There was a fire, wasn't there?
There was a fire.
People lie.
People do that.
People lie to impress.
People lie to hide their shame.
I lie to hide my pain.
I do it every day.
Where was the fire?
Tell me where the fire was.
Tell me something.
Tell me one... one true thing.
It was upstate.
Okay, upstate.
There, we started.
That's where
your family's from, right?
That's why you contacted me,
isn't it?
Part of you wanted
to unburden yourself.
You want to tell me the truth.
I'm here.
Tell me.
I was...
I was drunk.
The farm, my family's farm.
What happened?
It was a... a cigarette.
It...
It lit up the barn
and then the house,
and then by the time
I heard them screaming...
I tried to stop it.
My brother,
my big sister,
my parents, gone.
An accident, an accident,
an accident!
An accident, Chance.
- Does it matter?
- Yes, it matters.
All of it matters
because it's real.
It is your truth.
Do you understand?
All the rest of it,
you need to let go.
You need to just let it go.
Rose, it's Dr. Kao.
I've got some new medication
for you.
This one will work.
Sorry, did I scare you?
No.
Then why did you pull away?
I don't know.
Did something happen?
Did someone hurt you?
When?
A month ago.
I was walking home one night.
These two white guys,
they jumped me.
Beat me to the ground.
Blamed me for bringing
the virus to America.
I'm Filipina,
but all they see is...
I know.
Why didn't you tell me?
It was so long ago, and...
I protected my head.
What would that have to do
with blindness?
Did they hit
your abdominal area?
Yes.
Over and over.
Rose.
I think your liver was damaged
in the attack.
But because it happened
weeks ago,
your blood tests looked normal.
But most of your liver is
now not functioning.
It's okay.
We can treat it.
Without a doubt.
We're not doing the test.
Why do you get to make
that decision for me?
Because I'm your mother.
Maybe.
What?
Maybe!
Okay, let's all just
take a breath.
You are not who I want
to hear from right now.
Why can't you understand?
I wanna know where I belong.
You belong with me.
Look at our hands.
Our skin.
You don't get it.
I've always felt different.
I've always looked different.
From the entire family.
I've always felt
like an outsider.
Baby, that's the world
saying that,
not me, not your family.
I've never treated you
different.
How could you even think
something so hurt...
Here comes the melodrama.
There is no way you're my...
We don't need a DNA test.
But I do need a biopsy.
Why?
Because you could both
be right.
Where's all this blood
coming from?
His AAA just ruptured.
Okay, I'm gonna stabilize
the arterial stump
while you cross-clamp
the aorta.
Okay, I have the arterial edge
with my forceps.
I... I can't see anything.
Just follow my forceps down.
Cross-clamp just above the tip.
There are no landmarks.
Go by feel.
Okay, I think I got it.
Suction.
ACC time is 100 minutes.
Bleeding has stopped.
You got it.
But now his liver, kidneys,
and intestines are toast.
Not yet.
We got three minutes to find
a replacement aorta.
You can prepare
a Dacron graft
in three minutes?
92.
Ah.
Give me some of that
suction tubing?
Scissors.
Sponge count?
Suture.
The hell you doing?
Say hello to Mr. McGlynn's...
replacement aorta.
Pared-back space looks clean.
Until we get him up to the OR
for a proper graft.
Are you sure about this?
Jazz, right?
The ED called.
I know, diversion is
diverting back to us.
We have got to make this work.
Max, no one wants fine dining
in the vicinity of nurses
with urine samples,
sick or dying people,
and sirens blaring
in the background.
I know, but I think
I've got something
that's gonna drown out
those sirens,
that's gonna lift
people's spirits,
and for the love of God,
it's gonna inspire them
to donate blood.
- Alcohol?
- Nope.
Broadway.
Jazz hands.
Too much. Desperation. Sorry.
The performers are
former patients,
and with all
the theaters closed,
they jumped at the opportunity
to perform
for a real-life audience.
♪ Down by the riverside
♪ Oh, down
Oh, come on!
Really?
♪ Down by the riverside
Yeah, no, no, we're good
on the singing.
Stop with the singing, please.
Thank you.
Excuse me, can I ask you
a question?
- Me?
- Yeah.
All these people here are
donating their time,
their talents, their food,
their dogs
to get people like you
to donate their blood,
which is desperately needed.
I see you stopped in,
but not quite biting.
So I was just wondering,
what's it gonna take?
Do you have any idea
what people are going through
right now?
I'm homeschooling three kids
while taking care
of my ailing father.
I...
I've donated to every cause
under the sun.
I've marched
for social justice.
I've made meals
for the unhoused.
We're done.
Everyone is tapped.
I know, but... but...
People have given everything
this past year,
except their blood.
And I, for one, would like
to keep that.
- So that's it?
- People are just done giving?
All right, shut it down.
All of it.
You guys can go.
Get the food out of here.
It's over.
So...?
Anita, your biopsy revealed
something unusual.
The technical term for it is,
you're a chimera.
You have two different DNAs
in your body.
How is that possible?
It's a rare condition
that can happen in utero
in twin pregnancies.
But I'm not a twin.
You were.
When you were just an embryo,
you had a fraternal twin
who didn't come to term.
A sister.
In the womb, you absorbed her,
including her ovaries,
and that's the second DNA.
Which is why
the blood test said
you weren't Elisa's mother.
Elisa was born from your body
but from your sister's egg.
So I'm...
I'm not her daughter?
Elisa, you may
look different,
but what this proves
is you're actually more
than your mother's daughter.
Not less.
I'm sorry you felt different.
I should've made you
feel special.
I guess we both kind of are.
Well, I've seen a lot
of AAA open repairs in my time,
but none that used
suction tubing as an aorta.
I accept
your well-concealed apology.
Okay.
You've got your way
of doing things,
I've got mine.
Didn't work out
for us personally.
But professionally,
maybe we've got a future.
Jazz.
You looking for this?
Oh, my God, yes!
Where did you find it?
I saw the painters
setting up,
and I knew you'd freak.
So I grabbed it and stashed it
in the break room.
Thank you, thank you,
thank you.
Yeah, so...
just so I got this straight,
you're letting
a random homeless woman
live in a hospital closet
completely unsupervised.
Well, when you say it
like that,
it does kind of sound crazy.
Yeah, that's because it is.
I mean, what do you even know
about this woman?
Or what's in this bag?
I try to mind
my own business.
Since when?
Look, you are risking a lot
for a random stranger.
If it were me,
I'd wanna know
who I'm protecting.
They, uh...
they painted the closet today.
You went through my stuff,
didn't you?
Should I have?
Are you hiding something?
Wait, d...
It's nothing.
Why be so protective over it?
It's nothing to you,
but it's all I have.
I'm sorry.
It'd just be nice to...
know a little about you,
that's all.
I love Punjabi rap.
And...
Hawaiian pizza.
The kind with the pineapple.
But it's so tacky that I would
never tell anyone that.
It's totally tacky.
♪ Windows of light
Let's go get some.
♪ And everything emptying
Okay.
♪ Into white
This is all you.
It's gonna feel so good
to stop lying to yourself.
You'll see.
Make yourself comfortable,
okay?
♪ A simple garden
♪ With acres of sky
♪ A brown-haired dog-mouse
♪ If one dropped by
♪ Yellow Delanie
♪ Would sleep well at night
♪ With everything emptying
♪ Into white
Dr. Goodwin.
Thought maybe I should check
on you.
Look over your case load
for today.
Thanks.
But I was wrong.
I don't need to check on you
at all.
Rose Castillo?
I don't know any doctor
in this hospital
who could've made
that diagnosis.
I know I couldn't
How did you even think to ask
about her attack?
Something Dr. Kapoor
taught me.
To watch and listen.
When I touched Rose
to put in her IV, she flinched.
I used to do that, too.
Flinch at little movements
and sounds.
Sometimes, I still do.
When COVID was at its worst,
a man stopped me in the street.
He grabbed my arm
and spat in my face.
Then shoved me aside
like I was nothing.
Did you talk to anyone?
No.
It was happening
to so many of us,
and back then,
I just wanted to do my job
and help people.
Dr. Kao,
I shouldn't have made you
interim, interim chair
of neurology.
That was foolish of me.
I should've made you
interim chair
and not taken no for an answer.
And I know that Dr. Kapoor
would agree
this department is yours
till he comes back.
♪ With everything emptying
♪ Into white
Yeah.
Max, we need you
at the drive.
Have you given blood
in the last...
Have you had anything
to eat today?
- Are you feeling all right?
- Yeah.
- Um... hi.
- Mm-hmm?
What happened?
For reasons that escape me,
people are inspired by you.
- Me?
- Yep.
You've asked
the puppy wranglers
and the chefs
and the jazz hand people
to donate their skills...
Yeah, but I didn't ask them
to donate...
I mean, they'd donate
anything for you.
So now they're donating
what you really need
and called a few friends.
Well, that's amazing.
You're hired.
- Oh! Oh...
- Full-time.
Oh, goddess, help me.
Okay, you can stop that now.
- Come on, bring it in.
- Okay.
- We did it.
- Wow.
- Yep, we did.
- That's good.
- Sorry about that.
- Okay, nope.
- Got excited.
- Human touch, wow.
- Okay.
♪ Beautiful dreamer
♪ Wake unto me
♪ Starlight and dewdrops
♪ Are waiting for thee
♪ Sounds of the rude world
♪ Heard in the day
You know,
there's really no reason
things should be awkward
between us.
I know.
That'd be silly.
I haven't tried that yet.
That's good, right?
Okay, I'll do this one then.
Thank you.
Why didn't you tell me?
Didn't realize
I was supposed to.
No, you don't have to...
You're not supposed to tell me.
I just kinda thought
you might want to.
I see.
So you tell me everything.
There's no secrets between us.
- Well...
- Yeah, I knew it.
You don't know what I was
gonna say.
Oh, I know what you were
I highly doubt that.
You were seeing someone
last year.
Yeah.
That's exactly what
I was gonna say.
How'd you know that?
Why didn't you tell me?
I didn't tell anyone.
Why?
Because...
Be... I don't know.
It was...
It was fragile,
and I just thought...
that I should protect...
Protect what?
♪ Beautiful dreamer
♪ Beam on my heart
Excuse me.
M'lady.
May I have this dance?
I would be delighted,
kind sir.
Excuse me.
♪ Then will all clouds
♪ Of sorrow depart
♪ Beautiful dreamer
♪ Awake unto me
♪ Beautiful dreamer, awake
♪ Unto me