Previously, on
"New Amsterdam"...
Isn't that
why I'm here?
Because you feel guilty
for ignoring your brother
for all those years.
You're here
because you're my family.
That you ignored
for your whole life!
I was the one
who was ignored first!
My mother's raised
three kids,
owns her own home,
prays harder than anyone I know
for everyone else,
and now she needs
full-time care.
- What are you doing?
- I'm leaving.
No, come on.
Don't do this.
Why not?
I'm transferring you
to another therapist.
I'm sorry.
I had
a tremendous breakthrough
with the new patient.
Is that his hat?
♪ Talk that talk, hey
♪ Better walk that walk,
clap hands now ♪
♪ Talk that talk, hey
♪ Better walk that walk,
clap hands now ♪
♪ Talk the talk, baby
♪ Walk the walk
- ♪ Walk the walk
- Thank God.
103 degree heat,
suffocating exhaust fumes,
the sun reflecting
off every glass tower.
As you can see, she took it
with great dignity.
Oh, were you burning up
out there?
Come here.
I gotcha.
- Goodness gracious.
- Oh, I gotcha.
I think somebody needs
a little turbine cooldown.
- Max!
- No, she's fine.
She likes it.
God, it gets hotter every year.
I can't believe
it's not even June.
What is the world gonna be like
when you're a grown-up?
Because it is a slow moving
train wreck right now,
and nobody is doing anything...
Could you speak up?
I can't hear you
over the turbines
belching freon into the air.
Well, I make up for it,
all right?
I turn on the low flow nozzle
in the shower.
I compost.
I-I...
I turn off the faucet
whenever I'm brushing my teeth.
Okay?
Every time.
I have like 60 of those
reusable cloth shopping bags.
Yeah, so you won't mind
if I turn this off?
No, no, no,
just a second longer
'cause it's, you know,
making her comfortable.
Yeah, which makes you
comfortable.
Everyone talks a good game
about sacrifice
right up until the second
it threatens their comfort,
including you, Max.
♪ Talk that talk, hey
♪ Better walk that walk,
clap hands now ♪
♪ Talk that talk, hey
♪ Better walk that walk,
clap hands now ♪
♪ Talk that talk, hey
♪ Better walk that walk,
clap hands now ♪
♪ Talk that talk, hey
♪ Better walk that walk,
clap hands now ♪
- ♪ Oh, yeah, it's so you
- Coming through.
Jerry, tell me this isn't
how much trash
you throw out every day.
- Oh, no way.
- Thank God.
That's how much we throw out
by 7:00 a.m.
Hey, Jer, you dropped one.
- Eh, toss it.
- Toss it?
- It's unopened.
- Don't worry about it.
We got thousands
of these things.
Most of the patients throw 'em
in the garbage anyway.
You're cutting out
the middle man.
♪ Talk that talk, hey
♪ Better walk that walk,
clap hands now ♪
♪ Talk that talk, hey
♪ Better walk that walk,
clap hands now ♪
♪ Talk the talk, baby
♪ Walk the walk
*NEW AMSTERDAM (2018)*
♪ Talk the talk, baby
Season 03  Episode 11
♪ Walk the walk
Episode Title: "Pressure Drop"
♪ Talk the talk, baby
Aired on: May 11, 2021
♪ Walk the walk
♪ Talk the talk, baby
I can't believe you took
a whole week off to be with me.
Uhhh! Well, I haven't taken
a vacation day since 2009.
So was it worth it?
I'm pretty sure I answered
that question several times.
Mm.
You're gonna be late.
- I'm the boss.
- Bosses can be late.
Well, in that case...
Not that late,
but we can pick up right here
when I get back later.
Mina!
Mina, the hospital
is the other way.
Look, I know you're not
thrilled
about the prospect of therapy,
but it helps to have someone
to talk to who can see things
that you might be missing.
- I'm not going to therapy.
- Mina, will you listen to me?
I mean, one of those
American therapists
with those questions:
How do you feel about this?
How does this make you feel?
I'm not going back
to that hospital.
You need someone
to talk to.
I agree.
Islamic Center?
Don't look so surprised.
I grew up going to places
like this.
Yeah, no, of course.
Mina, I'm not against
you coming here.
It's just that I booked you
an appointment.
So you take it
'cause I think you're the one
who's missing something,
Ammeh Joon,
and you don't even know it's gone.
Hey, Dr. Frome!
You need to take this.
Was that why you wanted
to see me?
Man, I'm sorry.
I could have just come by.
Yeah, I know.
I should have told you
about Martin.
This needs to stop right now.
It was stupid.
I... I didn't mean
to freak anybody out, I swear.
It's only 'cause you wouldn't
see me.
You're not my patient
anymore.
You're not
my husband's patient.
Chance, you lied your way
into my home.
But you could help me
when no one else could.
I was getting better.
You know it's true.
I need you.
Just take the hat, please.
Don't do this to me.
I'm not doing anything
to you, Chance.
These are the consequences
for your actions,
your choices.
And if you continue
down this path,
I will get the police
involved.
What?
For your safety
and for mine,
you can no longer see me
or my husband.
Is that clear?
This behavior is dangerous.
It is obsessive.
And I don't want to do this,
but if you don't stop,
I will be forced to file a
restraining order against you.
Now show me
that you understand.
There's the boss!
Thought you decided you were
never gonna come back.
How was the week off?
It was fantastic, could not
have been more relaxing.
I'm glad you're rested
because your ED is a total,
complete train wreck right now.
Come on, we're always
in shambles during a heat wave.
I'm sure it's nothing
we can't handle.
You say that now.
Before you let it rip,
I'm aware that we're not
supposed to use the hallways
as overflow.
Casey, I appreciate you,
and I don't tell you that
enough.
What?
Okay, where's Turan?
- I know we're backed up.
- I'm working as fast as I can.
- It's fine.
- You're fine.
It is?
I am?
Yeah, whatcha got?
Got a patient brought in
by a concerned family member
complaining
of mild dehydration.
He doesn't look dehydrated.
That's because
he's not the patient.
Hey, Javier.
Why don't you tell the doctor
what you can do?
I can control the weather
with my mind.
Okey dokey.
I am gonna be right back.
Let's ask him
to make it cooler,
and then get Iggy down here.
Dr. Bloom, I know you said
only bother you
when absolutely necessary...
Especially on a day
like today, but I...
- Hit me, my friend.
- Oh, okay.
We got an interesting case.
Sister Edith Pursey,
a cloistered nun
from the Monastery
of the Precious Blood.
Let me guess,
she's hot.
No, she's cold...
Freezing, actually.
We just can't seem
to get her warm.
Could be anemia.
She has a low hematocrit.
Okay, let's double up
the warming blankets,
page Sharpe, and Dr. Walsh...
- And here it comes.
- What?
No, no, I was just gonna
suggest that you move her
from the nurse's station
to a procedure room.
Geez, why does everyone think
I'm gonna bite their head off?
Who says you can't run an ED
and be nice to people?
You did.
You said that last week.
Dr. Bloom, we are officially
out of space,
at capacity,
and it's not even lunch.
No problem, okay?
I am gonna fix it.
It's easy-peasy, okay?
Great work, everybody!
Great work.
Maybe I need a vacation.
The man knows Mama has
diabetes, Courtney.
Every time I turn around,
boyfriend is showing up
with poundcake
or scrapple and eggs.
What can I say?
They're in love.
Look, no one is taking this
seriously.
I'm up three times a night
every week checking her levels
'cause this guy's got
her blood sugar all jacked up.
- I'm telling you...
- Help, somebody help!
- He's trapped in the car!
- I gotta go.
- Must be boiling in there.
- What's going on?
- There's a kid in the car.
- Let me see.
- How long?
- Don't know.
I already called 911.
Anybody got a knife,
a pocket knife?
Or a pen?
Like, a heavy-duty pen?
I have a pen.
All right, stand back.
Okay.
Hey, man,
there's a hospital...
I know, I know.
- Sorry, but we're at capacity.
- We're not staying.
- What happened?
- Kid was locked in a damn car.
He's got a core temp of 107.
Out of the way!
I'm gonna get him up to the OR
for sedation, intubation,
and cold water gastric lavage.
Your hand's bleeding.
Just a scratch.
Oh, Max!
- About this heat wave...
- Yeah, tell me about it.
Did you know that sea level
rise will nearly triple deaths
from contaminated
drinking water
by the end of the century?
Oh, and my ED is already
at capacity.
This is not sustainable.
Couldn't agree more,
and we are part of the problem.
Don't get me started
on New Amsterdam's
carbon footprint.
I wasn't planning on it.
So to my point, I need
more staff, overflow beds,
and a second
ambulance triage unit.
- I will do you one better.
- Overtime pay?
I'm gonna fix
global warming...
at New Amsterdam.
Melting polar ice caps,
deforestation,
temperatures are expected
to rise at least ten degrees
in the next century,
and the people in charge
of solving this
can't even agree
that it's real.
So now it's up to us.
The radiology department?
Because global warming
is a healthcare emergency.
Who do you think's gonna
bear the brunt
of unchecked wildfires,
mass migration,
toxic algae blooms?
- The radiology department?
- Hospitals.
So here, today, together,
the people in this room
are gonna take up the fight
against global warming.
Now, I would like to debut
my new flagship program...
"The Gloves Are Off."
- Wait, literally?
- Yeah, literally.
Single-use latex gloves account
for 20% of our medical waste.
Do you know where that waste
ends up, Mike?
We need to wear gloves,
Dr. Goodwin.
Wrong answer.
On a barge, Mike.
It ends up on a barge.
I also would have accepted
"in our oceans."
So we are all gonna try
something new.
We are only gonna get one box
of gloves per day.
- Per person?
- Wrong again.
For the entire department.
What about
infectious patients?
Well, that's why
I chose radiology.
Your patients
are already diagnosed.
Nobody needs gloves to simply
walk a patient into an MRI.
But gloves are
how we protect ourselves
- from, you know, germs.
- Uh-huh.
But handwashing is undeniably
more effective,
which is why every
scrubs station and bathroom
on this floor has been stocked
with extra biodegradable soap.
Now, who's ready to save
this planet?
Say it with me, guys.
The gloves are...
Off.
Thank you, Jerry.
I'm not crazy.
No one said you were.
I didn't say you were crazy.
I just... you know,
it's rare to see someone
who can control the weather
with their mind.
I knew it.
You don't believe me.
- No, wait, wait.
- No, no, no, no.
You know, it's my brother
who is sick.
I just agreed to take him
to the emergency room.
- I don't need any of this.
- That's cool.
We're just...
We're just talking here, okay?
Just me and you.
Your brother, he's downstairs.
He's getting his fluids
replenished, and...
Can I come clean with you?
Can we sit?
Confession time here.
The only reason
I brought you up here
is because I'm kind of
a weather nerd myself.
- You are?
- Just a touch.
I named my first pet El Niño.
So yeah, you be the judge.
I just... I have to ask you
a couple questions
about your, you know,
your powers.
This brutal heat wave outside,
is that...
is that you?
Yeah.
Whoa.
How do you... how do you do it?
I get this throbbing feeling.
Starts in my head.
Then it moves down
through my whole body.
Then everything goes black,
and that's when it got hot.
That's it?
Are we done here?
Wait, um, look.
This is really exciting for me,
like, beyond,
and I know it's a big ask,
but, um,
Javier, can I get a scan
of that brain of yours?
- A scan?
- Yeah, I just...
I need to see what makes you
so special.
I know that's a big ask,
like I said,
and if you wanna say no, I will
respect that and back away,
but... I have to ask.
Sure.
- I guess.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
- Awesome.
That's awesome.
I am so sorry
to cancel Mina's session
last minute, Serena.
No, no, everything's fine,
except for the fact
that she doesn't listen,
she's completely
out of control,
and I don't know what more
I have to give her.
Sorry?
Me?
No, I don't need therapy.
I have to go, Serena.
Sister Pursey.
Hi, I'm Dr. Sharpe.
I hear you're the only person
in the city
not melting
from this heat wave.
It's not as promising
as it sounds.
Don't tell me I got this virus.
- Oh, no, no, it's not COVID.
- Okay.
Although your temperature
is still only 94.5.
- Do you mind if I take a look?
- No, please.
A little different from your
usual day-to-day, I imagine.
It's my first day outside
the convent in almost...
Oh, goodness... almost 30 years.
- Gosh!
- Mm-hmm.
Well, I'm sorry this is where
you have to spend it.
Will you excuse me a moment,
please?
- No, of course.
- Thank you.
Dr. Walsh.
I ordered four tests.
Why did I just see one?
Oh, I just ordered
the thyroid test.
And why would you do that?
Well, the ED was so jammed,
and hypothyroidism seemed like
the obvious diagnosis.
So you thought
that you'd just ignore me
and do whatever you wanted?
Sorry, what year
of your residency are you in?
And let's all just
lower the temperature.
A little heat joke
to diffuse the tension.
When I order four tests,
it's not a suggestion.
- It's an order.
- Helen.
Walsh.
We're doing the best we can.
What's going on with you?
With me?
Actually, do you know what?
It's fine, it's fine!
I'll run the tests myself.
Fran, I need a full-body PET
scan on my incoming patient...
Not a half body,
not a quarter body,
a full-body PET scan,
and you're out of gloves.
Yeah, we've already used up
our daily allotment
of exam gloves.
There's a ladies' room
with some biodegradable soap,
or you can wipe your hands
on your pants.
Max is solving global warming.
BP's down to 90 over 40.
Hang a bag of normal saline
at 15 degrees Celsius.
Run it wide open
into his central line.
Repositioning the catheter.
Inflating manual cuff.
Core temps still elevated.
Then push .2 milligrams
of Ativan.
- I need a syringe.
- Drop the temp on the cooling blanket.
Give me tape and scissors.
Come on, we've got to make
some headway here.
Much longer
and his brain's gonna fry.
Get me four by fours.
Gauze.
Core temp down to 38.2.
All right, lighten up
on the anesthesia.
Got it.
Oh, I didn't call
for a consult.
- How's he doing?
- Alive, barely.
Some idiot left him
locked in a car.
In this weather,
that's borderline criminal.
I'm sorry, why are you here?
He's my son.
Gretchen, what's
with the gloves?
Gloves, gloves.
Are you kidding me?
- Who restocked the closet?
- I did.
I'm sorry, let me get
this knife out of my back.
Your heart's
in the right place, Max.
It is, so why...
But your idealism
is ridiculous.
You know
what's not ridiculous?
Lung cancer, which is set
to increase exponentially
from pollution unless
we do something, anything,
about climate change,
like limiting exam gloves.
During a global pandemic,
Max?
- CDC recommends soap and...
- Listen.
If you want to battle
climate change,
then become a vegetarian,
buy an electric car,
invest in solar panels.
There are any number of things
that you could do
that we'd all be on board with,
but not like this.
The gloves are back on.
Max Begley Jr., come on!
Joining the climate fight,
I'm so proud.
Well, it's now
or, quite literally, never.
Yeah, I'm in, I'm in.
110% in.
When I think about the Earth
that our kids are inheriting,
it just... it breaks my heart,
so I really hope
this little glove debacle
doesn't slow you down any.
No, no way, I am committed
to ending global warming
- at New Amsterdam...
- Well, obviously.
Which by the way,
did you know,
is causing massive upticks
in vector diseases like
dengue fever, Zika, Lymes...
I'm already seeing increases
in stress, anxiety,
sleep disorders
in neighborhoods
- with poor air quality, right?
- Yeah.
I mean, sacrifices
need to be made.
Which is why I just came up
with an even bigger idea.
Even bigger?
Max Thunberg,
what have you done?
You eliminated red meat
from all patient meals?
Every rib, patty,
and sirloin.
But you can't do that.
I can, and I did
because New Amsterdam
is getting ready
for "turning down the meat
on global warming."
I'm not sure if that's
a slogan or an HR violation,
but we are not complying.
Do you hear me?
New Amsterdam buys 7,384 pounds
of red meat per week.
That is 13,291,000 gallons
of water,
and do you want to guess
how much methane
is produced by those cows?
No.
Good, 'cause that's the one
statistic I did not memorize,
but it is a lot.
Dr. Goodwin, I don't think
you quite understand
the effect this is going
to have...
No red meat?
My patients are going
to revolt.
- There will be violence.
- Over this?
Come on.
It's healthier.
Studies show that cutting out
red meat reduces the risk
of heart disease as well
as most cancers,
and we've been doing it
in cardio for years.
Well, I don't work in cardio,
Dr. Goodwin, I work in OB,
and when a patient's been
sucking ice chips for two days,
squeezing a bowling ball
out of their vagina
during an 18-hour labor,
believe me, they want blood.
- They want steak.
- Right, okay.
Well, if new mothers are
craving iron post childbirth,
you can lovingly
and instructively point them
toward legumes.
- You're gonna get me killed.
- Dr. Goodwin!
Every single patient in post-op
is complaining about our food.
Yeah.
How exactly is that any
different from any other day?
But without any history
of mental illness
and his delusions,
it has to be one of two things:
One, neurological...
- My bet would be meningioma.
- Yeah.
A small tumor impeding
his limbic system
could explain his behavior.
Right, or two,
he's a Tempestarii.
- Just tell me.
- I'm glad you asked, Dr. Kao.
Tempestarii were medieval
magicians who believed
that they could control
the weather with their minds.
- That's odd.
- Well, not really.
People used to believe
in giants back then, elves...
- No, no, no.
- Wacky stuff.
- I meant his scan.
- Oh, why?
- What do you see?
- Nothing.
No meningioma, no tumors,
nothing that would explain
his delusional state.
- Well, what does that mean?
- It means you're right.
He must be
a medieval weather magician.
He's doing much better now.
Thank you.
I had six surgeries yesterday,
one scheduled
for early this morning.
The employee lot was full,
so I had to park on the street.
Hey, look,
I don't need to hear this.
I need you to understand.
So I'm raising him on my own,
and school's on, school's off.
Sometimes I drive him,
sometimes I don't,
and so this morning,
I drove to the hospital
instead of the school.
I got an emergency page,
and so I just ran,
and hey, I forgot.
I... I forgot he was there.
He was asleep.
It was a mistake.
He's your son.
He should have been
your priority.
He's m... he is.
He is.
Tell that to social services.
Maybe they'll understand.
- What happened?
- She's in V-tach.
Heart rate shot up to 150.
Clear.
She's back.
Okay, let's get her
on amiodarone,
150 milligram IV.
That happened
because she has endocarditis.
What?
According to the test results
I ordered initially,
she's fighting
a raging infection.
Walsh, let's get her
on triple antibiotic therapy,
amp, gent, and vanco.
On it.
If your staff had just done
the work-up I asked them to
in the first place, we would
have known this hours ago.
- Spared the woman a code...
- On your left.
- You need an overflow, Lauren.
- Your ED's a mess.
Yeah, well,
I spoke to Max this morning.
- He says he's on it.
- Ha!
By taking away gloves from
radiology and meat from OB?
All right, I'll remind him.
Remind him?
A week ago,
you would have demanded it,
and he would've opened up
a triage unit already.
Whatever the hell you did
on vacation,
you need to shake it off.
You've gone soft, and it's
putting our patients at risk.
Max, hey, hi.
So, listen.
I just tried to order
a hamburger in the cafeteria...
I know, you can't.
Isn't that great?
Right.
I was under the impression
this was more
of a patient-centered
type program.
No, no, no.
It's gotta be hospital-wide.
Otherwise patients would just
have family members
go down to the cafeteria, and
they'd grab a burger for them,
and then we'd be wasting
all those perfectly good
vegetarian meals.
Right, yeah, uh-huh.
But do we really want
to dictate what people can eat?
- Is that our thing?
- Yeah.
I think that's exactly
what we want to dictate.
Well, what if a doctor just
wants a simple hamburger?
Then a doctor
can go off campus
and get a simple hamburger.
What if a doctor has patients
all afternoon,
and his 1:15 process meeting
got pushed back by half an...
Iggy, I thought
you were on board.
I am.
I am... oh, I so am.
I just... you know,
I'm on the keto diet,
and I'm not sure you know what
that does to a man, right?
I'm giving up cake, and bread,
and desserts, and French fries,
and every kind of sweet
you can imagine, you know?
And I'm down to wrapping my
burger patty in wilted lettuce,
and if we have it your way,
I'll just have, uh...
I just have the lettuce.
So you need to reinstate
the meat.
- Okay.
- Okay?
- Yeah.
- Really?
Sure, just answer me this:
How are we gonna
make a difference
when nobody is willing
to change a single thing?
No, no, no, no.
I am all for change.
I'm all about change.
You know that.
I'm here, I am down to change
the planet with you.
I'm right by your side.
Just, um... just not like this.
How are we feeling, Sister?
B...
B... mm.
Okay, just relax.
Relax.
- Dr. Bloom!
- Yeah?
It's okay.
- What's going on?
- She's slurring her words.
- She's aphasic.
- This isn't endocarditis.
How did I get it so wrong?
Whatever it is,
it's moved up to her head.
- It's attacking her brain.
- Autoimmune disease.
But I would've seen signs
of inflammation.
What the...?
Excuse me.
What are you doing?
Swapping out all the
fluorescents in the hospital
with energy-efficient LEDs.
Why?
Because Dr. Goodwin's
"shedding light
on global warming."
And you're doing this now,
in the middle of the day,
when we're stuffed
to the gills?
It's a big hospital.
Lot of light bulbs.
And you're not supposed to be
wearing those gloves anymore.
- Kevin!
- That's it.
Get me Max down here
now.
Mom is having a problem.
- What? What's up?
- You were right.
Her blood sugar
is off the charts.
See?
This is exactly what I was
talking about.
Okay, listen to me.
Go to the fridge.
Give her ten more units
of insulin.
It should be the last
of the bottle.
This bottle's full, Floyd.
It can't be.
Wait, there's another one
in here.
Another one?
It's an old prescription.
Wait, what?
It's expired.
No.
No, no, no.
That's not right.
Yeah, it's in front
of the milk, right?
Expiration five weeks ago.
Oh...
That's what I've been
giving her all week.
Are you serious?
The whole reason
you're staying with her
is to monitor her meds...
You could have killed her!
It was a mistake, I...
Okay, so first of all,
let me thank you again
for letting me take a look
at that brain of yours.
- What an honor.
- So you believe me?
You have quite the gift,
truly,
and your brother and I
were actually hoping
that maybe you would consider
staying on longer here
at the hospital with me,
so I could study you further.
Um...
no.
Just hear me out.
Your power is unusual,
and I would really like to know
what's actually happening here.
I'm fascinated.
I knew it.
I'm not making this up.
- We're trying to help you.
- By tricking me?
Lying to me?
Trying to lock me away
in some psych ward?
Because you're acting crazy!
Hey, now,
we don't use that term.
Javi, you're sick.
You need help.
We're trying to help.
There's nothing wrong
with me.
Your brother is just
concerned for you, okay?
He's worried.
We all just want what's best.
You want proof?
Here's proof.
You want more proof?
- Javier.
- How about this?
Oh, oh, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Grab him, grab him.
Gently, gently, gently.
Get him on his side.
- Javi, open your eyes.
- Gladys!
Javi.
Yeah?
I asked you for help
this morning,
and you have done
absolutely nothing.
I've been trying
to make changes all day.
- To combat climate change.
- Exactly.
I asked you for help
in my ED, Max.
And my changes would
significantly reduce
your patient load.
Years from now, not today.
My ED is coding today.
Okay, so when do we make
changes?
You tell me.
We run 24/7.
There's never gonna
be a good time
to change the lightbulbs,
or try a new policy,
or do anything
of any consequence.
We all say that we wanna fight
climate change,
just not like this.
Do you know what
"not like this" means?
It means never,
and never means
a lot of patients.
It means human suffering
on a scale
that we can't even imagine.
Max.
No, we can be a model for
other hospitals in New York,
for the country, the world
if we can cement
one single change...
Enough!
I am running
an emergency department,
not an environmental
think tank.
I don't care about
my carbon footprint,
or yours, or this hospital's.
I don't care
how many gloves I use,
or how many syringes I toss,
or my emissions.
I care about the patients
in this ED
lining these hallways
and waiting in ambulances
halfway around the damn block.
So stop making changes
that are gonna help people
a hundred years in the future,
and get me more staff,
more beds,
and a second triage unit,
so we can start helping people
right now.
Javier, the surgery was
a success.
How'd you know
how to fix him?
Do you guys know
what barometric pressure is?
I heard of it,
but what's that got to do
with my brother's brain?
Excellent question.
So barometric pressure
is the weight of the atmosphere
all around us, and it can
affect the human body
in many, many ways.
Like, for example,
if the air pressure is lower,
it pushes against
the body less,
allowing tissues to expand.
And when the storm started,
the drop in pressure opened
a fistula in Javier's brain.
And that fistula was hiding
a small benign tumor,
hiding it even from the MRI.
And that's what was causing
Javier's delusions.
I know.
It's been that kind of day.
So I wasn't controlling
the weather?
No, no, the weather was
controlling you, in fact,
which sadly is something
I think we're all gonna have
to get used to.
- How are you feeling, Sister?
- The same.
What's wrong with me?
We have run some more tests,
but at this stage,
we just don't know.
I have faith.
I'm not gonna lie.
I could use some of that
right about now.
Are there any spare rooms going
at your convent?
I'm not sure
that would be any help.
I found mine on a bender
in Panama.
Oh, you're serious?
You found your faith
on a bender in Central America?
Oh, yes.
At your age, I was what you'd
call a raging alcoholic.
- Sister Edith.
- It's true.
That summer backpacking...
Partying, really.
I think it took about six weeks
until I lost everything,
my backpack, my passport,
friends.
I managed to push everyone
and everything away.
I thought it would make me feel
more safe,
but I was never so alone.
And then suddenly, I wasn't.
I had faith.
It was all that was left,
and what I was missing,
and I never lost it again.
- In... in Panama.
- Yeah, that's right.
Will you excuse me a moment,
please?
She has malaria.
What are you talking about?
She's a cloistered nun.
Yeah, now, but 30 years ago,
she was a party girl in Panama.
You can't be serious.
She had a whole life
before joining the convent.
So, what, it's been dormant
all this time?
And only now triggered
due to the heat wave.
Look, her body temp,
her blood smear.
Cerebral malaria.
Get her
on intravenous artesunate.
I just couldn't see it
because I only saw one part
of who she is.
Apology accepted.
Dr. Reynolds.
What's gonna happen to him?
There's a lot
to unpack there,
but leaving a child locked
in a car in New York City
can constitute endangerment.
He could go to jail,
lose his son.
Is that...
is that too far?
The boy was five,
Dr. Reynolds,
abandoned in a car.
You found him.
You saw.
Right, right, right, right,
but you didn't...
you didn't see the look
on his face
when he came into my OR,
he had the...
His eyes.
I'm sure he felt awful,
but our concern must be
for the safety of the child.
Right, right,
that's why I called, but...
But what?
It was a mistake.
He made a mistake.
Is this a recommendation
for leniency?
It's a recommendation
for forgiveness.
- Coming through.
- Oop, sorry.
Hey, Jerry, you need some help
with that?
I won't say no.
I'm going to eight.
Yeah, or, and I'm really
gonna blow your mind
with this one, we could get off
at the next floor
and take the elevator?
- No can do.
- No?
Gotta get in my steps.
Heart issue, and I promised
my kids I'd stick around
to see 'em get married,
have kids of their own.
Well, that must feel good.
Don't get me wrong, man.
The exercise sucks.
I hate it, every step,
but someone's gotta make sure
the grandkids are Mets fans,
so I suck it up
and get it done.
What's the smile for?
I owe you an apology.
I came in here this morning
thinking
that I could make changes
without disrupting your lives.
Clearly, I was wrong.
So I'm gonna try
something else.
I'm gonna disrupt your lives
on purpose.
We're all
in favor of change
right up until the moment
it makes us uncomfortable.
So we're going
King Solomon here.
Since I can't implement
any changes
without upsetting someone,
I'm gonna implement
all of my changes at once
and upset everyone.
I didn't think
it could get any worse.
That's what they said
about climate change.
I'm asking everyone
to be annoyed,
inconvenienced, uncomfortable.
It will unquestionably suck,
but doing nothing is worse.
So we'll all put up
with the lightbulbs
and the fewer gloves.
And the surgeons
will say goodbye
to single-use scalpels,
and the anesthesiologists
will account
for their greenhouse gasses.
We will all dig
a little deeper,
and cope with a leafy salad
because if we want any chance
of a better future
for our kids,
there is only one move left:
Suck it up and get it done.
The only thing I can promise
is that we'll all hate it
together.
Annoying, but inspired.
You know, I get that a lot.
So what ridiculous name
are we calling this program?
Our last chance.
Ah, Ignatius, you are needed.
Oh, somebody knows
my core issues.
- Wine?
- Uh, yes, please.
Thank you,
and do we have children?
We do.
Saleem and Raffi
are mainlining "Fortnite,"
Harper is on a clothing strike,
Sameera will be back
from the park any minute,
and I chose the hottest day
of the year to bake a chicken.
Oh, my gosh.
I love my life.
I love you.
This is amazing, thank you.
Papa, Papa!
- I hit a ball!
- Ah, here's our slugger.
- I hit an overhand ball.
- Yes, Sameera, that's...
Sweetheart, why don't you go
tell your brothers and sisters?
Oh, hold on, kiddo.
- Where did you get the hat?
- Your friend.
"It hadn't rained for ages,
so the ground was very dry.
"He stamped his hooves,
he reared, he bucked,
and made the biggest
dust clouds ever."
♪ Take my love
♪ Take it slow
♪ Night to night
♪ It's finally home
"Just then, Mom called Gus.
"'Come along, dear,
we're going on a long walk.'
'But I wanna make dust clouds, '
said Gus."
♪ Can you know
♪ People are looking
for something ♪
♪ They think they lost
long ago? ♪
♪ When the hate blows over
♪ Hold my hand out
♪ I see your home
I hope you're hungry, boss.
How was the first day back?
We have to break up.
I...
I run the ED
at a major hospital,
and I don't have the time,
okay?
To be thinking about the...
smell of your hair
or your lips.
You make me soft, okay?
And soft puts my patients'
lives at risk.
I'm sorry.
But this is over.
I'm serious, okay?
Can you not... can...
Stop laughing at me.
Haven't you ever heard
of balance?
Give and take.
Hard and soft.
Be hard out there,
but in here,
with me...
So,
I can't break up
with you?
Not a chance.
♪ I wanted something
like this ♪
♪ I wanted something like
♪ I wanted something
like this ♪
♪ I wanted something like
♪ I wanted something
like this ♪
I know.
Got you.
Hot.
You hot?
- Yeah.
♪ I wanted someone like
♪ I wanted something
like this ♪