Previously on The Resident...
I have multiple sclerosis.
We could always use more
women in neurosurgery,
but I would never
try to recruit you.
- Why?
- Devon would kill me, for one thing.
He'll support whatever
I choose to do.
- Kit, I'm leaving Chastain.
- A leave of absence.
- Of course, to heal...
- No, permanently.
I was raped by our
neighbor. I was 13.
- He was a grown man.
- Billie...
Hey, come here.
No, I'm fine.
You're getting soaked.
I'm not gonna melt. Promise.
Hey, I need some help!
Hey. I was headed to a call
when I found her on the
Centerville exit off of 124.
She was all by herself.
She's limping, and
she's freezing cold.
She needs help, so I
brought her straight here.
You did the right
thing. What's your name?
She hasn't said a word
since I found her. She
hasn't cried either.
Not a sound.
I'm gonna take you inside
and get you warm, okay?
I'm a doctor. I won't hurt you.
I'm gonna take care
of you, I promise.
Don't be afraid.
My little girl made
that. Do you like it?
Okay.
-  Here we go.
- Thanks, Doc.
What happened?
Tow truck driver brought her in.
Found her alone by
the side of the road.
She is not speaking.
Clara, let's get a temp, change
her out of these clothes,
and get her on the monitor.
It's not registering.
She's hypothermic.
We need a core temp.
And some blankets
and warmed saline.
I'm on it.
Her right arm.
Posterior shoulder dislocation.
- No swelling around the joint.
- Let's reduce that, quick.
This will hurt, but then it
will feel much better, okay?
Not a peep.
- What's going on?
- I don't know.
Clara, can you call Winston?
- Tell him we have an unaccompanied minor.
- Yeah.
So, I did the math.
For you to be double
board-certified
in neuro and
cardiothoracic surgery,
it would take you,
like, eight years.
Think about it, Devon. I could
drain a brain bleed on a Monday
and hold a beating heart
in my hands on a Tuesday.
Look, I love that you want to do
all the things,
but I'm just concerned that
you're gonna get burned out.
There's only 24 hours in a day.
I'm spending two of them
standing outside in the rain
so you can buy sneakers.
Come on, the line's moving.
You're a good woman.
Look at you all
coming out in the rain
for this drop.
From my heart, I thank you.
- Now, come and get these kicks.
Oh, damn. These black
vapor lows are fire.
Geez. I have to have these.
Hey, Haircut. Caught your
drip the moment you walked up,
and I saw you eyeing
these.
Are you feeling all right?
Oh, don't worry about me.
I just got "big girl-itis."
My name is Dr. Pravesh.
This is Dr. Devi.
Seems like you're
having some chest pain.
Why don't we just
take a seat here.
I just need
another antacid.
Will you hand me my purse?
Just gonna
check your pulse.
How many of these
have you taken today?
Uh... all of them.
- Your heart is racing.
- It's just nerves, is all.
This is my big day. I have
been planning this for months.
We need to get
you to a hospital.
No, no, no, no,
no, ham, no, ma'am.
There is a photographer
coming from Best of Atlanta.
I got an interview later.
You could be having
a heart attack.
No. I... No.
-  - We are not
gonna take no for an answer.
Hey.
Hope you didn't
have plans later.
No problem. I
already cleared my schedule.
I want to hang out with
my new best friend here.
I'm sad to say no one's ever
mistook me for Mary Poppins.
Shoulder should
be feeling better.
Can you move your arm for me?
So, she understands what
we say. Follows direction.
That's progress.
Winston's here.
Nurse Clara's gonna
take care of you
while we talk to Winston, okay?
Be right back.
- Thanks for coming.
- Oh, not a problem at all.
You have an unaccompanied minor?
She was left on the side of the
road with a dislocated shoulder.
Seems like she was
running from something
or someone.
She's not talking,
so there's a lot
we don't know yet. We've
established her lack
of speech isn't a
lack of understanding.
Have you checked for
signs of physical abuse?
She's headed for scans shortly.
Oh, I'll contact Atlanta P.D.
If there's been a
missing child report,
we'll know soon.
In the meantime,
Chastain has to assume
an emergency temporary
guardianship.
Who's gonna be
taking care of her?
Dr. Sullivan, it's
your ER shift,
- so I presume... - Me.
Happy to.
She's bonded with me, so
I'll run point.
It's good with me.
Takes a village, right?
The village of Drs. Hawkins-Sullivan.
Got it. And the child's name?
Jane Doe.
Good morning.
Didn't I leave you in a
warm bed blissfully asleep?
Yes, you did. And for
that, I thank you.
But-but, listen, before
you get too excited,
I'm not here officially.
Just a social call.
The doctors at the Mayo said
you could return to surgery.
The steroid pulse
and immunomodulators
have been amazing at
stopping your M.S. symptoms.
I know, and I'm grateful
and I'm, and I'm hopeful
and I'm reassured,
but I'm... I'm not there yet.
If this isn't your
official return,
did you really come
all the way here
in the rain just to
bring me a latte?
No. There's something I wanted
to tell you. I've, um...
I've been shortlisted
for a seat at the
state medical board.
That's wonderful, Randolph.
They could use people like you.
Doctors policing doctors
has not worked
well for patients.
We all need to be more
accountable, and...
You know, it's been a
long career, and I've seen
mistakes happen
that shouldn't have,
and you know I've
made them myself.
And I'd just...
like to try and
make up for that.
It's a brilliant idea.
Well, it's-it's not a done deal.
There's-there's only one seat
- open on the board.
- Oh, they'll pick you.
You know, if I get it,
I can fight for
patients' rights without
having a patient's
life in my hands.
I hope it adds some new
meaning to my career.
Just promise me one thing.
You won't give up
on the OR just yet.
We still need you.
I need a full blood panel,
chest X-ray and EKG.
The EMTs said they
couldn't find a vein.
- Hundley?
- Leave it to me.
Sit up for me, Roxie.
Can we talk?
Woman to woman?
That normal BP cuff, that
is not gonna fit my arm.
Thanks for the tip,
but I'm one step ahead of you.
This is a leg BP cuff.
It'll do the trick.
In my ER, you get what you need.
Sit back
please. Thank you.
- Hi.
Hey.
I'm glad I listened to
you and Dr. Pravesh.
This pain is no joke.
Keep me posted.
Will do.
I brought you something
to eat and drink
from our world-famous
Chastain cafeteria.
Let's start with the juice.
No issues swallowing.
And no respiratory
symptoms either.
Her lungs are clear,
but look at this.
We just took off
her socks and...
Tachy. 140. She's in pain.
Let's get her some ibuprofen.
Got it.
Soft tissue is macerated.
This could be trench foot.
I'll elevate her feet.
Looks like she was standing
in the rain all night.
Must've been numb from the cold.
Now that we're warming her up,
her feeling's coming back.
Skin is already infected,
and it could get worse.
If you need to cry or yell,
or if you want to hold my hand,
you can do that,
okay, honey?
You try sitting still
while you're crammed
into a metal cage.
I got you.
I should've done
that. I'm sorry.
It's not your fault.
The world's made for
folks your size, not mine,
but I see you trying.
He's one of the good ones.
And that is one
of the fine ones.
Don't let him hear that.
Hey. I am Dr. Austin.
Dr. Pravesh tells me that
you're having some chest pains.
And
shortness of breath,
with a normal EKG.
We're just waiting
on the chest X-ray.
Reflux?
Here we go. Heard that
one a dozen times.
Not from what I can
tell. I think it's more.
It sounds like mediastinal
crepitus to me.
It's hard to hear anything
through the soft tissue.
There are no signs
of SUBQ emphysema.That's good,
but, Pravesh,
you know I can't do
a complete consult
without all the data.
Call me when you get
an X-ray, all right?
He always that way?
Well, he is a very busy surgeon.
And there's something going
on with his mother recently.
He's just got a
lot on his plate.
But that is not an excuse, I know.
Sounds like one.
Morning.
- Dr. Bell?
- Yeah.
The lieutenant governor
needs a few minutes
before your meeting
begins. Please have a seat.
Thank you.
Well, it's
the famous Dr. Bell.
Bob Porter.
University Hospital, Augusta.
I know who you are.
- The highest billing ortho in Georgia.
- Well, I'd prefer
to be known for my
outcomes, but I'll take it.
So you must be the other name
on the governor's short list
for a seat on the medical board.
So we are competitors.
Honored indeed.
Do you know Beaumont?
No. Never met him.
A lovely guy. He
and I go way back.
We were roommates at Dartmouth.
Okay, well, I
guess the fix is in.
No, no, no. Your reputation
speaks for itself.
Well, thank you,
that's very kind...
You mind if I ask you why
you want a seat on the board?
Licensing physicians,
investigating
patient complaints... I mean,
that can't hold a candle to
running four ORs at once.
Don't believe
everything you hear.
Seriously, why do you want it?
Well, I don't know, I guess
at this point in my life, I, uh...
just want to give back.
He's ready for you, Dr. Bell.
Nice meeting you.
Same here.
So, show me
this hand of yours
that hurts so much.
Yeah, it's really sore.
Is it sore in your thumb?
- Yeah, it's...
Is it this, just this
finger right here?
Really? And you don't feel anything on this side?
- No. Oh, yeah.
- Do you feel anything in your wrist?
- Anything in your forearm?
- Of course.
The elbow?
You're hurt everywhere.
There's got to be
a specific place...
Atlanta PD doesn't
have any missing child
reports that match
your Jane Doe.
But I notified DFCS.
And if anyone recognizes her,
they'll let me
know. Until then...
The hospital has temporary
emergency guardianship
and you two are in charge.
Thank you.
Did she have her psych consults?
Yes, and as we suspected,
her silence is very likely
the result of trauma.
Whether that's from
her recent injuries
or something much
worse, they don't know.
She has a cracked rib,
- a few suspicious bruises.
- All signs point to abuse.
Well, it's definitely
a possibility, but...
I'll keep looking for family.
Let me know if there's anything
else I can do to protect her.
Hey, I know you have a daughter.
So if this case is hitting
too close to home for you...
Yeah, it hits close to home.
But...
there's nowhere
else I'd rather be.
She's choosing not to
speak to feel safe.
I'm seeing a lot
of that recently.
My savior.
My last doctor used to make
me bring my own hospital gown
to her office. Sewed it myself.
Denim and rhinestones.
Well, that sounds fly as hell.
Where can I get one?
If y'all make me feel better,
I'll sew one for you, too.
- Deal.
Can we get her close-up
over with so she
can sit back down?
This will take just
a minute, Roxie.
Dr. Pravesh?
The picture probably
won't be very clear
because of... her size.
The lungs
are the same size
even when the patient
is very large.
Yeah, but the body mass
around the lungs can
mess up the image.
A CT might be better...
except the machine
has a weight limit.
The CT delivers 200 times
more radiation
than a chest X-ray.
I'm the doctor.
I ordered a chest X-ray.
So please make that happen.
How are we doing?
Her heart rate is normal.
And she just got her
first dose of antibiotics.
Okay.
So...
this is my house.
Can you draw yours?
Do you live in a car, honey?
This line...
tells us how your foot
is doing.
If the medicine is working,
the infection won't
spread outside the line.
You need another color
marker over there?
Trade colors with me.
He is so good with kids ever
since he had one of his own.
Well, I'm still struggling
to find a way to
make her trust me.
She bonded with him instantly.
Don't feel bad.
- You never had a chance.
- Yeah, no, I get that.
The guy's like a picnic
basket filled with cupcakes
and ponies and sunbeams.
Anyway, I reviewed
your patient's chart.
If she were unable to talk
due to damage to her brain,
she'd be making sounds or
struggling to be understood.
Which isn't the case.
So you're good with us
holding off on a head CT?
Completely.
She's been through enough.
Clearly. The question is what?
She's guarding some
kind of secret.
But we need the
truth to help her.
Now do you see any
evidence of pneumothorax
or pneumomediastinum?
- Because I'm thinking that maybe right here...
- No.
Okay.
But given her
symptoms, we have to...
You know how to read
an X-ray, Pravesh.
This one is not giving us
any actionable information.
With her body habitus, we can't
even comment on the lung field,
let alone make out
a subtle finding.
AJ?
- You are being dismissive.
- No.
I'm being real. There
are complications
when carrying around
that kind of weight.
Believe me when I tell you
that she is painfully aware
of that fact, and it's
part of the reason
- why she hasn't gotten treated.
- So stop dancing around the issue
and explain to your
patient that her size
is preventing you from
reaching a diagnosis.
She does not need me to
tell her that she is obese.
Why not?
It's a medical condition,
like any other.
Who do you think does
more harm, Pravesh?
The doctor who names the disease
or the doctor who
won't even utter it?
Get a better picture of what's
going on inside Ms. Cabot.
- What happened?
- Her heart rate shot up.
She's febrile to 102.
Her white blood cell
count is up to 25,000.
The cellulitis is advancing
outside the margins,
- despite antibiotics.
Pain out of proportion.
You're worried about
necrotizing fasciitis?
We need a surgical consult.
She might be headed to the OR.
We are talking about a
highly lethal infection.
Which we're not certain she has.
The CT shows no evidence
of gas in the tissue.
But a CT scan can
miss the diagnosis.
And if this is
necrotizing fasciitis,
we can't afford to wait.
She could lose
her leg. Or worse.
None of us
want that, but we have
to consider what
recovery from surgery
will look like for this patient.
Limited mobility or
amputation would be
a massive hurdle for a kid
whose basic needs
aren't being met.
You're asking me to open
up a little girl's leg
based on a hunch.
Yes, her leg is still red.
But the swelling is minimal,
no evidence of blistering.
I would have a hard time
justifying this kind
of exploration even on a
fully consenting adult.
We have no medical record
for our little Jane Doe, so
if we're wrong and she
suffers any complications,
then it's not just
surgery without consent.
It's criminal
assault on a minor.
What happened to our
emergency guardianship?
It allows
Chastain to do
anything necessary
to save her life.
Can you tell yourself
with certainty
that this falls into
those parameters?
Right now, my suspicion
for necrotizing fasciitis
is just a suspicion.
I agree. The infection doesn't
constitute an immediate
life-or-death threat.
But waiting is dangerous, too.
Things could change fast.
Get her admitted to
the pediatric floor.
We'll monitor her
leg like a hawk.
If she worsens, if she
becomes hemodynamically
unstable, if the wind
blows the wrong way,
I'll take her to the OR.
Regardless of the consequences.
Hey, Billie.
I have a favor to ask.
Well, if it's about jumping
in on these two hernia repairs
or the bowel
obstruction, then yes.
- A thousand times yes.
- No, I need a letter of recommendation
for the Georgia
State Medical Board.
Oh, well...
Georgia could certainly
use more doctors
willing to fight
for patient safety.
I'm competing for the
spot with another doctor.
And he's-he's
connected, he's a star
at his hospital in Augusta...
- top earner.
- And you want to outshine him?
Yeah, it's not gonna
be easy. He's, uh,
he's a powerful guy,
he's very slick.
I just need to stack the deck
- as much as I can.
- Who is he?
Robert Porter.
Oh, you know him?
Yeah, well, of course.
Well, maybe. There are probably
a lot of doctors with that name.
This is him.
You'll have your recommendation
on your desk by end of day.
Okay, thank you.
That is an esophageal
perforation.
Roxie, what that means is
fluid is leaking out of
your esophagus into
your chest cavity,
which is why you're in pain.
Can you repair it?
Well, the perf is a
tough surgery on anyone.
It's even more complex if
I'm operating on someone
- with a BMI of 50.
- Wow. Do you talk that insensitively
about all your patients?
Or just the ones whose body
type you don't approve of?
Forgive Dr. Austin.
- What he means to say...
- He meant to insult me!
Maybe I don't need surgery.
Maybe he can't handle me
because I have too much
- "soft tissue."
- My job is to assess the entire patient.
And make sure you are
aware of the risks.
I'm guessing you're 30, 31?
I'm flattered, but no, I have
a few more years under my belt.
I'm not asking your age.
I'm talking your BMI.
I'd put you at... 32?
Anything over 29
makes you obese.
- Which is why I work out.
- So do I!
Six miles on a bike
every other day
and yoga in between.
I'm a person, Dr. Austin.
And you're an arrogant jerk.
True.
But I'm also the most
straightforward doctor
you will meet in this
hospital. I heal with my hands.
Not my oratory
skills. Now, when
I look at you, Ms. Cabot, I
see a woman who is very strong
who can handle
some straight talk.
So...
are you ready to talk
about the vomiting?
Roxie, I found enamel erosion
and staining in your mouth
when I did the exam.
Classic signs of... bulimia.
Which caused the damage
in your esophagus.
The surgery will be a
waste if we don't get
to the root cause
of all the problems.
I've dieted all my life.
And no one believes
how hard I try.
I try...
Somewhere along
the line I just...
I got desperate, I...
There is nothing
to be ashamed of.
Obesity is a complex disease
with a myriad of factors.
But purging after every
meal is not the answer.
AJ.
No...
it's okay.
I'm actually beginning
to appreciate his candor.
Well, thank you.
And I appreciate
yours, Ms. Cabot.
I've never had a doctor talk
to me the way you two have.
They either ignore
me or write me off.
I gave up thinking
anyone could help me.
We can help you.
All right?
Dr. Austin is gonna
repair the perforation.
And we are gonna come up
with a plan for
treating the rest.
Deal?
Deal.
Hey, my shift is over.
But I couldn't leave
without finding out
how our little
Jane Doe is doing.
I have to show you something.
Hey.
Dr. Cade would like
to see that burn.
Is that okay?
It's a Lichtenberg figure.
From a lightning strike.
Lightning could explain the
posterior shoulder dislocation.
And maybe help us figure
out where she came from.
Let me check my weather app.
Three lightning strikes
touched down here,
here and here.
This is sort of near where
she was found... it's near
Black Shoals Park area.
I've biked out there.
It's a tough area for a kid.
Lots of homeless encampments.
She couldn't have been all
the way out there on her own.
Maybe whoever she was
with is still out there?
- I'll go find out.
- No, that's a bad idea.
- We don't know what you'd be walking into.
- I can handle myself.
And you have to stay
with her and if this
gets worse, you got to get
Kit to authorize surgery.
You can't go out there alone.
You stay. Let me go.
I'm glad to have
a way I can help.
What can I do for
you, Dr. Sutton?
This is hard.
I don't want to involve
you, but I have no choice.
I need to talk to the
state medical board.
And why is that?
Dr. Bell asked me to write
him a recommendation for it.
He told me Robert Porter
is angling for a
seat on the board.
Robert Porter, the orthopedic
surgeon in Augusta?
He has to be stopped.
He's a pedophile.
How do you know that?
He raped me when I
was 13 years old.
Oh, Billie.
I am so sorry.
It was a long time ago.
I survived.
My feelings aren't
what matters right now.
What matters is
there's no way in hell
Porter should be
allowed to judge
the moral failings
of other doctors.
You want to go before
the board and tell them?Yes.
I want to make a statement.
Porter will deny it, of course.
Do you have any proof?
It's complicated.
There's another person involved
that I can't bring into this.
It will have to be
Porter's word against mine.
You know women who come forward
with abuse allegations
are often attacked.
I know.
But I have to try.
Let me talk to the
lieutenant governor
and tell him you have
crucial information.
Perhaps we can keep them
from releasing your name.
But I can't guarantee it.
Thank you.
- Dr. Hawkins?
How's she doing?
Her infection is worsening.
I suspect it's bacteremic.
We are gonna have to operate
without family consent.
Well, I have something
you should see.
I may have found a family
member, though it's
not the kind any of
us hoped to find.
He has a record of
domestic violence.
Cade went to find
the girl's family
- out at Black Shoals Park.
- Oh, no.
Your call has
been forwarded to an automated
- voice message system.
- What's going on?
Winston, call the police. We
need to get them to Cade's location.
The cellulitis is expanding
beyond even the most recent
marker, her blood
pressure's borderline.
It's more swollen than before.
- And these blisters are new.
- We can't wait any longer.
- I don't know that we'll get parental consent.
- It's life or death now.
Then Chastain will
take the risk.
Let's prep her for surgery.
Your call has
been forwarded to an automated
voice message...
I'm sorry.I...
It's okay.
Do you have a few dollars?
I'm really hungry.
Of course.
Maybe you can help me.
I'm looking for a family.
They're possibly
living in their car.
- Have you seen any...?
- Can you help me?!
Are you okay?
My car, it was struck
by lightning. I-I'm hurt.
That's Ana.
Do you have a sister
around eight years old?
She has dark hair.
That's Scout! That's Scout!
She disappeared a few days ago.
- Please...
- She's at the hospital.
Let's get you there, too. Okay?
These blisters
are developing rapidly.
It means the
infection is moving fast.
Then we need
to move faster.
Making the
initial incision now.
Let's start
the debridement.
We're looking for
healthy tissue.
How deep
do we need to go?
Until we find some.
Forceps to me.
Better get equipment
for a below-the-knee
amputation just in case.
Amputation?
She's just a child.
It's a precaution.
We have to be ready.
Been calling you nonstop.
- Why didn't you pick up?
- This is Ana,
our minor's older sister.
She's hypothermic
with a wrist fracture.
Where's Scout?
- She's in surgery.
- What?
Let's just focus on
you right now, okay?
Clara? Page Winston.
I've got clean margins,
but the infection is close to
the anterior tibial artery.
If we compromise that,
we risk seeding the
infection further.
We'd have to amputate.
So let's not.
Let's lose the tray.
I want step stools
on both sides of the
bed. How many sides?
Both sides.
Thank you very much.
Roxie,
welcome to your OR.
Warm blankets.
- Am I flying business class?
Now we're gonna transfer
you to the bed, Ms. Cabot.
All you need to do is
lay back and relax.
Dr. Austin,
you keep talking to me
with that Barry White baritone,
I'll relax right into a puddle.
Where's Haircut?
I'm right
here with you, Roxie.
I thought we said no nicknames
in front of Dr. Austin.
Oh, too
late. I heard it.
I'm committing it to memory,
and I'll be using
it from here on out.
He stays.
Okay.
Change of plans, people.
Dr. Haircut will be
observing us today
very much the way a music stand
observes the first chair violin.
Silent and invisible.
It's time to rest now.
Winston, how's
the surgery going?
Not my area, but it's
still touch and go.
Please, I really just
need to see my sister.
We will take you to
her as soon as we can.
Scout wouldn't speak
or tell us her name.
She hasn't talked since
our mom disappeared.
Can you start from
the beginning?
We're from Memphis.
Father said our mom ran off.
I don't believe it.
She wouldn't.
He beat her.
And me.
And when he hit Scout,
I stole the car,
and we ran away.
We were living in the
car when that storm came,
and, uh, the lightning hit,
and I don't remember
anything after that.
When I came to,
Scout was gone.
I'm your
social worker,
and I will figure out how
best to take care of you.
Please, you...
You won't call our
father, will you?
No, you won't be returned
to an abusive home.
That's certain.
Hey. I'm here.
We're safe.
Everything's gonna be okay.
Ana.
Hey.
She speaks.
She does, indeed.
They saved you.
Thank you.
You are very welcome.
Your leg will heal. You'll
have quite the scar,
but otherwise,
you'll be just fine.
One more thing.
My daughter said I
could give this to you.
So, I think
they complete my drip rather
well, don't you think?
This is officially the
hardest I've ever had to work
for a sale.
Ms. Cabot,
just want you to know that
your surgery went flawlessly.
I expect a full
recovery very soon.
However, there is one
important open question.
- Do these come in 13?
You two sure know how to
make a girl feel special.
I made a referral for
you for Dr. Frank.
She's an obesity specialist.
I know her personally.
She creates individualized
plans for her patients
that include genetics,
environmental factors
and even metabolic function.
And she can get you
into a treatment program
for the bulimia.
It's a combination
of therapy and SSRIs.
So no more judgment.
No more one-size-fits-all
medicine.
You know, I do love my couture.
Being caught in a storm
nearly killed those two girls.
But running away may
have saved their lives.
These are the kind of choices
no kid should have to make.
- They needed help.
- Well,
their access to social
services may have been limited.
Chances are they would've
been returned to their father.
Tell me they won't be separated.
I will bend heaven and earth
to make sure that
doesn't happen.
Thank you, Winston.
This case got personal
for you, didn't it?
Got personal for all of us.
A child not willing to open up
even to those who
wanted to help her.
- A child on the run...
- Okay, full disclosure,
I'm beginning to
enjoy your company.
We work well together.
But I do not enjoy
being psychoanalyzed.
- Psychoanalyzed? Really?
- Just no third degree.
Offering you my umbrella?
Did that feel like the
third degree to you?
I'm not a minor in your ER.
I'm an adult who can
make her own decisions.
And I'm your colleague. I
helped you get this job.
Are you in trouble?
No.
I'm fully in control
of my past, present
and, to some extent, my future.
- If I need help, I will ask.
But will you?
I'll see you around, Hawkins.
So, what should we
do on our day off?
We can go have lunch in Roswell.
- Or we can go for massages.
-  Dev.
Well, we could quit our jobs
and go live in the
Maldives before they sink.
My schedule changed.
I have to do a valve
replacement with AJ,
and then Billie and I have a
schwannoma resection later tonight.
Don't be angry.
I'm not angry.
I'm worried, though.
Do Billie and AJ know
that you want to be
double board-certified
in the hardest
field of medicine,
neuro and
cardiothoracic surgery?
Yes.
I've mentioned that
I want to do this.
And did they think
you can do it?
No.
They didn't take me seriously.
Are you serious?
Have you thought it through?
There's a reason why no
one else has done it.
Can you please just support me?
I support you in every
dream you want to chase
as long as it's not impossible.
Leela,
this is literally impossible.
Even for the most talented
surgical resident in the world,
and I'm ready to say
that that is you.
Did I tell you how sexy it is
that you stood up to Dr. Austin
and lived to tell it?
It was a conversation.
I didn't wrestle
him to the ground.
Don't shortchange yourself.
You advocated for your patient.
I find that incredibly sexy.
Oh, yeah?
Okay, uh, why don't you
pencil him in for 3:00, then.
I have good news.
I could use some.
I extracted a promise from
the lieutenant governor
to assure your anonymity.
You can testify to him
and the whole board.
When?
Today. 2:00 p.m.
I cleared your schedule.
No sense delaying.
I've been private
about this for so long.
Are you sure you're ready?
You should know
there's still danger.
Porter is powerful within
the medical community,
and Randolph told me he
and the lieutenant governor
were in the same
fraternity in college.
So this is a boat
- that could spring a hundred leaks.
- Yes.
But he also told me
there are other ethics
complaints against Porter.
After your testimony,
they may take those seriously.
I hope so.
It's still risky.
I know.
And you're determined?
I am.