Previously on The Good Doctor:
Message received from Mom.
Hey, baby, I got your text.
We're gonna celebrate.
I'll see you soon.
I'm so proud of you, baby.
Here are flowers and chocolates.
- Are you asking me out?
- Yes.
I would love to.
Will we be doing this
during all the commercials?
It's possible.
Patient came in
through the celebrity track.
He was admitted through
the loading dock.
You're not to mention his name
even to colleagues.
- What is his name?
- Mitchell Stewart.
The conspiracy theorist?
That's a celebrity now?
A guy who thinks 9/11
was an inside job?
- He's an ass.
- He's an ass who needs liver surgery.
- Whoa. Hold it right there.
- It's okay, Dex, they're on the list.
Doctors Murphy, Park, Andrews.
Mitchell Stewart. I don't blindly turn over
my well-being to those in authority,
so I ran background checks
on all of you.
Including Nurse Villanueva.
Nurse Villanueva is not
a person in authority.
People can be gotten to,
bribed, threatened.
And don't bother hooking up that IV
until I know what you pump into me.
They're normal IV fluids,
Mr. Stewart. Please.
I'm sure you consider whatever
you give me normal medical treatment,
but we all know doctors are pushers
in the pay of the drug companies.
The bag contains
an isotonic crystalloid
composed of 0.9 percent sodium chloride
dissolved in sterile water.
Also, given that
we will soon be drugging you
into unconsciousness
and cutting into your body,
don't you have to trust us a little?
You must be the autistic guy.
Good, no bull.
Probably doesn't know what bull is.
Bet your parents got one of those
combination vaccinations...
Not connected because science
does not support an autism link.
- Yeah, that's what they told you.
Mr. Stewart,
suppose we focus on
what we'll be doing to halt
the liver damage
caused by your genetic condition.
Idiopathic portal hypertension
can cause ma...
My liver is damaged,
but that's not the cause.
I've been poisoned.
His internist heard the same theory.
Tox screen came back negative.
And KCNN-three genetic testing
confirmed the cause
of his idiopathic
portal hypertension.
He inherited it from his mother.
Worth running that tox screen again?
He has a web show where he claims
parents of children
who've died in school shootings
are crisis actors. He's earned enemies.
Once we start doubting the tests,
you can't trust anything,
and there's no point.
We know our patient needs liver shunt
surgery, we're doing the surgery.
You were late.
Your mom keeping you up
singing at night again?
No. She's been quiet.
Ms. Barstow, I'm Dr. Browne,
this is Dr. Reznick.
- What seems to be the trouble?
- Nothing much, really.
I feel silly for coming here,
but Jonas insisted.
Because you weren't getting better.
Lily likes to downplay her problems.
She's the rock and I'm the wimp.
Ah, fuss, fuss, fuss.
I've just been off food for a few days.
You have a fever.
Most likely an infection.
- Oh, my God. Lily.
- Sir, please step back.
Lay back for me.
We're gonna do an ultrasound.
Her pulse is up,
blood pressure's up too.
Uh... Her appendix is ruptured.
- Oh, my God.
- Page Anesthesia. Taking her to the OR.
We need pre-op lab results.
- Patient name?
- We can't tell you.
Celebrity track. You'll find the
results under the ID number.
Politics, arts, business?
Is it the president?
I'll give you a hint.
He's less popular.
Hmm.
That's disappointing.
We need to figure out
why her brain
isn't getting the right distress signals.
How should we go about that,
Dr. Browne?
We do an FMRI. Stimulate
her, and see how her brain reacts.
Sorry. You asked Claire,
but I have lunch plans.
- I have a question.
- Well, hopefully it's a quick one,
I've cleared my schedule
for the rest of the day.
Debbie and I are going
to City Hall to get married.
Not gonna make a big fuss
out of it, you know.
Get dressed up,
turn it into a big event.
After all, we are not kids anymore.
This is where you say,
"Congratulations."
- Congratulations.
- Thank you.
- Do you and Debbie hold hands?
- Yeah, why?
- Is that what Carly wants to do?
- Yes. She tried twice.
Have you tried to explain
why it's difficult for you?
- No.
- Well, I'd start with that.
How can this be important?
It's a little thing.
Carly and I are compatible
on so many big things,
children, geographic preferences,
work priorities,
the use of headphones,
color schemes for our home.
- You have a checklist?
- Yes.
Carly and I are still learning
about each other.
It's not like you and Debbie.
You already know these things,
or you wouldn't be getting married.
Four...
five...
- I'm feeling some pain.
- We can stop.
We're not getting anything.
She's fine. We need feedback.
Eight...
nine...
Claire, she's not feeling pain.
The only activity is in the parietal.
Nothing in the limbic, nothing
in the anterior cingulate cortex.
She's feeling touch.
- But why did she...
- My guess?
Because she's never felt pain.
She doesn't know what it is.
- Sleep apnea.
- What?
That poor guy over there,
I think he's got sleep apnea.
Maybe he's just tired.
So it's one of the most important days
of his life, and he can't stay awake.
Maybe you could tell him
there are treatments.
Me?
Otherwise,
he's gonna keep his wife awake
snoring the rest of his life.
It'll destroy their marriage.
You seem very sure about that.
There is literally no greater torture
than not getting a
good night's sleep.
Right. First, I don't think you mean
"literally" no greater torture.
Oh, no, it's true.
Once, when I was in
the Merchant Marine...
- Merchant Marines?
- It's "Marine." No S.
- You were in the Merchant Marines?
- Mm-hm.
And we were stationed off the Azores,
and every night, we were driven crazy
by this loud, just, like,
strangled sounds.
Turns out, it was just a bunch
of cagarro birds.
We were literally hearing the sound
of Daffy Duck drowning.
Of course, that was nothing comparing
to what happened in Valparaiso.
I'm sorry.
Are you okay?
Sorry. Ahem.
It's just I'm not feeling so good.
You're not feeling well?
- I can't do this.
- What?
Is that it? Are we finished?
Yeah, we're gonna get you out.
Uh, just a couple more questions.
Your mother died, age 66,
of a heart attack.
Were you there when that happened?
Yes, I called the ambulance.
She died while we were waiting.
Check the anterior cingulate cortex.
Physical pain and emotional pain
are processed through the same areas.
Nothing. But we don't know
how she feels about her mother.
It's your mother. When she goes,
there is a vacuum.
What about your husband?
Has he had any problems lately?
He had a cancer scare
about a year ago.
Slight activity here,
but it's pretty weak.
You wanna argue that she doesn't like
her mother and her husband?
Wow. She...
She's like a superhero.
Nothing can really hurt her.
Is everything okay?
Your right hand is red.
It's starting to swell.
What does that mean?
Infection.
Hello. Your surgery went well.
If there are no complications,
you should be discharged
in a few days.
Hey.
That's great,
but what about the big picture?
Once I'm out of here,
I'll go back to being poisoned.
You make many statements
that have been proven wrong.
Do you really believe them?
You wanna untangle
what's real and what's for show?
Now you're talking.
Okay.
Do you think vaccination damage
is being covered up?
Yes.
Do you think the parents of children
killed in school shootings
are crisis actors?
I can't answer for individuals,
but I do believe there's a force
in this country
that wants to scam our people
into laying down their arms.
But I no longer think
there's a paedo slave ring
in a basement under that pizza joint.
That was a wrong call.
What did you do when you realized
you'd made an error?
Nothing. No apologies, no admissions.
The second you say you were wrong,
they'll make it seem like
everything you know is wrong.
Can't give them that ammunition.
Then you're not really offering the truth.
Maybe if people saw you admit
you were wrong, they'd believe you more.
No. There is no middle ground.
Compromise is a scam.
When only one side
can get what it wants...
make sure it's yours.
We have to remove
all infected tissue immediately.
- Stop it from spreading.
- We discovered that Lily can't feel pain,
which is why the appendicitis went
untreated, causing
a widespread infection.
I can't feel pain?
That makes no sense.
Whatever stimulation
your nerves receive,
your brain doesn't acknowledge
it as pain.
- No, I feel pain...
- Do you? Because I'm pinching you.
- I feel it.
- You didn't jump or react,
you felt it as a touch.
Physical or emotional pain,
it doesn't matter.
Okay, let's go. OR Two.
Stop hiding.
I'm not hiding, I'm thinking.
Well, I've done my thinking,
and I've come up with
I deserve a better explanation
than, "I can't do this,"
because that was humiliating.
I'm sorry.
You're sorry?
What does that mean?
Are we going back tomorrow?
Never? What?
You're the one that proposed to me.
You're the one that told me how happy
our being together makes you.
It makes me happy, it does.
But when I proposed to you,
you even said, "I don't know you."
Is that what this is about?
Because I was...
Because I was in the Merchant Marine?
I mean, yes. Okay, it makes me wonder
what else I don't know about you,
but more importantly,
it makes me realize
you don't know anything about me.
I am really annoying.
I'm easily irritable.
Like when people use the word "literally"
about things that aren't literal.
I am impossible to live with,
maybe literally.
That's been made very clear to me
in the past.
I don't wanna go two years
and get divorced.
Divorcing you would hurt.
Thank you.
But that's a bunch of crap.
You know that, right?
We have different personal styles.
You like to examine things
from every angle,
and I like to take a leap
into the dark every now and then.
You're right.
I am not a leaper.
I am a toe-dipper.
It takes me hours to get into the ocean
when it's warm.
I know that you're good for me.
And I know that I'm good
for you, Aaron.
Since meeting me, you've jumped ship
from a comfortable career
because you decided that you
were missing something. And...
you asked a complete stranger
to marry you.
Who knows what's next?
I guess you'll have to keep thinking.
Dr. Browne, widen the debridement.
Extending the incisions
proximally.
Her husband thought she was a rock.
Turns out she's a rock
because nothing matters to her.
You're making assumptions.
We were monitoring her reaction to pain.
Love wasn't part of the test.
- You care, you hurt.
- Maybe not Lily.
She married this man,
she stayed with him for years.
Maybe for her, love can exist
without the pain of loss.
That would be paradise.
There is way more necrotic tissue
here than I expected.
She's gonna lose the hand.
If anyone can handle bad news...
- Are you going to take my hand?
- Not right now, no.
I don't like to hold hands.
Either we hold hands, or we don't.
There's no compromise.
Only one of us can get
what they want.
- I guess that's true...
- It should be me.
Holding hands makes me uncomfortable.
Not holding hands
doesn't make you uncomfortable.
That show we watched the other night.
It had a happy ending...
because they stopped
the story in a good place.
But in real life, it's gonna get dark
and cold out there.
All we have...
is this.
This says we're in it together,
we've got each other's back.
That we'll hold each other up
for as long as we can.
I can say all those things verbally.
You could shout them,
and it wouldn't say it as loud as this.
You said not holding hands wouldn't
make me uncomfortable, but it would.
I would feel...
separate.
It's all right.
You've actually been lucky,
considering you have no warning system.
You need to be doing self-checks.
Knees, feet, elbows, hands.
Look for bruises, discolorations,
anything at all that changes
could be dangerous, life-threatening.
But there's another option. Naloxone
affects the central nervous system.
It's been shown to block the action
of pain-lowering endorphins.
It could give you the ability
to feel pain.
I don't see the point,
I've been fine so far.
Guess that sounds silly,
I just lost a hand.
But now I know about checking myself,
and I'll be a lot more careful.
Why is one gesture so important?
- Carly still pushing you to hold hands?
- No.
I tried, and she said it was all right.
Huh.
You should give me context
for that "huh."
She wants it, she's just given up.
Good.
Not if it's gonna bother her
the rest of your relationship,
which may not be very long.
Huh.
Uh-oh.
We need to do imaging to make sure
the problem isn't the shunt.
Check there isn't a clot
causing backup...
The surgery was a success,
but I'm still being poisoned?
No. The surgery was a success,
but your liver's still deteriorating.
We don't know why.
Jen, check me out.
Find another hospital.
I can't approve that.
You're in no condition to leave.
You've just confirmed that someone
in this hospital is poisoning me.
You want me to cooperate
with the suspects?
Another hospital
wouldn't solve your problem.
People can be gotten to,
bribed, or threatened.
- Right. Someone here wants to kill me.
- No one is trying...
Let's constrain some of these variables.
One person touches me.
Him.
- He doesn't know how to lie.
- I can lie.
Yes, but not successfully.
Good choice.
- Will I be able to play tennis?
- Yes, eventually.
Funny, I never could before.
You always take things well.
We had to pick up
and move from Durham.
Well, that was for your job.
No sense in moping about it.
The miscarriage.
You never talked about it, so...
I never talked about it.
Didn't wanna hurt you.
But did you not talk about it...
because you just
weren't thinking about it?
What are all these questions for?
I thought we were carrying the load...
together, knowing how each other felt.
This isn't about us.
This is just a medical condition.
If I died, would you care?
Would you miss me? Or, uh...
would you just...
move on?
Would you want me to be miserable?
- I want it to matter.
- Of course it matters.
You know I love you.
Jonas...
Maybe...
you think it's love, but...
it's like the pain.
It just doesn't go that deep.
Isn't it possible for me to love you
without it being
all wrapped up in suffering?
But that's how it works.
When you lose someone...
it shouldn't be like your hand,
it should ache.
That's right, isn't it?
That's what loss feels like.
I need to get away for a while.
I'm sorry.
Next, we're going to test you for
autoimmune hepatitis and fatty liver.
Those are diseases
whose symptoms overlap yours.
They might have been masked by
your idiopathic portal hypertension.
Nurse Villanueva, welcome,
but you know I'm not gonna touch that.
The dietician ordered it,
and I'm required to bring it.
What are you eating
if you're refusing hospital food?
Uh...
Eighty grams of protein a day.
Kale, baby greens.
Hey.
"Leopard Spring."
Jen, Dex, you mind stepping out?
It's Chinese herbs.
To make you feel younger,
more energetic, more virile.
You don't feel virile?
Of course, but there's nothing wrong
with feeling more virile.
I need strength for the fight.
You're not talking.
Is there a problem?
No, these herbs are harmless.
- You asked about my virility.
- I was curious.
We're going to test you for
autoimmune hepatitis and fatty liver.
- What's up?
- I tested a patient
for autoimmune
hepatitis and fatty liver.
What's up with you?
Our patient decided
to take the drugs.
Because a husband walking out
can make an impression
even on a woman
who feels no pain.
- It's a lot of paperwork for two tests.
- They were negative.
I thought I might find something
in his mother's old records
that could help,
but, no, her case was straightforward.
His parents were both alcoholics,
but her liver was already
weakened by her condition.
Parents both alcoholics?
No wonder he thinks people in authority
like to deny the truth.
He's grown up now, Claire.
No longer in that position.
There's still plenty of lying
going on in the world.
That's not a situation you outgrow.
Yes, there is a lot of lying.
Want to hear my theories?
Fight with your mother is number one.
You're debating
whether to throw her out.
This explains what?
Why the compassionate Doctor Browne
envies a woman who feels no pain.
You're miserable, torn,
you don't know what to do
to make your pain go away.
Want to hear my theory?
People that aren't you are doing great...
so you're looking for a toy to break,
a pet you can torture.
- Is she in pain?
- No.
- What are her vitals?
- Vitals are fine.
- Then how can she be in crisis?
- I don't know, but she is.
Lily?
Are you okay?
I never noticed how
ugly the walls are.
I've discovered the cause
of your liver problem.
Really? Fatty liver? Autoimmune?
- I've never had symptoms of...
- No, you were being poisoned.
What? Who? Do you know who? How?
I thought maybe the dose of herbs
listed on the bottle was wrong...
- There's a toxic dose in there?
- No, there are no herbs at all in here.
It contains sildenafil.
It's the active element in Viagra.
It promotes blood flow in your penis.
I know what it does.
- They say it's natural herbs.
- They lied.
Your idiopathic portal hypertension
means your liver
is vulnerable to abuse.
The amount of sildenafil in here
wouldn't kill most people,
but if someone with pre-existing
liver issues took it every day...
You were right.
You've been poisoning yourself.
It's good news.
Those communist bastards.
I think they're based in San Pedro.
Mr. Barstow.
- Is Lily all right?
- She's on medication
to reverse her pain-free condition,
but it's hit her hard.
She's being wrung out by all
the negative thoughts and feelings
the rest of us have built calluses against.
But she made the right choice.
I mean, she needs this to be safe.
I don't think she's doing this to be safe,
I think she's doing this
because you walked out.
Why?
You were happy for years.
Now you can't be happy
unless your wife changes?
I want her to feel everything I feel.
The love, the pain, everything.
Wouldn't you?
The residents in this hospital
work long hours. Know why?
The surgeons in charge worked
long hours when they were residents.
They suffered, so we have to suffer.
It's human nature.
- What does...
- For someone like your wife,
so invulnerable, it's like she's
gotten away with something.
It's hard not to resent her.
Sure, we wanna cure her,
but how much of it
is to give her a warning system,
and how much is because
we wanna pull her down into hell
with the rest of us?
Are you married now?
No. I chickened out.
Apparently, I don't like change.
Makes me very nervous.
I'm not the easiest man in the world
to live with.
My first wife made that very clear.
It's true, you can be very irritating.
You saying I shouldn't get married?
Are you asking for my advice?
Yes.
You've never really asked before...
and this is an important decision.
Your happiness depends on it.
This is huge.
Well?
Oh. I don't have any advice.
I don't even understand the issue.
I also don't understand why you asked
when you've already
made up your mind.
What?
You usually call her your ex-wife.
You just called her your first.
It implies a second.
Why are you staring in your trunk?
Something in here?
The answer to your problem?
Yoga mat, gym bag, extra sneakers.
Here's a little earthquake kit,
so sensible. Dirty towel.
- Ooh, what's this?
- Put it back.
It's my mom.
Why are you jumping?
I'm not jumping, I'm leaping.
Come on. Come leap with me.
We both can't leap on that thing.
Oh!
Are you okay?
Never better.
Will you leap with me to City Hall?
Yes, I will.
Also, I may have done
something to my ankle.
- Do you want me to call someone?
- Je ne regrette nothing, baby.
I left the champagne
because I was so ready for victory.
Now I don't even know what
to do with the damn ashes.
Leave them on a shelf in the closet
with the spare towels?
Put them down the disposal?
- What did she want done with them?
- It was stupid, I'm sure she was joking.
Yeah, everyone jokes in their will.
The Marine Science Center.
She loved sea lions.
She'd take me to see them
all the time, it was a thing.
Any city we were in,
"I wonder if they have sea lions."
You need to do it. Now.
No. No. It is a pointless gesture
because my mother is dead
and she doesn't care.
Perfect. The center's open
this evening for an after-hours event.
We'll have to dress up.
The winner of tonight's vote
for most fabulous sea creature,
the vampire squid.
- I feel ridiculous.
- You look great.
You could give the vampire squid
a run for her money.
Now, let's find the sea lions.
- You came back.
- Yeah.
Thank God.
We'll stop this, it'll be all right.
Doctor, you gotta get this stuff
out of her IV.
You don't need it.
If you have to be careful
about getting hurt,
I'll be there to help you.
The "stuff" was removed
some time ago.
Before Dr. Browne went off-shift,
she told me that Lily
was experiencing some problems,
so I thought it best to discontinue
the medication for a while.
She's as she was when you left her.
You never cry.
When I saw you sitting there...
I've never been so happy
in my whole life.
I thought you didn't
want to make a fuss.
Yeah. Who knew?
This seems weird.
It is weird.
Most people have some kind of ritual
all ready for them,
so they don't have to think about
this kind of stuff.
You got a prayer?
Not religious. Neither was my mom.
Everybody has a religion.
Not everybody has a god,
but everybody has a religion.
Music.
Your mother's religion was music.
Sing.
By the sea lion colony
at a drag pride party?
Or you can just dump it out
and feel weird.
Your call.
Amaz...
Okay.
♪ Amazing ♪
♪ Grace ♪
Oh, God.
♪ How sweet ♪
♪ The sound ♪
♪ That saved ♪
♪ A wretch ♪
♪ Like me ♪
♪ I once ♪
♪ Was lost ♪
♪ But now ♪
♪ Am found ♪
♪ Was blind ♪
♪ But now ♪
♪ I see ♪
♪ 'Twas grace that taught ♪
♪ My heart to fear ♪
♪ And grace my fears ♪
♪ Relieved ♪
♪ How precious did ♪
♪ That grace appear ♪
♪ The hour I first ♪
♪ Believed ♪
♪ Amazing grace ♪
♪ How sweet the sound ♪
♪ That saved a wretch ♪
♪ Like me ♪
♪ I once was lost ♪
♪ But now am found ♪
♪ Was blind but now ♪
♪ I see ♪♪