Previously on ER:
Neela, say hi to Mae Lee Park.
She's our new surgical med student.
- Hi, nice to meet you.
- I appreciate you taking the time.
- Oh, it's my pleasure.
- Tell me you're not getting married.
- If you tell anyone I'll kill you.
- Wedding is on.
What am I supposed to do? "Can I
have DNA? I wanna find if I'm your father"?
- What if I'm not?
- I'm gonna send Alex away.
Mom, I don't wanna stay here.
Mom, please.
Mom, I'll be better, okay?
Neela...
No, I'm not buying
that silly excuse.
You've been cleaning
the room for three hours.
My patient needs a tele
bed right now. You hear me?
- Thirty-five, 21...
- Hello? Hello?
- What is wrong with the phones?
- Eighty-five.
They're working on
them today. Thirty-three...
Hey, Pratt. Pratt. Here's
your new medical student.
- What new medical student?
- Larry Weston, third year, UIC.
- Yeah, why wasn't I told about this?
- I'm telling you now.
Great, great. Look, Barry, I...
- That's Larry.
- Yeah, I'm sorry about that, man.
I didn't know you were coming
and I'm getting off soon, so Morris...
Uh-uh. Don't look at
me. Forty-one, 21, 55...
There's a Dr. Gates
working today.
Find him and tell him Dr. Pratt
said you're gonna be shadowing him.
- Dr. Gates.
- You can't miss him.
Swarthy, always has
his hands in his pockets.
- Got it.
- All right.
I always knew you had a cruel streak.
- Hey, Pratt.
Will you sign off on my
thumb-versus-table-saw guy?
- Anyone know who's on surgical
call? MORRIS: I think Neela is. Why?
- Hey, guys. Sam's birthday.
- No reason.
Drinks at Ike's later and
everybody has to sign her card.
Jeez, could you
find a bigger card?
Despite what you've been
told, Ray, size does matter.
Hey, I'm going to get coffee.
Does anybody want one?
- No, it's cool.
- No, I'm good.
You okay, Frank?
Oh, my back's a
little stiff. It's fine.
- Okay. MORRIS:
Twenty-four, 16, 69...
- Morris, what are you doing?
- It's a well-known medical axiom:
If the ages of all the patients in the ER
add up to a thousand, you can go home.
- So far, I'm up to 781.
- That for real?
I heard your shift is over when
you treat a pirate and his parrot.
Nobody's going
anywhere unless I say so.
And I say, Ray,
infected tummy tuck in 2.
Morris, we got a rig
pulling in any minute.
And you can go out
and calculate that.
Twenty-five, 29, 81...
Knuckleheads. I'm
surrounded by knuckleheads.
Hey.
Hey, Luka. Sorry,
I really need this.
- Long night last night?
- Sam, could you give me a hand?
Yeah, sure.
Don't worry. Your caffeine fix will
be waiting for you at the Admit desk.
- Hey, happy birthday.
- Thanks, Luka.
Alfred Gower, 63.
Blocked G-tube.
Under hospice care for
end-stage esophageal cancer.
- Hospice? Then why is he here?
- It's a G-tube. It's a comfort measure.
- What the hell?
- Been at it since we picked him up.
Ma'am, you need to stop that.
Hear we're going out for
drinks for your birthday.
We don't have to. It's not a
big deal. Know what, lady?
Knock it off or I'll rip that
camera out of your hands.
It's all right. She's with me.
I don't care. You're in our way.
Come on, I'm authorized.
Smile for the camera, birthday girl.
Hey, knock it o...
- Can I help you with something, Morris?
- No, but I can help you with one word:
- Las Vegas.
- Pardon?
Okay, two words. It is the hot
venue for destination weddings.
- What? How did you...?
- No, don't worry.
I've been sworn to
secrecy. So Las Vegas.
It has glitz, glamour,
Celine Dion...
Abby and I are not the
glitz-and-glamour type.
There are plenty of cultural
things to do. The Hoover Dam.
Liberace Museum. Nudes on Ice...
Morris, I'm not
talking about this.
And if I were you, I
wouldn't mention it to Abby.
What about for
your bachelor party?
Did I mention the brothels
in Nevada? They're legal.
- What's legal?
- Uh, cockfighting in Louisiana.
Good to know.
- You all right?
- I'm great. Great.
I'd love to have this chat, but
I think I hear Frank calling me.
Yep, there is it.
Frank, what's up?
Uh, hello, I'm Dr...
Lockhart.
- Uh, so you fainted at the...?
- Sun N' Go.
- I was waiting for a tanning bed...
- She passed out. It was awful.
- Did you have breakfast?
- Mm-hm.
Diet soda and two saltines.
That doesn't really
sound like breakfast.
We'll be tan and thin for
spring break if it kills us.
- Yeah.
- You're on your way.
Hey, Sam, can I get 2 liters
of saline and a chem panel?
Sure. Wow, that's some
color you guys got there.
- Thank you.
Tanning puts you at risk for cancer.
Think about self-tanner or spray-on tans?
You don't wanna have skin like
leather when you're in your 40s.
We're still at an age
where we care how we look.
Mm-hm.
Okay, uh...
We're gonna need to keep you
here while we wait for your labs.
Ouch. I cannot believe we just
got dissed by those walking raisins.
I hope it rains every
day on spring break.
- Oh, happy birthday, by the way.
- Thanks.
Hey, Mr. Gower. We got
a new G-tube in your size.
You can't unclog it?
They tried flushing it but it didn't
work, so a doctor has to replace it.
Let's forget about the G-tube.
I'll buy us all a steak
and a bottle of Cabernet.
That's tempting, but how about I get
you a puréed meal and an Ensure chaser?
Somehow that
doesn't quite make it.
Uh, I didn't get a chance
before, but I'm Diana Moore.
- Hi, Sam Taggart. Listen, about earlier...
- Don't worry about it. No problem.
Uh, no, I wanted to say that
even if you are authorized...
you can't get in the
way of us doing our job.
Uh, okay, it won't happen again.
Don't blame Diana. She's
dedicated to her work.
What is that? Patient paparazzi?
Yeah, actually, I'm documenting
hospice patients through their deaths.
But I keep mucking it up
by continuing to breathe.
It's all about you, isn't it?
I gotta hang around long
enough to convince her...
- to run away with me to Cabo.
- And I'm holding out for Maui.
- Okay, Maui.
- Well, okay, then.
Sam, do you have someplace
I could stash my stuff...
and maybe upload some photos?
You know what? Let
me check, I'll be back.
Hey, Frank. Can I get a
puréed meal for Trauma 1?
- You're asking me because...?
- Make it mashed potatoes and turkey.
- Somebody's getting bossy in her old age.
- I'm only 28.
Yeah, well, live it up while you
can. You're about to hit the big 3-0.
I'm not afraid of turning 30.
- Morris, I got the G-tube for Mr. Gower.
- Well, I think you should be.
That's when gravity takes over
and everything north turns south.
- What?
- He means you got a small window...
before you go from
miss to ma'am...
skinny jeans to relaxed fit, blond
highlights to little black chin hairs.
- Oh, that's so wrong.
- No, really.
You're a smart guy, and I
know Pratt assigned you to me...
but I do my best work alone.
- But I really wanna learn.
- Categorize the charts here.
- You want them by patient name...?
- Surprise me.
Frank, you know
anything about Bluetooth?
- What is a blue tooth?
- I'll take that as a no.
It's my little thing that's broken.
I can't dictate my notes into it.
Get a secretary.
- Oh. Hi. Getting coffee.
- Hey, uh. Tea.
Excuse me.
- Honey?
- Yeah. What? Um... Sorry. Here.
- You busy?
- Very.
How long you been
working on the project?
About a year.
- I'm gonna go.
- Me too.
- You don't find it a tad morbid?
- Well, yeah.
I mean, it's been known to stop a
few conversations at cocktail parties...
but I'm not really just documenting
the end of somebody's existence.
I'm telling the story of
people's lives, rich with history...
engaged in the
struggle to survive.
- But don't they ever wanna let go?
- Yeah, sometimes.
It could be beautiful
too, you know?
I've seen a lot of
dying in my life...
but it just made
me wanna live more.
What do you mean "dying"?
Name a war or civil unrest
since 1984, I've been there.
Covered it. Somalia, Chechnya,
Tiananmen Square, Iraq.
I can see why you're
a big hit at parties.
Yeah, well, you know what,
when their eyes start to glaze over...
I trot out stories of the
famous fashion photographer...
I worked with in
Paris out of school.
Paris?
Wow, I always
wanted to see Paris.
Eighteen, no responsibilities,
nothing to tie me down.
- You know what I mean.
- Oh, yeah, sure.
I went through this
avant-garde stint for a while.
That didn't pay the rent, so
I tried nature photography.
Think models have attitude?
Try working with a moose.
- An exciting life.
- The grass isn't always greener.
- You like photography?
- Oh, no, please.
I'm lucky if I don't put my finger
over the lens on a disposable camera.
I gotta go. Use the room
for as long as you want.
Excuse me, coming
through. Hey, what you got?
Derek Marchak, 32, driver of a
jackknifed truck on the Dan Ryan.
- Where's Mary?
- Good vitals, deep lacs, abdominal pain.
- We'll call her.
- She was with me. She rides with me.
They were cutting her out.
Truck was mangled bad.
I gotta go to her,
she'll be scared.
- I gotta go to her.
- Settle down.
As soon as we find
her, we'll let you know.
Corey Hales, semi versus compact.
Sheared the roof right off the car.
- Tachy to 132, systolic 74, sats 94.
- Was he conscious on the scene?
He went apneic
in the rig, GCS 7.
Vincent Hales,
restrained driver.
- Daddy's here. Hang in there.
- Why isn't he boarded and collared?
- He refused. Wanted to be with his boy.
- Not acceptable.
Was walking and
talking with good vitals.
Son was crashing, I
wasn't about to argue.
- He's gonna be okay?
- Sats down to 83.
- Okay, let's move it.
- Lungs clear, breath sounds are equal.
- Let them know we moved Mr. Gower.
- Belly's soft, stable pelvis.
- I'll get his arm for you.
- CBC, trauma panel, type and cross.
Got a flash. RAY:
What happened, man?
I don't know. It
was all so fast.
Okay, we need a tox screen
and an ETOH level as well.
- Hi.
- Hey, Mayday.
I got a page. I'm Dr. Rasgotra
from Surgery. Does anything hurt?
Not really. My wife, did
they bring in my wife?
Let us work on you.
- I'll find out.
Alert and oriented. Vitals
good, needs Surgery to sign off.
Lower extremities clear,
no step-offs, no deformities.
- Some nasty knee surgeries.
- Medial meniscus? ACL? Anything?
- Both. Old war wounds, football.
- Oh, yeah? Where'd you play?
Bunch of places, Indiana, Ohio.
I was pretty good for a while.
- Can I get you to sign this quick?
- What is it?
Consent to treatment.
We need you to sign before
we can do any labs or tests.
Where it says
patient's signature.
He may have hit his head
harder than we thought.
All right, better get
a scan. Sam, call CT.
Good mechanism for ICH, right?
Yeah, car crashes are
a leading cause of TBI.
- Phone's out. GATES:
Irrigation tray, 4-by-4 of 0 silk.
- Hey.
- Sats only 81.
Does your phone work?
Yeah. BOBECK: No,
I got it, I got it. I'm in.
Are you in pain, Mr. Hales?
Someone take him to Exam 3...
get a C-collar on him, have
a Resident check him out.
- I'm staying with my son.
- Chuny, call for a vent.
She needs to access first.
His pressure is too
low. He's too clamped.
We were driving back from
Ohio. Went to see my parents.
Okay, IO going
into the left tibia.
Okay, run a liter of NS through the
IO, place another one on the other side.
- I'll do a subclavian.
- BP's 76/24.
- What's that mean? ABBY:
His pressure's too low.
- He might be bleeding internally.
- Hey, Sam, is Neela next door?
- Yeah.
- Can you please ask her to come in here?
I got a stab wound to the neck in Triage.
I can't find anybody in a white coat.
- Pratt, you go.
- Pulse is in the 140s.
Push unit's almost in.
Hanging O-neg in the other IO.
Damn, I can't get a flash.
Hypotensive kid with no good
access? Shall I put in a femoral?
Yeah, go ahead.
Hey, I saw him
after the accident.
Eighteen gauge and
a Cordis introducer.
Hey, he was driving
the truck, wasn't he?
He's the one who caused this.
- We don't know that.
Hey, you. I'm talking to you.
Hey, look what you did to my son.
- Mr. Hales, calm down.
- He killed my wife and daughter.
- That kid gonna be all right?
- If you don't control yourself...
- What he's saying, is it true?
- Did I do that? VINCENT:
What am I supposed to do?
You killed my wife and daughter.
Bastard.
Stole the film
off the processor.
- How much in so far?
- Almost 3 liters.
Vitals? MARQUEZ:
Pulse is 138. BP 75/29.
- It's okay, son, you're doing great.
- The fluid's not touching him.
That's because it's not
getting into his circulation.
- SI joint disruption.
- Pelvic fracture. I'll get the T-POD.
All the fluid we're running into his lower
extremities is pouring into the fracture.
- He needs access above the break.
- How do I get this on?
- I'll show you.
- Mae Lee?
Dr. Dubenko sent me to observe.
You can do an IO up there?
It's a little trickier to get the
position right, but you can.
Two hundred mics
per kilo of Factor 7A.
All right, I'm in. Running
the blood up here.
He should go upstairs for
angio and then maybe the O.R.
- You mean an operation?
- Perhaps, but he should be okay.
You hear that,
buddy? It's all good.
CT results.
We got word on your wife. She's
being choppered in. Be here soon.
- Did they say how she is?
- Uh, no.
- But I'll get an update.
- Thanks.
Well, good news. Your neck is fine
and your brain looks normal and healthy.
Yeah, I bet.
If I wasn't so damn stupid, my wife
wouldn't be coming in here by chopper.
Kids wouldn't be hurt.
You need to be
observed overnight.
We'll keep you down
here till we find you a bed.
You should rest now,
Mr. Marchak, okay?
So, birthday girl, you
been getting your sexy on...
now that Alex is away at
that fancy boarding school?
It's not fancy, Morris.
I sent my kid there because he
needs help. More than I could give him.
Of course. I'm sorry.
Yeah, but now I feel like I
might've made a mistake.
I've been e-mailing him, I've been
calling him, but he's ignoring me.
No, no, no, you did the
right thing. Alex needed help.
It may take him
some time to adjust...
but don't worry, everything's
gonna turn out fine.
Hope so.
Hey, Frank, any updates on the
chopper with the trucker's wife?
- Negative.
- Any calls for me?
Double negative.
Hey, Abby, awesome
save on that boy today.
Oh, thank you, Hope.
You were a big help.
So there's something I'd like to
talk to you about if you have a minute.
I don't really right
now, but maybe later?
Sure, no problem.
Yeah, Alex Taggart. No. Has
he gotten any of my messages?
Sam, my pancreatitis
guy needs orthostatics...
- an NG tube and repeat blood gas.
- Yeah, sure.
Give the results to
Kovac. I'm out of here.
Will you just tell him that his
mother called again? Thank you.
- What is this?
- Oh, no, Sam, you don't have to...
"Ten Don'ts Before You Say I Do.
Taffeta or Tulle,
It's Up to You."
- Are you getting married?
- Me? No.
It's just... This is wedding research
that I've collected over the years.
It weighs a ton. How long
you been doing research?
- Since I was 10. SAM:
Ten? What's it doing here?
Well, someone I know
is getting married...
and I thought she
might like to borrow it...
without getting
angry or hurting me.
I have no idea how to plan a
wedding, when that ever happens to me.
Weddings are wonderful
and they're magical and...
Oh.
Oops. So sorry.
Well, I would be honored,
Sam, to help you...
when your day comes.
Thanks.
Wow. Tony, I can't believe
you let me do a paracentesis.
Well, my philosophy is 90
percent of learning is doing.
I was wondering, though.
As an intern, don't
you need supervision?
Let's just keep that
between you and me, okay?
Nobody really needs to know
about it. People like Kovac, Pratt.
- Yeah, got it, got it.
- Hey, Neela.
Why don't you go
check on the charts?
Double-check them.
Be thorough. It'll be fun.
- Yeah, cool. Cool.
- Okay?
- Need help?
- Oh, thanks, but we're...
I've got it, Neela. Lucien
wants you to stay down here.
Lucien does?
- So how are things?
- Good.
Sarah spent the weekend
with her grandparents.
It gave me time to think
about everything, you know.
I'm gonna talk to her about what Meg
said and the whole paternity-test thing.
- Any idea how she'll take it?
- I don't know.
I'm still having a hard
time with it myself.
If there's anything I can do...
I don't wanna put you
in an awkward position.
I know, but if I can help...
But I don't want you to feel...
like you have to do anything
more than you want to do.
I know, but I mean...
Actually, you know...
I just don't know how I fit in.
Well, I understand, I totally
understand. I'll keep you posted.
- Okay.
- Bye. Bye.
Unrestrained passenger,
prolonged extrication...
blunt trauma to chest. - Abby.
Hypotensive, hypoxic
with respiratory distress.
- Okay, Trauma 2.
- Updated vitals.
BP 90 palp, pulse
120, 89 percent sats.
Is she from the expressway
crash? Mary Marchak?
She needs an airway.
Seven and a half ET tube
with a scope and a curved blade.
Paradoxical chest
movement on the left.
Pulse is thready.
Flail chest, 20 of
etomidate, 120 sux.
Pupils equal and reactive.
Are you okay?
O-2 sat 86 percent.
CBC, trauma panel, Foley,
chest, pelvis and C-spine films.
- How long you had that?
- Didn't know you cared.
I don't. Find me later
and I'll check it out.
Have fun, kids.
The Medivan's right outside.
- Oh, great.
- Because he's really anxious to get home.
- He's a fighter.
Well, doctors gave him three
weeks. It's been three months.
He's also quite a character.
- Yeah.
I wanna make sure he's
set up before I get my things.
- I'll pack it up.
- Thank you.
Thank you, Miss Taggart.
It's been a pleasure.
Till we meet again.
- Cordis introducer.
- Spleen looks good.
- Damn it, where's our blood?
- Ten more minutes for cross-match.
Fluid by the liver,
hemopneumothorax on the left.
- You need me?
- Not big enough to cause tamponade.
- Crit 32 percent. NEELA:
Sterile 6s to me and Mae Lee.
- Yes, Sam, I did. NEELA:
Second chest tube and 10 blade.
- Give the first one a chance to work.
- There isn't time.
- Well, we don't have room.
- Hey, hey, hey, wait.
There are too many people
in here and a full ER out there.
- Abby, go clear the board.
- Morris.
Pratt's shift is over,
Kovac is at a meeting.
Someone needs to push charts.
- Fine.
Sam, find me a cell
saver now, please?
Please, what's going on? I
can't see anything. How's Mary?
- Doctors are doing everything they can.
- Is she gonna be okay?
- Found one.
- She has to be okay.
Please, please,
she's my whole life.
Mary, honey, I'm right here.
- Found it.
It's gonna be okay. Hold
on. MORRIS: Ray, set it up.
If this doesn't work,
think about a thoracotomy.
- For blunt trauma?
- Survival's one in 400.
That's because we don't
usually do it until after they arrest.
Make the incision in
the anterior auxiliary line.
- BP 65.
- Could have a cardiac laceration.
No, the scan showed
minimal fluid in the pericardium.
Hold the clamp so it
doesn't go in too far.
Can find it with my finger,
but I can't get the tube in.
Extend the incision.
Here, like this.
Let me show you.
- Scalpel. MARQUEZ:
Heart rate's dropping.
Hang another O-neg and
call the blood bank again.
- Sats, 82.
- Come on, Neela.
She's getting hard to bag.
- Whoa.
Get the Thora-Seal.
She's gonna bleed out.
She's getting blood. Do
the thoracotomy in the O.R.
- She's bradying down.
- She'll die before she gets there.
- This is the only time we have.
- You made your case.
Thoracotomy tray.
- Hey.
- Hey, how was your meeting?
- Oh. Long, boring, unnecessary.
- Sounds fun.
- How would you feel about eloping?
- Eloping? What brought that on?
Morris knows we're
getting married.
- You know, I bet Hope told him.
- What? Hope knows?
Mm-hm.
She's got this
bizarre wedding ESP.
Morris suggested we should get
married in Vegas with Celine Dion.
Ha, ha. Well, we need to shut
them down before they tell everybody.
How do we do that?
Beat them with a bag of oranges?
Because I hear it
doesn't leave any marks.
Or we could just talk to them.
- That's much better.
- Okay.
- Bye.
- Hey, Lockhart.
- Hey.
- Ready to play doctor?
- Yeah. Um...
Come on in here.
- Unzip your flight suit.
- Usually, I get dinner first...
Quiet or I'll give you a
rectal just for the hell of it.
Nice bedside manner.
- Did you get a flu shot?
- Yeah.
Good breath sounds, a
few crackles at the base.
Any change in
exercise tolerance?
I get short of breath about
halfway through a lap dance.
Thanks for the visual.
You know, I'm not much
for complaining, but...
But what?
Back in '01 after
the towers fell...
we jumped in my truck, drove
straight through to New York.
We worked the pile
for a couple of weeks.
Not that we found anyone alive.
You think that's
what caused this?
Well, we kept working, breathing
in pulverized concrete, glass...
dust particles laced with
benzene, dioxin, asbestos, lead.
Wearing any protective gear?
According to the government
and the EPA, we didn't need any.
Always reliable.
They got a name for
it, Trade Center Cough.
Some of the guys got it, they're
sick. Asthma, lymphoma, leukemia.
One of them died in January.
Sorry.
Pulse ox is okay,
but it could be better.
If I have something...
or if I'm gonna get
something, I wanna know.
I'll order a chest
x-ray and some labs.
This is just between us.
Even my wife doesn't know.
I don't wanna be grounded while they dick
around trying to prove a scientific link.
Okay.
I'm on till 8. Probably
have the results by then.
Lockhart.
I owe you.
- Okay, here's some light.
- I see the pericardium.
- Mayo scissors.
- Give 2 units FFP.
Two-0 silk with a
pledget. I feel a defect.
- Surgery, what's the story?
- Blunt trauma, flail chest.
Hypotensive despite fluid
resuscitation and transfusion.
We hooked up the cell
saver to recycle blood...
while I put in the
second chest tube.
- There's fluid in the...
- Pericardium.
I thought there was a ventricular
laceration from a fractured rib...
so we decided to
do a thoracotomy.
There was a defect in the ventricle
and now Neela's holding pressure on it.
- Excellent, Mae Lee.
- Wait a minute, that is not exact...
There's surgical
consults in the ER.
Go see to them. I'll do
the repair with Mae Lee.
- Yeah, well, I've already got...
- I've got it, Neela. I've got it.
Okay. Visualize the injury...
Self-portrait.
Ovarian cancer.
First time around.
First?
But they say the
third time's a charm.
- I'm sorry.
- And I'm pissed off and annoyed.
Are you in treatment now?
Two more sessions.
At least this time, I
didn't lose my hair.
Yeah, you look great.
I feel fine.
I felt fine when they
first diagnosed me.
Who knew a few days'
bloating was stage four?
Yeah, unfortunately, there's
no real reliable screening tool.
Yet.
Just need money and research.
We're still the poor stepchild of
the breast-cancer publicity machine.
All those pink ribbons.
Do you know what color is
associated with ovarian cancer?
Teal.
I mean, what is that?
It's not blue, it's not green.
And I'm guessing that your illness
has something to do with your project.
Yeah, my cancer
was my wake-up call.
It made me more
passionate about living...
about doing the things
that make me happy.
Not worrying about
the stupid stuff.
Happy birthday.
What? No.
- What? No, no, I can't take that.
- Oh, yes, yes, yes, you can.
Companies give me
free stuff all the time.
Really?
- Thank you.
- Use it. It's fun.
- Yeah.
- Point and shoot.
Just remember to
move your finger.
- Odd place for a bee sting.
- I know. I have no idea...
All right, best
not to talk, okay?
Half cc of one
percent lido and epi.
That should make her
tongue nice and numb. All right.
And got it.
Suck on Popsicles till
the swelling goes down.
Next time you go jogging,
keep your mouth closed.
Get all that?
I'll write it up and
add it to your charts.
- How's that going, by the way?
- All done.
Except, well, I didn't wanna mention
it, but I found several spelling errors.
Oh. That was just a test to make
sure you were paying attention.
- And you did very well. Bravo, Larry.
- Thanks.
Gates.
- I'm not your personal answering service.
- Sorry. Gates.
Uh, no, there's no Seymour Butts
here. Hello, Sarah, where are you?
Hey... Oh.
- Grandma and Grandpa drop you off?
- Yeah, they say hi.
- Look what I got.
- Wow, fancy. Who's gonna pay for it?
Grandma and Grandpa
are paying for it.
They say they'll be able to
keep in touch with me better...
and it's gonna be good for emergencies,
because I'll have it and then...
All right, I'm sold, but we're
gonna set up some rules.
Of course we are.
- Did you have a good time?
- Yeah, Grandpa let me ride Beauty.
She's the one that's jet black with a
white spot in the middle of her forehead.
- That sounds like fun.
- Yeah.
And they told me all
these stories about Mom.
Like when she was my age, she took
Grandpa's car for a ride without asking.
Yeah, well, don't get any ideas.
So you think maybe you'd like to
spend a little more time with them?
Sure.
Maybe, um...
I don't know, you think you
might wanna live with them?
Well, I don't know. I
mean, my school's here.
So I can't really do that.
And all my friends are here.
You're here too.
I mean, why would
I wanna do that?
Just asking. Come on, let's
get my stuff, get out of here.
- V-fib.
- Charge the internal paddles.
Tie the suture while
they prepare to defibrillate.
Tie the knot.
- Mae Lee, tie the knot.
- Charged.
Twenty joules.
Clear. Clear!
Uh, still no response.
Mae Lee, tie the knot.
- Out of my way.
- Got it.
Hypocalcemic from
massive transfusion.
She's also hypoxic from
the pulmonary bleed. Clear.
Yeah, got it.
Still no pulse.
She's in pump failure
from cardiac contusion.
Resume internal compressions.
V-fib again.
I don't think we're gonna
get her out of it this time.
No, she's coagulopathic,
I can't stop the bleeding.
Thirty joules. Okay, clear.
Stop, stop, stop it. There's
nothing more we can do.
Stop it. It's over. It's over.
Call it, Ray.
Okay, time of death, 13:25.
Repair of a cardiac laceration is way
beyond a fourth-year medical student.
I did the repair. Mae
Lee put in one stitch.
I was there. I was in a much
better position to assist you.
Learn to share the sandbox.
Mae Lee's here for four weeks.
You've got four years.
You'll get another chance.
This isn't the procedure. Do
you have a problem with me?
Do I have a problem with you?
Look, you're a very talented
surgeon, Neela, but, yeah.
Maybe I've let our
personal friendship...
get in the way of our
professional relationship.
Well, how? What do you mean?
I'm the chief and
you're an intern. That's it.
- M... Maybe I've sent off mixed signals...
- No, it seems very clear.
You're angry with me. I don't
understand. Is this about Manish?
I am not angry with you
and this is not about Manish.
It's just... I just think it's time
we reset our dynamic, that's all.
You gonna reset that dead woman
there? Reset her grieving husband?
No, you can't take it personally
when a surgery doesn't go well...
just as I can't make
surgical decisions based...
- Based on what?
- On my personal feelings towards you.
Look, um, we both know
that poor woman didn't die...
because Mae Lee was
in there and you weren't.
Her injuries were far too great.
Nothing on this earth could've saved her.
Give it to me straight.
Your blood work was normal.
Your chest x-rays were clear.
But there is some
evidence of sinusitis.
So here are your films
and your test results.
Plus a prescription for azithromycin
and Pulmicort, that's an inhaler.
It should help.
- So I'm okay for now.
- Looks like it.
This is a good thing.
There are lots of people who worked
at ground zero and at the landfills.
I mean, how many of them
are walking time bombs?
No good deed goes
unpunished, I guess.
- Maybe next time we'll be smarter.
- Maybe now you'll tell your wife.
What? And give her more
ammo to nag me about? Heh, heh.
- Night, Lockhart.
- Good night.
Someone from Social Work will be
down to help you with arrangements.
Is there anyone we can call?
No.
It was just the two of us.
We liked it like that.
We never ran out
of things to say.
Even on long stretches of
road that seem to go on for days.
Must be nice to spend that amount
of time with the person you love.
Actually, she was the
brains behind everything.
Did all the paperwork, paid
the bills, read the road maps.
I can't tell you how many times
she kept us from getting lost.
Today was gonna be different.
- Different?
- Yeah.
The rain makes her sleepy.
So I told her to take a nap.
I was sure I knew
what exit to take.
But the sign wasn't the sign.
I got confused.
I didn't wanna wake her up.
I wanted to do it myself.
Do what?
Read.
I wanted to read
the damn exit sign.
Derek...
You don't know how to read?
Mary was trying to teach me.
You graduated high
school and went to college?
They just passed me along.
Nobody cared long as I could read the
defense and get the ball in the end zone.
Coaches said I was gonna
get drafted first round.
I wasn't prepared
for it not to work out.
I'm sorry.
I just wanted to make you proud.
- Get.
- Heh, heh.
Sarah?
I'll do the dishes after I
do my homework, okay?
No, this isn't about the dishes.
Could you come back in here a sec?
I need to talk to
you for a second.
I've been trying to figure
out a way to tell you this...
and if I should tell you this.
What?
The night that your mom died...
she told me...
that I'm your father.
My dad's name
was Keith. He died.
I know, I know. We all
thought that your dad was Keith.
But, um, there's a chance
that that might not be true.
But Mom didn't tell me.
Why wouldn't she tell me?
I don't know, sweetie. She
must have had her reasons.
So are you my dad or not?
Well, there's a simple
test we can take.
It's called a paternity test...
and if you want, we
can take it tonight.
Why are you doing this now?
Is this because I don't wanna go
live with Grandma and Grandpa?
- Sarah, I just want...
- You're just trying to get rid of me.
- I want what's best for you.
- No, you're lying.
I know you're lying.
You're lying just like Mom.
She always lied.
- Sarah...
- No, okay?
I don't want you to be my
dad and I'm not taking your test.
You know, Morris
might have something.
Maybe we should get
married someplace exotic.
Like where?
The beach or the mountains. Why
don't...? We could go to Croatia.
Really?
No one from work
would be able to be there.
Do it. One, two, three, go.
Stop.
Would that be so bad?
Morris, Hope.
We need to talk to you.
Who? Us? KOVAC: Look, listen.
Abby and I really appreciate
your interest in our engagement...
- It's so exciting, a wedding.
- Hope.
Sorry.
And while your planning
is very thoughtful...
it's borderline obsessive.
- Oh, we just wanna help.
- Well, next time, just don't help.
And don't blab to anybody.
Not us, just no one.
Okay. I mean, if
that's what you want.
- We do.
Hey, everybody. Look who's here.
Sam!
Guys.
- Look at everybody.
- Let's have a toast, Sam.
To Sam, happy
birthday and many more.
Hear, hear.
B-10. You didn't actually mean
to put in "Get Down Tonight."
I like KC and the Sunshine Band.
It's better than the
choice that you made.
Oh, hey, "Woman" by Wolfmother?
That is destined to be a classic.
On what planet?
Now...
I know we're
pretending to be normal.
And I know we're pretending
that this isn't awkward.
- But it's kind of awkward, isn't it?
- Yeah, kind of.
So, what, are we just gonna
say that this never happened?
I know we should
talk about this...
but, uh, these days, I just feel
like my head's gonna explode.
There's just a lot
of stuff going on.
Gates.
I'm trying to figure it out.
I, uh, wanna figure
it out. It's just...
I just need some time.
I've been there once before. It
didn't turn out so good for me.
Well, you won't have
to wait long. Okay?
Okay.
- Oh, yes, B-10.
- Somebody make it stop.
- Sam, come and dance with us.
- Please?
All right.
Oh, wait a second,
you guys. Be right back.
Hello? Hey, wait, I can
barely hear you. Hold on.
No, no, no, don't hang
up. Wait a sec, wait a sec.
Alex? Hey, I'm
so glad you called.
I was worried.
Yeah?
Yeah, it is my birthday.
Thank you.
You okay?
If the test says you're my
dad, can I stay with you?
Absolutely.
Okay.
You sure?
Is it gonna hurt?
No, we just...
We'll take a little
swab of one cheek...
and then send it to the lab...
and then they send us
the results in the mail.
That's it?
Mm-hm.
And until then?
Nothing changes.
Of course I'm coming
up this weekend.
Yeah.
Uh. Well, maybe
what if I brought you...?
Oh, you gotta go?
Okay, time's up. I got it.
I miss you too.
Yeah, thanks for
calling me, okay?
I love you too, baby.
Okay.
Bye.
I don't mind If you don't mind
'Cause I don't shine
If you don't shine
Before you jump
Tell me what you find
So you already got a law degree and
now you're going to medical school?
Yeah, corporate
law wasn't for me.
I wasn't helping anyone. Besides,
I need to be where the action is.
What? What is this?
Come on, you jokers. Get out
on the dance floor, come on.
- No, sorry, no chance.
- Come on, Frank, you know you wanna.
- Larry.
- All right.
Slippin' in my
faith Until I fall
You never return that call
Times like these...
when I see all these
young people together...
makes me fear for
the future of mankind.
If you don't mind 'Cause I
don't shine if you don't shine
Put your back on me