Previously on ER:
If anything changes
with Jody, call me.
- Or just call me.
- I will.
- Who's going to Johns Hopkins?
- Dr. Rasgotra.
I'm just looking.
You keep mumbling about the hiring freeze,
pushing me to do interviews all over.
We have something worth saving.
Did you realize that before or
after you had sex with Daria?
I wanna be with you.
There, I said it. You can
go ahead and gloat now.
I'd rather do something else.
Frank, we gotta get
these tele admits up.
- I'm all over it.
- There's at least 30 in the rack.
What were you doing last night?
Playing "Guitar Hero,"
doing Jell-O shots.
- Two messages from Kelly.
- Kelly who?
She said you'd know. That's
her phone number at Swissotel.
- Car crash victim coming in.
- Clear Trauma 1 and get Surgery.
- We're gridlocked.
- Quick dispo in Curtain 1. Grady?
Off duty, and going to Jumbo Mart for
caffeine to get me through my charting.
- Well, who else is on?
- Well, we got Brenner, Morris and...
What do you need?
That's okay.
- I haven't picked up a patient yet.
- No, go meet the trauma.
It's busy. I got time.
Okay, fooling around with her
boyfriend, and they lost the condom.
She's fully dressed in the ER.
She should be in a private room
with a chaperone for a pelvic.
- Yeah, there's no need, actually.
- What?
Go on. Go get the history.
- Hello, I'm Dr. Gates.
- Tammy.
So the proverbial lost condom.
Yeah, it is kind
of embarrassing.
Well, don't worry. Tell
me what happened.
The condom came off,
and I couldn't reach it.
My boyfriend tried to
help, but he's useless.
I went to the bathroom
and gagged myself...
but I couldn't
vomit it up either.
I'm not gonna suffocate, am I?
- Dr. Rasgotra.
- Dr. Brenner.
How was your night?
Four hours of sleep.
You would've got a lot less
than that if you were in my bed.
Next time, you should spend
the night with me in the call room.
What, you mean on a twin
bed with scratchy sheets...
and phone
interruptions every hour?
That's kind of hot.
You know, I was thinking of getting
Neil Young tickets for Saturday.
- That sounds good.
- You like him?
Yeah, I love him.
Especially his early stuff.
- Really?
- Yeah.
"Old Man," "Only Love
Can Break Your Heart."
- "Heart of Gold."
Neela.
Trauma coming in.
Thank you.
Ahem. Are we out of sugar?
I don't think so.
What are they doing?
Our old medical records
are going in remote storage.
Let me ask you something,
kind of man-to-man.
Do you believe in
the three-date rule?
You seeing someone new?
I don't know if we're
actually seeing each other.
We had lunch
together in the cafeteria.
I bought her a burger
one night at Ike's.
Wow, sounds serious.
I like her. I just can't tell
if she's interested in me.
Well, I'm pretty sure I'm not the
right guy to ask for relationship advice.
Hey, the run got
diverted to Mercy.
Ooh. Whoa, whoa.
Hey, you all right?
Tony, Archie, I need some help.
- Grab a gurney.
- Looks like this guy got beat up.
- What's your name, sir?
- Oliver.
- Oliver what?
- No wallet, no ID.
- Pupils are equal.
- You know where you are?
Hospital.
Oriented to place.
What year is it?
Who's the president? Do
you know who the president is?
Hey, hey, LBJ, how many
kids did you kill today?
Chicago is a police state.
- Violating our constitutional rights.
- Let's go, come on, move. Come on.
Hey, hey, hey, LBJ.
You don't have to talk.
We'll take good care of you.
Relax, brother, enjoy the ride.
Decent breath sounds. Looks
like he got kicked a bunch of times.
- Yeah, or fell.
- He looks too good to be homeless.
No blood in the belly.
Abrasion where somebody
stole his watch. Definite assault.
We already called in the police.
Chest is normal. The head
CT's gonna be normal too.
Not if there's a brain bleed.
These old altered guys, it's
always something metabolic.
Just order more IV fluids.
Let me go clear the board.
No, stay on this. Buff him
up, find out where he belongs.
- Scanner's ready.
- Potentially unstable.
Dr. Gates can monitor
him in Radiology.
Last BP was 110/65.
- Hold it, hold it, hold it.
- Excuse us.
Are you a student driver?
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry you had to
pull me out of my car.
Is the oxygen helping, Donna?
I think so.
Have you ever had
any trouble breathing?
Not till last week.
- Mom, I parked the car.
- Thanks, honey.
- That's my son, Dylan.
- Hey.
She couldn't even talk.
So you were saying
about last week?
They told me I had lung cancer.
- Where are you being treated?
- Nowhere yet.
We were supposed
to go to Northwestern...
but in the car, her breathing
got so bad that I pulled into here.
I have papers and x-rays, if...
The Willow Ridge Medical Center.
Our local hospital
where they diagnosed me.
Okay, do you smoke
cigarettes, Donna?
Ten to 15 percent of lung
cancer occurs in nonsmokers.
- We've been on the Internet a bit.
- It's in the left upper lobe.
Liver function
tests are elevated.
Okay, and did they explain the
brain CT results to you, Donna?
Two spots.
They thought that surgery and chemo
and radiation could buy me some time.
Stage four lung cancer has a
five-year survival rate of 5 percent.
- But one in 20 survive.
- Well.
Okay, well, we'll have our
surgeons and oncologists consult.
- I was hoping to go to Northwestern.
- Yeah, you're too sick to move.
Yeah, I'm gonna cancel
the audition, Mom.
No, Dylan, you're not
canceling anything.
Now, get to orchestra
hall on time...
and you can stay with
Aunt Harriet tonight, okay?
Okay.
Dr. Morris, I'm looking for
an old guy, victim of assault.
- He should be right back.
- Okay.
You know, I could be
wrong, but I thought I saw...
you and Officer Diaz
eating lunch the other day.
- Yeah, we were on a case together.
- Really?
Because I've had cases with you,
but we've never had lunch together.
Plus, it must've been a funny case,
because I noticed a lot of smiling.
Yeah, well, Officer
Diaz is a nice lady.
We all know that.
And I know you know
cops stick together.
- Yeah.
- So be careful.
If you break her heart,
we may have to break you.
Head CT was normal,
just as I predicted.
And guess what,
he's hypernatremic.
- How bad is his sodium?
- Hundred and sixty-five, dry as a bone.
- Does this guy talk?
- Not really.
I'll check for Missing
Person reports.
- Did you calculate free water deficit?
- Six liters.
Hypernatremia
shouldn't be corrected at...
One milli-equivalent
per liter per hour.
Need a doctor here.
- You can have Dr. Gates.
- Well, shouldn't I stay here and finish?
No, you've been wanting off
this case from the get-go. See you.
- He's starting to open his eyes.
- That's a good sign.
Oliver?
Oliver, try to squeeze
my hand. Oliver?
Curtain 3 is open.
Hi, I'm Dr. Gates.
- Damien. My wife, Corazon.
- Hello.
Sam, did you ever call Kelly?
I didn't think so, because
now she's coming to see you.
Let me know when she gets here.
- You don't see many of these.
- It's a negative pressure ventilator.
When the air is sucked out of
the chamber, it flows into his lungs.
I had polio when I was 3. Don't
breathe too well on my own.
- Is that why you're here today?
- No, fever...
abdominal pain,
possible appendicitis.
I'm a retired RN.
- I need to get a BP.
- I'm gonna need to examine his belly.
There are portholes on the side.
Stick your arms through the
neoprene if you wanna poke me.
All right.
Are you in this all the time?
We have three kids,
so, no, not all the time.
I use it 18 hours a day.
- How long have you guys been together?
- Forty-five years.
I got an e-mail from Yale.
They want two more
letters of recommendation.
That seems pointless if
Dubenko can offer you a position.
I'm not sure he thinks I'm
right for the job. Oh, man.
That's the head CT.
This must be the
lung mass, yikes.
- Where's the patient?
- LFTs and CBC.
Looks like the horse
is out of the barn.
Son's at bedside. No dad.
Donna, this is Dr. Rasgotra,
Dr. Dubenko. Her son.
- Hello.
- Dylan.
- Hi, nice to meet you.
I've reviewed the films...
and I'm sorry to say that the tumor
is far too advanced for surgery.
Are you sure?
With cancer in the liver, the brain
and bones, I'm afraid that an operation...
would only mean pain and
suffering without prolonging your life.
- It's in my bones?
- We think so.
- What about chemotherapy?
- It's possible, but...
We'll see what
the oncologists say.
Have you thought about
your wishes for life support?
Perhaps this is
better discussed later.
I made a living will
about 10 years ago.
I don't wanna be kept alive...
- if I have a terminal...
- Mom.
You might wanna
explore hospices.
We don't need to talk...
What's a hospice? What is that?
A way to keep people comfortable
in the final stages of illness.
Are you saying that...?
Look, we're gonna come back...
after you've had a little
bit more time to consider.
Yeah. BRENNER: Okay.
Doctors?
- What are you doing?
- What?
I asked for surgical opinion,
not for the Grim Reaper.
I was being truthful.
They have barely processed
the cancer diagnosis...
You want me to
sugarcoat it? To lie?
I want you to give
them a bit of hope.
Maybe there's something
positive to offer. Thoracentesis?
Good idea. That should
make her feel better.
Good, well, why
don't we lead with...
Frank said you guys
have fresh coffee.
I hope you have half-and-half.
Okay, I'll just
make a fresh pot.
Oh, okay.
Hi, I'm Kelly.
Hi, I'm Dr. Gates.
Oh. What kind of doctor are you?
Well, this is an ER, so...
That must be complicated.
You gotta know a lot
of stuff about everything.
How long you worked here?
- A couple of years.
- Cool.
I've only been in town for two
nights, and I'm craving deep-dish pizza.
Oh, Lou Malnati's.
Oh, yeah?
Yeah, that sounds great.
What are you doing for dinner?
I don't think that would
be such a good idea.
Why not?
I just got out of
a relationship.
When you fall off a bike,
you get right back on it.
You got a sesame seed.
- Kelly?
- Sammy.
Wha...?
What are you...? Oh, my God.
- Hi.
- What are you...?
Oh, my God, look at you.
Look at you. Hi.
I'm really sorry to just
barge in on you at work.
You know, I got your message,
but I've been busy at work and...
No, that's fine.
So how do you two
know each other?
Tony, this is my sister, Kelly.
Tie up a few loose
ends, I could take a break.
I'll be fine, me and the
Home Shopping Network.
Ortho's on Line 4, and they
need you at the lung tap.
Go save some lives.
Stay out of trouble.
That's your sister, huh?
- She seems very nice.
- Yeah.
- Ortho?
- Sam, cytology and culture on this.
Take a deep breath.
- Much easier.
- Good, we can pull three liters.
- Dylan, it's late, you should go.
- I'm not going.
He has an audition today for
the Juilliard School in New York.
- Impressive.
- What instrument?
English horn.
I used to play the viola.
The English horn is lovely.
Honey, they're only here once a
year. You might never get another shot.
I'm much better. You
think it's okay if he goes?
- Yeah, I don't see why not.
- It'd be best to stay.
With the extent of your disease, things
could suddenly take a turn for the worse.
- You mean, that could happen today?
- That's pretty unlikely.
Yeah, I should, I should stay.
- Dylan...
- Mom, I'm staying.
Let's wait a bit and see
how she's doing, okay?
- Sam, you seen the old guy?
- Not in a while.
Oxygen's off, so
are the monitors.
- Looks like he eloped.
- Great.
- What happened?
- I think we lost a patient.
- Check the bathroom.
- We can see your polio guy now.
I need you on a paramedic run.
Tell my sister it's
gonna be a while.
I gotta find a
demented grandpa...
pick up an incoming off a rig and
pull a patient out of an iron lung.
April Robinson, syncopal
episode at Walgreen's, still altered.
- Any seizure activity?
- No.
- What's up with the handcuffs?
- Passed out, busted for shoplifting.
- How convenient.
- No, she's real.
Blood sugar is over 400,
12 lead EKG, negative for MI.
I gave a liter of saline
and got her sats up.
- What do we have? ZADRO:
This lady fainted at Woolworth's.
- Heart history?
- You got me.
- Doesn't have a pulse. MORRIS:
When did she stop breathing?
They pay me to drive them to the
hospital. Lucky I had an oxygen tank.
- She needs a cardiac arrest cart.
- It may be too late for that.
Dilated appendix,
non-compressible.
- So I'll need surgery?
- Yes, most definitely.
- Can it be done with the laparoscope?
- We'll try.
Sometimes we have to convert
to a conventional procedure.
- You mean opening up my belly.
- Yeah.
I use my abdominal
muscles to help me breathe.
His friend had colon surgery
and ended up traked for life.
All right, well, we'll
do the best we can.
Dr. Rasgotra will be
back with the consent form.
- He's a perfect candidate for NOTES.
- What?
Natural Orifice Transluminal
Endoscopic Surgery.
You wanna remove his
appendix through his mouth?
He needs the least invasive
procedure, and NOTES is it.
We don't do that
here. It's experimental.
There's Dr. Horta from San
Diego doing trials at Northwestern.
He's had over 50 cases.
You're cutting a hole in his
stomach, setting up for peritonitis.
It's a 2-millimeter incision that's
occluded by a balloon and transport.
When you're done,
you close with g-Prox.
- They've had success.
- Wanna call this guy?
Chance to be state-of-the-art.
See if he's willing to help
and available today? Long shot.
Blood sugar's down to 350.
Neela wants me in Curtain 2.
Drop the insulin to five
an hour before you go.
- What's going on here?
- Your diabetes is out of control.
- Paramedics brought you to the ER.
- Think of it as a pit stop before jail.
- What are you talking about?
- Why don't you take it easy.
- Step out until she's medically cleared.
- I didn't do anything.
Camera shows you
pocketing lipstick and mascara.
I was gonna pay for
that. I got distracted.
You can't keep me. My
daughter needs me home.
Should've thought about that before.
- Hey, come on, officer.
Can I ask you a question?
"I was gonna pay for
it." What a load of crap.
You know, she doesn't
seem like a crook.
- Does she have any priors?
- Any priors?
You have been
hanging out with Claudia.
- Hey, Morris, we found him.
- Excuse me.
Outside, barely conscious.
Pulse ox, 78 on room air.
Probably blossoming pulmonary
contusions from trauma.
- Open an airway tray at 8-0.
- Where's Sam?
On her way.
- Are we gonna do this?
- Yeah.
This guy could
be sharp as a tack.
- What do you need?
- Sublingual captopril, four of morphine.
Hey, Sammy, I've been
here for, like, two hours.
- It's kind of a bad time.
- I know, I just can't really wait around.
- I got appointments.
- Can you just let us finish?
- Has everyone met Sam's sister?
- I didn't know you had a sister.
- Hello.
- Hi.
Sam, take a break.
Chuny will take over.
Yeah, you know, looks
like you could use one.
Hey, doc, we busted the mugger.
I got an empty wallet and a
retirement watch from County.
Maybe he worked here.
- Suction on high.
- Call for a vent.
End tidal CO2 detector.
You look good.
I mean, considering the last time I
saw you, we were both in pigtails.
Yeah.
Yeah, it's been
a really long time.
We got some catching up.
You wanna go to
dinner? I get off at 8.
Uh... No, you know, my flight's at
7:30, and I've got my last meeting at 5.
What kind of meetings?
Well, I'm here for
the apparel show.
Oh, my God, I
remember those dresses...
you used to make for your
Cabbage Patch Kids, oh, my.
What, you actually
turned that into a job?
Yeah.
My clothing line just got bought
by Billabong for about $2 million.
- You're kidding.
- No.
You're kidding me.
Yeah, it's...
Well, I've got to travel
to Europe and Japan...
- to launch the new collection, so...
- Wow.
Wow. What, did you just come all
the way from Dallas to rub it in my face?
No.
No, I came to talk about Mom.
I had to move her
to assisted living.
You know, her
emphysema got worse.
- Yeah, well, three packs a day will do it.
- She also had a stroke.
You know, I visit
her, like, twice a week.
And it's not a lot, but
it makes her happy.
And I'm gonna be traveling
for months at a time, so...
You know, I wanna
move her to Chicago.
- No, please don't.
- I'll pay for everything.
Her moving expenses, living expenses.
All you've gotta do is just go visit her.
Look, I've been doing this for
a really long time now, okay?
- I think it's your turn.
- No, it's not.
Look, she's your mother.
You know, even after
everything, she's still your mother.
Who I haven't spoken
to since I was 15.
Well, you know, maybe
it's time that changed too.
All right, I'm in. Bag him.
AC, 14, tidal volume, 500.
Have Frank check personnel records,
see if we can figure out who he is.
Post-expansion pulmonary edema.
- Let's get her son back over here.
- He went to his audition.
- I thought he'd stay.
- I said he could go.
- How soon can he get back?
- I don't know.
We need BiPAP and
set up for an intubation.
Intubation?
She has a living will, she
asked for no heroic measures.
Okay, Donna, Donna, I
need to ask you a question.
- Donna? Donna?
- I should call her son.
Exactly what I didn't
wanna have happen.
Start with the BiPAP. It's
noninvasive, in the spirit of her wishes.
- That's a good idea.
- This isn't a surgical problem.
You're the primary physician
on the case, so you call it.
Let's go, Neela.
Did you reach the son?
No. I might have to intubate.
With a DNR? Can
you even do that?
Well, temporarily. I can
always remove it later.
I promised her son she would
be alive when he got back.
I see. BRENNER: Wait.
There's fluid around the heart. We
can drain that, buy her some time.
Neela, Dr. Horta's here
on your Porta-Lung appy.
PeriVac kit, Betadine.
Well, good luck.
Serum ketones are negative.
- Is that a problem? MORRIS:
Medically, it's good news.
But it means we have no reason
to keep you in the hospital overnight.
So I'm going to jail?
I think they'll let you
out if you pay a fine.
I don't have the money.
What about a loan?
They won't give you a
credit if you don't have a job.
Ever since I got laid off,
I've been cleaning houses.
Barely covers the rent.
- My daughter.
- Your daughter?
Pregnant.
On bed rest.
I'm trying to buy
her a crib and stuff.
You can talk to a social
worker about getting some help.
I have worked
hard my whole life.
I've raised two babies,
never been on welfare.
I had to get my medicine.
- So why would you...?
- Steal a tube of lipstick?
I return it for store credit.
Use the credit
to buy my insulin.
It works.
Dr. Morris.
We're making some
progress IDing your old guy.
There's a patient missing from
a nursing home on Dearborn.
Fits his age and description.
You hear that, Oliver?
Sounds like we found
out where you belong.
- Systolic's down to 80.
- Run in a liter.
You need a hand?
I just need to thread the
catheter over the guide wire.
There's the pericardial
fluid. It should help.
I'll check another
blood pressure, doctor?
What's wrong?
What do you need? You in pain?
- Relax, you're okay. BRENNER:
Hit him with some Versed.
"TB."
TB?
By any chance, does your
lady have tuberculosis?
No, she has cancer.
You're sure?
Do you have a confirmation
on the path report?
It'd be unusual, but TB
could explain everything.
Infection in the lung, the bone,
liver, the brain, around the heart.
You need a sputum stain for AFB.
Better get a mask on her.
You think your guy was a doctor?
Oliver, were you a doctor?
Wouldn't pull you out
if it wasn't important.
Real quick, what's
the fine for shoplifting?
And the maximum jail time?
No, the guys didn't
put me up to this.
Thank you. Get back to class.
- You don't look like you've good news.
- Could be up to six months.
All jails are overcrowded.
It won't be that long.
Her daughter's having
her baby next week.
Hey, Morris.
Okay, I will be back
as soon as I can.
Excuse me, my captain wants to
know how much longer she's gonna be.
- This needs to run in over an hour.
- I thought she was ready.
- If I discharge her, she'll bounce back.
- I gotta call the station.
You know what sucks?
There are guys stealing
cars, shooting guns.
- You're here babysitting a decent lady.
- I'm just doing my job.
- Where's Brenner?
- He ran to the lab.
We think this lady has TB.
Yeah, and this guy
might have figured it out.
Really?
- How long does an AFB stain take?
- Less than an hour.
"To O.M.K. 35 years of service."
Oh, my God.
Do you know who this is?
Yeah, this is Dr. Oliver Kostin.
As in Kostin's Textbook
of Emergency Medicine?
He's a legend.
- Dr. Morgenstern.
- The one and only.
Hey, Chuny. So good to see you.
So good to see you.
This is Dr. Morris
and Dr. Gates.
- Hi.
- Hello.
Dr. Morgenstern ran
this place back in the day.
- What are you doing here?
- I got a call from the nursing home.
Ollie, you gotta stop wandering.
Are you his doctor?
No, his proxy.
His wife died a few years ago.
They never had any children, so
I got a durable power of attorney.
You must have been close.
He taught me everything.
Treated me like a son.
He knows you're here.
And he's having a good day.
What's his baseline?
Multi-infarct dementia
and going downhill fast.
Mm.
He had a great mind.
Now, there's nothing left.
Well, something's
going on in there.
He thinks that lady
has tuberculosis.
Does she?
We don't know yet.
The swelling
behind the right ear.
Could be scrofula.
It's a TB-infected lymph node.
Used to be in the
textbooks, it's not anymore.
- So if he's right, he's still capable...
- No.
It's a flash of an old memory.
Every once in a while, a
stimulus, a sight or a sound...
brings up something from
the past, but it doesn't last long.
For all intents and purposes, he
doesn't interact with the present.
He hardly speaks.
I brought a copy
of his DNR order.
So we shouldn't have tubed him?
He never wanted
to end up like this.
Could we take him off the vent?
Maybe move him into a private room?
Sure.
What about Trauma 1?
He might be
getting a few visitors.
You know, the ER
used to end right here.
He designed your trauma rooms
and got them built 40 years ago.
Dr. Horta cleared his entire
schedule to operate on you.
- Thanks, doc.
- My pleasure.
- We'll see you upstairs.
- I'll be right behind you, honey.
I'm really looking
forward to this.
It's gonna blow your mind.
Oh, Lucien, this is
Dr. Horta from San Diego.
Oh, hi. Yeah, I've
heard all about you.
So this thing's
really gonna happen?
- We're all set to go.
- Oh, you should scrub in.
I can't, I've got a couple
of cases to check in on.
- Let the residents do it.
- Go ahead, I'll be in and out, you guys.
- Let's take the stairs.
- Okay.
- Nice to meet you.
- Yeah.
Lucien, I heard about the
NOTES appy. Pretty cool.
Yeah, it is pretty cool.
Excuse me, officer.
How can I stay at home when
they're sending you off to jail?
You need to be on bed rest.
This is crazy,
Mom. This isn't you.
Dr. Morris, this is
April's daughter, Kendra.
- Hello.
- Hello. Is she okay now?
Her diabetes is
back under control.
Mom, why would you
do something like this?
- I don't know, I guess I wasn't thinking.
- Your mother was trying to help.
This is between her and me, thank you.
- Mom, talk to me.
BP's way up, 170/100.
We should let her rest.
Yeah, I think
you're upsetting her.
What do you think
she's doing to me?
Sam, cycle the dynamap.
- Ow.
- Is that a contraction?
Kyle, grab a gurney,
let's get her up to OB.
- No problem.
- Slow deep breaths.
I'm okay. I don't need all that.
No, we have to
monitor your baby.
- Morris, positive AFB.
- Whoa.
ER's been exposed. Everybody
needs testing and follow-up.
We assumed it was a tumor...
but the other hospital
cytology was equivocal.
- Chuny, we're intubating.
- You are?
Positive TB stain.
She doesn't have cancer,
she has a treatable infection.
All right, GlideScope's ready.
Good call, Oliver.
TB is the great imitator.
That's what he taught us.
Twenty of etomidate,
100 of succinylcholine.
Dr. Kostin, are you mad?
Dr. Kostin, you can't give
succinylcholine down here.
I just did.
Paralytics and intubation
require an anesthesiologist.
I'll keep that in mind.
Your patient's too sick
for the emergency ward.
Patients like this
die in the elevator...
when we try to move them
up to the ICU without an airway.
Okay, gentlemen,
my work is done.
Beautiful shot of the cords.
Passing the tube.
Nice.
Sats are fine.
- Cuff is down.
- All right.
Deep breath in, Oliver.
And out.
David.
Where do we start rounds?
Right here, Ollie.
You're right where
you need to be.
Look, I have to get back.
But I'm really glad
you got in touch.
Yeah.
Yeah, you know, I've
been trying for 15 years.
Hasn't been easy.
You know, one day,
I had a big sister...
and then the next day, you took
off, just pregnant by some dude.
I didn't take off. Mom
kicked me out of the house.
- You could've called.
- She wouldn't let me talk to you.
- Written a letter.
- I did.
She must have tore them up.
I never knew that.
I had a baby. I had to work.
After a while, I
just stopped trying.
I figured you probably hated me.
I didn't.
You know, after you left, this
is the only guidance that I got.
My diary?
You must've left in a hurry,
found it underneath your mattress.
Oh, my God. Are you kidding me?
- What? Did you read this?
- Yeah, of course, like, a hundred times.
You taught me how to French
kiss, how to pierce my ears...
how to roll a joint. Heh.
- Six Flags?
- Yeah, when I was 7.
- That was the happiest day of my life.
- Oh, my God.
Mom took us home early...
because you puked your
funnel cake all over Shock Wave.
Oh, you are so wrong.
No, she took us home because
when she went to the bathroom...
you went and tried
to bum a cigarette.
- I did not.
- Yes, you did.
You were grounded
for an entire week.
I was so stupid.
She's really bad, huh?
Yeah, it won't be long.
- Well, ICU could take Trauma 1.
- Okay, let's move Dr. Kostin.
- Dylan, how'd it go?
- It's okay. Where's my mom at?
She's in a different room
on a breathing machine...
but something amazing happened.
It turns out your mom
doesn't have cancer.
- Are you serious?
- It's tuberculosis.
They told us that...
Cells from other hospital
were suggestive of cancer...
but they weren't definitive.
So we ran a special
stain, and we found TB.
Thank you. Thank
you, that's incredible.
She's not out of the woods yet.
Well, if it's a drug-resistant strain,
then she's gonna have very rough course.
But it's better than cancer, right?
I mean, her prognosis, it's good?
We're gonna have to
keep you in isolation...
- till we find out you're not infectious.
- Not a problem.
Donna, there's
someone here to see you.
Mom, I heard the great news.
I kind of rocked it.
They're not supposed to
give feedback, but the head...
of the woodwind department
said, "See you in September."
Sam, I'm gonna be
up in the O.R. for a bit.
Prescription for insulin...
and an appointment
with a diabetes clinic.
- Where are you taking her?
- County jail.
Are you okay?
I got some medicine
to stop the contractions.
I have to wait till
the baby's ready.
- We should be going.
- Hold on.
You've got nothing to say?
You're not gonna
explain this to me?
Maybe later. She's
had a rough day.
I thought I was gonna have some help
with this baby, but I'll do it on my own.
I just thought you
wanted to be a part of it.
- But if this is how you want it, fine!
- Come here.
You know what? Come here.
- What are you doing?
- Come with me.
What's going on?
I need you to understand
what your mother's doing.
- Shoplifting makeup.
- To trade for insulin.
She loves you. She's made
sacrifices for you and your baby.
She almost died today...
because she ignored her
own health to buy you a crib.
- I didn't know.
- Yeah, she's too proud to say it.
I know it's hard, but try to
appreciate what you have.
Stump is tied off.
EndoShears.
Nicely done.
Tension as you pull, Neela.
They're still at it.
Yeah, you're just in
time for the big finish.
Appendix is out.
- How cool was that?
- Very.
- You heard about the TB case?
- Yeah.
G-Prox, please.
Yeah, we were all guilty
of diagnosis momentum.
Despite incomplete evidence,
we heard the word cancer...
and we all ran
down the wrong path.
It's a glimpse of
the future in there.
Yeah, I wasn't on board at
first, but Neela persisted, so...
Well, that's a good
quality to have.
Especially in an Attending.
There are a lot of candidates
this year, you know.
It's going to be
very competitive.
Well, whoever gets
her will be lucky.
You think he's really mad at me?
You did undermine his authority.
But it was in the
interest of the patient.
Yeah, I agree.
I think he must be in Trauma 1.
I just hope he doesn't
hurt my chances here.
Well, if it does,
then they're all crazy.
I can't imagine
anyone more brilliant...
and skilled and
compassionate and sexy.
And you'd better take a nap,
because you're gonna need it for later.
I was pre-med,
volunteering at the hospital...
when they made him chief in '68.
Back then, the ER was a glorified
walk-in clinic where you were seen...
by unsupervised interns
and residents with no training.
And the community
ERs were even worse.
Staffed by moonlighting dermatologists
and psychiatrists or drunks...
who'd been banned
from private practice.
There was no 911.
No paramedics.
And if you needed an ambulance,
you called a funeral home.
What the hell is that?
Ollie once said:
"You stand a better chance of
surviving a gunshot wound in Vietnam...
than a car crash in Chicago."
But he changed all that.
He developed the 911 system, he
trained thousands of paramedics...
and started one of the finest residency
programs in emergency medicine.
You're all here
because of this guy.
Gunshot wound to the left
chest, dumped from a moving car.
- Lost the pulse.
- Starting compressions.
- Thoracotomy tray.
- Four of O-neg and Betadine.
Yankauer.
- Rapid infuser is primed.
- Prep for a subclavian.
- I need a cricoid.
- Hold compressions.
Okay, opening the chest now.
Shot in the chest
outside of a liquor store.
Ready? And lift.
Hold an elevator. He's gotta
go right up to the trauma ward.
Someday we're gonna take
care of guys like this down here.
- The surgeons will never sign off on that.
- You wait and see.
Dream on, Dr. Kostin.
Foley's in the heart defect.
Inflating to 20 cc's.
- Bleeding's slowing down.
- He's had six of O-neg, six of FFP.
I got a pulse, strong pulse.
Cardio-thoracic team's here.
- Take him away, guys.
Door to O.R., 12 minutes.
Not bad. MORRIS: Yup.
He could walk
out of the hospital.
How are you doing, Ollie?
Another two of morphine.
Got it.
Let's TKO his fluids.
He's bradying down.
Might as well
turn off the alarm.