♪ Sun's up, mm-hm Looks okay ♪
♪ The world survives
Into another day ♪
♪ And I'm thinkin'
'Bout eternity ♪
♪ Some kind of ecstasy
Got ahold on me ♪
♪ I had another dream
About lions at the door ♪
♪ They weren't
half As frightening ♪
♪ As they were before ♪
♪ But I'm thinkin'
'Bout eternity ♪
♪ Some kind of ecstasy
Got ahold on me ♪
♪ Walls, windows, trees
Waves comin' through ♪
♪ You be in me
And I'll be in you ♪
♪ Together in eternity ♪
♪ Some kind of ecstasy
Got ahold on me ♪
♪ Up among the firs
Where it smells so sweet ♪
♪ Or down in the valley
Where the river used to be ♪
♪ I got my mind on eternity ♪
♪ Some kind of ecstasy
Got ahold on me ♪
♪ And I'm wondering
Where the lions are ♪
♪ Wondering
♪ I'm wondering
Where the lions are ♪
♪ Wondering
♪ I'm wondering
Where the lions are ♪
♪ Wondering
♪ I'm wondering
Where the lions are ♪
♪ Wondering
♪ I'm wondering
Where the lions are ♪
♪ Wondering
♪ Mm-hm, wondering
Where the lions are ♪
♪ Wondering
♪ Uh-huh ♪
♪ Uh-huh, uh-huh... ♪
I guess winter's here, huh?
Yeah. Aren't you freezing?
Not once I get warmed up.
I used to be that
thin, you know.
The bitch stabbed
me through the bird.
Excuse me? I was
stuffin' the turkey.
Hey, Kerry.
Hey, Carol, I thought
yesterday was your last day.
I know, but I still
need to show Lydia
how to do the
productivity report.
She took off. What?
Yeah, she's drivin'
to Wisconsin.
You were supposed
to be here at 8.
I needed to sleep. I... I
thought she had a shift.
Yeah, the night shift. Well,
why didn't she call me?
I came all the way in.
She figured you bailed.
Didn't wanna
bother you. Oh, man.
Carol, do you feel all right?
No, my back is killing me.
Well, we're about
to do the potluck,
so why don't you stay and rest?
No, you know what? I'm
gonna go home, take a nap,
store up my energy
to deal with my family.
Hold up, I got you
down for dessert.
Oh, sorry, casualty
of pregnancy.
What, no pie?
Wait, okay, okay.
Time-out. Time-out.
There's no time-outs
in a snowball fight.
No fair. I'm a girl.
A girl who tried to ambush me.
That's very mature, Carter.
Oh, you want a piece of this?
Don't even think about it.
Okay, now you're dead.
♪ ...sail into eternity ♪
♪ Some kind of ecstasy
Got ahold on me... ♪
Well, I'm glad
you're enjoying it.
♪ I'm wondering
Where the lions are ♪
♪ Wondering
♪ I'm wondering
Where the lions are ♪
♪ Wondering
♪ I'm wondering
Where the lions are ♪
♪ Wondering
♪ I'm wondering
Where the lions are ♪
♪ Wondering
♪ Oh, wondering
Where the lions are ♪
♪ Wondering
♪ Mm-hm, I'm wondering
Where the lions are ♪
♪ Wondering
Oh, my God.
Carol?
Carol, are you all right?
My water broke.
How long ago?
Fifteen minutes.
You're already
having contractions?
How many? Two.
How far apart?
Seven, eight minutes.
Did anyone call an ambulance?
No, County's just one stop back.
Why don't you get on that train?
You try walking
during labor pain.
Yeah. How far along are you?
Oh, 38 weeks.
Was the amniotic fluid clear?
Ah, kind of hard
to tell on the el.
So no meconium, then, huh?
I don't think so.
Good, good, good.
Don't worry, I could
be at this a while.
Tell you what.
We wait for the next train.
If it doesn't come
in five minutes,
we call an ambulance, okay?
Oh, yeah.
10-9. That ain't
no fair. No hands.
I'm a goalie, man.
That's what we do.
It's too easy. Use the chair.
Okay, whatever you
say, bro. I still own you.
Hey, Cleo.
Workin' hard, Dave?
Yeah, I'm fast.
What can I tell ya?
Oh!
I'm cool. I'm cool.
Hey, Dr. Weaver.
Finish your notes, Dr. Malucci?
Ooh, absolutely, chief.
I was just, um, waiting
on a paramedic run.
Is it always this
slow on Thanksgivin'?
If you're bored, you
can start studying
for your National
In-Service Exam.
Yeah, I wouldn't wanna
bring down the average.
Ouch, and I
thought you liked me.
Whatever gave you that idea?
It'll pick up once people
start eating dinner.
Barf Central, huh?
Already started.
Shelly Robinson, 18,
persistent vomiting and diarrhea.
Hypoglycemic,
altered mental status.
Gave her IV fluids
and Compazine,
but her glucose
is still 42 after D50.
Did you get an
endocrine consult?
Yeah, he's probably at
home stuffing his face.
Did you get a travel history?
Not outside the U.S.
Well, how 'bout Florida?
Actually, she just got
back from there. Why?
Well, ask her if she ate
an oily, yellowish fruit
with black seeds.
What? Akee fruit.
Poisonous before it's ripe.
Induces vomiting
and low blood glucose
by inhibiting hepatic
gluconeogenesis. Known as JVS.
JVS.
Jamaican Vomiting Sickness.
But the akee also
grows in southern Florida.
You're kidding, right?
You better start a D20 infusion.
There's a high fatality
rate if it's left untreated.
If you don't believe me,
just check the differential.
Might be a doctor after all.
Jamaican Vomiting Sickness?
Look it up, John.
Jamaican Vomiting Sickness.
Okay, a little step.
Thank you for doing this.
Not a problem. It's okay.
Oh, God!
Is it a contraction? Oh, yeah!
Okay. Sit. Sit here. Sit here.
So maybe... Maybe
standing's better, huh?
Yeah. Okay.
Carol, have you
taken a birthing class?
Mm-hm.
Uh...
Just look at something.
Try to stare at something.
Stay focused on it, okay?
Uh, is...? Is she having a baby?
Yeah. W-we're
okay. She just started.
Are you sure?
Yeah, it's all
right. I'm a doctor.
She doesn't look all right.
Oh! Oh.
Uh... I-I think I better
pull the emergency cord.
No, no, no.
That stops the train.
Well, she needs help. No,
we only have to go one stop.
It's okay. Better to be safe.
No, no, don't pull the cord.
The sign says, "Pull cord
in case of emergency."
This isn't that
kind of emergency.
"Police, fire,
medical emergency."
Don't pull the
damn cord! Oh, God!
Can she cook?
What kind of a question is that?
So she can't?
I don't know. We eat out a lot.
My experience with English food:
it's always bland.
Would you rather I cooked?
Is she pretty?
Yes, she's pretty.
Prettier than Cynthia?
Different kind of pretty.
Beauty is overrated.
She's pretty, all right? Jeez.
Happy Thanksgiving.
See? What?
Nothing. Uh, Elizabeth, this
is my father, David Greene.
Nice hat.
Thank you. Come in.
This is Rachel. Hello, Rachel.
You're not supposed
to wear those.
They're for decoration.
Ah. Uh... Well, I saw
it in the drugstore,
and I thought it looked cute.
I got the wine.
Great. I'll open it.
No, no, no, I'll get it.
Scotch and soda
for me, if you have it.
Actually, I think I might.
Rachel, would you care
for something to drink?
Can I have some wine?
No. I have soda.
Okay.
Mind if I turn on the game?
Oh, um, my telly's
broken, I'm afraid.
Doesn't work?
Yeah, apparently my
neighbor was stealing his cable.
So the company came and,
um, they snapped the wrong line.
On Thanksgiving?
No, no. This was a month ago.
I just haven't had time
to ring up and complain.
No football.
We can play
charades if you like.
Let me just sit for
a second, okay?
The contractions
are too close together.
You're in active labor.
Oh, gee. You think?
I'm sorry. I just...
You might have progressed
more than you think.
No, I'm okay. It just hurts.
How dilated were you
on your last OB visit?
Uh, 3 centimeters, Monday.
Any back pain?
Yeah, for the last three months.
Worse lately? This morning.
Okay, let's go. Let's go.
Oh, can't I have
the babies here?
If you wanna make
the news. Come on.
Oh, God, they feel like
they're between my knees.
Yep, that's the idea.
Oh, son of a bitch.
Okay, sit. Sit here,
sit here, come on.
Okay. Okay, focus.
Focus, Carol. Carol.
Try... Try humming.
Huh? I-I know it
sounds very strange.
But it helped my wife.
Okay, just hum, like this.
Yeah, just do it.
Okay.
Hey, remember that
renal-failure patient?
Five-minute ETA?
Let me guess. Diverted to Mercy?
Now she's a Trauma patient.
Some guy plowed into the ambulance.
Ah, that was smart.
Hey, Dave.
Good call on the akee fruit.
She bought off a
curbside vendor.
Ah, I won't say I
told you so, but...
How'd you know about
it? I'm a good doctor.
No, really. Really.
And I might've seen it before.
Where? No, don't
tell me. You, uh...?
You did the Peace
Corps or something?
Yeah, exactly. I spent
some time in the jungle.
And if you're nice to me, I'll
show you my piranha scars.
Come on, where'd you see it?
Let's just say you
owe me a favor.
What is this, a secret?
What, you're suddenly
sensitive, Dave?
Oh, did you, um,
lose a patient to this?
Fine. Whatever. I saw
it in Grenada, okay?
You did a rotation in Grenada?
No, Sherlock, I went to
med school in Grenada.
Oh.
Oh. Your, uh, first choice?
I had fun in college.
From what I can remember
of it, my grades sucked.
My MCATs... Long story.
But I knew I could be a better
doctor than those ass-kissers
whose only hard-on was
for what was on some test.
Gotcha. So I did Grenada.
It's the Harvard of the
Caribbean, actually.
I'm sure that it is.
Still says M.D., Carter.
See? M.D.
I know. I know.
Well, now I can appreciate
you that much more.
Good.
So, what did you
get on your MCATs?
All right.
Hey, it started snowing again.
Yeah. You ready?
I think so. Okay.
So how long was
your wife in labor?
Sixteen hours,
for the first one.
How many has she had?
Two. At different times.
Oh, well... They
still live in Croatia?
No, not anymore.
Mm.
Oh! What?
Okay, sit. Sit down.
Come on. Deep breaths.
Hey, and don't worry.
It's probably a vagal
reaction to the contractions.
Oh! Okay? Deep breaths.
Oh, I have to go
to the bathroom.
We're almost there. No, I
mean I really have to go.
We must hurry. Can you stand?
Mm-mm.
What is it? What is it?
Another contraction?
Already? Okay. Okay.
Uh, don't push. Don't
push. Listen to me, Carol.
Carol, don't push, okay?
Carol?
Seventy-eight-year-old
woman with chronic renal-failure
and respiratory distress.
Missed her dialysis.
Other injuries
from the accident?
Maybe chest trauma.
She responded
to 10 liters of O2.
Decompensated after the crash.
Anyone else hurt?
Zadro banged his elbow.
The jerk who hit him is behind
us. He's faking a heart attack.
Kerry!
Oh, my God.
We need a gurney out here!
What happened?
Vagal reaction.
Is she in labor?
Uh, yeah.
Get her BP.
She had a syncopal episode.
I'm fine.
How far apart are contractions?
Three minutes. Babies moving?
All day long. What's wrong?
What do you think?
- What's open?
- Trauma rooms.
Oh, no, Kerry. Just take me
upstairs to Labor and Delivery.
Carol, you passed out. I
wanna check your vitals
and your cervix. Who's your OB?
McLucas. Please, Kerry.
Kerry, just take me
upstairs. Yeah, in a minute.
Malik, can you page Dr. McLucas?
Is he on the on-call list?
She. OB has it.
Do you want a fetal monitor?
Get the Doppler scope.
No. She's gonna check me.
Then I'm going upstairs!
Hey, I could use
help. I got two here.
Luka, can you help him?
Yeah, uh, sure.
Should I call Mark?
He's off. He's her Lamaze coach.
Oh, Carol, you
want us to call Mark?
Okay, let's go nice and easy.
I hope it's done.
I'm not used to serving
so early in the afternoon.
Well, we need time
to gorge ourselves,
so that we can pass
out on the couch.
It says 180.
You know, you didn't
have to do all this.
The two of them together
can be a bit much.
Don't be silly. All families
are eccentric in their own way.
I guess.
Okay, everybody,
dinner is served.
- Hit me.
- You have 18.
Soft 18 against
your nine. Hit me.
Dinner's ready, guys.
Rachel, can you get
the mashed potatoes?
Smells good. I
hope it's all right.
What's that on top there? Bacon.
Ew, on the turkey?
You don't have it that way?
Rachel? I said mashed potatoes.
I didn't think you
celebrated Thanksgiving.
Well, it's not really
my holiday, is it?
The Pilgrims came here to
escape persecution from the British.
Yes, so they could go
about persecuting the Indians.
Okay, everybody. Now.
I'll do that. I got it, Dad.
Mark, I said I'd do it.
Don't worry. Sit down. Relax.
Mark doesn't think I can do
things for myself anymore.
Be my guest.
Did you tell her you want
to put me in a nursing home?
It's a retirement community.
A retirement
community with nurses.
Can we talk about this later?
It's all you wanted to
talk about last night.
Sorry.
That's all right.
Uh, I think I have instant.
Are you on call?
No, no. It's yours.
Um, look. Let's clean
this up, shall we?
Okay, ready?
And lift.
Lungs are wet. Some
JVD. Not making any urine.
Mrs. Olson, why did
you miss your dialysis?
I was having my hair done.
Oh. It's nice to look good,
but your health
should come first, huh?
You think I look good?
Yeah, beautiful.
Oh, it's for my birthday.
Today? Yes.
Oh, happy birthday.
Well, thank you.
BP's 102/54. Pulse is 124.
Congestive failure.
Wet crackles halfway up.
You want Lasix?
No. Start a nitro drip
and call the dialysis unit.
Can I call a family member?
No, that's all right.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. Sternal tenderness.
You see, this is why idiots
need to stop for ambulances.
Muffled heart sounds.
Check for pulsus paradoxus.
Heart?
What's wrong with my heart?
Mrs. Olson, your
fluid overloaded
from missing your dialysis.
Some fluid is collecting
around your heart.
It's probably from
the renal failure.
But it could also be an
injury from the accident.
Oh, my.
Enalapril 1.25 IV push,
and get me an ultrasound.
They're using it next door.
Then get me another one.
Oh!
Carol, you're pushing, honey.
Don't push. Betadine?
Doppler sounds good.
Fetal heart tones are 140.
BP's 112/70. Pulse, 88.
Legs up, Carol. Okay, it's over?
The contraction's over?
Almost, yeah.
I'm gonna check your
cervix, Carol. Relax.
You'll remember this
Thanksgiving. Yeah.
Kerry, what is it?
You're at 10 centimeters, Carol.
What? Fully effaced.
Two plus station.
Haleh, open an OB.
No, no. I don't want it
delivered down here.
I don't wanna deliver in the ER.
Wanna deliver in the elevator?
How can I be 10 centimeters?
Probably contracting all day.
Oh, God. Call Pedes.
Let's rotate the gurney
and give her some privacy.
No, no, no. No,
Kerry, I'll just hold it.
Okay, I promise I
won't push. I won't push.
Let's make a deal.
We'll deliver this
one down here.
And have the next one upstairs.
Oh! MARQUEZ: Lift up your butt.
Okay, uh, I'm gonna
need that fetal monitor.
The second on the ultrasound.
Get out of here, Carter!
It's okay, don't
worry about a thing.
Give me some sterile
gloves. Carter, get out!
John, I've got it. Why don't
you see if Dr. Kovac needs help?
I've delivered babies before.
Not this one. Dr. Weaver?
She knows you. She
doesn't feel comfortable.
She just paged Dr. Greene.
Yeah, he's not
delivering. Get out.
Okay. Good luck. Oh. Oh, God!
Okay, let's break the bed down.
Fifteen of
etomidate, 100 of sux.
BP's down to 80 systolic.
Pericardiocentesis tray.
Get me an alligator clip.
You need some help?
Yes, please. Intubate.
What is it?
Pericardial effusion.
I can't tell if it's the trauma
or her renal failure.
Pressure's down to 70.
Number eight ET tube.
Double up on the dopamine.
Is she having the
babies in there?
At least one of them.
JARVIK: V-fib.
Charge the paddles.
Carter, CPR now.
What do you think
it is, hyperkalemia?
Probably high potassium.
Give an amp of calcium.
Come on, clear.
Still V-fib. Three hundred, now.
You want insulin and glucose?
Go ahead. And an
amp of, uh, bicarb.
Paddles ready. Clear!
Nothing. Three-sixty.
Stand by with epi.
Come on, come on.
Hurry up, hurry up.
Okay, clear.
Tell her I'll be right there.
What is it? Carol's in labor.
Is she in the hospital?
Yeah, and I might
miss the first one.
Who's Carol? Uh,
she's a friend of ours.
Dad, we gotta go. Why?
Well, I'm the Lamaze coach.
And so I gotta talk her through it.
Where's the
father? Dad, let's go.
Rachel, I'm gonna drop you
guys off on the way. Come on.
I'm hungry. Me too.
Mark, we might
as well eat dinner.
Could be a while.
Well, I can drive them home.
Are you okay with this, Rachel?
She's fine.
Go coach. We'll eat.
Here, take a biscuit.
Call with all the details.
Boys, girls, weight,
length, all that.
You're sure about
this? Carol needs you.
We'll be fine.
If they give you any trouble,
just lock 'em in the closet. Go.
No turkey for me.
Animal fat's bad for your heart.
Not today.
Push, push, push, push.
Good job, Carol! Almost there!
Okay, I see the head. Crowning.
Okay, keep breathing, honey.
Contraction subsiding.
Okay, Carol, I want
you to push hard for 10.
I'm trying! I know.
Come on. Come on.
Ten, nine, eight,
seven, six... Count faster!
Five, four, three...
Okay. Okay. Just relax.
Is he out? Not yet. Not yet.
Next contraction. Good job.
You're doing great,
Carol. Almost there.
Did you plan natural childbirth?
Hell, no.
Where's Pedes? I paged them.
Somebody get Cleo in here.
Dr. Weaver? Details on twin A.
What? No, let me see.
Okay, get the OB on call
and have L and D bring
down a vacuum extraction...
Vacuum? No.
Carol, look at me,
honey. It's just for safety.
The first baby's heart
rate is down to 90.
But we're okay
over 80, all right?
Okay.
Okay, good.
Let's go with a scalp electrode.
Oh, no, do you have to?
Yeah, it just gives me
more accurate monitoring.
Okay, you rest up.
In two minutes you're
gonna push this baby out.
How much atropine has she had?
Two amps.
How long since the
last epi? Five minutes.
Let's check in on the rhythm.
Asystole. That's it.
Time of death, ahem, 13:17.
Happy birthday.
- You got it.
- Seven, six, five...
- How close is she?
- She's there.
Fetal rate is 85.
Okay, the head's
out! Bulb suction.
Don't push. Carol, don't push.
Don't push, honey.
Is the cord around its neck?
Not anymore.
All right. Here we go.
Carol, say hello
to your daughter.
It's a girl?
Yes.
It's a girl. Congratulations.
Hi. Hello.
Let's check the
presentation of twin B.
It's okay. It's okay.
Looks like about 6 pounds.
- She's so little.
- So little.
But that's a good
size for a twin.
I have to take her now,
Carol. Take a good look at her.
She's healthy, right?
She's beautiful.
Okay. Okay. Okay.
Okay.
There we go.
Have you picked out a name yet?
Tess.
I think I'm gonna name her Tess.
Welcome to the world, Tess.
There we go.
You did great.
Carol Hathaway?
Hi. I'm Abby. I'll
be your OB nurse.
Heard you had a little
excitement downstairs.
Ultrasound showed second
twin is vertex and high.
Okay, just relax, Carol.
We'll get you through this.
Is the bag intact? Yes.
Hi, Mom, I'm Sandra.
I have to tag you and your baby
before I can take
her to the nursery.
Can't she stay with...?
We'll warm her up, bathe her,
and bring her back
after this one's out.
Well, what if she gets hungry?
Well, we can
supplement a little bit.
Sure? Yes, I'm sure.
Here, I need you
to scoot over a little.
Nice and easy.
There we go.
Oh, Kerry, could
you go with her?
Sure. I'll see that she
gets settled in, okay?
Thanks.
Three-five-one-six-four.
All set.
Say bye-bye, Mommy.
Bye, honey.
Bye. Thanks, Kerry.
Are the contractions
still strong?
Well, they're a little
spaced out. But yeah.
Well, we'll do
another ultrasound.
But if the baby's high,
it could take a while.
Is Dr. McLucas on her way?
We're working on that.
Do you want an epidural?
I can still have
one? Absolutely.
Oh, well, if I wasn't
sure before, I am now.
Wimp.
Mark.
Heard I missed the party.
Oh, God.
I'll call the anesthesiologist.
A girl? Hm. A girl.
Troublemaker already?
You hangin' in there?
It's brutal, Mark.
One down, one to go.
Uh-uh. I quit.
I don't think you
have much of a choice.
Well, you know,
you could shoot me.
Yeah, if it comes to that.
I'm sorry to pull you away
from your Thanksgiving dinner.
You kidding? I'd rather be here.
D-Day. Five beaches.
The Americans take
Utah, and... Here.
The potatoes.
And Omaha, the squash.
Now, the Brits land here
and share Juno, the, uh...
The stuffing, with the Canucks.
The Canucks?
The Canadians. Right.
Are you with me?
Yes, yes, yes, I'm
with you. Mm-hm.
All the heavy German resistance
is concentrated on
the American lines.
Massive casualties are
suffered by the Americans,
6000 in the first day.
The Brits had their
share too, didn't they?
Should the gravy
go with the potatoes?
Fine.
Now, instead of pushing forward
and cutting off the
Germans at Caen,
Montgomery, the
British general...
Yes, I know who Montgomery is.
Montgomery sat on
his ass and had tea.
I'm going to the bathroom.
Well, the British were
fighting the Germans
for nearly three years
before the Americans.
Perhaps they were just
a little more cautious.
"Cautious" is one word for it.
I suppose "tea-loving"
would be another.
That's two words.
It's a hyphenate, actually.
Well, anyway, the
82nd Airborne Division...
Do you have to
use a straight cath?
The epidural numbs your bladder.
You won't control your urine.
Great. Sorry, we
do it for everybody.
No catheter, no epidural.
Seems like a small
price to pay, Carol.
It's not your bladder.
Are we doin' this?
Carol? Hm...? Yes.
All right. All set.
Okay, Carol, you have to sit up.
Oh, can't we do it on my side?
No, it's better upright
when you're pregnant.
I'm a nurse. Tell me why.
To get a clear shot at
the intervertebral space.
You don't want
him fishing around.
Okay, come on, up
you go. Up you go.
You better get it
right the first time.
I generally do if the
patient cooperates.
Mark, is it? Yeah.
Could you grab
her other shoulder?
Okay, Carol, lean
into us. A little bit more.
Keep your back nice and round.
And you'll feel a little prick.
Carol Hathaway?
Carol, it's you.
Dr. Coburn.
Mark. I had no idea.
Congratulations. No,
he's my Lamaze coach.
Oh, I see. How are we doing?
High and intact, 6
centimeters. Six?
You shrink down
between deliveries.
I know, but 6?
You need some more local?
Oh, no. Contraction.
Just hold on, Carol.
You're doin' great.
Carol, Dr. McLucas
is in Wichita.
She asked me to cover her
practice over Thanksgiving.
Is that all right?
I gotta lie down.
No, Carol. He's
in the middle of it.
You have to hold still.
No, I can't!
Yes, you can. Yes, you can.
Here, hold my hand, okay?
You're gonna feel much
better once we get through.
It hurts, Mark.
I know.
No, I mean, it really hurts.
I know. I know.
Hang in there. Hang in there.
One night Stu
and I were on deck.
He asked me for a light.
I reached in my pocket,
and when I looked
up, he was gone.
What do you mean, gone?
Gone. He'd fallen overboard.
Oh, my God. Did he drown?
If the fall didn't kill him.
That's terrible. Yeah.
'Bout the only thing worse
than the working conditions
on that carrier was the food.
Probably took more
men than anything.
You mean worse than the English?
I was kidding. This is great.
I haven't had a
meal like this since...
Well, for a while.
Since your wife died?
Yeah.
I'm sorry. I can only imagine
how difficult it must be.
As difficult as you
make it, I guess.
What do you mean?
How's Mark? You
know, dealing with it?
Oh, in his stride, I suppose.
To be honest, he
doesn't speak of it much.
And I've learnt not
to force the subject.
There are certain
things he carries inside.
But you must know that.
Well, don't ask me.
His mother was the only
one who understood him.
He's not that big a mystery.
Well, don't get me
wrong. He's a good man.
It's just that with Ruth gone...
I don't know...
How 'bout some pie?
With his mother gone what?
Nothing.
Just seem to have
lost a bridge, I guess.
A bridge? Yeah.
Maybe you both just miss her.
I'll get some plates.
Hey, Rachel, come get
some pie. What's with her?
She's been in there a half-hour.
I'll check.
Rachel?
Are you all right in there?
Rachel, are you in there?
Go away!
What are you looking for?
I don't know.
Am I boring you?
No! No.
You wanna just talk?
Sure.
Okay.
What do you wanna talk about?
I don't know.
Hey, the post-game show's on.
Whoo.
How are you feeling?
I am in love with
the epidural man.
Some people call him
an anesthesiologist.
Oh, he will always be
the epidural man to me.
You know what, I'm just
gonna go get a magazine.
Oh, uh, I should
call Elizabeth too.
She's probably crawling
out on a ledge by now.
Hey, could you
call my mom? Sure.
What do you want me to
tell her? Just what you said.
One down, one to go.
Her number's in my
organizer in my bag.
Anybody else you
want me to call?
No, not yet.
Are you sure?
I just wanna get
through this first.
All right.
What's wrong?
Nothing. Just lost the signal.
Where'd it go? Hold on.
Sandra, could you call Dr. Coburn
and bring the ultrasound?
Right there.
Got it.
It's above the umbilicus.
What does that mean?
Baby could be rotating.
It's fine. Heart rate's 140.
Do we have an O.R. clear?
I'll see.
Wait, I don't... I don't
need a C-section, do I?
No, not necessarily. But
if the baby turns breech,
we'll have to labor
you in the O.R.
It's just a precaution, Carol.
Oh, man.
Hello and welcome
to a jam-packed
edition of Sports Tonight.
Steve Murphy alongside...
What's goin' on in there?
She sticking her
finger down her throat?
I'm afraid she's having
her first menstrual period.
Menstrual?
She's 10.
It can happen at that age.
It's early, but not abnormal.
So one of us needs
to go to the store.
Now, do you want
to stay with her?
Or shall I?
Uh, what do you
need from the store?
Sanitary napkins.
You don't have that stuff?
I only have tampons.
Um, it's not really the
best for a young girl.
Oh, right.
Listen, um, there's a
drugstore just on the corner.
Sanitary napkins.
That...? That's the flat ones?
Ask the clerk.
What if he's a guy?
How are we doing?
We'll move her right
after this contraction.
Baby's in lotus position.
What's this for?
We have to prep you for the O.R.
What, even if I'm not
being operated on?
Don't worry, I won't
take any pictures.
Ha-ha.
Uh-oh.
What is it?
I think my water
just broke again.
Let's see.
Sure did. Nice and clear.
We'll clean you up once you...
What? Fetal heart
rate's in the 90s.
Um, Carol, I have to check you.
Yeah, but we're good till 80?
Just relax, Carol, I
have to check you again.
What're you lookin' for?
I have to wait till this
contraction finishes.
Seventy-five.
What's wrong?
Damn it. Prolapsed cord.
Prolapsed? The cord
gets out before the baby.
Cutting off the oxygen?
Stat page Coburn
to the O.R., please.
All right, fetal
heart rate's 65.
We have to get
this baby out now.
She's only 6 centimeters.
We'll have to crash C-section.
Oh, my God!
The O.R. is not clear yet.
Yeah? We're goin'.
What are you doing?
I'm keeping the
baby off its cord.
Wha...? This can't be
hap... This isn't happening.
Just try and stay calm.
Mark, don't let this happen!
Don't worry, I'm
right here. Oh, God.
Is the baby hypoxic? We're okay.
What's the heart rate?
We're not on a monitor.
What happened?
Prolapsed cord.
Heart rate was 65.
Okay, scrub in, Abby.
She's got her hand on the
cord. Get somebody else.
I've got it, Dr. Greene.
Don't let go!
You wanna assist on a C-section?
Not really. Then I
need 10 seconds
for her to scrub in.
Take over Sandra.
Okay, everybody, on my count.
Nice and easy. One, two, three.
All right, get your
hand on that cord.
Mark, you gotta save the baby.
We will. No, promise me.
I promise. I got it.
Let's prep her fast.
Where's Anesthesia?
I just paged them.
Get Anesthesia down here now!
There's no time.
She had an epidural.
Keep 100 mics of
fentanyl standing by.
Okay, I'll monitor her vitals.
Please save this baby.
Gloves now.
Please.
Okay, Mom's BP, 118/84.
Pulse, 102. Satting
98 on room air.
Okay, nasal oxygen. - I'm on it.
Here we go!
One minute from
skin to baby. Scalpel.
There's skin.
And mark the time.
Please, God, please,
please. Don't worry.
Abby, stretch. Pull.
ABBY: I'm pulling.
Where's Pedes?
On their way. Bladder blade.
Retract inferiorally.
Scalpel again.
Uterine incision.
Okay. And another stretch.
Pediatrician's here.
Mark, what's happening?
- I see the baby.
- Blue towel.
Up.
Ah, looks like a girl.
Did you hear that? Hear
that? You got another girl.
Is she okay? Hold on.
Second shoulder.
Head flexed.
Another clamp. Scissors.
Is she out?
She's out.
Why isn't she crying?
She will.
I got her. COBURN:
She looks okay.
- She's not crying.
- How'd we do?
- Blow by 15 liters.
- Fifty-one seconds.
Mark, she's blue.
She'll pink up.
Uterus is boggy.
She needs Pit, 20.
What's the Apgar? Don't worry.
Mark, what's the Apgar?
Five-minute Apgar's
more predictive.
Oh, my God. What happened?
Damn ice. I slipped.
It was a pretty bad
spill. I saw it from here.
Let me see.
I'm fine. You should throw
salt out there.
Know what time it is?
Yeah, time my
10-year-old granddaughter
started her period.
You got this? Uh, yes,
thanks for buzzing me.
Right. We need to get you
to a hospital and stitch that up.
Like hell. It will stop
bleeding with a little pressure.
A nasty gash. You need
sutures and a tetanus booster.
What I need is a
Band-Aid and a drink.
Fine. Well, if you sit still,
you'll even get a lollipop.
Five-minute Apgar
is eight, Carol.
Can I see her?
Hold on. We've got
some active bleeding.
What's her pressure?
Hundred over 60.
What took you so long?
They just paged me.
She delivered five minutes ago.
Profuse bleeding.
Uterus is still boggy.
How much Pitocin has she had?
Forty units in.
Another 0.2 Methergine.
I.M.?
No, I'll do it intramyometrial.
Hemostat. More suction.
She's oozing everywhere.
Sponge stick. Check
another pressure.
Oh, my God.
I'm bleeding out.
It always looks like
more than there is.
How are we doin'?
Pressure's down, 80/40.
All right, let's pump
in some saline.
I'll put in a line.
I wanna see my baby.
You will. Just a little while.
I'll take her to the nursery.
We're at 70.
Okay, she needs blood.
Type and cross for four.
Okay.
Three liters are up.
Hemabate, 0.25 I.M.
The blood'll be
here in 10 minutes.
We don't have 10 minutes.
Open a hysterectomy tray.
What? Hold on. Are we there yet?
Carol, your uterus is atonic.
It's not firming up.
You're losing blood,
in spite of the medication
we're giving you.
Don't do a hysterectomy.
We may not have a choice.
Don't, please. Mark.
What else can we do?
Uterus is still boggy.
Another 500 cc's of
blood loss. Okay, Bovie.
There must be something
short of a hysterectomy.
Yes. Losing the patient.
Can't you clamp off an artery?
Please step out, doctor.
It's only 30 seconds.
It's 30 seconds
she may not have.
She doesn't want it.
She's a nurse. She
understands the risk.
Respect her decision.
O'Leary stitch. O-vicryl.
O-neg is up and ready.
Hold the transfusion.
What's her pressure?
Systolic is 80.
Cycle the dynamap.
Check it again.
That's a hypogastric.
She's lost 3 liters.
Needle driver and pickups.
Hang in there, Carol.
She needs a name.
Tess needs to know what
her little sister's name is.
Is she all right?
She's perfect.
They are both perfect.
Hm.
What happened?
You gave us a bit of a scare,
but you toughed it out.
Yeah, you still
have your uterus.
You're up.
How you feeling?
A little groggy.
Any pain?
Actually, no, for
the first time today.
Drugs.
Enjoy them while they last.
I wouldn't repeat this
outside of this room, but, uh,
you owe your friend
here your future children.
You know, they both
came out so well,
you oughta think
about doing it again.
Yeah, I'm gonna
get right on that.
So, what's her name?
You wanna name her?
Me?
What was your mom's name?
Ruth.
Middle name Katherine.
Kate? Oh, I like that.
Kate.
Dr. Greene, they
need you downstairs.
What for?
They brought your
dad in for a laceration.
What happened?
Oh, I don't know.
Um, I'll be right back.
Mark?
Yeah.
Thank you.
You did good, Mom.
Can you, uh, call long
distance on this phone?
You might need a calling
card. Where are you calling?
Seattle.
You come in handy. Thank you.
How many stitches, do
you think? Six, maybe seven.
Dad, what
happened? It's nothing.
He slipped on the ice.
I would have caught myself
if I hadn't been carrying
such a big bag.
How many different kinds of
sanitary napkins do they make?
Thin, maxi, mini...
What is he talking about?
Rachel started her period. What?
Scented, unscented. I had
to buy every kind they had.
Dad, hold on a minute.
Can I talk to you?
Couldn't just have regular.
Ra...? Rachel had her period?
I was as surprised as you are.
Well, where is she now?
She's on the phone,
talking to her mom.
She wants to go
back to St. Louis.
Why'd you let him
go out in this weather?
You'd prefer I left him with
your menstruating daughter?
Excuse me, Dr. Greene?
Uh, did she have the other baby?
Carol Hathaway?
Yes. And, uh,
what...? What was it?
A girl. Two girls.
Oh. And everything's all right?
Everything's fine now.
Good. Thank you.
Here. You stitch up your father.
I'm gonna say hello.
I like her.
Hm-mm.
Sometimes you'll have to
tickle her feet to wake her up,
'cause new babies
are sleepy. Hm.
Okay, wait till she opens
her mouth really wide.
That's it.
Yeah, make sure her mouth
covers the whole areola.
Yeah, see her little jaw moving?
Oh, she's a barracuda.
She's a natural. Ooh.
You listen for the
swallowing. Do you hear it?
Okay. I have to go.
Your postpartum nurse
will take over from here.
You're leaving? Yeah.
You'll be fine.
Congratulations.
Thank you so much.
You're welcome.
You were very brave.
I don't know about that.
Oh, trust me.
Good night.
Good night. Happy Thanksgiving!
Happy Thanksgiving.