Next.
Yeah, can I get a...
Hey, there's a line.
My shift starts in five.
You understand.
We've all got places
to be, I'm next.
Cut me a break, all right?
Can I get
a double espresso?
I said I was next.
What is your problem, man?
No problem.
Will, can I talk
to you a second?
What has gotten into you?
Guy's a dick.
I'm concerned about you.
Why? Because I wouldn't
let him cut in front of me?
No, because you're not
acting like yourself.
Yeah, well, maybe
I'm a little upset
about you throwing me out.
I didn't throw you out.
Right. The gun,
the gun, the gun.
Will, I think you should
consider talking to someone.
I think you're having
a hard time processing
all of it.
Anybody would.
Nat, I don't want
to process it.
I want to forget
it ever happened
and move on with my life.
Our life.
You were talking
in your sleep last night.
Really? I haven't
done that in a while.
Hmm.
What was I saying?
Your usual.
Barking orders
to subordinates.
Sounds like me.
Give me the box!
Hey, get back here,
that's mine!
You don't want that!
Hey, you okay?
Get off me, man!
Stay down.
Ethan!
Get out of here.
What happened?
He might be having
a heart attack.
His pulse is
through the roof.
I called an ambulance.
Here, here, here, here.
Let me do it. Let me do it.
Take deep breaths.
In and out.
Petechiaes all over
his chest, too.
Oh, my God.
Gangrene.
April, call General Surgery
for a consult.
He'll need to have
his leg debrided.
Meantime, start him on fluids,
hang a gram of vanc,
500 metronidazole,
order a CBC, CMP,
blood cultures,
and chest X-ray.
Add a cardiac panel and EKG.
Need to rule out his heart.
Dr. Choi, do you want
a cardiac panel and EKG?
Yeah.
Mags, any luck finding ID?
Not yet, and there was
nothing in his clothes.
I got some lock cutters.
Figured there might be
something inside.
Let me try.
He's a veteran.
Yeah.
Marks.
Reginald Marks.
Oh.
Silver Star.
Which one is that?
It's awarded for
heroism during combat.
Dr. Choi, CFD's coming in
with semi-conscious
26-year-old.
Ah, go.
I'll make a call
to the VA.
Find him
a housing placement.
Thanks.
All right, I got this.
I'm sure it's just
my asthma acting up.
It happened with the
last pregnancy, too.
Is this your second?
Yep.
Double the fun
this time. Twins.
Congratulations.
Thanks.
But actually,
they're not mine.
I'm a surrogate.
Usually, Nate and Stephanie,
the twins' biological parents,
come with me to all
my doctor's visits,
but I didn't want to
panic them over nothing.
Yeah, I hear some
scattered wheezes.
I think you're right.
Uterus is compressing
the lungs,
exacerbating your asthma.
Let's get a MedNeb
and 40 milligrams of IV
methylprednisolone.
Well, since you're here...
Ultrasound?
This isn't
your first rodeo.
Baby boy is doing
somersaults today.
Probably the salsa
I had with my eggs.
Spicy foods always
get 'em moving.
His sister,
on the other hand,
hardly ever kicks.
Celine, have you had your
anatomy ultrasound yet?
No, it's for next week.
Is something wrong?
The male fetus's
amniotic fluid is elevated.
But that can happen
with twins. I just...
I'd like to get
a better picture
of what's going on.
Well, should I call
Nate and Stephanie?
I think that'd be
a good idea.
Just take these three.
Yep.
Hey.
Will still crashing
at his brother's?
Mmm-hmm.
How long?
He can come home
whenever he wants.
Just not with that gun.
He's been through hell.
I get that.
He just needs time to get
reacclimated to his old life.
I hope so. I just wish
he'd let me in.
He'll come around.
Mr. Davis.
Hello.
Hey, Phillip.
Dr. Manning.
How's little Sophie doing?
She's good, she's good.
Um, they say that
we can, uh...
That I can
take her home soon.
I'm so glad to hear that.
Me, too.
I'm so sorry,
Dr. Manning. Heads up.
Ambo is in,
Treatment Six.
Okay.
Sorry about that.
I'm sorry, um...
It was good to see you.
You, too. Yeah.
Get the hell away from me!
Good Samaritan found her
wandering, called 911.
Fran Mooney,
83-year-old female
with Alzheimer's disease.
BP is 138 over 90.
I said let me go!
She was able
to tell you all that?
Medical alert bracelet.
Called the emergency contact
on the back.
Daughter should be
here any second.
Okay. Dr. Charles,
can I grab you?
All right, let's sheet
transfer on my count.
Ready. One, two, three.
Milty? Milty.
Tell these people
to get the hell away from me!
I'm actually Dr. Charles,
but could you tell me
a little bit more
about Milty?
Milton was her husband.
Who the hell are you?
Lungs are clear.
Mom, it's me. It's Alana.
Don't touch me!
2.5 haloperidol IM.
Help calm her down
a little bit.
I'm so sorry,
this is the third
time this month
she's wandered.
I don't know
how she keeps
getting out.
I always lock the door.
You notice any other
changes in her...
Her general disposition?
She's more agitated
than usual,
and she's lost
some weight, too.
All right, well,
we'll run some labs
and see if there's anything
out of the ordinary, okay?
Okay.
Might just have to
adjust her meds a bit.
Thank you.
Long night?
Exceptionally long.
Why don't you head over
to my place?
The new mattress just got
delivered this morning.
Don't you think that's
something we ought to
break in together?
I like where your head's at.
So listen,
we haven't really, um...
We haven't talked about
what happened at the gala.
Connor...
What Cornelius
told people...
It was vintage my father.
He's spreading lies
and using you
to get under my skin.
Look, he's a prick.
Bekker. Good.
There was a huge pileup on
the highway near East Mercy.
I had to send two surgeons
over there to assist.
Do you mind
sticking around the ED?
We could really use
the extra hand.
So much for sleep. Sure.
You hold onto those.
You two a thing?
What's it to you?
Well, give me a heads-up
when she dumps you.
Rhodes, head versus auto,
Trauma Three.
You got it. Courtney?
Leslie Taylor,
37-year-old female.
Car struck her
in the crosswalk.
GCS 12, heart rate 130.
BP 86 over palp.
Leslie, I'm Dr. Rhodes,
do you know where you're at?
Was there an accident?
You were hit by a car,
but now you're
in the hospital.
What happened?
Was I in an accident?
She lose consciousness
at any point?
Bystander said she was out
for a few minutes
after it happened.
I couldn't get
anything coherent
from her in the ambo.
All right. Let's get her
over on my count.
One, two, three.
There we go.
Her breath sounds clear
and present bilaterally.
Was I in an accident?
Maggie filled me in.
I'll clear the C-spine?
Can't. She's perseverating.
You gotta wait
until she's lucid.
Let's do a FAST scan.
She's jaundiced.
Yeah.
Maggie!
Check to see
if the patient's
in the system.
Look for anything that would
account for the jaundice.
Just pulled up her records.
She's got a lot of blood
in her belly.
All right, let's give her
a liter of fluid,
two units of plasma,
two units of blood.
Once her pressure stabilizes,
we're gonna move her to CT.
Yes, Doctor.
Jaundice is
from liver disease.
She's on the list.
Was I in an accident?
If her liver took the hit...
She doesn't have much time.
Yeah.
Dr. Halstead.
This is Nate
and Stephanie Addison,
the twins' parents.
Hi.
Hi, there.
I'm afraid I have
some difficult news.
What's wrong?
The male fetus has something
called a congenital
diaphragmatic hernia.
His abdominal organs have
migrated into his chest
through a hole
in his diaphragm.
Oh, my God.
It's treatable, right?
There are surgical options
post-birth,
but due to the
severity of his case,
his prognosis is poor.
And unfortunately,
that is not all.
The increased fluid
is compressing
the female twin,
jeopardizing her growth.
So you're saying
she's in trouble, too?
There has to be
something you can do.
Yeah.
Selectively reducing
the male fetus
would give her
the best chance
of survival.
You mean...
Lose him.
I am so sorry.
Is there a chance
things could stabilize
on their own if we just wait?
It's possible,
but in all likelihood,
the fluid will
continue to build,
hindering her
lung development.
Oh, no.
But the earlier
we intervene,
the better.
Dr. Charles. I got
Fran Mooney's labs back.
Her TSH is really low,
so I ran some more tests.
It's likely due to an overdose
of her thyroid medication.
Huh.
Yeah, so I'm gonna
put her on beta blockers
and start detoxing her
with charcoal.
Let me talk to the daughter,
find out who's in charge
of the meds.
Okay.
Your EKG and labs
were negative.
You didn't have
a heart attack.
Have you ever had chest pain
like that before?
Yeah, I have.
Panic attacks?
Yeah.
When I got back
from my first tour,
I started talking
in my sleep.
Shouted out
orders, mostly.
It was like every night,
I went back to Afghanistan.
Army?
Navy.
Squid.
Reservist now.
Vicki's active duty.
How long did you serve,
Reginald?
Reggie, please.
I was 12 years in the Corps.
I made it all the way
up to Gunny.
Mmm.
Three tours in Iraq
and two in Afghanistan.
The last tour
was the roughest.
I had an IED
that took my leg.
Took three of
my Marines with it.
Sorry, man.
Sorry to interrupt.
Dr. Choi, can I
talk to you?
Yeah.
Be right back.
Got the rest of
Reggie's labs back.
White count is 18,000.
His platelets...
His platelets
are what?
I'm sorry, I can't share
test results with someone
who's not on staff
at the hospital.
You know, I'll, uh...
I'll head back to the VA.
I'll pick you up at 6:00.
Yeah.
Bye, April.
Bye.
His platelets are
really low. 30,000.
He's got thrombocytopenia.
Guy can't catch a break.
Puts him at risk
for bleeding.
Page Hematology
for a consult.
Okay.
Wait a second.
What's with the attitude?
What do you mean?
Why are you giving
Vicki a hard time?
I was just protecting
patient confidentiality.
Following the rules.
Dr. Halstead?
We've decided that, um...
Celine will have
the procedure.
We've tried
for six years
to have a child.
These were our
last two embryos.
We just can't risk
losing both of them.
I'll let Obstetrics know.
I give my mom her pills,
but I only give her
one tablet every morning.
That's what
the doctor prescribed.
You mind me asking,
where are the meds kept?
Are they locked away, or...
I came as soon as I could.
Had to leave a client meeting.
This is my husband,
Patrick.
Patrick, this is Doctor...
Sorry, remind me?
Dr. Charles.
Nice to meet you.
They think Mom overdosed
on her thyroid medication,
but I don't see how.
Maybe Fran got
into the pills?
No, of course not.
She can't even button
her own shirt.
There's no way she could
open a pill bottle herself.
She unlocked the front door.
You know, when Fran
was first diagnosed,
she begged Alana
to euthanize her.
She couldn't stand
the thought
of deteriorating.
But she's not lucid enough
to attempt suicide.
Is she?
Periods of lucidity aren't
uncommon with Alzheimer's,
and, you know, the increased
agitation, the weight loss,
I mean, those both,
they could be signs
of depression.
I told you. Your mother
shouldn't be living with us.
We are not having
this conversation right now.
Why don't you two
take a break?
Go grab a cup of coffee.
Let me have a chat with Fran.
Okay?
You go ahead.
I have to respond
to some client emails.
Celine, you all right?
He just kicked.
I know it's him,
he's always on the right.
Wait, wait. Stop.
What is it?
I can't do this.
What?
You heard Dr. Halstead.
We don't have a choice.
He said there's a chance
things could stabilize.
Celine, we can't risk
losing both of our babies.
How about
we talk this out...
I'm sorry, but I'm not
willing to let him go.
I can't do the procedure.
I just can't.
Okay, here's the clause
in the surrogacy contract.
The parents have
the right to request
a selective reduction
for any medical reason.
And the surrogate agreed
to defer to their wishes?
She signed the contract.
But she has since
very emphatically
changed her mind.
Okay, well, that's
the funny thing
about contracts.
They don't really care
if you change your mind.
Well, I don't care
if she signed
the thing in blood.
Celine is not
a human incubator.
I won't force
a procedure on her
without her explicit consent.
You're not gonna do
anything at all,
Dr. Halstead.
This is a legal matter now.
Let the lawyers hash it out.
Waiting room's jumping.
What's going on?
Mass casualty
over at East Mercy.
They went on bypass
about an hour ago.
Started diverting
patients here.
Hi.
Uh, I think
my sister's here,
Leslie Taylor.
She was hit by a car.
Yes, I'm the nurse
who left the message
but I'm taking that
you're not Paul Taylor?
No, that's Leslie's husband.
Ex-husband. He called me.
Okay, just give me a second.
I'll get her doctor.
Okay.
Dr. Choi! I need you.
BP's in the toilet.
Heart rate's 130.
Must be an upper GI bleed.
He's got thrombocytopenia.
He won't be able
to make a clot.
He needs blood
and platelets now.
Trigger the MTP,
I'm gonna intubate.
Twenty etomidate, 100 of sux,
and grab me an EGD scope.
Gotta find the source
of the bleed.
The impact from the accident
destroyed the right lobe
of Leslie's liver.
We will be able
to fix it for now,
but she's gonna need
a new liver urgently,
and because of her condition,
she's gonna move up
the transplant list
from her previous status.
Wait, previous status?
What do you mean?
Leslie's already
on the transplant list.
You didn't know?
Right, right.
Of course I did.
I'm sorry. There's just
a lot to take in.
You were saying?
So if Leslie doesn't get
a new liver
in the next few days...
Oh, God.
There is another option.
A living donor.
Someone can donate
a lobe of their liver.
Really?
I'll donate, then.
What do I need to do?
First of all,
you should know
that there can be
complications
for the donor that...
I don't care.
Is there anybody that you need
to talk to about this?
No. There's no...
I need to do this
for my sister, Dr. Rhodes.
Okay. We'll get you
tested right away.
Fran, could you
open this bottle,
take out a pill,
and hand it to me?
Could you do that?
You do it, Milty.
Just pull down
the tab and press.
She's in a-fib with RVR.
Give me 10 of diltiazem.
Yes, ma'am.
Meds are in.
She's back
in normal sinus rhythm.
It's odd that she
flipped into a-fib.
We've already treated her
hyperthyroidism.
I'm gonna order an echo,
see what's going on.
Yeah, good idea.
But, um...
I think we might be
dealing with more than
just an overdose here.
April,
call the blood bank.
We're gonna need
more platelets.
Give the second dose
of TXA.
That's it.
That's where
he's bleeding from.
Epinephrine injector.
Ready?
Mmm-hmm.
There we go.
I think we got it.
Dr. Choi.
Damn it. It's not clotting.
They won't allocate
any more platelets for Reggie.
What? Why?
'Cause of the MCI
at East Mercy.
There's a citywide shortage.
Blood bank's been mandated
to dispense only to patients
who will benefit.
Go down there in person
and tell them the order's
coming from me.
Do not take no
for an answer.
We've given him
multiple doses.
It is not working.
I didn't ask
for your opinion.
Do it now, or I'll get
someone who will.
There's more.
I want to make sure
you understand you're in
clear breach of contract.
I'm sorry, but I think
we should just wait and see
if things stabilize
on their own.
With all due respect,
there is no we.
It's the Addisons' decision
and theirs alone.
It's her body.
That doesn't give her
the right to hold my clients'
fetuses hostage.
That's not my intention.
Listen.
I'd hate to have
to bring this to trial
because if I do,
you'll be facing
severe legal and financial
ramifications.
Let's take it
down a notch, okay?
You're not gonna force
her hand with intimidation
and scare tactics.
Why don't you stay
in your lane, Doctor?
This doesn't
concern you.
Oh, no, it does concern me,
because you're upsetting
my patient.
You need to leave.
Our lawyer
is not going anywhere
until we figure this out.
Celine, do you want her
to leave?
Excuse me.
I'm Sharon Goodwin,
Director of Patient
Medical Services.
Is there anything
I could help you sort out?
Yes. We'd like
a different doctor.
Dr. Halstead is clearly
biased against us.
That's not up to you.
I'm Celine's doctor.
Only she can make
that decision.
Dr. Halstead, can I
speak to you outside?
Ms. Goodwin...
Now.
You're wrong,
Dr. Halstead.
You know who else
can make that decision?
Me.
And if the Addisons
aren't comfortable
with you...
You're benching me?
I'm reassigning the case.
Yes.
Unbelievable.
When was the
prescription filled?
I don't remember.
I think Patrick picked up
the last refill.
It was about a month ago.
No good?
A little sweeter than I like.
Can I get you another cup?
No, no. It's fine.
Okay, so there's
20 pills left,
and the quantity
of the prescription was 90.
Sorry, I'm terrible at math.
It's okay.
There should be
60 pills remaining,
which means there's 40 pills
unaccounted for.
You think my mom
took 40 pills?
No, no, if she took
that many pills at once,
she would be in a coma.
The overdosing has to be
taking place over time,
like, a little bit each day.
And based on my evaluation,
your mom doesn't have
the cognition
to be able to carry out
a repetitive, multistep
task anyway.
Wait, you think someone's
doing this to her?
Is there anybody who comes
and goes from your home?
A part-time caregiver, or...
There was for a bit,
but she quit months ago.
And the only people with
access to my mom's pills
are me and...
My husband.
What if I don't get
a liver in time?
Well, the good news is that
we found you a donor already.
Really?
Mmm-hmm.
We tested your sister.
Turns out...
No, no. Wait, my sister?
Denise?
Yeah.
How did she know
I was here?
Hi, Leslie.
What are you doing here?
Leslie, please.
No, I told you to
stay away from me.
I just want to help you.
I don't want your help.
Leslie, hear me out.
Get out!
Whoa!
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Here, let's step outside.
Um, take a deep breath.
Deep breath, that's it.
Look, Leslie, I don't know
what happened between you
and your sister, but she...
I'll tell you what happened.
She killed my little girl.
Mary was only
three years old.
Denise put her to bed.
Went downstairs,
lit her bong,
and smoked herself
into oblivion.
When she woke up,
the house was in flames.
She managed
to get herself out,
but she was too stoned
to remember
that Mary...
My Mary...
Was still upstairs.
I won't accept
anything from her.
I'd rather die.
That's all you can do.
I asked her
to stick around,
see if we can get Leslie
to change her mind.
Denise doesn't think
she'll budge.
Yeah, no,
she was quite adamant.
I mean...
I can understand.
Connor,
she's cheating herself
out of life to what?
Punish her sister?
Denise has already
done that to herself.
Every day of her life,
she has to reckon
with what happened.
What do you mean,
with what she did?
She's not shirking
responsibility.
The opposite.
That's why
she's so desperate
to make amends.
Well, look, regardless,
we can't force Leslie
to accept Denise's liver.
No. We just have to stand by
and watch her die.
We both know the likelihood
of another liver
coming through
in time is slim.
She's got days, at most.
I'm gonna reach out
to the hospital's PR team,
get them to put out
an urgent public appeal
for a donor.
What?
Nothing.
No, that's a good idea.
Where are the platelets?
He's not getting any more.
They have to be conserved
for patients who have
an actual shot at survival.
He has a shot.
Once the meds kick in,
the platelets start holding,
we can get him up to surgery.
We both know
that is not
gonna happen.
We take him up to the OR,
he's gonna bleed out...
You have no right
to deny him treatment.
Dr. Choi?
He's bleeding
from his IV, too.
He's in v-fib.
No pulse.
April, charge to 200.
Doris, start bagging.
Charging.
Charged.
Clear.
Dr. Choi.
Amp of epi.
Charging to 200.
Clear.
Doris?
He's asystolic.
Another amp of epi.
Dr. Choi, enough!
Another amp of epi!
Give him an amp of bicarb
and an amp of calcium.
On it.
Come on.
Time of death, 16:48.
The Addisons aren't
speaking to me except
through their lawyer.
I don't know what to do.
I can't afford to be in some
long, drawn-out legal battle.
Maybe I should just
respect their wishes.
But I know they don't
want this either.
That's why I'm here.
I may have found another way.
It's an investigational
procedure called
fetal tracheal occlusion.
If successful, it would allow
the twins to reach viability.
I mean, it could even help
improve the male fetus'
lung function.
Hold on, though.
General anesthesia
always carries risks.
And because of your asthma,
the potential
complications
are increased.
You would be
putting yourself
on the line.
I know they're not mine.
And when it's time
to hand them over,
I'll be happy to,
'cause I know how loved
and wanted they are.
But while they're
still inside my body,
while their lives
depend on me,
I have to do
what I think is best.
I want to do it, Dr. Halstead.
This is absurd.
I can't believe that
you think I would do
something like this!
I don't know
what to think.
I know you resented my mom
moving in with us.
The imposition on our lives.
So you think I'm trying
to kill her?
No one's
accusing you
of anything.
Yes, you are.
We're just trying
to understand
how this happened.
Too sweet? Your coffee.
Is your coffee too sweet?
Yeah.
Why?
Alana, I'd like you
to get an MRI.
April, that man risked
his life for all of us.
We owed it to him to do
everything we possibly could.
Yeah, but we did, Ethan.
The situation
had become futile,
you just couldn't see it.
So you had to go
snitch to Lanik?
I was following
the chain of command.
Funny, you're such
a stickler for the rules
when they align
with your agenda.
My only agenda
is the welfare
of my patients.
Then you wouldn't have
interfered when I was trying
to save Reggie's life.
Did you go to Lanik
to get back at me?
Get back at you?
You made it very clear
you resent Vicki.
Are you serious?
You think I would
jeopardize a patient
to get even with you?
You two need to take this
outside right now.
You're disturbing my ED.
Sorry, Maggie.
We're done.
Alana. We have
the results of your MRI,
and we were just wondering
if we could discuss...
Please, just tell me.
Your MRI shows atrophy
to the hippocampus.
It's the area of your brain
associated with memory.
Combined with some
of the behaviors that
we observed today,
forgetting that you had
already put sugar
in your coffee,
problems with simple math,
the findings are consistent
with the initial stages
of early-onset Alzheimer's.
Jesus.
Wait.
You mean
I'm gonna end up
like my mom?
There are certain medications
that help slow the disease's
progression.
Not to mention hundreds
of new clinical trials,
some of the results
of which are promising,
especially when
started early.
What... Wait,
so it was me?
I was...
I was overdosing her?
Accidentally.
You were forgetting
that you had already
given her the medication.
Oh, my God.
What have I done?
I'm so sorry. I...
I can't believe
I suspected you.
Can you ever forgive me?
Honey...
It's okay.
We'll give you both some time.
Thank you.
Hey. I have great news.
We found a donor
for Leslie.
Someone answered
the hospital's public plea.
Really? That fast?
It just went out
a few hours ago.
I could hardly
believe it myself.
Um, is it a living donor,
or did the family
of the deceased
request it go to Leslie?
Uh, I don't know.
It's all anonymous, so...
Right.
Her disease
was staring her
in the face.
But she was never
gonna see it.
Well, that's
the kicker, right?
I mean, a primary symptom
of early Alzheimer's
is anosognosia.
Anosognosia?
It's when you don't realize
you have a disease.
You can't recognize
anything's wrong.
Dr. Charles?
Can I talk to you
about something?
Of course.
Dr. Halstead.
What part of
"you are off the case"
was unclear to you?
I felt I had
an ethical obligation
to present Celine
with all the options.
While you had no qualms
about leaving the Addisons
out of the decision entirely.
You know, this is
the kind of behavior
that almost got you
kicked out of residency.
You're an attending
physician now.
You know better.
Dr. Halstead.
Are you still planning
to observe?
We're about to start.
We're not done.
I'll deal with you after.
Dr. Choi.
I'm doing
the nursing schedule
for next month.
Wanted to let you know
that I'm putting you
and Nurse April
on alternate shifts.
Did April request that?
No.
But until you two
get your acts together,
I'm not gonna risk
another spectacle.
That won't work
for me, Mags.
Unfortunately, Dr. Choi,
it's not your decision
to make.
I understand.
Unless April objects,
I want her on my shifts.
Excuse me.
April.
I'm leaving.
Please don't.
You know what,
for the record,
I would never let
our personal history
affect my decision-making
when it comes to patients.
I know. I shouldn't
have accused you.
I didn't report you
to Lanik out of spite.
You left me no choice.
I'm sorry, April.
And maybe I could be
nicer to Vicki.
But it's hard.
Seeing you together is...
It's hard, Ethan.
April.
Don't. No.
Hey.
You okay?
What?
Maggie told me about Reggie.
Sounds like you did
everything you could.
I wish I could have
done more.
Come on.
Let's go.
What the hell
were you thinking?
If Leslie ever finds out...
She won't.
That's why
it's so perfect.
An anonymous,
self-directed
donation.
Denise's identity can never be
revealed without her consent.
There is no justification
for blatantly disregarding
Leslie's wishes.
Listen, I tried
to keep you out of it.
You kept me out of it
because you knew
I wouldn't be on board.
Okay, so go on.
Tell her the truth.
I can take the hit,
but her death,
that'll be on you.
We're saving her life.
The end justifies the means.
Oh, hey, Daniel.
You got a minute?
For you? Maybe.
What's up?
It's about Will Halstead.
Popular topic of
conversation today.
Is that right?
Did our babies make it?
Dr. Dennis will be out to
speak with you both shortly,
but the surgery was a success.
Yeah, both fetuses
have strong heartbeats.
Is Celine okay?
Yeah, she did just fine.
What, so I don't do
what you want,
and you force it on me?
What are you talking about?
Mandatory counseling,
Goodwin's orders.
Or I could take a leave
of absence, my choice.
Tell me
this isn't your doing.
I spoke with Dr. Charles
because I'm worried.
That's terrific.
You told
the Head of Psychiatry
I'm unstable.
You are the only one
who doesn't see that
there's a problem.
Will, please.
This is not you.
Or maybe it's not
the Will you want.
What does that mean?
I am done being
everyone's puppet.
How can you
put that on me?
I wasn't the one pulling
the strings. How could I?
You lied to me,
you kept me
in the dark.
You're still keeping me
Well, well.
Young Oedipus.
Come to hit me again?
What happened
between you and Ava?
Let me get you a drink first.