♪ Ohhh ohhh ohhh ♪
I've had this song
stuck in my head,
like all day, all night.
I mean, I slept
for six hours last night,
and the song underscored
the entire six hours.
What's the song?
I'm looking for
sperm donors, you know?
I mean, I fell asleep
reading medical histories,
files.
I mean, you'd think
I'd dream about that.
I'd like to hear the song.
Can you sing the part
that's stuck in your head?
I don't sing.
I don't judge.
All right.
♪ Tempted by the thrill
of something new ♪
♪ so now I turn
my lonely eyes to you ♪
♪ I promised you
that we could have it all ♪
♪ you trusted me ♪
♪ but I let you fall ♪
Who did you let fall?
What?
In your mind,
who trusted you
and you let them fall?
Your ex-husband?
Derek? No. Why would I be
thinking about my ex-husband?
You're choosing donors,
you're moving forward
into a bold new chapter.
Sometimes moving forward
makes us look back.
No, I'm not looking back.
All right?
It was just a stupid song
in my head.
It's never
just a song in your head.
Mm.
Hi.
Morning.
I'm really sorry about this,
because if you are
as hungover as I am,
it sucks to wake up
this early,
but I gotta go to work,
which means
you've gotta get out.
All right.
But, like...
Now.
Because I'm late.
Right. Okay.
The Ferrari 458 spyder,
is powered by a 4.5-liter v8.
It can hit 62 miles an hour
in less than 3.5 seconds
and reach a top speed
of over 198 miles per hour.
Well, that sounds
really good.
I'm more of a Porsche guy
myself, but--
Dr. Freedman,
porsches are not as cool
as ferraris.
- Oh.
- Ollie.
Ollie, can you take that Ferrari
out to the waiting room?
We need to talk
to Dr. Freedman.
Drive carefully.
It's a zoo out there.
Okay?
Um... Well,
he's certainly high energy.
But his blood pressure's
normal,
and the tests came back negative
for any kind of thyroid issue.
So I can't find
any physical triggers
for hyperactivity.
So you think he's a.D.H.D.,
just like Brian?
It could be.
Um, how is Brian?
He just got into Stanford.
What?
Congratulations.
You gotta give him
a high-five for me.
Although, he's 18.
He probably doesn't want
a high-five
from his pediatrician.
Dr. Freedman,
if Ollie has it, too,
we would like to treat it
as early and as aggressively
as possible.
I don't know. I mean,
the way he was
rattling those stats off
about that car,
it doesn't sound like a kid
who's having trouble focusing.
And if he's
just a little bit hyper,
you know, I was hyper
when I was a kid.
Respectfully, Dr. Freedman,
we've been
through this before.
A.d.h.d. Runs in the family,
and the medication
really helped Brian.
Mm-hmm.
Yeah, I mean, Brian was a little
bit older when we diagnosed him.
Ollie is having tantrums.
He's throwing fits.
Okay. I just don't want
to jump the gun.
But there are
some other tests we can run.
Uh, my associate,
who is a therapist,
Dr. Sheldon Wallace,
could probably see you today.
Great. Thank you.
Hey. Any progress?
Mm. Okay.
I think...
I have it boiled down
to...
The classical musician
and the geologist.
Okay, I'm gonna go ahead
and rename them
soft and softer.
I'm sorry?
The geologist--
that was the weird kid
who was always obsessed
with rocks
because he couldn't find
any friends.
Definitely didn't have
any girlfriends.
And the classical musician--
no, musicians are hot.
No, rock stars are hot.
Classical musicians
are soft.
You gotta find a donor
that's got a little more...
Testosterone.
Sam... look, i-i--
I've thrown out 48 donors
on medical history alone.
I mean, I've eliminated
all potential for heart disease,
stroke, uh, dementia.
I mean, are you really--
are you really telling me
that I now need to consider
potential testosterone levels?
I'm just saying, you're--
you're gonna be
an amazing mother, all right?
But this kid, you know,
is not gonna have a dad,
so it already is gonna have
enough soft, all right?
Having a donor that's got
a little bit more testosterone
might not be
such a bad thing.
You know what? My--my f.S.H.
Is through the roof,
I'm a woman in my 40's.
I mean, there's a good chance
that even with
all these
crazy-making hormones I'm on
that I'm still
the eggless wonder.
I mean, I don't even know
what I'm doing here.
Addison. Addison.
You always get
what you want.
Now is this something
that you really want?
Yes, I want this.
All right, then.
So pick some sperm,
just make sure it's got
some testosterone in it.
What game
are you playing?
"Drive."
I'm about to get three stars
on every level.
Wow.
That's very impressive.
How are your grades
in school?
Bad.
I got a "b" in English.
Three stars!
A "b" is bad?
Tell Dr. Wallace
how hard it is for you
to do your homework alone.
Mom and dad always
help me on my homework
because it takes me
too long on my own.
And you can't sit still
during reading time
at school, right?
When can we go home?
May I speak with Ollie
privately?
I don't see
why that's necessary.
He's 8, and he's
perfectly well-adjusted.
He doesn't need therapy.
Well, if he's
perfectly well-adjusted,
then why are you here?
He's hyperactive.
It would help me
to assess him
if I could have
a few moments with him.
He's a young boy.
You're a man we're just meeting.
We're not gonna leave him
alone with you.
Okay. I understand that.
Why don't we make
an appointment
for him to take
some diagnostic tests?
And if you give me the name
and number of his teacher,
I'll speak with her and...
Have her complete
some diagnostic inventories,
and... we'll get back
to you.
We didn't have to
go through all of that
when Brian was diagnosed.
Our diagnostic approach
has changed in the last decade
as we've come to
better understand the disorder.
And most people think
that's a good thing.
Prescribing any drug
for a child
is not something
that should be taken lightly.
Okay.
Well, thank you
for your time
and your somewhat startling
condescension.
Mrs. Graham--
we are good parents.
Our oldest son
is headed to Stanford,
and Ollie is on
the honor roll at school,
and that's not because
we're running around
getting prescriptions for drugs
that our kids don't need.
So thank you...
I--
for your time.
Come, sweetie.
But we'll be finding
a new doctor.
Thank you.
Dr. Turner.
Have a seat.
You're very smiley today.
I get really smiley
when I have good news.
For this reason,
I'm terrible at poker.
F-For me?
You have good news for me?
The board has agreed
to revisit your case.
Revisit? Wh-what do you mean?
What does that mean?
It means we have work to do,
because we've convinced them
that suspending you for a year
was not in the best interest
of your patients.
It means we have a shot,
Dr. Turner,
at getting you back to work
sometime soon.
Hey, Jason, I want you
to call me Violet
because I'm gonna give you
a hug right now,
and for that, I think we need
to be on a first-name basis.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
You're late.
I'm not feeling well.
Amelia.
Yeah.
I heard about
your friend Michelle.
I'm very sorry
for your loss.
Thanks.
But it's not an excuse for you
dropping the ball at work.
You've been late repeatedly,
your charts are a mess.
If you need
a leave of absence
while you mourn your friend,
all you have to do is ask me.
Charlotte, all I need is
for you to get off my back.
Do you think
you can do that?
I have a job to do here,
and--
this isn't your job.
Harassing me is not your job.
Babysitting me,
checking up on me,
breathalyzing me,
it's not your job.
It's your damn hobby.
You know, seriously,
Charlotte, what i--
what is your problem
with me?
What is your damage?
Hey, baby,
guess who I ran into today.
Aah!
Oh, my god.
Who the hell is she?
I'm his damn wife,
you whore.
Charlie, wait.
Now let me explain.
Aah!
You son of a bitch!
How could you do this?
- I'll kill you!
- Get off of him!
I'll kill you!
A decade before Ollie was born,
that's how long I've been
treating this family,
and five minutes with you,
and they're running
for the door.
You shouldn't have sent them
to me
if all you're looking for
was a rubber stamp.
I was looking for a second
opinion about the meds,
not some kind of judgment
about their parenting.
I mean, granted, Rosie is
a bit of a tiger mom,
and that can be off-putting,
but it's not uncommon.
I don't think
I got the whole story.
Ollie is
a little bit hyperactive,
but he doesn't seem like
he can't focus.
And his answers
seemed coached...
Oh.
You know, to put it mildly.
The whole thing was odd.
What, parents coached a kid so
he could score a.D.H.D. Drugs?
So says Sheldon.
I mean,
these are good parents.
I've known them a long time.
They're good people.
Good people make
terrible decisions every day.
My field is pretty much
based on that.
It doesn't surprise me.
The diagnosis of a.D.H.D.
Is epidemic in this country.
We all know the hysteria,
Pete.
But that doesn't mean
it's not real
and it doesn't mean that Ollie's
faking it or was coached.
Okay, maybe these kids
are unfocused
because we're pumping them
full of caffeine and sugar
and preservatives.
We should look at diet
and exercise
before we just write 'em
a scrip for speed.
A.d.h.d. Drugs can be
very effective,
but they have to be used
sparingly
and only in clear-cut cases.
Okay, I just don't
see that here, Cooper.
Yeah,
and if Sheldon is right,
the parents are coaching
their kid to get drugs,
it's--it's child abuse.
I need sperm.
I need you to help me
choose sperm.
I have to pick a donor today
and...
Oh, for the love of god.
I need a consult.
Can you all... just please
give me a consult?
A sperm consult?
Shut up.
Please just shut up
and help me.
What is this,
fantasy football?
Fantasy sperm ball.
Really?
Don't judge.
I needed help.
All right. I say,
go with the historian.
History's cool.
How is history cool?
You understand that the baby
isn't necessarily
going to be an historian?
Yes, but the historian
is Greek,
and they have some good genes.
They never sunburn, the Greeks.
They only tan.
So you're saying
I should choose a donor
based on the amount
of melanin in his skin?
I mean, you're pale as a ghost.
You want to spend
your whole kid's life
worrying about melanoma...
I think that's valid.
I'd tend to agree.
All right.
Take down the Swede.
Yeah, sure. The Swede is gone.
Okay, I think the phd
is gonna be too intellectual.
What's wrong with intellectual?
Well, Addison is fun-loving.
She doesn't want to sit around
analyzing everything all day--
are we talking about Addison
or--
oh, come on, Sheldon. I'm not
talking in metaphors here.
Not consciously, but you did
just describe your wife.
Okay.
Ooh.
Focus, people.
We are running out of time.
Now come on. Let's do the pros
and cons of the pro athlete.
Well, there--there are
no cons to a pro athlete.
Well, that depends
what sport he played
and how many times
he got hit in the head.
What, you think
his concussion rate
is directly related
to his spooge?
Can we please
not call it spooge?
You know, pro athletes generally
run high on testosterone.
Mm-hmm.
If you had a boy, it could be hard to handle.
Then you just
bring him to Cooper.
He'll dose him up on
some heavy pharmaceuticals...
You know what? You make this
so much less fun.
Where are the women
in this practice?
Where? Where are the women?
Okay, Addison,
you're overthinking this.
Okay, what if you met some guy
at a bar,
and you accidentally
got pregnant?
I'm with Sam.
I mean, if you weren't.
Women get pregnant every day
and give birth to babies
all the time
with guys who amount to
little more than sperm donors.
Look at Cooper with this kid
he never knew about.
It's true. Although,
Erica kinda did hit
the sperm jackpot
with me.
Mm. I vote for the activist,
for what it's worth.
Oh, yeah, they're
very level-headed.
Okay.
I vote for the Greek.
I'd go with the phd.
But I might just be
shining a light
on my own narcissism.
Listen, you have a lot
of love to give,
and that's all
you should be focusing on.
The sperm is just...
Sperm.
Excuse me.
This is not public property.
Get the hell off the deck.
Hey, you're home early.
Hey.
You're still here.
Yeah.
Well, you threw my clothes
at me this morning
and kicked me out,
which was, uh, actually...
Strangely charming.
Uh, so I thought i'd--
what?
I don't know.
Uh...
Get your phone number?
Also, i'm--I'm pretty sure
I left my wallet inside.
You have a name?
Ryan.
Ryan kerrigan.
Amelia Shepherd.
It's nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you, too.
You coming?
Ollie, come on! Stop!
No! I don't want another doctor!
Ollie, please calm down!
Come on.
Ollie, stop.
It's all right.
Stop it.
Ollie, control your--
oh!
Oh, my god.
Ollie.
You hit your father.
I don't want
another doctor!
It's okay.
You don't need another doctor,
buddy. I'm here.
Okay, just breathe.
Just breathe. It's okay.
Any chance you want to give us
that prescription now?
Oh!
I like you. You're fun.
You're fun.
I'm not fun.
I'm awesome.
You are awesome.
Could I ask you kind of
a personal question?
Okay.
Where did we meet
last night?
I have zero memory.
Yeah, you mix these
with a few drinks,
and memory sort of becomes
a thing of the past.
Dude, you had party favors
in your pocket,
and you held out
this long?
So rude.
I want to make sure
you remembered my name.
What is my name?
It's Ryan kerrigan.
You passed.
You got a razor blade?
They're much better
if we chop them up.
Yeah.
Razor blade coming up.
I'm sorry. I didn't realize
it was this bad.
That was mild.
They get worse.
His mind is racing
all the time.
He barely sleeps.
Is he having, um, soda,
or any desserts
right before he goes to bed?
'Cause that could absolutely
interfere with sleep.
A little sugar
makes him do this?
I don't like soda
before bed.
I don't like to eat
so much anymore.
The medicine makes me feel
not hungry.
Oh, what--
what medicine?
Ollie, go to
the waiting room, okay?
Let us talk to Dr. Freedman.
Am I in trouble?
No.
No, Ollie,
you're not in trouble.
We just need to talk,
okay?
We had Brian's medication.
We just thought we would see
if it helped.
Oh, please don't look at me
that way, Dr. Freedman.
Was he having tantrums like this
before you started giving him
unprescribed amphetamines?
With a.D.H.D. Kids,
the drugs calm them.
So if his brain
is functioning normally,
of course he's amped up.
You're giving him speed.
We thought
that it would help him.
You have to believe that.
And when you saw
that it wasn't?
We need him diagnosed so that he
can get extra time on his tests.
He needs the time.
Brian was a straight-a student
after his diagnosis,
but not before.
Ollie's grades...
They're not
what they should be.
He's in third grade.
Dr. Freedman,
do you have any idea
what it's like out there
these days?
We're not wealthy people,
but we spent $12,000 a year
on tuition
for Ollie's preschool.
More for donations
so that the right grade school
would consider us.
We didn't go through that,
we didn't spend that much money
to have Ollie underperform
in grade school,
because then he won't get in
to the right high schools,
and we can forget about
the right college.
So you took
his brother's medicine,
you amped him up
so that I would diagnose him
so you could cheat
the school system?
You see a third grader.
But I am his mother,
and I see his entire future
in that report card.
You don't want to help us?
Fine.
But please, until you've
been there, don't judge us.
And it's really
the strangest decision
I've ever had to make.
You know, and i'm--I'm looking
at these baby pictures,
and, uh, these
family medical histories
and personality assessments,
probably made
by the 21-year-old intern
who's Manning the desk
at the cryobank that night
when the 22-year-old
sperm donor
comes in to sell his sperm
for cash.
It's, uh, it's really
just disturbing is what it is.
I mean, the whole thing
is just so--
four.
What?
Four.
We got four.
Four eggs?
I made four eggs.
I mean, normally, I would
want eight or ten,
but, uh...
With my age, it's...
And your f.S.H. Levels,
I mean, this is--
I thought I was
the eggless wonder.
Well, you are not
Oh, my god.
Oh, my god. I've gotta, um...
I have to pick a donor,
right now.
No, no, no. Right now
I need to take these eggs
because you could start
ovulating any minute,
and I want to get them
before you do.
And then
you can pick a donor.
In fact, I have a friend
at the cryobank
so we can get
a same-day delivery.
Oh, my god.
Oh, my gosh.
Uh... wait. You're gonna, um,
fertilize today?
Oh, i'm--
I'm knocking you out now.
Okay.
Okay?
Why would any parents
want their kid saddled
with an a.D.H.D. Diagnosis?
Extended time
on standardized tests,
more attention from teachers.
So you get the kids
hopped up on drugs
to get 'em in
to a better college?
I think when they initially
started giving him the drugs,
they really thought
he had a.D.H.D.
I don't believe that
they would give--
those drugs are addictive,
Cooper.
They're not a toy.
Call the damn police.
Okay, I hear that.
I do.
But I don't really think
that the foster care system
is best for Ollie.
I guess I hear that, too.
Dr. King, I hate
to bother you, but i--
you're not a bother.
I have a patient--
Kelly garrity.
She's Dr. Shepherd's patient,
and she's showing
an atypical preoperative
visual field defect.
If it turns out to be
a pituitary apoplexy,
she'll need emergency surgery
immediately.
Dr. Shepherd
went home sick and--
she what?
Amelia's sick?
Cooper, I love you,
but go away.
And she told me to call her
if I needed her,
but she's not answering
her phone,
and I'm not sure what
the protocol is if she's not--
I'll find Dr. Shepherd.
You book an O.R.
just in case we need it.
Yes, ma'am.
Thank you.
So you hit it
on the cabinet?
I just... stood up
without looking.
It was stupid.
Knocked myself out.
Your husband called
the ambulance?
I guess so.
So where is he?
What's with the 20 questions,
Anderson?
Sorry.
I'm just sayin',
your bedside manner needs work.
But I learned from you.
Here, take a look.
There's no sign of a bleed,
but the loss of conscious,
the pain, dizziness...
It's a concussion.
I got it.
And as you know,
rest is your best bet.
I don't think you need
to stay for observation
as long as your husband
can help you out,
keep an eye on you.
Think you can rely on him
for that?
I'll be fine.
Can you write me something
for pain?
Yeah, of course.
Something strong.
Gonna need it.
You got it.
Hey, is it
all right to come in?
Oh, absolutely. She's, uh,
she's already out, though.
That's okay.
I just want to sit with her.
So you got some eggs, huh?
Oh, yes, we did.
Four of 'em.
Wow.
That's great.
That's really great.
It's all just kinda...
Halfway with you two,
isn't it?
What?
You showed up to hold her hand,
but, uh,
you waited
till she's already out.
So she doesn't even know
you're here.
I was running late.
Okay.
What are you trying
to say?
I already said it, Sam.
It's all halfway.
I mean, you're--
you're staying with her,
but you don't want to parent
with her.
It's one of the stranger plans
I've ever heard of.
I love her.
Oh, I get that.
Yeah, it's just bad timing.
I get that, too.
I think we can make it work.
Okay.
It's not halfway.
It's just...
It's halfway.
I'm worried about
my marriage.
I'm worried about Amelia.
Well, I'm not your therapist.
I'm your friend.
And that means I get to
talk about my stuff, too.
Well, yeah, okay.
Okay, you go first.
I hardly ever hear
from her.
Since Michelle died,
she's gone into hiding.
And i-I'm worried about her.
Worried how?
I'm worried about her
like I think about her
pretty much all the time,
and when I get a text message,
I will it to be from her,
and it never is, and I...
Want to check on her.
You know, I want to check on her
about 15 times a day.
But I...
I don't know
who I am to her.
if I'm just a colleague
or a friend.
I...
I think about her all day
and I'm pretty certain
that's not reciprocal.
All right.
Tell me about your marriage.
Really? 'Cause I was just
gonna give you
some profound insight
on this whole Amelia thing.
I really don't want
to hear about it,
so just--
you're
more comfortable listening.
Is that it?
Pete, please. Can we--
o-o-okay, okay.
Uh, you know, I-I tried
to do what you told me.
I tried to remember
all the reasons I married her.
But I'm overwhelmed
with this feeling of--
that--i-i don't know.
I-I don't trust her.
And I don't know why.
And I don't know
how to talk to her about it
because everything
I think to say
sounds like an accusation.
That sucks.
Wow.
That's your insight?
Yeah.
Dr. King, I have
an update on Kelly garrity.
The pituitary adenoma
is bleeding
and the blood is compressing
the optical chiasm.
Well,
how'd it start bleeding?
And how the hell
did Dr. Shepherd miss it?
It's unpredictable. The problem
is, the nerve will die
if the blood compresses it
for too long.
We have about 30 minutes
before she loses her vision
permanently.
Have you done
this surgery before?
No, ma'am, but I have watched
several and assisted twice.
I feel confident
that given the opp--
shut up
and page Dr. Shepherd again,
then prep the patient,
get scrubbed, and stand by.
Yes, ma'am.
Thank you.
Hey there.
Hey. Excuse me.
Anderson--
no.
It still hurts.
Charlotte.
It's called
post-concussion syndrome.
Charlotte, it's been months.
It's too long.
It's too many refills.
Please don't judge
my healing process.
I'm in pain.
I just need
some more painkillers.
It's really that simple.
Fine. I'll write you
something lighter.
Damn it, Anderson.
You think I don't know
what's best for me?
This stuff is addictive.
You think
I don't know that, too?
Look at me. Do I look like
an addict to you?
Or do I look like a person
who's showing up for work
every day,
doing my job, despite
the staggering headaches
that people like you
are causing me?
I bumped my head
again yesterday.
Same cabinet, same spot.
Hurt like hell.
It was stupid. I'm having
that cabinet removed this week.
Now just, please,
write the scrip for me.
All right?
This is the only thing
I can't do for myself.
♪ ...Past his prime ♪
♪ Come on, kid ♪
♪ you and I ♪
♪♪♪
Oh, god! Oh, god! Oh, god!
Oh, god.
Please live.
Please... don't die.
Please.
Uh, patient 135
suffered
from compulsive behavior
secondary to
borderline personality disorder.
I saw her for three years,
during which time she went
from jobless, promiscuous,
and sleeping
on her mother's sofa
to being gainfully employed,
abstinent from
her sexual compulsions,
and in a seemingly steady
relationship for about a year.
Um...
I-I don't know
where she stands right now
because we had to
abruptly end treatment.
Okay, uh, patient number--
Violet, I have enough.
You do?
Yeah, I-I have
a veritable mountain here.
A bad attorney could make a case
for your reinstatement,
and I'm not a bad attorney.
Are you sure?
Yeah, between
the procedural mistakes
the board investigator made,
the documented burden suffered
by your abandoned patients,
yeah, I'm sure I have enough.
I'm also sure the Sushi place
down the street
has the best spicy tuna
you've ever tasted.
Can I buy you dinner?
I'm married.
Dr. Barksdale.
I haven't heard
from Dr. Shepherd.
I have to get in now
if I want to save her sight.
Listen to me,
you save her life first
and her vision second.
And I want you to take
deep breaths
and pretend to yourself
that you're confident.
Pretend to yourself that you're
a hell of a lot more confident
than you're showing me
right now.
Yes, ma'am.
You can do this.
You trained for this.
Yes, ma'am.
Thank you.
Go.
I'm sorry.
Charlotte, will you let me
check you out now?
No.
I wasn't in the accident.
It's not my blood.
It's her blood.
Charlotte,
you're in shock.
It's not my blood.
It--it's her blood.
She wasn't wearing
a seat belt.
She was driving recklessly.
You did everything you could.
It's my blood.
It's her blood.
What's he doing?
He's pouting.
Behind closed doors.
I gave him 15 minutes
to pout,
which is almost up.
What's he upset about?
He's upset
about a "b" plus?
He likes to get
straight a's.
Ah.
I liked to get
straight a's, too.
Well, then that's definitely
something he gets from you.
So, uh, what happens
after 15 minutes?
I, uh, force feed him ice cream,
tickle him till he laughs.
Seriously?
He gets 20 minutes if he's
upset about something real,
but, yeah, a "b" plus?
15 minutes,
then forced fun.
Time's up, Mason!
And your father's here
to see you.
Hey.
Did she show you
my test?
She did.
So you think I'm stupid?
No.
You know what I think
is stupid?
Long division.
In all my years as a doctor,
I never not had
a calculator in my pocket
whenever I had to do
long division.
Wow. Look at that.
A smile without
even any tickling?
No tickling, mom.
None?
Not even a little bit?
Ah, you heard the man.
No tickling.
No tickling!
Stop it!
Oh, my goodness.
Oh, my gosh.
Oh, no "b" pluses either.
No tickling.
Put me down.
♪♪♪
Hey.
♪ and you're leaving ♪
How you feeling?
Did you choose yet?
You know, you can tell me,
'cause...
I'm sorry about this morning.
There's
absolutely nothing wrong
with being a geologist
or a musician.
Hey.
What's wrong?
I did this to myself.
What?
♪ Where you are ♪
Put myself
in a position where...
I'm trying to pick
a total stranger
to impregnate me and...
I'm a cheater.
Oh.
I cheated on Derek.
I did this myself.
Shh.
♪ I remember ♪
Addison, look at me.
Look at me.
Now I want you to tell me
what you think of me.
What?
Tell me
what you think of me.
Like, uh, describe my traits.
Just... humor me.
Okay.
Go.
You...
You're kind.
Really, you're really,
so kind.
And you're generous.
I mean, you'd do anything
for anyone.
And you're...
You're loyal.
I feel like
if you and I lost touch,
I could call you from a cave
in 20 years,
and you'd...
If I needed some help,
you'd find a way
to come get me.
What are you doing in a cave
in 20 years?
Did you become a terrorist?
You're funny, too.
And you're...
You're warm
and you're calm.
You know,
when everyone else is...
Frantic and scared
and... irrational,
you're calm.
You're centered.
And you're smart and wise,
which are not
both the same thing,
and not many people
have both, but you do.
You're...
You're just...
You're just good, Sam.
♪ Where you are ♪
Thank you.
And at the risk of
sounding terribly arrogant,
I think you're right.
I think I am a lot
of those things.
But, uh...
I also kissed my ex-wife...
When you were away
at your mother's funeral.
♪ Come back down ♪
Yeah.
It's a wretched thing to do.
It's not good,
it's not kind...
It's not loyal.
So...
I'm that, too.
Everybody's not just
one thing, Addison.
Not everybody's just
all good or all bad,
you know,
both light and dark...
Together.
♪ Blew right over ♪
And you're no exception.
♪♪♪
You are beautiful
and smart, sexy.
You're kind and warm
and unbelievably loving.
And you cheated.
That doesn't mean
that you should be punished
or that you should
punish yourself.
It just...
Means you're normal,
like everybody else.
♪ Where you are ♪
It means you're...
Imperfect...
Like me.
♪ ...are ♪
So...
♪♪♪
I think that you should go...
With the musician.
♪ Where you are ♪
Because we all could use
a little more music
in our lives.
Mm.
I want more.
Do you have anymore?
I'm out.
It sucks.
Ah, did I forget to mention
that I'm a doctor?
There is
an all-night pharmacy
right around the corner.
Holy crap.
I think I'm in love.
Dr. Freedman,
what are you doing here?
I just came to see
your mom and dad, Ollie.
Are they around?
Dr. Freedman.
Hi.
What's wrong?
You know what, sweetie?
Just go to your room.
I'll be right there.
It's okay.
Uh...
It's child abuse.
Not just giving him
the drugs,
which is...
You know, I should've called
child protective services--
you what?
I said I should've.
I didn't,
because the hell Ollie
could suffer in that system
is worse than the hell he's
already suffering here.
But...
Dr. Freedman--
it is child abuse,
the amount of pressure
you put on him.
It's child abuse that he's
afraid to bring home a "b"
in the third grade
because you're convinced
it's gonna keep him
out of the Ivy leagues, that--
Dr. Freedman,
are you a parent?
Do you have any idea what kind
of pressure these kids--
I-I am.
I am a parent.
And I feel...
I look at my son,
and I want to right in advance
every wrong
that could ever come down
and fall on him
in his entire life.
And I can imagine that that's
what you think you're doing,
because I believe
that you love your son.
But you know what?
People that hit their kids,
they love them, too.
And they think
that what they're doing
is for their kid's
best interest.
You're making him
afraid to fail.
An 8 year old can't be
I mean, 'cause, you know,
life is...
Full of failure.
It's how we learn.
And all Ollie is learning
is that the way he is
is not enough
to live up to your standards.
That's...
That's wrong.
It's abuse.
So here's what's gonna happen.
You're gonna bring Ollie in
to see me every month
for a checkup
and a blood test,
because I can't control
what kind of crap
you pump into his mind,
but if I catch you pumping
any more crap into his body,
I'm gonna skip
child protective services,
and I'm just gonna call
the damn police.
Do we understand
each other?
We do.
All right.
Uh...
I will see
you and Ollie in a month.
Amelia!
Go away, Charlotte.
You're taking drugs.
You're taking pills.
That's why
you're blowing clean.
This is harassment.
If you don't watch out, I am
gonna hit you with a lawsuit
and a restraining order.
Your patient
Kelly garrity,
she nearly went blind today.
What?
Her tumor started bleeding.
Frankly, we're lucky
she's alive,
'cause the resident
who had to do your surgery
sure as hell
coulda killed her.
All because
you went home sick.
I am sick.
- You don't look sick, Amelia.
- You look high.
Excuse me.
You want to sue me?
That's fine. Sue me.
But you won't step one foot
into my hospital
until you get some help,
'cause I'm not gonna stand back
and watch while you--
you know what?
Save your speech, Charlotte.
It's cool. I quit.
♪ mm ♪
♪ Do, do, do, do, do, do ♪
Hey.
Is he asleep already?
Yeah. He went down early.
Oh.
So I was with my lawyer
all day today,
and he says
there's a good chance
I'll be back at work soon.
And, uh, then I went to
the practice, looking for you.
I was here.
♪ I don't know how you
endure the pain ♪
♪ if you feel... ♪
I, uh...
I know you're having trouble.
And I think you're
having trouble trusting me,
and I think some of that
is maternal projection...
But part of is that you think
I'm gonna--
oh, my god.
No, no, hear me out.
No! No, Violet.
Hear me out. Hear me out.
I am so unbelievably sick
and tired of hearing you out.
I am sick of being processed
and psychoanalyzed
and being told
that I'm the only one
that has a problem.
That is not what I'm saying--
and I am so sick
of being lectured by you
that if I never
hear you out again
as long as I live--
Pete, you d--
no, I hate this.
I hate this!
♪ What I knew then ♪
♪ if I hadn't forgotten ♪
♪ what we meant ♪
How was your day?
Oh, it started out great,
ended...
It ended
on a pretty sad note.
Mm. Mine, too.
It sucks.
Yeah.
♪ If I hadn't forgotten ♪
I'm grateful that I have you
to come home to.
♪ Oh, oh, oh ♪
I'm grateful.
God, I am so grateful.
♪ Tempted by the thrill
of something new ♪
That's my egg.
That is your egg.
Oh, it's pretty.
All right, now...
Look over here.
The musician.
Wow.
His guys can swim, huh?
Okay, now...
Watch this.
Are you putting it
in the needle?
Yeah.
♪ If I'd done... ♪
Let's bring your egg
back over.
♪ To make things right ♪
Okay, watch this.
♪ I'd know love ♪
♪ before I lost it ♪
♪ if hadn't... ♪
Here we go.
♪ Forgotten ♪
It's in.
That's it.
Well, that's it for now.
Now we wait,
let it grow for three days,
then we--
then we implant them.
♪ Oh ♪
You're happy, aren't you?
I am...
Wow.
Yeah.
I'm happy.
Good.
I'm happy, too.
♪ Oh, what I knew then ♪
♪ yeah, yeah ♪
♪ if I knew now ♪
Sam cheated on me.
Okay. You look...
Are you happy about that?
No, no,
not happy, just...
Free.
You broke up?
No, no, it's just...
Okay, Sam did
this terrible thing,
but I still love him.
I still think
he deserves happiness.
I don't think
he's an awful person.
He's a good person
who made a mistake.
And I don't think
he deserves to be punished.
My god, he probably
punished himself plenty.
And you were right...
The other day,
about the song.
It wasn't just a song
in my head.
I was still punishing myself.
And that song...
It's not in my head anymore.
♪ Mm ♪