Stop!
- I need help.
- Maggie?
Right now. She's
lost a lot of blood.
We're going to trauma 1.
Pulse ox is dropping. Damn it.
Come on, Ms. Goodwin.
You saved my life.
I want you to promise
me that you'll
tear up your resignation.
Gaffney needs you, Dean.
After I got sober,
it took my family
a while to trust me again.
But they did, except
my sister, Lizzie.
Hey, I know you really
don't want to talk to me,
but love you.
Your spleen has been lacerated.
I can't, in good
conscience, release you
back into police custody.
Thank you.
Who wants to be a doctor
like his Uncle Rip?
He's a natural.
Yeah.
Who would have thought
he'd like babies so much?
I don't like babies.
Just this one. Just you.
- Dr. Stano.
- Dr. Ripley. Can we chat?
Yeah.
Your friend's injuries
seem to be healing up.
Yeah. Yeah.
He's giving me
hell all the time,
which is usually a good sign.
Yeah, well, unfortunately,
it also presents a problem.
If the injuries he sustained
from the fight are healed,
we have to discharge him.
You're going to send
him back to jail?
Tomorrow.
Tomorrow?
Sorry, that's just...
I understand his situation,
but I can't hold him any longer.
I'm sorry.
There's got to be
something we can do.
Hey, Sully had a splenic
lac when he came in, right?
Yeah.
OK, well, technically,
whoever was
the ED surgeon when
he was admitted
is still a consult
on Sully's care team.
Which means they'd
have a say in his care.
If you can convince them
to have a different opinion
than Stano's, then
they can mandate
Sully stay in the hospital.
Yeah. Yeah, you're right.
Hey, can I take a look at that?
Thanks.
Lenox.
What is that?
It's Goodwin's get
well card. You sign?
Oh, thank you.
How about you, Mags?
I bought the card, Doris.
Really? You sure?
Because I've been
telling people I did.
Yeah, I heard her.
She sounded pretty confident.
- Hey.
So listen, about dinner tonight,
thought we'd go someplace
special, Le Manchot Ivre.
Oh, that's pretty fancy.
OK, true.
But I thought we could
reenact our first date.
I'll even spill
wine on my shirt.
Mispronounce coq au vin.
Hmm?
Sounds good.
Great.
Incoming!
What do we got?
- No.
- Sloan Hunter,
experiencing upper back pain.
- Lucas...
- BP 130 over 80.
- No, no.
- O2 is good.
She called 911 for back pain?
Yep.
You are only saying
that because you are
lousy at your job.
The thing is, her on-call
doctor is in the Maldives.
And Sloan doesn't
like to wait in line.
Plus dividends.
And that's not even
including dividends.
So, Ms. Hunter, could you
describe your pain for us?
Lucas, I swear to God, if you
get your group to divest...
All right, Ms. Hunter,
we need you to listen...
I'm going to come to
your house personally,
and I'm going to
give you an enema...
All right, she'll call you back.
All right, let's try this again.
So where exactly are you
experiencing discomfort?
I have back pain.
It started this morning,
and it's only getting worse,
which is why I'm here
for you to give me drugs
so that I can feel better.
Is that enough info?
Well, it's not really the
way things work around here.
When you come in with
pain, we try to figure out
what's causing it.
CAT scan, 1,500
milligrams of Robaxin.
Fine.
When can I have my phone back?
When I leave the room.
Dr. Lenox, hey, do
you have a minute?
Ripley, good. Come with me.
We have twins in the
ambo bay, and one of them
is having trouble breathing.
Why are they in the ambo bay?
All right, what have we got?
Powell and Elijah Hughes, 34.
Elijah had difficulty breathing.
He said it felt like
someone was sitting on him.
They were able to get
into the ambulance.
- But on the way here...
- Elijah collapsed.
He can't stand.
And we don't have
a gurney big enough
to get them inside the hospital.
Scissors.
Average run-of-the-mill case.
Transpo's working on a gurney.
- Vitals?
- For which one?
Why don't we start with
the one who can't breathe?
BP 85 over 43, O2 87%.
This ever happen before?
No, but Elijah has
cancer, angiosarcoma.
We're supposed to have surgery
here in three weeks at Gaffney.
There's no breath sounds
in the bottom half
of the right lung.
We have a large
pleural effusion.
Run and get 40
milligrams of Lasix.
- What's that mean?
- Fluid in the chest.
Do you guys share lungs?
No. Two sets of everything.
It's just our hearts
that are fused.
It's worse.
Can't breathe.
Elijah, look at me. It's OK.
Don't panic.
They're going to fix you.
I'm always looking
at you. No choice.
Look, no more jokes, all right?
Save your energy.
I'll have to put
in a chest tube.
We don't have a kit,
only an OB pack.
That'll work.
We have to relieve
the pressure now.
We'll do a finger thoracostomy.
They're joined at the chest.
How do we even
know where to cut?
Figure it out.
We get it wrong, we puncture
a lung or hit the heart.
We can't risk waiting.
His respiratory system
is going to collapse.
We need a scalpel.
We'll do this together.
I'll listen.
You cut.
OK.
Now move the blade
a little higher.
Remember fourth
intercostal space.
OK, a little over.
Over again.
Hurry, please. He's choking.
You have to do something.
OK, stay above the rib.
- Please.
- There. Go.
Any chance you can
turn that way a little?
I guess I could try to...
No, you don't need to move.
You just almost died.
I think I had a
few more minutes.
Sorry, did you call Dr. Hayes?
Dr. Hayes?
You know him?
By reputation.
Yeah, he's kind of a rock star.
Well, he's the one
sawing us apart.
Wait, he's separating you two?
It's the only way to be able
to access Elijah's tumor.
X-ray.
Well, how do we look?
Let us touch base
with Dr. Hayes.
He's much more familiar
with your case.
And we'll talk again.
- Fresh from Taipei.
- Yes!
Did your grandma send these
for the Lunar New Year?
Let me get one.
Oh, I dream about
these every year.
- Thank you.
- Mags?
No, thanks.
- OK.
- Turning down free sweets?
I feel like I don't
even know you.
She got to save her
appetite for Le Manchot Ivre
tonight, right?
Hey, I just remembered
I have to run some
blood cultures over to the lab.
She seems a little
off today, right?
Hmm?
Maybe, but the nurses
have been working hard.
Might just be tired.
Yeah.
Hey, Han.
Hi.
What are you doing here?
- Is everything OK?
- Oh, yeah.
No, I'm good. I'm fine.
I... I came here to see you.
Hey, I'm Hannah's
sister, Lizzie.
- Oh.
- Hi. John.
Hey.
Wait, are... are
you the boyfriend?
- Oh, no.
- Oh, no, no.
- No.
- No, no.
- Just like regular friends.
- No.
- Got it.
- Yeah.
OK.
- Well, it's nice to meet you.
- You too.
OK. Yeah. I'll see you.
- Mm-hmm.
- OK.
I got your message, and I
was hoping we could talk.
Yeah, of course.
You know, I just need to
finish up with a patient,
and we can have
coffee in the café.
Sure. OK. Yeah.
I'll grab us a spot.
OK.
Well, he said he'd be down
momentarily, so... yeah.
You OK?
You seem nervous.
Oh, no.
No.
Just suddenly very
aware of my hands.
Right.
Well, while we have a
moment, I wanted to...
Oh, Dr. Hayes.
I'm Dr. Lenox.
This is Dr. Ripley.
Nice to meet you.
I heard you had a fun
morning with my favorite duo.
Which room are they in?
Actually, before we go in, we
wanted to discuss something.
We did an X-ray
and an updated CT.
The sarcoma has
grown exponentially.
The tumor has invaded
the vena cava and spine.
Caused the pleural
effusion in his right lung.
It's still a local invasion now,
but if it keeps
growing at this rate,
it'll be to the heart
in a matter of days,
and they'll be dead.
You'll need to move
up the surgery.
To when?
To now.
Are you serious?
Do you have any idea the
scope of this procedure?
We've been planning it
for nearly six months.
So then you should be prepared.
We'd need to gather
the team immediately.
I'm not even sure who's
in town right now.
I took the liberty
of making a few calls
while we were waiting
for you to arrive.
Most people are able to
make themselves available.
What did you say
your name was again?
Dr. Lenox.
And do you have a first name?
Caitlin.
OK, then, let's
update the twins.
And then we'll
gather the troops.
- Dr. Archer?
- That's me.
Sloan was asking, and I
know this is going to sound
absurdly privileged and
insane, if you have any kind of
protein wrap or... charcuterie.
Not since we changed chefs.
I know, dumb question,
but had to ask so I don't
get freaking
murdered in my sleep.
Mm. Tough boss, huh?
- Oh, she's a lunatic.
- Ah.
Well, then, you know, why stay?
That barracuda in there
has real influence, power.
I want that.
And if I hold my
nose for a few years,
I'll be on the path.
I mean, why should these
bastards get to make
all the important decisions?
I often ask that myself.
Speak of the devil.
Hello.
Sloan? Sloan?
Sloan? Sloan!
BP 68 over 38.
She's in V-tach.
Wait, what's going on?
I don't feel a pulse.
All right, get the crash cart.
What's happening? Is
she going to be OK?
Charge to 120.
Clear.
Still no pulse.
All right, get lidocaine 100.
Charge 200.
- Oh, my God.
- Clear.
She's back to sinus rhythm.
Blood pressure coming up.
What the hell was that?
You're saying once
they're separated,
you want to go in
through his side?
Yeah, to remove the tumor
and repair the spine.
If I go in through the
abdomen, I'm going in blind.
Well, the problem is the tumor
has invaded the vena cava.
If we go in through
the side for you,
we could cause catastrophic
bleeding that we can't control.
You ever seen this many
alphas in a room at once?
What if we prepare for bleeding
with endovascular access?
How do you mean?
Occlude the aorta to
staunch any acute bleeds.
Get vascular control
from the inside out.
And then repair the vessel.
And where have you
ever seen that work?
The Helmand River
Valley in Afghanistan.
We got pretty good at finding
ways to stop bleeding.
Creative.
But if we leave it too long,
we get distal ischemia
or thrombosis,
end up with heart
attack or stroke.
So we only use it
intermittently.
Take it down periodically
to allow blood flow.
Sam?
Yeah, that could work.
Look, we can troubleshoot
the procedure all we want,
but what about numbers?
We're short doctors.
What's your
specialty, Dr. Lenox?
General surgery.
But as I mentioned, I did
a fair amount of vascular
- when I was deployed.
- Great.
Would you be available to
scrub in this afternoon?
Absolutely.
There's one.
I'm sure we can find others.
Still two creams?
Thanks.
It's been a while, I guess.
Yeah.
So how are you?
Dad said you've been
temping at a law firm?
Oh, no, that...
that ended.
I'm back waitressing
now at Cozy Corner.
Where Matt and I used to
take hot pepper flakes
and crush them up
and put them...
And put them in the
salt shakers and then
watch people freak out when
they put it on their food.
- Yeah.
- Oh, my God, we were terrible.
You lost me a lot of tips.
You know, I'm really
glad you came by.
Me too.
I told him not to buy
illegal fireworks.
Luckily, it looks like you
jumped back just in time.
These look like second-degree
burns, so with proper care,
should heal up in
a couple weeks.
And the eyebrows?
They should grow back.
But I'm not going to lie, it
might be a tough few months.
My girlfriend's
going to kill me.
Look, I'll check back
with you guys in a few.
All right? Thanks.
- Hey, Maggie.
- Mm-hmm?
Let's get him dressed
with Xeroform, please.
Yeah.
I hate holidays with fireworks.
So your heart issues
and your back pain
both stem from an
underlying issue...
an aortic aneurysm
with a dissection.
And that means your
aorta is ballooning out
and tearing right
near your heart.
We'll need to get you in
for surgery to repair it.
But then she'll be OK?
Provided the surgery
is successful, yeah.
What does that even mean?
It means that while
it's the best option,
it's a serious procedure.
The aneurysm is affecting
the coronary arteries.
And that means that there's
a high risk of heart attack
in the operating room.
So you're saying I could
just die either way?
I'm not trying to
scare you, Ms. Hunter.
I just want to make
you aware of the risks
going into surgery.
OK.
Hand me my phone.
If you're telling me
that I might only have
a few hours left on this Earth,
then there are some people
that I would like to talk to.
Of course.
I'll leave you to it, then.
Good news.
We've coordinated
with your team,
and we can move up the surgery.
That's amazing.
To when?
We're still finalizing
some things,
but hopefully by this afternoon.
However, there are some
added complications.
The progression of the sarcoma
means we'll have to
resect the tissue
around Elijah's
spine and the vein
bringing blood to his heart.
Powell's chances of
survival are unchanged.
But Elijah's...
What... what are my chances?
I would say less than 50%.
Then we're not doing it.
Powell, I know you
don't think we should...
We're not doing a surgery
where the likeliest
outcome is you dying.
If the cancer is
untreated, it will spread.
It will kill you both.
So we'll do chemo or radiation.
I know that this is scary,
but we've been over this.
Angiosarcoma doesn't respond
to that kind of treatment.
It would take a miracle.
Well, that's just fine.
The fact that Elijah and
I are alive to begin with
is a miracle.
Right?
So we'll just bet on one more.
Well, what about you?
Are you... are you
seeing anybody?
No.
No, I was...
I was kind of seeing
this woman for a while,
but I broke it off because
she doesn't want kids,
and I really do.
Mm.
In fact, that's
actually something
I've been working on
for the last year or so,
doing IUI and then IVF.
Lizzie, that's amazing.
You're going to be the best mom.
Yeah, except it hasn't worked.
I was actually sort
of hoping that maybe
you could help me out
with some medical stuff.
Yeah, of course.
What do you need?
I need you to diagnose me with
polycystic ovary syndrome.
Wait, you... you have PCOS?
No, but... but my
insurance won't cover IVF.
And after the last
cycle, my savings are
just pretty much wiped out.
But PCOS patients apparently
get the same drugs.
So if... if you
diagnose me and then
- you write me the script...
- Lizzie...
Then I can afford another round.
And I really feel like
I know some things
that I did wrong before.
So I think that this
time, it'll take.
What you're asking for
is... is medical fraud.
Are you going to
lecture me about rules?
I'm not.
I'm sorry.
I don't want to... I don't
want to take us back there.
It's just... it's just,
you know how much I've
always wanted this.
And I want you to have this.
I do.
I can't jeopardize my career.
Sure, yeah, I get it.
It was a long shot.
Listen, I should get going.
No, Lizzie, there's...
I had something I
had to get to anyway,
but it was so nice to see you.
And I'm so glad things are
going so well for you, really.
Lizzie, that's...
So I may be completely
off base here,
but I feel like something
maybe is bothering you.
Why would you say that?
Well, I guess normally,
we have a certain witty
repartee between us, a
light banter, if you will,
which I've always kind
of considered our thing.
But today, you don't seem to
be enjoying it quite as much.
Well, maybe you
need better jokes.
See, now, that can't be it.
Come on. What's going on?
I'm sorry.
I just... it has
nothing to do with you.
It's just that, uh...
I'm breaking up
with Loren tonight.
Wait, you're breaking
up over dinner?
That's a terrible idea.
Why?
No, I... I want to
end on good terms.
And I want to give him a
chance to say what he needs to.
And we have to work together.
Mm-hmm.
I don't want it to be weird.
Oh, it's going to be weird...
for you, for him, for all of us,
no matter what he says.
All right, so skip the dinner.
Just get it done fast.
You know, I'm regretting
talking to you.
I'm just saying, all right,
it's like a Band-Aid.
- Mm.
- Get in. You break his heart.
Get out.
All right?
Frustrating, everyone
moves heaven and Earth
and then the patients
decline surgery.
Did you need something?
Yeah, actually, I've been
wanting to talk to you.
I was trying to
find a better time,
which this obviously isn't.
What is it?
I want to discuss
my friend Sully.
- Up on the seventh floor?
- Right.
Well, he's being
discharged tomorrow,
but I'm not sure I agree
with Dr. Stano's assessment.
I feel we could do
another CAT scan,
make sure he didn't
develop a splenic artery,
pseudo aneurysm.
Feels like a reach.
But you know that.
Your friend goes back to jail
if he gets discharged, right?
Look, he's like a brother to me.
And I can't just sit here
and watch him get ripped
away from his family again.
So if you could
just talk to Stano.
Sorry, the answer's no.
You're letting your emotions
cloud your judgment.
OK, I get emotion
is a vice for you.
So take emotion out of it.
Make it about standard of care.
Where do you think Sully's
going to get better treatment,
here or Cook County?
The care he receives in
jail isn't my purview.
I can't solve all
the world's problems.
I'm not asking you to.
Just this one.
Look, I'm just saying,
if you at least suggested
they run more tests,
it would pause things,
buy him a little more time.
Because there'd be no consensus.
Exactly.
If nobody agrees, they
can't discharge him.
We need to talk to
the twins again.
What?
Goodness.
Look at the time.
What is that?
It's a Patek Philippe Twenty-4.
- I just looked it up.
- It's diamonds?
- Yes.
- Looked it up.
Where... where did you get that?
Well, I went in to
check on that lady,
and she just gave it to me.
And I apologize.
I never should have said that.
Now, your son goes
to DePaul, right?
OK, that's it.
That's it.
Everybody out.
I need to speak to the patient.
You're supposed to
rest before surgery.
I am trying to tie up loose ends
before I go under the knife.
I might not have
enough time left.
And there are things
that I need to say.
To all of Chicago?
I know it may seem hectic.
But when my heart stopped,
I had an experience.
So you saw God and you
want to spread the word,
the pearly gates and such?
No.
I didn't see God.
But I did see where I was going.
And there was no white light.
Oh, you mean...
I'm going to hell when
I die, Dr. Archer.
Hell?
Unless I can buy it back
with whatever time I have left.
Sloan's asked me to reach
out to everyone she's wronged
to make amends.
Turns out, it's...
it's quite an extensive list.
Mind if we speak
with you a minute?
If you're coming to talk to us
about seeing me socially
outside of the hospital,
I accept.
Are we being discharged soon?
Not yet.
There's something we
need to find first...
a consensus.
Like with the other doctors?
No.
Between the two of you.
I think we were pretty clear.
I think you were pretty clear.
You were mostly quiet.
I don't understand
emotion very well.
So when I was a kid,
I would just say what
I knew to be true,
no matter the consequences.
And there was a price
to be paid for honesty.
My teachers hated it.
And other kids made fun of me.
And my parents,
you know, begged me
to keep my mouth shut.
But when I tried that, it
just made things worse,
because I was still ostracized.
And I just had this
pit in my stomach
of all the things
that I hadn't said.
Then I found medicine, this
world where speaking up
is essential, where
patients' lives depend on it.
And even if people
still said mean things,
I was fine, because I realized
that the price for honesty
is worth every penny
because you get to live
a life without regrets.
Elijah, this right now is
the most important decision
you will ever make.
And after today, you
can't take it back.
Don't you want a say in it?
Listen, I'm happy you found
your spirit animal or whatever.
But this is our life.
And we've made a decision.
So finish the papers
to discharge us...
- Powell...
- So we...
She's right.
We don't have a consensus.
What are you talking about?
You're opinionated,
and I go along with it
because you're
strong and selfless.
And I never know what to
say except to make a joke.
Elijah, we can't agree to this.
But...
I can't be the
reason that you die.
I can't just sit here beside you
knowing that I'm
slowly killing you.
We need to do the surgery.
It's just...
I don't know how to
live without you.
I know.
I'm awesome.
But you know I'm right.
OK.
What he said.
Excuse me.
Quite the crowd.
Have they started?
No, they're still setting up.
The red caps are Powell's
team, yellow are Elijah.
Hey, any luck with Lenox?
Trying to build up the
courage to tell Sully.
Hey, how was coffee with Lizzie?
Well, she wants me to
diagnose her with a disorder
she doesn't have so I can
prescribe her medication
she doesn't need so
she can get pregnant.
I say don't do it.
She doesn't talk to you
for, what, five years,
and then shows up
just to use you?
- Screw that.
- I don't know.
It's like, I can't be her doctor
and her sister at the same time.
So then don't.
What do you mean?
I mean don't.
Forget about being her doctor.
Just be the best
version of her sister.
And if that's not good
enough, then that's on her.
Ladies, gentlemen.
All right, I think we're ready.
What about you two?
Ready?
Well, I guess it'll be good
to finally get some privacy.
See you on the other side.
Yeah.
See you.
Hi.
OK, so the surgery
was a success.
She should make a full recovery.
And you'll be able to
see her in a few hours.
Oh, my God, I was so nervous.
I'm so glad, especially
after all the smack
I talked about her earlier.
- And then she was so nice.
- Mm.
I felt like the worst
person in the world.
Well, you're not.
And now you don't have to worry.
Hey, can I ask you something?
Yeah.
Do you think it matters
why people change?
Like if they're only doing
the right thing out of fear?
I... I think that if...
if you have a moment of clarity
and you see a better
version of your life,
don't ask too many questions.
Just run at it, and
don't look back.
Yep.
Hey, you got a second?
Mm-hmm.
Oh, I'll give you a minute.
I didn't realize
that you were...
It's nothing you
haven't seen before.
Going to get changed for dinner?
I was thinking that
maybe we could skip it.
OK.
You know, you're
amazing, um, obviously.
I mean, just going
back to the restaurant
where we had our first
date, and I appreciate
how thoughtful and
romantic you are.
I think we should break up too.
Wait, you want to break up?
No.
But I can tell you're
not feeling this.
You know, I told myself that
maybe it was stress
or something, but...
but it's been
evident for a while.
I'm not wrong, am I?
No, you're not wrong.
Yeah.
I really wanted it to
work, to be right and...
Wait, you're leaving?
You don't want to
talk about this?
I can't change how you feel.
It did have its moments, though.
I hope you find what
you're looking for, Mags.
You too.
They blacked out the Bulls game.
You think I can
call the station?
Do, like, a Make-A-Wish thing?
Get them to air it?
Don't love that look.
Guessing no luck buying
me some more time here.
Look, I was...
I was trying to talk to
a colleague, but that...
that didn't pan out.
But I have... I have a
call in with a lawyer.
And there's another
colleague I can...
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Slow down, slugger.
We knew this was coming.
And honestly, the fact
that I got any time at all,
I mean...
I got to hold my
kid, sit with Lynne.
You gave me that.
So stop feeling guilty.
And today isn't tomorrow, right?
So might as well enjoy it.
Yeah.
You know, Lynne's
coming by later
with something I've been
meaning to give you.
You should... you
should come up.
Yeah.
Sounds good.
Arterial cannulas in
on both, venous in.
Everything looks good.
Start bypass.
Let's get cross-clamps ready.
Amazing, isn't it?
Yeah, their hearts
beat in unison.
See that band of scar tissue?
It conducts electricity
between them.
Powell's heart acts as a
pacemaker for Elijah's.
It's hard to imagine being
that close to somebody.
Something to shoot for, though.
We're on bypass.
Ready to cross-clamp.
Arterial cross-clamp in.
Administer cardioplegia
and stop the heart.
What's happening?
Powell's pressures are steady.
The venous flow is decreased.
Venous pressure still dropping.
The sarcoma must be
invading the vena cava
more than we thought.
Flow still stable on Powell.
We need to recannulate
the venous line,
- go around the tumor.
- It'll take too much time.
And the risk of stroke
will be through the roof.
It doesn't matter.
If we don't do this now,
Elijah's not going to make it.
Scalpel.
So what's up?
So I thought about
what you said.
I can't diagnose you with
something you don't have.
But I wanted to give you this.
25 grand?
I can't accept it.
Yes... yes, you can.
You know, growing up
without Mom was...
I mean, it was
hard on all of us.
But secretly, I always
felt a little guilty
because it wasn't as hard on me.
Not because I didn't know
her, but because I had you.
You always took care of
me, made me feel safe.
It would be a tragedy if
you never got to be a mom.
So I will do everything
I can to support you,
because you taught me that
that's what sisters do.
Thank you.
Oh, my God.
Look at that.
What? What?
Why are you looking like that?
Did you not get all the cancer?
No, it's not that.
Powell.
Though the initial
separation was successful,
when he came off bypass,
your brother suffered
a massive stroke.
His brain swelled and herniated.
No, no.
We did everything we could,
but he lost all function.
Powell!
He's on life support now.
Elijah...
he's gone.
Sorry.
No.
Bring me to him.
I don't want to be alone.
I don't want to be.
Hey, you did the right thing.
If it weren't for you,
they'd both be dead.
I was thinking about
your friend Sully,
and you were right.
We... we should run more tests.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
A CT angio should get us
a bit more information.
And he'll just have to
stay in the hospital
a little longer.
Thank you.
OK, now you're just
making excuses.
Where is that cap table?
Sorry, I'm looking.
Ah, what is going on?
I was giving post-op
instructions, but...
I'm going to have
to call you back.
I'm not going to let
you end my call again.
I learned my lesson.
Oh, did you?
What happened to making amends?
I figured you'd just given
me a new lease on life.
I have 40 years to atone.
But my shareholders'
meeting is next week.
We got to keep our eye
on the prize, right, Meg?
Yeah.
All right, then, so
regarding your recovery,
there's a few important
rules for the first few days.
No lifting, no pushing or
pulling over 10 pounds.
Hey.
Meg.
Are you writing this down?
- Meg?
- Yeah.
I... I mean, no,
actually, no, I'm not.
What?
Sorry, it's... just I...
I quit.
You almost died today.
And now you're back to being
the same horrible person.
And that's not even
why I'm quitting.
I'm quitting because
out of everyone
you tried to buy back
today, I was the only one
in the waiting room.
Yeah, for all your money and
your power and influence,
no one would have cared if you
died on that operating table.
And I thought I
wanted what you have,
but you have nothing.
I think I found a
moment of clarity.
I think you might need
to write this down.
It's freezing up here.
It'll be worth it.
Just saying it's supposed
to start, like, soon, right?
Hey.
What are you doing up here?
Don't you have a
dinner to go to?
I ripped off the Band-Aid.
Ah, that's tough.
Sorry.
Hey, all right.
Told you it'd be worth it.
I thought you hated any
holiday that had fireworks.
Yeah, well, I guess I'm
turning over a new leaf.
Kind of perfect
with the New Year.
Yeah.
New Year, new you.
Mm.
Hey, I got good news.
I think we bought...
I wasn't here.
They said he had
a... a blood clot,
and... and it happened so
fast, they couldn't save him.
- Hey.
- And I wasn't here.
- I wasn't here.
Yeah. It's OK.
I wasn't here.
It's OK.