Has been bringing some snow
to the southern plains
and rain to Texas,
and it's heading
toward the northeast.
You see the trough here.
That's allowing some cold
air to come down tonight.
And then the snow, the
moisture intermingling with snows
in the western part of Kansas.
But this low that's moving
toward the northeast
is gonna pull up some
Gulf of Mexico moisture...
Dad?
Hey, Mark. You're up early.
Might snow later.
Fifty percent chance.
Dad, it's a little loud.
You ought to have a door
to that bedroom of yours.
No, I don't want a door.
I can build you one.
Dad, I don't want a door.
Can you turn that thing down?
Hello?
Yeah. I know... I'm sorry.
My... My dad's visiting.
Yeah. No. Won't happen again.
Who the hell's
calling at this hour?
My neighbor. You woke her too.
It's no wonder. The walls in
this building are paper-thin.
By the way, we're out of coffee.
So I see.
There was only a
little dibble-dabble left.
Barely able to get a
cup out of it myself.
Well, I think I'll just get
dressed and go to work.
This early?
Yeah. This early.
I like that Weather Channel.
There's no sense in trying
to watch it in San Diego.
"Clear and sunny,
clear and sunny."
"Chance of a
cloud. Mostly sunny."
Hey, Chuny.
Carol, welcome back!
Thanks. How are the twins?
Oh, they're doing great. I
don't know how I'm gonna do.
This is my first whole
day without them.
Oh. Seems pretty quiet, though.
Actually, uh, no.
Oh, great. Back to work.
See you in a minute.
I'm right behind you.
They'll fix you up.
Vito Camporsero, 29, acrobat.
Rehearsing on the trapeze.
He slipped off the platform.
How far did he fall?
About five feet,
but he was up 50.
Yeah, but he caught
his armpit on the cable.
That's what saved
him. It's not so bad.
Carol, welcome back. Thanks.
Uh, deep laceration
to the left axilla,
three-liter blood
loss. BP's 60 palp.
Okay, ready, steady, lift.
Get four units of O-neg.
Hi, I'm Mark, you
must be the new nurse?
Hey, Mark. It's good to be back.
I need a pulse ox probe.
A gram of Ancef.
Got any water here? Does
anybody know anything about this?
No. I just got on.
All right, I'm gonna
go check it out.
Luka, are you all
right? All set, thanks.
Pressure is crashing.
Carol, prep for a subclavian.
Two liters on the rapid infuser.
Are you hurt?
Uh, no, it's Vito's blood.
Dominic carried
him down the ladder.
Pulse is 124.
Carol, the Betadine.
Oh, yeah. I got it.
It's okay if you're
a little rusty.
I'm fine, thank you.
I didn't know the
circus was in town.
Laceration of
the axillary artery.
I'm Dr. Romano from Surgery.
Hello.
Doctor, please help my brother.
Check the crits first. I
wasn't gone that long.
Okay. Absent wrist pulses.
Let's have a look.
Whoa!
Easy, easy!
You're hurting him!
Give him morphine!
His pressure is too low.
Stop it, please.
Almost done. Hold on.
Doctor, please
step back a little bit!
Kovac, get these
guys out of here!
Okay. Okay... Stop, please.
Kovac... Hey!
Hey, what do you
think you're doing?
Let go of me!
Hey, call Security!
What do you think you're
doing? Get your hands off me!
Put at least four
liters at every sink.
What's going on? Oh,
a water main broke.
They're gonna fix it,
but it could be a while.
You're not on till tonight.
I know. Valerie Page
called me at home.
The girl you ordered
the L-VAD for?
Yeah, they found a match.
She's on her way in
for a heart transplant.
That is great.
Carter, listen they're
getting stacked up at Chairs.
I'm sorry, I'm on
the code team today
and I just got paged
for a respiratory arrest
in the cafeteria that
was a false alarm.
Okay, what do we got?
Carter, your amoebic dysentery
patient just used the toilet.
So? No water? We can't flush.
Oh!
Well, sorry. I got another case.
Put the "Out of Order" sign
on the door. Call Housekeeping.
Amira, can you see if we can
get a couple of portable toilets
for the ambulance bay and
maybe some air freshener?
You have a lot of
calamities at this circus, huh?
No. No, not usually.
But, uh, Peng... She is afraid
that she won't be
able to perform tonight.
No, no. The
laceration is not bad.
No, tell her she'll be fine.
Thank you.
How did this happen?
Uh, one of the
platform, she broke.
A piece of wood fell
right on top of her.
Yes, but if the
wood fell from above,
how did it, uh, hit
the bottom of her foot?
Like this. You see?
Wow!
You know what? I think I'll
go see that circus of yours.
There's one of them.
Get him out of here.
My mother's had
Parkinson's almost 15 years.
Hm, has her condition
recently changed?
Well, in the past
couple of days,
she's been so weak that
she can't use her walker.
I'm worried she had a stroke.
Hm.
Oh... Oh, no, no,
no, let us help.
No, I don't mind.
I do it every day.
Uh-huh.
Uh, good for my
health. Right, Mom?
To tell you the truth,
I... I'm a burden.
Louise has to lift me
onto the toilet and...
And s-sponge bathe me.
Oh, come on, Mom. Stop it.
She gets dizzy when she sits up.
Could it be her heart?
Well, we'll check.
Maybe... Maybe the
Parkinson's is... Is getting worse?
Well, I don't feel worse.
Well, you might not, Mrs. Duffy,
but I'm gonna examine
you, run some tests,
and find out what's going on.
You okay?
Oh, yeah. Fine.
Okay...
Carol, we got an IV
cefotaxime order for Exam Two.
I'll get to it when I can.
It's been in the
rack for an hour.
I just checked the rack.
Was it in the wrong slot?
Doesn't matter.
Lady's got pneumonia.
And this gentleman
has chest pain.
I can only do one
thing at a time.
Mark, I'm moving
as fast as I can.
I know you are, Carol. I
know it's your first day back
and I know you're
gonna take a little while
to get back into the flow.
Well, I don't think any of
my patients have suffered
from my being a little
rusty, as Dr. Kovac puts it.
I didn't mean to imply
that... Just give me the chart.
Why wasn't I paged
for the water crisis?
I mean, we have a comprehensive
plan for internal disasters.
I mean, I'm on the committee
that developed the protocol.
Well, there isn't
a crisis, Kerry.
We got two portable
toilets coming in.
We have plenty of bottled
water. Everything's under control.
Yes, except that the O.R.
can't sterilize the instruments.
They've canceled all surgery
and I've closed us to Trauma.
Well, that sounds
like a good idea.
If the patients can't
quite make it outside
or they don't want to
freeze their butts off,
we can use water from
the physical therapy pool.
A two-gallon dump
gives you a solid flush.
Ooh.
Careful, Kerry. Thanks
for the information, though.
Sure. That's good to know.
Hi! Hi.
Oh, God, I was just about
to have some pancakes
when my pager went off.
I about jumped out of my seat.
They said I had
one hour to get here.
I think this is news worth
missing breakfast for.
I'm so glad you called me.
I packed so fast I
forgot my slippers.
We'll get you a new pair
to go with your new heart!
Keeping up, Carol?
Oh, God.
Have you seen the old
records on my patient?
Yeah, the file
room's bringing them.
Did you fax his EKG
to his PMD? Yes.
Well, he said he'd call
me after he got them.
Well, maybe he's busy.
Ah, here's the
problem. Paper jam.
Fax it again, will you, Carol?
Anyone seen the x-rays
on that ankle in Exam Four?
Hm! Don't hold your breath.
Radiology can't process
the film without water.
Don't know how
long it's gonna be.
This water shortage keeps up,
some of us might
get out of here in time
to go grab something to eat.
Sounds like fun.
Yeah?
Have a good time.
Michael Mueller, 28. Had
a seizure while driving.
Crashed into a wall.
His air bags deployed.
He's post-ictal, good
BP, tachy at 120.
We were on our way
to a hockey practice
and he just started to shake.
Scared the crap out of me.
Curt Obarr, front
seat passenger.
He was up and walking
with a forehead lac.
Curt, you know if Michael's
had seizures before?
Not that I know of.
Okay, everybody, nice
and easy. On my count.
One, two, three.
Get a trauma panel.
C-spine, chest, and head CT.
They can't develop x-rays.
All right. Let's
get the fluoroscan.
Sinus tach, 130.
BP's 124 over 78.
Pupils are equal. Do you know if
he's had any medical problems?
Uh, he uses one of
those asthma inhalers.
Oh, old bruises. You guys
play pretty rough, huh?
He got checked
pretty bad last week.
Did he hit his head?
I don't think so.
Temp's normal, 98.8.
Whoa! Whoa! Let's roll him!
Add a theophylline level.
What's that?
Asthma medication. You
take too much, this can happen.
Louise? Hey.
Everything looks okay.
Head CT, EKG and the blood
tests are all essentially normal.
Then why can't she walk?
Hm, well, most likely
it's the Parkinson's.
But her neurologist can adjust
her medication as an outpatient.
C-could we talk outside?
Oh, yeah, sure. Of course.
Then you're, uh, not
going to admit her?
Not when there's no reason to.
Look, please, I love my mother
but I can't take her
home and care for her
when she can't walk.
I mean, I'm just too exhausted.
Well, maybe you
need a home aide.
But I can't afford a home aide.
I mean, she needs to be in
the hospital for a few days
where she can adjust her meds
and... And get a little stronger.
Well, unfortunately, we
can't admit her for that.
I'm... I'm asking you, please.
I'm... I'm ju... I'm
just so tired right now.
It's been such a
difficult few weeks.
If... If... If she could just
stay for a couple of days...
Well, I... I wish I could
help you, but unfortunately
the hospital doesn't allow
for that kind of admission.
I'm really sorry.
Yeah. Yeah.
Okay, thanks.
These are...
"Ridiculous" would be one word.
That would be one word. Yes.
Best the gift shop had to
offer. Then I'll take them.
Thank you. You're welcome.
I got a hold of your mom
and she is on her way here.
And your dad is...
Not around. Never has been.
I know the story.
Hello. Hi.
Dr. Weaver. Valerie,
how are you doing?
Oh, the proverbial
"couldn't be better."
Good. Lucy, do
you have a minute?
Sure. Excuse us.
We'll be right back.
Um, I've looked over the
chart. And Valerie has a fever.
Her temperature is 100.9.
That's pretty low-grade.
That could just be a cold.
No, she needs to go on high-dose
immunosuppressive agents
so she won't reject
the new heart.
With a weakened immune
system, even a cold could be fatal.
What are you saying?
We need to notify the
transplant coordinator.
We may have to
decline the heart.
Uh, is there anything we can do?
It'll be their decision,
but in all likelihood,
I think that's what's
gonna happen.
I can't believe this.
She was so close.
Want me to tell her?
No. No, I'll tell her.
Shooting.
Yeah, definitely got a
fracture on your hand
just below the pinky.
You can move your hand
back. It's gonna need a cast.
I guess I'm lucky. It
could've been worse.
How's Curt?
Oh, he's fine.
His forehead's being
sutured up, and, uh...
Actually, I'm... I'm a
little concerned about you.
I feel fine.
You know, your
seizure was caused
by an overdose of theophyllin.
An overdose.
Were you trying
to, uh, hurt yourself?
No, I just...
You know, my asthma flares
up whenever I'm stressed out.
So I... I took a
few extra pills.
Stressed at work? At home?
I'm a... A landscaper. You
know, January's a tough time.
Work stops, the
bills don't, that's all.
Why the third degree?
Under the circumstances, I, uh...
I have to ask about depression.
Trust me, if I wanted to kill
myself, I'd find a better way.
All fixed up.
They figure out what was wrong?
Yeah. I... I took too
much asthma medicine.
Busted up my hand.
We're gonna have to find
somebody new to play left wing.
He gonna be okay?
Yeah. Should be.
Hey, how's the car?
It's totaled. Don't
worry, you're insured.
Is it all right to, uh, use
one of these things in here?
Sure.
I'll just get a rental.
When was the last
time you passed gas?
About an hour ago.
No fever or vomiting.
Well, Peter, I agree
with your assessment.
Mr. Hoyt... you
are full of stool.
Dr. Benton will see
that you get an enema.
Excuse me, Doctor...
Not now, we're busy.
Unless somebody's
dying, come back later.
Okay, Peter, who's next?
Splenectomy from
last week. Mr. Jabour.
Valerie Page is here
for a heart transplant.
Old news. The transplant
service already called me.
I stay informed. Then
you know she has a fever.
I wasn't aware of that. Did you
call the transplant coordinator?
Not yet. Peter,
call the coordinator.
Let her know we're
gonna pass on that heart.
You're not even
going to examine her?
What's the point? Can't
operate if there's a fever.
But her white count, chest
x-ray and urine are all normal.
Gold star for effort,
but in my book,
a fever still spells infection.
You're right, and I think it's
an infection of her L-VAD.
I did research on Medline,
and I found articles from
Pittsburgh and Stanford.
The treatment
is give antibiotics,
remove the device,
then give the new heart.
Peter, go work her up.
I'll talk to the
transplant service.
Miss Knight, you are like
a crazed Energizer
Bunny on this one.
You just keep going
and going and going...
Thank you. And
going and going...
Carol, we're out of I
and D kits in Exam Two.
I'll check the suture room.
No, I... I don't need one. I
just wanted to let you know.
Oh, I'm... I'm sorry,
Kerry. Big trauma came in.
I haven't been able to
check all my rooms yet.
Hey, no, I'm not
criticizing you.
I'll get to it as soon as I can.
It must be strange coming
back after being off for six weeks.
Not really.
I mean, if you need
to take an extra break...
Why would I need a break?
You might not be
getting enough sleep.
Oh, I'm getting plenty
of sleep. Thanks, Kerry.
Dr. Malucci, is there a problem?
Uh, yeah, chief. There is.
Check this out.
Dolison? Mm-hm.
Her husband's been popping
these puppies for three weeks.
Now he's vomiting blood.
What is this medication?
They're from Mexico.
Combo painkiller and steroid.
Anyone can buy
them. Unbelievable.
Okay, be sure ICU gets
him on a steroid taper.
Cleo. Yeah?
All right, so when I
said I was, uh, you know,
trying to get out of here early
and going to grab a bite to eat.
Yeah, I wish I
could get out early.
Mm-hm. So, what
if we made it later?
I never know when I can get out.
Yeah. Don't wait on me.
Uh-huh.
Carol?
You all right?
Oh, I'm fine.
You don't look fine.
No, really. I am really fine.
First day back must be tough.
Why don't you just leave?
No. I'm just gonna sit here
and I'm gonna have a good cry.
And then I'm gonna feel better.
It's what I do at home.
You see? I am...
I'm better already.
Thanks, Elizabeth.
Carol, are you okay?
Oh, I'm fine.
It's her first day back
She's a little overwhelmed.
I don't blame her.
Between the diapers
and the dishes...
The feedings. Laundry.
Then come for a 12-hour shift.
I don't know how she'll do it?
Staying focused with patients.
All she wants to think
about are her babies.
Carol, if there's
anything we can do...
Okay.
I'm really confused.
You were all set to
cancel the transplant,
and now you say I
can have the heart?
With a driveline infection, you
need a day or two of antibiotics
before you can
get the transplant.
So I lose the heart after all.
Not necessarily. You
have a very low fever.
And we think that we
can clear up the infection
with a few doses of antibiotics
and still do the transplant.
What if the
antibiotics don't work?
Worst case?
Yeah. Worst case.
After surgery you could develop
a life-threatening infection.
What would you do?
It's your decision, Valerie.
I know, but would
you have the surgery?
The risk is small.
And you've waited a long time.
I would go for it.
How long have you
and Curt been together?
A while. Yeah, everything okay?
Yeah.
What happens when
the two of you fight?
What makes you think we fight?
Well, everybody has arguments.
You got bruises, stressed out.
You OD'd on your medication.
I'm just trying to
put it all together.
It's not uncommon for...
fights to turn physical.
People don't mean for
it to happen. It just does.
No, no. I... I know they don't.
Something just sets it off.
That ever happen to you?
I forgot to pick up
the dry cleaning.
He, uh... He hit me, and...
and he said he was sorry
and he promised
he'd never do it again.
Has he?
So there have been other times.
Yeah.
I'd like you to talk
to a social worker.
You know, they have experience
at dealing with these things.
Okay?
I don't know. I don't know.
Dr. Corday?
Lindsey, how are you?
I'm all right.
Um, it was my sister's
funeral yesterday.
I just... I wanted to thank you.
You really don't have to.
The police said that, um,
that he finally told you
where he left Jenny.
Yes.
I'm... I'm trying to forget him.
I... I just hear his
voice all the time.
And it's very gentle.
But it's just saying
these awful things.
Now, you listen to me.
That's what he wanted.
To make you suffer.
But you don't let him win.
Now, he's nothing. He
can't hurt you anymore.
I know. I know.
It's okay.
How long is the operation?
Four, five hours.
Do they let med students watch?
Only if they're on
the transplant service.
So that means
that you can't stay?
Nah, I'm gonna talk them
into making an exception.
Thanks. Yeah.
Oh, will you do
me a favor? Sure.
I forgot to feed Spoony. Spoony?
It's my cat. Will
you tell my mom?
Yes. Okay.
I'm gonna go change.
I'll see you.
Can I have a moment with him?
I knew you'd come.
Did you?
Mm-hm.
You know, when I woke up
and I found you hadn't done
what you'd said you'd do,
I was glad.
The fact that you were a coward
never even occurred to me.
Your conscience
is bothering you.
Isn't it?
It is, actually.
Why? Because
you nearly killed me?
Or because you
didn't have the guts to?
Because I enjoyed the
power I had over you.
When I could've let you
bleed to death at the crash.
When your heart stopped
while I was operating.
When the morphine
took you under.
I held your every
breath in my hands
and I so wanted to repay
some of the pain you'd caused.
But then I looked at
your sad little body.
And I saw what a
pathetic man you are.
And I realized I didn't
want power over you at all.
That my job, for
better or worse,
was simply to put
you back together.
See, I don't give a damn
if you go to the chair
or if you spend the
rest of your life in prison.
My job's done.
You were my patient, you
were sick, you're better.
Goodbye, Mr. Rollins.
You can take him now.
Come back here!
I haven't finished with you
yet! Get back here, Corday!
Corday!
Do you have any chest
pain? Shortness of breath?
Maybe a little lightheaded.
Oh, my God. What happened?
The parking lot attendant's
idea of a code blue.
What? She slipped on the ice.
I was helping Mom into the car.
My wheelchair fell over.
Did you hit your head
or lose consciousness?
Louise? Did she
lose consciousness?
I don't think so, but I
fell first so I don't know.
Put her on a monitor.
You want this one, Dr. Chen?
I just discharged her.
I believe in continuity of care.
No head trauma, check
her hips and pelvis. Bye.
I'm so sorry, Mom.
I'm all right.
Her BP is 170/95.
Is that bad?
It's a little high.
How about we get a CBC,
chem panel, cardiac enzymes,
EKG and postural vitals?
I'm fine.
I'm just so... So tired.
What was, uh, she here for?
Weakness. Exacerbation
of Parkinson's.
She hasn't been able
to walk for three days.
It's harder for me
to take care of her.
Her head CT was normal.
I see.
Right atrial
cannulation is complete.
Umbilical tape?
How long does the L-VAD stay on?
Until we go on bypass.
Great.
Aortic cannula's looking good.
Here we go. Kill the air pump.
Clamp the aortic graft, Peter.
Okay. And got it.
Open the venous line.
Anyone looking for a heart?
You're early, Shirley.
Making me look bad.
Sorry, Dr. Hanover.
Take it up with the FAA.
Is it too early?
No, no, no. It can
wait on ice for a while.
Wow! That's her new heart.
Yeah.
It sure is.
He denied everything?
Claimed the boyfriend
never even touched him.
I thought he was ready to talk.
Well, it's not uncommon for
victims to change their minds.
He probably loves the guy
and wants to protect him.
Yeah, or he's afraid. You
gonna be around all day?
Yeah. Why? Thinking about
making another run at him?
Maybe. Great,
well, give ma a call.
Okay, thanks. Uh-huh.
Carol, how are you feeling?
Four hours and 43 minutes to go.
You know, counting the
minutes is not a good sign.
Can someone take
this ingrown toenail?
She's been whining for
over an hour. A real bitch.
Carol.
The woman is
exhausted. I know that.
So she needs a break. I can't.
How's the parking
lot? They lived.
You can't? Or you won't? Both.
Just say that you're
ruling out a stroke.
I can't lie about a diagnosis.
Sometimes we make
what's called a judgment call.
If the rules need to be bent
a little bit, we bend them.
I bent them last week, John,
remember? And got into trouble.
Look, if you're afraid
of getting yelled at
then maybe you're in
the wrong department.
Listen, everybody
does soft admits.
It's just part of the drill.
Look, I know what you're
saying, but I'm not admitting her.
She's my patient. It's my call.
Okay. Okay, you're right.
Yeah? Not about the patient.
I don't agree with you.
But you gotta do
whatever you think is best.
Well, thanks for your input.
Anytime.
Hey, Amira? I need a
telemetry bed for Louise Duffy.
Wait. You're
admitting the daughter?
Yeah. Her hypertension's
out of control.
I want to rule out an MI.
You're kidding, right?
She's sinkable. She
might have unstable angina.
She slipped on some
ice. You said so yourself.
Well, it's my
patient. It's my call.
And where's the
mother supposed to go?
That's your patient.
That's your call.
You must have misunderstood.
A bunch of us got into
a fight at the hockey rink.
Michael, we both know
you're not gonna be safe
until you get out
of this relationship.
Ah, I'll wear more
pads next time.
Most domestic homicides
have a history of physical abuse.
Now you're trying to scare me?
Yes. You need to
get away from him.
Okay, I got the
rental. We're all set.
You okay? Yeah, fine.
Is he ready to go? No,
we need to get a CT scan.
What for?
He had previous head trauma.
I told him we play
a lot of hockey.
I want to clear him medically
before he plays again.
Uh, I'd like to take him home.
Michael, I think
you should stay.
I want you to understand
the risk that's involved.
He understands them.
I'm not so sure.
Curt, why don't we
let Dr. Greene...?
Mike, shut up.
If you need him to sign
something, he'll sign it.
Won't you, Mike?
Yeah.
You don't have to
go. It's your decision.
Thanks. Uh... Uh, I
feel better now, really.
We should get home. Yeah.
One more dispo
and I'm out of here.
What's that?
All that's left in the
vending machine.
What's wrong with the cafeteria?
No water. Can't cook.
Then don't eat.
That stuff will kill you.
Has anyone seen Chuny?
I've been waiting a
half hour for a translator.
Sorry.
What's the problem?
Father-daughter combo
present with aplastic anemia.
Both of them?
Yeah. Strange. No
history of toxic exposure.
Yeah, let me see.
Bone marrow's not making squat.
They in there?
Yeah. Why?
What are you doing?
I got a hunch.
Hola. Soy Dr. Dave.
Dave, what are
they saying? Hold on.
Son of a bitch!
What is it?
Ah, gracias.
What are they saying?
Last month they got a
bunch of shots for their colds.
Did you get the
name of the doctor?
No doctor. They
went to a pharmacy.
What kind of
pharmacist gives a shot?
Oh, the bad kind.
It's a back-room clinic.
They smuggle
drugs up from Mexico.
Oh, God!
Mm-hm. Plenty of stuff that
could give you aplastic anemia.
What are you doing?
They gave me the address.
Wait a minute. Hold on.
We should call the police.
Yeah. They see a squad
car, they'll bolt in two seconds.
Cleo, we could use you out here.
Go ahead. I got this.
Dave, these are my patients.
I can handle it.
Yeah, they're all yours.
What are you going to
do? Don't worry about it.
Trevor, my name is Carol
and we're gonna take
good care of you, sweetheart.
Femur fracture? Auto
versus pedestrian.
No head trauma.
He was all by himself.
Call my mom. We
already have, sweetheart.
Someone call Housekeeping!
Amira, can you call Ortho
about that trimalleolar in four?
Are you gonna be able
to walk? Yeah, I'm good.
I'll pull the car around.
Water's all hooked up.
Oh, finally!
Somebody has to sign this.
Dr. Greene, would you mind
signing for the water, please?
Sure. Why not?
Is the water turned back on?
Not yet. Gotta
check the pressure.
I'll be in the ambulance bay.
Hey, Dr. Greene,
can we page an individual
beeper on the code team?
If you know the number.
Isuprel's down to
four mics per minute.
Less than 50 cc's from
the mediastinal tube.
Wow! What?
That's weird. There's someone
else's heart keeping her alive.
Yeah, kind of cool, huh? Yeah.
Makes you wanna be a surgeon?
Vent settings?
Tidal volume: 700.14.02.5.
Shouldn't she be
breathing on her own soon?
Uh, general anesthesia
lasts longer in some patients.
Dr. Benton, her gaze
is deviated to the right.
Valerie, squeeze my hand!
We're going to CT. Call
Radiology. Lucy, unhook her.
Let's bag her. Let's go!
Come on, people! Let's move!
You sure you paged
the right number?
I hope so.
He's coming! He's coming!
Oh, my God! John,
are you all right?
Oh! Are you all right?
Yeah.
Now, that's a 10.
Looking good there, Carter.
So no code?
Mm. No code.
You okay?
Oh, that's very funny.
I could've killed myself.
Oh, it's payback time.
Just take it like a man.
Payback for what?
For blackmailing me.
I admitted Mrs. Duffy.
Really?
You're surprised?
You think I'm so heartless,
I'd ship an old lady to a
nursing home against her will?
I thought you were heartless
to discharge her the first time.
Oh, John, if I were
really heartless,
I wouldn't bother to tell you
that you've got toilet
paper stuck to your shoe.
What was that?
Somebody help!
What happened?
He was trying to put
our stuff in the trunk!
We should move him!
Not till we get a
backboard and a C-collar.
Yeah, it looks
like a flail chest.
Malik, go get an airway
kit and get Dr. Greene.
You got it.
And tell the driver
to turn this water off!
I thought I had
it in first gear.
It just went backwards!
He's not moving much air!
Oh, my God, I'm sorry!
Don't worry, bud. We
got it. Just stand back.
Guy's gonna need a
couple of chest tubes.
I'll intubate. 80 tube.
Michael, you need
to wait out here.
I'm losing the pulse!
Okay. Set up the rapid infuser
and prep for a thoracotomy.
Decreased breath.
Prep both sides of the chest.
Did he just back into him?
Yeah. He actually pinned
him up against the water truck.
Tachy at 128.
Pressure's down to 70.
Let me have the 10 blade.
Set up two Thora-Seals
and two suction lines.
Okay, I'm in. Bag him.
32 French. Let's go. Let's go.
Curved Kelly.
Pulse ox dropping to 82.
Okay, mine's in. Hook it up.
Uh, chest tube.
Thora-Seal's not bubbling.
Pressure's down to 60.
Hold on. There's no suction.
All right. Try the other one.
Nope.
What's going on?
Wall suction's generated
by the flow of water.
No water, no suction.
Chuny, go down to Central
and get a portable suction.
Run.
I'm in.
Pulse ox, 75.
Systolic's 50. We need
to re-expand his lungs.
Well, we're waiting on suction.
What about, uh...? What
about that vacuum cleaner?
What?
Yeah, the guy was
using it at Admit.
Lydia? Got it.
We'll need something
to make a seal.
Something like clay.
Merocel sponges.
Yeah, we'll need
about 20 of them.
He's bradying down.
Amp of atropine.
Get the crash cart.
Found him. He was down the hall.
Bring him down and get me water.
Lost his pulse. We're in P.E.A.
Okay, amp of epi.
Start chest compressions.
Sats are down to 72.
Okay, pour it.
Keep going, keep going, keep
going, keep going, keep going.
Okay. Okay, here we
go. Hold compressions.
Yep.
I hear breath sounds.
Pulse ox up to 85.
Ninety-two.
Good save.
Dr. Romano... Just
a second, Ms. Knight.
Thanks, Peter.
It was a stroke.
Yes.
They tried streptokinase but
couldn't open up the vessel.
Can she recover? Truth?
She's in a permanent
vegetative state.
It was the L-VAD, wasn't
it? We don't know for sure.
Threw a clot to her brain.
Don't blame yourself.
This is not your fault.
I'm the one who put
the thing in, remember?
We make these medical
decisions all the time.
Nothing is risk-free.
I better go talk to her mother.
Yeah. Oh, hold on.
Uh, UNOS has identified
a potential recipient
in Milwaukee.
What are you talking about?
A domino heart procedure.
We take out Valerie's new heart
and give it to someone
else who needs it.
You need to get
consent from the family.
But she'll...
She is already
dead, Miss Knight.
Wait, where's he going?
Four east, ICU.
All right. Thanks.
Is he gonna be okay?
We'll see.
You want to tell
me what happened?
He... He asked
me to pop the trunk
so he could put the bags in.
Then I was trying to pull
forward to give him room.
I thought I had
it in first but I...
You went backwards.
It's just... I... I'm not
used to driving a stick.
I thought they'd have to
admit me for hypothermia.
Do you want to use this?
I'm okay.
Cool trauma.
Yeah, it's not so bad when
two doctors work together.
Assess the patient, come
up with a plan of action.
John, are you still angry
about the way I handled
Louise and Mrs. Duffy?
No.
Then you're mad
about the practical joke?
No, I like a good
joke now and again.
You know, I'm just disappointed
that you couldn't come right out
and admit you made a mistake.
That your way of dealing with
it was to devise some silly gag.
You're right. You know, Deb,
things are gonna go a lot
easier for you around here
if you just deal
with things honestly.
John... Thank you.
Oh, and, um, no
more practical jokes.
That's a good idea.
She said yes.
Hey, Lucy.
I'm sorry.
Dr. Chen, I got x-rays
on that belly pain in One.
Finally.
The water's back
for almost an hour.
What takes them so long?
I don't know.
Oh, my God!
What?
My patient ate nails!
Chuny, call O.R and get
Surgery down here right now.
What are you doing?
So you made it
through the day, huh?
Just about.
Carol, good to have
you back! Thanks.
You're lucky to be
alive, you know that?
Hey, Malucci. What did you do?
Uh, nothing, chief. It
was just a sucker punch...
Any broken bones?
Short a few brain cells,
but otherwise okay.
Okay. Guard with
your left next time.
Right. Thanks, chief.
So anyway, I go in. I tell
him I have a sore throat.
The guy doesn't
even look in my mouth.
Dipyrone.
The FDA banned
this 20 years ago.
I know. It gets better. Then he
brings out a vial and a syringe.
Wants to give me a
shot. Chloramphenicol.
You didn't. What do
you think, I'm stupid?
I grabbed the vial, and I ran.
That's pretty much when
things got a little violent, so...
Hope it was worth it.
I got evidence now.
They're going down.
Hey, excuse me,
Cleo, you got a minute?
Sure.
Hold that.
So, you, uh...? You
gonna be able to get off?
Yeah, looks like it.
You wanna go grab some dinner?
Where you guys going?
Actually, it's just you and me.
What happened to everybody else?
That's what I was
trying to explain.
Peter, are you asking me out?
Yeah.
What do you think?
He's pretty shaken up.
Yeah.
He had a seizure? That's right.
Well, they revoke your
driver's license for seizures.
You cleared him to drive?
Yeah. He doesn't have epilepsy.
Too much asthma medicine.
But he didn't have any
in his system when he left.
Okay. Anything
else I should know?
No. That's it.
Okay, thanks.
Hey. Everything okay?
Police seem satisfied
with your story.
Yeah. I guess you
got what you wanted.
How's that?
I'll be safe at home tonight.
The social worker's
gonna be around.
Why don't the
three of us talk...?
No. No, I'm... Yeah,
I'm all right now.
Dr. Greene, your
pops is on line two.
He locked himself
out of your apartment.
Okay, Malik.
Thanks, Dr. Greene. I, uh,
appreciate your encouragement.
Lucy, you look
like you're freezing.
What?
It started snowing, and you
look like you are very, very cold.
I am.
No, no. That's okay.
No, come on.
I'm European. We like
to be gallant, you know?
Thanks.
So are you off?
I've got two tickets
for the circus.
No. Actually, I'm
just coming on.
Then what were you
doing here all day?
Not enough, as it turns out.
It's never been very
easy for me to be here.
Sometimes I felt like
I would never fit in.
That's something I know about.
But then I... I
moved around a lot.
And now I'm... I'm used to it.
But at the beginning
of every day,
I've been grateful
that I'm walking in here
of my own choosing,
and I'm not carried
in on some gurney.
And at the end of every day,
if I've helped just one person,
it's been worth it.
And that didn't happen
today. And it makes me sad.
Hey, your day is not over.
Maybe this is your one person.
I doubt it.
Yes, but, uh, let's
see if I'm right, huh?
And miss the circus?
You know what? I have had
enough circus for today, huh?
Come on.
What have you got?
Paul Galinski, 36. Put a
snowmobile into a tree.
Ejected with multiple
facial fractures.
Tried but couldn't tube
him. Too much blood.
He's all yours.
You can intubate.
Looks like a difficult one.
Yeah. I'll talk you through it.
Have you ever used
a...? A trach light?
No.
Okay. I'll show you how.