- Previously on The Resident...
- Why the QuoVadis valve?
It would have to take a
great product to get me
- to change my ways.
- The VNS went perfectly.
- His seizures have already
stopped. Bradley's coming in
- for a heart valve.
- Cheers.
The website said
QuoVadis is the new protocol
here at Chastain.
You don't get to make surprise
unilateral decisions
that affect our patients.
When you grab the
valve, it helps to...
This damn valve is too big.
You're holding it upside down,
which is what Julian
was trying to tell you.
I'll help you get your line down
if you give me some pointers
on how to run our
clinic. Dr. Shaw,
- you start tomorrow.
- I start now.
Coming.
This'll get you
through tomorrow.
It's a good thing Chastain's
right across the street.
I can't believe our
shipment was delayed.
- I can. How's your dad?
- Crabby.
Which I am embracing, because
it means he's feeling better,
so... look at this place.
I barely recognize
it. Very impressive.
Sheer force of will.
Are we forgetting anything?
Actually, we are.
Where did I put the...
Oh, there it is.
Ah, yes, the
ribbon-cutting ceremony.
We're here live at
the grand opening
for Chastain Park Memorial's
new community clinic,
where low-income or
uninsured residents can get
- the medical care
they greatly need.
- Guess we're open.
- Yeah! This grand opening
marks a new beginning
for those in need
in Atlanta, Georgia.
Lane Hunter was allegedly
giving chemotherapy
to people who
didn't have cancer.
In a dramatic turn of events,
Hunter was found dead
inside her Atlanta hotel room,
where she had been shot.
This morning, investigators
have identified the assailant
as Roger Stanley, the
brother of a former...
Thank you so much for
coming to the rescue, man,
I promise I am not one of
those guys that only calls
- when he needs something. Yeah.
- This is your big presentation,
okay? You land QuoVadis
as a client for your firm
and you will be the hottest
medical marketing consultant
- in Atlanta.
- You are right.
I have worked super hard
to get this meeting ever since
my surgery and I
can't blow it now.
Even though the idea of pitching
to Bell gives me the sweats.
Listen, just be yourself, okay?
You are a natural salesman.
But I got to have my props,
man. So please tell me
you can fix this, okay?
No slideshow, no bueno.
It's just a bad cable.
- You got a spare?
- Why would anyone
have two of those?
As it happens, I do.
- Hold on.
- Seriously?
Oh, you rock. I suck.
All right, so, tonight,
we hang, okay?
Get some pizza, couple of brews,
we'll play some Call of Honor.
I let you win
because we all know
that's where I
rock and you suck.
Hey. Not taking no
for an answer, man.
No pineapple on the pizza, ever.
- That's a deal-breaker.
- Selfish, okay?
But I agree to your terms
because I value this friendship.
But, for now, yeah, I got to go.
So you just come over
whenever. Uh, I should be back
around 5:00 and I'll
see you then, man.
- Thank you.
- Bradley.
Yeah. Oh.
I want that suit.
Five grand and my London
tailor will make it happen.
I'm in.
Oh. Back-to-back
marketing contenders.
This should be interesting.
By the end of the day we'll
have a winning campaign
to make QuoVadis
a household name.
- All we need now is...
- An offshore bank account
to hide all our money.
The new QuoVadis
website isn't just advertising,
it's an interactive
world built to engage
those people who
need medical devices.
Providing a hybrid of
technical information
and moving testimonials
from real QuoVadis patients,
one visit to the
company website,
and future clients
will be able to ask
for a QuoVadis device by name.
Using search engine marketing,
our ads and educational
materials will dominate...
with a big push in social media.
My only question: how fast
can we get it up and running?
I'm sorry. I, uh...
I, uh, I don't feel so well.
Call 911.
No pulse.
Uh, yes, we have an emergency.
Come on.
The QuoVadis building.
- Dr. Bell, what are you
doing here?
- It's Bradley.
- Go.
- 32-year-old male.
Witnessed cardiac arrest.
Recent mitral valve
replacement with a history
of ventricular hypertrophy.
ROSC achieved en
route, lost the pulse again.
Last epi two minutes ago.
Okay. Another large bore IV.
Okay. One, two, three.
Come on.
Still in asystole.
20 minutes since
he's had a pulse.
More bicarb.
Come on.
Pulse and rhythm check.
Another amp of bicarb.
It's Bradley!
Oh, my God.
Another round of epi.
Come on! Come on!
Hurry!
Come on.
Okay, okay.
Pulse and rhythm check.
Come on...
How long has he been down?
30 minutes.
I need a portable ultrasound.
Let's go!
Come on. Come on!
Hold compressions.
There is no cardiac activity.
♪ ♪
Preliminary autopsy results.
I just need to fill out
the death certificate.
Um, don't do anything yet.
I just want to make sure
this conclusion's warranted.
Okay.
The valves didn't fail.
Not a chance.
It's been implanted
hundreds of times
over the last year
with zero complications.
You're telling me not
one single patient...
I'm telling you people with
bad hearts have issues.
None of them were
caused by the valve.
Yeah, look. This is...
I mean, just, it's
irrefutable proof.
The strut in the valve just...
it shattered.
You have to ask
yourself why it shattered.
You're just assuming that
it was a manufacturing error
when it was clearly
damaged during surgery
by Dr. Austin.
You're saying my surgeon
broke the valve in the OR?
Exactly.
The cause...
of Bradley Jenkins' death...
is operator error.
Doesn't feel real.
Just... Bradley seemed to be
doing so well after his surgery.
He was... happy.
Early mortality from
valve replacement
has many possible causes.
Embolism, congestive
heart failure.
A defective heart valve.
You think the valve
that the Raptor implanted
- could have killed Bradley?
- Maybe.
His autopsy is being
presented at this morning's M&M.
We will have answers after.
Mr. Greenspan's case
is an unfortunate example
of the importance of
transparent labeling.
Mr. Greenspan was
given 25 milligrams
- of Olanzapine instead of 2.5...
- How are you doing?
A little nervous.
You and everyone else.
Presented to prevent...
How's the clinic?
We've seen over 60 patients,
and it's only our third day.
We can end labeling errors.
Up next, we have...
the Jenkins case.
The Jenkins case
will not be presented today.
Apologies for the
misunderstanding.
Thank you.
He is up to something.
Clearly.
Okay, um...
moving right along.
Are you keeping tabs on me?
Nope. When my dad
was touch and go,
you gave me a
great case I could fix.
I'm returning the favor.
I'm fine. I don't
need anything...
You can thank me later.
Good morning,
Marisol. I'm Dr. Pravesh.
Glad someone's
having a good morning.
To tell you the truth,
this pain has ruined mine.
And my life.
Oh right, and my marriage.
Well, that's what I
would call bad pain.
Mm, you and me
both, Dr. Pravesh.
You and me both.
When did this
life-ruining pain start?
Oh, about six hours ago.
It took six whole hours
to ruin a marriage?
Amateur.
- I didn't even make it
down the aisle.
- Let's see...
Kicked my husband to
the curb about a year ago,
two years of trying to
make it work before that.
Um, I had an ectopic
pregnancy, so my right ovary is...
Dud.
When I eventually
did get pregnant again,
I had a crash C-section.
They saved me,
but we lost our son.
I'm sorry for your loss.
The pain started
shortly after that.
And so did the marital problems.
Did you see a doctor about this?
Many.
And none of them
would listen to me.
I need a doctor
who will believe me.
I believe you.
And I'm gonna figure
out what's going on.
Floyd, how you doing?
Hey, the sun is shining,
it's a beautiful day.
I'm feeling fine.
That doesn't sound fine.
Dr. Shaw, meet Floyd Washington.
Retired mailman, Vietnam vet
- and awesome grandfather.
- How you doing, doc?
Nice to meet you, Floyd.
What's your name, kid?
Aw, don't mind Aubrey.
She hates attention.
Although the hair and the
piercings might say otherwise.
I'm gonna have you
breathe for me, Floyd.
Deep breath.
Yeah, if it's not anime
or tattoos or AP Biology,
this girl's quiet as a mouse.
- Floyd, do you have
any pain in your leg?
- No, no,
just-just the, uh, cough.
Why don't you change into
this for me, would you, Floyd?
I'm gonna perform a full exam.
Menthol, regular,
filtered, unfiltered?
None of the above.
Quit cold turkey
when Aubrey moved in with me.
Secondhand smoke kills.
Unlike firsthand smoke.
Nurse Nic, call
The Atlanta Journal,
my granddaughter speaks.
All right, but after
your chest X-ray.
We'll be back.
Thanks, Floyd.
Dr. Bell. Fred Harris, new
general counsel for Chastain.
Good to meet you.
The Jenkins family is
pursuing legal action
for the death of their son.
- I spoke to the pathologist...
- The official cause of death
- hasn't been determined.
- No.
Not official, but...
Y... She believes
- the heart valve shattered.
- There's a question as to why.
Mm. The board won't
like that narrative.
Puts our surgeon at fault,
makes Chastain vulnerable. No.
We have to avoid
surgical error at all costs,
and your job is to
make sure that happens.
Quickly.
Do whatever you have to do.
Of course.
What were the
results of the autopsy?
Bradley was our friend.
- We need to know what happened.
- I'm aware of the how important
Bradley was to you
and I'm doing my best...
- What was the cause of death?
- We're conducting
a closed investigation
to determine that.
I was there when he died.
I should be a part
of that investigation.
And I assisted Dr. Austin
on his heart valve surgery.
The investigation
should be transparent.
Done at an open M&M.
I'm trying to
protect Dr. Austin.
So, you're saying
that Bradley died
because Dr. Austin
made a mistake during surgery?
I'm saying that if you
don't want to ruin his career,
you'll stand down
and let me do my job.
I mean, is it possible
that The Raptor...
- No.
- Anyone can make a mistake.
- Not this.
We need to warn Austin
so he can prepare a defense.
- He won't be thrilled.
- All right,
I'll see you guys later. I
have a GI consult with Marisol.
I don't trust Bell.
Whatever he says,
he's protecting Chastain,
- not Austin.
- Yeah.
My guess, the problem
was the QuoVadis valve
and they're blaming him.
You're telling me...
Bell thinks these hands
killed Bradley Jenkins?
You know what I think?
That went exactly as I expected.
Dr. Bell.
Just the man I want to see.
I hear you're looking
for a scapegoat.
So I obtained the copy
of the autopsy report
which clearly states
that your valve...
The one Chastain
forced into my OR
due to your little
sweetheart deal... failed.
Because you made
an error inserting it.
Au contraire, Satan.
You must be Dr. Austin.
- Your arrogance proceeds you.
- This isn't about me, dawg.
This is about your defective
product, which does not
belong on Chastain's shelves.
Your mentor, Abe
Benedict, loves our valves
and all his patients
are alive and well.
Oh yeah? Well, prove
it. Show me your stats.
Right. I'm guessing no one
tracks long-term outcomes.
My devices... each one...
Are little works of art.
Perfectly designed to
make a failing body better.
But they must be understood.
They must be
treated with respect.
Did you respect my valve when
you implanted it, Dr. Austin?
I reviewed my surgical notes.
Bradley Jenkins' surgery
went without incident.
Uh, I think your surgical notes
are missing some
very important details.
Impossible. I'm an advocate
for transparency in everything,
especially my reports.
Our rep, Julian Booth,
was in that surgery
and she documented it.
Her notes tell a
very different story.
That you tried to implant
the device backwards.
I'm sorry, AJ,
that's what it says.
I picked it up wrong,
realized my mistake
and I picked it
up the right way.
- It was a nothingburger.
- Hey, stop talking.
So you're admitting error.
I am not.
This isn't over.
I've spoken to
some of the nurses.
Apparently, he's a terror.
This is gonna be easy.
AJ Austin is
practically a magician
in the OR. If I needed surgery,
he would be the doctor
that I ask for. So before
you go and smear a
man's name, have a look...
at the long list of people
whose lives he's saved.
Sounds like you're
rooting for the wrong team.
I am your partner.
I am also the
CEO of this hospital
and my board
doesn't want the finger
pointing at one of their
own any more than you do.
You have the power
to sway the board.
All you need is proof.
I want the truth.
And the word of one
of your employees...
is not gonna be enough.
Well, partner, Julian and Austin
weren't the only
people in that room.
Let's be thorough.
Hey, great. So,
good news, Floyd.
Your lungs are clear,
but now Nurse Nevin and I
are gonna take
a look at that leg.
Oh w-wait a minute. I just
came in here for my cough.
Don't pass up the chance
to show us some ankle.
Pop.
All right, let's see
what we have here.
What's wrong with Pops?
We're gonna have
to run some tests,
but I suspect after
years of smoking,
he has what's called
peripheral vascular disease.
What-what does...
what-does that mean?
It means you did the right
thing bringing him in here today.
What do you think's
up with Aubrey?
She's what... 17, 18?
She's probably stoned.
No, I don't think so.
Well, clearly you don't know
what a high teenager looks like.
Actually, I do.
I've been a solo
act for a while,
but I'm starting to like
this double-team thing.
Good.
Then I'll keep
teaching you new tricks.
Hopefully you're a fast learner.
Conrad, he has
a surprise for you.
So we thought we'd come
on by. Well, go on, Henry.
Dr. Conrad, I got to show you.
Show me what?
Oh...
MVP? Oh...
Oh!
That is a big trophy.
It's a big deal.
Mm-hmm. It's a keeper.
Coach gave it to
me after the game.
Called me to home
plate in front of everybody.
- Mm.
- I thought Daniel Pressley
was gonna get it.
Hey, Daniel is good, but
most valuable player...
That is all you.
Congrats, my man.
Hey. You okay, Bud?
Honey, look at me.
Why are you doing that?
Doing what?
What you just did
with your head... Why
are you doing that?
I don't know. But
it wasn't a seizure.
I never felt far away.
Hey.
You want to grab
some more napkins?
Have you ever seen
him do that before?
Once.
While we were camping
in Stone Mountain.
I thought he was
nervous, but-but...
Okay, well, you look worried.
Let's just take a
trip up to neurology,
make sure everything's okay.
Okay. Better safe than sorry.
How's Marisol doing?
This poor woman has been
ignored and dismissed by her doctors.
She's been trying to
advocate for herself.
All alone.
But now she's your patient
and you're helping her.
She's not alone anymore.
And you're not alone either.
There.
On her left
ovary... that a cyst?
No.
It's a thick-walled, fluid-dense
mass in her adnexa.
That's probably a
tubo-ovarian abscess.
I'll get her on IV antibiotics
and order an aspiration.
Yeah, minimally invasive
and it'll tell us exactly
what we're dealing with.
I'd say let me know if you
need anything, but you won't.
No, all we want to
know is did Dr. Austin
insert the device upside down?
Dr. Bell put him in
an impossible position.
He had no experience
with the new heart valve
and yet he had to insert it.
And that's why
Ms. Booth was in the
OR... To give him guidance,
to prevent a mistake.
We need to understand
exactly what happened,
Dr. Okafor. No judgment.
The facts. I know it's hard,
because you work
closely together.
Dr. Austin almost inserted
the valve upside down.
He quickly course
corrected. It was a non-event.
I don't understand.
While Ms. Booth was there,
didn't she try to instruct him
- on how to properly
insert that valve?
- Yes.
- So he didn't listen.
- That is not unusual for him.
It is his way.
I'm sorry, uh, it's not unusual
for Dr. Austin to
ignore expert instruction
on a new device?
Surgical errors drop drastically
when staff is
encouraged to speak up
- if they see a problem.
- I agree with that principle,
but Dr. Austin knows
what he's doing.
- He is a rare exception.
- So, over the course
of Bradley's surgery,
Dr. Austin did every
little thing correctly?
- No.
- Mm.
Because he refused
to listen to instruction...
and he may have made a mistake
that cost Bradley
Jenkins his life.
Yes.
In a minute, sedation will
kick in. You'll feel sleepy.
- We'll aspirate the fluid
and go from there, okay?
- Okay.
That crash C-section
and losing our son
was the worst thing that
has ever happened to me,
and I stayed because
I desperately
wanted to try again,
to be a mother.
Please make sure they
don't take the good ovary.
Okay, it's the last
chance I have left.
I'm gonna be here
the whole time.
I will make sure that
they listen to you, okay?
- Okay.
- Trust me.
- She's under. We're all set.
- Needle for aspiration.
Have a percutaneous
drain on standby.
More sedation!
I can't. Her blood
pressure's too low. It's 80/50.
All right, let's do
an ultrasound.
Go, come on.
Hurry.
There's no blood
flow to the left ovary.
The ovary is twisted on itself.
If we don't get her to
surgery, she'll lose it.
Page GYN, tell them
to meet us up there now.
All right.
I've just drained the abscess.
And now, if you want, Aubrey,
I could teach
you how to pack it.
Uh, m-me?
Uh, no, that won't be necessary.
Just teach me, I can get by.
Yeah, Floyd's right. This is
a lot of responsibility
for a teenager.
I mean, it has to be done
right, but I have no doubt
- that Aubrey can do it.
- But it's a staph infection
and if we don't
properly treat it,
it can spread to the
bone, and if that happens,
he could lose the leg.
But if Aubrey can help
him manage the infection,
we can prevent that
and keep him
out of the hospital.
She'll need to be very thorough.
Do you want to try?
All right, come on. Let's
get you some gloves.
There you go.
You see, now, how when I pull
on the gauze, it doesn't move?
You try.
Maybe go from the other side.
- Nice and tight.
- Oh...
Oh.
You know what, um...
let's take a break.
Here, come on.
That was a good try.
Untouched pie.
That's not like you.
Thank you for meeting me
on such short notice, Abe.
Hey, I'm always up
for the best pie in town.
Besides, it sounded urgent.
What do you know
about Gordon Page?
Ambitious, dynamic,
smart as hell.
Thank you.
That's a lot of high
praise coming from you.
What's this about?
A young patient of
mine died not long after
putting the QuoVadis valve in...
- The one that you recommended.
- I'm sorry.
And now Gordon Page
is pointing a finger at me.
He says I damaged it
because I handled it incorrectly.
And, personally, I
think that's absurd.
But have you ever
experienced anything like that?
No, but I suppose I could have,
if I hadn't had a device
rep in the OR with me
to walk me through
the procedure.
As did I.
I just didn't listen to her.
I don't know what
to say, Austin. I...
This was bound to
happen sooner or later.
You are great.
But you're not
invincible. No one is.
Your God complex has
always been your Achilles heel.
You want my advice?
Always.
Learn humility.
If you make a mistake, own it.
It'll make you a better doctor.
The blood flow's cut off.
In order to remove the
mass, we're going to have to
- take the ovary.
- You can't untangle the adnexa?
It's adherent to the posterior
cul-de-sac and side wall.
I'm trying to dissect it, but
there's something blocking
my visualization.
- Could you save it
if you converted to open?
- Maybe.
Maybe not.
There's still a chance.
We have to try.
I can't put her through major
abdominal surgery for no reason.
We have a reason.
She wants children.
As her doctors, we
have to honor that.
You can tell me with
absolute certainty
that she wants this at any cost?
Yes.
Convert to open.
There... the ovary's untangled.
Let's remove the mass.
Metz.
Wait. What is this?
It's... blue.
What kind of tumor is blue?
It's not a tumor.
Oh, my God.
It's a surgical sponge.
Aubrey, I think I kind of put
you on the spot back there.
I'm really sorry about that.
I just...
get the sense that this is
something that you could do.
And if I'm being honest,
if you can tend to
his wounds at home,
it would be better
for your grandfather
not to be in the hospital.
My mom was a nurse.
No way.
She taught me some stuff bef...
She taught me some
stuff before she died.
She made people better.
But what if I'm not like her?
What if I make Pops worse?
Aubrey...
I'm sure you're more like your
mother than you even know.
Sometimes I wonder
if I could be a
nurse like she was.
Maybe you could start
with your grandfather.
Uh, Our CABG surgery is in
an hour and we need to prep.
Dr. Hoffstead is
filling in for me.
- You can scrub in with her.
- Are you ill?
No. I'm pondering.
Okay, so you can ponder
during our case.
Don't you want to operate?
Yeah.
I do.
I need it.
Like I need the sun...
or peanut butter chocolate cups.
But the sun hurts my eyes
and chocolate makes me bloat,
so I won't be doing
any of it, not for a while.
I'm benching myself from
surgery until further notice.
Okay, well, even for you,
that's dramatic.
You made a mistake. We all do.
And Bradley paid for
my mistake with his life.
You know, you
were right all along.
My ego...
Well, of course I was right.
And it seems like you
already learned your lesson.
So be better, come back,
take your place inside the OR.
The OR is a sacred
place and I blasphemed it.
I don't have a place
there. Not now.
And I will not put
another life at jeopardy
until I learn humility.
"Blessed are the meek."
It's been an hour.
When can I take
this stupid hat off?
Not until you do
the motion again,
so we can see if your
brainwaves are normal or abnormal
while you're doing the movement.
Okay.
What if he doesn't do it
while he's on the machine?
Eh, we'll just try again.
It's the only way to know
if it's a manifestation
of a seizure.
Do I look like a mad scientist?
Ah, exactly like
a mad scientist.
How's Nic? I haven't seen
her around the hospital.
Yeah, she started a free clinic
that opened a few days ago.
- She's doing great.
- You must be so proud.
I am. Yeah, she's...
she's amazing.
Oh, oh, can I go see Nurse Nic?
I want to show her my trophy...
Okay. He's doing it again.
Please, God.
That's normal.
All right,
no abnormal brain activity.
If it's not a seizure,
then why is he
doing that motion?
Eh, it's a tic. Uh, very
common in kids Henry's age.
He just makes a movement,
usually a reaction to something,
and kind of gets
stuck in a loop.
But it's definitely not...
Definitely not a seizure.
Told you.
Hey. What are you doing?
Writing a Chastain
admission form for Floyd.
He needs heavy
observation and wound care.
There's too great a risk for
amputation to send him home.
PVD's chronic.
Even if we cure this
ulcer, there will be others.
He needs ongoing care.
Hospitals can't do that,
- Aubrey can.
- Her hands shake.
She can't look
anyone in the eye.
She's a teenager who
may be a drug user
and you want to put her in
charge of Floyd's care... why?
Look, you and I both
know that hospitals
can be dangerous
for people Floyd's age.
I mean, they get poked
and prodded all night long
and exposed to
hospital-based infections.
Sometimes home care
is just the better option.
Yeah, that's right.
And you're preaching
to the choir here,
but in this instance...
Okay, let me just
show you something.
All right? She can do this.
Not bad.
Not bad at all.
Mm.
Well, no need for a nurse.
You're a natural,
just like your mom.
Well, it looks like you're
headed home, Floyd.
Got yourself a great nurse here.
They left a sponge in me?
How... how could this happen?
I wish I could give
you a decent answer.
But the truth is the mistake
is inexcusable and it never
- should have happened.
- They must have
forgotten to remove it
during your C-section.
It's rare, but it happens.
It's been the cause
of all your pain
for all these years.
And you've suffered for so
long and it was avoidable.
That day I lost my baby
and they left me with...
the pain.
And then the guilt, as
if it were my own fault,
as if it were in my head.
And all of it...
it's gone.
The pain that ruined my life,
I still have an ovary
and I'm gonna have
a child someday.
You fixed everything,
Dr. Pravesh.
Thank you.
All in a day's
work for this guy.
Excuse me.
Is he okay?
He will be.
Just lost his best friend.
You are exactly what he needed.
Thanks, for everything.
Oh. Of course.
- Thanks, Doc.
- Of course. Always.
- I'll see you soon, yeah?
- Thank you.
- See you later.
- All right. Thank you.
We had a scared, shy teenager
and I thought "drug addiction."
Got that wrong.
Uh-huh.
So...
who is it?
Earlier, you got a little
snippy when I claimed
you didn't know what a
drug addict looked like.
Snippy?
Yeah, definitely snippy.
My sister.
I have recently come to terms
with the fact that I am
a classic codependent.
Well, as a former codependent,
I guess there are some
things I can teach you.
You want to get dinner?
- Hey.
- Hey. Good to see you.
Nurse Nic!
Hey, Henry, what's going
on? What are you doing here?
He wanted to show you something.
Oh, yeah? What do you got?
- A trophy.
- No way.
Are you serious?
That is so awesome. High five.
Looks like your son is
a star baseball player.
Oh, no. We're-we're not, um...
Conrad is... was... our doctor.
And now we're...
We're friends.
And they're together.
Uh, I guess that's my
cue to say good night, all.
Good night.
- I'll just be a second.
- Okay.
Ah...
Bye, Dr. Conrad.
- Bye.
- Ready?
You have something to say?
You, of all people...
A surgeon who has
made many mistakes...
Did not protect Dr. Austin.
I will protect him. Even if
he's named in a lawsuit.
He won't lose his job and
he'll be back in the OR.
No one can protect The
Raptor from The Raptor.
He's benched himself.
He won't operate.
We are surgeons.
Gordon Page is not.
He doesn't know what it
takes to cut into the heart
of a living human being
and end up curing them,
not killing them.
But you're his lapdog. Why?
If you won't tell me, I
will find out another way.
You have my word.
Yeah, maybe we don't
send this one to his mom.
It's not really
memorial material.
What about this?
Dust Bunny.
Now, that's Bradley.
Ah, our intern class photo.
Man, you hate that white coat.
- Yup.
- You could've
at least worn a tie.
Yeah, well I wore one last
week for Devon's wedding,
so there's that.
What do you got?
♪ If I had everything ♪
♪ Everything ♪
♪ I could change anything ♪
♪ If I changed anything ♪
Pizza. Someone grab plates.
♪ I mean anything ♪
♪ I would change everything... ♪
Hi.
I didn't know Henry
had a checkup today.
He looked good.
So did Zoey.
Yeah, after Bradley, I just
wanted to lay eyes on him.
- Hmm.
- How are things
at the clinic, with Alec?
He seems to really care
about what we're doing.
Mm. Well, that's good.
Come on, let's eat.
Yes.
Why is there
pineapple on this pizza?
It's a Hawaiian pie.
Bradley always said
it tastes like vacation.
To Bradley.
♪ If I changed anything ♪
♪ I mean anything... ♪
To Bradley.
- To Bradley. To Bradley.
♪ I would change
everything, oh, yeah... ♪
The patient died because
his heart valve failed
after, allegedly, being
mishandled by his surgeon.
Did you want me to
write "defective valve"
or "operator error" on
the death certificate?
♪ See, 'cause you've never
been the same as anyone else ♪
♪ Don't think the same
as everyone else... ♪
Neither. The patient
died of heart failure
due to underlying disease.
♪ Your... ♪
Captioned by Media
Access Group at WGBH