Windy City runners,
welcome to Mile 12.
You're looking great today.
Now, remember to stay
hydrated out there
to beat the heat.
Keep it up.
See? Taking a header
at your first
marathon is nothing.
Now, taking a header
into a pool
in your wedding dress?
Epic fail.
Epic fail. Right?
No, that would be
taking 20 minutes
to put on a Band-Aid.
Sorry.
Totally my fault.
No, no, not at all.
Take as long as you need.
You, on the other hand,
have a superhero
with super
intestinal discomfort
who requires your
immediate attention.
Almost halfway.
You holding up?
I'm sure that runner's high
is gonna kick in
any second now.
That or heatstroke.
Yeah. It's not
the best day for
a heat wave.
Yeah, I was thinking,
uh, maybe later we can
do something else.
What, like collapse?
No. Maybe
a bedroom activity.
Or kitchen table.
Shower.
Let's go, Doc.
Pick up the pace.
Now, try to keep it elevated,
and remember, ice, not heat.
Please, don't mention heat.
It's hot as balls out here.
We need help.
A guy got run over.
Grab an aid kit.
Got it.
Three, two, one.
My brakes went out.
You've got to help him.
We'll do all we can.
Ignacio.
Where does it hurt, Ignacio?
Maggie, we got
a bike versus auto.
Diminished breath sounds
on the left side.
Sounds like
it's full of fluid.
I think his lung collapsed.
Marathon traffic
and power outages
from the heat
have paramedics
backed up.
We're on our own
for a while.
He doesn't have a while.
He needs a chest tube now.
Not from you.
You've never put one in.
Be my guest.
Neither of us is
allowed to do it.
Then he's gonna die.
Maggie, I need Goodwin.
Sir, just hang on.
We're gonna do everything
we can for you, okay?
We're gonna help you, okay?
Just hang on.
Sit tight, April.
Dr. Halstead's on the way.
No, no, no.
You let him make that call.
All right.
You keep me posted.
How goes the battle?
Ugh.
It's supposed
to hit 105 today,
so we've got
a generator on standby
just in case our
grid goes dark.
Sharon, listen.
Bert called me.
Really?
Yeah.
He wants to get together
for drinks, and I just...
I wanted to check in with you
before I responded to him.
Daniel, you do
whatever you like.
I'm good.
Hey, Peter.
Um...
Your husband is
a divorce attorney,
isn't he?
Best in the city.
Text me his number.
I can do this.
With what?
We don't even
have a chest tube.
I got a suction tube.
No, you are not
gonna jury-rig your way
into this guy's chest.
He's got no chance
unless I do.
Goodwin said
to wait for Will.
How long is
that gonna take?
Got a neck pulse,
but it's thready.
He's out.
I've got to relieve
the pressure on his lung.
BP 82 over palp.
Sat at 82%.
I'm doing this.
Noah.
Noah!
Pulse is coming up.
You did it.
Yeah, but
the tube's not slowing down.
Damn, it's a bad bleed.
Come on. He needs surgery.
We need to intubate
and give him blood.
Where the hell is Will?
Hey, Nat.
Eight-year-old girl with
sudden onset deafness
in Treatment Two.
They said the heat wave's
supposed to be worse than '95.
Hi. I'm Dr. Manning.
I understand
Phoebe's experiencing
some hearing loss?
Yeah. Uh, we were headed
to cheer on the runners.
She was skipping ahead.
A semi started backing up.
I was screaming,
and she couldn't hear me.
A few seconds later...
What?
I don't want to
think about it.
It's okay, sweetie.
Can you
hear that, Phoebe?
Not really.
How about now?
Sort of. A little.
Okay,
her hearing is diminished
on the right side
and nearly absent
on the left.
Does she have
any prior history
of head trauma
or hearing loss?
No. Uh, not that
I can think of.
I mean, there have
been a few times
where I've had to
call her more than once
within these last few months,
but nothing like this.
Okay, well, I'd like to
order a head CT
just so we can figure out
what's going on, okay?
Okay.
Thank you.
Wait.
Are you going to fix my ears?
I'm sure gonna try.
Be back shortly.
Like, I can't...
I can't get it in.
You have to
capture the tongue.
Elevate the jaw.
What the hell
are you doing?
I'm trying to intubate.
He had a massive hemothorax,
and I had to put
in a chest tube.
No, what you
had to do was wait.
Dr. Halstead,
this man would have died.
Yeah, judging
by all the blood,
if we don't get him into
surgery in the next few
minutes, he will anyway.
I'm in. Bag him.
Any ETA on transport?
Still saying
it'll be a while.
We could open his chest.
Try to address the bleed.
It might buy him enough time
for the ambulance to show up.
Yeah, it might.
There's no guarantee
I could even find it.
The only guarantee is
he'll die if we don't try.
No, I've been
down this road before
trying extreme measures.
It doesn't end well.
His pressure is down.
Trachea feels
deviated to the right.
I need a scalpel.
We're going to
Treatment Five.
You got it, Maggie.
Olga Barlow,
74, lives alone.
Complex cardiac history.
Called the EMS for dyspnea.
BP 82 over 44.
Chronic a-fib at rate 105.
Tachypneic at 30.
Those are her meds.
I'll page Dr. Choi.
Okay.
Mrs. Barlow,
what happened today?
It's so hot out,
I was having a hard time
catching my breath.
Do you have an air conditioner
in your home?
Don't I wish?
Well, let's move her.
One, two, three.
There you go.
Pulse ox 89.
Temperature 101.
She's tachy up to 130.
I think we're looking
at heat exhaustion.
Let's pack her
axilla and groin in ice
and send a CBC,
CMP, LFTs and urine.
And give her
an amp of D50.
What's the story?
Uh, nonexertional
heat illness.
We're going to
lower her core temp
and keep her hydrated.
You check her meds?
Looks like she has
pulmonary hypertension.
That's right.
Jugular venous distention
means she's in
volume overload.
This fluid you ordered
could've sent her
into heart failure.
Am I gonna be okay?
We're gonna take
good care of you.
Let's get a chest film.
AP and lateral.
ECG and stat formal echo.
Yes, Doctor.
Start epoprostenol at two.
Dobutamine at three.
Is your arthritis
causing you pain?
Yes, it's
pretty... Pretty bad.
I bet.
That's a pretty
good dose of oxycodone.
Let's give her one...
No, 2 milligrams
of hydromorphone.
She won't even
notice 1 milligram.
Okay.
You're gonna be
feeling better soon.
Next time do
a complete history
and physical before
making a diagnosis.
Great. There you go.
Ms. Goodwin, a word?
Um, problem, Dr. Rhodes?
I filled in for
trauma last night.
Seven surgeries.
I was double-booked
going back and
forth between ORs.
Well, a month ago,
you were complaining
about not having enough to do.
Yeah, well, last night
cured me of that.
The hospital is
overscheduling,
Ms. Goodwin.
Well, maybe
someone thought
we needed the revenue.
I'll look into it.
Thank you.
Look, we're all having
our problems today,
Dr. Rhodes.
Go home. Get some sleep.
I can't.
I've got a consult
on a cold leg in IR
that needs
an aortofemoral bypass.
Retract his ribs.
Suction.
All right.
Anything?
Nothing but clots.
I don't see it.
I gotta get
behind the lungs.
Still has a carotid pulse.
Oh, man.
Rib perforated
the aorta.
Can you clamp it?
With what? My hand?
It'll buy us...
Him 20 minutes?
Any longer,
there's a good chance
he'll be paralyzed.
If you don't,
he'll bleed out.
All right.
Hemostatic?
Yeah, it stopped.
Now he needs more
blood and a miracle.
Which could happen
if we get him on
portable bypass.
They've been
doing it in France.
We have a unit in
clinical trial at Med.
April, call Maggie.
On it.
We've got about 19 minutes
to get Ignacio hooked up
before he's
paralyzed or worse.
Hey, I meant to ask you.
Uh, are flowers too much
for your mom tonight?
Well, roses tend to
wilt in her presence.
But don't worry about it.
She actually
canceled her trip.
She's too busy.
This is her idea
of an apology.
1,000 bucks?
Mmm-hmm.
I wish my mom
apologized like that.
She just bakes cookies.
It takes time
to bake cookies.
This just took
a call to her accountant.
Code Blue.
Her tongue has relaxed,
closing off her airway.
I'll do an oral airway.
I got it.
Intubation kit?
No, 2 milligrams
of naloxone IV.
I think this is an overdose.
Of what?
Hydromorphone.
I don't understand.
She shouldn't have had
this kind of reaction.
Respiration's
at eight per minute.
Take over?
Okay.
Dr. Choi. Dr. Choi.
Yeah.
I know I was off on
my original diagnosis,
but that won't happen again.
You can trust me.
Clarke, you're here to learn.
You're gonna make mistakes,
okay?
Jeff?
I need you to run
this portable bypass,
Satinsky clamps,
and 10 units of packed cells
out to Dr. Halstead
at the marathon
aid station, okay?
"Run"?
You doing anything else?
Ugh. Let's go.
This is gonna be great.
Sorry it's taking so...
I want to call Daddy.
I told you.
Is everything okay?
When can I call him?
He's traveling, Phoebes.
You know that.
I want to go home.
Hey.
Hey, Phoebe,
I promise, the CT is
not gonna hurt, okay?
It's just like
getting your
picture taken.
But, in the meantime,
will you do me a favor?
Can you color a picture
for the doctors' lounge?
Yeah?
Because of the marathon,
the hospital's way
busier than usual,
but it shouldn't
be too much longer.
Okay.
And do you mind if
we speak for a moment?
Sure.
Great.
Hey. I'll be right outside,
okay, sweetie?
So, you indicated
in Phoebe's chart that
her father was deceased.
I'm wondering
why she would
want to call him?
David had a massive coronary
and died a few months ago.
I haven't had
the heart to tell her.
I am so sorry.
He was away
on business.
I feel awful for lying,
but I just know
that she'll be crushed,
and I don't know how
to break it to her.
Yeah, um,
well, you know,
we have a really great doctor
that may be able
to help with that.
But, in the meantime,
just hang in there.
We'll get Phoebe
up to CT soon, okay?
Okay, thank you.
Yeah.
Dr. Rhodes?
Dr. Halstead
has a patient in the field
with a torn aorta.
He's putting him on
a portable bypass.
Seriously?
A portable bypass?
You can't regulate
blood flow to the brain.
Well, you can debate
the medicine
with Dr. Halstead
when he gets here.
Believe me, I will.
There's blood in the tube.
Saturation's 75%.
Must be
a pulmonary laceration.
We got to pack his lung
and get the blood
out of that tube
before he drowns.
You wanna pack the chest
when I suction the tube?
With what free hand?
I'll suction the tube.
I'll pack the chest.
Give me the suction.
Noah, grab both sides,
and try to keep 'em open.
All right.
My wrist is cramping up.
If you let go on the ribs,
I'm done.
Come on, man, pull.
I'm trying.
Hang in there.
Argh, it's closing
on my wrist.
I can't hold this.
Don't let go. Don't let go!
Come on, Noah, pull!
All right.
I got most of the blood.
Sats at 95%.
Ribs, ribs,
grab the ribs.
Got it.
Guys, guys, he's here.
Sorry it took so long.
Oh, man.
I need two clamps.
How long's it been?
Seventeen minutes.
Three to go. Hurry up.
Mrs. Barlow?
You gave us a scare.
How are you feeling?
Oh,
I'm much better,
Doctor. Thank you.
Your reaction to
the pain medication
surprised us,
because that dose
shouldn't have
been an issue for you.
Have you been taking
everything as prescribed?
I didn't mention it before,
because it's...
It's so embarrassing,
but I accidentally spilled
some pills into the toilet,
so I haven't taken everything
I was supposed to.
Mrs. Barlow, skipping doses
is very dangerous.
You should have
called your doctor.
Well,
I certainly know better now.
I won't let it happen again.
There's one other thing.
I was reviewing your labs,
and some of
the numbers indicate
that you haven't been eating
as well as you should.
No one,
except my late husband,
has ever accused me
of being a good cook.
Well, wait till you
taste the hospital food.
Excuse me.
Dr. Charles, I have a patient
I'd like you to evaluate.
She's 74, lives alone,
and, for some reason,
hasn't been taking her meds.
Her blood work indicates
she's undernourished.
It might be
dementia or depression.
I'm just not sure.
I'll have a little chat.
Shoot me her chart?
Yeah. Olga Barlow.
Treatment Five.
Great. Thank you.
Paramedics are close.
All right, we're good to go.
Circuit's primed.
Let's get some
more blood in him.
It's infusing.
Come on, Ignacio.
And it's up.
Time. How long
has he been clamped?
Twenty-four minutes.
Damn.
Mrs. Barlow?
I'm Dr. Charles.
How are we doing today?
Oh, pleased to meet you,
Dr. Charles.
Dr. Choi mentioned
that you were having
some trouble with
your medication,
and he asked me
to look in on you.
Of course, but this is
all just a big mistake.
Tell me, how did
you end up here today?
I spilled some pills
and didn't take
all my medication.
It's so boring.
Huh.
Charles.
That's an English
name, isn't it?
Yes, it is.
Mmm.
My late husband,
Robert, was English.
He had a Charles
on his mother's side.
Have you been? Hmm.
Not for a while.
Well, when I was
quite a bit younger,
Robert and I took
the final voyage
on the RMS Queen Elizabeth
across the pond from New York.
Wow. That sounds
like quite a trip.
Yeah. Oh, it was.
1968.
There was a sense
of design back then
that you just don't see today.
Now it's...
It's all screens,
and technology, and...
People have forgotten
the importance of style,
haven't they?
Boy, you can
say that again.
I'm sorry for
running on like that.
Was there something else
you wanted to ask me?
You know,
I think that I'm all set.
Thank you. It was
so nice to meet you.
It was really nice to
meet you, Dr. Charles.
So, in my opinion,
Mrs. Barlow is competent
and definitely
a bit of a charmer.
One who's not taking her meds
or eating properly.
Not suicidal.
Not depressed,
as far as I can tell.
I mean, what she is,
is she's nostalgic for
a more refined culture.
Which is a far cry
from eating cat food.
She told you
she was eating cat food?
Look at her blood work.
Raised taurine level.
That's the telltale sign.
I thought she was
lying about eating regularly,
but cat food?
Uh, this happens
when money's tight.
You know,
elderly woman,
fixed income.
She'd be way too embarrassed
to say anything.
And what about
dropping her pills
in the toilet?
You think that's
a lie, too?
Oxycodone, sildenafil, benzos,
all have a very high
street value, buddy.
You think this
sweet old lady's
selling them to get money?
Sweet old lady in need, man.
I've seen it before.
You know what
the sad part is?
It's that even
selling her meds,
she doesn't seem to
be making ends meet.
Twenty-five-year-old male.
High-velocity impact.
Found with aortic
and lung lacerations
from a rib.
Aortic cross clamp in place.
Bleeding controlled.
We've got eight units of
packed cells in the field
via a portable bypass
in progress at 3 liters.
Portable bypass?
That your call?
It was our only option.
I got it from here.
Sharon Goodwin,
this is Lawrence.
Wonderful to meet you.
Sorry it's under such
difficult circumstances.
I'm gonna leave
you two alone.
Um, I don't have much time.
It's a busy day for us.
I understand.
Now, uh, would you
prefer that I call you
Ms. Goodwin or Sharon?
Oh, Sharon is fine.
Sharon,
before we go any further,
are you sure that
you don't want to
try to reconcile?
While legal separation
is not a divorce,
it is a big step
down that road.
We're past
trying to reconcile.
I know we talked a little bit
about this on the phone,
but pending court approval,
you and your spouse
are agreeing to live
independent of each other,
both financially
and physically.
Which we have been
for months.
Illinois law allows a spouse
who is without fault
to receive reasonable support
and maintenance
while parties
are living apart.
We would need to ask the court
to determine that amount.
I don't want
anything from him.
In that case,
when you're ready,
I need you to sign
at the bottom of both copies.
Ms. Kastpen?
Yes?
I'm Dr. Charles.
This is Dr. Reese.
Nice to meet you.
Dr. Manning mentioned
that you were struggling
with how to
break the news
of your husband's
death to your daughter.
Oh, yes.
We were thinking
that if we all sat down,
we might be able to help you
come up with a plan to
how to best discuss
this with Phoebe.
You know, I really appreciate
you're trying to help,
but the timing
is just all wrong.
Phoebe is scared
enough just being here.
I can't add stress
to her right now.
If you'll excuse me.
I think
she's lying to us.
The pause before answering,
throat clearing,
and hand-to-face activity
all point to her
not being truthful.
Just so you know,
all that behavioral cue stuff
about how to spot liars,
bunch of hooey.
Having said that,
I think you're
absolutely right.
She's hiding something.
What do you think?
I think an ED doc
opened him up in the field.
Can you repair it?
Well, it's not every day
that you see
a rib in the aorta,
but I'm gonna try to
repair it by graft.
Whether there is impaired
brain activity or paralysis,
well, that remains to be seen.
You must be one hell
of a poker player.
Why is that?
It was a hell of a gamble.
What's the word?
We had to try.
Did we?
Mrs. Barlow, there are
some things about your case
that are puzzling.
I was hoping I could
ask you a few questions.
Of course.
As I mentioned, your labs
show you're a little
undernourished.
I just want to make sure
you're getting enough to eat.
I am.
Good.
I'm glad to hear that.
Because sometimes
people skip meals
when they're finding it
hard to get by.
"Get by"?
Well, when money's an issue.
We've seen some patients
who felt they had no choice
but to sell their medications.
Are you insinuating...
No, ma'am.
I'm just trying to
understand these results.
I have no need
to sell anything,
and I resent
the implication.
Of course.
Mrs. Barlow,
I just want you to know
that there are
resources available for you,
if you need anything.
I already told you.
I just... I dropped my
pills down the toilet.
That's all there is to it.
Yes, ma'am.
Forgive me.
Olga Barlow,
you gave me such a fright.
Ruth, my hair.
I look terrible.
You look fine.
I've just brought you
your purse,
and wanted to see
if there was
anything you needed.
I'm sorry, Doctor.
I'm her neighbor.
Hi.
And you mustn't
worry about Princess.
I fed her.
I'll give you two some
privacy, Mrs. Barlow.
Excuse me.
Now, what's going on?
She won't admit to it.
Well, I'm not surprised.
People think sex
is a touchy subject.
Believe me,
money is a lot touchier.
Dr. Charles.
I've been doing
a little digging
into Phoebe's mother,
Michelle Kastpen.
I can't find anyone
in or around Chicago
with that name.
Hey. Phoebe's
CT results are back.
Mom has clearly not
given us a full history.
Ms. Kastpen, is there
any other information,
anything at all,
about Phoebe's
medical history that you'd
like to share with us?
Not that I can think of.
The reason we ask
is that Phoebe's CAT scans
revealed several
healed skull fractures.
These explain
Phoebe's hearing loss.
They're also
possible indicators
of child abuse.
Wait, you think it was me?
I would never do
anything to hurt Phoebe.
The way this works,
Ms. Kastpen,
is that unless you
can shine some light
on your daughter's injuries,
we don't really
have any choice
but to contact
the authorities.
I would never, never...
You have to understand
how we're seeing it
from our perspective.
It wasn't me.
I lied. I'm divorced.
It was my ex.
Phoebe would get hurt
when she was with him a lot.
A sprained ankle.
A broken arm.
Too many things to be random.
Did you ever confront him?
I tried, but he has money.
He out-lawyered me.
So, it sounds to me like
your ex-husband's still alive.
I felt powerless,
so I took her.
You kidnapped your daughter?
I had to.
You can't call the police.
Please.
They'll just send Phoebe back,
and I don't know what
he's gonna do to her.
You have to
protect my daughter.
Please. Please.
This woman has
given us a false name
and admitted to
kidnapping her daughter.
But I think she's
finally being honest.
She is legitimately concerned
for her daughter's safety.
Just because she thinks
she's telling the truth,
Doctor,
doesn't necessarily
mean that she is.
Yeah, but if she is,
I'd hate to tear
this child away
from her mother.
It's not our job to
figure out what the truth is.
If we suspect abuse,
it's our duty to report it
and let the proper
authorities sort it out.
Hey. Any news?
I'm headed back up to check.
We found Ignacio's family.
They're in St. Louis.
Be here in four hours.
Let's hope it's
a happy reunion.
S, s. In Chicago Med.
Allow me.
Oh, thank you.
Thank you, Doctor.
Ruth, wasn't it?
Uh, yes.
Those are beautiful earrings.
Emerald?
Oh, yes. Thank you.
And nice bag.
I noticed the one
you brought Mrs. Barlow
was a real beauty, too.
Well, we both have a weakness
for nice things.
Ah.
The thing...
Never mind. Excuse me.
No, no.
What were you going to say?
Um...
It just doesn't fit.
How Mrs. Barlow can afford
to spend so much on a purse.
Why?
Please.
I could be wrong,
but I think she's
economizing on food.
Not eating.
You think Olga has
financial issues?
Well, what do you think?
I don't know, but now
that you mention it...
Yes?
I was over there
for coffee last week,
and when I went
to get the sugar,
all she had were
those little packets
that you get in restaurants.
Is it possible Mrs. Barlow
might feel pressured
to keep up
appearances with you?
Oh, dear. I...
I... I may have given Olga
the wrong impression.
How's that?
Actually,
I don't have that much.
It's my son.
My son sends me
nice things.
Uh...
And you never told
Mrs. Barlow that?
No.
I see you care about her,
and you want to help her.
I do.
Then please,
let her know the truth.
Excuse me.
Hi. Can we speak
for a moment?
Mmm-hmm.
You made the call.
Yes. It is our duty
in these types of cases
to alert the authorities.
Now may be a good time
to have a conversation
with Phoebe to prepare her.
Oh, I'll get that.
Well, that's a pretty drawing.
I used to color better.
Yeah? What changed?
I don't know.
Hey, Phoebe, you mind if
I take a look at your hands?
Mmm-hmm.
All right.
All right, now,
can you squeeze my fingers
as hard as you can?
What are you doing?
Just making sure
we haven't missed anything.
How about with this hand?
He hasn't woken up yet.
It could be a sign of
impaired brain function.
It's too soon
to make that call.
You do a Babinski?
It's your patient.
I didn't want to overstep.
What did I do
to this guy?
Listen, Will,
he's still got a good amount
of paralytic in him.
He's also
acidotic and cold.
You can't expect
a good reaction just yet.
Hi.
So, after I observed
the weakness
in Phoebe's hand,
I ran some tests on
the blood work we took,
and the results showed
an explanation for
her hearing loss.
She has a genetic condition
called Osteopetrosis.
What?
It's a bone disease
that can cause
progressive hearing loss.
It also explains
the carpal tunnel
that's causing
weakness in her wrists.
But I don't have it,
and neither does her father.
It just means that
you and her father are
both genetic carriers.
Is she gonna be deaf?
Not necessarily.
We've had some success
in treating the condition
with bone marrow
transplants.
Okay.
What aren't you telling me?
Osteopetrosis makes bones
abnormally dense
and prone to breakage,
which explains
her skull fractures.
What I'm trying to say is
I don't think
she was ever abused.
Oh, my God.
He didn't hurt her?
What have I done?
Ms. Kastpen?
I'm Detective Olinsky.
What have I done?
Still hasn't come to.
Dr. Halstead,
we saved his life.
For what?
To lie like this
on a ventilator
for God knows how long?
We don't know
that's the case.
He's been off sedation
for an hour and a half.
He should be coming around.
Okay, so let's give
him a little nudge.
Flumazenil,
0.2 milligrams IV push.
Wait. We don't know
his history.
If he's an alcoholic
or on a benzo,
he could seize.
That's not gonna happen.
Please.
Yes, Doctor.
We need to know
his mental status.
Hold on.
Mr. Garza, I'm Dr. Rhodes.
You're at Chicago Med.
You were in an accident.
You were hit by a car.
Do you need me
to translate?
Oh. Uh, no. Thank you.
Good.
Nice.
You got a good grip there.
Mr. Garza, I want you
to push your foot down,
like you're stepping
on the gas pedal of a car.
Okay. How about this?
Mr. Garza,
can you move your toes?
Yes.
You're a rock star,
Mr. Garza.
You did great.
Now we're gonna let
you get some rest.
I'm so sorry.
No, it's... It's okay.
He's okay.
Then why...
I'm just so relieved.
Oh...
Hey.
Good job getting
the bypass out there.
It's okay, baby.
Don't go.
Stay.
No, don't go,
Mommy! Don't go!
Baby, it's okay, it's okay.
Mom, come back! Mom!
No! Come back, Mommy!
Mom!
She thought she was
doing the right thing.
She risked everything
and lost everything
to get her daughter
out of harm's way,
and we're
sending her to jail.
I understand
why she did it,
but couldn't she
have had a doctor
evaluate Phoebe
before going on the run?
She messed up
so many lives.
Yeah, but...
It still feels wrong.
I know.
So, this was all just about
keeping up with the Joneses.
It was a good
catch, Dr. Choi.
A new one for me.
Pride.
It can literally kill you.
I guess sometimes
that's all we
have left, right?
Someone's happy.
Ignacio is going to make it.
Yes!
We did that.
Man, you really
stepped up today.
You impressed me out there.
Hold up. Is...
Is that a compliment?
'Cause as I remember it,
you were like,
"Don't you even think about
putting in that chest tube."
Yeah. You know what?
I was proud of you,
and now you're
just being a dick.
Bye-bye.
Nothing, Mom.
I just wanted to say
thanks for the check.
No, I... I...
I appreciate it, Mom.
I appreciate everything.
All right, bye.
Seriously?
I thought you were
pissed off at her.
Yeah, I was.
I mean,
you know, she wasn't...
She wasn't a great mom,
but she tried her best.
I realize that.
Okay.
Uh...
Anyway,
I've got all this money,
so where do you want to eat?
I hear there's this
great place uptown
with a lobster mac to die for.
All right.
Rough day?
You could say that.
Yeah.
Wait. I thought
you had a win today?
Only thing I did right
today was double-time
some heavy stuff
across the city.
Same thing any grunt
could do in basic.
Jeff...
Whatever you did,
it saved a life.
That's something.
Come in.
Hey, I just thought
you might like to know
that Dr. Halstead's
bypass patient,
he's doing well.
Oh.
Good. So now you can finish
your marathon shift.
Go home, Dr. Rhodes.
Put your feet up.
Oh, actually, I had something
a little different in mind.
What about you?
Uh, just gonna go home.
Okay.
You know, this place
I'm going, it's... It's...
It's pretty fun.
Maybe you want to join me?
A few more feet,
you can officially check
marathon off your bucket list.
Yeah, "officially" is
a bit of a stretch.
Hold that thought.
Doesn't get more
official than this.
With a time of 10 hours
and six minutes,
Dr. Nina Shore has just set
a new marathon record.
There it is.
Ah.
Now, this is different.
Dr. Downey
loved this place.
He said it was as close
as you could get
to the real thing.
Aloha!
Oh!
Oh, thank you.
It's real.
Any friend of Connor's.
Ms. Goodwin, this is Keoni.
He owns this place.
It's a pleasure to meet you.
Pleasure's all mine,
and it's good to see you, bro.
It's good to see you, too.
Enjoy.
Thank you.
Do you know
what aloha means?
Isn't that what they say
when you get off the plane?
I thought it meant welcome.
No?
Not exactly.
Okay.
Uh...
Aloha actually means
to consciously manifest life
joyously in the present.
Hmm.
Well, in that case, aloha.
Aloha.
There it is.
Excellent.
Yeah, right?