There's been a
collapse in the subway tunnel.
Over here! I'm Jack Dayton.
Over there. He works for me.
His lung is likely collapsed.
Let's get him out here.
No, no, no.
If we're gonna save him,
we got to do it right here.
I mean, what do you do if you
can't get the only drug
that'll treat an infection?
Start calling around.
Everyone
I talk to is out.
I know someone
that has access to everything.
You're talking like
some kind of drug dealer.
But no one can
ever know about this.
In the future, maybe at least
page me before administering
a very high dose...
Six milligrams is well within
the standard of care, I...
The standard of care
is not some blanket template
you follow without any regard
for the person
you're supposed
to be helping.
I just don't always trust
my own instincts.
I can promise you, you will
get there. I don't have
a shred of doubt in my mind.
Good morning.
Hi. So night shift left us
three patients.
A bipolar woman, 38.
Checked herself in.
A gentleman with CTE, 64.
Got booted from his board
and care home.
Let me guess,
smoking violation?
Ugh, yeah.
And lastly,
a 31-year-old psychotic
in an extrapyramidal state.
You know, that gentleman
looks like we probably
just have to rebalance
his meds, but these other two,
I think we're gonna
have to admit.
Agreed,
but once again,
there are no beds
in the psych unit
and all the other local EDs
are at capacity.
Well, we got to branch out.
Check the TRCs. See if they
have any room.
Every morning
it's the same thing.
Psych patients
just stashed
around the ED.
You know, my parents,
where they come from,
no one talks about psychiatry.
In fact, they're not convinced
I'm even a real doctor
because my brother is
a pediatric spine surgeon.
So they see him helping kids
walk again, but me...
Pretty good argument.
I'm not even treating
patients,
just shuffling them off
somewhere else.
Will. Will. Hey.
Good morning.
So I reached out to Rose
Fremont, our UTI from
the other day,
and I know what
happened didn't happen...
That's okay.
I've been thinking
about her too.
How's she doing?
She's amazing.
She said she finally
feels like herself again.
That's really great news.
Yeah, you know, still,
we never buy drugs
from that dealer again.
Or any dealer.
Hey.
You and Will
are getting close.
Uh, yeah.
I guess, we are.
Hey, where are you headed?
Treatment four.
No, I need you
in treatment six.
Archer's already there.
Yeah, oh,
treatment seven then.
Dr. Halstead,
I need you in treatment four.
I'll send you the chart.
Will, Will,
Will, scratch that.
I already got it.
Wait. Hold...
Mags, Mags,
I'll be in four.
Yeah.
April.
Ethan.
Uh...
And you got
the chart, so...
I got to go.
Hey, I'm Dr. Choi.
Brock Huntley.
Nice to meet you, sir.
So, uh...
Sorry.
I should've
introduced you.
Dr. Choi and I used to
work together.
He is an excellent physician.
Thank you.
Um, so, Brock,
what's going on?
Feeling pretty lousy, sir.
For how long? Days, weeks?
More like months.
Yeah, that's why
we're here.
Brock has been
seen by a number
of internists at my group.
Fever, headache,
abdominal pain, diarrhea,
high white count.
It sounds like viral
gastroenteritis.
That is what we thought
as well, but bugs usually
come with vomiting.
That hasn't been
a symptom.
It's a little tender.
Sorry about that.
Sometimes small talk's
a good distraction.
So what do you do, Brock?
Uh, I'm a mechanic.
I'm in between jobs.
I work on Honeywell AGT1500s.
It's a gas
turbine engine, right?
Yeah.
High powered.
So, Dr. Choi,
what do you think?
Well, the, uh, diffused
belly pain could indicate
a surgical issue,
but the other symptoms
like headache, diarrhea...
They don't support it.
No.
All right, Brock, next steps.
Labs. Stools, ultrasound, CT,
the works.
As long as we figure this out.
I'll be right back.
Hey, Ethan.
Dr. Choi.
Yeah.
Hey, I'm really sorry
for the sneak attack.
I just was worried
that reuniting
in a treatment room
would be awkward,
which it was.
Yeah, a little, uh,
but, uh, no harm, no foul.
I hope not.
I know using Maggie to skirt
the system and cherry-pick
a doc must be a headache
for the ED chief.
Yeah, but good thing
it's not me anymore.
My choice.
April Sexton in the flesh.
Dr. Marcel.
Man, it's been forever.
Maybe for you.
I mean, for me,
it feels like
yesterday.
Oh, that's because
it was.
I saw you. The Trib,
the "Sun-Times".
The tunnel collapse.
Mmm-hmm.
I got to say, the heroics
were not a surprise,
but I didn't see
transplant surgeon coming.
Yeah, well, I guess
like you, I was looking
for something more.
Excuse me.
It's the ICU.
It's really nice
to see you.
You too.
Hey. I came in
to say good morning
and suddenly alarms
start going off.
Nathaniel,
what's going on, bud?
I can't breathe.
Sats are into the 80s
and dropping.
Heart rate's climbing.
Yeah, he's in
respiratory distress.
Cannula, mask him.
High flow O2 please.
I was in with his sister
yesterday, telling jokes,
laughing. He was fine.
And call anesthesia.
We're intubating him.
CT PE to follow.
What's happening?
I'm gonna find out, okay?
Lift your chin up.
There you go.
He's looking better.
I gave him two
of benztropine.
Gonna let him rest a bit
and then discharge him.
How's it going with those
transfers? You know, the
overnight intake?
I found them each
a spot in therapeutic
residential centers.
Oh, excellent.
They are successfully
shuffled off
to someplace else.
Dr. Charles, I just sent you
treatment three.
Good Samaritan found him
wandering in the street.
No phone, no wallet,
no ID, and very confused.
Thanks, Mags.
Right.
Where am I?
You are in the hospital.
Um... I'm Dr. Charles,
and this is Dr. Cuevas.
Uh, what's your name?
I, um...
I don't know.
Will.
Hey, you.
Hey.
I was hoping
I'd run into you.
Odds were in your favor.
I've been working a bunch
of double shifts.
Money troubles again.
Wait. What?
I heard you bought
a whole apartment building.
Long story.
What's... What's up
with your gig?
Oh, well, COVID burnout.
You know, hit the practice
really hard.
And you know what?
It's been a challenge,
but really rewarding.
I'm proud of you.
Thank you, Will.
So he doesn't know his name,
age, where he lives,
or how he ended up
wandering the streets.
I mean, you think
he's unhoused?
I'm not really
getting that vibe.
His clothes are clean,
they fit. Fingernails
are trimmed.
Well, he's clearly anxious
and in some sort of
dissociative state.
Could be drug induced
or self-medicating
mental illness.
Yeah, perhaps.
I mean, unless it's a stroke.
I didn't see any
facial paralysis
or muscle weakness.
Hmm, I was thinking
more atypical TIA.
Okay, well, since right now
it could be anything,
I'm gonna order head CT,
labs, tox screen,
chest X-ray, EKG,
EEG to check for subclinical
seizures, and CT to check
for stroke.
Excellent.
Sounds like a plan.
Okay.
Excuse me. Please,
could you help me?
My name is Elinor Whipple.
I fell last night.
Actually, this watch
that my son gave me
called the paramedics.
He lives in Oregon.
Oh, boy. Well,
are you all right?
You feeling better?
Oh, yeah.
I just have
a bruise on my hip.
You know, the doctor
discharged me hours ago
and the van was supposed to
drive me home, but it's been
a long time. Nobody's come.
Let me, uh... Let me see
if I can figure out
what's going on.
Okay? Um...
Thank you.
Mags, do you have
an update on Elinor
Whipple's transportation?
Medicar still hasn't come?
No.
I'm gonna make a call
and light a fire.
Thank you.
Maggie, the charge nurse,
is gonna call the company
and see what's happening.
I just want to go home.
My husband spent
his final weeks in hospice.
I don't like hospitals.
Why don't we see
if we can find you
a place to, um...
To sit while you wait.
Oh, thank you.
Okay?
I'm Dr. Charles, by the way.
Thank you, Dr. Charles.
Male, late 20s.
Stoned out of his mind.
Picked him up talking to a
mailbox. Wouldn't give a name.
Oh, my God, Devon.
You know him?
Yeah, sort of.
From med school.
Wait, wait!
Get off!
I'm out of here.
Come at me! Let's go!
Get back. Get back.
Hey.
Get off, man.
Taser, Taser!
No. Don't hit Ethan.
Pile on.
All right.
Ethan, are y'all
all right?
I'm good. Dean got
the worst of it.
Hey.
Wait. That's Devon. Seriously?
Guy who just went all
"Incredible Hulk"
is the dealer we're using
to treat Rose?
It gets worse. His tox report
just came back. Cocaine laced
with PCP.
PCP? Hold on, you told me
this guy was into party pills
and medicine cabinet pharma.
I thought he was.
We had to use him,
though. I mean, Rose
needed those meds.
She could've died.
We didn't have another play,
but that was then.
I mean, now, we have to
call the police.
Laced drugs? Come on.
Whoever gave them to Devon,
they have to be
off the street.
If we call PD,
they're gonna ask Devon
a lot of questions
and my name could come up.
Vanessa, as long as
there's a bad batch out there,
someone else could OD.
No, you're right.
We call CPD.
If I would've known Devon
was involved in hard drugs,
I would've
never suggested
going to him.
Hey. I know.
I think they
might be a thing.
Keep walking, Doris.
Easy, easy.
You're lucky
I tired him out for you.
Yeah, the way you went at him
with your face and ribs,
that was impressive.
Even smiling hurts,
all right?
'Cause your jaw's swollen.
Let me see your ribs.
All right, I got it.
I got it. I got it.
All right.
Flesh wound?
Oh, yeah, yeah.
Nice one.
Hey, Zach, do a work up.
No, no. First year
resident, no, no.
I don't think so.
Hey, come on.
We're still a teaching
hospital, Dean.
It's already been
a day, okay?
Just order me X-rays
for my ribs and a CT
for my jaw, will you, please?
Yeah, you got it, man.
Hey.
Man. I go upstairs
to deliver a baby
and miss all the action.
How you doing?
I'll live.
Okay.
If you need anything,
I'm around.
All right.
This is Nathaniel's
chest X-ray from
when he was admitted.
The left chest had
a hemopneumothorax.
The right chest,
however, was okay. Gene.
Now, his chest X-ray
from 30 minutes ago.
Night and day.
Wait, this happened
in 36 hours?
It caught me by surprise too.
Yeah.
Peter.
I'm sorry to interrupt.
Peter, what's going on?
Nathaniel has given
permission for the hospital
to share his medical
information with Mr. Dayton.
Now, I know this
is unorthodox,
but I built that train.
Nathaniel, he's been
with me for years
and my team,
they're more than
just employees.
They may as well be family.
Legal signed off on it.
Okay. Peter, thank you.
Bilateral multi-lobar
consolidation.
Heavy scarring,
inflammation.
Which means?
His lungs are destroyed,
but this much damage
this fast, how?
Only thing I can think of...
Train's batteries.
Mmm-hmm.
From when he
was trapped in
the conductor's compartment.
The tunnel was full
of moisture. Leaky lithium ion
batteries plus moisture?
Hydrofluoric acid.
Highly corrosive, toxic.
Nathaniel inhaled it.
So what's the fix?
At this point, a lung
transplant.
I'll put Nathaniel
on the list immediately.
In the meantime,
I'd like to get him off
the vent and onto ECMO.
Take some pressure
off his lungs.
I'm afraid ECMO's
not an option.
Tubing shortage.
The machine's down
until the shipment arrives.
When will that be?
Maybe two days, three?
People spend weeks
on ventilators.
Sometimes longer, right?
So maybe we're in good shape.
We're not.
Nathaniel's lungs
are so injured,
the vent's barely doing
the job and I've only
got a little wiggle room
with the settings
without risking
further damage.
Even with the vent,
we're sinking.
Fever notched up a bit.
I've just been laying here,
but I'm spent.
Your body's at war.
Unfortunately,
I don't know yet
what it's fighting against.
The labs and scans
didn't show anything?
Nothing definitive.
A mild enlargement
of the liver and spleens,
swollen lymph nodes,
global intestinal
inflammation.
So all viral symptoms,
but not pointing
in a specific direction.
Brock, you've got
an extensive
vaccination history.
I see the requirements
like mumps, measles, rubella.
Some optionals like flu and
COVID, but there are a few
that are, um...
only for international travel.
Have you left
the country recently?
No. Never.
I'm from Chicago.
I, uh...
I've been in Georgia
since graduating high school.
First, the south of Atlanta
then near the coast.
I just recently
moved back home.
Should we bring
in Infectious Diseases?
Uh, I could call a fellow,
but if there's been no travel,
then, uh, I don't think
she'll have anything
new to add.
Where do we go
from here then?
More labs.
Blood and stool cultures,
a mono spot test,
but I'll definitely put you on
empiric broad-spectrum
antibiotics.
Hopefully, we can
get that fever down.
So our mystery patient,
EEG and CT, both negative.
He didn't have a seizure
or stroke. Tox also negative,
so not drugs.
His electrolytes were
a little off, but I'm
not buying amnesia.
No, me neither.
I just hung a second bag of
fluids. He seems more alert
than when he came in.
Thank you, Nancy.
Good.
How you doing?
It's, uh...
It's Dr. Charles
and Dr. Cuevas again.
Do you remember us
from before?
Kind of.
Do you know
where you are?
Looks like the hospital.
Emergency room.
Mmm-hmm. And do you
know who you are?
Harris. I'm...
I'm Harris Bevel.
And how old
are you, Harris?
28.
And where do you live?
Wrigleyville.
Near the ballpark.
Wow. That's
the north side of town.
Do you know how you ended up
here in the West Loop?
No. I'm not sure.
I don't know why
I would be outside.
I... I don't know
why I would take that risk.
What do you mean by that?
Taking the risk.
It's dangerous outside.
It's... It's hard to hide.
You got to always have
a hiding spot.
Okay. Okay.
Yeah, well, I noticed you
haven't really touched your
sandwich. What? No appetite?
Uh... Didn't have
the energy. I'm...
I'm tired. I don't sleep
that much.
So is that having
a hard time falling asleep,
having a hard time
staying asleep...
Yeah, yeah, that one.
Every night, 3:00 a.m.,
I'm wide awake thinking,
you know, worrying.
About anything
in particular?
No. Just...
everything.
Yeah. I... I get it.
That happens to me
sometimes too.
It does?
Oh, yeah.
Sometimes the world just...
moves too fast. You know?
What about family, Harris?
Anyone live nearby?
Uh, no. Tucson.
Any friends?
I have... I haven't
seen them in a while.
Okay. You know what?
That's been really
helpful. Um...
Dr. Cuevas and I are gonna
step out for bit.
Do you mind hanging out
for a little while?
No.
We'll be back soon, okay?
If I were a gambler,
I'd bet big
on Harris having
undiagnosed depression.
I don't disagree.
I don't think
he's a suicide risk,
but I'm just not crazy
about discharging him, either.
Yeah, me too.
One problem,
psych unit's full,
and I used up all the TRC
options this morning.
I'm gonna call up
there anyway.
I mean, you never know.
There could be
somebody's on a hold
who's expiring today,
getting discharged early.
It's worth a shot.
Okay. I'll call
Harris' family. See if
I can get more of a history.
Excellent.
I need some help,
Dr. Charles.
Patients are piling up.
I need trauma two back.
Elinor's still here?
Yeah, I called Medicar
three times. They're
short on drivers.
Skip them all together
and call Uber or taxi?
No, no, no,
let's stick with
medical transport.
I mean, at least
we know them.
Copy that,
but I still need
the room.
Mags, do you mind if we just
set up a chair for her
in the nursing station?
I know it's not ideal,
but she's just had
a really rough day.
Yeah. I'll find a corner.
Thank you very much.
Okay.
So news?
A pair of lungs
has become available.
Well, that's great.
The donor died in
a car crash. These lungs
are beat up pretty good.
Will they work?
No, not right now,
but I believe with EVLP,
they can be resuscitated.
EVLP?
Yeah.
Ex vivo lung perfusion.
Instead of sitting on ice,
the donor lungs are attached
to a machine that
circulates blood through them.
Well, thank God
for tech, huh?
There is one issue.
The hospital doesn't have an
EVLP machine.
Supply chain disruptions
have led to a delay
in delivery.
Why are we talking about EVLP
if we don't have the machine?
We think that you
and your engineering team
can build an EVLP machine
using parts from machines
that are already
in the hospital.
All the schematics
are online.
Here's the thing, Jack.
If we pass on these lungs,
I don't think
another pair will
become available in time.
So, intricate machinery,
a ticking clock,
and a life at stake.
Yeah. It is
a monumental challenge.
No question.
Well then, I'm on board.
Excellent.
Great.
The police.
Multiple non-displaced
lateral rib fractures.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Heavy contusions.
Yeah, yeah. My jaw.
Dislocated temporomandibular
joint. It needs
to be reduced.
All right.
Grab Ethan.
He's with a patient.
Dr. Halstead and Dr. Taylor
are busy also, but I'm free.
How many jaw reductions
have you done?
Get Asher.
Patients all over
the place.
A battle royale
in the football.
I guess it's just another day
in the ED, huh?
You miss the action?
Yeah. A little.
But really,
I miss y'all.
What are you doing
this evening?
X-ray tech Mike
moonlights as a DJ.
He's spinning tonight.
A bunch of us are going.
We can dance away
the day like we used to.
I'm in.
Yeah?
- Yeah.
- Nice.
Soon.
Okay.
Oh, and apparently we have
a lot to catch up on.
Yeah.
Full disclosure,
it's been a decade
since I've reduced a jaw,
but I just watched one
on YouTube, so see one,
do one, right?
That's not funny.
It's a little funny.
It's not funny.
Okay. Here we go.
Open up.
Let's do this. Ready?
Uh-huh.
One, two...
Uh-huh. Uh-huh.
Damn.
Holy...
You're welcome.
Ah.
Hey.
The empiric antibiotics
aren't doing anything.
His fever's
still ticking up,
now he's having
trouble breathing.
And his belly pain?
It's worse.
Is there anything
in the latest labs?
No. Mono test was negative.
The blood cultures
are unremarkable so far,
but his lymphocytes
were on the high side.
You're thinking lymphoma.
It's been in the back
of my mind all day.
I just didn't want to jump
straight to the worst option.
Well, I still don't.
His sed rate and CRP
are high.
Rising inflammatory
markers could point
to an autoimmune issue.
Kawasaki disease?
Kawasaki primarily affects
children and often presents
with a telltale rash.
That wasn't one of
Brock's symptoms.
Doesn't rule it out, though.
It could just be
an odd presentation.
You know what?
You're right. Uh...
I don't think it's Kawasaki,
but you've given me a thought.
I want to run one more test.
Okay, I like it.
Arterial and venous tubing
from a dialysis machine.
Pumps, oxygenator,
gas and heat exchanger
from an ECMO.
Bits and pieces
of an enclosure bed and
added plastic for the housing.
It's not fancy,
but I think it's gonna work.
You're not sold.
I don't like the housing.
It's too flimsy.
It's got to be stronger.
It can't tear.
It can't collapse.
I mean,
this is what holds
the donor lungs.
Yeah, the lungs,
they're precious.
They have to be
treated as such.
Cradled. Hmm.
Like a newborn.
How about an incubator?
Yeah. Hey, Alex, baby floor.
Get me an incubator.
Donor lungs have arrived.
Great. Let's take a look.
Thank you.
Oh, geez.
It's worse shape
than I thought.
Yeah, but seven, eight hours
of perfusion and aeration...
I'm cautiously optimistic.
How long until the machine
is ready?
Five minutes.
Prep the donor lungs.
Sharon.
We have a situation in the ED.
I cannot believe you put
this hospital in that kind
of legal jeopardy.
And yourselves.
You are to fully cooperate
with these detectives.
Is that understood?
Okay.
What the hell is going on?
Will and Vanessa
went rogue. It's bad.
Bought meds
off a drug dealer.
That guy.
What's your pain level now,
one through ten?
Thirty-five.
IV fentanyl isn't doing it.
The line's working fine.
I've... I've reduced dozens
of jaws. I've treated
thousands of broken ribs.
Pain meds help
those patients, they
should be helping me, yeah?
Here, let me...
Let me see
my chart, please.
Are you kidding me?
Get Dr. Asher in here now.
Oh, hey.
So I was able to free up a bed
in the psych unit for Harris,
so that's good.
That's great, because I think
his depression stems from
childhood PTSD.
Really?
Do you remember
a couple weeks ago that
shooting on Clark Street?
Yeah, that guy
with all the body armor.
Like, 2,000 rounds of ammun...
That was at Wrigleyville
where Harris says he lives.
And it turns out that all went
down in front of Harris'
apartment building.
Oh, my God. So he, like...
He saw the whole thing?
He heard it. I just talked
to his sister in Tucson,
and she said that he locked
himself in the apartment
and laid low in the closet.
So he was never
in danger,
but apparently
since that day,
he's just been off.
Yeah, this morning he said,
"It's dangerous outside.
"You always need to find
a hiding spot."
Talking about mass shootings.
I was in sixth grade
when I had my first
active shooter drill,
and speaking from experience,
they're terrifying.
So it's reasonable to think
that this incident
triggered some deep-rooted
fears that led us
to where we are now.
I mean, in my day,
it was, you know,
it was air raid drill
in case of
nuclear frickin' war.
Duck and cover, you know?
Your patient.
Harris Bevel, he's gone.
What?
I'm gonna call the other EDs
and see if he shows up
at one of them.
I'll reach out to CPD,
ask them to do a welfare check
at his apartment.
I'll call security
in case somebody
saw him leave.
All right.
You underdosed...
You underdosed me.
Come here.
All right, I'm 6'0, 180.
The healthy, responsible
dose of fentanyl for me
would be 150 mics.
You gave me 25.
I'm so sorry.
I got a dislocated jaw
and broken ribs,
not a papercut.
I'll fix it. 150 mics.
I'll put in the order.
Do it.
Oh, now the doctors
are fighting with each other?
I just want to
go home, please.
I'm sorry, Nathaniel.
I know you're uncomfortable.
"Never say die."
That's the spirit.
I'll be right back.
Vent's not cutting it.
Donor lungs have only been
perfusing for four hours.
Is that long enough?
It's gonna have to be.
Please have answers.
I do.
The last lab I ran
was a COVID antibody test.
It was positive.
I have COVID?
No. You had COVID.
Your symptoms now
are the lasting effects
of the virus.
You're thinking MIS.
What's that?
Multisystem inflammatory
syndrome. It's a condition
associated with COVID-19.
It can impact the heart,
lungs, kidneys, brain,
or gastrointestinal organs.
It's rare and it's been
affecting children.
And it's only been found
in a handful of adults.
That's why it wasn't
on our radar until
everything else was ruled out.
Few months ago,
I had a couple weeks
of complete exhaustion.
I COVID tested multiple times,
rapid and PCR,
but the results
were always negative.
I probably had it,
didn't I?
Yeah, very likely.
It threw my world into chaos,
especially at work.
Yeah, I couldn't pull
my weight at all.
Boss got on me.
Colleagues didn't trust me.
It all got to be too much,
so I... I bolted.
I left in the middle
of the night.
Went home.
I'm sorry, man. I, uh...
I know how physical setbacks
can upend your life,
but they don't have to
hold you down forever.
MIS is manageable
with high dose steroids,
and you can get back
to your life.
Return to work in Savannah.
That's where you said you were
most recently living, right?
No, he just said
near the coast.
Oh, my mistake.
Anyway, I'm gonna have
to admit you for treatment
and a nurse will be by
to start the paperwork.
Okay? April, speak
with you a moment?
Is Brock AWOL?
The engine he works on,
the Honeywell AGT1500,
it powers the M1 Abrams.
That's an army tank.
The army's third infantry
uses that tank.
They're based at Fort Stewart,
Savannah, Georgia.
Near the coast.
Third ID also has
soldiers in Africa.
Looking at Brock's vaccination
history, if he had to deploy
there, he could.
I know Brock is army,
but when he said,
"left in the middle
of the night,"
did that mean
he was on active duty
and went AWOL?
That's why
you didn't want me
taking this case.
You thought if I found out,
I'd turn him in.
Can you blame me?
Ethan, when it comes
to the military, you've
rarely looked the other way.
No, guess I haven't.
I assume you're
gonna call the MPs.
No, I'm not.
I wasn't expecting that.
Guess the world's not
so black and white anymore.
Still, skipping out
on a commitment
is a serious offense,
so whether he goes back
to his unit or gets out
of the army altogether,
he's gonna need some help.
I am texting you a contact
to a military attorney.
Will you pass it on to Brock?
Absolutely.
Security didn't see Harris.
You check the local ED?
Hasn't turned up and CPD's
welfare check came up dry too.
Dr. Charles,
just heard back
from Medicar dispatch.
Elinor's van is gonna be
in the main entrance
in three minutes.
What? They told me
Ambo Bay in an hour.
Well, welcome to my world.
The left hand has no idea
what the right hand is doing.
Grab me a wheelchair, please.
Okay.
Elinor, guess what?
Your ride is finally arriving.
I haven't taken
my blood pressure
or cholesterol pills
or my arthritis.
My joints really hurt.
Oh, I'm so sorry.
Well, you know what?
You're gonna be home
before you know it and you
can take all your meds then.
When will that be?
Now. Right now.
Come on.
Well, it's about time.
I have been waiting here
since last night.
You can't do this to people.
You are absolutely right,
which is why we need to
get you out of here
as quickly as possible.
Did she eat or drink
anything today?
I don't know.
I reached out to Upton
at CPD.
She thinks even
with Devon's statement
and your confession,
the state's department
is unlikely to pursue charges.
That's a relief.
Yeah.
Hopefully, we dodged
one bullet.
Just have to see
if the hospital hits us
with disciplinary action.
How's Devon doing?
Drugs are out of his system,
so he's gonna be okay.
For real, Will?
Buying drugs off the street,
and then you just
pull Vanessa into it?
It's a little more
complicated than that.
I mean, you want
to risk your own career,
I mean, that's fine.
But don't...
Maggie.
Don't risk Vanessa's.
Where's the van?
You said it was here.
I'm sure it's just
stuck in traffic.
I'm sure it'll be here
any minute.
I'll call them.
Hey, Elinor. Can you breathe
with me? Slow and deep
just like this.
Yeah, I'm at the main entrance
with Elinor Whipple.
There's no van.
Please do not put me on hold.
How do the donor lungs
look to you?
Better than when
they came in. Riley,
can you open it up, please?
Okay.
Ah, finally.
Look, Elinor.
The van's here.
There it is.
I don't even
care anymore.
I'm so tired.
I just want this
whole thing
to be over.
Uh...
Is that just venting
or is that a threat
of self-harm?
I don't know.
Sorry it took us so long.
It's our eighth
run of the day.
Still got two more.
Okay. Well,
you're here now.
Guess what, Elinor?
It's finally time to go home.
Let's get you
into the van...
You're hurting me. Get away.
We're just trying to help you
get home. Do you want
to get in the van, Elinor?
What's going on?
She's exhausted,
in pain. She missed
her daily medication.
Hasn't eaten all day,
and she's likely dehydrated.
I don't think we can
take her like this.
Yeah, well, I'm not
gonna let you anyway.
Okay, well, at least
we have a bed.
I'll call psych.
Tell them we're
on our way up.
Gave her 0.5 of Xanax
to calm her down.
You know, fluids,
good night's sleep,
getting her back
on her regular med schedule's
gonna help a lot and then
we'll go from there.
We move mountains to be
in a position to open up
space for Harris,
a man seriously
in need of help,
but now he's
in the wind
and Elinor,
who should've
been home hours ago,
is in the psych unit.
Irony sucks.
Yeah.
Pushing the rock uphill
and we're not even
helping people.
We're just creating
patients along the way.
Maybe
my parents were right.
Not much to do
for busted ribs
except ice them down.
Maybe this Velcro binder...
Oh, thanks.
Will help keep
the packs in place.
Yeah.
Moving, breathing,
feels like I'm
being stabbed.
Good times.
I'll just put this
in your bag.
Thank you.
Uh, listen, um...
I'm sorry for blowing up
on you earlier.
It's the pain talking.
Dean, no.
Everything that
happened today,
that is totally on me
and my complicated history
with opiates.
Okay, I know
their dark side,
so my instinct is
to protect people
from getting sucked in.
I know I was
projecting, but...
No, it's okay.
It's okay. I get it.
All right.
Can I give you a hand
with your bag?
Uh...
I'll help you out.
Ah, Dr. Taylor,
Dr. Halstead, a moment.
So the board is not happy
that two of our ED doctors
went to a street dealer.
That was...
I'm sorry...
But they're not going to press
the matter any further.
You're good doctors.
You're fighting
for your patients
and you're being put
in an untenable situation.
And I'm sorry about that.
I... I understand
with your backs
up against the wall
how you'd need to look
for creative solutions.
All I ask is that
in the future,
you give me a heads up.
He's back?
Walked in a few minutes ago.
Have you talked
to him yet?
Briefly, but he specifically
asked to speak to you.
Me?
Yeah.
I mean, he feels rapport
because you connected
with him today,
and I saw it happen.
Nellie, of course the system
is deeply flawed,
and it often feels like
wins can be really hard
to come by,
but you got one today.
So... So good work,
Doctor.
Really.
Thanks.
Dr. Marcel.
Yeah. Hey.
You already started
weaning the vent?
Uh... The new lungs
are working. Uh...
I hope to try an SBT tomorrow,
but we're off to a good start.
Well, internet's
gonna blow up.
I got 30 million
social media followers waiting
to hear how this story ends.
Yeah, Med's gonna
go viral, huh?
Not just Med, Dr. Marcel.
You saved Nathaniel's life
twice now.
Both in spectacular fashion.
What are you on,
by the way?
Twitter, Insta, TikTok?
None of the above.
Ah, well, no worries.
I'll text my PR team.
Set up accounts for you.
In the meantime,
get ready for what comes next.
What's that?
Fame.
Put your hands up! Yeah!
When I'm gone
I'm never really gone
You think you're moving on
But it won't be for long
You'll see
When I'm gone
I'm never really gone
You think you're moving on
But no one's gonna feel like
Feel like me
I'm tired of you
Touch you like I do
Know you never forget
When I'm gone
I'm never really gone
You think you're moving on
But no one's gonna feel like
Feel like me