Previously on ER:
Change the orders.
This means war, you know.
Look, we never talked
about being monogamous.
- Never said about not being monogamous.
- The surgery is gonna take away my crutch.
Who will I be then?
- You're sending me to Africa?
- How the hell did you get here?
I got lots of experience
getting into dumps like this, Vic.
Pow.
Hey, this is Jodie. Leave a
message and I'll call you back.
Hey, Jodes. Yeah, I know it's late
there and you're sleeping and whatnot.
I just wanted to call
and say hi. Yeah.
Yeah, well, board's a mess and
it's the usual bunch of lowlifes.
Yeah, I don't know
when I'm gonna get out.
Yeah, you know, I heard
you got six inches of snow.
Yeah, in April. Go figure, huh?
All right.
I'll call you tomorrow.
I love you. Bye.
Dr. Clemente?
Lateral ducubitus
on the coin ingestion.
Dr. Lockhart said we
could discharge the patient...
- Hey, who are you?
- I'm Jane. I'm an intern.
Oh, yeah? How come I've
never seen you before, Jane?
I don't know. I
mostly work nights.
I work nights. And?
Did you wanna see these?
I thought you were
gone two hours ago.
I'm a dedicated guy.
What can I say, huh?
- Wanna help me stock some shelves?
- Do I wanna help you what?
Dr. Clemente, Dr. Pratt
for you on line two.
Yeah, it's about time.
Hey, Pratt?
I got a patient here, Ottley. Claims
you promised him some Vicodin.
Right, he came in with a
migraine. I resolved it with Imitrex.
Said I'd gave him Vicodin
in case the pain came back.
Yeah, well, I think he's playing
us, drug-seeking and whatnot.
Vic, write him a scrip, man.
Know what I was thinking the other day?
Remember that time on top of the roof?
- And we talked, remember that?
- What is the matter with you?
- Is Jodie okay?
- Yeah, Jodie's great. It's just...
It's just her ex, Bobby. He keeps sending
these weird freaking sympathy cards.
This one, the latest, was filled
with this bunch of little dead goldfish.
- What?
- What do you think he's trying to tell me?
That "sleeps with
the fishes" thing?
Okay, look, I think you should
give Mr. Ottley his drugs...
go home and get
some sleep, all right?
Okay, all right, all right.
Thanks, man. Thanks. Okay.
- Have fun in the motherland, all right?
- Right.
Two Vicodin? That's it?
- Dr. Pratt said...
- Dr. Pratt's not here. Okay, Mr. Ottley?
What if my migraine comes back?
You take those and you call your
regular doctor in the morning, okay?
You got any more questions?
Hey, Jer. What
else you got for me?
Possibly the slowest night on
record. And I am out of here.
- What, you're going?
- Yeah.
- Well, hang on, hang on. I'll go with you.
- Yeah, all right.
Wanna go to Ike's
and grab a beer?
I would, but actually, I'm waiting
for my friend to pick me up.
It's all right. Why don't he
join us? What's the big deal?
Well, it's actually a friend
of the female variety.
Ah, I got you, got you, right.
- Next time.
- Okay.
Yeah. So, well,
I'll be going, then.
- Okay, good night.
- Yeah, take it easy.
You want to take
me on, you little prick?
Want to take me on?
Is that what you want?
Okay, you did it.
I can't believe I'm done.
Happy graduation day. Looking
forward to getting back to work?
I've been back for about a week,
trying to keeping up with my paperwork.
Well...
Here's one thing you don't
need to keep up with anymore.
- Thanks for everything.
- No.
- Abdominal bracing. Ten reps a day.
- Okay.
Lenore Bee, 43, 10-foot fall
from a second-story window.
- Are we here? What are we doing?
- What happened to the 12-year-old?
- Morris, why are you wearing...?
- A Prada suit? No reason.
Is he a doctor? I want him.
Dr. Archie Morris at
your service, ma'am.
Twelve-year-old, MVC, complains
of tenderness over the sternum.
- What's your name?
- Ruthie Pooler.
- You got this?
- Yeah.
And you get to have this too.
And I'd recommend a face mask.
Damn mutt farted all the way here.
Abdominal pain, low-grade fever.
Doc was worried about appendicitis
so he figured he'd get a surgical consult.
The guy seems fine to me.
Kovac. Nice to see you again.
You didn't need to
come in, Grandma.
Of course I needed to.
- My eyes don't hurt.
- I'm checking for signs of head trauma.
I was only going like
two miles an hour.
You were driving? Did
you know about that?
Did you tell your family everything
you did when you were 12?
I did not know.
I wanted to pick up your
prescriptions and still get to school.
Let me see. What
about your parents?
Oh, uh, Ruthie's mother and father
died when she was 6 months old.
- I was about a year, Grandma.
- I'm sorry.
I would be too, if I remembered.
Bob. Ooh, he's a regular wind
tunnel this morning, isn't he?
Ruthie, we have to keep you
here for a while for observation.
Grandma, maybe Dr. Lockhart
can ask you about your cough.
- Sure, we'll check that out.
- What about the dog?
Oh, I think it's his diet.
No, he can't be here, even temporarily.
Is there some place you can keep him?
- So should I call the SPCA?
- Oh.
Bob's 13 years old.
Don't get me wrong,
I support the SPCA.
But they take him, I'm
stuck here a day or two...
and my Grandma
can't get him out...
they might put him down.
So if Bob goes, I go with him.
You're sure you don't want this?
- You'll be sorry.
- Lenore, did you lose consciousness?
No, Dr. Archie, I remember
everything. Cleaning my windows...
- BP's 90/50, 300 of saline.
- Gotta worry about the spleen.
Paramedics came. Kind of cute,
kind of like the two of you guys.
- Is she on meth?
- Okay. Possible left 10th rib fracture.
Whoa. MORRIS: Whoa. Okay.
You know...? You know
what? If you don't mind.
- You want me to hold it?
- What's with the suit, man?
Uh, keep this on the QT, but I took
a job with Ladokern Pharmaceuticals.
Doesn't start till July
1st, but signing bonus.
Always been my dream. Pushing
overpriced meds to people...
who probably don't need them.
Always been my dream
to hold Dr. Archie's coat.
Okay, trauma panel, C-spine, chest,
page Surgery and let's get an ultrasound.
- Will Ruthie's x-rays take a little while?
- Only about 30 minutes.
- Isn't that what you said?
- Something like that.
Can you take another
deep breath in, please?
How long have
you had that cough?
About three or four years. Since
Jimmy Carter was president, I guess.
Since you wish Jimmy Carter
was president, right, Grandma?
I write his name in every time.
Still waiting for Radiology.
Shouldn't be long.
Thanks.
Don't worry, dear. They said
it'd only take about 30 minutes.
Can you remind me again?
When was Jimmy Carter elected?
- I think it was back...
- Mrs. Pooler?
Well, sometime
before this latest bozo.
Oh, thank you.
You know, I don't
much like any of them.
You wanna know why?
I don't think Dr. Lockhart
cares much about our politics.
Stamps.
The price of stamps.
They all keep raising them.
This latest increase,
can you believe it?
Nineteen cents for first class.
Nineteen cents?
Come on, Grandma, you know
it's gone up a lot more than that.
Yeah, I know, I know, but
I don't like to think about it.
If Ruthie has to stay in here...
it won't be more than
a couple of days, right?
Because I really do
want her home for Easter.
- Grandma...
- I think Easter was last week.
Well, I certainly hope not. We're
picking up the ham on Saturday.
I've got four cases backed up in
the O.R. so this had better be real.
I'm Dr. Albright from
Surgery. Does your belly hurt?
- I guess so.
- Here you go.
- Fluid in Morison's pouch?
- That looks like it.
Blood anterior to the bladder
and in the splenorenal recess.
I've seen enough.
Prep her for the O.R.
I think we should get a CT.
- She's unstable, she's anemic.
- Could be chronic.
- She's hypotensive.
- BP normalized with a liter.
She's bleeding in her belly,
end of story. Get her upstairs.
Guess you told her.
Repeat the HemoCue, get a
serum albumin and a urine protein.
- Yeah, but that could take...
- Yes, Haleh, it could.
- I wanted to give you a heads up...
- Steve's in Exam 2? I know.
- Hey.
- It's okay.
- We can get another nurse.
- Luka, thank you, but I can handle it.
Hey, Sam.
They thought it
was appendicitis?
Yeah, I was in a lot of pain on
the drive over, but I feel okay now.
Figured they'd assign
me another nurse.
Just doing my job.
So things are going
pretty well, huh?
Alex writes me a
lot of letters now.
Yeah, I know. Your temp's 99.4.
I'm happy for you, Sam.
New job, new place to live.
What's with the cross?
The chaplain gave it to me.
Are you keeping up
on your Bible studies?
Yeah.
I'm picking up a thing or two.
And it doesn't hurt that those are
the guys who'll watch your back.
Your BP's 124/80.
That's good, right?
It's normal.
You think I'm faking
this pain, don't you?
A lot of guys do just
so they can get out.
- Yeah.
- I can't say I blame them.
If there's one thing
you can say about
jail, it's everything
it's cracked up to be.
One of the docs will
be in to check you out.
Steve Curtis, 35-year-old detainee
with abdominal pain. Rule out appy.
- How'd we get a detainee?
- Pain was 10 out of 10. It's resolved.
Resolved. That's convenient.
I feel I should let you know
that Mr. Curtis and Sam...
Neela.
It's my ex, my kid's dad.
Oh, that must be really
tough on your little boy.
- It is what it is.
- Hello, Mr. Curtis. I'm Dr. Clemente.
Are you feeling any
tenderness at all anywhere?
- No, it's better now.
- His white count's 10,000.
- That's not very impressive, is it?
- Pulse is down after a liter.
- It was pretty painful for a while.
- Oh, yeah?
Could be the stomach flu.
You live in close quarters.
That could run rampant
through half the population.
Close quarters? You're a riot.
Anyway, anyway. Well,
you're feeling better, right?
And Dr. Rasgotra
here will sign you out.
He has a low-grade fever.
We should observe him...
Come on, it's barely a
low-grade fever, please.
- CBC shows a left shift.
- Yeah, but there's no leukocytosis.
I can appreciate these guys wanting
to get out of the can now and then.
But we're not running a timeshare
here, okay? Just release him.
I'm sorry if you didn't want
me to mention your relationship.
It's okay. I just don't
need people protecting me.
You wanna write
up his aftercare?
- No, repeat the CBC.
- Neela, you don't have to do that for me.
I'm not doing it for you.
His history tells me to do it.
- History? What, lies and deception?
- You never really thought he was sick?
I don't know. Clemente
examined him and released him.
- He's a patient like anyone else.
- Repeat the CBC.
So it's not Alzheimer's?
No, but there are similarities
in how it affects people.
And with this type of dementia, it
can sometimes progress very quickly.
But that means
sometimes it can be slow.
Ruthie, let the doctor talk.
There are some concerns, Mrs. Pooler,
about your ability to take care of Ruthie.
- To make decisions, to cook.
- I can cook, I can make decisions.
Like you did about
driving this morning?
And Social Services is
going to wanna talk to you.
Most likely, they're gonna wanna
discuss putting Ruthie into foster care.
They can't do that. You
can't do that, that's not fair.
- We're not gonna let them, are we?
- Ruthie.
I don't take the car much and
I've never hit anything before.
I know everything she
needs, all of her prescriptions.
- Neurontin, 300 milligrams, twice a day.
- Ruthie.
Diltiazem, 240 milligrams a day.
- Stop it.
- Lanoxin, 0.125 milligrams a day.
Stop it now.
Please, please,
don't let this happen.
I don't want anything to change.
Ruthie?
When your mama and daddy died...
I thought that nothing
would ever be the same.
And then we took the
worst possible moments...
and we turned it into years and
years of the best possible moments.
- Didn't we?
- Yeah.
Oh, now, I know that at
least about this one thing...
Grandma is not confused, am I?
- No.
- No, that's my girl.
Oh, yeah.
Okay, so you don't want
me to hold the coat this time.
Had a talk with myself this afternoon.
I said, "Archie, you know what?
You are Dr. Archie Morris. You
don't need no stinking Prada suit."
- What did you spill?
- Coffee.
Little numbing
medicine here, Lenore.
- Morris, what the hell are you doing?
- Peritoneal aspirate.
- Is your name Morris?
- Her crit was stable.
- So I decided to do...
- I've been waiting for half an hour.
I discovered she's been
on lithium for a year.
- Oh, and that changes everything?
- Not quite everything, but...
- Whoa, wait, she's prepped and draped.
- And bleeding internally.
- What's going on?
- Wait, wait.
- The lithium causes nephrotic syndrome.
- Tell me something I don't know.
Her hypertension could be
vasovagal from the rib pain.
- You wanna make that assumption?
- Where am I going?
- Hold on, honey, they're figuring it out.
- She may not need the O.R.
I feel very strongly
about this, Dr. Albright.
- Oh, you do, do you?
- Yes, I do.
Morris!
- Wow.
Straw-colored fluid, not blood. It's
ascites from nephrotic syndrome.
She doesn't need surgery. She
needs steroids and a kidney biopsy.
Double trauma pulling up
if you're looking for action.
No, I gotta head upstairs.
Sorry we missed you in your suit.
- How'd you know about my suit?
- I know everything.
- Everything?
- Dr. Weaver.
Don't suppose I can get you
to look at this open tib-fib in 4?
- Sorry, Chuny, I'm not on today.
- All right.
- Dr. Weaver.
- Dr. Albright.
- Don't worry, I am handling it.
- You haven't called Social Services.
I didn't say that. I said they put
me on hold. I don't have the time...
You really think you're gonna make
things easier by keeping them around?
No.
It's not easy. They've
always had each other.
I know, and it's horribly sad,
but they can't stay that way.
We don't know that a hundred
percent for sure, do we?
This woman has
bilateral lacunar infarcts.
She's gonna decompensate
sooner rather than later.
And what? She's gonna
raise a 12-year-old?
Well, a very mature
12-year-old that seems so far...
to have done a very good
job of holding it together.
They're a family, Luka. Why
aren't we fighting for that?
Kids shouldn't be caretakers.
Sometimes they have to be.
I know in Croatia, you grew
up like Ozzie and Harriet.
I'm sorry, I know you don't
know what Ozzie & Harriet is.
But whatever. The thing is, it's
going to get harder and harder.
That doesn't mean that
they're not better off together.
Like you were better
off with your mother?
- Sorry.
- You know, that girl is healthy.
She's in school. She's
in a loving environment.
The grandmother is still
functioning. She can handle her ADLs.
Yeah, for now, but what...?
If you asked me if I wanted to
be taken away from my mother...
I would have said no.
It's not our job to let
the 12-year-olds decide.
Ruthie? Hey,
Ruthie, stop. Ruthie.
Very mature.
Neela, your repeat blood work's back
on your no doubt unfairly prosecuted...
wrongly incarcerated,
rule-out appy.
- I told you to discharge him, didn't I?
- His white count's up to 12,000.
- So what?
- If his appendix burst on the way...
his pain might be temporarily
relieved. Wait, see if he declares himself.
- I examined him. Here.
- His temperature's up to 100.4.
- Could be an appy.
- Right.
- No way. It's impossible.
- Let me take a look.
The initial exam could've been
in the post-perforation window.
- But he'd have signs of peritonitis.
- Takes a while to develop.
Steve.
- Hey, Steve.
- He's diaphoretic, barely has a pulse.
Two liters, wide open,
put him in Trendelenberg.
- Take the cuffs off, please.
- All right.
- His abdomen's rigid as a board.
- Can't be, it was soft.
- Pressure's only 70 palp.
- He's gonna need a second IV.
- Give him a gram of cefoxitin.
- Are you gonna take him to the O.R.?
If we get pressure up.
He's septic. Dopamine.
- Run a V-tach.
- Okay, get the crash cart.
O.R. 3. They bumped your
lap chole. Hey, how are you?
- I wasn't faking.
- Yeah, I know.
Rasgotra, Barney Fife here wants to
know how long you're gonna detain him.
I was thinking, what?
As long as possible?
Yes, that would be correct.
Yeah?
You've been working
pretty long hours, Vic.
Getting any sleep?
Bobby, I'm not doing this. You
hear me? I'm not doing it, man.
I've been wanting
to talk to you all day.
Even stopped by to drop something off,
but there was this sheriff's van outside.
What did you do, go
and hire protection?
I'm not playing your game.
You hear me? I'm not
playing your little games.
Okay, okay, calm down,
buddy. I'll let you go.
Oh, and one last thing, though.
What time are you
going home tonight?
- Where's Dr. Lockhart?
- We'd have to check.
Please tell her Ruthie Pooler's here
and I'll be in with my grandmother.
- Exam 3?
- Sure.
Any word from Social Services?
I think Dr. Lockhart called them,
but no one has been down yet.
It's just I haven't been
getting any sleep lately.
And the thing is that I've been
really, really needing some.
It's been kind of
rocky since Jodie.
- Is she okay?
- Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah, she's great.
It's just...
I was wondering. Can you write
me a scrip for some Ambien?
- Is herbal tea not working?
- Ha-ha.
- Very funny.
- Did you ask your doctor?
Docs don't have
docs. You know that.
Abby, thank you. Thank you, I
really appreciate it, I really do.
Sure.
- What? You give me two? Just two?
- Tonight, tomorrow night.
And I'm sure by the next day, you'll
have your own primary-care physician.
Ruthie Pooler's back. She's
looking for you, she's in the room.
- Thanks, Jerry.
- Come on, you're killing me.
Have you tried those nature CDs?
Birds chirping? Waves crashing?
I wasn't running away.
I didn't think you were.
I didn't think you would
leave your grandmother.
Or your dog.
Ruthie...
Believe me, I know this
is not gonna be easy.
Keys to my grandmother's car.
El passes. Three months' worth.
Italian Cooking Made Simple.
Rachael Ray's 30-Minute Meals.
Better Food for Dogs.
This one's for Bob.
This one's for us.
I can do this, Dr. Lockhart.
We can do this.
For this to happen, Social
Services has to follow up with you.
Probably once a week.
You're gonna need home health-care
workers, probably every day.
You said it wasn't
going to be easy.
ER.
Don't you ever pull
that crap on me again!
Excuse me. Excuse me.
- But the last time I looked, I was right.
- You were lucky.
A hypertensive patient with a low crit
and a positive ultrasound needs surgery.
It was vasovagal, it was chronic anemia
and it was ascites. I saved your ass.
She could've bled to death.
You would've sliced her open
on the table for no good reason.
Hey, Jerry.
- Olivia, how you doing?
- Where are we?
- Pick your poison. Trauma 1 or 2.
- Thanks.
Dr. Pratt dropped this for you
before he took off for the airport.
They're lovely. Too
bad they're not mine.
Good afternoon,
ladies and gentlemen.
This is the captain speaking...
- and welcome to Flight 1 1 17.
- Thank you.
- Here you go, sir, vodka tonic.
- Thank you very much.
You're welcome.
How you doing?
I'm Greg Pratt.
Vatima Abika.
Nice name.
So if you don't mind me asking,
what's taking you to Khartoum?
I live there.
I work for the government,
Ministry of Education.
Wow.
I'm a doctor. An emergency
physician, actually.
And I'm on my way to Darfur, to do
some work at one of the refugee camps.
You mean IDP camp.
They're not refugees, they're
IDPs. Internally Displaced Persons.
- Right, right.
- Why?
- Why, what?
- Why are you going?
Um, I don't know.
Something new, I guess.
You know, something different.
And you've read up on Darfur?
Oh, yeah.
It's a lot.
Yeah, well...
I work in Chicago, at County ER.
And I've treated hundreds of
gunshot wounds, knife wounds...
- domestic violence.
- Ahem.
I think I know my way around.
AIDS, malaria, dysentery.
Two million people homeless.
Not to mention the nearly
400,000 already slaughtered.
Boys, babies,
tossed onto bonfires.
Women and young girls
raped, sometimes by men...
sometimes by bayonet.
The work of gangs, all
things you have seen.
But in Darfur...
it's political and
on a massive scale.
And while this insanity
rages on and on and on...
the rest of the world
continues its debate:
Is it or is it not genocide?
This is not debate,
this is paralysis.
Can you treat that, Dr. Pratt?
Can you cure paralysis?
I don't speak
Arabic, only English.
Work? Where are you working?
Yeah, I'm going to
work in a refugee...
An IDP camp.
Dumtala. I'm a doctor.
Is there a problem?
Ibrahim, you're gonna
run the battery down.
Come on, we need you.
I was wondering if you
could help us, Mr...?
- Mudawi.
- Mr. Mudawi, we're here to pick up...
that gentleman right over there.
It would be a lot easier if they had
someone who could speak English.
Yeah, the whole language
thing, very inconvenient.
Giving me the third
degree over a paperback.
They wanted to confiscate it like it
was the Nazi master plan or something.
Guess they don't put
much money into road work.
I'm just gonna assume
you're being facetious.
Doesn't look like they put
much money into anything.
Money is not the real
currency around here.
Life is mostly about a little
bit of food, little bit of firewood.
Safety is the scarcest
resource of all.
Mm. Well, it's hot as hell.
You got any cold sodas
or waters in this cooler?
Oxytocin, measles, Hep
B and tetanus vaccines.
I can't believe it. We're in middle of
nowhere and he's got Sonny and Cher?
Ibrahim speaks English, Pratt.
Hey, sorry about that,
man. How you doing?
Whoa, what the hell is that?
Keep driving, but slowly.
Maybe they won't stop us.
- Who are these guys?
- Janjaweed.
Don't do anything,
don't say anything.
- Aah!
- No, no, no.
It's okay.
- No, I'm not leaving you.
- He won't hurt me.
I'm not leaving.
He's not Sudanese. He's an ex-pat
doctor, only here to help. He has no gun.
We have no guns. We're
on our way to Dumtala Camp.
Pratt, tell him. Pratt, tell
him who you are in English.
Tell him!
I'm a doctor. We're all doctors.
We're on our way to the Dumtala
Camp to help the sick people.
We're not armed, we have no
guns. We're only here to help.
Okay, Ibrahim, let
me take a look, man.
- Ouch!
- Okay, okay, okay.
Yep, it might be broken.
No septal hematoma, so you'll be
okay. Just pinch it, keep the pressure on.
- Radio's no good.
- Yeah, what a surprise.
What are you looking
for, a phone booth?
Who feels like walking?
Mouthwash? You've
gotta be kidding me.
You're a weird dude, Pratt.
Ow.
Ah! Unh.
Do you need some help?
What? No, take it easy. Relax,
I'm a doctor. Take it easy, relax.
Sorry, sorry.
I'm a doctor. Do you speak
English? Do you need some help?
Actually, I think it is you
that needs some help.
I'm Stephen Dakarai,
medical director here.
Hi.
- Nice to meet you, I'm Greg Pratt.
- I know.
I was trying to see if
I could do anything.
The girl was raped.
It is custom that only women
take care of those patients.
But don't worry, Zahra is an
excellent nurse. She will handle it.
- Yeah.
- Come.
So you just got here.
- And not easily, I heard.
- Yeah, well, that's one way of putting it.
The Janjaweed, generally, they do
not hurt the doctors or the NGO workers.
One never knows
what might happen.
Are you okay?
I caught myself a stomach virus.
You must be careful what you eat here.
- Here you go.
This is the best we could come up
with. We don't have a supply sergeant.
- Thank you.
- We'll take up a collection for you later.
Dr. Carter.
A young girl's outside. Wants
us to check on her grandmother.
What's the problem?
She's got vomiting and
diarrhea. Too weak to walk.
Hey, Greg? You wanna
take the 10-cent tour?
Yeah, sure. I'll be right out.
I'd offer to come too, but these IV
poles, they don't run so well in the sand.
- Hey.
- Hey, Pratt. How are your feet?
- Still working.
- See you later.
- All right.
- Debbie and Dakarai, huh?
- Yeah, they're an item.
Tell me the news. What's
the news from County?
Uh, well, Susan Lewis left,
took a job over in Iowa City.
Yeah, I talked to her. She
thinks she got kind of screwed.
She did. Now we've got
this guy named Clemente.
He's the new Attending.
Frank calls him Dr. Schizo.
He's really not a bad guy. He's
just, I don't know, a little nutty.
And the R-2s?
Well, we're still keeping our fingers
crossed that they don't kill anybody.
Even Abby?
Abby's always ahead of the rest.
You know, her and Kovac
are back together again.
Really?
Yeah, man. They're
about to have a baby.
Wow, that's news.
It's great news. I'm happy for them.
I'm gonna have to send them something.
From here? Well,
good luck with that.
Harun, stay with her.
Ishaak, what happened?
He rode too close to the village by
himself. They took him off his horse.
Janjaweed. He is Janjaweed.
They're beating the hell out of the guy.
- Stay back.
No, Pratt. Let Ishaak handle it.
Is that vodka or gin?
Something like that.
With a little green
food coloring?
It's a good trick.
Yeah, well, I'm a guy who
really knows his way around.
Welcome to Darfur.