I want to be your friend again.
Why, Shaun? What happened?
People need friends.
Well... Yeah, they do.
But you said you wanted me
to stop interfering, remember?
You wanted space. You wanted
to make your own mistakes.
I need a friend more
than I need space.
You were a good
mentor, and a good friend.
Well, thank you, Shaun.
You don't know how much it
means to me to hear you say that.
But I think...
I think you may
need a new mentor.
I'm dying.
Twelve to eighteen months.
And I'd appreciate it if you
didn't tell anyone, okay?
- I will in my own time.
- Okay. Have you had a full work-up?
Yes, of course.
It could be a secondary tumor
metastasized to your
brain from somewhere else.
It's the only tumor found.
It could be an inflammatory
or infectious process.
- It was a tumor, Shaun.
- You should get a second opinion.
Shaun, I've been a
neurosurgeon for 30 years.
I think that qualifies
as a second opinion.
You should get a second opinion.
- You have to know whether or not...
- All right, Shaun.
- I'll get a second opinion, okay?
- Okay.
Can I go to work now?
Okay, Doctor, what's
your diagnosis?
- I'm drunk.
- Not you, other doctor.
Well, given the
degree of the rotation,
and the fact that the
break is almost compound,
I'd say we're dealing with a
bimalleolar or trimalleolar fracture.
Very good. What else?
Um...
Color?
Blood flow's restricted.
His foot's dying.
Oh, no.
I'm gonna have to
reset it now. Hold his leg.
- No. No, no.
- No, it's okay.
This is just gonna take a second.
I need you to count to three. One...
One, two...
Is Caden's leg gonna be okay?
How long has his leg been like
this, and how exactly did it happen?
Well, he's been like
that since I found him.
He probably, like, tripped
over a curb or something,
because that's where he was.
Any reason you felt
the need to tell me twice
that you found him like this?
Dr. Park, the boy's going
to surgery. You're going with.
Don't go anywhere.
Shouldn't I be asleep for this?
Well, your blood alcohol
level complicates anesthesia,
and we think you have a concussion,
so, we wanna keep you responsive.
We did give you a
regional nerve block,
so, you shouldn't feel anything.
Oh, cool.
Bend the LCP plate about two
degrees on the proximal end.
Contouring pliers.
BP's dropping.
Heart-rate's rising.
Let's tube him. IV fluids
and phenylephrine, stat.
We need to abort until we get a
handle on what else is going on.
Give me full body CT, full
blood panels and an echo.
I think Jared and I may be
able to dig up an answer quicker.
Great. Get on it.
Come up with anything?
Neither did I.
I had a friend, a
neurosurgeon at SF Muni,
she looked at the scan, she
came to the same diagnosis.
Shaun, I have an
inoperable glioma, okay?
I think you should
go back to work, yes?
I need to go to work.
- Be reasonable.
- Beg your pardon?
Be reasonable.
I have no idea what
you're talking about.
It'll be clear.
- What the hell happened to Caden?
- I don't know. He twisted his ankle.
You lied to me before,
you're lying to me now,
you spoiled little coward.
Hey, hey. Be reasonable.
His friend's hurt, he's scared,
and you're freaking him out.
He's angry, but he's not wrong.
Caden's in bad shape,
and we don't know why.
We need to know what happened.
No, no, no. Don't worry
about him. Talk to me.
You tell me the truth.
You won't get in trouble,
you'll just help a friend.
All right.
We were pledging,
and there's this, wheel-of-torture
thing you gotta do for initiation.
- "Torture"?
- But it's mostly stupid stuff, dude.
It's like drink a cup of olive oil,
or eat a tablespoon of cinnamon.
- And what did Caden land on?
- Laundry.
He had to do laundry?
No, like, he had to eat
those laundry things.
As many as he
could in 30 seconds.
Detergent? Eat detergent?
And how many did he have?
I don't know, like,
six. Maybe seven?
He ate detergent.
Could've burned a hole
through his esophagus,
or his stomach and intestines.
- Catch that bleeder, please.
- Let's hope he doesn't breed.
What, he isn't an idiot?
We have healthy bowel attached
to healthy bowel. Let's close him up.
Dr. Melendez?
The trauma SOD is asking
for you in OR number two.
We've got an
emergency thoracotomy.
Who can give me the
remaining steps for closing?
Cut anchoring sutures, clear
laps and reposition the bowel.
Remove clamps from the
duodenal resection site,
keeping clear of
the underlying aorta.
Close the fascia using a
looped-O monofilament.
Close the dermal layer,
then re-approximate the skin.
Also, you need to ensure no omentum
is caught in the fascial suture line.
Close him up.
Murphy, you're lead.
Clearing laps.
I will hold the repaired
segment in place,
while you run the bowel for me.
Bowel is clear and
ready to be repositioned.
Shaun... Shaun, is
everything all right?
- I lost something.
- In the cavity?
No, but I know where it is now.
Shaun?
I left my scalpel
here earlier today.
You should get
diffusion tensor imaging.
A DTI?
Brain masses are difficult
to diagnose accurately.
You should get more imaging.
- People make mistakes.
- That's not gonna happen, Shaun.
My scalpel isn't here.
- What happened this time?
- He's got a bleed somewhere.
I want a capsule endoscopy to
check the entire length of the bowel
for bleeding and leaks. And get me
a coagulation and metabolic profile.
On it.
Dr. Glassman is dying.
What?
What do you mean?
He seemed fine.
They say he has a glioma.
That's a brain tumor.
And he won't do a DTI
scan to confirm the diagnosis.
Did he get a second opinion?
He has, but delayed or missed,
or incorrect diagnosis has an
occurrence rate of 10 to 20%.
Doctors make mistakes.
Shaun, I don't know
what you want me to do.
I want you to sit down.
That's what people say when they
want to tell you something important.
The part about him dying,
that wasn't the important part?
He won't listen to
me. He is stubborn.
- That, he is.
- Stubborn... He will listen to you.
Okay, you have known him longer,
you're his friend, he trusts you...
Shaun, I can't make
him do anything, either.
You're an attorney.
I'm not skilled at
lying, or manipulation.
So, you want me to what?
You want me to manipulate him?
You want me to use our
relationship and our history,
to trick him into doing this?
Yes, please.
I knew you wouldn't let him die.
Our patient has disseminated
intravascular coagulation.
Can anyone tell me
why that is very bad?
Blood clots form throughout the
blood vessels and rapidly deplete
the body's clotting factors,
thereby causing a systematic bleed.
It's also a catch-22.
If we treat the clotting, he might
end up with a terminal bleed.
And if we treat the bleeding,
he'll have a terminal clot.
So, how do we treat it?
We figure out the
cause. Treat the cause.
More damage from the detergent?
Margins were
clear. It's not that.
He could have a crush
injury from his ankle.
Or a bacterial infection he
picked up before or during surgery.
He might have been
set off by drug use.
Or, we did this to him.
And by we, I mean Shaun.
He spaced out in the OR when he
was closing. Kind of like he is now.
- I'm listening.
- Comforting. He wasn't focused.
He could've nicked a vessel,
which could have caused...
Okay, we're talking about Shaun.
Yeah, he's quiet, but he was
focused. He's always focused.
His stitches looked like they
came out of a sewing machine.
Okay, complications happen.
The kid was in pretty bad
shape when we got him.
Physician error is way down
on the list of likely causes.
Crush trauma being top.
Get him started on fresh frozen
plasma, and crystalloid fluids.
Yeah?
You got a second?
Well, that's an open question.
What can I do for you?
I got a patient with DIC.
One of the possible
causes is surgeon error.
- Your patient? Your error?
- Shaun's.
He got distracted during
surgery. Spaced out.
It's not like him. One place he
never misses a beat is the OR.
Is there anything going on
that I should know about?
- He got some bad news.
- About what?
It's a personal matter.
Shaun was distracted?
By a personal issue?
What, did Lea come back?
Does she have a new boyfriend?
Did his cable get cut off?
I have an inoperable glioma.
Eighteen months.
Aaron, I am so sorry.
Me, too.
Is there anything I can do?
I wish.
You should have told me.
Or at least, you
shouldn't have told him.
His coagulation factors are still
off. Crush trauma isn't the issue.
And his tox screen came
back clean. It's not drugs, either.
We don't know that. He's
had so many transfusions,
the blood in his veins isn't
the same blood he came in with.
The drugs could still be
in his organs, causing...
I get that you don't
wanna think that
this could be caused
by your friend...
The kid came directly from
a frat hazing, hammered.
What are the odds
he wasn't on drugs?
We should start IV midazolam and
sodium bicarbonate to counteract...
That's the treatment
for amphetamines.
If you're wrong, that could
cause a fatal arrhythmia.
I'll find out what
drugs he's on.
You're gonna find out by asking?
Blake was honest with me before.
It's a lot easier to be honest when
you're not confessing to a crime.
We don't have a lot
of choice in the matter.
That's not true.
- Thanks for doing this.
- Yeah, no worries.
Noticed it was cut
when I first saw you,
figured it should
get cleaned up.
Is it all right if I
draw some blood?
I just wanna make sure you
don't have any toxins or infections.
Sure.
So, the nurse said
that Caden has DIC.
Do you know what that is?
Mmm-mmm.
Well, in short, his body is clotting
and hemorrhaging at the same time.
If we can't figure out
what's causing it, he'll die.
If you could just hold
that there for me? All done.
Blake, buddy,
you're on something.
Your pupils are dilated and you're
sweating in a 68-degree room.
I can hand this
over to the cops,
or you can tell the truth
about what Caden's on.
Molly.
I would've told you
the truth if you'd asked.
I'm sorry.
You have time to talk?
- Shaun told you.
- He did, yeah.
I wish I would've
heard it from you.
Yeah, I'm sorry.
- We're friends.
- I get it.
- I wanna be there for you.
- What, are you mad at me?
Yes! I'm supposed
to be there for you.
To do what? To do what
exactly? Hold my hand?
Yes, if that's what's needed.
Okay, well, what I need
is to be left alone, okay?
Well, you told Shaun, so,
that was brilliant strategy.
Okay. Okay, I get it. Stupid,
stupid, stupid, stupid. Okay?
Sometimes, when people are told
they are dying, they do stupid things.
Sometimes, people around
them do stupid things.
Shaun told you to come here
to try to convince me to
get more imaging, right?
Aaron, you can't stop fighting.
- Maddie wouldn't have wanted you...
- Don't, don't. Don't you dare.
Don't you dare.
What are you gonna say,
huh? That Maddie was a fighter?
Huh? That she never quit?
I'm sorry.
Thank you.
And you should get the DTI.
Not for you.
You've accepted your diagnosis,
Shaun hasn't.
He needs to.
Hey, Neil. I heard there was a
complication in one of your cases.
Caden Hauley?
"Heard"? Or you been
monitoring all of Murphy's cases?
I monitor all my
department's cases.
Eighteen-year-old with
DIC. Any idea what set it off?
Complications happen.
The kid was in pretty bad
shape when he got to us.
I'm also wondering why you
were in two surgeries at once.
You left three
first-years unattended?
You know we do
this all the time.
We couldn't function
efficiently if we didn't.
- Yeah. Hope Caden pulls through.
- Yeah.
You got a very
quick appointment.
I have connections, Shaun.
Why did you listen to
Jessica, but not me?
- Well, Jessica's pretty smart, too.
- Yes, but what did she tell you?
- I don't think this is a good time.
- When is a good time?
I have a lot to learn from you,
and if you're dying, less
than two years to learn.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
There were some
surprises on your images.
The previous
diagnosis was incorrect.
You have a glioblastoma
multiforme located in your pons.
I'm sure I don't
need to tell you this,
but it's the most aggressive
form of brain cancer.
We estimate three,
maybe four months.
I can have my assistant
get it in touch with you,
to refer you to a therapist...
He still has low blood
pressure and thin blood,
which means the treatment
for the MDMA didn't work.
So, the Molly
wasn't the problem?
It certainly didn't help
him, but we now think...
Our best guess is Caden
has a bacterial infection.
Thanks.
DIC? What happened there?
We're not sure yet. He was
pretty sick when he came in.
I guess sometimes
complications just happen.
Interesting choice of words.
Eerily similar to what
Dr. Melendez said to me.
Yeah, he said it
during a differential.
I guess the phrasing
just stuck with me.
It's not like Melendez
to be that laissez-faire.
He usually likes to know
exactly why things happen.
One of the traits I
admire about him.
Yeah, well, we're
trying to figure it out.
But so far, cultures are negative,
Shaun's closing was textbook,
drug use doesn't
seem to be a problem.
I didn't realize Murphy did
the closing. Good for him.
Oh, my God. Shaun.
Yes, there are many
different explanations...
You asked me to get a second
opinion, I got a second opinion.
You asked me to get more
imaging, I got more imaging.
- Shaun, you have to accept...
- No, I don't accept.
I don't accept. I was right.
No, you were not
right. I'm dying, Shaun.
I said doctors make mistakes...
Yeah, they made a mistake. I have
even less time than we even thought!
Shaun was right.
Imaging is unreliable.
The imaging that
you asked me to get.
Imaging is subject
to interpretation.
Yes, studies have shown
that experts rely on...
On subjective measures based
on experience, rather than object...
- Shaun. No more.
- Rather than objective...
- No more. No more.
- Many theories consistent with...
You can't do a biopsy to confirm
because many tumors look alike.
Some are treatable, some are
curable, some are curable and...
Stop, will you? Stop,
please, will you?
Stop, stop, stop talking! Stop!
- Okay.
- Stop!
I am not hurting you.
Oh, my God, stop.
I'm helping.
No, you're not. You're not
helping. I don't need theories.
I don't need whiteboards.
I don't need doctors.
I don't wanna think about the
tumor. I don't wanna think about dying.
You know what I want? You
know what I actually want?
I wanna go on a long drive
somewhere. I wanna eat pancakes.
- I wanna watch football!
- It's not football season.
Oh, my God. I know
it's not football season.
Do you mean you
want to have fun?
Yeah. I wanna have fun.
So, you can keep fighting.
Keep fighting if you want.
It's futile, and it's stupid.
Or you can come with me.
- How long has he been hypoxic?
- Came on suddenly five minutes ago.
He's on 100% high-flow oxygen,
and numbers aren't budging.
No, he's ventilating fine.
He must have thrombosed
his pulmonary artery.
We need to dissolve this
clot before his heart stops.
- Jared, prep for jugular access.
- On it.
Fifty milligrams TPA infusion,
now. Let's go, let's go, let's go.
Is this fun?
The Saturday after
Valentine's Day,
her favorite day of the year,
even more than her birthday.
The Chamber of Commerce
would decorate this place,
and put out a crappy
buffet meal, hire a DJ.
And I'd put on a tux, and she'd
put on a yellow Belle dress,
and she'd pin my bow-tie on me,
and I'd pin a little
yellow corsage on her,
and we'd come and
we'd eat, and we'd dance.
Whenever I see your smiling face
I have to smile myself
Because I love you yes, I do
- I love you, sweetie.
- I love you more.
You think so, huh?
Well, I'll tell you what.
You can take how much you
love me, which I know is quite a lot,
and then you can double
it, and then you can add 10,
and that's how much I love you.
I love you more.
Oh, how much longer
I thought I was in love
a couple of times before
With the girl next door
And I remember thinking,
"This is the moment that I
know will be in my mind when I...
"When I...
"When I close my eyes to die."
Only, I thought that she'd be
sitting there right next to me,
and I'd hear her
say it one more time.
I lost my toy scalpel.
The one that Steve gave me.
Yeah, I figured
that was the one.
I've been looking
for a whole day.
I think it may be gone forever.
Maybe I'll come here
when you're dead.
Okay.
Are your memories of your
daughter enough for you?
Not even close.
Do you need me to
listen to you anymore?
- No, Shaun, you should go.
- Okay.
Not all the cultures are back.
But since he's not
responding to any antibiotics,
- we can rule out bacterial.
- It was never a great fit.
It's a better fit
than surgical error.
What if it is bacterial,
but resistant to all...
Then he's dead.
What about a paroxysmal
nocturnal hemoglobinuria?
A PNH? The incidence
is literally one in a million.
What's the odds of
Murphy screwing up?
I'd put them about that.
No, it's not PNH. Caden
had normal flow cytometry.
Exotic snake venom can trigger
consumptive coagulopathies.
So can pre-eclampsia,
but he's not pregnant and
he wasn't charming snakes.
Murphy, any thoughts here? It
is kind of your ass on the line.
I know why Caden has DIC.
I squeezed the artery
between two clamps.
I must have ruptured the aortic
wall, causing a pseudo-aneurysm.
It was my mistake.
And, also,
I have to make a bowel movement.
He's lying. He's gonna puke.
He's going to Glassman.
I told Dr. Melendez I had
to make a bowel movement.
I think he believed me.
- Color me proud.
- I have the answer.
Shaun, I hope you're
referring to your patient,
but due to the fact that you're here
pretending to be in the bathroom,
- I kind of doubt that.
- It's your answer.
We already... We already
have my answer, Shaun.
We can't do a biopsy on you
because of the arteries in the way,
like the arteries in
Caden's abdomen,
but we can't move the
arteries in your brain.
Why did we go to the carousel?
Because you were sad.
What didn't I wanna do?
Do you not know the
answers to these questions?
I do know the answers, Shaun.
I don't think you know the
answers to these questions.
You're not hearing
me. I'm dying.
There's still hope.
Shaun, look at me.
Look at me, please.
There is no hope for me.
I mean, hope. What is hope?
You hope the
49ers find a defense.
You hope the number
four bus comes on time.
Doesn't mean they
magically learn how to tackle.
Doesn't mean the bus
driver suddenly drives faster.
Hope is irrelevant for me.
Hope is painful.
I don't wanna spend
what's left of my life chasing
my tail around in a circle.
You understand?
Okay.
Your tumor is located
at the base of your skull.
An open cranial biopsy
would tell us what's wrong,
but there are blood
vessels in the way.
The biopsy would cause
an aneurysm or a bleed.
But if we go through
your nasal cribriform plate,
we can cross the tentorium
on the contralateral side
and avoid all
those blood vessels.
We can do a biopsy
through your nose.
You can't die, too.
I have to throw up.
So, how do we do
this? Do we file a report?
- Talk to Andrews personally?
- You wanna report Shaun?
- I don't want to, I think we have to.
- No, you want to.
And we'd certainly have to
if our sole agenda would
be to take down Shaun,
and to give you one less
person to compete against.
And certainly we'd absolutely
have to cover up and bury
a possible fatal medical error if our
sole agenda was to protect a friend?
And protocol would seem to
favor the bitch over the friend.
Thanks?
I threw up.
Look, we have a duty to report
errors, so, they won't happen again.
The process saves lives.
And exactly what errors are
you trying to avoid a repeat of?
Are you worried about the next
time an autistic surgeon operates on a
drugged-up frat kid after finding out
his mentor's dying of brain cancer?
Dr. Melendez told us,
Shaun. We're really sorry.
It's okay.
It's okay. I think
he's going to be okay.
The protocol exists, so that
we don't ask questions like that.
That seems like a bad idea.
You trust your judgment. Do
you trust Morgan's judgment?
Do you trust the judgment of
all the doctors in this building?
If you can make
judgment calls, so can they.
That's why we need these rules.
So, the protocol is fine for everyone
in this building, except for Shaun.
They'd reprimand any one
of us, but they will fire him.
Okay.
We report it, we
get the investigation,
make sure nothing like
this ever happens again,
but we tell them I did it.
- They'd fire you, too.
- It's not a terrible idea.
Jared's out the door either way.
Okay, can we get
back to the medicine?
Caden is still alive,
and if we can keep it that way,
there won't be an M&M review.
Which means no one
will be asking questions,
and no one will have to give
answers. It all goes away.
If Caden dies,
we tell the truth, and we face
the consequences together.
No.
I thought I'd found
my toy scalpel.
We need you to come
back to the group, Murphy.
Get me imaging on
that pseudo-aneurysm.
Hey. What's up?
Do you still feel the same way about
Dr. Murphy as when he got here?
Dr. Glassman gave
us certain assurances.
"If Shaun proves anything
less than excellent...
"If Shaun doesn't live up to
everything I know he can do,
"he will be immediately released,
and I will resign my position
"as president of the hospital."
And you wrote it down?
I made sure it
was in the minutes.
Shaun has exceeded
my expectations.
Mine as well. And?
And my feelings about
Dr. Glassman have not changed.
Thank you.
- We need to cut him open.
- We cut him open, and he dies.
He'll bleed out before we can
even get the artery exposed.
If we don't cut
him open, he dies.
- Don't cut him open.
- Murphy, if we don't...
We should insert an endovascular
graft through his leg instead.
Fix it from the inside out.
I've done that for large
abdominal aorta dilations,
but this is a lengthy,
dissecting pseudo-aneurysm.
It's safer.
The aorta wall is compromised,
it could rupture completely.
Caden could die as soon as we
deflate the balloon inside the graft.
- But doing nothing will kill him.
- Not definitely.
I mean, there's still a chance
Caden will simply come out of this
without any
surgical intervention.
- 5%, 10% maybe.
- Not nothing.
We're doubling down on Shaun
after we know he caused this problem.
How's that gonna look at an M&M?
I trust Shaun's idea.
He makes mistake no
one else would make,
but he also makes saves none
of us would have ever thought of.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
I still don't think you
should be working here,
I don't think the
trade-off is worth it.
Let's prep him for surgery.
Pull the guide wire, Reznick.
I'm passing in the graft.
You're right over the
pseudo-aneurysm now.
Inflating the balloon
to deploy the graft.
- Deflating.
- Can I do it?
- It's delicate.
- No, it's not.
But it will either
work, or it won't work.
If my idea is wrong, he'll die as
soon as we complete this next step.
You shouldn't have
to live with that.
Everything that happens in
this room is my responsibility.
We'll do it together.
Deflating.
Nobody's going home.
I am proud of this team, and
what we accomplished today.
Drinks are on me
at Harry Hope's.
We're celebrating?
Today was a disaster
and we got lucky.
You're right.
But when you get lucky,
you celebrate. Let's go.
Hup.
At some point in your career,
you're going to kill someone.
And I hope for your sake,
there is a doctor out there who
still believes in you when you do.
It was there all along.
I have to go drinking, but I
wanted you to know that...
Is that from an IV?
- You did the biopsy.
- I did.
I have a low-grade glioma.
Not a GBM? I told you...
It's cancer, Shaun.
It's still cancer.
I have to undergo brain surgery,
which is really scary because
I'm not the one performing it.
Five days a week for
six weeks of radiation,
- 10 more weeks of chemotherapy.
- And then?
And then, with a little luck,
you and I can go to the
Super Bowl next season.
You're going to live.
There's hope.
Now, go. Go have some
fun with your friends.
Yes. First, I have to tell
Dr. Andrews about the mistake I made.
Shaun, you can't.
Protocol is clear, and
reporting saves lives.
And I hear Caden is
on the road to recovery,
so, your mistake couldn't
have been too bad.
No, I made a mistake.
Shaun, I understand that,
but Dr. Andrews will use this.
And do you remember
the commitment
that Dr. Glassman made
when you were hired?
I promised you'd be
excellent. Right, Shaun?
And you have been excellent.
You can't give
Dr. Andrews this excuse.
I was not excellent.
This time, I was bad.
And surgeons have to
be excellent every time.
- Right, Shaun?
- You agree with him?
I'm not gonna ask him
to lie to save my job.
Don't do this.
It's up to Shaun. I
trust your judgment.
- I'm not doing this to hurt you.
- I know.
- We are friends.
- Yes, we are.
- I love you.
- I know. I love you, too.
I love you more.