Oh, God, what time is it?
It's late.
Go back to sleep, Natalie.
What?
I said go back to sleep.
You... you just
called me Natalie.
It's not Natalie?
Mm-mm.
Sorry.
It's okay.
I... I forgot your name, too.
Don?
Doug.
Pamela.
Hi, Pamela.
Hi.
Are you going someplace?
Work.
At 4:00 a.m.?
Man's got to eat.
I'll call you.
No, you won't.
Hey...
don't let the cat out.
Huh...
Huh!
Huh, damn, it's cold out.
Slow night?
Calm before the storm.
In a little early, aren't you?
Actually, I am a
dedicated pediatric resident
struggling to
fulfill the promise
of a brilliant early career.
You been drinking?
I wish.
Nobody's in four,
if you want to get a few
winks before your shift.
No, I'll just catch up on
some paperwork. Thanks.
You're in early.
You're in late.
Yeah, I'm still waiting for
someone to pick up Tatiana.
Family and Children's Services
said they'd be here by midnight.
Did they say what year?
Nice shirt. Sleep in it?
Something like that.
You working today?
Yep. On at 7:00.
Why don't you
get a couple hours.
I'll keep an eye on Tatiana.
Really?
Yeah. I can practice
up on my Russian.
She's in three.
Thanks, Doug.
What are friends for?
I know, I'm early.
Hey.
Hi.
Oh, God.
Hi, yourself, kid.
Jesse...
Baby, leave Uncle Peter alone.
Now go on upstairs. Go.
Put some clothes on.
I'm sorry, honey.
I was trying to let
you get some sleep.
Yeah.
What time is it?
It's about 6:30.
I was going to make
you go home last night
but you were snoring
to wake the dead.
I do not snore.
Worse than Daddy used to.
Oh, man.
Be advised that Archer Avenue...
Look what the cat dragged in.
Any juice?
Is that blood on your shoes?
Probably.
She give you any
trouble last night?
No, she went to bed early.
Hey, how was the movie?
Wack.
Jesse liked it.
Jesse's four.
You going to make it back
in time for dinner?
Today's Thursday. I don't
watch Mom on Thursdays.
It's the 16th, Peter.
Mama's birthday?
Oh, yeah. Today.
Yeah, for the last 76 years.
Come on, kids. The
dad bus is leaving.
Steven, come straight
home from basketball practice.
Don't make me have to
send your father after you.
Here.
You going without your books?
I don't know what
this lipstick is about
but we're going
to talk about this.
So you're not coming?
No, no, no. I'm coming.
I just got to figure
something out, that's all.
Lamb?
Standing rib roast.
Right. The American
Heart Association diet, right?
Hey, it's what she
likes, and it won't kill you.
It might.
Peter, please
don't disappoint her.
You're the only one she
really remembers anymore.
WMAQ weather for tonight:
Cloudy, cold, low 18...
Jackie, I'll be here.
50 degrees, currently
48 degrees in Chicago.
I'll be here.
I've been on for
24 hours, Peter.
I'll take your Christmas shift,
New Year's, Thanksgiving,
Fourth of July, Flag
Day, you name it.
You owe me three days already.
All your hemorrhoid
cases for a year,
half my future practice,
my firstborn... Mort!
Hey, man, it's my mother.
She's sick.
I-I-I need to be there.
Not this time, Peter.
I can't. Sorry.
Lily, get Psych down here now.
Jerry, what the
hell is happening?
Carter's got a guy down here
who's poured gasoline
all over himself,
says he's going to drop a match.
Is he serious?
Who knows? But
I'm playing it safe
and looking for marshmallows.
Get any closer and I'll do it.
You don't want to do this,
Mr. Halgren. Really, you don't.
Yes, I do.
No, you don't.
Yes, I do! No, you don't.
What, are we arguing? I do.
Back up. Back up!
I'm backing up.
You know, if you do
this, you're going to set off
the sprinkler system, and then
all you're gonna be is a bald guy
with no facial hair and
a really bad sunburn.
You don't have a
sprinkler system.
We...
We don't have a
sprinkler system?
All right.
We can talk about this, right?
We can because I
don't want to see you
hurt yourself and I don't
want you hurting anybody else,
so let me be your
friend here, okay?
I can be your friend.
Please? Come on.
When you're finished
making new friends, Dr. Freud,
Sparky there will
need an eyewash
and a shower.
Daddy. ROSS: There's
something you don't see every day.
Ow. MAN: He climbed
up on a chair in our den,
stuck his head in,
started screaming.
He's bleeding a little bit.
It hurts.
The teeth are
jammed into his neck.
Ow. Ow. Hang in there, buddy.
We're going to get
you out of there.
I took him to see
The Lion King again
for the ninth time last night.
This is the thanks I get.
No more Lion King,
Gus. You hear me?
No more.
Daddy...
Did you bag this?
My great-grandfather
was a roughrider.
He bagged it in India
with Teddy Roosevelt.
Mmm-hmm.
Ow. Sorry. When did it happen?
1910. They were
in the Punjab, I think.
No, I mean, when did this
get stuck on Gus's head?
Oh... gee.
A half an hour ago.
I might have made it a
little worse trying to pull it off.
He's going to need stitches.
Malik, why don't you go
up to Ortho, get a bone saw.
Ho-ho-hold up.
You're going to cut
into my kid's neck?
We're going to saw
the jaw off the tiger.
It's been in my
family for 90 years!
I mean... it's historical,
for God's sake.
I mean...
Gee... Teddy Roosevelt.
17-Year-old female,
B.P.'s 90/60, pulse 108.
Empty bottles of
vodka and brandy,
Valium, flexural, Darvon...
Father thinks she may have
others stashed away somewhere.
No note.
Okay.
Okay, ready? On three.
One, two, three.
All right, let's get a CBC,
chem-7, cath. urine for ruds,
a tox screen and
a blood alcohol.
What have you got?
One of your old favorites, René.
Whoa, René, it's
been a long time.
What? A couple of weeks?
René..? René!
What are you on, René?
I got a headache.
I bet you do have a headache.
Give me something.
Something? What, were
you taking, uh... aspirin?
No.
Ah. You're not getting
Demerol, René, so forget it.
Lavage?
Ewald tube...
Saline, three liters.
I'll get the charcoal.
It's stomach pump time, René.
Oh, no. No!
Calm down or this is
going down your nose
and you know how
much you hate that.
So, who brought
her in this time?
Her dad or the creep?
Her dad.
You know, if we gave
out green stamps,
René'd have a car by now.
The people over at Sunshine
House have agreed to take her in.
And they're set up
to handle AIDS kids?
That's all we do.
What are her
chances of adoption?
With advanced AIDS, zero.
There's foster care.
So she goes there to die?
The people at the
hospice are great.
She'll be with other kids,
there's full-time
nursing care, teachers.
She's fortunate there
is a Sunshine House.
Yeah, it's her lucky day.
She's in here?
Uh-huh.
Tatiana, eta Mrs. Brown.
Ana zaberyort tebya
va troy noveya doin.
Malgoo ya astatsa staboy?
Nyet.
Eta horoshia mesto.
What's she saying?
She doesn't want to go.
Hi, Tatiana.
I like your doll.
What's her name?
Scaggee yeh eemya
tvayeh, kooklee.
Anna.
That's a very pretty name.
Tatiana, you need
to come with me.
Please?
Edee.
Vsaw budict, okay?
Start an I.V., five
milligrams morphine.
How'd this happen, Mr. Kazuo?
Boning fish.
All right, let's get a CBC,
Ancef I.V. and a DT.
X Ray? Whoa... Yeah.
Where's your finger?
I couldn't find it.
It hurt too much.
Well, if we can find it, we
may be able to reattach it.
The guys brought the crate in.
Dr. Benton? Yeah.
All right. Carter,
Chen, let's go.
All right. While the good
news is the finger's on ice,
the bad news is, it's in here.
All right, dig in.
Let's get the
replantation team up here.
Carter, Chen, move.
If that tissue freezes,
you might as well
serve it as sushi.
René's going to be okay.
We pumped your
daughter's stomach.
The tox screen showed
cannabis, opiates,
benzodiazepines.
Her blood alcohol
level was .375.
She had a fight
with her boyfriend.
Said she wanted to kill herself.
You want me to get
Psych down here again?
What for?
They'll just let her out
in a couple of days.
Have you thought about
any in-patient treatment
centers for René?
We did that.
She cut her wrists.
What am I going to do?
Oh, God.
Have you decided
what you're going to do
in your sub-I next year?
My elective? I
don't know. Uh-huh.
We've still got a couple months
to make up our minds.
Well, sure, but the good
ones are going to be long gone.
I thought we just
had to sign up?
Uh, no.
It's really competitive.
Oh.
I was thinking about
just staying here.
Trauma placement?
They've already got 12
requests for the one spot.
In the E.R.?
Mm-hmm.
We're here, so we
have the inside track,
but it's the
resident's decision.
Benton?
Uh-huh. It's not supposed
to be, but they always go
with who the resident wants.
So have you already applied?
Are you kidding?
As soon as I got here.
I didn't want Ben
to think I wasn't interested,
and...
I got it!
He already told you?
One missing digit.
Six-year-old male,
gunshot wound to the back.
C-7, T-1 region, no exit wound.
B.P. 70/50, Pulse 112.
Oxygen, 15 liters by mask,
two large-bore I.V.'s wide open.
All right, let's get
him on my count.
Nice and gentle...
One, two, three.
Good bilateral breath sounds.
Cap refill's poor.
Blood coming up?
GCS 201. I.V.'s wide open.
Type and cross four units O-neg.
Let's move.
All right.
Start a flow sheet.
Okay.
A C-spine and chest film.
Get them up here now.
I think we've got a cord injury.
Okay, start a flow sheet.
He's going to need a Foley.
All right.
Good bilateral breath sounds.
All right, blood coming up.
Pass the trauma scissors... Hey.
Hey!
Are you hurt?
Are you hurt, too?
I killed him.
I killed Drew.
Connie, let's get
another gurney in here.
Switch him over to a dynamap.
Where's that O-Neg?!
I killed him. He's in shock.
I killed Drew.
Here we go.
I shot my little brother.
Let's get him on mask,
start an I.V. Of saline.
I shot my little brother.
Got them.
Damn.
C-7, T-1 vertebrae.
Gardner-Wells?
Yeah.
All right, bolus 600 migs,
methylprednisolone over 15 now.
Start a Foley catheter
and an NG tube.
Kid's father's here.
I'll take it.
Call Neuro and book an O.R.
He was okay a
couple of days ago.
Now he's confused.
He's agitated.
Dick.
Dick?
Mr. Thornberg, do you
know where you are?
Do you know what day it is?
Would you scratch
that for me, Dick?
It itches like crazy.
Do you know where you are?
Dick, damn it, I'm telling you.
Has he been sick
on any medications?
He has lung cancer.
Chemo, radiation?
They gave up a
couple of months ago.
Come on, Dick.
Come on.
Let's get a CBC,
lytes, calcium level.
Want an EKG? Yeah.
Get out of my car.
I'll get somebody.
Are you Mrs. Thornberg?
Uh...
No. Just... just a friend.
Have you contacted
anyone in his family?
He's got a daughter somewhere,
but they're not in touch.
Can I please stay with him?
Oh, sure. Sure.
Hey, Mark, Susan, we've
got end-stage lung cancer
with altered mental
status in one.
One, two, three.
Don't let the screen
door hit you on your butt
on the way out.
What is that smell?
Halibut.
It's the same thing, all right?
Dr. Benton?
Walt, come on, man.
You know how I
feel about birthdays.
All right, all right.
Look, I gave my
word. I'll be there.
Do me a favor, tell Jackie
don't make a big deal out of it.
Okay. 7:00.
Today your birthday?
Carter, my personal
life's my own
and don't eavesdrop
on my phone calls, okay?
Sure. Sorry.
Uh... I had a question about
next year's Trauma Sub-I.
What about it?
Well, I understand that
12 Students have
already applied,
and I was wondering
if I was interested,
if you could tell me wh-what
my chances would be.
12 People have applied, right?
Right, yeah.
With me, it would be 13.
Well, then I'd say your
chances are one in 13.
You walked into that one.
Yeah.
The creep is here.
He's in the waiting
room with dad.
Great. My day is complete.
It's Dr. Benton's birthday.
Really? It's my
daughter's birthday, too.
Think we should do something?
Like what?
I don't know. Throw a party?
A part? Oh, God.
He would hate it.
Talk to Lydia.
She can pull those things
together pretty quickly.
Mr. Thomas?
I'm Dr. Ross.
The bullet entered
your son's back.
It smashed his vertebrae.
We need to do some
exploratory surgery
to determine the
extent of the injuries.
He does have reflex activity
and anal sphincter tone,
both of which are hopeful signs.
Kyle, stop.
Will my boy live?
Uh, well... we don't know.
It-it-it'll be a few hours.
Doesn't look good.
Kyle, stop it.
I said shut up.
I'm sorry, son.
It's okay, son.
It's okay.
I'm sorry, Kyle.
It's going to be all right.
I always keep my guns locked up.
I must have forgot.
I told them to stay
out of that room.
I told them a million times,
but I must have forgot.
Good Lord, I must have forgot.
Hypercalcemia. Normal saline
300cc's per hour
and diurese with
40 migs Lasix I.V.
There's too much calcium
in your friend's system.
We're going to get it out.
Is it from the cancer?
Mm-hmm. It's not
uncommon, but he needs
to see his oncologist for
long-term drug treatment
to prevent this from
happening again.
Just gets worse and worse.
He'll feel better in
a couple of hours.
His calcium level
wasn't that high.
Mike's too stubborn to die, huh.
Have you known him long?
Not really.
About a year.
We met at church.
He's a real character.
He's fun to live with.
You two live together?
Oh, no, no. It's not
romantic or... or anything.
I liked him.
Thought maybe I could help out.
He's a sweet guy.
He's got no one, no family.
It just seemed like
the right thing to do.
Huh?
I was trying to get
rid of a headache.
Maybe you should
just stay in the hospital.
I want to go home.
You don't know what I want!
So, René, your father said
you were threatening
to kill yourself.
I was just upset.
You know, T.J. and I
had a fight, that's all.
Hey, this I.V.'s hurting her.
Can you give her
something for her pain?
So you weren't
considering suicide?
Hey, she just told
you what happened.
T.J., shut up. You're
not part of this family.
Hey, don't you
tell me to shut up.
Why don't you shut up?!
Leave him alone!
Why don't you all shut up, okay?
So, René,
you weren't trying to
kill yourself this morning?
I just wanted to go to sleep.
Why don't you check
yourself in voluntarily,
get cleaned up?
I want to go home.
I got to get to work.
Mr. Franks.
Sure. Whatever.
Let her go.
Dr. Benton.
I understand you're anxious
to change your shift tonight.
Not anxious, but I was hoping
to find somebody to
cover for me, yeah.
Well, it's happened
a lot lately.
A couple of times, yeah.
Four times. I checked.
Peter, it's not
forbidden to swap shifts,
but we don't want
to encourage it.
Look, Dr. Hicks, I
assure... Let me finish.
Dr. Morgenstern and I have
spent a great deal of time
with the schedule,
and we try to provide
every resident with a
well-rounded work experience.
And swap shifts, you
upset the balance.
Peter, you've got two
women with abdominal pain
in curtain two.
Yeah. Um...
My, uh... my mother's been ill.
It's always difficult,
but if your mother's
declining health
becomes an impediment
in your completing
your residency,
you may want to
consider taking a hiatus.
Peter.
He'll be right there.
It's not uncommon.
You're an excellent doctor.
These things happen.
You can rejoin the
program next year.
That won't be necessary.
So we understand
each other, then?
Yeah. Yeah.
Some time this century, Peter.
They're sisters.
Got some sort abdominal
seizure from something they ate.
B.P.'s 5o over nothing.
I think they're crashing.
What the hell is
wrong with them?
I can't stop twitching.
Her B.P.'s racing.
Oh, my God.
Doctor, I can't stop.
Okay, okay. Carter,
hold her down.
Doctor, please help me.
Carter, I said hold her down!
Happy birthday, Peter.
♪ ♪
Wow.
Happy birthday, Dr. "B."
♪ ♪
Paramedics brought in a baby,
fell out of a
second-story window.
I need you.
Pulse 160, B.P. 65 palp.
Four years old,
fell out of a window.
Father says she's been
unresponsive ever since.
I couldn't get an I.V. going.
Let's cross-table and
C-spine to the neck.
CBC, type and cross
two units and a head CT.
You the father?
Yeah.
How'd this happen?
She, uh... fell off our balcony.
How far?
How far did she fall?
Maybe 15 feet
onto the driveway.
Pulse is strong.
I've got no bowel sounds.
Let's get an abdominal CT.
Get Benton in here.
Moves all extremities to pain.
Abdominals soft...
pelvis is stable.
Tough day to be a kid.
Hey, hey.
Hey!
I hate it!
That is a beautiful church.
It's a mausoleum.
My family's been
coming here for years.
Why don't we just
rent Soldier Field?
We can invite fewer guests.
We don't have to fill it up.
Look. Hey, Beth
got married there
and it was lovely.
Oh, yeah? Your sister.
Great! Maybe I could
borrow her wedding dress, too.
Look, Tag, you know
what, I hate it, okay?
Isn't that enough?
Sure! Fine!
I'm sorry.
I'm tired.
I was up all night with Tatiana.
I'm worried about her.
I... I was thinking that maybe
I could do more to help her.
I was thinking... maybe
we could adopt her.
You want to adopt
a kid with AIDS?
Yeah.
She doesn't have anybody.
She doesn't speak the language.
She's completely alone.
How advanced is the virus?
She doesn't have a lot of time.
What, a month? A year? Five?
What difference does it make?
We could be watching a child
die for years.
Wh-Why do you
have to do this now,
three months before
the wedding? Why?
Because she needs us now.
So, if I don't want to do this,
does that make me a bad person?
No.
I have to get back
to the hospital.
Carter, I keep telling you,
it isn't my birthday, all right?
N-N-N-No, I heard
you on the phone.
I was talking about
my mother's birthday.
Uh-uh-uh-uh-uh.
Hey. Happy birthday, Dr. B.
Mary.
Hey, Mark, what
happened with René?
Uh, gone home.
Her dad signed her out.
I've got this rule
out M.I. in One.
Today is his 60th
wedding anniversary.
Sixty?
My record's 60 weeks.
I don't think I'll
ever get married.
Yes, you will.
I don't know.
All the marriages I
know are pretty rocky.
Well, thank you very much.
Jerry, I need the Olan chart.
Where the hell
are the lab results
from the MVA in Four?
I ate them.
Yeah, well, I need them.
Your sister called.
Twice.
Peter, another MVA. Coming in.
How long?
Six minutes.
Sounds pretty bad.
E.R.
Sure.
Excuse me. Hang on.
Is Dr. Ross working today?
Uh, he's with a patient.
Could you please tell
him I'm looking for him?
Diane Leeds. Yeah. Sorry.
Yeah, it's going to be
a little bit later than that.
Dr. Benton.
Shoot!
The, uh, the check
didn't bounce, did it?
It isn't going to, is it?
No. I... I just haven't had
time to make a deposit.
I'll, uh, take care of it
first thing in the morning.
Tomorrow's fine.
Look, I was hoping
to catch a ride
to the birthday party tonight.
She invited me,
and I'd like to go
if you can give me a lift.
Where's your car?
In the shop.
My husband can
pick me up afterwards.
I didn't know you were married.
Well... I take it off
when I work with patients.
Mm-hmm.
Happy birthday, Peter.
You and your mother
have the same birthday?
No. It's... it's a long story.
So, can you give
me a ride or not?
You know what,
um, I don't even know
if I'm going to be
able to make it,
so maybe you'd better catch
another ride somewhere else.
So how long has
he had this cold?
Couple of weeks.
He keeps getting
sick this winter,
and his school says
he's falling asleep in class.
Dr. Ross, woman at the
front desk looking for you.
Says her name is Leeds.
Tell her I'll be there
as soon as I can.
All right, kiddo,
open up for me.
Let's take a look.
Now, when was the last
time Billy saw a dentist?
Uh... I don't know.
Um... last year.
All right, kiddo, let's
put your shirt back on.
It's cold in here. Okay?
All right.
I think he's anemic,
Mrs. Larson,
probably because he's
not getting enough iron.
So he needs some vitamins?
Well, no. What he really
needs is a better diet:
some vegetables,
some grain, meat, milk.
He's malnourished.
I try to get him some
meat every week.
You're going to have
to do more than that.
Are you on food stamps?
Mm-hmm.
How many kids do you have?
Four... and in the winter,
after I pay for the heat,
there is not much
left to go around.
Dr. Ross, that kid who fell
out of the window, I need you.
You're going to have to get
more food for your children to eat.
Lydia here is going to give you
the name of several food banks
and some local church groups
who feed families.
Shelter? I won't
go to a shelter.
You don't have to live there.
Just go there for the food.
I can feed my kids.
Mrs. Larson, Your son's teeth
are rotting out of his mouth.
Get the food wherever
you can, okay?
Thank you, Lydia.
Kids starving to death
in downtown Chicago.
What? We got those X rays.
Neck film was fine.
So, we undid the backboard
and cervical restraint,
and we rolled her
over to check her back.
Yeah, and?
Yeah, I think you
should see for yourself.
Mm-hmm.
Hey, honey.
Right over here.
Son of a bitch!
Doug!
Dr. Ross! Damn!
What is that?
Footprint.
Dr. Ross!
Thanks for coming.
Let me see your foot.
What? Hey!
Son of a bitch!
Doug!
Son of a...
Doug! Doug! Back off! Doug!
I'm all right!
I'm all right.
It's all right.
Uh, I really screwed
up this time, huh?
Yeah, you did.
Is he going to press charges?
I doubt it.
I don't think he wants
his friends to know
that he let a
pediatrician beat him up.
He's got other problems.
A couple of detectives
from Domestic Violence
talking to him in
the lounge right now.
God, it's freezing out here!
I won't say I'm
sorry, 'cause I'm not.
Then don't.
So, what happens now?
I had to tell Morgenstern
what happened.
What did he say?
He wasn't very happy.
I think you're looking
at ink blots, couch time...
probably Resident
Review Committee.
Your friend's still here.
What?
The brunette.
She's waiting for
you at Admitting.
I'm heading home.
Tell Rachel happy birthday.
It's her birthday, right?
Uh, yeah, I was supposed
to be there an hour ago.
Jennifer's going to kill me.
Tell her it's my fault.
I always do.
Mr. Thornberg, you can't
smoke inside the hospital.
What are you going
to do, arrest me?
You could blow yourself up.
Well, it hasn't happened yet.
Mr. Thornberg, you
have lung cancer.
One more won't make
any difference now.
There, you see?
Now you don't have to arrest me.
BP's 110/70, pulse
108, resp 24, GCS. 15.
Defensive wounds on
hands and forearms.
He sounds stable. What
is he doing in Trauma?
Except for that knife sticking
out of his chest, yeah, he's fine.
He's had 15 liters
of oxygen by mask
and he's as high a kite,
so we had to restrain him.
All right. I think
it's in his heart.
Looky here... a swastika.
I got a "Die, nigger, die" here.
How do you feel about Asians?
He took a crowbar to a
black kid on West Adams.
Another brother
jumped him with a knife.
Maybe somebody ought to
drive the knife all the way through.
All right, people,
let's do your damn job.
Get a CBC, type and cross-match
eight unit packed
cells, point eight narcan.
Check the glucose and get
a portable X ray down here.
And I mean now. Move.
Hey.
Are you all right?
I'm fine. I, uh, hurt my
hand a little bit, but...
You wanted to
talk to me about...
It was about Jake,
but it can wait.
I'll come back tomorrow
if you promise not to
beat anyone else up.
That's not a daily event.
I just wanted to make
sure you were okay.
Have someone
take a look at that.
It might be broken.
Lydia, como estas?
Muy bien. I'm
going home, aren't I?
All right, Rolando, my man.
What's up, Jerry?
Easy day, huh, esse?
Yeah. When Benton
comes down from the O.R.,
let him know his sister's
been calling every five minutes
for, like, the last
two hours, will you?
Rolando, make sure
Mr. Thornberg in Two
gets moved upstairs.
Also, there's a
rule out M.I. in One
waiting on labs.
Can you call, please?
Ah... yeah.
Good night, all.
Good night. Night.
Who's on tonight?
Me and Benton.
Good night, everybody.
Good night, Carol.
I don't think we lost
a single patient today.
No kidding. Really?
Benton's still got
that knife wound
up in the O.R.
Close enough.
Good night.
All right, Jerry.
E.R.
Uh-huh.
The muscles of
the left ventricle
must be holding
the knife in place.
We'll begin with a
medium sternotomy
to expose the structures
around the knife.
Then we'll open
the pericardial sac
extract the knife,
tamponading the wound
with your finger
as you make horizontal
mattress sutures
to avoid the coronary arteries.
We'll be out of
there in no time.
Dr. Benton, your sister's
on line two.
I'll, uh, I'll have
to call her back.
You cut, I'll watch.
We don't accept children
over ten years old,
so she'll have plenty
of kids to play with.
We're full right now,
so we put Tatiana
in the infant room.
We'll move her into
her own age group
as soon as there is an opening.
Hi, Tatiana.
Tee okay?
Da.
Kak tebya zovut?
Anna.
Oh, that's right.
She's very pretty.
You speak Russian?
Oh, just a little.
Just a little.
Oh!
Hey. Daddy.
Oh! Happy birthday.
Thanks. Bye.
Bye? Kiss first.
Thanks for getting
home in time to help.
I couldn't get away.
I'm sorry.
It's okay.
Craig helped.
Craig?
You know, the other clerk.
So...
where is young Craig?
At the store.
We ran out of ice cream.
Rachel loved her gift.
What did we get her?
Super NES.
Thought we weren't
going to do that.
Well, she asked five times
a day for three months,
so I gave in.
So you found time.
Oh, that's from Susan Lewis.
Oh.
Don't start.
Judge Franklin asked me
to clerk for him
again next year.
And?
I am going to do it.
No running in the house!
That's it?
You just decided?
Well, you made your
decision unilaterally.
Now I've made mine.
Did I miss It? Is
the party over?
About an hour ago.
Is she still up?
No.
She's asleep.
Jackie, I'm sorry.
I wanted to be here,
but this man came into
the hospital with a knife...
Jackie, I'm
talking to... Jackie!
She's at that "not
talking" stage.
Now, trust me on this one, okay?
Why don't you just
finish cleaning up
give it a couple of
days, and I'll talk to her.
Got stuck in surgery, huh?
I couldn't be at my
mother's birthday party
because I had to save a
man with "Die, nigger, die"
tattooed on his forearm.
That's my husband.
Good night.
Susan! Susan! Dr. Lewis!
Huh?
René is back.
Pulse: 50. B.P.: 80/60.
Respiration's 14.
René? René, what are you on?
Mr. Franks, what did she take?
What did she take, Mr. Franks?
I don't know. Pills, maybe.
I heard a noise. I found
her in the bathroom.
Where's her boyfriend?
I don't know.
All right, on
three, bring it up.
One, two, three.
Repeat a tox screen, and BA.
No gag. Let's intubate.
René, we haven't
lost anyone today.
We are not starting with you.
Prep for lavage.
René, you are not going
to die tonight, you hear me?
Not tonight.
Get the charcoal.
Captioning sponsored
by WARNER BROS.