Every doctor has
a dirty little secret.
We're all competitive
science nerds.
In grade school, we made the
biggest and the best volcanoes,
which erupted actual
fake molten lava.
In junior high, we spent hours
laboring over our rat mazes.
The computer diagnostic is
complete. Everything checks out.
Finished the robotic
prosthetic inspection.
It's all in order.
So, we're ready to try again?
Let's get her connected. Okay.
Okay. Every time you do that,
I feel like The Bride
of Frankenstein.
So that one day
we'd be the person who changed
the face of medicine forever.
This is so exciting.
Your first printed portal vein
is going into a test subject.
How do you feel?
Like a farmhand
behind the back barn.
Here. Why don't you
take over the clippers?
Look at us.
Changing the face of
medicine, shearing a sheep.
No, I was shearing a sheep.
You are just giving him a fade.
There you go. There
you go. Look at us.
We're changing
the face of medicine.
Oh!
Wow. That was...
You really know
what you're doing.
Are you grading me?
Maybe I am, a little. Mmm.
You're gettin' an
A. I don't know.
I'm kind of an overachiever.
I'd like to go for the A-plus.
No. We have a ton to do
before the procedure today.
Okay.
The conduit's coming off the
printer in two hours 47 minutes,
which gives us another 30
minutes before we have to start prep.
All right.
Maybe a little extra credit?
Ahh.
How's your research going?
Oh, the diagnostics look
good. I just slipped out for a sec.
I don't want to miss this. Mmm.
Do you think you're gonna
make it to the shower?
Oh, crap. Kepner's
shower is today?
Yeah, it's today.
And she's our friend, so...
I know she's our friend.
You don't have to tell
me she's our friend.
Sorry. I just... I'll
be there if I can.
Great. Great.
Dr. Robbins. Dr. Torres.
Dr. Murphy. Dr. Murphy.
That was good.
Professional. I bought it.
Mmm-hmm.
You're dying inside, aren't you?
There's still two
seats left in the gallery.
Who wants them? I do.
Whoa. Hey, wait.
What about my surgery?
There's plenty of room.
It's just me and Dr. Grey,
an anesthesiologist
and a veterinarian.
You lost me at "Veterinarian."
He's putting a seeded
conduit into a baby.
Who is human. You
are bothering a sheep.
Plus, I'm allergic to wool.
I'm allergic to boring surgeries.
- Wow!
Hey. Big day. It is.
You gonna watch?
Watch?
Cristina's surgery.
I have my own. Oh, yeah.
The, uh, the pig. Sheep.
The sheep. Yes.
Hey. Uh, here he comes.
What are all of you doing here?
We came to see you off.
We couldn't let you leave
without saying good-bye.
We'll miss you.
I'm just going home.
I'm not retiring.
But first, I just need a
vacation from all of you.
You did it, sir. You
got yourself better.
No. You did it, Bailey.
You got me better.
Is Dr. Webber leaving
very stressful for you?
No.
Then why are you
counting your fingers?
Here's to our little Duckie
finally getting married.
To Duckie and Matthew!
"Duckie"? Don't ask.
Mmm. We thought for sure you
were gonna be a spinster for life.
Maybe take it a little easy
on the mimosas, Kimmie.
Oh, leave her be.
She's celebrating.
You two could stand to add
a little champagne to that OJ.
We're on call. Ohh.
He is such a dreamboat.
Responsible, handsome.
Duckie, I hope you
know how lucky you are.
Speaking of dreamboats, who is
that and why is he waving at us?
Hey, guys. Hey, Avery.
Jackson, these are my
sisters, Libby, Kimmie and Alice.
O-M-gosh!
You're Jackson. The Jackson?
Look at that. I
gotta go to work.
Yeah. It was nice
to meet you guys.
Oh, wait. You'll be done in
time for mani-pedis, right?
I will try. Can you take
them back to my apartment?
Roger that. Oh, no way!
We wanna go with you. You
won't even know we're there.
We can see the room for the
shower tomorrow, plan decorations.
Whoo! Field trip.
Come on, Duckie.
Bye, boys.
Gosh, those eyes.
You know, I totally get why
you'd name a pig after him.
Hey. Someone paged me?
That man over
there requested you.
Hey, hon.
What are you doing here?
I think I'm gonna puke.
You have to go.
Are you high? No.
I'm... I'm trying to get clean.
That's great, but
you can't do it here.
You said...
When I was here,
you said you'd help me.
Yeah, I tried to, Jimmy,
but you refused my help,
and that ship has sailed.
Now I can get some
names for you...
Damn it! I need some help here!
All right, well,
I'll see you later.
Yes, indeedy.
Oh, you, uh...
I... Yeah, parked over... Right.
There.
I did, too. So we can
just... We can just walk.
Yeah.
You not gonna drink that?
Yeah, I try to hold off so I
don't drink it all before work.
Oh, yeah. That's...
That's a good plan.
Hey!
Hey! This is my cab!
Take a walk, hippie.
What? Not cool, man.
Aren't you people supposed
to love bikes or something?
Hey, open the door.
People are freaking
animals. Right?
Hey, my tie.
Open the door. Go!
Whoa!
Whoa, whoa, whoa! Hey!
Is he breathing?
All right, I'm a doctor.
I need all of you to step
back, please. Step back.
Make room. MAN: I don't know.
He's not moving.
He's not breathing.
911 said a rig's 10 minutes out,
but we gotta get an airway now.
I swear I didn't see it happen.
It was an accident, all right?
Step back. Back, sir.
Oh, God! Is he breathing?
I need you to back up!
Back up! Okay! Okay!
I need you to back
up, please. All right.
Seriously, stand
back. Thank you.
Back up. Back up. I'm
not kidding. Back up.
Back it up. WOMAN:
He's not breathing.
Whoa! Jeez! CROWD: Ohh!
Whoa! What the
hell are you doing?
Good chest rise.
I hope he knows what he's
doing. I think he's breathing.
Guys, just move back.
The cameras are only recording
the doctors and
the surgical field.
Your son's identity will
be completely protected.
Good morning. Big day.
We're just hearing
about the cameras.
Sorry? We just told the Glaziers
we have a lot of people
who'd like to observe,
so we've set up a live stream.
Okay, but I think
we would feel better
if we knew the focus was on
our baby, not putting on a show.
The cameras are
there so that, in success,
other doctors can
learn this technique
to help other kids like Nathan.
No. No, that doesn't
work for me. He's a baby.
He's a baby. Ashley.
Ashley, look at me.
I will be performing
the operation,
and my only focus
will be your son.
That is all I care
about, okay? That's it.
You spring this on
me the day of surgery?
What? This circus?
Ross said that
this came from you.
Everyone in the hospital's been
asking to watch the procedure.
I got e-mails from UCLA and
Baylor. They wanted a stream.
And I felt none of that
should be on your plate,
so I made some
executive decisions.
I'm happy to have
you veto any of them.
Yeah, like all of 'em.
If that's what Dr. Yang
wants, consider it done.
Ross, hang on.
This is a teaching hospital.
We need to create conditions
where more people can
learn from what you're doing.
Live streaming? What if
something goes wrong?
Even if something goes wrong,
you're doing important work,
and people should see that.
I need to take this.
Cristina?
Fine.
Okay, now we're
gonna start small today.
Just wiggle your fingers.
Got it. Okay.
Let me do it. Okay.
Yeah, okay. How
about just one finger?
Now just a finger? Mmm-hmm.
Which one?
Your choice.
Keep it clean, though.
And just try to relax.
I'm pretty relaxed, John.
Not gonna distract you.
I'm just gonna go grab a bite.
Do you want anything?
I wanna move this stupid finger.
You can do it.
Try again?
Whenever you're ready.
Damn it!
You put the sensors
in weeks ago.
I haven't moved
the damn thing once.
You will. Just focus
on wiggling the fingers.
Okay? Just bend it from here...
I can't focus on anything
with you talking at me.
Okay, hang a banana bag
and give him two of Ativan.
I've treated him before.
He's a heroin addict.
Okay, let's, uh, start a tox screen
and start him on methadone.
No.
No methadone.
The methadone
will help you detox.
I haven't used in months.
I gotta get totally clean.
Off the methadone, too.
I gotta do it.
Let me do it.
Okay, then. No methadone.
Let's admit him and watch him.
Can we send him
to a rehab facility?
He's... He's Alex's dad.
There's history.
Like, bad history.
I don't care who he is.
For you, he is a patient
who had heart surgery
less than three months ago.
And you are his
doctor, so act like it.
Get him admitted.
Oh, uh, Dr. Hunt? Hey, I did it.
Um, I did two days with her
following me around everywhere I go.
I don't need help anymore.
I'm doing really well.
You're pulling
your fingers again.
Oh, God! Go away.
Uh, look, I... I just wanna
be cleared for surgery.
Dr. Alma, is she
clear for surgery?
No, she's not.
Hmm. Dr. Bailey, you're not
clear until she says you're clear.
Okay, um...
We need to fast track this
because I have patients trying
to schedule surgeries. So...
Just... Just tell me what hoop
I need to jump through
for you to clear me.
And this is the ER, where
I spend most of my time.
I kind of run it.
Ah, hey. Who's this?
These are my sisters. ALL: Hi.
Hi, I'm Arizona Robbins. It's...
Arizona!
I feel like I know you.
April told us
everything about you.
Are you gonna make it to the
shower? We throw the best showers.
I... I wouldn't miss it.
I have a cat at
home who lost a leg.
Every time I see
him hopping around,
I just think that
is real strength.
Stop talking. Well...
It was super nice
to meet you guys.
And I will see
you at the shower.
She is such a good walker.
Okay, um, I'm just
gonna get dressed.
And then we'll head out. Okay?
Coming through!
32-year-old male.
We just lost his airway.
I'm gonna change it over a wire.
We need a 5-millimeter shiley and
a percutaneous trach kit right away.
Let's get him set
up for transfer.
By my count, one, two, three.
All right, let's go,
betadine the neck.
He couldn't breathe,
so I trached him.
You trached him?
Oh, yeah, he did.
Took out his little
Boy Scout knife
and sliced a wide and
horizontal incision into his throat,
way lower than it needed to be.
All things I'm gonna
need to fix in surgery.
Ready?
Whoa!
Mother of... Sick.
You guys cannot
be in here. Damn it.
All right, let the OR
know that we gotta
come up there and fix your mess.
Hey, I had to do it like that.
When you take a closer look,
you're gonna see that. It
doesn't matter right now.
What matters is we have
to get him ready for transfer.
So, can you just take
my sisters and go now?
Alex, I have to
tell you something
that you're not
gonna wanna hear.
Well, then don't tell me.
Your dad's here. Jimmy's here.
What? Why?
He's going through withdrawal.
Kick him out. I can't.
I can. Alex...
Get up.
Hey, son. How you doin'?
You're not staying here.
We've helped you once.
We're not helping you with this.
Alex... Son, listen...
Oh, stop calling me
that. I know who you are.
I didn't remember...
I don't care.
I didn't remember till
I saw you pissed off,
till I saw you standing over me.
Like when you were 15, you
said you wished I was dead.
I've been trying to get right
since the bar. I'm still trying.
Not here. No, Alex, stop.
I'm not gonna help a
guy who made my life hell.
No, you're not. But I am because
he needs help and I'm a doctor.
You can go. I got
this. Really, it's okay.
So it's not the sensors.
Is it the coding?
Coding's been
tested and retested.
So it's Becca.
It's Becca.
Look, she is not the
most positive person.
I mean, every day it's a fight.
But she's trying.
She's no ray of
sunshine, but she's trying.
Uh, maybe it's me.
Maybe it's not Becca.
Maybe I'm just not saying
the right thing to get her to do it.
It may surprise you to learn
that I am quite good at sutures.
It wouldn't surprise
me in the least.
What would surprise me is,
if you were able
to do five of them
without engaging
in OCD behaviors.
And if I can, you'll sign off
so I can go back to work?
That's the deal.
Five sutures.
That's all?
That's all.
Game on.
Uh... Just a sec.
Now, only use the tools
to your immediate right.
If you touch any of
the trays, we start over.
If you count your fingers, if
you double-check a stitch,
if you rearrange any of the
instruments on the trays, we start over.
Five sutures.
Whenever you're ready.
I can't believe you yelled at
Matthew in front of my sisters.
Now they're gonna think
I'm engaged to a nitwit.
All right, Duckie...
Don't call me Duckie!
Okay.
It means "Ugly duckling."
Because I grew up
with braces and pimples,
and they still see me that way.
It's like idiot incapable
of doing anything right.
I'm a freaking trauma surgeon!
He did a great job.
Actually, I would've done
exactly the same thing.
Matthew was right? Yeah.
You should go spread the word.
You are not engaged to a nitwit.
You know what, this is actually
gonna be a pretty easy fix.
So why don't you just
go ahead and go? I got it.
Really? I was kinda hopin'
that I could hide
out here all day.
They came all this way
to see you. You should go.
Smile.
Edwards, can we stop
fiddling with the camera?
And let's get started.
Getting proximal
vascular control.
She said she's getting
proximal vascular control.
You're changing the face of
medicine, you need to be louder.
Do you know who doesn't talk
about changing the face of medicine?
People who change
the face of medicine.
They just do their job.
Okay, preparing to
place the portal vein.
Doctor...
Dr. Yang, surgeons at
Baylor have joined us.
Okay, at this point, I have
dissected the scar tissue
and put the patient on bypass.
Timing is everything.
We just received word that
the conduit has gone
through its final round of tests
and is on its way to the OR.
While we wait, Dr. Karev
can give a brief patient history.
Nine-month-old born with
hypoplastic left heart syndrome.
He's rejected the synthetic
conduit that was previously placed.
This conduit was granted by
the FDA with compassionate use.
This is Dr. Ross.
And this is the conduit we
printed on the 3D printer.
All right.
Okay, let's commence with
the implantation process.
Declamping the portal vein.
Oh! We have blood flow!
Okay, let's recheck vitals.
Oh, uh, blood
pressure's 115 over 75.
Blood pressure's falling.
You know, the conduit is a
little smaller than anticipated.
I'm gonna do a
triangular cut with a patch.
Call the lab and try to...
Excuse me. Global testing.
Did she move her hand?
No. That sucks.
Yeah.
Well, it's just
takes time, right?
I don't know.
Well, cheer up.
Why?
My research just stalled.
Why would I cheer up?
I don't know.
I don't know, that's just
something that people say...
I know, I know. I'm
just... Let's not fight.
Callie, I... I should get back.
All of our preliminary
testing, however...
Wow! Did you see that?
Yeah, that was intense.
Mmm-hmm.
Do you think they're
gonna break up?
CVP is low, he doesn't
have enough volume.
Okay, uh, give
another, uh, bolus of LR.
You're gonna fluid overload him.
What's that piece
sticking up on the conduit?
Is there a gap in the
anastomosis? Dr. Yang?
Say something.
For posterity.
Uh, this is Dr. Meredith Grey.
Today, we implanted
a 3D-printed portal vein
with seeded cells into a sheep.
Currently, her
vitals are stable,
and Dr. Edwards will continue
to monitor her via ultrasound.
Our hope is that the portal vein
will continue to
heal, without stenosis.
SHANE: He's in V-fib.
Damn it. Starting CPR.
- Internal paddles.
- Okay.
Charge to 10.
Turn the camera off.
Clear.
Ross, get the camera off.
Stop filming.
We've sat outside all night
long waiting to hold him,
and now you're telling us
that we have to wait longer?
Nathan's numbers still
aren't stable enough for...
We should've never
let you talk us into this.
We should've gone
with the synthetic graft.
We should've listened
to you. It's still early.
The conduit could
still be a success.
Do you believe that?
Look me in the eye and
tell me you believe that.
Let's focus on what we know.
Right now, he's
on the oscillator
to force oxygen into his lungs,
and if he can maintain his sats,
we hope to be able to get
him on a normal ventilator.
One step at a time.
Okay?
Nurses' station.
Thanks for the strong
show of support.
Sorry, I've got...
I got a lot on my mind.
Alex...
Yeah, it's just been
a crap couple of days.
Alex...
Do you really think the
conduit's gonna be a success?
I don't know. I hope so.
Do you want another blanket?
Where's Alex?
Alex, come here!
Shh. I'm here.
Who broke this?
Where's he at?
Jimmy, Alex isn't coming back.
Just tell me what you need.
Helen, you let the damn
kid do whatever he wants.
I told him not to play with
my stuff. Now look at this!
Alex! Look at this!
Jimmy. Jimmy.
It's Dr. Wilson, you're detoxing,
which causes hallucinations.
Ah!
Oh, God! Don't start that
crap with me right now.
Helen...
I swear to God.
I...
Shh. Alex.
Okay. Okay.
Okay.
Okay. Shh.
Dr. Ross, how's it going?
Don't be smug.
What?
You won, we lost. I get it.
Dr. Ross, you do not
get to talk to me that way.
Congratulations.
Dr. Ross, get back here!
Nurses' station. Please hold.
Where's April?
Oh! Um...
A trauma came in. She
got pulled into surgery.
You know, I don't
know how long she'll be.
So, what? We just
cancel the shower?
We already paid for the
flowers, the food, the champagne.
When she came in
this morning to work,
she promised she'd
be done on time.
Yeah, we say a lot of things.
Look, we're just not in
charge of our schedule.
This is just how it works.
Why do you live this way?
Because we save people's lives.
She'll pop in at some point.
No, it's her shower.
She can't just pop.
You may have
to settle for a pop.
Done.
See? Two down, three to go.
I thought that a good night's
sleep was gonna make it easier.
You know what
will make it easier.
Miranda, I hate to
see you suffer like this.
Take the medication.
Two down, three to go.
Okay, okay, um, why don't
we take a five minute break?
I'm gonna go visit
the ladies' room.
And, um...
Just for reference.
Oh...
I'll be back.
Sir, what are you doing here?
Well, if I was gonna come back
to work, I need to practice my skills.
But you are jeopardizing
your recovery.
You should be home, not...
Sitting on the couch,
flipping through the channels
isn't gonna get me back
to work in an OR any faster.
I mean, I'm sitting there
watching housewives flip tables
and celebs flip houses.
And pretty soon, it's just like I could
feel my brain cells wither and die.
Bailey, these trays are a mess.
I don't know how you
expect to find anything on 'em.
Okay, now visualize the ligaments
in your right index finger contracting.
Stupid, stupid, stupid.
Hey, babe. They got
those chips you like.
John, leave us alone.
I'm sorry.
Just wait outside, and
I'll call you when I'm done.
Just go.
My God!
Did you see that?
I just keep snapping at him.
And pretty soon, we can't
even look at each other.
It's awful. I'm awful.
Because he does
everything for me.
And I started this
because I wanted
to do something
for him for once.
And it seemed like
something I could do.
- I just wanted to do...
- One damn thing.
And I can't.
I'm done.
I can't do this anymore.
Okay. Let's take a break.
No, you're not hearing me.
I don't wanna do this anymore.
I can't. I hate this.
Take this crap out of my head.
Do you wanna schedule
surgery to have them taken out?
Dr. Torres, we
are not there yet.
Well, if she doesn't
wanna keep...
Dr. Torres, may I talk with you?
Yeah.
Excuse us.
No, no, no, no, no, no! No.
She distended. She
dropped pressure and flatlined.
She's been down for
20 minutes, Dr. Edwards.
It's over.
So sorry, little girl.
We tried.
Edwards, do you know how many
dogs the Russians sent into space
before a man walked on the moon?
Those poor puppies.
Edwards, we are
going to do a necropsy,
and we are going to
find out what went wrong.
And then we'll try
again, and we'll fail again,
because that's what
progress looks like.
Progress looks
like a dead sheep.
No, progress looks
like a bunch of failures.
And you're gonna have feelings
about that because it's sad,
but you can't fall apart.
And then one day,
we will succeed,
and we will save
a person's life.
And we will walk on the moon.
Figuratively, anyway.
Are you with me?
Yeah.
She hates being here.
- She shows up every day.
- She is trying.
No, I can't fight
anymore. Every day.
Every day is a fight.
My whole world is a fight.
At home, I fight with
Arizona, and then I come here
and fight with Becca, and
now I'm fighting with you.
Well, we just haven't
figured it out yet.
How to get her to do it.
So we're frustrated,
and she's frustrated.
Mmm.
Is it wrong that I wish that
water were a bottle of gin?
Is that gonna be for me or...
We need to talk to Becca.
It is so great that you two
are trying to work things out.
It is so much
better for the kids.
Duckie doesn't know this,
but my husband had an affair.
Oh, that's...
We have, uh, three boys,
so we stayed together.
Wow, so, did you go to therapy?
Because we can't
even agree on that.
Oh, no. Mmm-mmm.
We didn't feel the
need to talk it to death.
We just focused on moving
forward, putting it in the past.
Oh. Hoping things
would get better one day.
So, well, did that work?
Well, we are still
getting through it.
And we're back to two.
Let's try for a third.
No, no, this is the seventh.
Two stitches ago, you
tugged on your fingers.
Two before that,
you straightened an
instrument on the tray.
Look, I can't... I can't
keep doing this. I can't...
I know.
Then you really need to
consider taking the medication.
Okay, no, I'm not
taking the damn pills!
Bailey, I was gonna head up to
Kepner's shower to steal some food.
Come with me.
You just need a break. I need...
To get back into surgery.
I heard Nathan's
not doing so well.
I'm sorry.
Yeah, I'm trying to figure out
if there's a plan B we can try.
But I don't even
know if he's gonna...
I heard your sheep
did great. Congrats.
Thanks. Actually,
the sheep died.
Oh, sorry.
Did you need the printer?
Yeah, but if you need it more...
No, I'll finish this up,
and then it's all yours.
So can I ask you a
question, um, about Ross?
Yeah, what about him?
He seems different.
Do you notice that?
Well, no, not really.
Well, he's not the same guy
he was when he started here.
He's not the guy who
delivered my baby.
Yeah, well, we're not the same
as when we were interns either.
Well, I understand that. But
he is aggressive and mean.
I don't know, I mean, he spends
a lot of time on your service.
Do you think he's
trying to be like you?
Or... Do you notice that?
I'm sorry.
Are you saying I
taught him to be mean?
That's what he's
learned from me?
No.
Because a little edge is not
the worst thing for a surgeon.
I understand that.
And I am not
mean. I am effective.
Are you implying that I'm not?
Well, no, you just
said I ruined a resident.
No, that is not what I said.
I said something
is off about Ross.
Well, maybe he
got tired of people
thinking he was soft
around the edges.
Maybe his focus is being a
doctor and not a flight attendant.
And my job is his surgical
skill, not his personality.
Talk to me, Ross.
What's going on?
Nathan's O-2 sats
are stable, so...
Dr. Ross says
that's a good sign.
It's an excellent sign.
He can come off the oscillator.
It's working?
I think so.
Yes!
Helen!
Jimmy. Where are the car keys?
You didn't get Alex.
Jimmy, it's all right.
Let's just take you...
He's... He's still
out there waiting.
You said you'd get
him. I come home,
you're just sitting
on the bedroom floor!
Alex is all right, Jimmy.
It's after dark! He
could be anywhere!
You stupid... Leave her alone!
Get out of here! Go!
She was supposed to
get you. I was afraid you...
Just shut up!
Alex, please! Alex, don't!
Go sleep it off!
Come on. Go get some sleep.
You okay?
Yeah.
I'm sorry. Why are you sorry?
He's a junkie. She was crazy.
I started running interference
for them when I was six.
It's like riding a bike.
I'm just asking
for one more time.
Last time, I swear.
If you wanna go, we can just...
John, hush.
Fine, you wanna waste your time?
I don't care.
All right. I'll be outside.
Actually, John,
we need you here.
You're gonna stand
right here, okay?
Okay.
When you're thirsty,
you don't think about
moving your fingers
or grasping the cup.
You just get a drink,
and the rest follows.
Becca, I want you
to look at John.
Hi.
When do I move
the hand? You don't.
Just look at John.
Think about what
you want to say to him.
You don't have to say it.
Just think about it.
Did it just... Shh.
Look at John.
What do you want to say to him?
Becca...
Becca, you touched me.
I never thought
you'd do that again.
Me, neither.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Oh! You are gonna
love that thing.
I use mine all the time.
Great!
It's a salad spinner.
I don't know what it does.
But the guy at the store
recommended it and...
The receipt is on the
back. Thank you, Mer.
Ooh, another bow. Who's
making the ribbon bouquet?
Ooh, hey, yay.
So she can carry it at
the rehearsal. Super fun.
Ooh, we are late.
Do you think she
noticed that we're late?
I don't even think she
knows we're invited.
- What did we miss?
- Um...
Garlic press, coffee maker
and a delicious tray of bruschetta.
Oh, beautiful!
Did you even see what she got?
It doesn't matter, as long
as you say something nice.
You gotta try the
quiche. Lovely!
Love it. Fantastic!
Okay, um, you know what?
This one is from your sisters.
Oh, no, not that one.
We wanted to save that
one, Duckie, to open in private.
Oh, my God! You guys,
you actually remembered?
You remembered how much
I wanna wear Mom's veil?
No, we didn't. Grab it, Alice!
I'm trying, stop!
Oh, this isn't Mom's veil.
Adorable!
Delightful! It's not.
We are sorry. That was
supposed to be for later.
But since you've opened it...
Surprise!
It's for your wedding night,
for when you and Matthew...
Oh, God!
There's no reason
to be embarrassed.
We all had our first
times, too, right, ladies?
We wanted to give you
the lingerie and some tips.
The pearls, by the
way, are for the inside...
Stop. Just stop talking.
But Matthew is your
first real boyfriend.
We're trying to
help. Please, don't.
And he's a great catch.
And you don't have the
best track record with men.
No, she doesn't
have any track record.
When I found out you
had a boyfriend, I was like,
"Don't make any
sudden movements."
Oh, my God! Stop talking to me
like no man has ever found me sexy.
Duckie...
And stop calling me Duckie!
I'm not Duckie anymore.
My acne cleared up years ago.
I got rid of my braces in college.
I wear contacts. I use makeup.
I did years of physical therapy
to correct my pigeon toes,
and in case you haven't noticed,
I've learned how
to condition my hair.
I'm not your hopeless,
ugly little sister anymore.
I am not an ugly duckling.
I'm a swan.
And a surgeon. A
freaking kick ass surgeon,
who, by the way,
has had sex before.
Oh, my! Does Daddy know?
You know what?
You're fired as my
bridesmaids, all three of you.
I don't want a single one of you
standing up for
me at my wedding.
Honey, don't be silly. You
have to have bridesmaids.
And I will.
These are my people now.
Right?
Right. Yes.
These are my bridesmaids.
Yeah. Yeah. Yay!
You owe me an apology.
April said you would've
done exactly what I did.
Yeah. Yeah, I told April that.
But the truth is that you
messed up this guy's neck,
and I spent eight
hours fixing it yesterday.
So how 'bout "Thank you"?
How 'bout you should've
waited one second
for the surgeon standing
right next to you?
I mean, what was that?
You felt like you had to
be the big man out there?
I mean, you feel
threatened by me or...
No, I don't feel
threatened by you.
I was trying to
save the guy's life.
Great. So was I.
Okay, I don't have
a problem with you.
I... I don't have a problem
with you either, man.
Hope to see you at the wedding.
Yeah, I, uh, actually don't know
if I'm gonna be able to make it.
Well, I know it would mean
a lot to April if you could.
Since we're good,
you should definitely come.
Before my accident,
you called me a drunk.
I am so sorry.
There has not been a day
since that I haven't regretted...
You're right.
I am a drunk.
Sir... I'm an alcoholic.
Which is why I'm here
now instead of home.
It's boring there, and lonely.
And when I'm bored and
lonely, I wanna have a drink.
Hell, I wanted to have a
drink when I'm happy, too.
I always want a drink,
because I have a disease,
and it can't be cured.
But it can be managed.
But I can't do it by myself.
I need help.
Accept that you have
a disease, Bailey.
Accept help.
We're all here for you when
you're ready to get started.
Sometimes the key
to making progress
is to recognize how to
take that very first step.
Then you start your journey.
That is not what I said at all.
Yeah, well, it's
not what you said.
It's how you said it.
That tone that you...
Oh, okay, so now we're gonna
fight about how
we fight? This is...
I am sick of this!
I mean, every time we
talk, it turns into this...
Okay, I'm sorry, do you think
that I'm not sick of it, Callie?
'Cause everything I say
seems to piss you off!
Like everything's loaded
and I don't know if it's...
I think talking may
be the problem.
Maybe we shouldn't talk as much.
You hope for the best.
And you stick with
it, day in, day out.
Even if you're tired,
even if you wanna
walk away, you don't.
Because you are a pioneer.
Alex, Aaron, get
your asses in the car...
Before I give you
something to cry about.
But nobody ever said
it'd be easy.