Hut-hut-hut, hike.
Button-hook at
the manhole cover.
Boom.
Ooh!
Montana to Rice.
Ho!
They're on different teams.
Since when?
You and I watched
their last game at Carol's.
But that was way back. I'll say.
Go long.
Me go long?
I'm out of shape.
You go long.
I'll go long.
All right.
Doug...
Too far for the Ivy League arm?
Car!
Hey, you butthead!
What, are you out of your mind?!
Not another one.
Go get a gurney, Doug.
I'm not playing catch
with you anymore.
Nice of his buddies
to drop him off.
What are friends for?
Dr. Ross, three-month-old
seizing in One. Temp's 105.
I got him, Doug. Go.
Is Dr. Benton... Oh!
Give her three more of morphine.
Make it five.
Call X ray down here stat.
Susan, I need you in here.
Okay.
Come on, Carter, move, move.
Please, Petey. Oh, it hurts.
Okay, Ma. Okay, Ma.
Listen, all right.
Get an X ray of the right
hip, chest and pelvis now.
What about a C-spine?
Carter, come on, get the
hell out of here, all right?
Carter, come with me.
X-ray tech's on his way.
Pulse thready and weak.
He's bleeding somewhere.
What do you got?
Multiple trauma. Gown up.
O2, 15 liters.
Start a flow sheet.
What's Benton doing?
His mom broke her hip.
That's bad at her age.
B.P.'S low, 60/30.
CBC, type and cross eight units.
Run the saline wide open.
Carter, Deb, guy's out of it.
Primary survey's done.
Now what do you get?
Uh... get a C.T.?
Narcan 0.8.
And then you got to get the...
Glucose 85.
Get smart, nurses,
and nod sagely.
Get her another
five of morphine,
CBC, Chem seven, U.A.,
EKG, hip, chest and pelvis.
Move. Come on.
No, no, no.
Don't take it off.
Somebody call the
chief of orthopedics,
tell him to get off his ass
and get down here now!
We need to undress
you, Mrs. Benton.
Please, not in front of Petey.
Peter?
Peter...
What?
She doesn't want to be naked
in front of her son.
Okay. All right, Ma.
Um... all right, I'll
be outside, okay?
Here's the blood lab...
I'll be right out here.
He's going down the tubes.
Can I intubate?
Not this time.
It could be a neck fracture.
Always look everywhere.
We'll roll him.
I got his head.
Ready, and now.
There we go.
Single gunshot wound. And back.
Heart's racing, 180.
He barely has a pulse.
Put the blood on a pressure bag.
No pulse. He's arrested.
All right. Carter,
take over. CPR.
We got to crack his chest.
I got it.
Thoracotomy tray.
We do a thoracotomy when?
A penetrating
trauma and full arrest?
Exactamundo.
I need the rib spreader.
We have towels, scalpel.
Move your hands, Carter.
Put the blood on the pump.
There we go.
Rib spreader.
I'm in.
Pericardium's dry.
Aorta... Statinsky.
Is the O.R. team on alert?
They just finished
that perfed appy.
Suction.
Tell them they got
another customer.
There it is.
Nice save, Mike.
We got a faint pulse. Let's go.
I got to get home.
I'm on tonight.
I'll have the place
emptied out for you.
Deal. You taking the El home?
Yeah.
Hang on a sec, I'll go with you.
Lily, I'm back tonight.
Could you finish
the nurse's notes?
Sure. Bye.
Who the hell
stat-paged me down here
for some old lady
with a broken hip?
Hey, Peter... Dr. Wilson,
I'm Dr. Benton.
Pulled me out of a damn
department head meeting.
This is my mother and,
well, she broke her hip, sir.
That she did, Dr. Benton.
All right, Blair, put her
on your O.R. schedule.
No, no, no. Sir, I want
you to do the surgery.
E.R. admits go
to the teaching...
I don't want a resident
operating on her.
She's my mother.
I'll scrub in.
So does that mean you're
going to be the one
holding the knife?
All right, I want
to scrub in, too.
I'll be in there.
That's not good enough, sir.
Now, look, I know
this is your mother,
but you are way
over the line, son.
I'll page you when we're done.
Now back off.
So... you tried to sand it off?
Isn't that what you do?
Yeah, but we don't
use a power sander.
Hmm.
Mr. Longet is a diabetic
as well as an
amateur dermatologist.
Vera didn't want me
just crossing it out.
Well, uh... one gram of Ancef,
update his tetanus,
and get Plastics to see him.
They may have to do a graft.
Ah. Maybe you can
move that serpent head.
Onto the body of a goddess?
I'll be right back.
Did you eat lunch?
Nah. The cafeteria
was already closed.
Voila.
Thank you.
Hey, word's out
you're going to be
an E.R. attending.
Congratulations.
Well, it's not a lock.
Can I borrow your pen?
Yeah. A lifetime of this, huh?
Well, you know, E.R.'S great.
Your free time's your own.
What free time?
Well, after your residency.
You get skilled in every
aspect of medicine,
you see a variety of cases,
you have an immediate
effect upon your patients' lives.
But, mainly, it's like
joining the circus.
I'm telling you, the
opening goes in the back.
Hold it, hold it, hold it.
Oh, my God, I'm big as a house.
Hi.
Hi. Hi.
I'm Dr. Mark Greene.
Sean O'Brian.
I'm Jodi.
Jodi, why don't you
hop up on that bed?
I don't think I can
hop anywhere.
Okay. Easy.
All right. What seems
to be the problem?
Our baby's due in two weeks,
and I have to pee
every 30 seconds.
It burns, and my stomach hurts.
Sounds like a bladder infection.
Does this hurt?
No. Just don't push too hard.
I got to go again.
Okay.
36 minus four.
Baby's about five or six pounds.
Do you have any
other medical problems?
No. No.
Oh...
Is that cold?
Yes.
I'll just take a
quick listen here.
I love that sound.
That's great.
Any, uh... cramping?
Any vaginal bleeding?
No.
You can feel the baby move?
Uh-huh.
Think you can give me
a urine sample?
Are you kidding?
No.
Yes, I think I can do that.
Okay, I want you
to follow my finger
with just your eyes.
Good. Okay, now squeeze
your eyes tight like this.
Mm-hmm.
Great. Okay, press
against my hand
with your face.
Great. Okay.
Show me your teeth.
Is Grandma ever going
to be able to walk again?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
She's going to be fine.
I know what you're
thinking, Jackie,
so why don't you just
go ahead and say it?
Shut up, Peter.
No, no. Go ahead and say it.
I mean, it's my fault
that this happened, right?
I'm so pigheaded
and self-centered.
Peter... just shut
up and sit down.
B.P.'s 90 over 60.
Found him in the greenhouse...
Passed out in the back.
Comes to visit me
at my place of work,
and this is the
shape that he's in?
Hydrate with a liter of saline.
You're going to go
where I tell you to go.
I am not losing another son
to alcohol and drugs.
I am not!
38 weeks, but I
think her dates are off.
Baby's small on exam.
Initial B.P. is 130/90
but, over a couple of hours,
B.P.'S been fine...
Around 120/80.
FHT's normal, no
cramps or spotting.
Got your test results.
U.A. shows white cells
too numerous to count,
bacteria two plus protein,
CBC's normal, no fever.
Simple cystitis.
Fluids, rest
and a course of bactrim.
It's a bladder infection.
Who are they?
Med students.
They're so young.
I know. It's
disgusting, isn't it?
Near term, antibiotic of choice
is Macrodantin, okay?
Now, I want you to take these...
lots of fluids,
rest, and follow up
with your doctor in the morning.
Okay?
The sulfas compete
with the bilirubin
for the binding
sites on albumen,
increasing the risk
of neonatal jaundice.
He saves lives, he teaches,
he slices and dices...
Listen, Deb, can you work up
a "weak and dizzy"
in Three for me?
Uh... Doctors?
Would you sign a get-well card?
Sure.
Who is this for?
Me.
What is it?
Hemorrhoids.
Yeah, that's right there.
Dr. Ross, kid's crashing.
What? Here.
His pulse is down to 40.
Pupils are pinpoint.
Haleh, get a B.P.
He's frothing at the mouth.
Is it drugs?
Something else is going
on. He's incontinent.
Negative drug screen.
B.P. 70/50.
Where do you work?
Wrigleyville Nursery.
Nursery, as in school?
No, like in plants.
Outside, or in the office?
Both.
Mig of atropine, I.V. push.
Take off his clothes.
Wear gloves.
Let's start a drip,
milligram an hour,
2-pam, one gram over 30 minutes.
What's wrong with him?
It's insecticide poisoning.
What kind of
chemicals do you carry?
I don't know. We use everything.
We were spraying in the
greenhouse this morning.
Is he going to be
all right? I think so.
I'm going to call the nursery.
What do you have?
Elderly man with hemorrhoids.
Oh, yuck.
Everyone is so old
and sick around here.
Yeah. This is a hospital.
Yeah, I guess.
Where's Benton?
He's in surgery
with his mom. Hey.
Hi, guys.
You working graveyard?
Yep.
7:00 p.m., no Benton.
Maybe I'll get home
by 8:00 for once.
Somebody help me!
My wife's
unconscious in the car!
Dr. Greene!
Please, somebody help me!
She's pregnant! Hurry!
She just passed out!
Okay, fine.
Freeze right there!
It's my mother; I
want to scrub in.
Well, you take one more step,
and I will have your
ass hanging on my wall
right next to your residency.
I want to help.
Don't test me.
Out!
Now divide the iliotibial tract.
Hemostat.
Watch her airway.
Charging 50 amps.
Get a stat B.P.
She looks postictal.
How much O2 do you
want? 15 liters by mask.
Oh, my God. What's going on?
Carter, help Mr. O'Brian.
Mr. O'Brian, we really
need to work here.
B.P.'s high. 160/110.
You okay, babe? Here's a vein.
We got a second I.V.
Do you need bloods?
She's eclamptic.
Mag sulfate, four grams I.V.
I'm right here, baby.
Get your coffee yet?
Do you need bloods?
Yeah, she needs a
chem 24, a coag panel
and put her on a fetal monitor.
Cap refill's fair.
Mr. O'Brian?
Yeah.
Your wife has eclampsia.
Is she going to die?
No, no. We just need to get
her admitted and medicated...
She's seizing!
Carter, grab a bite block.
Is that mag in?
I got it.
Restrain her.
Somebody do something!
Somebody help her!
Help her.
Push another
four of mag sulfate.
Baby, you're going to be okay.
Another four mag.
I.V.'s out.
The other one's blown.
I'll thrown in an
external jugular.
Two migs of Ativan.
Where's the prep pad?
Restrain her.
Ativan's in.
All right, restrain her.
It's in.
You got her? Sort of.
Two Ativan.
O2, 15 liters.
Okay, seizure's stopping.
All right. Let's
hyperventilate her.
Get doptones. Grab the ambu.
I'll do a quick pelvic.
Let's get a blood gas.
Lift up this leg.
Fetal heart tones strong at 140.
That's good news.
Running 30cc's of saline.
Two centimeters
dilated, 80% effaced.
Membrane's intact.
Call upstairs, see
who's on call for O.B.
Doctor, what the
hell is going on?
Your wife has a
disorder of late pregnancy
known as eclampsia.
The blood vessels go into spasm,
causing a lack of
oxygen to the brain,
which leads to the seizures.
We're relaxing them
with this medicine.
What about the baby?
We'll need to deliver.
When?
Soon.
Very soon.
So who's in Trauma One?
30-year-old pregnant woman
with an eclamptic seizure.
She's postictal, but
she's coming around.
B.P.'s stabilized? Mm-hmm.
Mag sulfate going? Mm-hmm.
Okay, well, I'll take
over. Go home.
Nah, that's all right. I'd like
to see her through to O.B.
I can handle it.
No, it's not about you. It's me.
I saw her earlier, and
I diagnosed a U.T.I.
I sent her out,
and she seized
in the parking lot.
Oops. I thought the
protein in her urine
was due to cystitis,
and I blew off
one borderline B.P.
I'd feel better if I
saw her through.
Yeah.
Fundal placenta.
Looks okay.
B.P. 120/70. That's very nice.
Look at little Hunter.
Dermot.
Jason.
Patrick.
Is that a boy, or what?
Four plus turtle sign.
What's that?
He looks like a little head
kind of peeking out.
You give a score
of zero or two
for each category.
Movement?
He seems very active.
Every night, around
the same time.
Okay. Score two.
Also breathing tone,
amount of fluid...
He's an eight.
Anything less
than a six, and you worry.
You do the A.F.I.
Yeah.
You divide the
abdomen into four.
Okay.
Find the deepest
pockets of fluid
without fetal parts
or umbilical cord.
You mark each corner
of the quadrant, measure,
then add up.
Is that what
this number is over here?
No. That's
the baby's heart rate.
That should be
between 120 and 160.
So 140's perfect.
Yeah.
The baby's in great shape.
Biophysical profile's eight.
A.F.I.'s 14.
Cervix is favorable.
I've got a non-stress
test started.
Mm-hmm. I feel very comfortable.
I've delivered a
couple hundred babies.
It's 9:00. So we'll see
you in about an hour.
What did Coburn say?
She's at Saint Luke's,
and she says she'll be here
as soon as she's finished
with her repeat C-section.
Oh, and she wants
me to start an induction.
That is, of course,
if I feel comfortable.
She said that?
Yeah.
What a bitch.
Yeah. Hmm. Hey, Drake.
How do things look?
Looks great.
B.P.'s have been
perfectly normal.
Oh, boy.
How can I...? Excuse me.
He can't be more
than 12 years old.
He's the O.B. resident on call.
I just spoke with Dr. Coburn,
our O.B. attending,
and she agrees that we
need to deliver you soon.
Does that mean you
have to do a C-section?
I want to deliver naturally.
Your eclampsia's under control,
the baby's in good shape,
and the cervix is favorable.
I'd say we do a trial of labor.
And if that doesn't work?
I think it will work.
I want to give it a try.
Let's do it!
Excuse me.
Yep?
Mark, do you feel confident
to handle this down
here without me?
We're getting slammed upstairs.
I think I can muddle through.
All right. I'll check back
with you at, say, 2300.
Roger.
Carol? Yeah?
Could you give Mrs.
O'Brian .5 Pitocin I.V.?
You're inducing down here?
Yeah. We're going to start here,
then we'll get her up to O.B.
Okay.
How frequent are
the contractions?
Every ten minutes or so.
Let's have Dr. Greene decide.
You're kidding.
We can't call him "Baby
X" when we call our parents.
All right, let's
take a quick look.
Okay.
Okay. It's five
centimeters dilated,
90% effaced, station
minus two. Membrane's intact.
You want to look, too?
May I?
Why not? Everybody else
has been poking around in there.
Here.
Hmm...
"Ian, Patrick, Dermot..."
Sounds like the cast
of Finian's Rainbow.
Ow!
Sorry.
"Hunter."
Hunter O'Brian?
You agree with my assessment?
Uh... yeah.
Your labor's progressing
along nicely and quickly.
The baby's doing great.
Is it normal for the
baby's heart rate
to be going down like that?
As long as it's briefly,
and stays over 120.
Jared's on both lists.
Oh, no.
It's not my favorite.
Compromise is
the soul of marriage.
"Jared" it is.
"Jared." "Jared."
Jared's...
Jared?
Yes.
Okay, feel better.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Hey, Mark, how come
the O.B. case is still here?
They're still busy upstairs.
I got to call again.
Dr. Greene!
Something's wrong.
The baby's heart...
The monitor's down to 90.
Something's not right.
It's not supposed
to go that low, right?
Hey, Ma. Hangin' in there?
Hey, how you doing, Ma?
Why so long in recovery?
She's 76.
Estimated blood loss?
500cc's.
All right. Post-op orders?
She may be your mother,
but she's my patient.
We're taking the O.R. elevator.
She's going to 604.
It was bound to happen
sooner or later, Peter.
Okay, Sweetie, let's try
deep, cleansing breaths.
Let's exhale on
a count of three.
Shut up, Sean!
Call O.B. and
get the fas in here.
How we doing, Mrs. O'Brian?
I believe I'll have an epidural.
Contractions are two
to three minutes apart.
No kidding.
Tracing's showing
decreased reactivity.
What's that?
The baby's heart
rate is reacting
or varying less than it should.
But, babies sleep
in 20-minute cycles,
so what we want to
do is wake him up.
Rise and shine.
Whoa.
There we go.
He was just sleeping.
The heart rate's back up.
Get an ETA on Coburn. Okay.
I'm Dr. Urami, Anesthesiology.
I'm here to do your epidural.
Oh, yes, please, let's do that.
How's that epidural?
Wonderful.
These are great.
I'm going to show these pictures
of little Jared to my students.
Eighth graders?
Yeah, you know,
like Show and Tell.
In math class?
Now we can get a pressure
reading inside the uterus.
This scalp electrode
monitors the pulse
rate more exactly.
Enjoying the show?
Yeah.
I mean, no.
She's eight centimeters dilated.
Completely effaced.
Won't be long.
There's another decel.
Variable with a late component.
Let's infuse
500cc's normal saline
through the uterine catheter.
Like a regular I.V.?
Yeah.
We need to get her up to O.B.
I'll see if I can light a
fire under someone's butt.
Is something wrong?
No. We're okay.
Page Coburn again.
Okay.
Why can't I just send her up?
She's inches away, and
the epidural's wearing off.
Then find Drake. Hurry up!
Breathe, breathe.
You want to try
some of the breathing?
You know that fantasy you have
about me quitting
work, staying home,
and having a bunch of kids?
Forget it. This is it!
Competitive lates.
We need to deliver.
Okay, I need to take a look.
Try some single breaths.
Fully dilated, 100% effaced.
It's time to start to push.
Already? Yep.
Here? Here.
Run and get Carol.
Oh! Oh!
Try some breathing.
I love you so much, babe.
So much. So much.
Shut up! Oh!
Get a baby warmer
and a newborn resuscitation
tray in Three, stat!
Okay, push, push. Nine, ten.
Good, good. Good. Take a breath.
Take a breath, sweetie.
Welcome back.
Did I go home?
Push, one, two, three,
four, five, six, seven...
eight, nine, ten.
I'm not ready to be a mother.
Bear down.
I can't! It's going
to rip me apart.
One, two, three,
four, five, six...
I can't! I can't!
Get it out!
Carter, Carter,
Go to O.B. and drag Drake down.
Tell him to bring some
forceps, okay? Go, go.
She's not progressing.
The baby's heart
rate's dangerously low.
I'm going to start
the pudendal block.
Okay.
O.B.'s got two C-sections
and three imminent deliveries.
Mark, Mark, no one will
blame you if you wait for O.B.
The baby monitor
says now or never.
Why put your ass on the line?
Cause I've come this far.
I'm going to see it through.
Where's Coburn?
In transit.
What, is she coming by camel?
Get her B.P.
B.P.'s still climbing, 150/100
Go, Mark, baby's bradying down.
Okay, now don't
push. No, don't push
Before I break the blades,
cut a median episiotomy.
Here comes the head.
Can you breathe?
All right, here comes the head.
Look at me.
Get a blanket? Damn!
Get him out.
He's stuck.
Shoulder dystocia.
What's that?
His shoulder's hung
up on the pubic bone.
It's okay, sweetie.
Oh, my God.
Leads off.
Macrobert's maneuver.
Push the legs up
towards her head.
Okay, lift her legs.
Okay, I've got her legs.
I've got it. Straight up in
the air, straight up in the air.
Someone push
down on the abdomen.
What are you doing?
Trying to free his shoulders.
Push. Carter, not
fundal pressure.
Down here. Down here.
He's jammed.
Stat page O.B.
Oh, God. Do something!
Let's try a woods.
I need to extend the episiotomy.
If I can rotate the
posterior shoulder medially.
I love you, baby.
Try to deliver the posterior
shoulder. Come on.
He's jammed in.
Come on.
Come on! Come on!
Why can't you deliver this baby?
Mr. O'Brian, please.
It's not working.
Let her go. Let her go.
Zavenelli.
What are you doing?
Zavenelli. We've got to
push the baby back in.
Then what?
We're almost home.
We got to roll her
on her left side.
Susan, get your hand in here.
Grab a caesarean tray. Run!
Climb on up. Hold her head in.
Throw a sheet over her.
Get her into trauma one.
Find out if Benson's still
here. Splash and crash.
Okay.
Where are you taking her?
We've got to do an
emergency C-section.
I need your consent.
What the hell are you doing?
Have you done this before?
I've scrubbed in many times.
No. I want somebody
else in here.
It can't wait. If we
wait five more minutes,
your baby's brain dead.
Oh, my God. Go! Go! Go!
Watch the I.V. Do it!
Get moving!
Mr. O'Brian, please
get out of the way.
Sweetie, I'm right here.
I love you so much.
Put a rush on the blood.
We're almost home.
Mr. O'Brian.
I love you. I'm right
here, right here.
Call respiratory, stat.
Come on, Mr. O'Brian,
you have to wait outside.
I love you, I love
you! Wait out here.
I'm right here. I'm right here.
Splash it with Betadine.
B.P.'s sky high, 170/120.
What about anesthesia?
There's no time.
I'll throw in a local.
Oh! She's seizing!
Grab the bite block.
All right. Let's
paralyze and intubate.
Versed four migs.
Norcuron ten.
Intubation tray.
Get respiratory down here.
Seven point five.
Here's your 7.5.
Suction standing by.
Okay, O2 at 15.
Carter, try to get in here.
We're just going
to bag her for now.
Get that typed blood
cross-matched and down here.
I need you down here.
Where's the coag panel?
Get a vent ready.
Her B.P.'S 200/130.
She's going to stroke out.
Okay, everybody, just
take a deep breath, all right?
Okay, hydralazine ten migs.
Another bolus of mag sulfate.
Somebody call N.I.C.U.
and get somebody
down here for the baby.
Somebody physically
go up to the O.B.
and drag somebody
down here, okay?
Go!
Get the suction in.
Scalpel.
Let's see...
is that the fascia?
Uh... yeah, yeah,
that looks right.
Grab with those clippies.
Hydralazine's in.
Grab an army/navy. Suction.
Metz.
The long scissors.
Retract there.
Okay.
I'm in.
Isn't there something
about a bladder flap?
Pickups.
Suction.
I'm dividing the peritoneum.
Hemostat.
Okay, we're in. Grab
that side and pull.
Okay.
Get a retractor in there.
We need exposure. Pull.
Oh, man.
That's wide enough.
All right, now, scalpel.
You cut across
the lower segment of the uterus?
You're asking me?
I'm asking God.
Suction. No. Here.
I don't think you're
all the way through.
I don't want to cut the baby.
Open a pack of lap pads.
Retract this way, more. Okay.
Here...
There. I think I'm in.
Oh, my God!
There's two liters in there.
She's got an abruption.
She's bleeding out.
Carter, Chen, gown up.
Get the baby out.
Open those IV lines.
Hurry, Mark, get him out.
Get the baby.
Pump in the saline.
Forget that cross-match.
Eight units of O-neg
down here stat.
Hurry up.
I got him.
He's big.
Hurry up. Suction his airway.
B.P.'s okay, 120 over 80.
Hurry up.
Cord's free.
Suction, suction his nose.
Umbilical clamp.
He's not breathing.
Okay, clamp.
All right. Bag him.
Carter, get in here.
Huh? Carter?
Get in here.
Follow my hand down.
Feel the aorta?
I don't know.
It's pulsing.
Yeah. I do.
Okay, push down
on it and don't let go.
You got it?
I think so.
Don't think, do.
I got it.
P.D. mask.
Is he alive?
Apgar's one.
B.P.'s 110 over 70.
Move. Move.
No respiratory effort,
pulse 32. Start C.P.R.
I'm going to intubate.
All right. Clip.
Heel stick of glucose.
Tone is flaccid.
We need a blood gas.
I can't see.
Suction.
O-neg's here.
All right. Pump it in.
I think I'm in.
Bag him.
Let me take a quick listen.
Chest expands well with bagging.
Yeah, okay. We got it.
Tape it and keep bagging.
All right, blood sugar's 20.
Give him D-10.
He's got no veins.
Hyperventilate him.
I'm going to try
an umbilical line.
What about some epi?
Point zero four.
Epi down the tube.
Here's the epi.
Release that clamp
after I tie this off.
Here, I've got it.
Release the clamp.
Oh, my God, how can you see?
I don't know.
Grab a bag of O-neg.
Stick with ten per kilo.
40cc's.
Oh, come on.
Come on.
That's the umbilical vein.
Okay, hook it up
while I advance it.
Okay. It's going.
Glucose at five mil per kilo.
Follow me down.
20 Mils.
Come on, little guy.
Come on.
He moved. I swear
to God, he moved.
It's going, 100.
He's pinking up.
She's had three units,
two liters normal saline.
Vitals?
B.P.'s 80/50, pulse 112.
I can live with that
and so can she.
Baby's five-minute
apgar's much better, eight.
That's good.
Go ahead and re-gown, Susan.
Cavalry's here.
What's going on in here?
I intubated. The baby went bad.
I tried forceps and
got a shoulder dystocia.
She seized.
I paralyzed and
did a crash section.
Got in there and there were
two liters of blood in her uterus.
You knew she'd abrupted?
No, once I got in there.
Baby nearly died.
Who is this and what's
he doing in there?
John Carter, med student
and I'm pressing on the aorta.
It's a damned mess. What
did you use, a chain saw?
Well, I couldn't just
stand around waiting
while that baby died.
Get an N.I.C.U.
transport team over here
and the O.B. resident on call.
You should have let me know
you were in over your head.
Let's get a Foley in.
We got hemostatsis.
Someone call respiratory.
Okay, Carson, you
can let go of the aorta.
Wait, wait.
Wait. Wait. Just stop.
Looks good.
Bleeding stopped.
Go talk to the father.
Suction.
Is my baby all right?
He was apneic at first,
but his five-minute
apgar was very encour...
Stop hiding behind
that damn medical crap.
I think your baby's
going to be fine. Let's go.
Don't take my son.
And Jodi?
There was bleeding.
She's had transfusions,
but she's stabilized now.
Dr. Coburn,
the O.B. specialist, is
in there with her now.
She's closing the incision.
How can this happen?
What we need to do right now
is get your son
upstairs. Now! Go, go!
Everything's okay, right?
Go be with your baby.
There's nothing you can do now.
She's going to be okay, right?
She's stabilized.
Go with your son.
I have never seen such a
chain of errors in judgment.
Hey, I did what you said.
You miss a pre-eclampsia.
You underestimate
the fetal weight.
I was expecting O.B. backup.
You miss a placental abruption.
What?
Blood clot, right there.
You do an ill-advised
forceps delivery
on a baby that's too big
and then you do a
hack job of a C-section.
Hey, look... it was
me in the barrel
with a baby going
down the tubes.
The only thing that saved you
from disaster was dumb luck.
Yeah, well, if it wasn't for me,
the mother would be dead
and the baby a vegetable.
Who's on O.B. call?
Drake!
Mark... Mark...
she's just covering herself.
She was right.
It was my screw-up.
You were great in there, Mark.
No, no. I couldn't
have done that.
It was my fault, you know?
It was my fault
that she went sour.
She's my patient.
No one is going to blame you.
Nah, they don't have to.
Dr. Greene! She's crashing!
How many units has she had?
B.P.'s falling, 70/40.
Two O-neg, two saline packs.
I can't get a blood gas.
You run the resuscitation.
Her cap refill's bad.
I'll throw in an arterial line.
Somebody put those blood
bags on a rapid infuser. Get the kit!
Hook up the transducer.
Give her a mig of atropine.
Check a manual B.P.
She's really bleeding
from the puncture site.
Somebody put pressure on it.
I've got it.
I.V. Site's oozing, too.
I don't hear it. 60 by palp.
Hang a dopamine drip.
Pull her off that
respirator and bag her.
The blood stopped clotting.
She's going into
D.I.C. Oh, damn.
Order up ten units
cryoprecipitate and platelets.
Uh-oh. Multi-focal P.V.C.s
Oh, what now? Lidocaine
100 migs, I.V. push.
I don't get a pulse.
Start a drip.
Mark the time,
0542. Charging. 260.
Clear.
Let's go again.
Three hundred.
Clear.
She's oozing from
every cut surface.
We're chasing our tails in here.
Time down?
33 minutes.
More PVC. She's
maxed out on lidocaine.
Add pronestyl, 30 migs
a minute, up to 200.
No pulse. We're losing her.
Get a dopamine drip.
Charging.
Out of the way, out of the way.
Again, 360.
Off.
Give her 300 I.V. push.
Blood gas is bad. PO2/150.
It's been five minutes
since her last high dose epi.
Another seven.
Mark, she's gone.
It's 30 minutes past too late.
I'm calling it.
Time of death, 0646.
It's not flatlined.
It's fine v-fib.
Another seven migs epi.
Dr. Greene?
I, uh, just wanted to
say... to, or, to tell you
that, um, I thought what
you did was a heroic thing.
It's just one stop the other
way, right by the train station.
I got to get going.
Come on.
Not only does Shorty's have
the greasiest eggs in town
stuff falls from the ceiling
every time the el goes by.
Sounds attractive, Susan.
I just got a million
things I got to do.
Are you sure you're okay?
I'm fine, scout's honor.
Is Jen home?
Captioning sponsored
by WARNER BROS.