My son, 15 years ago,
I lost him to drugs.
I just don't know where he is.
You have a call from...
Sean Archer.
An inmate
at Cook County Jail.
Dad?
You have
a relationship with
our perfect daughter.
I'm married,
and I love my husband,
and I can't be a part of that.
You all right?
All my clothes,
everything, it's gone.
Jessa Rinaldi,
we're placing you
under arrest.
You're charged
with aggravated arson
and one count
of attempted murder
against Dr. Will Halstead.
Hey, are people
still coming
in and out of here?
Yeah, my contractor
came by last week
to work up an estimate.
You know, he thinks
we can salvage
a lot of this.
Now I'm just waiting
on the frigging insurance
company to approve my claim.
Well, you're in violation
of building code
sections 13-117-12
and 125.
And until such a time
they're remedied,
a fine of $700
will be assessed daily.
Hey, hey, hey.
Can you give me
a break here?
I don't know
what I'm supposed to do.
Hey, if it were up to me,
I'd call in a wrecking ball
and get it over with.
You got old.
Yeah, it's been
a while, so...
Fifteen years.
I wasn't sure
you were coming in.
Well, I would have
come earlier,
but it turns out that
it takes a while to get
granted visitation.
So I was talking
to your lawyer,
a Lisa Bly?
Uh...
From the... The public
defender's office?
Mm-hmm.
She said something
about a plea deal.
Yeah, we talked it over.
She didn't think it was
a good idea to fight this.
Doesn't sound like
she fills you with
confidence, does she?
I'm gonna get you
a new lawyer,
somebody who knows
what the hell
they're doing.
It's okay.
I'm cool with it.
You're cool with it,
just staying in prison?
That can't possibly be
what you want.
Can we change
the subject, please?
Oh, for Christ's sake!
Sean, you've been like this
since you were a kid.
You're always giving up
on things too easily.
Kind of like how
you gave up on me.
Are you still using?
Hmm?
You know what?
This was not a good idea.
Hey, I'm just trying...
I'm hanging up now, Dad.
We should do this
again sometime,
maybe in another 15 years.
Wait a second.
I'm just trying to...
Seven hundred
dollars a day.
Can you believe that?
It's like I just got
hit by a truck
and they want me
to donate the little bit
of blood I have left.
Maybe you should
just tear it down
like the guy said.
Are you kidding me?
Hannah, I got
way too much invested.
No, screw them.
I'm gonna file an appeal.
It's been, what, like,
a month since the fire?
Yeah, and?
I'm feeling like you're
embracing this modern-day Job
thing a bit too vigorously.
Hey, we could use
the two of you.
So, do you think I'm acting
like some kind of martyr?
I'm just saying that
the sooner you
let this go,
the sooner you can
move on with your life.
Nine-year-old male,
25 mile-per-hour
motor vehicle crash.
Mom and son
both restrained and stable.
No loss of consciousness.
Kid complaining of pain
in right arm.
Mom has no vocal complaints.
She's coming in
right behind us.
I got Mom.
It looks like they might be
living out of their car,
for what it's worth.
Good to know. Thanks.
Hey there.
I'm Dr. Halstead.
Actually, I'm Will.
What's your name?
Uh, Hen... Henry.
Can I ask what
you got in that jar?
It's a chrysalis.
One day, it's gonna
turn into a butterfly.
That is super cool.
Would it be all right
if Nurse Doris here
holds on to it
while I look at your arm?
Thanks.
Let's get X-ray in here.
Yeah.
Now let's look at this arm.
Does it hurt?
Yes.
I know.
I'm sorry, buddy.
Ow.
Okay, that's it.
Anything else hurt?
No.
Good.
Now, do you remember
what happened?
Um, we were looking
for a new parking spot,
and, uh... I don't know,
Mom just kind of
drove off the side
of the road.
Okay. We're gonna
get a quick picture
of your arm, all right?
Hey, you're being
really brave.
All right, X-ray up.
Well, now that doesn't
look too bad.
All right, Henry,
I'm gonna go talk
to your mom for a minute.
I'll be right back.
Here you go.
How are we looking?
X-ray is clear.
Beyond a scrape or two,
I'd say she's doing all right.
Ms. Mitchell,
I'm Dr. Halstead.
I just saw your son.
He's fine,
except for some arm pain.
The X-ray
showed a nondisplaced
distal radius fracture,
just a fancy way of saying
he broke his arm.
What?
It'll heal quickly
with a simple cast.
I just need
your consent to treat him.
No.
Excuse me?
What have you done
with my boy?
Henry's right next door.
Who are you?
What am I doing here?
Jenny,
you had a car crash.
I don't believe you.
You've been brought
to Chicago Med. I'm Dr. Asher.
This is Dr. Halstead.
You're... You're with
the collection agency,
aren't you?
I told you already.
You can't have our souls.
Okay, whoa, whoa, whoa.
All right.
Give five of Haldol.
Jenny...
Let me out of here!
It's okay, Jenny.
Right now!
Calm down.
Let us help you.
Nobody touches my son!
No.
Hey, can I get everyone's
attention, please?
Thank you.
I'm sure that
you have all
noticed lately
that we are running low
on a number
of key supplies,
dialysis tubing,
contrast dye, syringes.
And I am just as frustrated
as all of you are
at the seemingly intractable
and unpredictable
supply chain disruptions,
but we are working
to find solutions.
Meanwhile, I'd like
to remind you that
we are all in this together.
Be mindful of that,
all right?
Let's all get back to work.
Are you two looking
for a consult?
Yeah, I got a 9-year-old
in Three with a broken arm
whose mom won't give us
consent to treat him.
Her behavior suggests
some kind of
psychiatric disorder.
We were forced
to sedate her.
What did you give her?
She still seems
pretty animated.
Five of Haldol.
Maybe she's
a little resistant to it.
Yeah, at least now
you can go speak with her
and convince her
to let us help her son.
You know, I'd rather wait
for the labs and see
what the tox screen says.
What about the boy?
I'll go talk to him.
Any other family around?
Father, grandfather?
No, none that we could find.
Okay, I'll report back.
Ah, there's a vaguely
familiar face.
You're finally back
from vacation, I see.
You know, for a second there,
I thought we, uh...
We lost you for good.
Hey, I came in early
to get a coffee with you.
You weren't in.
Uh, yeah, I had
to get my oil changed,
but you look well-rested.
No cell service,
no Wi-Fi.
Just surf, sand,
and the stars
for two weeks.
Yeah.
I am, as they say,
totally chill.
Excuse me,
Dr. Archer.
I was wondering if I could
go over this patient with you.
First-year resident,
Dr. Zach Hudgins.
Allow me
to introduce you to
one of your attendings,
Dr. Ethan Choi.
I'm sure Dr. Choi
would be, like,
totally happy to assist.
Pleasure to meet you, sir.
Hi, Zach.
What do we got here?
Fifty-one-year-old male,
progressive cough,
congestion in his chest.
His sats are kind of crappy.
Crappy, you say?
Low 90s, high 80s.
Did you get
a chest X-ray?
That's happening now,
but here's the thing.
The patient
has advanced stage ALS.
Kind of a detail you might
want to lead with, Zach.
What's the patient's name?
Albert. Albert Marrero.
Whoa. Let me see that.
Albert Marrero.
Take a deep breath.
All I have.
Well, I think
you're holding out
on me, Al.
So I understand
you two go back a ways.
Dean, first to diagnose.
It's a little over
six years ago now.
I won that bet,
by the way, Al.
Check's in the mail.
Well, I don't think
you have a pneumonia yet.
Your X-ray is okay,
but these things can lag
by a day or two.
Oh, goody.
But your lungs do sound
a little junky.
You're just not clearing
your secretions adequately.
ALS can weaken
your diaphragm,
and thus, your cough
just isn't strong enough.
Uh, we call it plugging,
but it could be
a little difficult to clear.
Right, which is why
I think it would be prudent
to just run
a bronchoscope down there
and clear it all up.
No muss, no fuss.
Would you need
to put me under?
Light sedation,
so as to make it
easier to intubate.
No.
Al, it would
only be temporary.
It's not as invasive
as it sounds.
I have a DNI.
I don't have control
over what this disease
is doing to my body.
I, at least, want to keep
control over how I die.
Al, look, we're getting way
too ahead of ourselves here.
We're just talking
about clearing some mucus.
Dean, can I talk to you?
Sure.
Excuse us.
Hey, Dean, I think
we can clear the plugging
without bronching him.
Eh, doubtful.
Put the percussion vest
on him, chest BT,
breathing treatments,
just like a CF patient.
Come on.
It's worth a shot.
Yeah.
Huh. Only a two?
It's okay if it hurts
more than that, you know?
Matter of fact,
what I'm hearing is
that the higher the number,
the more likely
the nurses are to
bring you some ice cream
from the cafeteria.
I'm just saying.
My arm really
doesn't hurt that bad.
Okay.
Are you here
to take me away
from my mom?
No, Henry, I'm not.
Why are you, uh...
Why are you
asking me that?
A lot of people have
been talking about that.
What I really want to talk
to you about is this beautiful
chrysalis you have.
How long
have you had it for?
Maybe a month or so.
Your mom get that for you?
Mm.
Has she been
going through a bit
of a tough time recently?
See those markings
at the bottom of the wings?
And that means it's a girl.
No kidding? You know,
I didn't know that.
She might not look
so good now,
but pretty soon,
she's gonna break out
and be beautiful again.
I know it.
I tell you what,
that's one gutsy
little kid in there.
Look, far as I can tell,
his mom started
to act out around,
I don't know,
first of the year.
Psychotic break?
I don't think so.
I mean, bipolar,
schizophrenia,
they just rarely present
this late in life.
Mm.
Tox screens come back yet?
Clear. Nothing
in the blood or urine.
Okay, well,
I want to take a look
and then maybe try and have
a conversation with the mom.
So what about Henry?
His arm is stable, right?
I mean,
not getting any worse.
We got a bit of time.
How long is a bit?
I mean,
this kid needs our attention
in more ways than one.
Mom clearly can't help him.
They're living
out of their car.
I think we should
double doc his consent
or get a court order.
In order to do that,
though, Will,
I've got to declare her
incapable of caring
for her child,
which means put her
on a psych hold, which means
getting DCFS involved.
Look, I'm worried
about the kid, too.
I just really want
to make sure we're
right before we go there.
Yeah, of course.
Okay.
Maggie? Maggie?
Yeah.
Grant, what are you
doing here?
Is everything okay?
Look.
Keith here had an accident
on the worksite.
They asked us to wait
for an intake nurse,
but I was hoping maybe I had
enough pull to cut the line.
I don't know.
We kind of have
a system here.
Hey, Grant.
What's up?
We've got a bit
of a situation
here, V.
Okay, yeah,
let's take a look.
Room Five is okay,
isn't it?
Sure.
Okay, come on.
We were doing
some site prep for
a new sports therapy clinic
I designed down
in Hyde Park.
Anyway, the team was clearing
some dead trees, and...
Okay. Okay, how about
I take a look?
Let's see.
Don't touch it, okay?
Let's just
have you chill here
for a second
while we come up
with a game plan.
Thanks, Vanessa, Maggie.
We're gonna need
a CT of this.
Put the order in.
I'll call CAT scan.
Okay.
Dr. Choi!
What's going on?
He's really struggling.
O2 sats 82 and falling.
Nasal cannula.
You can't clear
the mucus.
Don't worry, Al.
We'll get you through this.
Help me
sit him forward.
Now bang on his back.
No, use your fist!
Pound with
your first hard!
Sats at 70s.
I don't want to hurt him.
For Christ's sakes.
Get out of here.
There it is.
I'm not losing this one,
not today.
I know it might not
seem like it
at the moment,
but you, Keith,
are a lucky guy.
Somehow this stick managed
to lodge itself cleanly
along the side of your orbit
without penetrating
your eyeball.
So we can just go ahead
and take it right out.
Right now?
It'll be fine.
Are you sure
you're qualified
to do this?
Well, she finished
top of her class, Keith.
I can give you something
to calm your nerves,
if you'd like.
No, no,
just get it over with.
Okay.
Hold still.
There. All done.
Thank you.
How does it feel?
It still hurts a ton,
but yeah, better than
a second ago.
Yeah, we'll give you
something for the pain.
In the meantime,
if you could just
follow my finger.
Yeah.
Did you just see that,
how steady her hand is
and how confident?
I know.
It's like we created
some kind of Jedi Knight.
I'm honestly
just blown away.
She's your
spitting image, Maggie.
It's crazy how that works.
Any word yet
from Ophthalmology?
They're swamped.
They say they'll be
down this afternoon.
I really don't want
to discharge Keith
until they see him.
If you've got to get back
to work, I can call you
when we're done here.
No, Keith's worked for me
for, like, 15 years.
I'm staying until
he's cleared to go.
But maybe we can
all have lunch together.
Yeah, that's
a great idea.
Uh, I don't know.
I don't think
I can get away.
Oh, come on, Maggie.
It'll be fun.
I'm sorry. Crockett, Kai,
we have incoming.
Please, Maggie.
Could you just for me?
Okay, but not for
another hour.
Let's go!
We're going to Baghdad.
What do we got?
Julián Sanchez, GSW.
Two holes, left thigh,
maybe through and through.
Moderate blood loss
in the field.
Put a pressure dressing on it,
but not actively bleeding now.
Dropped his pressure
in the ambo.
Gave him a liter of fluid.
BP now 100 with
a heart rate of 125.
Okay, Julián,
I'm Dr. Marcel.
We're gonna take
good care of you, okay?
Hang in there, bud.
Okay, everyone.
Nice and easy...
On my count.
One, two, three.
Easy, easy.
Let's get him up
on monitors.
Okay, DP and PT pulse
has diminished.
Let's strip and flip him,
make sure there's
no other holes.
Okay, here we go.
One, two, three.
Easy, easy.
Just two in the thigh.
No active bleeding.
Okay, let's have X-ray
get us a quick chest
and pelvis, okay?
Why do we need a chest X-ray?
He was only shot in the leg.
One whole bullet in,
one whole bullet out.
Make sure they connect.
He was shot twice.
Bullets travel
in unexpected ways, right?
How would you feel
if you left a bullet
in his chest?
X-ray is ready.
Okay, you know what?
Why don't you go tell Maggie
that we're gonna need an angio
to find where the injury
to the artery is.
I'll finish up here.
Jenny? How are you doing?
I'm Dr. Charles.
They sent you in here
to get my consent,
didn't they?
Who's "they"?
The other ones pretending
to be doctors.
That redheaded one
tried to convince me
my son had a broken arm.
You know,
Dr. Halstead is,
in fact, a doctor.
And, you know, Jenny,
he wasn't lying. I mean,
I can show you the X-ray.
You think I can't tell
a fake?
I want to see
your supervisor,
or I swear, I...
Jenny?
You all right?
What's going on?
Who are you again?
I'm Dr. Charles,
and we were just talking
about Henry,
about your son.
I already told you.
I'm not giving anyone
permission to treat my son.
Well, you know what?
I'm actually, um...
I'd like to get
your permission
to treat you, if that's okay.
Me?
There's nothing
wrong with me.
But unfortunately,
we can't release
you or Henry
before we rule out
any trauma
from the car crash.
So if it's okay,
I'd just like to send you
upstairs for a quick scan.
And as soon as that's done,
I'm free to go?
I tell you what,
how about we do the scan
and see what it tells us
and then go from there?
Does that sound like
a plan?
Okay.
Did you get her consent?
Not exactly.
Um, I want to send her
upstairs for a head CT
with contrast.
And also, can you
tell Sam I want
his eyes on this, too?
Roger.
So what's going on?
You know, it just doesn't
seem like a garden-variety
psychosis, you know?
There's this odd
rhythm to it.
And she had
this temporary loss
of mentation,
and I really think
we could be looking
at something neurosurgical.
Let me guess.
Henry's broken arm
has to wait?
Well, just bear
with me, buddy.
Let's take a look at
this scan, and I think
we're gonna get some clarity.
We can continue riding out
the percussion vest
and nebs.
With a little more time,
there's a chance
it could work.
But not
a good enough chance.
The only way to clear
the plugging for sure
and restore your breathing
is with a bronchoscope.
No intubation.
I think we've
established by now, Al,
that I'm no alarmist,
so believe me
when I say this.
This thing
will kill you today,
right here in this room.
If it does,
I'm okay. I'm ready.
Really?
Just like that? Really?
You can honestly tell me
that you've got nothing
left to live for?
Your son, how's he doing?
Wife's pregnant again.
My second grandchild.
See? That's something
to look forward to,
isn't it?
It's my biggest fear, Dean,
being stuck helpless
on a vent.
I promise you, Al.
I will not
let that happen.
Hey, what's going on here?
Why isn't my patient
prepped for angio?
You're not gonna
believe this.
Apparently,
they can't find
any contrast dye.
Are you kidding me?
We need to look at
the femoral artery.
His AVIs are at 0.7.
Hey, man,
it's not my fault.
Talk to this guy.
All right,
keep an eye on his vitals.
I'll see if radiology has any.
You lucked out.
This is literally the
last drop of contrast we got.
You're kidding.
Blame COVID or the war
in Ukraine. I don't know.
She had no response
to the Haldol?
Nada, and these
weird lapses
in awareness.
And as you know,
resistance to antipsychotics
can sometimes mean...
Something's going on with
her neurotransmitters.
Yeah.
Hey, Gene?
Yeah?
I was told you might have
some contrast dye left.
Not after the scan,
I don't.
No, no, no, no.
Stop, stop.
I need that dye.
I honestly don't even know
why we're having
this conversation.
This is triage 101,
head over leg.
With all due respect, Sam,
perhaps it's not so cut
and dry in this case.
What happens, Dr. Marcel,
if you're not able
to perform your angiogram?
Well, I'll probably
have to filet
the poor guy's thigh open
in order to find
and fix the damage.
It'll be a much bigger
surgery with more blood loss
and a greater risk.
Dr. Charles?
You know, truthfully,
I'm not completely
comfortable
making the case that
our patient is of any greater
need than Dr. Marcel's.
Well, I am.
Look, Sharon,
if I'm being asked
to follow the breadcrumbs
of Ms. Mitchell's
symptomology,
I'm suspecting
she might have
an astrocytoma
or maybe a leaking aneurysm.
Now, there's no way of knowing
for certain, however,
without a CT with contrast.
But I can assure you,
if those are
the possibilities,
without intervention,
her outcome is gonna be
a whole lot worse
than a limp for
a few months.
I'm sorry,
but that sounds
so nebulous.
I mean,
we know precisely
what we have to lose or gain
with our patient.
You're just on
a fishing expedition.
Who's this guy?
Kai Tanaka-Reed.
First-year surgical resident.
It's a pleasure to meet you.
You're an intern, Kai.
Learn not to speak
unless spoken to.
Okay, can't we just
dilute the dye enough
for two procedures?
We could, but we risk
the chance of neither scan
being adequate.
Look, there's no ideal
option here, but for now,
head over leg.
The hospital
is going to prioritize
the CT scan
for Ms. Mitchell.
Once again, Sharon,
you've proven yourself
wise beyond your years.
I'll see you
up in Radiology.
Well, this sucks.
It is what it is.
Have Maggie prep an OR.
Where are we?
Just getting the RSI drugs.
All right. Let's tube him.
Yes, sirree.
Let's, uh...
Let's do that.
You all right?
Your hands look
a bit shaky.
Just feel like
I'm auditioning here.
That's not the trachea.
Neither is that.
What's taking so long?
Zach is having
a little difficulty.
It's just not lining up
for some reason.
What's the matter?
You've never done
one of these before?
No, I haven't.
Are you kidding?
My med school
all but shut down
during the pandemic.
Said it was too big
a liability to have us
interact with patients,
so we did everything online,
but I'm a fast learner.
Yeah, I don't have time
for handholding.
I'll do it myself.
Get out of the way.
No, I'm gonna need
to use a GlideScope.
Keep bagging him
until I get back.
Bag him! Bag, go!
These kids,
I swear.
Yeah.
Hey, before
you get started,
I wanted to tell you about
a book I picked up
on the beach.
It's about a death doula.
Nancy, where'd that
GlideScope blade go?
It's over there
in the cabinet.
It's all about helping
people transition
from one plane of
existence to the next.
Uh-huh.
I'm wondering
if we're doing that with Al.
What?
Honoring his journey.
You want to translate that
into English for me?
I don't think we should
be doing this bronchoscopy.
Wait, you don't think
we should be doing everything
we can to keep him alive?
Not if he doesn't
want us to.
So what, you catch
a few juicy waves,
and all of a sudden,
you're preaching
palliative care now?
Maybe.
When it's appropriate.
This is an ED, Ethan.
We save lives here.
We don't end them,
at least not on purpose.
Maybe you should have
stayed on that beach.
Mm-mm! Don't change a thing,
'cause you look fine
as you is.
Ben,
what are you doing here?
You remember?
My biannual to check
my blood markers.
Right.
Yeah.
I was supposed
to get in and out,
but they said something
about a shortage on syringes.
Can't get to me till later
this afternoon.
Oh.
But the good news is
that I am free for lunch.
You want to grab
a sandwich?
Mm-hmm.
You know what, I am tired
of the same old, same old.
There is
a food truck out there
that I'd like to try.
Okay.
Where's my angio patient?
Are we all good?
Okay, let's do a run.
What's going on here?
Trying to get
an angio done.
I thought we already
established we can't
do that without contrast.
I found a workaround
using CO2 instead.
CO2?
It works a lot like
a contrast.
Yes, I'm aware,
but it's 10 times
as dangerous.
If a gas bubble
finds its way
up to his heart...
We're injecting into
the arterial system,
Crockett, below the diaphragm.
We're all good.
Hold on.
CO2 has been delivered.
Look, right there.
That's the injury.
Should we stent
or go in open?
Damn it, drop the head.
Sats are plummeting
here, guys.
Eighty and falling.
What's going on?
Vapor lock.
Move the C-arm.
Move it. Move it.
A gas bubble is occluding
the venous return
to the heart.
But that's impossible.
Well, clearly not.
Now down to 79.
He's getting super tachy.
Let's wire a catheter
up to his heart.
No, no time.
We have to change
his position,
see if we can get the blood
past the bubble,
hope the CO2 reabsorbs.
Put your hand on his back.
Give him a couple of pats.
Right there.
That's it.
Come on, Julián.
Stay with me.
Sats are back up.
91 and climbing.
Vapor lock cleared.
Oh, man.
You're lucky
that didn't kill him.
Let's set up to open.
I don't get it, Crockett.
How the hell did that bubble
find its way to his heart?
We'll find out,
but it's Dr. Marcel.
I'm not sure I'm reading
this right, but her scan
looks completely clear.
Yeah, it's a surprise
to me, too. I was convinced
we'd find something.
I'm so seldom wrong.
Where is my son?
Where is he?
Jenny, Jenny.
Come on.
We're gonna
get out of here.
Jenny.
Henry has a broken arm.
Your son has
a broken arm, Jenny.
We need some help here!
Jenny, listen...
You said if I agreed
to that test, I'd be done.
I am tired of waiting.
You've got to let us
take care of your son.
Four of Versed IM.
Please!
Listen to the doctors!
Security!
Just do as I say.
Mom! My chrysalis!
For God's sake.
Whoa, whoa.
Jenny, careful, careful.
Watch it.
Hurry up.
No, let go of me!
Let's put you
back in the bed, bud.
It's okay.
She's okay. You're okay.
No!
It'll be okay.
No, no, no.
Are you finally gonna
give me my court order?
So DCFS will take
temporary custody of the boy
until the mother's
deemed ready to resume
her parental
responsibilities.
How long do you plan
to hold her for?
Seventy-two hours, for now.
Well, we'll just take it
day by day then.
Dr. Asher, let's get her
prepped for
transfer upstairs.
Okay, Henry, we are ready
to put a cast on that arm.
Really important question.
What color would you like?
We can do green,
purple, blue.
Blue, I guess.
Blue coming right up.
Where did those people
take my mom?
So your mom is gonna be
resting here in the hospital
for a little while,
but when we're finished here,
this nice woman
is gonna find you
a cozy place to sleep tonight.
How does that sound?
Hi, Henry.
My name is Madeline.
You know, we can put that
in a specimen cup,
if you like.
I promise to keep it safe.
Chest X-ray looks better.
Airway pressures are down.
It looks like the bronch
did the trick.
Just like
we should have done
from the beginning.
Uh, let's lighten
his sedation.
Come grab me
when he's ready to
have the tube taken out.
You got it.
Hey, Maggie.
Oh, hey.
Hey, sorry about lunch.
I just couldn't pull away.
Yeah, I saw you
and Ben head out.
Looked like you were trying
to keep him and Grant apart.
That's 'cause I was.
I haven't told Ben
about Grant yet.
Oh.
I feel bad
for pressuring you
to join us earlier.
It wasn't
very sensitive of me.
Look, I really don't want
to make anything strained
between you and Ben.
It's not your fault.
It's just something
I have to deal with.
Okay,
let's see how bad
the damage is.
Oh. Clamps.
Oh, man.
Suction.
Okay.
Yep, here's how the bubble
got to his heart.
A fistula.
What? Where?
Do you see the mix
of dark and bright red blood?
So the bullet hit
both the artery
and the vein
when it went between them,
fusing them together.
Look. You see that?
That's how the CO2
got up there so fast.
Yeah, like a superhighway
straight to the heart.
Well, nobody
could have foreseen that.
So the delusions,
the volatile mood swings.
We could be looking
at some kind of atypical
bipolar disorder.
I mean, at this point,
it very well could be.
We could start her
on a course
of olanzapine
and see how
she responds.
You're moving her upstairs?
Yeah.
Nellie, we might as well
get that going.
Okay.
Hey, listen, I pulled the tape
from when Jenny
had that episode.
You see how everything
just kind of falls off
off the ledge here,
her heart rate sats,
her BP?
Whatever's happening
with her just has to be
physiological, right?
It's what I've been saying
all along, but, you know,
the scan came back clean.
Well, we took this X-ray
of her chest upon intake.
And you see
this area of haziness
around her mediastinum?
Is it just me,
or does that appear
to be abnormally wide?
It's definitely wide.
And there's
no certain way
to tell without
more detail, but...
Often caused by a tumor.
And that can trigger
an autoimmune response
in the brain, right,
like psychosis?
Absolutely, and would
completely explain
these weird...
These dropouts
she's been having.
Hey, Dr. Cuevas,
could we hold off
on that transfer, please?
Dr. Asher, nice work.
Ophtho cleared you
to go home.
I made you a follow-up
appointment a week from now,
but from what she says,
you shouldn't have
any long-term issues
with your vision.
The patch stays on,
though, for now.
Thank you, Dr. Taylor.
Yeah.
Okay, let's go over
your at-home
and care instructions.
Excuse me.
Yeah.
Hey.
I wanted to thank you again
for helping Keith out here.
This is an ED, Grant.
We would have done that
for anybody.
Still, I just wanted
to let you know
how much I appreciate it.
The world works
in funny ways,
doesn't it?
You know, I really got
a lot of work to get done
before my shift ends, so...
Hey, Grant.
We're a little understaffed.
Do you mind helping out
and wheeling out Keith
for me?
That's okay.
I can walk.
Hospital policy, sorry.
No worries.
I got it, Taylor.
Thanks.
All right,
let's get you home.
Excuse me.
Please, after you.
Vanessa.
So I'm finally done.
Should I stick around
and give you a ride?
Sure. Thanks, babe.
Al, can you hear me?
Okay.
Okay, we're gonna
take this tube out now
by putting you
on a spontaneous
breathing trial.
So I want you to give me
some slow, deep breaths.
All right?
Okay, that's right.
Slow and deep.
Don't chase after it.
The air will come.
Just slow and deep.
That's right.
What's his RSBI reading?
130.
Are you sure you're
reading that right?
The vent says so,
and I calculated it as well.
Okay. Okay.
Hey, maybe
we should stop.
No, no, no, no, he can...
He'll get there.
All right.
Let's put him on a rate.
We'll resedate him.
I'm sorry, Al.
It's too soon
to take you off.
So we're gonna take
a couple of steps back,
and we'll try again
a little later, okay?
Please don't, Al. Al.
No, no, no, no,
Al. Al, don't.
Get self-restraints, please.
Al, stop.
Put him back on Precedex.
I'm sorry, Al, we're gonna
have to resedate you
to ease your discomfort.
I'm gonna get you
off this thing.
I promise.
So am I gonna
be able to walk?
Walk, run,
jump, whatever.
When the ambo
was bringing me in,
I didn't think
I was gonna make it.
Thank you, Dr. Marcel.
Let's not have to do
this again, all right?
Thank you so much.
You bet.
So this is
how it's gonna be?
How what's gonna be?
You taking credit
for everything.
I was just as responsible
as you for saving that
guy's life, maybe more so.
Really? After that stunt
you pulled?
That stunt pointed us
directly to the problem
and saved his leg.
All day long,
you've been
talking down to me.
I was right about
the bullet holes.
You never gave me props
for that.
And then you left it to me
to duke it out with Abrams
over the contrast dye.
You can't be serious
right now.
All I'm asking for is
credit where credit's due.
It's not that big a deal.
You're right.
I should have
given you credit.
I was very impressed
with the way
you nearly killed
our patient.
Did I tell you lately
how much I love you?
Ben, I need to
tell you something.
I know. I know,
you don't really
want to go bowling.
No.
I can tell.
You were
a little lukewarm.
No, it's not about that.
About a month or so ago,
I helped Vanessa
with finding and reaching out
to her biological father.
His name is Grant Young,
and he's an architect in town.
Okay.
I didn't want
to tell you about it earlier
because I didn't know
how you were gonna
take it.
I'm just wondering why
you're telling me this now.
Because he came in
as a patient today.
Not as a patient.
It was one of his employees.
So he was here,
and you didn't
mention that?
Listen, I made it
very clear to Grant
that I am not interested
in reconnecting with him
in any way, shape,
or form.
Ben.
You felt the need
to tell him that?
No, I didn't want there
to be any confusion.
And it's going good
between him and Vanessa.
She seems happy.
Glad to hear it.
Dr. Marcel?
Hey.
I was wondering
how today went with
young Dr. Tanaka-Reed.
Yeah, fine.
Uh, not according
to him.
He filed a complaint
with HR and claimed
you were disrespectful
and condescending.
Did he now?
And we are required
to take every
complaint seriously,
though I suspect
he must have done
something pretty egregious
to raise your hackles.
You care to file
a counter complaint?
No.
You sure?
I could have him
reassigned.
No, not necessary.
I'm sure Dr. Tanaka-Reed
and myself
will find some common ground
moving forward.
Like you said,
we're all in this
together, right?
Hey, Doris said something
about Jenny
being in surgery.
Yeah, we located
a small tumor
on her mediastinum.
Daniel thinks
that might have been
what caused the psychosis.
Really?
Mommy!
My baby boy! Oh!
Look at your arm.
I'm so sorry.
It's okay. It's okay.
I'm okay.
I thought you were trying
to hurt me and Henry.
I'm... I didn't understand.
It's all right.
You're not gonna
have to worry
about that anymore.
Mommy, look, my chrysalis.
It turned into a butterfly.
It's so beautiful.
What's that?
Your new best friend
for the next two weeks.
Welcome to boot camp.
I'm sure you already know
this about your
old man, that...
I've got a tendency
to override everything
but the sound
of my own voice.
I don't know
if you have anything
that you want to say to me
after all this time,
but if there is...
I'd like to try
my best to listen.