Oh!
Let's see if maybe...
Crap.
Doctors never mean to screw up.
Crap, crap, crap. Crap!
Are you sure you don't
want me to call for...
No. There's no time.
You make a bad call, and
the unthinkable happens.
Can I help you? Uh...
Yeah, don't you have any
just, um, regular panty hose?
We can't do that.
We have to. Lap pads!
But we still haven't... I don't
care! We're closing him up.
Zero Vicryl. Zero Vicryl, now.
Am I not being clear? Why
do you look so confused?
What about these? They're
popular. They shimmer.
No. No, no shimmer.
No footless tights or
freaky little toe sock thingies.
I just want panty
hose, basic nude.
I used to buy them
at the grocery store.
They come in a little plastic
egg kind of panty hose!
That's what I need! Is that
really so hard to understand?
It's not like we
do it on purpose.
want to hurt anyone.
But sometimes we do.
Sometimes we make mistakes.
I'm...
I'm sorry.
And when we
blow it, we're sorry.
That was inappropriate.
I'm... I'm just...
I'm under a lot of
pressure right now,
and I have a really
big day tomorrow.
You know what? That's fine.
These are fine. These are great.
Actually, I'll take all these.
I'm gonna take 'em all.
Really? Yeah.
Just, uh, ring me up.
Even these, the ones
with the rhinestones?
Even those. Okay.
Not that being
sorry really matters.
Not anymore.
No apology in the
world matters now.
Brain mapping is not
an exact science yet.
But this array brings
us one step closer.
Dr. Torres and I have had
tremendous success so far,
and because of that,
we are moving from an
animated hand to a robotic one.
Oh, she's on the stage.
I'm sorry, sir. Are you lost?
Sorry. I'm looking
for Dr. Torres. Yes. Hi.
Great. You're being sued.
Love what you're
doing here, by the way.
Robot hands. Freaky.
Who is that from? - Travis Reed?
As in the Travis Reed,
the snowboarder?
Uh, he needs a new hip.
I told him he wants you.
Wait. How do you even know him?
I was a second-year resident. He
was my first solo valve replacement.
Wow. Yeah, and six months
before he came out of nowhere
and won all those gold
medals on the half-pipe.
I believe my valve is
what gives him his edge.
Mmm-hmm.
His heart is my Mona
Lisa. Don't screw it up.
Excuse me. Where's the
onesie decorating station?
There isn't one.
There's a margarita
decorating station, though.
What? Limes.
Whoa, what kind of
baby shower... Salt.
Doesn't have a onesie
decorating station?
I mean, I had already
figured out my design.
It was gonna be
a star and a moon,
and it was gonna say "McDreamy."
Get it? That's cute,
right? Excuse me.
Is it time to open the gifts
yet? I need to sit down.
My feet are like sausages.
Oh, come on, Mer.
Oh, look at her. She's
all glowy and pregnant.
With sausage feet.
Let's have a baby. What?
Wait, wait. What,
are you serious?
We've had such a hard
year since the crash,
and wouldn't it be nice
to have something new
and happy to think about?
Yes, yes. But, um...
And I could carry this time.
And then that way, only one
of our feet would be sausages.
Arizona...
So, you want to?
Yes! Oh, my God, yes! Yeah?
You seem happy.
Oh, I am happy. I am
really, really happy.
He is so much more
attractive in person.
I got him to sign my board.
I got him to sign my bra.
Yeah, sign my cast.
So are they.
Cristina Yang!
Oh!
Oh, you look better and
better every time I see you.
Dump your husband.
Run away with me.
Oh, come on. Don't
you have a girlfriend?
We've got a deal.
I'm allowed to flirt
with hot doctors
who've had their
hands inside my chest.
It's a very short list.
Hey, I'm Travis. Hi.
You're the ortho god?
Callie Torres. I prefer
"goddess." Right on.
Ready to build me a new hip?
He needs to be able to do this.
See? Right there.
Can a new hip do that?
More importantly, will he
be doing it by December?
He's got Olympic
qualifiers coming up.
You mentioned a crash last year?
They said it gave me arthritis.
He can't win the
gold with arthritis.
I want the Peterson hip.
Buddy of mine got this one.
He was back on the
mountain in no time.
This is what I need.
Okay.
Even if I did agree
that a hip replacement is
the right course of treatment,
I've never even used the, uh,
Peterson resurfacing hip joint.
I doubt you or your team
want you to be my first.
She makes a good point.
I was Yang's first valve
replacement. That worked out.
I was the first guy to land
a triple cork in competition.
Now it's practically standard.
You're the first
orthopedic surgeon
to grow cartilage
out of nothing.
The reason we are who we are
is 'cause we're not scared of firsts.
I'll research the joint.
I'll learn what I can.
I'm not making any promises.
I'm not worried.
You're gonna say yes.
For the hundredth time, no.
I am not admitting to negligence
when there was no negligence.
They're willing to call
you a "non-party at fault."
Jury payouts are always
bigger than pre-trial settlements.
If this goes south...
Do you think it'll go south?
There was a minor
complication during surgery
because we thought the patient
had developed a pulmonary embolus.
Post-operative infections
are a common recognized risk.
And that's when the
jury's eyes will glaze over.
All they're gonna
hear is a bunch of
big words they don't understand.
And what they will see
is that you made a mistake,
and your patient paid the price.
No, it wasn't a mistake,
Greg. I'm not settling.
Okay. Okay.
And there are things
to remember tomorrow.
Let the jury see your
face. You wear a suit.
Dark, not bright.
Skirt, not pants.
Minimal jewelry,
heels, panty hose...
Panty hose?
Professional but feminine.
You still have
your wedding ring?
Yes. Wear it.
Juries respond better to
married women with families.
Now there'll be water
in front of your seat.
You drink it sparingly.
There are no bathroom breaks
till the judge calls for recess.
I don't own any panty hose.
I have to go shopping.
Did you flush? I
didn't hear you flush.
Oh, and wash your
hands! It's almost time to go!
Hey, I'm sorry I'm
late. There was traffic.
No, no, it's fine. She's ready.
She was, until she
decided she had to wear
the purple dress
instead of the heart dress.
And then she had to go potty, but
she didn't want help going potty. Sofia!
You should probably go check
and make sure she's okay in there.
What, are you okay?
Uh, I have no idea.
Hey, listen, I know you're
supposed to have Sofia tonight,
but if it'd be easier for you
to spend some time alone
or if you'd rather not be alone,
then, you know,
you just tell me,
and whatever you
need that's what we'll do.
Okay, thanks.
What? Nothing.
You put your ring back on.
They told me to.
Anyway, good luck today.
Thanks.
You ready?
Sure.
Excuse me. No comment.
Uh...
Greg. Greg! Step aside.
Good morning. Hey,
what are you doing here?
Uh, a bunch of us
are taking shifts.
We wanted you to have at
least one person in court with you
the entire time.
I had to fight Bailey
for this first shift.
Turns out she punches pretty
hard for such a little person.
Excuse us! Thank
you. Dr. Torres!
I can't even swallow.
My mouth is so dry.
You can do this. I will be
sitting right behind you. Okay?
We're up here.
Callie? Hmm?
Oh, damn it!
All rise.
Would if I could.
Crap.
This case is about a man
that you probably already know
at least by reputation,
Mr. Travis Reed.
I got here as soon as I could.
My nephrectomy went long.
What'd I miss?
They're still on
opening statements.
This guy's been
going for a while.
He's doing that folksy charm
thing, and the jury is eating it up.
Now serving as a juror in
a medical malpractice case
isn't easy.
I don't know about
y'all, but I'm no doctor.
Hell, I barely made it through
high school biology, so...
But you are going to get
a crash course education
in orthopedic medicine
and post-operative infections.
And you're gonna hear words
like "pseudomonas" and "emboli."
Don't let that intimidate you.
The only thing that
matters is the evidence.
Those things are part of the
evidence. What is he talking about?
And the evidence in
this case will focus on
a 16-day period last spring.
And during this
time we will establish
that Dr. Torres agreed
to perform a surgery
she did not fully understand.
We will establish that Dr. Torres
made a series of faulty decisions,
eventually costing
Mr. Travis Reed,
a thriving, healthy
Olympic athlete,
his legs.
And we will establish
that all of this started
because of one careless
mistake made in surgery.
Implant's in place.
Everything looks good.
Now I just need to irrigate...
His heart rate just
jumped to the 150s.
Having trouble ventilating.
Increasing his oxygen to 100%.
Damn it. All right,
could be a PE.
We've gotta get
him off this table.
All right, let's start
closing. Irrigation, please.
Wait, the sponge count is
off. We're missing one sponge.
Are you kidding me? We
can't close until we find it.
Sats are continuing to drop.
Switching to manual ventilation.
All right, it's gotta be on
someone's shoe or something.
There's nothing in here.
You want me to call
for a portable X-ray?
No, that'll take too long.
He could go into shock.
BP's dropped to 70 over 40.
Crap, crap, crap.
Are you sure you don't
want me to call for...
No, there's no time.
All right, we're closing
him up. You can't do that!
Well, you know, we
have to. Lap pads.
We still haven't... I don't
care. We're closing him up.
Zero Vicryl.
Zero Vicryl, now. Now!
Hang on, hang on, hang on.
Are you saying
that Dr. Torres knew
she left a sponge
in Mr. Reed's body,
and she didn't care?
No, of course she cared, but...
No, but still, she knowingly
left behind a sponge.
The patient was running
out of time. He would have...
Hon, hon, it's a yes or
no question. Thank you.
Did she knowingly
leave a sponge?
Yes.
I've got a boy in
college. Good kid.
And I went to visit
him last month,
and you would not believe
the sponge I found in his sink.
I mean, there's no tellin'
what was growing on that thing.
Objection.
Irrelevant. Sustained.
All right, let's fast-forward
to the next time
you saw Mr. Reed.
About two weeks later.
And how was he then?
Was he good? Happy?
Recovering well?
He had an infection.
Hi, there.
Travis, I hear you
got quite the fever.
Temp's 103. I'm just
starting his workup.
He's burning up. He won't eat.
I had to force him to come in.
How are you feeling, Travis?
I've seen worse.
Dr. Torres, you wanna
take a listen to this?
Yeah.
Okay.
Is that a murmur? A small one.
Travis, I'm just gonna take a
look at your incision site, okay?
Oh, wow.
"Oh, wow"? What
does "Oh, wow" mean?
Whitney, I don't
want you to worry.
The wound looks
a little infected.
So we're just gonna go in
and clean it all out, okay?
Yeah. Okay.
Okay, get him on
vanc and clinda, stat.
Call upstairs. I need
an OR right now.
What about the murmur?
Could the infection have
traveled to his heart?
His vitals are stable.
So first, we've got to
clean out that joint, okay?
We can't afford any delays.
Okay. Should I call Yang?
All right, if she's not available
in the next five minutes,
she waits until post-op.
We've got to get in
there and kill this infection
before it spreads any further.
I am not turning an Olympic
athlete into a doorstop.
Yeah, the infection's
going through the fascia
down to the prosthesis.
Get in here and irrigate
before we move on.
Looks like there's
pus in the acetabulum.
Oh, Damn it!
No, there's no way
to salvage the joint.
I'm gonna have to
remove the whole thing.
And just leave him with no hip?
Well, for now.
It's the only way to get
this completely cleaned out.
Osteotome and mallet?
That sounds pretty nasty.
Post-op infections are very
common. They happen all the time.
Is that your
professional opinion?
It is. I see.
And in your
professional opinion,
is it also common
for a post-op infection to
result in a double amputation?
Does that happen all
the time, too? No, but...
No further questions,
Your Honor.
That's not fair. You're
not letting me finish.
That's enough, Dr. Wilson.
But I need to explain...
Another word out of turn,
and I'll hold you in contempt.
Tell me I packed a spare pair.
Oh, thank God.
Oh, hi. I'm sorry.
I'll come back.
No, no, no. It's fine.
It's fine. I'm just...
I have to sit in there
and listen to that guy.
And I can't react or that'll
make me look unlikable or petty.
But how the hell am I
not supposed to react?
He's awful. And he's
making me sound awful.
Um...
I think I have something
that will make you feel better.
So Sofia drew this in
the car this morning.
And she said that it's of a
jellyfish and a rainbow mermaid.
I'm not sure which one is which.
But you should have it.
And then when you
feel like screaming,
you can look at the jellyfish
and then it will calm you down.
Oh.
I'm surprised you're here.
Thanks. Thank you.
I should get back. Oh, God.
Um...
Callie? Yes?
Are you sure that
you wanna wear, um,
rhinestone butterflies in court?
I mean, it's your
choice. It's a strange one.
But I suppose that lots of
people like butterflies so...
Yeah.
They're cute.
What? What?
Are you kidding me?
No more ridiculous than
vetoing every guy under 6'3."
We are not choosing our sperm
donor based on his taste in music.
Well...
Oh, look. Oh, this one's cute.
Oh, that's a super cute baby.
He would make super
cute babies. Yeah!
Okay, so. Here... Oh.
Hmm. He's a college dropout.
Pass. Pass.
Okay. Ooh, I'm empty.
Now this one says he's a
mathematician with a graduate degree.
Oh, wow. And he runs marathons.
Oh, picture?
Oh.
Okay. Um...
Well, I still like the
Ivy League poet.
Okay, let's...
Smart and creative.
Okay.
You think I'll like
being pregnant?
Oh, yeah. It's the best.
Oh, except for the nausea.
Oh, and the stretch marks.
And the peeing. Mmm.
And the lack of
sleep, the exhaustion.
Oh, and then the no booze.
No booze? Mmm-hmm.
Oh. Mmm-hmm.
Oh, I will miss you most of all.
Arizona?
You're early.
I thought you said you weren't
bringing her by till after dinner.
Daddy. Mija.
Mmm.
You mentioned the
trial like it was nothing.
It's never nothing.
You know how many
times I've been sued?
My lawyer's on speed
dial, for crying out loud.
He's very good. Technically,
his tactics are legal.
You really didn't have
to come all this way.
Of course I did. Of course
I did. My baby's in trouble.
But first, where's my
grandbaby? Mmm-hmm.
Come on, now.
Abuelo needs a hug.
Don't tell me she's
already asleep.
No. No.
She's, um...
She's... She's not here.
Arizona's gonna
bring her by in an hour.
Oh, all right. I don't
understand. What's going on?
We split up. She cheated
on me. It's been bad.
I really don't
wanna talk about it.
When did this happen?
A couple months ago.
Why didn't you tell me? I
didn't wanna get into it, Dad.
I fought so hard just
to get you to accept us.
Mom hasn't spoken to me
since the wedding, and I just...
Apparently, I marry
people who cheat on me.
It's pathetic.
I am pathetic. No.
When that O'Malley
kid cheated on you,
I was ready to
knock his teeth out.
Mmm. Mmm?
Now I won't hit a lady,
but I can make it happen.
I know people. Just
say the word, all right?
No, Dad. God, no.
All right.
Look at me.
Mija, look at me.
Nothing about you is pathetic.
Don't hate me!
I know I said I was
gonna cook dinner tonight,
but I've still got a lot
of work to catch up on.
So... Who wants pizza?
Hey, sweetie. Where's Mommy?
Callie?
Yeah. Hi, I'm home!
Is everything okay?
Callie!
Are you okay? Is
everything all right?
We're having a baby.
My boobs were hurting,
and then I thought, maybe,
but I'm only a day late,
and I didn't even think that it
would show up on a test so soon.
We're having a baby!
Oh!
Hi.
Hi, sweet baby.
Mmm. Mmm. Mmm.
Dr. Hernandez to oncology.
All right, gonna make this
quick. I know we are all busy.
Callie, I thought you
understood you can't be here.
I know. I know it's
a conflict of interest.
I wanted to say something
before you get started.
Travis Reed is suing
both me and the hospital.
I have no intention of settling
with him, but the hospital should.
As an owner and a
member of the board,
I know how hard it's been to
get this place back on its feet.
And I don't want you to
jeopardize that because of me.
What did our legal team say?
Um, yeah, they
said that we should
settle now, quickly and quietly.
What if we don't? ALEX:
If this thing goes to trial
and there's a judgment
against us, we could owe millions
or we could settle
this for much less.
If we go to trial, we risk
bankruptcy all over again.
Only if we lose. There's
another side to this.
If Callie isn't settling,
maybe neither should we.
Uh, no. I was there.
I saw firsthand what
happened with this patient.
And he has a case. A
good case. We should settle.
And, frankly,
Callie should, too.
Dr. Yang, what is your
relationship with Travis Reed?
Travis first came to me six years
ago with a bicuspid aortic valve.
I replaced the valve
and have overseen his
cardiac care ever since.
And it was you, I believe, who
recommended him to Dr. Torres.
Is that right? That's right.
Why was that?
Because she was the best
orthopedic surgeon I knew.
Was? As in past tense?
You don't believe
she's the best anymore?
There are vegetations
all over his aortic valve.
Why didn't you page me sooner?
We just heard the
murmur this morning.
This morning? Yeah.
Look at this growth. You
knew he was a heart patient.
This didn't concern you?
Of course it did.
That's why you're here.
So what do we do? The
infection is eating away at his graft.
Best case, I go in,
clean it out and repair it.
Worst case, he needs
a whole new valve.
Dr. Torres, you
need to see this.
I was changing his
compression socks and I saw this.
His leg's gray, cold.
I can't find a pulse.
Okay, where's Whitney?
I told her she had time to grab
lunch before Travis woke up.
All right, you
need to go find her
and tell her that Travis
needs another surgery.
Okay.
Okay, I've gotta go in and
do an embolectomy on this leg.
Uh-uh. No. I gotta
go in and fix his heart.
You can do that later.
I need to do this now.
Later? It's already later.
He has lost blood flow!
He's clearly throwing
emboli into his extremities.
And where do you think
the emboli is coming from?
His infected heart. Cristina...
Hey, hey, hey!
I can hear you two from all
the way the damn hallway.
Will you tell Callie to back
off and let me do my job?
Yeah, tell Cristina to back
off and let me do mine.
If I don't try this embolectomy,
he could lose his leg.
He can live without a leg. He
can't live without a functioning heart.
Look, if you do
the heart tomorrow,
it gives him an extra day
on antibiotics, all right?
He'll be more stable, and the
heart surgery will be less risky.
Cristina, this is Travis
Reed we're talking about.
Let me try to save his leg.
Dr. Torres performed the
embolectomy that afternoon.
Against your wishes?
We had a professional
difference of opinion.
You know, in my office,
if one of my co-workers
was shouting at me so loudly
that you could hear him
all the way down the hall,
it would be more than
just a difference of opinion.
It would be grounds
for a dismissal.
We are passionate
about our work.
And in the end, I
agreed with Dr. Torres,
that the heart
surgery could wait.
You agreed? Yes.
Are you sure you
weren't bullied? Objection.
Yeah, I know.
The embolectomy could
not have gone better.
I mean, his leg was
already pinking up
by the time I saw him
in recovery last night.
What's his temp?
Oh, he was febrile overnight,
but his white count's stable.
All right.
What's going on? Travis?
What aren't you telling
me? What's wrong?
What the hell is
wrong with my legs?
Are we losing this case?
It's too early to panic.
We haven't presented our side.
There she is.
Richard! You shouldn't be here.
That's what I told him,
but he insisted on coming.
It's a miracle I made it here
at all. Kepner's a terrible driver.
How's it going?
You knew it was bad.
His legs were black.
I knew it wasn't good.
They cut them off that night.
Now, did you have any indication
that Dr. Torres was even worried
about something like amputation?
I mean, did she ever mention
that it might be even a risk?
No. But she was
worried about it.
She was worried about what
it would do to her reputation.
What is she talking about?
Now, why would you
say that? I have no idea.
I heard her talking
in the hallway.
She didn't know
I could hear her.
What did she say?
She said, "I can't be the doctor
"who turns an Olympic
athlete into a doorstop."
All right, quiet down!
Quiet down, everyone!
Quiet down!
Do we knock?
No, there's an open house on
Sunday. We can come back then.
Oh, oh! There's a swing set.
Oh, and a pool! A pool!
Callie, there's a pool!
Ooh! Yeah? Yeah.
Oh, I can just see us playing
with the girls in this yard,
having a picnic and
swinging on the swings.
Oh. What makes you think
we're having another girl?
Come on.
Can you get off of that
thing for five seconds
and look at this place?
Yeah, I know, hold on
a second. I'm just, uh...
I'm following up
on that clinical trial
in Germany using
Peterson hip joints.
I'm trying to get them
to send me their data.
Well, they're not gonna release
anything until it's published.
Eh. It's worth a shot.
There, sent.
All right, now you can
show me the swing set.
Okay. Oh! Ooh.
You okay? Yeah.
You all right? I got it.
I've got it.
Do you swear to tell
the truth, the whole truth,
and nothing but the truth? I do.
Hey, Travis. Hey.
You know, I'm, uh...
I'm thinking about snowboarding.
In fact, I picked up a
board, a Burton Blunt.
You familiar with that
one? That's a good board.
There's better
boards for beginners.
What size shoe are you?
I'm a 13.
You might wanna
look into an extra wide,
so your toes don't
hang over too much.
A little overhang's fine, but
too much is gonna cause drag.
And drag's bad? Well...
Objection, Your Honor.
Where's this going?
Look, I'm simply consulting
an expert on snowboarding
about a snowboard.
I mean, who should I trust more,
this guy or the kid who's
helping me out at REI?
Get to the point, Mr. Hamilton.
Travis, when you
first met Dr. Torres,
did you ask her about
a certain kind of joint?
The Peterson joint. I'd
heard it was good for athletes.
Quicker recovery,
better range of motion.
So you were consulting an
expert on joint replacement
about a joint? Yeah.
Is it true that Dr. Torres
had never actually done
an operation with this
kind of joint before?
It's true. But you went
ahead with it anyway.
She said she had
done a lot of research.
She said she was confident.
So you trusted her to use
her expertise to advise you
and to keep you safe.
When, in fact, what you
got was a botched surgery,
an infection, a revision
surgery, a heart surgery, and...
I mean, look at you now.
Just let me pull up the blanket.
Why? So you don't
have to look at them?
There's nothing there.
Is it her?
Hey, Travis.
Tell her to go.
I don't wanna see her. I
don't wanna talk to her.
Um...
I just brought you some
information on support groups.
Um, try to get him to go.
And, on the back,
there's a name of an
incredible prosthetist...
Tell her to get out.
I trusted her.
I trusted her completely, and...
You know, I get that
people live without legs
and it's not the
end of the world,
but it's the end of my world.
I've been snowboarding
since I was five.
I used to steal cafeteria
trays from school
and ride 'em down
my parents' driveway.
Snow or no snow, I didn't care.
It was the thing I did for fun.
Then it became my
job and my world.
And now it's everything.
My family, my friends.
Without it, I don't
know who I am.
And now it's gone. It's just...
Gone.
And it's Dr. Torres' fault.
You feel very
strongly about that.
It's not just a feeling.
I know it. She told me.
What, she admitted
that she was at fault?
Yes, she did.
The day she cut off my
legs, she came into my room,
she'd been crying.
She told me she
was sorry. Objection!
It is illegal to use a
physician's apology
against them as
evidence of guilt.
Your Honor, this isn't
about the apology.
This is about everything
else she said with the apology.
I'll allow it.
Travis, I know this is gonna be
painful, so you take your time.
What else did Dr. Torres say?
She said if there was
anyone to blame, it was her.
She said this never
should've happened.
She said if there was any way
she could change things, she would.
Those were her exact words?
Yes, they were.
The prosecution rests.
Yes, we had so much fun today.
Big hugs.
I love you. I love you.
I know.
Okay, all right, honey.
I'll see you soon.
Hey, your dad's making
me a little nervous.
Yeah, you should
probably go now.
Definitely go now.
Bye! Bye!
Bye-bye. Bye-bye!
Thank you for not
saying anything to her.
If my grandbaby hadn't
been standing right there,
believe me, I
would've said plenty.
Dad, don't start right now.
I have to be in court soon.
I have to take the stand
today, and I'm just...
Your mother and I have
been married 38 years.
You think it's been
easy? No, don't.
You think we
haven't had troubles?
Don't do that. Don't
start comparing. Don't.
What happened to her "good
man in a storm" baloney?
It's not right.
She should be here
every day trying to fix it.
It's not like that.
Oh, no? The hell it isn't.
She hurt you, and now she's too
much of a coward to even face you.
Now she's running away,
abandoning her family.
No, she's not running away,
all right? I kicked her out.
It was my choice to
split up. It was mine.
All right, so just
drop it, okay?
You chose to break
up your family?
Dad, not now.
Did you even try
to work things out?
Dad.
I knew what I was doing.
I did extensive research
on the Peterson hip.
I even spoke with the
team who invented it.
Everyone agreed that
Travis was an ideal candidate.
And the surgery?
It went smoothly?
The cut position and the
femoral resurfacing were perfect.
What wasn't perfect?
At the end of surgery,
the patient desatted,
which means his
oxygen level went down
and his heart was
beating really fast,
which is really dangerous.
We thought he might
have a clot in his lungs,
so it was vital that we
finish the surgery quickly.
And that's when you
left the sponge. Yes.
And I would do it again.
The patient's life was at risk.
I believe that the sponge
wouldn't compromise the joint.
I made a call, and I was right.
It was the right call.
So leaving the sponge was
deliberate. Not a mistake.
You weren't being
careless or distracted.
Make sure his BP and
O-2 sats stay stable.
And bring me his post-op
X-ray. I wanna locate that sponge.
Got it.
Oh!
You missed our appointment. Hmm?
Oh, damn it!
I'm so sorry.
My surgery went long, and I
completely forgot. How'd it go?
I mean, I know the ultrasound's
just a blob at this point,
but still.
Did you get a
picture of the blob?
There's no picture.
And no heartbeat.
What?
She did the ultrasound and
she looked and she looked.
But there's no heartbeat.
We lost the baby?
I remember the day very
clearly. I wasn't distracted.
Sure, I had other
things going on.
Big things, actually.
But it's my job to prioritize
my patient, and that's
exactly what I did.
I wasn't focused on
anything or anyone
other than my patient.
Let's talk about
this embolectomy.
Dr. Yang wanted to do
the heart surgery first.
You wanted to
work on Travis' leg.
Yes. Why?
Well, his foot was turning gray,
which is an indication that
the limb is starting to die.
And I wanted to
restore blood flow.
Once a limb turns black,
there's nothing we can do.
According to
Dr. Yang's testimony,
she wanted to go first
because the infection
had moved to Travis' heart,
throwing out emboli, or
clots, all over his body.
And she knew that
the heart would keep throwing
out clots until it was repaired. So...
Do you cook?
Uh, a little.
Okay, let's say you're cooking,
and you start a grease
fire in your kitchen.
And then it spreads
to your curtains.
What do you do? Do you
put out the grease fire?
Or do you extinguish
the curtains?
Which disaster
do you tackle first?
If I hadn't treated
the emboli when I did,
Travis would've
lost his leg for sure.
I was just picking which
disaster to tackle first.
I cannot believe you're
picking this fight right now!
I'm not trying to pick a fight.
I am trying to
tell you how I feel.
Okay, I feel like crap, too.
Okay? It wasn't just your kid.
I know. I know that.
Look, we'll just...
Look, we don't have to try
again right away, all right?
We can wait a while
before we try again.
No. We...
No, no. You're missing
the point. What point?
I can't take another loss,
Callie. I can't handle it!
I can't think about
this right now.
It's too hard.
It's just too hard!
What... What are you saying?
Now you don't want another baby?
Answer me.
I don't know.
I have to go check
on my patient.
Tell her to get out!
WHITNEY: Travis...
I don't want her here.
Kick her out, Whit, now!
God knows I can't
do it by myself.
So get her the hell out of here!
What's wrong with you?
Why aren't you doing anything?
Okay, that's enough!
Whitney, go to the family
lounge and get a snack.
We need a minute, okay?
Don't you dare
take this out on her.
You are hurt and angry,
and you have every
right to feel those things.
But Whitney has
nothing to do with that.
You wanna take your
crap out on somebody,
you take it out on me,
all right? I can handle it.
You need somebody to
blame? Then blame me.
Go on. Yell all you want.
This never should've
happened to you.
And if there were any way that
I could magically change things,
believe me, I would.
I wish there was
something I could do.
I wish I could fix this.
I tried. I tried so hard.
I'm so sorry, Travis.
I'm so, so sorry.
Yes, I apologized.
I understood what
Travis was feeling.
I went through the
same thing with my wife.
She lost her leg last year,
and, um, it's changed us.
It's, uh, cost us in ways that I
can't even begin to understand.
I wouldn't wish this
experience on anyone.
And now it was
happening to my patient.
Of course I was sorry.
I still am.
I'm so, so sorry this
happened to you, Travis.
That makes me human. That
does not make me negligent.
And if I can't feel for my
patients without getting sued,
then I guess I'm just
gonna keep on getting sued,
because that's who I am.
I won't apologize for that.
Dad, we're home. We're back.
Oh, I guess he's still out
in the park with the girls.
How long do you think it's gonna
take for the jury to come back?
I don't know. Could be
days, sometimes weeks.
What's that?
I think it's from a clinical
trial on the Peterson hip.
I thought I never heard back.
Uh...
"Enclosed is the
data you requested.
"But please be advised, we've
currently put a stop to our trial.
"There've been five
instances of infection
"caused by the
pseudomonas bacteria.
"We've traced the source
back to the Peterson joint."
What's the postmark on that?
Three weeks before
Travis' surgery.
I can't just sit on this. I
have to tell them, right?
I wouldn't. You didn't
willfully ignore any data.
You didn't act
irresponsibly or maliciously.
You worked off the
information you had at the time.
And then an act of God happened.
The letter fell
behind the bookcase.
It could've just as easily
gotten lost in the mail.
But it didn't. Accidents
happen. It's the job.
This one happened in your
living room, not in the OR.
You know, I was distracted.
I wasn't paying attention.
I should've followed up
when I never heard back.
You feel bad because
of what happened,
and anybody would.
But that envelope
is not a magic cure.
It's not going to
grow his legs back.
But what it could do,
it could sway a jury.
It could make a jury
think differently about you,
and that could end your career.
Not because you were negligent
and not because you
did anything wrong.
But because you feel bad?
Because you feel guilty?
Let's not confuse
emotion with fact.
And the fact is, you
did nothing wrong.
Yes, I did.
Hey.
Okay. Thanks.
They've reached a verdict.
We've all done things
we aren't proud of.
I understand that.
I know nobody's perfect.
But how do you live with it?
How do you get up every
morning and face the world,
knowing you
could've done better?
That you should've done better?
Is being sorry enough?
Can an apology
actually heal our wounds?
Ease our pain?
Can it undo the hurt
that we've caused?
I really don't think so, Dad.
It's not enough. Just
because she says she's sorry...
You're married. You took a vow.
You don't walk away from that.
If things get hard,
you work harder.
I mean, you have a child
together, for God's sake.
She cheated on me.
I cheated on your mother.
What? I'm sorry, what?
A long time ago. We
were young. I was stupid.
Uh...
But your mother found it
in her heart to forgive me.
Why?
Why would she do that? Why?
Because she believed we
were stronger than one mistake.
And I thank God
every day she did.
Because otherwise,
I wouldn't have you.
Thirty-eight years.
We've shared a life.
And it all started
after that one mistake.
Now things between you
and Arizona might not work out.
You know, you might
not be able to fix it.
But how will you
know if you never try?
Just a second!
Hi...
Oh, you're not bringing
me extra pillows.
You did something impulsive, and
you were thinking about yourself.
It seemed right at
the time, and, uh,
you made a mistake.
One mistake. Do we
have to get into this now?
I did something like that today.
Oh.
Okay.
Look, I have something to ask,
and, uh, you should probably
take some time to think about it.
I don't need an answer
tonight, but I would like to know
if you'll come home.
You should get
dressed now and leave.