Previously on ER:
Dear Michael, it's been
months since I've heard from you.
Tell everybody I'm still here,
still doing the doctor thing.
She could die without
the proper burn care.
She can't get that here.
Yeah, okay. I'll try.
- What's going on?
- She's talking to Gallant.
You got 72 hours,
son. Get her there.
For Laura, my little one.
Neela, your favorite patient
is in Waiting asking for you.
- Oh, no, please.
- Back-pain guy?
Third day in a row.
- Sign out to me...
but take care of your
boyfriend before you leave.
Deal.
The Iraqi girl's coming today.
Have you talked to Gallant?
Not since we set it up.
When she does, I'll call CASH.
All right. But this time,
I want to talk to him.
Who's that?
Well, that is Tio Escobar, 17.
Superficial stab wound to the right flank.
- Not him. Her. TIO: He
cut me, I didn't do nothing.
Word is you told Drake you
were coming for him with a gun.
- Didn't say that.
- There were witnesses.
- May I take a look?
- Other doctor already saw it.
Well, I'm the supervisor, so I
have to check it out anyway.
Well, the wound is superficial.
We'll be back to clean
it out. You got lucky.
This time.
- Hi. I'm Dr. Pratt.
- Olivia Evans. I'm with Ceasefire.
- Ceasefire?
- Violence prevention program.
How many shooting
victims do you see in a shift?
- Too many to count.
- Exactly.
So how could you not
know about Ceasefire?
Hey, the name sounds
familiar. Tell me more about it.
Tio and I, we're not... We're
not done here, are we, Tio?
Anything else?
I'll be back.
So, what's she like?
She's a health professional,
Ray. Don't be such a dog.
I shouldn't have taken Franklin.
Mom, what day is it?
- Wednesday.
- I meant date.
- It's right in front of you, Alex.
- The 27th.
Dad will be coming soon.
- You spoke to him?
- No. He wrote me a letter.
You never said anything.
- He wrote it to me.
- And he said he was coming to see you?
Yeah.
Alex, honey, how many
times has he told you...
he was gonna do
something and then he didn't?
Okay, Mr. Kirkendall,
we'll do this one more time.
Thanks for your patience.
- Dr. Rasgotra, you got a minute?
- Go ahead, I'll be there soon.
Okay. I'll wait right here.
Thank you very much.
- Uh, congratulations.
- On what?
- The Iraqi mother and daughter arrived.
- That's great.
Dr. Gallant around? I wanted to
introduce him to the Plastics attending.
- Excuse me?
- Dr. Gallant.
- Michael was in the hospital?
- Yeah. I was just with him an hour ago.
Oh.
So if you see him,
send him my way.
The unit staff
wants to meet him.
He's, uh... He's a
bit of a hero up there.
Yeah.
Registration, Urgent
Care in the atrium...
Primary Care Clinics over here.
Thirty-six state-of-the-art exam rooms
with a dedicated outpatient pharmacy...
lab, and an X-ray suite located
behind the sculpture garden.
- And this? What's this?
- Commercial space.
We're already taking bids. It'll
probably go to some fast-food joint.
- What?
- Sorry I'm late.
Kerry sends her apologies but
she had an appropriations meeting.
So, what do you think?
- Very impressive.
- Well, listen.
Public Affairs is working
on a press release...
- about the Carter Foundation...
- Dr. Anspaugh...
I thought that comprehensive HIV
care would be very much a part of all this.
We cannot get into
subspecialties yet.
We struggled getting
family med to come.
Primary care docs
can staff the HIV clinic.
There is no space for that.
Maybe we should pitch a
tent in the sculpture garden.
Maybe we could stake out a
few tables in the burger joint.
The clinic was your idea. We
are trying to make it happen.
Primary care and
comprehensive HIV treatment.
Not Architectural Digest
and super-sized meals.
Call me when you
have something else.
Twelve-year-old Victor
Hopkins, GSW to the groin.
- Pulse, 115, resps, 20, 98/60.
- And my sats are okay.
- Ha-ha. How do you know about sats?
- I heard her say it on the radio.
Got two of morphine en
route. Mom's on her way in.
It's a weird trajectory for a
GSW. Who shot you, Victor?
- Nobody. It just went off.
- You shot yourself?
- No. It was in my pocket.
- What's a kid like you doing with a gun?
Protecting myself.
Michael, I don't know if
you're checking this cell phone.
Are you in town?
I'm a bit confused.
Call me back at the hospital, okay?
I'll be here for another hour or so.
You ran away from your back-pain
guy. But he's waiting for you.
He can wait.
I heard Michael was here.
Did you know he was coming?
- Yeah, sure.
- You didn't mention it.
Didn't I?
He didn't stop by?
I guess he just didn't
want to go over everything.
Should I continue being oblivious
or do you want to explain...
why you're bleeding
from your cuticles?
- I'm not crazy, am I?
- Crazy?
How did I manage to build
up feelings for someone...
I've spoken to once
in the past year?
Well, you exchanged letters.
Letters?
What are letters?
You can think, feel, say whatever
the hell you want in a letter...
to someone thousands
of miles away.
It's all speculative, imagined.
It doesn't mean anything.
It's just on a piece of paper.
- It's okay if you're mad at him.
- Mad?
More like furious.
I'm furious that he didn't
tell me he was coming.
I'm furious that he could
just walk away like that.
I'm ridiculously
desperate to see him...
none of which is based on
anything more substantial...
than the inner workings
of my neurotic brain.
You know, I was ready to
bestow my sage wisdom...
but I think you got it covered.
Am I so pathetic...
that I have to concoct a
love life out of nothing?
That's not fair.
You and Michael were very close. It's
not so crazy you're having these feelings.
Graze wound to
the right testicle.
It's just superficial.
Victor, you're a lucky man.
GSW to the right thigh. No exit.
Belly's soft. What
happened here?
I got hurt last summer.
Victor, you got shot before?
Some kid at school.
I'm not that popular.
Victor?
- Hey, Mom.
- Thank God you're all right.
What happened?
Well, your 12-year-old son
had a 9 mm pistol in his pocket.
He did?
- Do you know where he got it?
- No.
Mrs. Hopkins, who
does the gun belong to?
Boo, I taught you how
to keep the safety on.
- Oh, Neela.
- I'm sorry, Dr. Lewis.
- I'm getting to him now.
- Am I that much of a hardass?
- I was gonna ask if you've seen Gallant.
- Uh, no, sorry. Patient's waiting.
Can you sign off on an order
of Ancef for Victor Hopkins?
- The prepubescent gangbanger?
- More like aspiring vigilante.
- His mom's behind it.
- What?
- She gave him the gun.
- Get Social Services down. And, Sam...
- somebody called for you.
- Who?
Well, he didn't leave a name
and he sounded a bit agitated.
Frank said you got a
similar call yesterday.
Yeah. I took care of this
wheelchair vet with ascites last week.
- He's got a thing for me.
- You want me to alert Security?
No, no. It's nothing like
that. Thanks. It's fine. Really.
- What's going on?
- Oh, a patient wants me on the phone.
Sam, what's going on?
Nothing. What?
You don't want to tell me? Fine.
Hey.
Come on. Let's
get a coffee. Okay?
- Have you been taking the ibuprofen?
- Yes.
- Resting?
- Trying.
Like I said yesterday
and the day before...
It was Tuesday.
- I couldn't come Wednesday.
- A muscle spasm like this...
- can take weeks to heal.
- Oh, I know.
So why do you keep coming back?
I believe in you. And I keep
thinking maybe you can fix me.
All right. Let's do a full exam.
Uh, it's a unitard.
You know, like
a... Like a bodysuit.
Okay, I'm gonna step away
and let you take that off...
and get into a gown, okay?
Uh, ahem, I... I
can't... I can't do it.
Why not?
Mr. Kirkendall, do you
want me to help you or not?
Look, don't laugh. Okay?
- Okay?
- Okay.
My wife used to call me,
uh, Clark. As in Clark Kent.
I can't examine you
properly unless you undress.
She said she could see through
my, you know, everyday disguise...
and underneath my
unassuming façade there was...
- There was something else.
- Something else?
A, uh...
A secret strength.
A special person.
- The power of a locomotive.
- Mr. Kirkendall...
On Tuesday, it'll be 19
weeks since she died.
I'm sorry.
Yeah.
Allergic to nuts...
and accidentally ate an almond
in someone's birthday cake.
That's awful.
So, after she passed,
I bought the suit...
and I wear it under my
clothes on the really bad days.
And, I don't know, it
makes me feel, uh...
better.
You weren't
wearing it yesterday.
Oh, yesterday was a good day.
You think I'm crazy.
- Well, I wouldn't say that.
- No, you think I'm crazy.
No, I think...
I think I can examine
you over your suit.
I wasn't sure what the calls were
until Alex told me about the letter.
- So he's here.
- I guess so.
What do you want to do?
I'm not gonna run away
again, especially not now.
I don't want you to have
to worry. It's my problem.
I kind of think
it's our problem.
I'm Dr. Carter. What
do you got, Dr. Pratt?
Twelve-year-old, GSW to the thigh.
Vitals stable. Waiting on an x-ray.
And a social-work
consult. The kid had a pistol.
He's too smart for his own good. Bullies
tease him, he mouths off right back.
He tell you what
happened last year?
Tony Ramsey, the
biggest doof at my school...
I told him he won a Darwin
Award for the most inbred.
Didn't think he'd
actually shoot me.
- He shot you at school?
- No. On my way home.
Kid went to Juvie, was back
in class four months later.
- A gun's not the answer.
- Didn't know what else to do.
Nine-millimeter in the femoral triangle.
- Pulse is weak.
- I'll page Angio.
- May not have time for that.
- What's wrong?
- Gonna need surgery.
- Surgery? Again?
- Afraid so.
Curtain 4 has biliary colic.
Ultrasound and lipase are normal.
- Better after two of morphine.
- Okay. Home and follow up with a PMD.
DUB has settled down and
going home with a gyn follow-up.
- And in Curtain 2, I've got the...
- The superhero over there?
A repeat customer
with lower-back pain.
- No reproducible paraspinal tenderness.
- Is it true? Is Gallant back?
- That's the rumor.
- Is he drug seeking?
- Went to his parents.
- He's lonely. I put him on ibuprofen...
gave him a referral
for counseling.
Is that right? Gallant's
parents in Texas?
Yeah. Yeah, I believe so.
- Is that it?
- I don't know much about his parents.
- I meant the patients.
- Oh, no. That's it.
- Okay.
Coffee and a jelly
doughnut, please.
Same thing every day, doc.
Try a cruller. Crullers are nice.
I'll stick to the
doughnut, thank you.
I didn't even know
you were coming.
Uh, Jamila was touch-and-go.
My C.O. sent me
at the last minute.
You didn't call.
We were only in Germany
for about an hour or so.
I meant today. Dubenko
told me you left, so I thought...
I had to do something.
But I couldn't leave
without seeing you.
I mean, I thought it
might be easier that way...
but I couldn't.
Everyone's sad
you didn't come by.
It's just, it...
I mean, it feels weird, you
know, being back in the world.
The thought of going into the ER
and having to answer the questions...
about, you know, what I'm doing
and what it's like over there...
How long can you stay?
I fly back out tomorrow morning.
I only came to make sure
the girl got here safely.
Hello?
I left all the orders on
the chart. It's all there.
I'm at lunch, Frank. At Ike's.
No, I can't come
back. He'll be fine.
What happened there?
Uh, nothing. It's
just a little gash.
This morning I went to, uh...
I went to see the family
of a guy I knew from Iraq.
He died right before I left.
And I, uh...
I brought something that
he got for his daughter.
I'm sorry.
One day, his wife...
saw two men walking...
towards her door
in dress uniforms.
She begged them to
go away. Told them, uh...
Told them that they must
have the wrong house.
But they didn't.
And she knew why...
She knew why they were there.
She knew.
- Neela's superhero won't leave.
- What's the problem?
- Won't say.
- Want me to call security?
Hey, um, do you think maybe
someone could page her?
Know what? I'm sorry.
She's home in bed.
- No, she's not. She's over at Ike's.
- Well, who's Ike?
Maybe we could call him.
Why don't I see if I can track her down?
- Thanks.
Hey, you got a hot nurse here
named Samantha Taggart?
- Yeah. What's your name?
- Steve. Steve Curtis.
It's okay, Frank. I got this.
You still hanging in there?
- Looking for Sam?
- Yeah.
Can't believe she lasted
over a year in this place.
- Need some water?
- If she hasn't run off...
- you must have her chained to a bed.
- Let's step over here for a minute.
How long do I have to wait for
these scans? I need those now.
Hey, Olivia. I'll
call you back. Hey.
I was very impressed with
what you said to that kid.
- Thanks.
- I was wondering if I could talk to you...
about another patient of mine,
12-year-old kid. Came in with a gun.
- Unfortunately, that doesn't surprise me.
- But this is a smart kid.
Not a tough guy. Not yet.
And I was hoping, you
know, you could do your thing.
My thing?
Wow, somebody's been practicing.
I didn't like the way you
ran the table last time.
- Hey, wait, wait. Hold on a second.
- What?
I'm your bridge.
Go ahead. You can reach.
I hope you're not about
to get too competitive...
because it looks as if
I'm about to beat you.
- Michael.
- Hey.
- Abby, hi.
- Thought you left already.
- Well, not exactly.
How's it going?
Uh...
- That's a tough one to answer, I guess.
- Yeah. How you been?
Very good.
Yeah. Uh, I came by to try to
bring you back to that Kirkendall guy.
- But I'll just take care of it.
- Thank you.
- Are you gonna stop by?
- Um, I'm not sure.
Say I said hi.
It's good to see you. - Yeah.
And I hope you know
we all think about you.
- Yeah. Me too.
- Okay.
I know it's a bad thing. But I'm
just trying to level the playing field.
They all have
weapons at his school.
You really want your little
boy walking around with a gun?
- Give us a minute to talk.
- Victor was shot last year.
- I can't let that happen again.
- It just did.
- Excuse me?
- I work two jobs.
I can't watch him every minute.
- But he's a good kid.
- I can tell.
But you know what?
A man like you can be tough...
just by staying away
from problem situations.
You gotta grow up so you can be
the president and fix our public schools.
I'd rather be a pilot.
Whatever you want, so long as
you don't mess up your young years.
- Avoid those bad kids.
- How?
They follow me on
my way to school.
Here's what we're gonna do:
You see that tough
guy over there?
When you get better, he's gonna
walk you to school for a week.
- What? Wait...
- And, if you give up your gun...
I'll have someone walk you to
and from school every day after.
And each week, your escort is gonna
get bigger and scarier than that guy.
Just point me to her. I
don't need a babysitter.
You're not allowed to be here.
We're making an exception.
- Wow, thanks.
- There's a lounge down the hall.
Well, aren't you the man?
Listen, this is where I work,
okay? I don't want any trouble.
- So just get her for me.
- She'll be out as soon as she's free.
- Any tingling here?
- No.
- How about here?
- Uh-uh.
- Here?
- A little.
All right, here we go, Victor.
I will be your driver today.
- Ray.
- You can thank me later, Sam.
Come here for a second.
All right.
Look at this bullet.
There's a chip missing.
Okay. Let's talk
ballistics later, all right?
Fifteen minutes is not
gonna change his outcome.
- Show this to Carter.
- Okay, Vascular's waiting.
He's got a bounding
popliteal pulse.
Surgeon's set to
do a femoral repair...
but he's got a fragment
in the popliteal artery.
He's gotta be in preop in five
or they're gonna cancel the case.
X-ray. I wanna make sure they're
not operating on the wrong spot.
- Easier to figure out upstairs.
- We need a check for a right knee.
Come on. We don't need this. This
is my patient, Sam. I don't want this.
Yeah, you do. Show that to Carter.
Make Vascular wait. Thank you.
She can't be pulled away
while she's with a patient.
Okay, boss. I think we're done.
It's okay. Thanks.
Got it.
Big guy's kind of tense, huh?
So it's serious with this guy?
Yeah, it is.
Glad it's working out for you.
Do you wanna talk?
- Has anybody been looking for me?
- No.
- Nobody's contacted you?
- Why?
- Never mind.
- Steve, what'd you do?
Nothing. Noth... I just... I
owe a guy some money.
- Can I borrow some cash?
- Steve...
I... I need it.
I do, Sam. I'm gonna take
Alex on a little trip, okay?
- What?
- I may not see him for a while.
I'd like to spend time with him.
- He's in school.
- What is he? Third grade?
So he'll miss
finger-painting class.
He's in the fifth grade. He's
studying the Constitution.
But he's still my kid, right?
Please, Steve. You
know it's a bad idea.
Yeah, I guess you're right.
Hey, if you want,
maybe the three of us...
could go get some dessert
or something together.
You could catch up with
him a little bit. He'd like that.
Yeah.
I gotta hit the road.
I'll... I'll just
call him. Okay?
But, uh...
what about the money?
Look, I only have about 40 on
me. How much do you need?
A couple hundred.
Come on. There's an
ATM around the corner.
So you're still having
a bad time at work?
Oh, I'm sure I overstated it.
It's just I came to work here...
and fell into old patterns
from college, from growing up...
stuff I wanted to get away from.
And one day you realize
that's how people see you.
It's who you are, even if
that's not who you wanna be.
So you don't like who you are?
- I don't always like how people see me.
- Ah.
Well, you can change that.
Be someone different tomorrow.
- Come on.
- What? Where are we going?
Millennium Park. It's new. And
then I'm taking you to dinner.
Dr. Kovac, can I talk to you?
- Sure, Frank.
- I know it's none of my business.
I was a cop. And I can still
sniff out a skel when I see one.
- Guy's name is Curtis, right?
- Yeah.
A detective I know at the
one-five checked the NCIC for me.
- NCIC?
- National Crime Information Center.
He pulled up this arrest
warrant from Colorado.
- Thought you should know.
- Thanks, Frank.
Is the film back on my GSW kid?
I'm not sure. Pratt and
Ray are in with him now.
You okay?
- Yeah.
- Where's Steve?
Gone. He just wanted some money.
No. There's something
else we need to talk about.
- Hey, just a minute. PRATT:
Nobody's cutting your leg off.
Do I sign something? RAY:
Anesthesia has the consent forms.
- Where are you going?
- The O.R.
No. We have to
wait for Victor's...
- x-ray.
- X-ray.
You were right. Fragment
in the popliteal fossa.
Nice catch. Vascular's
scrubbed and waiting.
My mom says I can have ice
cream for dinner after I wake up.
Yeah? Well, your
mom is pretty cool.
- Thanks for everything.
- Yeah. Ditto that.
Anytime.
- Alex left school with Erica.
- Yeah, she's tutoring him tonight.
- Frank got this. It's about Steve.
- What? You had Frank snoop on Steve?
He just did it.
He robbed a market outside
Denver. The cashier got hurt.
What?
Oh, my...
He's gotten in trouble
before but nothing like this.
We should call the police.
No, I can't. He's Alex's dad. I can't be
responsible for getting him locked up.
Oh, Sam. I need you to work a couple
hours of overtime. I lost my MICN.
- I can't.
- I need someone who can work the radio.
- I'm sorry, but I got...
- Till Chuny gets in. She's on the I-90.
- I know. But I got to...
- I've cut you some breaks. Help me out.
Susan, I'm gonna take
this sled collision in Two.
Oh, okay. Wait. Thanks, Sam.
It's okay. I'll go
straight home.
- Call me as soon as you get there, okay?
- Okay.
Chuck and I have basically been
hibernating for a year with Cosmo.
And I'm trying to get us
to reenter the social world.
I was thinking maybe you and Wendall
could come over sometime for dinner...
if you don't mind talking
over a baby monitor.
That's a really nice
offer. Yeah, I'd love to.
But things with
Wendall didn't work out.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Yeah. It's weird. She's actually not
really even speaking to me. Ha-ha.
- Are you all right?
- Yeah, I'm good. I'm fine. I just...
Just what?
I don't know. I just feel like
lately I've fallen off the tracks.
It's taking me a little while to
figure out how to get back on.
Will you call the office and let
me know how Victor's doing?
- You got it.
- After he's discharged...
we'll set up a schedule
to walk Victor to school.
- You weren't serious about that.
- I'm serious about everything I say.
- Um, I'm kind of busy.
- We're all busy, Dr. Pratt.
You're gonna stamp out violence
in Chicago one kid at a time?
That's the plan.
It's like any other epidemic.
How do you contain TB?
Knock on doors
and give out meds.
You stop the flu by giving vaccine shots
on street corners. It's the same thing.
But there's no meds
and no vaccine.
The kids with guns, you
can't talk them out of it.
We react to every shooting,
even if no one gets hurt.
We mobilize a neighborhood
response every time someone fires a gun.
Stigmatize violence
and death rates will drop.
Sounds good.
It's working.
Come by and see for yourself.
The address is on the card.
It looks like a frat house.
Yeah, it's definitely lived-in.
Well, that's what you get for
rooming with a rock 'n' roll resident.
- Where are you staying tonight?
- Uh...
A buddy of mine took
over my old lease.
So I'm probably
gonna sack out there.
I'm hungry. Are you?
Yeah. Yeah, definitely.
Well, I'll just go and
get changed then.
Me too. I could use walking
around in some civvies for a while.
- Okay. Well, I'll be back in a minute.
- Okay.
What are you craving?
What's that?
What kind of food do you want?
Chinese, deep-dish, burgers?
Uh, deep-dish sounds good.
Or Thai. There's this
great place on Indiana.
Yeah, yeah. You know,
whatever you think is good.
I'm just picking up
some of my stuff.
You broke into our apartment?
- Alex let me in.
- Where is he?
- Upstairs.
- Where's the babysitter?
I sent her home.
- Okay, put it all back.
- What?
It doesn't belong to you.
You see this?
I gave her this. Okay?
- What about the TV and the stereo?
- You keep whatever you want.
- I'm gonna go check on Alex.
- Alex is fine.
- I'll go see.
- No.
You don't wanna do that.
Luka.
It's nothing, kiddo. Just
a little disagreement.
What's all that for?
We're going to Florida. My
dad's got a place by the beach.
We can watch whales migrate.
Mom said it was okay.
Alex, go back up.
- No.
- Alex, now!
Easy, hoss. Not your kid.
Listen, you can take
whatever you want. I don't care.
But he's not going
anywhere with you.
Think about it.
You really want to
get him into all that?
Hey. We'll catch the
whales in the fall, kiddo.
- I'm going the other direction.
- What?
- Come on, now. Don't be upset.
- You said we...
- You said we're gonna go to Florida.
- You can't miss that much school.
Doc here's got a point.
We'll do it next time.
Come on, buddy.
Don't make this harder on me.
That's my buddy.
Wow.
If that's your deep-dish-pizza outfit,
I'm glad I didn't say French food.
Let me just turn off the light.
It's pretty.
Can't sleep?
No.
Does it hurt?
No, not really.
What happened?
There was a... A
patient brought in.
He was a part of a unit
that got caught in a firefight.
They had men down and
needed help getting them out alive.
Get him out of here quick!
Let's go, let's go!
I never thought I'd
be in the middle of it.
Let's go.
We'll cover you! Get going!
But there I was.
And all I cared about was
getting us both the hell out of there.
Three of our men
died there that day.
I don't know how many Iraqis.
It's funny what you were saying
earlier about wanting to be...
someone different.
I keep wishing I could
go back to who I was.
All we can do is
keep moving forward.
Wish you didn't have to go back.
It won't be too long
before I'm home for good.
They're in 3L?
Yeah, burn unit.
- Morning.
- Dr. Gallant, didn't realize we'd see you.
- I'm just on my way back.
Hayat, this is Dr. Rasgotra.
Neela.
We were able to lighten her
sedation for a few minutes.
- She squeezed her mom's hand.
- Good.
I'm sorry.
It's the ER.
I'll be right back.
I'll be a minute. I probably
forgot to sign a chart.
Okay, uh, yeah. I'll
wait right here then.
Why don't you come down?
Abby's there, and Pratt.
I don't have a lot of time.
Okay. I'll come get you.
Systolic's down to 60.
Fluid's open. Hang two
0-neg, type and cross four more.
- I'm in. Pass me the bag.
- Oh, no. Saw him yesterday. He was fine.
Never left. He just
signed in at triage.
Got good breath. Call X-ray.
Aorta's dilated.
Abdomen's full of blood.
- What happened?
- Looks like a ruptured triple A.
Prep the chest.
Thoracotomy tray to Dr. Pratt.
- Well, his pain was musculoskeletal.
- Bradycardic: 58.
Mg of atropine. Get the
blood on the rapid infuser now.
- Ten blade.
- I missed it.
He's a young guy with no risk
factors. It's an atypical presentation.
I could have done a CT.
Nobody would have done that.
- Never lost a pulse. Got a shot.
- Let's go, Neela. Get sterile.
I didn't know you were up.
I know you're mad.
And I know that he's your father,
nothing's gonna change that.
But you and me and Luka,
we're a team now. Right?
We're in this together.
And last night, he
had to make a decision.
And what he did, he did
because it was best for you.
And that was the right thing,
whether or not you like it or...
- I have to pee.
- Hey, come here.
Talk to me, okay?
I know you're sad,
and that's okay.
Subclavian's in. Good flush.
Run in a liter while we
wait for the other blood.
- This clamp keeps slipping.
- Try the DeBakey?
- Already did. ABBY:
Systolic's down to 54.
Chuny, get the burn
unit on the line for me?
- Don't need the unit.
- I know. I just...
Oh, aorta's flat.
He's bleeding out.
This is a race. Get that
blood up as fast as we can...
up the dopa to 20,
stand by with epi.
The O.R. wants to
know when he's coming.
- Not till he's cross-clamped.
- I'll make sure they get ready.
Neela, hold the descending
aorta. Don't let go.
- Neela, I can do that. It's okay.
- No. I got it.
Oh, look who's here.
Pratt, call for FFP and
cryo. He's gonna need it.
Ha-ha-ha! Big Mike, I knew you'd
show. But you got the worst timing.
- We got a nasty triple A in there.
- Yeah. Can't stay anyway.
Hold on. Yeah, this is
Dr. Pratt in the ER. No, wait...
You're gonna let
me buy you a beer?
Not this time. I need a favor.
Yeah, I need two units of cryo
and FFP right away. Name it.
Can you give this
to Neela? I gotta go.
No. Just send it straight
to the O.R. All right, thanks.
What's up?
Yeah, tell her not
to open it unless...
Unless something happens to me.
Nothing's gonna happen to you.
I just want her to
have it just in case.
You okay, man?
Everything all right?
Come on, Pratt. Let's go.
He could code on the way.
Dr. Carter.
Hey, Mike. Good to see you.
Take care of yourself, huh?
Back off the tidal volume
or you'll blow a lung.
Systolic: 65. CARTER:
All right. Crank up the epi.