You've been
helping me do my job better
since you got here.
I couldn't help it.
No need to help it.
I'm the fart
doctor now. A punchline.
What happened today
was a result of
a medical ailment, okay?
Like anyone's
gonna care about that.
Jack wants to convert Med
into a for-profit hospital.
He wants to put it
to a board vote.
If Jack succeeds,
there goes Med as we know it.
I'm officially
in end-stage
renal disease.
Sean would be your best
possible donor match.
No, that's not an option.
Your dad, his health
is getting worse.
He can't know that
you learned this from me.
Hey.
Hey!
What are you doing here?
I was in the neighborhood.
Yeah?
Thought I'd swing by.
All right. Come in.
You hungry?
Got some oatmeal.
Oh, no, I'm good. Thanks.
Got your scrubs on.
Going to work?
It's Wednesday.
What's going on?
Why are you really here?
Can I have a word
with you, please?
Yeah, you look like
a man on a mission.
What's going on?
Sean stopped by this morning
to offer me
one of his kidneys.
Whoa, that's...
That's an incredibly
generous gift.
Yeah, he just decided
to do it out of the blue,
for some reason.
I just felt like Sean
needed to know how bad
you're actually doing.
Why, because
he's a blood relative,
and so he might have a shot
at being a match for me?
You put him up to this.
Offering you a kidney was all
Sean's idea.
He has not thought
this through, Hannah!
He has thought through
what it'll be like
to lose his father.
He doesn't know
what it means
to give up a kidney,
and I'm not gonna
let him find out, either!
Dr. Archer?
What?
I'm sorry, you have a patient
waiting in trauma 2.
Be right there.
You went to Sean,
against my wishes.
I wanted to help you.
You wanna help me, eh?
How about
stay out of my life?
I've been really tired
these past few days,
and I can tell
something's wrong.
Two years ago,
I was diagnosed with
myelodysplastic
neoplasm, unclassifiable.
That's a stem cell disease,
if I'm not mistaken.
Incredibly rare.
And always with
the threat of turning
into leukemia,
unfortunately.
Kira, show Dr. Archer
the folder.
Sorry, I must have
left it in the car.
Kira, I reminded you
three times.
That's all right, Kimberly.
I've got plenty to work
off of here in your chart.
It says here you've
been on steroids since
your diagnosis.
That's all I can do
to fight the disease.
For now.
Unless a stem cell donor
comes to the rescue.
But I haven't had
much luck with that.
I'm a hard match.
Kira?
Kira!
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Let me get her
in another room.
It's official.
My new house opened escrow.
I feel jittery.
Well, I mean,
I'd be worried
if you didn't.
It's a big deal.
And cause for celebration.
I'm taking you out tonight.
Any restaurant you want.
Any restaurant.
My apartment.
Oh.
I'm making golumpki.
Don't ask.
You will love it.
Oh, and my brother's
coming, too...
Pavel.
I was wanting you
to meet him.
Pavel?
Mm-hmm.
Golumpki? I'm in.
Okay.
8:00?
7:30.
Okay.
You help me cook.
See you there.
Good.
Dr. Charles, do you
have a minute?
Yes.
My patient in
treatment 3 is deaf.
He was clipped by
a motorcycle speeding
through a crosswalk.
Banged up a shoulder,
nothing too bad.
Okay.
His sister is here with him,
and she asked if they
could see a psychiatrist
as soon as possible.
I asked for a certified ASL
interpreter,
but they're out today
with COVID,
so she's been helping out
on that front.
Okay.
Thank you.
Good morning, I'm Dr. Charles.
Hi, uh, I'm Sandy.
And this is
my brother, Aiden.
Nice to, uh...
Nice to meet you both.
What's going on?
How can I help?
That.
That's what's going on.
Aiden's hearing voices.
CHICAGO MED
So Aiden,
can you, uh...
Can Aiden read lips?
He's okay. Not great.
It's usually best if I just
interpret through ASL.
Got it.
Aiden.
Hey, Aiden,
pay attention
to Dr. Charles.
He's here to help you.
So Aiden, have you
been deaf since birth?
No, I...
when I was a young kid,
I got sick,
and I became deaf.
He had meningitis as
a nine-year-old.
Got it. And so these voices
that you've been hearing,
what are they like?
What kinds of things
are they saying to you?
The voices
that I hear,
they're gentle and kind.
They ask
a lot of questions.
They tell me things.
Like today, they told me
to go outside...
Head to Navy Pier...
And enjoy the sunny day.
And that's where
the accident happened?
I was crossing the street,
and I didn't see
a motorbike coming.
I can certainly
understand
how this would be
a very intriguing,
even exciting,
development for you.
Yes. Yes.
I can hear again.
So you know what, Aiden?
I'd like to order
some tests
to just determine
if maybe there have been
any neurological changes
that you've undergone
recently.
You think these are
real voices
Aiden's hearing?
Asking him questions,
telling him to go
to Navy Pier?
I think it's important
for Aiden
that we rule out
any physiological
developments
before we do anything else.
Fine. Let's run the test.
I'm just gonna need
his permission.
Yep. You got it.
Okay. Great.
Hi, Kira. I'm Dr. Asher.
How are you feeling?
Better. I'm not sure
what happened.
Well, you fainted.
Your blood work showed
that you were dehydrated.
And it also revealed
that you're pregnant.
Did you already
know this, Kira?
Are you gonna tell my mom?
No, not if
you don't want me to.
Please don't.
She won't understand.
Okay.
Hey, you think maybe
I can do an ultrasound?
So you and I can check out
the fetus together?
Yeah? Okay, great.
I'm just gonna
pull this up, okay?
I haven't done
this part yet.
Kind of nervous.
Do not worry.
It will not hurt
at all, I promise.
Just might be a little cold
in the beginning.
Okay, here we go.
All right.
That is the heartbeat.
From its size, it looks
to be about 20 weeks.
What's wrong?
Usually, the fetus
and the placenta
are attached to
the inside of the uterus,
but that's not
what I'm seeing.
What are you seeing?
I am not exactly sure,
so we are going to
send you for an MRI
to get a more
precise look.
This seems really bad.
No, no, no.
Let's not get ahead of
ourselves, all right?
And I will be right
here with you.
So Kira is awake, stable,
and another doctor
is checking on her
as we speak.
It's drugs, isn't it?
She's been so out of it
recently, so secretive.
We'll know more
about Kira soon.
I do have your results,
however.
You have a low-grade fever.
Your white blood
count is low,
which means your immune
system is weak.
Here on your chest X-ray,
all right, you have these
small infiltrates
in your lungs, which is
a sign that you could
have pneumonia.
So I'm gonna
start you on antibiotics,
just in case.
Okay, but I need to know
what's going on with Kira.
You have to
tell me something.
Please?
Okay, just sit tight.
I'll see what I can do.
What's the status
with Kira Ray?
Still working her up.
Yeah, well, her mother
would like to be
looped in.
When I have something
to report,
if Kira gives the okay,
I'll share it.
Oh, so now, you're concerned
about confidentiality, huh?
You do realize that Kira
is a minor and Kimberly
has the legal right to know
her daughter's health status?
I'm well aware of the issues
surrounding my patient,
whom you are not treating.
Okay, everyone.
Gravity rounds.
We'll start from the top
and work our way down, okay?
Oh, and let's not
forget to welcome back
Dr. Tanaka-Reed.
Glad to have you back
on your feet.
Thank you, Thank you.
All right.
Let's get it.
All right, hey.
Everyone get that
out of your systems?
Oops.
Yeah.
All right, let's go.
Come on.
Too bad you didn't go
into anesthesia, pal.
'Cause you really know
how to pass gas.
I'm just saying,
it's not as cut and dried
as you make it sound.
Well, we're a hospital.
We're entrusted with
saving lives.
I don't see how turning
a profit even comes into it.
Advanced technology
costs money, Will.
For-profit hospitals
are able to provide
better services,
state-of-the-art
diagnostics...
While gouging the average Joe,
who just needs a chest X-ray
and some antibiotics.
I'm not saying
it's a panacea, Will.
I'm saying money is
not the root of all evil.
It's like I'm dating
Gordon Gekko.
Why do I get the feeling like
I'm sleeping with the enemy?
I've got surgery to get to.
See you in a bit.
What about Abe and Ginny?
Well, they're both
backing Jack.
To turn Med into
a for-profit hospital?
That's surprising.
Well, Jack can be
pretty persuasive.
And he's selling it
as the only way
to keep Med
on the cutting edge
of medical advancement.
Like OR 2.0.
We've got ten votes for
and five against.
Now, Jack needs a two-thirds
majority to abandon our
non-profit status, so...
It seems
I'm the deciding vote.
We're hoping we can
count on you, Vernon.
Yeah.
I've been proud to sit
on this hospital's board
for 23 years.
As far as I'm concerned,
if it ain't broke,
don't fix it.
Well, maybe
if it's badly sprained.
Thank you, Vernon.
This is a big relief.
Yeah, as long as
we won't have any
last-minute defections,
I think we can
breathe easy.
Are you okay?
Yeah, yeah, just a headache
I can't seem to shake.
You look pretty wobbly
there, brother.
A couple of aspirin,
I'll be fine.
Oh. Vernon?
I don't know why I got
so dizzy all of a sudden.
So Aiden's scans
came back, all right?
No sign of a stroke,
um, nothing on the MRI,
labs came back clean,
all of which suggests...
He still can't
hear anything.
Correct.
And so at this point,
I have a strong hunch
that what we're probably
looking at
is an early presentation
of schizophrenia
or schizoaffective disorder.
What do we do?
There's gotta be some
sort of medication
he can take to make
the voices go away.
There are a lot of options.
It's a treatable disease,
okay?
First thing we need to do,
though, is just to bring
Aiden up to speed.
Aiden is wondering
why it's a bad thing
for him to hear voices.
Look, you're hearing things
for the first time in years,
and it's wonderful, right?
These voices, they're kind,
they're gentle.
Problem is, that's very
likely gonna change.
Chances are good
that these voices
could become unpleasant.
They might even ask you
to do something
that could put you
in harm's way.
Aiden's wondering
if medication
is the best treatment.
Medication is an excellent
treatment, okay?
I've had countless patients
who have been
helped tremendously
by medication.
Will the voices
go away completely?
You know, there's no
ironclad guarantee.
At the very least,
they will be tamped down,
if not suppressed
altogether.
Then, yeah,
I want to do that.
Can we start now?
Absolutely. Yeah.
We can absolutely start now.
Okay.
Well, great.
Thank you.
Wonderful.
Well done. It's a big step.
A nurse
will be in shortly,
and I'll be back
to check up on you later
in the day, okay?
So you said you've
been experiencing
headaches recently?
Uh, off and on for
about ten days.
Okay, well, Vernon,
I'm inclined to send you
for a head CT,
just to be safe,
but in the meantime,
here, follow my finger.
Morning, Tess.
Oh, wow.
Who are you
looking to impress?
Impress?
I had to get
my driver's license renewed.
I have to live with
that thing for,
like, five years.
True. You look fabulous.
Thank you.
Better go get changed.
All righty.
Seizing!
Two milligrams
of Ativan, IM, stat.
It's okay!
Everything's gonna
be all right, Vernon.
Hold on.
I don't understand.
He was fine this morning,
and now you're telling me
he has some kind of
brain tumor?
A noncancerous tumor.
"Acoustic neuroma" is
the technical term.
It's most likely
been growing slowly over
the past few months,
compressing your
husband's brain stem
and impacting his hearing
and balance.
So how do we fix it?
I go in and take it out.
But it is open-brain
surgery, right?
What are the potential risks?
Because of the tumor's
location, it might be
tricky to resect.
There's an elevated risk
of asymmetric paralysis.
His face?
Phyllis, Dr. Abrams is
the best neurosurgeon
in the city.
That's true.
Are there any other options?
Any updates?
Not yet.
And I guess with
this development,
the vote's gonna need
to be canceled now.
Jack's looking
to push the agenda as-is.
You're kidding.
No.
He's eager to come
to a quick resolution
so that everyone can
have an extended break
while Vernon recuperates.
Yeah, and he can secure
his two-thirds majority.
Well, Jack didn't make
his fortune by not taking
advantage of opportunities.
She's electing
to forgo surgery
and move forward
with a noninvasive
radio treatment.
Abrams is hopeful that will
shrink the tumor over time.
When can he be extubated?
I don't know.
Even intubated, we're still
having trouble controlling
his seizures.
Well, I'll go
whip the vote again.
See if I can flip someone.
They're still gonna
have the vote today?
Don't even concern
yourself with that,
Dr. Halstead.
Just see that Vernon gets
the best care possible.
What do we got?
35-year-old Brendan Metz,
took multiple GSWs
stopping a bank robbery.
Hole in right thigh,
actively bleeding
when we got him.
Pressure's stable.
Lost about 500 mils
of blood
before we got
the tourniquet on him.
Pushed 50 mics
of fentanyl
on the way over.
Okay. Hey, Brendan,
you're at Chicago Med.
We're gonna take
good care of you, okay?
Hang in there for me, bud.
Nice and easy,
on my count, okay?
One, two, three.
Thank you, Matt, Juliette.
So Brendan, seems you're
some kind of hero, huh?
I feel more like a fool
at the moment.
Well, the world could use
a lot more fools like you.
What are we looking at?
Hole number one,
right anterior axillary line
at the umbilicus.
Number two,
midaxillary line at the flank
at the same level.
Okay, do they connect?
Uh, yeah, I think so.
Let me swab.
Definitely connecting
our superficial.
How about the leg?
Thank you.
Um, uh, two holes
here as well.
Number three,
mid-medial thigh,
four, lateral mid-thigh.
No pulses
with a tourniquet up,
so let's go ahead
and loosen that,
see what we're
working with.
Type and cross him
for 6 and 6, and push
one of each for now.
Ooh.
Definitely arterial.
It's a hard sign.
Go ahead and retighten
the tourniquet,
and get me X-rays
of the leg and torso.
Come here.
What was that?
Rookie mistake,
putting yourself in the
line of fire like that.
I guess I'm just
a little off my game.
All right.
Go get changed
and cleaned up.
Hi.
Kira, have you ever
heard of the term
"ectopic pregnancy"?
It's when a fertilized
egg implants
in the outside
of the uterus.
Is that what's
happening to me?
Mm-hmm.
Your MRI revealed that
you have a rare type
of an ectopic pregnancy.
It's called an
abdominal pregnancy.
The fetus has attached
to the vena cava,
which is a huge vein
that leads to your heart.
But the baby's okay, right?
I mean, we saw
its heartbeat.
Yeah, at the moment, it is.
But if the placenta
damages the vena cava
for any reason,
that could cause severe
internal bleeding,
which would, in turn,
put your life in jeopardy.
So what are you saying?
For your safety,
you need to have surgery
to remove the fetus.
Will the baby survive?
At only 20 weeks, no.
I'm so sorry.
No. No, you don't
understand.
My mom needs this baby.
What do you mean?
My mom has a rare
stem cell disease.
It's why we came in today.
She needs a donor,
but the doctors
couldn't find one,
and I'm not a match
for her, so...
so I got pregnant.
In hopes that this baby
would be a stem cell match
for your mom?
Yeah.
Okay, Kira, this is
a human being that
we're talking about.
I know, but I'm gonna
raise the baby, and
I'm gonna be a good mom.
You're so young, Kira.
Being a mom right now,
your life would never
be the same.
I can do this,
and I want to.
And... And I always
planned on having kids,
so why not start now?
Because it's just
too dangerous
right now, Kira.
But what if we waited
a little bit
and let the baby
grow a little more
before the surgery?
Would it survive then?
Hey, you're free, right?
Yeah.
I'd love your eyes
on this acoustic neuroma.
Hmm.
You think your mapping
tech could help
someone like Abrams
confidently resect that?
Abrams wants a second
opinion from 2.0?
That's hard to believe.
I'm just doing some extra
legwork for a patient
I'm concerned about.
Well, let's upload
the CT and MRI and
see what they say.
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
I know, I know!
It's okay!
Aiden! Stop,
please, look at me!
Aiden, Aiden, Aiden!
What happened?
I don't know!
It's okay, buddy!
What's he saying?
I don't know!
Take it easy, buddy.
Wait!
Soft restraints, please!
Calm down!
Five of Haldol.
Calm down, Aiden!
Uh, care to explain
your plans for this
abdominal pregnancy?
Of course you checked
Kira's chart.
She needs surgery
immediately.
Move her upstairs.
I'm holding off
for now.
Why?
Kira wants to delay
the surgery until
the baby is viable.
She hopes that it
could be a stem cell
match for her mother.
Oh, you're joking.
You're joking.
It's the reason
Kira got pregnant.
That is absurd!
And morally repugnant.
She might as well be
organ harvesting.
She's operating
from a place of
care and concern,
not just about her mother,
but for the baby,
and she seems pretty
clear-headed about it.
That cannot possibly be
what her mother wants.
If you can't convince Kira
to change her mind,
then Kimberly will.
Kira doesn't want
her mother knowing
anything about this.
And she has
medical emancipation
because she's pregnant,
so she can do
anything she wants.
So, good news, Brendan.
The bullet you took
in your side passed
through your love handle.
It's superficial,
and there's nothing
more to do.
It'll heal on its own.
Your leg, however...
it's gonna need surgery
emergently, okay?
We're gonna have to
fix the artery,
or you will lose your leg.
The OR is ready right now.
We just need you to sign
the consent forms,
and we'll bring
you up, okay?
You're in good hands,
all right?
Is my leg gonna
be all right?
Excuse me?
Well, I prom...
I promised my kid
I'd coach his soccer team
next season.
I'll be able to do that,
won't I?
We can for sure
fix the artery.
But the nerve runs
right next to it.
We won't know if
you'll have full motor
and sensory function
until after...
Walk in the park
for us, Brendan.
Don't you fret
a lick now, okay?
Okay.
What was that?
I was just answering
his question.
No, you were raising
a patient's stress level
unnecessarily.
He needed to be informed.
Things happen in surgery.
Why would anything go wrong?
For any number of reasons.
I don't know.
Is this about the teasing?
Is what about the teasing?
All right, look.
You've been lording
over Liam and
the other residents
for almost a year now.
You had to assume
they'd try to knock
you down a peg
if they found a vulnerability,
and well, you gift-wrapped
them a doozy.
Whatever. It happened.
Proves you're human.
Laugh it off, and don't
let them get to you.
I'm not letting them
get to me.
Maybe it's best
if I sit this one out.
I'm sorry.
I don't have
the manpower
to spare.
Sorry to interrupt.
Not sure if you heard,
but Vernon's wife okayed
the craniectomy.
She's moving forward
with the surgery?
Dr. Abrams and Song are
prepping OR 2.0 as we speak.
What got Phyllis to
change her mind?
Once Dr. Song confirmed
2.0 could reduce
much of the risk,
I guess she felt
the assurance
she needed to go ahead.
Wow.
When can we expect
Vernon to come out
from under anesthesia?
From what I understand,
about three or four hours.
Ha!
Perhaps I can delay the vote.
At least until
Vernon wakes up.
Good job, Dr. Halstead.
Hey, Mags,
if I recall correctly,
you know ASL, right?
That means yes.
Okay.
What does this mean?
Something like,
"You take voices away."
Huh.
You know, I'm treating
a deaf patient,
and his sister's been
interpreting for us.
I'm starting to wonder if,
I don't know, we're getting
our signals crossed
or something like that.
You want me
to spy for you?
Too strong a word.
How are we doing?
You think it might
be time to get these
restraints off?
See if we can maybe
figure out what
happened earlier.
Aiden's calmed
down a lot.
Great.
Uh, Aiden's upset
because the voices
told him the nurses
were gonna make
his shoulder
pain worse.
Um, Aiden, I'm sorry.
Risperidone is typically
one of the faster-acting
medications,
but sometimes takes
a little longer.
So, uh, how about
we check back in a bit,
and maybe we can
have a chat then?
Okay?
He didn't say anything
about a nurse, did he?
He's upset because
he can't hear the voices
in his head anymore.
He suspects it's
because of the pills
that he's been given.
Yeah, the antipsychotics,
which I dispensed with
his permission.
Or so I was told.
He thought
it was painkillers,
not antipsychotics.
Huh.
Her BP is dropping,
and her hemoglobin's
down to 8.
Kira?
It hurts! It hurts!
Free fluid in the belly,
likely blood.
Kira, we can't hold off
on the surgery any longer.
Call the OR, tell them
to open it stat.
We're bringing Kira up
right away.
No! Please, no!
I need to talk
to you about Kira.
I need you for a second.
Please, no!
If at any point
during the surgery
you have to make the call
between Kira and the fetus,
please, please,
save my little girl.
We have every intention
of doing just that.
We'll have someone
keep you in the loop,
Kimberly.
I thought you should
hear that for yourself.
I cannot believe
you told her.
What about HIPAA?
Her daughter is heading
into emergency surgery.
If there's a crisis
and a decision
needs to be made,
it's Kimberly who'll do it.
Just came from
the pharmacy.
They wouldn't fill
Aiden's prescription
for Risperidone?
Well, I canceled it, Sandy,
because it turns out
it was prescribed
without the permission
of the patient.
We should probably
have a talk.
She knows ASL?
She does.
What's he saying?
He's saying that
he knows that she's
been lying to him.
Take the medication.
I was trying to help you.
But the voices,
they aren't real.
Aiden says that
he doesn't care that
the voices are not real.
Sandy, the only way
that we're gonna forge
a path forward...
I'm not sure
there is a path
forward here.
Aiden only cares
about hearing
the voices in his head.
And I won't stand by
and watch
if you won't do
anything about it.
Okay, great.
Looks like we have enough
length to sew the two ends
directly together.
5-0 Prolene stitch.
I'm sorry, Dr. Marcel?
What is it?
I was told to inform you
that there is an emergent
situation in the OR 2.0
that requires your
immediate attention.
They're aware I'm in
the middle of surgery?
They are aware, yes.
Oh, come on.
All right, everyone.
Dr. Tanaka-Reed
will continue on with
the anastomosis
until I return.
Follow his lead.
We can wait
until you get back.
No, I don't wanna prolong
his ischemic timing
any more than necessary.
Get the anastomosis done.
I'll be back
as soon as I can.
That's great.
Thank you, Trish.
Pull up the feed in there
so I can watch.
Oh, sure.
All right.
Here goes.
Awesome. Thank you.
Trust me, I get how
frustrating it can be
to try and help somebody
who doesn't want it.
He has no idea
what he's doing.
You know,
I'm not sure any of us
can really understand
what he's going through
right now.
You must think
I'm a horrible person.
I do not.
Not at all.
I understand how difficult
it can be for family members
to get this kind of news.
And I completely get
the impulse to just wanna
fix it immediately.
You know, I had my own issues
with mental illness before.
I know it's not
schizophrenia,
but I suffered
with depression.
Really?
It was especially bad
after our parents died.
Car accident.
Aiden was still in
high school at the time.
Oh, man.
I can't even imagine.
Aiden got by somehow.
Maybe it was because
he had already suffered
his own personal tragedy,
losing his hearing,
but he was more resilient.
I was such a mess.
My meds saved my life.
I don't know what
I would do without them,
honestly.
And I can't stomach
the idea of watching Aiden
go through anything
like what I did.
I get it. I do.
Have you ever told Aiden
about any of this stuff?
The last thing I'd ever
wanna do is burden Aiden
with my problems.
He doesn't need that.
I think you might be
surprised by what he's
capable of handling.
You know, people who learn
to manage this disease,
they live full,
productive lives.
I mean, they can, really.
You know, listen,
outcomes improve significantly
when loving family members
stay involved.
So you know, he's gonna
be relying on you,
especially at first.
But with a little luck,
sooner rather than later,
he's probably
gonna be able to
return that favor.
And, um, how wonderful
would that be?
Vernon should be out of
surgery any minute now.
Strange how Phyllis
changed her mind.
Happens pretty frequently,
actually.
A big decision like that.
Sometimes people need
a little time to process.
So how'd it go?
Fairly certain we got
a complete resection.
No problem with the margins,
as far as I can tell.
Electrophysiology
looked perfect.
But you don't know
for sure yet, right?
So how long exactly
until he wakes up?
I'm a brain surgeon, Jack.
Not a soothsayer.
Is it gonna be today?
What can I say, Jack?
When he's ready to be
extubated, he will be.
Jack seems awfully interested
in Vernon's recovery time.
Pretty sure it's about
the board meeting later.
He's probably sweating
now that Vernon might
be able to vote against him.
Vernon's the deciding vote?
That's what I hear.
Were you aware of that
when you urged me
to get involved?
I heard rumors of you
acting like a cowboy.
That's not
what happened today.
I came here out of
concern for the patient.
Who are you trying
to convince with that?
Me or you?
Well, your facial
movement's symmetrical,
and your hearing
appears to be intact.
What a relief.
Thank you all.
Well, I understand
a celebration is in order.
It appears so.
My apologies to
everyone for the scare.
The board is gonna be
excited to hear the news.
Speaking of, um,
the meeting's
about to start.
Look, Vernon, no one
would question you
if you opted to
sit this one out.
Well, I certainly don't
feel like I'm ready
to get out of bed,
but I wonder
if it'd be possible
for me to
video-conference in.
Of course.
We can make that happen.
Great.
Well, I'll see you then.
Triphasic signals.
Well, is that good?
Pulse is strong.
Exactly what
we were hoping for.
In a few weeks,
you can start getting
ready for soccer season.
Man, thank you.
Thank you both.
You bet.
Nice job, by the way.
Like you said,
I can handle it on my own.
Indeed.
I checked the board
when I got out of surgery
and noticed that Abrams
was using the OR 2.0
this afternoon.
No record of you
stepping in at all.
Yeah.
Wires must have gotten
crossed somewhere.
It was actually Onc Surg
that needed a hand.
I know you're probably
lying to me.
But I'm appreciative
nonetheless.
It'll be okay.
Kira!
Mom?
Is she gonna be okay?
Yes.
She has some recovery
time ahead of her,
but she'll be okay.
Unfortunately,
we were not able
to save the fetus.
I'm so sorry, Mom.
Oh, Kira, honey.
What were you thinking?
You need a stem cell donor.
I thought that maybe
if I had a baby, then...
Look at me, honey.
I'm gonna be...
We're gonna
get through this, okay?
We haven't found
a donor yet,
but these things,
they take time.
What if we can't?
We just have to be brave.
I know that won't be
hard for you.
We're gonna give you
some privacy.
Boy, is she lucky.
Oh, absolutely.
Kira could have died today.
I'm talking about Kimberly.
How unbelievably lucky
she is to have a daughter
willing to make such
a generous act of love.
How are Aiden
and Sandy doing?
It looks like
they're working it out.
Aw, looks like they made up.
Yeah. Nothing like
coming clean to
re-establish trust.
Hey.
Can we talk?
Yeah.
Yeah?
All right, uh...
This morning,
your offer, uh...
You realize what this
could mean, right?
If you have some sort
of health crisis someday
with only one kidney left...
I know what I'm risking.
You do not have to do this.
Dad, you don't understand.
I need to do this.
Well...
If you turn out
to be a match,
I won't say no.
And golumpki?
Oh, my gosh, delicious.
Thank you.
Liliana is a wonderful cook.
And you know what?
She can clean.
A professional.
You don't need a maid now.
Pavel.
What?
It was a joke!
Here.
No, I'm good.
Thank you very much.
It's delicious.
I gotta drive. Gotta drive.
Oh, good!
Responsible.
So.
Pan Daniel.
Pan? Pan Daniel?
It means "sir."
You are an important man
with an important job.
Oh, I don't know
about that.
Um, I can't imagine
doing anything else.
Certainly keeps me
on my toes.
A lucky man who
doesn't hate his job.
Say that again.
Lucky indeed.
So tell me, Doctor.
You deal with any
crazy people today?
You know what, Pavel?
Even if I wanted to,
I wouldn't be able
to tell you.
And honestly,
I don't love that word.
I don't know, maybe it's
a shrink thing. Anyway.
I'm sorry.
My English is not so good.
It's okay.
Not so correct.
I didn't mean to offend.
None taken, whatsoever.
But you must have
some good stories.
Pavel!
What?
He doesn't want to
talk about his work.
I get it.
I think I'm going to
check on the babka.
And I'm gonna get rid
of some of these dishes.
What did he...
What did he say?
Oh, he was, uh...
He was just wondering
if we had any more vodka.
Hey, Sharon.
Do you have a minute?
Oh, is it important, Maggie?
This is really
not a good time.
It kind of is.
Okay, come. Come here.
What's up?
I lied to you earlier,
and I feel horrible
about it.
Lied? About what?
I didn't get all dressed up
to renew my driver's license.
I was meeting with
a headhunter.
About maybe
finding another job.
Okay.
I was frustrated last week
in ED, and I...
I called them.
I instantly regretted it,
and I feel guilty even
thinking about leaving.
With all the changes
that are going down
in the ED
and all this chatter
about going for-profit...
I have a bad feeling
about the direction that
Jack is taking us.
I get your
frustration, Maggie,
and I promise you,
we're working
on a course-correction
as we speak.
The board is in the process
of defeating Jack's agenda,
and we're going to
hold the line.
Good.
I really don't
wanna leave Med.
It's a great day
for Gaffney, everybody.
Thank you.
I'm gonna make sure to have
an even brighter future.
Thank you.
George?
What's going on?
Jack.
He got the votes.
We are now
a for-profit hospital.
How?
Who flipped?
Vernon!
Apparently, he was
so impressed with 2.0,
he decided to be
supportive of
any measure
that would bring in
more advancement in
high-tech medicine.
Sharon, I am so sorry.