♪ Ohhh ohhh ohhh ♪
We're in the back
of the store.
Dad has just given me
two pennies.
I liked to hide them
in this big crack
in the floorboards.
I'm saving them
so I can buy a town.
That's what I tell
my big brother Derek anyway.
Two guys come in.
They'd already pulled a gun.
They'd already taken
the money.
And now they want
his watch.
Hey, Coop.
Amelia?
Morning, Addie.
Let me grab some coffee,
then I'll be back.
I have news.
Hey, everybody.
Coffee. I need coffee.
Okay, I took all the coffee,
but I will make a fresh pot.
Wow.
Okay, hi.
Sheldon.
What?
Do you guys know already?
Was Ryan here or something?
I'm engaged.
Hello!
Whoa.
What the hell was that?
We called the police.
And every hospital in L.A.
And the morgue.
Why?
Because we thought
you were dead.
Why would you think
I was dead?
Because no one has seen you.
What are you talking about?
I miss a couple of days
of work and suddenly i'm--
12.
What?
You missed 12 days of work.
No one has seen you
in 12 days.
12 days?
Amelia.
What are you on?
What are you talking about?
Are you high
right now?
Look, okay...
I was...
On drugs. I was.
I slipped.
I went on kind of a bender,
and it...
Well, it was scary.
It was really scary.
For a minute, I thought, um,
I thought I was
going over the edge.
And then even Ryan
got worried about me.
He says there's partying
and then there's...
What I was doing was scary.
So he dragged me
to a meeting--
many meetings,
a lot of meetings--
and I am so grateful to him
for that
because he helped me.
You know, he helped.
And I didn't realize
that it was 12 days,
and I can just imagine
what all of you thought,
and I am so sorry
that you thought I was dead.
Addie, I am so sorry,
but that's what I was doing.
I was going to meetings
and I was getting right
with my higher power
and I was just being sober
every day.
You're okay?
I'm okay.
I mean, I'm gonna have to go
to two or three meetings a day
for as long as it takes,
but I'm good.
I swear. I was lucky.
Oh, I was so worried
about you.
I know.
Thank you for worrying.
But you didn't need to.
Ryan saved me.
I mean, he helped.
Now apparently, I have
a lot of work to catch up on,
so I will talk
to you guys later.
Oh, that's a relief.
I know.
I thought that, uh--
she's lying.
She is lying.
Charlotte, she--she seemed
okay to me.
That's because you're not
an addict.
She didn't seem
strung out.
You'd be surprised
at how adept an addict can be
at hiding their addiction.
I toyed with the idea
of specializing in addiction
before I chose fertility.
We have to do something.
If she's lying.
Charlotte...
Is it...
Possible--
I mean, is it just possible,
given your history,
that you're blowing this
out of proportion?
Because of my history,
I know the games,
the secrets,
and the lies.
And I am telling you,
that girl is using.
♪ Oh ♪
♪ ah ♪
♪ ain't nobody ♪
♪ no, ooh ♪
I've never been in love.
♪ Ooh ♪
I've loved...
My mother,
my brother,
my sisters,
friends...
♪ Oh ♪
My father.
♪ That's the way it was ♪
I've loved, I've been loved.
♪ It happened so naturally ♪
I mean, I'm not saying...
I know what love is.
I just...
♪ Holdin' me close ♪
I've never been in love.
I've never...
♪ I let myself go ♪
♪ now we're flyin'
through the stars ♪
I love you.
♪ I hope this night
will last forever ♪
♪ oh, oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ ain't nobody ♪
♪ nobody ♪
I'm in love with you,
okay?
♪ Ain't nobody ♪
♪ can make me feel this way ♪
Don't freak out
or leave me.
♪ Ooh, and first you put
your arms around me ♪
♪ then you put
your charms around me ♪
Do you want to get married?
♪ I can't resist
this sweet surrender ♪
Are you serious?
♪ Oh, my nights
are warm and tender ♪
I mean,
we can't get married.
I mean, that's insane.
It's not.
Amelia,
I'll never leave you.
I'm in love with you, too.
♪ No surprise ♪
♪ got a feeling
most would treasure ♪
Oh, my god.
We're getting married?
You have to say yes.
♪ Nobody ♪
♪ loves me better ♪
Yes. Yes.
♪ This way ♪
♪ Ain't nobody ♪
♪ ain't nobody ♪
♪ loves me better ♪
♪ no, no, there ain't no ♪
♪ ain't nobody ♪
♪ ain't nobody, no, no, no ♪
♪ makes me feel this way ♪
♪ oh ♪
Coop.
Yeah.
Come take these
from me, please.
She's in the parking lot.
Hey.
Morning.
Can we talk to you
for a minute?
Who's we?
Hello.
Hi, Amelia. I'm Lenny.
Does she have a brain tumor,
a giant carcinoma that she
wants me to excise?
That had better be what is
going on here, because--
Amelia, everybody here
cares about you,
and they'd like you to stay
and listen to what
they have to say.
Will you do that?
An intervention?
Okay. You know what?
I have patients to see.
There are no patients
coming today.
Today is about you.
Are you
freaking kidding me?
Amelia--
doctor. Dr. Shepherd, and I know
how an intervention works.
You're not the one who talks.
You are just the party planner.
One of you--
one of you is supposed to have
the guts to speak up
instead of hiding
behind this chick.
One of you has to have the balls
to say something to me.
Do you?
Any of you?
Okay.
Great intervention.
I have been intervened upon.
I will see you tomorrow.
I'm not letting you leave.
Sheldon.
Addison.
She's upset. She has
a right to be upset.
Addison--
she thinks
she's being ambushed.
I'm just saying
that I'm not sure
this is the right way
to go.
Do you want to do this?
Then you can.
You can do this.
Amelia, get off the elevator.
Screw both of you.
If you don't get off
the elevator, I will fire you.
Then I quit.
Amelia--
Amelia, get off the elevator,
or I'll call the police on you.
And tell them what?
And tell them you've been
writing prescriptions
for your own personal drug use.
You don't know
what you're talking about.
Yeah, actually, I do.
Okay. Fine.
I will stay at the practice.
Amelia--
I said I would stay
at the practice.
I did not say I would
hang out with you.
- This isn't working.
- A united front.
She just walked out.
So go after her.
You have to be in this.
You can't just come along
for the ride.
There are times that you're
gonna have to steer the ship.
We're using sailing...
Metaphors now?
I mean, can I just--
what are the qualifications
for this anyway?
Are you even--i mean, is there
a certification for this?
Are you qualified to do this?
Addison--
we all agreed.
Fine. I'll go.
Look, I know...
This is...
Would you just listen to
what everyone has to say?
Addison, I got sober young.
And then I spent the bulk
of my 20s in a library,
studying my ass off--
college, med school,
residency, neuro fellowship.
So now I wanted to have
some fun.
I made a mistake,
and now I'm fine.
I would think you'd get that.
I do. I get that.
But... you are an addict,
Amelia.
You down a bottle of wine
with every meal.
You drink when you're happy
and when you're sad
and when it's Tuesday.
Should we do an intervention
about your alcoholism?
I don't have a problem.
That's the difference here.
I don't need to drink.
I haven't had a drink
in months.
Yeah, because the only thing
you're more addicted to
than booze is having a baby,
which is sad,
because, hell,
you're friggin' barren.
You waited too long,
and your junk dried up,
and you've ruined any man
who would want to even consider
impregnating you.
Poor Derek. Poor Mark.
You aborted his kid, right?
And now you've got Sam,
and at least he's smart enough
to not want to try
and breed with you,
because let's be honest--
not even Rosemary's baby
would want to live
amongst the tumbleweeds
in your uterus.
Mm.
Amelia--
dude, seriously?
I barely know you.
What are you even doing here?
You're right.
You don't know me.
I'm here because we all agreed
we would be here.
And I'm here because
you don't get how lonely
most people are.
See, most people,
they just go to work.
They go to work, they come home,
maybe they have friends.
But on any given day,
they're not sharing as much
or caring as much
or giving as much
as all of you give
to each other on a--
on an average Wednesday.
So, yes, you're right,
I don't know you.
But I know that you have
a family here
and I see
that you're destroying it.
If you continue
down this path,
you won't just
go down alone, Amelia.
You'll take all the people
that love you down with you.
What do we do now? Do we
just, like, leave, or is it--
Coop.
No, I'm just saying,
she's not listening.
She's not listening.
I'm not
in favor of this.
Research shows that group
confrontational strategies
with alcohol and drug abusers
do not work.
She's going to go
into withdrawal soon.
What?
She's using.
At a certain point, she's
going to go into withdrawal.
That's our chance.
We just have to keep her here
till that happens.
Yeah, but she's not high
right now.
Yes, she is.
No, she's not.
She is. She is.
She'll be coming through
those doors any minute.
Her high
will be on its way out,
and we stand between her
and getting out of here
to get more drugs.
She'll be a little bit sweaty,
irritable, twitchy, tweaking.
My guess is,
she's an oxy girl?
Nothing like oxycodone
to turn a nice girl
into bitch on wheels.
Any minute...
She's coming through
those doors.
Whatever you have to say,
spit it out so I can go.
I don't have all day.
My watch?
No. You have the money.
Just take it and go.
Just... go.
Shh.
My mom gave my dad
that watch.
It was a symbol
of their life together...
Of how much she loved him.
Okay. Okay.
Everyone's gonna take turns
talking now.
And they're all here
because they want to help you.
So try to keep that in mind.
This is not about anyone
judging you.
This is--
okay, lady.
You have clearly
never met these people.
Amelia--
fine.
Who's talking first?
Perfect.
Shrink talk. My favorite.
So, um,
we're not--we're not close,
so I don't have anything
personal to...
Uh, I was just gonna ask you
if you're feeling okay.
You're sweating
and your foot is shaking.
And you're aging
and your husband hates you.
So, you know,
things could be worse for me.
A-Amelia--
it's okay. Pete. It's okay.
She's scared.
She's lashing out.
I've had patients that are
angrier than you
and sicker than you,
so I can take it.
Awesome. Are you
lookin' for applause,
as usual?
Amelia--
it's okay, Pete.
No, i-it's not okay.
Honestly, Pete,
all I have been able to think
since I saved your pathetic life
is, was it worth it?
'Cause you're
kind of a tool.
I mean, maybe saving you
was a waste of my energy.
Maybe it was a waste of
my mad, mad surgical skills.
Maybe you're a waste of life.
Maybe angel-of-death dude
should call it a day
and swallow some pills
yourself.
What do you say, cross on over
to the other side?
It'd give your wife some great
material for her next book,
and she'd love that.
That's her thing--
raping her personal experiences
for attention.
Oops. Did I say rape?
Sorry, Charlotte.
Oh, my god. Are you okay?
Yeah. Are you?
Yeah.
Oh.
She's like a dog.
She's like...
She's like a cornered dog.
She's like a cornered,
injured--
Rabid...
Rabid dog. Oh.
Oh.
You two all right?
Yeah.
Did she shoot anyone yet?
Not yet.
Look, I can't ask everyone,
because we're
in the middle of it,
but...
I think it's time.
Violet?
Why is it all on me?
You're the shrink.
Do it.
Is this all there is,
your big intervention--
just screwed up people
telling me how screwed up
I am?
Because last I checked,
I'm a world-class neurosurgeon
with a near-perfect
surgical record.
So if you want to intervene,
fine.
I can go all day.
Can you?
Go all day?
Are we talking
in riddles now?
Are you the riddler?
Are you riddling me stuff
right now?
Because I might need a pen
to write this down.
I gotta admit,
I'm kind of loving you
right now.
I am loving you.
You are winning
better than Charlie sheen...
As long as I overlook the fact
that you're a giant oxy addict
who's killing herself.
Everyone here
is in agreement.
You will
no longer be enabled.
Enabled?
Is that one of your special
s.A.T. Words?
I'll change the locks.
Until you get help,
You can't live
at my house anymore.
I will change the locks.
I will throw you out.
Then I will
call in your mother
and your brother
and your sisters,
and then I will call
the medical board
and report you,
because I love you, Amelia,
but I will not
love you to death.
Water?
Bupe.
Nice little drug.
You dissolve it in water.
It'll make withdrawal symptoms
go away immediately.
It'll also prevent any drugs
from getting me high
for 72 hours.
Excellent work.
Big pharma has done us all
a favor.
Amelia, please.
It could help you.
It'll at least give you
a chance to hear us
without being high,
without going through
withdrawal.
I told you, I'm drug free.
I have been for five days.
I am not
going through withdrawal.
I'm clean.
Well, then take the bupe.
Amelia, we all love you.
It--
it'll help you feel better.
Give it a shot.
Then we can talk you
through this.
Please.
You want me to stay and listen
so that I can get sober?
Yes.
Okay.
Fine.
Get me some oxy.
Score me some oxy...
And then I will stay
as long as you want.
Why don't you
come back to bed?
I want to give you something...
'Cause we're engaged.
I didn't give you anything.
♪♪♪
You give me love.
And you'll give me a ring...
At some point,
when we put on clothes
and leave this room.
♪♪♪
Here it is.
♪ I can love you
with my eyes closed ♪
♪ I see your heart
through a blindfold ♪
It was my dad's.
My mom saved up
for three years to buy it.
♪ Baby, ain't no way ♪
You like it?
This is amazing.
I-I love it.
Amelia, you don't
have to--
you give me love.
And you don't judge
or try to change me.
And you make me feel...
Beautiful.
♪ 'Cause I got days and days ♪
♪ oh, days and days of love ♪
Come back to bed.
Let's get high first, okay?
Okay.
♪ Days and days of love ♪
If she gets on that elevator,
it's over.
She can't leave.
We lose her if she leaves.
Are we seriously
considering doing this?
Okay, what if--what if
we make her worse?
We don't know what's in
her system already.
We could cause an overdose.
We're talking about giving her
40 milligrams of oxycodone,
not shooting her up
with heroin.
Look, we're eight doctors
in a medical office.
She'll be more than monitored.
No, no.
We're not doing this.
We're--we're not supporting
her drug habit.
Just because
she lacks discipline
and--and is acting like
a child--
she is an addict.
She has a disease.
It's a disease, Sam.
Okay, all right. Well,
I think we should take a vote.
All those in favor
of giving her oxy?
Seriously? Just me.
I don't--
I shouldn't vote.
Thank you. Who else?
I mean, I'm here
to support Addison.
If she votes for drugs,
I'll vote for drugs.
Thank you.
Who else?
I think it's dangerous.
You people...
You have no idea what you're
doing to her. And you.
What kind of doctor are you?
You should know better.
Hey.
Look,
we have a difference
of opinion, all right?
It happens
around here all the time.
You're about a century behind
in your thinking.
You think addicts should,
what, be locked up,
institutionalized
instead of treated?
I think that Amelia should take
responsibility for her actions.
You think Pete
should take responsibility
for his heart attack?
Uh, that's not
the same thing.
Why not?
Because Pete
has heart disease.
Amelia has a disease, too.
That's your opinion.
Look...
Jake, we both know that
that is up for debate
in the medical community,
all right?
The whole disease model
comes from a.A.,
where the first thing
they try to do
is get people to admit
that they're powerless
against their addiction.
Because drugs function
differently in their bodies.
Addiction is
a threefold disease.
It's a "disease"
that doesn't fire up
unless you take the drugs.
Amelia has control
over that, right?
I mean, she made a choice
the first time
she took those drugs,
just like she has
a choice today.
Wow.
You think
people choose that misery?
You think they--you think
they choose that life?
You think they want to be
licking drugs
off of bathroom floors
and neglecting their kids
and destroying their husbands
and killing themselves?
You think anyone who is not
in the throes of a disease
would consciously do that
to themselves?
- Is that what you think?
- Jake.
What?
Are you okay?
Do you want to talk?
No.
You think it'd be all right
if, uh...
Yeah, yeah, there's
lots of us in there.
I guess I hit a nerve.
Yeah, well...
There's a lot of those
flying around today.
Kinda hard to avoid.
We should probably
get back in there.
Do we have to?
"You are
someone's child, Amelia.
That's all I keep thinking."
"I don't care how old you are,
you are always someone's child.
"I work with kids all day.
I see that love.
I have to give news
to parents every day"...
I want my drugs.
"Leukemia, cancer,
kids with diseases"...
Give me my drugs.
I want my drugs.
- Give me my drugs.
- I want my drugs.
Give me my drugs.
"Kids with diseases..."
What do we want? Drugs.
"There's no worse news."
When do we want 'em? Now.
What do we want? Drugs.
"It's killing me to see what
this disease is doing to you."
When do we want 'em? Now.
What do we want? Drugs.
"There are things that you could
do to treat your disease"...
When do we want 'em? Now.
"And get your life back"...
What do we want? Drugs.
"And you're not doing them."
When do we want 'em? Now.
"You owe it to the people who
love you to try to get well."
What do we want? Drugs.
When do we want 'em? Now.
"You at least have to try,
because you are someone's kid
and because you're my friend."
What do we want? Drugs.
When do we want 'em? Now!
What do we want? Drugs!
Thank you, ladies and gentlemen!
My next show
will be in five minutes!
Addison, where are you going?
What does she want? Drugs.
When does she want them? Now.
We agreed that we wouldn't.
I didn't. I didn't agree.
Addison--
that--
that thing in there?
That used to be
a person, okay?
And she was sweet
and she was funny,
and I took her to get
her ears pierced,
and i-i-i-i did her hair
for her for prom,
and I told her all about
birth control
when she didn't know
who to ask,
and we were sisters,
you know?
We were closer than sisters.
Now she's...
That used to be
Amelia Shepherd.
That used to be someone
that I love,
and I want her back.
And if it means
me giving her some oxy
so she can
shut up and listen,
so she doesn't
get on that elevator?
Great. Fine.
I'll be her drug dealer.
I just want her back.
Where are you going?
To get the keys
to the drug dispensary.
Outta my way, Sam.
You have a tough life?
Everybody's life is tough.
Life comes with pain.
Sometimes that pain
is unthinkable,
but that--that's no excuse
to throw it away like this.
Everybody here has been
through hell and back--
Pete, Violet, Charlotte.
We're not using.
I swear to god, Sam--
shut up! You want to stop
being a drug ad--you--
this is how you stop
being a drug addict.
Stop using drugs!
Grow up! Take some
responsibility for yourself.
That's my girl.
Addie...
Gotta love that woman
of yours, Sam.
Of course, we all know
you can't commit,
so maybe you don't gotta,
but I do.
Addison-- we talked about this.
Absolutely not.
What the hell
are you thinking?
She's thinking that Amelia's
in trouble,
and if we let her leave--
thank you, Addison.
Oh, no. Here.
What?
You want to do your drugs,
you do 'em here,
in front of all these people
who care about you.
Show them who you really are.
Or don't do the drugs
at all,
and show them
who you want to be.
It's your choice.
Ahh.
Sure as I'm sitting here,
if you keep up at this,
you're gonna kill someone.
You're gonna
walk into some O.R.,
you're gonna get behind
the wheel of a car...
You're gonna kill someone,
Amelia.
That's where this goes.
And when you do...
When you do that,
you don't come back
from it.
Maybe you get sober...
But you don't come back.
You spend every day
trying to be a better person,
trying to save a life,
trying to make it right.
But you can't give
that mother back her child
or that husband back
his wife.
You walk and you talk
and you breathe,
and sometimes you even
smile or laugh...
But you don't come back.
Okay, I gotta ask.
What is the point of this now?
She's so high,
she can't even listen to us.
I'm listening.
What Charlotte said
was very beautiful...
And real.
And I worry about that.
I do.
Just give us 30 days--
30 days to get you
clean and sober--
then you can start over again.
A clean slate.
That sounds nice, but I...
I don't think
I can do it.
Oh, you can.
You can. I know you can.
We'll help you.
I'll help you.
Amelia, please.
There's a great rehab facility.
They have a bed waiting for you.
It's... it's right near
the ocean.
Will you come, too?
I'll come see you
every day.
I'll... I will.
I'll be there.
Yeah, I will.
Ryan.
Oof.
Oh!
You need to go.
Sam--
no. He's gotta go.
Leave.
Ryan and I are getting married.
Now.
- Don't speak to him like that.
- You realize
you'll never get sober
if you stay with him, ever.
Amelia's addiction
is not Ryan's fault.
As a matter of fact, Ryan,
if you want to get sober,
we'll help you, too.
No, no, we won't.
Yes, we will,
if that's what it takes.
No, our commitment,
our concern is for Amelia.
I know, and she will do better
if the person she loves
is also in the program,
is getting sober as well.
There's studies on this.
Sheldon, back me up.
Okay, I just think we need
to discuss this before we s--
I think what Violet
and Lenny said is right.
I believe we can help anyone
who wants to get sober.
He didn't say
he wants to get sober.
You gave him
your father's watch?
Amelia.
Amelia, look at me.
It's his engagement present.
It's your father's watch.
Leave me alone.
Maybe just give her
a little bit of space--
this is none of your business!
I am speaking to my sister!
I'm not your sister.
Look at this.
You took this
from your mother?
Do you know how that's
gonna make her feel?
Okay,
let's, everyone, calm down.
What is the significance
of the watch?
Nothing. It's a watch.
Amelia.
My mom gave it to my dad
for their anniversary one year.
That is not the significance.
Addison--
it's not,
and you know it's not, Sam.
Amelia.
Two guys came into
her father's store
when she was 5 year--
shut up!
Whoa.
You do not tell that story!
That is not your story!
He was not your dad!
He was my dad!
You shut your mouth!
Shut up,
you stupid,
ignorant monster bitch!
You do not tell that story.
You do not ever
tell that story.
You ever tell that story
to anyone...
And I will kill you
with my bare hands.
Let's go. I want to go.
Come on. Please...
Stay.
Sheldon...
I will never love you back.
You get that, right?
It was nice to see you all.
Hope to see you all again
real soon
when things calm down.
We're in the back of the store.
Dad has just given me
two pennies.
Two guys come in.
We can hear them talking.
But we don't pay attention
until dad yells.
Shh.
Two guys shot my dad
for his watch.
Your--your friends, um...
No one's ever tried
to save me like that.
No one's ever cared enough.
And I've never been around
anyone like you before.
You make me want...
Your mom gave your dad
this watch
for their anniversary.
I want to have anniversaries
with you,
lots of 'em,
and kids.
If we were sober,
we could have kids
and a life.
We could have a life, too.
You want kids?
We'd have to be clean.
My father was a cokehead,
and I won't--i...
I can't.
We have to be clean.
Okay.
Do you want to get sober
with me?
Yeah.
Let's get sober together.
This is great.
This is gonna be so great.
It is. I can get the names
of some rehab places,
and we go in together
and we go out together.
This is a commitment.
This is important.
Can you do this? 'Cause if
you can't, we can al--
I can do it. I can.
We should probably
flush these.
Yeah. Yeah.
Or...
One last time?
I don't--i don't know.
Okay. Okay, flush 'em.
One last time.
So how many kids
do you want?
Three.
Two boys...
And a girl.
How about four?
Two boys, two girls--that way,
no one gets lonely.
Deal?
Deal.
You are so gorgeous.
What now?
Now you
have to cut her off.
When Amelia calls,
and she will call,
unless she's ready for help,
you don't give her a ride.
You don't give her money
or a place to stay
or her job back.
The only call
you can respond to
is Amelia calling you for help
to get off drugs.
That's it.
It's up to her now.
This was a bad idea.
This is what works.
But it didn't work.
She's out on the street.
Doing god knows what.
Yeah, with Ryan.
We lost her.
No, I lost her.
I lost her.
You don't know that. We started
something for her today.
Progress was made.
You may not see it.
Sometimes it takes time.
Results aren't always
immediate.
Sometimes... an addict
actually has to hit rock bottom.
Amelia snorting oxycodone
off the reception desk
doesn't qualify as rock bottom?
15 years, 3 months,
and 4 days ago,
I took my 5-year-old son
to the park.
He was on the swings,
having so much fun.
It was a beautiful day.
The sun was shining.
He had other kids
to play with.
We had all afternoon.
He was on the swings.
He was okay.
I knew he was, 'cause I could
hear him laughing
as I was shooting the tenner
of heroin I had on me.
I passed out.
I came to
an hour or so later,
and my son was gone.
They never found him.
♪ I don't understand ♪
Honey, that is rock bottom.
♪ You ♪
She called last week
and invited me to come
for a visit.
And she actually suggested
that I-I stay in the dorm room
down the hall.
Can you see it?
Me and a bunch of
college freshmen doing what,
beer bongs?
I told her, look, I'll come,
but I'm gonna stay
at the four seasons.
She misses you.
But...
I don't want you to worry,
'cause I'm taking care of her.
And I know she's yours,
I know that...
She's not mine.
She has a real dad.
But...
That guy, Lily, man...
There's nothing real
about him.
I miss you.
I miss you, too.
Still.
Every day.
♪ Well, I found you out ♪
But, you know,
for the first time since you...
Since you left,
I found some people that, um...
Well, I got a job that...
I like it.
I like these people.
I like this job.
I'm less...
I feel less alone.
♪ Someone to love you ♪
I hope you're not alone, baby.
I hope that, uh...
♪ Someone to love you ♪
I hope you found
some peace.
♪ When you look at me ♪
I remember that...
Whenever you were trying
to get clean, you...
You used to eat crullers--
a lot of crullers.
♪ Well, I found you out ♪
♪ discovered your secrets ♪
I hope you're clean, baby.
♪ Oh, honey ♪
♪ it ain't a sin ♪
I brought you some crullers.
♪ You ♪
♪ Need someone to love you ♪
♪ you need someone to hold you ♪
♪ tonight ♪
Ryan.
♪ Love you ♪
Ryan?
♪ Oh, someone to love you ♪
Ryan!
Ryan! Ryan!
♪ Yeah ♪
Ryan!
Ma'am,
do you know where you are?
Can you give me your name?
♪ ...help to be ♪
Four kids.
Two boys, two girls.
You can't die,
because we're getting clean
and we're having a family.
Ryan? Ryan?
♪ Ooh ♪
Ryan!
♪ But you ♪
♪ You need someone to love you ♪
Don't touch him!
We're getting married.
Two guys shot
my dad for his watch.
I've never
told anyone that before.
♪ Someone to love you ♪
♪ someone to love you ♪
Ma'am, is there anyone
you want me to call?
♪ Someone to love you ♪
Call
Dr. Addison Forbes Montgomery.
Tell her I said I'm ready
to go to rehab.
♪♪♪