As anyone who's ever had
their tonsils out can tell
you, surgery isn't cheap.
It takes a lot of money to
keep a hospital's doors open.
And when the funds run out,
it's on us to get out there
and raise some more.
Which means
it's time to put on makeup.
It's time to dress up right.
It's time to get things started
on The Muppet Show...
Crap! Sorry.
I've been watching a lot of
children's television lately.
Are we ready to go?
But you get the idea.
Uh, almost. Someone doesn't
want to put her shoes on.
Can I just get a word?
Hey. Hey. I, uh, really
hope this red carpet
is something you had laying
around the house, Avery.
We're trying to raise
money tonight, not waste it.
I grew up in this world.
I know how it works.
We're attracting serious
people with serious money
and tailoring an event to them.
Tonight is gonna be tasteful,
sophisticated, conservative.
Come in.
You and I have very different
definitions of the word "conservative."
Cheers!
Ari, what did you
spend my money on?
This is what you want.
You want spectacle, pizzazz.
Do I look like someone
who wants pizzazz?
When people think of hospitals,
they think of death,
disease, old people.
Not sexy. We are
giving them Las Vegas.
We are giving them a show.
People are more inclined
to open their wallets
if they're having fun. Boop.
He's falling apart.
He's refused to use
incentive spirometry.
Look, and his right lung is
just about ready to collapse.
If he wants to suffer,
then maybe we let him.
Oh, so you're gonna let him die
because he hurt your feelings?
There isn't anything
that he can say to me
that I haven't heard from
my mother 1,000 times.
I'm bulletproof.
But we can force all the
treatment on him we want.
It won't make a
difference if he decides
he does not wanna
fight for himself.
Maybe he just needs
to see what it feels like
to hit bottom.
Dr. Bailey?
Radiology wants to see you regarding
Gene Steers' PET scan results.
Um, call respiratory, and get
Dr. Webber started on CPAP.
Oh, he is not
going to like that.
He doesn't have to like it.
He just has to do it.
Trade assignments with me. No.
You're in a bad mood
because your crappy boyfriend
didn't invite you to the gala.
But you know what's
gonna make you feel better?
Spending a night
on the peds floor
with all of the
delightful little children.
Or, I could just punch my
crappy boyfriend in the junk.
Why not both?
Shane, trade with me.
I'm a surgeon, not a babysitter.
Me either. Why do I get screwed?
Cruel twist of fate?
Hey! Ross, Edwards.
It's just the two of
you down here tonight,
so if you find yourselves in
over your head, call a grown-up.
Kepner, kid in bed eight has
abdominal pain and vomiting.
If CT's negative, give him
fluids and send him home.
Don't we look spiffy.
Yeah, I do.
You look like crap.
I haven't had a chance
to freshen up yet, you ass.
Watch your back, coming through!
Holy heck.
Hey, what's the story?
Once upon a time, three idiots got
wasted and ran their car into a tree.
They're drunk?
No, high as kites.
Lucky they were the
only ones that got hurt.
Hey, Sinatra, I'll give you
a fiver for a glass of wine.
Sir, what did you take?
It's heroin. Add a tox
screen to their trauma labs.
What's your name?
No ID on any of 'em.
We've been going with
John, Jerry, and Jake Doe.
Cute. APRIL: Okay, let's hustle.
Get a full trauma workup
so I can get upstairs
and run a brush through my hair.
Oh!
Meredith Grey, as I live and
breathe. I haven't seen you in ages.
How's, uh, Derek
liking maternity leave?
He's on paternity leave.
Yeah, okay. We have a deal.
I don't work. Neither does he.
It's working out well.
I live in your house. You're
bored out of your minds.
Yeah, they've got all this
pent-up surgical energy
and now everything's
a competition.
It is not. And he's winning.
Oh. He is not winning.
He couldn't even get Zola
to put her shoes on tonight.
I did that. I got her
to put her shoes on.
So I'm winning.
I need to come back to work.
Drink?
Ooh. Excuse me.
That's the creepiest
waiter I've ever seen.
Bailey's gonna lose her
mind. She can't stand clowns.
This is gonna be hilarious.
Bailey's not coming.
What? Wait, we can do that?
Okay, I have been
dreading having to
be in the same
room with Arizona.
If this isn't mandatory,
I'm going home.
Wait, nobody's going home.
I'm giving 10% of tonight's take
to the department that
raises the most money.
Spread the word.
Wow.
Derek is really good
at this kind of thing.
I should get started
before he does.
Oh, I think he already has.
- Amazing.
Oh, come on.
I have to confess something.
I know who you are.
I saw your video from the
TED Conference and I just...
I'm sorry. I'm a
little starstruck.
Really?
Yeah. You know, I go every year,
and so many of the talks
often focus on the tech
or something
clever, but yours...
You spoke from the heart.
You might be surprised...
The truth. You're
an inspiration.
If I lost my wife
in a plane crash...
Oh, I'm sorry. What?
Your wife. She
passed away, right?
Yes, she did.
It's been really hard.
Cristina.
You and I have to join forces
so that Derek does
not win Avery's money.
Prison's changed you.
We are in trouble.
Avery bet the
farm on this party.
Listen to you two.
This is not that difficult.
Just be charming.
Use the same skills you would
if you were picking
someone up at a bar.
I know you know how to do that.
And you need to practice.
If we're gonna get serious
about meeting new people.
You need to let that go.
Ooh, Richie Rich, 10:00.
Mr. Steers, I know
this is hard to hear,
but the PET scan showed
your cancer has spread.
I'm afraid surgery is
no longer an option.
I'll tell you what's hard.
This pillow.
Why don't you have that Oriental
nurse bring me a new one?
Gene, we've talked about this.
Victoria is from
the Philippines.
That's what I
said. No, it isn't!
Okay, fine.
So no surgery. What's that mean?
More chemo?
What's the next step?
We talked about
worst-case scenarios
before the PET
scan, and this is it.
Um, these are brochures
from several local facilities
that can help ease
you into the final stages.
When you're ready, we can talk
about which might be the best fit.
Best fit is gonna be the
one with topless nurses.
Mmm.
I don't need any of
that fully nude business.
They don't serve
booze at the joints
where the girls
ditch their skivvies.
Matter of fact, how
about I slip you a tenner,
you slip me a
bottle of something?
I'll be available
when you're ready to
talk about your options.
I'll call if I start
to feel weepy.
What are you doing?
Eating shrimp at a party.
I just spent 20 minutes
talking to donors about you
when they'd prefer
to be talking to you.
You need to... Alex!
You even listening to me?
I gotta get some air.
Alex!
Where the hell are you going?
Hey, Jackson!
Champagne?
Oh!
This is amazing!
Oh, the magician,
incredible! This is warm.
Oh, yeah, Big Bird
said there's no ice.
Apparently, a miscommunication
between the caterer
and the venue.
Cooling blankets. We have
some back at the hospital.
They can bring a
patient's temperature
down in minutes, right?
No reason those
can't chill a bottle.
That's ridiculous.
Then it's on
theme for the night.
And I can't leave.
Um, could you please
run back and grab 'em?
What? No, but, uh,
the magician is the...
Please?
Fine. GUESTS: Ooh!
And that is not even close to
the strangest thing I've seen.
Though, honestly, that
story I don't think is, uh,
appropriate.
Well, I'll tell you what, chief.
I'm gonna take a
walk over to that table,
and I'm gonna stick a little
something in that cash box.
Now when I come back,
maybe you'll be a little less
reluctant to give up the goods, Owen.
Well, now I want
to hear that story.
Emma Marling. Owen Hunt.
Oh, chief of surgery.
Well, I guess Grey Sloan is
pulling out its A game tonight.
I wasn't sure when I
got a load of the clowns.
Oh, come on. Clowns are great.
People love clowns.
You worried me
there for a second.
I was afraid you and I weren't
gonna have anything to talk about.
Um...
Hey, um, buy you a drink?
Isn't it an open bar?
The price is right.
Oh.
Okay. Thanks.
What was that? What was what?
That whole sparkly eye thing.
Well, I can't help it if my
eyes have a natural sparkle.
You were flirting. I don't
know what you're talking about.
Go juggle some balls.
You just brought a
knife to a gun fight.
Arizona? Uh...
Hey, um, it turns
out we needed more
IV kits up in peds, but I
can't seem to find them.
Do you need a hand?
No, no. Um, I'll be fine.
Okay. Just gonna
grab these.
Cool.
Jake's febrile and he's got
a crazy-high white count.
You factor in the heroin, and we're
probably looking at endocarditis.
And I think he's got
a pericardial effusion.
So, he could tamponade
at the drop of a hat.
And there's another
multiple trauma on its way in.
This is like medical
Whac-A-Mole. I love it.
Kepner said we
should call someone
if we're in over our heads.
Oh, good. Dr. Karev.
Hey, I just wanted to follow up
on the abdominal pain kid.
CT was negative, so we
gave him a couple fluid boluses
and sent him home.
Great, uh, what
about those guys?
Uh, they're pretty banged
up, but nothing we can't handle.
Great. Good. Uh, keep it up.
Nothing we can't handle?
We've been preparing
for this all year.
They have their party
tonight. This is ours. Enjoy it.
Oh, he's bleeding
from his chest tube.
Did you check his coags?
They're still pending.
Uh, get me a petroleum
dressing and some gauze!
And call X-ray to get here stat!
Doctors! Incoming!
You want to call someone,
or do you wanna be a rock star?
Somebody call the blood
bank, make sure they've got
plenty of O-neg on deck.
I want those trauma
rooms ready for action.
Anyone who can be
moved, move them!
We need all the
empty beds we can get!
Hey! You heard
her. Lock and load!
Okay, let's move!
Ooh!
I know, look. Isn't
that something?
You pulled a sleeping baby out
of day care to do your dirty work?
You're disgusting.
He's got his mother's sparkle.
Hello, baby.
Oh, and he's hungry.
Convenient.
He's my guy.
I'm gonna kill you dead. Mmm.
Oh, you're under a
lot of pressure at work.
Lots of late nights
and weekends.
But still, you stay active.
Lots of, uh, physical activity?
You can tell all
that from my pulse?
Sure, and the way the tux fits.
Oh, my, this watch is gorgeous.
It's vintage. It was my
father's, actually. Hmm.
He, uh, would wager
watches. Mmm-hmm.
And so he won this one. You
know, you need another one.
I'll be right back.
Ooh!
There is a gal over there
doing close-up magic.
You have to see it.
Uh...
Emma Marling, this is Dr. Cristina
Yang, our best cardio fellow.
How's it hanging?
Go on. You're missing the magic.
- Whiskey soda.
- Coming right up.
You are barking up the
wrong tree with that one.
You're never gonna
get a donation out of her.
Those shoes, outlet
mall all the way.
You want
that.
That old lady?
That old lady in Chanel.
Here you go. Thank you.
Go get 'em, tiger.
It was a beautiful
service, but after,
little Sofia just kept asking,
"Why is Mommy not
coming home with us?"
You are so strong.
No, it's... Really it's my
work that's kept me strong.
This hospital, you
know, these people.
That's beautiful.
Where can I make my donation?
Right over there
next to the stairs.
Ooh!
The nights are the
hardest, though.
I know exactly what you mean.
Ever since Harvey died, I
can't fall asleep in our bed.
I spend all of my nights
on the couch with the cat.
Exactly.
Wait, what?
What is the matter with you?
I know this is a difficult time,
but you cannot talk
to my nurses that way.
Your move. What?
I figured out your problem.
Your mind is all closed off.
Oh, oh, my mind is closed?
We need to get it fired
up so you can figure out
how you're gonna get
this cancer out of me.
Here, I figured you'd want to
play black, 'cause, well, you know.
If there was anything I
thought we could try...
There is. Make a move.
Yeah, I have other patients.
I can't just stand here and...
What would Rosa Parks say?
Excuse me? Or
Martin Luther King?
You think they would
just stand over there
and make excuses like you are?
You people are supposed
to be tougher than this.
Yeah, oh, I believe that you and I
have reached the end of our ability
to work together.
I'll have a counselor come by
and talk to you
about the brochures.
Oh, I see.
You're giving up on me because
you don't like the way I talk.
You're just gonna let me
die 'cause I offend you.
I am trying to give you
the best care I possibly can
despite the fact
that you offend me.
You are rude and demeaning,
and I am still trying
to help you move on
in the most comfortable
way possible.
I am not going to move on.
I'm not gonna pass away or go to
heaven or make a journey home.
I am going to die.
My lungs are gonna deflate.
I'm gonna lose
control of my bowels.
My tongue's gonna roll
to the back of my head.
I am going to be dead.
There's no making it
sound nice or pretty.
It is not good. I am
going to cease to exist.
And I don't want
to. I am not ready.
So get off your ass
and do something!
What the hell are you doing?
He needs a pericardiocentesis.
Yeah, we can't just do that.
I thought you wanted to be
a rock star. That was before
you started talking about
shoving needles into hearts.
Stop! I'm calling
someone. Not yet.
Shane! Not yet.
This is really
very sweet of you.
But, you know, you don't
have to sit here with me.
I don't mind.
I just...
I can't stand the way she looks at
me, the way that everyone looks at me.
Uh, no one's looking
at you. Please.
I grew up gay.
I know what it feels like
when people are staring.
You're missing a
leg, and they stare.
And everyone knows you're
a cheater, and they stare.
And they talk, and they
judge, and they stare.
Like that.
What?
Come on now,
you were telling
a story. I know...
I know how you
must feel about me.
And I know you try and hide
it, but I can see it on your face.
What do you think you see?
You know,
Jesus.
Oh, come on.
Oh, what, I'm
incapable of empathy
because I go to church?
What is that about?
I can empathize like
nobody's business,
especially with a cheater.
You're right. I'm sorry.
Thank you.
I'm sorry for calling
you a cheater.
I am, though.
I know.
She stared at me, too.
But the way she stared
felt really, really good.
You know?
Actually, I do.
And then he
chainsawed his leg off.
But that's not even close to
the strangest thing I've seen.
Though, honestly, I'm not
sure that story is appropriate.
Gentlemen, that story's
gonna have to wait.
Okay, I look forward to it.
I've been watching you. Oh.
Chatting up our donors,
stealing my stories.
You're a thief.
You've been watching
me? Mmm-hmm.
Who are you?
Dr. Emma Marling, maternal-fetal
medicine, Seattle Pres.
After that storm,
we've been hurting, too,
badly.
I've been pushing our board
to throw a fund-raiser for weeks,
and I can't get any
traction. So here I am,
borrowing yours.
I'm not a thief.
You stole my story.
It's a good story.
I don't get this. You are
here to get donations,
and you spend all
this time talking to me.
You want me to say it?
I mean, look at you.
Impressive party.
Another whiskey soda.
That's your fifth one.
Who are you, my
mom? I'm not drinking.
Gotta stay sharp.
This is for the CFO
of AEC Interactive.
Got him on the ropes.
Every drink he knocks back
is another zero
added to the check
I collect at the
end of the night.
That sounds wrong.
Right and wrong
don't live here, son.
This is the Wild West.
This is so much fun!
It's like when we were interns,
stealing surgeries,
playing dirty.
I don't really get
to do that anymore.
Does this look stupid?
The kid spit up on my
dress, and in my dress.
All over, really.
Oh, for the love of God,
Mer. You're making it so easy.
Every night, Harvey would
whisper, "I love you," into my ear
just as I was falling asleep.
It's been 10 years
since, and still,
every night, I feel like
I can hear his voice.
Do you ever feel like that,
like she's still with you?
All right. Can I have
your attention, please?
Oh, speech! Speech!
Everybody, hush up!
Oh, sorry. He's gonna talk now.
Thank you. Good evening, ladies
and gentlemen. I am Dr. Jackson Avery.
And on behalf of the board of
Grey Sloan Memorial Hospital,
I just want to say, "Welcome."
Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you very much.
Now over the past year,
we have seen many changes,
from a change in name
to a change in leadership.
And it has all been a challenge.
But it's been a challenge
that we've all been more
than happy to accept.
Thank you.
As surgeons...
Wait!
Was that part of
it? I don't think so.
Oh, no, no, no!
You need to stop.
You could have internal
injuries or breaks.
Um... I think I'm okay. See?
I'm okay. I'm fine.
Ow!
So, yeah, I'd say
there's a break.
What's the update on
those paramedics, Avery?
Should be here any minute.
No pulse. Okay. Hold
still. This is gonna hurt.
Ready on my count. One, two...
Three!
Do you think he's watching? Who?
Richie Rich. 'Cause we look
freaking amazing right now.
Cristina, gross!
Edwards, someone
better be dying.
I'm really hoping to
avoid that, Dr. Yang.
Ross is doing a pericardial
window in the ER.
Okay, when he
aspirates the fluid,
get him to the
OR. I'm on my way.
- Go. We got this.
- This way, guys.
Where are you going?
Oh, back to the hospital.
Some junkie with
endocarditis is tamponading.
Which junkie?
There's more than one?
- It's all about forgiveness.
- Mmm-hmm.
And that's what's important.
He sees me for who I am.
And he accepts me
for what I've done.
But that's everything.
Are we talking about
Matthew or Jesus?
Dr. Robbins? Yes!
You paged me... Hi.
To a closet? I need you
to run across to the gala
and grab a bottle of champagne
because we're low. We are low.
You want me to steal booze
from the party I wasn't invited to?
And snacks!
Screw this day. ARIZONA:
Uh, thank you, Murphy.
Thank you.
You think Callie's
ever gonna forgive me?
Probably not.
She's telling everybody at
the gala that you're dead.
You know, we're
about ready to roll.
Hey, I'm coming, too.
How are we doing on
our fund-raising goal?
Oh, we're not
even halfway there.
Well, then you've
got plenty to do here.
We're taking them
out of downtown.
I'm worried about
internal injuries.
Make sure they rush
her to CT. All right.
You're not coming?
We're on maternity
leave. We have a deal.
Mer, let's go. We
need all hands on deck.
Let me go!
Let go! Dr. Webber, please!
Dr. Webber... I can
take it from here.
I can take it. Let go!
I don't want this.
There's a man down
the hall. He is ornery.
He's a jackass. He's dying.
And he won't stop fighting,
even though there isn't
anything I can do for him.
And then I've got you.
You've got a million
options, and you refuse to try.
You have atelectasis.
You are in danger for
pneumothorax pneumonia, RDS.
And Meredith Grey is ready
to let you slip into a coma.
But I am not! You
breathe in through this,
your lungs get
stronger, you get better.
It's damn simple math.
What do you wanna do?
This is dumb. Put this on.
No. No.
Richard! Richard!
Get the hell out.
Let's take him off bypass
and see how we did.
Everything okay, Dr. Yang?
Pericardial window is a
pretty risky move for an intern.
I didn't have a choice.
The fluid was too thick
for a pericardiocentesis.
You had a choice.
You could have called someone
the minute he tamponaded,
but you didn't.
You basically got to
do a surgery in the ER.
And now you're up here with me,
while Edwards is down in the pit.
You're a shark.
I'm not! I swear.
Ross, it's a good thing.
All great surgeons are sharks.
You see what you want and
do whatever it takes to get it.
Like me. And never apologize.
Sharks don't apologize.
Monitor. MAN: Here you go.
Where's that coming from?
It's coming from inside. That
means we have two options.
One, we can put him back
on bypass, undo all our work,
and find the source, or,
two, I can take a
guess, throw in a u-stitch
and hope I don't shred
the heart in the process.
Dr. Ross, what do you think?
Sharks don't swim backward.
Only forward. Or they die.
Option two it is. 4-0 Prolene.
Here you go.
There it is.
What's supposed to happen?
If it worked, nothing.
If it didn't, lots.
That'll do, sharky. That'll do.
Murphy, those aren't
for you. Yeah, I know.
Have you seen my wife?
Uh, she, uh, hopped on
a rig with the paramedics.
Damn it.
Hey, Shepherd? Shepherd!
Wilson, where the hell is Karev?
Question of the night!
You know, I should
be at work right now.
You know, Stephanie doesn't
realize how lucky she is.
She should be thanking you
instead of being pissed at you.
Yeah. Wait, what?
She wanted to come
tonight? She bought a dress.
She never said
anything. Of course not.
If she had to say something,
it wouldn't mean as much
as if you'd had the
idea on your own.
Oh, my God. My
head hurts so much.
It doesn't matter now.
The party died the minute
the aerialist fell on Big Bird.
People see a woman's
tibia impale her own foot,
it's hard to steer the
conversation in a different direction.
They're gonna be fine. All right.
There's a hospital right down...
Down the street.
You know what? Ladies and
gentlemen! Folks, wait a second.
Dr. Bailey?
Dr. Bailey, please?
Dr. Stuart to ICU.
What do you need?
I haven't played
chess in a year.
I can't keep having
this fight, Gene.
No, I know. I just...
The guys at the park
stopped letting me play.
'Cause of the things I say.
I'm not trying to offend you.
That's not true.
I said a couple of
those things on purpose.
So, I'm sorry.
You don't have to play
the game, but please.
I'm scared.
I don't have anybody.
I don't want to be alone.
What are you doing?
Repairing a gastric
rupture. It's fun.
You can't just
decide to operate.
Derek, you're better at
charming the donors than I am.
I admit it. You can have it.
We had a deal.
You're more than welcome
to come and join me.
Come get a little
blood on your hands.
I'll even let you
hold a retractor.
All right, I'm gonna change.
Oh, this is really, really
fun, and I needed fun.
Me, too. Yeah.
Oh.
Can I try on your leg?
You said what?
I was cornered by
the Widow Amos,
who was, you know,
actually a widow.
Her story was so sad, and she
took out her checkbook, and I...
Ugh, I'm so gross.
Yeah.
I sort of get it, though.
Really? Mmm. This
stuff, it's not easy.
And Cristina, she keeps
pushing me to date.
God, I can't even
think about that. Yeah.
You really can't keep
telling people that she's dead.
I know.
Doctors, we have visitors.
What is he up to?
I don't know.
Okay, now if you'll notice
the pins that Dr. Torres
is drilling into place,
that is the external fixation
I was telling you about.
Are we allowed to be here?
Yes, I spoke with
Irina's husband.
He said that if there's one
thing that she believes in,
it's that the show must go on.
Now we showed you
guys a circus tonight.
But this, this is the real show.
This is what we do here.
We are gonna get this
woman back on her feet.
And then before you
leave this evening,
I would ask that you please
consider helping us get back on ours.
How much do you need?
Wow!
I usually have really
good radar for this crap.
What are you talking about?
What the hell is this?
Oh, that's not funny.
Don't freaking joke
like that. I don't do that.
I'm just trying to do
a freakin' blood draw.
Why?
I think my dad's
in the hospital.
I don't understand
what that means.
I don't know. I can't...
I haven't seen him in 20 years.
And this guy, some old junkie,
crashed a car, has no
ID, he's ragged, wrecked,
but his voice in the ER,
guy called me Sinatra.
It was like somebody poured
ice water down my neck.
That feeling hasn't gone away.
So this is a paternity test?
I don't know.
No.
I thought I could
live the rest of my life
and never see him again.
I don't want it to be him.
If you take the test,
then you'll know for sure.
If it isn't him, then that
feeling will go away.
I guess that's true.
Mmm-hmm. Yeah.
You know, I'm
actually pretty smart.
You'd know that if
you tried talking to me
instead of ditching
me at fancy parties.
I'm sorry. Yeah.
Okay.
That surgery was incredible.
I haven't felt this
relaxed in months.
Me either.
What? Reminiscing.
About?
You, me, an exam
room, and your panties
pinned to a bulletin board.
Oh, the prom.
Except you didn't
have blood on your suit,
and I wasn't
wearing a sweatshirt.
I think it's sexy.
Now you're doing
the sparkly eye thing.
I have no idea what you're
talking about. Mmm-hmm.
Is it working?
Hey, hey! What's this?
You're getting a roommate.
Gene, Richard. Richard, Gene.
Calm down, Dick.
The way you look, can't imagine
you're gonna be around
much longer anyway.
These are a few
options for facilities
that assist with
end-of-life care.
Since you two are
in the same boat,
figured you could go
through them together.
Crack a window when you go.
Smells like
something died in here.
Jake's in the ICU, should pull
through. How are things down here?
Oh, you know.
Only amazing.
I cannot believe
I was in such a snit over
not going to a stupid party.
I mean, I have done
burr holes, a crike,
and I pulled a hunk of glass
this big out of a dude's face!
You were totally
right. I am a rock star.
You are a rock star.
We are rock stars.
We're not rock
stars. We're sharks.
We're rock sharks!
Hey.
Okay, then.
Jackson!
I heard you were here.
I just wanted to, um,
catch you before you leave.
Here I am.
I like the blue. Oh, thank you.
Oh!
There are more zeroes
than fit in this little box.
Let's get outta here.
To, uh, where?
Come on. Don't be coy.
You like me.
There's no way this
was all about the money.
Oh...
No, it was all about the money.
You flirt with me all night,
get me to write this big check,
and then nothing?
Yeah.
And you don't feel even
a little bit bad about that?
No.
That's actually even hotter.
You have a good night.
It doesn't have to
be all about money.
You could sleep
with me for free.
I have to talk to you.
Look, I don't know what
happened... Oh, would you stop?
I've been here too
many times, honestly.
I'm too old. I'm too busy to
be playing games with you.
I'm not playing games.
You're pissed because I didn't
invite you to this stupid thing,
and now you're getting
back at me with Ross.
That's not true. Oh,
you're not pissed at me?
Yes! I was. Yeah, I was, okay?
You threw a party,
and you didn't invite me.
So, yeah, my feelings
were hurt a little bit.
But that has nothing to do
with what happened in the ER.
Ross kissed me.
I don't know where it came from.
I did not ask for it.
I swear.
Fine.
Fine? Yeah, fine.
And this wasn't a
party. This was work.
Nobody wanted to come.
I never thought you did.
If you and I are gonna do this,
you've gotta
start talking to me.
No more getting mad
and then waiting to
see if I know you're mad
or any of that. Yeah, okay.
I didn't want him to kiss me.
I want you to kiss me.
Look at this.
They got a picture
of a damned rabbit
hopping through a meadow.
Sunshine and daisies
and friggin' bunny rabbits.
Could be worse.
You could die in
that bed, in this room.
This hospital could be
the last place you see.
You don't want to die here.
No. I don't.
It is a pretty lawn.
If I gotta kick, could
be nice to do it outside.
The food's gotta be better
than what they serve here.
I wouldn't feed
that slop to a gypsy.
Mmm.
I said, "I wouldn't."
I was being nice.
Hey! Are you gonna
head back up the street?
Uh, no, I was just heading home.
Listen, I don't blame you for not
wanting to get out there and date.
People are gross.
But we look great. So
you wanna go hit Joe's?
Hey. Hi.
Oh, sorry, am I interrupting?
You're here?
Yeah, I, uh, really, uh, had
a good excuse all worked up,
and now I'm completely blanking.
I was just heading home.
It was really nice to
meet you. You, too.
Good night.
Overture, curtain, lights.
I have the results.
This is it.
The night of nights.
I don't wanna
know. He's your dad.
What?
Oh, my God. I jumped the gun.
I am sorry. I am so sorry.
Alex!
Shotgun! I get
carsick in the back.
Oh!
Ugh, I might get
carsick in the front.
Thank you.
I'm about to take
my intern exam,
which means I am about to
be a second-year resident.
My babysitting days are done.
And I would appreciate,
if moving forward,
you would treat me with
the respect that entails.
You're adorable.
Excuse me.
No more rehearsing
and nursing a part.
We know every part by heart.
Ross, what's going on?
Multi-car mash-up in the ER.
Be a shame to wake the kids.
Tonight, what heights we'll hit.
On with the show.
This is it.
I'm Dr. Grey.