Infections are like
sleeping monsters.
You can't see them.
You can't feel them.
But...
You must do everything
in your power...
To contain them.
Because when the
monsters wake up...
They're out of control.
Hey. Bailey, you
shouldn't be here.
How is Seth Lepik? The
computer says access restricted.
They won't even let me
check on my own patients.
They swabbed my nose.
They're swabbing
everyone's noses.
Well, are they sitting
everybody down for interviews?
'Cause they think I
did something wrong.
Now I think it's the grafts.
I narrowed it down
to... Look, Bailey,
they've isolated the strain
of staph in your patients.
Now they need to
find out how it spread.
- Your job is to cooperate.
- I've got Seth.
Now go answer their questions.
Please.
We are throwing
Bailey under the bus.
Come on. That is
not what we're doing.
Yeah, it seems like that's
exactly what we're doing.
Two of our patients are dead
of the same post-op infection.
A third one's barely
hanging on. It was time.
We get the CDC In here
and figure this thing out.
By treating Bailey
like a criminal?
She hasn't done anything.
I hope that you're right.
The truth is, we
don't know that yet.
CDC is simply asking us to
temporarily freeze Bailey's files.
Oh, come on.
And that we not discuss
this investigation with her.
So today, just
keep your distance.
That is ridiculous.
Also I think now's the
time to put out a statement.
No, no.
No. About what? I
mean, we don't even know
if Bailey's the
source of this thing.
If one of ours is at fault and
we just sit on this information,
we look like we're trying
to cover something up.
The only way to
let the public know
that we can be objective
is by being transparent.
Vote?
I'm just saying, people
should learn the news from us.
There's no news. Okay, vote?
There's no news yet. Vote.
All in favor of
no press release.
Okay. No press release.
No statement. Clear?
Oh!
Watch it, members only.
Promise me you'll be nice.
These guys are trying
to take down Bailey.
They don't deserve nice.
No, not to the CDC. To Jason.
I'm nice to Jason.
Two minutes ago, you said,
"Hey, I have a surgery today
with your d-bag boyfriend."
Yeah, but I said
it with a smile.
Fine. I won't call
the guy a d-bag.
At least not to
his face, anyway.
I'm moving in with him.
So what do you think?
I think it's great. Really?
No. I think the guy
is a douche bag
who you've known
for about two minutes,
and that makes you an
idiot for moving in with him.
Alex... I'll be nice!
I'm gonna rock this corner kick.
Later, I promise. Right
now I have a surprise for you.
Look who's here.
Grandma!
Oh.
Oh, Ethan. Oh, Ethan. Ethan.
As you can see,
there aren't any residual
effects from the surgery.
So, I can go home?
Well, I'd like to keep an eye
on you for another few days.
Well, we can handle
a few more days.
Right, buddy?
Hey, Grandma, do you want
to see Dad? I can take you.
Oh, uh, is that...
Can he? Sure, sure.
He sees his dad every
day. He chats up a storm.
He told him all about
you coming to visit.
Dad's still unconscious. That's
because his brain is resting.
It's not uncommon after a trauma
for a person not to
wake up right away.
You shouldn't have to know
about these things, Ethan.
Well, he does,
and I think it's cool
that he's trying to help Paul
by learning all about his illness.
And speaking of Paul,
I'd like to see him, too.
If that's all right?
Ethan, do you feel up to pushing
your mom around in a wheelchair?
Oh, yeah.
All right. Let me
get one for you.
Oh.
Murphy? I'm not supposed
to talk to you about this.
Dr. Bailey.
Come in.
Tell me there is someone
down here that I can help.
It's five against one
with the board today,
and I need a victory.
Bed three. Femur's broken.
I'm sending him up to angio.
Okay. Alert the press.
See what I mean?
You all right?
Matthew dumped me.
Oh.
Because I lied to him about
my virginity like you told me to.
That's not...
I lied because I had
something to lie about.
April, hold on a
second... You took my...
I shouldn't have let you,
but I did, and now he's gone.
I'm not board certified,
I'm not a virgin,
and everything I care about
has been ruined because of you.
So you know what?
Thank you. Thanks for that.
Six against one.
Help! Yeah, help! We
need some help over here!
Jane, honey, you okay? No!
What happened?
God, I'm gonna pass out.
We lost some
fingers. A lot of fingers.
We had a tug-of-war.
With what, razor wire?
Even better. Clothesline.
Does anybody have
the severed fingers?
Yeah, I got 'em. I got 'em.
Whoa! That's a lot of fingers.
Yeah, I counted six.
No, five. This
one's a turkey dog.
I would like you to take
me through each operation.
Well, I mean, if you're
looking for the source,
look at the grafts.
Okay? I used the same
ones on each patient.
This part of our investigation
concerns your interaction
with the infected patients
in the operating room, to
the best of your memory.
Well... I'd never used
this brand before.
I remember not
recognizing the company.
Dortmund or something.
Dr. Bailey,
we've looked at the
grafts. It's not the grafts.
Uh...
May I begin?
Oh, I was expecting a probing.
That's really more
of a gentle swabbing.
Speaking of probing, I've
decided to have the baby naturally,
but I know the second
I start to scream,
Derek is gonna have
them pump me full of drugs,
so I'm going to need
you there in my corner.
Yeah. Uh, I'm not gonna do that.
When babies come out,
people poop on the table.
Cristina... Uh, no.
Karev. And can you make it fast?
Peckwell's HLHS mom
is gonna be admitted.
We gotta go walk her
through the procedure.
She wants me to
watch her give birth.
You're gonna poop on the table.
I am not.
You are. Almost everybody does.
Okay, so I poop on the table.
It's part of the miracle of life.
It's nasty.
Did I ask you to
watch me give birth?
No.
Cristina?
We have been
friends a long time.
You want to know how?
By not watching each other poop.
Holla.
Well, the good news is,
these wounds look salvageable.
I wasn't even gonna play,
but my brother Al insisted.
And then we were
losing, and Al was all...
"Wrap your hands
with the rope"...
Then I did.
What are you doing?
Uh, I just need to identify
whose fingers are whose.
That looks like a
pretty good match.
Except for the red nail polish.
Yes. That's my sister-in-law's.
Jane, good news.
Your manicure's intact.
Hi, Jane. I'm Dr. Avery.
You mind if I take a look here?
How's my daughter, Frances?
Tony, how's Frankie?
It's bad, honey.
The bone's still sticking out.
This is all Gigantor's fault. What's
he doing at our reunion anyway?
He's not even related.
He's Uncle Tony's weird friend.
I didn't mean to pull so hard.
Lay off Gunnar,
Cash. It's not his fault.
He didn't suggest to play
tug-of-war with a clothesline.
You want to blame
somebody, blame your uncle Al.
Okay, Kellers, I'm back and
I'm armed with French fries.
Huh? Any takers?
We can't eat, Al.
We're just about to get
our fingers reattached.
Okay, uh, anybody
cold? I can find blankets.
Stop, Al! Just stop!
Nobody's hungry or thirsty
or wants to run a relay race!
Reunion's over.
Okay, Frankie. I'm gonna
need to get some x-rays.
You gonna be okay being
away from your family
for a little while?
Yes, please.
Yeah. Okay.
Dr. Hunt says it's
good to talk to him, too.
Hey, babe.
Sorry I haven't been
by to see you, but...
Well, I've been kinda busy
with the brain surgery and all.
Rachel.
Don't. Don't do that.
Don't joke.
I gotta be honest with ya, babe.
You've looked better.
Me? Well...
I haven't looked this
good since that summer
that we went to the river
and I got that stomach bug
and I lost, like, 15 pounds.
You're missing it.
Stop it.
It's not funny.
None of this is funny.
My son is dying.
He's not dying.
We are a long way off from that.
I know that this may
look bad, but you...
It should be me.
Hey, Ethie.
Why don't we give Grandma a
little one-on-one time with Pop?
You want to take me for a spin?
I think that's a great idea.
Go on. Give her the nickel tour.
All right?
Can I hold him after he's born?
Just for a minute.
Uh, he's gonna need
to go right into surgery.
Your baby has hypoplastic
left heart syndrome
and an intact atrial septum
that is causing a
restriction to blood flow.
He's fine when he's in
utero, but once he's out...
The condition is fatal.
Which means he won't
be getting enough oxygen.
We'll let you hold
him when he's stable,
after his surgery. ALEX: Okay.
So we'll do the C-section,
and then we'll have 60
minutes to get him to the cath lab
and perform the operation
to open his septum.
And if you don't make
it in time, he could die?
No, we can do the
C-section in the cath lab.
It'll give us more time.
Deliver in one room
and operate in the other.
Can you do that?
I don't see why not.
There are about
1,000 reasons why not.
You know, people have
babies all over the place.
Taxi cabs, high
school bathrooms.
If we don't have to waste time
moving the kid from
one floor to another,
why should we? Because you
don't do C-sections in Cath labs.
Oh, Karev, back me
up. I'm with Peckwell.
Not my name, but okay.
This whole
situation is high risk.
If something goes wrong,
we don't have the tools
on hand to deal with it.
Are your tools
glued to the floor?
Bring them with you.
Okay, we have an opportunity
here to do something new
and badass.
I mean, don't you
want to be the badass
who delivers the
kid in a cath lab?
Who does that?
Nobody... But you.
Okay.
Okay, I'm in.
All right. Karev,
you with Peckwell?
Myers. Dr. Jason Myers.
Nobody cares. Karev?
All right. I'm good.
Sounds like one
nasty tug-of-war.
It was the height of idiocy,
which is saying a lot for my family.
I'm a journalist.
I cover the sophomore
beat for my school paper.
And they chose me to edit the
spring supplement this weekend,
but my parents told me I had
to go to this stupid reunion,
that it was more important to
pretend not to hate people I hate.
And now my hand is
ruined and my career is over.
Whoa. Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Your hand is
going to be just fine.
I will see to that.
Okay? And...
You have lots of time to
worry about your career.
Okay? Okay.
All right. So do you have
any questions before we start?
Just one. Someone
took my cell phone.
Can I get that back?
Sure. Right after the scan.
And I have a follow-up.
What's the CDC doing here?
Okay, we're gonna lie down now.
Good. All right. Try to
stay still. Try to stay still.
Thank you.
Okay, beginning with Joyce.
Joyce Basche, I placed
an AV graft for hemodialysis.
Take me through that.
I made an incision over the
radial artery and basilic vein...
I'm sorry.
I'm going to ask you to
go back a little further.
Did you scrub?
Did I scrub?
For how long did
you scrub, roughly?
Four minutes, 36
seconds, exactly.
You're sure about that? I am.
I used Think, The
Aretha Franklin song.
I run it in my head. It's
two minutes, 18 seconds.
Hospital protocol is
a four-minute scrub,
so I go through it twice.
And the scrub nurse who handed
you your instruments, that was?
Fran. She was
right across from me.
Well, now the graft is
in place, and you secure.
I did a standard vascular
anastomosis with running prolene.
I checked for leaks.
There were none.
And you closed or Dr. Murphy?
Wait. The doppler.
I confirmed good
flow with the doppler.
Then I closed.
And it went perfectly.
All right. Anything
else you remember?
I remember saying,
"That went perfectly."
All right. Let's move
on to Seth Lepik.
I got this.
What the hell's going on?
These guys won't
tell us anything.
Sir... I want my son outta here.
I want him transferred to
another hospital right now.
I understand. I'll
have to tell you,
moving Seth now would put him
at greater risk for
more complications.
If we're hoping to
avoid another surgery...
You're damn right, we are.
You're not touching
my son again.
See what you can do
to arrange a transfer.
Hey, Myers set up for the
C-section in the cath lab.
We need to run through
the steps of the procedure.
Look at you. "Myers."
You say it like he isn't
nailing your girlfriend.
She's not my girlfriend.
Whatever. You love her.
She's my friend.
You sound stupid
when you say that.
She's moving in with the guy.
What am I supposed to do?
Beat him up.
No. I'm gonna try to be
nice to him and get along
so I don't lose my friend.
Or you could punch him
and take back your girl.
Ouch. I know,
right? And it's a kid.
Listen, I'm gonna
take her up for surgery,
and I was hoping that
you'd want to assist.
Oh, last time I checked, I was
a world-class peds surgeon,
and interns assisted attendings.
They do, it's just...
I want someone
in there I can trust.
You know, I want to
avoid a Bailey situation.
Plus, you're cute
when you irrigate.
Sold.
Oh, the kid's gonna ask
for her phone back. Stall her.
She's gonna tweet about the
investigation. She's a journalist.
For what, like, the Sunshine
Elementary newsletter?
She's, like, nine.
Hi, Frankie.
Hey, have you
found my phone yet?
Uh, not yet. So
this is Dr. Robbins.
She's gonna assist
me in surgery.
Now your hand was
pretty badly crushed
from the trampling, so it's
gonna mean an extensive surgery
to repair these
bones here and here
and fixate these.
Oh, my God.
It's gonna be
okay, though, right?
I mean, she's gonna be able
to, you know, use her hand?
Oh, that's the goal.
Sweetie, I'm gonna go tell
your mom you're gonna be okay.
Okay.
It's worse than
we thought, honey.
All right, so do you have any
questions before we take you up?
No. Okay.
Actually, I do have one.
The CDC is
investigating Dr. Bailey
because several of
her patients died, right?
Um, who told you
about Dr. Bailey?
I asked an orderly. Oh, shoot.
I mean, I can't
reveal my sources.
But you just
confirmed it for me,
so you can be my second
source. Oh, no, I didn't.
That's Dr. Robbins? Hey!
What are you doing?
Checking Bailey's post-ops.
I thought Richard was
taking care of Bailey's patients.
Just Seth Lepik, the
infected guy. I took the rest.
Bailey's patients are
all turning up with staph.
You're pregnant.
Why take the risk?
Because I'm
looking out for Bailey.
And I'm trying to
look out for you.
This is why I need
Cristina in the room.
What room? The delivery room.
Wait. What?
Hey. Hey, hey, hey.
On-call room, you and me?
Oh, I wish.
Uh, but I have an atrial
septostomy with Karev.
But after I save a baby's life,
I'm gonna need to celebrate.
Okay. Well, find me.
Oh, how is the grandma?
Uh, she's sweet, but useless.
Rachel's doing better, though,
so at least Ethan's got her.
Paul's gonna wake up.
I've been doing serial neuro
exams. I have a good feeling.
Spoken like a true scientist.
Thank you.
Thank you for
having a good feeling.
Anytime.
Oh, Mer asked me to be at her
birth and watch her poop on a table.
You have to do that.
Can't I just show up after when
everyone has control of their bowels?
Watching a baby be born
is like seeing God in person.
Spoken like a true scientist.
I used
scissors to shorten
the graft to fit.
Took about a centimeter off.
I remember, Mr. Lepik
had deep vessels.
Uh, so I asked Fran
for more retraction.
I'm sorry. Fran?
You named Linda
as your scrub nurse
on Mr. Lepik's surgery.
Yes. Yes, right. Sorry. Um...
Then I finished the
graft, and I closed.
Well, what about the leak?
According to Mr. Lepik's chart,
there was a small
leak on the venous side.
Yes. Lepik.
Yes. Uh, he had a leak.
Um, and I put in
an interrupted stitch.
You remember that?
Yes, I remember.
I irrigated with
antibiotic solution
to avoid infection,
then I closed.
You closed? That's important.
I did. I closed.
You're sure? Because your...
Did you put the cap
on the toothpaste?
Sorry?
I assumed you brushed
your teeth this morning.
So did you put the cap back
on the toothpaste or didn't you?
Or can you be sure?
Because when you do a
thing every single day...
Dr. Bailey, we're talking
about the lives of two people.
What, you don't
think I know that?
Don't insult me. These
are my patients who died.
You think I don't know
that far, far better than you?
So again, uh, are
you sure you closed?
Could I take a break, please?
There's only a
little more to, uh...
Do.
Dr. Reynolds to ICU.
Hey. Is your interview over?
We're on a break. Wait. Wait.
Aren't you supposed to be
avoiding me like the plague?
Come on. What can I do to help?
Anything?
I just want to know
how Seth Lepik is.
I'd like to see his chart, but
they locked me out of the system.
Dr. Grey.
She wants to check
on her patients.
What do you think she's
gonna do, alter their charts?
That's what the CDC
is gonna think, yes.
Well, maybe you
called them too soon.
I am thinking of the
bigger picture here.
She's part of that picture.
We need to stand by our doctors.
Even if she's at fault? We
stand by her then? She's not.
But we should cross that
bridge when we get to it.
We're kind of at that bridge.
Uh, excuse me, Dr. Avery?
Yes. Sorry to bug you,
but I was just kind
of wondering, is there
any update on my family...
Or their fingers?
Mom? Mom! Somebody help my mom!
What's wrong? Mom?
She needs some help. Uh, ma'am?
Hey, what's your
mom's name? Rachel.
Dr. Bailey, step away
from the patient, now.
Okay, let's clear the
wheelchair and the tables.
I got it. Make room.
Okay, lay her down.
All right. All right.
Call a code. MAN: Right away.
Mom! Page Dr. Shepherd, stat.
Yes, doctor.
Okay, Amelie, here we go.
Scalpel.
It's gonna be okay, honey.
But what if it's not?
Shh.
No! Stop.
I can't do this.
Not right now.
His heart is okay now.
And you all know that
when he comes out,
it's going to stop working.
I'm not ready for him to die.
Amelie, honey... No.
Look at me. Look in my eyes.
You have to do this.
Your baby's life depends on
it, and you are wasting time.
We're all here.
We're all doing our best
to save your baby's life.
Breathe with me.
Okay. One more
time. One more time.
You can do this.
Right?
Right.
She's ready.
Just confirm what I have so far.
There's some
kind of an infection
going on in the hospital
linked to Dr. Bailey.
You don't even
have to say anything.
You can just nod if I'm close.
Let it go, Woodward.
Who's Woodward?
Uh, you should know that.
You should give
me back my phone.
You're denying my
second amendment right.
Wait. You want a gun now?
Duh. First. I meant first
amendment, obviously.
Look, there's this
girl named KK.
Who wrote an article
about some bird
that everyone
thought was extinct
living in her backyard.
It got picked up by the AP, and
now she's a stringer for the Times.
This is a real story.
I mean, I have an opportunity
here to be awesome.
Why don't you count
backwards from ten?
Mmm-hmm. Okay?
Ten...
Nine...
You're obstructing
the free press.
What's after nine?
Eight...
Seven...
What are we gonna
do when she wakes up,
roll her up in a rug and
stick her in the trunk of a car?
Is he okay? Is he alive?
He's beautiful.
Thank you.
I got him.
Please save my baby!
Let's move, people.
Coming through. Clear
the way! Shepherd?
Her pupil's blown.
She's re-hemorrhaged.
I need to get her to an OR.
What the hell happened?
I'll let you know when I know.
Okay, let's go. MAN:
Check her pressure.
I'll see you up there.
Hey. Hey.
She's gonna be okay.
We've got her and we're
gonna take care of you.
Hey, hey. Room 10-24.
She's gonna take
you to your grandma.
Wait for me there.
Come on. This way.
What is it?
He's dropped his pressure. I can't
hear breath sounds on the right.
Okay, run fluids wide open.
Get me a chest tube tray, fast.
Right away, Doctor.
In the vena cava.
What is the oxygen saturation?
Thirty-five.
Inside the right atrium.
Nobody move. Nobody breathe.
Oh, Seth.
Oh, dear God.
Chest tube, now.
Hold on.
Perforating the septum.
Why isn't the blood
going through?
Because I'm not through.
Just give me a minute.
Now I'm through.
Man, I'm good.
So my mom's dead?
Yes.
But Dr. Shepherd said she
was getting better this morning.
Yes, but there was something
going on in her brain that was...
Sudden and
couldn't be prevented.
There was no way of knowing
that this was going to happen.
Could it have been the ice
cream? Like a brain freeze?
No. No.
Ethan...
There was nothing anyone could
have done to have stopped this.
Well, I need to go
now to my grandma.
She needs someone
to hold her hand.
I'm so sorry.
All right, Deedee and Jane's
surgeries both went very well.
They'll be in recovery soon.
Cash is still in surgery, and
Dr. Torres is in with Frankie now.
Her fractures were complicated,
but hopefully, with therapy,
she'll regain full use of her hand.
Therapy?
How much therapy?
Well, that's hard
to say now, Tony.
But it could be anywhere
from six months to a year.
You hear that?
A year of physical therapy, Al.
And then she might
get full use back. Might.
Well...
Let's look at the
bright side now...
The bright side?
Everyone is mangled.
Well, not Frankie.
She got lucky.
She's still got all
her digits, Tone.
Her hand was crushed!
I know. It's horrible.
I know it. And...
And I'm sorry, but, hey, well...
We're all here for you. And
that's why we're a family, right...
For stuff like this?
Hey. Come on, huh?
Mr. Keller.
Let me get a look
here. You all right?
I think I broke my hand.
He's not stabilizing. He
needs surgery immediately.
No, not in this cesspool.
An ambulance is coming for him.
No, he's too
unstable to transfer.
I'm canceling all...
You guys have some
infection running rampant.
It's not safe.
It's not the hospital.
It's one doctor.
The infection came from one
doctor and one doctor alone.
She's been isolated and the
infection has been contained.
I've been tested. I'm clean. The
OR has been tested. It's clean.
If we don't go right now,
your son's gonna die.
Do what you have to.
Save my son.
You cleared to scrub in?
Yes, sir. They cleared
me this morning.
Okay, prep him.
So Bailey did do
something wrong.
Of course not. I only said
that to get their kid into surgery,
and if you repeat it,
I'll have your ass fired
before you finish
talking, you understand?
Dr. Rizzo to the ER.
Baby's looking good.
Heart function's
hypokinetic but improving.
Yang says that's to be expected.
That Yang's a piece of work.
Yeah. Well, try living with her.
Listen, man, I appreciate
your work today.
I think this thing with Jo
got us off on a bad foot.
She cares a lot about you.
We're friends. That's all.
All right. All right.
I had a messed-up
childhood, too.
I was a foster kid
like her. It was crappy.
But I didn't have it
near as bad as Jo did.
I was never homeless,
never had to live in my car.
But she's really turned
it around for herself.
And I just...
I want the best for her, is all.
Yeah, okay.
Yeah. Thanks for today.
Every year, it keeps on getting
harder and harder
to plan these things
and to get everyone to come.
Why do it?
It doesn't seem like
they appreciate it much.
They're all that I have.
I almost got married a few
times, but I always messed it up.
My family is Tony and Jane
and Deedee and Cash and...
Everybody else out there.
And I'm just meant to be...
Annoying uncle Al.
Well, you'll think of
something for next year.
I mean, you just gotta...
Just gotta keep trying.
Do I have the staph strain?
I'd like to start again
with Seth Lepik, please.
I made a small
transverse incision,
minimal blood loss.
I deepened the incision
into the subcutaneous tissue,
asked for retraction.
BP was good. All
vitals were good.
BP's 90 over 60 and falling.
- More laps.
- There you go.
Suction. MIRANDA:
You tested me for staph.
Can I get those results, please?
There was a leak
on the venous side?
There was a leak on the
venous side, a little blood loss.
But very little.
Now just can you get
me my results, please?
Come on. More.
More. Pile 'em in.
Yes, doctor. Look, I gotta
try and find it. Hold on.
More suction.
Just again, I'd like you
to take me through...
Okay, I can take you
through my scrub technique
and how I hold my instruments.
But the only thing
you need to know
is do I have this
staph infection.
You should know that by now.
More lap pads. More.
Okay, more suction. Right there.
Come on.
Other doctors have been cleared.
So why am I going through this?
Just go down there
and get my results.
You have my results?
You have my results,
and I...
Have this strain of staph?
Did I do this?
I did...
Didn't I?
I'll be there in the room
when fetus arrives. You will?
Yeah. You're gonna
want me there.
Okay.
You're gonna poop
on the table, though.
And I'm gonna have to see it,
and then I can never unsee it.
You know what's worse than
you seeing me poop on the table?
What? Me knowing you've
seen me poop on the table.
So you'll suffer
more than me. Yes!
Oh, okay. That
makes me feel better.
Hey. Hey.
I'm sorry. I heard
about Paul's wife.
Yeah. I appreciate that.
Are you angry with me?
No. No. I just...
I'm angry at the situation.
Okay, well, you
know, after this,
let's just go home, and then
I can make some dinner...
No, I'm gonna stay.
I'm gonna stay just in case
Paul's condition changes
or if the kid needs...
You know, I just... I just
don't feel like I can leave,
you know?
I mean...
What would you do?
I would go home,
because I'm his
doctor, not his family.
Yeah.
I'm gonna stay.
Okay. I understand.
Come to see your
boyfriend's miracle baby?
Why did you tell him that? What?
That I'm a homeless dumpster
diver. I don't tell anyone.
You don't tell people about me.
You told me... Yeah,
it's called a secret, Alex.
It's what friends
tell each other.
Look, what's the
deal? What did he say?
Why'd I tell you? So stupid.
What is the point of a new start
if there's always some dumbass
dragging you back down?
Whoa, whoa. Listen.
No, you listen.
You don't tell people about me.
You don't talk about
me or to me, ever.
Our investigation has
determined the presence
of methicillin-resistant
staphylococcus aureus usa600.
Bailey...
Oh, Dr. Bailey, you should
not be here right now.
This is about me.
I'd like to hear it.
That's your call.
We have a protocol for a reason.
Okay, we vote.
She stays.
Staph aureus usa600 is an
antibiotic-resistant infection
with a range of symptoms
from simple skin rashes
to fatal sepsis.
We have traced the source
of the infection to one doctor.
Dr. Miranda Bailey
is a carrier of mrsa usa600.
But the real culprit
here is the gloves.
Records show the
surgical gloves in use
at the time of
outbreak, March 15,
shipped from the manufacturer
Hemming Synthetics Incorporated.
We switched to Hemming's
gloves when Pegasus was here.
Our testing reveals
manufacturing defects.
Microscopic tears in the
gloves, which facilitated
the transmission of staph usa600
to Dr. Bailey's patients.
It is the CDC's determination,
were it not for the
defective gloves,
the patients in question
would not have been infected.
As for Dr. Bailey, we
recommend eradication measures
before she can go back
to any kind of patient care.
All right. Thank God.
Best possible outcome.
Here are copies of our report.
The CDC thanks you for
your time and cooperation.
And please...
Feel free to call my office
if you have any questions.
Thank you.
You've harmonized
now. Drink it all.
You seem more like
the French cinema type.
I'm just a teenager.
Mmm-hmm.
What's this?
It's a press release.
We're putting it
out in the morning,
which means you have 12
hours to scoop the Times.
Or the AP. Or whatever.
Hey.
Be awesome.
Wait. I have a question.
One.
And I have a follow-up.
Turns out Bailey wasn't
at fault. Defective gloves.
I heard. That's great.
Yeah.
You know what?
I spent my entire day getting
treated like the bad guy here.
I'm not gonna do
this with you anymore.
You want to feel guilty
about what we did? Go ahead.
Just leave me out of it.
I didn't force you
to do anything.
I'm sorry that
you're hurt. Okay?
I'm sorry that Matthew
broke up with you.
As far as us sleeping together,
I'm never gonna
be sorry about that.
April?
Anyway. Good night.
I'm sorry.
What? No.
No, no. I am sorry.
You have nothing
to be sorry about.
No, you made a mistake
and you asked for a do-over.
Well, I made a mistake, too.
I was hurt and I
acted like an idiot.
I was hoping...
You could forgive me,
that I could have a do-over.
Yes.
It could have happened
to any one of us, Bailey.
We'll get you treated,
get you cleared...
I killed two patients. No.
You didn't know.
You scrubbed
properly, you gloved...
How's Seth Lepik?
I lost him.
The infection formed
an abscess that...
Eroded into his innominate vein.
I'm so sorry.
Bailey, how can I...
No! Now you want to help me?
Where were you when
my patient was alive,
when I could've helped him?
You shut me out. You left me.
Bailey, I was trying to
protect you. That's all.
No, no, the hospital.
You were trying to
protect the hospital.
It's all that matters to you.
And I don't know
why I'm so surprised.
Adele complained about
that every time I saw her.
And I protected you.
I made excuses to her for you.
I stood by you. Bailey.
No, you were a drunk.
You were operating
on your patients drunk,
and I stood by you.
I expected the same from you.
I deserved it. I earned it.
But all you cared about...
No.
You...
Are not who I thought you were.
But I am going to be in there.
I know. You'll be
looking into my eyes
and holding my hand
and feeding me ice chips,
and that's just where
I want you, just there.
Cristina can run interference
and handle the bossy nurses,
and if I decide I want drugs...
Fine. Whatever you want.
Or if I poop on the table...
If you what?
All that time you spent
convincing yourself
the sleeping
monster wasn't real...
Yeah.
It was gathering strength.
Oh, crap. It's you.
The infection was spreading.
What's the matter?
You were right... About Jo.
Of course I was.
What did I say again?
Forget it.
Oh, Alex.
I'm such an idiot.
I love her.
What?
Just...
You're weird.
Give it a minute.
It's just...
She just...
But I always screw myself
out of everything good.
I think I'm losing Owen.
What?
Not today, but...
Soon.
The monster's awake now.
And there's nothing
you can do about it.