What are you doing?
I'm sorry, lover.
Did I wake you?
No. I just... I didn't know
that you were still here.
I can't figure out these locks.
No, don't-don't do
that. Let me, let me...
Thanks.
Hey, hey, hey, here.
You're not driving, are you?
Oh, is that an
invitation to stay?
No. I'll call you a cab.
Leave my car all
the way over here?
No. I swear, Officer,
I can walk the line and
I can touch my nose.
You can pick up
your car whenever.
If you want me to drink
a pot of coffee, I can...
I'll drive you.
Hang on.
Well...
Well, gee, they
say chivalry's dead.
Good morning, boys.
It's not good. It's
not even morning.
I brought doughnuts.
You guys catch
the game last night?
You're kidding, right?
Conway went 70
yards for the touchdown.
It was mayhem.
Somebody remind me
again why I picked surgery.
For a scut zombie, Carter,
you're looking very crisp.
Yeah, that's part of the
joy of moving back home.
Reina insists on
using the extra starch.
Reina? The maid?
I haven't had time to breathe,
let alone look for
another apartment.
My place burned down.
I've been living
out of a suitcase.
A Louis Vuitton suitcase.
You might want to dress down
for the plumbing accident in Two.
He's very stinky.
Thanks for the carbs.
Yo.
Hey, your parents live
out in Oakbrook, huh?
Oh, don't start.
Oh, no, no, no. I'm just saying.
I got an extra bed in my place.
It's two minutes away.
Got all the Cup O'
Ramen you can eat.
And best of all, you
don't have to worry
about the help
overstarching your shirts.
Are you serious?
It's time to leave the nest.
That's great. Thanks.
Okay. I'll see you at
the firm conference.
Firm conference?
That's not next week?
Pancreatectomy lecture?
Presented by Dr. Peter Benton,
assisted by John
Carter? Oh, my God.
Benton's slides were
in the fire. They're toast.
Why couldn't I just have
been home at the time?
I could've had smoke inhalation.
I could be sucking air
through a nice ET tube.
Where's the fire?
I'm just trying to
get back to bed.
Me, too.
Oh, damn it.
I forgot my watch
and stuff at your place.
Can we go back, please?
You know what? I'll...
I'll send it to you, okay?
Oh! Do you mind?
I have a headache.
I'm not surprised.
All right. Come on. I'm
not in the mood, all right?
Don't, don't, don't,
don't, don't, don't, don't.
Just don't mess around
with me right now, okay?
If you're going to throw up,
just roll down the window there.
Lean out of the window.
You all right? Hey...
Hey, hey, hey! Are you...?
Hey!
Hang on... Hang on!
Have a doughnut if you want one.
Oh, no, thanks.
Weaver's looking for you.
Yeah, it takes a while
to get in from "D" lot.
Did you get your
car back yet? I will.
I need some help
here! She's in status!
I don't know if she's epileptic
or it's what she drank.
What was she drinking? How much?
Vodka and tequila shots.
Give me four migs of
Ativan and an amp of D-50.
Doyle, clear Trauma Two!
What have you got?
Tonic-clonic seizure.
Need a CBC, Chem 20,
blood glucose, tox screen
and a blood alcohol.
Where'd she come from?
Get me a blood gas kit, too.
Where'd you find her, Doug?
My house. What's her name?
I don't know.
70/40. Pressure's
still dropping.
Keep the fluids wide open.
Temp's up to 105.
This seizing's burning her up.
Get some cooling blankets
in here before her brain fries.
Morning, folks. What's the word?
We've got a Jane Doe in status.
We're about to
put her in a coma.
Load her up with Dilantin?
Maxed out on the Benzos.
History?
Came in 30 minutes ago.
Seizure history unknown.
Meds unknown.
Could it be meningitis?
Doug seems to think
she's been drinking.
Thought you
weren't on till noon.
I'm not. She's with me.
Temp's 106.2.
She's hyperthermic.
Doyle, alert Neuro
and Anesthesiology.
Bring in a two-channel EEG.
Done.
We need a loading
dose of pentobarbital,
100 milligrams over two minutes
and an intubation tray.
Jumping the gun
now, aren't you, Kerry?
She's been seizing
for a half hour, Doug.
You have a better suggestion?
Mark...
Her blood gas is back.
PH is 7.1.
She's acidotic.
Let's put her in a coma.
Kerry, you want to
help me intubate?
Okay.
7.5 ET tube.
Let me go to the car,
find the registration,
see if I can get some
kind of an ID or something.
Another modification
to the system will be
a return to professionalism.
We're surgeons.
Let's look like it.
From here on
out, I'm instituting
a jacket-and-tie
policy for all surgeons
outside the OR.
Except, of course,
for the ladies on staff,
who I trust will
dress appropriately.
As I was saying...
Well, so much for
the dos and don'ts.
Oh, I would like to
remind everybody
that we're still woefully short
on surgical volunteers for...
Pancreatic versus
local procedures...
Carter, you're late.
I had to set up the projector.
I know, but I
want to talk to you.
Look, you can run a
projector, can't you?
Yeah, I can, but... Right,
aw, damn, it's starting.
Will be presenting
a fascinating paper
on total pancreatectomy
versus the Whipple procedure
in the palliative treatment
of pancreatic carcinoma.
Dr. Benton.
Thank you, Dr. Anspaugh.
I'm going to be talking
today about, uh...
the use of the Whipple procedure
in lieu of total pancreatectomy,
which is, I guess, what
Dr. Anspaugh just said.
Lights, please?
Uh...
Pancreatectomy removes...
the potential for recurrence
due to multifocal disease
and avoids
pancreatico-jejunostomy.
Now, uh, uh, slide, please?
If you observe here, the
attendant risk of leakage
is... the...
Path slide one, please?
That's... that's what I
was trying to tell you.
What were you trying to tell me?
Maybe I could speak to
you alone for a moment.
Is there a problem, Dr. Benton?
Oh, no, no, Dr. Anspaugh.
No, not at all.
Carter, put in the damn slide.
I can't. My apartment
burned down.
I lost the pathology slides.
The tables?
And the operative
photographs?
Those, too.
Looks like she's stabilizing.
No spikes. That's more like it.
All right, I'm going
to check with Neuro,
see what's keeping them.
Uh, could I have a minute?
Sure.
What's up?
In, uh, all the commotion,
I wasn't sure if you remembered
that today we start
our pilot study...
Th-the medical-surgical
division of duties.
All right, that's
where one attending
gets all the real emergencies
and the other hands
out aspirin and antacid?
Well, actually, one
takes the medical cases
one takes the surgical.
You wanted surgical when
we discussed it before.
No, I wanted neither
when we discussed it before
'cause I think it's a bad idea.
Well, Dr. Anspaugh approved it,
and since you just walked
in and effectively took over
this seizure patient,
perhaps you...
Okay, fine. Why don't you
take surgical, I'll take medical.
She's seizing!
She's all yours. Report to him.
All right, looks like you and I
are going to be handling
all the medical cases today.
Only medical?
That's the grand plan.
Thought she was stabilized.
Okay. Uh, six of Pavulon.
We going to paralyze her?
Yes. And do you know why?
'Cause it's her only chance?
That's right.
Hey, girl. Hey.
You missed all the drama.
Dr. Ross brought
a lady in in status.
Oh, yeah?
You okay?
Yeah. It's just autumn.
You know, my allergies go crazy.
Dr. Benton
I just want to apologize again
for the slides.
Did you replace them?
Not yet. Well, get busy.
Dr. Anspaugh was kind enough
to reschedule the lecture
for tomorrow morning.
Tomorrow? Is there a chance...
Bye-bye, Carter.
Oh, the infamous Dr. Carter.
We haven't been introduced.
I'm Abby Keaton.
Pleased to meet you!
Uh, this morning
was totally my fault.
Oh, it was a godsend.
May-may I join you?
Oh, yeah, please.
No offense, Peter...
Oh, thank you.
No offense.
I love a nice, juicy gut lecture
but your intern bought
me an extra half hour
for my dictations.
So...
what did you think of
Laura-Lee, Dr. Carter?
Who?
Does Dr. Benton
keep you so busy
running the projector
that you don't have time
to follow up on cases?
Uh, the, uh, film
showed a, uh...
dilated cecum, and
she's at risk of perfing.
She's in 203.
Why don't you two go
down, meet her, answer
her mother's questions and
then bring her on up to the OR?
Oh, you know, uh,
I can do it myself.
Hmm. Bring Dr. Carter along.
I guarantee, it'll be a
real learning experience.
Excuse me, ambulance zone. Sir?
Oh, good morning, Dr. Ross.
Would you mind moving
the car, sir, please?
Yeah.
Sir?
Yep.
Thank you.
How's Dr. Ross's friend?
"Friend" may be overstating it.
You know, I don't think
it's any of our business.
Her name is Nadine Wilkes.
Doug, Doug...
She's dead.
I thought you'd gone home.
My shift starts in five minutes.
Why would I go home?
I just thought
you wouldn't be up
for working today.
I feel bad for what
happened to her.
But if you are in
some way suggesting
that I am responsible...
No. I just thought
maybe you were upset.
I guess not.
I'm confused, Mark.
Does it come as
a big shock to you
that I was intimate with someone
who I've been less
than soul mates with?
Doug, you didn't
even know her name.
Tox screen came back.
Did you know she tested
positive for cocaine?
No. I mean, do...
You think I would
have withheld that?
I hope not.
That's right. No.
You were together all night.
She tested positive.
You think that I did cocaine?
Is that what you
were really asking me?
Should I ask? You want a sample?
You want me to piss
in that mug right now?
Will that satisfy you?
Use a specimen cup.
You want to watch?
Just send it to the lab.
Mark, we've got a three-year-old
went on a bender with a
bottle of dandruff shampoo.
You want me to wait for Doug?
No. I'll handle it.
Mark, Doug lives his own life.
Yeah, that's kind
of the problem.
I-I'm just saying, we
can't live it for him.
Dr. Benton, I think
Dr. Keaton was inviting me
to do the colostomy with you.
Well, that's because
Dr. Keaton doesn't know
how busy you're going to be
at the photo lab this afternoon.
Screw you! You can't make me!
Get out of my way!
Excuse me, I'm Doctor Benton.
Just tell her I'm out of here!
I'm afraid that's impossible.
Look, you're scheduled for a
major operation in 15 minutes.
The hell I am! I'm gone!
Laura.
Look, hold on. What is this?
Huh? What, do you
want to die, is that it?
I'd make a real
good-looking corpse.
I'd want to die, too.
Yeah, well, you're gonna if
you don't get out of my way!
I'm just saying that if I
went to Proviso West,
I'd rather be six feet under
before a championship game.
We're semi-finalists
this year, lame-o.
Ha! Last time I checked,
you had a semi-backfield.
You should start some
of your cheerleaders.
They look tough enough.
Okay, okay, Mom,
okay, Doc Magoo's, 5:00.
No disrespect, E-Ray, but I
was looking for a welding class.
I can't really see
myself in genie pants.
It's a simple means to
stress reduction and serenity.
Oh, God, whatever
it is, sign me up.
What, you couldn't
get her to cancel?
Nope. Something's on her mind.
You'd really be interested
in my yoga class,
Nurse Hathaway?
Is there a mantra
that will get me
through my dinner
with my mom tonight?
There is. You'd have to take
my intro class in preparation.
8:00 p.m., Thursday nights,
Malcolm X Community College.
What's my old alma
mater coming to?
You went to Malcolm X?
My first year.
Hey, they've got a very
prestigious premed night school.
Wait a minute.
Wait. See there?
Bio one, organic chemistry,
physics, all your basics.
You got a problem with that?
Hey, Jerry.
Hey, Dr. Ross, we got a
12-year-old GSW coming in.
All right. Put
this in Mark's box
and make sure he sees it, okay?
Carol, do you know if
anybody's run a search
for Nadine Wilkes'
medical records?
Well, Connie
tried to pull her up
but she's never
been a patient here.
We ought to try countywide.
See if she's had any
previous admissions.
Well, don't you think
the autopsy will reveal
any preexisting conditions?
Probably, but it's worth
a shot. Don't you think?
Sure. If you need any help,
E-Ray can do the search.
Dr. Ross, that
gunshot wound is in.
12-Year-old GSW to the chest.
Jerry, clear Trauma one.
Pulse thready and weak.
Got any ID?
His street name's Shamrock.
Usually, he's on the
other side of the piece,
but the owner of the place
was a little faster on the draw.
Oh, God, he looks like a baby.
Wait till you talk to the cops.
It's either the protease
inhibitor or the AZT
that's making me nauseous.
I'm not sure which.
No, I understand.
I haven't missed any doses.
Thanks, Dr. Angelo.
I'd appreciate it.
Okay, bye.
Hi. What's up?
Take the ankle fracture in two.
Okay. I'm buried.
You won't have any trouble
finding a nurse to assist.
You okay?
Short stick gets it.
Who's free to help me
with an ankle splint?
We'll tell you in a second.
Damn.
I thought you were engaged.
Shoot. I might be
engaged, but I ain't dead.
A behind like that could
bring me back from the dead.
Oh, yes! I'll send
you a postcard.
Two out of three?
What's so great about Exam Two?
You take Dennis
Quaid, Robert Redford
and James Dean,
put them in a blender,
you got Exam Two.
Mr. McKenna?
Hi. I'm Jeanie Boulet.
I hear you have
an ankle fracture.
Yeah. I was welding a
girder up on the ninth floor
of that new office
building on Addison.
Wendy? Wendy? Wendy. Splint.
Right.
Lost my footing,
my ankle went snap.
If it hadn't been for
Mickey's fast catch,
I'd have been a goner.
You up for one more
good deed, Mickey?
Sure.
Okay, I need you to hold his
foot steady at a 90-degree angle
and we're going
to splint it, okay?
Ahh! Ahh!
How's that?
Perfect.
What about the food
poisoning in Three?
Didn't I already see that one?
That was diarrhea.
Take the food poisoning, Two;
compazine, clear liquids, etc.
I'm down.
Let me know as
soon as he's back.
Mark, could we talk?
Sure.
I heard Nadine
Wilkes' tox screen
was positive for coke.
That's right.
And Doug Ross is working today?
It's been taken care of.
I know Doug is your friend,
but I'm attending
on this shift, as well.
He got a tox screen.
It came back negative.
Yeah, well, how about
his blood alcohol?
He's fine.
Good, 'cause he's
putting a chest tube
in a 12-year-old right now.
He may need some help.
Good idea.
Tension pneumo.
I'm going to
decompress. 14-gauge.
He's cyanotic.
Any ID?
No, but his prints are on file.
Cops were right behind me.
Vitals are improving.
28 French.
Thought you might
need an assist.
Nope. We've got
it under control.
I'll just stay and watch.
Okay.
O-silk. I'm in.
Hook it up.
Hey, Carol, what's
the hourly rate
for baby-sitting
these days?
Well, I am amazed, Peter.
I thought you'd need backup.
Yeah, well, it wasn't easy.
I know. I've gone a
few rounds with Laura.
But you didn't have
to call in the cavalry.
I am impressed.
It was fine.
You know, actually,
Carter was very helpful
in breaking the ice.
She's got a couple of
more questions for you.
Dr. Carter,
how would you like
to scrub in with us?
Unless Dr. Benton
needs you elsewhere.
When I was a kid,
we just boosted a
couple of bags of chips.
Now they want the whole store.
Grab a cup of coffee?
I should probably stay close,
Yeah. keep an eye on his crit.
Pardon me. Are you Dr. Ross?
Yeah. Listen,
that kid... he's out.
He's going to be out
for a couple of hours.
Actually, Doctor,
we want to speak to
you about Nadine Wilkes.
Okay, fine.
Uh...
Let's go back here.
There's a room back here.
Excuse me.
When did her medical
condition first come on?
Uh... she started
seizing around 6:00 a.m.
And she died at 7:34?
That's about right, 7:34.
Oh, sorry. I didn't
mean to interrupt.
Someone said you
wanted to see me.
We'll be out in a minute, Mark.
Are you Mark Greene?
Attending physician?
That's right.
Pronounced Nadine Wilkes?
I did.
Why don't you stick around okay?
We got a couple questions
we'd like to ask you, too.
So no idea at all
about next of kin?
No. I told you, we'd just met.
Last call, Roarke's
bar. I got that.
Hmm.
What?
Roarke's bar.
Kind of a hinky crowd.
But, at this joint, or later on,
when she went
back to your place,
you never saw
her take any drugs?
No. We, uh...
she went to the bathroom
a couple of times.
In between?
Mm-hmm.
And at no time did she ask you
to write her a prescription? No.
You didn't give her
just a little something
No. to help her make
it through the night?
You're not that kind of guy?
No.
Okay.
Can we speak to
you outside, please?
As you can see, in a 16-year-old
the organs are identical
to those of an adult.
In a neonate, on the other hand,
you've got a liver
as big as Kansas.
Needle-holder.
Boy, you could do this
with your eyes closed.
So, John, tell me how you
got Laura-Lee into the O.R.
without hired
muscle or sedatives.
Uh... gym pass.
Gym pass?
Yeah.
Locker rooms can be tough
enough without an ostomy bag.
Kids are vicious.
And I am a doctor.
So you wrote her
a pass out of gym?
Yeah, and told her
that she probably wouldn't have
the bag by championship game.
And that's in...?
November. Late November.
Mm-hmm.
She's in the...
I hope I didn't, uh, put...
No. With any luck,
she should make it.
Hi. Oh, hi.
I'm afraid Ortho's
still backed up.
It could be a couple
of more hours.
Mr. Mckenna wanted me to
tell you he's going to take a cab.
He doesn't want you
to miss your class.
Thanks, Miss
Boulet, but I can wait.
Anyone hungry?
More pudding.
They said County's unfriendly.
You look like you're
being taken care of.
So, um, what kind of
class are you taking?
Uh... I sort of moonlight
as a dance instructor.
Oh, what type of dancing?
Well, all types,
but country, mostly.
Like line dancing.
Oh, there's more
to country than that.
Why don't you show us
a few moves, cowboy?
Here?
Why not?
Um... no music.
We can fix that.
So, the good news
is you're not pregnant.
Can you understand me?
Yeah. It's good.
But now we have
to do a pelvic exam
to find out why
you're having pain.
You do the exam?
No. A doctor's going to
come and do the exam,
but he's very good.
No, no, no. I don't need.
I'm fine. Not pregnant.
Okay.
All right, Miss Jung Koo Bek.
What seems to be the problem?
No problem. I could go home now.
Doctor, can I talk
to you outside?
Sure.
You just sit tight.
I'll be right back.
We'll be right back.
This girl's 15 years old.
One sexual experience,
two months ago.
Abdominal pain, fever's 101.
She complains of
vaginal discharge.
She's not pregnant.
Sounds like PID.
I'll give her a pelvic.
Well, she's a little jumpy.
She's never had a pelvic.
I don't think she's
seen many doctors.
I think I can handle that.
I'm afraid she's going to bolt,
but she'd probably let me
take the cultures.
So you're second-guessing
me, too, now, right?
No, Doug. I don't
give a damn about you.
I'm trying to take
care of a patient.
Whoa-whoa. What's up?
Nothing. Carol just thinks
that she's better suited
to perform a pelvic without me.
Carol, you know that...
I just want to take the swabs.
At least diagnose her for PID.
She's really afraid of men.
Doyle, you free?
Almost.
Mark, that's my patient.
Come help Carol do a pelvic.
Sure.
Okay?
You're overreacting, Doug.
What is it with you?
I got Kerry Weaver
breathing down my neck.
I got people parting
like the Red Sea
every time I walk
down the hallway.
You asked for a tox screen.
It came back negative.
You didn't get a
blood alcohol, did you?
Oh, for God's sakes, Mark.
You can't work with a
measurable amount...
How many times
have you and I gone out
for margaritas
into the wee hours?
You check your blood
alcohol every morning?
You check it?
Huh! Unbelievable.
Doug, let me tell you
something, as a friend.
As a friend?
No, see, you can't be
my friend and be my boss.
You chose to be my boss.
Listen, I don't need
your sanctimonious
approval of my life.
Do me a favor. Don't come to
me for tips on women anymore.
If I choose to have a Roman orgy
with farm animals
in my free time,
that is none of your business
That is none of
anybody's business.
I am a doctor here.
I do my job.
Nothing gets in the
way of that. Nothing!
Oh, yeah? Today, it did.
Today, you brought a
dying woman in to this ER,
and you messed up
everybody else's work.
Okay? That's a problem.
If you don't see that,
you don't belong here.
Yeah? I tell you what.
Hello, everybody.
Thought I'd check in
and see how the first day
of your pilot study's going.
Medical-surgical
division, wasn't it?
We still have a few
kinks to work out,
but let me, uh...
show you the board.
Dr. Greene, um...
there's a single-vehicle
high-speed TC coming in
that looks extremely surgical.
Want me to let Weaver know?
Screw the new
system. I'll take this one.
Call surgical.
Get a consult down here.
Mark, we're not
finished yet.
Yes, we are.
Oh, man, I haven't done
one of these in six months.
Don't worry.
I've assisted a million.
Thanks.
Mm-hmm.
Okay, just relax.
Good.
Now let your knees fall open.
Okay.
Uh, this is going
to feel a little weird.
Okay, Jung Koo,
take a deep breath.
Good. Good.
Dr. Doyle's going to
take a deep breath, too.
Now, angle lower.
Right. All right.
Relax these muscles.
Don't push away.
Dr. Doyle isn't
going to push, either.
Nobody's going to push.
It's just going to slide...
right in.
There.
Now, rotate and click.
KOH and wet mount
and chlamydia.
There you go.
Mrs. Armitage.
Hi. I'm Dr. Benton.
We met earlier.
Oh, yes.
I-I'm sorry Laura was
so rude to you before.
It was nothing.
Frankly, I just don't know
what to do with her anymore.
She's going to be on IV
antibiotics for five days,
and then she's going to be
discharged in seven, okay?
Uh... Peter?
Mrs. Armitage knows the drill.
Hi, Diane.
Hi, Abby. Hi.
I think Mrs. Armitage's concerns
are more related to
Laura's overall well-being.
Oh, yeah. Um...
Yeah. Yeah, sometimes, uh...
they have problems
making the adjustment.
We have a psychiatrist on staff.
Maybe I could contact them.
Maybe they can help.
Diane...
You've got to stop babying her.
She knows how to be a patient.
She's done that for years.
Now she's a teenager.
She's going to rebel,
and you've got
to be the bad guy.
Set the limits.
You're right, I know.
God willing,
this surgery will be her last.
Dr. Greene...
You called for a surgical?
Yeah. Sounds like a spatula job.
How's your day going?
Oh, fine.
Hey, great card
from Dr. Lewis, huh?
Only she would send
a postcard from O'Hare.
You got a card?
Yeah. You didn't?
No, I didn't.
Thanks for all
your help in there.
Part of the job.
I want to do a pelvic
ultrasound for her.
You already did.
Just need to sign it.
Jerry, what is going
on over there at Chairs?
Oh, some guy's trying to seduce
the nursing staff.
Ma, you're early.
Ten minutes.
It'll take five to walk over.
I'll get my purse.
They don't have a locker
where you can put that?
No, Ma.
And this is how you work?
Excuse me. Excuse me.
I'm looking for Dr. Ross.
Oh...
Uh... he's out in
the ambulance bay.
Come on. We'll show you.
Hey, Doug.
Hey, Helen.
Haven't seen you in a long time.
How have you been?
I have been well.
And yourself?
Can't complain.
Uh... this lady is
looking for you.
Okay. Have a nice dinner.
Thanks.
Hi.
Uh...
Do I know you?
I'm Claire Wilkes.
You worked
on my sister Nadine.
Right. Yeah.
Uh... Sorry.
I... just wish there was more
that we could have done.
Nadine died just
like she lived...
Drunk, high and alone.
Actually, uh...
a friend... brought her in.
I know what kind of
friends she had at 4:00 a.m.
Did she have a...
a medical condition
that we didn't know about?
Wasn't she wearing her bracelet?
Nadine was an epileptic.
She knew she wasn't
supposed to drink
but that didn't stop her.
Can I see her?
Sure.
The coroner's office
still has to do a...
an autopsy.
So that's why the... the
tubes are still in there.
She had so much to give...
a fire in her...
and then, when
the seizures started
it just made her lose
her confidence somehow.
She could always find the guys
to help her sink
just a little lower...
chip away at her self-esteem.
Whatever you were
looking for, Nadine...
I hope you found it.
Oh, God.
Come on, how
about some two-step?
That is a quick quick, slow slow
quick quick, slow.
Oh, okay.
And quick quick
slow slow...
Hey, it works.
All right.
Ooh, work it, Lydia.
Yeah!
I just got a call from ortho.
Your friend's next
up. They promise.
Great, uh...
How about some two-step?
No, no, no.
It's really easy.
It's quick quick, slow slow.
Quick quick, slow slow.
All right, girl, come on.
Okay, here.
And...
All right, girl.
All right.
Whoa, hey!
You're going to have
to call ortho again.
Yeah!
Ah, let's see here.
How's that?
All right?
Um, I have to, uh...
X rays for trauma two.
Good.
Thank you.
You're quite the dancer.
You're not half-bad yourself.
How's that pie, Ma?
Well, at least here,
they don't overcharge.
A good thing when
you're on a budget.
Uh-huh.
A lesson I hope that
you finally learning.
So I got in a little
over my head.
Because you had
to buy a big house.
It's not so big.
An apartment
should be big enough
for one woman.
A house is for a family.
Okay, Ma.
And you don't want to marry.
Dr. Ross wasn't right, I agree.
Dr. Taglieri
wasn't, either. Fine.
But then you can't live
like a doctor's wife, that's
all. You know what, Ma?
I really don't need this today.
All I'm saying
is a nurse is not a queen.
Believe me, I've noticed.
A nurse has to watch her money.
Yeah, while she
teaches all the interns
to make quadruple her salary.
You can't change that.
Maybe not.
Anyway, anyone can
get into a little trouble.
What's this?
To pay your plumber
and your roofer.
And there should be enough there
to finish the plaster.
I don't want you
to live in a dump.
Oh, Ma, that is so sweet.
But I can't take this from you.
From who then?
It's too generous.
I can't even take
that as a loan.
You'd rather owe strangers
than your own mother?
Yeah.
Well, what if it's not a loan?
What if it's more like
a kind of rent?
What kind of rent, Ma?
Pediatric surgeon of the year?
The Price Award?
Oh, man...
That's very prestigious.
I wanted to tell you
I was really pleased
with how the
Armitage surgery went.
Well, you know, thanks
for the opportunity.
You're a gifted surgeon
and you do really
well in the O.R.
It's outside the operating room
where you need work.
Peter, pediatric surgery
focuses on the child
not just the illness.
That mother needed
something from you today
and you acted as
though your job was over
as soon as you took
the surgical gloves off.
You've got great hands.
Now you've got to
show some heart.
Well, I'm sorry.
Don't be sorry.
Learn.
Yeah, I'm looking
at it right now.
One-hour photo guaranteed.
What do you mean that
doesn't apply to slides?!
All slides are are
see-through photos.
Hey, E-ray, can I look at
your catalog of classes?
Yeah, help yourself.
Benton's going to kill me.
Again.
Mm-hmm.
So, Carter, was it that bad
living with your parents again?
Uh, pretty strange. Why?
Well, you know, my mom,
she moved back to the 'burbs
and now she misses all
her old friends from church.
She wants to stay with
me Saturday nights,
go to early services.
Just one night a week? Uh-huh.
You can always sign
up for work on Saturday.
That's a good idea.
We start Qi Gong next week.
Uh, no.
Do you mind if I
tear out a page?
Go ahead.
Pre-med?
It's for a friend.
He's still not up there?!
Oh, no, no. I took him out
to the car, crutches and all.
Okay good. Well,
tell him to take it easy.
I just wanted to say thanks.
You're welcome.
I was wondering if, uh...
maybe you wanted to
go out dancing some time.
You know, grab a
bite, I don't know.
Um, I'm sorry.
I can't date patients.
I wasn't the patient, so...
No, really, I can't.
I'm a good guy.
We can go out dancing.
I'll buy you a steak.
You don't like me, at
least you got the steak.
I can't.
All right. Sorry.
I got you.
See you around.
Table for one?
Uh, yeah.
Listen, is Carla
working tonight?
Yeah, man, she's
here every night.
Okay. Can you tell her
Peter Benton is here?
You're Peter Benton.
I can seat you at the counter.
Enjoy.
Thanks.
Hey.
Well, well, well.
Mmm.
Uh, the place looks great.
Thank you.
That's right, you
haven't seen my baby
since it was a little
bitty greasy spoon.
Well, okay. Grand tour.
And, come with me, sir.
I would like to show
you the kitchen.
You know Tyrone
Harvard? He cooks here.
This is it.
Yes.
We just got two
Sub-Zero freezers,
which is very, very nice.
Do you remember that
little Italian place, Simeone's,
on Seneca... you remember.
So, they closed, they closed,
and I picked up a bunch of stuff
for almost nothing. It's great.
Yeah, it looks like
you made quite a place
for yourself here.
A lot of hard work.
Well, you must have a taste
in your mouth for something
to come all this way out here.
This isn't your line.
That's a buck down the drain.
A girl came in this afternoon...
Nadine Wilkes' sister.
Oh.
She came in
to I.D. her, and...
she just thought I was
another caring doctor.
I let her go right
on thinking that
because...
that's what I want
everybody to think.
And, Carol...
I think I really
did it this time.
You came up here for what?
Cry on my shoulder?
Tell me how
worthless you really are
deep down inside?
And I'd say, "No,
you're not, Doug.
You're one hell of a guy."
And you'd be able
to live with yourself
until the next time?
No. No, thanks.
I'm just not playing.
You're on your own.
I didn't know she was sick.
You didn't know her at all.
Hey, Doug.
It's Lauren. Give me a call.
Thursday, 4:20 p.m.
Hey, Doug. It's Michelle.
We met at the Stanhope
Pharmaceuticals conference.
Anyway, I wanted to take
you up on that drink offer.
So give me a call.
I'm still at Children's.
Bye.
Thursday, 5:17 p.m.
Dr. Anspaugh's Office calling.
Our records indicate
you have not signed up
for the Healthmobile.
Please do so.
Thursday, 5:52 p.m.
Doug, Tina.
Busy tonight?
Give me a call.
Thursday, 6:48 p.m.
Your messages have been erased.