Previously on "ER"..
'I can't watch him..'
...suffer anymore.
'Help us, please.'
Mr. Abbott is accusing you
of murdering his son.
I gave the mother
the entry code.
I showed her
how to change the dosage.
'You don't need anybody else.'
You are a country unto yourself.
What the hell is wrong with you?
If you wanna destroy
your own career, that's fine.
But you stay
the hell away from mine.
'We got a school bus
flipped over by a snowplow.'
Bunch of kids are trapped.
Firemen need
a doctor on the scene.
I'm going with you.
'Doug!'
Mom! Dad! Ow!
Mom! Dad!
'Mom! Dad!'
Worst kids are up front.
They were coming home
from a ski trip.
Three of them were
trapped under the plow.
'Patient number three,
ten‐year‐old female'
'with closed head trauma.'
'Blown pupil,
altered mental status.'
'Left leg's pinned.
Pressure's 110 palp.'
'Breathing's labored.
Rate's 32.'
Alright. Tube and
hyperventilate her.
Notify County that we have
a possible intracranial bleed.
Have neurosurgery and CT
standing by. What do you got?
Patient number five, broken
left femur, foot's pulseless.
Yeah, mottled leg.
Poor cap refill.
‐ Can we move her?
‐ No. Seat has us wedged.
How do I get
to the rest of her?
‐ Up and around, doc.
‐ Alright.
Thank you.
'I want my mom!
Mom! Dad!'
‐ 'Calm down. It's okay.'
‐ 'Mom! Dad!'
‐ 'Your parents are on the way.'
‐ Mom, help!
Mom! Dad!
Is this the broken femur
from the other side?
Scrapes and bruises. Pressure's
100, resps 16.
Gave her eight of morphine.
‐ Any bleeding under there?
‐ Not that I could see.
‐ Her name's JJ.
‐ Hi, JJ.
My name's Mark.
How are you feeling?
‐ I'm scared.
‐ 'I know you are.'
Just hang in there.
Listen, your leg is broken
'but I need you
to be brave for me.'
‐ Can you be brave?
‐ Okay.
Okay, good.
Alright, splint that
fracture as best you can
and throw another
blanket on her.
‐ How long has she been trapped?
‐ About 30 minutes.
‐ How much time have we got?
‐ How much time for what, guys?
‐ Till she loses her leg.
‐ Six hours.
‐ Any of the others trapped?
‐ Oh, yeah.
We got a boy
jammed between the seats
trapped underneath
the girl here.
We can hear the little guy
but we can't get to him.
Take it easy, Dennis!
Got a kid in the back, doc.
'BP's 50 palp.'
He's not moving his legs.
Keep an eye on her vitals.
Let me know
if anything changes.
Could be lumbosacral plexus
injury with paralysis.
Have you been reading
the Rosen's again?
Taking the MCAT's
in a couple of weeks.
They popped the back.
'What the hell is that?'
'Crane.'
That ought to do it.
Dr. Anspaugh..
...may I speak with you
for a moment, please?
I have to finish my rounds.
You know that Dr. Romano
has closed the ER clinic?
You left us little choice.
‐ You can't do it.
‐ Listen, I am in a hurry.
If you wanna discuss this
further, call my office.
Set up an appointment.
Doctor, please..
I have worked here
for ten years
and this ER clinic
has made a real difference.
Preventing people
from getting sick
helping them make better
choices in their lives.
I no longer trust your judgment.
So hundreds of patients
have to be punished
because of my mistake?
If this hospital
is required to pay
millions of dollars in damages
more than a few
hundred clinic patients
are gonna find themselves
without treatment.
Then I'll quit.
I'll quit.
I'll hand over
the clinic to someone else.
Someone you do trust.
But don't close it, please.
Not because of me.
'Jeanie?'
'911 emergency'
I've been in an accident.
I've got a woman badly hurt.
I need help, please!
What's going on?
School bus got hit
by a snowplow.
Oh, man, I was hoping
for an easier night.
‐ How many?
‐ At least 15.
Uh, I should have
called in sick.
Good evening.
The board is up to date.
Dr. Doyle is waiting
for films in curtain three
the lab is late with blood
work for Weaver in exam four
there are seven waiting in
chairs and I am out of here.
Police are still in trauma.
I told them to be out
in five minutes.
Jerry, where the hell
you think you're going?
I'm off at 7:30.
Hey, you're off
when I say you're off.
‐ Wait, is that nurses too?
‐ You betcha.
‐ Damn.
‐ Carter and Lucy?
In exam six.
Carter and Lucy,
what in exam six?
Uh, Rural Minnesota,
North Dakota..
In the middle of winter?
Yeah, well, you know,
it pays 4,000 a week.
It sounds miserable.
Yeah, it sounds like tuition
and a tutor for reese to me.
Do we know
what's coming in first?
Blunt chest trauma,
traumatic amputation
and a kid with a possible
spinal cord injury.
‐ All at once?
‐ Lovely.
I've gone through the files.
Medicine will take
the diabetics.
Said they could use them
on their teaching service.
OB's agreed to
look after the prenatals
once they hit
the third trimester.
The rest are on their own.
Anspaugh isn't
closing the clinic.
What?
He decided to keep it open.
Well, that's great news.
What did you have to do,
sell your firstborn?
‐ No, I had to quit.
‐ You're joking.
Well, I get to keep
my job in the ER
but I'm out of management.
So who‐who's gonna
run the clinic?
‐ You are.
‐ Mm‐mm. No, no, no way.
I don't want that
kind of responsibility.
Tough.
Look, paperwork,
the fundraising
the endless crap from admit?
I've done it. No thanks.
Would you rather shut down
the clinic instead?
Carol, I'm bad at it.
I yell at the wrong people,
I piss everybody off.
I'll be around.
I'll help you out.
I mean, it's either that
or all these people
have nowhere else to go.
Your choice.
‐ Oh, Chuny. Hi.
‐ Hi.
‐ You got a minute?
‐ Sure. What's up?
Um..
..earlier, with Lucy and I
I'm sure that
you have your suspicions
about what we were
doing in there
but actually, we were just‐‐
‐ Knocking boots?
‐ What?
Doing the old nasty?
Hey, the more
the merrier, I say.
Actually, we weren't
doing anything.
Mm‐hmm.
I mean, she's
a med student, you know?
I'm a...resident.
That stuff happens all the time.
Lucy's like,
Lucy's like a little..
...sister or something to me.
Ah, you do that with
your little sister?
Nothing happened.
We didn't do anything.
Do you hear what
I'm telling you?
Besides, I already
have a girlfriend.
Ah, that insurance lady?
‐ She's a financial advisor.
‐ Mm.
Roxanne and I have
a lot in common.
'Units are pulling up!'
She's too pushy, you know?
Always trying to
sell you something.
I'd stick with Lucy.
You two make a cute couple.
We are not a couple!
Maggie, Elizabeth,
take the first one.
Carter, Lucy,
you're on three.
'Peter, you come with me!'
Ten‐year‐old female.
Traumatic amputation
below the left wrist.
BP 90/60,
heart rate 120.
‐ Lost 500cc's of blood.
‐ Do you have the hand?
'They're still looking for it
at the accident site.'
Nine‐year‐old boy
who was sitting backwards
slammed into the edge of
the metal seat in front of him.
He's not moving his legs.
Resps 16,
BP's down to 70/40.
Could be a lumbar fracture.
What about spinal shock
with that low BP?
Internal bleeding more likely.
Alright,
let's round up an ultrasound.
11‐year‐old female,
blunt chest trauma
decreased breath
sounds on the left.
‐ BP's 80/40.
‐ Pneumothorax?
Or a hemopneumothorax.
‐ I need an ultrasound!
‐ X‐ray!
Trauma two!
Maggie, trauma one!
Carter, take exam two!
This way. Tear it down!
Just tear it down!
Let's go!
‐ This is a crime scene!
‐ Not anymore. It's not.
Let's clear this
crap out of here.
Abdomen's soft.
Decreased bowel sounds.
Okay, no reflexes
below the waist.
Let's get a cross‐table
lumbar and hang steroids.
‐ Get out. Go!
‐ What happened in here?
It's a long story.
I'll tell you later.
I'm so cold.
Carol, check up on
the other patients.
BP's 80/50.
She's got a strong
brachial pulse.
Get me another BP cuff.
Okay, the amputation is distal
to the radius and the ulna.
‐ 'I'll clamp that bleeder.'
‐ How you doing?
‐ Peachy.
‐ Can you save it?
Well, if they find the hand,
maybe we've got a chance.
‐ Pulse ox down to 88.
‐ You doing okay?
Uh, she dropped her sats
and her respiratory
effort's getting worse.
‐ Where's that portable X‐ray?
‐ Corday's got it.
Can't wait.
Let's get a chest tube tray
and Lucy, palpate
the fifth intercostal space.
‐ Like this?
‐ Yeah, that's right.
Now incise with a scalpel.
Spread with a kelly,
insert your finger.
‐ Oh, my God, what is that?
‐ What?
Bag for me.
That's intestine.
Did I make the incision too low?
No, the diaphragm's ruptured.
The force of the impact must
have pushed everything up.
'Let's call the OR, right now.'
‐ No free fluid in the belly.
‐ 'Everyone's alright.'
Carter's got ruptured diaphragm.
Corday called vascular.
There's two more
ambulances coming in.
Both patients are stable
with multiple lacerations
and possible
extremity fractures.
'Foley cath is in.'
'Let me know when they arrive.'
Have Jeanie start
suturing the lacs.
‐ Jeanie's not around.
‐ Where is she?
‐ I don't know.
‐ I can find Doug.
‐ He can do it.
‐ No.
‐ It's just lacerations‐‐
‐ I said no.
Alright,
he's got gross hematuria.
Let's prep for a one‐shot IVP.
Call CT. Let's move.
Jerry, find Jeanie.
We need her.
‐ Find her how?
‐ I don't know.
Just find her.
'Come on!'
Let's go!
Come on!
I got a woman in the car.
Come on. Yeah, I need gloves.
I need gloves.
I'm a doctor.
I got a woman.
She's got multiple lacerations.
‐ She's HIV‐positive.
‐ What happened?
I slid on the ice.
She's unconscious.
'Lost control. She wasn't
wearing her seat belt.'
'Hang on, hang on.'
Jeanie?
Alright.
'I got it.'
Alright, Jeanie.
Nice and easy. Okay.
Jeanie? Give me your penlight.
‐ You got a light?
‐ Yeah. Right here.
Good carotid.
No step off.
Multiple lacerations.
Pupils are..
...equal and reactive.
‐ Oh, we need to transport her.
‐ Come on. Let's go.
Hang in there,
Jeanie, hang in there.
'That thing is too unstable.'
If I start lifting
the weight may shift forward
crush everything
underneath that blade.
Well, how about
attaching it to the front?
I don't know.
I can't go in there.
I could take that
whole chassis with me.
We just need
the weight lifted off
so that we can
pull the kids out.
I've got railroad
ties on the truck.
Maybe we can put
some under the chassis.
Take some of
the weight off the blade
put it back onto the truck.
Well, let's do it.
Boys, we need some muscle.
Doc! I found the hand.
One of the fingers
is pretty smashed up
but otherwise it's okay.
Alright, just pack it
in saline gauze with ice
and get it to County.
How's she doing?
She's calmer, but she's
still in a lot of pain, doc.
Hang in there, JJ.
We'll get you out.
‐ It hurts.
‐ Yeah.
‐ How much morphine has she had?
‐ 20 migs.
Respiratory rate's down
but she's still moaning.
Alright, give her another five.
Keep an eye on her breathing.
The trapped little boy
stopped talking.
‐ When?
‐ Couple of minutes ago.
Hey, Dennis, Dennis,
can you hear me?
Alright,
we're running out of time.
‐ Tell them we got to go.
‐ Under the front!
‐ One more!
‐ What's all the noise?
We're just trying
to get you out, okay?
‐ I got it.
‐ 'Alright, we're ready.'
‐ Everybody out.
‐ I'm not comin'.
‐ The hell you're not.
‐ I'm stayin' here.
Go on. Get out. Go, go, go.
It's alright.
Here, doc.
Don't worry, darling.
I'm right here with you.
Okay, doc. Let's go.
‐ Take it up.
‐ Okay, don't worry.
Don't worry.
I'm right here.
It's gonna be
a little loud, okay?
‐ Just relax.
‐ 'Here we go, up!'
Up.
It's okay, JJ.
It's almost over.
‐ That's it. It's free.
‐ Alright. Let's go.
Okay, I need somebody to guide
the leg on the other side.
'I got it.'
‐ 'Whoa. We got a pumper.'
‐ 'I'm on it.'
'Watch the femur.
Unstable open fracture.'
Careful, careful.
'Apply a pressure dressing'
and get a hare
traction on that leg.
‐ Let's find the boy.
‐ I got him! I got him!
‐ Is he breathing?
‐ Resps about 16 and shallow.
He's got multiple lacerations.
A possible fracture
of the right forearm.
We found the boy.
He's still alive.
‐ Can you get him out?
‐ We need a backboard.
'You'll never be able
to move around in there.'
We'll cut in from the outside.
'Doc, we need you out here.'
‐ I got him. Go, go!
‐ 'The leg's a mess.'
She's still losing
a lot of blood.
Pump up a BP cuff
proximal to the fracture
and clamp it off
with a hemostat.
That ought to hold her
till she gets to the ER.
Have ortho and
vascular standing by
ready to do an angiogram.
Tell them we don't
have much time.
Are you coming with me?
I'll meet you there, okay, JJ?
‐ Okay.
‐ Alright.
BP's 90/60, pulse 120.
Large contusions over
both upper quadrants.
Okay, we need to evaluate
for a splenic rupture.
Start two lines and
then transport him.
The twos and threes
have all been transported.
All we have left are minors.
Alright, get the other kids
to us as soon as you can.
‐ Good work, skipper.
‐ Thanks, doc.
‐ What?
‐ They're all alive.
So far.
David Martino.
M‐A‐R‐T‐I‐N‐O.
The police told us that our
daughter was brought in here.
Please, look, everyone,
I know that you're worried
but yelling at me
isn't gonna to help.
I need your name,
I need your child's name so‐‐
Blunt trauma to the abdomen.
Temporary response to
crystalloids in the field.
He just dropped
his pressure again.
Dennis? That's my son!
Dennis, you alright?
He was trapped, okay?
He's stable now.
We need to take him for
further evaluation and tests.
What do you mean?
What kind of tests?
Sir, you're gonna
have to wait outside, okay?
We are gonna find you
as soon as we know more.
Yeah. But he's gonna
be alright, right?
Can you help
this gentleman, please?
Come on, let the doctors
do their work, sir.
He's shocky.
Could be a spleen injury.
He'll need
an ultrasound or a DPL.
How are the rest?
Amputation's
already up in the OR.
‐ Has the hand made it?
‐ Yup. One, two, three.
Anspaugh took
the fractured kidney upstairs.
Romano and Edson got
the ruptured diaphragm.
Type and cross for six.
Get a stat H&H.
BP's 80/60, pulse 120.
How about the girl
with the pulseless foot?
Corday's got her.
She's prepping for an angiogram.
Connie, can you see
if CT can take another one?
‐ No seat belts on the bus?
‐ Nope.
'Air bags in
every new car in America'
but we send our children off
like lambs to the slaughter.
You're a mess.
Why don't you get cleaned up?
Great. Thanks.
'Out of the way!
Out of the way!'
‐ How's she doing?
‐ Big subdural on CT.
Neurosurgery's waiting.
Let's go!
September 5, 1989.
Mark, hypothermic
boy's coming in.
I'll be right back out.
‐ Somebody order four pizzas?
‐ Yeah.
'Forty two, fifty.'
Bus driver's
admitted to cardiology.
I'll take
the eye injury in exam one.
This is County General,
come in, 29.
I got a kid that's gonna need
50 stitches. Where's Lucy?
Uh, she's in surgery with Edson
on that ruptured diaphragm.
‐ What about Jeanie?
‐ Still AWOL.
Call somebody upstairs
that can sew
and get their ass down here.
‐ Who else is coming in?
‐ Uh, hypothermic kid‐‐
‐ I'll take him.
‐ Two minutes out.
Found him in the snow,
20 yards from the wreck.
Must have been thrown by
the force of the collision.
Blunt abdominal trauma,
no obvious head injury
BP 70 palp, pulse 40.
His name, Anthony Martino,
was written inside his jacket.
‐ He's throwing PVCs.
‐ Must have irritated his heart.
Prep for
a warm peritoneal lavage.
How's she doing?
Angiogram showed
a partial tear in the popliteal.
I reduced her fracture,
got back a weak pulse.
There's good
collateral circulation.
We've bought
vascular a little time.
‐ Hi.
I see you still have
your fireman's hat.
Is my mom here?
I'm not sure,
but I'll go find out.
‐ What's your last name?
‐ Mitchell.
I'll find her
if she's here, JJ.
How long till
they take her upstairs?
They're handling
life threats first.
Limb threats are stacked up.
It's been
three and a half hours.
You know, if they don't
get to her in the next hour
I'll start calling around
see if we can transport her
somewhere else.
Don't wait. Call now.
OR's backed up. Some on‐call
surgeons can't make it in.
Yeah, he can't wait.
You take him.
‐ What's up?
‐ DPL's positive. He's going up.
Call the blood bank on
that cross‐matched blood.
‐ Dr. Greene?
‐ Liver?
‐ 'His spleen.'
‐ Kerry, core temp's 84.
DPL's grossly positive.
Did you give him
warmed intra‐abdominal?
Warmed gastric
lavage is going.
I held up on
the peritoneal lavage.
I didn't want to dislodge
a clot in his liver.
Start the bladder re‐warming.
I'll be right in.
‐ More vent.
‐ Dr. Greene?
Mark, paramedics comin' in hot.
‐ Kid crumped in the rig.
‐ From the bus?
‐ Yeah.
‐ Okay, clear a trauma room now.
Okay, I'm gonna go, check on
Carter's hypothermic kid.
‐ Dr. Greene?
‐ What?
Kobe Ikabo. You talked
to my husband, Mobalage.
Yeah, of course, I'm sorry,
it's a little hectic now.
We went to see the doctor
and Mobalage has been scheduled
to have the surgery tomorrow.
Connie, can you see if there's
someone here for a JJ Mitchell?
Hey, Carol, do
you got a minute?
Yeah, what's up?
‐ I'm sorry. What?
‐ Um, the surgery.
I think it might be a mistake.
‐ Why?
‐ Does he need it?
‐ If he wants to get better.
‐ Does he need to get better?
‐ Oh, God.
‐ Carol! Carol!
Ms. Ikabo, it's normal for you
to have anxiety
before a surgery.
There's always some risk,
but in your husband's case
it's minimal.
He should regain full function.
‐ Hey, we need a hand!
‐ Which one is it?
Patient number 13.
Broken ribs,
minor head injuries.
‐ I thought she was stable.
‐ She crashed en route.
'Sinus on the scope, no vitals.'
Tubed her,
but I couldn't find a line.
‐ Okay, how long?
‐ 'Eight minutes.'
Let's go, darling.
Here we go.
Pupils mid‐range and sluggish.
Jerry, where are we?
Uh, pedes clinic. Best I can do.
Dr. Greene?
Mrs. Ikabo,
I can't talk right now.
Look, wait in chairs.
I'll be there as soon as I can.
No pulse without CPR.
‐ Last epi?
‐ Three minutes.
Alright. Another amp
down the ET tube.
Malik, what happened to Carol?
Doug and Jeanie crashed
head‐on into an overpass.
Doug's alright, Jeanie's hurt.
Unit 29's pulling in
with them right now.
Mark, we're here.
Vitals are stable, contusions
of face, forehead and abdomen.
‐ Precautions, everyone.
‐ BP's 130/94, pulse ox 98.
She came to a few minutes ago.
Jeanie, do you know
what day it is?
‐ Thursday.
‐ Doug, are you okay?
She lost consciousness.
Trachea midline
no apparent chest injuries.
She wasn't wearing a seat belt.
'Stupid, huh?'
Doug, let me look at your head.
We need a CT and a trauma panel.
Doug, we got it. Back off.
You're guarding, tenderness
in the right upper quadrant.
‐ Get a CT.
‐ Everybody get back to work!
‐ Get out of there, Doug.
‐ Dr. Ross, step back!
She could have a liver injury.
Yeah, we'll catch it
if she does.
Carol..
...Carter's hypothermic
ten‐year‐old's in trouble.
‐ Okay, Peter, you got her?
‐ Yeah.
Jeanie, I'll come back
as soon as I can.
Kerry, Kerry,
look, I'll take Carter
you stay here with Jeanie.
No, I will take Carter.
‐ It's a pedes case.
‐ You are off this station!
You are not working
in this hospital! Not tonight!
Now sit down and
let Carol look at your head!
Alright, no peritoneal signs.
Let's get the, uh, trauma panel.
‐ Come on.
‐ Move.
Get a CT on the head
and, uh, a belly.
Get the O‐neg!
We're actively re‐warming
with foley, NG and ET.
But he's still
hypothermic at 84 degrees.
‐ Okay, what do you suggest?
‐ Cardiac bypass.
Heart rate's down
to 30, BP's 60 palp.
‐ He's soaked.
‐ Oh. Oh, God. Conductive loss.
Let's get these
wet clothes off of him.
You're headed
in the right direction.
No bypass, just keep warming.
Lily, notify the OR. They've
got another ex‐lap pending.
‐ What if he goes into V‐fib?
‐ He won't make it to the OR.
Mark, Mark, I couldn't find
anybody for a JJ Mitchell.
You want me to see if we
have a phone number, call?
Yeah, could you?
How are Doug and Jeanie?
Okay. Jeanie's got a concussion.
Hey, Jerry,
why is everyone in the hall?
Uh, all the beds are full
and the minors are showing up.
We got a broken jaw with
a tongue laceration coming in.
Yeah, well, why don't you
call up to medicine
see if they have
any spare residents.
ORS are still backed up.
I'm gonna start calling around
see if we can transport JJ
to another hospital.
It's not
a surgical case, I trust?
Yep, girl with
an open fracture.
It's been four hours.
We're running out of time.
‐ Where's my ruptured spleen? ‐
Trauma one.
Sounds like
a great teaching case.
Yeah, if they don't
get to her soon
she's gonna lose her leg.
We got at least two hours.
‐ Call Mercy anyway.
‐ Damn right.
You're gonna need sutures.
Sorry..
...for everything.
I'm gonna go to Anspaugh.
I'm gonna throw
myself on my sword
see if he'll open
the clinic again.
Anspaugh's gonna
keep the clinic open.
He changed his mind?
I threw myself on my sword.
Lynette Evans is gonna
take over the clinic.
I'm back to my blue‐collar roots
punching the clock in the ER.
I don't know what to say.
There isn't anything to say.
It's done.
Just have to accept it
and move on.
I'm gonna resign..
...take responsibility for
everything that happened.
I'm destroying
my relationship with you.
I've probably
lost my best friend.
I've certainly damaged
both of your careers.
I hate Weaver.
I hate Romano.
It's time to go.
Where?
I liked Seattle
when I was in med school.
I didn't see much of it
but I liked it.
‐ Seattle?
‐ The Pacific Northwest.
Take that job offer in Portland.
It's pretty up there.
It's clear.
You'd like it.
Come with me.
Carol, we got
another rig coming in.
I'll be right there.
I love you.
I grew up here.
My family's here,
my friends, my job.
You just got demoted.
Yeah, well, you had something
to do with that, didn't you?
Hey..
...come with me.
I got to get back to work.
We'll talk about it later, okay?
Vitals stable.
Minor lacs to the abdomen
dislocate her right index finger
and ear laceration.
My hoop earring
got stuck on my coat.
How many more
you have coming in?
Elise is the last.
Mark, Maggie needs you in two.
Alright, find a spot for her.
Oh, man. Uh, Mrs. Ikabo..
‐ Carol, do you have a second?
‐ Not really. No.
Can you talk to Mrs. Ikabo?
This is Mobalage's wife,
the custodian.
He's gonna have surgery tomorrow
for erectile dysfunction.
She's a little anxious.
Okay. Sure.
Mrs. Ikabo, I...I'm sorry.
Nurse Hathaway's gonna
be able to answer
any of your questions, okay?
I'll be right with you.
Jeanie's head CT is normal,
no sign of a bleed.
Her abdominal CT shows
a small amount of
fluid around the liver.
‐ Yeah. That could be blood.
‐ No, no, no.
‐ Liver's intact, no laceration.
‐ There's pain on palpation?
‐ Mm‐hmm.
‐ Those her labs?
Yeah. CBC's normal.
LFT is elevated,
especially ALT
PT is high.
From a trauma?
Bilirubin's abnormal,
albumin is low.
So..
...what do you think?
I think these results
don't have anything to do with
the accident.
Yeah. Neither do I.
So what do you wanna do?
Draw up a hepatitis panel
and, uh, give her some vitamin K
admit her to medicine
for a liver biopsy.
Oh, Mrs. Ikabo.
I'm sorry
for making you wait.
Do you want a soda?
Um, Dr. Greene said that
you might have some questions
about your husband's surgery.
Do you know
what happened to Mobalage?
He was tortured
in Nigeria, right?
Um..
...Dr. Greene said
that after tomorrow..
...he will be able to..
...have relations again?
Yes, if it's successful.
I don't know if I can.
Can you tell me why not?
Mobalage was a student leader.
A dissident.
After they
tortured him, he fled.
When‐when I joined him here,
he was happy we were together
but not interested
in me in that way.
Well, um..
...you have to, you have
to help him through this.
I should go.
I'm sorry to bother you.
Wait, Mrs. Ikabo.
What is it?
‐ I can't.
‐ You can't...what?
After he left..
...they came for me.
Ten soldiers..
...each took their turn.
All night and
into the next day.
In our home.
I never told him.
I‐I want him
to be happy, but..
I don't know if I can
be with a man again.
You have to tell him.
It would kill him.
‐ But he loves you.
‐ No.
‐ Hey.
I didn't mean to
wake you up. Sorry.
What time is it?
It's, uh..
...2:30.
Sutures look great.
Who did them?
Peter.
Took forever.
He's kind of a perfectionist,
if you hadn't noticed.
I got a bed for you upstairs
so you can get some real sleep.
How are you feeling?
Sore.
So what is it?
Peter took some more blood.
Um..
...how‐how have you
been feeling lately?
A little run‐down.
‐ Is it AIDS?
‐ No.
Your T‐cell count was normal
but your liver
function tests indicate
that you might have hepatitis
'and your abdominal CT'
'showed a small amount of fluid
around your liver capsule.'
'Uh, have you been tested?'
Yeah, I had, um..
...hepatitis "B" vaccination
five or six years ago.
I hadn't had an "A."
‐ So you think it's "C"?
‐ It might be.
We need to admit you
and do a few tests.
That sounds like
the doctor answer.
I was..
...kinda hoping for
a good friend answer.
‐ Yeah.
'That'd be my guess.'
All this time,
I'm worrying about HIV
and I get hepatitis "C."
Huh?
We should do the biopsy.
Oh, I mi‐might,
I might be wrong.
Wouldn't be the first time.
Maybe the second time.
Maybe the third time.
Wow, I just thought she was
anxious about the surgery.
She is.
It's scheduled
for this morning.
I know. We need to
get them some therapy.
I'll call Riley,
see if he knows anybody
who specializes in PTSD
in torture victims.
Doug says he's gonna quit.
Yeah?
I think he's serious.
Maybe he should.
You want him to go?
I'm done, Carol.
I love him like a brother
but I can't do this anymore.
It's too hard.
He says he wants to move
to Seattle or Portland.
He wants me to go with him.
Are you going to?
I can't remem‐remember
a time when I didn't love him.
I'll miss you..
...maybe more than
I'll miss him.
I gotta go.
Mrs. Martino?
Anthony's stable.
So is he okay?
Well, he's gonna
need exploratory surgery
but I think
he's gonna be fine.
‐ Can I see him?
‐ Yes, please.
Follow me.
Thank you.
‐ She seems happy.
‐ Very.
It's gonna be light soon.
When did you sleep last?
Day before yesterday.
You?
24 hours ago.
I feel like an intern again.
‐ Good work.
‐ Yeah, you too.
Is this where you work?
Most of the time, yeah.
I'm surprised to see
you're still here
this late at night.
I thought doctors made
life‐and‐death decisions
about other people's families
and then go home
to their million‐dollar homes
and stoli martinis.
He was in agony.
He was dying
not in days, in hours.
You stole my son from me.
'Joi called and I caught
the first flight out.'
I came as quickly as I could.
'Ricky died and I wasn't there.'
'I didn't get to hold his hand.'
'I didn't get to say goodbye.'
'You stole that from me.'
Mm.
‐ Mm.
‐ That's disgusting.
Really? It's not bad.
I was thinking about
getting another one.
You got anymore quarters?
Stab wound to the chest,
large kitchen knife.
BP 70 palp.
Ran two liters saline in.
Couldn't get
the pressure back up.
Pulse ox is 91 on ten liters.
‐ Mark, it's Mrs. Ikabo.
‐ What?
‐ Wh‐what happened?
‐ Her husband freaked out.
Called 911,
but wouldn't let us in.
She was bleeding
all over the place.
Hang two units of O‐neg.
Order four type‐specific
'and cross match another four.'
Pulse is weak
and thready at 140.
Okay, everybody, we're gonna do
this on my count, nice and easy.
Ready? One, two, three.
‐ 'Let's get an EKG.'
‐ 'Poor cap refill.'
Mark, she's cold.
No breath sounds on the right.
Tracheal shift to the left.
She's got dilated neck veins.
Tension pneumo, 14 gauge.
I'll decompress.
Where's her husband?
‐ He jumped out the window.
‐ What?
Cops had to ram down
the door for us to get in.
He took off on foot. They were
still chasing him when we left.
Where the hell's
the trauma team?
We're not very compatible.
I think the best thing for us
to do is to go back to being‐‐
‐ Hey.
‐ Hi. Hey.
‐ What are you doing up here?
‐ Uh, waiting for you.
‐ Really?
‐ Um, yeah.
Look, is there someplace
that we can, uh, we can go?
Um, we could go back to my dorm.
‐ My roommate leaves by 6:30.
‐ Your dorm?
‐ Okay, fine, your place, then.
‐ Weaver's house?
No, no, see,
this is the problem.
You're a student
and I'm a resident.
‐ Right, so you said.
‐ And we're not very compatible.
Yeah, that's true.
Very few people drive me
crazy the way that you do.
Yeah, but you irritate
the hell out of me.
Right.
So clearly, this is not
something that's gonna work.
And I mean between
hospital policy
and us not really
liking each other
we should just accept the fact
that yesterday was a mistake
and we should, uh,
things should go back
to being the way
they were before.
Oh.
I think that's
the smartest thing
to do for everyone involved.
Oh.
‐ We could just have sex.
‐ No, no, that's my point.
‐ We can't just have sex.
‐ I don't wanna have s..
Hi. How are you?
It was a mistake.
‐ It was wrong.
‐ Got you.
Carter, you're really
gullible, you know that?
‐ Ha, ha, ha. That wasn't funny.
‐ Sure, it is.
Look, you don't wanna hang out
that's fine with me.
I'm not really
attracted to you anyway.
‐ Oh, you're not?
‐ No.
You're a little
closed off for my tastes.
‐ Closed off?
‐ Emotionally withdrawn.
Not really in touch
with your feelings.
‐ I am not.
‐ Sure, you are.
‐ I am not!
‐ Just forget it, okay?
You're right.
We're not compatible.
Believe me, I'm in touch
with my feelings right now.
‐ And I wanna throttle you.
‐ "Throttle?"
There's an in‐touch‐
with‐your‐feelings kinda word.
Oh, now you're gonna
ridicule my vocabulary.
I just, okay, I just meant
opposites attract, okay?
We sound like my grandparents.
They've been married 56 years..
...still having great sex too.
‐ My wife, is she dead?
‐ No.
‐ So where are they taking her?
‐ To surgery.
They're...trying to save her.
‐ Can they?
‐ I don't know.
Oh, what have I done?
'Carol, what's going on?'
Are you...are you alright?
Yeah, we're fine.
We need Mark, though.
Can you...can you get Mark?
Yes, Dr. Greene, please.
‐ Sure, I can do that.
‐ And security PTSD.
You've got a big
cut on your leg.
I ran away.
Oh...God.
Thought I'd find you up here.
How's she doing?
She's fine. Sedated.
So I spoke to Anspaugh.
I told him I was quitting.
And what'd he say?
Well, he was polite enough
not to burst into song.
Didn't try and
talk me out of it.
‐ Well, did you expect him to?
‐ No.
Uh, Julian in genetics
stood up for me with the cops.
‐ And?
‐ They're not gonna prosecute.
‐ That's great.
‐ Yeah.
Long night, huh?
Yep.
You're not coming
with me, are you?
Are you really leaving?
There's nothing for me here.
I'm here.
I mean work.
I can't stay here.
‐ Not even for me?
‐ Come with me.
I want you to stay here.
I can't.
I don't understand that.
I have to go, Carol.
I can't stay here.
Doug..
...I don't wanna
wake up alone tomorrow.
I love you.
'Well, this is living.'
Brown‐bagging it on
the lake in February.
If this isn't
the coldest place on earth
I don't know what is.
It was your idea
to come out here.
I'm just trying
to remind myself
why I'm so happy getting
the hell out of here.
You're not gonna become
a trail blazers fan, are you?
Maybe..
...or the sonics.
That's just wrong.
Seahawks?
I don't know. Maybe.
Doesn't it rain, like
300 days a year out there?
Save me a lot of money
watering my lawn.
You don't have a lawn.
‐ Want to play some hoops?
‐ Sure.
Come on.
You know what
I am going to miss?
What?
Whipping your ass on the court.
Oh, right.
I don't think
I ever lost a game.
‐ In your dreams.
‐ Play for a buck a point?
‐ Hell, no.
‐ What, are you scared?
No. You cheat.
‐ I do not.
‐ You do cheat.
‐ You're a cheater.