Previously on ER..
Carter, you come
here every day.
Sometimes you're really cooking
and sometimes you're not.
Alright,
let's auto‐transfuse him.
‐ What?
‐ You're kidding.
'He needs blood, Carter.'
And he's gonna get it.
Dad, I told you
I was gonna rent a car.
Your mother
appreciates you coming.
Oh, there you are!
Oh, I'm so glad!
‐ Jerry!
‐ What!
Answer the damn phone!
Did you withhold treatment
from that kid?
It's my decision.
It was good that you
stayed focused on the patient.
Thanks.
Take as much
time as you need.
I'll wait.
Let's say we pull
into the ambulance bay
with a gunshot victim.
What are you thinking about?
‐ Excuse me?
‐ A fresh trauma patient.
What goes through your mind?
The basics of course,
airway, breathing, circulation.
Oh, yeah? But you docs don't
ever think about the scene.
You see two IVs, C‐collars,
backboards, monitors..
...all packaged
and ready to go.
But you have no idea
what we have to go through.
Which is why I'm here.
Listen,
a one‐day ride‐along
is not gonna tell
you the whole story.
You know, sometimes
we get shot at.
Sometimes we're out there
trying to save a banger
and there's airmail
coming in on us from all sides.
‐ Airmail?
‐ Yeah.
Garbage,
bottles, bricks.
Thrown from
the windows, from the roof
and we're down in the streets
trying to save a life.
Yeah, you gotta
keep your mind right.
It can make you cynical.
Well, let's hope
we have an easy day.
That's the way it usually
is when you docs ride along.
That's why you don't
get the big picture.
Remember, you're here
as an observer.
We have protocols,
so don't go off on your own.
Don't worry.
Hey, sure picked the right
day for your first ride‐along.
‐ So, where do we begin?
‐ Right here.
‐ Come on through here.
‐ What do you got?
20 to 30 victims, mostly minor.
Lacerations, burns.
One fatality.
We set up triage out there.
Hey, captain,
we're all shored up.
I need to take
a paramedic down.
We got a guy
trapped under rubble.
Well, I'll go.
I'm a trauma surgeon.
County General,
Dr. Corday.
You have any experience
with confined‐space rescue?
No, but, uh, take me to him,
I'll see what I can do.
Okay. Gear her up
and take her down.
First section's pretty vertical,
maybe eight to 10 feet.
‐ Better to go head first.
‐ Uh‐huh, head first?
Yeah, once you get under
there's no room to turn around.
Now, the walls...are
pretty uneven
so, it's easier to brace
yourself with your hands.
Do you ever
do any rock climbing?
No, I'm afraid I haven't. Look,
will I actually fit in there?
Yeah, it's tight at first,
but near the victim it opens up.
‐ You claustrophobic?
‐ Uh, no, not really.
Alright.
Well, best if you go first.
If something goes wrong
I'll drag you out.
Yeah. Okay,
well, let's get on with it.
‐ Alright.
‐ Could you help me?
Ah.
‐ Alright?
‐ It's okay.
Alright, it's not far now.
Be careful, don't bump against
those four‐by‐fours.
'That's all that's holding
this place up.'
It's a little more open here.
We jacked up as far as we can.
All this is pretty unstable.
I can see him!
We're on the way!
Sir, are you okay?
Get me out.
It hurts.
Yes, I'll give you
something for the pain.
'Then we're going to
get you out, okay?'
Don't leave me.
We won't.
We won't leave you, I promise.
Okay, Dewey,
Give me the drug bag.
I need to start a line.
It's okay, sir.
If you just hang on.
Alright, okay.
‐ Hm?
‐ Mm.
‐ Oh, lilac.
‐ It's called "Spring Rain."
‐ It's nice.
‐ Really?
You don't, you don't think
it's too young for me?
No way. My mom wears
something just like that.
You know, I'm not gonna
have time to sit down.
I'm on from three to eleven.
‐ Really?
‐ How's it been going?
Uh, I got busy after lunch.
Doyle's out with the flu.
You heard anything from Mark?
Yeah, he's gonna try
to catch a flight
back either today or tomorrow.
‐ One coffee, please.
‐ 'Sixty cents.'
Hey, Carter!
How's the Optho rotation going?
Only a week to go. Long week.
Hey, maybe you can help me out.
I've been getting headaches..
...re‐reviewing these
hospital financial reports.
I think I need a new pair
of reading glasses.
Yeah, sure, come on up.
I'll check you out.
‐ Get you a new prescription.
‐ Thank you.
You keep that.
Jack Arteburn, 52,
fainted at a breakfast meeting
at Stanton Savings and Loan.
A and O on arrival,
vitals normal.
No ectopy on the scope.
Started a line for kicks.
Mr. Arteburn, did you
have any chest pain?
No, no, I was
just a little dizzy.
My secretary overreacted.
‐ Are you a doctor?
‐ I'm a physician assistant.
But I'll be, I'll be
seeing a real doctor?
Dr. Weaver, county dispatch
is calling, there's been
a fire and explosion
at a chemical warehouse.
They want to send us six minors
with burns and lacerations.
‐ Yeah, no problem.
‐ No problem.
Just a little bee sting, Leo.
Sorry. It's the only place
to put an IV.
Get me out of here!
Yep. We're working on that.
Now, you just hang on there.
I'll give you some morphine.
Make you feel much better.
Dewey, can you lift
up the saline?
Yeah.
He's got a good pulse.
Probably some broken ribs
and he can wriggle his toes.
But I can't assess
the right arm.
It's pinned at his shoulder.
If we could raise the concrete
just another inch or two.
No. Any movement
could bring all this down.
Just an inch,
then we might free it.
And I won't have to amputate.
No! No, please
don't cut off my arm.
No. We're trying
to save it, Leo.
We're gonna lift up that slab.
What else can we do,
if we're to get him out?
Okay.
I'm gonna need
more shoring down here
before we try anything.
I need a bone saw.
No. Don't do it, please.
Only as a last resort, Leo.
What about something
to reduce the friction?
Uh, grease?
No, it's too thick.
We need something we can pour,
like...vegetable oil.
‐ We got motor oil.
‐ Ah, yeah. Motor oil.
Lots of it.
We're gonna get you slick
as an eel and slide you out.
E, L, M.
N, E.
Very good. Very good,
Mrs. Melenger.
Okay.
Now I want you to tell me
which one is clearer, okay?
Number one..
...or number two?
Number two is very dark.
Okay, let's try
that again.
Number one..
...or number two?
It's black.
I can't see through that.
Yes. I think that is probably
a little too much tint for you.
‐ Okay, give me a minute here.
‐ Everything okay?
Not really. I think
your student needs some help.
Why don't I finish
up here, Dr. Carter?
There's a...a..
...glaucoma
patient in the ER.
‐ Needs a consult.
‐ Right.
Glenn Krakowski, 32,
working in a chemical warehouse.
Obvious right
tib‐fib fracture.
Starting to complaining
of abdominal pain.
BP 132 over 75.
Pulse 92. IV's in the field.
Okay, what about these guys?
Minor burns
and lacerations from glass.
‐ Anything for me?
‐ Yeah, right here.
Blood trauma,
abdominal pain.
‐ Is T‐1 open?
‐ Yeah.
Get start on him.
I'll take the others.
Sir, are you on any medication?
No, nothing.
I...I never get sick.
Uh, message
from Dr. Anspaugh.
He's giving
a lecture in Virgin Gorda.
That is the phone number
of the hotel.
'Hey, is that
Mr. Arteburn's chart?'
Yeah, yeah. Actually,
check this out. Blue Cross.
Not the HMO,
not the PPO.
Traditional
indemnity plan, gold.
Jerry, we treat
everyone the same.
I'm just thinking
about the budget deficit.
Mr. Arteburn, I have some
preliminary results
and I'd like‐‐
Look, if there's, if there's
any cause for concern
I'd really rather
go see my own doctor.
Well, you have some
changes in your EKG
that suggest that you may
have had a small heart attack.
Heart attack?
Yes, we should check a blood
test to make sure there was no
heart muscle damage, that takes
a couple of hours and if that's
normal, we can arrange
for a treadmill heart scan.
Look, would you call
my doctor, Greg Fonarow?
He's up on Chestnut.
I‐I just wanna
get his opinion
on what ever
you're gonna doing.
I'll call him as soon as
I get the blood test results.
Don't worry,
I think you'll find
we give the highest
standard of care.
It's your last quart, Leo.
I raised it
an inch. That's it.
Right.
‐ You ready?
‐ Ha.
One, two, three!
Let me check his arm.
‐ You got room?
‐ Uh, yep.
You said you wouldn't amputate.
Don't worry
it won't come to that.
Another good tug and we'll
get you out of the hole.
‐ You ready?
‐ Ready.
Then pull!
We don't have enough leverage
to lift him out of here.
‐ I need a come‐along.
‐ What's that?
It's a kind of winch..
Ah!
‐ What was that?
‐ I don't know.
Dewey here.
What the hell's going on?
'Explosion in the chemical area.
Abort and get out.'
Acknowledged. Cap says out.
No, you tell them
to bring that thing
we need so we can get him out!
Captain's not gonna
let anyone come down.
‐ Then you go get it.
‐ And leave you?
Yes. They've gotta
let you back down if I'm here.
Now go! I'm not leaving him!
‐ But hurry!
‐ Okay. I'll be back.
We're gonna die down here.
It's okay, Leo.
Just one more
piece of equipment..
...and we'll get you out.
Doug, I've got an 8‐year‐old
with altered mental status,
short of breath.
Babysitter called 911.
Ah, I stopped by
to see you this morning.
I had an early morning meeting.
Before 7:00?
Are you monitoring me?
Just offering you a ride.
Sophie? This is Dr. Ross.
‐ Hi, Sophie.
‐ Hi.
Hey, how long's she been sick?
Uh, her mom said she's had
diarrhea for a couple days now.
She said to give her
a spoonful of bee pollen
and raspberry tea
every four hours.
How are you feeling, Sophie?
I have to practice the piano.
She's altered.
When did that start?
I found her on the floor
and she had a bowel movement
and there was, uh, blood
in it. I couldn't wake her up.
Give her the ABG, a CBC,
a chem 20 and a chest X‐ray.
Want an IV of saline?
Uh, no, just a HEP block.
Is she gonna be alright?
Did you talk to her parents?
'I beeped her mom earlier.'
Could you try again?
Yeah.
You know, doctor, maybe,
if you'd gone to public school
you could've seen
one of my science programs.
I started them
right after the war.
Yes, try to keep
your eyes still.
Look at my earlobe.
You know, about 1950
I was on a TV program
and I liked it so much I wanted
to make it my life's work.
Yeah, what happened?
What happened?
I'll tell you what happened.
That son of a bitch, Mr. Wizard
came along
and left me dead in the water.
Yeah. Go ahead, laugh.
‐ Well, it looks good.
‐ Um.
I'm gonna need to
check your eye pressure
with a tono‐pen, Mr. Bikel.
‐ Dr. George.
‐ Dr. George?
Yeah, Tono‐pen,
I...the state‐of‐the‐art
we used to use the big one
with the air puff.
Oh, yeah, I'll put numbing drops
in your eyes first
and then we'll
measure the pressure.
Solid‐state micro‐circuitry.
But all in all, just a simple
pressure transducer.
That's what..
Oh, zip.
That's numbing already.
The numbing's coming fast.
Yup, let's press
this button and it works.
Don't you wanna know how?
'I could build you one.'
Sure, out of an ink jar,
finger cot and a swizzle stick.
Yeah, alright.
Uh, thirty‐five.
Your pressure's up a bit.
It doesn't look good.
Creatinine's 6.8.
Potassium's 7.3.
She's got acute renal failure.
Get me glucose,
insulin and Kayexalate.
What do you think
is shutting down her kidneys?
Uh, it could be,
uh, bloody diarrhea.
E. coli, probably.
Push two of Versed.
'Get an ET tube 6.5.'
'That's good. She needs
a central line for dialysis.'
Call for a pediatric
nephrology consult.
When can I go home?
Not for a little while, Sophie.
Dr. Ross' gonna
give you some medicine
that gonna make you very sleepy.
And when you wake up,
you're gonna have
a tube in your mouth
to help you breathe.
You won't be able to speak,
so we're gonna have
to do some hand signals.
Do you know what this means?
Okay?
Good. Are you good at charades?
'Here we go. Hold on.'
Alright,
crike, crike, crike.
Honey? What's going on?
Alright. Hang on. Okay, I'm
in, bag her. Are you the mother?
Get me an 11 French
Double‐Lumen catheter.
Sophie? Sophie?
Why is she unconscious?
We had to sedate her
to get the breathing tube
down her throat.
Oh, she wasn't sick when I left.
She had a little diarrhea.
We believe it's an E. coli
bacterial infection that's
causing the kidney failure.
E. coli? That comes from meat.
It's impossible!
She doesn't eat meat.
It can also come from
raw juices or sprouts.
Still, however she got it,
she needs dialysis.
Oh, no, I want
another opinion before
anyone put her in some machine.
‐ Don't have a lotta time.
‐ This is my daughter.
I have a right
to decide how she's treated.
Her high potassium
is high enough to cause
a cardiac arrest.
She needs dialysis.
If she doesn't get it, she is
gonna die. So, sign the consent.
Please?
No. My leg! I'm caught!
His foot's caught.
I'm gonna try and free it.
Can you reach it?
Can you loosen it?
What are you doing?
Don't touch that ja‐‐
‐ Just a tiny bit.
‐ 'No.'
The shoring's down! Get out!
‐ Ah!
‐ C'mon, let's go!
Wait.
‐ We can pull him out!
‐ 'C'mon, let's go.'
He's free!
Pull! Pull!
'Hang on!'
Pull, pull, pull!
‐ How are you doing?
‐ Last one.
See you tomorrow
for a wound check.
Since the workers comp cases
make sure you call
the employee‐health coordinator
at the chemical plant
and fax them all‐‐
'I need some help!'
‐ What happened?
‐ We're from Prusack Chemco.
We were behind Building five
when the tank blew.
Manny went right into the stuff.
What kind of stuff?
Everyone got soaked.
It was a mess.
I threw these guys
in back of my pickup.
What‐what is that smell?
Solvent. Everyone got sick.
Okay, Jeanie,
take the other guys.
'Bag and seal all the clothes.
Glove up, everybody.'
I‐I'm gonna open some doors.
I want you to use one drop,
three times a day.
Three times a day.
One drop. Thank you.
Um‐hm.
What's the matter?
‐ Benzene.
‐ What?
It's benzene.
Don't you smell it?
Probably just stripping
the floors.
Stripping floors with benzene?
I don't think so.
‐ It's much too toxic.
‐ Um‐hm.
Ah, Doctor, before I go
...find out where
that smell is coming from
as quick as possible.
'Set up oxygen.
Pulse is weak and thready.'
Bilateral wheezes.
‐ What's going on?
‐ 'Chemical spill.'
Yosh, bag these clothes up
and get them outside.
'Take slow, deep breaths.'
'You want me to call your wife?'
You might be here a while.
We need fans in here.
I'll call Maintenance.
Get housekeeping to clean up..
‐ 'Give me a hand!'
‐ Oh, my God! Wait!
No one touch her
without gloves on.
Her clothes are soaked
through with this stuff.
Ready? One, two, three!
‐ Get a mask on her!
‐ 'Pulse ox.'
Roll her on her side.
‐ Don't let her aspirate!
‐ 'Suction.'
Ativan, two milligrams IV, now!
‐ She needs a line.
‐ 'Oh, my God, It's Dr. Weaver!'
Hey, don't walk through those
puddles. It might be benzene.
What is that?
It's a, it's a solvent.
It's toxic.
We don't wanna spread
this stuff around.
Keep this stuff contained.
'I mean let's go
with the Ativan.'
'Need to intubate.'
When we give an order,
it's for a reason!
I'm sorry. But we were so close.
You all could've been killed!
I'd have three deaths
to explain!
Man, I was worried about you!
Leo Leipziger.
Crush injury to the right arm.
BP 90 palp. Pulse 110.
We had a prolonged extrication.
‐ No kidding!
‐ Stay to the right.
We've got an unknown solvent
leaking out from a holding tank.
HazMat's setting up
for decontamination.
Chuny, we need at least
four more
of these to cover
the floor by "Admit."
I'll call Central. Here.
Anna, I want you to check
Ellenhorn's toxicology.
See what it says
about benzene exposure.
‐ Got it.
‐ Where to?
Uh‐h, Trauma 1.
Let's move the sickest patients
away from this stuff, double‐bag
all of the contaminated
clothes. Put them outside.
Heads up. Let's get the clean
patients to the back hall.
I'll cover them.
Randi, grab their charts now!
You guys need to air
this place out.
‐ Did you call HazMat?
‐ They're on the way.
There's another one
of these puppies
in the maintenance closet.
We'll blow that stuff
out of here in no time.
No, no, no! Don't plug that in!
Any sparks might
ignite the fumes.
‐ Great.
‐ Jerry, give me a phone!
Okay, what's the ETA on HazMat?
You gotta find that
disaster manual, Jerry.
I need surgical drapes,
the waterproof ones.
‐ 'Okay.'
‐ Yeah, better send a dozen.
Dispatch,
this is County General ER.
They'll be here
in less than five!
No, this is an emergency!
‐ Send the drapes up now!
‐ Wait, I need oxygen.
Yes, we're closing down to all
paramedic. No, immediately!
Hang in there, Leo.
Carol, I've gotta
major trauma patient.
‐ What's going on here?
‐ Benzene!
There's fumes all over the place
contaminating patients.
No, no, no, Dr. Corday
we're moving everybody out.
This man needs pre‐op labs
chest X‐ray,
peritoneal lavage
and immediate surgery
to re‐vascularize his arm.
Okay, take him
to the back hall.
‐ I'll call X‐ray.
‐ In the hall?
Malik. I want you
to prep that guy for a lavage.
‐ Notify the OR.
‐ You got it.
Where are you taking me?
What are we doing in the hall?
No, no, no, get outta
here! Get outta here.
There are fumes are coming
off the grills of the gurney!
I want to get out of here!
Where are my clothes?
‐ What happened to Randi?
‐ I don't know. She's fainted.
‐ You hit the lobby?
‐ Alright, Let's go!
‐ Clean patients only!
‐ How do we know who's clean?
‐ Hold, hold!
‐ Is Randi contaminated?
If it's on her clothes
she is, alright, let's move.
‐ Elizabeth, you okay?
‐ Yes, I'm fine, a bit messy.
But my patient's critical.
Where are we going?
'If the CEO's in a meeting,
get me her assistant.'
I'm‐I'm in full
disaster mode. I need a high..
Three victims from the blast
hole, decontaminated scene.
‐ What's the hell is this?
‐ You can't come in here.
‐ The ER's contaminated.
‐ What happened?
They just showed up
covered in benzene.
Okay, someone,
clear out the lobby!
You shouldn't have let them in!
You didn't control the scene.
They came in‐in a pick up truck!
Move this gurney out of the way!
‐ You just need to move!
‐ 'Move! Just move!'
'Okay, somebody
clear out the lobby!'
'Send them to Mercy
or something!'
Alright, everybody shut up!
‐ Everybody shut up!
‐ Send them to Mercy!
We're going to evacuate
the entire ER!
Check every room.
All contaminated
patients and staff
go to the ambulance
bay right now!
Well, now, how do we know
who's contaminated?
If you got a spot on your skin,
if you got a spot on your gurney
if you got a spot on your
clothes go outside right now!
You gotta move,
move now, move!
Let's move out.
Let's get him out
‐ Let's get her out.
‐ Dr. Weaver, how you doing?
Her seizing stopped.
She's postictal.
No, I‐I'm not going
outside without my jacket!
Can you get some blankets
for these people?
Anna, any non‐urgent cases we
should send home right now.
If you need stitches or if you
need X‐rays, go to the lobby!
Let me have this for a second.
How many critical
patients do we have?
‐ Right here.
‐ I got three, I got three.
Right here in the ambulance
bay, right here.
Seven, eight.
There's three outside.
That's 11.
All critical patients
should move to the, um..
...uh...go to,
go to the cafeteria.
‐ The cafeteria is big enough.
‐ Let's go.
Let's stock it
full of portable monitors
and all the oxygen cylinders
that we can find, okay, that's
where we're moving, so that's
where we're going. Let's go!
It's not advisable to move
the machine during dialysis.
Happens during a power failure.
This thing run off a battery?
No battery.
There's a hand crank.
Then start cranking.
Doc, pedes unit has a bed.
Alright. Get her ready.
Joint Admission Protocols
Quality Assessment
and Improvements.
Jerry, what are you doing?
I need Ellenhorn.
Um, check under the stack.
I'm looking
for the disaster manual.
It's gotta be here somewhere.
‐ Anna, what does it say?
‐ Uh, hold on, I just found it.
Hey, Carter, what about
Policy and Procedures?
‐ Maybe something in here that‐‐
‐ No, no, no, forget it.
Listen, go to the admit desk
grab all the charts
and take them
to Dr. Benton in the cafeteria.
‐ I'm sure there's probably‐‐
‐ Run, Jerry, to the cafeteria!
I got it,
it's under Hydrocarbons.
"Excreted in urine
as sulfate conjugates‐‐"
No, no, we don't need that.
Let's go
to Clinical Presentation.
Pulmonary System.
"Coughing, choking,
pulmonary edema
"where aspiration occurs."
I think that guy Manny aspirated
I don't think Weaver did.
Central Nervous System,
"inhalation displaces oxygen
"causing depressing sodium
lestogene
"and rarely, seizures from
hypoxia."
Supportive Care.
"Only treat with oxygen."
‐ That's what we're doing.
‐ She should be okay.
Alright, let's move
this table over here
up against the wall. Let's go!
Doctor, don't push it.
You're scratching my floor!
You, help him,
get it over there.
You do not order my people
around, you talk to me‐‐
The outlets.
Where are the outlets at?
Along that wall and that wall.
Alright, alright,
everybody, listen up!
Listen up, now, when
I call out the patient's name
give me their diagnosis.
Arteburn?
Uh, right here. Rule out Ml.
Alright, let's get him
over here. Center aisle.
‐ Nguyen?
‐ Shock, respiratory failure.
Alright, up against the wall.
He's gonna need a vent.
‐ Okay.
‐ W‐W‐W...where are you going?
I can't wait, Peter,
I need pre‐op labs
I need X‐ray
and I need to get him cleaned
and up to the OR.
Williams!
We gotta get some heat out
here or we're gonna freeze.
HazMat. What's up?
There's a benzene spill inside.
These patients are contaminated.
‐ We need some shelter.
‐ We'll set them up out here.
Keep 'em covered.
Hey, take these to the cafeteria
and set up a portable suction.
‐ Where's the spill?
‐ On the other side of the desk.
We're evacuating.
Right. That means everyone,
you too, doctor, uh?
‐ C...Carter.
‐ Captain Dannaker.
We're setting up a decon
in the ambulance bay.
Okay, we‐we're not
quite finished stocking
the ambulance bay and cafeteria
with medical supplies.
Our people will get
you everything you need.
Get everyone out now. You're not
gonna know what to look for.
You won't even know where
to find it, give me five minutes
I'll clear you the whole place.
‐ You got two!
‐ Okay!
Hey, Chuny, grab a crash cart
defibrillator
and a bunch of mayo stands.
‐ Right!
‐ You guys okay in here?
‐ Yup.
‐ Okay.
Hey Chuny, get a lot of saline.
Lots of it. Anybody in Exam 4?
'Carter, I need you down here.'
Inga Paulson,
coronary artery disease
congestive heart failure,
on dopamine and heparin drip.
‐ Help me move her out.
‐ Okay, I'll do it.
I need you take ACLS
drugs to the cafeteria.
Grab the biggest cart that
you can find and load it full.
You're gonna
move her and bag her?
Yeah. Just go, go, go!
Don't worry, Inga. We're gonna
get you out of here, okay?
This is ridiculous!
It's not gonna work.
There's not enough room.
Think we'll be better
off in the cafeteria.
No, I need her
in the ICU, alright.
Let's pull the lines
and close the circuit.
Stop cranking
so I can disconnect.
There's a liter of her blood's
in that machine, Doug.
I'm aware of that.
We should go
to the cafeteria now.
Hang on.
Alright. Now we got a loop.
Alright, start cranking
again. You come with me.
You take the other elevator
and meet us at PICU.
Keep cranking, don't let
that blood clot, let's go.
Good, Inga. Big squeeze
every three seconds.
Doing fine.
This is the last one.
It's all yours.
‐ Get moving.
‐ What the hell?
A fire alarm. I'll deal with it.
Dannaker here.
Get me the fire control room.
What's that?
Fire alarm. Hang on.
Ah.
Wow, I lost the bag!
‐ Can you stabilize the tube?
‐ I‐I, I got it, I got it, yeah.
‐ What did you push?
‐ Nothing. I..
'What the hell's going on?'
It's elevator recall,
we're going down to the lobby.
It happens during emergencies.
Sophie, you okay?
Why have we stopped?
I don't know. How's her oxygen?
She's got two‐thirds of a tank.
20 minutes left.
Look at this.
Look, look at that!
Think they'll hear that?
Yeah, they'll hear it.
Damn.
‐ Excuse me. You're a doctor?
‐ Yes, I am.
I have to find my daughter.
She is a patient in the ER.
They won't let me in.
‐ Okay, um..
‐ You can't be here, ma'am.
‐ Ma'am, you can't‐‐
‐ No! Somebody help me!
You should check
in the cafeteria.
‐ She might be in there, okay?
‐ Let go of me.
Captain Dannaker?
Copy. No fire
verified on floor two.
Fire patrol, do a reset.
False alarm. Somebody smelled
fumes and panicked.
Jeanie...Jeanie,
why are we outside?
It's okay, Kerry, we're gonna
taking you to the cafeteria.
‐ Is she okay?
‐ A few wheezes.
‐ She's still altered.
‐ It's not from the benzene.
It's from the seizures.
She should be fine.
Some patients might need medical
attention before they go inside.
Your tents in the cold zone.
‐ Cold zone?
‐ Out here.
In there's the warm zone.
That's where we clean them.
Nobody goes in there
without a suit.
Same goes for the ER,
that is a hot zone.
‐ Are you Carter?
‐ Yeah.
Harriet Spooner,
VP of Operations.
Tonight,
I'm the incident commander.
Did you evacuate
the ER to the cafeteria?
Yeah.
The disaster plan calls
for evacuation
to Physical Therapy.
Well, it got a little chaotic
in there. We had to improvise.
We have an elevator
stuck between floors.
I'll find the building engineer.
‐ Is anybody on it?
‐ I dunno, the phone's dead.
The alarm's gone off.
Just keep your eye on it.
Now listen, Sophie?
We're going
on a little adventure.
'You are gonna
be fine and will have'
'a cool stories
to tell your friends about.'
Multifocal PVCs.
Let me see this.
Potassium's too high.
Push an amp of bicarb.
Buy us a little time.
Gotta run of seven, three.
Here, take it.
Bicarb. She'll be
going into V‐tach.
We don't have any.
Did you check the box?
You can't...you can't treat
hyp‐hyperkaliemia
without‐without bicarb.
It wasn't my idea
to move her like this.
Put a..
‐ So‐you can't..
‐ It's okay. It's okay, Sophie.
Alright,
what do you have in there?
Alright. We got epi, atropine.
How about lidocaine?
Lid‐alright,
I'll take lidocaine.
Uh, uh, 50 mg bolus,
and five every five minutes.
‐ Alright, alright.
‐ How's the oxygen?
Ten minutes.
You'll be fine.
Lavage is negative.
Let's get him up to the OR.
Hey, transport! Give us a hand.
Dr. Weaver?
I'm sorry. Have we met?
You're my doctor.
We should let her rest.
We got two more vents coming
down. Who gets the first one?
Um, let's start with Inga.
Are you sure, Inga?
It could be awhile.
Carter, where's your Attending?
Uh, Dr. Weaver's over here.
Listen, do you need
more nurses down here?
‐ Yes, we do.
‐ Alright.
I can float you
three from the ICU.
Kerry?
Harriet. Now, what,
what is going on?
I am so sorry,
I had no idea you were
debilitated by the incident.
What incident?
Kerry, remember I told you
there was a toxic spill?
Is she gonna be alright?
Yeah, lack of oxygen
caused a seizure.
But, we don't expect
any long‐term effects.
Uh, we'll
this is the action packet
for the chief medical officer
which I guess
for the moment, is you.
Here's a walkie.
I'm on channel four.
I'll‐I'll check
in with you in half an hour.
I've got to get back
to deal with the elevator.
Did you get the people out?
Yeah, the repairman's
on the way.
It'll shouldn't be
more than an hour.
'Where there two sets of doors?'
Yeah. Could you get your body
in here when I get it opened?
Doug, I can't. I gotta bag her.
Reach in! Get your body in here.
‐ Right there.
‐ Alright.
‐ Hang on.
‐ Ah!
‐ Watch your knee. Go.
‐ I got it.
Hang on, alright,
we've got two and a half feet
short of the floor.
‐ Hang on.
‐ Doug!
There's gotta be
a latch up here.
Doug, come down from there.
What if it starts to moves?
Well, you don't have
to worry about commitment.
‐ I'm serious, Doug.
‐ I got it. Right there.
‐ 'Oh.'
‐ Pull it. Give me another pull.
‐ 'What's that?'
‐ Oh, man.
It's not the EKG.
It's her pulse ox.
‐ How's her oxygen?
‐ The O2 sat's down to 89.
Oh, God! Sophie? Sophie?
‐ Alright, I got it.
‐ She's unresponsive!
‐ 'Anybody in there?'
‐ Yeah, here.
We got a little girl in here!
Got that? Okay.
Hold that there. We need oxygen!
‐ Get us out of here!
‐ We don't have time! Let's go!
'Get that box out,
we need oxygen right away.'
‐ Got it?
‐ Yeah.
Doug, it's not gonna
go any further than that!
Come on! Yeah,
It's gonna work. Hang on.
Watch your fingers. Hang on.
‐ Alright.
‐ Ouch.
‐ You alright?
‐ Yeah.
Okay, hang on.
Hold it, hold it
right there. Try this.
‐ Alright.
‐ It's not gonna open.
It's gonna open!
Come here.
Guys get your hands in here.
Grab hold!
Uh, alright, guys.
One, two, three!
‐ She needs oxygen!
‐ Got it. Got it.
Hook her up.
Go.
Ah! Here's our
little action hero.
How does it look?
Like ground beef. No, actually
more like chopped liver.
Yeah, but you think we have
a chance for limb salvage?
You want my honest opinion?
No, I don't think you do.
Well, I'd like
to give it our best shot.
You got it, Lizzie.
No holds barred. 110 percent.
‐ Can you feel this?
‐ Ah, it's kind of numb.
Is that bad?
Well, It means
the leg is getting tense.
I've got to measure
the internal pressure.
Transducer's up in the ER.
HazMat will never find it.
Alright, well,
then I need an 18‐gauge needle
IV tubing and a BP manometer.
You got it.
Then I watched them put you
on a gurney and give you oxygen.
Then what happened?
They moved me from
a yellow room to a green room.
That would be Trauma 2.
But where was I at that time?
Well, then they brought
you into the yellow room.
That's where they
removed all of your clothes
and put them
into a plastic bag.
‐ Two more to go.
‐ What about the ER?
It's gonna take awhile.
Is there a doctor around?
‐ Yeah, right here.
‐ It's kinda hard to breathe.
‐ I'll be right with you
‐ No. Suits only.
Suit me up. He's in trouble.
Even if you were certified
it'd take you
15 minutes to suit up.
‐ He'll be out before that.
‐ Doc, do something!
You're not gonna let me
in there? This guy could die.
‐ Mike, give him oxygen!
‐ Morrie!
He's not talking,
doc, do something!
Get me an airway kit now!
Give him
a little more minute, doc.
You can tube him
as soon as he comes out.
'Morrie! Morrie!
'Help him!'
'Do something! Help him!'
‐ That's pretty stupid.
‐ 'Do something for Morrie!'
'Morrie!'
He's dirty now. Let him do it.
‐ Anybody here an EMT?
‐ I'm a medic.
‐ You bag him when I'm done.
‐ You got it.
I'm in.
‐ Scrub him.
‐ Let's go, doc.
‐ Let's go.
‐ Wait.
'Dr. Carter. Dr. Carter.
Come in, Dr. Carter.'
Whoa‐whoa‐whoa,
I need to talk to her.
I got you covered, doc.
How's he doing?
He's picking up. Looks good.
Great.
‐ 60‐70.
‐ Wh‐what does that mean?
Uh, the pressure's too high
from the bleeding
inside your leg.
‐ We need to operate to‐‐
‐ Dr. Benton.
Dr. Del Amico, I
need you over here.
Jerry, book a room!
Charging to 200.
Clear!
Still in fib.
Alright, charge to 300.
Clear!
'Can we take him inside?'
Uh, in a minute.
Hey, what about my shoes?
Ernie, take care
of Dr. Carter.
SAT's up to 98.
He's waking up.
Yeah, sounds pretty good.
I think you're gonna
be okay, Morris.
Dr. Carter?
No, man, real shoes.
Malik.
‐ Help us move him inside.
‐ 'Hold up a minute.'
They're coding some old lady
in the cafeteria.
Chuny, I said charge
it to 360, let's go.
Wait a second
it takes time.
The battery's
low, okay.
Alright.
Clear!
Asystole, how long
we've been at this?
18 minutes.
She never had a rhythm,
never had a pulse.
That's it.
Time of death, 22:09.
Peter, OR's ready
for Krakowski.
Uh, I've got a
fasciotomy, alright.
See if you can
find her family.
Did that lady just die?
I mean, is she dead?
Oh, then, they're not gonna
leave her there, are they?
Alright, where are
the pre‐op labs?
‐ Right here.
‐ How long will I be in a cast?
Four to six weeks.
Anna's running the code?
Yeah, but you know
what we just..
Five rounds of epi,
two of atropine
lidocaine..
Uh, bretylium,
amiodarone..
I should've had
her up in the ICU.
'Wouldn't have made
a difference.'
Might've.
No, you turned this
place into an ICU.
This isn't an ICU.
This is just something
we threw together.
She was strong, this
shouldn't have happened.
Take a look at her chart
inoperable triple vessel
disease.
'It was only a
matter of time.'
Mr. Arteburn, you okay?
Dizzy, very dizzy.
Supraventricular tachycardia.
'Adenosine, uh..'
‐ Six milligrams IV.
‐ We don't have any.
Jerry, run to the
pharmacy we need it.
Carter, do you need some help?
Jeanie, see if you can
help out Dr. Weaver there.
‐ Take it easy.
‐ Pulse is weak, and thready.
Any chest pain,
Mr. Arteburn?
We can't wait for the Adenosine.
We gotta cardiovert.
Uh, Lily, grab a crash cart.
Let's get him into
trendelenburg.
I'll try carotid
sinus massage.
‐ Yosh.
‐ Yeah.
‐ Can you get a BP?
‐ Got it.
Lily, charge to 100.
Mr. Arteburn? Mr. Arteburn!
‐ He's unresponsive.
‐ Come on, Lily.
‐ Give me those paddles.
‐ I can't.
‐ The battery's dead.
‐ I'll find an extension cord.
No, no, wait, there's
an outlet, right there.
Help me push it
to the wall.
'Move that gurney
out of the way.'
'BP's 60 palp.'
He's not moving much air.
'I got to tube him.'
Carter! Carter!
'Jeanie, get ready
to start CPR.'
I need an intubation tray.
Carter!
Lily, as soon
as you get power
we need to move him
against the wall.
Get over here, Carter.
John, I need you to bag him.
Almost ready.
Hold that.
Normal sinus rhythm.
What the hell are you people
doing to me? Give me a towel.
You passed out from an
abnormal heart rhythm.
We had to treat you
right away.
‐ By drowning me?
‐ The diving reflex.
It slows the heart down,
breaks the tachycardia.
You call this is the
highest standard of care?
Get my...get my doctor
on the phone now.
I got the adenosine.
We're okay.
I'll meet you in recovery
in a few minutes.
I want to be there
when he comes around.
‐ Alright.
‐ Okay?
‐ Yes.
‐ Elizabeth.
Hello, Peter.
I'll be right there.
Oh, your eye
looks worse.
It's nothing, I'm sure it looks
nastier than it really is.
Uh, let me have
a look anyway.
You could have,
uh, hyphema.
So, I heard about
the big rescue.
Uh‐huh.
You were under a
collapsed building?
Yep, went to a lot
to avoid an amputation
but we had to take
his arm anyway.
‐ Esk, ow!
‐ Okay?
‐ You okay.
‐ Mm‐hmm.
I have to tell Leo about
his arm when he wakes up.
What about you?
You on call tonight?
I've got a fasciotomy.
After that, I'm free.
I could do with
some debriefing.
Take a deep breath in.
Now blow out.
Good.
Can we get a blood gas
in about 20 minutes.
Throat's sore.
‐ Give her some water.
‐ Yeah, here you go.
That was pretty
scary, wasn't it?
No, no, we do that kind
of thing here every day.
No, you were scared.
Tell the truth.
Yeah, I was pretty scared.
I was really scared.
Honey, I've been
looking all over for you.
‐ Is she okay?
‐ Yeah, she's fine.
I heard about the fumes.
‐ 'Was she exposed?'
‐ She was on a ventilator.
So her lungs weren't exposed.
‐ She was never in any danger?
‐ No, mom.
They took really
good care of me.
‐ Excuse me, the ER.
‐ Mm‐hmm, okay.
Dr. Lemley, if you'll..
I'll come back, and check
up on your lil' bit.
You're in good
hands so, okay?
‐ Thank you.
‐ You're welcome.
Carol, hey.
You know, we should get pharmacy
to restock the drug box.
Sure.
So, you still mad at me
about this morning?
I was mad?
You accused me
of spying on you.
I never said that.
That's what you meant.
No, I was annoyed.
You don't need
to check up on me.
I wasn't.
I just wanted to see
you last night.
Me, too.
So we shouldn't let that
happen too often, should we?
Well, I actually think
we shouldn't let
that happen
at all, but..
Here goes nothing.
Okay, Mr. Arteburn
let's put you down
into curtain one.
Lily, take Manny, and
put him in curtain two.
‐ Chuny, Morris, 2‐B.
‐ Carter.
'Carter, I can
take it from here.'
Anna, take the sickest
patients and put
them in the trauma rooms
and curtain three.
‐ Got it.
‐ Hey, Jeanie.
I‐I like you, and Jerry
to update the board, and
get the phones back
where they belong.
‐ You okay?
‐ Yeah, I'm fine.
Uh, Carter, I spoke with Harriet
Spooner, the incident commander
and I'd like to thank
you for helping me out.
And, uh, the administration
would like you
to speak with the press.
'We'll meet them
together in the'
'first floor conference
room at 11:15.'
Well, in terms of dealing
with these people
I think I've had a
little more experience.
You know, it‐it's important
that the emphasis‐‐
Nope! Morris get's that vent!
It's important that the
emphasis, emphasis be placed
on the institutional
response to the crisis
as opposed to any
individual act which they
would tend
to sensationalize.
I think it's best
to say, simply that we
'followed a well‐rehearsed
disaster plan, and'
'worked in concert
with the HazMat team'
'to ensure the safety
of our patients'
and also of the medical staff.
Carter, the fire captain wants
to speak with you outside.
Oh, right.
Uh, 11:15?
‐ That's right.
‐ I'll be there.
Dr. Weaver, I've looked at
some of the causative factors
and I believe that I can
now identify those at blame.
Jerry, what are
you talking about?
Well, I've been on night's,
and during that time
the day unit service
coordinators have
really let the central
work area deteriorate.
Jerry, this was
a chemical spill.
Yes, and‐and we were
impaired because we were
unable to find this
important manual.
I'm just saying that now
that I'm back on days
you can count on a higher
level of efficiency
at the central work area.
If you pass out again I'll have
everything under control.
'Dr. Carter.'
Want these back?
'No. Souvenir.'
So, how do you think your
people handled things?
Oh, pretty good.
No, it was a
total disaster.
You guys were caught
with your pants down.
But, uh, you, you
personally did okay
under the circumstances.
I think you're the
guy to work with
on a schedule
of disaster drills.
Oh, I don't have that
kind of authority.
I'm, uh, just an intern.
You had me fooled.
You should talk
to our chief of staff.
It was good
working with you.
‐ Hey, Carter.
‐ Hey!
'When did you get back?'
Came straight
from the airport.
I'm on in five minutes.
It's good to see you.
How's your mom?
She's doing better.
What's with the boots?
It's kind of a long story.