- Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah,
yup, right here.
Yup, yup, copy.
We'll be ready.
Okay, trauma is
a minute out,
including
a uniformed CPD officer.
I need rooms, people.
Rooms, stat.
Treatment 3, talk to me.
- Wrapped up the frostbite.
Just waiting on
a discharge order.
- Okay, Dr. Choi?
- Got it.
But first, guy got spooked
in the ladies room.
Gotta get the skin
out of his zipper.
- All right, people.
I got a waiting room
full of snot,
and I have traumas en route.
No room for coddling, people.
Let's go, let's go,
let's go.
Incoming!
- 18 year-old male,
GCS 12, tachy's to 130.
Suspected DUI, parked his Beemer
in someone's living room,
broke the gas line,
started a fire.
- Okay.
Dr. Rhodes, you got this?
- Got it.
- Thank you.
- X-ray!
- Talk to me.
- GCS 6, BP 12O over 80,
King airway in the field.
- All right, Dr. Choi,
Dr. Reese, now.
You're going to Trauma 2.
- He's hypoxic.
Inhaled a lot of smoke.
- All right, rotate.
- I pulled the driver,
the kid,
- My partner insisted
on clearing the house.
- Draw trauma labs, an ABG,
and a carboxyhemoglobin.
On my count.
- Thank you, officer.
- One, two, three.
I'll take over.
- Let's start a saline line.
Let's get him set up.
- Tough to bag him.
He's pretty spasmed down.
I need suction.
20 of Etomidate
and 100 of succs now.
We need a better airway.
- On it, prepping succs.
Watch his BP.
Heartrate's still tachy.
- Bilateral pubic rami fractures
on the x-ray.
Let's FAST him.
- Pressure's dropping.
- There's free fluid
in his belly.
Possible pelvic hematoma.
All right, let's get him
up to the OR now.
Start two units
of rapid transfuser.
Put trauma and angio on standby.
- Mm-hmm.
- Let's go.
He's not going anywhere
till I get a DUI blood draw.
We're charging him.
- His belly is shredded.
If I don't operate right now,
you're not gonna have
- You already have him
on IV fluids.
I got ten minutes, at best,
to get an accurate
blood-alcohol level.
You take him to the OR,
it'll be too late.
- The officer wants
to do a draw
to test your blood-alcohol
content.
Do I have your consent?
- No.
- There's your answer.
- State law says
I don't need consent.
- Go.
- Hospital policy says you do.
- You need to stop--
- Move, move. Hey, uh-uh.
- My partner could've died
back there.
You step aside.
Our priority is to treat
patients, not to make arrests.
As soon as he's out of surgery
and awake, he's all yours.
- Get me that blood,
or you're under arrest.
- Obstructing
a police investigation.
- You're being ridiculous.
- Get me that blood.
- Do what you have to do.
- Maggie, Maggie...
- Take the phone.
- You don't have to do this.
- Stay back.
- I don't know.
He wanted you to ignore
her DNR, didn't he?
- It was complicated.
Everything happened so fast.
- Dr. Halstead,
we've been over this.
If you say that
at your deposition,
are gonna have your job
and your medical license.
- But that is not
what happened.
- Look, it is my job
is to protect this hospital,
and we have a strong case.
Now, Jennifer Baker is enrolled
in a promising drug trial.
That is not the behavior
of a woman who's ready to die.
And in order to win this case,
we need to point that out.
- Peter, we need an approach
that can both maintain
Dr. Halstead's integrity
and help our case.
- Okay, look,
if Sal Baker was as conflicted
as you've said,
might one infer
that at least a part of him
wanted his wife to live?
- Yes.
[phone ringing]
- Just wait.
- Goodwin.
I'm on my way.
Yes, thank you.
I just got off the phone
with the 21st district.
They're stonewalling.
- They're still holding her?
I can't believe that.
That's outrageous.
- Yeah, I'm going down there.
April, tag in for Maggie.
Get my waiting room cleared.
- Me? I got--
- I paged the on-call.
with the same flu
as all those people
in the waiting area.
Don't worry.
You got this.
- Okay.
- Let me grab a coat
and come with.
We all know
what happens when you
back a wild animal
into a corner.
- Maggie needs a friend,
not a shrink.
- I wasn't talking about Maggie.
- Well, I'm fine.
I'm just going to have
a little conversation
with Voight, see if
there's anything he can do.
By the way, you need
to change your shirt.
Coffee stain.
And where's your tie?
- Hmm, I must've
got dressed in a hurry.
Good luck.
- Let's see.
43-year-old migraine patient,
Treatment 1.
Dr. Choi?
- Copy that.
- All right, uh...
Reese, Treatment 3,
guy got clipped by a car
while crossing the street.
- Aye, captain.
- Help! My baby!
Somebody help!
- Got it.
[baby crying]
- She's been fussy
and crying all morning,
but every time I try
to put her down for a nap,
she just--she just wails.
I'm telling you,
something's really wrong.
- Her color's good.
She's responding
to external stimuli.
Who's your pediatrician?
- Um, uh, uh, Dr. Simon
at Advocate South.
- All right, April, let's get
those records sent over.
- Copy.
- It's okay.
- All right,
her ears are fine.
Looks like
retinal hemorrhages.
Could she have hit her head
on something?
- No, I don't--
I don't think so.
- All right, let's order
a babygram and head CT.
- I'll let them know
you're on the way.
- Don't worry, I'm going
to take really good care
of your baby, all right?
- Okay.
- Don't worry.
April?
[baby cries]
- You think I look bad?
You should've seen the car.
- Ah.
[both chuckling]
Let's take a look at that leg.
- I was rushing to my 11:00.
On my cell phone,
which I know is a horrible idea.
Didn't even look
before crossing the street.
I mean, it's totally my bad.
But still, whatever happened
to pedestrians
having the right of way?
- Mm, that's why
I take the bus.
Does it hurt
when I press here?
- No, not much.
- You don't get extra points for
tolerating pain, Mr. Dietrich.
- It's not bad.
It just clipped me
as I was jumping out
of the way, really.
- Well, good news is,
it doesn't appear to be broken.
But there is fluid
on your knee.
I think we should have
ortho take a look.
- Is that really necessary?
I've got to file an emergency
motion before lunch.
- I understand,
but we can't release you
without a complete workup.
I play tennis
with Bernie Goldstein,
Chief of Orthopedics
over at Northwestern.
If you can just brace my leg
and get me on some crutches,
for an office visit
first thing tomorrow morning.
- Make your appointment.
I'll check with my attending.
- Great.
Thanks.
- [exhales]
- Hi.
- I-I can wait
for the next one.
- Sorry, just needed to go out
for a quick smoke.
That's not the first time
I've got that look.
Don't worry, I didn't smoke
when I was pregnant.
- Well, you know, there is
also secondhand smoke--
- Yeah, or around the baby.
- Okay.
- I'm sorry.
Sorry.
It's just, uh--
it's just the stress.
It's been really tough
these last few months.
- Is there anyone
you'd like to call?
Maybe Grace's father, or--
- I wouldn't know
who to call.
- You don't know
who the father is?
- It's not so much
a matter of who.
It's more which.
There were a couple guys.
because they all bailed
when I told them I was pregnant,
so--and then my parents,
they thought I should terminate.
'Cause, you know,
"A baby needs a father."
But no, no,
I just--I couldn't.
So here we are...
The two of us,
just doing the best we can.
- Chicago Med
has a strict policy
against forcible blood draws.
- I got that.
Maggie might've been
following hospital procedure,
but from patrol's
point of view,
she obstructed
a time-sensitive investigation.
- And if we had delayed
that operation,
we could have put
that boy's life in jeopardy.
- Did you come here to argue
or ask a favor?
Listen, Windham told me
that kid was doing
close to 80 in a 25 zone.
And that house he hit--
there was
a family inside.
If they can't get
DUI charges to stick,
that kid is gonna post
and be back behind the wheel
in a couple of days.
They're not happy.
that one of my people
is sitting behind bars?
- Sharon,
you overestimate my pull.
- Hank, it's Maggie
that's in there.
And I'm asking you
as a friend,
find a way to get her out.
- Look, they're not gonna
release her
until after she's been
processed and arraigned.
I'll see if I can have her
moved up on the docket,
but other than that,
there's nothing I can do.
- Can I at least see her?
[indistinct chatter]
- Maggie?
- Sharon.
- Girl, I am so sorry.
- Hey, you got five minutes.
- So I guess you're not here
to take me home.
Voight said they can't release
you until you've been arraigned.
- They're actually
gonna charge me for this?
- Kalmick's got
the gloves off.
of getting the charges dropped
or at least reduced.
- Hell, I was doing my job.
- You handled the situation
exactly as I would've.
That blood draw
would've left the hospital
open for litigation.
Next time to fill out
a credit application,
that's what I'll tell them
when they ask me,
"Have you ever been arrested?"
- Maggie, we're gonna get you
through this.
- You better.
- Okay.
- Dr. Manning.
- Yeah?
- A word.
- Sure.
- Not only
retinal hemorrhages,
but we found a subdural hematoma
and cerebral edema.
- The classic diagnostic triad.
This is a case
of Shaken Baby Syndrome.
- Is there any other caregiver
in the baby's life?
A nanny,
her father?
- Nope.
She did this.
- And Dr. Grant agrees
with your diagnosis
of Shaken Baby Syndrome?
- She does.
We both reviewed
Grace's CT scans.
The findings are consistent
with the neuropathological
triad of SBS.
any other explanation
for the symptoms?
- I cannot draw any other
conclusion here
other than child abuse.
- [sighs]
Dr. Manning, once I pick up
that phone and notify DCFS,
it's out of our hands.
- A mother
intentionally harmed her child.
I think it's
the right call to make.
- Hey, how'd the surgery
with the DUI kid go?
at the dome of the bladder,
so it took a while to repair.
Uh, where's Maggie?
I was wondering
if she got ahold
of the kid's parents yet.
- You didn't hear?
Maggie got arrested.
after we took the kid upstairs,
they couldn't get the blood
and charged her
with obstruction.
I know.
Goodwin's working on
getting her cut loose.
- Ms. Reese,
beautiful day, right?
- I guess,
it's kinda cold.
- Hey, hey, is that for
the gentleman in 3?
- Yeah, Kevin Dietrich.
- You know what?
Those buckles are actually
a lot trickier than they look.
How about if I give you
a little hand?
- Okay, sure.
- Mr. Dietrich,
I'm Dr. Charles.
- Hey.
- How are you?
- Good, good.
- I have come
to render an assist
with this deceptively
tricky brace.
- Sure.
[chuckles]
Chief of Psychiatry?
- Technically, yeah.
Today, more like Chief
of Physical Therapy.
I blew out my knee out on
the slopes a couple years ago,
got stuck with one of
these suckers for a few months.
The trick is the buckles.
- Okay.
Great, good to know.
Thank you.
- So, uh,
how'd you do this?
- Oh, just one
of those mornings,
completely overbooked.
Point is,
I was running late--
- And on your cell phone.
- Right, I was on the phone
with my insurance broker--
need to up our homeowner's.
Anyway, so I stepped
out into the crossing,
tried to jump out of the way
but couldn't.
So, boom, I'm on the ground.
[chuckles]
- Wow, hell of a morning.
- Yeah, well, I'm just thankful
for the intrepid Ms. Reese here
for patching me up
so I can get on with my day.
- You know, you can't
really drive like this.
So what--should we
call your wife?
- No, no, the--
I just mean she's really busy.
- Ah.
- Billed nearly 80 hours
last week.
So I don't want to bother her
with something like this.
- Great.
Nice to meet ya.
- Yeah, a pleasure.
Thank you.
- Ms. Reese,
could I just see you for a sec?
- [mouthing]
- Could you do me a favor
and give me a heads up
before you discharge
Mr. Dietrich?
- Okay.
- Thank you.
- Ahh.
- Okay, good.
All right, we'll get her back
as soon as possible.
- You're Mommy's doctor.
You saved her.
- Hi, Bailey.
What are you doing down here?
- I need more markers.
- Do your parents
know where you are?
- Uh-uh.
- I'm sorry,
we can't have that.
Come with me.
- Hey, Leah,
can you take Bailey
back upstairs
- I can't leave the desk,
but I will find someone who can.
- Okay, thanks.
- I need more colors
for my rainbow.
- Wow, that's very pretty.
- I'm making it for Mommy,
to make her feel better.
- Has she been sick?
- Real sick.
- Did something happen,
Bailey?
- She had to get a shot.
- Okay.
- Dr. Manning,
DCFS just arrived.
- Ms. Fisher,
this is Madeline Gastern
from the Department
of Child and Family Services.
- I'm here to investigate
a possible case of child abuse.
- Child abuse?
What, you think I hurt my baby?
That's crazy.
- We need you to come with us.
- What? No! No, no,
I don't want to leave my baby.
No, you can't do this!
I didn't hurt her!
You can't make me leave my baby!
You can't do this!
I didn't hurt her!
You can't make me
leave my baby!
- Oh, thank you.
- Mm-hmm.
Ah, Dr. Charles, good news.
I'm out of here.
- Before you go, could I
just talk to you for a sec?
- Um--
- Ms. Reese,
do you mind excusing us
for--for just a moment?
- Mm-hmm.
- Thanks.
- Yeah, I really have to go.
- I will not keep you for
more than a minute.
I just want to understand
a little better
what happened this morning.
- I already explained.
It was an accident.
And I'm sorry,
but I'm really late.
- I understand.
You're a very busy man.
Listen,
off-the-wall question.
Have you been...
having a hard time
getting out of bed
in the morning recently?
- No.
I have to go.
Thanks.
- Mr. Dietrich.
- Excuse me.
[clears throat]
- Mr. Dietrich, I'm sorry.
I can't let you
leave just yet.
- What are you
talking about?
- I am not convinced
that it was an accident
when you stepped in front
of that car this morning.
I think you were trying
to kill yourself.
- [laughs] What?
- Dr. Charles.
- And I'm, um...
I'm worried
that you still might be
a suicide risk.
And if you insist on leaving--
- I do.
under a temporary
psychiatric hold.
- [scoffs]
This is ridiculous.
- Well, Earl here is going
to take you someplace quiet.
- I--
- And hopefully we can talk.
- I will sue you
and this entire hospital.
- Thank you, Earl.
- I'll have
your medical license.
You can't--
you can't do this.
- I can, actually.
- What?
- Back to work.
- I've got a charge nurse
in city hospital,
an ongoing child-abuse
investigation,
and now you bring me this?
- He tried to commit
suicide, Sharon.
I wasn't about to let
it happen again.
- He's a successful lawyer
with no past history
of depression.
- I know the type, okay?
Look, the way
he recounted what happened,
his need to sell
this way too-detailed version
of the narrative, right?
Look at this x-ray.
He took the impact directly
above the knee--directly.
That means he stood in
and took the brunt.
He wanted to get hit.
- That's conjecture, Daniel.
You're usually not this quick
to make a diagnosis.
- With this condition,
you become a master of disguise.
Just give me a little more time
to see if I can get him
to drop the mask, okay? Okay.
- All right.
Just find a way to do it
without further
complicating my life.
Is there something else?
- I'll sure be glad
when Maggie gets back.
Advocate just sent over
those medical files
you requested on baby Grace.
- Oh, right.
- And I'm sorry it took so long.
They're just as backed up
as we are today.
- Sure.
- Hey.
- Am I gonna be okay?
- Yeah, you are.
Surgery went well.
- Like, totally okay?
I want to be a pilot--
naval aviator.
- Do you realize
what you did today?
Hmm?
- Yeah, yeah, it was stupid.
- Trev, you're awake.
- Hey, Dad.
- Did you say anything
to the police at the scene?
- No.
- Attaboy.
He did the right thing,
refusing the blood draw.
Just talked to Sid Burstyn.
He thinks he might be able
to make this all go away.
so it looks like we can all just
move on, put this behind us.
- Somebody got hurt.
- You must be Dr. Rhodes.
Thank you for everything.
- We'll do
a cystogram next week
to see
how your bladder's healing.
You can schedule it
with radiology.
If you'll excuse me.
God, I wanted to pop that guy.
that same stupid sense
of entitlement.
My DUI kid, he's ruined.
- Connor, look,
we don't get along.
You don't like me.
But I need a favor,
and there's no one else
I can ask.
I have to access some records,
and I can't use
my code to log in.
- Why not?
- Because no one can know
I looked at them.
- You caught me
on the right day.
- Don't tell me; I don't want
to know anything about it.
[typing]
- I realize this is a very
uncomfortable situation, really.
- Do you?
I don't have to talk to you.
- Of course not.
I hope you will.
- What does it matter?
I could tell you
that I'm a happy man,
that I have a perfect life,
which I do.
But you've already got
your mind made up about me.
- Mr. Dietrich,
I don't have my mind
made up about anything.
I am genuinely here
to help.
- Help?
- Yeah.
- No, this is
how you justify yourself.
Look at you.
So smug, so sure of yourself,
like you know me.
You don't know me.
So go ahead, tell me
what my problem is.
- Tell you
what your problem is?
- Yeah, come on.
Enlighten me, Dr. Freud.
- It doesn't really
work that way.
- Okay, wow.
So you don't know,
do you?
This is your job,
and you don't have a clue.
So you've got all those people
fooled out there, huh?
- You know what?
Um, I think we are
hitting a bit
of a wall, so--
- Yeah, you know why?
'Cause I shouldn't be here
in the first place.
- I'll check in
on you later.
- Okay, yup,
hope you've got your malpractice
premiums paid up.
- Dr. Charles,
has he admitted
he tried to kill himself?
- No, he says
he's a happy man
and has a perfect life.
- So what are you
going to do?
[sighs]
- I don't know.
- Great.
Thanks for
letting me know, Hank.
[knock at door]
Come in.
Tell her I'm on my way.
Dr. Rhodes, I hope
you can make this quick.
- I was the one
that kept the cops
from drawing
that kid's blood, not Maggie.
If anybody should
be held responsible, it's me.
And I'm gonna go
turn myself in.
- That's a nice gesture,
but things don't work that way.
Besides, Maggie
just made bail.
I'm going
to pick her up now.
- These are baby Grace's records
from Advocate South.
I made a horrible mistake.
We have to stop DCFS.
- I'll go get Maggie.
- Talk to me.
- So if it's not
Shaken Baby Syndrome--
- Grace suffered
an injury in utero--
an intracranial hemorrhage,
which I believe occurred
when her mother was
in a car accident
at 30 weeks gestation.
- And this happened
before the baby was even born?
- Yes, when her
prenatal ultrasounds
were sent over
from Advocate South,
I showed them to Dr. Heller,
head of radiology.
There's a small hematoma
on the images.
It's easy to miss,
but it is there.
- But wouldn't the doctors
have noticed it at birth?
- It likely healed soon
after the accident,
But even the slightest bump
on the head
or a roll in her crib could have
caused her to re-bleed.
- And mimic the SBS triad.
- Yes.
- Let's go.
[knock at door]
[knocking]
[door opens]
- Dr. Charles?
- Yeah?
- I'm sorry,
but I texted you
and didn't get an answer.
- What is it, Ms. Reese?
- Um, have you been back
to see Mr. Dietrich?
- No, I haven't.
- Oh.
Dr. Charles,
this isn't like you.
I mean, you never give up,
and you always know
what to say.
That's why we all
admire you so much.
- Ms. Reese,
did it occur to you
that you might be
overstepping the bounds
of a fourth-year
medical student?
- I'm sorry.
- [sighs]
- I told you
I didn't hurt her.
- I know.
I am very sorry.
- We all are.
- You people are horrible.
- Ms. Fisher,
please understand,
we were following
hospital protocol.
Whenever there's a case
of suspected abuse,
we have to
take it seriously.
- You started judging me
the second I walked in here.
So does this mean
my Gracie ain't sick?
- No, I'm sorry,
but, symptomatically,
your child is still
in the same condition.
We can't be certain
how her development
might be affected.
We'd like to keep her here
for monitoring--
- No, no, no, no,
I don't want you or anybody else
at this hospital
taking care of my baby.
How soon can I get her
out of here?
- We'll check with Dr. Grant
to see when
she can be discharged.
- I want to go
see her now.
- Of course.
- Mr. Dietrich,
how you doing?
why I think you threw yourself
in front of that car.
It's precisely because
you think you have
the perfect life,
and you're still miserable.
- So, what, I'm an ingrate?
- No, it's called
endogenous depression,
and it's caused
by your brain chemistry.
And like so many people
who suffer from depression,
you're ashamed
to tell anybody about it,
'cause you think
it's your fault.
- [laughs]
Okay, yeah, I'm--I bet.
Sure, sure.
- Okay, look,
why don't you call your wife?
Tell her where you are
and why you're here.
She's an attorney; she can get
you out of here in five minutes.
She knows what to do.
What, you don't want to--
what--
you don't want to call her?
Why? Are you worried
that maybe, if she finds out
that you're not the brave,
strong man she married,
she might not
love you anymore?
Do you know that
the single greatest challenge
that I face is trying
to convince people
that depression isn't
a sign of weakness?
- Okay, I'll remember that
if I'm ever depressed.
- Okay.
[taps the bed]
You know, I got
to hand it to you.
You are--you're one hell
of a performer.
I mean, a real trouper.
I mean, keeping it up
for so long.
You know, selling this idea
of who you think you need to be,
all the time...
Carrying around the weight
of that...performance.
Isn't it tiring?
Aren't you exhausted?
I think it'd be exhausting.
- [soft laugh]
I have absolutely
no excuse to be sad.
- You don't need
an excuse, man.
You're a human being.
- [scoffs]
[crying]
[sniffles]
[cries]
- You're, um...
You're not alone,
Mr. Dietrich.
- [exhales]
- So what's the story?
Sharon didn't need to send
a trauma surgeon to pick me up.
- I wanted to do it.
I felt bad.
- Why, 'cause I'm the one
who got busted?
- Mm.
- Listen, I know you think that,
because you're a trauma surgeon,
But the ED's mine, and nothing
happens in my kingdom
that I don't
take responsibility for.
- You're right,
you're right.
Maybe--the system's rigged...
and it pisses me off.
- Pisses you off?
- I have sat in jail.
My buddy and I--
summer before I went to college,
we got busted trying
to buy drugs
off of an undercover cop.
- You?
- Yeah.
I mean,
come on, at that age,
you think
you're invincible, right?
Turns out,
only one of us was right.
My dad pulled some strings,
and he got me off.
- What about your friend?
- Well, his dad didn't own
a department store.
Turns out the lifeboat
was only big enough
for one of us,
so I had a choice.
I could stand by my friend,
or I could jump in.
So I jumped in the boat.
- I'm honored that
you would share this with me,
but if you want to make amends,
you need to call your friend.
- I can't.
He died of an overdose
before I could--
before I could
work up the nerve.
- Zoe--
- Hey.
- Jennifer Baker had a pulmonary
embolism four days ago.
- How'd you hear that?
- I saw her chart.
- Will, the woman
is suing you.
If you accessed those records,
they'll know.
- Someone did it for me.
- Dr. Manning?
- No.
That's not important.
The records show that
her doctors prescribed heparin
to dissolve the clot.
- So?
for use with the medication
being used in her drug trial.
That means Jennifer's not
on the medication.
She's on the placebo.
- Oh, Will, I'm so sorry.
- She's going to die
if we don't get
Is there anything you can do
to make that happen?
- You know the oncologist
running the trial, right?
Maybe you can petition.
- I-I-I can't.
- All right, then we'll do
something without him knowing.
Like back-date a scan.
- No, Will, please.
God.
Listen, I am asking you
for this--for this one thing,
for me--
to let this go.
- I'm sorry.
I can't.
- [sighs]
- What's wrong with her?
- What's going on?
- She's seizing.
- What's wrong?
Please, help her!
- Get the crash cart
and page Dr. Grant.
What's her Broselow?
- She's pink on the tape.
- Push .7 milligrams
of lorazepam.
- .7, I got it.
- All right, sats are 66.
Start bagging her.
- What's wrong with her?
What's going on?
- She's stopped breathing.
- [sobs]
- Sats are coming up.
- Is she breathing?
- She's postictal
and protecting her airway.
Let's get another head CT
and page pediatric neurology.
- This is what you were
talking about, huh?
- Yes, seizures can be
a part of her condition.
- How long will she have 'em?
- I don't know.
- Her whole life?
[baby crying]
- That woman has a long road
ahead of her.
They both do.
- You know, there are maybe
17 different agencies
ready to jump
in when they suspect abuse.
But who jumps in to help
when it's a single mother
who's struggling?
- You know, she's right.
I did judge her.
And you know why?
Because I can imagine it.
Owen is bawling his head off
at 3:00 in the morning.
and I am exhausted,
and I have no one
I can hand him to.
So yeah, I can imagine it.
- And there isn't a mother
alive who hasn't.
The difference is,
you won't do it.
- And neither did she.
- It's Maggie.
- Look who's back.
- Maggie.
- Dr. Rhodes said
you were covering for me.
- Yes, and thank God
you are back.
- I'm sorry
I couldn't pick you up.
- That's okay.
If he was driving Uber,
he'd get five stars.
- I was worried about you.
- I'm fine.
Why is everybody
standing around?
Back to work, Reese.
Chop chop.
- You're Dr. Rhodes?
- Yeah.
- I had it checked.
Dr. Halstead used your code
to access Jennifer Baker's
records, didn't he?
- Look, I-I didn't--
- I don't care about any of it.
He found out that
she's only on a placebo.
I'm afraid he's
going to tell her.
- I'll handle it.
[panting]
Eighth floor.
Clinical trial wing, seriously?
When I helped you out
earlier,
I didn't think it was
gonna lead to this.
- What do you care?
- Well, I'm not going
to stand by
and watch another guy
ruin his life.
- Hey!
- No.
[alarm ringing]
- You're not gonna stop me.
- Actually, I am.
Hey.
[struggling]
- Damn it!
[grunts]
- You're not supposed
to go near her.
You tell her
she's on a placebo,
that's your license, okay?
- She can go home!
- You're a good doctor.
The world needs good doctors,
you ass.
[panting]
[alarm stops,
elevator hums]
- Ms. Reese.
- Hmm?
- Um, I was unkind to you,
and I hope that you'll
allow me to apologize.
- It's okay.
You were sleeping.
I woke you.
- That is
a good way to put it.
- You don't like
Chicago-style popcorn?
- Mixing caramel
with cheese flavors?
- Sweet and salty--
it's the greatest duo.
- I thought the great duo
was Jordan and Pippen.
- Oh.
[sighs]
- I've been off my meds.
- Since when?
- I started titrating myself
down about ten days ago.
I'm sorry. It was
a little chemistry experiment.
I really should have told you
during our last session.
- How's the experiment going?
- Not great.
The black cloud
is descending.
There ain't no denying it.
- Why did you go off?
- About a month ago, I just-- I
started to feel fuzzy, you know?
Like I was losing my edge,
like my antenna--
I mean, you know the focus
that it takes to treat patients.
I was worried that I was
gonna make a mistake.
- Danny, you also can't treat
patients if you're depressed.
- You'd think I would've
figured that out by now.
- Let me adjust your dose.
We'll figure out a balance.
- Okay.
- Hey, there you go.
So, how was your day?
You save some lives?
Okay, got it.
Not feeling chatty.