♪ Ohhh ohhh ohhh ♪
I can come with you.
There's no need.
No, I should come with you.
I'll cancel all my patients.
No. There's no need.
I'm fine. I can handle it.
This is too stressful
for you, Addison.
Bizzy had an aneurysm.
She died in her sleep.
I'm a doctor. Patients die
all the time. I can handle it.
This isn't some patient.
This is your mother's funeral.
Those bags aren't
going to load themselves.
♪ Is it all a dream? ♪
I'll be back in a week.
♪ Should I even try? ♪
♪ Are you coming clean? ♪
♪ To tell the truth ♪
♪ I need you right now ♪
Have you been to see Brett
this week?
It's a long drive out there,
and I don't have a lot
of spare time these days.
It's hard to even take
the hour to come here.
I-I would think seeing Brett
this week would be a priority.
Then you don't understand
my priorities.
Hilary, I seem to be
irritating you today.
Am I irritating you?
What's your position
on the death penalty?
Well, i-I'd like to keep
the focus on you--
I know. All you shrinks prefer
to keep the focus on me.
I know
that's your preference.
But I'd still like you
to tell me
your position
on the death penalty,
because in 48 hours,
the state plans
to hang an innocent man
in the public square.
That's what they're gonna do.
Even if they've planned to do it
with a table and a needle in his
vein, it's no less barbaric.
And you seem to want me to
give over to that, to give up,
to spend hours
crying in my husband's lap--
hours that could be spent
on the phone
to the governor's office
trying to save his life.
I honestly don't even
understand that.
I just want you
to get some closure.
You want me to give up.
That's not a thing
I'm ever gonna do.
I haven't heard
from my wife this week.
I understand
she's fighting hard
to get another stay.
My son stopped by to see me.
How was that?
Um, he was 9 months old
when I went away,
and now he's got facial hair
and an attitude.
Hard to be
any kind of decent father
from death row.
Are you afraid that's
the last time you'll see him?
I'm not afraid.
I'm not afraid to die.
Is that
what you told your son?
I told him... that he should
go take a drive.
You know, just...
He should go take a road trip
with his friends.
His mother and I...
Don't want him here this week
for...
He believes his father is...
Being wrongfully executed.
How does a kid
forgive the world after that?
How does he make anything
of himself
when he believes
that's the way the world works?
That's an interesting choice
of words. "He believes."
You've maintained
your innocence for 17 years.
We've worked together
for several months.
You've never said anything
like...
I'm guilty.
I did it, Dr. Wallace.
I'm guilty as sin.
Your wife doesn't know.
No. My wife, my son--
they believe me.
He doesn't know me
except in prison,
so he believes his mother,
and hilary...
She knew me for a long time
before I was in here.
We've been together
since high school.
I was 27
when they put me away.
She's never heard me
raise my voice let alone a gun.
I never raised a hand
to anybody.
So, uh...
What happened?
I snapped.
That's about all I can say
to that.
I met a guy in a bar
who was rude, disrespectful.
Followed him home,
saw where he lived,
and I went blind. You know
the phrase "seeing red"?
It's like
something inside me broke.
We kept a gun in the house
for protection.
I went home, I got the gun,
I went back to Mr. Miller's,
and I shot him.
And never in a million years...
Would hilary ever believe
that I would do something
like that.
I don't even
believe it myself.
Do you want to tell her?
Do you want her to know?
No, I don't want to tell her.
But I don't want her
to spend any more of her life
hating the world.
And I don't want that
for my son.
It's better that they hate me
than hate the world.
Don't you think?
It was creepy.
She's grieving.
No, I-I get grieving.
I-I get that.
This--this I don't get.
It was creepy.
Was she like,
"you don't have to come,"
or was she like, you know,
"don't come"?
She didn't
say anything really.
She didn't even look at me.
It was like Addison
was taken over by the ghost
of her cold and waspy mother.
It was creepy.
Why aren't you in Connecticut with Addison?
She told me
I didn't have to come.
Oh. In all those years
of marriage,
did I really
teach you nothing?
So you're saying now
I should have gone anyway?
Yes, you moron.
You shoulda gone.
But you didn't,
so you should go now.
We should all go.
W-Wait, all--who all?
Yeah, you know, Charlotte's
not gonna want to go.
Go where?
Connecticut
to support Addison.
Oh, we should absolutely go.
When big daddy died, you came.
It meant everything to me.
We should all get on a plane
as soon as possible.
Hey. How did things go
with hilary?
As well as can be expected.
I'm gonna check tickets
and hotel rooms.
- I fly first class.
- Yeah, me--me, too.
Wh--tickets?
We're talking about going
to be with Addison.
Oh. Oh, god. I can't go.
My, um, my patient's husband
is, uh,
well, if he doesn't get
a stay,
he will be executed
in the next 48 hours,
so I need to be here.
I'm sorry, you guys. You're
just gonna have to survive
without us.
Oh, no. Pete, you should go.
Okay, what--
what just happened?
The mailbox is
in a different zip code.
That's not normal.
Nothing about these people
is normal.
It's amazing Addison turned out
so relatively sane.
You say that now.
Wait.
Hello. Thank you for coming.
Look, we, uh, we didn't mean
to ambush you or anything.
We just wanted to be here
for you.
Of course. How lovely.
Won't you come in for a drink?
Oh, yeah.
Totally creepy.
A few of bizzy's friends
stopped by
to pay their respects.
Which means gossip
and drink our booze.
Hi. It's good to see you all.
Thank you for coming.
Of course.
- Uh, is Violet...
- Uh, not here.
She had an emergency at work.
Shame.
Sends her best.
Well, if it isn't
the entire cast
of "the tan and the beautiful."
God, I miss California.
Hello, beautiful.
Hello, Archer.
Thanks for coming.
My mother died. Be nice.
Given that
the last time I saw you,
you climbed out of my bed
and disappeared--
bygones. Dead mother.
Mm-hmm.
Come on. Give me something.
I'm here, aren't I?
We should, uh, probably
get back to the hotel.
Oh, no. We have
plenty of rooms here.
No, no, Archer.
That's not necessary.
No, I'm grieving. It's decided.
You're all staying.
I don't mean to be
rude, but we have to sit down
for a meeting
with the funeral director.
Ahh.
Go ahead. We--we can--
we can take care of ourselves.
You'll have to pour
your own drinks.
The house has been closed
since bizzy left.
Pour our own drinks? Shame.
Hey.
I know
you didn't want me to come,
but I'm happy to see you.
Thank you.
He did it?
I was his therapist
for four months.
I believed he was innocent.
How do you think
it makes me feel about me?
So I-I have a patient
who has spent
the last 17 years of her life,
full-time, fighting
for her husband's freedom.
You should hear her
go on about this case.
She can tell you the exact
number of white pickup trucks
registered in California
in '94.
She can tell you the exact
number of 38-caliber handguns.
She can tell you the name
and cell phone number
of every gubernatorial aide
who's worked in this state
for the past 20 years.
Look, I understand,
believe me.
It isn't right. I mean, if he
wants to clear his conscience
at the eleventh hour, then let
him talk to you, not to her.
He doesn't get
to unburden himself
at the expense of her sanity.
And you don't think
she deserves to know the truth?
I think she deserves
a little peace.
And you think she's gonna
get that, when her husband,
an innocent man, dies
at the hands of the state?
My client asked me to talk
to you and then to his wife
on his behalf.
He's a dying man,
and I find myself inclined
to honor his request.
He is a dying murderer
who's been lying
to those who love him
for nearly 20 years.
Well, be that as it may--
all right. Let me spend
some time with her.
Let me spend some time
on her turf, and, uh,
and I will get back to you with
my professional recommendation.
Let's keep the emphasis
on "professional."
You know what?
It's comments like that--
that's why
you have trouble with women.
In lieu of flowers,
Mrs. Montgomery stated
that donations
could be made in her name
- to the city ballet or the garden club.
- I'm bored.
Is there a reason
I have to be here for this?
Yes, the reason being
that our mother is dead and you
are a part of this family.
I've spoken
to a lot of her friends,
but I may have missed some.
I'm not sure
where bizzy's address book is.
Not to worry. Mrs. Montgomery
met with me every year
to update
the contact information
of the people
she wanted to invite.
God forbid
the wrong sort show up.
Well, to be clear, she wanted
a public memorial service
with a reception to follow
at the house.
The interment is just for
family and close friends
the following morning.
Well, it sounds like
bizzy thought of everything.
One last thing.
Mrs. Montgomery requested
that there be one eulogy.
I'd be happy to do it.
Actually, sir. She asked
that Addison do it.
Ha.
Why aren't we staying
at a hotel again?
They've asked us not to.
We're being polite.
Hotels have room service.
I vote for the hotel.
Hotels also have heat
and blankets
and emotional warmth.
Hotels have emotional warmth?
Or at least the possibility
of it.
Thank you.
Are you people still here?
Oh, they're staying, captain.
Actually, sir--
our mother died.
You're staying.
Well, in that case,
someone can refill my drink.
If you all will excuse me,
it's been a long day.
I'm gonna go lay down.
I have a question first.
You're all doctors
in this room, right?
Every single one of you.
So how does an army of doctors
let my wife die
without even
a good old-fashioned fight?
I mean, how many hundreds
of thousands of dollars
did your parents waste
on medical school
so you could let a relatively
young and healthy woman
just die on your watch?
It was a heart attack,
captain.
It happened fast, and we
weren't there. I told you that.
I thought it was
an aneurysm.
What?
Uh, you said she died
of an aneurysm.
Right. That's right.
Well, just now
you said heart attack.
It's an aneurysm.
I'm just tired.
She's grieving, Sam.
You're gonna split hairs?
- If you'll excuse me, I'm gonna go lay down.
- Addie.
If you need someone
to talk to--
thank you.
I just need to rest.
I just wanted to make sure
you were okay.
I'm too busy to be sure.
What--what are you doing?
Trying to get an online petition
finalized, and i--
do you have any contacts
in the press?
Hilary, I know we've only been
working together a few months,
and, uh, and--and we didn't
get a lot done earlier,
but i--
Dr. Turner, with respect,
in the last 17 years,
I've filed
nine separate appeals,
I've petitioned six courts,
I've written 368 letters to
the state justice department,
I've lost two houses,
had three nervous breakdowns,
and I haven't slept through
the night in almost two decades.
And it all comes down
to this week.
So please, I'm busy.
What if it doesn't work?
What if you can't get
Brett's execution stayed?
I told you,
I'm not thinking about that.
Hilary--
I said no.
Look, spare me
"the world isn't fair" speech.
Car accidents, sick kids--
I know bad things happen
to good people.
But what's happening with Brett,
it's not the same.
It's preventable, and if I
don't do everything I can
to try to stop it--
and you really think you can?
After all these years
and all this work, you...
I'm--I'm worried about
what is gonna happen to you
if this doesn't go your way.
When everything you've
surrounded yourself with here
is--is moot, what then?
It'll never be moot.
I won't let go.
I won't stop.
Whether Brett's here or not,
I will clear his name.
For our son's sake,
for my sake...
I won't stop.
Oh, I, uh, I thought
you'd be sleeping.
Susan's in there.
What?
In the urn.
I had her cremated
at her request,
and they delivered
the urn today.
It's pretty,
don't you think?
Uh, okay.
Cremation
is such a strange thing.
Addison--
I don't think I'd want
to be cremated,
except for the poetry of it,
the biblical allusion.
Ashes to ashes,
dust to dust.
That's nice.
Look, baby,
why don't you lie down?
All right? Let me hold you
while you sleep.
I don't want to be cremated.
Maybe I'll donate my body
to science.
Remember...
Our cadaver
in medical school?
Uh, yeah.
Yeah.
What did we call him?
We called him Mr. Mulligan.
Mulligan. Mulligan.
I have no idea why.
It was Derek's idea.
Actually, he named it after
his favorite math teacher.
Mr. Mulligan.
Remember...
What we did with him
when we were done?
We gave him
a memorial service.
We thanked him
for his sacrifice
and his contribution
to our education.
God. We were earnest.
We lit candles.
That was nice.
That's nice.
I think that's what I'll do.
Donate my body to science.
Where you going?
I don't think I can sleep
with Susan in the room.
I don't care.
Archer, I-I know that
the relationships
in--in your family
are--are complicated, but--
oh, we're like
a bad Russian novel.
Yeah, but still,
bizzy was your mother.
You should care.
Sam's your ex-husband,
and Addison is probably up there
right now, screwing him.
Shh.
Do you care?
Sam and I were over
a long time ago.
So were
the captain and bizzy.
Doesn't stop him from simmering
with jealous rage.
Yes.
Yes, it...
Yes, of course it--
it bothers me.
I care.
But there are so many things
in life that bother me.
You know,
abortion bothers me,
and--and overpopulation
bothers me,
and those things are
at such horrifying odds,
that I can't even--
I can't even wrap my head
around it, you know?
I can't wrap my head around
anything, you know?
I mean--
you know I'm a grandmother?
I'm a grandmother,
for god sake.
And that,
that seriously bothers me.
But I can't control anything.
I just, uh...
Can't control anything.
Certainly not
anyone else's feelings.
You know...
Sam and Addison
are beyond my control.
And, yes, it does bother me.
But, uh... I choose
not to be angry
and, uh...
Not to be bitter.
And just, uh, you know,
live in the moment.
Okay.
Let's.
Oh, no. This--Archer,
that is--
that is not what I meant.
I don't care.
Sorry. I was just, uh...
Cooper needs a little something
to help him sleep.
So do I.
You shouldn't drink alone.
To bizzy.
Right. To bizzy.
How are you with words?
Sorry?
I have to write a eulogy
by tomorrow,
and I could use a little help.
Are you a good writer?
No, not really.
Plus, I didn't really
know bizzy.
No one did.
Well, maybe don't write it.
Maybe just, uh,
get up there
and speak from the heart.
Sorry. She did this
to me, you know?
This is her final insult,
her final cruelty,
to pick me...
To stand up
in front of everyone and lie.
You really think
you have to lie?
Believe me. Nobody wants
to hear the truth.
You mean that your mother
killed herself?
I'm
the hospital administrator.
I saw the death certificate.
For what it's worth,
I'm really sorry.
I can't imagine
how it must feel.
So if you want to talk,
I'm your gal.
And even if you don't,
my lips are sealed.
Either way,
tomorrow in that chapel,
you stand up,
say whatever the hell
you want.
Funerals aren't for the dead.
They're for the living.
They're to help us survive
when it feels like the grief
might just kill us.
Tomorrow's for you, Addison.
You hear me?
Say whatever the hell
you want.
You'd think
after all this time,
I would know what to say,
right?
Take your time.
The words will come.
Okay,
you're freaking me out.
Spit it out.
Whatever it is, as long
as you're not asking me to quit,
I can handle it.
I did it.
You did what?
I murdered Paul Miller.
It was me. I did it.
Laughter relieves tension.
People laugh at funerals
all the time, you know?
It--it's--it's okay.
I never--i never--
I never wanted you to know.
I-I always wanted you...
To believe in me.
I don't know
how I did that thing.
I still to this day don't know
how I did it. I am so sorry.
I am so sorry.
Hilary, I can't imagine
what this feels like.
But Brett did want you
to know the truth.
That's--
that's worth something.
No. No, no.
Please, don't, don't, don't.
Don't go. Don't go.
Baby, baby, please--
step back and put your hands
on the table.
Please don't go.
Step back now.
Baby, baby.
She needs time to process.
I don't have any time left.
Archer, you're not allowed
to oversleep
and miss bizzy's funeral.
Mm.
What?
We're both adults.
Some clothes would be nice,
preferably something black.
Hilary, are you there?
The door was unlocked,
so i--what are you doing?
The governor usually
has dinner around 5:30,
but his assistant
thought maybe
if I tried his
old office number--
hilary, you have to stop.
I have to find
my address book.
I just had it here,
and I don't know where--
look at me. Look at me.
Look at me.
Do you remember
seeing Brett this morning?
Do you think
I could forget that?
Do you think I could ever
forget that?
Well, he's--
he's ready to go, hilary.
He's made his peace.
D-Doesn't that mean anything,
th-that he's accepted his fate,
that at--
that at the very least,
it wasn't a wrongful execution?
Do you think
there's any such thing
as a rightful execution,
Dr. Turner?
That is not--
Justin was a colicky baby.
It started when he was about
a month old
and it didn't stop
for a year.
We never slept. It felt like
we were going crazy.
And then Brett got fired
when we were already broke.
And then his mother,
who was our only help,
dropped dead in the street.
So Brett went to a bar,
and he had too many drinks.
He had too many drinks
and he had
so much rage inside him,
that...
But what about all
the good things that he did?
There were
so many good things.
Doesn't that count
for anything?
A lifetime of kindness,
doesn't that count?
Doesn't that...
Hilary--
make up for one mistake?
Let's talk about
your feelings.
You had a lot of feelings
come up this morning
when Brett told you the truth.
I want to talk about them.
I don't have time
to talk about my feelings
because my husband
is about to be murdered!
There it is.
Listen, I...
I need to go somewhere.
Will you come with me?
Yes. Yes, of course.
Dear lord, take back the soul
of Beatrice Forbes Montgomery.
Amen.
And now
bizzy's daughter, Addison,
will say a few words.
Addison.
Uh...
My mother told us that
we should never cry in public.
The forbses didn't do that.
If we needed to shed tears
it should be in the privacy
of one's own home.
Even better, in the privacy
of our own room.
I'm going to do my best
to honor that today.
In her 62 years,
bizzy taught me and my brother
a lot of things.
For as long as I can remember,
she always told us
never to settle for second best.
It wasn't enough
to be good at something.
We had to be standouts
at whatever we did.
Bizzy didn't believe
that every camper
should get a feather.
My mother threw herself
into everything.
She did more volunteer work
than anyone I know.
She was also a leading member
of greenwich society.
She was president
of the junior league
for almost 20 years.
She also ran
the chamber of commerce
book sale every year.
But even though
her volunteer duties
kept her extremely busy,
she always had time
for her family.
She was also
very good at sports.
She held
the state high school record
for the 50-yard backstroke.
That record was
only recently broken this year.
My mother was a woman
who believed in accomplishment
above all else.
I think she remained true
to that belief
until the day she died.
May she rest in peace.
Addison making it hard?
Mm. Impossible.
I've been there.
You in the mood for advice
or just another drink?
Both.
All right.
When Charlotte's father died,
she beat me up
because I was close
and I was safe.
But there's only so much
you can take.
If you really want to help
Addison start to heal,
you gotta push back.
Not hard, not to get even,
but just so that she knows
that you're strong enough
to help her get through this.
♪♪♪
♪ only ♪
♪ in my head ♪
This is a lovely home.
Are the curtains homemade?
Hilary,
what do you want?
♪ Only in... ♪
He did it.
My husband
killed your husband.
♪ Will I ever
find some peace ♪
He's guilty.
I already knew that.
All these years, you were
the only one who seemed not to.
I'm very sorry
for any extra pain I've caused
your family with my denials.
I'm very, very sorry.
Thank you.
♪ Only ♪
♪ in my head ♪
You know, uh... I have
some work I have to do.
Ellen, I didn't just
come here to apologize.
Although,
surely I owed you that.
I came to ask you...
♪ ...you ♪
I want you to ask the governor
for a stay of execution.
♪ Always an excuse ♪
Hilary...
♪ And I'd like to meet you ♪
I know what my husband did
was horrible. I know. I know.
It was horribly wrong.
If I could go back to that night
and stop what happened, I would.
I pray that you know
that I would do that.
But I can't. And so here I am,
doing what I can do,
as a wife and as a mother,
as one human being
to another, i'm...
Ellen, I'm not asking you
to set him free.
But I'm just asking you
for a little more time.
♪ ...get it right ♪
♪ And it got so hard ♪
♪ only in my head ♪
You see that, uh, picture
on the fireplace,
the little redhead
in the soccer uniform?
That's my son Dylan.
On the day
he made his first goal.
He was so happy about it
that he pulled his shirt
over his head
and ran around the field
with his arms out
like an airplane.
It was an amazing moment.
♪ Only you ♪
But my husband
wasn't there to see it.
The one next to it--
that's Hailey on her first day
of gymnastics.
My husband
didn't see that either.
And he didn't see
either of them ride a bike
or sing a solo or write a poem.
And he won't see Dylan
when he graduates
and... he won't be there
to give our daughter away
on the day
that she gets married
because 17 years ago,
your husband decided
that all those moments
weren't important enough
for my Paul to be around for...
That he wasn't needed,
that I could handle it myself.
So I have.
Every party, every sleepover,
every skinned knee--
I've handled it all.
And I will
until the day I die.
You asked me for more time.
I don't have any to give.
Your husband took it all
from me.
♪ Only in... ♪
We should go.
♪ Head ♪
♪ inside ♪
♪ will I ever
find some peace ♪
You can let yourselves out.
♪♪♪
I'll take that.
You've surprised me.
I-I mean, most of the time,
you seem...
Immature?
Irresponsible?
I was gonna say ridiculous,
but you've stepped up.
Well,
Addison's like my sister.
And she is in so much pain
underneath that frozen grin
that I can barely breathe
looking at her.
Shopping and cleaning is all
I can think to do to help.
Dr. Pete.
You know...
Violet...
Was kind to me, and...
It was the first kindness
that anyone had shown me
in a long time.
She's like that.
We're both damaged.
Kindred spirits, really.
You know, I'm trying as hard
as I can to be appropriate,
but you
talking about my wife--
She wasn't always
your wife.
I'm sure that came out wrong,
didn't it?
I know you're grieving,
but you cannot
talk about Violet that way.
Don't tell me
what to do in my own house.
Coward.
You stayed in a marriage you
knew wasn't real for 40 years,
and you're calling me
a coward?
Oh. Ohh.
Did Dr. Turner
speak to hilary again?
Yes.
She tried, but I...
I'm sorry.
She doesn't want to see you.
Excuse me, Dr. Wallace.
We need to prepare the prisoner.
No.
No, i'm--I'm not ready.
I'm sorry, but it's time.
No, I'm not ready.
I'm not ready. I'm not ready.
I'm not ready. I'm not ready!
I'll be there
on the other side of the glass.
You won't be alone.
I'll be there till the end.
Tell hilary I am sorry.
What kind of pills
are you taking?
You already succeeded
in making me look like an idiot.
Do I really have to endure
a lecture, too?
What kind of pills?
Pour those down the drain.
The doctor gave me these.
They're for grief.
There's
no medication for grief.
You just have to feel it.
And if we delay it
by taking pills,
we just get to feel it
for longer.
I thought Violet was
the shrink in the outfit.
Fine. When your doctor
prescribed those,
did he happen to mention that
you shouldn't drink with them?
He might have.
You're lucky.
It's only been a few days.
If it had been a few weeks,
you would've wrecked your liver
and probably
most of your relationships.
So drink if you have to,
but no more pills, okay?
I don't have to listen to you.
No, you don't,
but you have a shot here--
a shot at a relationship
with your kids, a shot
to right some wrongs before you
follow in bizzy's footsteps.
Oh, I see.
I talked about your wife,
so now you get to talk about
my wife.
I'm talking about your kids.
They're adults.
Not today.
Not when their mother
just died.
They're your kids.
And they need you
not to be drunk and stoned
and...
Throwing punches
and being
just all-around useless.
They need their father,
and this might be
your last shot.
And i'm
just trying to help you
not blow your last shot.
I was happy
when Susan got sick.
I know how that sounds,
but... where was bizzy
gonna go when Susan died?
I was all she knew
for 40 years.
I assumed she'd come home.
You know, not to be romantic,
just... to live out
our lives together
instead of alone.
I am so sorry for your loss.
I don't know
what to do with Susan.
It seems wrong that she wasn't
at the memorial.
I just keep moving her
from room to room.
That was a nice eulogy.
Thank you.
Now I want to hear
the real one.
I need a drink.
I want to hear the real one.
Sam, I really don't have
the energy for this.
I want to hear the real one.
No, Sam--
be real with me.
Sam--
give me the real one.
I need to hear your real voice.
Because this Stepford wasp
thing, it's not--
Sam, please back up.
No, I'm not backing up.
Sam, you're scaring me.
No. Well, you're scaring me.
I want to hear the real eulogy.
I want to hear the truth.
I want to hear from the woman
that I love...
Back off, Sam!
From the woman that I love--
my mother died.
I know. I know. I know.
I know. It's okay.
What time is it?
Late.
It's getting late.
You don't have to go.
You don't ever
have to see him again.
But you do have to accept
that he is dying tonight.
And as awful as that...
Is to accept,
it might give you a chance
to say good-bye
on your own terms.
Give you a chance at least
to tell him you love him.
He knows I love him.
If there's one thing
that man has to know,
it's that I love him.
The way you left this morning,
he might doubt it.
If I were him,
I would doubt it.
What are you doing up here?
Oh, I'm honoring bizzy.
Not that she ever got
sloppy drunk.
Say what you want about her,
the woman could hold her liquor.
Come on back to the house.
I'll make you some coffee.
Oh, no, no, no, no, no,
no, no, no, no.
Ahh.
You and me, how'd we end up
such messes, huh?
Look at us.
You're screwing
your best friend's ex,
and i'm--well, I'm screwing
anything with a pulse.
I...
Am in love with Sam.
Huh.
And you are up here
all alone, grieving,
because we're real people
with real feelings...
Despite bizzy's best example.
Well, here's to that.
She killed herself, Archer.
It wasn't an aneurysm
or a heart attack.
She took some...
Took a bottle of pills.
Well, isn't that
just par for the course?
I've spent so much of my life
judging people.
You know that?
I've been so judgmental.
It was actually
one of the few traits
I did get from bizzy.
I mean, when I was younger,
I would've thought it was weak.
Suicide--it's so weak.
I mean,
what was she thinking?
How could she do that
to us--
to the captain,
to her children?
But... when I found her...
All I thought was, well...
That's that.
People who do that,
they're not... thinking.
She wasn't thinking,
laying there broken.
She was broken from grief.
She was out to sea
and she drowned.
It doesn't make her selfish.
It doesn't even mean
that she didn't love us
in her own way.
Maybe that's
what I would've said.
If I could've told the truth,
that's what I would've said.
I need to see my husband--
Brett loveman.
I'm sorry, ma'am.
She only needs a few minutes.
Once a prisoner is in prep,
he isn't allowed
any more outside contact.
I can let you in to witness
the execution, but that's it.
No, please.
I don't--
I don't know
if I can do that.
Okay, listen to me.
I don't say this lightly.
You are
one of the strongest people
I have ever had the honor
of knowing.
So the question isn't
can you do it.
It's do you want to.
♪ I dream that your arm ♪
♪ lifted me out of harm ♪
♪ joining me from far away ♪
♪ we will drink wine ♪
♪ we're just giddy on life ♪
♪ touch me
and I'll float away ♪
♪ Float away ♪
♪♪♪
♪ Is it all a dream? ♪
♪ Should I even try? ♪
♪ Are you coming clear? ♪
♪ To tell the truth ♪
♪ I need you ♪
♪♪♪
♪ Is it all a dream? ♪
♪ Should I even try? ♪
♪ Are you coming clean? ♪
♪ To tell the truth ♪
♪ I need you ♪
♪ right now ♪