Here's what I learned
my first day at medical school.
Think long and hard before
choosing to become a surgeon.
It takes 100% commitment.
This is killing me.
I need coffee.
Four days back to work,
and I'm ready to end it all.
I don't even know how
we survive four days.
Coffee's on!
That's how.
You have to be on your A game
every single time
you walk into that OR.
When patients are
lying on your table
completely at your mercy,
they need to know that
when you make that first cut,
you know what you're doing.
No other specialty
requires the time, the focus,
the complete dedication,
except, maybe, being a mom.
Okay, so Daddy is gonna
drop you off at day care,
and I am going to
pick you up, okay?
Then we'll have a
princess tea party
at the end of the day.
Okay, ladies, let's go.
Wow. We're good at this.
Oh, pump!
Yeah. Oh. Okay.
Maybe we're too good at this.
James Evans, 57, post-op day 6
from an emergent
tricuspid valve replacement
due to endocarditis.
Hey, could you
change it to Jimmy?
And go ahead and fix
the age, while you're at it,
to something in the 40s.
Deep breath.
Is that thing you put
in there still working?
I think you're good.
The new valve should
last 10 to 15 years.
Dr. Wilson's going to do a
treadmill stress echocardiogram
just to be thorough.
Thanks, Doc.
Anything to get
me out of this dress.
Okay.
Oh. UNOS has a possible match
on one of my transplant patients.
Uh, page me with his results.
Okay.
Looking at your dad's chart?
He's not my dad.
That's why I took
my mom's last name.
So there's nothing
connecting me to the guy.
He's funny.
Yeah?
You should talk to him.
Tell him who you are.
Maybe he's changed.
You've changed.
The last time I saw his face,
I was punching him so
hard, I could have killed him.
I'm just afraid I'll
pick up where I left off.
Hey! You're doing a
heart/liver on Samantha Calder?
Yep. I saw her
before I went on leave.
I'm the one who diagnosed
the familial hypercholesterolemia.
Oh, well, you were right.
So let me take the liver.
Really? Yeah, really.
Why didn't you think
of me in the first place?
I guess I thought you
were easing back in?
I don't ease back in. I
jump in the deep end.
I swim.
All right.
Uh, well, have you
read the Cleveland article
on simultaneous heart/liver
transplants under CPB?
I have not. Is it different
from a regular heart/liver?
I will read it.
Hey, you're doing a heart/liver?
Yeah. Uh, but I don't need you.
You paged me.
You stole my liver?
Uh...
Come on. I deserve this.
I've been on the bench for
months. You deserve nothing.
I named my son after you.
You can't be mad at me.
Your son is the devil's spawn.
He drinks the
milk of a liver thief!
Morning, Dr. Kepner.
Dr. Robbins. Mmm. Hi.
Coffee? I thought
you could use it
before your big surgery
with Dr. Shepherd.
Oh.
That's nice.
What did I do?
Something nice, apparently.
I didn't get a coffee.
No.
No. I think I actually did
something really, really bad.
I think that I brought
her back to my apartment
the night of the gala.
You think?
I don't know. I was drunk. I barely
remember even getting home.
And then I have a vague
memory of her in my kitchen.
And now she's
being really friendly.
Did I flirt with her that night?
Uh, all I remember is waking up
in my bathtub with
my Spanx still on.
Oh, well, at least
we know you're good.
Oh.
Hey, um, some mortgage
slips for the apartment came.
Oh.
Okay.
You're welcome.
You want me to
thank you for giving me
the mortgage slips
to my apartment
that you're living in?
Listen, if you want me
to move out, just say so.
I don't want to live
in the apartment
that I shared with
my cheating wife.
I gotta go. Thanks!
I think I overslept.
What do you think?
Of?
My shirt? Yes.
You're introducing
me to your mother.
I need to make a
good impression,
so I am going for, "Yes, I
am an intern dating your son
"who is a fellow and a member
of the board and an Avery.
"But before you write
me off as a gold digger,
"you need to know I
am a kick-ass surgeon,
"and your son is
lucky to be dating me."
That is a lot of
pressure to put on a shirt.
Oh, it's not working alone.
There's a lip gloss in
my locker that'll assist.
Oh, yeah.
Well, she is gonna love you.
Mmm, not here.
What?
Stop. We're not those people.
Oh, I know. Yeah.
Banana bread.
I'm starving.
Mmm. Help yourself.
I was too busy feeding
my family breakfast
and getting my sister
wife's breast pump packed
to feed myself
this morning. So...
You have a sister wife?
Derek and Meredith
and I are in a relationship.
Huh.
I used to dance in my underwear.
And I thought I'd get back
to that when I left Arizona.
Instead I walked
right into Big Love.
I rebounded to the McDreamys.
Mmm.
Hmm, hang glider trauma? Yeah.
Where did you get
this? It's amazing.
It's good, right? Emma made it.
Mmm-hmm. Mmm.
Fetal surgeon
Emma from the gala?
Mmm-hmm.
Oh, my God. You're
rebounding, too.
Mmm. Yeah.
What have we got?
Her name is Reese Woods, 22.
Hang gliding over
Tiger Mountain,
BP's 100/70,
open tibia fracture,
and complains of abdominal pain.
Can I say, "I told
you so," now, Reese?
Who's this?
Oh, that's Donna.
She's the sister. Mmm.
Although she acts
like she's my mother.
I am not doing this again.
I'm not watching
you try to kill yourself.
It's just a little break.
Don't be so mad.
Okay, this isn't
bone. This is a rod.
When did you
have this rod put in?
This March. She broke it
heli-skiing in New Zealand.
She's also broken,
uh, both forearms,
lost a kidney,
dislocated her shoulder.
Wow, you really do
have a death wish, huh?
I guess I'm just
making up for lost time.
I'm seeing a lot of free
fluid in Morrison's pouch.
We're gonna need to
get her up to CT stat.
Okay, now show Catherine
your party trick, sir.
Yeah.
Oh! Oh, he's acting all too
cool for school right now.
But yesterday, when
he made it to the chair,
he was smiling from ear to ear.
Okay, okay. Okay.
Oh!
You are doing so well!
I think you'll be doing
laps by next week.
Excuse me, sir. Your, uh,
drain output has been a little low,
and we were told to
come by to strip your JP.
We can come back later
if this isn't a good time.
Well, I actually wanted
to talk with Dr. Bailey.
So right now is a great time.
I need a hand to
get back in bed.
Well, what are you two
waiting for? Help the man!
Oh, yeah. Of course.
Okay.
I was expecting more.
But he couldn't sit
up two days ago.
He's depressed.
Have you considered
antidepressants?
Of course I have.
And he refuses. He
says he's fine, and he is.
He needs time,
support, and more pillows
if he's ever gonna be
able to sit up comfortably.
I'm gonna go get those.
Miranda, I'm so sorry.
You've done so much,
and I am grateful.
I'm here to help. So let me.
All right, pillows.
Oh, my God!
Oh...
Hi.
Jackson, where are your manners?
Mom, this is Stephanie Edwards.
Steph, this is my mom.
Dear, would you mind handing
me the pillows from the top bunk?
Okay.
Mmm.
I don't think she
liked my shirt.
Mmm.
Ma, hold on.
You are aware that you're
on the board of this hospital,
as well as an Avery.
You don't know what I went
through to get these pillows.
Meant to lock the door. Good
morning, sir. How are you feeling today?
He's a mess.
Who taped this IV?
It's fine.
Maybe it was Edwards.
Her mind's obviously
not on patient care.
That is not fair, Mom. This
is not me being a prude.
I like sex just as much
as the next person.
Oh, God, please.
But there is a time
and there's a place.
He said he meant
to lock the door.
You be quiet.
Where are your
compression socks?
They went to get another pair.
Maybe they got distracted
by Edwards' breasts.
And I'm out.
I'm just looking out for you.
Hey, Sam.
Dr. Grey, where's
your baby belly?
It turned into a baby boy.
Congratulations.
I would show you a
picture, but he's so cute,
you may have
another heart attack.
She's had a bunch of them.
Not recently, though. I
think the yoga music helps.
Absolutely.
He hates the music.
I loved it.
Mmm-hmm. For
the first few months.
Well, now that we're getting
you a new heart and liver,
you can flip out
like the rest of us.
And have a baby, like Dr. Grey.
Or be a groundbreaking
surgeon, like Dr. Yang.
I'm a surgeon, too.
Oh, yeah. Of course.
Dr. Grey does it all.
It's so impressive.
I don't know how
you handle everything.
I don't know either sometimes.
What?
Did you want to
examine the patient?
Oh.
Hello, Mr. Samuels,
I'm Dr. Edwards.
It says here you haven't been
able to urinate since yesterday.
Let's take a look.
Wow.
Uh, it's no wonder you can't
urinate. Your penis is quite swollen.
I think I got a bug bite.
That's a big bug bite.
It's more of a bee
sting than a bug bite.
Still pretty swollen
for a bee sting.
Do you have a
history of allergies?
It wasn't really one
bee. It was several.
Well, what's several?
I don't know.
Twenty-five? Thirty?
Thirty bees?
I know. It's crazy, right?
Hmm?
But see, it was Saturday, and we
have this hammock
in the backyard.
And I thought I'd make some
lunch. So I took my pants off
and made a honey sandwich.
A honey sandwich?
Peanut butter and
honey sandwich.
'Cause who eats a
honey sandwich, right?
Right.
And I was eating
the honey sandwich.
And I fell asleep. And I
guess I got some honey on
myself.
And the bees caught the scent.
Okay. Mmm-hmm.
Well, I'm gonna get you a dose
of IV Benadryl and a steroid.
And then we're gonna get
you a catheter so you can pee.
Dr. Edwards.
Would it make a
difference if it were hornets?
The patient is a
14-year-old male...
All right, one
second. Excuse me.
Fourth day back, and
I'm already scrubbing in
on a heart/liver
transplant with Cristina.
Oh, fantastic! Yeah.
Can you pick up the
kids this afternoon?
I would, but I have to
entertain all of them.
They're visiting neurosurgeons
watching my AVM Q&A after.
I promised Zola a
princess tea party.
Have Callie do tea.
It was supposed to be
me, or in a pinch, you.
It's so she knows
that she hasn't been
replaced in our hearts
by a new baby brother
or by a multi-organ transplant.
It's an over-determined
tea party.
I'll talk to Callie.
I didn't realize I'd have to
work this hard to get out of here.
Five more minutes.
I lost out on three gigs
since I've been in here.
If I can play tonight,
maybe this trip
won't be a total wash.
Do you have any family or anyone
I can call to come pick you up?
No, I'm good.
How about I make a
call to a rehab clinic?
Don't you worry
about me, darlin'.
I know I had some junk in my
system when I came in here,
but I'm a recreational user.
Your left arm, right
arm, and the backs
of both your knees
tell a different story.
It took me half an hour to
find a usable vein on you.
I know what you're gonna
do when you leave here.
I've got people I
can call. I got family.
I don't think you do.
Or maybe you did,
but I think that you're
on your own now.
Well, you know all
about me, don't you?
I know that we have you
on methadone right now,
which is a big step
towards recovery.
Let's just try to keep
it going somewhere.
Kid, I play blues guitar.
I'm not Christina Aguilera.
I can't afford those
places, not the good ones.
Let me make some
calls for you, please.
Boy, you are as persistent
as you are annoying.
You can walk as
fast as you want,
but you're not going anywhere.
Neither am I.
What is wrong with Callie?
She still hasn't called me back.
Ooh! Ooh!
Ah, the recovery team texted, two
minutes until they open the donor.
Hey, Ross? Could
you run down to the ER
and ask Torres if she
can pick up the kids today?
Sure, but I have to get
this blood to the lab...
And remind her about
the princess tea party.
It has to be today.
Well, that's pretty cool.
The tea party? Yeah. I mean,
it's just apple juice and cookies,
but she's excited about it.
Not the tea party.
You and me doing
groundbreaking surgery.
That was the idea
when we started.
Yeah. It's pretty cool.
Do you need to go pump?
No, I'm fine.
You're holding your boobs.
But we're having a moment.
I don't want to spoil it.
Mer, your boobs are
exploding. Go pump.
Thank you.
So she might lose the kidney?
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
let's not jump ahead.
No, please. Worst-case
scenario. I like to be prepared.
Well, the worst-case
scenario is she needs a kidney.
So we start to look for a donor.
Okay. Well, that's me.
I'm her donor.
So you've been
through this before?
Oh, yeah. Yeah. Take your pick.
Bone marrow, blood, uh, liver,
anything you can think of, I've given.
What's mine is hers.
Except I haven't given
a kidney yet. So... Yay!
Sounds like she's extremely
accident-prone, even for a daredevil.
No. All the
parachuting and stuff,
it started when she
went into remission.
My sister was diagnosed
with aplastic anemia
when she was two.
Well, that must have been hard.
It was lucky that
you were a match.
Oh, it wasn't luck.
I'm a donor baby.
You're her younger sister.
Yeah.
My parents only
had me to save her.
Ahh!
How did that happen?
It's a long story.
Can you see any access
to get the catheter in?
No, it's too swollen.
It looks like it was mauled
by a pissed off badger.
You should have seen it
before the IV Benadryl kicked in.
Ah!
We need to get someone
from urology down here now.
Don't you think I tried?
There's an emergency,
and the on-call guy
is 20 minutes away.
Dr. Wilson, it feels
like I might explode.
I don't think he's
gonna last 20 minutes.
Dr. Avery, I'm...
Darling, save your
breath. There is
nothing you can
say after this morning
to get in my good graces.
I have a giant penis.
No, not me. I don't have a...
I'm a girl. Uh, I have a patient,
and he has a giant penis.
It's the biggest one I've ever
seen, and I've seen a lot of...
You make me nervous.
I need a consult.
Better go take a look.
This rod caused
a lot of bleeding.
We're gonna be here a while.
I hope you don't have plans
with your girlfriend, Hunt.
She's not my girlfriend.
She baked you banana bread
and brought it to you at work.
You're practically engaged.
Matthew brought me breakfast
burritos, and now we're getting married.
Just saying.
Damn it. The
superior pole of this
kidney is almost
completely avulsed,
and the pedicle is
gonna need some repair.
Do you think the sister's
prepared to consider donation?
She can't seem to say no.
Dr. Torres? Hmm?
Dr. Grey is going into surgery.
She wants to know if you
can pick up her kids at 3:00.
She said to mention promising
Zola a princess tea party?
Tell her I'll be out
of here by 6:00.
So she can't say no.
Oh, my God. You're right.
I need to get a life.
You know what? Maybe
I should kick Arizona out
and move back into my place.
But she needs the
elevator. And it's
right across the
street from the hospital,
which is perfect for her.
We drank three bottles
of champagne and puked.
It bonds you.
Mmm-hmm.
Plus it's already been retrofitted
to be handicap-accessible.
Kepner... I'm shutting up.
No, no. Look at the kidney.
We're gonna need some laps
and a vascular clamp. Kepner,
get the 4-0 Prolene stitch.
Of course, now my mom's
convinced that Stephanie
is some kind of
gold digger, trying to
use sex to nab herself an Avery.
Dude, you and your
rich boy problems.
You know what the worst part is?
I think she actually
likes Stephanie.
Well, so then you need
to tell your mom that.
Stand up for your girl.
That wouldn't work. She'd
just hate her even more.
So what are you
gonna do? Nothing.
You know, it's like
walking into a hornet's nest.
You know, you gotta stay still,
let the whole frenzy die down.
How you doin' with
that coffee, Karev?
You wanna make the damn coffee?
Be my guest. It's a
freakin' crap machine.
What's wrong with him?
Beats me.
Alex just broke
the coffee machine.
You're dead to me.
Dr. Yang just got a call
from... Oh, God. I'm sorry.
Oh, Shane, all my parts are
covered. You can turn around.
I'm fine looking at the wall.
Oh! Um, organs are good.
Let's go tell Samantha.
She's lactating.
I need 10 minutes. I have
four more ounces to go.
Uh, okay. Page me
when you're done.
Oh, Dr. Torres is in surgery.
She can't get the kids
until 6:00 at the earliest.
6:00 is too late
for a tea party.
Tea time is at 4:00.
Do you want me to
tell that to Dr. Torres?
No, it's just that I promised.
Just forget it. Forget it.
There will be other tea parties.
Well, this is how it starts.
I make a promise. I break it.
Ten years later, I'm my mother,
and Zola's snorting
oxy behind the school.
Nice.
You know, it goes faster
when you do both sides
at the same time.
How about I quiz you?
I thought you hated me. I do.
So hook up the pump
before I change my mind.
Dr. Robbins discovered
the spinal AVM
when the patient was
12. It has since grown.
We are going to use a
far lateral retroperitoneal...
Excuse me. Yes.
You suggested a
posterior approach?
Why go anteriorly?
Did I say that?
Well, I also said the Segway
was gonna hit big, but, uh...
Anyway, that theory
has been elaborated.
Excuse me. Sorry. Pardon me.
Who knew Dr. Shepherd
was such a big shot?
What are you doing here?
You told me to scrub in.
The night of the gala?
At your house, remember?
Oh, yeah.
That night was so fun.
Yeah.
Don't worry. I won't tell
anyone what happened.
Hey, um, it's a
little tight in here.
Uh, you could
probably be more useful
managing patients on the floor.
Oh.
Yeah. You're probably right.
Okay, sweet girl, just one
more. That's it. Shh. Shh, shh.
Stop. Stop what?
Doing that, making
that dog face.
It's puppy dog
eyes, and I'm not.
These are my regular eyes.
What do you want?
Your dad passed his stress test.
Yang told me to discharge him.
Good.
Say it.
I never had a father.
I made up, like,
15 versions of one.
A college professor
who would read to me,
a plumber who
snuck me into movies.
Like, three doctors,
one who would take me
to feed the ducks
in Boston Commons.
I want to cry when
I think about it,
and I made it up. I
wanted one so badly.
Alex, you have a father.
I know, and he's a dirtbag,
and I didn't make that up.
Just discharge him.
Then, uh, he woke up, and
hornets were stinging him.
Just on his penis? Accidentally?
Um...
Yeah?
Young man, did you put
your penis in a hornet's nest?
No.
Maybe.
Yes!
Get another 50 of
fentanyl for the pain.
When there's no
access for a catheter,
you need to go
directly into the bladder.
Any intern should know that.
Let's just pray we're not too late.
What happens if we are?
Hey, something just happened.
I... I feel like I don't
have to pee anymore.
That.
The bladder bursts. There's
a moment of relief and then...
Book an OR.
Get Dr. Hunt to
extend me privileges.
I am going to the OR.
One of your fine young residents
just let a man's
bladder explode.
Which resident?
The one who was so busy
shaking her tail in front of my son.
Oh, Edwards isn't dumb.
You're right.
She's strategic.
Jackson is dumb.
Catherine...
I'm going to go and salvage
this patient's manhood.
But when I come back,
I want to have a serious
conversation with you
about coming home with me.
Sorry. I came to see
if your drain output
picked up after we stripped it,
but I can come back later.
You're not progressing
very quickly here.
They're all in love with
you, and afraid of you.
So they're coddling
you. It's very sweet,
but ultimately a disservice.
You need to push yourself.
You need someone to push you.
This is a long road, and
the slower you go down it,
the poorer your chances are.
I love you, but I
will not coddle you.
I never learned how.
Come here.
Just think about it. Please?
You're a goddess. I know.
This is Grey. WOMAN: Dr. Grey.
It's Karen at the
day care center.
Zola took a spill off the slide,
and she nicked
the side of her head.
She's probably going
to need a few stitches.
Is she able to stand? Did
she ever lose consciousness?
What happened?
I'm a teacher... She
cut her head open.
Well, go. I'll tell Yang. Okay.
So tell Cristina to go ahead
and talk to Samantha without me,
and I will meet her in the OR.
Okay. Poor baby.
All right. I got a quick consult
on a Stevens-Johnson syndrome,
and then I'll be right in to
check in on my mother's penis.
I mean, the patient's penis that
my mom asked me to consult on.
Why couldn't she have been a
hand specialist or ears or something?
Does it really have to be
you and me and your mom
all staring at a penis?
It is not that loaded for her.
Okay, it's her work. She loves it.
Just ask her questions
and make it medical.
She'll probably forget
about me and you.
Honestly, she
probably already forgot.
How nice to see the
two of you together again,
and all dressed this time.
I did it. 'Cause I'm amazing.
Wait. What are you doing?
I'm discharged, right?
Oh, no. We're keeping
you here overnight
'cause I got you 28
days at Somerville
starting tomorrow.
It's a good center.
Strong program, great people,
and they said that they
would waive the fees for you.
I appreciate it.
Mmm-hmm.
That's all right.
It's all set up.
And they're gonna
come get you tomorrow.
Why are you doing this?
What is your deal here?
I mean, you pull
your strings for every
itinerate junkie
musician that shows up?
You said that you
would go if I set it up.
You said that you would go...
No, see, I never said that.
That's against my policy.
That's how you screw up.
You tell someone you're
gonna do something,
you set 'em up
for disappointment.
That's how you lose
your home, your family.
Make your children hate you.
Look, you're a sweet kid,
and I don't even know you.
But I don't want to let
you down, too. All right?
'Cause you'd never let me
hear the end of
it, you damn nag.
Jimmy, if you keep going
the way that you are going...
I appreciate your concern.
More than I can say.
Just take care now.
You can help.
Oh, my God.
He's leaving, and
he's miserable,
and he's full of
regret about you.
And you're angry. And
you've always been angry.
And I think this
could help you, too.
And I think it's
your last chance
because he's gonna
go and use again,
and he's gonna die.
Look, don't talk to
me about this again.
All right? Ever.
Oh, how's Zola?
Oh, she'll be fine.
Once Grey gets down
there, she'll stitch her up,
and be back in time to scrub in.
It's happening again!
Oh, she's desatting.
Uh, I'm gonna intubate.
Push 5 of Versed and
100 of succinylcholine.
What happened?
She's gone into
heart failure again.
Check on the organs
and book an OR.
We're bringing her down
as soon as she's intubated.
Okay, got that closed up.
Now let me see. Did
I miss anything else?
I don't see anything.
That's what's called a
rhetorical question, my dear.
All right, let's take a look
at this penis, shall we?
Mmm.
Uh, Dr. Avery, can
you elaborate on
some of your more
interesting cases?
I'm fascinated by
all things penile.
Yes, I saw evidence of
that earlier this morning.
How's it looking, dear?
Well, it's possible he's
gonna need a skin graft,
- but nothing I can't fix.
- Mmm.
Yeah, he'll be able to
stick it in a hornet's nest,
an ant hill, a tarantula's...
Wherever they live.
Well, I find that men
often put their penises
in places that
they don't belong.
Mmm-hmm.
Suction, dear, come on.
Okay, Supergirl. That's
the only ouch-y part.
Now you're not gonna
feel anything at all.
You are so brave.
I'm so proud of you.
My patient's going into the OR.
When? Right now.
It wasn't supposed to be
for another hour at least.
Well, go ahead. Uh, I'll have
Jenna come in and hold her.
Doesn't that sound a
little Ellis Grey to you?
To leave my kid to go to surgery
while she's getting stitches?
You're a good mom, Mer. Take
it from me. I had crap parents.
I know the difference. Besides,
she's not gonna be alone.
She's gonna be with me, who she
loves more than her own parents.
I can't believe I'm doing this.
Yeah. Can you
send Jenna in here?
Look, don't cry, or she will.
The general surgeons
weren't able to
repair your
sister's kidney, so...
We're gonna... Let's
just cut to the chase.
Eventually, she's
going to need a kidney.
Right?
Okay.
Well, here I am.
Open the toolbox. Take
whatever she needs.
Hey, look, this doesn't
have to happen right now.
Okay, she'll be on dialysis
until we find a donor.
You don't need to be spare
parts for your sister anymore.
Here's what I need.
I need a boyfriend and a job.
And a Caribbean cruise.
And I would like to
learn to ride a bike,
because I never learned
to ride one when I was little.
I couldn't get injured 'cause
Reese might need some body part.
And I'd love to not be spare
parts for my sister anymore,
but can I do that?
Can I say no?
Yes, you can say
no. It's your life.
You know, you
should ride that bike.
Go on that cruise.
Get a boyfriend.
Dance in your underwear.
Yeah, you can say no.
I can say no. Yeah,
it feels good, right?
I can say no!
You can say no!
No! No! No!
No!
Oh, sweetie.
I'm his wife. I was out
of town. What happened?
Well, he came in with quite a
few stings in his groin area. And...
Oh, no. He didn't.
He stuck his penis in that
hornet's nest, didn't he?
You knew?
How?
I saw a nest on
the eaves as I left.
I knew I should
have had it removed.
So this is something
he's done before?
He's someone who
likes a little pain
with his pleasure.
Any kind of sting, really.
Bee, ant.
I'm sure he was ashamed.
That's why it took
him so long to come in.
I don't understand it either.
But it's just one thing. There
are 500 things about him
that are so much
more interesting.
That is not possible.
Whew! I'm here.
What's she doing here?
She's doing the liver.
I'm doing the liver.
She needed two staples. I actually
left her in the hands of Jenna.
That nurse that... I
don't care about Zola.
I'm thinking about the patient.
Whoa, dial it back for a second.
Does she have a concussion?
No, she's fine. Are you?
You're gonna be worried
about that and 100 other things
besides my patient and my liver.
She is my patient, and
she was my patient before...
Did you finish reading
the article on performing
simultaneous transplants
completely under CPB?
Dr. Bailey knows the procedure.
Dr. Bailey is scrubbing
in on my patient.
Sorry.
Probably should have
checked back earlier.
Your white blood
cell count is elevated.
I'd like to start
you on antibiotics.
Why do I need antibiotics?
Because there's a left shift?
You need to examine me to find
out what's causing the elevation.
Murphy.
I don't want to be coddled
or pussyfooted around.
No offense. It makes
you a bad doctor
and me a sicker
patient. So buck up,
lift my gown and give me
a proper hands-on exam.
Yes, sir.
It feels distended.
Okay, what does that tell you?
There could be fluid buildup.
Okay.
You're checking the drain?
There's no output.
Okay, what else?
You have epigastric
tenderness, increased WBC,
and little to no drain output,
which means you have a
symptomatic pancreatic leak.
Okay.
Which also means I'm
in a great deal of pain.
Now you need to try
and unclog the drain
with a Fogarty catheter so
this doesn't happen again!
God.
There's the bossy
Richard I know and love.
They're gonna learn
how to look me in the eye
and explain to me what
they're doing so I understand.
When I ask a question,
they're going to answer it.
They're gonna figure out why
my pancreas still requires a drain.
So take it you're not
coming home with me.
These fools need me, Catherine.
Well, what if I need you, too?
Come here.
You got me.
I'm right here.
Hey, going back to the tribe?
After I grab Sofia.
How about you?
Seeing your not-girlfriend?
That was the plan, but I'm going
to talk to the hang glider's sister.
She decided to
donate a kidney after all.
Take it easy, pal.
How'd it go?
Her initial labs look good.
She's, uh, headed down to
the cardiac ICU. If you want...
You stole that surgery from me.
I'm sorry.
I really wish you could
have been in there with me.
I worked my ass off to
do that surgery with you,
and you stole it from
me. That was low...
Meredith, you were unprepared,
you were unfocused,
and you were late.
I didn't steal that
surgery from you.
I rescued that surgery from you.
Oh, I... Because
you couldn't do it.
I understand that you believe
you are God's gift to medicine,
but I am every bit as talented and
competent a surgeon as you are.
No, you're not.
I'm sorry.
But you're not.
And that's...
That's okay.
You have different
priorities now.
You cut back on
your clinical hours,
you log in less time in the OR.
I mean, you don't do
research, and I get it.
I mean, you have Zola and baby
Bailey and you want to be a good mom.
I don't believe you.
You are saying that I can't
be a good surgeon and a mom.
Of course not. Bailey is a mom,
and she was
fantastic in there today.
Then what are you
saying? I'm saying...
Okay. Bailey never let up.
Okay, she, like, lives here.
Callie never let up.
Ellis Grey never let up.
And I know you don't
want to be your mother.
I'm saying...
I'm saying
you and I started running down
the same road at the same time,
and at a certain
point you let up.
You slowed down.
And don't say that I don't
support that, because I do.
You made your choices,
and they are valid choices.
But don't pretend they
don't affect your skills.
You are a very
good surgeon. It's...
We're in different places now.
And that's okay.
I mean, they were huge.
They were hard to hold.
Yeah? Yeah, they
kind of hooked like that.
You see those people
down there? Mmm-hmm.
Those are the top 12
neurosurgeons in the world,
and they need a
drink. You got it.
Hey.
I am going to need
my place back.
Look, I feel bad
about kicking you out,
but I need to stop taking
care of other people.
I took care of you for a year.
I picked you up off
the bathroom floor.
I took your abuse.
But you're not sick anymore.
Now you're just someone who
cheated, and you did that to yourself.
So, I'm sorry, but I
need my life back.
I need me back, and
I need to do it tonight,
or I'm afraid I'll
change my mind.
So, I will have an
intern pack up your stuff
and bring it to the
hospital tomorrow.
You can stay at my place.
Okay, you know what?
Okay. Just tell me,
what did I do? What did we do?
'Cause clearly something
happened after the gala,
and whatever it was,
I'm sorry, I don't...
Oh, my God.
I can't believe you
don't remember.
Well, I was drunk,
and you're pretty...
We hung out.
Oh.
After I put you in the cab, I called to
see if you and Kepner made it home
and you didn't answer,
so I went to check.
And good thing, because you were
passed out on the hallway floor.
Oh.
I helped you inside.
And you insisted on
having a dance party.
We made the most amazing
grilled cheese sandwiches
and ate them while
we watched the films
of Dr. Shepherd
doing the spinal AVM,
which he did today,
which is when you
asked me to be there.
Oh.
It was the first
time I felt like
I found someone
around here who got me.
Do you really not
remember any of it?
I vaguely remember
the grilled cheese.
Let's go back to the part
where you said I was pretty.
That part?
Excuse me, Dr. Avery.
Do you have a minute?
I'm meeting my son,
Edwards. It's been a long day.
I just think that we probably
got off on the wrong foot.
Your feet were
not the issue, dear.
I know how it looked.
I'm quite sure you don't.
No, I really do. I
was having a quickie
with your son in
the on-call room.
And it suggests I
have no self-respect.
It suggests that I, like
much of my generation,
don't understand that
where we choose to have sex
says a lot about what
we think of ourselves.
And a lot of the work you
did to break down barriers
for women, and in
particular, women of color,
was a whole lot
of wasted effort.
Mmm.
I picked a shirt to wear today
because I knew I'd be meeting you.
A really respectable one.
Meeting Jackson's mother
meant something to me.
I care about him.
And the shirt coming
off in the on-call room,
that was really, like, a joke about
people who have sex in on-call rooms.
And that's the only thing
you're gonna think of
when you think of me now.
There are 500 other
things about me
that are so much more
interesting than that.
Well, I will also
think about the fact
that you didn't
put in a catheter
until the man's bladder... Okay.
In all fairness, I wasn't
getting all the information
I needed to diagnose.
When in doubt,
assume they put it someplace
unimaginable and move on.
Oh, hey, um, I was just leaving.
Well, what's your
hurry? I'm buying.
So...
Sleep tight.
What if your focus splits?
What if you can't be all in?
Are you left with
nothing at all?
Maybe you just need
to find a different path.
Hey! How's Zola?
Karev filled me in. Said
she was a real champ.
She didn't get her
princess tea party.
Wait. I thought Callie
was gonna do that.
Callie has moved out,
and she was
supposed to do the food
shopping. So now
there's no food.
Zola has two
stitches in her head
and had cereal for dinner,
and the house is a mess
because I couldn't
get the baby to sleep.
And she didn't get
her princess tea party.
Why are you yelling at
me? I had a big surgery.
So did I!
But you didn't
answer your phone.
She cut her head, and you
didn't answer your phone.
So I had to go comfort
her, which means that
I didn't get to do my surgery.
A heart/liver transplant.
Those never happen,
and I didn't get to do it.
I'm sorry, but
that is not my fault.
It is your fault
because you didn't
answer your phone!
I was in a surgery.
I shouldn't have to choose
between being a good mother
and being a good surgeon.
I never asked you to do that.
Never have I
asked you to do that.
Here's what's horrifying.
What if you can't give 100%?
Maybe you just need to
go back to the beginning.
And start all over again.