- Look at--
- Oh, he's so cute.
- Of course he is.
He's half Natalie.
Look.
- Aww!
So precious.
Oh, and would you look at that.
He got my eyelashes.
- You delivered him.
That doesn't give him your DNA.
- You'd be surprised.
The power of these hands.
- You can sign out
the patient in four.
- Look--look at Owen.
- Cute.
- Have you been up to see
Natalie today?
- Not yet.
- What's up with him?
Thought he wouldn't leave
her bedside.
[phone rings]
- Dr. Zanetti.
- Dr. Rhodes.
- How was the conference?
- I spent an entire week
listening to people
talk about surgeries.
All I wanted was
to actually do one.
Kept hoping a speaker would
choke on his dentures
so I could cric him.
- Dinner tonight?
- I can't.
I'm in-house on call.
- Head's up. Incoming traumas.
CFD called with a Plan 1.
Multi-victim car crash.
Let's go!
- Maybe someone'll need surgery.
I'm ready to cut.
- What do we got?
- Female, mid-20s. GCS 3.
Struck the dashboard
and starred the windshield.
- BP?
- Uh, 90 over 50.
Tachy 140. Stats 100%.
Pressure dressing on her head,
but she's seeping through.
- All right, we're gonna replace
the King with an ET.
Grab an intubation kit.
Let's move her on my count.
One...two...three.
[sirens blare]
- Jess?
Jess...Jess...
- Mike Carter, 24.
GCS 10. Vitals holding steady.
- Jess?
- Blood?
- Not his.
- Jess, talk to me!
Jess!
- Mike. Mike.
I'm gonna ask you to calm down.
- Jess!
Where is she?
- Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
You have to lie back down.
- All right, on my count.
- All right.
- One...two...three.
- Does Jess have any family
in the area we should notify?
- I think...her mom lives here.
Maybe.
- Any allergies to medications?
- I don't know.
- Do you know if she's currently
on any medication?
- I don't know.
- Is there anything
you can tell us about Jess
that could help us?
- No. I'm sorry, I--
I don't even know
where she lives.
We're on a first date.
- Breath sounds good
on both sides.
Good color change.
- All right.
Hang two units of blood.
- Yes, Doctor.
- Get me a plastics tray.
- Got it.
- We need to stop
these bleeders.
Saline?
- Got it. Here's saline.
- Okay, she's still got
glass shards in her scalp.
- Heart rate is erratic.
- Suction.
- Yeah, got it.
- Please, I need to know
how she is.
- Jess is in good hands.
Right now, we just need
to make sure that you're okay.
- I'm fine, just please,
help her.
Ah!
- Sorry.
I'm guessing that's tender.
- Ah. Yes.
- Pressure's falling.
- Get me the ultrasound.
- Got it.
Call pharmacy.
Get dopamine going.
[overlapping chatter]
- There's free fluid
in her abdomen.
- Pressure's still low.
- She's not stable enough
to go to CT.
Call the OR and tell them
we're on our way up.
- Yes, Doctor.
- Talk to me.
- Walter Blevins. 53 years old.
GCS 14, SBP 104 over palp.
Stats 100.
- Dr. Halstead, Treatment 1.
- Got it.
- 4 of morphine per
the tele doctor.
- Ah.
- Let's rotate.
Give him the head.
Let's go.
- What happened?
- He was driving the car
that t-boned
the couple they just brought in.
A stolen car.
- On my count.
One...two...three.
- Transfer. Get this out.
- [moans]
- Airway's intact.
Let's get him off that
backboard.
Mr. Blevins, we're gonna
roll you onto your right side.
I need you
to take these handcuffs off.
- He carjacked a woman
at gunpoint
50 yards from me and my partner.
Led us on a high-speed chase
before hitting that couple.
This guy's dangerous.
- I'll take my chances.
- He served nine years
for armed robbery.
He's an ex-con.
- He's also my patient.
I can't treat him properly
until the cuffs are off.
- All right.
- Dr. Halstead, you got this?
- Yeah, we're good.
- [groans]
Ah...
- All right.
Okay, you're all right.
- [groans]
- Any pain on contact?
- No.
- Good.
- I'm sorry.
- Oh, Dr. Halstead, his arm.
- [heavy breathing]
- All right. Yep.
That's likely a two-bone
forearm fracture.
Let's get an X-ray.
- Lap sponges, keep 'em coming.
- Yes, Doctor.
- There's too much blood.
I can't see
where it's coming from.
- Feel for it.
[monitor beeps]
- Pressure's dropping.
- Dr. Rhodes, I'll clamp.
- The belly's packed.
The spleen is in pieces.
Something else is bleeding.
- Okay.
Run the bowel.
Oh, the mesentery's bleeding.
I will clamp it, Dr. Rhodes.
You get the spleen.
- Curved 8 to me.
[dramatic music]
♪
Metz scissors.
- Scissors.
- And bowl.
- Bowl.
- Thank you.
I'll hold the clamp, you tie.
- All right,
the bleeding stopped.
How's she doing?
- Pressure's coming up.
- There we go.
- Okay.
You guys finish up here
and bring her down to ICU.
- Okay, let's close him up.
- Happy to be back
in the saddle?
- Boo-yah.
- April. Nice to see you.
- Bobby,
back so soon?
- Yeah, my feet this time.
- What happened to your shoes?
- There's this new guy
at the shelter.
He needed winter boots.
I still have my slippers,
though.
- All right, this is
a tetanus shot.
Is that okay?
- Oh.
Anything you say.
- Okay. Thank you.
- Mm-hmm.
- All right.
Now, Bobby, you shouldn't be
giving away your boots.
Particularly in January.
- Oh, I'll manage.
I always do.
- How did you manage last week
after you gave away your gloves?
- Frostbite's all healed.
- You're too much.
All right, soak your feet.
- Ah.
- I'll be back to check on you.
- Okay. Thanks.
- That excuse is so lame
it needs crutches.
Roger, I put in that order
hours ago.
No, I will not hold.
Roger?
Rog?
Oh.
Normally after that,
I would go downstairs
and ring Roger's ass.
But not today.
I'm in too good a mood.
- And why is that?
- Christy Pierce.
- Oh, yeah.
Today's the big day.
- Uh-huh.
- Christy Pierce?
- Yeah, a teen
with aplastic anemia.
Been in and out of Med
the last ten years
due to infections,
but finally,
today she's getting
a bone marrow transplant.
- It hasn't been ten years.
- Yes, it has.
I know because I was
sitting in your chair
the first time her mother
brought her here.
- You think I'm tough?
You should've seen her.
- I'm going up to say hello.
- Give Christy a kiss for me.
- So Dr. Farinas has told me
that a transplant isn't painful.
You'll be awake the whole time.
- It's a simple process.
We'll administer
the donor's stem cells
through your central line.
- It's just like
a blood transfusion.
- Is it really happening?
Finally.
- Well, we just heard
from the clinic in Springfield.
The bags are en route.
- Oh, my God.
- Mom, you promised.
No crying.
- I'm sorry, I just--
I can't help it.
- And, Nick,
I can't believe you.
You're almost as tall as me.
- And he has been
a very busy little brother.
He's got all his friends
together
and they've been shoveling
driveways to raise money.
Oh, show Mrs. Goodwin the flyer.
- We're gonna send
Christy's donor and her family
on a vacation.
- They've already raised $1,000.
- That's a sweet gesture.
- He's just trying
to build up his muscles
to impress the girls.
- Am not!
- Well, I'll leave you
in good hands with Dr. Farinas.
I'll check back later.
- Thank you.
- Dr. Rose,
pretty slick in the OR.
- Thank you.
- That was a very fast
splenectomy for a fellow.
Had to be under 30 seconds.
Where'd you pick that up?
- Riyadh.
- Mm.
- Oil workers
got a lot of abdominal injuries
on the derricks.
- Hmm.
- Hold the elevator, please!
Hold the elevator!
- Ah! Ow!
Damn it.
- Sorry. Thanks.
- You okay?
- Yes.
I, um, just banged it
on the shower in Orlando.
- Let me take a look at it.
- No, no, no.
It's fine.
- No, no.
- It's fine, really.
- Just--hey, hey.
Shush, shush. Just, shh.
[elevator bell dings]
- [laughs]
Wait, no. No, no, no.
What are we doing?
- You are going to Ortho
to get that checked out.
- No, it's not necessary.
- Uh, your elbow is red
and it feels hot.
So, yeah, it is.
- Yeah, well,
I put myself on Cipro, so--
- Oh, so you know
you have an infection?
- Just as a precaution.
- Well, as a precaution,
because that may need
to be drained.
- [laughing]
- Look, Sam? Sam.
This is serious.
You know better.
Don't mess around.
- Okay. All right.
I will get it looked at.
- Okay.
That's all I'm asking.
- [chuckles]
- Ouch.
- You were right.
Two-bone distal fracture,
moderately displaced.
Needs to be plated.
- It didn't take
a diagnostic genius.
Not with that
degree of deformity.
Mr. Blevins--
- I'm done here.
Let 'em take me away.
- Well, I'm afraid, first,
you need surgery
to realign
the bones in your arm.
We're gonna have
an orthopedic surgeon
come down right now to--
- No. No surgery.
[coughing]
- Well, without it, your arm
may not heal properly.
You could have
a permanent deformity
and reduced function.
- Put a cast on it.
- Mr. Blevins,
you want some water?
- No--no, what I want
is to be taken out of here.
Put the cuffs--
[gurgles]
Put the cuffs on!
- Whoa. Mr. Blevins.
- [coughs]
[screams]
- Okay.
I need--
- [screams]
- All right, I need suction.
Get a crash cart
and have atropine ready
in case his heart rate drops.
We are not losing this guy.
- Where is he?
Where is Walter?
- We are running a few tests
right now.
When he's done,
I can take you to him.
Oh, Dr. Halstead,
this is Mrs. Blevins.
- Please, someone tell me
what's going on.
- Your husband
was in a car accident.
He has a badly broken arm
and in the last half hour
he began coughing up blood
and passed out.
- Oh, my God!
- Is Walter being treated
for any illnesses?
- No.
No, he's--he's fine.
I need to see him.
- Okay.
I can take you to his room.
- Excuse me. Um, Mrs. Blevins?
My name's Jay Halstead.
I'm a detective with
the Chicago Police Department.
I need to ask you a few
questions about your husband.
- Why are the police involved?
I thought Walter
was in an accident.
- Uh, yes.
He was driving a car
that he stole.
At gunpoint.
- What?
- There's multiple witnesses.
- That son of a bitch.
- I'm sorry.
Ma'am?
- My husband is no angel.
I knew that when I married him,
but he has been straight
for 18 years.
Has a job, a kid,
and now, out of the blue,
he throws it all away?
I warned him, if he ever
committed another crime,
I would leave him,
and that is exactly
what I'm going to do.
What do you want to know?
- Um, why don't we go
sit down somewhere?
Yeah.
- I'm looking for
a Robert Parker.
- Bobby's in Treatment 3.
Wha--who called
for a psych consult?
- The attending,
Dr. Movitt.
Why?
- I know Bobby.
Treated him for a month now.
He's just really kind.
- Huh.
I guess there's some concern
that he can't
take care of himself?
- Because he gave
some clothes away?
He just likes to help people.
- Oh,
just gonna have a little chat.
- He is such a good nurser.
I think it took Jeff
three or four days
to actually get the hang of it.
- He's so beautiful.
- Mm-hmm.
Oh, look at this.
I couldn't resist.
A little something for him
to wear on the way home.
Isn't that cute?
- Oh,
I think he's finished.
- Oh, you think he is?
Here. I'll get him.
You come here.
You come here to me.
Yeah. Oh.
[baby coos]
Oh.
[chuckles]
- You know,
my parents emailed.
They should be here soon.
- Oh.
Well, they'll be so happy
to see the baby.
They must miss you terribly.
- Yeah, they complain
about it all the time.
Always asking when I'm gonna
move back to Seattle.
- Do you ever think about that?
- Oh, yeah,
but I want to finish
my fellowship.
- Oh.
Well, you met Jeff here.
You must have a lot
of good memories here.
- Of course I do.
- I mean, I know the weather's
not good in Chicago,
but Seattle, ugh.
That rain?
I'd get depressed.
What do you think?
- So, uh, how long you been
living at the shelter, Bobby?
- Uh, about two months now.
- And where were you
before that?
- At home.
Uh, Lincoln Park.
- Ooh, nice neighborhood.
Shelter must have been
quite a change.
- I don't mind.
The people there need me.
I don't have much anymore,
but what I do have,
I'm happy to give.
- And what prompted you
to make the move
from Lincoln Park?
- It's my wife's idea.
She said I was giving away
all of our savings.
Bankrupting the family.
She didn't know
what happened to me.
Why I changed.
- Uh, tell me how you changed.
- [chuckles]
I used to be a regular guy.
Corporate job, a house,
a couple of cars.
One morning I woke up,
and I realized that
the only thing I wanted to do,
the only thing that mattered,
was helping other people.
Giving whatever I had to them.
- Any idea of the, uh--
the source of this inspiration?
- You mean did God talk to me?
Or an angel?
No, no, I--
I just knew...
inside.
- I can barely see it.
- It's the gray spot
right here.
That's the hematoma.
We often see it in car crashes.
When the seatbelt you were
wearing tightened,
it caused a deep bruise
around your intestine.
- So I'm, like,
bleeding inside?
- Not anymore.
Blood's clotted now,
formed a solid mass,
causing the swelling and pain
you're feeling in your stomach.
The swelling should go down
in a couple days.
For the next few hours,
we'll continue to monitor you.
So sit tight, all right?
- What about Jess?
- She's still in ICU.
- We met at this coffee shop,
but it was too crowded,
so I suggested we drive
to one a few miles away.
That's when it happened.
Can I see her?
- I'll have a nurse
take you up to ICU
once Jess has been cleared
for visitors.
- Thanks.
- Sure.
- And initial there, please.
And sign here
to acknowledge receipt.
That's two bags HLA-matched
bone marrow-regenerating
stem cells
for patient Christy Pierce.
- Thank you.
Careful with these.
Thanks.
- Fingers crossed.
- Sharon.
I'm sorry to have to tell you
this, believe me.
- Tell me what?
- The hospital's decided
to shut down
Christy Pierce's transplant.
- What?
- Have you seen these?
- Yeah, Christy's brother
put them up.
He organized a fundraiser.
- For Christy's donor.
And the hospital is concerned
about the appearance
of an individual being
compensated
for donating an organ, which--
- Violates federal law.
I know that,
but no one's being paid.
The donor agreed months ago.
- Well, it still puts
the hospital and its staff
at risk for hefty fines,
sanctions,
I mean, even imprisonment.
- It's a kid doing a good deed.
He's a minor.
- It doesn't matter.
These flyers have put us
in an impossible situation.
- Well how about Christy's
impossible situation?
- Maggie.
- It--
- Christy has just gone through
five days of chemotherapy
and radiation.
Her body has been ravaged
in preparation
for this transplant.
Without it, she will die.
- It's out of my hands.
- No, Peter,
it's still in your hands.
Find a way to fix this.
- I will do my best,
but the law does not give me
a lot of room to maneuver
on this.
You need to look
for another donor.
- [sighs]
- I don't understand.
They can't just
shut the transplant down.
They can't do that.
- I'm sorry, Kathleen.
They can and they have.
- No, there must be
something you can do.
- We're exploring
our legal options,
but the only thing
we can do right now
is look for another donor
which we're doing.
- Wha--what if we promise
not to give any of the proceeds
to the donor?
- Unfortunately, the intent
was to give a financial gift
to the donor,
which is enough
in the eyes of the law.
- Intent?
Are these lawyers
gonna go in there
and tell my daughter
that intent
is more important than she is?
Are they willing
to let her die?
- Do you want me
to break the news to Christy?
- No.
I'm her mother.
I'll tell her.
- Mr. Blevins,
how are you feeling?
I hope that means better.
Has anything like that
ever happened before?
- How's the couple I hit?
- She's in the ICU.
We're monitoring him.
- Can they take me away now?
- First, we need to discuss
the results of your chest X-ray.
- [sighs]
- We discovered a mass,
approximately two centimeters
in diameter,
in the left lobe of your lungs.
Now, a finding like that,
in conjunction with
coughing blood--
I'm concerned.
We need a CT scan, and then
a possible biopsy--
- Don't bother.
- Well, we really should
determine--
- It's cancer.
I've known about it
for a few months.
- When I spoke with
your wife earlier,
she didn't mention
that you were diagnosed.
- She doesn't know about it.
- Well, have you started
treatment, or--
- Look, you've run
your little test.
You've checked all the boxes,
but now,
I just want the cops
to get me out of here.
- Well, I can't release
you until I'm sure
you're stable enough for jail.
- Well,
do what you have to.
- All right.
- Don't tell my wife
about this.
[sighs]
[monitors beeping]
- [whispers]
Jess.
- Mike.
- I wanted to see
how you were.
How are you feeling?
- Oh, he smells like heaven.
Think he knows me?
- Of course he does.
[door opening]
- Hello!
- [gasps]
Mom!
- Hello, sweetheart.
- Hi, Daddy.
- Helen.
Hello, Helen. Congratulations.
[gasp]
Oh, let me hold him.
- Well, he--he's asleep.
- Oh, yes, he is.
Yes, he is.
Oh, yes you are.
Yes, you are.
- Look at this beautiful boy.
- Can you believe
we're grandparents?
Oh, I think he has
your daddy's mouth.
- You think?
- Watch his head.
- Oh, here. Here he is.
- Oh, my goodness.
- Oh.
- Oh, wait till
Auntie and Uncle Cliff meet him.
for when you and Owen
come to visit.
- Just don't take down
my Nick Carter poster, okay?
- We won't. We promise.
- Good. Right.
- Dr. Charles.
I heard Bobby was upstairs
getting a CT?
- Yeah, just want to rule out
any organic cause
for his behavior, that's all.
- You think he's crazy?
- You mean like delusional
or psychotic?
Not at all.
Quite rational, in fact.
- Then why the CT?
- Actions are a little
obsessive, if not compulsive.
You know,
giving your shoes away
in Chicago
in the middle of the winter?
You've, um...
taken quite an interest
in Mr. Parker, haven't you?
- Yeah, I guess I have.
It's...
never mind.
- Try me.
- St. Francis.
He reminds me of St. Francis.
I was raised Catholic.
- Ah.
- And growing up, we had
this little statue
of San Francisco in the garden.
Of all the saints,
he was my favorite.
He gave away all his money,
all his possessions,
to the poor.
Took care of the sick
with no thought of himself.
- Remarkable fella.
- I'm not saying Bobby
is an actual saint,
but...saintly?
Yeah.
- We're just--
want to make sure
we're doing the right thing
by him, that's all.
- Yeah.
- Boss?
- Yeah?
- Peter Kalmick's
in Treatment 4.
- What?
- Mm-hmm.
- What happened?
- I've been getting
these pounding headaches.
- His blood pressure spiked.
Dr. Movitt put him
on a nipride drip.
Pressure's coming down.
- Thank you.
- Christy Pierce,
there's nothing I can do.
You understand why the sale
of human organs is illegal.
Once they have monetary value,
at best,
poor people will sell them.
At worst, people will get
killed for them.
- I get all that.
How about you try this?
Bone marrow is not an organ.
- According to the National
Organ Transplant Act, it is.
- But that's wrong.
A donor's marrow regenerates
itself within two weeks.
It's just like giving blood.
- Come on, Sharon.
I've done my homework.
In 2011, the Ninth Circuit
Court of Appeals
ruled that bone marrow donors
can be compensated
because the cells are
blood parts, not organ parts.
- So what's the problem?
- The problem is that that's
the Ninth Circuit.
It's Arizona, Montana.
We're in Illinois, the Seventh.
It hasn't ruled.
Look--
[sighs]
I shouldn't just gone into
estate planning like my brother.
It's so much less stressful.
- I'm sorry you're suffering,
Peter,
but your stress is nothing
compared to
what's going on upstairs.
[alarm blares]
- Help!
- That's Jess's room.
- She must have thrown a clot.
- Help him, please. Somebody!
- He was complaining of
abdominal pain.
CT showed a duodenal hematoma.
- Oh, Mike!
Mike--
- Ah!
- It must've ruptured.
We need to get him
up to the OR, now.
- Yes, Doctor.
- Is he gonna be all right?
- We'll do our best.
- [grunts]
- There's too much blood.
More suction.
- Suction.
- There's food particles
mixed in with his blood.
- Slow down,
it won't do you any good
if you make the injury bigger.
- If he bleeds out,
it won't help me, either.
It's a big duodenal hematoma
with pretty brisk bleeding
along the anterior perforation.
Stitch?
- The lac extends
into the second portion.
- I can see that.
- Stay clear of the ampulla.
- What did the Ortho say
about the elbow?
- Just concentrate
on your surgery.
- Did he drain it?
- Make sure you close
transversely.
- I got it.
- In two layers.
- I know what I'm doing.
- Don't take that tone with me,
Dr. Rhodes.
I'm your attending.
- Right.
Close him up.
Unless Dr. Zanetti
would prefer to.
- Helen?
Maggie.
- Why are you out here
and not with Natalie?
- Oh, um,
her--her parents
flew in from Seattle,
so...
they're in there with her.
- Okay.
- [sobs]
- Oh.
- [whimpers]
Je--Jeff was my--
my only child,
and...
and his dad and I divorced
when he was three.
He's remarried and...
lives in Arizona someplace.
The rest of my family is...
gone.
Jeff is gone...
and Natalie and Owen...
[sobs]
They're--
they're all I have.
They're all--
- Oh, honey.
- I don't want Natalie
and the baby go to Seattle.
- I'm selfish too.
I don't want Natalie to go.
- [sobbing]
- Hey there, Bobby.
- Hey.
- Got your CT results back.
I'd like to go over them
with you if you have a sec.
- I can finish this later.
- No, no. Stay.
It's--it's fine.
- So...
when we talked before
about the change you
experienced,
you said that it was sudden.
Happened overnight.
- That's right.
- The abrupt nature
of the change
made me wonder if there might
be a physical cause.
So here, I want you to take
a look at something.
This...
is an image of a typical brain.
And this...
is yours.
- Why does it look different?
- Because you, my friend,
had a stroke.
- That's--
I know stroke victims.
- There are actually many
different kinds of strokes.
Yours caused lesions to form
in the frontal lobe.
That's the region of the brain
that controls,
among many other things,
behavior and judgment.
- So you're saying
I'm brain damaged?
- I'm saying that,
in your instance,
the stroke didn't cause
any physical impairment,
but it did cause you to become
what, clinically,
I would describe as
pathologically generous.
Making you compulsively
driven to give.
- So I help people
because of damage to my brain?
- Basically, yeah.
- But it feels good.
It makes me happy.
- Makes sense.
- I--I...
don't want you to fix it.
- Well, that's fortunate
because,
truthfully, even if you did,
aside from some
behavioral therapy,
we can't.
- Okay.
I got back in touch
with the shelter.
They're happy
to have you back.
In case you didn't know,
you've become
something of a star there.
Do you mind if I share
some details of your condition
so that they can
help take care of you?
- Sure.
- Great.
- [chuckles]
- Please call me
if there are any changes.
Thank you.
- Was that the
National Registry?
- So far no matches,
but we're in touch
with every donor network
in the region.
We're not giving up.
- Mom!
- What is it?
- Something's wrong
with Christy.
- Oh, God.
[dramatic music]
[monitor beeping rapidly]
No, Christy!
- No, no, no.
We should stay out here.
♪
- [whimpers]
No.
[crying]
- Mr. Blevins is stable.
I'm gonna go grab
a cup of coffee.
- Take that basket to Natalie,
would you?
Radiology sent it.
- Maggie?
- Uh-huh.
- You know,
I don't want to give anyone
the wrong impression.
- The wrong impression?
- Natalie just had a baby.
- Oh. Uh-huh.
I know that.
- Her husband died
only six months ago.
- I know that too.
- So, I don't want to give
anyone the wrong impression.
- It amazes me
how dumb a doctor can be.
Everybody knows
you like Natalie.
- They do?
- So, don't make things
too complicated.
Just take the basket.
[baby coos]
- From your fans in radiology.
- Well, hey there, stranger.
- What can I tell you?
These crazy sick people
just keep
rolling into the ED.
- Owen started to think
you forgot about him.
- Pretty sure the only thing
he thinks about
is his next hit of dairy.
- [laughs]
So, tell me what's been
going on downstairs.
- You want to talk shop?
- I'm desperate.
- Well, I do have
this one patient.
He...
- Hi, Will.
- Hi, Mrs. Manning.
- Oh, please. Call me Helen.
I'm so glad you came up.
Natalie's been looking for you.
- Oh, don't guilt him out,
Helen.
- I'm afraid I'm good at that.
You're a Chicago boy,
aren't you, Will?
- Canaryville.
Three generations.
- We used to live out
in Canaryville. South Aberdeen.
- Okay.
- Wait.
You guys are talking, so--
- You know, Mom and Dad
just went down
to the cafeteria to grab a bite
if you want to join them.
- Oh, yeah,
I'll do that.
- Great.
- What's up with her?
- What do you mean?
- Yesterday
she wasn't so friendly.
- It's the birth.
It was very stressful for her.
- Yeah.
- All right,
tell me about this patient.
- Okay, so,
he was in a car accident.
Severely fractured arm,
lung cancer,
and as soon as I discharge him,
he's going to jail.
Oh, and his wife just left him.
- Ooh, sounds like
a country song.
- Yeah. Pretty hopeless case.
- Hmm.
Well, the one thing
he's got going for him.
At least in prison,
he'll get the treatment
that he needs.
- Yeah, he will.
[elevator bell dings]
- Hey.
- About what happened
in the OR today--
- Pro forma,
I was acting as your
supervising
attending physician.
- I think maybe
it was more than that.
Look, Sam, you're a surgeon,
that's who you are,
and right now,
you can't operate.
- Oh, I see.
So out of my frustration,
I laid into you.
- Well...
- Couldn't possibly have
anything to do
with you or your performance,
it's just me.
I'm the crazy bitch.
- Aw, come on. Look.
You're taking this
the wrong way.
- You are such a macho cliché.
- Sam,
you put yourself at risk
to do some serious damage
to your arm,
and for what?
This need to be the big,
mighty surgeon?
You know that was stupid.
- You have this
all figured out.
You are so full of yourself.
- Come on, that's--that's
hilarious, coming from you.
- You know what, I think this
whole thing was a mistake.
- Yeah,
I'm with you on that.
- Christy developed
staph myocarditis,
causing her cardiovascular
system to collapse.
- Well, considering
her suppressed immune system,
it was just a matter of time.
How is she now?
- Antibiotics are controlling
the infection,
but it's not a long-term fix.
Only by giving her
a new immune system
can the infection
be eradicated.
Otherwise...
[sighs]
- Wait...
Is Christy stable enough
for the transplant?
- You mean right now?
- Right now.
- Yeah, she is.
- Then do it.
Do the transplant.
- But the hospital shut it down.
We--
- Yes, I'm aware.
- Sharon, they'll have your job.
And legally, we--
- I will take
full responsibility.
- All right,
I'll prep the team.
- Thank you.
[dramatic music]
♪
- Now, you got to promise
not to give these away.
- Okay.
- Or any other
pieces of clothing.
I don't want to see you
back here.
- I promise.
I'll be--
- Bobby? Bobby!
- Dr. Choi!
♪
He's stroking.
- Let's roll him on his side.
♪
[knocking on door]
- Mr. Blevins?
Mind if we talk?
- Nurse says
I'm being discharged.
- Yeah, we're almost finished
with the paperwork.
- Then what's there
to talk about?
- My brother. He's a cop.
- Good for you.
- He tells me stories about
dumb crimes people commit.
He says there are no
smart criminals.
If they were smart,
they wouldn't be criminals.
- Okay. And?
- I don't think
you're dumb, Walter.
Yet you carjacked a woman
right in front
of two police officers.
When you first came in,
you said you were sorry.
I think you really were.
You never
meant to hurt anyone.
That wasn't
part of your plan.
You don't have
health insurance.
And without it, the cost of
surgery on your arm,
that'd be pretty expensive.
Not to mention the cost
of cancer treatments.
Those could easily
exceed $200,000.
- Man,
what do you want from me?
- You wanted to get caught...
because in--in prison,
health care is free.
You don't owe me an answer,
but your wife,
she ought to know the truth.
- [sighs]
- Bobby suffered another
ischemic stroke,
much more severe this time.
His judgment remains impaired
despite the medications
we've given him,
and we have noticed
further changes
to his temperament.
- What kind of changes?
- They're profound.
I've contacted DHS,
and they're gonna provide
a guardian who can help Bobby
get placed in a--
in a state-funded nursing home.
I'm sorry, April.
- Hey, Bobby.
Here, let me fill that
for you---
- It's mine.
- I just want to fill it up--
- It's mine!
- Okay.
- Thank you.
- Vitals are stable.
Incision looks good.
He's gonna be fine.
They both are.
- A few hours ago, they
didn't even know one another.
- Really?
Yeah, wouldn't know it
to look at 'em.
- Shared trauma.
Saw it in the Navy.
People who experience a life
and death situation together,
it creates a bond.
- Hm.
- Some kind of brain chemistry.
I'm sure Dr. Charles
can explain it.
- Right,
so what happens later?
After they get back
to normal lives?
Does it last?
- I have no idea.
- Doubt it.
- Nick, you'll have to say
"Happy Birthday" to your sister.
- It's not till summer.
- Well, when a patient
receives a transplant,
we call that "Day Zero."
So, in a way,
it's like a second birthday.
- We're so grateful,
Sharon.
What changed their minds?
- I think they just had to get
their priorities straight.
- Don't start, Peter.
I know what I'm in for.
- Hey, hey.
I'm the bearer of good news.
The hospital's not gonna
take action against you
given the gravity
of the situation.
"U.S. prosecutes hospital
administrator
for saving girl's life."
I don't think
the Justice Department
needs that kind of publicity.
So I think it is safe to assume
you are in the clear.
- Well, ain't that great.
- Sharon?
- A girl has to almost die
for this hospital to realize
that it's actually
here to treat patients?
You stay on your
blood pressure meds, Peter.
and then he nearly gets
that couple killed
so he can get free health care?
They should let the guy rot.
- The guy was trying
to protect his family.
- Sure. Sure.
- Here's a stat for you.
Health care expenses
account for over half
of all bankruptcies
in the U.S.
Be thankful you got
a great health plan.
- I hope you report this.
- Doctor/patient
confidentiality
and you're not gonna say
anything, either.
- This knucklehead ready
to be signed out?
- Yeah.
- Okay, then.
- It isn't exactly
free health care, Jay.
The guy is going to prison.
- [sighs]
[sighs]
- Here. Hey--
- I got benched
for two weeks.
- How about dinner?
I'll even
cut your steak for you.
[laughter]
- Okay.
[gentle music]
♪
- So you're off?
- Mm-hmm.
- All right.
See you later, little man.
Oh.
Let me know
if you need anything.
- Thank you.
- All right.
Helen.
- Will.
You know, I think that Will's
a very nice man.
- Yeah, he is.
- Oh!
Hi.
Dad's outside with the car.
[baby talk]
- Okay, here we go.
Here we are.
- Cover him up.
- Want me to take that?
- Oh, I'm good.
- He's gone.
The Bobby I knew
is gone.
- Hmm.
- I mean, maybe
he never really existed.
I wanted to believe
that self-sacrifice
came from the soul--
- And not lesions
on the brain?
- I mean, what if there's
no such thing as saints?
What if Mother Theresa,
Gandhi, Saint Francis--
they all just...
were people who suffered
a stroke to the frontal lobe?
- Who knows?
Theories abound.
I mean, as a shrink,
I'm supposed to tell you that
we project saintly qualities
onto others 'cause we need to.
Makes us feel hopeful.
Safe.
- Hm.
- But this I know for certain:
whoever those people
were or weren't,
they absolutely
understood the power
of a simple act
of human kindness.
- I guess I'm just trying
to figure out
what to believe in right now.
- I don't know.
Sometimes I think...
proof's all around us.
- You're almost there.
You're doing great.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa.
- I got him.
I got him. I got him right here.
- Hold him. Oh. You good?
Here we go.
- Be more careful.
- Yeah.
Be careful.
- I got you some tea.
- [cries]
[inspirational music]
- You just got to remember
where to look.
♪