When you sign a medical directive
or a consent to surgery,
there's an important question we ask.
Ready?
No.
"In the event of a possibly
fatal complication..."
Thanks for coming...
"...do you want us to use
extraordinary measures
to prolong your life?
If your heart stops,
do you want us to begin CPR?"
Hey. You just get back in town?
Yeah. I landed last night.
Um, listen.
I'm sorry I didn't call you back.
I didn't think it was a good idea for you
or your... your mom to come
to Sabrina's service.
Mom didn't go?
Ah, the family's not ready to see anyone,
especially from Seattle.
- "Do you want to be violently shocked...
- Okay.
...with 360 joules of electricity?"
So, the book says we can't
start sleep-training
until after six months.
One book. One book says that.
Other books say that you
can start at four months
or when they start dropping night feeds.
Or when the mom starts losing her mind
because of cumulative sleep deprivation.
- Everything okay?
- Allison had us up till 3:00.
Us? You slept through the whole
thing. Or you pretended to.
Hey, hey! Is that coffee?
M-Maybe you should just take it.
Thank you so much.
I don't remember all you people
putting in requests for the day off.
And whose fault is it they need to?
Richard.
- Nice to see you.
- Bailey.
"Do you agree to multiple injections
of adrenaline into your veins
or a tube down your throat?"
How far will you go to stay alive?
No one's suspending
Meredith Grey's license.
She won a Catherine Fox award.
She's a legend.
Well, I heard she operated
on a fellow resident.
She took out a healthy appendix.
No, she and Cristina Yang
rescued an intern
who removed another
intern's appendix, incorrectly.
They were helping.
That wasn't the other Dr. Grey,
the one that died in the plane crash?
Our Dr. Grey cut a patient's LVAD wire.
See, you consider these things legendary.
They're also crimes.
I'm a witness at the hearing.
- And I forgot a tie.
- Sounds about right.
My lucky tie was in my locker. Come here.
Okay, if anyone should speak
on behalf of Dr. Grey,
it really should be me.
Everybody shut up.
Most of the attendings will be
out for the hearing today,
myself included,
which means you guys have to cover.
If you get into trouble, call me,
but if it's not a disaster,
I will bury you in scut for a month.
Don't kill anyone.
We'll be right back there,
Meredith, okay?
- Okay.
- All right.
If I was on your operating table,
you'd want me to follow
your instructions, right?
Lie there. Breathe in.
Fall asleep. Let you do your job.
That would be my best shot
at survival, right?
I see where you're going with this.
I'm begging you, Meredith.
Sit down, don't talk.
And let me do my job. Please.
I'm not a baby.
No. You're an adult
who's completely unable to be quiet
no matter how much
your well-being depends on it.
And today, it could cost you
your entire future.
The prosecuting attorney
is Ashley Cordova.
Getting questioned by her is like someone
ripping hangnails
off all 10 fingers at once.
Sitting quietly and remaining respectful
will go against every fiber
of your being.
But please.
Just for today.
Just for the next few hours.
Sit still and shut up.
Okay.
Thank you. Okay. Let's do this.
Good morning.
Based on the number of witnesses
on the list I just read,
this one's gonna be a circus,
so let's go ahead on record.
My name is William Benson,
I am the judge who's been
assigned to this case.
We have Ms. Ashley Cordova,
who's representing
the Medical Commission,
and Ms. Nancy Klein, who will
represent the respondent.
The commission panel
includes Dr. Aaron Rosenberg,
Dr. Maria Lang, and...
I'm here. I'm here.
I'm here. Sorry. Traffic.
Light was out on Broadway.
Dr. Rosenberg, Dr. Lang,
and panel chair Dr. Paul Castello.
Mrs. Shepherd, there's some
things you need to know. Ma'am.
Give me the papers!
How do we switch out one
of the doctors on the panel?
We don't. Why?
Because that one killed my husband.
Synced & corrected by -robtor-
www.addic7ed.com
We will follow these protocols
throughout these proceedings.
Paul Castello was the trauma surgeon
who operated on my husband at Dillard.
He did not get a head CT.
Okay. Does he remember you?
It doesn't seem like it.
Which is enraging.
Can we appeal or something?
Yes, but it could be six months
before you're rescheduled.
Ohh.
Okay. No, he's taken enough.
He doesn't get another six months.
Let's... We stay.
We are here today in the matter
of Dr. Meredith Grey,
who is charged with allegations
that she practiced
below the acceptable standards
of medical practice in a manner
that exploited patients
and insurance carriers.
In fact, Dr. Grey is...
Dr. Bailey, you've known
Dr. Grey a long time.
Could you speak about that at all?
I met her when she was an intern.
Would you say the two of you
have grown close
- over all this time?
- No.
Didn't Dr. Grey name her son after you?
If you're asking if
her son's name is Bailey,
then, yes, it is.
Dr. Grey is a well-respected
general surgeon.
You've agreed to that.
Is that a question?
Well, when you became chief of surgery,
you asked Dr. Grey to become
your chief of general surgery.
And from my estimation,
a chief of general surgery
is extremely skilled,
organized, dedicated, communicative.
Does that sound correct to you?
It does. And she is no longer
my chief of general surgery.
No more questions. Thank you.
Ms. Cordova? Any cross?
Uh, actually, yes.
Dr. Grey has developed
quite the disciplinary record
over all those years
you've known her, hasn't she?
Your name is listed as the doctor
who reported the following incidents...
interns, including Dr. Grey,
admitting to cutting
a patient's LVAD wire.
I do not want to have to testify
against any of you in a court of law.
Dr. Grey performed a surgery
on an intern without an attending.
Dr. Grey instructed a younger resident
to remove a brain tumor without consent
from the patient or attending.
Dr. Grey would not allow
an education consultant
to enter her O.R.,
- so you suspended her.
- You're suspended.
All of these things familiar
to you, Dr. Bailey?
All true.
My daughter, Gabby...
she had terrible stomach pain,
and my neighbor told me about
the free clinic at the hospital.
So you took Gabby there,
where you were seen by Dr. Grey?
Yes. She said that Gabby
had a mass in her intestine.
Mm-hmm. And she needed surgery.
But you didn't have health insurance.
For you or your daughter.
No, I didn't have insurance.
I see.
You must have been terrified
during all of this.
Were you by yourself?
Yes. Dani, my wife,
she was in a detention center
at the time, at the border.
This is before they sent her
back to Honduras.
I am so sorry to hear that.
And how's Gabby?
They said that she was
responding very well
to the medication.
Because we caught it early.
Because Dr. Grey did. She saved us.
The world needs more people like her.
More doctors like her.
And were you aware Dr. Grey
had committed insurance fraud?
No. I found out when Dr. Webber
approached Dr. Grey in the scrub room.
He saw her daughter's name
on the schedule and was worried.
Ms. Cordova, can I jump in here?
- By all means.
- Can he do that?
The panel can do whatever they want.
Dr. DeLuca, your relationship
with Dr. Grey at the time.
She was an attending, and you were...?
I was a fourth-year surgical resident.
I'm now a fifth year.
And you're in a romantic
relationship with your boss.
There's documentation
from Human Resources.
I'm sorry. How is this relevant?
You didn't alert a supervisor
when you found out
what Dr. Grey had done,
so, yes, I'd consider it relevant.
Well, unless... Is it consensual?
It is.
Thank you, Dr. DeLuca.
Not quite yet. I'd like to ask about
when you applied for a transfer
from Grey Sloan.
Sure. It, uh... It was nothing.
I was having a bad time in
my intern year, and, uh...
- I figured it out, changed my mind.
- Mm-hmm.
And by "bad time," you're referring
to your mistreatment
by specific attendings
after a violent incident
with Dr. Alex Karev?
I dropped the charges against Dr. Karev.
Oh, I know. I'd like
to present Exhibit B-5.
This is from Dr. DeLuca's personnel file.
Dr. DeLuca, could you do me a favor
and read the highlighted section?
Alex! "Since I charged Dr. Karev
with a felony,
I feel his fellow attendings
want to keep me off their services
and out of the O.R.
Because of this,
I feel my residency experience
will be compromised."
And a little further down, you named
one of these attendings.
What's the highlighted name?
Dr. Meredith Grey.
But I-I changed my mind.
It was a long time ago.
Ancient history. We've worked it out.
Yes. Dr. Grey seems
to have made sure of that.
No further questions.
It's okay.
Dr. Schmitt.
I'm sorry. I, uh...
I've never been in a courtroom before.
You still haven't. We're in a hotel.
Right. Um...
What was the question?
Dr. Grey is one
of your teachers, correct?
- Yes.
- Mm-hmm.
And she's the best teacher I've ever had.
Dr. Grey always gave me an opportunity.
And she didn't jump in
with the mean nicknames
like everybody else.
And when the hospital got hacked,
it locked the blood bank,
so Dr. Grey had me
become a human blood bank.
For the patient.
It was incredible.
I did pass out in the O.R.,
but I saved the patient.
Wow. That is... very helpful.
I was more interested in your
involvement with Gabby Rivera.
Right.
I rounded on her once
during a peds rotation,
but I was barely there.
Well, you were there
long enough to see a name
on Gabby's I.D. bracelet.
Um...
Dr. Schmitt. I'd like to
remind you you're under oath.
And I don't recommend perjuring yourself.
I had heard Mr. Rivera
call his daughter "Gabby,"
but the bracelet said Ellis Grey,
so I thought that the hospital
had made an error.
I wanted to take it
to Dr. Grey and ask, but...
she wasn't there that day.
So what did you do?
Dr. Schmitt. What did you do?
I brought it to Dr. Bailey.
I thought it was a mistake.
And I c... I couldn't make
any more mistakes.
- No further questions.
- I...
I'm sorry, Dr. Grey.
I-I-I thought that I was doing
the right thing. I'm sorry.
God. What happened?
15-minute recess.
Luis was great, uh, Bailey was a robot,
they know that DeLuca
and Mer are a thing,
so they're probably gonna ignore him,
and Schmitt turned her in.
Schmitt? Damn.
They've gone through everyone's files.
It's a crap-pile of crap.
- How's Meredith?
- She needed some air.
Today may be my actual
last day of being a doctor.
Meredith, it's not over.
We won't make it.
If I lose my license...
and I can't cut, but you can...
we won't make it.
Dr. Hunt, as an Army surgeon,
you've trained and worked with
doctors all over the world.
I have to know,
is Dr. Grey really as good
- as people say she is?
- No.
She's better.
The Catherine Fox award that she won
was for a surgery
that saved my sister's life.
Now, if Megan could have
been here today, she'd be...
She'd be showing you
her transplanted abdomen herself.
- So you've come around.
- I'm sorry? Wh...
Exhibit C-2.
These are Dr. Bailey's surgical notes
after Dr. Grey botched
your sister's first surgery.
"Hunt has concerns that Dr. Grey
could not close patient's
abdomen the first time.
If she fails again,
patient has no other options."
The "Hunt" in this note is you, correct?
Dr. Webber, would it be safe to say
that you've seen Dr. Grey partake
in a lot of groundbreaking work?
Absolutely. Most recently,
she was published for her
studies with mini-livers in mice.
And going back, I read about a
trial for Alzheimer's disease
carried out under your tenure as chief.
I'm curious why it didn't continue.
Well, that trial ended at Grey Sloan
because someone tampered with it.
Could you elaborate on that?
Is that necessary for this investigation?
Answer the question, Dr. Webber.
My wife...
My late wife was a participant.
And I discovered that she was selected
for the placebo
instead of the experimental drug.
I changed the envelopes.
I got her the drug.
And you were the only one involved?
- That's right.
- Thanks for clearing that up.
I know there have been
instances when you...
how should we put it... bent
the rules in favor of Dr. Grey.
Objection. That's pure conjecture.
Is it?
- State your name, please.
- Patricia Murphy.
Hi, guys!
You used to work for Dr. Webber?
Sure did.
I was Chief Webber's
administrative assistant.
I also was the point of contact
for the National Residency
Matching Program.
First person to see who had matched.
Please see exhibit D-1,
the list of interns who matched
Dr. Grey's first year.
Ms. Murphy, could you find
Dr. Grey's name on that list?
Oh, her name isn't on here.
Why not? Didn't Meredith Grey match
at Seattle Grace that year?
No. Uh, not at first, anyway.
Dr. Webber asked me to set up a call
with the President of the NRMP.
And next thing I knew,
I was adding Grey's name to the roster.
I'm sorry. That sounds like
you're saying Meredith Grey
was never supposed to
work at that hospital
in the first place.
Dr. Grey and I worked
together through internship,
boards, specializing, everything.
We all started out
competing with each other,
but I stopped competing with her
a long time ago.
Did you just call me a nurse?
She makes me better. A better,
uh, surgeon, better person.
The Medical Commission's
trying to establish a pattern
that Dr. Grey is rash, reckless.
Would you agree with that?
Absolutely not.
She has her reasons
for how she treats patients,
and I always agree with it.
Dr. Grey's oldest daughter
is one of your patients, correct?
You've treated her through the years,
which means you most likely had
to sign off on the adoption.
Why was it held up? Do you know?
What did I do?
U-Unfortunately, those things
always have delays.
I, uh... I mean, I see it all the time.
It wasn't because Dr. Grey was
briefly fired from Grey Sloan?
Did Dr. Grey's insubordinate behavior
almost cost her her daughter's
adoption, Dr. Karev?
I'm sorry. I don't...
I don't see how her family
life is relevant here.
Well, she seems to be
fairly cavalier about the law
in both her professional
and personal life,
so I'd say it's relevant.
In fact, she used her
youngest daughter's identity to
commit insurance fraud, so...
Alan Brown, Farrah Alazari,
Deborah Greene, and Sam Carter.
Dr. Grey, we have your list of
your patient testimonies here.
You don't need to repeat them.
Those are the names of the spouses
of every patient I've ever lost.
I remember every single one of them.
Okay. Uh, thank you for that.
You don't get to sit up there
and ask questions about my daughter.
If you want to take my license
and make sure I never see
another patient again,
then you do that,
but you have absolutely no right
to ever mention my daughter's name
because you are the one
who killed her father.
You don't remember me.
Meredith.
But I remember you.
As the coward who stood
over my dying husband...
You're gonna be fine.
...the love of my life,
and you didn't even attempt
to do burr holes
after he failed to get him a head CT.
Burr holes!
We don't have time for a CT!
I was doing burr holes as an intern.
That one night should have
cost you your entire career,
but instead you're sitting
up here judging me?
You don't deserve to judge anyone.
Your Honor, if we could, um,
just take a short recess
to evaluate the situation,
see if Dr. Grey's, um, conflict
of interest is, um...
My conflict of interest?!
My medical license should not be
in this man's hands.
- Okay, come on.
- He is dangerous.
Okay, come on, let's go.
Come on. Let's go. Let's go.
Put the jacket under his head.
- Yeah, yeah, I got it.
- Okay. Do we know
if he has a history of epilepsy?
I'm gonna check for medical
bracelets and I.D. here.
Hey, the paramedics
are here with the gurney.
- What do we got?
- We got a male in his mid-40s.
Started seizing about four minutes ago.
We're maintaining his airway.
And take him to Grey Sloan.
He should have
the very best care there is.
- Meredith.
- Can you do that?
Get him on his side.
And get him a damn head CT!
Hey, hey. Ma'am.
Head of trauma.
I wouldn't "ma'am" her.
Seizure stopped two minutes ago
after multiple doses of Diazepam.
His last BP was 220/128,
and he's tachy to 145.
He needs clevidipine and a head CT ASAP.
I called ahead. Let's get him upstairs.
- Let's go, go, go!
- You guys left the hearing?
We weren't gonna put this all on you.
But it... in just
a couple of weeks, it had...
it had... had grown so much
in size, that it was...
it was squeezing up
into the pulmonary artery.
Like, the... Do you know
what that is, Jake?
Brett. And no.
Well, it's, um...
It makes sure that blood
gets to the lungs, which...
You know, important.
But, um, her blood had...
had clotted all the way from here to...
Do you have a red pen?
No. And I kinda need that one back.
And another one of these, please.
Did you come to gloat?
Just checking on you.
It's 2:00 in the afternoon,
and you appear to be well past
the legal limit.
So gloating.
What are you doing here? Are
they on a break or something?
No. It may be canceled.
One of the doctors on the panel
apparently is the one that killed Derek,
so Mer went off on him, and he collapsed.
Possible seizure disorder.
We're not sure yet.
Maybe he forgot to check
the activated clotting time.
You know what happened, right?
My mom told me about it, yeah.
Richard's never gonna speak to me again.
I don't blame him.
Why don't we just leave this here
and I'll get you home?
But I need it.
Maggie, I'm sure you have
some wine at home, too, okay?
Come on.
You lied to those people.
You flat-out lied.
And you answered those questions
like you barely know Meredith.
No. I do know Meredith.
I know she will put everything at risk
to suit her needs.
Meredith is anything but selfish.
Oh, no? She hasn't asked you
to sideline your career
to save her ass?
No, she has not asked me to do that.
Right. 'Cause you just do it.
Instead of reasoning with her,
stopping her from
doing something illegal,
like a mentor would do,
you just cover for her.
That's my business. My decision.
Meredith Grey could commit murder,
and you'd hide the body.
You know what? I really
don't have the energy
for this right now.
You cheated the system
to get Meredith into my program.
No, that was my program.
And I did not cheat.
I wrote a recommendation.
You chose to go around the system
to get Meredith Grey her way,
no matter the consequences.
And you've been doing it ever since.
You choose her! You always choose her!
My God. You sound... jealous.
Well, I'm getting enough
of that from my wife.
Hey. How was the trial?
I-I was really surprised
neither side called me in.
I moonlight as an expert witness.
I need you to operate.
Wow. You trying to up my bad outcomes?
Tom.
Well, now, whoever smelt it dealt it.
This one's all you, Shepherd.
This man killed my brother
on an O.R. table
because he refused to order a CT scan.
And now I have found a massive
hypertensive intracerebral hemorrhage.
He needs a craniotomy. Can you do it?
Shepherd.
Can you do it?
I'll cancel the rest of my day.
Thank you.
Evacuating the hematoma...
gel foam...
Here we go. Nice and steady.
Nicely done.
Look, I'm not gonna pretend that I never
give Meredith special treatment.
There is a history.
- Her mother.
- Yes.
Meredith is family.
And she also happens
to be one of the more
brilliant surgeons that I've ever taught.
So sometimes putting my career
in jeopardy for her...
is just what you do for family.
Glad to know where I fit in.
That's not what I meant.
Tom Koracick is my boss.
Because of your actions.
Because of Meredith's actions.
Because you chose to help her
instead of coming to me.
If I'd have come to you,
my wife would have fired you, too!
Did you not hear the part
where I just said
- Tom Koracick is my boss?!
- You didn't lose your job!
Meredith is fighting for her license!
No, I've lost more than my job!
I've lost my hospital!
I lost my best surgeons.
And my best friend.
All because someone I thought
I raised betrayed me.
Now, do you know how that feels?
It hurts pretty bad, doesn't it?
That's right.
I stuck my neck out for her
because I know she'd do the same for me.
And until recently,
I thought you would, too.
Thank you all for your patience.
The Medical Commission has decided
to postpone Dr. Grey's hearing.
Most likely, an entirely new
hearing will take place,
based on today's events.
You can't postpone.
Dr. Karev, we're not exactly
holding a town hall.
Can you please find a seat?
No, you can't postpone
because these people
have come from all over
to speak for Meredith.
I-I'm sorry. What people?
Were all these people
on the witness list?
No idea.
You gonna tell them all
they need to go home?
I was trapped in an ambulance,
upside down, soaked in my own blood,
while my best friend was dead beside me.
It was the most scared I've
ever been in my entire life.
And what did Dr. Grey do?
She climbed into the damn thing with me.
Admitted she was scared, too.
Then she proceeded to stab me in
the chest with a giant needle.
Which saved my life.
When Dr. Grey diagnosed
the tumor in my liver,
I retired.
I gave my cats away to my daughter,
bought a pair of designer shoes,
and splurged on the trip of my dreams.
And now I'm broke.
Dr. Grey pioneered such
an incredible surgery,
I had to go to the
superintendent of schools
and beg for my job back.
She diagnosed my cancer
and saved my life.
And my treatment's being done pro Bono.
And Dr. Grey saw to that.
She hasn't claimed credit for it,
but I know she did it.
I guess I met her on
her very first day as a doctor.
And it showed. I mean, someone needed
to help her unlock the wheels
of the gurney.
She was green. And I was just awful.
But on Dr. Grey's very
first day as a doctor,
she was the only one
that could figure out
what was wrong with me.
And because of her, I am sitting here,
with a newborn baby girl at home,
and I just hope that I can give her back
a little of the help that she gave to me.
Hemorrhage has been evacuated.
Miraculously, if I do say so myself.
Drain, please.
How you doing?
Do you want to go somewhere?
I want to stay.
I have dreamt about this day.
I have dreamt that the world
would be fair and just
and that the man on that table
might experience
a fraction of the pain that
he caused when his arrogance
took away my favorite person
in the entire world.
And I thought...
if I saw inside that man's skull,
I might jam a scalpel
into his motor cortex
just to paralyze him.
Just so that he would
have to lie in a bed
for the rest of his life
knowing what he took
from me and Meredith...
and the kids, my mom.
I think we should stay.
Thank you.
But up here...
far away from the scalpels.
And, you know, I...
I could get us some popcorn if you want.
Damn it.
"Dear Medical Commission,
people who know me
would describe me as selfish to a fault.
After that, they'd say honest.
I can honestly tell you
that if I were dying
and a surgery stood between me and death,
Dr. Grey's hands are the only ones
that I'd want inside my body.
Taking away her license is
signing the death certificates
of countless future patients.
She is a light in a broken
system that she will fix,
whether you want her to or not.
She is the sun, and she is unstoppable.
Sincerely, Dr. Cristina Yang."
Um, I have more.
I've got, uh, Dr. Calliope Torres,
uh, Dr. Arizona Robbins,
Dr. April Kepner...
That's enough. Thank you. That's fine.
Um, no, I can keep going if you want.
- It's fine.
- Addison Montgomery.
- You don't?
- That's good.
- Okay.
- Good.
He sparked a re-bleed.
Pressure's through the roof.
Can you get control?
Suction.
- V-Fib.
- Push one of epi.
Let's get him flat
and get the paddles ready.
Thank you, everyone,
for your time. Again.
Uh, now, if I could please have
everyone clear the room.
Uh, excuse me. Sorry. Sorry. Excuse me.
Hi. Hi. I'm sorry. Your Honor.
Uh, I... I have something more to say
about Meredith Grey.
For God's sakes, who doesn't?
Okay, well, ever since
I first met Meredith Grey...
I knew she was going to be
a thorn in my side.
You're worried about her breaking rules?
Well, that's not gonna stop.
She's been doing that since day one.
And, yes, she broke a law to save a life.
So she deserved to lose her job.
She deserves to pick up trash.
No one should be questioning her license.
She's too good at what she does.
And she's worked too hard
to get to where she is.
And with all...
all that she has survived,
it hasn't made her... hard.
It hasn't made her mean or... or cold.
It hasn't made her not care.
It's made her...
better.
It's made her better
than anyone in this room.
Well, except me.
I'm Dr. Miranda Bailey,
chief of surgery
at Grey Sloan Memorial Hospital.
And I approve this message.
He's gone.
Castello didn't make it.
Wasn't me. I didn't kill him.
Should I be blaming myself
for yelling at him?
No, he gets all the blame.
Not only was he a terrible
doctor to patients,
but he forgot that high blood
pressure's the silent killer.
And, boy, did he let it get to him.
- Tell me.
- They're not postponing.
Uh, should one of us tell them
that their panel chair died?
Ooh. They'll ask when they're ready.
Right now, they're sending
their recommendation
to the Medical Commission.
- What?
- Okay.
It's a majority vote.
So even if Castello voted
to suspend Meredith's license,
the other two doctors voted
to drop the entire thing.
- It's over.
- I still have my license?
Yes. And I'm so grateful it's over
because you're one of
the most exhausting clients
I've ever had.
Congratulations, Dr. Grey.
- Thank you. Thank you.
- Yeah!
- Aww.
- Congratulations.
Thank you. Thank you. Good job!
You said some very nice things
to the panel in there.
Thank you.
Uh, so, um, see you Monday then.
What?
Come back.
I'm sorry?
Come back to Grey Sloan.
Ooh.
You are a pain in my ass.
But you're a fine surgeon.
And your name's on the damn sign.
And I need you.
So you fired me and now
you want me to come back?
You want me to beg?
Thank you.
Is that a yes?
That's a big, fat yes.
I'll see you Monday.
I hate to bring this up now, but have you
seen or heard anything
with Richard and my mom?
Any idea how they're doing?
You're asking the wrong person.
Right. Sorry.
I just didn't know if maybe
he mentioned anything...
before.
And do you think, um...
think they're having some problems?
I don't know. It's just kind of
a sense that I get. I guess.
I mean, it can't be easy.
With him being fired
and working somewhere else...
...and her traveling all the time.
Owen.
Mer gets to keep her license.
Yay, Mer!
I didn't help at all.
You did help by not testifying.
Wow.
This is kind of nice.
Not fighting?
I've missed it.
You. I guess I missed you.
Us being able to talk,
knowing what's going on
in each other's lives.
Ah, I can't. I'm sorry.
I can't. I shouldn't.
Obviously, I'm in something...
Oh, my God. Uh, you should leave.
Okay. We can...
No. Get out, Jackson. Go. Get out now!
- Hey.
Congrats on your license.
Thanks.
Maggie, what just happened?
I hate someone I used to love.
Don't let him in.
I don't want to see
or speak to him ever again.
Okay, okay.
- Hey.
- Can we talk?
- Yeah.
Extraordinary measures can have a cost.
You may be alive,
but life may not be the same
as you remember.
Didn't think you had it in you, Schmitt.
I just heard Schmitt here
was the one who ratted out Grey.
Damn, man. You're lucky
she kept her license.
Your body may not move as easily.
Feelings may be gone.
And it can take a long time to recover.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry for what I said.
I... I didn't mean
that we wouldn't make it.
I just... I don't know.
I don't know what I meant.
I-I was scared.
Mer, don't. Okay? Y-You meant it.
No, I-I didn't.
I stood up for you in court.
I defended you at the hospital.
I went to jail for you.
I know, and I didn't ask you
to do any of those things.
I know. But I did it anyway
because I love you.
Because I'd do anything for you.
Because that's what you do
for your partner.
But I'm not your partner.
Am I?
There's a reason
it's a difficult decision.
The look in your eye when
you spoke about Derek today
made me realize what it is
I've been feeling
this whole time.
You didn't just love Derek.
You respected him.
That's different.
And you can't compare.
- I do respect you.
- Come on.
Y-You're telling me there's
not some small part of you
that doesn't wonder if I'm your equal?
If I'm at your level? If I ever will be?
Take some time, Meredith.
Figure out what it is that you want.
And...
Let me know if I'm a part of that.
Good night.
You just have to decide
if it's all worth it.