Ladies and gentlemen, step around.
Step around. Come on. Gather around.
We'll show you a little way to
make a little easy money today.
You understand what I'm
saying? These are the blacks.
Don't follow the blacks. You
wanna follow the queen. Know why?
'Cause she's red and
that means she is hot.
You gotta find the
queen. Find the queen.
The first of the day is free
to play. Who wants to play?
You look interested, my man. You
wanna step on up? Come on now.
Who wants to play? Oh,
what about you, sweetie?
You're cute. Come
on up. All right.
Come on here and play. Cute
girls win money. You look lucky.
Now, you look lucky.
Now, follow the queen.
Here we go, ladies and
gentlemen. Follow the queen.
Follow the queen.
Ain't no Helen Mirren,
but this queen is for you!
Which one? Which one?
Which one is it? Which one is it?
It's right there. Right there?
Beginner's luck. Beginner's
luck. I'll tell you what.
It takes a woman
to know a woman.
It takes a lady to find a queen.
There you go... Wanna double up?
All right. All right,
we've got a chancer.
We got a chancer.
All right. Here we
go. Here we go.
All you gotta do
is find your queen.
You will not win again. You
will not win again. All right.
Here we go. Here we go. Find
your queen. Find your queen.
Where is she? Where
is she? Where is she?
Can you find her?
Right there. This one? Oh, my...
She is killing me here.
Taking all my money.
Anybody else wanna get
behind the good-luck girl?
I can do it.
You can do it? All
right. You're next.
Just give me a chance to
recover and get my money back
or else I'm gonna be out
here sleeping on the street.
Here we go. All right? Ready?
This is the last time. I'm not
messing with you no more.
You're taking all
my money, girl.
I'm not messing
with you no more.
Here we go. One more
chance. This is your last chance.
You're gonna follow
the queen, baby.
Follow the queen. Where's
she at? Where's she at?
Just one time. I'll show you
one time and there she is.
Boom. Boom. Boom. Pick a card.
I can't decide.
What do you mean? Just pick
a card. Just make a decision.
I can't decide.
Come on. Any card will
do. Left? Right? Center?
I don't know.
Do you want the
right? I don't know.
The left?
The center? I don't know. I...
Move out the way and just
let somebody else play then?
I can't decide. I can't.
You wanna flip a coin for it?
What's wrong with me?
Is she okay?
Scariest 30 seconds of my life.
I couldn't do anything.
It's like I couldn't
move inside my head.
It's called abulia.
The inability to make a
decision or exercise will.
Is it going to happen again?
It's part of a TIA. A
transient ischemic attack.
Blood was cut off to a
section of your frontal lobe.
Is it like a stroke
or something?
A little.
What drugs have
you taken recently?
No drugs.
Toxins are another possibility.
You might have been exposed
to something at work, for instance.
No real job right now.
Exposure can build up over time
and lie dormant for a while.
What was your
last job? Pet store.
Exotic pets?
Tropical fish.
And before that?
Unemployment.
And before that,
I sold subscriptions
on the phone.
And before that, unemployment.
Before that, I worked
at Jeans Gone Wild.
Before that, unemployment.
Before that, I walked dogs.
And before that...
Loss of free will. I like it.
Maybe we can get Thomas
Aquinas in for a consult.
What caused the TIA?
Arteries are clear.
No sign of a clot.
Could have dissolved. Most
likely came from her heart.
We should do a bubble study.
Clots are unlikely in a
28-year-old who's not on the pill.
It's probably a vasospasm
caused by drugs.
I don't think so. She
goes from job to job.
Maybe there's some
kind of ADD here.
Help us pinpoint
where the neurological...
She goes from job to job
because she's a scam artist.
She works just long enough
to qualify for unemployment,
then gets fired and gets high.
I still don't think it's drugs.
Did you check for infection?
LP showed nothing. No fever.
White blood count is normal.
Could be toxic exposure.
You're the one always
saying it must be drugs.
You figure she's a minority,
she must be stoned?
You know that's what I...
She seems like a nice girl.
You haven't met her!
She was pregnant at 15,
dropped out of high school.
She's a real overachiever.
Come on. Cut her some
slack. Her baby died of SIDS.
This isn't some romantic story
about a nice girl
scarred by tragedy.
She's a drug-using scam
artist scarred by tragedy.
On the other hand, the
tox screen just came back.
She's clean.
You're wasting my
time. He's wasting...
Second ex-Mrs.
Wilson want money?
I am no longer paying alimony.
She wanted her independence,
so she got her
realtor's license.
Market's doing badly.
She wants money.
She's moving into a condo.
She wants... She
wants me to take Hector.
Pool boy?
Dog.
No longer interested.
We got him on our honeymoon.
So I'm like the other parent.
But I can't take him.
My hotel doesn't allow dogs.
Besides, I'm always here.
I asked Cuddy to
a play Thursday.
Oh, you... Okay.
She said she was busy.
And you didn't believe
her, so you bribed a janitor,
broke into her computer,
checked her appointments...
I asked her as a test.
What would you have
learned if she'd said yes?
A lot about bondage.
She was busy for
me but not for you.
She's not interested
in play qua play.
She's interested in you.
No. I'm not getting sucked into
the vortex of your insanity again.
Don't pass me notes in class.
Don't tell me to
ask her to the prom.
You cannot see her socially.
You're leading her on.
I'll consider that. After I take
her to the Hockney exhibit.
On Thursday.
See, she is busy.
It's not a date.
She enjoyed the play. I
enjoyed her enjoying the play.
The woman works hard.
It's nice to see her relax.
So all this enjoying
is an act of charity.
I'm keeping the
receipts for tax purposes.
What's life without the
ability to make stupid choices?
She needs her free will.
Find out why her brain froze before
she can't decide to take her next breath.
You find the toxins. You
run your bubble study.
You won't find anything
but I'll get the office to myself.
There's a lot of porn
piling up on the Internet.
Doesn't download itself.
Eric? Eric!
Hello, Mr. Foreman.
Dr. Chase. How are you? Good.
You're lucky you
caught us, actually...
I'll meet you outside.
Hey, Dad. I've got to
go. Why are you here?
Everything okay?
Good as ever.
We're staying at a
hotel down the street.
You didn't bring Mom with you?
It's gonna be her 60th
birthday in a few days.
I know. We talked
about it on the phone.
You said you couldn't come home.
You didn't have to come.
You haven't been
home in eight years.
She should see you,
while she still
knows who you are.
Dad. I've talked to
her on the phone.
She only knows
who I am sometimes.
Sometimes
is important.
So what's up with your dad? Didn't
know he was gonna be in town?
No.
Building this old, could be
toxic exposure anywhere.
Asbestos, mold, the coloring
agents in the old wallpaper.
Or it could be drugs.
I thought we ruled out...
Clean tox screen means
drugs didn't cause the TIA.
Drugs can be laced
with toxic substances.
Arsenic, rat poison.
The drugs wash
out of her system,
the toxins stick around.
Exposure could come
about any number of ways.
There's no reason to assume
it was through drug use.
Absolutely. Except
for the crack pipe.
I'll test her blood for
arsenic and rat poison.
Yeah. Yeah. You'd
like that, wouldn't you?
And your dad asked
you out for dinner?
I'll do the tests. You're
stuck with your family.
You like Hockney?
You heard about that.
The pop stuff or the
Venezuelan pictures?
That's a trick question.
Yes. But you have
no idea how it's a trick.
I like art. I'm open to new
things. What's the problem?
You're going to a gallery to see
Venezuelan pictures that don't exist.
But you won't go to
a play with me. Why?
House, why is my social
life suddenly red hot?
One minute I'm mushing
along with the huskies as usual
and suddenly it's
global warming.
You think you saw somebody
else pick up a toy from the sandbox
and suddenly you want it.
Is that why you said no?
Maybe I just want a friend and I
thought Wilson was a safe choice.
I'm not safe? Cool.
James Wilson is
never the safe choice.
We're going to a gallery.
We're not getting married.
Sure, you say that now.
He always marries
them in the end.
Is that Eric? Eric!
Oh!
Oh, baby. Baby!
I wanted to find that picture I
took at your high school graduation.
I had it reframed.
It's in one of these
suitcases, but I don't know...
You can show it to me later.
Your father wants to
know if you've been praying.
You don't have to just
come out with it like that.
But I only want to
know if you're happy.
Sure. I'm okay.
You like it here?
You have friends?
Yeah. Everything is great, Mom.
That's why I brought
the picture for you.
I remember when you were little
you liked to look in the back of
the math book because you knew
even though it
made no sense then,
by the end of the year
you'd understand it all.
That's why you
brought the picture?
You wanted to look ahead,
to see how far you'd go.
Now you're a grown man, I
thought you might like to look back
to see how far you've come.
It all makes sense
now. Doesn't it?
That isn't mine.
It was in your closet.
It belongs to this guy
who used to live with me.
You might want to let him
know he's got arsenic poisoning.
We should get a
sample of his hair
so we can see the extent of it.
But I don't do...
I don't do drugs.
Get a crash cart in
here! Respiratory arrest!
Are you sure it isn't
from the arsenic?
Dr. Foreman said I was poisoned.
Your hair showed
only a trace amount.
Not enough to damage
your lungs like this.
We need you to stay still now.
Six-millimeter cuts
starting at the apices.
Also, I just wanted
to let you know
should you change your
mind, I'll be available.
Aren't you getting tired
of hearing me say it?
I have no intention
of going out with you,
of having sex with you,
of doing anything with you.
Except work.
We don't have to
make a big deal about it.
I just thought I'd let you know.
I decided Tuesdays would
be a good day to do that.
You did not suddenly
fall in love with me.
You were looking for something
and I happened to be standing...
Cameron, it's fine.
No need to go on about it.
Advancing through
the lung bases.
We need to put this behind us.
Understood.
But you keep bringing it up.
You're the one
who's still talking.
Look, I'm not demanding
anything from you.
I'm not following you home.
I've got no expectations.
A gentle, polite reminder
once a week is hardly stalking.
There's a mass. Just
outside the lingula.
Biopsy shows there
are white blood cells
in the walls of
the blood vessels.
They're not supposed
to get past the bouncers.
Got to be autoimmune,
something lymphocytic.
White blood cells are
attacking her own body.
Only question is, what
kind of autoimmune?
Doesn't matter what kind.
It always matters what kind.
Treatment's always steroids.
Treatment is always boring.
Diagnosis... Okay.
It's affecting the
larger blood vessels.
Gotta be giant cell arteritis.
I'll start her on steroids.
It's affecting the
smaller blood vessels.
Gotta be lupus vasculitis.
I'll start her on steroids.
It's affecting... Yeah. Got it.
Start her on steroids.
Good idea.
Told you. That was boring.
I gotta go out. Why?
Wilson's got a date.
It's got 15-foot ceilings.
It's got an open floor plan.
You know, I can't
believe you called me.
Hey. I need a condo.
Didn't you and Wilson have
your first date around here?
Wow! You remember
where our first date was?
I didn't think you
were paying attention.
Really? He's my best friend.
Our first date was in Boston.
Oh.
Not quite as close to
here as I remember.
But we're not here
to talk about him.
Absolutely not.
Wait till you see the kitchen.
All-granite countertops.
Since I wasn't paying
attention back then,
what was it like dating him?
So this is Hockney? No.
I don't know what happened.
I'm sure you don't.
I never knew your
tastes were so eclectic.
Oh, the Hockney exhibit
finished on April 20th.
I thought it was May 20th.
Okay. My bad.
This is not somewhere I'd
bring someone on a date.
Not that this is a
date. Obviously.
I was just thinking...
He's doing landscapes
on multiple canvases now.
And they're kind of peaceful
and you're always so busy...
Wow.
I don't think I've ever seen
you embarrassed before.
Oh, it was never a date.
I was coming off
a bad relationship
and he said we could
go out as friends.
You know, just go see
plays, go to a museum.
I didn't think you
liked Trenton.
Love it.
So he'd say it's not a date
but then he'd jump you.
Oh, no. He meant it.
James Wilson,
carefully calibrating
his level of protectiveness
for your individual needs.
Did you just compare
Wilson to a tampon?
No.
It was very endearing. He
really just wanted to be a friend.
So I jumped him.
The bedroom's through here.
That's such a bad idea.
There's no way that won't cause
damage to the large intestine.
Are you keeping us
here to torture me?
Is that a bicycle pump?
That's what I'm saying.
It's like walking
into a sticky trap.
And once you're the focus of
all that attention, it's addictive.
This unit's kitchen's
got a chef's oven.
I cook a lot. Go on.
But it's the emotional stuff
that really sucks you in.
He's just so
knight-in-shining-armor, you know?
Always there to support
you, until one day he's not.
But by then you're hooked.
Hey, do you think that you could
talk to him about taking the dog?
He's the only one that
Hector really gets along with.
Hey, we're here to talk
real estate, not Wilson.
So you're saying if
you'd actually had sex
before you connected emotionally,
you'd have gotten over him.
Oh, yeah. Seems weird, right?
'Cause sex with
James is fantastic.
Nobody works harder to
give a woman what she wants.
It's got six burners.
The chef's oven.
Right.
How you feeling?
That wasn't my crack pipe.
You told me. Are you tired?
I just took a hit off
it a couple of times.
What's wrong with
having a little fun?
Your personal life is
none of my business.
You don't like me
though, do you?
That's your imagination.
I've seen every
kind of drug abuse.
No offense, but you don't
even stand out of the pack.
I'm betting you got money in
the same place you got attitude.
You know, people who quit
drinking and people who lose weight.
They think they're better
than the people that couldn't
and because you
got out of the projects,
you think that
anybody who didn't
is weak and stupid.
I'm not judging you.
Now take a breath.
The only difference
between me and you
is that I made
some bad decisions
and you made some good ones.
You make bad decisions
every day of your life.
Stop doing drugs.
Stop having fun.
Go back to school
and get your GED.
Yeah, where's the
money coming from?
The system's not set
up for people like me.
What are you staring at?
Your eyes.
There's yellow in the sclera.
Her liver's failing.
Without a transplant, she'll
be dead in the next 48 hours.
We should increase her immunosuppressants
and target more specifically.
Add methotrexate.
Yeah, let's do more
of what's not working.
This isn't an
autoimmune disease.
Her white blood cells
are attacking her body.
That's autoimmune.
First brain, then
lungs, now liver.
All getting worse
and all in two days.
It's moving too fast.
It's gotta be cancer.
Lymphomatoid granulomatosis.
It's rare even by our standards
but it fits her symptoms.
Explains why the steroids aren't
working, poor fingernail growth.
A lot of people
have bad fingernails.
A lot of people don't have three
organ systems shutting down.
Her blood vessels are
taking this thing everywhere.
She needs total body radiation.
We can't do anything
until we can confirm...
Running those immunochemistries
could take a week.
She'll be dead by the time...
That doesn't make
radiation any safer.
Okay.
Suppose Chase and
Cameron are right.
Suppose it's an
autoimmune disease.
What's the biggest danger
of total body radiation?
It suppresses the immune system,
which is what we're trying to
do with the steroids anyway.
I don't usually put
out on my first date
but I gotta say
that is a rad move.
Get her consent.
Start the radiation.
The patient's not
too thrilled with me.
I'll get her consent.
Foreman's got
personality issues,
so you're gonna step in?
Patient doesn't like
Foreman. I'm interested.
Fatigue, hair loss, possibility of
damage to the lungs, infertility.
All possible side
effects of radiation.
Why don't you like Dr. Foreman?
He thinks he's
better than he is.
How good is he?
I don't know.
Can we get back to
what's wrong with me?
There's a small possibility of
leukemia at some time in the future.
Hardly worth mentioning.
You can't say he thinks
he's better than he is
if you don't know
how good he is.
No one's as good
as he thinks he is.
I am.
You might also get cataracts.
Sign here.
I don't know.
You're telling me
how dangerous this is.
We're saving your life.
We're that good. Sign there.
I can't decide.
Would you rather
a pencil or a pen?
Who's the better James Bond,
Sean Connery or Daniel Craig?
You see? That's
not even a decision.
It's happening again.
I can't. I can't.
Up her blood thinners and
get her down to Radiology.
The attack will be
over in 20 minutes.
Then she'll wanna sign this.
Bonnie called last night
to talk about the dog.
Your name came up.
Good Lord!
How do you still have teeth?
She's the worst
realtor in New Jersey.
What is this? Escalation?
I go out with Cuddy,
you hook up with my ex?
I don't even know what
that's designed to do.
You're an addict.
I'm saving you from yourself.
By condo shopping? Thank you.
If I can figure out where
you keep going wrong,
then I can nip this
Cuddy thing in the bud
before she becomes
the fourth ex-Mrs. Wilson.
Yes. I was worried there
was no way to stop that train.
You have to have sex with Cuddy.
Wait. To stop the train?
Bonnie said I'm bad in bed?
Huh?
Yeah. She also said
that if she'd slept with
you before she liked you
then it would've made
it easier to handle
when you turned into the
sorry bastard who left her alone.
I told her you were
wasting her time, by the way.
You think that's gonna stop her?
The woman's the worst
realtor in New Jersey.
How do you feel?
Weak.
Sleeping a lot.
That's normal after radiation.
Deep breath.
A little queasy, too.
When I feel sick to my stomach
I always want vanilla
ice cream. It's soothing.
It's best to stick
with liquids for now.
I'm getting a murmur.
Oh, my arm! It's hurting me!
Take it off! Take it off!
Oh, my God!
Pain is the issue.
Just the pressure of the BP cuff
was enough to
start her screaming.
That's not cancer.
It sounds like...
Sounds like she's septic.
A lot of things can cause pain.
How much pain?
Too much.
It's not cancer. It's
not autoimmune.
It's an infection and we
fried her immune system.
But she had no fever.
Her LP was clear.
Do an echo. Confirm
it's in the heart.
And then I'll tell our patient
that we just killed her.
I'll tell her.
Hi. You haven't been
returning my phone calls.
I'm busy.
Well, but if you
have half an hour
a little later this afternoon,
I just found this unit
ten minutes from here.
It hasn't been
on the market yet.
I'm off the market for condos.
James was right?
I never had the teeniest
chance of selling you anything?
Of course he was right.
Wilson doesn't stop giving good
advice just 'cause you're divorced.
He's compulsive about remaining
on good terms with his exes.
Do you wanna know why
I named that dog Hector?
No. Let's keep it a mystery.
Because even when
he was a puppy,
he was the worst-tempered
dog we'd ever seen.
He was supposed
to be house-trained.
He'd pee on the
carpet every morning.
When we had people over,
he had to nip at their ankles.
"Hector does go rug" is an
anagram for "Doctor Greg House".
That's how early in the
marriage I resented you.
Wow. Did I ever waste
money on that place setting.
James at least had the decency
to feel guilty when he hurt me.
Whereas I didn't hurt you.
I didn't even marry you, cleverly
hoping to avoid moments like this one.
You always needed him and
he was always there for you.
If you keep yelling, I'll
think you'll owe me sex.
You knew he had a wife
waiting at home. You didn't care.
Now, I'm not saying you broke
up the marriage, but you didn't help.
First, "Hector does go
rug" is a lame anagram.
You want a better one for
Gregory House? "Huge ego. Sorry."
Second, find a new career.
You're never gonna sell anybody
if you let them
control the agenda.
And third, I don't
owe you anything.
I'm not Wilson. I'm not gonna buy
a condo just to make you feel better.
You okay?
Yeah.
Tell me how to do this.
House says people
thank you after.
It's not typical.
I already killed this woman.
All I can do now is not
make any more mistakes.
First of all, stop thinking
you can minimize the hurt.
A lot of people are
afraid of the word "dying."
If you pussyfoot around it,
she's not going to read your mind.
Okay. No, it's not.
When you look in her face,
you're gonna feel the
instinct to temporize.
Crush it.
Yeah.
Then wait.
Give her time to
process the news.
Let her know you'll be
with her through all of it.
Wait till she's done thinking,
till she meets your eyes again.
Then if you feel it's
appropriate, you can touch her.
Maybe put your hand
on her arm like this.
Let her know she's still
connected to another human being.
You've got this
down to a science.
You're freaking out.
I told you... Give
her what she needs.
What she doesn't need is a
doctor who's not there with her
because he made the wrong call.
You are freaking out.
You should be freaking out.
I won't let her see it.
Let her see it.
Hey.
How come no mask?
We think...
You have an infection.
Didn't the radiation work?
It did what it was
supposed to do.
You're dying.
What do you mean? Like things
are bad and that someday I'm gonna...
How much time?
We can't know exactly.
A year?
Less than a year?
Less than 24 hours.
I don't understand.
Why are you saying this to
me? You're trying to scare me?
Why would you do that?
I'm sorry.
It's true.
How bad is this cancer? Yesterday
you thought I had a chance.
You don't have cancer.
You came in with an infection.
We didn't catch it.
What kind of infection?
Doesn't matter.
Radiation was the worst
thing we could have done.
We destroyed the part of
your body that was fighting it off.
It's spread to your heart.
Then give me drugs.
They have drugs for infections.
Antibiotics work with
the immune system,
but your immune system is
nonexistent because of the radiation.
If it's my heart, you
can get me a new heart.
People have heart
transplants all the time!
It wouldn't help.
The infection's everywhere.
There's nothing anybody can do.
I'm so sorry.
We'll call your grandparents.
Get the hell away
from me! Get out!
Get out!
I think it's broken.
Nothing like a melodramatic
gesture to solve everything.
We were wrong, too. Steroids
wouldn't have helped her.
I didn't not help her. I
actually pulled the trigger.
There's nothing
left for you to do.
One of us could go home with...
You're trying to
make me feel better?
Yeah. I killed a woman.
Don't you think it's appropriate
I feel like crap for
at least a little while?
It won't help her.
Where is he?
He went to the ICU.
What are you doing?
Prepping for an aspiration.
We still don't know
what infection...
It's not gonna help her.
It's not gonna hurt her.
Well, it is gonna hurt
her but it's not gonna...
No.
This'll just take a few minutes.
I'll grab a piece of an abscess,
some pus... You
really don't care.
You really don't care
why she's gonna be dead.
She's gonna be dead because...
What?
What did we screw
up? What did we miss?
I need to know.
You'll have to wait.
We're moving her
back to her room.
Patients who've had total body
radiation have to stay in ICU.
ICU isn't going to help her.
Let's give her some privacy.
What do you want?
Want to see if I'm
dying on schedule?
Or do you want me
to tell you it's all right,
I'm okay with it?
I'd like your forgiveness.
I don't expect it.
Good.
'Cause this isn't like you ran your
cart into mine at the supermarket.
No.
Your grandparents
haven't arrived yet.
If they don't make it on time,
is there anything you'd
like me to tell them?
I never really knew them.
You got any friends
you want me to call?
It's the middle of the night.
They're not the kind of friends
you ask to help you move,
never mind watch you die.
I never did much.
No kid to leave behind.
When I go, the world's
not gonna be any different.
Kind of a relief for you, huh?
You were right about me.
Yeah? Which time?
I had a problem with you.
But you were wrong, too.
I've made some bad decisions.
Stole cars. Robbed houses.
Killed a woman.
But then I got another chance.
Left home, went to college,
entered a whole other world.
And there's some part of me I
can't get rid of, always thinks,
if I'm not the smartest, if I'm
not the first, everywhere I go
they'll figure out I'm
not supposed to be here.
They'll send me back.
You know that's
not gonna happen.
You're out.
I'll never be out of there.
When I came home that last
Christmas I was in college,
it was like the rooms
felt so small.
It was suffocating.
But when I was standing
on the stoop saying goodbye,
my mom put her arms around me.
That was...
That was the last
time I ever felt at home.
I only put distance
between you and me
because I know there isn't any.
You were right about me, too.
That stuff about the system
being against people like me...
I know it's crap.
I mean, it's true
but it's also crap.
I just wasn't
ready to try again.
But I always
thought I was young.
I had time.
Aren't you ever gonna leave?
No.
Yeah?
Time of death, 3:35.
Do whatever you want.
You wanna go and get drunk?
No, thanks.
I've got paperwork.
Listen, I don't...
I don't know what I believe
but sometimes I need to think
there's something out
there paying attention.
So when I can't talk to anybody,
I talk to God and pretend
somebody's listening.
We were all wrong. You know?
Even House was wrong.
I know.
I got your consent.
Her bra hook.
What?
She scratched herself
with her bra hook.
That's how the infection got in.
Staph aureus.
She died from a
simple staph infection?
That and some bad decisions.
I'll be outside.
Go home. Have a
few drinks. Go to sleep.
Get up tomorrow.
And do it all over.
Only better.
If you need absolution,
go to a priest
or give alms to the poor.
Whatever ritual comforts you.
I killed her.
Yeah. Me, too.
This wasn't, "Oh, I should've
thought of that idea sooner."
This wasn't messing up a dosage!
We see a disease rushing
down on someone like a train,
we can't always get
them out of the way!
But this wasn't that.
No.
And you'll do it again.
For a lot of doctors,
this would be a
once-in-a-lifetime mistake.
But we're not a lot of doctors.
And we'll save more patients
than the guy down the street
but a few of the
ones that he'd save
by doing what everyone
else does, we will lose.
So you're giving me numbers.
Because they don't lie.
I can't forgive you, Foreman.
Because there's
nothing to forgive.
What did you tell him?
That guilt is irrelevant.
You wanna get something to eat?
Can't.
Got a dog waiting at home.
What's wrong?
I did something bad, Mom.
I hurt somebody.
It wasn't your fault.
It was.
Then I forgive you.
I forgive you.
I can see from your face
you'd never hurt
anybody on purpose.
Do you know who I am, Mom?
It's Eric.
Of course.
My little boy's name is Eric.