♪ Ohhh ohhh ohhh ♪
You say
you've been depressed?
Not depressed, really.
I'm not clinically depressed,
so don't write down
that I'm depressed.
I have a good life...
A great job.
Good news.
You're six weeks pregnant.
Let's see how those twins
are growing.
♪ you gotta learn to trust ♪
Okay, I think you're ready
to start pushing.
I love my job. I do.
I can't imagine
doing anything else.
The rest of my life is fine.
It's fine. It's just...
♪ ...highly strung ♪
♪ it's easier said than done ♪
I miss him.
♪♪♪
I'm missing him.
I'm missing my life.
I'm disconnected from my life,
like it's a really...
Boring movie
that I don't want to watch.
I mean, I spend all day long
helping other people
have a life.
Need to clear the field.
Almost got her.
And I can deal with that.
I can, if I just knew...
That something
was gonna change.
Something has to change,
right?
When is my life gonna change?
When you make it change.
Hey.
Hi.
Uh, I was just wondering,
uh, how do you tell
when these things are ripe?
Well...
They smell sweet.
That's how you know
if it's ripe.
Thank you.
No problem.
Oh.
Make it change.
You're my mom now,
forever and ever.
Forever and ever.
That's good.
Yes, it is.
Is Gabriel my new dad?
Um, no, honey, no.
It's just you and me.
But you kiss him.
I u--
I used to kiss him, yes.
But not anymore.
No, Gabriel's going to
go back to Washington, D.C.,
and you and I
are gonna stay here.
That's too bad.
I like him.
Yeah, me, too.
Lucas was asleep
before his head hit the pillow.
Mm. I might be
right behind him.
That morning run getting to be
too much for you, old man?
No. My morning run is fine.
It's just 6 miles
is a little much.
My legs felt like lead.
What is it, Violet?
It's a letter
from the medical board.
They're suspending
my license.
You're kidding me.
Uh, it gets worse.
Now they're coming after
the practice.
I can't believe
we're being investigated.
I'm sorry. I never meant
for any of this to happen.
You didn't
do anything wrong.
The point is, the medical board
thinks she did something wrong,
which means they might think
we all have.
Let's not overreact--
oh, come on, Pete.
We're under investigation.
Once they start
digging around--
face it. We're all screwed.
I mean, what, we share
confidential information.
We lie to our patients
for their own good.
We pushed the line so far back,
it isn't even a line anymore.
We're not doctors. We're
friggin' cowboys with guns.
No. We refuse to follow rules
made up by people
that don't take the cases
that we do--the hard cases.
We refuse to let them determine
the course of people's lives.
And if we cross a line
every now and then, big deal.
It's for the benefit
of the patient.
This isn't helping.
The--the original idea
of oceanside wellness was
doctors working cooperatively
to do everything they can
to help their patients--sharing
ideas and debating cases.
It's not wrong. This works.
It's not a question
of whether or not it works.
The question is, are we
willing to fight to protect it?
And I think that we should.
Am I wrong?
An emergency
at the hospital.
I have a patient, so...
You okay?
This job is...
My whole life.
If something were
to happen...
This job is my whole life.
What do we got?
32-year-old Caucasian female,
sustained blunt trauma
and possible kidney injury
from a sexual assault.
I can get another doctor
to look at her, it's just that
you were signed up with
the rape crisis team and--
what's her name?
Kaitlin mills.
Hi, Kaitlin.
I'm Dr. King.
Are they still out there?
The police?
Don't worry about them.
They want me
to talk to them...
But I can't.
Can I take a look at you?
There we go. Easy.
When can I go home?
Uh... there's blood
in your urine...
Which means
there's possible kidney damage.
We need to get a scan.
You're gonna have to stay here
a few days for observation.
I need to do a pelvic exam.
We should also do
a rape kit.
No.
I know this is difficult--
You don't know.
Don't stand there
with your fake,
practiced doctor compassion,
l-like you know
what this is like.
I'm not gonna lay here
and...
Let you--no.
No rape kit.
Of course.
Let's just get you admitted.
What happened?
Routine examination.
She started seizing.
Epileptic?
Juvenile krabbe's disease.
She already had
marked deterioration
of her neurological system.
Marisa, mommy's here, okay?
Mommy's here.
This is our fault. We reduced
her meds this month.
The sedatives
were making her a zombie.
Okay, lorazepam's on board.
Phenytoin going in.
Let's turn her.
Get her over.
Oh, wait. Wait, wait.
She's breathing again.
Oh, thank god.
She gonna be okay?
For now.
She was healthy
until about the age of 3.
Um, she's lost most of hearing,
part of her vision,
and she's slowly losing
the ability
to control her own movements.
Prognosis?
Six months to a year.
I've been trying
to help them to adjust,
but how do you
get someone to accept
that a disease
is killing their child?
You know, I remember reading
about a case like this.
Haven't they had some success
transfusing hematopoietic
stem cells
to slow the progress
of the disease?
Yeah, I read that, too,
the problem is, it has never
been used on someone whose
illness is this far advanced.
Even so,
if there's a chance that
we could buy her some real time,
where she's not getting worse,
isn't that worth a shot?
It could exacerbate the damage
that's already been done.
That would give Marisa
even less time.
So what do we do?
Poor Violet.
Poor us.
God. Can't you believe
this is happening?
It'll all end up fine,
right?
I mean, the worst has
already happened, hasn't it?
I hope so.
Fife is leaving.
Yeah?
Without me, which is...
Which is how it has to be.
I mean, I can't go with him.
I... I have Betsey,
and she needs me.
I need to devote all my time
to her, right?
I don't think I'm qualified
to give advice
on relationships.
I mean, after Sam? You know,
I was in the grocery store.
I tried flirting with this guy
the other day,
and the best I could
come up with was...
"How do you tell
if these things are ripe?"
Like some kind of freak or--
Dr. Montgomery, Neal chaplin
from the medical board.
We spoke--
yes, I know who you are.
This is the guy
who interviewed me when Violet
was being investigated.
How can we help you?
As part of the medical board's
investigation
into this practice, I'm going to
need to sit down with
each of the doctors here and do
a comprehensive interview.
Wait.
Do we have to
talk to this guy?
No, absolutely not.
You could call your lawyers,
consult, and then we could
start the process of setting up
times which are convenient
for them and for me
and for all of you.
That could be
extremely time-consuming.
Please don't come into
our office and threaten us.
I have a job to do,
but I'd be happy to start
by sending in a team
to copy all of your files.
And judging
by what we've gotten
from our review
of Dr. Turner's records, uh,
we should have plenty
to work with.
Okay, uh, with all
due respect, Mr. Chaplin,
you need to turn around and get
the hell out of our office.
Sam, you didn't have to tell
the investigator off.
You think that helped?
Look, he came in here,
into our office,
and tried to push us around.
Y-Yes, it helps us.
We're still gonna have to
talk to him.
All you did
was make him mad, Sam.
Neither one of you understand
what's happening here.
That man is a shark,
and he is circling us.
If we give up, then that--that's
blood in the water. We're dead.
We may be dead anyway.
No, we need to fight.
We need to stand up
and fight for this practice.
How come nobody wants
to fight for the...
We could call our lawyers,
get their advice.
Yes, but whatever they say,
we do,
even if they tell us
not to fight.
I could use
an a.A. Meeting.
Want to join me?
I'm waiting on a motorcyclist
too cool for a helmet.
Oh.
What about after work?
I'll wait for you.
I'll go with you tomorrow,
okay?
Like you were gonna
go with me yesterday?
You've had
a lot of excuses lately.
Charlotte, I have a mother,
a good mother.
Let her do her job.
Let's go to a meeting
tomorrow morning on Montana.
She does it so fast,
sometimes I can't even
keep up.
I didn't know
you knew sign language.
It helps to know a little bit
for my deaf patients.
Oh, ha ha ha ha.
So this, um, p-procedure,
how much more time
would it give Marisa?
Well, it's impossible
to say.
But studies suggest
that it could give her
an extra two or three years.
Th-that's amazing.
That's amazing.
Didn't you hear them?
I heard them,
but they also said
that they weren't sure
it would work
and that
it could make her worse.
The idea of more time
with her... Jason--
if this were your child,
Dr. Wilder,
would you risk the time you knew
you had left with her?
Well, this is
a very personal decision,
and it's really not relevant
what Dr. Wilder
or anybody else would do.
It's all about how prepared
your family is emotionally
to deal with the outcome of
this, you know, whatever it is.
What did she say?
She wants to know
when she can go home
and sleep in her own bed.
Do you come here every night?
I couldn't get the idea
of fresh pineapple
out of my mind.
What about you?
Do you--do you come here
every night?
No.
I lied.
I hate pineapples.
So...
Tell me about yourself.
Well, I...
Let's not.
Oh. Okay.
No. I mean--
look, I-I could tell you
about my ex-boyfriend,
my dating history,
what's going on at work.
I could tell you
all of that, but...
Let's make a change.
You want to make a change?
Yeah. I don't want to do any of
the things that I usually do--
no drama, no games,
no history.
Just you and me
in the present,
start clean.
Is that weird?
No. Not at all.
Okay.
No histories,
no names,
just... here and now.
What, is there...
Do I have some--
I'm just wondering what it might
be like to kiss those lips.
Oh.
Oh, no. We can't do that.
I-I don't even know
your name.
Hey, you set the rules.
Yeah, but we're in public.
We're in the present.
Best date ever, so far.
Missed you at the meeting
this morning.
Yeah, I was wiped out
from being on call.
I heard it was pretty slow
at the hospital last night.
Okay, um, we just got off
the phone with the lawyers,
and they felt strongly
that we need to be proactive
about protecting ourselves
as best we can.
What does that mean?
It means that we have to start
by going back through
all of our files,
making lists of patients
we consulted each other about,
and then we need to
separate out the instances
when the advice was medical
from those where we just
debated each other for sport.
That is not what we do.
Which is exactly
what I said.
- Sam, we said we would listen to the lawyers.
- And then what?
We're gonna just sit back
and let them pick us apart?
Well, look, we pushed
back as hard as we could.
And the bottom line is,
the practice is already
a target of the medical board.
They don't care about truth.
They don't care that we're
trying to help people.
You know, I'm just saying.
The lawyers gave us two choices.
Either we figure out
every single point
of vulnerability now
and prepare
to defend ourselves.
Or?
We dissolve the practice,
go our separate ways,
and hope that the medical board
or the lawyers
don't come after us
individually.
How's it going?
I'm doing good.
Good.
Well, not exactly good,
because now I may not have
a job to go to,
and everything is a mess,
but...
I met a guy...
Over a pineapple.
And that makes you
feel better?
♪ set a still frame in my mind ♪
It makes me feel like
my life is changing.
♪ It's time ♪
♪ to go ♪
♪ it's time ♪
♪ oh ♪
I shouldn't even be here.
Well, apparently,
none of us should be.
No, I mean, I just...
I'm not even a doctor anymore.
You're still a doctor.
I can't practice medicine.
That's not a doctor. That's...
Nothing. I'm nothing.
Come on. You're a wife.
You're a mother.
That...
I help people, Pete.
It's who I am.
So... yeah, yeah,
I guess I could learn
to bake bread
and go to playgroups
and learn how to quilt,
and I guess everything
would be fine for a while,
but that's not me.
You know
that's not me, Pete.
I... I would get sad
and dark.
And why is that
good for Lucas?
Dark mommy
with a drink in her hand.
No,
I'm just saying that...
My identity
is what I do.
I need to work to feel alive.
What are you trying
to say, Violet?
My publisher has been after me
for a while to do a book tour.
And I think
I should do that now.
A book tour?
Three weeks.
Four tops. I could
bring Lucas and a nanny.
I could help people
through my book.
I think that's a good idea.
You can't just run away
from your problems--
I know that, Pete.
I'm a shrink.
Oh, wait. I'm not anymore,
which is the point!
Just...
Think about it, okay?
A-A book tour now?
Are you kidding?
I mean, she needs to stay here
and fight this thing.
Man, you gotta get her
to stay and fight.
She's upset. She's devastated.
I don't know how I would feel
if my license was suspended,
but this is such a bad idea.
How does she not see that?
Because she's Violet.
All right.
Starting the chemo infusion.
I mean, she blames herself
for what's going on
at the practice, but that--
Her pressure's dropping.
Marisa had
a severe allergic reaction
to the medication.
We were able
to resuscitate her,
but... she was deprived
of oxygen
for a significant period
of time.
She may have sustained
additional brain damage.
I'm very sorry.
Oh, god.
But she's going to
wake up, right?
She's only
minimally functional,
and she's not going to get
any better.
No.
This can't be happening.
This morning we could talk
to her, and now...
The two of you
pushed us to do this.
Now you took my girl from me.
I'll go after him.
No, I will.
Oh.
Kinda quiet around here.
What did you do to
all the, you know, patients?
I thought you left.
I almost did.
I just thought...
Look, I'm not gonna say
all the mushy things again.
But I'm taking one more shot.
I am leaving tomorrow.
Come with me.
Gabriel, I...
The practice
is falling apart,
and I can't uproot Betsey
before I've even
gotten her settled.
You could. If you wanted to,
you could.
Okay.
Nice knowing you, Naomi.
I'm not the kind of man--
I've never talked
to my wife like that,
much less the doctors trying
to take care of my daughter.
It's okay.
No, it's not.
None of it is.
I shouldn't have dropped
my guard.
I shouldn't have let myself
imagine a future
where I could teach my girl
how to ride a bike
and how to drive a car.
I want to blame someone,
but that
won't change anything.
I can't watch my baby
or Angela suffer anymore.
I can't.
Isn't there another way,
a more humane way to treat her?
I'm sorry, Jason.
I can't imagine
how difficult it is for you,
but we've run out
of medical options.
That's not what I'm asking.
I want you to help me
end Marisa's suffering.
So I had coffee
with pineapple guy.
And I kissed him...
Which I have decided
is a good thing.
It's new, so...
Right?
What?
Fife came back.
And he asked me to go away
with him... again.
And you said?
No, again.
You could go.
Start fresh.
Change your life.
I can't.
I have to be responsible.
I'm the responsible one.
I... I can't leave,
not with the practice
in a mess,
and I can't abandon the practice
and I can't abandon you guys--
and--and Maya. Did I tell you
she got into Columbia?
What?
She got into Columbia,
and she wants to go.
How am I supposed
to help her with that--
going to college with a baby--
and Betsey--
I mean, I-I know I owe it to her
to give her the stability
that poor child
has never managed to have.
I mean, i--why can't he
understand that?
Why can't he understand that i'm
just trying to be responsible?
What--what's...
What's going on there
with your face?
I'm just trying not to cry.
Oh. All right.
For the next ten minutes...
I'm gonna be
the responsible one,
and you go ahead...
And cry.
Go ahead.
It's okay.
You cry.
I'm here.
Hey.
So this whole thing that's
going on with the practice...
Yeah.
Right? I mean...
I mean, there's gotta be
some way we can win this.
I can't stop thinking
about it.
Do you want to grab dinner
or something
and try to figure
this whole thing out?
I have somewhere to go.
I have a date.
Oh.
I'm sorry.
I didn't want to lie.
No, it's fine.
I totally--i get it.
Uh...
No, go. Go have fun.
Go have fun on your date.
Maybe we shouldn't
fight it, Sam.
Maybe we should
let the practice die
and just go
our separate ways.
I have an 8-year-old girl
who's gone from smiling
and signing this morning
to a permanent
vegetative state,
and her father wants me to...
He wants me to euthanize her.
And I swear to god,
Charlotte,
I'm seriously considering it.
For the last two days...
I've been dealing
with a patient who was raped.
They brought her in
looking exactly like
the way I felt--
just... wrecked.
I'm not like Violet.
I can't share everything
about my personal life
with people.
I'm never gonna write
a book.
That's not how I'm built.
But here, even though
I wanted to say something,
knew I should...
I couldn't.
I just folded up.
I'm sorry.
I didn't tell you
to make you feel bad.
I told you because...
I don't know either.
I guess I'm looking...
For the same thing
you are.
What's that?
Someone to tell me
how hard to push,
how to untangle
my patient's best interest
from my own.
How do we do this?
I think...
We do
what we've always done.
We put our patient's needs
ahead of everything else.
We take care of our patients.
Yeah.
So I'm guessing lawyer.
I'm not a lawyer.
Anthropologist.
That would be fun,
but no.
And stop with the 20 questions.
I thought we both agreed.
We're gonna have to tell
each other who we are
sooner or later.
On our next date,
I promise.
I don't know if I can wait
two whole weeks.
Two--what--two weeks?
We have to wait two weeks
for our next date?
I am taking
a much-deserved vacation--
14 days in Fiji...
White sand, blue water.
Oh, I'm jealous.
Well, you should be. But hey,
I'll bring you back a gift.
Or you could come with me.
Oh, right.
No, I'm serious.
We could spend our days
telling each other
our life stories.
We could spend our nights
having--having hot sex
in this amazing hut
out over the water.
I can't go with you to Fiji.
Why not? Why not? What do you
have holding you here, huh?
You're tempted.
I know you're tempted.
Hey.
Hey. You don't look so good.
Oh, I've felt better.
Where's Lucas?
He's already sleeping.
Do you--do you want me
to get you something?
No, I'm fine.
I just...
I had a tough a day.
And I know
that we have to finish
talking about
this book tour thing...
Yes.
Um... I have thought
about it, and...
I-I need to do this.
Does it matter
what I think?
Of course it matters
what you think.
But I'm hoping
that what you'll think is,
your wife needs this,
and because she needs it,
you'll support her.
That's not what I think.
Okay. What do you think?
I think you're being selfish.
Okay.
This is about what you need.
It's not about what Lucas needs.
It's not about what I need.
It's about you.
Well, this book
is important to me.
This book is tearing
our practice apart.
Do you want it to tear
our family apart, too?
Okay, now you're blaming
the book... the one thing--
the one good thing that came
from Katie slicing me open--
Lucas is the one good thing--
you know what I mean.
I don't want you to go.
It's only for three weeks,
and Lucas can come with me.
Lucas is not going.
He can stay here if that's
easier for you. We can make
that work, too. Pete, I do not
want to make you unhappy, but--
I swear, Violet,
if you run away again--
again?
You dropped Lucas in my lap
and you ran!
Because I needed to!
Okay, once again...
This is not just about you!
If you run--
just stop it, Pete.
Just stop it.
Don't say anything else,
because what is about to come
out of your mouth right now
sounds like an ultimatum,
and I do not respond
to ultimatums.
And this isn't the past.
I-I know my leaving triggers
you. I know you are triggered.
But this isn't the same.
So please just--
don't say anything.
Don't do this to us.
Just... let's be silent
for a minute. Please.
Just... stand here with me.
I'm going.
Yeah, I know.
Violet, I love you.
But right now,
I'm done with you.
Hey, Charlotte.
Uh, it's Amelia.
I was hoping
you'd pick up.
Listen, uh... this whole thing
with the practice
sort of caught me off guard,
and, uh...
Well, now this motorcycle dummy
has taken a turn for the worse,
so i'm, uh, kinda walking into
this pretty tricky surgery,
and... you know,
I probably should've met you
for that meeting this morning,
but, um...
Anyway, uh...
You know what?
Um... it's fine.
I'll be fine.
I just... look,
forget that I called.
I'm--I'll talk to you later.
We're ready for you
in the O.R., Dr. Shepherd.
Is everything okay?
Yeah.
Yeah, I just need a minute.
Okay.
♪♪♪
There's nothing I can say
that's gonna make Marisa better
or take away...
The pain
that you and Angela have.
And... what you asked me
to do, I understand it,
but I... can't do it.
You don't
have to do anything.
Just give me some pills.
She's still your daughter.
In that body is still
that girl that you love.
She's suffering.
Can't you see that?
I want to end her suffering.
You're the one
that's suffering.
And ending her life
won't end your suffering.
It won't make it better.
It's crossing
an uncrossable line,
and it'll destroy you.
I'm supposed to help her.
You're her father,
and your job--
your only job--
is to love your daughter
for as much time
as she has left.
And...
That will help her.
Loving her helps her.
And we will be there with you
every step of the way.
♪ I feel ♪
♪ at home ♪
Getting through
what happened to you...
Is gonna be
a special kind of hell.
There's no way around that.
But I'm here to tell you,
you can do this,
'cause you're not a victim.
You're a survivor.
You survived this.
There's a way
to move forward...
Past the pain...
The shame...
The guilt.
You won't forget.
But you will get there.
It's possible.
I know it's possible.
♪♪♪
Hey.
You seen Addison?
Uh, I think she went home.
There's no reason for her
to hang around.
It's not like we have
any patients coming in.
Yeah.
You okay?
Yeah, i'm, you know,
I'm just...
Fife's gone.
I didn't go with him.
So, you know, whatever.
Oh, Nai.
If I could have made it work
with Addison, I would've.
I wish...
Honestly, I-I wish
that we were still together.
That makes me feel
so much better. Thank you.
No, that's--I'm sorry.
I'm just saying, it's hard,
you know...
To--to find happiness,
so you find happiness
wherever you can,
and... if that's with fife,
if he makes you happy--
it's not that easy.
Nai, it's exactly that easy.
No, it's not. No.
I've got the practice
and I have Betsey...
Nai, listen to me.
Maya--
I am the father of your child,
standing here telling you
to run off and be happy
with another man.
Now you need to listen to me,
because this is the only time
I'm gonna say this.
Now... you're making excuses
not to be loved.
Don't stick around
for the practice.
I mean, the practice--
maybe it's time to let it go.
And Betsey--
all a child needs is love.
And as long
as you two are together,
she can be loved
by you anywhere.
But you and...
God knows why...
But I guess
you can only be loved
the way you need to be loved...
With fife.
♪♪♪
You deserve to be happy.
You deserve to be loved.
So you should go.
♪♪♪
Go.
Hey, sorry I missed your call.
How'd your surgery go?
Great. No problems.
I'm glad to hear it.
What about your phone call?
It was just a blip.
I'm good now.
Breathe on me.
Do it.
You've been drinking.
You operated on a patient
after drinking.
I'm not drunk.
Look, I just slipped,
and then I got paged.
Okay, I had a slip.
You get that, right?
Starting now,
your surgical privileges
at this hospital
are revoked.
You and I,
we're going to a meeting,
right this minute.
Screw you, Charlotte.
So I think I'm gonna go.
I mean, you said to change
my life, to make a change.
This is a change.
I mean, he's a nice guy,
and Sam's gone,
and the practice is dying.
Why should I hang out here
when I could be with
a gorgeous guy in Fiji?
You said to make a change.
This is change.
I think it's good. I do.
Right?
♪ I don't know ♪
Hi, baby.
Hi.
♪ Felt this feeling
was a warning ♪
So I'm going away
for a couple of weeks.
But I'm gonna see you
every day
when I call
on the computer, okay?
I love you.
I love you so, so, so much.
And I'll be back soon, okay?
It's just a couple of weeks.
Take care
of daddy while I'm gone.
♪♪♪
Mm.
Bye-bye, baby.
Bye-bye.
Good-bye.
♪♪♪
Bye-bye.
♪ I don't know ♪
♪ Oh, I don't know ♪
Oh, I wish I could've
saved her.
I wish I could've given her
more time. I wish--
Cooper, I just came
from a meeting.
There's something
we say there,
and it helps me,
and I think
it might help you.
God, Grant me the Serenity
to accept the things
I cannot change,
the courage to change
the things I can...
And the wisdom
to know the difference.
♪♪♪
Flight 7-2-4 with
nonstop service to Miami
is now boarding at gate 2-0-4.
Flight 724, with
nonstop service to Miami...
Violet?
What--what--
what are you doing here?
I'm going on a book tour.
What are you doing?
I'm... going on a date.
With a suitcase.
Yeah.
Um, good luck
with your book tour.
Good luck to you
on your date.
Nai?
Addison, what are you--
i'm--i'm--i'm, uh,
I'm looking for gate 211.
There are
too many gates here.
Wh-what are you doing here?
Oh, there it is.
I'm--i'm--I'm trying
to stop fife.
I-I want to be with fife
if--if he'll have me.
Good for you.
Yeah. But I-I-I just
want to say that...
Listen, I love you...
And that
I will always be here for you.
Wherever I am, I will always
be here for you,
just a phone call away.
You're my very best friend
in the whole world,
and I thank you for that,
okay?
♪♪♪
I'm so happy for you.
Thank you.
Go.
Okay.
Go get your happy ending.
No, uh, wait. I, uh--
I'm sorry. The gate's closed.
There--there is--there is
somebody on that plane
that I really, really need
to speak to.
There's nothing I can do.
She really can't open
that door.
T.s.a. Regulations
are very strict.
Gabriel, what...
Why weren't--
why aren't you on the--
on the plane?
Because I knew
you'd come rushing after me.
It was easier this way.
I can't believe
how cocky you are!
Can you still call me cocky
if I'm right?
♪♪♪
You'll have to forgive me
not going down on one knee,
but, uh...
♪ find ♪
♪ your voice ♪
♪ and make a noise ♪
Yes.
Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes.
♪♪♪
Oh, but, um...
I'm not going to D.C.
with you.
We're moving to New York,
I've already decided--
you, me, and Betsey.
Maya's gonna be at Columbia
with Olivia,
and I'm gonna open an office
for the foundation,
and we can work together.
Touché.
♪ Be looking much too far away ♪
♪ to recognize ♪
♪ to find ♪
Last call for Fiji air
flight number 2-6-9-6,
boarding at gate 215.
♪ Find ♪
♪ your voice ♪
♪ and make a noise ♪
♪ oh, we all were born
before the war ♪
♪ but worlds collide ♪
♪ look at all the people
fighting for ♪
We could fight it,
what's happening to us.
We could block their
interrogations, bar the doors.
Or we could accept it.
Or we could change it.
We could make a change.
I would like us
to officially dissolve
oceanside wellness group...
Okay, h-hold on a second--
and open a new practice.
I'll use my money.
I'll fund it.
Meanwhile,
we hire a consultant,
somebody who's been
a medical investigator,
someone from the inside
to help us figure this out.
But o.W.G. As we know it,
it doesn't exist anymore.
We start over. We start fresh.
We start clean.
We stay a family,
but we change.
Make a change for the better.
♪ And make it right ♪
♪♪♪
♪ and make a noise ♪
I missed you.
I missed you, too.
Mm.
I'm still gonna want
a baby, Sam.
Not with you.
I know how you feel.
I don't know. I'll adopt
or get a sperm donor.
I don't know,
but I'm gonna have a baby...
On my own.
♪ But worlds collide ♪
But having you
and having a baby
aren't mutually exclusive.
More change.
You'd have to love me...
With my baby...
Or at least...
Just love me
for right now.
Can you do that?
I can try.
♪ ...were born
before the war ♪
♪ but worlds collide ♪
♪ if you see the world ♪
♪♪♪
♪ you make it right ♪
- Whoa!
- Whoo!
♪♪♪
♪ run away,
run away, run away ♪
Oh.
♪ Run away,
run away, run away ♪
♪ Run away, run away ♪
♪♪♪