Previously on ER:
Pupils are equal an
reactive. What year is it?
- Seven.
- Good. Let's go to Trauma 1.
Quick and concise. How is she?
Hypertensive, anemic,
with abdominal pain.
- Extensive crush injuries.
- Neela.
- It's been great.
- Your day might have been a lot better...
- if you never met me.
- No so sure about that.
- Hope I see you around.
- Yeah.
- You can check yourself in the ICU.
- What?
There are lots of
good lessons for a guy
like you up there. Trust
me, you should know.
- You're kidding, right?
- No, I'm not kidding you.
Luka's not the chief anymore.
Moretti's the man now.
Well, someone should
talk to Anspaugh.
- All right, good luck,
Mr. Stoll. MAN: Thanks, doc.
Hey, Dr. Anspaugh.
You know, you're one busy guy.
I've been calling all week
to schedule an appointment.
My assistant can fit you
in as soon as possible.
Do you have a few
minutes? I need to talk to you.
I need to get to a council meeting. If
there is a God, I can beat this traffic.
It's about Dr. Moretti.
He's all wrong for the ER. He
doesn't understand how it works.
Kevin is a brilliant physician
certified in emergency medicine.
The guy is smart, I'll give him that,
but he's in way over his head, and...
And what?
You should replace him with someone
who knows how to do the job: me.
Well, I admire your chutzpah.
Well, you call it what
you want, but I'm serious.
Look, change is always hard.
I'm sure he's gonna settle in.
- Dr. Anspaugh, I can do this.
- Ask me in another year or two.
And next, go from
trash to treasure...
when we learn how
to make lamps...
- Hi.
- Out of egg cartons.
Won't that be fun?
- Got some magazines. MAN:
That just sounds "eggcellent," Tina.
- And your favorite, gummy worms.
- Thank you.
Okay, okay, why can't
you tease egg whites?
And Brad Pitt.
- They can't take a "yolk."
- He's outside.
He's over Angelina and
the whole adoption thing...
and he wants you.
Are you okay?
I think I'm addicted to
Mornings With Phil and Tina.
Oh. Well, hang in there.
You'll be home tomorrow.
Correction: today.
My staples came out, and
my creatinine's down to 0.9.
- Worm?
- No, thank you.
- Who sent you these flowers?
- ER nurses.
- Think they went a little bit overboard.
- No.
- Everyone's just happy you're doing well.
- Yeah.
- Any luck with Joe's passport?
- It's so crazy.
I mean, there's all
these new travel rules...
so even with an expedited
passport, it takes like four weeks.
- What time are you getting out of here?
- Oh, I'm not sure.
Lucien wants me to stay home
for a week before I go back.
- Lucky you.
- What I am gonna do sitting at home?
Um, relax, recuperate...
try and kick your Phil
and Tina addiction.
- Okay, I'm late. See you later.
- Okay, bye.
Take the light
cord... MAN: Right.
And pull it through the base.
And that means no more boarding
admitted patients in the ER hallways.
If there aren't enough
beds, they can wait upstairs.
Oh, Lord, it's me, your
servant, Bernie. I'm dying, Lord.
- Do the nurses upstairs know about this?
- Sam, your hair is brown.
And from now on, I want all patients
to have full physical examinations.
- Take me, Lord. It's my time.
- You're kidding me, right?
No. Clothes off. No more
of these half-assed exams.
And we need to have more
consistent treatment protocols...
in line with
evidence-based guidelines.
- Here I come.
- Should we go help that guy?
Mr. Zucker? Comes in every week
with a hangover, claims he's dying.
He offered to put me in
his will if I gave him a bath.
These are standard order sets...
for acute coronary
syndrome, stroke...
sepsis, alcohol withdrawal,
and procedural sedation.
I expect you all to
make use of them.
- Get to work. BERNIE:
I'm coming home.
Now we're doing
cookbook medicine?
Why don't they just hire
trained monkeys to work the ER?
Hey, Morris, do you have any
known relatives in Bulgaria?
- What?
- Frank's new hobby is genealogy.
He discovered I'm a
descendant of Spanish royalty.
Yeah, then I found this
Archibald Morrisnov in Plovdiv.
No, I don't think we're
related, but check Venezuela.
I may have a cousin who
runs a kidnapping ring.
Crime is just the desperate
cry of the poor, Archie.
- Gates? I thought we got rid of you.
- I left my otoscope here.
Yeah, I was about
to auction it on eBay.
Oh, stop pretending. You
know you miss me, Frank.
Hey, Abby, have you
seen Neela today?
Yeah, I was just there.
She's going home.
- That's great.
- So this is your last chance to visit her.
- I've visited her.
- When she was unconscious.
I'm busy and starting
my first shift in ICU.
Tony, go see her.
- It's a little...
- Yeah, weird.
I know, stuff happened.
But you just gotta get over it.
Know what? This is
Sarah. I gotta take this.
- Hey, Sarah. What's up? Yeah.
- Here I go. Here I go.
Dr. Lockhart.
So nice of you to take time out
of your busy schedule to join us.
- I was visiting a friend of mine...
- Fascinating.
I'm instituting a new system,
and I need a volunteer: you.
Today you'll be working
your shift in the waiting area.
- Lord, it's me again.
- Do you mean Triage?
- No, Waiting.
- Here I come.
It's a chance to intervene
at the earliest stage.
Do you really think
that this is the best use?
- Open your eyes, Abby.
- This is the end.
- Take a fresh look.
- Just say the word.
Excuse me.
Bernie, this is God.
Hurry it up already.
Yeah, your toe is infected, ma'am.
We're gonna have to remove the nail.
- Is there anything you're allergic to?
- I don't like cheese.
Okay, someone will be
here shortly to take you back.
- Then we'll see about some shoes.
- Oh, I like Jimmy Choos.
Hey, how much longer do I
have to wait around this place?
- Sir, you have to sit down. Sit down.
- Don't you know who I am?
"Carlos Vega."
- Hi.
I'm Dr. Lockhart. What
seems to be the problem?
He threw up all night.
We thought it might be something
he ate, but he's getting worse.
Maybe you can give me something
for my stomach, and we can go.
Yeah, I think you have a fever.
It's probably not food poisoning.
Oh, no. He played with
our baby all day yesterday.
Honey, Tyler's fine.
Doctor, I gotta get to work.
How long do we have to wait?
Um...
You know, why don't we just
take you back right now, okay?
- Oh, thank you.
- Come on. You all right?
All right. Let's do this.
I was thinking about going down
to Baton Rouge and visit Ray.
Yeah. We'll go together.
The three of us could
catch a Saints game.
That sounds good.
We should do that.
"Seaweed Scalp Mist."
Ray was a little hair-obsessed.
But I gotta say, the man's
lid always looked good.
Oh, boy.
- Are these a size nine?
- Don't even go there, Morris.
Well, what's he gonna
do with them? I mean...
Sir, back away from
the shoes, all right?
Guys, is that locker available?
- What?
- I haven't been assigned one yet.
- Stop. No one's using this locker.
- It's retired.
You can't retire an ER locker.
Can you?
You can use one of
those lockers over there.
This one's off-limits.
So, what can we bring to
dinner tonight at Chez Pratt?
It's not necessary, but
maybe some red wine.
Vino it is. Thanks
again for the invite.
It was Bettina's idea
to do this double date.
- She really likes you, man.
- Hey, Pratt, mazel tov.
You having a stroke?
Did you know your
great-great-great-grandmother...
on your mother's side
was an Ethiopian Jew?
Wow, black and Jewish.
You're like County's
own Sammy Davis, Jr.
Get out of here.
Who can take a rainbow
Wrap it in the sky?
- Archie.
- The Pratt man can
Sam, you said you wanted
to get out there again.
Oh, I don't know.
You and your new hair
need to come with us tonight.
- Where you gals going?
- Speed dating.
What is speed dating?
It's a way for losers to
meet other losers fast.
No, you get six minutes,
you sit at a table...
and talk to a bunch of guys.
How are you supposed
to get to know somebody?
- Chemistry. MORRIS:
Seems more like desperation.
- Sam, are you in or not?
- It sounds like fun.
Maybe she doesn't want to because
she has her eye on someone else.
- What? Who?
- Officer Litchman.
Oh, he is so cute. I thought I
noticed a spark between you two.
Yeah? I mean, no.
I mean, yes, I think he's cute,
but I would never date a cop.
Frank, you got it wrong, man.
My grandfather was
Steven with a V. Look.
MVC, second victim behind me.
Sixteen-year-old unrestrained
driver ejected from vehicle.
- What's your name?
- Where's Joanna?
Casey Barnes, blunt head
trauma, awake but altered.
CBC, chem panel,
type and cross four units.
Twenty-five-year-old
passenger. No LOC, vitals stable.
- How's Casey? Is he all right?
- Let's worry about you first.
CBC, type and screen, UA.
- Joanna.
- Airway's patent. Spontaneous resps.
- IV blew.
- Regular rhythm.
Carotid pulse is thready. Look at
me. Do you know where you are?
Sam, he's tachy.
Get that bolus up.
I can't get a flash.
His pressure's too low.
We need access.
I'll go central. Cordis
and sterile sevens.
When a trauma rolls in,
you're supposed to jump on.
- Thought you could handle it.
- I'm handling it fine.
- Agitation could be a sign of ICH.
- I'll call for a head CT.
Pupils equal but sluggish.
Sorry about earlier.
I can't stop thinking
about the mosquito thing.
- Mosquitoes love redheads.
- We'll talk about it later tonight.
Somebody hand me
the introducer? I'm sterile.
Not sterile enough. No
drape, no gown, no mask.
We prophylactically remove all ER lines
because your rate of infection is so high.
My fault. Kid was
crashing. I asked her...
That's not true, I...
Spare me. Just do it right.
- All right, pupils equal and reactive.
- Guarding a little.
- How's she doing?
- Well, airways good. GCS 15.
I'm Dr. Moretti.
How you feeling?
- Been better.
- She's tachy. You got a pressure?
- 126/76.
- Please, is Casey okay?
Doctors are working on him.
- Oh, God.
Her pelvis is stable.
We got superficial
abrasions to the right thigh.
- I should've never let him drive.
- Is he your brother?
No, my student. I teach
math at Edgewater.
I was tutoring
him before school.
- In the car? JOANNA:
He just got his license.
Begged me to go driving.
- Chest film's back.
- Okay.
My son was in the National
Math Olympiad in high school.
Now he's squandering his
talents as a comp. lit. major.
Go figure. What do you see?
- Is that a little pneumo?
- Yep.
Let's put her on a high flow of
O2 and set up her for a chest tube.
- Whoa, whoa. Overkill.
- She's got a 20 percent pneumothorax.
What does that
mean? Is that bad?
It means part of your lung has
collapsed, and we need to reinflate it.
- Okay, Dr. Pratt. Your patient.
- All right, lido and 10 blade to me.
- Why don't you take off your shirt?
- No, that's okay.
I need to examine your abdomen.
Do we really need to make a big deal?
My boss is a real pain.
- He won't like that I'm late.
- It won't take long.
My boss is a real pain, and he
won't like if I don't do a thorough exam.
- What's that?
- Oh, he got hurt at work.
It's nothing. I was stupid.
- Elena helped me clean it up.
- Still, I need to check it out.
No, you don't, really.
How'd this happen again?
Funny, this doesn't
look like the waiting area.
So, sir, how'd you manage
to get yourself shot?
There was a
drive-by, and I got hit.
- When did this happen?
- Three nights ago.
- Why didn't you go to the hospital?
- Well, he doesn't like doctors.
It's all right. I don't
take that personally.
It's not what it looks like.
All right. I'll be right back.
Start with a plain film,
find out where the bullet is?
And notify the police.
- Morning, Neela.
- Morning.
- What happened to you?
- Field hockey. Your LFTs look good.
You should be able to
go home in an hour or two.
That's what they said four hours ago.
- Any trouble voiding?
- No, my Foley is out.
- Are you still passing gas?
Would you stop, Dusty?
She's been through enough.
No going home until
Neela makes a poo-poo.
You know, my postop
ileus has resolved.
That's the ER. Let's go, Dusty.
It's good to see you up and around.
Okay. Thirteen-year-old.
Pneumonia, dysphagia, normal CT.
Chang, what crucial historical
detail did Dr. Udesky omit?
Weight loss? Night sweats?
No, no, no, the one thing we must
know to narrow down this vast differential.
- MRI results?
- You're breaking my heart.
- Excuse me.
- Duration of symptoms.
Sudden onset, we're thinking
stroke, infection, trauma.
Slow onset, we're
thinking tumor, metabolic...
- Yes?
- Dr. Shuster, I'm Dr. Gates.
- Moretti sent me here.
- Yet you show up 20 minutes late.
I was doing a
follow-up on a patient.
This is the Critical Care Unit. I don't
have time to potty-train ER rejects.
Get me an MRI. Call Neuro. I
want a diagnosis before lunch.
Looks like the boss lady
ripped you a new one.
Oh, you're too young to
know what flirting looks like.
See what's taking so long in CT.
- You don't even speak Spanish.
- I'll learn.
- Sats down to 82.
- Okay, get him on a non-rebreather.
And, Hope, get
ready to tube him.
- This is the kid's mom.
- Baby? Baby, it's Mom.
Honey, I'm right
here, right here.
Your son's been in a car
crash. He's lost a lot of blood.
- Run of 10.
- Casey, come on.
Throw me the bag.
Ma'am, I'm Dr. Morris.
We're gonna put a tube
in to breathe for him.
What happened?
He was driving, and
he hit a guardrail.
- He was ejected 20 feet.
- Driving? Casey doesn't have a car.
He came in with her.
- Do you know that woman?
- Yeah.
Darn, bulb's out. I need
a new scope, Mac 2.
Casey, honey, wake
up. Wake up. Talk to me.
I'll get it. BOBECK: He's
in V-tach. Lost the pulse.
Charge the paddles.
Starting compressions.
- Is Casey okay?
- He's pretty sick.
- How we doing?
- She's got a hemothorax.
- Good thing we put in a chest tube.
- It was the right call.
Systolic only 85.
Dawn, let CT know that we're
coming up for a chest and abdomen.
- I wouldn't do that.
- Why not?
She's pregnant. PRATT: What?
Right there. That's
a fetal heartbeat.
Didn't you order an ICON?
Yeah, he did. The
lab's backed up.
I'm pregnant?
Looks like you weren't
the only one in the dark.
Small-caliber bullet in
the T12 vertebral body.
He's febrile, probably infected.
He needs the O.R. for débridement.
- Abby. The detectives are here.
- You called the police?
We're obligated to
report gunshot wounds.
Get a CT. Make sure there's
nothing in the spinal canal or abdomen.
Mr. Vega.
- Heard you were the victim of a drive-by.
- Yeah.
- Can you tell us when and where?
- Three nights ago, on my block.
That would be 3027 Pierce?
- Right.
- We don't have a report of that.
But there was a shooting
at a deli on Leavitt.
Owner was shot,
but he returned fire.
- Carlos had nothing to do with that.
- Elena.
Why don't you call your mom?
Have her take Tyler home.
- It's all right.
- Three Latino suspects got away.
But witnesses say one
of them was wounded.
- It wasn't me. Ask the store owner.
- He's in a coma.
As long as your bullet isn't a match
for his gun, you don't have a problem.
- Gross hematuria.
- We're taking her to the scanner.
- Is that okay in the first trimester?
- Nope. Too much radiation.
- Please don't hurt my baby.
- We need to focus on you now.
Please, someone go
see how Casey's doing.
- I need to know.
- I'll check.
- What?
- You can't do a CT.
- She'll never consent.
- She's not competent.
Let's follow with a formal ultrasound.
We'll get a good look at the kidneys.
We cannot do the
formal ultrasound that fast.
Why? You're a resourceful guy.
So you expect the radiologist to be
at my beck and call Q 15 minutes?
- Yeah, I do.
- They don't have enough machines or...
Hey, guys. They
need help in here.
What's wrong with Casey?
Make it happen, Dr. Pratt.
Charged to 360. Clear.
Still no pulse. V-fib.
Resume CPR. SAM: Epi's in.
How many rounds of meds?
- It's the fifth.
- Amiodarone?
- Yes.
No.
You're coding a patient in here, and
nobody bothered to come and get me?
I'm on top of it.
Really? You're blasting
the myocardium with drugs...
and you're hoping for a miracle.
- Please, you've gotta save him.
- Sam, give the amio.
Did you hear what I just said?
- He's a kid.
- I am aware of that.
Mom? Come here.
We've been trying to restart his
heart for over half an hour now.
- You have to keep going.
- His injuries are too severe.
He's lost too much blood.
No. No, this isn't happening.
I'm gonna stop CPR
now, which means... No!
Oh, no, no, no.
Please don't stop.
But he's just a boy.
He's my baby.
Casey.
So where's your mom?
Oh, she's at work.
She'll be here later.
Dr. Shuster was
obnoxious, no question...
but you could've been
a little more contrite.
- You know, played the game.
- I'm trying.
How about an eight?
Would an eight work here?
No. And I'm not
talking about Sudoku.
You know, the game, life.
Playing well with others. You
seem to have a problem with that.
How about a six?
Would a six work here?
Your evasiveness tells
me I'm onto something.
Did your dad hit you
when you were a kid?
What?
Parental abuse.
It's a common root of authority
and ego problems in adulthood.
Thank you, Dr. Freud.
I'm more of a Jungian.
You have no idea
what I'm talking about.
No, I never watched Star Trek.
And you're starting
to freak me out, kid.
Yeah, I have that
effect on people.
I'm in college now at U of C.
When I raise my hand to ask a
question, the whole class stares.
That must be weird, huh?
Yeah, I kind of stick
out at frat parties.
Yeah, well...
I'm having troubles these days
trying to figure out where I fit in.
And you were right
about me and my dad.
If you wanna impress those
stuck-up ICU types, three words:
Fazio-Londe disease.
It's very rare.
Who knows how long it'll
take them to figure it out?
Is that what you think you have?
I don't think, I know.
Well, when you were admitted,
why didn't your mother tell them?
Well, she doesn't know.
I haven't told her.
That's not good enough. I need
that ultrasound now, not in 45 minutes.
Pratt, your alter cocker in 3
is kvetching about his kishke.
- What?
- It's the language of your people.
You want to get in
on a detached retina?
I have to go back to Waiting.
Mussolini was not happy
to see me out of my cage.
- Doctor, can I talk to you?
- Sure.
Carlos doesn't wanna
have the operation.
Why not?
Well, he was at
the deli that night.
- I don't need to hear this.
- Please.
- I don't wanna hear it.
- He was there to buy milk.
Please, you have
to listen. Please.
Okay.
That night in the deli,
two guys came in...
and they started making
trouble and pulled out guns.
Carlos told you this?
He tried to stop them, okay?
But they just started shooting.
And he ran so fast, he didn't even
realize he was hurt until he got home.
Why didn't you call the police
when you saw he was shot?
Well, Carlos wanted
to, but I didn't let him.
Why?
The guys who did this, they
are from our neighborhood, okay?
They know who we are.
They know where we live.
Well, that bullet is lodged in his
spine, and surgery really is the only...
He won't do it.
Some more fluid in
Morison's, but no hematoma.
Renal anatomy's intact.
- What of the fact she's peeing blood?
- Probably just parenchymal contusions.
If the urine doesn't clear in an hour,
do an IVP like Dr. Moretti suggested.
She's good.
I'll be back in 15 minutes
to repeat the scan.
I knew you'd find a way.
- He was 16, a child!
- Hey, hey, hey.
I have your e-mails,
photos. You're going to jail.
- I know this is hard, but you can't...
- She molested my son.
- You've got to leave.
- This is your fault.
He's dead because of you.
- What? JOANNA:
You saw the blood.
He was rushing me here.
That's why we crashed.
Oh, no.
You're gonna have to stop
hating me. I am having his baby.
- Okay, okay, okay.
- What?
Okay, come on. Come on,
you have to leave. I'm sorry.
If they take the bullet, cops
will place me at the scene.
Tell them what happened.
They won't believe me.
All they see is another spic.
Hopefully, the owner will come out
of his coma and back up your story.
If he doesn't, then
Carlos will go to jail.
I got a good job, Elena, the baby.
I mean, I don't wanna lose them.
Look, just get a lawyer...
The legal system doesn't
work for guys like me.
Do you understand that
you could be paralyzed?
I'll take my chances.
They talked to Carlos. Now
they wanna speak to the surgeon.
- He won't consent to the débridement?
- He's convinced he's screwed.
And he understands the risks?
It's his right to refuse. Detectives.
The DA just got off
the phone with a judge...
who's issuing a court order
compelling Carlos Vega to have surgery.
- What?
- It'll be here within the hour.
The state can't dictate treatment.
- It just did.
- The bullet will tell us if he's guilty.
- It doesn't matter if he's guilty.
This patient has rights.
We're not going to do it.
- It's not up to you.
- Really? What's next?
Forced sterilizations?
Mandated amputations?
Abby, maybe it's for the
best. Carlos needs the surgery.
These guys are only
trying to do their job.
We'll get an O.R. ready.
Thanks, doc.
You're kidding me.
- I don't like it, but it's done.
- He has the right to refuse.
If we leave the bullet in,
he ends up in a wheelchair.
Not immediately.
We can start him on IV
antibiotics and then talk to Legal...
Very high-minded, but naive.
If we refuse, they'll get
some other hospital to do it.
- You don't know that.
- As a matter of fact, I do.
Since a tricky spinal procedure
is inevitable, I'd rather I do it...
- How did this become about you?
- Let it go.
- You're not even gonna try.
- This case is no longer your concern.
Type and cross four
units and send him up.
- It's called Fazio-Londe syndrome.
- That's incredibly rare.
Yeah, only 30-something
cases in the literature.
It's a progressive
motor disorder.
Pneumonia is from decreased function
of the ninth and tenth cranial nerves.
I did an EMG, MRI. It all fits.
You need to confirm
this with a muscle biopsy.
- Well, Neuro's on it this afternoon.
- Way to be proactive, Dr. Gates.
- We'll round again at 3.
- Bye.
- So it worked.
- Yeah, it worked.
What I wanna know is,
how did you figure this out?
At first it felt like a
lump in my throat.
Then it got to where solid
food made me throw up.
You didn't go to a doctor?
I convinced a grad
student in neurophysiology...
to do a muscle biopsy on the DL.
Confirmed what I already knew.
But your mom, you
didn't tell your mother?
What's the use in telling her
before she absolutely has to know?
Because she's your mother.
She wants to help you. She
wants to take care of you.
This news is pretty
much gonna ruin her life.
She'll spend everything she
has trying to keep me alive...
which is silly, because this
disease is invariably fatal.
Well, there must be some sort
of experimental treatments, right?
Trials?
Yeah.
Well, you know,
you have to tell her.
You have to tell her.
You know that, right?
Would you like me to be there?
It's okay.
I'll tell her tonight.
Did the doctor
tell you anything?
- Okay, what happened here?
- Killer bit me.
- What kind of dog is Killer?
- He's not a dog, he's a gerbil.
Wow. That's a good name for him.
Let's just clean him up,
give him some antibiotics.
And, ma'am, what
brings you here today?
I'm here for the air.
County air is very therapeutic.
Okay, so you don't wanna
see a doctor or anything?
You're just here to...
- Breathe.
- Right. Knock yourself out.
Uh, Chuny, the guy in the sunglasses
has been in the same position like all day.
Another drunk sleeping it off.
Hey, sir?
Sir?
Sir? Please don't
be dead. Sir? Hey.
I need a gurney over here, now.
So the drunk isn't drunk,
he's bleeding into his head.
- Yes, we know that. Thank you.
- Systolic's 182.
All right, bolus 50 of mannitol,
20 per kilo of Dilantin. Tube.
It's a classic example
of availability bias.
I have no idea what that means,
but I'm sure you're about to tell us.
The waiting area's full of
drunk homeless people...
- so that's what Chuny saw.
- I feel bad enough, all right?
All right, I'm in.
Toss me the bag.
- Call Respiratory for a vent.
- Nice pickup anyway.
Stabilize him and get
back into the waiting room.
Clearly, we need you out there.
Call CT, let them know we're on our
way, and get Neurosurge down here.
There's no ozone in the
Tropics. Our skin will melt off.
Okay, enough.
You don't wanna go.
- I'll go without you.
- Without me?
- It's a once-in-a-lifetime opportunity.
- But I'll worry.
I'll miss you, and I
want us to be together.
- It's only for six months.
- Hope.
Morris.
Did you know your gal Hope there
descends from a tribe of Gypsy whores?
You obviously don't have
enough work to do here.
- Has anyone seen Sam?
- She's still in with the MVC mom.
We're going to Ike's early to
premedicate before speed dating.
- Wow. I could use a drink.
- I'll bring some extra Manischewitz.
Yeah, we know how your
tribe loves the fruit of the vine.
Will you knock it off already?
You know, you guys can
be a real pain in the tokhes.
Hey. Any news yet?
- No. It's been over two hours.
- Well, Carlos is gonna be all right.
They shouldn't have forced him
to have an operation. It isn't right.
Yeah.
I know you tried to
fight this. Thank you.
- Hey, the surgery went well.
- Oh, thank God.
- He has full function of his extremities.
- Well, that's good.
- I can take you to him if you'd like.
- Yes.
Abby, come walk with us.
- Did you get the bullet out?
- The strangest thing happened.
I removed the bullet,
placed it on a stand.
There was a bleeder, things got
hectic, stand got knocked over...
and the bullet
somehow went missing.
Went missing?
Cops have been
looking for it for an hour.
It just sort of vanished.
Oh.
- Well, can I go in?
- Yeah, absolutely.
Thank you.
- Vanished?
- Yeah. Weird, right?
Kidneys look good, and the
blood is clearing from your urine.
- So I don't need surgery?
- Doesn't look that way.
And the baby's gonna be okay?
No CT, no radiation.
Everything should be fine.
Thank you, doctors, so much.
We'll get you upstairs as
soon as the bed's ready.
- Hey, Dr. Moretti.
- Kevin.
All right, I just wanted to say that
the ultrasound was a good idea...
and it's a good thing that
we did it. So, you know.
- You're welcome.
- All right.
Maybe you'll think twice before
selling me out to Anspaugh...
and trying to steal my job.
- I wasn't trying to steal...
- Don't lie.
It belittles us both.
Um, we're gonna get
an ETA on your bed.
You think I'm some kind of
terrible person, don't you?
- He was a kid. You were his teacher.
- I'm only nine years older.
A few years from now,
no one would care.
But now they do.
I just can't believe he's gone.
Ma'am, you need some help.
His mom showed up at
my house this morning...
told me to stay
away from her son.
- You can't really blame her.
- It got heated. We had a fight.
I hit my head, and she ran
off. That's when I called Casey.
If only she had left us alone.
We were going
through a rough time.
He'd shut himself off.
Stayed in his room.
Things were getting better.
He was starting
to talk to me again.
I don't understand why
this is taking so long.
I thought my case for
custody was as strong as...
Because that's what you said.
Well, that's not good enough.
Sorry. I know you filed the
papers. You're doing all you can.
I gotta go. Thanks.
- You didn't have to do that.
- Yes, I did. Dr. Gates.
I know. Joshua's
been raving about you.
I'm Serena, his mom.
- He's a great kid.
- Yep. A handful.
Made me go to the library to pick
up some books he'd put on hold.
So has he talked
about what's going on?
Yeah. It sounds
pretty straightforward.
Straightforward?
I don't mean to sound cavalier about
pneumonia, but he's much better today.
I'm really relieved.
Excuse me, I have to fill out
some insurance thing for the clerk.
Okay, nice to meet you.
And don't let my kid run the place.
He's got that kind of personality.
I'll try to keep him in check.
You didn't tell her.
I started to, but I couldn't.
Joshua, she has to know.
So when she comes back later,
you and I will tell her together, okay?
I just... I can't see the look on her
face when she realizes I'm gonna die.
You do it.
I'm not really sure
I'm in the mood for this.
- You're just nervous.
- No, it's not that.
Come on, Sam, shake it
off. This is gonna be fun.
Come on.
Ladies, just let me say...
that we are the hottest
girls up in this place.
- Wow, a lot of people signed up for this.
- It's a numbers game, Sam.
And I like the odds.
You know, wouldn't it be great if
tonight we all met our soul mates?
Three cosmos, please.
I would just be happy to meet a
nice guy and go on a nice date.
- We're happy you came with us tonight.
- It's about time.
- I know, I gotta get out there.
- Girl, life is too damn short.
- Yes, it is.
- Yeah, I will drink to that.
- A toast. To meeting the nice guys.
- To falling in love.
To sex without batteries.
Come on, come on, come on now.
- That's it.
- I'm gonna go get me some.
Let's go.
I was thinking maybe you should
stay at our place until you get better.
- Oh, no. I can't do that.
- Well, at least while Luka's out of town.
- I don't want to impose.
- Hey, hold that elevator. Going down.
And I wouldn't want you to think
you'd have to wait on me hand and foot.
Believe me, that'll
never happen.
- Come on, it'll be fun. You, me and Joe.
- You already have a lot on your plate.
Neela, your taxi's out
front. Take care of yourself.
- Thanks, Frank.
- Yeah, but it's so quiet with Luka away.
And besides, I could
use some free babysitting.
I guess Joe needs to get
to know his Auntie Neela.
- Yeah.
- But isn't Luka coming home soon?
I hope so, but I don't know.
His trip is taking
longer than we thought.
It's gotta be hard for
him without you and Joe.
Yeah, I mean, he misses us...
but you know, on some level, I
think he's really happy in Croatia.
You know, he's comfortable
there. I can hear it in his voice.
- What do you think?
- Thank you. I'd love to stay.
Okay, great. Joe's
nanny will let you in.
There's Thai food in the
fridge. I'll be home in a while.
- Brilliant. I'll see you then.
- Okay, bye.
That waiting room
looks like a ghost town.
- You did a great job today.
- Thank you. And it was such a pleasure.
Well, I'm so glad you enjoyed it,
because you'll be doing it again tomorrow.
Good night, Abby.
Dr. Lockhart, you got a minute?
It's an all-day bridge
tournament. You'll be bored.
- Teach me to play.
- I already have a partner.
- Yeah, but who's better-looking?
- It's a tossup.
He is 78, very distinguished,
and he knows what a shallot is.
- Well, what do you call that thing?
- It's an onion.
- Aren't they the same?
- No.
- Morris.
- Hey.
Look, now I can "challah"
at you all through dinner.
- Get it?
- Hi.
- Where's Hope?
- Oh, she's not coming. She's sick.
- Oh, that's too bad.
- Sick of me.
- What?
- I'm sorry.
Maybe I should go. I don't
wanna burden you with this.
- Oh, no, no, don't be silly. Stay.
- Okay.
But I've completely
lost my appetite, though.
I built a time
machine in my garage.
I really plan on sticking
with women this time.
What's the oldest guy
you've ever balled?
I hear you'd never date a cop.
How did...?
I am gonna kill Chuny and Dawn.
I like the new look.
Thanks.
So, what's your beef
with Chicago's finest?
Well, it's just, in my line of work, I
see you guys get hurt, shot and killed.
So you'd worry about me.
Yeah, I guess I would.
- I'd worry about you too.
- Really?
I see the people that
come into County.
The drunks, the drug seekers.
It's a pretty dangerous place.
On second thought, maybe
I shouldn't date a nurse.
You like Italian food?
- I love it.
- I know this great place over on State.
Hey, you're holding
everybody up. Time to go.
Yes, it is.
I think it's great that she wants to
go do a medical mission in Caracas...
I really do.
But I have a job,
okay? I have a life here.
- Do you have any more of this cake left?
- She'll be back before you know it.
I can't help but think that this trip
is an elaborate excuse to break up.
Have you ever considered
that it's not about you?
I mean, the long-distance
thing never ends well, does it?
Morris, you're not listening.
This isn't about your relationship.
It's about Hope and her doing
something that's important to her.
- I mean, you gotta respect that.
- I do, I do.
But living in a tent city without
running water or a toilet?
- That's not my idea of fun.
- All right, I get it, it's not your thing.
- That's okay.
- I know, but...
Look, just give her
some breathing room.
Hope is smart and independent...
and that's the reason why you
like her in the first place, right?
But what if she meets somebody
else? Some hunky humanitarian type?
You're just gonna
have to trust her.
Hey, Lucien. Hey.
The police found a large
sum of money and a gun...
in Carlos and Elena's apartment.
A lot of people have guns.
Yeah, $1830, the exact
amount stolen from the minimart.
You'd think after years of this,
you'd start to get a handle on people.
The reality is, everybody lies and
manipulates to get what they want.
- I believed them too.
- Everybody.
It's sad. Okay,
I'll call the police...
let them know somebody
found their bullet.
It was lodged into a crevice
in the anesthesia cart.
Strangest thing. Night, Abby.
Good night.
He looks like a little
boy when he sleeps.
He's a cool kid.
The antibiotics seem to be working.
You think he'll be coming home soon?
Serena, there's
something I need to tell you.
What?
Joshua has a
neuromuscular disease.
- What?
- It affects the nerves in the brain...