Previously, on
"New Amsterdam"...
As your new chair,
I will restore dignity
to this department
by throwing away
every last thing
that Dr. Kapoor
has ever touched.
Chance, you are trying
to fill a void in you,
but the way you're trying
to fill it, it's not real.
I'm transferring you
to another therapist
at another hospital.
Dr. Frome, no!
There's this, uh,
record store in East Village.
Want to go Saturday
and maybe grab dinner after?
I'm flattered, but...
Oh.
Oh, God.
Ah!
Leyla?
What happened?
Oh, okay.
Uh, how bad's the pain
from one to ten?
Is that a smile?
Are you smiling?
I passed
the medical board exam.
What?
I can train
in the U.S. now.
You took the boards?
But how?
You gave me
a bed at the hospital
and then this.
I didn't have to worry
about surviving.
I could study.
Leyla, that's amazing.
I'm so happy for you.
I...
I should get some ice for this.
Uh...
Lauren, because of you,
I can be a doctor again.
Uh...
I'm so sorry.
Yeah, no, no.
No, it was, uh, fine.
Um, totally fine.
Actually, I just remembered
I've got to get to work early.
Okay, uh, well, look,
I will see you later, okay?
Oh, good. You're up.
Chop, chop,
you'll be late for work.
Chop, chop, I'm working?
Yes, indeed,
because I know someone
who knows someone
who pulled some strings
and got you a job at...
New Amsterdam.
I don't want to work
at New Amsterdam.
Yeah, that feeling
usually goes away by lunch.
I'm a child.
Isn't it illegal
to make a child work?
Well, it's no more illegal
than letting her quit school.
I'll get dressed.
Good.
Think, um,
public hospital chic.
Jane Munsee,
history professor.
Her students brought
her in with a massive DVT.
How's her recovery?
It would go a lot better
if she weren't demanding
- to be discharged.
- Uh, why exactly?
Something
about imperialist crimes
against Native Americans.
Oh, that.
Professor Munsee,
I am Max Goodwin,
the Medical Director.
Nice to meet you.
Please sign this so I can go.
Well, uh, the thing is
you have a pretty sizeable
blood clot in your leg
and standing or walking
or moving of any kind
could cause that blood clot
to break free
and travel to your lungs,
and we need you
on a heparin drip now
and here at New Amsterdam.
Those two words,
Doctor, are exactly why
I need to leave.
New Amsterdam?
You know what New Amsterdam
means to me?
Death, lies,
the erasure of my people.
I see.
You mean when the
Dutch colonized Manhattan.
Before this land
was New Amsterdam,
It was Lenapehoking...
the home of the Lenape people,
my ancestors.
We were here
long before the Dutch.
As long as the name
New Amsterdam
is emblazoned on this building,
you're accepting,
even celebrating
the destruction
of indigenous lives.
Okay.
I hear you.
You don't want to stay here,
but right now
you have a ticking time bomb
in your veins.
You need this heparin drip,
or you could die.
So tell you what,
if you think you
can make up for 400 years
of crimes
against Native Americans,
I'll stay here
at New Amsterdam.
*NEW AMSTERDAM (2018)*
Season 03  Episode 10
Episode Title: "Radical"
Aired on: May 04, 2021
Give me your phone.
Girl, where I'm from,
jacking a phone
gets people got.
A, I'm not people,
just a colleague here
to edify your day.
So...
give me your phone.
B.
Uh, C, I made you...
A playlist.
Text me when you
get to track five.
- Dr. Frome?
- Talk to you soon.
- Do you have a minute?
- Yeah, of course.
I need to talk to you
about the new chair
of neurology.
Dr. Lucille... Agnes,
oh, my gosh, what a coup.
- How did you get her to join us?
- That's the thing.
Is there any way
that she could maybe unjoin us?
Oh, that's just a formality.
Don't worry about that.
The board officially
approves her tomorrow.
It's gonna be gravy, okay?
And I got to tell you...
I didn't think anybody
could do better than Vijay,
but you nailed it.
I'm thinking
maybe I didn't... nail it.
You nailed it. Trust...
Oh, my gosh.
Hi, Dr. Romy Lucille, hi.
I'm honored.
It's, uh...
You don't know who I am.
I'm sorry.
I'm Dr. Iggy Frome,
chair of behavioral health.
Oh, it's a pleasure
to meet you.
Yeah, likewise, and, uh,
let me just say,
I'm really looking forward
to working with you.
Dr. Kapoor and I...
We had a number
of collaborations
going on here,
and I just can't wait
to pick your brains about them.
Oh, uh, fabulous.
But, uh, if you'll excuse me,
patients call.
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, yeah, yeah,
get in there, go.
Sorry.
Look at you two.
Nice to meet you.
Have a great day.
Can you please make sure
I'm never alone
with that weirdo?
His breathing
was bad last night
and even worse this morning.
He's a lymphoma survivor,
an asthmatic,
but he's never been this bad.
Well, his COVID test
was negative.
Niall, is the oxygen helping?
I'm pretty sure
that's your call.
He never takes
anything seriously.
That's why she loves me.
Do you know how he got these
scratches on his hands?
Oh.
We went mushroom foraging
yesterday.
I'm gonna get my colleague
to take a look at him.
Is that okay?
Shh, you're gonna be okay.
Hey, uh, I got a patient
in the procedure room...
Niall Fincannon.
He's got some pretty
serious lung issues.
Lymphoma survivor.
Girlfriend brought him in.
What did his chest X-ray say?
I'm looking
for Niall Fincannon.
Uh, Niall's my patient.
How can I help?
I'm his boyfriend.
Dr. Reynolds
was just heading over there.
He can show you the way.
Follow me.
Michael.
Hey, baby.
Uh, okay, that's great.
I bet you're all wondering why
I have called this
emergency session.
That's okay.
Don't worry about it.
Particularly because you
don't have that authority.
Great, thank you
for joining us, Karen.
So this morning
I was challenged
to reckon
with this hospital's past,
to do something about
the crimes that were committed
on this very ground.
Lindsey, did you know
that as Americans,
most of us live our lives
on land that was taken
by brutal imperialistic
violence.
I live in Hoboken.
Yeah, so I know there's
not a lot that we can do
about our past,
but there is something
that we can do
about our present.
We can honor the original
people of Manhattan,
the original stewards
of this land
that we are currently
standing on...
The Lenape people.
Max, what in God's name
are you talking about?
We're changing the name
of this hospital.
Say goodbye to New Amsterdam
and welcome...
to Lenapehoking.
Well, the good news
is that it's pronounced
exactly like it's spelled.
I sincerely apologize
for wasting your time.
This meeting's adjourned.
No, not adjourned.
Uh, Evan, Evan, did you know
that New York
has a larger Native American
population
- than any other city in America?
- No.
No, no, so just imagine
for a second
what it must feel like for our
Native American patients.
I have a patient
right now upstairs who is ready
to walk out these doors and die
because of that name,
because it says to her that
her history doesn't matter,
that she doesn't matter, but...
Evan, just listen.
A simple name change
could reckon with our past,
rectify our present,
and cost us
practically nothing.
Aside from decades
of carefully crafted
branding efforts
and multimillion-dollar
design campaigns,
New Amsterdam has been
here for almost 300 years,
and it will be around
for another 300.
The name stays.
Meeting adjourned.
Meeting's
not adjourned, Karen.
We're gonna un-adjourn, guys.
We're re-adjourning,
so everybody go ahead
and adjourn around the table.
Back me up.
I need a little help.
I'm all alone here.
People who try to shame
themselves into losing weight
are actually acting in direct
conflict with their goal.
Harsh self-criticism triggers
a flood of stress hormones,
like cortisol and adrenaline,
that create anxiety
and can lead
to emotional eating.
You get far better results
with regular exercise,
a nutritious diet,
and self-care.
You know what I mean?
Yeah, I do know
what you mean.
Although I had
to go to school for 13 years
to learn about it, but I do
know what you mean.
Saffy, look at you.
Look at this.
You don't even need me
on this journey.
No, I don't.
What I need is your signature.
My signature...
for gastric bypass surgery?
Yep.
I'm a little lost here.
What about everything
you just said?
It's all true, I guess.
It just doesn't work for me.
Dr. Frome...
look at me.
I-I am.
Saffy, I am looking at you.
I'm looking right at you,
and I see
an incredibly impressive,
beautiful young woman.
That's what I see.
Gastric bypass surgery...
I get the allure,
but it is not always effective.
It can be dangerous.
So I say we recommit.
We stick with the plan.
- Six more months of exercise...
- Come on!
And healthy eating.
Saffy, that's how we do this.
Dr. Frome...
I'm genetically predetermined
to look this way.
But I don't want to.
I assume that you need
my signature on this
because your parent
refuses to sign it?
She refuses.
Yeah, that's because
she loves you
and she wants you
to be healthy.
No, my mother
doesn't care what I eat.
She wants me to be fat.
He's a lymphoma survivor,
but there's no lymphadenopathy
on his chest X-ray.
Uh, Michael mentioned
that on their morning run,
Niall had to stop
because of chest pain.
So cardiac ischemia?
Troponins are flat.
Oh, I also noticed that Niall
had scratches on his hands.
Zara said the went mushroom
foraging yesterday.
- Amanita mushroom poisoning?
- You think?
It's an odd presentation,
but that explains everything.
I'll get him started
on treatment.
Uh, can I help you?
My boyfriend was brought in.
- Niall?
- How'd you know?
Follow me.
Hi, hi.
He's gonna need
a bigger room.
Don't be such a square.
Right, your job, my dear,
is to input these records
into the online database...
All of them.
This is from 1998.
Who would ever need this?
I'm glad you asked.
It's quite interesting,
actually.
Extending the chronological
span of our records
creates a researchable X axis
of diagnoses across time...
- Did I die?
- Sorry?
Am I in some kind
of weird, boring hell?
A question working adults
grapple with every day.
Uh, Helen, uh...
Oh, hi.
Okay.
I just thought you
should know that the board
is blocking my attempts
to change New Amsterdam's name
- to Lenapehoking.
- Shocking.
I know, I think
I'm saying it right.
It's like "hawk."
The Lenape-hawk-ing.
Is this is guy
you were dating?
Mina, that is completely
inappropriate.
Oh, no, that's fine,
because we're not dating,
so, you know...
I mean, we never dated.
We just, uh,
have spent time together.
We spend time together
from time to time,
you know, as people do.
And I think that other
people get ideas,
- and they talk...
- Max.
Yeah, shut up.
Idiot, sorry.
Real quick...
Did you say "were dating"?
Does that mean you and Cassian
are not dating now?
- Are you...?
- You might be right.
- This may actually be hell.
- Nice meeting you.
Let me rewind.
I need your help.
If I can change
this hospital's name,
then I can save
my patient's life.
Max, I don't know what this
is about,
and I don't want to ask,
but if you really want
to change the hospital's name,
you're gonna need
a lot more support than me.
Justice for Lenape!
Justice!
- This is our land!
- You're on stolen land!
Put that camera away.
- Who's in charge here?
- Hot white guy.
Karen, grab a Sharpie
and some cardboard.
- What the hell is going on?
- Well, first off, it's safe.
Everybody has been tested.
And, secondly, it looks like
we are renaming New Amsterdam.
- These people are trespassing.
- Get them out of here.
- Sorry, I can't do that.
- Why the hell not?
Because this is their land
and we're the ones trespassing.
How about a plaque
commemorating
the Lenape people?
Look around, Karen.
This protest is filled
with Native Americans,
all of whom are residents
of this city.
They deserve to feel at home
in their city's hospital,
and so does my patient.
Well, fine, a statue.
We'll take a wing.
Oh, look, here come
the TV cameras.
Damn it, Max.
You can rename this lobby.
And that's my final offer.
That's very generous of you.
You've just did a good thing.
Don't act so surprised.
You're amazing.
Thank you all for coming.
Excuse me.
Helen!
Romy.
We'll be really quick.
Dr. Kao and I wanted
to fill you in
on some departmental changes.
- Is that right?
- Mm-hmm.
As you know,
our departments have
a lot of overlaps.
Yes, our support staff,
for one.
Oh, exactly.
And I plan on downsizing
the support staff
and uncoupling our budgets.
Uncoupling oncology
and urology?
We share almost all
of our equipment.
Dr. Sharpe's right.
Well, we're still share
everything, Helen.
This is just on paper.
Okay, then,
I look forward to seeing it.
And I look forward
to seeing more of you.
If we uncouple out budgets
but downsize support staff,
that means we get the savings
on staff,
but oncology still foots
the bill on equipment.
You're quick.
Oh, and maybe
don't contradict me
when I'm talking
to the other doctors, okay?
Gastric bypass surgery?
Saffy!
And you went behind my back?
And before you start,
our numbers are stellar...
Cholesterol, blood sugar,
all of it.
And do you tell him about
the booty Zumba classes
I drive you to twice a week?
It's obviously not working.
Ms. Zaree,
Saffy says that she thinks
you want her to stay fat.
Does that sound right to you?
Is that what you said?
I spent years
starving myself...
hating myself.
And I raised Saffy to know
that healthy and beautiful
can look a lot
of different ways.
But here she is...
Falling right into
that same trap.
You're going
to sign the form, right?
Saffy...
I, uh...
I just... I can't help but wonder
if by signing off
on the surgery,
I'm not just making the world a
harder place for kids like you,
for kids like me,
like your mom.
She's here for you.
My dad, when I was your age,
he taught me to hate my body.
I was ashamed of it.
He weighed me every day.
Why are we talking about you?
You're the therapist here.
It's not my problem you're fat.
Saffy! You will not talk
like that in this office.
And my mother's
not supportive.
She just wants me
to look like her...
to make her feel like
being fat is okay.
Being fat is okay.
Then why are you trying
to lose weight?
We are not...
We're not here
to talk about me, Saffy.
We're talking about you.
Well, I am talking about me,
and you're not listening.
♪ Mm, L.A.
♪ Proved too much
for the man ♪
♪ Too much for the man
♪ He couldn't make it
Blasting music in the E.D.
is a really great idea.
Ease of communication
just doesn't matter here.
Sorry.
Hey, what do you think
this song is really saying?
I think the title
gets us most of the way there.
Yeah, but
could it be something else?
Like... like a metaphor?
In other news,
Niall is now on treatment
for Amanita mushroom poisoning,
and so far, so good.
I'm gonna go give
his quad the update.
Do you think you could be
in one of those, uh,
polyamorous relationships?
Okay.
You are
in a really weird space,
and I like it on you.
Seriously, could you?
I think the jury
is still out on me
and relationships in general.
You?
There is no way
that I could share my person
with someone else.
And what makes a person yours
to share anyway?
I don't know.
It just seems wrong to me,
like, morally.
Morally, okay.
Not every relationship has
to look like yours and Evie's.
Oh, I think it's better
if they don't.
It's hard to find a person,
period...
let alone share them.
Yeah.
Especially people our age,
you know?
With all this...
history.
History isn't always
a bad thing.
- What's happening?
- O-2 sats are dropping.
All right,
we need to intubate.
Which one of you
is his medical proxy?
- Uh...
- Um...
Okay, I need
to do a lung biopsy now.
Who can legally
sign off on that?
His wife.
- He's married?
- To someone else?
Don't bring Tweetie
into this.
Tweetie?
Maggie. She left him when he
came out to her as bi.
- She broke his heart.
- They haven't spoken in years.
Listen to me... Niall could die
if we don't figure out
what's really happening,
all right?
Now, whose got
the wife's number?
It is amazing
what a group of students
and protesters
and an impending
TV spectacle can do.
Professor Munsee,
we are naming the lobby
for the Lenape people.
The Lenape legacy will live on.
Hold it.
Hold it?
The Lenape legacy?
The Lenape are not extinct,
Dr. Goodwin,
nor do we intend to be.
Does your sign improve
Native American
access to healthcare?
Does it address
tribal health disparities?
This hospital
has a long way to go
to earn the trust
of patients like me.
Professor Munsee...
please...
Just let me treat
the clot in your leg.
That's the only thing I know
for certain I can fix.
So rarely does someone
in a position of power
try to make change.
So why would
I let you stop now?
Because you could die
while I'm trying.
Dying for change...
I couldn't think
of a better legacy.
Uh, Lauren,
sorry to interrupt.
I have a potentially loaded
and inappropriate
question for you.
Should I leave?
No, it's fine. He knows.
- He does?
- I do?
Yes,
Floyd and I used to hook up,
but we have no problem
working together,
and, in fact, our relationship
has never been better.
That's not, uh...
Anyway, I have a patient
upstairs right now
that I think would like
to be treated
by a Native American doctor,
but I'm having some trouble
tracking one down.
- "Tracking one down"?
- No, see? So many landmines.
I don't know how to ask
if someone
is Native American or not.
Yeah, you absolutely
shouldn't.
Yeah, don't do that.
Yeah, but it would...
I'm trying to save
my patient's life.
She won't let me put her
on a heparin drip,
but the more I think about it,
the more I realize she's right.
- Why should she trust me?
- Because you're a doctor.
American doctors
and Native American patients,
not the easiest history,
but if I can find
someone to convince her
to get on that drip,
then I can keep her alive.
Okay, so what
do you need me for?
Because I may have heard
a long time ago a little rumor
that you were maybe
a quarter something.
"Shmative Shmishmerican."
No way this ends well
for you.
Wrong kind of Indian,
but I did do ayahuasca once.
Does that count?
Nope.
Seriously?
Nope, but some people
think I look like Cher.
I'm Jewish.
Mazel tov.
You knew about this,
didn't you?
Oh, boy.
Your new rock star chair
has orchestrated
a little reorg that's
gonna suck the funding
out of oncology
and stick us with the bill
for operational costs.
Dr. Sharpe,
I wasn't in on this, I promise.
But I know she's been
sucking money
out of other departments
and out of patients
who don't have much to give,
and I know that's
not what we do here.
Agnes, you need
to get rid of her
before she systematically
dismantles
every other department
in this hospital.
I agree,
but the board loves her.
Can't you fire her?
- You're deputy medical director.
- Not anymore.
I never should
have hired her.
Wait, you hired her?
Were you even
on the search committee?
No.
No, I wasn't.
Maggie McGuire?
- Hi, I'm Dr. Reynolds.
- How is he?
Well, Niall's
lung biopsy shows
interstitial pneumonitis,
and we're not sure
what's causing it,
but his lungs are enflamed,
and they're getting worse
by the second.
We'd love to be a part
of your private conversation
since the three
of us are still actually
in a relationship with him.
Okay, I'm sorry,
but legally speaking,
Maggie is the only person here
who has a say in Niall's...
It's pretty insulting
for you cut us out like this,
when we're the ones
who've been here all day
worrying about him.
All right, I'm gonna have to
ask you all to leave.
Dr. Reynolds,
they can stay.
I know none of you
think much of me,
and I still don't understand
this relationship of yours.
But I'm here now...
Because I still love him.
Maggie, your hand.
African Greys...
My parrots.
- You have parrots?
- Yes.
Quite a few.
I'm sorry I yelled at you,
Dr. Frome...
and called you fat
in a negative way.
I shouldn't have done that.
Apology accepted.
And I feel like
I should apologize
because I brought my issue
into the discussion,
and that wasn't okay.
Apology accepted.
And I'm going to go ahead
and let Saffy
go through
with the gastric bypass.
I mean, what...
Are we sure that's a good idea?
I've chosen
to love my body as it is,
but I can't impose
that choice on Saffy.
I need to respect
her right to determine
what happens to her body.
Yeah, well,
look, look, you know,
there are a lot of steps
that we can take
before we just jump
into a drastic surgery.
- You mean like therapy?
- Yeah, exactly like therapy.
Saffy is young.
We have a really good shot
at getting you somewhere
great mentally and physically.
You think therapy
is gonna make me happy?
My mom thinks radical
self-acceptance is the answer,
and isn't surgery
an answer, too?
It's a risky one...
one that could be a mistake,
a mistake
that you cannot take back.
Well...
It's Saffy's mistake to make,
Dr. Frome.
Well, guys, guys, I'm, uh...
I'm not used to my sessions
ending like this. Saffy...
You mean with your
suggestions being ignored?
Yeah, yeah, exactly.
You know, I feel like I've...
I did a disservice
to you somewhere along the way.
I hijacked your issue,
I totally made it about myself,
and, um, I'm doing
that right now, aren't I?
Yeah.
I just feel like I failed...
I failed you.
Sometimes you just
have to own it.
I whiffed it.
You whiffed it.
Yeah.
Dr. Goodwin,
how's Professor Jane doing?
Still refusing treatment.
Nothing I've tried
has changed her mind.
- Sounds about right.
- Professor Jane's relentless.
I even tried reaching out
to Native American personnel
- here at the hospital.
- And how did that go?
Well, we don't have any
Native American personnel
- here at the hospital.
- And you're surprised by this?
To be honest, Doc,
I've never seen
a Native doctor either.
Back in high school,
I told my guidance counselor
I was interested
in medical school.
He handed me a flyer
for landscape design.
Of course he did.
And even if med school
felt like an option,
even if you did get in,
it's expensive, you know.
Who's gonna ask their family
to go into more debt?
Cool sign, though.
Uh, it's Jane.
O sat's below 80,
and her heart rate's rising.
- Clot's moved to her lungs...
- We need to get her
to the operating room
right now.
Wait, wait.
You're going
to save her, right?
She was ready
to die for this.
If you don't save her,
you'll fail us again.
Why are you standing there?
I need to tell you something.
I really looked up to you,
but if modernizing
means milking patients
for all they're worth,
rushing them out of consults
and into admissions,
and if it means fleecing
other departments
out of their budgets...
then I'm not sure
you belong here.
And Dr. Kapoor
may have been old-fashioned,
but his methods are not a joke.
They were hopeful
and compassionate,
whereas yours are heartless,
cold, and manipulative.
All right, get to the point.
You're fired.
That's kind of funny.
I didn't know you were funny.
No.
I'm not funny.
You're fired.
I'm firing you.
Well, I'm sorry, Agnes,
but I don't think
you have the authority.
Well, that's the thing.
I didn't have the authority
to hire you either
or even recommend you
to the board,
which means that I am still
the interim chair of neurology,
and as the interim chair
of neurology,
I am terminating
your interim employment.
You can leave your keys
and I.D. badge
with security on your way out.
Oh.
How are you feeling?
Yeah.
Fantastic.
Thanks.
You have psittacosis,
Niall...
also known as parrot fever.
Maggie.
Maggie, indeed.
Oh, God.
They won't be happy.
And we haven't even done
anything, Maggie and me.
Just talked.
Well...
I thought polyamory
was all about freedom...
letting people be themselves.
You know, I spent years
putting labels on myself,
monogamous, polyamorous,
bisexual, but now...
I want those three
beautiful beings out there...
And I want Maggie.
I can't apologize for that,
but I also can't find
a label for it.
And you feel like
you need a label
to explain what you want?
It's terrifying
to ask for something
when you can't put
a name to it,
but there you go.
I'm a greedy bastard.
I want them all.
I love them all.
Just don't know
what to tell them.
I think you tell them that.
- Hi.
- How are you feeling?
- Okay.
- Hi, baby.
- Hey.
Hi, Professor Jane.
Why am I still here?
That blood clot
in your leg broke free
and traveled to your lungs.
We had to do
a pulmonary artery embolectomy
to get it out.
It was clear to me,
to all of us,
that your life
mattered more than your death.
You really don't listen,
do you?
400 years,
they mean nothing to you?
I can't make up
for what this country did
to you and your family,
but after listening
to your students...
I think I may have found
a way forward.
Have you heard
of the Jane Munsee
Medical Pathways Program?
No.
Well, that makes sense.
I just came up with it
about an hour ago.
It's this amazing
new program that gives
Native American students
shadowing programs
and scholarships
and test prep courses
and a direct pipeline
into the medical profession.
And the way the new students
pay it forward
is by giving back,
mentoring local
and tribal schools.
A living, breathing new wave...
of Native American doctors.
Like me?
Like you.
Well...
It's a start.
Start.
It's a good start.
I'm so glad I was here
to see it.
Me too.
♪ Take a load for free
- Hmm.
- Oh, sorry.
You got it?
♪ Yeah, hey, hey
♪ Yeah
♪ Put the load on me
♪ Picked up my bag
♪ I went looking
for a place to hide ♪
♪ When I saw
Carmen and the Devil ♪
♪ Walking side by side
♪ I said "Hey, Carmen,
♪ Come on,
let's go downtown" ♪
♪ She said, "I gotta go
♪ But my friend
can stick around" ♪
♪ Take a load off, Fanny
I'm sorry your day
was so weird.
Oh, so weird.
So weird. I whiffed it.
- Their words, not mine.
- Oof.
Yeah.
What about you? How's yours?
Uh, I had
a tremendous breakthrough
with a new patient.
He's a combat vet,
so you can imagine the PTSD.
- Mm.
- But he wants to get better.
In fact, I'm seeing
him tomorrow.
Is that his hat?
Oh, uh,
he left his hat in my office.
His name wouldn't happen to
be Chance Becker, would it?
Uh, yeah, how'd you know?
I do hope
you've made some progress.
I...
I did with most of them,
I promise.
Mina?
These are all people.
Each one.
This is a long file.
I knew her...
For years.
I knew her children.
She died.
She just died.
There's a drawer over there
for inactive files.
You mean dead people.
Yes.
How do you do this
every day?
Don't you get sad?
It's part of being a doctor.
I just have to put
some things away.
Well, I don't want
to do that.
I don't want to forget!
I can't!
Mina...
I'm so stupid!
Coming here to you,
I thought it would
make things better,
but nothing gets better!
It's just worse!
Every day it gets worse!
My baba is gone.
Mina.
Mina...
My baba is gone.
Come here.
You know, if you keep
taking my spot up here,
I don't know where
I'm gonna solve
all the world's problems.
So you didn't
change the name
- of the hospital, I take it.
- Surprisingly, no.
How'd you do?
Well...
I traumatized a child.
Makes you feel any better,
I'll probably do that
when I get home.
I stupidly brought
her into the hospital,
not realizing that...
being here,
the illness, the death,
it would take her right back
to losing her father.
I should have seen it coming.
I should have...
I should have protected her.
I don't think
we can protect our kids
from that kind of pain.
I couldn't.
But it helps not to be alone.
I'm sorry about Cassian.
I don't know what to... say.
I mean, we never talk about it.
Max...
Yeah?
What you said earlier...
What... what did I say?
I'm really glad
that we're friends.
Me too.
What are you doing?
I have been packing
and unpacking all day.
- Oh, come on.
- But I decided I'm leaving.
No, come on, don't do this.
I am so sorry
for this morning.
- No, no, don't be.
- I made you run out of here...
- Your own house.
- No.
I made you feel...
Surprised, okay?
I was just surprised.
What, that I like you?
No.
I'm just surprised that...
it felt normal.
I'm not used to normal...
or real.
You think...
this is real?
I've been thinking about you
all day.
And I don't think that you
should walk out that door.
Why not?