.
- Tell me it's not a game.
- Hey, take it easy.
- You've got more lies.
- Hey, over here.
Over here.
- I'd like to name you
interim chief.
- I'd be honored.
- When I was 16,
I got pregnant.
- It wasn't difficult for me
to find out
you're my birth mother.
I don't want anyone
to know about us.
- They won't.
- My mom was so sick, I stole
meds from Will's trial.
- I have a lot of history
with Natalie.
I won't apologize for it.
- Did you tell her
you took them?
- You're fired, Dr. Halstead.
- I had to.
- I was the one who sold
the trial meds for my mom.
♪
- I guess that's everything.
I'm going to be okay.
- I know.
- You?
- Yeah.
- You need to go back.
Please, call her.
- Yeah.
Hey, you better keep in touch.
All right, I'll come find you.
- Take care of yourself.
- Yeah, you too.
Bye, Natalie.
- I look at that spot
every day, too.
So I understand Ethan's
physical therapy is going well.
- That's what he says, yeah.
- Oh, you're in contact,
that's good.
Glad he didn't
hold a grudge.
- A grudge?
- Well, come on,
you're telling me
that you don't think
about that?
The shooter? Neil?
What's his name?
If he'd been
put on psych hold...
- What?
Ethan wouldn't have been shot?
No. You know what?
I never think about that.
Not even for a second.
What I do wonder about, though,
is if any of this
would have happened
if you hadn't taken the guy's
appendix out against his will.
That's what I wonder about.
I mean, come on,
he was aiming at you, right?
- Sinus tachycardia at 120.
Sats at 90. Let's go!
- Okay, let's get her to CT.
- Dr. Cooper.
- Hello.
- What happened
with your patient?
- It looks like
pulmonary embolism.
- But no DVT?
- No.
- So is this due
to the insertion
of the cardiac output monitor?
- I wouldn't think so.
The Vas-COM is a good device.
Rarely have any problems.
Excuse me.
- Yeah, sure.
Dr. Halstead.
- Dr. Marcel.
- Yeah.
- We've got an open
radial fracture.
I need you in five right now.
- Yeah.
- I can't get a straight story
out of him.
- We'll figure it out.
I want you to go get
something to eat.
All right, now,
your dad's out of the room.
You gonna tell me
what really happened?
Those there
are puncture wounds.
That's a snakebite.
And I gotta know
what kind of snake
so I can take care of you.
- I'm gonna be sick.
- You're gonna be a lot sicker
unless you tell me
what kind of snake.
- Rattlesnake.
- Mix 5 vials of antivenom
with 250 ml of NS.
- Right.
- So how'd you meet up
with this rattlesnake?
- I stuck my hand in a box.
- I'm guessing the snake
was in that box?
- Yeah.
So why the Wild, Wild West?
- Huh?
- Ambo picked you up
on Chicago and Pulaski.
You don't live over there.
Your shoelaces tipped
in yellow and black.
Those are gang colors.
The 66 boys.
- What are you, a cop?
- I used to be.
But now I'm a doc. So come on.
- I was with some dudes.
- Uh-huh.
Dudes your daddy
don't approve of?
- Yeah.
All right, so sticking your
hand in a box with a snake,
was that some kind of
gang initiation or something,
to see if shorty's
got what it takes?
Yeah.
Hey, who's got that snake?
Hook him up.
I'll be right there.
Maggie, could you
do me a favor?
Call CPD, 23rd District.
Ask for Lieutenant Scott.
- Scott?
- Yeah, my dad.
Tell him I need him to send one
of his guys and animal control
to pick up a rattlesnake.
Yeah, a rattlesnake.
I'll text you the address.
- I want to come back to Med.
It's where I belong.
You know I didn't steal
the trial meds--
- Skip it. Are you familiar
with the Vas-COM?
- The Vas-COM?
- Cardiac output monitor
made by Vasik Labs.
- Yeah, no, I know it.
It's pricey.
Other monitors
are just as good.
What about it?
- We're billing Medicare
for its use 60% more
than any other hospital
in the area.
- Okay?
- Well, if it's being
used unnecessarily
and Medicare's being billed,
that's fraud.
And it's an invasive procedure.
So it's also
putting people at risk.
- Ms. Goodwin, I-I just came
to ask for my job back--
- And I heard you.
Dr. Cooper, Matt Cooper,
you have a relationship
with him.
- Barely.
I mean, he dated my cousin
Moira back in the day.
- Well, Dr. Cooper is our
biggest booster of the Vas-COM.
And I suspect it's because
he's getting kickbacks.
Now, I could go to the board,
but his father-in-law
sits on it.
So I need something solid,
an admission of wrongdoing,
preferably on tape.
And you're going
to get it for me.
- Hold on. Wait.
You're saying you want me
to be your spy?
- If that's what
you want to call it.
But if you want to come back
here and practice medicine,
that's what you're
going to have to do.
- I don't believe this.
You're serious?
- As a heart attack.
Look, I have a doctor
in my hospital
who's scamming the system
and putting patients at risk.
I'll do whatever it takes
to stop him.
Now, are you in or out?
I know he's been missed.
- Yay, Dr. Halstead!
- Yeah!
- Whoo-hoo!
- And there are a couple
of folks that you haven't met.
Dr. Dylan Scott,
and Dr. Stevie Hammer.
- I know Dr. Hammer.
- We were in med school
together.
- Oh, okay. Nice.
All right, thank you, everyone.
- All right, everyone,
we've got patients to see.
- Hey, don't get me wrong,
I'm thrilled to see Will again,
but I thought that
you weren't inviting him back.
- I'll tell you about it later.
- So I heard your clinical
trial was a rousing success.
- I'm touched. You still care
enough to track my failures.
What brought you back
to Chicago?
- Home sweet home.
What made you stay?
- Same.
Look forward
to working with you.
- Likewise.
- What's up with you and her?
- The Hammer?
- Uh-huh.
- God. Never lets you forget
she was first in our class.
- Ah, and you were second? No.
I'm glad you're back.
Natalie would be happy.
- Natalie and April gone.
Ethan in rehab.
- Get back to work.
Treatment six.
Twisted ankle.
It's good to have you back.
- Good to be back.
- What do we got?
- Lois Durant. 65, fatigued
and short of breath.
- Hey, Lois. I'm Dr. Marcel.
I'm going to be
taking care of you, okay?
- BP 95/100. Heart Rate 115.
- Been here before.
Lots of times.
- Okay. Maggie, can we get
Ms. Durant's chart, please?
- You got it.
- Okay, folks,
we know what this is.
Nice and easy.
On my count, all right?
One, two, three.
- Where's my doctor?
- Lois, I'm your doctor, okay?
Can you come forward
for me a little bit?
There you go. Nice and easy.
Yeah, lungs are wet.
All right, there you go now.
And I'm hearing
a systolic murmur.
Have you had
that problem before?
It's okay.
Yeah, you're retaining fluids.
Let's set up
for a bedside echo.
- Okay.
- Call my doctor.
- Okay. Well, let's have a look
at your chart, all right?
What?
Hey, Maggie.
- Yeah.
- Hey, where's Ms. Durant's
chart?
- We don't have it. She's one
of the Kender trial patients.
- So?
- Well, when Kender
pulled the trial,
thanks to Dr. Halstead,
they took all the records.
- And now they won't
release them.
- Okay. Well, it looks like
she's in heart failure.
So I'll need her history.
- Well, you're in luck.
The aforementioned
Dr. Halstead is in the house.
I'm sure he'd be happy to share
his knowledge of the patient.
-  Perfect.
- Yeah.
- Halstead, I could use
your help in three.
Hey, Lois, you remember
Dr. Halstead?
- There's my doctor.
- Lois, what happened?
You were doing so good
a few months ago.
- Don't...know.
- Lois, can you lay back
for me?
There you go.
- How's your son?
Terence, right?
Did he finish law school?
- You remember.
- Sure.
- Yeah, I'm seeing severe
mitral valve regurgitation.
- Yeah, Ventricular pressure's
really low.
- Yeah. Let's give Lois
morphine 5mg IV.
That'll help dilate
your blood vessels,
make it easier
for your heart to pump.
And 40 of Lasix IV, please.
It'll get rid
of some of the fluid.
- We'll check back,
see how you're doing.
- This makes no sense.
Lois only had mild
regurgitation six months ago,
and she was doing better
on the trial meds.
Oh, man, I think we're looking
at hypertrophic cardiomyopathy.
- Well, can't really tell
from the echo windows.
But morphine should work.
- Well, I hope you were able
to assist Dr. Marcel.
- I remember the patient.
- Yeah.
Got to tell you, it wasn't
my idea to bring you back.
- Thanks, Dean.
And, hey, congratulations
on being made Chief.
I mean, it's what you
wanted all along, wasn't it?
- Dr. Archer.
- Thank you. Looking forward
to your next train wreck.
- Ow!
- Hey, Ms. Brooks.
I'm Dr. Archer.
- Hey.
- I'm Emma. Gemma's sister.
- Gemma and Emma.
Dr. Taylor,
why isn't Gemma gowned?
- She refused unless her sister
was also gowned.
- We always dress alike.
- Uh-huh. May I?
- Mm-hmm. Ow! Ow! Ow!
- Okay.
So I understand
that you're suffering from
abdominal pain and bloating?
- Really bad.
- Okay.
Well, I can help with that.
Start an IV hydromorphone .5mg.
- Can you put a needle
in my arm, too?
- I'm sorry, you said what?
- Oh, we'd like a needle
in my arm, too.
- I'm sorry, no,
I can't do that.
- Both sisters were born
with only one ovary.
And Gemma has a history
of ovarian cysts.
- Which is not
necessarily problematic.
I do need to check
your belly with ultrasound.
- Here you are.
- Thank you.
- Okay, I'm going to
raise your blouse.
If you could lower
your jeans for me.
- It's going to be
a little cold.
Okay, here we go.
- Okay. Yeah.
I see free fluid,
which indicates an ovarian
cyst has likely burst.
I'm going to do more
imaging to confirm.
And I'm going to track
your hemoglobin.
Now, if your blood count drops,
you will need surgery,
and we may have to
remove your ovary.
- Then you'll have to
take mine out, too.
- I'm sorry?
- We're identical.
- In every way.
- Well, we just want
to make sure we know
what we're dealing with here.
Dr. Taylor,
what would you recommend?
- A CBC, BMP,
transvaginal ultrasound,
and a pregnancy test.
- Okay. Good. Good.
- She's not pregnant.
- Well, just standard fare.
We'll get back to you.
Page Dr. Charles.
- Got it.
.
- We're the last people
who need a psychiatrist.
- We're very happy.
- I'm really glad to hear that.
- I'm feeling much better.
- It's probably
the hydromorphone,
the pain medication
we gave you.
Look, the tests have showed
that a cyst has ruptured,
and there's bleeding.
Well, Gemma,
you need an operation,
and if we can't
save your ovary,
we do have to remove it.
- Just as long
as they take mine, too.
- Why is that?
- So we have the same scar.
- But not just that.
We always planned to get
pregnant at the same time.
And If she can't,
I can't either.
- Oh, okay. All right.
So have you guys
always dressed exactly alike?
- No.
When we were kids,
our mother wouldn't let us.
- We hated that.
- As soon as we could,
we moved out.
Remember the first time
we bought matching dresses?
- It was heaven.
Now we do everything together.
- Hmm? Everything?
- Eat, sleep, take showers.
- Go to the bathroom.
- Wow.
- COVID was actually
really good for us.
- How's that?
- Lockdown, we were with one
another and no one else
for a year and a half.
- Brought us even closer.
- Kind of hard to--to tell
where one of you begins,
and the other one ends.
- Exactly.
both: We're one person.
- So look, it's not unusual
for monozygotic twins
to have a very strong bond.
- So that's normal?
- No. Not at all.
Not to this extent.
We're looking at an extreme
lack of individuation here.
- What does that mean?
- Well, normally,
when children develop,
even identical twins,
they start
to form a sense of self,
you know,
an individual identity.
Somehow, with these two, that
just--it just never happened.
- All right.
Okay, so they're--well,
what's the word
I'm supposed to use?
Delusional?
And now he's going to tell us
that they have
decisional capacity
and that we
can't force treatment.
- That's correct.
- See?
- I've been over it with them
a couple of times,
and they fully understand
the potential consequences.
- So what do we do?
- Well, we certainly can't
operate on the healthy twin.
- Are you seriously thinking
that I was considering that?
- You know, with your history,
I mean,
I guess you just never know.
- Is there any chance that this
will resolve without surgery?
- Yeah, a small one.
I mean, we can keep an eye
on her hemoglobin,
but if it drops lower
or she becomes unstable,
then we have to take her
to the OR.
- With their consent.
- Okay.
- Hey, Will,
I wanted to tell you,
I know your brother, Jay.
- Really? How's that?
- Used to be
in the same line of work.
- No kidding?
- Dr. Scott, we need
a peds consult over in Baghdad.
Ten-year-old girl.
Extremely lethargic.
- Catch you later.
- Yeah.
- It's not a diabetic issue.
Blood glucose is normal.
- Heat exhaustion?
- No. We hung fluids.
She hasn't responded.
- Hey, Jasmine.
Can you hear me?
- She's never like this.
- Jasmine? Hey.
- I wanna go home.
- That's better.
Now, can you squeeze
my fingers?
Good. Other side.
- Honey, do what
the doctor says.
- Jasmine, come one.
There you go. Thank you.
Motor and speech intact.
- Does Jasmine have any
pre-existing conditions
that we should know about?
- Well, when she was born,
they told me
that she had sickle cell.
But it doesn't seem to
bother her
other than getting some pain
once in a while.
- Head CT?
- Yeah, but I doubt
it'll tell us anything
we don't already know.
Maggie?
- Right here.
- You need to send Jasmine in
for a head CT.
- All right.
I'll let Radiology know.
- Ooh!
- Are you all right?
- Yeah. Fine.
Just a little stiff.
- We also need to set up
for an exchange transfusion.
- Okay.
- A transfusion? Blood?
- Yeah. We believe
your daughter's condition
is because of her sickle cell.
- Blood with normal cells
will help her feel better.
- I'll make sure
they red cell phenotype.
Aleesha, you'll give us
the best match.
- We'll talk with you after
Jasmine has had her scan, okay?
All right.
- So do you think a guy
who orders
the same thing every day
is dependable or boring?
- Depends on the man.
- Hey, Matt.
- Will.
Hey, I thought
they gave you the boot.
- Turns out they can't live
without me.
If this guy's done
bothering you,
I'll take a chicken Caesar.
- Thanks, Skyler.
- It's been a while, huh?
- How's Moira?
- Good. And married.
- Wow, I blew that one.
- I'm sure you're doing fine.
- I'm married now.
Trying to be a good boy.
- You're not busy.
We should get a drink.
Catch up.
- Yeah, sure.
- Chicken Caesar.
- Hey, good to see you, man.
- Yeah. Take care.
- Dr. Archer, Dr. Taylor.
- Ow--ow!
- Help her!
- Another milligram
of hydromorphone.
- She's tachycardic
and hypotensive. Temp's 101.
- All right.
Only one unit of blood.
And a unit of FFP.
- Got it.
- All right, Gemma,
you are bleeding.
We need to get you up
to surgery right now.
- Take us both.
- I cannot do that.
- Then no surgery.
- All right,
listen to me, okay?
You could bleed to death.
You understand? You could die.
- You have to save her.
Take me to surgery.
- Anything? Hmm? Any ideas?
- Okay, let's get you
on your back.
Let's get you on your back.
One, two, three.
.
Her pain's lessened.
Fever's down.
The antibiotics are working,
but for how long?
- Yeah. Okay, thanks.
- We don't have anything
more to say.
- If you really want
to save Gemma,
you have to operate
on me first.
- You know, I've been thinking
about our first conversation.
And you mentioned that you--you
both wanted to get pregnant
at the same time.
And I-I absolutely appreciate.
how much joy that
that would bring you.
- We'll be okay.
- I'm sure you will.
But you also said
that sometimes you like
to think of yourself
as one person.
- We are one person.
- Okay.
Well, genetically, anyway,
you absolutely are, right?
You were born
from a single egg.
You share the same genes.
- Yeah, we know that. So?
- So if one of you were to
have a baby, say, Emma,
with her one ovary,
were to get pregnant,
well, it might as well be
Gemma's child too.
- That's true.
- So, in a sense,
you would be bringing a child
into the world together, right?
And I just still think
that that would be
a tremendously satisfying,
joyful experience
for the both of you,
I mean, wouldn't it?
- That sounds kind of
nice, Emmie.
- We'll think about it.
- Okay.
- Your daughter's scans confirm
what we had suspected.
Jasmine suffered a stroke.
- What? Stroke?
She's a little girl.
- The abnormal shape
of the red blood cells
can cause the blood
to become thicker,
which can cause clotting
and lead to stroke.
- When Jasmine was diagnosed,
didn't your doctor
tell you about that?
- No.
- Kids with sickle cell
should have a type of scan,
a Transcranial Doppler,
once a year,
to see if
they're prone to stroke.
I'm guessing nobody told you
about that either.
- No.
- And they should be
on a medicine
called Hydroxyurea.
- What is that?
- It helps the red blood cells
maintain a normal shape.
- Are you saying this
shouldn't have happened?
Jasmine, she shouldn't
be sick like this?
- I'm sorry, Ms. Russell.
- Oh my God.
I let this happen.
- No.
- My baby.
- No, this--this was
not your fault.
- I'm her mother.
I'm her mother.
I'm supposed to protect her.
- This is your doctors' fault.
They should've told you.
- It doesn't appear
that Jasmine's stroke
was very severe.
She'll recover,
and we can make sure
that this never happens again.
- She's getting a transfusion,
and she should get better
right away.
- I just wanna be with her.
- Why didn't anyone tell her?
- Where were you
working before here?
- Grosse Pointe.
Beaumont Hospital.
- Ah. Well, this happens a lot
to kids who have sickle cell.
Less than 50% get screened.
On the other hand,
kids with cystic fibrosis.
Well, they get a case manager,
regular check-ups.
- 'Cause most CF patients
are white.
- Mm-hmm.
- Yeah, I get it.
- So the twins have agreed
to Gemma's surgery?
- Yeah, that's what I hear.
Good news, right?
- Yeah. Sounds like you played
into their fantasy.
- Yeah, maybe a bit.
But can't really address
their psychiatric issues
if one of them is dead.
Whatever you say.
- Cesar, what have we got?
- 60-year-old female.
Hour prior to arrival, she had
an ataxic gait, garbled speech.
Lost consciousness
in the ambo, and we intubated.
No corneal reflexes. No gag.
- Nancy, Dr. Taylor, with me.
- Help her, please.
- Sir--sir, we're going to
take care of her.
Angel.
- How are things
with you and Dr. Taylor?
- Ugh! She keeps her distance.
And I try to keep mine.
- Well, it's not so easy.
Not easy for most mothers,
but you'll keep trying.
- Right.
- Ooh, Dr. Halstead.
- Yeah.
- So?
- Yeah, I said we should
go out for drinks, catch up.
- Good.
- Matt didn't seem
that enthusiastic.
I don't know if it'll happen.
- Well, you'll make it happen.
- Dr. Halstead.
- Excuse me.
- BP's even lower.
- Yeah. I was afraid
the morphine wouldn't work.
- I need to take her
to surgery.
- And do what exactly?
- Replace the valve.
Unhook her. Let's go.
- Well, the primary problem
isn't the valve.
It's the outflow track.
It's obstructed.
She needs a completely
different procedure
from what you're suggesting.
- What I see is severe
mitral valve regurgitation
and an enlarged heart.
Let's go. Okay, guys, come on.
- Crockett, you asked me
to consult
because you know
I know this patient.
- I understand.
But I don't have
precise measurements, and
we don't have a cardiac cath.
- So, do a cardiac cath.
You'll see I'm right.
- I don't have time
to screw around, Will.
With her condition this bad,
I need to operate now.
- Yeah, and the bigger
the procedure
the bigger the fee, right?
But, hey, Medicare's
paying for it.
- Keep going.
What was that?
You think
that's what I'm about?
Padding my bill?
- No. No, I don't.
Forget it, man.
- That's my patient.
I'm taking her to surgery.
We all set with
the valve sizers?
- Yeah.
We've got both mechanical
and biosynthetic valves.
- Good.
- Hey, Will.
My scrub nurse
told me you were up here.
- Yeah. Patient
from the clinical trial.
- Oh, so already a history
of heart failure?
- Mm-hmm.
- Hmm.
Not using a Vas-COM
to monitor cardiac output.
- I guess not.
- Vas-COM's really
a lot more accurate.
- Oh, yeah?
- I don't want to
step on any toes here,
but you might
want to suggest it.
- Yeah, sure.
Crockett.
- Yeah.
- Dr. Cooper thinks
you should use a Vas-COM.
- Oh? Hey, Matt.
Well, I've got this
handled, bud.
Old set-up's just fine,
all right?
- Yeah.
Sorry, your patient.
Didn't mean to intrude.
- Yeah. Okay, then.
- Vas-COM really should be
standard of care.
Well, he'll come around.
- Okay, let's replace
the valve.
- Hold on.
- What?
- This doesn't look valvular.
TEE indicates a sub-aortic
outflow obstruction.
- Can you calculate
a gradient for me?
- Gradient is 70MM of mercury.
- Consistent with
hypertrophic cardiomyopathy.
- Yeah.
- All right, folks,
change of plans.
We are not gonna
replace the valve.
We're gonna move to a myectomy.
♪
.
- How's Ms. Jasmine doing?
- She's sleeping.
- Good. Why don't you step out?
Hmm?
There's some coffee over
at the Nurses' Station.
- Could use some.
Oh--ooh!
Oh God.
- Let me help you. Okay.
- Here, I got you.
- No. Please, I'm okay.
- No, let's just get you
where you can lie down.
- I'm going to get you
two ready, okay?
- All right.
- Come on. Just take it easy.
- Come right here.
- Okay.
- Nice and slow.
- I don't need anything.
- Your knees are giving you
a lot of trouble.
- Aleesha, let the doctors
take a look, okay?
- Did you injure yourself?
- No.
- Burning sensation?
- Let's get an x-ray.
- Okay.
- Clear.
- Your knees
are severely arthritic.
How long have
they been like this?
- I don't know. Few months.
- Have you seen a doctor?
- Told me to take some aspirin.
- We're going to give you
something
a little more effective.
Toradol, 30 mg, IM.
Your hips seem to be giving you
a lot of pain as well.
Aleesha?
- Yeah.
- There you go.
- I have to ask...
are you living in your car?
- No. Why'd you ask me that?
- You're very young to have
such advanced arthritis.
And you're not overweight.
I'm sorry.
I don't mean to embarrass you,
but I've seen arthritis
like this in people
who sleep sitting up
in the confines of a car.
I'm only asking
so that we can help you.
Aleesha?
It's okay. It's okay.
We're going to get you
some meds to manage the pain,
maybe a brace.
Get you in
a physical therapy program.
The important thing
is exercise.
Gotta get you moving.
It's going to be okay.
♪
- Okay.
- That was an impressive call.
How'd you guess they were
sleeping in their car?
- Oh, you mean,
the Grosse Pointe thing?
Actually, I was surprised
you didn't catch it.
I mean, don't cops
have a lot of experience
with homeless folks?
- Oh, you mean like,
"Move along,
you can't sleep here"?
- Yeah, just like that.
- Yeah.
- I need a doctor.
- You better go in.
- You need to call it.
- Time of death, 1605.
I am so sorry.
The stroke was too massive.
There was nothing
that we could do.
- I know that was hard.
I'm sorry.
- Dr. Halstead.
- Ms. Goodwin, I can't do this.
I am not the guy
for what you need.
I'm uncomfortable.
I don't like being suspicious
of people, lying.
So if my staying here
is dependent
on doing this for you,
I'd just as soon work
somewhere else.
- Hold on. I was expecting
this conversation.
I've got something
I want you to see.
- What's this?
- A recent case.
Young man, 23 years old.
After insertion of a Vas-COM
catheter,
he developed infection,
gangrene.
Spent two weeks in the ICU,
and lost his leg.
If the Vas-COM was indeed
an unnecessary procedure,
then this was a tragedy
that never should've happened.
- Okay.
So it's not a big procedure.
Probably won't take more
than an hour. You ready?
Okay, Camila?
- Gemma, I'm going to put you
to sleep now.
Can you count back from ten?
- Ten, nine...
- How are you doing?
Emma, I know what a difficult
decision this was for you
and your sister. I do.
- We always wanted
to have babies.
- You can.
And, trust me,
I know that you would come to
think of them as both of yours.
What?
- I'm sorry.
- For what?
You're sorry for what, Emma?
- I didn't want her to do it.
She wouldn't listen.
- Do what?
No. No.
Stop the surgery!
- What the hell, Dan?
- They switched places.
That's not Gemma.
It's not her.
.
- While your dad's
getting the car,
we got a minute to talk.
- Oh, man.
- Your little
knucklehead friends?
You're done with them.
I mean it.
You see that cop over there?
He works the West Side.
He sees you over there,
he's going to tell me,
and I'm going to tell your dad.
Ah, there he is now.
- Thanks, Doc.
- Yeah. He's a fine young man.
Keep an eye on him.
I don't want to
see him here again
- You can count on that.
I still don't see
how he got bit by a snake.
- Yeah, we have to
ask him that.
- Seems like we need
to have a discussion
when we get back home.
- Hey, stay safe, all right?
People care about you.
- They have matching scars now.
Maybe that'll be enough
to satisfy them.
- You know, I've been doing
this almost 40 years.
Never have I ever...
- I mean, not even close.
- Yeah, they really did
hoodwink us, didn't they?
But at least you caught it
before I took her ovary out.
I'd say that's a win.
What? You're wondering
if I'm being genuine, huh?
See, that's the curse
of being a shrink.
- Hmm.
- Hey, so you were right.
You did know your patient.
- You know,
Natalie's mom is doing well.
In large part thanks to you.
- That's nice to hear.
You miss her?
- Yeah.
- Yeah, me too.
I'll see you tomorrow.
- Yeah. See you tomorrow.
- You're admitting this patient
with sickle cell?
- Yeah.
Just waiting on a bed upstairs.
- Good work today.
- They'll bring in
a cot for Aleesha.
Kid has to have a stroke
for her mom to get a bed.
- Med's running a gene
therapy trial for sickle cell.
Possible cure.
If I can enroll Jasmine,
Aleesha will have a bed
for more than just a night.
- Mom? It's me, Mom.
- Can I come inside?
- Step over that.
- It's taken me a while
to find you.
What happened to the van?
- Broke down.
- You been taking your meds?
- I thought you moved.
- I'm back now.
Here, let me have a listen.
- I ran out.
- I'll get you more pills.
Deep breath.
You sound a little congested.
- Yeah. Well, just so you know,
I got vaccinated.
I'm not stupid.
- Okay.
But Mom, please, we've got
to get you off the streets.
- I can take care of myself.
- No. You're not doing that.
No. I'm not going to
let you live like this.
Hear me?
♪