Zola!
In your first year
as an attending surgeon...
...you're told to take baby steps.
Look for the easy cases, the sure wins.
Hey. Come on.
Is it hard to learn to play guitar?
Apparently, yes.
No sense of making an ass of yourself.
I can't understand what he's singing.
And let's be thankful for that.
Better to rack up some easy victories.
Mom, your trophies.
Are you bringing them for show and tell?
No. Show and tell is when
you're proud of something.
This is more like...
if Mommy bought milk, and it was spoiled,
and I have to return it.
Andrew, I'm going to work.
At the hospital.
Remember, the big building with
a lot of sick people inside?
- Would you like to come?
- I already called in sick.
You know you're not sick.
My whole body just... it hurts, okay?
I'm sick.
How come Maggie's friend never
has to take a bath and we do?
Because he's European.
Would you go get your brother
and sister, please?
You can't avoid bad outcomes
for your whole career,
but you can sure try.
Excuse me. Do you work here?
Yes, I do.
Oh, great.
Can you respond to this
morning's harassment allegations
by the radiologist in Phoenix?
She claims Harper Avery
shoved her up against a...
How does it feel to be working
under the name
of an alleged sexual predator?
Are those Harper Avery Awards?
What are you doing with them?
I'm returning them.
Excuse me.
Excuse me. Excuse me.
'Cause getting a bad reputation...
Excuse me.
...can finish you before you start.
Hey, I'm pulling the plug
on your contest.
I'm killing it.
What do you want me to do
with the $100 million?
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
No, no. If word gets out
that Harper Avery's grandson
secretly funded a competition
that he entered himself?
Well, that's just gonna mean
more nasty headlines
that we do not need right now.
Dr. Bai...
You funded the contest?
You knew, didn't you?
I beg your pardon?
Of course you knew. You had to know.
You made up the rules.
"Rules." What a crock.
Look, I really have no idea
what you're talking about.
I am not a cheater.
I have never cheated
on anything in my life.
Um, why are you telling me this?
I know Jackson
put up the money for the contest
and asked you to judge.
Wait. Wait.
Jackson put up the money for the contest?
Who asked you to judge?
Slimy!
That's what it was. It was slimy.
Come again, now?
You set me up to make it
look like I'm in cahoots
with my ex-husband?
That is... That is low.
What the hell are you talking about?
I'm talking about you duping me
into a phony director position
where I unwittingly decide
who wins the prize money
that my ex-husband put up
so that I look slimy.
Because you are! Slimy!
All due respect!
Mom, we need to talk about this contest.
Honey, come in. I want you to meet...
Erin Mason, crisis management.
You're just the man I was looking for.
And he sure is camera-friendly.
That doesn't hurt us.
You assured me you and I could
handle this together.
Dr. Avery, if I had an aggressive cancer,
would you recommend I operate on myself
or hire a professional?
Sweetheart, this is what Erin does.
Let's hear her out.
That lawsuit brought by the 13 women
who signed and then violated their NDAs?
It's tip of the iceberg.
This is a developing situation,
and it's getting worse by the minute.
So, this is how you get out
from under the bad name
of Harper Avery?
With a surgical innovation contest
secretly funded by his damn grandson?
- What?
- And that's out. Okay.
Wait. Jackson,
you're the anonymous donor?
What's this now?
You put up the money, and then
you entered the contest?
You entered your own contest?
Oh, God. Is this some kind
of tax-evasion scheme?
What? No. It's just me
trying to do some good.
Anonymously. That's it.
Well, that didn't work.
Public perception is everything,
and they're going to destroy you
if this gets out.
Then, let's not let it get out.
Agreed. And to that end,
I have some good news.
You are welcome.
What's this?
It is a distraction for the press.
I've been in touch with
the various medical charities,
and Angels of Humanity has a very
high-profile surgery for you.
You want me to operate on
a child as a PR stunt?
- Are you kidding?
- No. I want you to heal a child.
This patient is arriving this morning,
and we would like you to work
with Meredith Grey.
Of course you would. Maybe because
she just won a Harper Avery?
No, because she's giving
hers back... and her mother's.
We're in a Category Five storm, here.
We need good press, yesterday.
Then, we are going to
go after these women.
We are going to attack their...
No, no, no, no, no.
You will not go after any
of these wom... no.
Listen, Boy Scouts and Girl Scouts,
someone is going down for this.
I have spent most of my adult
life building up the Avery name,
and now it's gonna take me down.
I guess I could just go back
to being Catherine Fox.
Oh, that's great, Mom.
Thanks, from your Avery son
and granddaughter.
Look, if it's a scapegoat they want,
I'm the one that signed the settlements.
Catherine.
- I could live with that.
- Absolutely not.
There's no way a powerful black
woman is gonna take the fall
for a rich old white guy
that couldn't keep
his damn hands to himself. No.
Jackson, I love your passion,
but this is not up to you.
I'm still in charge of this foundation.
It's not your decision.
Now go. Meet your patient.
Hey. You returned the awards?
Is that really necessary?
Yes, it was.
You didn't want to give us
a heads up, Meredith?
Did you really think
you were gonna get away
with rigging the contest?
No. How does the news travel so fast?
I didn't rig any contest.
It's pretty ballsy.
Were you gonna act like
you weren't gonna win,
and then, at the minute,
just pull ahead and be like,
"Hey, look, I won"?
Right. Are you joking,
or do you really think
that's something I would do?
I mean, I don't know what to think.
Do you care to explain?
I don't, no.
I do need your help on a
craniofacial dysplasia excision.
- What do you say?
- A PR stunt?
No, thanks.
Whoa.
Is that...
I think that is our patient.
Are you sure you don't want to help?
What. Is there something on my face?
Synced & corrected by -robtor-
www.addic7ed.com
Okay, Grassy Lane Farm? Too pricey?
No. I mean, if you like it, let's do it.
Okay, the Old Piano Factory.
There's this 3-tiered pricing thingy.
Old Piano Factory is gorgeous,
but you would...
you'd need a time machine.
'Cause you'd have to go back
like six months
to even think about booking it
for this year.
But have you thought about Magnolia's?
Or Cloudland Inn?
- Ooh, ooh, ooh!
- Green Shutters. Look that one up.
Karev, Wilson, what are you doing?
Well, my surgery got cancelled
'cause of Handsy Avery.
So, we are trying to plan
a wedding, but we suck at it.
Yes! That's good. Plan your wedding.
Set the date. Put it on the calendar.
This place needs morale.
This place needs some things
to feel good about
and look forward to.
Yeah, yeah, lock that down.
Great, now it's a work thing.
I'll do it.
I mean, I just lost my contest.
I know I left my own wedding
at a pretty inopportune time,
but prior to that,
I planned the hell out of it.
If you need help, I can do it.
I just need a date and a budget.
Okay, we're doing that.
- Really?
- Yeah. We hate party planning.
And if I promise not to
leave you at the altar,
can we just let her do it?
I feel like I just won the lottery.
Okay.
So, budget.
Okay, this...
This is what I can kick in.
Now you check your account.
What's wrong? Are you broke?
Do I have to tell Beyoncé
that we can't afford her?
Seriously, what's wrong?
Did it just turn into,
like, a BYOB kind of thing?
Can't do this right now.
Are you sure you don't want to
take him somewhere else?
I mean, it's only his 6-month checkup.
No. Karev said he'd do it.
It's a perk, so I'm taking it.
Plus, the birth mom's coming here.
Right.
And I still think it's weird
that she has the right
to just show up at
his doctor's appointments.
Owen, you're fostering. You
might not get to adopt him.
I know.
I keep trying to think of it as,
like, a practice baby.
But he is such a cute practice baby.
Okay.
Now, protect him like
a football. Let's go.
Okay.
No comment! No comment!
Ooh! Hey!
Oh, hey.
You're so late.
Did you get stopped by those reporters?
No. I was dealing with a very
sad Sofia. Sobbing again.
Refusing to go to school.
I mean, I just... I had to
bribe her with snuggle time.
And I promised her I would
stay home with her tomorrow.
Poor thing, she just hates school.
And I don't...
I don't know what to do.
That's too bad.
Maybe you can bribe me with some
snuggle time after my consult.
His parents are loving people.
They took him for a surgery in Caracas,
but no one would touch it.
And it kept growing.
He's a great kid.
Do you think you can help him?
We certainly hope so.
- Will you excuse me?
- Yeah, of course.
Hello?
In these old scans,
it's extending into the orbit
and putting pressure on his optic nerve
Yeah. That's definitely a concern.
I'm also worried about his airway.
Helm, his head's tilted a bit. Can you
get in there and readjust, please?
Copy that.
Just need another angle...
Oh, good. This is my good side.
Totally.
I know what you're thinking...
good-looking and funny.
Some people just have all the luck.
Thank you.
It's growing deep into the retropharynx
Which is why I'm worried about him
losing his ability to speak...
asphyxiating in his sleep.
I mean, look at this.
It would be impossible
to excise that entire thing.
I'm gonna have to just contour it down
to get the best
cosmetic outcome possible,
preserving his breathing and his sight.
No. We have to do a total resection,
pull the whole thing out.
I mean, your way avoids a bad outcome,
but it doesn't solve our problem.
Yeah, well, neither does killing him.
Okay, sure, you're right,
he's gonna have to come back
for further resection.
He lives in Venezuela.
Which is why they sent him here.
We pull this off, he gets a
chance at having his life back.
Plus, you and I know
we really can't afford
a bad outcome right now.
Oh. Okay.
Well, at least our motives are clear.
Come on, Mer.
No, I get it...
safe option, solid odds,
and glowing press.
I'm sorry, Doctors, we have a problem.
I'm afraid we have to
cancel this surgery.
We're a religious charity.
Our donors are very concerned
by the disturbing accounts
of the Harper Avery abuse.
I don't get it... so, they just
take it out on the boy?
- I mean, seriously?
- Angels of Humanity, my ass.
- I beg your pardon?
- It's not our decision.
This came from the executive
director and our board.
They want us to take him
to another hospital.
Harper Avery is not even here!
He's not even alive.
And we completely understand
that you don't want to be associated
with the Avery name... neither do we...
but you won't find a better
surgeon than Jackson Avery
to help Diego.
He's stuck with the name, and so are you.
Our organization
won't pay for the surgery.
There's nothing we can do.
There is. Because we can do it pro bono.
And at least Diego
has a shot at survival.
We'll book an O.R.
Thank you.
I think Harper Avery's
caused enough casualties.
This is such a fun day!
- Excuse me. Can you tell me...
- No comment.
No comment? Aren't you a doctor?
No comment at all.
This is an E.R., right?
I need someone to look at my son. Milo!
- Hi.
- Hi, how can I help?
We think we might have
swallowed a chew toy.
Say hi, Milo.
Good diagnosis. Yeah.
I think it might be lodged
in the epiglotis.
Should we go to trauma one?
Which is where?
I'm so turned around.
It all looks different now.
I used to be a nurse here.
Another lifetime.
Olivia Jankovic.
Oh, okay. Well, welcome back.
Trauma one is right here.
Yeah, we're gonna see Dr. Karev.
That's right.
Hi.
We're here to see Dr. Karev.
Wellness baby check?
Hunt.
Fill out the first page.
Yeah, I work here.
I'm the head of trauma?
Well, that baby doesn't.
Fill out the form, and have
a seat until we call you.
Mm.
Did you like her?
I didn't.
Okay.
You mind covering your mouth,
or get a mask from the nurse?
Oh, they said...
they said I could be here.
I'm Betty.
I'm Leo's mom.
Do you know how long
it's been down there?
About an hour.
We were having dinner at my parents',
and my dad started
talking politics, so...
maybe he was looking for an easy way out.
Uh...
It's a joke, Skippy.
I see we're still getting
the interns straight from Mensa.
Okay, so, the whistle
isn't compromising his airway,
but I'd still like to get some
X-rays to pinpoint the location.
Okay. I swear to God,
this kid will stick
anything in his mouth.
Dude, careful.
Times have changed.
No whistlin' at the ladies.
So, this Harper Avery stuff...
Ugh, nightmare.
I can't say I'm surprised.
When I was here, you wouldn't
believe the pig doctors
we had to put up with.
So...
what are we looking at?
Alex Karev.
Perfect.
Olivia.
You two know each other?
Is he still giving nurses syphilis,
or has he moved on to gonorrhea?
Do you want to hold him?
No. I better not.
Why are we in a hospital?
- Is he really sick?
- No, no, no. No, no.
I work here, and these doctors
are my friends,
and I trust them.
Oh. That's cool.
That's...
Hey.
I thought you'd be done by now.
Yeah, Karev's tied up in the E.R.
and we're just sitting here...
Is this how we treat patients?
'Cause it is horrible.
Well, I guess the mom flaked.
You didn't have to worry about that.
Dr. Shepherd, this is Betty,
uh, Leo's mom.
Oh! Betty, goodness. Hi.
It's nice to meet you.
Hi.
Ahh.
So... peds surgery?
What happened to plastics?
Lucky for you, I dropped it.
Okay, bud, when you breathe or swallow,
does that feel uncomfortable?
So, you still in Seattle?
God, no. Got the hell out.
Sacramento. Met my husband.
He's intelligent, kind, faithful...
not your crowd at all.
Okay. Well, it looks like
it's lodged in his bronchus.
Go ahead with X-rays.
- What was that about?
- Nothing.
Get chest and abdominal films.
Keep an eye on his pulse-ox.
Alex, wait.
If you want to do
a cheaper place, that's fine.
We can give Kepner
whatever budget we want.
Jo, can we just drop it?
Alex, it's a stupid wedding budget.
How hard is it to give me a number?
So, is someone gonna come get us, or...?
Yeah. We're gonna bring him up right now.
Okay.
Are you and Karev engaged?
Yeah.
Best of luck with that.
Thank you for doing this.
Oh, my gosh, it is a treat.
I rarely get to treat healthy
babies, and this is one.
Doesn't that bother him?
No, no, no.
He's just reacting to the light.
It's a good thing.
You can come in closer
if you want. He's your...
All right. Let's flex and rotate
to check for hip dysplasia.
Oh, yeah!
He's super strong and limber.
He's a future Olympian!
Look at those strong, powerful legs.
He gets those from me.
I was the fastest kid on my soccer team.
Coach called me "Lightning Bolt Betty."
Okay, this is my least favorite part,
but Leo needs this, and I
promise I'll be super fast.
You know, I get really squeamish
around needles, too.
You want to step outside with me?
Hi.
All right, let's make it really quick,
really quick, really quick, really quick.
A-a-and...
So stupid.
What is?
I got a dress.
Like, I went out and got
a new dress for this.
Like Leo would know if I'm
wearing a dress or not.
This guy's a friggin' doctor.
What can I do for him?
You hungry?
I skipped breakfast. I'm dying.
Come on. It's on me.
Syph Nurse.
Sorry?
That's what they called me...
"Syph Nurse."
It was all over the hospital.
A lot of laughs.
And I got it from Karev, but
nobody was calling him "Syph Doc."
I'm sorry. That's awful.
Oh, please. I'm over it.
I should shut up, but you
seem pretty great and, just...
You know he cheated on his first wife?
Um...
- Who told you that?
- Nobody.
He cheated with me.
So, I kind of lost the moral
high ground on that one.
And to be fair, they weren't married yet,
so it's slightly less horrible
on his part.
Well, I appreciate that, I guess.
But that was a long time ago.
People change.
You're right. Absolutely.
Of course, it couldn't hurt
to get tested.
Okay. I reviewed his X-rays.
The whistle is lodged
in his right mainstem bronchus.
I'd like to get it out of there
before it causes a bronchospasm.
You good with that?
You're the doctor.
And after we dissect
the internal maxillary artery,
we'll continue to remove the tumor burden
and prevent compromise
to the orbital floor.
I still think we should take
the whole tumor out.
We're past that.
But why?
Diego is going to have to come
back here time and time again,
and risk bleeding out every single time.
We could just do a bone graft right now.
- It's too risky.
- "Risky"?
Jackson, everything is risky.
Surgery is risky.
Not too long ago,
you did a throat transplant.
Where's that guy?
That's the guy Diego needs today.
Yeah, well, it's not that simple.
Yeah, it is that simple.
It should be that simple...
if you weren't so concerned
with getting bad press.
I'm not!
Fine. Maybe I am, all right?
That's only 'cause I'm concerned
about the foundation.
But why are you even thinking
about that right now?
I'm sure Katie Simmons
isn't thinking about that.
- Who?
- Katie Simmons.
She was all over the news this morning.
She was a 3rd-year neuro.
She was harassed, assaulted, paid off.
She dropped out of the program.
She's a waitress now.
Do you think she's thinking
about the foundation, Hellmouth?
Preach.
All right, I'm not trying
to diminish the trauma
experienced by these victims, all right?
If you take the foundation down,
that's 72 hospitals that go down with it.
Every single person in this
hospital... multiply that by 72.
We're talking about thousands
of jobs, thousands of families.
You know, of all people, I really
thought you would understand.
Understand what?
We're not exactly raised
by people who were easy.
No. You don't get to do that.
You don't get to compare your
grandfather and my mother.
My mother had to fight tooth and nail
for every inch of ground she gained.
Harper Avery had everything...
except decency.
We're ready. Let me know
when the O.R. is prepped.
Turn the scope to the right.
Nope, your other right.
Yes...
Just looking for the whistle.
And I see it.
Secure the object with your forceps.
Do me a favor... try not to
perforate the airway.
His mom hates me enough as it is.
Well, you did give her syphilis.
Olivia has a right to be pissed.
I was an idiot back then.
They used to call me "Evilspawn."
Evilspawn?
Okay, last time I complain
about "Glasses."
Shut up, Schmitt. All right.
Angle the tip down and rotate
your wrist 90 degrees clockwise.
If anything, I think I was
more troubled by the cheating
on your first wife.
We've known each other forever.
Do you really think I'm like that?
No. But I think you're being really weird
about setting a date.
Bingo! I got the whistle.
How cool is that?
Okay.
Bye.
Thanks for earlier. I know you're busy.
No, no, I'm not.
Actually, I was home
with Sofia all morning.
I had to push some things.
- Is Sofia okay?
- Yeah.
No. No.
She's sad, all the time.
Do you want to bring her over?
She might get a kick out of
playing with Leo.
Kids love babies.
Yes! Thank you!
That is a normal human reaction!
Thank you! Thank you!
You seriously can't beat this truck.
It's so much better than the food inside.
Yeah. It's pretty good.
So...
...how long have you been using?
I don't know where you got that idea.
I guess from the itching
and the bruising on your arms,
the constricted pupils.
I have allergies.
Ah. Yeah.
I had "allergies," too.
For a long time.
I was never into drugs.
I never smoked weed.
I didn't hang out with the stoners.
I thought they were losers.
Whoops.
You were a jock?
Soccer.
AYSO, high school, two club teams.
I tore my ACL in the playoffs,
and the operation sucked,
so they wrote me a prescription.
Painkillers.
10 days' worth, that's all.
That's all it takes.
That was two years ago.
And now I have a baby whose
father is some dealer and...
And I'm on the streets.
It's so stupid.
I guess the question is...
where do you want to be
two years from now?
So, that was awkward.
Not now.
Can I run something up the flagpole?
- No.
- I mean, I'm not gonna lie...
Flu-like symptoms, sore throat,
headaches, fatigue?
I've not not had them.
Stop talking.
Now, no sores, thank God,
no moist wart-like patches.
Ew. Seriously, stop talking.
It's just, you know how they say,
if you sleep with a partner,
you sleep with all
your partner's partners?
And, obviously, I love what we had.
It's just, I keep thinking
about Karev to you to...
Schmitt!
It was a billion years ago.
You don't have syphilis.
Okay, great.
We're good. That's all I needed to hear.
I think I need a meeting.
I met someone.
And I don't know, I...
I think we made a real connection,
and I think I'm about to do
something completely crazy.
Well, I'm happy for you, Shepherd.
She's 15.
Okay, you need to talk to
a professional... now.
No. No, listen, this is a kid.
This is a young mom.
She's Owen's foster kid's mom.
And she's a junkie
partly because some surgeon
prescribed opioids she probably
could've done without.
I'm thinking about taking her in.
Do you think I can do that?
I wasn't sober when I met Ollie,
and I wasn't ready to get sober.
But she saw something in me,
practically dragged me off
a barstool to a meeting.
Whatever is was, it stuck.
You see something in this girl,
you go ahead and drag her.
Now, it might now work,
but if it does, you've saved a life.
Hey.
- Hey.
- How's the pleasure business?
Always learning.
What's up?
Do you like kids?
- What?
- I just... I mean, in general.
You know, some people,
they don't like kids.
Have I done something wrong?
It's just, when I talk about Sofia,
you don't seem particularly interested.
I don't really know Sofia.
I only know what you tell me
of her, and how you treat her.
And I...
I just don't believe in
coddling the children so much.
- That's all.
- Coddling?
I don't coddle the children... the child.
If Sofia stayed home for part of today,
why should she want to go
to school the next day?
It's very complicated.
I mean, her parents split up,
and she's...
My parents split up, too.
I stayed in Italy with Papa,
baby Andrew goes with our mom.
I had my first job at 9,
sweeping up in the cafe.
Meanwhile, Andrew is sobbing
on the couch because
his girlfriend left him.
She was basically deported.
It's because he was coddled.
Food for thought?
Okay, kiddo, you're good to go.
And don't let me
catch you in here next week
with a skateboard or an Xbox down there.
Deal?
I know it was dumb.
Well, we all do dumb things.
Then, we, uh, outgrow them.
Thanks...
Dr. Karev.
You got a good kid.
I'm happy for you.
She's too good for you.
You think I don't know that?
I know it's a lot...
"Unconventional" was
the social worker's response...
but I think I can help her.
What did Meredith say?
That's the part I haven't figured out.
Tell Meredith to blow up
the air mattress,
a teenage drug addict
is moving in with her kid.
Yeah, I don't think that's gonna fly.
I'll figure something out.
She bought a dress...
just to see her baby.
Or maybe she stole it.
I don't know. Either way...
She cares about him.
She should be with Leo.
It will give her something
real to fight for.
Wait. No, that's not what I'm saying.
You are great with Leo.
That's your thing. I don't want
to mess that up for you.
No, no, you're not. She's his mother.
If there's a shot that Leo can
have his mother in his life...
I want to give him that.
Really?
Really.
So, you guys should stay with us.
But Leo's mine, she's yours, okay?
Okay, but I don't want to feel
like I'm stealing your thunder.
Okay, Amelia, how about we don't
make this all about you?
You know, I wasn't comparing Ellis Grey
to Harper Avery earlier.
I was talking about our moms.
They've both been through
a ton of obstacles,
they both made sure
we had an amazing future,
and now I have to take hers away.
Well, how does your mother...
Well, she's trying to take
the fall for this whole thing.
I mean, Harper Avery's name's
all over it, but she built it.
It's her heart and soul
that went into it.
I mean, it's not as easy as just
giving back an award, you know?
You think that was easy?
I worked my whole life for that award.
I'm pissed! You know,
I'm mainly pissed at my mother
for selling out Marie Cerone.
And then, when I think back on it,
it was all due to the behavior
of one awful man.
And then, I get mad at myself
for blaming the women.
Why do we do that?
Why is it so easy to blame the women?
A couple thousand years of patriarchy.
Okay, so, now do you care to explain
why you threw $100 million
at a contest that you could win?
Look, I created the contest
because I'm not allowed
to compete for Harper Avery.
I want to compete with the best...
an even playing field.
So, maybe it wasn't
the smartest thing in the world
to pay for the playing field,
but look what it created...
Webber's cancer pens.
You got Pierce's rechargeable hearts,
your mini livers, Robbin's crash cart,
Bailey's butt... thing.
But I lit that fire.
I created something
where there was nothing.
And even if they try to
take that from me...
if they shut down the contest...
I'm not gonna be ashamed of that.
Yeah, you could've just bought
a "World's Best Surgeon" trophy
and had your name engraved on it.
Are you ready to do this?
Not even a little bit.
You really didn't know?
About the contest?
No. No idea.
I'm just a wedding planner now.
Ugh, I could strangle him.
Right?
I mean, I just can't believe
that he did it.
I mean, everything I know about him,
it just doesn't seem like...
Wait, wait, wait. Jackson?
No. No, no, no,
Jackson has an explanation.
What? What is it?
Oh, I don't know what it is,
but he has one.
Maggie, I've known him for a long time.
He can be complicated but not morally,
not like that.
He's a good man.
He deserves the benefit of your doubt.
Webber, on the other hand...
that guy played me like a bassoon.
Bovie to me, please.
Finishing marking incision.
10 blade.
That... Mer, watch it. Watch it.
Kelly clamp.
Helm, suction.
Liga clamp.
Crap, he's bleeding from everywhere.
Bovie!
You know what?
We should reach out to them.
- Who? The women?
- Yeah.
And not just the ones
in the lawsuit, either.
I mean everybody who comes forward.
I don't care how many there are.
37, as of lunchtime today.
I get alerts on my phone.
And do what? Apologize, or write checks?
For starters. We can do more than that.
We can rebuild the foundation.
The foundation bears the name of the man
who sexually assaulted them.
Their lives and careers were destroyed.
And now they have to see
the name of their abuser
on hospitals all over the world?
He's been lauded and celebrated
while they suffered in silence.
If you want to rebuild,
you have to tear it down first.
You're right. I'm not putting
him through this ever again.
I'm taking the whole thing out right now.
Prepare the saw.
Tumor comes out... here we go.
It's good. Says what we want to
and sets the record straight.
Well, hopefully, it'll get the job done.
Oh, I think it will.
Places enough blame on you
that people will feel like
a real change was made.
I'll call a press conference.
This can't wait till the morning.
Okay, you know what?
Let's just take a breather
and think this thing through.
Honey, look...
Hey, Mom!
I think we found a solution
that all of us can live with.
Uh, well, we beat you to the punch.
But we would love to have you
on camera next to your mother...
You know what? Let's hold it.
I-I want to hear what they have to say.
Sweetheart, I've already
written my statement.
Erin wants me to read this to the press.
Yeah, no. We're not doing this.
Well, you're too late.
You're fired. You can go now.
Now wait just a minute. I...
I'll be damned if I'm gonna
let my grandfather do to you
what he did to all these women.
Just read it.
"The time has come for new
vision, new light, and new hope.
We know that a culture can't
change with a single statement.
Comprehensive,
systemic change is required.
But let that change begin now...
with the dissolution of
the Harper Avery Foundation,
effective immediately."
Darling, this is insane.
- Thank you.
- Keep reading, please.
"In its place, a new foundation,
dedicated to the preservation
and nurturing
of all 72 hospitals..."...
If I am not buying this,
I don't know how you think
the public will.
Why are you still here?
Because I am trying to save you
from committing financial suicide.
Will you please just read
the underlined part?
"We also make a solemn promise...
To give voice to those who were silenced.
To listen to, and to learn from,
every woman's story.
To repay, retrain, and rehire
every victim of Harper Avery's abuse.
We hope you'll join us in
supporting, with enthusiasm...
...the Catherine Fox Foundation.
Sincerely yours, Catherine Fox."
Ugh. What a lovely moment this is.
A billion-dollar moment, one might say.
Honestly, the name idea was Meredith's.
It was all him.
But can we please get this re-engraved,
because I worked way too hard for it.
"Meet me at my house?
Come through the back door?"
It's all so mysterious.
Shh. DeLuca.
Oh. Oh.
I get why you did it.
You wanted to compete. I get it.
Thank you.
You were very impressive today.
- Was I?
- It was hot.
Still gonna be hot if I go broke?
Are you going broke for noble reasons?
Maybe.
Yep, still hot.
Cooking?
Oh, I'm full of surprises.
Risotto.
Salmon.
It was a stupid idea, anyway.
She probably thought
I was some nut job...
"Hey, we just met.
Why don't you move in with me?"
Amelia...
...she's here.
She showed.
Oh, God. Um...
I'm her Ollie.
Okay.
Well, if this is gonna work,
there need to be ground rules.
First off,
you text your family... tonight.
You let them know that you're safe
and that you're off the streets.
You cannot do drugs at all, okay?
That is a non-starter.
I can give you a prescription
to take the edge off your
withdrawal, but that's all.
And you have to come with me to meetings.
She's so bossy.
Oh, yeah.
We define ourselves by our actions.
Who's ready to go home?
But it doesn't mean we have
to live by that definition.
We can change our own story.
Robbins?
I'm glad I caught you.
You're close with DeLuca, right?
Close? Well, we were roommates,
so, yeah, okay.
Okay. So, I'm worried about him.
Maggie brought him home about a week ago,
and he hasn't gotten off the couch since.
I mean, I'm literally gonna have
to put it out on the sidewalk
- when he leaves.
- Ooh, yikes.
Yeah. So, I was hoping you could
talk to him, maybe.
We can refuse to accept the way
people define us.
I don't that I'm the person for the job,
but I think I do know
the person you should talk to.
We can work like hell
to escape a bad reputation...
...only to wonder if we succeeded.
Okay, we're having it out right now.
Oh, come on. You're seriously
gonna listen to
some nurse I slept with
when I was a stupid intern?
No! I'm talking about
your psycho mood swings
and treating me like crap all day.
I won't do weirdness
and silence and anger, Alex.
I can't do that again.
It's not what you think.
It started when I asked you
to check your bank account.
Is it money?
Are we really fighting about money?
Because that is such a cliché.
I grew up in my fricking car, Alex.
Do you think I care if
you're having money problems?
It's not.
I have money...
way too much money.
I haven't checked this account
in over a year,
and all of a sudden,
my balance is crazy high.
Okay.
It's my mom.
I send her money for rent and food,
and she hasn't been cashing the checks.
Which means she's dead
or walking the streets half-naked
or throwing garbage at people.
I'm out here living my life,
and I'm just throwing money
at a problem without paying attention.
I don't know.
Maybe I haven't really changed that much.
No. That's not true.
You know that that's not true.
It can be hard to shake
the mistakes of the past.
They'll always come back to haunt us.
Dr. Miranda Bailey?
I told y'all, I have no comment
about the ongoing Harper Avery...
Sanjay Roy. I'm representing a client
in a wrongful-termination suit.
Wrongful...
Well, who was wrongfully terminated?
My client is Dr. Vikram Roy.
Roy?
Is this your brother?
Dr. Roy was under your employ
when he was fed
psychotropic marijuana cookies
by a superior in the workplace.
This is just a courtesy visit,
to inform you
we'll we suing for restitution
of employment
as well as unspecified damages
for pain and suffering.
I have weekend plans, but I'm
happy to start back on Monday.
But one thing we never do...
we don't stop. We don't quit.
Hey, Garfunkel...
Leave me alone.
I have something for you.
We get up and rejoin the fight.
Andrew, this is disgusting.
Oh, no, no, no. Why did...
No, no, no, no. Why did...
No, come on.
Please, God, don't let him
forget his guitar.
Synced & corrected by -robtor-
www.addic7ed.com