Got a 41-year-old male.
Status post: grand mal seizure.
Any history?
Found a bottle of
Dilantin. He's post ictal.
What's open? Curtain 3. I think.
Coming through!
Can I help you?
Uh, no.
Draw 10 of Ativan, give two now.
Need a Dilantin level.
Did you mess with
my IV? Look at it.
I didn't touch it. That's how
it was when I picked it up
If the bag is empty, you
ask them to change it.
Did you see my wallet?
They took my wallet.
Mr. Parker, stop worrying.
Whoa. Sorry.
Four units of pac
cells, chest film.
Where's Benton? He's on his way.
We need him. We need
a Foley and an NG. Go.
Okay, lift your tongue.
That should help.
I'm in. Set me up
for a chest tube.
What time are you off?
Hey. What are you doing
here? It's almost midnight.
What time are you off?
Now.
Coming up tomorrow...
I'm going now.
Okay. Thank you, Mrs. Anderson.
I put the nice
tablecloth in the washer,
and you should
tumble-dry it on low.
And if you need
anything, you'll call me,
because my number's
right there on the fridge.
Uh-huh. I will.
Uh... And, Mark...
I'm really sorry.
She was a lovely woman.
Yeah. I know.
Okay. Good night.
Good night.
You're not afraid about
waking up the neighbors?
Harold's deaf as a post.
They all leave?
Yeah.
Good.
What are you making?
I promised your mother
I'd build her a linen chest.
'Kay.
Good night.
That was a good
speech you gave today.
Those things you
said about your mother.
I had good material.
Yeah.
The color guard was nice, Dad.
You okay?
Depends what "okay" means.
You want me to stick
around a little longer?
A few days?
Rachel loves San Diego.
Dad?
Doesn't seem real, Mark.
I buried my wife today.
Ow.
Fun stuff, huh?
So, you get a good
look at the bastards?
Well, they're skaters.
They all look the same.
Dr. Malucci?
It's Dr. Dave to you, Lucy.
No new fractures.
Jeez, Rick, it looks like you
banged up your chin before.
They don't like the way I dress.
Last time they slammed
my head in a car door.
Like they're the
height of fashion.
Hasn't your principal
done anything about this?
Where did you go to school?
I'll let that get numb,
come back and stitch ya up.
Um, Mr. Zito, the
COPD'er, is retaining.
Can I decrease his O-2?
Sure. Why not?
Two liters?
Hey, Dave?
'Scuse me. Did you
call Plastics on that lip?
Uh, nah, I got it.
If it's through-and-through
and crosses the vermilion
border we call Plastics.
Well, he already has a scar...
All the more reason.
Randy's got the on-call list.
Two liters, okay? What?
How much should
I decrease his O-2?
Ooh. I don't know.
Crank it down.
If he turns blue,
crank it back up.
You're kidding, right?
No. Purple ain't good.
Just keep his pulse
ox above 90. Okay.
Hey, it's Jackie Joyner.
Hi, Jackie, nice spandex.
Get a life.
That's good.
She's hot for me.
You've been here three
days, she's hot for ya?
Doesn't take long, bro.
Looks like your drunk is back.
Aw, dude, what happened?
I discharged you two hours ago.
You gotta know when to hold 'em.
He was passed out in
the middle of Wabash.
When did he have time?
You haven't met Vodka Joe?
Some days he's in
two or three times.
You gotta know when to fold 'em.
Should've left his IV in.
Nice of you to bring
him back, officer.
Just doing my duty, ma'am.
Ya gotta know when to walk away.
Exactly. You...
You got this? I got it.
Thank you so much.
Hey, sweetheart.
You wanna meet
up with a gambler?
Hey, hey, watch it,
cowboy. That's my fiancée.
Reggie... What?
Fiancée? You guys engaged?
Not exactly. Pretty much.
Know when to run!
I want to commend
the Surgical Service
on their timely response
and clinical competence.
We had excellent outcomes
with no significant delays...
Hey. Can you cover
for me this morning?
I have outpatient clinic.
Yeah, I... But,
uh, it's important.
Performance... You have
something to add, Dr. Benton?
No.
Then please give us the
courtesy of your full attention.
As a final note,
you should all offer
Dr. Corday your congratulations
since most of you
will be working with her
in her new position as
associate chief of surgery.
All departmental concerns can
be funneled through her office,
including O.R. schedules,
research funding,
uh, committee assignments,
et cetera, et cetera.
Uhh, thank you and
have a good day.
Melanoma?
It started as a small
mole on her back,
but it was stage four,
metastasized all over.
Liver, lungs, then her brain.
She failed chemo?
Six cycles.
Then immunotherapy.
Pulse ox 89 on two liters.
Possible pleural effusion.
There's fluid in her lungs.
Last time it was this
bad they had to drain it.
Has she had a seizure recently?
No. Why?
Might explain her
altered mental status.
She's been out of
it for the last month.
Her oncologist feels
it's the brain mets
or the liver failure.
I see.
Let's get a chest
x-ray, CBC, PT, PTT.
Look, you should know something.
She doesn't want to
go back to the ICU.
She has a "do not
resuscitate" order?
I just brought her in because
her breathing and pain
seemed to worsen. I thought you
could make her more comfortable.
Well, that we can do.
Oh, Mark. When did you get back?
Late last night.
Plane was delayed four
hours out of San Diego.
How did it go?
All right, I guess.
Rough, huh?
Wow, you grew in a week.
Thanks, Mark.
Dr. Carter.
Hey, Dr. Greene. I'm
sorry about your mom.
Thanks. What do you got?
Uh, 20-year-old girl,
end-stage melanoma.
Mark, can we have coffee later?
Uh, you on all day?
Yeah. I just started.
She's DNR actually.
Her Father just brought
her in 'cause she's in pain.
What is this all about?
What? Oh, that's Dr. Weaver's
new charting system.
Uh-huh, what was
wrong with the old one?
It's actually kind of cool.
There's a separate form
for every chief complaint.
Uh-huh. Multiple-choice
medicine?
Yeah, sort of. So anyway
I was thinking about doing
a thoracentesis or
tapping her belly.
Did you get a chest x-ray?
Yeah. Shooting now.
Well, I'd pull up the old ones
for comparison.
Mark. Welcome back.
Thanks, Kerry. Nice
new, uh, checklist.
Oh, yeah. It's
great. The T-system.
I'll train you on
it later, okay.
Can't wait.
Lizzie. Twenty minutes.
It took you 20 minutes to
come and see me. I'm shocked.
I thought it would
be five... Ten tops.
What's all this about, Robert?
No "Thank you, I'm honored"?
No "I hope I don't disappoint"?
Everyone thinks you're serious.
That's because I
am serious, Lizzie.
You know me, I'm bound to
ruffle a few feathers in this job.
I need you to
smooth things over.
Walk with me. I
have to hit the head.
If you wanted to
offer me a position,
why didn't you ask me privately?
Where's the fun in that?
I knew you'd take it.
I haven't taken it.
Oh, is that a "no"?
I didn't think so.
As much as you may view
me as a loathsome toad,
I know your pragmatic
and, more predictably,
your ambitious
nature will prevail.
You'll leapfrog
five or six years.
That's not the point.
No, the point is, I'm
handing this to you.
A fast-track career.
Independence in the O.R.
The freedom to make
your own schedule
with the minor
annoyance, of course,
of having to report to me.
I don't view you as a
loathsome toad, Robert.
Well, I can't tell you how happy
I am to hear that, Elizabeth.
There's a smile.
Oh, he's a cutie, huh?
You're gonna break
some hearts, aren't ya?
It's time for his cocktail.
Any side effects?
No. He's a trouper.
The pneumonia's cleared up.
He's eating solids.
Normal white count?
Yeah, 10,000.
All done.
Such a good boy.
I'm gonna miss you.
Is he being discharged?
DCFS will be here soon.
So they found a foster family.
No, he's going to an
Emergency Intake Center.
He needs foster care.
One-on-one nurturing.
Intake's temporary.
I'm sure they'll find someone.
Someone who'll want
to adopt an HIV baby?
That mother is not
gonna pull though.
That mother died yesterday.
TM's are clear.
You talk funny.
Hunter.
Thank you.
Say "ah." Ahh.
That's 'cause he's
from very far way.
How far?
How far? So far that
it's dark there already.
Throat's red, all right.
Probably an, uh,
upper-respiratory infection.
So he'll need antibiotics?
No, usually it's viral.
Just give him lots of fluids.
Okay.
I'll come back soon, okay?
Uh, we should do a
rapid strep to be sure.
You got it.
So where are you from?
Croatia.
Oh. Wow.
Here's a prescription
if it's positive.
Great. Uh, you forgot Tylenol.
Usually the docs give a
standing order for fever.
Yes, but, uh, fevers
have a purpose.
Yeah, they tell us
when someone's sick.
And it's the body's natural
way to fight infection.
That's good, no?
I suppose.
So... why stop it?
Make the kid feel better?
Okay.
Uh, got a LOL in
three. Needs a nurse.
Not much I can do for
her. Hey. How ya doin'?
I told the mediator I'm not
trying to take Reece from Carla.
But I can't let Carla
take Reece from me.
Do you think she's
doing this to hurt you?
Well, she doesn't seem to care.
Do you care about her situation?
What is it?
I've just never talked to a...
A therapist before.
Dr. Benton,
I'm not here to
psychoanalyze you.
I only need to assess the
family dynamic for the court.
Well, it's simple. Carla
and I both love our son.
But she's trying to
take him away from me
so her new husband
can pursue his career.
How do you feel about him?
Who, Roger? Yes.
He's a decent guy, I guess.
Good to your son?
Yeah, sure. Loves him?
Look, why are we
talking about Roger?
Who cares about Roger? This
is about me, Reece and Carla.
Like it or not, he
factors into this.
How do you think
you'd deal with it
if Carla was able to take
Reece out of the country?
That's not gonna happen.
If it did?
The two most recent chest
films are June 28th and July 17th.
I'll take the folder.
Hey, congratulations.
Nice to know you're in the loop.
So it's true.
Sorry, Carter, I have a patient.
Aye, aye, chief. Please.
Here ya go.
Vanessa?
I'm sorry, I didn't
mean to disturb you.
You're in the hospital.
The nursing home sent you over.
One of the nurses
brought this by.
She said you don't usually
let it out of your sight.
Maggie. I think so.
I wish I had the discipline
to keep a journal.
Oh, it's not mine.
Paul kept it.
I just like it near me.
Is that the sacred heart?
You're Catholic.
Eastern Orthodox. Sort of.
I hope it works out for you.
I'm sorry?
In the end it doesn't help
much. It didn't help Paul.
Hard to believe in a God that
does that to a man like him.
Too bad.
Heaven sounds good right now.
Would you like
to talk to a priest?
Oh, God, no.
We have them on call.
Ah, don't trouble yourself.
It's really no bother.
Oh, really, don't.
Bob.
Hi. Hi.
Did you get my page?
I'm sorry, I'm
swamped. What's up?
You're discharging the
Ortega baby to Intake?
Yeah, I couldn't find anybody.
I'll take him.
What?
I'll take him
home. I'll take him.
You're a licensed foster parent?
No, but I can become one.
That's nice of you
but I'm afraid
not very realistic.
Why not? Well, you
have to be screened first
then have a few
months training...
I-I can do all of that
and take care of
him in the meantime.
It has to be better than Intake.
He needs a mother.
Do you have any other children?
No. I can focus on him.
Support system?
I can do it.
I don't know. It's not policy.
Maybe it'll be a good,
short-term solution
until I can find a
licensed foster parent.
Or until I get licensed.
Let me look into it.
No promises.
Okay.
Hey.
Mwah!
Hey, Reece.
How are you doing?
Hey, Carla.
Peter.
Ms. Simmons?
I'm Debra Wexler.
Hi.
Whenever you're ready.
Uh.
Go ahead. It's pretty painless.
Go ahead, Reece. Go to Mommy.
Go ahead. Go. Go.
Oh, I know. I know. It's okay.
Hey, man. It's okay. It's okay.
Hey, Reece.
Hey, I'll see you later, huh?
I'll see you later. I love you.
I know. I love you.
Loculated fluid around
the lungs and lots of mets.
Is this going to help?
Belly was pretty tense.
It's gonna relieve
some abdominal pain
and take pressure
off the diaphragm.
But she's still going to
have trouble breathing.
This is three liters.
Okay.
I'll take this to the lab.
You have a payphone around here?
I'm gonna have
to call her mother.
Sure. I'll take you.
I'll be right back, okay?
I'll be right back. Okay.
You didn't call.
Oh, I... Sorry, I got in late.
You okay?
Yeah.
How's your dad?
We'll see.
He was shaken up
but... I don't know.
Numb.
Mom was okay.
And then, boom. Heart attack.
It's gonna take a while for
it to sink in for him, I guess.
And you?
I don't know.
I did hear a vicious
rumor about you.
Really? Which one?
Well, it was actually, uh,
more of an announcement.
It was as much a
shock to me as anyone.
What is he up to?
Oh, you know Robert. He
always has to be dramatic.
Yeah, but why'd he pick you?
I don't know.
Perhaps he thinks
I'm a talented surgeon.
That's not what I meant.
You're not gonna
take it, are you?
I was considering it, yes.
Okay. What?
Nothing.
So I'm going to have
to deal with Romano.
Well, he's a small price to
pay for such an advancement.
It's better than anything
I could get at rush.
If you say so.
Stop it.
If you feel the need
to express an opinion,
at least articulate it.
Fine.
You can't trust that guy.
He screwed you in the past.
He's not gonna
hesitiate to do it again.
But I think you know that.
Yes, and it's my
problem, isn't it?
I think it will be.
Okay, Rick, you're on
soup and milkshakes
for a couple of days.
Stitches come out in five.
When can I get this pierced?
Gonna put that thing back in?
Screw that. I'm not
gonna let those losers win.
Good for you, bro. I'll
see ya next time then.
Finally got ahold
of Plastics, huh.
Nice job, huh?
Did you even call 'em, Dave?
Yeah, I called 'em.
They tried to recruit me.
Hey. I need two milligrams
of morphine for Mrs. Braga.
Braga?
Your LOL.
Oh, yeah. Sure.
Don't you want to see her?
No, I trust you.
Is that roach coach
out there all day?
Yeah.
Hi, I sent up peritoneal fluid.
Patient name:
Stehly. S-T-E-H-L-Y.
Medical record
number: 4-5-2-9-8-6.
Okay, thank you.
Hi. How are you?
How are you?
I'm famished. I was
in the neighborhood,
so I thought I'd stop by and see
if you wanted to get some lunch.
In the neighborhood?
Yeah. I had a meeting
in the Hancock Building.
So can you slip away?
I don't know. Um...
Hey. Whose rig is that?
Yo, Betsy, whose rig is that?
What are you screaming about?
Paramedics who drive
that rig, where are they?
I don't know. Try
the cafeteria. Why?
Hey, Dave, what's goin' on?
Call 911! Construction
site accident!
Well, hang on a second! Hold on!
You're busy. Tonight?
Tonight's a given.
What are you doing,
Dave? Gotta help this guy.
His friend is trapped.
What happened?
Workin' the crane,
dropped a beam,
we can't get him
out. Ran here for help.
A block away. Your
friend conscious?
No. Is he breathing?
I don't know! Are you coming?
Hold on.
County to dispatch,
we have reports
of a construction site accident
on the 1200 block of Clybourn.
We need you there code three.
Come on, man, let's go,
We don't have time. Come on.
Docs responding.
If he's breathing,
we don't touch him.
Yes, Mom.
It's right there!
How'd it happen? Oh, God.
The choker must have
slipped. It swung right into him!
Coming through. Come on, doc
Hey, I want you to be careful!
I don't want you to burn him!
I almost got it!
Anybody call 911?
Ain't you the 911 guy?
Nah, you get the
real deal, my friend.
Go back to the truck and
make sure Gordy called! Go now!
Sir? Sir, can you
tell me your name?
- What's his name?
- Joe. Joe Sanders.
Mr. Sanders!
Be careful!
Pulse: weak and thready.
Mr. Sanders!
His leg is totally crushed.
I don't see his chest moving.
We gotta tube him. We
gotta get in there first.
You can reach him,
right? Yeah, but I can't see.
We gotta do it.
Ever done a blind intervention?
No, but we gotta do something.
I'll do it.
Come on, let me.
This isn't a teaching case.
Find a window. Be my eyes.
All right. I'll talk
you through it.
Hey, watch it!
Something's loose!
All right, where am I?
Move to the left. No,
wrong way, wrong way.
My left or your left?
My left, your right.
Okay.
Okay, that's his cheek.
You gotta move over.
That's his ear.
There you go, there
you go. Move up.
you go. Open it. Bingo!
You got it?
Hold on.
Have you done this before?
Once.
On a cadaver.
All right. All right...
There's the epiglottis.
I'm in the vallecula.
All right.
Put it down the right pipe.
Yeah.
I hear EMS boys.
Too little, too late.
All right, I'm in!
Amy, you need to keep
that mask on, okay?
Amy.
I can't... breathe.
Amy, my name is Dr. Greene.
You're in the hospital.
Your father brought
you here. Okay?
I need you to keep that mask on.
Okay?
Help me.
Amy,
I can give you some morphine
to make you more comfortable.
Not today.
What?
I don't want to die today.
Do you want me to
put you on a ventilator
to help you breathe?
Is that what you want?
There's a good chance
you'll never come off of it.
I Don't want... to die.
Lydia.
I need rapid induction,
15 milligrams
etomidate, 100 of sux.
You're gonna intubate?
Yes.
She's a DNR.
Not anymore.
Let's go.
She was on a vent for
over two weeks in that ICU.
Then she had a
stent for her liver
and needed over eight units of
blood. Now, she's had enough.
Okay, listen. I
understand your feelings,
but this is what she wanted.
You don't know what she
wants. She signed a DNR.
Coming through. Watch yourself.
She changed her mind.
Crush injury to the left leg.
Why'd she tell you and not me?
Where's Dr. Benton?
He's on his way.
It's a femur fracture, why
didn't you use a Sager splint?
There was debate about that.
Hypotensive. Had to get
here. You were in the field?
Super-docs had him intubated.
He wasn't breathing.
On my count. One, two, three.
What do we got, people?
Crane operator versus
H-beam. Plowed right into him.
Multiple blunt trauma.
Crushed left femur.
Why wasn't he put in traction?
Crashing. We were wasting time.
You got it from here,
Peter? Yeah, go.
You've known her for
20 minutes. I'm her father.
How many times do I
need to tell you this?
She does not want
this. We decided.
Excuse me. I'm Dr. Weaver,
chief of the emergency department.
I've got it, Kerry.
Are you his supervisor?
What seems to be the problem?
My daughter is dying
of cancer, and she has
a "do not resuscitate" order.
And when I left the room,
he put her on a ventilator
and now he won't take her off.
She asked me to.
She wouldn't do that!
Do you have the papers with you?
I can get them.
Maybe you should.
Now that your
daughter's intubated, it...
It gets a little complicated.
What are you talking about?
I'm not sure that we
should extubate her
until she's breathing
on her own.
BP's 90/60. Pulse, 110.
He's bleeding.
Peritoneal lavage. Let's go.
Hold on. Let the
doctor take it from here.
Yeah, I am a doctor. He
only thinks he's a paramedic.
This is Dave Malucci,
new second-year Resident.
Dr. Dave. Okay,
good breath sounds.
Yo, DPL. Let's go.
Hold on, hold on, Dr. Dave.
All right, let's get
a trauma panel,
lateral C-spine, chest
and pelvis, left femur.
Who is this guy?
Surgical trauma fellow.
Call him "Dr. Pete."
You want O-neg?
Yeah, four units.
Get a pressure dressing,
put him in traction,
set me up for DPL.
Is there an echo in here?
Didn't I just say that?
Get outta here. What?
I said, out. Get
out. What did I do?
I don't understand.
Dave, let's go.
Come on, I'm not
leaving. This is our patient.
You wanna be
the hero in the field
you gotta drop
'em off at the door.
Shut up! Carter. Now!
Hey, hey, hey.
Okay. Let's get a new
kit. You okay, Carol?
Yeah. Fine. All right.
Come on, let's go.
I'm gonna call my lawyer.
I can't believe you did this.
Mark? What are you doing?
My job, Kerry. It's
not your problem.
It is my problem. I'm
head of the department.
Eh. By title, remember?
You said so yourself.
I don't know what
your problem is,
but steal my gear
again, I'll kick your ass.
He wasn't breathing. They
teach the importance of an airway
in paramedic school? Relax!
We didn't know where you
were, it sounded important,
and it was down the street.
What if we were called
to a site and didn't
have our equipment?
It's in there. Go rip
it out of his throat.
Let's break it up.
This is not the
appropriate time or place.
You wanna take it outside?
I'll take it outside.
Nobody's taking
anything anywhere.
Zadro, go back to work.
What's the point?
I got doctors to do it for me.
Go back to work. Get outta here.
You two, hold on.
Hold on. Get back here.
Can we tell you what happened?
I heard what happened. Do
you have a brain between you?
Dr. Weaver, we
called them... No! No!
I talk, you listen.
You work in this
hospital, not on the street.
You are not trained for it.
You are not covered for it.
And you have patients
here who need your attention.
One of them might have coded.
Or... Or we might have been hit
with two or three other
traumas while you were off
playing paramedic. Were you?
Don't even start
with me, Dr. Malucci.
I'm only cutting you this much
slack because you're new here.
And you, Carter, you
should know better.
You're emergency
Residents, not paramedics.
Is that understood?
Is it understood?
That was great, Dave.
Thanks. I appreciate that.
We document all
consents in the chart.
Is there a problem?
You didn't tell me you
tested the baby for HIV?
I told you he was positive.
I thought we were assuming.
I didn't know you tested him
without the mother's consent?
The mother was comatose.
We had to get him started
on the antiviral drugs.
Well, who authorized it?
I did.
I was looking out for the baby.
We gained 10 days of treatment.
You broke the law.
Will this affect your
decision about foster care?
I'll have to
explain this. Will it?
No. You obviously
care about the child.
But?
It's not gonna work.
Why not?
The director won't
approve it. Did you ask?
I'm sorry, Jeanie. I
said I'd look into it.
I did.
Is it because I'm black?
What?
I'm black. The baby's Hispanic.
What do you take me for?
I'm not really sure.
'Cause you'd rather
put him in a facility
even after I told you
that I would take him.
You're not qualified.
It's as simple as that.
Is it because of my HIV status?
It doesn't help.
Look, I'm healthy.
There's no reason to think that
I won't continue to be healthy.
What about when the child is 5?
When he's 10? Can
you say that then?
Can anyone say that?
Look, I don't know how to
tell you no any other way.
I know his needs.
I would be bet...
It's no, Miss Boulet.
The answer is no.
Lavage is negative.
Lost a few liters from
the popliteal artery.
What's the tibia look like?
Fracture in 20
pieces. Ah, it's a mess.
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Where
do you think you're going?
Shirley cleared O.R. 1.
Yeah, thanks for
buffing him up, Peter,
but Lizzie can
take it from here.
Yeah, but he's a trauma patient.
Indeed he is. And this
trauma fellowship of yours
is through the ER,
correct? Yeah? So?
So that's an O.R.
That's for surgeons.
I've been operating the last
three weeks as a trauma fellow.
Yes, I know. But
now as chief of staff,
I have to be concerned
with credentials.
You chose this. Not me.
Elizabeth, I leave it up to
you. Under no circumstances
is that man to go into
that operating room,
call security if you have to
and enjoy your
first solo surgery.
Solo? Yes.
An associate chief
can operate by herself.
Dr. Benton.
Peter?
Hey.
You okay?
Uh, this case.
That dying girl...
Dad's called a lawyer. Weaver...
Forget it.
Mark, maybe you
should take a few days off.
I-I just had a week off.
That wasn't a vacation, Mark.
Losing a parent is
as stressful as it gets.
I oughta get back to work.
Why isn't he here?
Vanessa?
I'm sorry?
Is who coming?
El padre. The priest?
Why isn't he here?
No. You told me not to.
I don't want to go alone.
Okay. Okay. He'll be here.
Jeanie, I didn't know
that you were considering
becoming a foster parent.
Robert Martin called
me this afternoon
asking for a referral.
I think that'd be great.
Yeah. Unfortunately,
it's not gonna work out.
Why not?
I didn't get a clear answer.
I guess too many things
stacked against me.
Is there anything I can do?
No. Thanks, Kerry.
Some things aren't meant
to be. I'll see you tomorrow.
Next time wait till they
stop swinging at the piñata
before you dive
for the candy, okay?
Excuse me. Mark.
Uh, Mr. Stehly's
making a lot of noise.
I'm gonna need a detailed record
regarding the care
of his daughter.
Your new charting
system should help.
This is serious, Mark.
Do you understand the
position you put us in?
I followed the standard of care
based upon my patient's wishes.
She's over 18.
She signed a DNR and gave
her father power of attorney.
She still has rights.
Dr. Greene, Amy's throwing PVCs.
How many? Ten to 12.
Did you give her
lidocaine? Not yet.
Just want to make sure
she's no longer DNR?
Yes. No.
So, what do I do if she codes?
Resuscitate her.
No, Carter, don't.
Kerry, she's my patient.
I can't allow you to
ignore a standing DNR.
She revoked her DNR.
She can't. Yes, she can.
Not with altered mental status.
Did you see her CT?
That girl has mets
all over her brain.
She's on morphine.
Probably hypoxic.
I talked to her, Kerry.
She was clear,
conscious and alert.
Well, I didn't see that.
You're gonna have to trust me.
I'm not sure you're in
the state of mind right now
to be objective.
Kerry... Perhaps, I should
take over on this one.
I've got it covered.
Mark, I'm taking this patient.
You're gonna
have to fire me first.
So, what do I do if she codes?
Nothing, Carter.
You do nothing.
If she codes, call me, Carter.
Randi, are you
sure this list is right?
I've paged Father Erps twice.
Oh, I think he's on
sabbatical in Brazil.
There's a junior
Jesuit subbing for him.
Well, where's his number?
It's around here somewhere.
Find it, Randi. The lady
doesn't have much time.
Lucy, where's Malucci?
He prefers "Dr. Dave."
Whatever. Where is he?
I don't know. Try
the Coast Guard.
Maybe he's off doing
search and rescue.
What's the problem?
This woman's BP
is down to 60 palp.
Her kidneys have shut
down. She needs dopamine.
I got it. Really?
Yep. Thank you.
Carol, have you seen Mark?
He was just here.
Is he still on?
I think so.
Hey, Elizabeth.
I hear you laid up
today in the O.R.
"Laid up"?
Golf term. Played it safe.
Lived to cut another day.
That's not a criticism. We
all get more conservative
when we're in the driver's seat.
Welcome to the big leagues.
Listen, Robert. About Peter...
Peter, Peter, Peter. Don't you
ever get tired of that subject?
He accepted this
fellowship on the assumption
he'd be operating on his
trauma patients. He's a...
I know. I'm just
messing with him.
So you'll let him operate?
Mm. For you, Lizzie... anything.
But only on trauma,
not elective cases,
and no general surgery.
Naturally. I want
you to police him.
I don't wanna deal with it.
Fine.
So, is that an official
acceptance of my offer?
I suppose it is, yes.
Wise choice. I'll
see you tomorrow.
Oh, uh, here's a,
uh, termination list.
We need to cut loose
some dead weight,
and it'll sound better
coming from you.
Dr. Corday.
Uh, Carter, have you seen Mark?
Uh, he's around here someplace.
Uh, I think you saw a patient
of mine in Radiology today.
Nichols? Your patient?
Yeah. Came in a couple
weeks ago. Fender bender.
Said she had some
minor cervical tenderness.
Did I miss something?
No, it was nothing
to do with an accident.
She came for a second opinion.
Ah. On, uh... On what?
Infiltrating duct
cell carcinoma.
Breast cancer.
So she's, um,
looking at surgery?
Has to have a
mastectomy, I'm afraid.
Mm.
Carter! This girl's in V-tach!
What? Trauma 1!
You need some help?
No. No, I got it.
She have a pulse? A weak one.
What's her BP?
Sixty palp. Paddles are ready.
Dr. Carter?
Get Dr. Greene. Get my cardio.
Let's open up the pads.
No need, Haleh. She's a DNR.
Dr. Weaver...
It's all right, John.
I understand that you're
in an awkward position.
You... You're
gonna let her arrest?
I'll take it from here.
How about a chemical code?
No.
This woman is not
to be resuscitated.
Just an amp of lidocaine.
John, she has no chance
of a meaningful recovery.
She wanted this.
Her family wants it.
Don't touch her.
I know.
But I want to believe.
Now you can.
He forgives me?
He forgives you.
Can you bless me, Father?
Padre.
Where is she?
V-fib.
Damn you, Kerry. All
right, Carter, start CPR.
Let's charge to 200.
Haleh, charge to 200 now.
Okay, Kerry, you're chief.
You need to make a decision.
We do this, or I go.
Ready.
Clear!
Three hundred.
Charging. Push in amp of epi.
How far are you gonna go?
She wanted a ventilator.
Did she say she wanted this?
Clear!
Still in V-fib.
All right. One more time,
360. One hundred of lidocaine.
Did she say she wanted
you pounding on her chest,
shocking her heart?
Shut up, Kerry!
Or get outta here!
Clear!
Asystole.
You want atropine?
No. It's over.
Time of death, 20:34.
Mark, I...
Hey there. Hi.
What are you doing here?
I need to talk to you.
What's wrong.
I've been thinking... Uh. Oh.
No, listen. That day
when you proposed to me,
most of me just
wanted to scream "Yes!"
and run to the courthouse
and do it right then.
Most of you?
But the rest of me was scared.
I... I knew that I loved you.
But I've just been with this
little baby who needed a mother.
And I knew instantly that I
wanted to be that mother.
I didn't wanna say yes
for the wrong reason.
I see.
But they told me today
that I can't have him.
Baby, I'm sorry.
No, it's okay.
It's okay because I know
that I really do
want to marry you.
I know that now.
Hm.
Do you still want to marry me?
Yes. Okay.
Isn't it a sin to
fake a sacrament?
It was a blessing. Anyone
can give a blessing.
Not posing as a priest.
It was her faith. That's
what's important, right?
So how did you know what to say?
I faked it.
You know, a little bit of Latin,
a little bit of Croatian.
You faked it well.
Ooh.
Are you all right?
Yeah. Yeah. It's
just, uh, there active,
moving around down there.
May I?
What?
You know.
Don't you?
Yes.
You should just leave now.
Elaine.
Peter.
Peter!
Did you hire a
private investigator?
What?
Some guy talked to Dafina
and asked her if
I've ever done drugs.
Whoa, Carla, the only
person I hired was my lawyer.
Well, did he get this guy
to start asking
questions about me?
No!
I... I... I don't know.
Why are you doing this?
Why am I doing this?
The restraining
orders and lawyers...
Carla, I only have one son.
Roger can get another damn job.
This is a great
opportunity for us, Peter.
What about Reece, huh?
Ever think about that?
You wanna take
him from his father?
You may not even be his father.
What?
He might not be yours.
Th-there was somebody else.
It was just casual.
And then there was you.
I did it for Reece.
Now, he needed a father,
and Roger can be that...
Look, Reece is my son, Carla!
Reece is my son.