Previously on ER.
‐ Well, that must be tough.
‐ What?
Competing with your boyfriend.
Not boyfriend, just competing.
Any indecision you're feeling
about your future
Dr. Benton, I can help.
Just say the word
and I will take
the cardiothoracic fellowship
off the table.
By all means, feel free to apply
for the trauma fellowship.
You're a little closed
off for my tastes.
‐ Closed off?
‐ Emotionally withdrawn.
Roxanne called. Twice.
‐ So..
So what?
You plannin' on going
through with the pregnancy?
I was hoping to.
What does Doug think?
I mean, do we even pretend to be
living in a democracy anymore?
You know, it's just
a medieval power play
between career
republicans and democrats
and who hates who more.
If there were still guillotines
and burning at the stake
I swear, they'd be
doing that to each other.
Uh‐huh.
Hey, this is where I do
two reps of ten.
You wanna go first?
‐ Go ahead.
‐ Okay.
I didn't know anybody
actually stopped at these.
Oh, yeah.
End of your first trimester
you get this sudden
burst of energy.
Just have to keep
my heart rate under 140.
So, did you read it?
Yeah.
What'd you think?
That it's a good letter.
You're very clear about what you
want and don't want from him.
Yeah, I had to write it
all out, you know? Whoo!
But you're gonna talk to him.
Oh, sure. Sure.
I just, uh, you know..
...after he reads it.
I know Doug's gonna
go on his gut reaction
and I don't want him
coming running back here.
You don't?
When are you gonna
send the letter?
I'm gonna fax it. I got his fax
number a couple of days ago.
What do you think he'll do?
Honestly..
...he'll be on the first plane.
'Oh, Lucy, Lucy, oh.
I'm late. I'm sorry.'
That's okay.
Thanks for meeting me.
I didn't mean to sound
so mysterious.
I didn't know what you drink.
Oh, no. Gave up caffeine for
lent. I didn't even miss it.
Look, let me get right to the
point. We're both busy people.
‐ Okay.
‐ It's about John.
‐ Carter?
‐ Yeah.
I've tried to bring
this up with him
and I got nowhere fast,
so let me have a run at you.
If you two are involved
you know, harmless
workplace flirtation
or out‐and‐out twice‐a‐day
sex in the lab.
Whatever, just,
someone needs to let me know
and I'll fold up my tent
and get out of the way.
Uh, there's nothing going on
between me and Carter.
Okay, maybe at one point I
thought there might be, but no.
I mean, we haven't really
spoken to each other
in the last few months.
Well..
...so much for that theory.
Honestly, Roxanne,
he works so hard
I doubt he has time
to cheat on you.
You mean our relationship
has just stalled out on its own?
I don't know about that.
Well, it has. I mean, it has.
We have been at the
lotta laughs phase
for two months too long.
I'm sorry to hear that.
You were my last resort for
an obstacle I could tackle.
I wish I had better
news for you.
You know, I don't envy you.
He's one mixed up guy.
Mmm.
He is.
Sweet...but mixed up.
A deadly combination.
Mm‐hmm.
'I think about your
breasts all day.'
They think about you.
'I'll come to
work with you.'
'Do. I want you to.'
Oh, I'm sorry.
'Oh, here we go again.'
I lost power twice last night.
We didn't.
'It's the weather.'
It's the humidity.
It's arcing at the substation.
Can't be late.
‐ I love you.
It's spring.
No, really, I, um, admire you.
I like emergency medicine.
Still, it takes guts.
What takes guts?
For Lucy to do another
ER Rotation.
It takes guts
to tackle something
that got the better of you
the first time around.
Glad you feel that way,
because you're gonna get
a second chance
to supervise her.
Carter, what am I supposed
to do with this?
Uh...I called UPS for a pickup.
If they're not here by this
afternoon, let me know?
‐ The oriental?
‐ Mm‐hmm.
Gotta be in Bangkok by Sunday.
Good boy, Carter. Mother's day.
Oh, no.
‐ Is that this week?
‐ You forgot your mothers?
Ah, I better call
the bowling alley.
That's what she likes.
So what are your kids doing
for you or is it a surprise?
Oh, big surprise every year.
Runny eggs
and burnt toast in bed
two hours before
I wanna wake up.
I can't wait.
I never let mother know
what's in store.
Last year it was a helicopter
ride and a concert in grant park
and this year, I've hired a limo
and I'm gonna take
her to all the places
she liked to take me as a kid.
The zoo, the Adler,
this little tea room
back in our old neighborhood.
What?
Didn't think I had
a mother, did you?
Just trying to picture her.
‐ So, what do we got here today?
‐ We?
Yeah, didn't Kerry tell you?
I'm spending the day down here.
Kerry just asked
for the day off.
Well, as acting chief poo‐bah
I decided I wanna get
a better understanding
of what the hell
goes on down here.
Okay, you wanna start with
oozing pustules
or projectile vomiting?
I don't wanna see patients.
I just want to watch and marvel.
After you.
So, together again?
Hey, bet you were about to call.
We got a late start
this morning.
Oh, hey, Reese.
Is Carla's van
in the shop again?
Uh, no. She just had
a big day today.
You know what. Next time she
gets stuck, tell her to call.
Ah, man, we weren't stuck.
I love being with Reese.
Alright. Let's get him in here.
So, I'll pick him up
at three, right?
No, I'll bring him home
after his speech therapy.
Oh, he's still in that?
I thought you were
going the signing route.
I'm not going any route. I'm
doing what's best for my son.
You're right. Be good, son.
Next?
76‐year‐old male
came in hypotensive
febrile with purulent sputum.
Septic.
Yeah, we had to tube him.
Brought his pressure up
with dopamine
and gave him
some cefotaxime.
So what's he doing here?
Why don't you get him
up the ICU?
We're waiting for
beds upstairs, aren't we?
Carol, can you tell
us what you have?
74 year old woman took a spill.
Temp's a little
elevated at 99.9.
Well, she fell out of her
wheelchair down the back stoop.
I‐I‐I was ringing the doorbell
up front and I heard the bang
and my heart sank.
I mean, you see, I'm‐I'm
the Armstrong's ' neighbor.
I‐I‐Insisted on driving them in.
BP's 160/90.
Mr. Armstrong reports symptoms
of disorientation.
Alzheimer's.
But they...they don't wanna
call it that.
H‐he frets about
his health plan.
Gladys doesn't have
her hearing aid in.
'I do the best I can
looking in on them.'
I mean, she's such a dear.
Army's not much of a cook.
Okay! I get the picture!
'Have Carter or Lucy
take a look.'
'Are they done? Is she okay?'
And that is why I prefer
my patients anesthetized.
Hey, is, uh, she putting
on a little weight?
That nurse what's her name?
Carol Hathaway?
Is she porking out a little bit?
Hate to see that happen.
I've had some decent
fantasies about that one.
Okay, in exam four, we have a
36 year old with calf pain..
...recurrent DVT
On a heparin drip.
Ever dream about Lizzie Corday?
What?
It'd be understandable.
It'd be one motive
I could follow
for the ER trying to poach her
away from surgery.
Uh, trauma fellowship is not
about poaching, Robert.
How long has it been, Mark?
Since you had a trauma
come in, I mean.
‐ What? Today?
‐ Yeah.
Five, six hours.
They usually‐‐
Okay, so, if you actually
had a trauma fellow
for the last five or six hours
that highly skilled
surgical resident
would've been sitting on
her pretty little hands
or maybe baby sitting gorks,
waiting for ICU Beds.
Mark, we got a partial
scalping on the way in.
Woman fell down an
escalator at O'Hare.
Not a moment too soon.
Well, timing is everything.
‐ Pher catch. That I need!
‐ Go for it.
That one has no
perfume enhancement
just pure, synthetic pheromones
for those who wanna maximize
their biologic signals.
Ooh, I'd like to try this on Al.
No, if you're already in
a committed relationship.
Full pher is for you.
It has a sandalwood fragrance
but with a, with a
dopamine like boost.
Mmm, nice. And I'm not one
for perfumes.
This isn't perfume.
It's biochemical
awareness therapy.
They say pheromones
are responsible for
who you're attracted to
and why women friends
get their periods in sync.
Exactly! Medical professionals
always understand.
Lookin' for me?
Oh, uh, this is uh,
Phyllis Farr and, um
she experienced some shortness
of breath this morning.
She has a history of a‐fib
and had an embolic CBA
two years ago, and she's now on
coumadin and dig.
One teeny, tiny little stroke
and I was smoking
like a chimney then.
Some men are inherently
less receptive.
Hmm?
Uh, I think it was just
anxiety this morning.
I had this mega meeting with
Marshall Field's. I'm sorry.
Ms. Farr is thinking
that she doesn't need to stay
but I'd like her admitted
to telemetry.
Her dyspnea was relieved by
nitro and it could be angina.
Darling, I told you,
I'm entirely too young for that.
I don't think we need
to admit you quite yet.
'But we should get
you on an EKG.'
And monitor you here in the ER.
Also check a triponin
with a CPK.
You're saying to cancel
with Marshall Field's?
Oh, they want you all the more
when they know you're busy.
Carol..
...did you send it?
I am. Today.
I'm ravenous.
You know, it's true.
You really do get cravings.
Can you steal away
to the cafeteria?
Do you know if they have
a surf and turf?
'Cause that's what I feel like.
A big, buttery lobster
and a thick, raw steak.
Morton's, after
the shift, my treat.
No, I‐I want it now.
You have a patient for me?
Oh, yeah. Sweet old lady.
But watch out for the husband.
He's a grouch.
Do you know where the ruleout
thoracic aneurysm is?
Maggie's patient?
I don't know. Peter told me
to take the consult.
Oh, I think she died.
Check in sutures.
Thoracic aneurysm.
Is that the patient?
Uh, no, she's back from x‐ray.
Where do they want her?
Oh, uh, sorry.
Check at the desk.
Lizzie.
Peter's already
been paged on this
but you'll probably
wanna see it.
It takes more than
a ten‐centimeter
scalp avulsion to
get my heart pumping
but hey, I'm not
a trauma wonk.
I had stuff in both hands
and somebody shoved me
from behind.
I hate escalators.
How about here?
'Yeah. That hurts.'
‐ Elizabeth, nice to see you.
‐ Scalp injury?
Uh, Ms. Price tried to get
to baggage claim head first.
Am I bleeding a lot?
Mm‐hmm. The scalp likes to gush.
Okay. Would you like
to help me tie it off?
Oh, I'd be delighted.
‐ Whoa!
‐ Okay.
Curved kelly. 3.0 vicryl.
Yeah, I need some suction.
They had our plane circling
for two hours
because of the wind.
It's about to storm.
There it is.
Now, can you get a clamp on it?
Mm‐hmm. With your help.
Okay...holding steady.
There you go.
That's it. Mm‐hmm.
Good. Got it.
Now...show me your tip.
You two want me to leave?
Oh, um, actually,
it's surgeon talk.
He elevates his clamp
so that I can slide my suture..
Hmm. Actually, that sounds
even worse, doesn't it?
You know what they say..
Uh‐oh. Power's out.
Okay, folks, in a few seconds
the auxiliary generator
will switch on.
Connie, who's charge nurse
for internal?
We have a power failure.
Make sure all vents
and infusion pumps
are plugged into
the red outlets.
'Okay, like I said..'
...false alarm,
power's been restored.
I never heard no backup
generator kick in.
It takes a few seconds
for them to switch over.
All of your family members
would've been taken care of.
You better hope.
My uncle's connected.
All the machines are
on a battery backup.
I wasn't talkin'
about machines.
Little excitement, huh?
Did Roxanne find you?
She wanted to have lunch.
It's a little busy today.
She was in chairs.
Carter, can you help me reboot
Ms. Farr's EKG Monitor?
The battery pack was low.
I think it shut off
when we lost power.
Yeah, I'll try.
'It's the perfect time.'
'But we haven't
gone public yet.'
All the more reason to act now.
'Look, some companies won't
consider clients'
with high‐risk profiles,
especially those
with pre‐existing
conditions.
‐ Roxanne?
‐ Oh, Dr. Carter.
I seem to be powerless.
Yes, I know. I'll take care
of that in a minute.
‐ Roxanne?
‐ Yeah. Bye.
I had a free hour and
I thought that maybe, um..
What are you doing in there?
You hawking my patient?
That woman might have
suffered an MI.
Oh, come on. Lydia said
her EKG was good.
Are you selling her insurance?
No, actually, it was
a counter‐move.
She was trying to sell me
a 100 shares
of pheromone enhancements, or..
Roxanne, it is unethical
to prey on people
while they're vulnerable.
Prey on people?
John, I...I sold insurance
before I met you.
I sold you insurance before
we even went on a date.
Why are you trying
to pick a fight?
I'm not trying
to pick a fight.
‐ Yeah, you are.
‐ Why would I pick a fight?
I don't know.
But maybe...maybe
you wanna break up
and it would be much easier
for you to do so
over some failure of mine.
Wrong.
If you wanna break up I‐I think
you should just say so.
Okay, I wanna break up.
And I think it is sleazy
to push insurance on people
when they're patients.
Who the hell left this patient
out here in the hall?
I saw an x‐ray tech.
Did he just leave her?
Well, there's no chart.
Oh, god.
What the hell happened?
She's not breathing.
Let's get her to trauma.
We need a hand here!
What's going on?
Female patient.
No ID. Respiratory arrest.
‐ I think she's been beaten.
‐ Intubation kit. Now.
'Put her on a monitor.'
We need some help in here.
'What is going on?'
Young woman found
in the hall.
May be asphyxiated.
Looks like she's
been beaten up.
And sexually assaulted.
I'm in. Bag her.
Okay, I need
post‐intubation film.
Is Peter still next door?
He took Miss Price
to radiology.
BP's 110/80.
Pulse ox is 97.
Order a head
and belly CT.
Feels like fractured ribs.
Where'd you find her?
She was outside exam four
on a gurney.
I'd seen her earlier. A tech
brought her down from x‐ray.
An x‐ray tech or
someone from transport?
I don't know.
I've never seem him before.
‐ From medicine?
‐ Sulla Andrews.
‐ I'm Mark Greene.
‐ When was she found?
‐ A couple of hours ago.
‐ When did you last see her?
10 O'clock this morning.
We've all been frantic.
It didn't make sense
that she disappeared.
‐ She was a patient here?
‐ On the medical ward.
No wonder the cops
are everywhere.
I sure hope Dr. Corday
got a good look at the bastard.
‐ Pretty scary.
‐ I know it.
You know, even I'm looking
over my shoulder.
Let's keep our voices down.
The police agree that
we should alert all staff
to the possibility
of a tech or someone
who looks like a tech
and may be dangerous.
But let's try to avoid
a general panic.
You mean,
not tell the patients?
Ah, at this point,
it doesn't seem necessary.
The guy probably bolted.
Still, don't leave
any patients unattended
for any period of time
and don't relinquish patients
into the hands of anyone
who you don't recognize
or who doesn't
have proper hospital ID.
What if you're not sure?
There's a policeman
stationed in every hallway.
'Call them.'
Alright?
Oh. Oh, that smarts.
I know, Mrs. Armstrong.
We're trying to be gentle.
Did you change
these dressings?
No, I thought you might
want to x‐ray her first.
Are you okay?
Yeah, I just suddenly got tired.
Oh, great.
I need the right hip.
Oh, oh, did she break
anything, doctor?
That's what this x‐ray
will tell us.
I knew as soon as
I heard that bang.
I knew she'd fallen.
Uh, t‐this is a waste of time.
You know, um, I think
it would probably be best
if we, uh, we could
just come over here
away from
the x‐ray, okay?
‐ Okay?
‐ Thanks.
It won't‐won't matter.
Gladys, get‐get, get your car.
You know, uh, Mr. Armstrong,
have you had anything to eat?
You've been here for hours.
'Shooting.'
'I'm not hungry.'
Get the car.
Army never eats.
Look at him.
Like a scarecrow.
I‐I'm taking her home.
N‐no one can help.
How's everything going in here?
Well, there
certainly are
plenty of doctors on hand.
Ha ha, I'm Dr. Carter.
No one can help.
Put her on IV Antibiotics?
Uh, Mrs. Armstrong
had a bleeding sacral decubitus
with surrounding cellulitis.
‐ She has what?
‐ Bedsores.
And, uh, she's in pain
after a fall.
I'm guessing
it's a fractured hip.
Her leg is internally rotated.
'I'm Gladys,
their neighbor.'
I brought her in.
Good work, Gladys.
Okay, everything looks
under control in here.
Do you, uh, need any help
with the husband?
He seems like a handful.
I was thinking
about calling psych.
He seems depressed.
See, the wife's your patient.
You might want
to stay focused.
But he's her
primary caregiver
and her situation is
not going to improve
unless he's able to help her.
Can you really think
he's going to talk to psych?
Maybe.
Give it a try.
Also...Carol needs a break.
Her name is Laurie Heller.
Ward nurse said her bed
was empty after rounds.
Yeah. She's talking
to the detective now.
Unfortunately, no one
up in medicine
saw anyone resembling
the man I saw.
She still hasn't
regained consciousness.
I don't think she will.
She's been admitted
since a traffic accident
ten days ago.
In a vegetative state.
Oh, god.
Her family
has just been persuaded
to extubate her..
...and transfer her
to long‐term nursing care.
They've been hoping
for a miracle.
It's barbaric.
Here I am, the worst
eyewitness in history.
How I could hardly
tell them anything.
I didn't pay attention
to the guy.
Well, I'm sure you helped.
Uh, average height...I think.
White, but with
a dark complexion
maybe Latino,
maybe Middle Eastern
but he didn't have an accent
as far as I remember
and...I don't know.
I'm just afraid that what I do
remember I'm making up because
I‐I just don't want
to be of no help to them.
Well, maybe talking
to him scared him off.
CT Confirmed a small
splenic laceration.
Romano wants to do an ex‐lap.
He's going to operate?
Not that an operation
is going to mean
much to Miss Heller
but according to Robert
she's a liability nightmare.
What do you think?
I think it's better
than doing nothing.
Poor woman already
got pushed down an escalator.
It wasn't intentional.
Now you want her
to sit here
while I go get
my stinking badge?
Hey, you're supposed
to wear your ID at all times.
Since when does
the Chicago PD Care?
‐ Officer, I can vouch for him.
‐ Thank you.
What's the deal?
You'd think I was a felon.
Is this Mark Greene's scalp lac?
‐ That's me.
‐ Yeah.
CT gave the green light
to stitch away.
Okay. I want you to put
her in the suture room
and Tony, wear your ID.
‐ How come?
‐ Because I said so.
Carter, I heard
a terrible rumor.
Oh, yeah. Apparently,
a patient got assaulted and‐‐
Yeah. Yeah.
That is true
but I was asking
about Roxanne.
Did you break up with her?
‐ Who told you that?
‐ She did.
Oh. Yeah, it's true.
So, she won't be
coming around anymore.
Man, can't you think
of the rest of us?
‐ Oh, you liked her?
‐ What's not to like?
Hey, Carter, can you come?
Miss Farr is a little altered.
Lucy wants to send her
for a head CT.
Doesn't Lucy
have her own patient?
What's this one called?
Oh, shoot.
What is that?
It's right on the tip
of my tongue.
Hey, Lucy.
Did you get that hip x‐ray
results back on Mrs. Armstrong?
No, It's not done yet
and psych is on their way down.
'Good.'
I actually,
I'm little worried.
Miss Farr seems
a little bit confused‐‐
I'll check it out.
I think with her history,
she should probably have‐‐
Yeah, I'll handle it.
I'll see you
later, Miss Farr.
Sex.
What?
That's the name of the scent.
"Pher‐sex."
So your head hurts?
It might be stuffy in here.
Maybe we should put
your perfumes away.
Some of them are
a little strong.
You have a very slender nose.
‐ Do I?
‐ It makes common sense.
The size of
the VNO would correspond
to the size of the nasal cavity.
‐ VNO?
‐ Vomeronasal Organ.
The structure
that picks up subtle messages
from other
people's glands.
Do you find yourself
affected by the opposite sex?
Oh, I'd say, I, uh...
I notice them.
What about your ability to bond?
‐ Follow my finger.
‐ Mmm.
Are you experiencing any
weakness or numbness, Miss Farr?
See, people with deficient VNOs
often have, uh, trouble
sort of appreciating oxytocin
which is the hormone
that provokes deep inimacy
inta‐intim‐intimacy.
Lydia, I think we should
set Miss Farr up
with a head CT.
‐ Dr. Carter?
‐ Mm‐hmm.
Were you breast‐fed?
So, I heard I missed
another trauma.
Tragic case, actually.
Is Romano doing the ex‐lap?
It's perfectly routine. You
needn't join us if you're busy.
Yeah, well, he'll
need an assist.
We both know
I can handle that.
Elizabeth, you're an intern.
Stop seeing every move
I make as a competition, okay?
Huh, right.
Just the way I see it,
it looks as though
you're going for the trauma
fellowship full bore.
I haven't made
up my mind yet.
My, my, my, how many surgical
heavyweights does it take
to screw in
a light bulb?
It depends on what's
at stake, I guess.
I heard you were
zonked out in the lounge.
I closed my eyes
for two minutes.
‐ I was on a break.
‐ Okay.
I'm entitled
to a break
15 minutes,
every four hours.
I know. I've just
never seen you take one.
Well, I'm going to start.
I need to fax this.
Be my guest.
Or you want me to, uh‐‐
Oh, uh, no, thanks.
It's kind of personal.
I'll do it myself,
if that's okay.
Do I look like
Kerry Weaver?
A‐ah. It looks like
we're out again.
Uh‐oh. Uh‐uh.
'Damn. I wish I hadn't
just made that incision.'
'It's okay. I can see
enough to suction.'
'I've got nothing.'
'Alright, everybody hold on.'
The auxiliary power
will kick in.
Don't worry, Miss Farr. We keep
flashlights by all the..
Whoa.
Aah.
‐ Uh‐oh.
‐ What did I spill?
Damn it.
A‐auxiliary power
is online.
Come on...damn it.
Damn it.
Carol, I need
you on task. Hit every room.
Make sure all vents and pumps
are in redundant plugs.
‐ Yep. I know. I'm coming.
‐ What the hell is going on?
Hey, do you
have any batteries back there?
My flash light's on a blink.
Oh, leave it for
the cops to be prepared.
Hey, is this all the lighting
we're going to get?
Lighting is not
priority use. Carol?
Yeah, uh, Jerry, could you try
and get my letter out of it?
Yeah, I'm doing my best.
Okay. We're going
to follow the plan.
Critical equipment first,
patient concerns second.
Right.
I wish it weren't
getting dark.
What about the rapist?
‐ Still missing.
‐ Oh, no.
Look, everyone please calm down.
Everything is under control.
Don't worry, Mr. Haskins.
We do have a loss of power
but our backup generators will
supply power to the ventilator
that's helping you breathe
as well as to the pumps
that delivers your meds, okay?
'We need some light over here.'
'I think Lucy's
getting a flashlight.'
‐ Uh‐h, there we go.
‐ Oh, no, Gladys.
The red plugs are
for priority medical use.
Why?
We need to conserve
our auxiliary power.
Carol, Dr. Greene's
looking for you.
The ICU wants
to send down six criticals.
Six?
Apparently, they
have this new backup generator
that never came on.
Oh, boy. Here.
Um, Mr. Armstrong..
...this is Dr. Myers
from psych
and he just wanted
to talk to you in another room
for a few minutes
if that's okay.
Everyone
is welcome to stay
but until city power
is restored
we won't be starting
any non‐critical cases.
Try 670. I'm telling you.
‐ 670 is not transmitting.
‐ Jerry?
‐ Static is all I can hear.
‐ Well, shut up and listen.
Jerry, I'm not getting
a line on this phone.
‐ Outside lines don't work.
‐ Now, this is the PT line.
It's hardwired to
the ICU, isn't it?
Mark, we can't possibly
take six more criticals.
I know, I know, that's why
I'm trying to offer the ICU
four of our
life‐paks instead.
That'll only give
us two life‐paks.
Well, what can I do?
Officer, can
you get radio contact
with the ICU
on the seventh floor?
I can. Beat
three to 740.
‐ What's that noise?
‐ Uh, sounds like a low battery.
‐ I'll find out.
‐ Thank you.
Whoa, Carter, Carter.
‐ Sorry, Carol. Sorry.
‐ Slow down.
What's that smell?
'No retroperitoneal bleeding.'
The liver, duodenum
and pancreas look okay.
This isn't so bad.
Makes you hopeful
about Y2K.
Dr. Benton, it's out everywhere
in the building.
‐ Did you try calling?
‐ Couldn't get through.
Go check
on the little nipper, Peter.
I, uh, it's Reese, you know.
He has this thing
about the dark.
It is just a spleen.
Shirley, do you have
an extra flashlight?
We'll fix you up.
This is bull.
I want a smoke.
Believe me, we would love
to let you out, okay.
I‐I got the code here.
‐ That it?
‐ Nada.
I don't think
the keypad's getting any juice.
Fine. I'll smoke in here.
Jerry, why don't you walk that
guy out the employee entrance
and call engineering
and get them down here.
'An hour. You need an hour
to get a protime?'
I‐I can't wait that long.
What? Did an animal
die around here?
Anyone see where psych
took Mr. Armstrong?
Look, CT is down.
This woman has a history
of embolic CVAs
and now she's altered.
‐ Miss Farr is worse?
‐ Who is Miss Farr?
I knew she needed a CT.
Uh‐oh.
Aren't we closed
to internal disaster?
Well, maybe they didn't
get the news.
Listen, just get it done.
Hey, what's with the doors?
I think the generator's
on a magnetic lock
and the keypad
which releases the door
is on non‐essential power.
'What does that mean?'
'Means we're screwed.'
Open up.
Yeah. We're trying to.
Do you have anything
on the truck
to pry open the doors?
I'll check.
We've got a 33‐year‐old
Chicago Ed repairman down.
‐ Can you hear me?
‐ Yeah, yeah. Go on.
A possible electrocution
in a 15‐foot fall.
He was found unconscious
by his coworkers at the foot
of a power pole.
'Frequent PVCs
in the field.'
‐ Normal sinus now.
‐ Here, let me try.
He may have been
struck by lightning.
His coworker
said it hit pretty close.
Okay, people.
We're going to
take him in through the window.
Okay everybody, we're going
to need you to get up
and move to the other
side of the hall. Thank you.
Let's get all these
chairs out of here.
Everything's got to go.
Eric, give me a hand.
‐ Can we get this window off?
‐ Let's try lifting it.
Can't we just smash it?
Everybody look out.
No, no, no. We got it,
we got it. It comes out.
‐ The whole thing?
‐ No, no. Just the backboard.
We need a gurney in here.
‐ Bring it in lengthwise.
‐ Are you ready?
Okay, everybody,
grab a hold.
'Easy, easy.'
Okay, you guys let go.
How you doing there?
Yep. Welcome to county general.
Morales get
on the radio to dispatch
and tell them that we are
officially closed to trauma.
‐ Got it.
‐ Carter, she's crashing.
‐ Miss Farr.
‐ Oh, no.
Get on it, both of you.
‐ Jerry, page Benton.
‐ Yeah.
Reese.
'Reese, where are you?'
‐ Hey, it's daddy.
‐ Right over here Dr. Benton.
'Hey.'
Hey, man.
What you doing?
Huh?
'What is that?'
'You looking at the stars?'
'Is this fun?'
Penny for your thoughts.
I hesitate to say.
We're ready to close.
4‐0 vicryl, please.
I was just thinking.
Miss Heller's body's
been through quite enough.
An accident, a coma,
a brutal attack
the kindest thing might be
to let her go in peace.
Of course we can't.
Careful what you ask for.
She's bradying down.
Oh, don't tell me that.
'EKG looks good.'
Looks like
a lightning strike.
I don't know.
I was up the pole.
That's all I remember.
Yeah. Flashover effect.
I‐I want to keep that shirt.
It's all yours.
Full thickness
burns to the legs.
Alright, what do we got?
'What have you got?'
Hi, Reese.
Mr. Joiner took
a hit of lightning.
‐ Fell 15 feet.
‐ No guarding or tenderness.
Let's prep for
a lavage. Let's move.
Thank you.
Hang on, man.
Why are you doing
a naso trach?
We won't have to paralyze her.
Alright. I'm in.
Go ahead. Bag her.
‐ Good job.
‐ Not really.
Without a CT.
I have no idea
what to do next.
Well, don't you think
she threw a clot?
Maybe, if she's
inadequately anticoagulated.
So, she needs heparin
to thin her blood
and to prevent
further clotting, right?
Unless she's
over‐anticoagulated
and bleeding
in her brain.
Then she needs
vitamin K and FFP.
Heparin would kill her.
Okay, good breath sounds.
Let's hook her up.
That's why you
needed a protime.
Bingo.
Is an AC of 14
okay on the vent?
Oh, never mind. We're dead.
‐ Got it. I'll bag her.
‐ What the hell?
Oh, we've just
lost backup.
Oh, this is still
on from battery.
Oh, god. All patients on vents
are gonna have to be bagged.
Go. Get them started.
I lost my monitors
for a 62 year‐old.
History of CVA
and heart disease.
‐ Auxiliary power has cut out.
‐ Where's the life‐paks?
‐ We gave the extras to ICU.
‐ Go, I'll take care of this.
Peter, what do you think?
This guy's stable.
She can take that one.
Thank you, gentlemen.
So what happened
to the generator?
I thought it was supposed
to be foolproof.
Yeah, but apparently not.
Connie, can you take
Reese from me?
Sure. Jerry can look after him.
Mark, Carter needs you.
Okay, go, Mark.
I got this one.
‐ Go. Go.
‐ Okay.
'Another unit in.'
Still no pressure.
Damn it. Damn it.
Hard to believe
she's crashing.
I can't think
without all the alarms blaring.
Try phenylephedrine?
Wait.
The neck veins
are distended.
No pulse in the aorta.
‐ Tamponade?
‐ Exactly.
60cc syringe,
18‐gauge needle.
‐ Going in blind?
‐ Yeah.
Okay. Retract the left lobe
of the liver.
‐ Got it.
‐ This is living, huh?
Pericardiocentesis
without electronic monitor.
Careful, you don't
puncture the ventricle.
Thanks, Robert.
Got it.
Give me a minute
to check the pressure.
I think it's coming up.
Ho hum.
All in a day's work, huh.
So basically, we're boned.
The wrong treatment
could kill her.
Miss Farr, don't worry.
We're here with you.
Our hands are tied
without the CT.
‐ Watch her chest expansion.
‐ I am.
‐ Whole‐blood clotting time.
‐ What?
Something from the dark ages.
Oh, Lydia, you don't have
an extra red top on with you?
Of her blood? Yeah.
I always hold one.
How long ago
did you draw it?
‐ Uh, about 45 minutes ago.
‐ Okay.
Yeah. No signs
of clotting.
I'm going to say
she's over‐anticoagulated.
So we just treat her?
No. We do
an LP first.
Miss Knight?
Do you have a minute?
Yeah.
Oh, I'll take over.
Alright, good news.
Lavage is negative.
Oh, there's blood
in the urine.
Well, he could have ruptured
his bladder or kidneys.
No CT you want to do an ex‐lap?
What, and carry him up?
Let me see this.
Alright, let's get
a specimen cup
and set up a microscope.
Uh‐oh. I've lost his pulse.
‐ What?
‐ He's in v‐tach.
Oh, damn. Move.
Let's get
the defibrillator back.
Carol, where's Haleh's patient?
Oh, exam one.
‐ You okay in here?
‐ Fine.
Get away from her.
‐ What the hell?
‐ Step back. Security.
‐ Hey, relax.
‐ Who are you?
I'm Tom Frawley.
I'm an RN at mercy
but I live down the block.
‐ Do you have ID?
‐ Yeah.
'I came in to help with
the power outage.'
'They told me to irrigate
her scalp lac.'
He's doing
a real nice job.
Okay, I'm...I'm sorry.
I didn't know you.
It's okay.
'It was a good pick‐up
on Mr. Armstrong.'
I've got him on ativan.
Yeah. he seemed pretty
depressed.
Worse than that.
He's having suicidal ideation.
‐ Really?
‐ Yeah, no guy like that.
It happens more
than people know.
A lot of thoughts
of pulling the trigger.
He's definitely
a danger to himself.
What about others?
'I need that.'
Keep your finger on her pulse.
I'll bring it back
as soon as I can.
‐ Still no pulse.
‐ I'll hook up the leads.
Don't bother.
I'll take a quick look.
Ah, he's in fib.
Let's shock him at 200.
‐ Set.
‐ Clear.
Damn it. 300. Clear.
‐ 375. Clear.
‐ It's not charged yet.
‐ Hold on.
‐ Batteries take longer.
'Yeah, we'll be lucky if
there's a charge left.'
‐ Come on, come on.
‐ Set.
Clear.
‐ Got it. Thank god.
‐ Alright, that's more like it.
Okay, lets push lidocaine to 100
and keep an eye on him.
Where's the microscope?
‐ How am I doing here?
‐ Great.
Maybe I'll take
the M‐cats.
Such a long way down.
I know, Dottie.
So Gladys you said
you heard a bang
when you walked up to the door?
I did.
And you could hear Dottie
fall down the back stoop
even without
your hearing aid?
Well, I heard a bang.
Can you see okay?
Yes.
That bedsore's
a bad one, isn't it?
It's not a bedsore.
'Kerry?'
Yep. Anyone want
fried chicken?
Oh, my god,
you read my mind.
Hey, who fixed the doors?
Oh, they popped open when
we lost the generators.
You lost a generator?
That's scary. Hey, Reese.
Yeah, it is scary.
It's been 40 minutes.
Our battery packs
are only guaranteed for 45.
Hey, this chicken
smells great.
Yeah, everything in my freezer
was going to mush.
It was cook it or lose it.
‐ You made this?
‐ Yep, always cook with gas.
So, what can I do?
Well, I've already checked
all the exam beds.
See if Benton needs help
in trauma one.
And Kerry, thank you so much.
‐ So good.
‐ Mm‐hmm.
'Prepped with
the vitamin K?'
'And mannitol in case
she herniates.'
Don't worry, Carter,
I'm using a 22‐gauge needle.
You holding up, Lydia?
Oh, yeah, strong hands.
'Don't be afraid
to let Carter know'
'if you need
to be spelled.'
Good.
Let's get the FFP.
Give vitamin K,
ten milligrams
slow IV Push.
How are
the pupils, Carter?
Equal and reactive.
Thanks for the backup.
No problem.
And he zaps the guy back
with one shot to spare.
Then he's sticking
a slide of urine
under the microscope.
And it's bright red.
He's telling
us it's not blood.
Rhabdomyolysis, huh?
And myglobinuria.
The guy was breaking
down muscle probably from
the lightning and trauma.
Just needed to get
fluids on board.
Sounds like you
didn't need me at all.
I don't know.
Didn't you say something
about some chicken?
Well‐done, Dr. Corday.
Thank you.
I'd be remiss
if I didn't say this
especially after today.
You are an exceptional surgeon.
It would be tragic for you
to waste your time
on some trauma fellowship.
Let me finish.
Now..
...I'm aware that you don't
relish working with me.
I'm in your face.
I can't resist.
But, know this..
...I would do anything
in my power
to have you stay in surgery.
Including making myself
as scarce as possible.
I appreciate that.
Think about it.
I'll take over.
The cops want to see you.
The facility engineers
found him in
the switch room.
He hung himself.
Is that the guy?
Yeah, that's him.
Let's get everybody
back on vent.
‐ And reboot all monitors.
‐ You got it.
This place is a mess.
Hey, CTs holding a table
if you can get her
there in two minutes.
How are you doing, Mrs. Farr?
Yeah. we're going to take that
out as soon as you come back.
Don't worry, I was very
careful with your VNO.
So, Carter,
I need to ask you.
W‐what was going in there?
I was, I was worried
that she'd herniate.
No, no, I mean
between you and me.
I was getting this
weird energy.
I mean, it was
almost like you were, what
you were being
territorial
or admiring me.
Ah, I don't want to say
that you were flirting
'cause I mean obviously
you weren't
you know, you weren't
flirting with me.
Oh, man, you know, I spilled
those pheromones on me.
‐ Like, a whole bottle.
‐ Is that what I smell?
Maybe that's what
you were picking up on
one of those chemicals.
Wow, that's
pretty far‐fetched.
I mean, I admired you
when you went
for the LP.
But, you know,
that was it.
I better get these
to the lab.
‐ Get him?
‐ Got him.
Ten months after I retire,
they were bought out.
Our health plan's kaput.
She can't get out of bed.
I‐I wrote my pension wrong.
If I go first, she gets nothing.
I had to take
care of her.
I know.
But what I don't
know about is the bullet.
What kind it was
and...whether you were
firing from above.
And in that case
it might have
hit her bladder.
Or if you were aiming
directly at her spine.
Ah, w‐well..
...it‐it was
a Walther automatic.
I took it off a German officer.
Uh, the..
...th‐the army g‐gave me
papers for it.
At the end of the war,
pistols were the only thing
they'd let us GIs keep.
I see.
‐ God, what a day.
‐ Yeah.
ComEd says there was arcing
at the substation.
According to facilities, our
back‐up generator shut down
because of a failed bearing
in the fan motor
that cools the system.
Oh, that makes
it all clear.
I'll admit it. I'm not 100%
comfortable in the dark.
Oh, I guess
a candlelit dinner
would not be
an enticing offer?
I'm afraid not.
I'm heading home.
Some advice.
I wouldn't do that.
‐ Oh?
‐ Yeah.
Rule number
one of trauma.
After a day like today,
you should shift gears
not take it home with you.
So what do you suggest?
Okay, Jerry, we're out of here.
Okay. I hope you guys
have power at home.
We'll be fine.
‐ You looking for this?
‐ Oh, you got it out.
Yeah, the transmission
didn't go through
and I didn't have
a number to send it again.
That's okay,
I'm, I'll fax it later.
‐ Okay.
‐ Did you read it?
No, you said
it was personal.
'So the neighbor
interrupted a suicide pact?'
No, I wouldn't exactly
call it that.
The wife wasn't in on it.
Myers said it's
not unheard of
depression over aging,
loss of control
a downward spiral.
How long were they married?
54 years.
'It makes you wonder if
something was always missing.'
Hmm?
Oh, I'm not the one to ask
what makes a lasting
relationship.
Oh?
Never had a lasting
relationship.
Not that
I don't want to..
...find that someone.
Just haven't.
I know.
Your parents stayed together
but they completely shut you out
and lived like
childless jet‐setters
and they made marriage
a complete mystery to you.
No.
My problem,
on the other hand, is that
I was raised by such a capable,
self‐sufficient single mom
that it's hard for me to see
the need for a partner at all.
How long was
that psych rotation?
Go, go, go, go.
Good, good.
Go, go.
Hang in there.
That's the hard part.
You just got
to watch out.
Hey, you have a go.
No, no, no, after
a fall like that‐‐
I'd be in traction
for the rest of the season.
No, no, you got to get back up
on your skis, on the slopes.
Okay, I can do this.
You can do anything.
'Three, two, one.'
Okay, and go.
God bless electricity.
Go, go, go.
'Why did I have
to bring that up?'
'Ah, just give it a minute.'