Move from Bhujangasana
into Adho Mukha Svanasana.
And hold that.
- Do you like this?
- Mm...
I'm not sure.
I like that you like it.
Time for work.
Guess we'll finish Vinyasa
flow next time I come over.
You shouldn't come over anymore.
You should move in.
Things are different now.
You lived here before.
What's different?
Everything is different.
Then we were
roomies, pals, buddies,
and now we're a real thing.
A better thing for sure,
but also more complicated.
We're the same people in the
same place doing the same things.
It's bigger than that, Shaun.
I hope it is.
I... Living together means
more commitment, more trust.
And I don't think
we're quite there yet.
You don't trust me?
No, I do, it's just...
I need a bit more.
Copernicus1543.
It's my banking password.
- Yes, I got you!
- No!
- Bow to your queen.
- No, bitch!
- Yes!
- No!
Ahh, where did you find the
10,000 hours that you put into that?
I like filling my evenings
with numbing mindlessness.
Mm.
Oh.
Morgan needs me to go in ASAP.
You figure she
shouldn't page you?
She can handle it on her own
because she used to
be a surgical resident?
Be the bigger person.
It's an ingrown hair.
Mm.
Definitely an ingrown hair.
Unfortunately, the ingrown
hair caused an abscess
that needs to be lanced.
By a surgeon.
Please give this man
the VIP treatment.
I have another case to attend to,
but don't worry, I'll be checking in.
- Such a nice lady.
- Hmm.
So how shall we proceed?
I'm going with drain the
abscess and dress the wound.
Set it up.
Maybe we should do a biopsy?
Well, it could be a cutaneous pili
migrans or have a deep sinus tract
or a creeping eruption
caused by a parasitic disease.
Give him the VIP treatment.
Abdominal pain can be
scary when you're pregnant.
But I wouldn't worry. You
have two rambunctious boys.
I know. It's like a
cage match in here.
- Shaun, where's your first-year resident?
- I have two first-year residents.
But I don't want to teach
them. They're very distracting.
You have a dizygotic,
dichorionic, diamniotic pregnancy.
It just means your twins are
fraternal and in separate amniotic sacs.
First-years aren't
distractions. They're godsends.
She has edema.
Not surprising for someone
who's 26 weeks pregnant.
Look, they'll do
anything you want.
Scut work, follow-ups,
coffee runs...
- I don't like coffee.
- Laundry, apple runs...
I already did that.
- What was her BP?
- Normal.
BP's no longer normal.
She's hypertensive.
What does that mean, Dr. Murray?
- Is your vision blurred?
- A bit. I'm tired.
Sounds like preeclampsia.
If we don't get your BP down
ASAP, you could lose your pregnancy.
We need to start you on
antihypertensive meds,
but your edema makes
it difficult to place an IV,
so we need to
run a central line.
Dr. Jackson?
Mind if I give a
hand, Dr. Murphy?
Mm.
- Is there anyone you want us to call?
- Uh...
My boyfriend decided his obligations
ended at offering to pay for an abortion.
Soft man in a hard world.
Fetal heart rate's dropping.
But only one of them.
- Did you have another birth?
- No.
Any pregnancy?
Miscarriage, abortion, stillbirth?
I had an abortion when I was 15.
It's not preeclampsia.
One fetus is Rh-positive,
and the mother is Rh-negative,
and her body is
perceiving him as a threat
and attacking him
with antibodies.
Antibodies she could only have
if she had an earlier pregnancy.
My body is trying to
kill one of my babies?
Yes.
Waiting on Billy's
biopsy results?
To confirm an ingrown hair?
You grew up in a
Hasidic family, right?
How are they handling
you being a doctor?
I haven't spoken to them in...
four years, except one sister.
I chose not to live
by their rules. I...
I knew the consequences.
My dad was a real-estate agent obsessed
with two completely unrelated things,
teeth and taxes.
Thought I'd spend the rest
of my life selling condos.
Now I'm a surfing surgeon,
but I still floss three times a day
and pay my installments
four times a year.
So, what's my dental floss?
Fire and brimstone.
Mm, actually, that is
from the New Testament.
I don't even know
what brimstone is.
I meant you fear disaster.
Your people's history
is kind of filled with it.
Billy has cancer.
How are your first-years doing?
Jordan talks too much,
and Olivia talks too little.
And Olivia does not know
where the jugular vein is.
You see her résumé?
Her grades and USMLE
scores were nearly perfect.
So if it's not a lack of
knowledge, what do you think it is?
I think Olivia has the potential
to be an exemplary doctor
if you push her, give
her a little extra attention.
Isn't that unfair to Jordan?
Well, was it unfair to the applicant
who didn't get your position
because Dr. Glassman thought
that you needed some extra attention?
Olivia just doesn't like being
in the spotlight, that's all.
Olivia's résumé didn't say
anything about not liking the spotlight.
Exactly. Don't trust résumés.
Locate jugular vein.
Insert needle.
Get a venous blush, remove
syringe, leaving needle in,
- then thread...
- Thread wire into needle.
Remove needle, scalpel to skin,
while being aware of a persistent
left-sided superior vena cava placement
present in 4% of those with
congenital heart disease.
Remove wire, suture
in line to skin, and done.
I guess you were nervous before.
- Didn't you have first-case jitters?
- No.
The sick twin has gone
into severe distress.
You have amelanotic
melanoma. Skin cancer.
But there's good news. We
should be able to remove all of it.
We can do it today.
Sorry, car trouble.
Hi, Dr. Park. Just telling
Billy about his cancer.
I got a great mechanic for you.
If you tell her Billy sent you,
she'll give you a friends-and-family.
Okay. Thanks for that.
You have an amazing attitude.
You know, my wife used
to tease me about that.
She died three years ago.
I'm sorry.
You know, on our
second date, I got a flat.
Now, I think she thought
I was gonna curse,
but all I could say was:
"Good timing. Costco's
got a sale on tires."
It's Addy's Auto, Los
Gatos and Gateway.
We are through the uterine wall.
Dr. Jackson, what's
our next step?
Advance through the trocar
15 millimeters beyond the tip
until the opening of the distal
basket can be confirmed by ultrasound.
Exactly.
What would you like me
to advance, Dr. Jackson?
Oh. Yes, right.
Obviously, you would be advancing
the double basket rocket catheter
and not this.
Sorry.
Not your fault.
If a junior resident is ill-prepared,
that's on the senior resident.
How is it fair that I get blamed
for a first-year's mistake,
and how can I help that person
without being unfair to the other one?
And how fair was the
preferential treatment
that you gave me,
and how fair was it to
the other first-year resident
who didn't get placed because
you helped me, and how fair was...?
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Put the list down.
Only four questions at
a time. That's my limit.
What kind of mistake?
Even though I went over
the procedure with Olivia,
she still gave
Dr. Andrews the pusher rod
when he needed the rocket
catheter, and he said it was my fault.
It was your fault.
You gotta help
her a little more.
- That is not fair to Jordan.
- What does fairness have to do with it?
It's not about equality.
It's about figuring out
what each person needs
and then teaching
them how to get it.
How do I know what they need?
Well, you've taught
them medicine, right?
So maybe it's something else.
Maybe it's an emotional issue.
Then I definitely can't
give them what they need.
You can ask them.
- About their emotions?
- Yeah. Ask them how they feel.
I don't care how they feel.
That's the beauty of it.
You don't have to care.
You just have to ask
them how they really feel.
Then they start talking.
Because people love to talk.
Oh. Oh.
Have you been working out?
I could only find mediums.
You know how many sets
of large scrubs I had to hide?
Thirty-one.
Injecting dye.
BP's dropping, diffuse skin
flushing. He's in anaphylactic shock.
- He's allergic to the dye.
- Ten cc epinephrine.
BP barely measurable. We
should intubate. Initiate CPR.
You should cannulate his femoral
vein to give pressers and volume.
Let's intubate and cannulate.
His jugular's distended.
Maybe he has cardiac tamponade
from a pericardial effusion.
He might need
open heart surgery.
Worst-case scenario
worked out the first time.
- Think lightning's gonna strike twice?
- Maybe not,
but I'm not gonna stand
on a hill in a thunderstorm.
Let's call Lim.
Prep the patient
for a pericardiotomy.
Two for two.
Okay, you can't do yoga at work.
I do it at home.
What's the difference?
Work behavior is not the
same as home behavior.
Ooh. So you're
saying context matters.
Of course.
The same way that two
roommates living together
is different from a
couple living together.
Same people, same
place, different context.
Once our feelings change,
everything changes.
I still feel the same
way when I'm with you.
Happy.
Kenzie's BP and
edema have improved.
The fetus's echo shows
improved heart function.
Catheter's working.
How do you feel?
Okay.
How do you really feel?
Uh...
Really okay.
You wanna know why
I'm so nervous all the time?
I don't know.
I've always been
very terrified of firsts.
First day of school,
camp, church.
All the new faces watching me,
just waiting for me to screw up.
First day of fifth grade,
when Mrs. Deloitte asked
me what six times nine was,
I told the whole
class it was 45.
Yeah, I can still hear
them laughing at me.
Two nights ago,
I dreamt I was standing in front
of Mrs. Deloitte's class again.
Couldn't wait to wake up.
But when I did, I realized that
if I got the answer wrong today,
no one will laugh,
but someone may die.
Kids laughed at me too.
Even though I knew
six times nine was 54.
One of the amniotic sacs
ruptured. The strong twin's.
It's metastasized to his
liver. So, what do we do?
Laparoscopic
radiofrequency ablation.
Short recovery time,
but a significant chance
his cancer returns.
Care to rebut?
I think we should consider
a hepatic lobectomy
and lymph node dissection.
Remove the affected area of
the liver, all the surrounding tissue,
and every swollen node we find.
And that's the
aggressive approach.
Longer recovery time, high
risk of complications, and, uh...
admittedly the best shot
at beating the cancer.
By complications, you mean
a barely functioning liver,
a persistent threat of fatal
bleeds, and chronic pain.
As surgeons you can gut
him, but as his primary doctor,
I have to find the balance
between longevity and quality of life.
Last week you were trying to
perform surgery from the gallery,
and now you hate surgeons?
Pick a side.
A piecemeal approach is
not going to work with Billy.
Every time we try to solve a
problem, we discover another one.
You may have left
your religion in Brooklyn,
but you keep looking for
meaning in random events.
- Dice have no memory.
- I'm not looking for meaning.
I'm looking for patterns.
Maybe he's got some
underlying condition?
I agree with Asher.
The dice have no memory,
but they can be loaded.
So safe and
seriously compromised
or aggressive and possibly dead?
Your case, Dr. Browne.
Your call.
How are you feeling?
You've sacrificed a lot.
Your hands, your career.
And you're taking it out on me and
Claire and the whole surgical profession.
And I get it. It hurts.
You're pathetic.
You're worried about me because
I'll never be a surgeon? Boo-hoo.
You're worried about me
because I took pleasure in
screwing with you and Claire?
That's who I am.
The question is, who are you?
You don't show up late
with lame-ass excuses,
and when you get
dissed, you diss back, so...
how are you feeling?
Forget I asked.
He's lost most of his amniotic
fluid. Won't last very long in utero.
In helping the weak, we
hurt the strong. C-section?
If we do a C-section
to save the strong baby,
there's a 90% chance
the weak baby will die.
But if we do an amnioinfusion
to save the weak baby,
there's an 85% chance
that strong baby will die.
It's the better option.
Five percent to decide
which baby lives?
Kenzie's body has
already made that choice.
If there's a strong baby and a weak
baby, it's pretty clear which one we save.
Survival of the fittest.
Sorry, it's just...
That's not really what we're
about, is it, as a civilization?
Aren't the strong morally
obligated to help the weak?
And if they don't, isn't
everybody ultimately worse off?
Neither baby has to die.
Delayed interval delivery.
We induce labor,
deliver the strong twin,
then stop the labor to
keep the weak twin in utero
until his lungs mature.
The chances of stopping
labor are very slim.
That's true.
There's about a 70% chance
that both babies would die.
Which makes it the
worst possible choice.
- We need to ask Kenzie.
- No, we don't.
Once she hears there's
the slightest chance
of saving both babies,
she won't listen
to any alternatives.
Statistically, it's
a terrible option.
But it is an option.
No. No, you can't
seriously be asking me this.
I know that this is something no
mother should ever have to decide.
There are no good options
here, but there is one
that will most likely make you
the mother of a healthy baby boy.
Okay.
- Prep for an amnioinfusion...
- Have you named them?
Dr. Allen.
Braydon and...
Landon.
No. No, I can't do this.
You have to save both of them.
We're at the tumor.
Unipolar ablation probe?
Pretty cool to think
we diagnosed Billy
with metastatic melanoma on Tuesday
and send him home on a Thursday.
Well, let's wait till Friday
to congratulate ourselves.
Current at 480 hertz, please.
Wait. We got a leak, bile duct.
Suction, suture,
linear stapler, stat.
I believe she made
the right choice.
She made the choice
any mother would make
because the alternative
is unthinkable.
Isn't that exactly what
made it the right choice?
She has to live with it.
The safe choice is not
always the best choice.
If it were, I'd be on an
army base in Germany,
married to First Lieutenant
Dwayne Buckman.
Dr. Andrews, you
wanted to see me?
Yes, Dr. Jackson.
Please come in.
Dr. Jackson.
I cannot say those two
words without grinning!
I know.
So?
I'm just checking
in with you, Livy.
Like you do with
all your first-years?
You wanted hands-off,
you're getting hands-off.
But I can still say
hi to my niece.
It looks like you're
settling in pretty well.
Wait... No, no, no, the way
you spoke up yesterday?
I mean, that's a tough case,
tough crowd, but you held your own.
I'm getting there. Dr. Murphy's
been very supportive.
Murphy? Yeah, I'm glad to hear
it. I'm sure he sees your potential.
- But if you need anything, you...
- Mm...
ask anyone but me.
Very hands-off.
Hmm.
Shaun, this is not an argument
I ever thought I'd have
to have with a boyfriend,
whether moving
in together matters.
It so obviously does. It so
obviously changes everything.
But one of the reasons
I'm in this relationship...
is because of that.
You are different.
And when I think about
us, say, a year from now,
I can't imagine us not living
together, so if it's inevitable...
Shaun, I am moving in with you.
Does that mean you think we
have enough commitment and trust?
Honestly...
I'm not sure.
So...
you want to do it just
because it's inevitable?
Mm, that makes
it sound terrible.
But that is kind of how I feel,
so... yeah.
You're moving back in.
Oh.
My girlfriend is
moving in with me.
We need additional venous
access to start the oxytocin.
I'll insert a 16 gauge IV.
How do you feel?
Good.
Insert a 16 gauge IV.
Okay.
There's gonna be a pinch.
Very good.
Once we start that drip, at
least one baby will be born.
I understand.
Okay.
Where are you going?
Kenzie's only 2 centimeters dilated,
and even though I'm not a surgeon,
- I have other important things to do.
- You were wrong.
First-years aren't godsends.
They're a lot of work.
- But I fixed Olivia.
- Wonderful. Now fix Jordan.
- She's the one you have a problem with.
- No. I don't.
Well, technically, she
has a problem with you.
And anyone in authority.
You need to rein her in.
Okay. How do I do that?
How'd you fix Olivia?
No new paint, no new parts,
no way you took this to a shop.
So there is something up
with you. Something personal.
- Something you don't care about.
- That goes without saying.
Except it's messing
with my games.
I just wanna humiliate you without
feeling like I'm punching a kitten.
I was finalizing my divorce.
- I... thought you were already...
- Not until yesterday.
And we didn't wanna deal with a
formal custody arrangement for Kellan.
But now that he's
18, it's official.
I know it's been over for
years, but when it's really over...
it hurts.
And I'm pissed at
myself for being hurt.
And, uh, now I'm
pissed at myself
for admitting that to the
coldest person I know.
My place has two masters with
en suites, and it's rent-controlled,
so it's still probably
cheaper than your motel.
But staying with me will cost
you. Kitty gotta punch back.
Thanks. But I'm good.
She's at 10 centimeters.
Prepare packed red blood
cells for possible transfusion.
Prepare forceps,
clamps and scissors.
How do you feel? Really feel?
I feel fine.
Why do you have a
problem with authority?
Seriously?
I have a problem with you
not acting like an authority.
You're not doing the one thing any
junior needs from their supervisor.
If I'm screwing up...
Not now. Not gonna screw up now.
I need to know you're
at least watching.
I need to know you've
got my ass covered.
The leak in your bile duct
has caused an infection
that could lead to peritonitis.
We've got you on multiple
aggressive antibiotics,
but this infection
acts very quickly.
Sometimes in a matter of hours.
Well, I feel fine.
Dopey but fine.
Billy, do you understand
what I just told you?
I might die tonight.
I get it.
How do you do it?
I've had worse days.
The day after Linda died...
I went to buy a gun.
Never used one before.
But I figured, how
hard could it be
to put it in my mouth
and pull the trigger?
On my way to the store...
I saw a car parked on the
side of the road with a flat.
Couple of kids who clearly didn't
know what the heck they were doing.
And for some reason, I pulled
over and changed their tire.
As I was leaving, I told them,
"Good timing. Costco's
got a sale on tires."
That's when I
heard Linda's laugh.
"Hey, dummy.
If you kill yourself, who's
gonna change the next tire?"
That's what saved my life.
Just wanting to help people.
Makes life worthwhile.
Brady.
His lungs are also underdeveloped.
He needs to be placed on a ventilator.
Let's get him to the NICU.
Starting magnesium sulfate.
That's to stop your labor.
I also need to ligate the umbilical
cord and return it to your uterus.
Okay. I have to focus on the
patient, and I have to focus on Jordan,
and I also have to focus on you.
I don't know how
to do that. Clamp.
Don't worry about me.
I appreciate you noticing I
needed help, but I'll be fine.
I didn't.
- Dr. Andrews?
- Your uncle. Absorbable sutures.
He told you?
Not that part. I Googled that.
I couldn't trust your résumé.
How do you feel?
I feel like my uncle
doesn't think I can hack it.
I feel sick.
She's having
another contraction.
Adding terbutaline and
calcium channel blockers.
Am I gonna lose Landy?
Am I gonna lose both of them?
I don't know.
She's still in labor?
BP's 95 over 60.
Kenzie, we need
to do a C-section.
- No, no. If he comes out, he'll die.
- If he doesn't, you both will.
- No.
- Sixty-nine over 40.
We're doing a C-section.
- No.
- Let's prep and drape her.
No, I can't. I can't
lose Landy! No!
- We need to restrain her.
- Landy's going to be just fine.
- Landy is not...
- Shh!
Kenzie, just listen to my
voice, okay? Just focus.
What's your favorite board game?
No! Okay. Restraints. Please.
Look at me. Don't look at them.
Board game.
- Uh... Scrabble.
- Mm-hm.
A classic. Nice.
Eight years from now,
Landy hits a triple word
score with the word "breathe."
Try it, breathe.
Good.
What's Brady doing?
Uh... he's...
He's mad that his
brother just schooled him.
Of course he is.
Hundred over 65.
Contractions are stopping.
Words with X and Z.
Only way you're gonna beat them.
I better brush up.
A delayed interval twin
delivery? That's awesome.
I can't teach.
Did you ask the
first-years how they feel?
Yes. Unhappy.
Okay. That's great.
Not that they're unhappy,
but that you asked,
they confided in you, and
you learned something.
I learned that Olivia
needed help, so I helped her,
and now she feels sick
because I helped her.
Morgan says Jordan needs help,
but Jordan says she doesn't need help,
but Jordan's mad
because I didn't help her.
Okay. That sounds tricky.
That was my point.
You know what?
You'll figure it out.
And even if you don't this time,
that's okay, you'll
learn something.
And you know what?
You're a wonderful teacher.
Been learning from you
since the first day we met.
How's he doing?
Well...
either he wakes,
or he lapses into a coma
and slowly fades away.
Beautiful day.
♪ You've been walking ♪
♪ Alone for so long ♪
You call Addy about your car?
Not yet. Been a little busy.
Helpers aren't so
good at asking for help.
Kind of glad I did, though.
♪ This time I know
you'll be all right ♪
♪ 'Cause I'm standing
at your side Whoa ♪
♪ 'Cause when you feel
like You've been falling... ♪
Congratulations. You
helped save a life today.
Despite the bickering.
Opposing points
of view are great,
as long you actually listen
to the other point of view.
You're carrying baggage
that is affecting your decisions.
You saw that because
you're good at reading people.
Other people.
Figure out what you're carrying.
♪ There is a light ♪
♪ At the end of this
long ride Whoa ♪
♪ This time I know
you'll be all right ♪
♪ 'Cause I'm standing
at your side Whoa ♪
♪ 'Cause when you feel
like You've been falling ♪
♪ Hold on to me ♪
♪ And when the river
Sweeps you right off your feet ♪
♪ Hold on to me ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ Hold on to me... ♪
It's a list of all the things
you did right on this case.
You can hack it.
It's a list of all the things
you did wrong on this case.
I'm covering your ass.
♪ Hold on to me now ♪
♪ Take you to higher ground ♪
♪ Hold on to me ♪
Well, don't be late if you
don't want no bloody nose.
Do me a favor, Harry?
What?
Drop dead.
Great to see you've started
your own clothing line.
The official gear of
those who've given up.
By en suite, I meant there's
a trash can in your closet.
Hey, want a ride?
Murphy told you.
You never knew
your great-aunt Winn.
She moved in with us when...
I was 8.
Your grandparents weren't
getting along, lot of fighting.
But whenever it got really bad,
Auntie Winn would take your
mom and me into the kitchen,
make cupcakes,
something out of papier-mâché,
or teach us a card game.
I've always wanted to be
that kind of person for you.
You have been.
But now I need to know
you think I can do this.
Accepting your help...
makes me feel like garbage.
- Livy, I'm sorry...
- I know.
I love you too.
But I have to make this work.
Feels like home. Again.
It feels like home
again to me too.
Maybe you were right.
Maybe things are the same.
No.
You were right.
It's not the same.
It's better.