Oh!
I was just dropping off
yesterday's post-op notes.
That's okay.
I was, uh, I was up reading.
Didn't you have
surgery this morning?
Oh, damn!
File on Mrs. Rubadoux.
You finished with it?
Uh, yeah. I'll, uh,
drop it off later.
Get going.
I'll take care of it.
Hey, Carter.
Morning.
And a grand one it is.
Yeah, easy for you to say.
I'm not on until noon.
Yeah, well, it's much more fun
to ride in together.
Don't you usually drive to work?
My car's in the shop.
What, did you drive around,
like, two, three weeks
with that brake
warning light on?
No. A week... at most.
Is your apartment on this line?
No. I'm on the
Congress-O'Hare line.
But you're taking
Ravenswood today?
Yeah. It's Mark's line.
This is us.
Stop and shop at
Davey's Liquor Depot.
What?
Tequila shopping.
Doug Ross's birthday.
Yeah, margaritas at
my apartment after work.
Okay. See you later.
Bye.
Right.
I'm doing an
endarterectomy at 11:00,
if any of your Residents
want to observe.
Give them an excuse
to miss my rounds?
How thoughtless of me.
Peter.
Morning.
Peter, so good of you to wake.
I'm sorry.
I was working late last night...
And you overslept?
It won't happen again.
I certainly hope not.
If you'd been
responsible for this patient
I think he might have questioned
your professionalism.
I stayed up reading some
of the research study files.
Well, that's very impressive,
but diligence is no excuse.
There now, the lecture is over.
Mrs. Rubadoux, Mr. Roth,
Warrington, Dorgan, McFarland...
And these patients
have what in common?
You used Lazerol
and the clamp-and-run
technique on all of them.
We used the clamp-and-run.
I went through the charts.
I'm just trying to understand
why all of these patients
were excluded from the study.
Well, each had complications
which made them
unsuitable candidates.
Shouldn't we have
determined that
before the clamp-and-run?
They were emergent cases.
Would you have let them die?
Of course not.
Now, this is your
first research project
you've participated
in, isn't it?
Yes.
Well, then it's my fault.
Obviously, I failed
to communicate
the magnitude and
scope of this kind of study.
No, I understand the scope...
No, Peter, I don't think you do.
Mrs. Rubadoux had
pulmonary disease,
renal insufficiency, and
congestive heart failure.
She was never a candidate
for the study.
Now, thank you, Claire.
I'll sign those later.
But with Mr. Roth...
Ah, with Mr. Roth,
we changed surgical
procedure in mid-course,
which was to the
benefit of the patient.
Now, would you have us continue
the clamp-and-run
just to include
him in the study?
No, but there are rules
for compiling data, right?
We're talking
about saving lives.
You and I have talked
about risks before,
particularly when related
to this extraordinary
level of medicine.
We'd never take the first step
if we didn't take risks.
Now, I hope that,
as we go along,
you can grasp that.
I'll try to.
Perhaps I was foolish
to bring you in on the team.
No, sir. I don't think so.
Third-year residents
rarely have the maturity.
You are very lucky
to have had this opportunity.
Perhaps you don't realize
how lucky you are.
Maybe you ought to
take a day to consider that.
Sorry.
Thanks.
Carter...
Yeah?
Since you have
time on your hands,
I have a knee lac
on a six-year-old in 2.
Can't do it.
We are observing a
thyroidectomy at 11:00.
And we've got rounds
with Dr. Vucelich at 10:00.
You've got time. What?
Make yourself useful, Carter.
About that knee lac, Carter?
Doug, do you mind?
Paramedics are pulling up
with an apparently
intoxicated and disheveled
street individual.
Be my guest.
Man...
Come on. I've
missed you, Carter.
By the way,
happy birthday, Dr. Ross.
It's not my birthday.
That's an ugly rumor.
And, Jerry,
Groundhog Day is over,
so let's get rid of that guy.
I am so sorry, Marguerite.
I just can't understand
how this happened.
My foot hit the ice,
my bum hit the bricks.
I thought I'd
shoveled all the steps
but there it was,
third from the top.
A small, yet undeniably
slick patch of ice.
I'm gonna live, Edward.
Don't worry about it.
Yes, but why, why
did this happen?
It was an accident.
There are no accidents.
He tends to overthink things.
Studying to be an analyst.
Psychoanalyst?
Scary, huh?
I still can't believe my
daughter married him.
Nathan Conley, 27 years old.
ETOH intoxication, ALOC, ataxic.
Oh, man!
Nystagmus, BP 90/40, resps 14.
Excuse me, I'm just
gonna move upwind.
Who called it in?
He and his girlfriend
were bunking up
with some other deadbeat guy.
Nathan couldn't
stop throwing up.
Said he drank a gallon of vodka,
took some Xanax.
"Some" Xanax?
"Some" being the only
number he could think of.
Whoo, man!
Did you make up
today's schedule?
Like every day.
Where is it?
That is it.
Well, I was assisting Dr. Zarem
on a parathyroidectomy
at 11:00,
and Dr. Enari on a
nephrectomy at 3:00.
This says Bachtell's assisting.
Dr. Vucelich said you were
going to be tied up in the ER,
so I reassigned.
Mark and Susan? Really?
Carter said that they
were very chummy.
On the El?
I thought Susan drove to work.
I saw them in the
lounge yesterday.
Hey, I saw them
in the cafeteria.
Susan, how are you this morning?
I'm fine, thank you, Doug.
Haven't I already
seen you today?
Yes. You know, you have.
You have seen me today.
Carol, what do you say
we get to that earache in 1?
Oh, right. Earache.
Mm-hm.
Did you lose consciousness?
Uh, not this time, she didn't.
This time?
Two months ago
I stumbled over his new puppy
and hit my head on the driveway.
My wife and I,
we want children, but...
Okay, let's just... We'll
get it out in the open.
I have some problems
with commitment...
Accepting responsibility.
We thought a puppy might help.
Any blurry vision this time?
No, just the cut.
Do you think
that I could somehow be
causing these accidents?
I know that we've been
having some difficulty
since you moved in.
Let the doctor work, Edward.
Are you allergic to lidocaine,
Mrs. Janeway?
I wasn't before.
Got stitches on my
arm last summer.
Edward sliced me
with the Weed Whacker.
Oh, my God, I
did. I did, didn't I?
I can't believe this.
I'm experiencing displacement.
That's an immature
defense mechanism
wherein your
feelings of hostility
are inappropli... in... ina...
Inappropriately redirected.
Sorry about this.
My daughter, the
only one with a job,
had to go to work today,
so Edward brought me in.
That's okay.
Have you had a tetanus booster?
Three months ago.
Cut my leg on the
basement stairs.
Tripped over
Edward's golf clubs.
Banana bag's going.
Are we done?
What's the deal, Carter?
Surgery withdrawal?
I ordered a blood alcohol level
and a tox screen.
Okay, get a CBC,
stick him for a glucose,
and let's get a Chem-20.
His lytes have gotta
be all screwed up.
Got it.
Scattered rales bilaterally.
Did you check his pupils?
Equal, round and reactive.
Saline's going.
Let's give him naloxone,
two IV push,
and why are we
doing that, Carter?
To reverse the narcotic effect.
Are we boring you, or
is it the way he smells?
Sorry.
Okay, check his
head for contusions.
Glucose is 40.
Give him an amp of glucose
and 100 migs of thiamine.
Why are we giving him thiamine?
I don't know.
Given his poor
nutritional state,
glucose can precipitate
Wernicke's encephalopathy.
Symptoms which include ataxia
and paralysis of eye movements.
Isn't it nice to know you
can learn something new?
Mm-hm.
Prep for a gastric
lavage. I'll be back.
Oh, and Carter,
I want you to do a neuro check
every 15 minutes,
and don't forget to
do a stool guaiac.
Good to see you back
down here, Carter.
We missed you.
Hey, Mark, how's it going?
I am ready for a margarita.
Little celebration?
What do you mean?
It's your birthday.
No, about you and Susan.
I want you to know
I think it's great.
What?
I understand you two
went home together
last night.
Wh... What are
you talking about?
We arrived this morning, but...
You know what?
You can fill me in later.
Dr. Greene...
Hi. I'm Reilly Brown.
We haven't met. You're doctor...
Mark Greene.
Shouldn't you be in
high school somewhere?
I'm a lot older than I look.
21.
Well, what do you got, Reilly?
Wilson Wolfe, 50.
Stuck his right hand
in the snow blower,
and ouch!
BP 120/80, pulse 106.
I think he's a little nervous.
Lose any fingers?
Oh. No, got 'em right here.
Ah. Good work, there, Reilly.
Dr. Benton?
What is it, Carter?
I can understand
if you're still upset
about my claiming that aneurysm,
but I don't see why
my surgical education
should suffer.
There's no surgical
service today.
Get back to work.
Who needs help in here?
Carter, get back to work...
Get back to work.
Hi. I'm Reilly Brown.
We haven't met. You're...
Mark, can I talk to you later?
Yeah, sure. Everything okay?
Yeah. No big deal.
All right, Reilly, that's all.
You can go now.
BP's 120/80.
Mr. Wolfe here seems
to have put his hand
into a snow blower.
Yeah, something was blocking it.
I... I cannot believe
I was that stupid.
Ah, lots of people are.
Whoa! Okay, we got a pumper.
Okay, Lydia,
inflate the BP cuff.
We have the two fingers.
Mr. Wolfe, are you right-handed?
Yes.
Not anymore, you're not.
Haleh said Nathan's waking up.
Yay.
Hey! Hey!
What are you doing?
No! Leave us alone.
Haleh, call Security.
Leave us alone.
No. No! You cannot be here!
I have to take care of him.
Uh, Carter...
It's okay, baby.
I'm going to take care of you.
Must be the girlfriend.
What exactly do you suspect?
I'm not quite sure.
But you do have suspicions?
I think he's not including
any bad outcomes.
And you're certain?
Yeah.
And when you confronted him?
He said it wasn't true.
But you think it is?
He explained two of them,
but there are three others.
First, there were five, and
now, there are only three?
Yeah.
Well, I'd make sure.
Well, I'm going over
the charts again.
Maybe he can
explain all of them.
He took me off
the surgical service.
Well, he could have
dozens of reasons
to do that.
Look, if I was going
to talk to somebody,
I mean, officially,
who would it be?
The dean.
Going up against a
guy like Vucelich...
He's one of the top
cardiovascular surgeons
in the country.
What if it comes down
to your word against his?
You don't think I
should pursue it?
If you do, and you're wrong,
your career's over.
I can't believe
you made me eat that chili.
I didn't make you eat it.
Yes, you did.
You held a gun to my head...
Whoa! Watch out!
Oh, man! Help! Help! My leg!
All right, don't move.
We're going to help you.
What's your name?
Paul. He's going to kill me.
Just relax. We're going
to get this bike off you.
Got it? Thanks, Jerry.
Let's just back it up, here.
It's a cool bike.
It's kinda heavy.
Please don't tell him I'm here.
Don't tell who? Is
someone after you?
He's going to kill me.
Who's gonna kill him?
My father. He won't let
me have a motorcycle.
He doesn't think they're safe.
Yeah, well, I guess
you didn't listen to him.
All right, lie back down.
I bought it this morning.
It was great until
the throttle stuck.
Lie down. Lie down.
I couldn't stop it.
Dr. Benton...
What is it, Carter?
Well, I now know
that you have the utmost
lack of respect for me.
If you want to quit the study,
that's your business,
but you should have told me.
Who told you I quit the study?
Everybody I've run into
in the last hour.
And I think I have
the right to know
before they did.
It's more complicated
than that, Carter.
I did not quit the study.
Right.
I've gotta get rid of the bike!
Settle down, Paul.
No, really, I've
got the pink slip
in my pocket.
Maybe somebody here will buy it.
It's a little damaged.
How much you want for it?
Mark...
I'm just trying to help him out.
His father's gonna clobber him.
Yeah, sure.
Ow!
Looks like a fractured fibula.
I can take him from here, Susan.
Yeah, "take him" is right.
Okay. See you later.
You don't have to
tell my dad, right?
How old are you?
17.
Yeah. I'm sorry. You're a minor.
Maybe he'll be grateful
that you didn't kill yourself.
I doubt it.
Miss Boulet...
Ruby, what are you doing here?
I just wanted to thank you again
for all your help.
You're welcome.
And to let you know
my sweetheart
passed away yesterday.
Oh, Ruby. I'm so sorry.
How are you doing?
Oh. Okay.
Not great.
I knew it was gonna happen,
but I guess you
really never believe it
until it does.
Anyway,
the services are
this afternoon at 4:00
at the Mount Sinai Cemetery,
you know, off Grand.
I know you're busy,
but if you'd like to come,
it's okay.
Thank you, Ruby. I
would like to come.
Okay, then.
I'll see you later.
Carter...
Nathan's back asleep
having puked three more times.
Angel's awake,
weepy, and full of regret.
"Never gonna drink
another drop again,"
she says.
Great couple of
shpos, these two.
What did you just say?
"Shpos." It means
subhuman pieces...
No, I know what it
means, thank you.
Well, I gotta get
these x-rays to the O.R.
Carter's been hanging
around Benton too much.
Haven't we all?
Bad day at Black Rock, Dr. Ross.
Multiple seven-year-olds
on their way in...
Animal bites.
Something about a
petting zoo run amok.
♪ Happy birthday Dear Doug... ♪
Hi.
How's Ruby? Mr. Rubadoux.
He's hanging in.
His wife died yesterday.
The service is at 4:00 today,
Mount Sinai.
I'm going,
if you want to go with me.
I don't think I can make it.
I'm pretty jammed up today.
These elevators take forever.
I'm gonna take the stairs.
How long have
you had that cough?
Oh, I don't know.
A while.
Well, your chest x-rays
will show us more.
Do they show everything?
Why?
Maybe they'll show I have AIDS.
Do you?
Yeah.
Look, you don't have to
tell Nathan about me, right?
Have you been sick
with anything else?
Fevers, rashes, night sweats?
No.
Just the cough.
Okay, get a CBC, ABG, Chem-20,
a UA, hepatitis
titers, place a PPD,
and get a CD-4.
I'm concerned that you
might have pneumonia,
so I'm going to keep
you here for a while
and run some tests, okay?
Look, um...
you don't have to
tell Nathan about me,
right?
It's against the law
for me to tell him.
You should.
He has a right to know,
and if he is sick,
he should be getting treatment,
and so should you.
I just think he might get
mad at me, you know,
and, uh...
he might wanna
take off or something,
and, uh...
he's all I have.
Can you make that out to "cash?"
You got a deal.
You got robbed.
I'm doing this as a favor.
You still have to explain
what happened to your leg.
Oh, God.
We'll tell your dad
that you were hitchhiking,
and you got picked
up by a motorcycle,
and then bam! Mark!
Well, he hates hitchhiking too,
but, you know, at least,
I'll only be grounded.
Oh. Watch out for the throttle.
So I got lucky.
In more ways than one, I hear.
What?
Nothing.
Lydia, what did you hear?
Do you have pain anywhere else?
Only my stomach.
Okay, okay. Sit back.
What do you got?
Oh... oh...
T-Ball, is that you?
I haven't seen you in a while.
Oh, my stomach,
it hurts for real.
Uh-huh.
It does! I ain't lying to you.
Yup.
Jeanie...
I can't remember his real name,
but he's under T-Ball
in the turkey file.
Frequent flyer. Drug-seeking.
Are you sure?
He really seems to be in pain.
You'll get used to these guys.
They'll do anything
for Valium, Percodan,
preferably Demerol.
Let him moan and
groan for about an hour.
He'll get bored, go
somewhere else.
Carter!
I asked you to wake
Nathan Conley up
every 15 minutes.
I had something to do.
Yeah, you had that to do,
and you didn't do it.
Okay, I'm sorry.
I want chest films on him,
P.A. and lateral.
Jerry...
I need you to call
Social Services.
I've got an AIDS patient
who's going to need placement.
This thing's still here?
Belongs to Dr. Greene now.
Mark bought a motorcycle?
Got it cheap.
There's only one helmet, though.
You're going to
have to get your own.
What?
When spring comes,
you guys will be
riding in on this
instead of the El.
I know I would.
What are you talking about?
You and Dr. Greene.
I think it's terrific,
by the way.
You make a great couple.
Excuse me.
I'm looking for
Dr. Douglas Ross.
He's with a patient right now.
Can I tell him who's here?
All right, now, you, over there.
I want to sit by Joseph.
I don't want her next to me!
Bet you can't wait
to have that baby.
Hmm. The baby part's fine.
It's when they get
to be this age...
Hey, hey! You know what, guys...
Uh, Nurse Hathaway,
will you give us a
hand over here, please?
I want to sit by Joseph.
Get her away from me!
I didn't even want you
to come to my birthday party!
All right, take off. You got it?
You're gonna sit
over here. Yeah.
Dr. Ross...
Yeah.
A guy at the desk
wants to see you.
Who is it?
He said you'd know him.
Surprise for your birthday.
Wha...
Doug?
Who is it?
My father.
Carol...
Yeah?
I looked up T-Ball's
card in the file.
He's always claimed back pain.
This time, it's his stomach,
not his usual M.O.
Guess he's branching out.
Maybe,
but I ran some
additional blood tests,
just in case.
I wanted one in high school,
but my parents wouldn't let me.
Then I wanted one
after med school,
my wife wouldn't let me.
Whoo! Got a good one here.
You know about motorcycles?
Five brothers?
Had them all over the backyard.
You'd better get
a lock and chain.
E-Ray got his stolen.
Keep it in your apartment.
Third floor, no elevator.
Susan could keep
it at her place.
Jerry, I'm looking for Carter.
I haven't seen him.
All right.
Oh, have you seen Carter?
Is he missing again?
Angel's chest films are back.
It looks like pneumocystis,
and I asked him to order
a bronchoscopy.
Angel...
Oh, man,
I was afraid this would happen.
I had a feeling she
was gonna leave.
That girl was too scared.
If you need to
help, I can wait...
I'm a pediatrician, Ray.
This is a damn exciting job
you got here.
Only if you're unlucky,
which I happen to be today.
Don't they need this?
They got plenty of those inside.
Yeah? Come on. Go on out, Doug.
Come on, Dougie, go on.
You know, my name
isn't Dougie anymore.
Is that why you came here?
Play ball with your boy?
Not with this.
Now, if this were
a basketball...
We don't have a basketball.
Remember when you were a kid,
I used to put you
on my shoulders,
and you'd slam dunk?
"Two points, two
points!" you'd scream.
How's your mother?
She's fine. She's happy.
God love her. She deserves it.
I'll tell her you said so.
No, you won't.
You wouldn't even
tell her you saw me.
Afraid it'll upset her.
Afraid she'll get
all melancholy.
People never gave
her enough credit.
She's a strong woman.
She kind of had
to be, didn't she?
She walked out on me once.
Compared to the 12 times
you walked out on her?
You mean walked
out on you, don't you?
What are you doing here, Ray?
What do you want from me?
I don't want anything from you.
You're all over the airwaves.
You're a big hero.
I was feeling proud of you.
I do have regrets.
I gotta go to work.
Yeah.
Uh, Doug...
Happy birthday, son.
Uh...
I'm all turned around.
Is the El this way?
It's that way.
Dr. Vucelich...
Mr. Carter.
You look winded.
Yeah, I was hurrying.
Dr. Vucelich...
I know Dr. Benton
left the study,
and I just wanted to say
that I've learned more under you
than in four years
of medical school,
and I'd very much like
to continue on the team.
Well, there's initiative,
wouldn't you say?
For better or worse,
there seems to be a
plethora of students
on the team right now.
I can't see
that I would have anything
of substance for you to do
since you're way
beyond scut work.
Best of luck.
Excuse me.
Did you ask Nathan
if he'd take an AIDS test?
He says it gives him the creeps.
Bilateral perihilar
infiltrates right there.
He needs to know
that Angel has AIDS,
and he might have it, too.
Yeah, well, you can't tell him.
The law protects her privacy.
I could if they were married.
And they're not.
Who's protecting Nathan?
And if he has AIDS,
who's protecting all the women
that he might have sex with?
Ethically, I agree with you.
But the law's the law, right?
Even if it's not right.
Hey, T-Ball, you giving up?
CBC showed microcytic anemia.
Blood smear showed
red cell stippling.
Got a blood lead level
80 micrograms per deciliter.
Erythrocyte protoporphyrin,
confirmed lead poisoning.
I was just sleeping
in that old building at night.
I didn't care
they was fixing it
up during the day.
Dust from the renovations.
Full of lead.
Didn't think I needed
validation on this one.
I called Medicine.
They're admitting him.
You seen Doug?
He's still got that
birthday boy in 1.
The llama bite?
Mm-hm.
He's out talking to his dad.
Probably, he'll never come back.
Have you seen Benton?
He's looking for you
to check on some patients.
I can't right now.
There's an arm lac in 6,
rule out appendicitis in 3,
and Dr. Lewis
wanted to talk to you
about that girl, Angel.
She split AMA.
Uh, I can't deal with
those right now, Jerry.
Whew. Oh, man...
You!
You tell me!
What the hell are you doing?
They're wine coolers.
They're really good.
You want some?
Oof!
I fell.
You fell.
Couldn't be because you
were drunk again, could it?
Hey, man, you leave her alone...
Get up.
- -there's
nothing wrong...
Get up! Nathan, make him stop.
Carter...
You guys are the
ones who won't stop.
You're sick, and you get drunk,
and you both
rip out your I.V.'s.
Carter, that's enough.
What's the matter with you?
Oh, man, look what you did.
Look what I did?
Carter, out of here.
Out of here now!
Okay, you, back in bed.
He made her cry, man.
Haleh, can you help
Angel out of here?
Come on, back in bed. Now.
So what's going on?
You saw what was going on.
No, not with them, with you.
These people come in
here on drugs and booze,
and they don't listen to us,
and we're supposed
to treat them.
We're supposed to treat them.
What good is it?
Tomorrow, they're going
to be back on the street
doing the same thing.
Day after that they're back in
here doing the same thing to us.
Well, that's what the job is.
If you don't like them needy...
I don't like the abuse.
Well, none of us do.
Well, at least
you're used to it...
with... your sister.
You know, when
you first got here,
we were a little
concerned about you.
You seemed to care too much.
We're not worried
about that anymore.
What happened to you, Carter?
Loretta... Hi, Dr. Greene.
How you been?
We've been looking for you.
Jimmy was dying to
see The Lion King again.
No, I wasn't.
How about some ice
cream in the cafeteria?
I was just going on a break.
It's a little cold
for ice cream.
Hot chocolate?
Oh, I couldn't hear you.
Thank you.
We need to talk.
Exam 1?
Conni...
Could you take
Loretta to Exam 1?
Sure.
Thanks.
How'd he do it?
Playing soccer.
I thought you said he was 60.
With his grandchildren.
There's a large joint effusion.
I'll do an arthrocentesis.
Tell him to stick
to the sidelines.
Do you have another minute?
Certainly.
Dr. Vucelich is telling people
that I left the study.
I wasn't sure you'd
want to talk about it.
I didn't exactly leave.
Oh, Carl's very discreet.
He didn't think it
would look good
that he had to
fire his star pupil.
Is that what he said?
I believe the euphemism was
"we're experiencing
a difference in style."
Hell, I'd have just fired you.
Our differences had
to do with the data...
Who's left in,
and who's left out.
Well, that's a matter
of interpretation.
It's his research study.
He did get the
grant on the strength
of his reputation and
accomplishments.
Do you know how much money
he brings into this hospital?
If you've had a
disagreement with Vucelich,
I suggest you
retreat immediately
and apologize.
It wasn't a disagreement.
Peter, you have the arrogance
of a great surgeon, the ego,
and someday, one
hopes, the talent,
but what you don't have
is the ability to get along,
to be a member of the team.
Once you're a Carl
Vucelich, you don't need that,
but you can't be a
Carl Vucelich without it.
Here you go, Joseph.
I'll give your dad another call.
Mark, you got a minute?
Someone check out that bite?
Yeah, it's okay,
but he could use
someone to talk to.
His dad was supposed to be here
two hours ago.
Sure. In a few minutes.
Please, sit down.
I have some difficult news.
Yeah. I've been tired,
but what do you expect
from an old hooker?
The new job's going great,
kids are doing well at school.
Everything's good, Dr. Greene.
Your biopsy last time was
positive for cervical cancer.
It's stage 1-B,
which is relatively early
in the spread of the disease,
although, that can
only be confirmed
through surgery.
Treatment is
radical hysterectomy
with removal of the
uterus and cervix.
Sometimes, radiation
therapy is done.
Statistics show with treatment,
the five-year survival rate
is over 90%.
Five years...
My kids won't even be teenagers.
Mr. Rubadoux...
I'm very sorry about your wife.
I made a mistake.
Not in the way I
treated her, but...
in the way I treated you.
I wasn't honest. Wasn't fair.
I was wrong...
and I'm very, very sorry.
This day isn't about
you, Mr. Carter.
How's Angel?
She's still asleep.
Are you kicking us out now?
Mm. Not quite yet.
Oh, God, I gotta
stop this, you know.
Angel's better at it.
She can stop drinking
for a while, you know,
but I just drag
her right back in.
I don't know why she stays.
Nathan, there's something
that Angel's scared to tell you,
but it's something that I
think you have a right to know.
She has AIDS.
She has AIDS?
You mean, the whole thing?
Yes, which means
you could have it, too.
Have you ever been tested?
But could I have
given it to her,
or could she have
given it to me?
Well, if you test positive,
there's no way to know.
Loretta needs a little time
to let it settle in.
Is she going to
have the surgery?
Yeah. She's just worried
about who's going
to take her kids
for five days.
Al and I can take them.
He thinks, after we get married,
we should adopt three or four.
This'll get him off that kick.
Where have you been?
On the longest walk known to man
and I'm freezing.
Start the margaritas in an hour.
Mark, thank you,
and thank Susan,
but I'm gonna have to pass.
Things went that well
with your dad, huh?
No, that was fine.
Same old thing.
He just wanted to
borrow 100 bucks.
Llama birthday
boy is still here.
What?
Bite's been treated,
but his father is running late.
Joseph?
Hey, how's the arm?
Did you know
that you are my first llama bite
in my entire pediatric career?
Which makes this
a very special day.
Also because it happens
to be my birthday.
I hate my birthday.
Yeah, me too.
My dad's always late.
So's mine.
He gave me a trip to that zoo,
and then he didn't even come.
Mm...
What did you get?
Uh... I got a card,
and I got, and I got...
I got two tickets
to the Bulls game.
All right, get this.
There are some
brownies in the refrigerator
in the lounge.
They are not birthday
cake, and they are not mine,
but I think we
should steal them.
Yeah?
Yup. Yup.
Peter...
I'm sorry we couldn't
meet in my office.
I can't get rid
of that endarterectomy team
from Philadelphia.
I, uh...
I went over the charts again.
All of them.
Well, I can see
that spending a day
thinking about this
hasn't helped you,
so let's stop right here.
Agree to disagree,
and you can move on.
Apparently, I already have.
Oh, I didn't fire you.
I just let people
know that you quit.
Which I hadn't.
Well, I thought you needed
help making that decision.
I don't understand.
At least three of those patients
should not have been
excluded from the study.
I determine who's
in and who's out.
I thought the protocol
determined that.
If you're manipulating the data,
how can the study be valid?
How dare you question me?
I give you the
opportunity of a lifetime,
and you have the temerity
to challenge my reputation.
The results won't be accurate.
Aren't lives at stake here?
Yes, Peter, lives are at stake,
lives that I save.
Mothers, fathers,
grandparents are living
because I made choices.
I risked everything to
do what I know is right.
The rules are
there for a reason.
Grow up, Peter.
You aren't some junior
chemist at the FDA.
You're a surgical Resident
in a struggling county hospital.
Now, how do you think
money comes into this place?
Takes more than a "please,"
and, "I promise to do
what's right for my country."
It takes results,
and that, at any cost,
is what I produce.
Now, you screw with that,
and you will be
off surgical service
for a hell of a lot
longer than one day.
Boy, when they made you stupid,
they made you really stupid.
That's the only funny thing
I've heard all day.
I'm going to die,
and you're going to tell me
I should give these up.
Actually, the cold's
doing more damage.
You do have pneumonia.
Maybe quicker's better.
I told Nathan.
I know it's illegal,
but I did it anyway.
He's really worried about you.
He's worried
that maybe he gave it to you.
He wants to go
through this together.
Yeah.
Sure. If he has it...
but if he's clean,
and I'm sick...
why is he gonna
want to stick around?
Which option are you hoping for?
It's cold out here.
I'm gonna go inside.
Sorry about this.
The dean's staff meetings
usually don't take this long.
That's okay.
Does the dean know
what it's regarding?
No, he doesn't.
Hmm.
Yes?
Of course.
It'll just be another
minute or two.
I don't know,
I just really think I've
turned into a cliche.
Don't do this, Mark.
Yeah, I mean,
don't you think I've got that
guy-about-to-be-divorced look
all over me?
I mean, here I am,
in a very attractive,
single woman's apartment
drinking like I'm
still in my 20's,
with a brand-new,
used motorcycle.
You are a guy
about to be divorced.
Yeah, but I don't
have to act like one.
Here. Try this.
Mmm.
Not as good as the first,
better than the second.
Does it matter?
People at work are
making up stories
about you anyway.
About us, you mean.
Mm...
Yeah, and what is
that, can I ask you?
My car's in the shop.
I drop Susie off at my parents',
meet up with you to
go tequila shopping,
and all of a sudden,
we're having a torrid affair.
Who said it was torrid?
No one. I'm just
assuming it would be.
That's not what I meant.
That's okay. I know
what you meant.
I'm sure it would be, too.
Why wouldn't it be?
No reason at all.
There's not enough lime in this.
Hey, bro.
Hey, what's up, Walt?
Same old thing.
What happened?
You look like you
lost your tenth patient.
I don't know, man...
I don't know.
I'm off that research
study I told you about.
Thought the main man loved you.
Yeah, well, he was
breaking some rules,
and I called him on it.
Were you right?
I just thought it'd
be different, man.
I mean, the work we were
doing, where I was going.
Different from what?
Different from everything
that got me here.
You know, scratching my
way through med school,
playing this game and that game,
and I just, you know,
you angle for the best
Residency no matter what, and...
Whew!
You did what you had to do.
What we all have
to do every day.
Yeah, so why do
we keep on doing it?
Well, that's up to you, man.
The world doesn't change
just because you're
moving up in it.
I went to the dean to, uh,
tell him what was going on,
and, uh, I don't know,
I waited around...
20 minutes, and I left.
I just left.
You know, I'm stupid
enough to ruin my career,
but I don't even
have the... courage...
to do it the right way.
You don't understand, Walt. I...
I always thought
when the time came...
I'd do the right thing.
That's...
Hey...