Previously, on ER:
How would you feel
about an ortho rotation?
You have a surgical elective
requirement, so now you're all mine.
- I'm Jaspreet, Neela's cousin.
- My pleasure.
- Wait.
- Excuse me.
Wait, but... I'm your friend...
Are you really about to lecture
me on love with your track record?
- Don't.
- Because I'm thinking right now...
Ray is really wishing
he didn't meet you.
I need to go somewhere,
a facility with professionals.
So take Joe, go to Croatia
for your father, while I do that.
Your full reinstatement,
Dr. Lockhart, has yet to be determined.
You'll be allowed to work
shifts on a probationary status...
until several contingencies
have been met.
Okay. MURTON: A
minimum of two weekly...
physician diversion group meetings.
Plus at least three AA meetings a week.
- Okay, understood.
- Random urine tests...
- several times a month.
- Whatever it takes.
Under normal circumstances
this committee would require you...
to attend another 30 meetings in
30 days, before allowing you back.
In addition to the 30
you've already attended.
But because you were so forthcoming,
and volunteered to check yourself...
into a domestic detox facility,
we've decided to make an exception.
Dr. Pratt also asked us to make
some concessions on your behalf.
So effective immediately, you
are cleared to return to work.
Oh. Thank you. Thank you.
But I need a little more time.
My husband, Dr. Kovac,
and our son are in Croatia.
They've been there... I just need
to spend some time with them.
And I think I would be better
for it when I come back to work.
We have no problem
with that. Dr. Pratt?
It's fine by me. I can
always adjust the schedule.
- How much time do you think you need?
- Couple weeks, maybe.
Since we won't be able
to monitor you in Europe...
you understand we'll have to ask
you to start over again when you return.
Sixty meetings, 60
days, diversion group.
Random urine tests.
Absolutely, agreed. Thank you.
Jaspreet, I gotta pee.
Jaspreet.
I heard you got
in late last night.
Where'd you end up going?
Some club called "Le
Passage"? DJ was wicked.
What are you doing? I have
to pay for hot water, you know.
Okay, no pronator drift.
Mrs. Smalls, hi, I'm Dr. Gates.
Oh, another cute doctor.
Must be my lucky day.
She's been having
trouble sleeping.
No past medical history,
and exam was normal.
I haven't had a
good night in weeks.
You have any
belly or chest pains?
This is all Marty's fault.
He's my husband. He's the
one that keeps waking me up.
I hear him calling me in
the middle of the night.
So I don't quite follow. He wakes
you up while you're sleeping?
Yes, every night.
Have you considered telling
him to stop waking you up?
It doesn't help. Then I
just dream about him.
Well, is he here?
Maybe we can talk to him.
He's been dead for six years.
Don't worry, Mrs. Smalls, we're
gonna take good care of you.
I'm gonna get to
the bottom of this.
Psych consult?
Yeah, check the CBC,
chem panel and UA...
in case she has
hypercalcemia, okay?
- And call Julia Dupree.
- The chaplain?
She's pretty hot for a chaplain.
She's pretty hot period.
How's that working out?
- I'm gonna go order these labs.
- Sam, you seen any attendings?
- Oh, my God, please make it stop.
- What the hell happened to you?
Bad baba ganoush.
I need you to sign off on our CHF-er,
and the board's getting pretty full.
And I need one too.
Why don't you go
home? You look like ass.
Thank you. I was home
until Skye got sick with the flu.
Morris, are you sick?
No, Frank, I got this IV because
I'm feeling a little parched.
- I can't get sick, I got a date.
- Food poisoning, you can't catch that.
Gates, gyn has a bed, but they
can't take your PID for two hours.
- That's what they said four hours ago.
- Don't get uppity, I just work here.
- Sam, what's with my chemo lady in 4?
- Still waiting for Oncology.
Are we the only department
working today? I need a coffee.
Dr. Pratt and Abby need
some privacy for a few minutes.
- Abby's back?
- She was in Croatia.
What are they doing?
What's so private?
If they wanted you to know,
they would have invited you.
Where am I gonna get my coffee?
- Jumbo Mart.
In fact, you should
get us all one.
Oh, yeah. I'll
take a large latte.
- Mm. Black, regular, hold the cream.
- Get me a hot tea, will you?
Large, no foam, per
cent latte americano.
- What the hell's that, Frank?
- Tell Bheru to fix Frank's regular.
- I don't drink coffee.
- All right.
If anyone needs me,
I'll be at the Jumbo Mart.
Freeloaders.
Somebody help!
- What happened? EDDIE: I
heard some guy beating on her.
I broke in and fought him off.
All right, all right.
Get a gurney in here.
- What's her name?
- Sally.
Sally. Okay, Sally,
can you hear me?
He hurt her bad this time.
I think her arm is broken.
Okay, what are people saying?
Well, they think you've been
in Croatia since Christmas.
That's it?
I was sure the rumor
train would been running.
Thank you. Well,
you know how it is.
One minute it's Thanksgiving,
then all of a sudden it's next year.
People do their own thing.
Mm.
Listen, thank you very much
for your discretion, and...
And I'm sorry I had to
burden you with this stuff.
It's not a burden,
Abby. It's management.
The only reason I know the whole
story is because I'm your supervisor.
I gotta say it. I thought
we were friends.
Of course we're friends, Greg.
Then why wouldn't you
come to me for help?
You know, it didn't
have to go like this.
Well, it turns out I'm not so
great at asking for help. Heh, heh.
Well...
Well, I'm here, okay?
You do know that, right?
Chuny and the nurses sent a
condolence card for Luka's dad.
I told them I'd call when I got
back. And I just... I hate this.
I'm so embarrassed and ashamed.
Well, you shouldn't be.
Really? I was a bad friend.
I was a bad doctor.
I was a bad wife.
- I was a bad mother.
- No.
We see bad mothers come
through here all the time.
And you do not qualify.
We all have flaws, Abby, but how
many of us actually work to fix them?
Sorry to interrupt. Victims
from a building fire are en route.
All right, go ahead and prep the
trauma rooms. I'll be right there.
- Damn, terrible day for multiples.
- What's up?
We're short-staffed.
Hey, I can work
for a couple hours.
Really, I'm cool. My
flight's not till tomorrow.
Might even feel good.
Wow, your cousin, Neela, is truly
gifted. Do I look taller? I feel taller.
You know, my
advice is cut and run.
Are you insane? Cut and
run? I'm putting this on my blog.
Oh, God, that's just wrong.
If that's wrong, I
don't wanna be right.
Uh-oh. Surgeons are here.
- Hey, what's up, party people?
- Hi, guys.
Neela, how's Jaspreet doing?
She hasn't called me in a few days.
Jaspreet? She's doing
just fine, buddy. Trust me.
Somebody call for a doctor?
- Hey, you.
- Hey, welcome back. How was Croatia?
- You know, European.
Sorry for your loss. - Thanks.
- Harms, what's it look like?
- Dexter Jackson, 11, building fire.
Burns to hands and chest,
crush injuries from falling debris.
- Tachy to 160. BP, 100.
- Dex, don't worry.
We're gonna get you fixed up. Morris,
to Trauma 1. Grady, you go with him.
What we got here?
Kayla Weeks, 7,
smoke inhalation.
- Minor injuries, some wheezing, sats 92.
- Having trouble breathing?
- Firefighter behind is pretty bad.
- Okay.
Get her set up on nebs,
check a baseline chest.
Chuny, come with me. - Yup.
- Zades, talk to me.
- Jake Gleason, 28.
Floor gave way in the fire, 15-foot fall.
Burns to hands and face, spine injury.
- Jake, where you hurting at, man?
- Back mostly.
- Sats 91.
- All right, let's get him in Trauma 2.
Hey, do me a favor.
Wiggle those toes for me.
Like that?
I'm sorry, I know it's last
minute, but they surprised me.
- Well, that was nice, right?
- Yes, from a certain point of view...
one's big brother and his wife
showing up unannounced is nice, yes.
- Not nice?
- No... Yes, it's very nice.
It's just that usually by dessert,
they're telling me how worried they are.
Because, you know, I'm wasting
my life away as a chaplain.
Well, if the shoe fits...
- Kidding. What, are they not religious?
- Hardcore Catholic.
He's a hedge-fund millionaire...
so it doesn't help that I'm
a $35,000-a-year chaplain.
- Yeah, yeah.
- Are you scared to meet my family?
Who, me? No, I would love to
meet your family. It's just that...
You know, I just don't know
what time I'm gonna be done here.
Well, if you can, I could
really use some backup.
All right, I'll let you know.
- How's she doing?
- Out cold.
Sally?
- Got a little ETOH going here, huh?
- Yeah, don't light a match.
And it's not just alcohol.
All right, we still need a head
scan. Did the plain films come in yet?
Uh-huh. The CT will be ready for her
in a few minutes. I already paged Ortho.
- Okay.
- Is she gonna be okay?
I think so.
They're always fighting over there,
man. The guy, he's a real prick.
It's a good thing
you were close.
C-spine is clear.
How's her arm?
Well, it's broken pretty
bad, but it's fixable.
You get the finger traps
ready when they take her to CT.
Should I wait here?
That's fine.
Oh, your head's bleeding.
- Hey, don't worry about it.
- Well, we should look at it.
It's okay, we won't bite.
All right, let me take a look.
You wanna sit down here?
It doesn't look too bad. We can
fix that up with a couple staples.
- Mm-hm.
- Sam.
Car accident.
Head-on with a drunk driver.
I used to be a
grade-school music teacher.
Now I do courses online.
It's kind of hard to scare the
students that way, you see.
- Wait, wait, this is Ortho.
- Yeah, I start today.
I thought that was next
week. Dubenko hates me.
- Well, Dubenko's not on. Crenshaw is.
- Yeah, great, he hates me more.
Neela.
Aah! GROSSMAN: Ohh!
- Just a bit outside.
- Okay?
- Ow. Look at you, you're early.
- Well, you know, first impressions.
- Dr. Rasgotra, meet Doctors Ramsey.
- Hey.
- Craig.
- How's it going?
- Hi.
- And Pavelich.
- Hey, what's up? RAMSEY:
Heard great things about you.
What's that?
This is Dr. Zelinsky,
a surgical intern.
You okay, man? You
need a glass of water?
- You look a little dry.
- No, I'm good.
Yeah, Harold was just leaving.
Good luck.
Hockey, I used to play a
little at school. Field, not ice.
- Take a shot.
- I couldn't, it's been years.
- Come on.
- Come on, take a shot.
Let's see it.
Yes. Girl power, come on. Yes.
First albuterol's done.
You want continuous?
No, sats are up to 97,
and the wheezing's better.
Repeat treatment in half an
hour. Is that your brother in there?
No, he's not my real brother,
but he's nice to me so far.
- Are you guys foster kids?
- Yeah.
Okay, you sit tight. I'm
gonna go check on him.
My name is Abby, this is Malik.
Let us know if you need anything.
- BP's up a little to 85.
- How's he doing?
- Not great, still taching away.
- Blood in the belly?
No free blood, but look at the liver.
- Subscapular hematoma.
Films are back.
- How's Luka holding up?
- You know, it's hard.
- My dad died when I was 19.
- At least, you're back in the States.
Always nice to come
home after a long trip, huh?
- Okay, C-spine looks clear.
- Nothing on the chest or pelvis.
- Kids' foster mom is here.
- Hi, I'm Dr. Lockhart.
We were in the laundry room when
the fire broke out. Are they okay?
Kayla has some smoke
inhalation, she's gonna be fine.
Dexter's more serious. He's
got bleeding around his liver.
It's probably stupid's fault.
You leave the oven on again?
Keisha, I told you,
stop calling her that.
You got a phone? I need to
get somebody to cover my shift.
Right there. Dial 9 first.
- Pratt could use a hand in here.
- I'll go.
Solu-Medrol, 2.4 grams over 15 minutes,
then infuse at 430 milligrams per hour.
Somebody page Neurosurge.
Can you get central line going?
- Good. MARQUEZ:
Nice to have you back.
We missed you. How's Luka?
He's good. Sterile 6's, please.
- Neurosurgery's on the way.
- Good.
If you're gonna have a funeral,
Croatia's a good place to do it.
- How is he?
- Fracture at T11.
T11, what's that mean?
Well, it looks like you've
got a fractured vertebrae...
with bruises of the spinal cord.
Will it get better? I'm not
gonna be paralyzed, am I?
It's just a little too
early to tell right now.
- Those kids I saved, are they okay?
- So far, so good.
If that girl hadn't broken
that window and screamed...
- we wouldn't know they were in there.
- Damn it!
All right, go, just go, go.
- Okay, prep and drape, I'll be right back.
- All right.
Another 600 cc bolus.
- Hemoglobin's down to 12.4, BP, 70.
- Type and cross two more units.
See what you did, stupid?
- Keisha.
- I didn't leave the oven on.
- Liar, you know...
- Stop.
- Dexter's gonna die and it's your fault.
I hate you.
Kayla, wait.
Kayla.
Oh, my God, are you okay, honey?
Okay, come here,
sweetie. Are you okay?
It's not my fault. I
didn't leave the oven on.
I didn't.
How many fingers
am I holding up?
- Um, three?
- Okay, what about here?
No, sorry. Two.
Can you follow my finger?
Okay.
- How long have your eyes been like that?
- I don't know. Forever.
You ever seen a doctor for it?
No, I keep it a secret
so people won't hate me.
Sweetheart, nobody hates you.
All my foster families do.
That's why I keep getting moved.
Listen to me, grownups can
be really weird sometimes.
It may seem like
they don't like you...
but that's probably
because they're really busy...
or they're sad, or they're mad.
But I guarantee you, it's not
about you. You understand?
And for what it's
worth, I like you.
I left the oven on once, but I
turned it off all the way this time.
I know I did.
Ortho's here.
Hey, Mayday. NEELA: Hey.
Since when are you Ortho?
- This morning.
You guys mind if maybe we
catch up later? I can see some films.
- Here you go.
- Who are these guys?
Orthopedic specialists,
here to look at her arm.
What ligaments are disrupted
in a perilunate dislocation?
Scapholunate and the
lunotriquetral interosseous ligament.
And?
- Back from X-ray?
- Never went, sats are dropping.
- Down to 91.
- Tube him before he goes to CT.
- Grady, you're up.
- Is he okay?
He might have smoke damage to his
lungs. We're gonna help him breathe.
Suction please.
You know anything about
Kayla's vision problems?
- Vision problems? No.
- Cricoid pressure.
She's only been with
me for a couple of weeks.
That explains a
lot. She's clumsy.
- You see the cords?
- Yup.
Now why would they
send me a disabled kid?
They should know better
that I can't handle that.
I'm a single foster mom,
and I got five of them.
- I'm in.
- I don't think they knew.
She's been keeping this to herself.
- Sats are up, 96.
I'd like to run a few
tests if that's okay.
Surgery's here.
- What do you need us to fix?
- Twenty-five percent surface area burns.
Crush injury with liver
hematoma on FAST scan.
- Pressure's down.
- What's happening?
Following the Parkland
formula? Four cc's...
Yes, we know.
Hematoma could be
expanding. Let's look.
Throw in a central line. I
want his BP up before CT.
Intraosseous is faster.
No, I can give more
fluids with a central line.
- Wait, wait, wait.
- Hey.
Oh, and I am in before
you even gloved up.
All right, let's
get him up to CT.
Squeeze in another few liters,
and you should go with them.
Let's just follow them.
- I hate surgeons. ABBY:
Seems like it's mutual.
- How you feeling?
- Like hell.
Morris, have you ever heard of
a genetic disorder called LCA?
- No, but it's just food poisoning...
- Not you. The little girl from the fire.
Leber's congenital amaurosis. It
causes center-field vision loss in kids.
And she had a normal fundoscopic
exam and nystagmus, which are indicators.
I've never heard of it. Send
her to Optho, let them sort it out.
Can somebody please give
me a shot? I'm dying here.
- What is it, Compazine?
- Yeah, I've been puking my brains out.
What are you doing?
I'll do the arm, no butts.
- Well, it hurts way more in the arm.
- No. Here.
Come on, be a professional.
All right, Abby, make it quick.
Right cheek or left?
Okay, exaggerate the
deformity slightly, and then pull.
- Ow! What the...?
- Not bad. Splint.
Want a sugar tong extended
to the ends of the phalanges?
- Thanks, hon.
- Or Sam.
Post-reduction films,
get her on the surgery list.
Stabilize the wrist.
You think I can go home soon?
I wanna get a tetanus shot
for that head lac first, okay?
Hey, how long is that
gonna take? I should go.
Just hang out, we'll take
care of you soon, okay?
- Wow, what happened to that guy?
- Car accident.
- You did great.
- I did?
Hi, stranger, we
heard you were back.
Hi. SAM: Hi.
What's up? GATES: Nothing.
- Hi.
How are you? ABBY: Good.
Been gone long, we didn't
know if you were coming back.
- Where were you?
- I was taking some private time to...
- Personal time... Who are you?
- Barry Grossman, Orthopedics.
Hi, Abby Lockhart.
So you're up in Ortho?
- Yeah.
- That's great.
How was Croatia?
I hear it's gorgeous.
- Yeah, well... Yeah, I'm going tomorrow.
- Oh, you mean you didn't go?
No, Joe and Luka are there, but I
had some stuff I had to take care of, so...
Okay.
Sorry to break up the
little reunion, but we gotta...
- Hey, I'm gonna call you tonight, okay?
- Okay.
- I'm gonna go work on that splint.
- Cool, I'll meet you there.
- Good to see you.
- Welcome back.
Thanks.
Then the rabbi
says to the priest:
"I'm sorry, sir, I didn't
know you were sitting here."
That's hilarious. I've
never heard that one before.
- Hi, looks like you guys are having fun.
- Oh, she's delightful.
Well, your labs came
back normal, which is good.
There's gonna be another doctor
to come talk to you soon, okay?
Take your time. I
got nowhere to be.
- You mind if I borrow her for a sec?
- Go ahead.
I'll be right back.
Thanks for coming. I thought a
little God talk would do her good.
She's actually an atheist.
But did you know she was
a Rockette back in the '50s?
That's how she met her husband.
He came to the show and
hung out at the stage entrance...
just so he could meet her.
He said of the whole line of beautiful
girls, she was the only one he saw.
So no prayers, no meditation,
just shooting the breeze?
She's alone and grieving. And
no matter what you believe in...
even if it's nothing, grief
is something I'm good with.
Dinner's at
Gibson's, by the way.
- If that sweetens the deal.
- Doesn't hurt.
- See you later.
- Okay.
Could you page
Psych for me again?
- What you mean, she wasn't in Croatia?
- Luka and Joe went without her.
- Where's she been?
- Said she had some personal stuff.
Sounds like divorce talk to me.
- No, you think? Really?
I knew it all along.
Just a matter of time.
Guys.
- Everything okay?
- Yeah.
- Yeah, it's all good.
- You bet.
- Optho returned your call.
- Thanks, Frank.
- Watch his IV.
- His IV's flowing.
Trauma 1 is ready.
- Hang packed cells now.
- What happened?
Crashed before
we could scan him.
- What's he mean?
- Rapid infuser's primed.
He's bleeding internally.
He needs an ex-lap. He
probably opened up his hematoma.
- We need more access.
- BP's 82/58.
Hold on, maybe
it's a pelvic fracture.
- You didn't see one.
- It's a tough call on kids.
The symphysis is wide, there's
a separation and S-I diastasis.
We don't have time to
argue a questionable finding.
- He could be bleeding in his pelvis.
- Liver's the most likely source.
Open his belly and it's
a fracture, he'll bleed out.
- So we just screw around?
- Keep looking.
Show me free fluid, and
you can do your ex-lap.
- T-pod him and fuse two units.
- We need to take him up now.
All right, just give her two minutes.
You know how this goes if you're wrong.
This should tamponade
any pelvic bleeders.
Liver hematoma's
enlarging. Kid needs the O.R.
- It's not that impressive.
- Two minutes are up.
- How much blood has he had?
- Twenty per kilo.
- Okay, let's get this show on the road.
- Wait, hold on.
Pressure's good, 100/60.
- Hemoglobin's up to 14.
- You see any free fluid in the belly?
- I suppose surgery can wait a bit.
- What's going on?
We stopped the bleeding.
Okay, stable. Take him up to CT.
- What are you doing out here?
- What's the deal with my tetanus shot?
No one's come for that yet? Man,
I'm sorry, we're really slammed.
Why don't you go lay down on one of
the beds. You'll be more comfortable.
She's been mumbling.
I thought she might wake up.
I'm definitely not the first
thing that she wants to see.
Oh, I'm guessing she won't
mind. You saved her life, man.
One night I found her in the
hall, passed out and drunk.
So I went in and I fished
the keys out of her purse.
I couldn't just leave her there.
But when I brought her inside,
she woke up and she freaked out.
Yeah. Good times.
I'll go check on your tetanus,
all right? Hang in there.
Hey, man, listen very
carefully, all right?
I don't care how backed
up you are, just fix it.
Thank you, I'm glad somebody
finally gave it to Radiology.
I was on the phone with my landlord.
My toilet's been running for weeks.
Dr. Gates, daughter of your
patient in 2 returned your call.
- Did Psych come down for her yet?
- Not that I know of.
- Check on my tetanus guy, please?
- Sure.
Thank you.
Oh, my God, pinch me, I'm dreaming.
Yes, gentlemen, may I help you?
- We're looking for Dr. Pratt.
- That's me.
- You must be here for Jake Gleason.
- He all right?
He's still in surgery
but I'll take you guys up.
- I can do that, Dr. Pratt.
- Yeah, thanks Javier, but I got this.
Come on, fellas.
We need to do a test
called an electroretinogram...
which tells us if the cells in
the retina respond to light.
If it is this LCA
thing, what then?
We'll know what we're
dealing with for one.
And there are some new
therapies that could help.
- You just need to sign here for consent.
- Okay.
And they can actually
take her today if you want.
Dexter's up in surgery.
Shouldn't I be up there?
Okay, how about this? On the
way up, we drop you off at the O.R...
and I go with
Kayla for her test.
You okay with that?
Yeah, she can come with me.
Where the hell is the rest of my stuff?
- Get back in bed.
- Who are you?
- Dr. Gates. You have a serious fracture.
- Whatever.
- You need surgery.
Shut up. Will you just take
this off, so I can go home?
- Who stole my shoe?
- If you don't keep this immobilized...
- it's not gonna heal right.
- Take it off.
- Wanna sign out against medical advice?
- Right, I'm not letting you touch me.
Fine by me, I'll
get the paperwork.
You walk out that door, you're gonna
lose the use of your hand. Want that?
- What?
- Just get back in bed, okay?
Let us do our job.
- Do you know what happened to you?
- I don't know.
You got beat up, and your
neighbor, Eddie, intervened.
You mean, the freak? He
should mind his own business.
Oh, yeah. Well, he
saved your ass, okay?
He's got a pretty nasty
cut on his head to prove it.
How long's this gonna
take anyways, huh?
Does the posterior
technique have a name?
- The Kocher approach.
- And who was Kocher?
A 19th century Swiss surgeon,
perhaps the most famous in his day.
Published Kocher's
Operative Surgery, 1892...
won the Nobel prize
in Medicine in 1909.
- She Nobel prized you, bro.
- It's not funny.
Oh come on, give it up. She's
money. You're money. Ignore him.
Dude, give her some.
- I need some too.
- Oh, no.
- What?
- Wendy can't play next week.
Out-of-town baby shower.
What position did you play?
- Sorry?
- Field hockey, what position?
Center forward.
We're squared away with your tetanus.
We'll get you signed out, you can split.
- Did she finally wake up?
- Yeah, just a bit ago.
And her CT was clear,
so she's gonna be fine.
She say anything
about what happened?
- No, but she was pretty out of it.
- Dr. Gates?
- Not now, Grady, I'm busy.
- It's important. Like, urgent important.
I'm sorry, I'll be right back.
Stay.
- What?
- It's Mrs. Smalls in 2.
- Psych not come down yet?
- No, that's not really a problem now.
I found her pulseless and apneic.
She's got rigor mortis and lividity.
- She must have died like, an hour ago.
- Didn't anyone come and check on her?
We were waiting for Psych.
- You doing okay, kiddo?
- Yeah.
You know, if it is LCA, it
might be worth a write up.
- We could co-author.
- That's okay, it's all you.
- It doesn't hurt at all.
- See? Told you.
All right, now move your forehead
right up to the dome and touch it.
Good, right there.
It will just take a
minute to calibrate.
What do you wanna
be when you grow up?
- A doctor and a singer.
- Wow, both, huh?
Well, I can't help you with
the singing. I'm really bad.
- I'm pretty good.
- Why don't you sing me a song?
I am beautiful No
matter what they say
Words can't bring me down
I am beautiful In
every single way
Yes, words can't bring me down
Oh, no
So don't you bring me down today
Gates, heard you killed
another happy customer today.
That's nice, Frank, great.
Psych just came down to see
her. Said they'd meet you in Sutures.
Somebody's got a
lot of explaining to do.
- Can you sign off on our GI bleeder?
- I need one for my chemo lady.
All right. SAM: How are you?
I'm good.
I just wanted to say if you need
to talk or anything, I'm totally here.
I just wanna make sure
that everything's okay.
It's good, I'm good. Thanks.
The bone fragment was
removed from his spine.
Surgery was successful.
He's already started
moving his legs. It's all good.
- Thank you for everything, Ms. Dupree.
- My pleasure.
You know, I'll make sure the chapel
stays open for your guys all night.
Oh, hey, excuse me. Hi, I'm
Dr. Lockhart, I worked on Jake.
- That's really good news about him.
- Thank you.
- We appreciate everything you did.
- You're very welcome.
Listen, do you, by any chance,
know how that fire got started?
Ms. Rosemary Smalls,
what happened to her?
- We don't know.
- All right, then. Love the easy ones.
Have a good night.
Okay, great, thanks. Good news,
Dexter's surgery went very well.
- He's in Recovery right now.
- Thank God.
Malik can take you there
as soon as we're done.
So there's no treatment
for this LAC thing?
It's "LCA." Leber's
congenital amaurosis.
Sorry, this day has
just... It's been a lot.
I know.
Well, there may be some
gene-replacement therapies...
or clinical studies
we can enroll her in.
You know, this is
manageable. There is hope.
There's no reason why she can't
be a perfectly happy kid with a full life.
You can do all those
tests right here?
- No, there's an organization in Iowa...
- Iowa?
Yeah, but we just have to
send them a tube of her blood.
And all the tests
are free of charge.
Okay, baby girl, let's
go ahead and do this.
Oh, and...
I talked to the fireman
and he told me...
there was an electrical problem on
the second floor that started the fire.
It had nothing to
do with your oven.
So she didn't do it?
You got something to say?
Keisha.
- I'm sorry.
- But don't call me stupid anymore, okay?
Don't worry, baby, she won't.
Kayla, it was really
great to meet you.
- You take care, okay?
- Okay.
So how long will I
have to stay here, huh?
Surgeons will answer all your
questions when you get upstairs.
- A day? Two days? A week?
- We don't know, Sally.
- I got a life, you know.
- Could have fooled me.
- What did you say?
You... EDDIE: Excuse me.
How do I get out of this
place? This place is like a maze.
Just take those
doors back there if...
Hey, it's you.
Hi.
What, you can't look at me?
Take off your hood.
Thank you, for what you did.
You're welcome.
See you around.
You can just go out
through those doors.
Thank you. Take care.
Bye, Eddie.
- Poor guy.
- Yeah, it must be tough.
Hey, Alex is in town.
We're gonna go see a movie.
You and Sarah wanna come?
Can we go another
time? I have this thing...
- Yeah, anytime.
- Yeah?
- Okay. You sure?
- Okay. Mm-hm.
Go.
- Come on, go, go, go.
- Go, go, go.
Come on, here we go. - Come on.
Bring it, bring it, bring it.
- Go, go, go.
Whoa!
- Oh, yeah.
- Five seconds.
- What are you doing here?
- I came to say goodbye.
- What's with the skates?
- Oh, long story. Where are you going?
I'm gonna see Cousin
Maya in San Francisco.
My father's coming to Chicago.
- I need to skip town before he gets here.
- And what do you want me to tell him?
Tell him I've completely disappeared,
and you have no idea where I went.
Okay, I'll call him.
First, I need you to do
me a really big favor.
Rasgotra, practice is Wednesdays
at 6. Game is Thursday at 7.
We'll be at Ike's if you wanna
join us. Hey, congratulations.
Night.
Congratulations? Did
you win something?
No, I think I just got recruited.
So, what's this big favor?
Starting tomorrow, docs
will not be permitted...
to ask a nurse or a
clerk to call a consultant.
It has to be a written order.
- More work for Frank.
- Me too.
Why? What if we're in
the middle of a trauma?
It's just for a month.
We have to present real data to
Admin if we wanna eliminate delays.
Unless anybody has anything else
to say, come on, let's get back to work.
Oh, yeah, hey, can I have
a minute? With everybody?
Um, I know some of
you have been wondering.
And I appreciate the concern.
I wasn't in Croatia
for the last few weeks.
After Luka's father
died, they left without me.
And I was in a
residential detox facility.
I'm an alcoholic.
I just wanted to set the record
straight and tell the truth...
because I have way too much
respect for all of you to keep lying.
And I'm very, very sorry because I
know what I did didn't only affect me...
it affected all of you too.
And I just hope I haven't
done any irreparable damage...
to any of the
relationships here.
But I'm sober now, and
I'm going to stay that way.
- So you were in rehab the whole time?
- Yeah.
Were you ever drunk at work?
Let's get signed out and
get back out on the floor.
- We still got a lot of patients out there.
- Thanks.
Thank you.
I told her daughter
she was fine.
I worked her up,
everything seemed normal.
Did you do everything
you were supposed to?
Proper history, labs?
I could have done an EKG.
You know, cardiac monitor.
Maybe I missed
an MI, arrhythmia.
I'd be worried about you if you
weren't upset about Mrs. Smalls...
but I think it's pretty obvious
what the cause of death was.
She missed her husband,
and she wanted to be with him.
- You're kidding me, right?
- No, I think she was a pretty lucky lady.
Julia, she died.
She had a beautiful daughter. She
had a full life filled with happiness.
And she found true love.
Some people live their
whole lives and never get that.
How else do you explain her
husband calling her from the other side?
And you really believe that?
Yeah, I do.
That's because I have faith.
- Faith.
- Yes.
Look, we all end up
like Rosemary Smalls.
Who knows when? Who knows how?
But love, trust, truth, higher
power, the things that really matter...
you can't have any
of those without faith.
Especially love.
Now, we are losing precious
pre-dinner drink time...
and I need at least two
martinis to deal with my brother.
So come on. Come on, come on.
- Some meeting, huh?
- Yeah, some meeting.
Admit to Med-Surg for IV antibiotics.
Where are diverticula most likely to be?
Narrowest portion with the highest
intrasegmental pressures: sigmoid colon.
- Excellent work, Harold.
- All right, you, you, come here.
All right, so here's the deal.
Jaspreet's gone, and
she's not coming back.
- Where'd she go?
- Well, I could tell you that...
but then I'd have to kill you.
She asked me to relay the following:
Archie, thank you for a wonderful night.
It was great, but please stop
calling. And don't ever call again, ever.
Harold, thank you for a wonderful night.
It was great, but please stop calling.
And don't ever call again, ever.
So there you go.
And I'd very much appreciate it if
we never speak of this again, ever.
- You?
- Abby.
- Hi.
Hey, how was
your first day back?
- How's Ortho?
- Great.
I heard about the staff meeting.
Yeah, that was fun.
It's good you said all that.
- Listen, I owe you an apology.
- No, you don't.
I do.
You tried to help me and
I just pushed you away.
And you don't deserve that.
I'm still here if you
need help, you know.
Thank you.
- God, you had me so worried.
- I know, I'm sorry.
- It's so great to have you back.
- Yup, just in time to leave again.
- When do you go?
- Tomorrow morning.
I can't wait. I miss Joe
and Luka like crazy.
- Well, give them my best. Travel safe.
- Thanks.
- Okay.
- All right.
Bye. ABBY: See you.