Is your mom
flying in for tonight?
No, she's got
an early day tomorrow.
Doesn't wanna red-eye back.
She sent me a check.
Well, then after the ceremony,
let's you and I go
out and celebrate.
Depends on
how late it is.
(CHUCKLES) Reese,
it's your graduation.
You've earned it.
Okay.
Okay, well, I'll be the guy
clapping the loudest.
Please don't.
I'll see you later.
Morning.
Hey.
Oh, no. Don't tell me
you lost it again.
What?
Your wedding ring.
Oh, uh...
No.
I just thought that it
was time to take it off.
Can't get used to it
not being there, though.
(BABY CRYING)
Dr. Manning.
Six-month-old boy,
Michael Thomas,
suffering from
diarrhea and vomiting.
You're going
to Treatment Six.
Hi, I'm Dr. Manning.
Something's
really wrong with him.
Hey, don't worry, we're gonna
take good care of your baby.
Okay.
(BABY CONTINUES CRYING)
(PAGER BEEPS)
Page Dr. Rhodes.
Dr. Halstead,
you're with me.
It's Dr. Downey.
Talk to me.
BP's 90 over 60,
rate of 110.
Respiration's at 38.
Okay, we'll go to
Trauma Three. Baghdad.
CESAR:
He was found at home.
He dialed 911 himself,
but he was down by
the time we got there.
Dr. Downey,
can you hear me?
(GROANS)
Are you in pain?
MAGGIE: Get ready to rotate.
No breath sounds
on the right.
Need an X-ray.
Sharon,
we need you in Baghdad.
On my count...
One, two, three.
MAGGIE: Transfer.
(GRUNTS)
Get it out.
MALE NURSE: Gotta bag it.
FEMALE NURSE:
Start a saline line,
get a pleurovac.
X-ray clear.
WILL: There's fluid
in his chest.
He just had an RFA yesterday.
His liver must be
bleeding into it.
(STRAINING) Yeah.
Yeah.
All right,
hemopneumothorax
on the right.
All right.
We're gonna put
in a chest tube
to drain the blood.
Two of Versed and
five of morphine.
Right away.
Sorry about the shirt.
Pulse is thready.
All right, get
a groin line in. Will you?
Yep.
Dr. Halstead.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
CONNOR: Okay, I'm in.
How is he doing?
His liver is
bleeding into his chest.
I need to open
him up to stop it.
How close are we?
All right, I'm in.
Activate the MTP.
Tell them to send
all the blood they have
and meet me in the OR.
Copy.
You gotta stop the bleeding.
I'm barely keeping up.
(GRUNTS SOFTLY)
PATEL: Dr. Rhodes?
CONNOR: I can't get
to the diaphragm.
The right lung is in the way.
Can you collapse it?
Give me some room?
DR. VORSPAN: Yeah.
CONNOR: Set up the Argon
Plasma Coagulator.
DR. VORSPAN: Putting in
a bronchial blocker
right now.
Allen.
It's coming. In a sec.
Lung deflating.
PATEL: Good.
Okay, I see the bleed.
All set with the erbe.
Bleeding's slowing,
it's still pretty oozy.
How much product
has he gotten?
Six platelets
and one cryo.
We're gonna have to
warm him up in the ICU
and continue transfusions.
Make sure
he can form clots.
Want me to close?
No.
My teacher. I'll close.
So, insomnia,
obsessive pacing,
aggression?
Some of that.
And this is a parrot?
Right.
What else you know
about the bird?
He was kept by a hoarder,
basically lived
in a trash heap.
Abused?
Certainly neglected.
Yelled at a lot.
Look, I don't know
what to do.
I tried to give him away,
but nobody'll take him.
How does he feel
about you?
How should I know?
He's a bird.
Can you do me a favor
and before you try
and get him away again,
can I come by
and meet him?
You wanna meet
the parrot?
Very much so.
How about lunch today?
I'll bring sandwiches.
Okay.
SHANNON: What's wrong
with our baby?
He's probably
just weak, right?
From the diarrhea?
We've given him fluids,
so he's not dehydrated.
Was he born prematurely?
No.
His liver's enlarged.
SHANNON: Oh, my God.
NATALIE:
Was he exposed
to any toxins in the house?
NICK: No, we're careful
about that.
Anything else
you can think of?
Only, he had just
started sitting up,
but he hasn't
been able to do that
the last couple of days.
Okay. Let's order a CBC,
CMP, UA and blood cultures.
And let's start a
10 cc bolus of albumin
and page Dr. Grant.
What is all that?
We just need to run
some further tests.
And I'm bringing in
a specialist to consult.
Okay?
We're gonna find out
what's going on with you.
NATALIE: I'll be back shortly.
You could've just
dropped me off.
My mama told me,
"Escort a lady to the door."
(CHUCKLES)
Well, here I am.
Safe and sound.
Mmm-hmm.
Yes.
See you tonight.
(INAUDIBLE)
Hey, Maggie?
MAGGIE: Yeah.
Any word on Dr. Downey?
He's out of surgery
and stable.
Oh, good. Good.
How's the renovation going,
Bert's "man cave?"
Oh, you know, I thought
it would cheer him up.
But he's not showing
any interest at all.
I feel like I'm
being punished for
not retiring with him.
Rough at home, huh?
That's an understatement.
Morning, Ms. Goodwin.
Dr. Halstead.
That woman
does not like me.
You haven't exactly
made her life easy.
How's the
job search going?
Hey, got an offer yesterday
from Mount Sinai, Miami.
Oh.
Plus Memorial
West in California.
So, either way,
looks like sunshine for me.
What about Med?
Lost cause.
I should've heard by now.
Oh, well, and you know
Dr. Manning...
What?
She's not wearing
her wedding ring anymore.
Why would you
tell me that?
Timing, Dr. Halstead.
That's what it's all about.
(SLURRING) I'm fine.
His fault! Shouldn't have
been wearing that shirt!
Oh, lovely.
Ugh, that seems
like a pleasant one.
Take them to
Treatment Three, please.
Oh, Thank you.
April, you busy?
I'm with you.
All right, fellas,
I'm Dr. Halstead. Follow me.
(CHUCKLES)
I don't need this.
Fin, just let them
take a look.
(CONTINUES CHUCKLING)
I'm fine!
All right, come on,
let's get you
on this bed?
No, no. Just,
just wanna go home...
Hey. What happened?
(GRUNTS) Okay.
Went out to
party after the game,
he sees these Cards fans...
Douchebag's wearing
a "Cubs suck" shirt.
And we won,
how could we suck?
Hey. Sit down!
Sit down!
Douchebag!
Sir, I need you
to stay on the bed!
Sir, stay on the bed!
No, let me go!
WILL: Hey!
Ow!
WILL: Security!
You, hold him!
(PANTING)
TY: Dude.
You all right, April?
(COUGHING)
You okay?
Yeah, I'm okay.
Get this guy
in restraints.
SECURITY: I got it.
Five of Haldol.
FINLEY: No! No!
You're good?
You're okay?
(PANTING) I'm fine.
All right,
let's move here.
Cardiomegaly.
What?
Michael's heart
is enlarged.
What would cause that?
Given everything else,
I'd say we're looking
at a genetic disease.
How can that be?
We're both fine.
You can each be
carrying one faulty
recessive gene which,
when paired together,
can express in Michael.
Dr. Manning,
BP and sats are dropping.
(RAPID BEEPING)
He's not breathing.
Oh, my God.
Tube him now.
Ten mics dopamine
per kilo and 15 of fentanyl.
FEMALE NURSE: Right away.
NATALIE: I'm in.
SARAH:
Sats are coming up.
Right, let's get him
up to the PICU.
I'll go with him.
Where is he going?
What's happening?
He's stable.
We're taking him up to
Pediatric Intensive Care.
You can come with.
And then what?
There are many
genetic diseases
that could be causing this.
We need to
determine which one.
Chicago Med can do
fast genetic sequencing.
We'll need blood samples
from the three of you
to analyze.
Hopefully, we'll have
a diagnosis in 26 hours.
But, what if he
keeps getting worse?
We're gonna do
everything that we can.
Okay? Go ahead.
Didn't mean to hit her.
Sorry. Sorry.
Really, I'm fine.
Lungs are clear.
So, can I go
back to work?
Just hold on.
Does this hurt?
No.
You finished?
Here?
Ow!
Okay. On a scale
of one to ten,
how bad's the pain?
Three.
That means it's
a seven or eight.
Hey, you are probably okay,
but I'd like to get
a chest X-ray
just to be safe.
No way.
April,
you have some
pain and tenderness.
A broken rib
could've punctured
your liver, or your lung.
I wanna make sure
you don't have
a pneumothorax.
I'm not short of breath.
We don't wanna see you
wheeled back in
here on a gurney.
Ms. Goodwin,
I appreciate that.
But you are all
over-reacting.
I'm telling you, I'm fine.
He's been off
the lorazepam for two hours,
and he still hasn't woken up.
And he's still
completely reliant
on the vent.
(SIGHS) So? You needed me
to tell you he should've
come to by now?
No, I needed you to
tell me why he hasn't.
Could it just be that
his poor liver function
is preventing him from
metabolizing the lorazepam?
Dr. Rhodes, you called
a neurosurgeon in to consult.
Obviously, you suspect
something else.
I'm afraid he might've
stroked on the table.
And you were hoping
I'd tell you otherwise.
I can't.
His pupils are sluggish.
We need a head CT.
You should've
already ordered one.
Call me when he's
down in radiology.
(MONITOR RAPIDLY BEEPING)
A hundred mics of epi.
Got it.
What happened?
Heart's slowed to 40.
IV's blown.
We need to give the epi
through the tube.
(PANTING)
Holding compressions.
(MONITOR FLATLINING)
(MONITOR RESUMES BEEPING)
(COOS)
Heartbeat's normal.
I know.
Let's just hope
this little guy makes it
until we get
those results back.
He won't fly.
Just does this all day.
Paces.
What else did he do?
I know this sounds crazy,
but I think he
gets nightmares.
He'll suddenly
cry out in his sleep.
It's not crazy.
It's actually consistent.
ETHAN: With what?
Don't touch that.
PTSD.
Post-traumatic stress?
Come on. A parrot?
Parrots are highly
intelligent and very
socially attuned.
There is, in fact,
a program at the VA
in San Francisco
that matches vets with PTSD
with similarly
afflicted birds.
So, he can help me.
Possible.
Don't touch that.
What do I do?
Take care of him.
Talk to him.
Hang out with him.
For starters, teach him
something else to say.
(CHUCKLES)
PARROT: Don't touch that.
We've extracted
DNA from the baby
and both parents.
And, the DNA samples
have been prepared
so that we can load
it into the sequencer,
which will give us
the genetic code of each.
Once we have that,
we can target specific parts
of the baby's genome
based on the baby's
symptoms and give
a gene-based diagnosis.
Mmm-hmm.
(SIGHS)
Reese.
Hmm?
I mean, that's pretty amazing,
don't you think?
Yeah.
Oh, you're thinking
about your graduation.
No. Uh...
I'm thinking about
the baby.
He's so little,
and helpless,
and in so much pain.
I know that you've
had second thoughts,
but it's actually a
good thing that you stuck
with pathology.
It is?
Yes.
You don't wanna get
so involved with patients.
What if that
poor little baby
doesn't make it?
You're gonna feel terrible.
Yeah, I am.
I would, too.
That's why
I like it down here.
I'm not good
with suffering.
It's just too much
up there.
Dr. Halstead.
Mmm-hmm?
For you.
(CHUCKLES)
WILL: From the
Hiring Committee.
Didn't even have the balls
to tell me in person.
"Dr. Halstead,
we are pleased
to offer you
"a full-time position
as attending physician
"in emergency medicine
at Gaffney Chicago Med."
Hey. Congrats.
Well, well, well.
"Lost cause," huh?
I can't believe it.
I must have some,
uh, mystery friend
on the committee,
overruled Goodwin.
You dope.
Nobody overrules Goodwin.
You wouldn't have
gotten that
without her say so.
Congrats.
(CHUCKLES)
Oh.
What do you see?
You want
the good news
or the bad?
Let me have it all, Sam.
David didn't have
a stroke.
He is gonna wake up.
But the problem is here,
in his temporal lobe.
CONNOR: It's a mass.
The cancer's
spread to his brain.
Metastatic
hepastatic carcinoma.
It's very bad news.
(MONITOR BEEPING)
Is it operable?
No.
Hold on just a second.
The core of the mass
is centered over area 5,
the superior
parietal gyrus.
Meaning?
If I resect,
he'll have
asteriognosis.
You won't recognize
objects by touch.
You won't know
the meaning of sensations
or be able
to coordinate
between your visual
and tactile systems.
And, that would
be a good outcome.
You can't be sure
that's gonna be the case.
Without the surgery,
what can I look forward to?
Well, headache...
Already got that.
Loss of motor skills,
bodily functions,
neuropathic pain,
seizures, delusions...
A smorgasbord.
I'll give surgery a shot.
It's your call, David.
You know my reservations.
All due respect, Dr. Abrams
is not the only neurosurgeon
in this hospital.
No. But he's the best.
No surgery.
Dr. Downey, we should
at least get
a second opinion.
I'm satisfied with
Dr. Abrams' prognosis.
Thank you, Sam.
David.
By the way, Sam.
I've always appreciated
your bedside manner.
Come back later.
I may feel like
some company.
(GROANS)
Ms. Goodwin.
I wanna thank you.
I'm going to
accept Med's offer.
My fear is,
is you're gonna
find a way
to get yourself
kicked off the staff.
I'm curious to see
how long it'll take.
I'm headed home, Mag.
Any plans?
I'm just gonna make
a big meal. Bert always
loves my cooking.
That should put him
in a better mood.
Let's hope.
Hey.
I checked on the baby.
He's stable.
Oh, I'm gonna go up
to see him.
You're graduating
tonight, right?
Mmm-hmm.
Why don't you just take off?
We won't know anything
until the morning.
I won't stay long.
Bye.
Night.
Hey.
Remember when you were
a kid and you lost
a tooth?
And you kept
running your tongue
over the gap?
Without my wedding ring,
it's like the same thing.
Something's missing.
Well, don't know
if it's any consolation,
but what do they say?
"One door closes and
another one opens."
I don't know about that,
but thanks.
Night.
Natalie.
Yeah.
Hey, did you hear?
I got an offer from Med.
That's great!
You're gonna
take it, right?
Of course.
Good.
Yeah, and I promise,
from now on,
I'll never argue with you.
You will be an attending.
So you won't have
to argue with me.
You can just boss me around.
That's a good point.
Yeah.
No, uh, I'll never
do that either.
(CHUCKLES)
Well, congratulations.
Thank you.
Good night.
(DOWNEY SIGHS)
(SOFT MUSIC PLAYING)
(WEAKLY)
Between the incision
and my head,
I'm not sure
which hurts worse.
Those fentanyl boluses
aren't doing much for you.
I'll order
a morphine PCA.
No. I hate morphine,
makes me loopy.
Turn that up a little,
will you?
(MUSIC GETS LOUDER)
How's that?
Yeah.
(SIGHS DEEPLY)
I'd hoped to make
it to the Islands
one more time.
But, flying's
such a hassle these days.
And as soon as we can,
we'll get you
out of the ICU
and into a room.
One with a view.
(CHUCKLING) Oh.
Hey, hey, easy there.
(PANTING)
Dr. Rhodes,
you know what I'm facing?
I do.
I'd just as soon skip it,
if you know what I mean.
Check out a little early.
I'd need some help, though.
You know I can't do that.
Yeah. Yeah.
Well...
I guess we're all given
our measure of suffering.
God's medicine.
Parrots are
supposed to fly.
Don't you know that?
Here.
Maybe this will help.
Come on.
Like this.
Flap your wings. Come on.
Flap your wings.
Come on. Fly.
Come on. Like this.
Watch me!
Can you fly? Like this.
Come on.
Flap your wings. Fly!
Come on, you can fly.
Fly! Fly! Fly!
(SIGHS)
We're not making
much progress here.
(CHUCKLING)
Okay. Good night, son.
Ah. (CHUCKLES)
Sweet dreams.
(CLEARS THROAT)
And what you need to do,
is tell me who this
guy is that popped you.
So, I can have a little, uh,
talk with him.
(CHUCKLES)
No. I do not wanna
see him back in the E.D.
Thank you.
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
You're welcome.
Anyway, it's not that bad.
I've taken worse shots.
So, you've been
hit like this before?
Lots of times.
Nursing is
a dangerous profession.
Maybe you should leave it.
What? Quit my job?
Yeah.
And do what?
Marry me.
(CHUCKLES)
What?
I want you
to marry me, April.
JOEY: Reese.
(GASPS)
What?
You missed
your graduation.
I fell asleep.
I was afraid to
leave the baby.
I texted you. I called.
What?
Dead.
Did we get the results?
I need to call
Dr. Manning.
(SQUAWKING)
Have a nice day.
Can't you say that?
Okay. I'll be
back tonight.
Be back tonight.
Say that again.
Be back.
Yeah. I will.
(CHUCKLES)
(MONITOR BEEPING)
I'm really sorry
to hear about David.
I can imagine
that's gotta be
very difficult for you.
He's given me so much.
How do I ever pay that back?
How do you know
you haven't already?
Yep.
Get out.
What did you say?
I said I had to
think about it.
You better.
He give you a ring?
No. It was the spur
of the moment thing.
Hmm.
You even love him?
Yeah, I love him.
It seems you have
a big decision to make.
Hey, Maggie.
Hey.
You seen Goodwin?
No.
She missed
the budget meeting.
It's not like her.
No, it isn't.
NATALIE: Michael has
a condition called
long-chain
acyl-CoA dehydrogenase
deficiency or LCADD.
I know it's a lot of words,
but what it basically
boils down to,
is he can't process fat.
So...
When, um, the body
can't use fat for energy,
it relies on glucose.
But there's only
a limited amount available.
Michael suffered
a severe drop in blood sugar.
Blood sugar?
That's what caused
him to stop breathing?
And his heart?
It doesn't have
to happen again.
It can be managed.
How?
We're giving him
intravenous dextrose,
getting his blood sugar up.
That will keep him stable.
So, he's gonna be okay?
Michael will always
have the condition,
but by altering his diet,
we can control it.
He'll be able to live
a long and healthy life.
Oh, thank you. Thank you.
(NICK CHUCKLES)
(NICK AND SHANNON CHUCKLE)
(EXHALES SHARPLY)
You're in pain.
It's no big deal.
Enough.
April, you're getting
that X-ray.
Really, I do not...
No! Go to radiology now.
I'm putting in the order.
Okay.
Bert? Is that you?
No, it's me, Maggie.
SHARON: Maggie.
Sharon,
I've been calling you.
What happened?
Bert.
Is he all right?
What is it?
He left.
Oh.
He said, uh,
"I don't know how much time
I have left, but I want to
spend it happy."
No, he didn't.
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
I don't make him happy.
He's just being a fool,
Sharon.
He's gonna be coming
right back. You'll see.
No, Maggie.
(SNIFFLES)
He's gone.
Oh, Sharon.
I can't do this.
I gotta get myself together.
I gotta go to work.
No, wait a minute now.
(GASPS)
I missed that budget
meeting this morning.
It doesn't matter.
Come on, let's go.
Let's go.
You sure you don't
wanna stay at home.
Come on.
(SHARON SNIFFLES)
Let's go.
Thank you.
Reese.
You were supposed to
get this last night.
What is it?
Open it and find out.
(CELL PHONE CHIMES)
I gotta get back
to the lab.
Um...
Enjoy that.
Hey, Reese.
Pardon me, Dr. Reese.
(CHUCKLES)
Well done.
(BREATHING RAGGEDLY)
Dr. Downey.
(WEAKLY) Dr. Rhodes.
So, you had mentioned
wanting to get
back to the Islands,
so I thought...
There you go.
(INHALES)
Hmm.
Pikake.
Sorry?
Hawaiian name
for this jasmine.
I thought
you should know,
I'm starting my
cardiothoracic fellowship.
So, I haven't
been wasting my time.
Not entirely, no.
(BOTH CHUCKLE SOFTLY)
(SNIFFLES)
I never asked.
Do you have any family?
I had a sister.
Passed away.
If you're wondering,
I've left instructions.
Cremation.
Okay.
Thank you.
For everything.
It's been a good ride.
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
Yes, it has.
(SNIFFLES)
(EXHALES)
(MONITOR BEEPING RAPIDLY)
DINA: Dr. Downey's coding.
He has a DNR. Let him go.
(KNOCKING)
Dr. Shore.
Dr. Reese.
We are thrilled
to have you.
Hey, you wanna see
one bad-ass
gastric carcinoma?
(CHUCKLES)
Yeah.
Doctor Shore?
You have been
really nice.
And, I appreciate
your encouragement.
But, I have decided
not to go into pathology.
What are you
talking about?
I think I would do
better treating patients.
But, we're counting
on you.
I'm really sorry.
You realize, don't you,
that pathology is your match.
If you don't take this,
you won't have a job.
I know.
What are you going to do?
I don't know.
(CHUCKLES)
This is the E.D.
you'll be rotating through.
On this side are
the trauma bays,
over there are
the treatment rooms.
That is called Baghdad,
you will learn why later.
I have schedules.
Uh, Jeff, Jeff Clarke.
Welcome.
Our new
fourth-year students.
It's time for my
welcome-to-Chicago-Med
speech.
How do I look?
(SIGHS)
Visine? My eyes that bad?
You can get through this.
Okay.
Jeff?
Hey, Natalie.
What?
Oh, my gosh.
You're in med school?
Yeah, um, I hurt my back
on the job so no more
lugging firehose.
I always liked
the medical side of things,
didn't realize biochem would
be such a bitch but...
(CHUCKLES)
Hey, Maggie!
You see who's here?
Hey! I heard the rumors.
It's good to see you, Jeff.
How are you doing,
Maggie?
Good to see you.
So, clearly,
I am the oldest one
in my class...
(CHUCKLING)
They call me Pops.
Wow. (CHUCKLES)
That's cute.
Hey, Will,
you ever meet Jeff Clarke?
You were
a firefighter, right?
That's right.
Hi.
Jeff and my Jeff were
really good friends.
We used to call
them "The two Jeffs."
(CHUCKLES)
That's great.
We had such
a great time together.
How is Lisa?
Divorced.
Oh, I'm sorry.
No.
FEMALE NURSE: Dr. Halstead.
Oh, thank you.
Well, it's really
great to have you here.
Good to be here.
See you.
Bye.
Uh, excuse me.
It's good to see you, Jeff.
April.
Hey.
Your X-ray...
Yeah.
The blow didn't cause
any significant damage.
Told you.
It did show us
something else.
There's a coin lesion
in the upper lobe
of your lung.
Now, given your history,
I think we can rule out
lung cancer or lymphoma.
Then, what is it?
Well, we'll need
a bronchoscopy
and an IGRA to confirm.
But I'm pretty sure
that you have tuberculosis.
What?
I've got TB?
I'm afraid so.
Dr. Rhodes, we're so
very sorry for your loss.
Thank you.
Ms. Goodwin, I'm gonna need
a few personal days,
if that's all right?
Of course.
Thanks.
Yeah.
Thinking about you, pal.
Appreciate that.
So, uh,
how are you doing?
What do you mean?
I don't know.
You haven't quite
seemed yourself, lately.
(SIGHS)
Hasn't been a good day.
Huh.
Sorry to hear it.
Oh, Dr. Reese,
I understand that
congratulations are in order.
I just quit pathology.
Nice freaking move.
Right on, sister,
I knew you were smart.
I don't have a job.
So, what?
You're gonna be fine.
(SQUAWKING)
His vocabulary's improving.
He said "Be back"
to me this morning.
Nice.
Pretty smart.
He knew I was leaving.
Come on, show Dr. Charles.
Say, "Be back."
"Be back tonight."
(WHISPERING)
Performance anxiety, man.
He did say it.
I heard him!
He said it to me
this morning.
I believe you.
Whoa!
Look at that.
Dang.
Good job.
More success than I have
with most of my patients.
Congratulations.
To the both of you.
(INAUDIBLE)
(CHUCKLES)
(BOTH GRUNT)
(BOTH LAUGHING)