What do they need us for?
A lady's been trapped
in a car for over an hour.
We can't move her
until we intubate her.
They always drive this fast?
Yep.
They ever hit anybody?
All the time.
How can you eat through this?
I'm hungry.
All right, we're here.
Grab the O-neg, stay close.
Cherokee missed the runway,
slammed into a car
on the access road.
Guy in the plane is toast.
The other victim's already out.
There's a lady
pinned in the backseat.
Fire's been trying to
get to her for 50 minutes.
The plane's been leaking fuel,
so they haven't been
able to use the jaws.
I'm freezing.
Anybody got a coat?
Get the doc a coat, will you?
I.V.s. B.P.'s 70/30.
Golden Hour's almost over.
Head trauma, A.L.O.C.
We've been bagging her,
but she's been biting
down and gagging.
Husband and two kids
already at the hospital.
Carter, follow me in.
Get that O-neg going, all right?
If we don't get her out of here
in the next couple of minutes,
she's not going to make it.
Start with Pavulon.
Next, Versed
to sedate.
Cricoid pressure.
I got it.
Finally...
succinylcholine.
What the hell is that?
It's aviation fuel.
I wouldn't smoke if I were you.
You think gasoline
comes out of camel hair?
Can we get in here?
Two seconds.
Tube's in.
New coat?
Christmas.
Nice.
It was.
Release pressure.
All right, clear out.
Slide out, Carter. Come on.
Keep bagging.
Start the chopper.
Let's move! Let's move!
They're coming out.
Move it! Move it fast!
Thank you.
May I?
Yeah.
Thanks.
Watch out.
So, you decided
on a specialty yet?
My folks are set on cardiology.
Yeah? Well, hat
are you thinking?
I'm thinking this
is pretty exciting.
Yeah, it's not bad.
Stress, late nights,
hard work, low play.
It's hard to beat.
Watch her head.
Let's go, guys.
Move her. Move her.
Both femurs broken,
possible spinal cord injury.
Pressure's 80.
We'll notify the O.R.
before we get there.
You fly before?
Oh, yeah. Lots of times.
What's the M.A.R.?
County General.
Faster!
She going to make it?
She is now.
All right, guys, we're
going to mover her on three.
Ready? One, two, three.
No room.
Can't go. Stay
here, grab our stuff,
then ride back with
the paramedics.
It's a hell of a life, isn't it?
What?!
It's a hell of a life.
I said I want to have
sex with your wife.
God, he's in a foul mood.
Today is a good day.
You finish your
trauma presentation?
Not yet. I was
going to try and grab
a couple of minutes
this morning.
What about you? You do much?
Really, I am so far behind,
I may not even finish.
Benton's going to kill me.
Don't worry about
it Just do your best.
How does he expect us to prepare
when we're following him
around on 36-hour shifts?
Ms. Chen, if this surgical
rotation is too much for you,
there's always dermatology.
48-Year-old MBA,
fractured right femur,
pressure 60/40,
abdomen's rigid.
All right. Let's get
some O-neg going...
Wide open. Already did it.
What's your name, sir?
Bill McClintock.
Mm-hmm.
Mr. McClintock,
is it tender here?
Were you wearing a seat belt?
No.
You will the next time, I bet.
Peritoneal lavage.
Carter, look at his abdomen.
Either he's bleeding out
and he needs to go
to the O.R. immediately
or he's giving birth
to a basketball.
Haleh, call up to O.R.
I already called.
Dr. Benton, head trauma in one.
All right, I'll be right there.
Ms. Chen, get a
Foley catheter started.
Ever do one before?
You're in for a treat.
Carter, since when does it take
two students to start a Foley?
Let's move.
Clean it with Betadine,
put KY on the
catheter, and thread it in.
Give it to me.
42 years old, collapsed
playing handball
pressure crashing, 40 palp,
tachycardic 110, resps 30.
Two liters NS in, 15 liters 0-2.
Name's Jonathan Weiss.
Man, it hurts.
Am I having a heart attack?
Do you have a history
of cardiac trouble?
No.
I'll get a CBC, Chem
seven, enzymes
coag panel and chest film.
He's very pale.
He's not oxygenating.
Pressure's still 40 palp.
What do we got, Susan?
Possible M.I.
I don't want to die.
We don't want you to die,
so you do your part,
and we'll do ours.
His breathing's not
improving with oxygen.
Could be a pulmonary embolism.
What?
A blood clot in your
lungs, Mr. Weiss.
Have you had surgery
recently?
Car accident? Any trauma?
Spend a lot of time
traveling? Sitting?
EKG?
T-wave inversions.
I'm thinking heart.
I'm not. V-Q scan.
He has no risk factors,
and mid-sternal chest pain.
I need that chest film.
And I need an echo.
All right, well,
that can't hurt.
Let's do it.
Mr. Conally?
Yes?
Where are you?
Right here, under the sheet.
Why are you under the sheet?
I've been dead for two days.
Okay, but you are still
suffering from headaches.
Oh, boy, am I ever.
And what precipitates
these headaches?
Death.
What was that?
Nervous tic. I've
had it for years.
Ow! Ooh!
Blood gases are back.
P-O2's low; 50.
Where the hell
is the chest film?
Behind you, Dr. Greene.
Pulmonary artery's enlarged.
Perfusion scan?
V-Q mismatch.
You were right.
1.5 million units streptokinase.
Forget the streptokinase.
Let's get him to Trauma.
We need a fluoroscope down here.
Somebody get Morgenstern.
Get his pants off.
Rolando, we got a trauma room?
Yeah. Two's open.
You're going to do
an embolectomy?
Yeah. First time for everything.
What the hell's going on?
A saddle embolus.
Mark 's going in.
He's doing an
extraction in the E.R.?
Mr. Smitrovich is in four.
CBC, Chem seven,
blood gases, I.V. started.
Luchesse's in Six...
abdominal pain, vomiting blood,
N.P.O., a nasogastric tube...
Dr. Benton?
What is it, Carter?
We... I would like to observe
Dr. Greene's embolectomy.
All right. Well,
who's stopping you?
Go.
Thanks.
You want to go, too? Go. Go.
What's the matter with you?
Luchesse.
Vomiting blood,
NPO, nasogastric tube,
gastric lavage.
You ordered a gastric lavage?
No. I wrote it down.
You still have to sign it.
I write my own orders.
Nurse...
If you're having
a problem today,
don't take it out on me.
I write the orders,
you carry them out.
Understood?
Nurse...
What?
Isoproterenol's going.
Okay, ease the
catheter in slowly,
and thread it up to
the pulmonary artery,
being very careful not to
puncture the vena cava.
How's Mr. Weiss doing?
Resps are up
to 45.
Pulse ox down to 63.
Hang in there, Mr. Weiss.
You'll be feeling better
before you know it.
Carter, Chen, why don't you
get over here so you can see?
See that?
I'm in the right ventricle.
Is that cool or what?
Carter, you see the embolus?
Yeah. It's huge.
Position the cup
against the clot.
Good. Now, start
your syringe suction
and aspirate the embolus
into the cup.
Got it.
Now, work it back down.
Just like snaking a drain.
Well, folks, I got a date
with a bile duct.
Carry on, one and all.
Pulse ox up to 85.
Resps are coming down.
How you feeling
Mr. Weiss?
I can breathe.
Okay, Harold, so,
something bit you, huh?
Pet snake.
Oh, yeah? I used to keep frogs.
Frogs are amphibians.
My snake eats frogs.
What kind of snake?
Yellow eyelash pit viper.
You have a pet pit viper?
Is it poisonous?
Very.
I'll call poison control.
Are you feeling weak, Harold?
Nauseous? Any chills?
No. Not that kind of stuff.
Can you tell if it's
poisonous just by looking?
I don't think so.
'Cause I got him
right here in the bag.
We're going to keep
him in the bag, Harold.
No. He's cold-blooded,
and I had him on the El all day.
He was here a minute ago.
You shouldn't have
contradicted me
in front of the nursing staff.
I wasn't contradicting you.
We disagreed on a diagnosis.
I'd appreciate your showing
a little more
restraint in the future.
The man was dying.
Are you going to
give me respect?
I wasn't being disrespectful.
Yes or no?
I respect you, Susan.
Thank you.
Try to show it once in a while.
I'll get Animal Control in here.
Doug, what is going on?
Dr. Ross in E.R.
Pit viper got loose.
A snake?
A big snake.
36-Year-old woman
with breast cancer.
E.M.T.s brought her
in from Dignity House.
Two modified
radical mastectomies.
It's spread to her lymph nodes.
Who are you?
I'm Anita Risberg, a
nurse over at the hospice.
Mark Greene. Is she on chemo?
Tamoxifen, but
it's metastasized.
Pelvis, spine.
You got her on morphine?
120 milligrams, just to sleep.
But, the last couple of
days, it's just not enough.
I got worried, if I
upped the dose,
it would cause further
respiratory depression.
You're right. It would.
What's her name?
Grace. Grace Holsten.
Hi, Grace.
I'm Mark Greene.
We're going to try and make you
a little more comfortable.
Doctor, please let me die.
Please.
Let me die.
Animal Control guy
believes it's a tree snake.
He thinks it'll crawl up
someplace high where it's warm.
Sorry, Doc.
Terrific. I'll spend
the rest of my day
on my hands and knees...
Lydia, Doug, come over here.
Okay. Okay. It took
about six months
and a couple thousand
requisition forms,
but I finally did it.
Guess what's under the sheet.
Come on, guys. Guess.
We don't want to guess.
Oh, come on! Please!
New daybed for the lounge?
Nope.
New vending machines?
Ta-dum! New crash carts!
How did you get those?
Well, Cardiology wanted
them, but I was relentless.
Dr. Benton, you got
an abdominal pain
in Curtain Three,
and you got a gunshot
victim coming in.
Now, no raiding off the
new crash carts, okay?
Everything on these
carts stays on the carts.
Thank you.
Dr. Benton...
about this afternoon's
trauma presentation...
uh... I'm not quite
fully prepared yet.
You've known about it for weeks.
Yes, sir. I know that,
but I was hoping...
Don't call me "sir," Ms. Chen.
Yes, sir.
I mean, Doctor.
I'm sorry.
I only need a half hour or so.
And what about you, Mr. Carter?
Do you also need more time?
No. I'm all set.
Well, Ms. Chen,
when you find you have the time
to rejoin us, please do so.
84-year-old man
complaining of abdominal pain.
Where's his chart?
In the rack...
at the desk.
Carter, go get his chart.
I'll need a CBC,
Chem seven, coag panel,
and drop a nasogastric tube.
You going to write this down?
I'm not comfortable
taking verbal orders.
I think you better
write everything
down for us.
Us?
The nurses.
Here's his chart.
Start writing.
Grace...
we've added Fentanyl
to the morphine.
See if that helps.
If it doesn't work, we
have three choices:
We can insert a catheter
into your spinal cord to
deliver the morphine...
No.
Or we can surgically
cut the spinal tracts
that carry the pain
from your legs and back,
or we can increase
your morphine.
But your dosage is already
so high, it might depress
your breathing.
Can you stop this pain?
I'm not sure.
We're trying.
Try harder.
Resps?
Fourteen.
Let me know if her
breathing gets any worse.
Okay.
Don't even ask.
Mark, keep me company.
Good call on that
pulmonary embolism.
Thanks.
Oncology saw him...
Found a small polyp.
Probably, if he
hadn't tossed a clot,
who knows how far that
thing would have gone
before baring its
ugly little head.
What's all this?
Some kind of tree
snake got loose.
Really? I was really
impressed this morning
about your concern for
the medical students...
Making sure that they
were involved and learning.
You're a fine teacher, Mark.
You given any thought as to
what you're going to do next year?
Start repaying med school loans.
I've sent out a few letters,
but haven't really started.
I'd like you to give thought
to joining the staff here.
As an attending?
Of course, you won't
make as much money
as the cowboys at
the private hospitals,
but there are other rewards,
ephemeral as they may be.
Well, think about it anyway.
No. No. I'd be honored. Really.
Ah. Here's my bus.
Thank you.
No. Thank you.
You earned it.
12-Year-old male.
Multiple gunshots
to the legs and abdomen.
We scooped and ran.
I.V.'S wide open...
Had two liters.
No palpable pressure.
All right, people,
let's look alive.
Let's go!
O-neg. Let's move!
Grab me that dynamap!
Is that I.V. infiltrated?
Ready? Lift.
Come on.
No pulse.
He's still breathing.
We tried to apply pressure.
He was a sieve.
His name is Yummy Jackson.
Drive-by?
Drug deal gone bad. Gang thing.
At 12 years old?
Kid had a Tech-9
and a Ruger on him
when we found him.
Get in here now!
Watch that line.
She's still in a lot of pain.
Okay.
Grace, I'm sorry the
Fentanyl isn't helping much.
It's helping a little.
Anything we can do to
make you more comfortable?
You can shoot me.
I'm sorry. I didn't bring
my gun to work today.
I don't think it's safe
to up the morphine any higher.
Afraid it'll kill me?
It might.
There's not a lot more
that the E.R. can
do to help you.
Uh... Do you want me to
admit you to the hospital?
Can I go back to the hospice?
Yes, you can, but they're
going to need to bring you
back here for a higher dosage.
Can I take a little
while to decide?
Sure.
Can I help you?
Excuse me. Can I help you?
You can't be back here.
You must go now.
Son of a bitch!
Get out the way!
You're too late.
He's already dead.
It's madness.
You can clearly see
the posterior
dislocation of the knee
consistent with
this sledding injury
which occurred when the impact
of the sled applied direct force
to the anterior tibia
while the knee was flexed.
I'm really nervous.
Don't worry about it.
I picked too easy a topic.
I should have worked up
something more difficult.
Relax. Dr. Benton doesn't
expect that much from you.
It's your first rotation.
Should be attempted
using analgesia
with horizontal traction
and realignment of the joint.
Angiography should be considered
with attention
paid to the five P's:
Pain, pallor,
paresthesias,
pulselessness and paralysis.
All right, who's next?
Carter.
While attempting a
rollerblading maneuver,
this 12-year-old male
fell on his
outstretched right hand,
resulting in a...
Salter-Harris Type
II epiphysial fracture
of the proximal humerus.
To avoid damage
to the growth plate,
the humeral head, which
is in varus angulation
and external rotation,
must be reduced by abducting,
and externally rotating, the arm
and then slowly
bringing the arm down.
If the reduction is
not accomplished,
then the arm must
be maintained in a cast
in the Statue of
Liberty position.
Is that it?
Any questions?
Ms. Chen.
You're going to do great.
Here.
Um... facial fractures.
You'll find an outline
and recent research articles.
Would you pass it down?
Here we see examples
of a depressed fracture
of the left frontal bone
with disruption
to the orbital rim,
both the result of
blunt force trauma
when the patient's face
intercepted a tire iron.
John, if you would
please, the projector?
Thank you.
Orbital rim and
frontal sinus fractures,
along with other fractures
to these facial bones,
often result in
concomitant C.N.S. injury.
Diagnosis is established
with radiographic studies
and computerized tomography,
preferably using a
three-dimensional image
of the patient's skull.
As you can see,
the frontal sinus and
orbital rim fractures here
are easily appreciated.
How's her breathing?
Depressed but okay.
She's finally out.
Maybe we got the balance right,
and she can get some sleep.
Kathy.
Kathy...
Who's Kathy?
Her little girl.
Does she know she's here?
She lives out west somewhere
with Grace's ex-husband.
Seattle, I think.
Grace gave up custody
when she entered the hospice.
She lost her child?
She entered the hospice to die.
Life goes on.
Then, again,
sometimes it doesn't.
Old hospice joke.
Oh, God! Oh, God! Oh, God...
The Fentanyl's wearing off.
It hurts!
Lie down.
Her resps are too low.
I can't give her
any more morphine.
I can't stand it!
I'm so sorry.
It hurts.
Please, Doctor...
There's nothing else I can do.
Please, kill me.
Please. Please. Please.
Shh! Relax. Relax.
Please. Please.
Shh!
What do we got?
53-year-old male.
Grabbed his chest and collapsed.
Hypotensive, 80/60.
Tachycardic at 120.
Hypertension treated
with Altace and Tenormin.
What are those? Skates?
Guy's a hockey ref.
Collapsed during a game.
Some of the kids
followed us in a van.
He's had eight migs morphine.
He's diaphoretic.
Get an EKG and enzymes.
End of the line, guys.
You've got to wait
in the waiting room.
He going to be okay?
We don't know yet.
Malik, can you take
them to Waiting?
Yeah. Be there in a minute.
We'll do everything we can.
Come on, guys.
He's in fib.
Crash cart.
Where's the cart?
Right here.
Where's the new cart?
Paddles.
I put one in here
less than an hour ago.
I can't believe somebody
already stole one of my new carts.
Clear.
Hey, is Jake around?
Oh, he went to get a soda.
Nice digs.
This how the other half lives?
I could do with a little
less glass, actually.
There's no blood on the carpet,
so it's a step up from the E.R.
Mind if I sit?
I've had my shots.
Cindy was right. You
are kind of charming.
Is that bad?
Depends.
Jake's a great kid.
He is a great kid.
Hope you don't mind if we
shoot hoops now and then.
I promise not to pass
along any misogyny
with these basketball tips.
Don't worry. If misogyny's
genetic, he's inherited plenty
from his father.
Does he see his dad much?
They communicate by check...
when it comes.
You know, if you don't like
me, you don't have to hide it.
You can just come
right out and show it.
I didn't know I
was being subtle.
Hey.
Hey, yourself. Dr. Ross
has come to see
if you want to play
some basketball.
We'll be about
half an hour, okay?
And put the jacket on.
I'll make sure he wears it.
D5 NS, 100cc's per hour,
NG tube,
gastric lavage, CBC,
Chem seven and amylase.
Call the O.R., book a room.
Dr. Benton, what does this say?
NG tube.
And by that, you would
mean a nasogastric tube?
Yes.
And this?
Dextrose 5, normal saline.
An I.V., in other words?
Yes, an I.V.
I've examined the patient.
Frankly, I believe she needs
a fine surgical hand like yours
to get an I.V. going properly.
I'll have Carter do it.
And the nasogastric tube?
You'll notice she has
a deviated septum,
and I don't feel
comfortable putting one in.
I'll do it myself.
Tell the cath lab his
coag panel's cooking.
Here are his chest films.
See if you can find
those hockey kids
and tell them he's going to
be okay, will you? Thanks.
Susan. Susan!
Susan.
Susan, come on, please.
I'm busy, Mark.
I need to talk to
you about a patient.
End-stage breast cancer.
Bone mets to her back and legs.
Morphine's not working.
Neither is the Fentanyl.
Susan, she's in agony.
There's nothing I
can do to help her.
Spinal morphine
therapy? Cordotomy?
She refused both of them.
She just wants to die.
Sounds like she's going to soon.
She wants me to help her.
Her resps are down to 12.
If I give her a little
more morphine,
her breathing will stop.
What would you do?
Uh... I don't know.
I got to go.
How long you going
to keep this up?
You weren't there for me, Mark.
It was professional,
not personal.
We're not married.
We work together.
Professional is personal.
I miss you.
You could have told me
you were doing facial fractures.
And that thing
with the computer?
I looked like an idiot.
No, no. Keep irrigating that.
I can give you the
graphics program.
It's easy to use.
That's not the point.
The point is that
I need a good recommendation
from Benton if I'm going
to get a surgical residency.
Vertical mattress, 4-O nylon.
You want to go into surgery?
Yeah. Why do
you say it like that?
No, I mean, I think
you'd be great.
No, you don't. You
just sounded surprised.
I do know surprise
when I hear it.
You just... she just... you
just sounded surprised.
You really want
to go into surgery?
I don't know. I might.
Well, look, John, I've seen
my mother's surgical residents
and the ones around here,
and it just doesn't
seem like you.
What do you mean,
your mother's residents?
Your mother's a
surgical attending?
She's a chief of surgery.
Could I get some more 4 x 4s?
Chief of surgery?!
Where? What hospital?
Saint Bart's.
Why even bother
coming to school?
You're not going to have
any trouble getting a residency.
It's not like that.
She won't help me at all.
She didn't even want me
to go into medicine.
Just don't say anything
to anyone, okay?
They always jump to conclusions
and I end up having to
prove myself all over again.
Okay? Please?
John?
Found the snake.
Billy...
Don't, please.
Mark, we need you in
Two to rule out an M.I.
Don't...
Don't.
Billy, please.
Mark?
I love you.
Cardiology would
steal our crash carts?
They steal everything.
Are you sure they're up here?
They were two hours ago.
Okay. Okay, Connie and Bob,
you stay with the carts.
You guys come with me.
I think we're in
the ladies room.
Ow!
Oh, man...
Dunphy's there.
What do we do?
Sheri Dunphy?
Not a problem.
Sheri?
Doug, hi.
How have you been?
Good. You look great.
You lost some weight.
I got married last
year, remember?
Believe me, I'm
still in mourning.
Mm-hmm. What are
you doing up here?
Is the cath lab still up here?
Yeah, it's right where
it's always been.
If you could give me a
hand, really, just quickly.
Nope, I can't.
I'm out of here.
I've got a patient,
six-year-old:
Tetralogy of Fallot.
Yeah. Okay.
All right.
He's unbelievable.
And you wonder
why I slept with him
on the first date?
Really? First date.
You're kidding.
Yeah. He rang the doorbell,
next thing I knew
we were on the kitchen floor.
Kitchen floor?
Geez, I got to
start dating again.
Kids are having fun.
Yeah. They're the hockey players
from my M.I.
Haven't been picked up yet.
How did he do?
He's not dead, if
that's what you mean.
No. That's not what I meant.
He's going to be fine.
How is she?
She died a couple
of minutes ago.
Respiratory failure?
I was listening to
those kids playing,
and watching the snow fall.
You know, if you
stand right here...
Just... just right over here...
You can see the El from here...
Faces looking out the windows
into the darkness...
Life goes on, Mark.
Do you want to get
something to eat?
I can't.
Uh... Jennifer and
Rachel are in town.
Another time maybe.
Susan?
Mm-hmm?
Thanks.
See you tomorrow.
Stop now! Stop!
Where are they parents?
Carol...
Yeah?
I'm having problems with Haleh.
So I heard.
I'd like you to reschedule her
so that we don't have to
work together anymore.
From what I hear, you're the one
who needs to be rescheduled.
So what does that
mean? You won't do it?
No, I won't. The nursing
schedule is my prerogative.
Even if that situation
is endangering patient care?
You work every day
and every third night.
Haleh's got four
kids to support.
When is she supposed to work?
The woman refuses to
follow my instructions.
Why should she? You're
still in training. Remember?
She already graduated.
Oh, come on, Carol. Don't
give me that. We are not equals.
She may not know how
to cross-clamp an aorta,
but Haleh's been working
in emergency medicine
for 20 years, and if you
would ever hop off that pedestal
you've put yourself on, you
might see that the nurses
make this place work, not you.
I smell food.
I'm actually cooking.
You mean, like, from
scratch, and everything?
Yeah. Who knows?
It might become
an annual tradition.
I don't know.
I remember you cooking
something last summer.
I think it was meat loaf maybe.
Definitely, it
was... it was brown.
Semiannual then.
When did you get home?
7:00 or so.
Traffic was awful.
Where's Rach?
She's in the bathtub.
Mmm.
God, what a week.
I'm exhausted.
How was your day?
Great, and awful.
Tell me great.
I'm too tired for awful.
Morgenstern offered me a job
as attending
physician next year.
And what did you say?
I said yes.
Without discussing
it with me first?
An attending.
I figured
I'd be spending
nights and weekends
at some community
hospital in Winnetka.
Is this a problem?
Can you tell Morgenstern
you need more
time to think about it?
I don't need to think about it.
This is a great opportunity.
Well, I'm not going
to know until March
if Judge Franklin needs me
to clerk for him again next year.
Whoa. You're considering
spending another
year in Milwaukee?
If he wants me to, yes.
Well, I assumed...
Exactly. You assumed
things would be
the way you want them to be.
For the last six months,
things have not been
exactly the way
that I want them...
Living by myself,
without my wife,
without my daughter...
My wife? My daughter?
Mark, it's only been six months.
What about the
last six years, huh?
What about medical school
and rotations and residency?
Who was a paralegal
so we could put
food on the table?
Who was in night
school for years
trying to finish college?
Was that you?
No, that was me.
So, now, I want it to be
about me for a change.
Not you.
How are you doing, Mr. Conally?
Are you still dead?
Oh, yeah. Very.
My head feels better though.
Oh, well, that's good.
You just let us know
if we can get you
anything else, okay?
Okay.
Night.
You're late.
It's almost 10:00.
Yeah. I got held
up at the hospital.
Where's Walt and my sister?
Something at
your niece's school.
Look, if you say you're
going to be here at 8:00,
I need you to be here at 8:00.
I've got an early
shift tomorrow.
Okay.
How was your first day?
How long ago was
your mother's stroke?
Eight months.
It was a right parietal C.V.A.?
Yeah.
Well, she's still suffering
from left hemiparesis.
Has she had any
physical therapy at all?
Of course she has,
in the beginning.
Look, my mother doesn't have
any problems getting around.
That's the problem.
I mean, she's
always wandering off.
She's masking well,
but she has limited use
of her left arm and leg,
and she's got bruises
all over her left side
from running into things.
And you should have warned
me about the incontinence.
Yeah, well, that's, uh...
That's just a sometime
thing, you know?
Not tonight, it wasn't.
Can you help my mother?
Well, I can't make her younger,
but I can probably
improve her mobility.
She's a great lady.
I wish I would have
known her before the stroke.
Sure heard a lot about you.
She wouldn't stop
talking about her Petey.
I'm sorry about that.
No, hey, you're the
baby in the family, right?
I'm the... youngest
in the family, yeah.
Uh-huh. My baby sister, too.
My mom just loves her to death.
It still pisses me off.
Good night.
Captioning sponsored
by WARNER BROS.