Previously on "ER."
Dr. Greene,
excuse me.
But, I've actually done
quite a few more
ER procedures than she has.
I used to sell vitamins
over the phone.
Th‐that's kind of
in the health field, isn't it?
You know, you just want your boy
to have his daddy's last name.
So, what's wrong with that?
How's your busy social calendar?
It's not as busy.
This is Elizabeth Corday,
new surgical resident.
It's a pleasure,
how do you do?
Maybe it would be best
if I stepped in
and took over some
of the administrative duties
while you're recuperating.
Bless you, Kerry Weaver.
You got the job.
What?
Wait.
Hold on, hold it.
Here!
Oh, thanks.
It's five minutes by car.
Fifteen minutes on the el.
‐ You're not enjoying this?
‐ No, should I?
Doug, it's a secret romance.
Isn't that what
sells bad novels?
It shouldn't be a bad novel.
That's my train.
Ah. Oh, yeah, get that.
‐ See you at work.
‐ Bye.
'He continues to gain weight
at a very good rate'
and he's spending
more time awake.
What about his lungs?
We've weaned him down
to a quarter liter.
'So, when can he come home?'
'I'd say, a week or less.'
Oh...you hear that, pumpkin?
'You're gonna come home
in a week.'
Are you sure
that's not premature?
I'm concerned
about his immune system.
Frankly, I think
there's more risk of
nosocomial infection here.
Should he be circumcised
before he comes home?
That's what my mother told me.
Dr. Tabash and I discussed it,
and we decided against it.
Well, isn't it healthier?
Some studies seem
to indicate that circumcision
protects against UTI's
and may reduce
the risk of cancer.
Yeah, I don't find
those studies conclusive.
I'll just teach him
proper hygiene.
Peter, I don't want
to take any risk.
Uh, Dr. Tabash..
...what about immunization?
'After discharge with OPV,
he could shed virus'
and I don't wanna put
the immunosuppressed children
here at risk.
Oh, I've got a thymectomy.
Peter, are we gonna
talk about the circumcision?
Honey, he doesn't need one.
‐ Good morning, Doug.
‐ Hey, Mark.
You don't wear scrubs
to work anymore?
I get tired of...having people
hit me up for a diagnosis
in line at Starbucks.
Dr. Greene, there's an explosive
diarrhea in exam four.
Yeah? Well, what's
Weaver doing?
She's not in yet.
See if Del Amico
can take it.
The decision
to appoint you
acting chief
of emergency services
did not come simply because
Dr. Morgenstern recommended you.
Of course.
In fact, many feel
Dr. Morgenstern's approach
to management is...not something
we wish to see perpetuated.
With all due respect
to Dr. Morgenstern
I'd have to agree.
I know we're way beyond
our projected budget.
One point seven million
over last year.
We are in a crisis situation.
And that's why
I've drafted this.
It outlines measures
that if applied now
would put us back on budget
within six months.
So much waste is simply due
to lax administration.
Well, you've never
struck me as lax, Kerry.
And this job is not about
winning popularity contests.
That's never been
my goal, Donald.
Just Don.
There will, of course, be a
re‐evaluation of the situation
when Dr. Morgenstern recovers.
But, I'm confident
that you'll make things work.
Thank you for your trust.
Yes!
Hi. I'm Cynthia Hooper.
I think they called
from personnel‐‐
Sure, sure, hi.
‐ Hi.
‐ Cynthia. I‐I‐I'm Jerry.
I'm the unit service coordinator
so I'll be training you.
Come on around. Uh..
Uh, Cynthia, this
is Nurse Haleh Adams.
'Uh, Dr. Ross, Cynthia Hooper,
my new assistant.'
‐ Hey, hi.
‐ Hi.
Oh, Nurse Hathaway, hi.
Well, here I am.
Yeah, hi.
Cynthia Hooper, remember?
You interviewed me.
Oh, yes, I did.
Anyone seen Mark?
Check in the lounge.
Uh, so, let's start you
on some basic procedure.
Anything interesting,
Dr. Carter?
Yeah, thought I'd take
a look at this cellulitis.
From now on, cases
will be taken in order.
No more cherry picking.
Here's a little old lady,
weak and dizzy.
Jerry, have you paged
my med student?
Yes. I paged him twice.
Oh, Anna, uh, there's a patient
in curtain three if you wanna
teach your student
how to debride an ulcer.
‐ Yeah, thanks, Maggie.
‐ Sure.
Haleh, I'd like each nurse
to get a copy of these
policy changes
by the end of the day.
Did you give personnel
the wrong name?
I picked her.
She'll be fine.
Fine? Mark,
she was a disaster.
She has no previous experience
that matches the job
description.
Well, I considered all
the other candidates.
And she seemed like
the best of the lot.
Well, you know, we could always
interview more candidates.
Wasn't necessary.
Look, I spoke with her
after the interview
and she explained to me that
she was just having a bad day.
‐ A bad day?
‐ Don't worry. She'll be great.
What?
New chief of
emergency services
has decided
to change some policy.
"No shift overlapping."
What does that mean?
If we don't punch out by 7
she'll do it for us.
Dr. Del Amico,
do you remember me?
Of course, Carla.
How are you?
I hear the baby's
doing great.
Yeah, he is.
I was wondering if you have
some time when you're finished.
‐ You know, if we could talk.
‐ Oh, yeah.
Actually, we can talk now,
Old Tim won't mind.
Debriding his ulcer seems
to have a sedative effect.
I've started
nursing little Reese.
He's coming home
in five days.
‐ That's great.
‐ Yes it is.
I'm real excited,
been buying car seats
baby strollers, you know?
I love those baby shops.
Everything in 'em is so cute.
Um, I was wondering.
‐ I want to ask you a question.
‐ Yeah?
Do you think I should
have him circumcised?
It would, it would be
my preference, sure.
Uh, hold on a second.
Debride to here and then
dress it with tegederm, okay?
Is circumcision healthier?
I recommend it, I don't think
there's any question
that it's better for hygiene
and uh, I dunno
between us, I just
like the way it looks.
Don't let Peter
hear you say that.
Oh, yeah?
No, seriously, I wouldn't
have any second thoughts about
having it done. It's really
in your son's best interest.
Could you do it?
Sure, I'll do it today.
Hey, I heard a laforte 3
facial fracture came in.
Dr. Doyle gave it
to Dr. Del Amico.
She's in with
the maxillofacial surgeon‐‐
'Coming through!
Coming through!'
I got it!
Forty‐one year old male.
Motorcycle versus
delivery truck.
Wearing a helmet.
Blunt trauma
to the chest and abdomen.
BP 110 over 70.
Pulse 110.
We couldn't get a line in
the field, he's a tough stick.
Okay, follow me to trauma two.
On my count, everybody,
one, two..
...three.
CBC, chem seven,
type and cross for four.
Let's get a portable c‐spine
chest and pelvis.
You're not kidding,
"tough stick"
nothing but track marks.
Let me slide
around you, Connie.
Whoa! Right upper quadrant
tenderness with guarding.
'Let's get an abdominal
CT with contrast.'
‐ I can't get a vein.
‐ Mmm...I got one.
Damn! It blew.
Okay, give me
a central line kit.
'And what you got, John?'
Don't worry about it,
I got it.
I'd like to hear it.
Forty‐one year old male.
Motorcycle versus
delivery truck.
Right upper
quadrant tenderness.
'I ordered a CT and now I am
putting in a central line.'
Anna will take this, you know
there's three patients
waiting for sutures, nobody can
find your med student.
Come on,
I already started.
Carter, sutures.
Start the saline.
Vitals are stable.
Estimated blood loss 300 cc's.
We got 800 cc's in so far.
Repeat blood pressure‐‐
Al? Al? What happened?
Clutch slipped on a crane
and the cart knocked me and Bill
into a ditch,
but I'm alright, I'm fine.
‐ Just a little dirty.
‐ Jeanie, don't worry about him.
We've taken harder knocks
playing one‐on‐one.
Alright, come here.
‐ What do you need?
‐ Uh, prednisone.
This med room
really needs reorganization.
Why don't you write
a prescription for that?
I only need seven.
You know, we can't keep giving
away our pharmacy stock.
You know, I was reviewing
our financial records
and I noticed that
your salary's being paid
by emergency medicine
and not pediatrics.
Mm‐hmm? That's something
that Morgenstern
and Bernstein worked out.
But doesn't that mean the ER
is underwriting your fellowship?
For which they get
my full services.
Morgenstern thinks
it's a two‐way street.
No, but Morgenstern
is not in charge now.
Wh‐what is the exact nature
of your fellowship?
M‐maybe I could review
your research proposal.
Sure.
Can you get me a copy
by the end of the day?
If I can find one.
Dr. Weaver, they need you
in trauma one.
‐ Thanks.
‐ Uh‐huh.
Yes, this is Dr. Carter
calling again.
Can you have Henry page me?
No, no, actually,
don't have.. Hello?
Don't have him page me,
have him come to the ER.
Because he's doing
a clerkship!
That's right, he's on duty,
he's on duty.
Dr. Greene, Dr. Doyle
pulled me off of a trauma
this morning
to cover sutures.
I really don't think that's
the best use of my time.
Well, maybe she thought she was
more qualified to cover it.
Well, she didn't cover it.
She gave it to Dr. Del Amico.
Which is getting to be
standard procedure around here.
Carter, the suture room
is the intern's place
unless you can get your student
to carry the load.
Anna, how's your
student doing?
‐ Oh, she's a gem.
‐ There you go.
Hello?
Henry, is that you?
I think it's
this damn hallway.
You better be careful
with that thing.
Oh, I‐I don't use this
around patients.
I don't mean that.
I know a guy who got one free
from a pharmaceutical rep.
The first month,
his bill was 300 bucks.
Oh, hey, well, I, hey,
I limit my calls.
Plus, the whole thing you
can write off on your taxes.
Right.
So, it's like
an economy move.
It's not all that bad,
I'll get you cleaned up
and then I'll suture it.
I guess we lucked out,
huh, Bill?
Oh, yeah.
I can't figure out
where all this blood came from.
It's Al's from when
he fell on me.
I knew it would
tear me up
but, uh, I had
to grab the cable.
Can you move
your fingers?
That's good.
Have you had a tetanus shot?
Uh, yeah.
Uh, about a year ago.
‐ Are you allergic to any drugs?
‐ None that I know of.
Hey...there's my guy.
‐ How's the hero?
‐ How's it look?
They'll fix you up.
They can fix anybody up, right?
You know, this man
saved two lives.
How are those guys?
They got away
without a scratch.
Listen, Casey...I want to take
care of you on this, okay?
Whatever this costs,
I'm gonna pay for it.
I wanna keep everybody working
like we've been working.
But, uh, you know,
I got to keep a lid on things.
So, I don't want this going
on to workers comp.
I don't know how bad
this is gonna be.
Well, what are we
talking about here?
‐ Some stitches, a cast?
‐ He might need surgery.
'That's okay, you put it
on your health insurance.'
I pick up whatever
spills over
and I keep you on
the employment rolls.
I don't know how my hands
are gonna work after this.
You know what this is gonna cost
me if it goes on workers comp.
If he doesn't go
on workers comp
he won't qualify
for disability.
Suddenly, nurses
know everything.
I'm gonna go
make some calls.
I had an interesting wound
earlier this morning.
A linoleum knife.
'The cut was as clean
as with a scalpel.'
‐ Huh.
‐ 'Hey, Carter.'
Can you take a case for me?
I'm suddenly swamped.
Sure.
Hey, uh, Chasity..
...dress that for me, would you?
Twenty‐seven year old woman,
altered level of consciousness.
No evidence of trauma.
Her husband brought her in.
Thanks, Anna.
Mr. Torren?
I'm Dr. Carter.
I'll be taking
care of your wife.
I don't know what happened,
last night, she was fine
but I couldn't wake
her up this morning.
Could she have
hit her head somehow?
I don't think so.
Did she complain earlier
about having a headache?
Fever? Nausea?
No, nothing.
She was fine.
Heart and lungs are normal.
That's good.
She's not having
any trouble breathing.
Kirsty, honey,
can you hear me?
For God's sake,
baby, what's wrong?
Please just wake up.
Pupils are
mid‐positioned and fixed.
Corneal reflexes still intact.
That's good.
What‐what are you doing?
I'm going to check
the movement of her eyes
adjusting to the changing
position of her head.
It'll tell us if there's
brain stem involvement.
‐ Uh, no doll's eye response.
‐ What does that mean?
'Uh, It's a little
early to tell.'
I‐I wanna check some labs
and do a head CT.
Why don't you go
wait in the waiting room
and I'll, uh,
keep you posted.
It's bad, isn't it? I can tell
by the way you're acting.
We're really not gonna
know anything
until we've run the tests.
Well, do whatever
you have to, anything.
I have really good insurance.
‐ Okay.
‐ Please?
Excuse me.
Where's the Benton baby?
‐ Reese?
‐ Yeah. No. Benton.
Reese Benton?
He's in the procedure room.
Okay.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, wait, wait,
What are you doing?
I'm circumcising him.
No. I don't
want him circumcised.
Well, you don't want me to leave
it half‐done, do you?
There.
Look, I didn't
want him circumcised.
Who gave you permission
to perform this procedure?
Will you open up
the xeroform gauze, please?
‐ His mother.
‐ Well, she had no right to.
Look, I'm sorry.
I assumed it was agreed to.
No, it wasn't.
But, uh, this isn't
between you and I.
It's between
you and Carla.
And uh, it's done.
Let's get this little guy
back into his‐‐
No, no, I‐I‐I got him.
I got him.
Come here, come here, come here.
I'm sorry.
Come here, come here.
Shh shh shh.
It's okay, it's okay.
Edema of the brain stem.
Probably an infarct.
I'd go along with the
symptoms you described.
How did she respond
to sternal rub?
Withdrawal.
Alright, let's see.
Yeah, she's decerebrating now.
I don't think it'll
be long before she goes
into full respiratory arrest.
She's 27 years old.
Any family members around?
Her husband.
He's in shock.
He doesn't know
what to, what to think.
Be sure you talk to him
about organ donation.
They'll be taking you up
to x‐ray in a few minutes.
‐ How's the pain?
‐ Okay.
Since whatever they're
giving me through that tube.
Better living
through chemistry, huh?
I'm sorry we had to cut
your shirt to pieces
in order to get it off.
Time for a
new one anyway.
'With my first
disability check.'
Is this yours?
Uh, no‐no, officer,
not mine.
Did you smoke this today?
Never saw it before.
You were operating dangerous
machinery, men were hurt.
Men are alive because
I grabbed a running cable, lady.
Because I tore
my hands to shreds.
You can smoke it..
...or stick it where
the sun don't shine.
I told you,
it's not mine.
Alright, I'll just
ask your boss.
Maybe he dropped it.
Okay.
Oh, Dr. Greene.
Hi. How was
your first day?
Oh, she's doing great.
We're, uh, we're just
starting lab requisitions.
Oh, I'm so lucky.
After my interview
I didn't think I had a chance.
‐ What‐what happened?
‐ A disaster. I cried.
We're glad that you're here.
Thanks.
‐ Hi.
‐ Heather.
I left a message
on your machine
about the sports
medicine dinner.
Yeah, and I left
a message that
I wasn't gonna
be able to make it.
Yeah, well, you sounded
a little vague
so, I'm giving it
a face‐to‐face try.
Come on, it's such a coup
if I show up
with a handsome,
brilliant doctor‐‐
Oh, and you couldn't find
anyone else, so..
Okay, busted.
Look, I already bragged
I was bringing a doctor.
I know it's a mercy date,
but I'll make it up to you.
‐ I promise.
‐ I'm sorry.
Tonight, I just can't.
Is it me or the event?
I mean, um,
does "no" mean never?
No. It, just tonight.
'There's a truck in the
ambulance bay, someone's hurt.'
‐ I‐I should check this out.
‐ Okay.
If there's a lot of blood.
It could be an arterial injury.
Grab some lab pads.
Let's get a pressure
dressing out here.
He was ejecting a clip
and shot himself in the leg.
Glenda, don't leave
the ordnance.
Yo, you can't take
no weapons in there.
This is our best stock,
I can't leave it in the truck.
Give it to me.
Hey, Jer, keep these safe, man.
Jerry, we're going
to trauma two.
‐ Glenda.
‐ I'm right here, honey.
You secured the weapons, baby?
Yes, baby, I did.
We were on our way
to a guns and flags show
up in Lansing
to set up a booth.
Glenda, come close.
Don't let them take the leg.
Don't let 'em, Glenda.
I was concerned
about his health.
My son's health is on my mind
24 hours a day.
‐ Our son.
‐ What?
You can't divide our
baby's life into categories.
'Say I'm in charge of health,
and you do the diapers, no.'
You use the medicine
to hide behind so we don't talk.
Carla, we're talking now.
This isn't
a conversation, okay?
'Cause you don't care
what I think or feel.
I might not be your choice
for the mother of your child
but I'm not gonna be left out,
we'll have to share.
Like you shared
in the circumcision, right?
I was mad.
Come on, come clean, Peter.
Your attitude about circumcision
has nothing
to do with his health.
It has to do with
you wanting him
to look like you
in the shower.
So, what if I do?
Carla, he's my son.
Then why didn't
you say that, then?
I understand that.
Instead of you blowing off
a lot of medical steam
that don't make no...damn sense.
Carla, what happened
to that boy's penis
should have been
left up to me.
This type of stroke
can happen to anybody.
It might be
something congenital.
It's so unfair.
But as long as
she's still alive
I mean, there's hope, right?
As the swelling increases
it may affect
her ability to breathe.
'Then, the question
becomes whether'
'it's in Kirsten's best interest
to put her on a ventilator.'
Let her die?
We can sustain her life
on a respirator..
...but the question is,
what kind of life would it be?
I can't believe that it's all
just gonna be over like this.
Mm‐hmm.
You might think about whether
organ donation is something
that she would want.
Yeah.
Kirsten would wanna
help people.
Did you see that?
Oh, she may move a little bit
'from time to time.'
'Oh, my God, she's talking.'
'Do you hear? She's talking.'
Kirsty honey, can you hear me?
‐ What?
‐ 'Yes.'
Yes, honey, it's me.
She's coming around.
Oh, my God!
'She's alright.'
Sinus tach
on the scope.
Entrance wound on the left
medial thigh crossing
the midline exit wound
by the lateral fibular.
Let's get him portable
x‐ray down here.
‐ Ed, you feel this?
‐ Yeah!
No DP
or posterior pulses.
Dr. Greene, that woman
with the stroke, she's awake.
‐ What woman?
‐ 'The brain stem bleed.'
‐ No, she can't be.
‐ She is. She's talking.
Go on.
I'll call vascular.
Did you show me
the right CT?
Yes. She was comatose.
Carter...people with
brain stem infarctions
they don't just wake up.
Hi. I'm Dr. Greene.
What happened to me?
Well, that's what we
want to determine.
Follow my finger.
How do you feel?
She's fine.
Look at her.
Fine.
Just a little tired.
How long do I
have to stay here?
We need to keep you under
observation for a while.
‐ Dr. Carter.
‐ Excuse me.
See this?
This little schmutz?
Could be a warning leak
from the aneurysm
trickled down and caused
her brain stem to swell.
Sh‐should we do an LP?
No. That'd be
a waste of time.
Uh, this could blow.
Let's get an MRI
right away. Okay?
Brought some clothes
for you to wear home.
Nice.
Does Bill know
you're HIV positive?
No.
Well, I‐I think
you better tell him.
My blood didn't
get mixed with his.
I mean, you saw for yourself
he doesn't have a cut on him.
He's got
some skin abrasions.
Look, Jeanie, uh..
...these are working
guys, okay?
It‐it's not like
around here.
That gets out,
I'll be out of a job.
It was rough telling
people here, but I did it.
He should be tested, he should
be put on the triple cocktail
until his test results
come back.
‐ For a few scratches?
‐ Yeah!
How long you think they'll
take doing Ed's x‐rays?
Uh...just depends on
how backed up they are.
Whoa! How much is this?
Two hundred
and seventy five bucks.
Here. Put this up
to your shoulder.
Feel the potential.
'Last year, we sold
those to everybody.'
'You ever hear
of Colonel Draht?'
Uh‐uh.
He is doing some fine work
with weapons, training
patriots down in Texas.
Like that guy
from Waco?
What's the range on it?
'That'll chug a grenade'
into an area target
at 350 meters.
Buy it!
I'll give you a break.
But with Ed hurting all week,
we sure won't make the gun show.
‐ Jerry!
‐ 'Honey, it's disarmed.'
The Feds have us hamstrung.
It's illegal to sell
usable ordnance.
'But if you
take that home..'
...there's a kit
for 70 bucks.
Mm‐hmm, my neighbor
has this dog
that barks all night
every night.
Woof!
Damn, I guess Ed
used a kit on that one.
No. No, I‐I don't belong
to any organizations.
‐ This was all an accident.
‐ I think it's against the law.
Look it up in the book.
I don't write them.
That is our personal property.
I know my rights
according to your constitution.
'Can you hear me?
How about when I speak
like this?
Yes, but the‐the ringing
is really loud.
‐ Oh, what?
‐ It tickles.
Oh, sorry.
Well, eardrum
is intact.
Let me take a look
at the other side.
I hope they're clean,
my ears.
Very clean.
If the tinnitus
continues‐‐
Tinnitus?
The ringing
in your ears.
Uh, you may have to go
see a specialist
just to get your hearing
checked, okay?
Uh‐huh.
Thanks.
You know, I feel
really safe here.
After today?
I think it's having
all you doctors around.
I don't feel like
I'm out there on my own.
Out there on a smile
and a shoestring.
Isn't that from something?
Oh, "Death Of A Salesman."
We did it when
I was in high school.
My teacher told me
I had talent
but he was just trying
to get into my pants.
I think I saw
that play in college.
It's so sad when that guy
looks back over his whole life
and there's
just nothing there.
Yeah.
I better get back
to learning codes.
‐ So...thanks again.
‐ Sure.
So...do we have exposure?
We've mobilized
the proximal segment
and we've
got a clean edge.
So this is the
weapons merchant
who cost us
an ambulance?
Damn lucky
it won't cost him a leg.
Dr. Corday will assist
in the anastomosis
of the popliteal.
5‐0 prolene
on a c‐1 needle.
Uh, we normally use 6‐0.
No. 5‐0 is fine.
What is your preference
on procedure, Ms. Corday?
I've had good results
with the triangulation
technique of carel.
Ah! Favorite
among the British.
I had the pleasure of working
with the British surgeons
on the joint NATO
exercise in 1974.
Tell me, do you know
Sir Lyle Sugden?
Oh, Suggy? Yes!
Perhaps you don't know.
He's dead.
‐ Oh! Great loss.
‐ No. Rather a relief, actually.
Towards the end he got a bit
shaky for slash and dash.
"Slash and dash?"
Oh, I love those British terms.
Dr. Benton, suppose Ms. Corday
asked you for a torch..
...what would you give her?
Actually, I've taken
to saying "flashlight."
Once in the field hospital,
mid thoracotomy..
...we had
a power failure.
Sir Lyle yelled,
"A torch, a torch!"
I thought
he had snapped.
Is he going
to burn the OR?
I said,
"Maybe when we finish
we should all break
for a cuppa, what oh?"
Stand back!
‐ What have you got?
‐ Laura Quentin, 18.
Upper GI bleed.
Tachy at 115.
I gave a liter
of normal Saline.
I know her.
Alright, come on.
Let's go, everybody!
‐ Ready?
‐ Everybody ready?
One, two, three.
Let's get a CBC, PT and
a type and cross four.
It's probably from repeated
vomiting. She's bulimic.
She was in here
a few weeks ago.
Why wasn't she admitted
to psych?
I'm scared.
Am I gonna die?
No. You're gonna be okay.
Well, no wonder
she's back here.
Run another liter.
Who's attending?
Greene.
So we're picking
up his slack?
Well, we are, aren't we?
Yeah, right there.
That's a bleed
in the left anterior
inferior cerebellar artery.
Yeah, process the film.
‐ I'll call a neurosurgeon.
‐ Yeah.
Mrs. Torren?
Mrs. Torren!
Dr. Greene,
she's decerebrating!
I'll set up
for intubation.
Carter, get her husband
to sign a consent
for immediate surgery.
I'll book an OR.
‐ Is she alright?
‐ No.
‐ She needs immediate surgery.
‐ Surgery?
The MRI just showed a leaking
aneurysm in her cerebellum.
It has to be operated
on immediately.
We'll need you to sign
this consent form.
I'm not signing
anything.
You just told me she was dying
and you wanted her organs.
And now she's fine and‐‐
She is not fine. She has a
hemorrhage in her cerebellum.
When she went in there,
she was fine.
Carter, transport is on the way.
Be ready to intubate.
I have to find Dr. Corelli.
He's in surgery.
‐ We don't have consent.
‐ What?
She was fine...talking.
I don't want you
opening her head.
Mr. Torren, listen
very carefully.
Your wife will die
if she does not have
an operation as soon
as possible.
I want her moved!
That will kill her.
Is that what you want?
I know how you care
for your wife
but please
let us operate.
I'm serious.
We are talking minutes.
These are the post‐op forms
Dr. Anspaugh prefers, okay?
What a dreadful
old gasbag!
I mean, he's a
decent enough surgeon
but all that banging on,
pathetic anglophilia.
Tell me, do you
call it "pimping?"
‐ What?
‐ You know.
Treating you
like a med student
with all those
silly questions.
We call that "pimping."
Yeah. Yeah, that's
what we call it.
Fortunately, in the UK
the old tosses
are too lazy
to come to the ORs.
What?
We don't usually refer
to our senior surgeons
that way.
Oh, so I should stop
speaking my mind?
Oh, no, no, no.
Not on my account.
I watched her talking
on the phone to Anspaugh
and girlfriend
did not look happy.
Her first day,
and the ER blows up!
I don't imagine
he would have said, "Attaboy!"
I see they got
that door repaired.
‐ Dr. Weaver.
‐ Yeah.
I‐I'm just so relieved
that no one was hurt.
Thank you, doctor.
‐ 'Doug.'
‐ Yeah?
I know it's been
crazy today
but did you get a copy
of your research?
Yeah, I just haven't had
a chance to do it yet, Kerry.
Maggie? What have you,
uh, got?
‐ Uh, abscess.
‐ Simple I and D.
Hmm. Looks like
a fairly deep abscess.
Uh, booths in that bar
are all rotten.
There's nails sticking up,
maybe an inch.
Did you, uh,
read my directive?
Uh, yeah.
'Oh, that really hurts.'
Yeah, most people don't
understand what's at stake here.
The county is just looking
for an excuse to close this ER.
Lab tests, x‐rays, CT scans.
They just cannot be justified.
Next time you sit on a nail,
you should get in here sooner.
People just won't realize that
I'm trying to save this place.
Uh, I‐I need
the half‐inch iodoform.
I'm hoping that a few people
will understand
and come on board.
Oh...yeah.
Cut?
Where's Dr. Corelli?
In three, finishing
a laminectomy.
You can't go in there.
Dr. Corelli?
Mark Greene.
ER attending.
You know
this is not allowed.
Dr. Corelli, I've
got an emergency.
It better be good,
Dr. Greene.
Twenty five year old woman
came in comatose
followed by periods
of brief lucidity
after which
she decompensated.
She's posturing GCS 5.
MRI shows a cerebellar bleed.
I took the liberty
of booking OR five.
Helen, can you
close for me?
‐ Five pounds enough?
‐ Alright.
Okay, buddy, you're gonna
feel a little pressure
right here at the top
of your leg.
In the past I've found
ice and trendelenburg
excellent adjuvant therapies
for reduction
of these inguinal hernias.
‐ Can we get an ice pack?
‐ Sure.
Alright, buddy.
Now we're gonna fix you up.
But first thing we gotta do...
is stand you on your head.
‐ Kind of weird, huh?
‐ 'I like your technique.'
‐ Cranking the bed?
‐ No. With the children.
You're so at ease with them.
Well...that's where
I spend all my time.
All your time?
That's certainly dedication.
I've come to crave
a bit of leisure.
Yeah, it's not all work
and no play.
How you doing there,
big guy?
So, when one plays,
where does one play?
I mean, here in Chicago?
Alright. Now...I know
you can take pain.
Let's see if you could
take a little cold. Ha?
Aah, what a guy!
Alright. Why don't we
just wait and see?
So you were about to tell me
how to unwind..
'...or perhaps you'd
like to show me?'
That's if you're up
for playing Virgil to my Dante.
Uh...well, um, nothing really
comes to mind, um..
I have a patient to see.
Well...if you think of a place,
I'd like to invite you.
I'm‐I'm involved with someone.
It's not a problem.
Bring her along.
Hey, man, we ever
getting out of this place?
Pretty quick. I think they're
about through with us.
How's that wrist?
It's okay. The doctor called it
a "Colles' fracture."
It's not so bad.
Bill, uh, Jeanie's here
because you've
got to be tested.
Well, tested for what?
I'm HIV positive.
HIV? You're not talking
about having AIDS, right?
Yeah, I am.
Uh, when we landed together,
I was bleeding pretty bad.
I‐I'm‐I'm sure my blood
didn't get mixed
when you were scratched up,
but you should be tested
just to be safe.
So I could get AIDS?
It's a very
remote possibility.
You got it?
Oh, man!
You're out there
working with us
and you got AIDS?
I gotta get by
like everybody else.
We know how to live with it, we
know how to take precautions‐‐
Except now maybe
I got infected.
Jeanie will take
some blood.
That way we can
make sure you're okay‐‐
No!
Not her!
I want someone else.
Hey, come on, man.
We're talking about Jeanie‐‐
Not her!
I'll get a nurse.
Carol, hey!
I know what you're thinking
and you're wrong.
I'm busy.
I just got to follow
you around‐‐
Why follow me?
Why not follow her?
'If I didn't have to do
this secrecy tab‐‐'
I think this secrecy thing
works for you just fine.
‐ I didn't flirt with her.
‐ 'No, no!'
She asked you out for a drink
because she likes
the way you hold an ice pack.
I told her that
I was attached
I didn't say
who I was attached with.
Couldn't say that
Carol Hathaway was my‐‐
‐ Your what? I'm your what?
‐ Come here.
I wanna be with you
and I wanna be here with you
because I wanna be with you.
If you don't trust me,
then this doesn't work.
I have a lot
of things to do.
I'll be at the el.
Dr. Greene?
I just got off
with the OR.
They clipped the base
of her aneurysm.
‐ Caught it in time?
‐ Yeah.
She stands a chance
at a full recovery.
Her husband's sitting in tears,
he wants to say thank you.
Uh, Carter, this was more
your case than mine.
Oh, come on!
You made the diagnosis.
Look, when credit
is offered, take it.
It doesn't happen often
around here.
‐ Taken.
‐ Mark!
‐ Laura Quentin's back.
‐ Who?
The bulimia patient.
I need your signature,
so medicine can come down
and admit her.
Is that a problem?
Because I didn't
admit her before?
It was a mistake. I should have
admitted her last time.
Well, last time,
she wasn't critical.
So, technically,
it wasn't.
Well, I didn't
go the extra mile.
No, it shouldn't depend on
doctors to go the extra mile.
We need a safety net.
We're an ER,
not a clinic.
‐ She's doing it.
‐ What?
Weaver's punching us out.
We are working for nothing.
'Yo, she can't do that.
I got another hour.'
Kerry?
Kerry.
This is a really
bad idea.
It's not a matter of choice.
I'm not singling out nurses.
All departments
have to cut back.
Well, who's gonna do
nurses' duties?
‐ The interns.
‐ The interns?
Come on, Carol, I see
people standing around
at the end of their shifts
talking, planning social events.
It can't go on. Nurses' time
isn't billed for.
They don't
generate income.
No. They just
generate care.
No, no, no. I just had
a change of plans.
D‐don't worry. There's a tux
rental place right by here.
Yeah, listen, instead
of that rubber chicken
you know, uh, why don't
we go to Stella Mare.
You know,
have a nice dinner?
We can be a little late.
Great!
Okay.
‐ Big night?
‐ Yeah, why not?
‐ Sounds great.
‐ Yeah, it is.
Sorry.
Ah, looking good.
Looking good.
Yeah, um...hey,
you just, uh...
there's one more spot
right there by the door
where the paint's
chipped off.
A couple
of finishing touches
and they're gonna
have it all cleaned up.
I've been checking
your employment file.
You've accrued 26 days
of vacation time.
Yeah, I've never‐never
taken a day off.
I'm thinking about
using it to go down
to the Gulf Coast of Alabama
after the first of the year.
Perhaps you should start
taking that time right now.
Now? It's like
a million degrees down there.
I've never
been to Mobile.
I understand there's some lovely
antebellum homes down there.
Did you ever find
that student of yours?
The lab said he went to the fish
hatchery for salmon sperm.
They got pretty
backed up in sutures.
You saying
that's my fault?
I'm saying that's
where I assigned you.
Will Dr. Del Amico
be doing sutures anytime soon?
What?
I'm just wondering.
How long you're
gonna continue to give
Dr. Del Amico all
the interesting cases
while I get assigned
to suture Siberia?
What the hell are you
talking about?
I'm just asking if there
isn't something about
Dr. Del Amico that you find
especially...appealing?
Meaning?
Oh....you know
what I mean.
Oh! That's great!
That's great!
‐ What?
‐ Ask him.
By the way, Anna,
I‐I love your hair.
Thanks.
What's that about?
Nothing.
Oh, come on.
It's the end of the day.
‐ I could use a laugh, too.
‐ It wasn't that funny.
She has a weird
sense of humor.
Okay. So it's
a private joke.
Hey, congratulations
on that, uh..
...that stroke lady.
I heard it was a good save.
Thanks. Thanks
for giving it to me.
Yeah, I was swamped.
I'd like to return the favor.
Don't. Please.
I hate feeling indebted.
Wait, you know what? There is
something that you could do.
‐ Sure.
‐ Uh..
Th‐this morning you said
something about the cellphone
being deductible,
you know, about taxes.
I'm getting
completely hammered.
Yeah, yeah, yeah,
you could deduct
stethoscope, lab coat, books.
Otoscope?
Oh, yeah! Absolutely.
All equipment.
Why don't we have dinner?
We can talk about it.
Uh...tonight's
the laundromat.
Ah...me too!
Me too.
We could do
our laundry together.
I'll do your
tax planning.
You know,
laundry's deductible.
Really?
Okay. I'll, uh,
get us some sandwiches.
Great!
Doug.
I had prepared
a very elaborate argument.
Does this mean
I don't need it?
I already had
the argument...with myself.
I hope there wasn't
any name calling involved.
No, it was very civil.
You won.
Oh, so I do better
when I'm not there.
This time, yeah.
‐ So you trust me?
‐ This time.
Hey.
Are you
keeping score?
‐ Yeah! You're ahead.
‐ I'm sorry, what?
"Talk on rotator cuff injuries
in track and field."
What exactly
does that mean?
You're the doctor.
You're supposed
to know that.
Yeah, well, I probably
did know that
before we drank this.
I have an idea.
Why don't we drink
another bottle
and then we can obliterate
all medical knowledge.
Sounds good.
What?
I missed you.
Oh, come on.
You never called.
You vanished.
I was a fool, okay?
I'll make it up to you.
Promise?
Won't work with dimes
and nickels.
You gotta use quarters.
You don't happen to have any
quarters on you, do you?
Cool.
You should let
your wife do this.
My wife?
Oh, yeah! She's getting
some sandwiches for us.
Better she does it.
You don't know
what you doing.
What are you doing?
Sorry!
‐ Wait‐‐
‐ I don't know.
This thing just,
like, broke on me.
It can't take
this kind of load.
I mean, you've ever
used a dryer before?
Sure, yeah. I've used
a dryer before.
It's just, the one in my
neighborhood handles
loads like this.
Even bigger ones all the time.
Wow!
Okay.
Alright,
we gotta get this.
Um...uh, let me see.
Okay.
Wow!
How about a hoagie?
Here.
Oh.
Oh, no!
Eww!
Wow!
It's gonna be a long night
in the laundromat.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
I just, uh..
I don't know.
I...used
to turn you on.
No, no, you..
you turn me on.
I just..
I guess I've just
been a lil'..
...stressed out.
Um...I'd rather
you didn't smoke in here.
I'm...allergic.
It would be better if I..
You know, if I got going.
I...I didn't say that.
Yeah, um..
Maybe it is better if you go.