Previously on ER:
There is no settlement.
We agreed to the meeting as a show of
good faith in case we went back to trial.
See the initials? C.A. Curtis Ames.
I think he's trying to threaten us.
You wanna talk about what's bugging you?
- No.
I thought I'd be reporting
on topical medical issues...
not doing puff pieces on
BOTOX and unsanitary manicures.
Luka, this is...
Eddie. ABBY: Eddie.
- You the husband?
- Oh, my God.
Meg, Sarah, this is Neela.
Hey, Greg.
Can a straight guy go
through a gay phase?
I think it's more
likely that he's gay.
Just what I like to see.
A brother taking his education
seriously. What you got?
Art History final today.
- We pulled an all-nighter.
- We?
Chaz, do you have an extra
toothbrush I can borrow?
Oh, hi. I'm Nicole.
- This is my brother, Greg.
- Morning.
Nic's my study partner.
- She lives on campus, it got late so...
- Yeah.
- I hope we didn't make too much noise.
- No, I didn't hear a thing.
Tongue stuck in bowling
ball, waiting on a drill...
bedbug couple, 1
percent hydrocortisone.
Need an exterminator
too. Those critters are nasty.
Sleep-eater guy wants a
prescription for a padlock.
- For his refrigerator.
- Hey, Ray.
Three's ready for transfer.
How do we do that?
- What about belly pain in 2?
- Bowel obstruction.
You need to fill out a
transfer packet, um...
to document the reason for
transfer, and consent for transfer...
and stability for transfer.
If you don't do this, then it's an
EMTALA violation and a big fine.
- All right. Got it.
- So, uh...
We're okay, right?
Yeah. These look
pretty self-explanatory.
I mean, about keeping
you and me under wraps.
It gets out that we're dating, it
could get weird around here for you.
Oh. For me?
You two make such a cute couple.
- What? Her and me?
- No, we're not...
- What should I do...?
- Sorry, you gotta talk to Morris.
I'm due at the station.
- You must be excited about tonight.
- Tonight? What's tonight?
Dr. Weaver's special report
on the Channel 5 news.
Hey, everybody.
This is Ben Parker.
He's a new RN, all the
way in from Savannah.
- Hi, Ben.
- Hello. Hi.
It's nice to meet y'all.
We got ourselves a Southern boy.
- Yeah, a real Georgia peach.
- Hey.
It's his first shift,
let's not scare him.
We need him to
come back tomorrow.
Twenty says Gentle
Ben doesn't last the week.
- No, I give him five days.
- Three, and make it 40.
What's up, man?
- Hey, Kerry. You on today?
- Not anymore.
All right. What
am I walking into?
We got slammed at midnight,
but we're under control now.
Good. Hey, hey.
I wanted to say
thanks for the advice...
but I'm happy to let you
know you got it wrong.
- Advice?
- Yeah.
As it turns out, not everyone
who experiments is gay.
Excuse me?
I'm talking about
my brother, Chaz.
It was like he said,
it's just a phase.
- Is that so?
- Yup.
Hey, you remember
that girl he took home?
- Mm-hm.
- Well, she spent the night.
My brother's straight.
Gee, Greg, you must be so proud.
What...? No, that's
not what I meant.
What I meant was, uh...
Uh, you know what I meant.
Yeah. And you're not
my only black friend.
Joe, next time, try eating your
apricots, not throwing them.
Hey, do you think this is funny?
So the budget committee
is pressuring you that much?
And girls don't like when
you wear your food. Trust me.
Yeah. They're all
over me about it.
How much do they
want you to cut?
- They want me to cut an Attending.
- What?
- That's crazy.
- Yup.
And this is between
me, you and Joe.
Hey. Hi.
What's it like out there? Is it too
cold for Joe to go to the park today?
I can't believe they want you to
cut an Attending. It's ridiculous.
How does the budget committee
expect us to do our job when...? Luka.
Hey! Luka.
What is up with you?
You're acting so weird.
You're running out
without shoes and a jacket...
I saw a tow truck. I thought my car was
parked on the wrong side of the street.
They don't have alternate-
side-of-the-street parking in Croatia?
Danielle Davis, 13, unresponsive
with vaginal bleeding.
BP, 90/60 in the
field up with a liter.
What happened? HOLLIS:
Found her on the school steps.
Danielle, open
your eyes. Danielle?
- What is it?
- Syncope, trauma with vag bleed.
Or ectopic pregnancy and she's
bleeding out. I'll clear a room.
Hang on, Danielle. We're
gonna take good care of you.
Well, you may
have torn a ligament.
Looks like a case of Boomeritis.
Well, that sounds bad. - Okay.
Mr. Pachecko, remember to
warm up before working out...
and consider taking up
swimming or riding instead.
He's gonna need a knee
immobilizer, crutches and Vicodin.
- "Boomeritis." You come up with that?
- Mm-hm.
Hey, Morris. I need
you to sign off on this.
Probable ACL tear.
- So how's Katey working out?
- Uh, who?
- Katey. Aren't you supervising her?
- Oh, no. No. Not me.
Oh. Hey, is it me or do the med
students keep getting younger every year?
- What is she, like 24?
- Ah, I don't know.
- I've never noticed how hot she is.
- What?
- I didn't say about her being hot.
- She is hot, but...
- Eh, well...
You have to be certified as an
MICN in order to take radio calls.
But you can use it
to do a status check.
Can somebody get
Ortho on my knee guy?
- Yeah, I'll take it.
- Thank you.
- There's a new course. I'll get details.
Dawn, is the white count
back on my gallstone guy?
- Ten-point-eight.
- All right.
He needs four of morphine. Here.
- Sure, I'll get to it in a minute.
- Oh, whoa, Hope.
About your
newlyweds with the flu.
Why would you prescribe, "Long walks,
holding hands and romantic dinners"?
Oh, I sensed tension in their marriage.
When we're tense or stressed...
our immune systems
weaken, which, as you know...
limits our body's ability to
fight off infections and viruses.
I felt if, uh, Andy
and Phyllis...
carved out more time for one another,
they could strengthen their marriage...
thus speeding their recovery
and preventing illnesses.
- Hope, you can't... MAN:
Bitch, it's mine and I want it.
Come on, now. You stole
it and I want it back now.
Sir, you're gonna have
to calm down, okay?
This guy has been acting
up since he got here.
Sir, what are you missing?
When I came in here, I had
a 5-carat ring in my pocket.
And now it's gone.
- And this bitch stole it. Come here!
- Ahh!
Now, give me my ring. - Okay.
Hey.
You shut your pie hole
and you come with me.
- You okay, Hope?
- Yes, thank goodness for Ben.
Yeah, he really took charge.
- Say that again.
Come on, let's
break it up. All right?
Get back to work,
not a big deal. Please.
- I think we got shown up by a murse.
- Huh?
- Male nurse.
- Oh, that's bad.
Yeah, he's pretty
macho, though, huh?
Pupils, 4 millimeters
and reactive.
Contusions and
lacerations to the labia.
CBC, coags, type and cross.
- She was assaulted.
- Pregnancy test is negative.
Okay, let's get her to
CT to rule out brain injury.
I'll check on CT and notify OB.
- C-spine's clear.
- When's she gonna be able to talk?
- I don't know.
- All right.
- Her clothes need to be inventoried.
- Of course.
Okay, let's use Dermabond
to fix this forehead lac.
- She probably hit her head.
- Scanner's ready in 20 minutes.
- Trying to run from who did this.
- Twenty minutes? Not good.
- Surgery is down on your consult.
- I'll get there when I can.
We're okay here. Go.
Hi, this is Dr. Kovac. Put
her on a portable monitor.
Yeah, I've got an unconscious
kid down here, clear the scanner.
There's a Mrs. Arrida
here from the girl's school.
Okay. Okay!
- We're gonna need an evidence bag.
- Sure thing.
I'm the vice principal at
Lakeside. How is Danielle?
Uh, she's not
very well right now.
Oh, my God. KOVAC: Please.
- Do you know what happened?
- No. No one saw anything.
We've never had
anything like this.
Her parents, have
they been notified?
The school nurse called
but had to leave messages.
They need to be here.
Danielle's mother is
here. She works at County.
- What's her name?
- Gilliam.
Angela Gilliam.
What makes you think
this is bowel obstruction?
Abdominal pain, distension, no
bowel movement for three days. Ouch.
No history of abdominal
surgery, no adhesions...
and he's too young for
a colon lesion. Upright.
How's that? That better?
Air-fluid levels,
but no dilated loops.
- Not consistent with obstruction.
- Can't be sure.
You know, sometimes things
aren't always the way they seem.
- About the other night...
- Stop.
It's over. I told Meg it's over.
Maybe for you, but any idiot could
see on her face that it's not over for her.
It's an ileus. The
bowel's asleep.
Doesn't help that he's
been popping Vicodin.
Just give him a laxative
and wait for him to poop.
That's ileus. I-L-E-U-S.
Pulled me out
of a staff meeting.
- What's the emergency?
- There's a patient in Trauma 1.
Okay, let's go. We couldn't
discuss this on the phone?
We don't know what happened.
They found her outside of her school.
Luka, what's going on?
We think she was
sexually assaulted.
- Who?
- CT can take her, Dr. Kovac.
Uh.
Angela, it's Danielle.
My baby.
My sweet baby girl.
Okay, Trudy, can you explain
to me how this happened?
Wes... That's my boyfriend.
- -he's always talking on his cell.
But when I'd ask, "Who you
calling?" he gets all secretive on me.
- Does your old man do that to you?
- No.
- My old man's pretty cool.
- Lucky.
Me and Wes are in
bed and his cell rings...
so I rolled over and
grabbed it before he could.
- It's pretty smart, huh?
- Very.
Wes gets mad, starts chasing me around
the room when I see it's Debbie calling.
- I say, "Who the hell is Debbie?"
- He tells me it's none of my business.
And that's when you decided
to swallow his cell phone.
Okay.
I'm gonna order an x-ray...
and we'll find out if we can
pull it out here in the ER.
If not, you're
gonna need surgery.
It's tiny. I could stick my finger
down my throat to try to barf it up.
- Hey, Abby. Got a sec?
- Hold that thought.
This is Ben Parker, new RN.
- Hi. Abby Lockhart.
- Hi.
- You're the nurse that became a doctor.
- Yeah, guilty as charged.
- Got seduced by the dark side, huh?
- I use my powers for good, not evil.
Abby's an R-3 now.
Nice to meet you.
Oh, I forgot.
Uh, there's an asthmatic
at triage asking for you.
Hi.
Okay. Uh, I'll be back
when GI gets here.
- What is it?
- You hear that?
It's probably that stupid
bitch, Debbie, calling.
- Sounds pretty wheezy.
- It's been worse.
- How long you been off your medication?
- Since my prescription ran out.
And that was when?
Sixty of prednisone p.o.
- You giving me steroids?
- Yes. Sorry.
But only for five days to
knock down the inflammation.
And something tells me that,
uh, you didn't get your flu shot.
I'll add that to the orders.
How's your buddy?
Your friend here at County?
You were gonna visit him?
Better. Yeah, he's doing better.
Good.
- You'd be better if you quit smoking.
- Killjoy.
- You two ever smoke?
- I did but I gave it up.
Miss it?
Hey, you work here too.
- Small world.
- Yeah, hi.
Can I talk to you? I need
you in Trauma 1 now.
Sure. Can I get a chest
x-ray, PA and lateral?
- And I'll be back.
- Yeah, you got it.
I need you to do a rape exam on
that girl we brought in this morning.
- She's Angela Gilliam's daughter.
- Oh, God.
- How's Angela?
- Keeping it together. Just barely.
Okay. I'll find you
when I'm done.
Officer Hollis?
You have a minute?
Sure, doc. Maybe we can
get some coffee sometime.
- Can we talk outside?
- Sure.
What do you think? - Maybe.
Don't tell me I don't.
I've read about it.
Then you should know...
- Glucoside's negative.
- Thanks.
There are no known
cases of avian flu in the U.S.
Maybe I'm the first.
I demand Tamiflu.
You have no symptoms.
No fever, cough.
I've been in
contact with poultry.
You cannot contract avian flu
from eating chicken chow mein.
What caused my diarrhea?
It could be a stomach
virus, food poisoning...
And avian flu virus
does not cause diarrhea.
Viruses mutate, it happens.
Okay, Dawn, get Mrs. Martinelli
two of loperamide, q.i.d., p.r.n.
And dispo her before she
convinces me we have it.
All right. Katey, nice work.
I have a good teacher.
How long you two been dating?
Uh, we're not dating.
You're not?
My bad.
It's all ready.
Thanks, Haleh.
Okay, Danielle.
Let me explain what
we're gonna do. All right?
First, we're gonna put
your feet in these stirrups.
Then I'm gonna examine
you inside with this.
It's called a speculum.
It has a light in it.
When the speculum is in, I'm gonna
take some swabs and sweep inside.
And then I'm gonna irrigate with water,
and remove that with a syringe. Okay?
Okay.
Can you scooch down towards me?
Little bit more.
All right, here we go.
Sam.
Hey, why did you blab about Katey
and me when I asked you not to?
- What are you talking about?
- Everybody knows, even the patients.
I didn't say anything, I swear.
- Ew.
- Oh!
Hell, man. I liked this shirt.
- That's a fag shirt.
- Look, just cut it out, all right? No...
- There's no spitting...
- Incoming!
All right, we gotta get
a mask on this guy now.
Ben. Your friend's
acting up again.
- Yeah, I see that.
- Up yours.
Ew, ew, ew. Who knows
what diseases he has.
Yeah. Don't just stand
there, help me find a mask.
No, I've seen guys like this
bite through masks before.
Wow.
Where'd you learn that?
It's a parlor trick I picked
up at Savannah General.
Never seen that one before.
Can I get you some fava
beans and a nice Chianti?
Dr. Morris, um, I need you
to see my patient in Curtain 1.
- Yeah, what's the problem?
- Well, he complains of a migraine, but...
- Whoa, whoa. Did you say migraine?
- Yes, but...
Hope, would you drive a Lamborghini to
a Laundromat? Hitch Seabiscuit to a plow?
Have Eddie Van Halen play air guitar?
I'm Dr. Morris. I don't do migraines.
I think it's more than that.
You think?
I don't want a restraining
order. I want him arrested.
I know you're frustrated, but
Ames hasn't done anything illegal.
So he has to hurt my family
before anyone will listen?
I wouldn't worry about this guy. He's
just a sucker, working a crappy job.
If you pursue this, you
might piss him off for real.
Piss Ames off?
Look, do yourself a
favor, forget Ames.
He's already
forgotten about you.
- Hey.
The exam evidence for Danielle
is sealed and waiting for signature.
- Just see Haleh.
- Thanks. Take it easy, doc.
- Are you okay?
- Yeah.
Did you send Danielle's
cultures to the lab?
Yeah, GC and chlamydia and I
told them to rush the vaginal washing.
Okay. I better get back in.
She's still pretty agitated.
Okay, try a mg of Ativan.
Is your daughter dating anyone?
She's 13.
You'd be surprised how
young they start these days.
Luka, my husband, Paul.
- Hi.
- Dr. Kovac. Was Danielle raped?
Well, the initial results are
negative for the presence of sperm.
Thank God.
But there's something else.
Well, it looks like Danielle was
assaulted with a sharp object.
It appears she was, uh, cut...
and penetrated repeatedly
with a razor blade.
- What kind of monster would do this?
- I'm so sorry.
Which one of you two saw
Danielle last this morning?
I usually drive her to school but I
had an early meeting, so Paul took her.
- And what time was that?
- About 7:15.
Anyone see you
drop Danielle off?
- I don't know.
- What time did you get to work?
- Okay, do we need to do this now?
- How is that important?
- Mr. Gilliam, let's step outside.
- I'm staying here with my stepdaughter.
Some lunatic cut
up our daughter...
and you're treating my
husband like a suspect?
Mom.
- What's going on?
- Okay, that's enough. Outside.
I can't have you
upsetting my patient.
- That wasn't our intent.
- Paul, listen to me. Listen to me.
The police want to catch whoever
did this to Danielle as much as you do.
- Of course, but...
- So just go answer their questions.
And then you can
rejoin your family. Please.
Everything's going to be okay.
I need you to talk to me.
Danielle, honey.
Do you know who hurt you?
Yes.
Then tell me.
I can't.
You'll be mad.
My head hurts
just looking at it.
How did he get it in so deep
without hitting any vital structures?
Managed to stay
outside the brain...
miss the internal carotid,
optic nerve and pituitary.
- Lucky bastard.
- Hey, I heard you guys had a cool case.
- Is that a...?
- Ice pick.
What makes someone
shove an ice pick in?
Ran out of Q-tips?
Hearing voices,
wanted them to shut up.
But I wonder why he didn't
try pulling it out himself.
Said the demons in his
head would get loose if he did.
Hey, is this an ER case?
I'd say Neurosurgery.
- No, ENT.
- Definitely Psych.
I say we page them
all, let them fight.
You don't want in on this?
Nope. Nope, nope, nope. I'm leaving
it all in your capable hands, Archie.
Heh, heh... Whoa!
Nice move for an old dude.
What's up, man? How
did you get back here?
- I got some moves of my own.
- I don't doubt that.
- How was the final?
- It was nothing.
Okay.
- Can I talk to you about something?
- Yeah. Go ahead.
Is there someplace
a little more private?
Uh... Yeah, come on.
- If this is a bad time, man...
- No, it's all good, man.
So does it have anything
to do with this morning?
Yeah. Kind of, man.
Ha, ha, let me tell
you something, man.
You and I, definitely
brothers. You got good taste.
- The girl is fine.
- Greg, listen. I...
Heads up.
I think I kind of gave
you the impression...
that something happened
between me and her.
- Sure looked like that to me.
- No.
The truth is Nicole
and I are just friends.
I like her, and she's cool to
hang out with, but I'm not hitting it.
Mm. That's cool.
That's nothing, trust me.
- Give the girl time if...
- Greg.
I'm gay.
I mean, you said it was just a phase.
You're 18, come on. What do you know?
You just need to meet...
All the talk in the world about chicks
and sports isn't gonna change me.
- You were lying.
- I was lying to myself.
And I'm not gonna do that
anymore, man. This is my life.
- Sorry if it makes you hate me.
- I don't hate you.
Oh, you don't hate me
but can you deal with it?
Are we still cool?
Pratt, can I give your vomiting
guy another five of Compazine?
Look, I can't do this right now.
- It's okay, I can do it.
- No, no, I better, um.
Look, I gotta go.
- Sorry, sorry, sorry.
- It's okay.
I have a bunch of
eighth-graders with gastroenteritis.
Potato salad left out
too long in the cafeteria.
How's it going in there?
Surgery's coming down to
rule out intra-abdominal injury.
It seems Danielle knows her
attacker, but won't say who it is.
- Protecting somebody?
- I don't know.
- Well, what does Hollis think?
- Hollis?
Hollis, the cop.
That you were talking
to about Danielle.
Uh, he doesn't know much more.
- Your bar buddy's still here.
- Oh, shoot.
- I have my eighth-graders.
- Don't worry.
- I'll take him.
- Thank you.
He's had a couple of
treatments for asthma.
You can send him
home with prednisone.
- I'll have Sam bring in the x-rays.
- Okay.
Hey, doc.
You draw the short straw?
You taking care of me now?
Dr. Lockhart's
with other patients.
I'm only guessing, but you're
not from around here, huh?
No. Croatia.
Long way from home.
Well, this is my home now.
You have some mild wheezing.
First-time visitor myself.
I probably should've
come in spring.
A friend of mine told me
winters could be tough.
No, it's not too bad.
You, uh, planning on
raising your son here?
Abby told me. Congratulations.
You mean Dr. Lockhart.
- Luka, you need these?
- Yeah. Thanks, Sam.
I'm not discussing my
personal life with the patients.
Hey, Sam. Five of albuterol
and check on him in 30 minutes.
- Have me paged if somebody needs me.
- Listen, doc, if I spoke out of line...
- Hey.
- No, sir. Don't touch, don't touch.
Okay. It's official.
- Every department has passed the buck.
- Surgery, Neurosurg, and ENT?
Well, they all claim
it's not their problem.
What are we gonna do?
I say we pull it out. - Huh?
Come on. Come on, Let's show those
wusses that the ER's not afraid of a...
Ten-inch ice pick
in a man's skull?
- Nope, nope. Push three of Versed.
- I don't know, it's kind of...
The films show it missed
everything on the way in.
So all we have to do is ease
it out along the same path...
and admit him
for IV antibiotics.
- I know, but what if...?
- Not to mention...
this is a publishable
case report...
for any ambitious med
student, intern or Resident.
- It's not the craziest...
- No.
- He can't walk like that.
- If we don't, he's gonna.
Okay.
Who wants to do it?
- I'll do it.
- Attagirl.
- All right, don't wiggle the handle, Hope.
- I won't.
- Give it one good tug.
- Don't be nervous.
- Relax and pull gentle, but firm.
- Okay.
Oh.
Is there any pain when I press here?
- No.
- How about here?
- Uh-uh.
Okay. I'm gonna need
to take a look inside you.
- They did that.
- I know. I'm checking for other things.
It's okay, honey.
Angela, the detective is asking if
you could step out for a moment.
I need to stay with my daughter.
It's okay, Mom.
You can go.
I want you to.
Okay, if that's what you want.
I'm going to see how
deep the cuts are.
They're not bad.
I know.
How do you know
the cuts weren't deep?
Honey...
did you do this to yourself?
Please don't tell my mom.
- How many loads hauled today?
- Four.
Boss wants you to get that
load you left in the corner.
Go screw yourself.
Mr. Ames.
- What are you doing here?
- We need to talk.
I'm working now.
This is not a good time.
I don't care. MAN: Ames!
I don't pay you to chitchat.
Is it okay if I, uh, take
my break right now?
Ten minutes.
- You're lying.
- Check time cards if you don't believe.
I don't know where you live.
It wasn't you in the park? You
didn't send me my son's toy?
Your initials were on it.
Why are you doing this to me?
You sent the police to my job.
I can't have you doing that.
- This job is all I got left now.
- Stop playing games.
I'm trying to live my life and
make it through one more day.
My family is gone,
my house is gone.
I'm living in my
car. My damn car.
- That's not my problem, okay?
- What is it you want from me?
You've been watching my family,
following us. That stops right now.
I would never do
anything to hurt your family.
I know what it's
like to lose one.
You do too, right?
I heard that you were
married once with kids.
Must be horrible
going through all that.
I gotta get back
to work, all right?
Listen to me, Ames. Come
near my family again, I'll kill you.
- I am so sorry. It's all my fault.
- No, no. It was my idea.
- Maybe I pulled the handle too hard or...
- No, Hope.
You were the only one in the
entire hospital to step up to the plate.
I'm proud of you.
So how is he?
The human shish kebab will be fine,
no thanks to that imbecilic stunt of yours.
How were we to know
the handle would break off?
Okay. All right, just for fun, let's
pretend that you each had even a modicum...
of gray matter that you somehow
managed to fashion into some crude...
rudimentary
semblance of a brain.
You would know never pull something
near a vital structure unless in the O.R.
We remove foreign
bodies all the time in the ER.
Pulling a vibrator out of
someone's ass? Not the same.
Hey, hey. Dr. Bobek acted under
my supervision and my orders.
- Perfect. Half-wit leading the dimwit.
- Look, you obnoxious boor.
The ER works damn hard
for every patient we see.
We acted in this guy's
best interest when no one...
not even Surgery,
would give him time.
Did we do something
that didn't work? Yes.
Fine. It happens sometimes.
I will take full responsibility.
But at least we got off
of our asses and tried.
Well, gold stars
for the ER asses.
Hey!
What is it about your need
to belittle other people?
Does insulting someone
make you feel like a man?
Bolster what little
self-esteem you're clinging to?
Wow, you know, I can't even begin to
imagine what happened in your life...
to make you the kind of
person everybody hates.
I could kiss you right now.
Really?
Hm.
Now it's gone.
Sorry this took so long.
It's just kind of the
way things work.
- Oh, I didn't mind.
- Don't forget to fill your prescription.
And remember to take
the prednisone with food.
Yes, ma'am. If you say so.
And you need to follow up
with your doctor in a week.
Right, um.
- What are your office hours?
- Ha. Um...
I can refer you to
the pulmonary clinic.
- That's all right. I'll work it out.
- Okay.
Hey, hey. Where
did you disappear to?
- Dr. Kovac, I need to talk to you.
- Yeah.
Nowhere. I'll see you later.
He seems like
an interesting guy.
Could use work on
his bedside manner.
Well, it's been a rough day.
Hey, Abby. Weaver's coming on.
Okay. Goodbye, Eddie.
- Take care.
- Good night.
- I miss anything?
- No. She's after the weather.
Timmy, Channel 5. Now.
Nothing more dangerous than
a man in control of the remote.
Pretty easy once you
get the hang of it, huh?
Yeah. I appreciate you
showing me the ropes today.
Oh, please. I was once a brash,
overconfident new nurse myself.
I just hope we haven't changed
your mind about County.
No, not yet.
Why don't you let
me buy you a drink...
or take you out to dinner,
just to say thank you?
- You mean like a date?
- Does it sound like a date?
Kind of.
Call it whatever you
want. Just say yes.
Neela. So my
incarcerated hernia guy?
Still in line for the O.R.
- You think he needs a colostomy?
- You know what?
We'll have to wait.
Hey, Ray. You forgot to fill out
the consult request on your CF'er.
Hey, this is
Dr. Rasgotra, I was paged.
- Thanks. I'm sorry about that.
- Hey, and you guys gotta knock it off.
I'm talking about Katey.
She's a med student, Ray.
- I'm not evaluating her.
- Doesn't matter.
- I don't want your judgment impaired.
- My judgment is fine.
It's not like it's not
going on here all the time.
As long as I'm
running the floor, it isn't.
Tell you what, when it's your
business to know about my love life...
I'll let you know.
Hey, hey! She's on.
Somebody turn up the sound.
Last week, while looking for cans
and bottles in the Dumpster behind me...
Weaver's a real natural.
What they thought was
a child's discarded doll.
Wow, this really
turned out good.
It's only TV.
- You're kidding, right?
- Shh.
Henry just fell asleep.
How many patients do
you treat in one ER shift?
- Like, 25, 30 tops?
- I don't know. It depends.
Okay, well, on TV, you can reach
a hell of a lot more than 30 people...
and still help them.
No. I mean, it's not the same.
Yeah, well, it still counts.
Oh, my gosh.
I can't believe
it's me up there.
Yeah, well, you better get used to
it because you're really very good.
I couldn't have done
it without my producer.
Hey.
Hey. You heading out?
Thank God. It's been a long day.
Yeah, this place can suck at times.
Better leave while you can, huh?
You know, Pratt's right.
It's not cool to date a student.
- So this is your business too?
- I'm only saying.
She's nice and
everything, I like her, but...
But what, Neela? What?
Well, nothing. I'm concerned.
Well, thank you. I'm good.
And Katey's good. In
fact, things are going great.
Then I'm happy for you.
- So, what's this really about?
- What?
- Why do you care all of a sudden?
- We're friends, right?
That's what friends do,
talk about each other's lives?
Oh, that's how it is.
Okay, friend, how's Gates?
Because you know what? Really
not into playing your games anymore.
- What?
- Do you think I'm gonna hang out...
waiting for you to find out
he's jerking you around?
- Ray.
- Neela, you made your choice.
You can't have it both ways.
Miss Gilliam, if you can think
of anything else, give us a call.
- Sure.
- Thank you.
- Is your husband back?
- He'll be back soon.
The police wanted to look
at Danielle's computer...
see if she kept a diary.
Angela, I need to tell
you something. Uh...
When Danielle was being
examined by surgeons...
she told the doctor and the
nurse in the room that she did this.
She cut herself.
That's not possible.
They must've misunderstood her.
Well, she said
she's done it before.
But today, she couldn't
control the bleeding.
She got frightened.
She tried to run home and
that's when they found her.
She also said a boy kissed
her before class today.
He tried to reach under her
skirt, she pushed him away...
but she said she
remembered something.
Remembered what?
That's when she went to
the girls' room and cut herself.
Luka, I don't understand.
Angela...
Danielle talked about something
that happened to you in Detroit.
Something she witnessed.
Oh, God.
She saw.
When Danielle was 9, a man
came to the door of our apartment...
said he was doing
repairs in the complex.
He wore overalls, carried a
toolbox, so I let him in and, uh...
He raped me.
Danielle was playing outside.
I never thought
she had any idea.
I never told anyone.
Not even Paul.
I didn't wanna upset Danielle, I
just wanted to put it all behind me.
What did I do?
- This isn't your fault.
- What did I do?
I was so busy trying
to keep it all together...
I didn't even see what my own
daughter was going through.
You did what you
thought was best.
You were just trying
to protect your family.
Hey, Neela. Neela, wait up.
- Oh, not now. Really, not now.
- Didn't tell you earlier, I'm moving.
- Oh, yeah? Where?
- Well, I haven't found a place yet...
I don't have time for this crap.
It's not like I can just
walk out of there tomorrow.
- No?
- No.
Sarah and Meg have had it rough,
and they've come to count on me.
It must feel good
to be the hero.
I promised my buddy that
I would take care of them.
Oh, yeah, right, the promise.
Was sleeping with your
friend's wife part of the deal?
It wasn't about that.
You're not making this easy.
Oh, I'm sorry. I didn't
realize I was supposed to.
All right, look, right or wrong,
yes, Meg and I sometimes...
Out of comfort, or
convenience, or loneliness.
I don't know what.
But it wasn't love.
Enough! Just stop.
Stop lying.
You're right. You're right.
I haven't been
honest for a long time.
I mean, for 10 years, I've dealt
with people and things in my life...
in a way that I wouldn't
have to get too close.
- Now you're gonna tell me it's different.
- Yes. Since I met you, I've been a mess.
You're making me think about
the way I want my life to be.
The way it could be.
I am?
My train's here.
Hey, Chaz. Chaz.
Hey, hey, hey, man.
What are you doing?
- Wait in the car for me, okay?
- Sure.
- Come on, now. You don't have to leave.
- Yeah, I do.
I never said I
wasn't cool with it.
You never said you were.
All right, look. I work on
gay patients all the time.
I work with gay doctors.
When it comes to my own blood,
I just need some time, that's all.
Ha. Some time.
That's funny.
- You're more like Dad than you realize.
- No.
It's not coming out like I mean.
I could see when I told
you, you weren't okay with it.
And maybe you'll
never be okay with it.
I sure hope you prove me wrong.
So tomorrow, they're taking
Danielle to a private facility.
Well, it sounds like she's
getting the help she needs.
Yeah. It's gonna take some time,
but I think they'll all get through it.
Abby, you asked me
about where I went.
Yes, and you said
something about nowhere.
I went to see Curtis Ames.
The patient who sued you?
That guy in the park?
When you lost Joe's toy?
That was Ames.
- How do you know?
- And this morning, he was on our street.
He's been following us.
- What?
- I didn't have proof, but today...
- Wait, you didn't say anything?
- No.
- I just...
- Luka!
I... I've been walking all
around Chicago with our son.
- I know, I know.
- The babysitter takes him out every day.
And there's a crazy,
angry guy following us?
- But it's over now.
- How do you know that?
- I know because I took care of it.
- How?
Look, hey, let's just go home.
We can talk about it there.
- Abby.
- Taxi!
- What are you doing?
- The train is slow. I wanna get home.
Okay.
I can't believe this. I cannot
believe you didn't tell me.
- I didn't want you to worry.
- You didn't want me to worry?
- Yes.
- I thought we were past this.
- Past what?
- This... In our relationship.
This need you have to protect me or
shield me from the hurts of the world.
- Why are you bringing all that now?
- Taxi!
- It's different now. We're different.
- That's what I thought.
Look, I know I should've told
you, but this is just about Ames.
- Don't make it about us.
- It is about us.
I'm going. Are you
coming or what?