I asked you
to plant one bug
then walk away.
But, no,
you couldn't
do that.
Hell, you don't
seem to get it.
As a physician, I have
a responsibility...
I'm so tired
of hearing that.
After the MRI fiasco,
Ray Burke said
he was done with you
and still you called him.
Well, I need to speak to him
about his MRI results.
I'm concerned.
Concerned how?
There are some old subdural
hematomas and plaques
in both his carotids.
It could mean
he's at risk
for a stroke.
Could?
I can't make a diagnosis
without more of a work-up.
In that case, there's nothing
to report to Ray about.
We could have nailed
that scumbag a week ago
if you hadn't
screwed things up.
No more calls.
I can't just walk away.
You can and you will.
It's over, Dr. Halstead.
Hey, you made this mess
when you took Ray's kickback.
This is on you.
Will, who was
that woman?
Oh, just a drug rep.
They just won't
leave me alone.
Really? I've never
seen her before.
So, listen,
the DJ texted me.
Uh, the wedding's only
three weeks away.
We haven't given him
a song list.
What was she pushing?
The drug rep.
Oh, just some
calcium channel blocker.
Um, so about the DJ...
It's Maggie.
Yeah, me too.
Father and daughter
hit-and-run victims.
This is Abigail Jones,
two years old.
GCS 9, blunt head trauma
with lacerations.
IO line in the left leg.
Abigail, it's gonna be okay.
Where's the father?
En route.
Other ambo was trying
to get an airway
when we rolled away
from the scene.
They were in crosswalk.
They had the signal.
Car plowed
right through them.
Let's transfer on my count.
One, two, three.
Abigail? Abigail?
She's unresponsive.
I need to intubate.
Broselow tape.
And a chest X-ray.
Just about 12 to 14 kilos.
Yellow drawer.
4 of etomidate, 20 of sux.
BP 100 over 70.
Heart rate 136.
Sats 88.
X-rays in place.
Nat, tell us when.
All right, I'm in.
Go.
Clear.
Right side's
whited out.
Chest tube.
Ultrasound.
Sats down to 80.
FAST scan's negative.
No blood in the belly.
Tube's in.
Sats coming back up. 100%.
BP and heart rate
stabilizing as well.
Pupils are reactive,
but sluggish.
Heads up,
paramedics are coming in
with the father right now.
You go take him.
I'll finish this.
Marc Jones, 32.
GCS 3,
intubated in the field.
Suspected C-spine injury.
There's a step off
on the back of his neck.
All right. Let's transfer him.
One, two, three.
Thank you, Cesar.
Yep.
Good breath sounds
bilaterally.
BP 88 over 58.
Heart rate 120.
Should we start a neo bag?
Yes, titrate
to a pressure of 110.
Need a chest X-ray
and an ultrasound.
Yep.
Oh, my God.
Dr. Halstead.
Hold on.
How's the little girl?
Her vitals are stable
and no long bone fractures.
But CT head shows diffuse
intraparenchymal bleeding.
And what did neuro say?
I just got off
the phone with them.
They put in
a pressure monitor,
and they agreed with me
to treat with
hyperventilation
and mannitol
to reduce
the intracranial pressure.
And what about the father?
Intubated but unresponsive
without sedation.
So, a brain injury?
I'm not sure.
Pupils are
equal and reactive,
so that's a good sign.
We're just waiting
on scan results to see
how bad the injuries are.
Look, Marc's stable now,
but what if he goes downhill?
He's wearing a lot of ink.
Is this "Do No Resuscitate"
a legit advance directive?
The hospital's got
a team of lawyers trying
to figure that out.
What about his family?
Do they know
if he meant it or not?
We're looking for them too.
It seems it's just Mr. Jones
and his daughter, Abigail,
in the world.
He had on a wedding ring.
There's no wife?
There was, Melinda.
Legal found an obituary.
She died last year.
Ovarian cancer.
If his wife had to be
intubated and wasn't able
to get off the vent,
seeing her like that could be
why he got that tattoo.
Yeah, maybe that's what
he was feeling then,
but what about now?
He's all Abigail has.
I can't see him not wanting us
to do everything in our power
to keep him alive for her.
Well, the truth is,
we don't know why
Mr. Jones got the tattoo
or how he feels
about it now.
So, let's not jump
to conclusions until
we have real facts.
And in the meantime?
While the hospital
does their due diligence,
err on the side of life.
Thank you.
Keegan and I
have been neighbors
for a few months.
Since I moved back.
I'm only here
'cause Vicki
talked me into it.
At this point,
I've given up on doctors.
No, no, no.
No more scratching.
I can't help it.
It's been three years.
Three years. Never stops.
And it started with
a MRSA infection?
The antibiotics to treat it.
Linezolid. Side effect
was pruritus.
Bad itch, huh?
Mmm. The worst.
Everywhere.
And I mean everywhere.
But the reaction went away
when she stopped
taking the pills.
Except for right here,
and it is killing me
not to scratch it right now.
The itch never lets up?
In the shower?
When you're sleeping?
Never.
I've used toothbrushes,
pencils, even steel wool once.
Nothing stops the itch.
Easy, Keegan. Keegan.
Stop, stop, stop, stop.
I know it's hard.
Just try not to scratch.
All right,
I'm gonna clean it out
and apply some steroid cream.
Should help calm it down.
That won't do anything.
I've tried creams
and antihistamines,
acupuncture.
I've seen dozens of doctors,
dermatologists, allergists.
Nothing helps.
I just can't stop.
Don't. Don't. Don't. Don't.
Doesn't that hurt?
All I feel is the itch.
It's all day, every day.
Please just find it
and cut it out.
Okay.
Let's get a full set of labs
and go from there.
I'll be back with the results.
No more scratching.
Thank you.
I've never seen
anything like this.
She's down to the muscle.
And she was serious
about trying everything.
I looked inside her medicine
cabinet, it's like a pharmacy.
I tried to help her,
but she didn't serve,
so I can't bring her
to the VA.
How much do you know about
Keegan outside of the itch?
Is she...
Crazy?
I don't think so,
but an itch
for three years...
Yeah.
I'm gonna get psych involved.
Thanks for bringing her in.
Thanks.
Yeah.
So, Vicki's here.
She just brought in a patient.
This is the only
hospital in Chicago?
You trying to
tell me something?
No.
Okay.
April, I appreciate you
covering for me
every time I'm in
the Hybrid OR.
Of course I don't expect you
to know everything
that I've learned,
so I made
a reference guide for you.
Well, I haven't had
any problems.
Well, not yet,
but it's good to be prepared.
"Obligations and Proficiencies
of the Charge Nurse."
People don't realize
how complex the job can be.
How many pages
is this thing?
Is there a PowerPoint
presentation to go with it?
Is that gonna be a problem?
No problem.
Vicki brought in
the patient.
Vicki. Your, uh...
Your friend, Vicki?
Former friend.
Yeah.
Keegan. I'm Dr. Charles.
How you doing?
Of course. The shrink.
Look, this isn't because of
feelings and it's not OCD.
I don't have
delusional parasitosis
or a conversion disorder.
And the itching didn't start
after my dad died
or my boyfriend left me.
Look, I'm not insane.
My head just itches
and I want it to stop.
Okay.
Well, um, let's try
to make that happen.
Really?
Usually docs are writing me
a referral, so I'll leave.
Well, you came to us for help,
so we're gonna help you.
Just for now, though,
do you think you can keep
your hand away from the wound?
I can't help it.
Okay.
So Dr. Choi told me
that you've tried OTCs,
prescriptions,
host of home remedies.
Mmm.
How about bupivacaine?
What's that?
A local anesthetic.
5 mil should do it.
I'd like to apply
a little bit to the area.
If it provides relief,
it would suggest
that the problem
might lie in your
cutaneous nerve endings.
And that would help
suggest a treatment plan
going forward.
Then stop talking
and get to it.
You're gonna
feel a pinch.
Do it.
Whoa.
Okay.
It feels different.
Different how?
Better.
I mean, it tingles a little,
but it itches less.
Hmm. It's a good start.
Yeah.
We'll check on you
in a bit.
So, anesthetic should
provide relief for like,
three or four hours.
Itch doesn't come back,
then set her up with some
topical patches to take home.
Sounds good.
Mannequins?
Look, I was
a department store
latchkey kid.
So, I took
what I could get.
Jenny was basically
my first girlfriend.
Which is why I am
such a good kisser.
I don't think I know
how to feel about this.
On the one hand,
it's very disturbing.
On the other, I should
probably be thanking Jenny
for those, uh...
For those years of practice.
Hold on. It wasn't
years, okay?
Dr. Rhodes,
was looking for you.
I wanted to tell you
before you got the memo.
The Hybrid Room
will be used
for general surgeries
when needed.
General surgeries?
Appendectomies,
gallbladders...
So, everything but trauma,
which is why we built it
in the first place.
Look, the Hybrid Room
was expensive.
It came in over budget.
Using it when we can
will help balance the books.
You mean, pad them?
Well, profit's
not a bad thing.
Ms. Goodwin,
this is Chicago.
We get six traumas
before lunch.
What are those patients
supposed to do?
I don't know, take a number?
Well, your displeasure
is noted, Dr. Rhodes.
And overruled.
When does all this start?
Today.
In fact, Dr. Lanik
will take the lead.
This is a terrible idea.
It's gotta be Gwen Garrett.
Let it go. This isn't
a hill to die on.
Damn it!
Call Dr. Charles.
Keegan, stop.
Don't scratch.
Oh, the itch is back
and it's worse than before.
You have to stop scratching.
Then you have to tie me down.
5 milligrams of diazepam.
On it.
I can't live
like this anymore.
I'd rather be dead.
What happened?
Oh, God.
She scratched through
to her skull.
How's Abigail?
Fighting.
How's the dad?
Scans are back. CT brain
revealed no bleeding,
and there's no obvious
brain trauma.
Well, that's good news.
Yeah, except the CT C-spine
revealed a subluxation
at C3 and 4.
MRI confirmed?
Complete spinal cord
transection.
He's paralyzed
from the neck down.
I'm sorry.
I just spoke with Jay.
PD caught the driver
who hit them.
He blew through a red light
because he was texting.
BP's spiked, 146 over 94.
Heart rate's down, 54.
Cushing's Reflex.
Her intracranial pressure
is worsening.
She needs
more hyperventilation.
Get her off the vent.
Heart rate's still dropping.
47.
2 milligrams of atropine.
It's in.
Come on. Come on.
Heart rate's coming
back up. 49...
51...
Come on. Come on.
Come on, Abigail.
Dr. Rhodes,
you're going to Baghdad.
Yep. Talk to me.
James Brice, 24.
GCS 7. Hypotensive.
Intubated en route.
Belly's distended.
What happened?
He was putting in
storm windows
for the nursery.
He fell off the ladder.
At least 20 feet.
I was worried the baby
would be cold this winter.
It's okay. Don't worry.
It's not your fault. Maggie?
I got her.
Mrs. Brice, why don't you
come with me, and let the
doctors work, okay?
He keeps trying to die on us.
All right. On my count.
One, two, three.
Good breath sounds
on the left and the right.
Let's get a chest X-ray.
Field IV's blown.
We don't have access.
All right.
Ava, can you get a line in?
Give me a kit.
X-ray's up.
Everybody clear.
Looks good.
Belly's hard as a rock.
Give me a FAST scan.
It's full of blood.
I need to get in there
and find the bleed.
We'll use the Hybrid OR.
We can make it upstairs.
There are operating rooms
available.
There's also one
right across the ED.
Much closer.
Connor, Goodwin
just told you...
I know what she said.
Find Maggie. Have her
page my team.
It's probably CT
looking for you.
I got this.
You're going to
get yourself
into trouble.
I can't worry about that now.
Get James ready to go.
Lanik. I'm taking
the Hybrid OR.
My patient is on the table.
His gallbladder can wait.
Bring him back next week.
I'm not your resident, Connor.
You can't order me around.
Is your patient
about to die?
Because mine sure is.
Get Dr. Lanik's patient out
and re-prep the room for mine.
Natalie.
I just need a moment.
Yeah, of course.
All right. Thank you.
April, I'm getting
pulled into surgery.
Okay, I'll hold it
down out here.
Oh, and I've got a delivery
of NG tubes, Hep-Locks
and ABD pads coming in.
I called it in
late last night.
I'll double-check the order
against the invoice,
make sure it's all there.
All right.
Oh! And it's payroll week,
so it means that you have...
All the nurses
need to sign off
on their time cards.
Maggie, you're
driving me crazy.
If anything happens,
I'll handle it.
Okay, and you've got
the reference guide that
I wrote, so we're all good.
All good.
Good, good, good.
You want some company?
I get it if you'd
rather be alone.
No, I'm glad to see you.
How's Marc?
No change.
Still unconscious.
Abigail was only two.
And now she's gone.
All because some guy couldn't
look away from his phone.
But maybe something good
could come from all of this.
I mean, all these kids
waiting for transplants.
There are so few
pediatric donors
in comparison to the thousands
of children in need.
Abigail could be
an organ donor.
As a minor, you know,
she's gotta get a parent
or guardian to sign off
before she can donate.
Yeah, I know that.
And if Goodwin
can't track down
any of her other family,
then all that's left
is her father.
Do you think
Marc will wake up?
I've seen patients
in worse shape turn around.
Well, that's a new one.
Usually I have to
cut them open myself
to get to the brain.
So, what do you think?
Well, for whatever reason,
the cutaneous nerves
in that part
of her scalp
went haywire.
It makes them
always feel itchy,
so she keeps scratching.
There a fix?
Yeah, surgery.
Sever the nerve.
No more feeling,
no more itching.
And no more scratching.
Yeah, and possible serious,
irreversible side effects.
Facial paralysis,
blurred vision.
Worst case, she ends up
in a wheelchair.
I'm not cutting her open
in an alley, Daniel.
The risks you're describing
are dwarfed by the reward.
Yeah, we hope.
What do you suggest?
Twice-a-week
counseling sessions?
Of course, we'd have to put
a cone around her neck
to keep her from scratching.
Sam, all those
years of scratching,
those nerves are shot.
There's nothing left
to go haywire.
Dr. Charles, if that
were the case,
Keegan shouldn't
feel anything.
Let alone an itch.
If those nerves were active,
that anesthetic would've
provided relief for hours.
It didn't.
You only used 5 mil.
It wasn't enough.
I agree.
The anesthetic didn't work
for long, but it did work.
Proves the nerves
are involved.
Great, we have a majority.
Not that I care.
We done?
Sam?
All I'm saying,
I don't think
operating is gonna do
a damn thing.
Thanks
for your input.
But the last time I checked,
I was the neurosurgeon.
Put her on the schedule.
Isn't surgery supposed to be
the last option?
Dr. Charles, she scratched
into her skull.
What happened?
He suddenly went into v-fib.
Shocked him multiple times
and then he went asystolic.
Another round of epi.
It's in.
Check for a pulse.
Nothing.
Come on, Marc.
Don't you give up.
Pulse is back. Sinus tach.
He's back.
All right.
Prep him to move.
I'll call ICU,
tell them we're
sending him up
for cooling.
How long was he asystole?
Almost 10 minutes.
What's your
boyfriend thinking?
This guy's not waking up.
Hey, is your ulcer
getting worse?
Today's not helping.
Yeah.
So, I looked at
the paramedic's report
from the accident scene.
Marc was down
at least five minutes
before help arrived.
And after this last code
it was almost 10.
I mean, that's almost
15 minutes with no oxygen.
I know.
Increases the chances
the brain function he has
is now compromised.
But we won't know
if that's the case
until he wakes up.
You think he really will?
After he coded?
I don't know.
Maybe it's time to start
thinking about honoring
his advance directive.
Advance directive?
Nat, it is a tattoo,
not a legal document.
It might be
a proxy to one.
And what if Marc does have
the paperwork to back it up?
I mean, it could be
at home in a file
or in a safety deposit box.
If something binding exists,
the hospital's lawyers
will find it,
and I'll obey
whatever it says.
But until then, it's just
a tattoo, and one of many.
Will, Abigail's organs
are still healthy.
But they won't be
viable for long.
Without Marc or any family to
consent, we can't donate them.
But if we honor his tattoo
and we let him go,
then the hospital
can petition to become
Abigail's legal guardian,
and we can make the decision
to donate her organs
before they go to waste.
Natalie, you are asking me
to let Marc die.
I can't do that.
Well, if by some miracle
he does wake up, it'll be
to brain damage, paralysis,
and the loss of his daughter.
So, please
help me understand
why you won't
even consider this.
I have a responsibility
to my patients
to do everything I can
to save their lives.
Anything less,
then I am failing them.
Okay.
He's losing blood faster
than I can replace it.
Massive bleed from
behind the liver.
There must be a hole
in the vena cava.
Long Allis clamps.
Damn it,
this isn't working.
I can't reach the tear
without making it worse.
All right, Maggie,
get your hands in here.
Push on these packs.
Press hard. All right.
That'll buy us some time.
Call Dr. Lanik,
get him in here.
I don't care
what he's doing.
Just make sure
he's scrubbed up
and ready to work.
Give me an 8 ET tube
and a sternal saw.
Sternotomy? You're gonna
open up his chest?
I gotta get
to the bleed somehow.
Hey, got your page.
Come on in.
Dr. Abrams is in
surgery right now.
As soon as he's done,
Keegan's next.
Uh-huh.
What's all this?
It's an experiment.
For what?
Well, you don't think that
Keegan can experience her itch
without cutaneous nerves.
And I do. I think
I can prove it.
Have a seat.
Okay.
So, can you take
your left arm
and put it on the other side
of the partition here?
Thank you.
So, is this
like a magic trick?
Yeah, kind of.
Okay, so I'm gonna start
to brush your real hand
and the fake hand
simultaneously.
But I just want you to look
at the fake hand.
Okay?
Whatever you say.
So, amputees sometimes
still feel the missing limb,
right?
Yeah. A phantom limb.
The nerves are transmitting
confusing signals.
Or do amputees still feel
missing limbs
because the brain
is just assuming that
it's still there?
'Cause if that
were the case,
the nerves
would be irrelevant.
Right?
So, you're suggesting
Keegan's got a phantom itch?
Her brain
is telling her it's there,
even though it isn't?
Yeah.
Just like amputees perceive
a limb that used to be there.
Keegan still perceives an itch
that she got three years ago
from a drug reaction.
I mean, the brain's basically
playing a trick on her.
Interesting theory.
Where are you going
with all this?
That's not your hand. Right?
But the more you stare at it,
while feeling me brush
your real hand,
the more your brain
might start to
blend them together.
Well, I guess I can buy that.
Yeah.
Very powerful,
the connection between
what we see
and what we feel.
But, Dr. Charles, I still know
which one's my arm.
Huh.
Do you?
Uh, for a second there...
You felt the hammer.
Yeah, I did.
Yeah.
Well, and we both know
there aren't any nerve endings
in this thing, right?
Amazing the tricks
the brain can play on us.
Keegan. Keegan, wait.
I've changed my mind.
I don't think you should
have surgery just yet.
Oh, here we go.
What crazy idea
has Dr. Charles
talked you into?
It may not be
a nerve problem.
It could be
a perception problem.
In fact, I'm not sure
your itch is real.
Not real?
Are you two serious?
Look at me.
I have to be tied to the bed
so I don't scratch
a bigger hole in my head.
If surgery will work,
I have to do it.
But what if it doesn't?
What if you wake up
and nothing's changed?
It has to work.
Because I can't live
like this anymore.
I want my life back.
Surgery will give it to you.
All right, let's go.
Wait, Keegan. Wait, wait.
The brain can change
in response to experience.
It's called neuroplasticity.
Three years ago,
a drug reaction
created a chronic itch
that you can't
seem to satisfy,
because it rewired your brain.
No surgery is gonna
fix that. Trust me.
Daniel.
Please. Please, Keegan.
Let me try something before
you go under the knife.
It's been three years.
What can you do for me that
no other doctor has tried?
A trick.
What the hell's going on?
I was told you needed help
with a liver bleed.
Retrohepatic cava tear.
Can't fix anything
until I control the bleed.
I'm gonna do that
with an atrial caval shunt.
You gotta be kidding.
Nope, I'm gonna snake
an ET tube down his heart
and bypass the tear.
What, you couldn't think
of a riskier move?
Atrial caval shunts have
an abysmal success rate.
Yep, I'm aware.
Then you also know that he's
cold and coagulopathic.
So, if you don't pack him up,
and get him up to the ICU
to be warmed,
he's gonna die here
on this table.
At least
this gives him a shot.
If we send him up
to the ICU,
he bleeds out
and dies for sure.
Scissors and ET tube.
If you cut into that heart,
there is no going back.
Yeah, I know.
Don't do it.
God damn it.
You kick me out of here
only to force me
to help you kill this guy.
You're a prick, Rhodes.
If her father
doesn't wake up,
what happens
to Abigail's organs?
They're no good to anyone.
Ms. Goodwin, can I speak
to you about something?
Could've driven a truck
through this hole.
He never would have
survived in the ICU.
It's the right call.
Don't act like you didn't
get lucky as hell.
Let's finish this up.
What do I do?
I don't know how long
I can go without scratching.
Okay.
I want you to look
at your reflection
and scratch the non-itchy
side of your head.
In the mirror, the image
is gonna be reversed.
It's gonna look like
you're actually scratching
the itchy side.
Oh, I see it.
But how is scratching
this side of my head
gonna make the itch go away
on the other side?
Keegan, trust me.
We know that you've been
feeling this thing.
But I just want you to
consider the possibility
that maybe,
just maybe that
this itch isn't real.
And no amount of scratching
is gonna satisfy it.
Well, then what the hell
am I doing?
Giving your brain
new visual input
to the override the experience
you had three years ago,
so it can begin
to rewire itself.
Okay, you're losing me.
By feeling yourself
scratch one side of your head
while you're seeing yourself
scratch the other,
your brain'll be tricked.
It'll realize
something's not right.
Now, hopefully,
that experience will force you
to perceive a new reality.
A reality in which
the itch doesn't exist.
So you say,
but nothing's changing.
And I feel stupid.
The exercise is designed
to confuse your brain,
so don't worry about that.
Just keep scratching.
Like this?
Harder? Softer?
Just like you're doing.
Be patient.
Good. Give it a chance.
Keegan, we'll be
just outside.
You're doing great.
How long are we gonna
let her keep scratching?
She's been dealing with this
for, what, three years?
I mean, honestly, Ethan,
I don't know how long
it might take.
If it takes.
The phantom itch theory
makes sense,
but it's still just a theory.
I just really don't wanna
give her any false hope.
Dr. Charles.
Something's
definitely happening.
The itch is less.
Okay.
All right,
I'll be back in five.
I'm gonna run these over
to sterile processing.
Hey. Have you seen April?
I wanted to
check in on her.
Nope.
She's probably putting out
a fire somewhere.
That girl is on it.
So, things went well
while I was in surgery?
Yeah, didn't even realize
you were gone.
Oh.
That's great.
Yeah.
Dr. Halstead,
could I have a moment?
Of course.
An emergency ethics committee
was formed to evaluate
Marc Jones' current condition
and future prognosis.
Wait, "was formed"?
Who asked for that?
Between his spinal cord injury
and his high probability
for irreparable brain damage,
the committee concluded
with reasonable
medical certainty
that he has
no quality of life.
No.
Listen, the hospital
will honor
Mr. Jones's tattoo
as an advance directive.
If he codes again,
you will not resuscitate.
I cannot just walk away.
I'm sorry,
but it's over,
Dr. Halstead.
I wanna talk to you.
An emergency
ethics committee?
What, I don't bow down to
your decision on my patient,
so you go over me
to Goodwin and bench me?
You forced my hand.
I tried talking to you.
You shut me down.
Because you'd already decided
Marc should die.
He has a tattoo
across his chest that says,
"Do Not Resuscitate."
We don't know
that's how he feels.
We don't know he doesn't.
But what I do know is that
if we don't act now,
we will lose
Abigail's organs.
Those are children's lives
in our hands.
No, don't turn this on me.
Don't guilt me into thinking
that I'm the bad guy.
You don't think I know
the stakes of this case?
I am sick of everyone
telling me what I can
and what I cannot do.
I am just trying
to save my patients.
What are you talking about?
Who is everyone?
You betrayed me.
How can I ever trust you?
How can I trust you?
In the past, you have let
patients go who you knew
were hopeless.
But you know what?
It is more than that.
No, look at me.
You have been
acting strange for weeks.
And this morning,
that ridiculous story
about a drug rep, really?
Well then, here we are.
And about to get married.
Maggie.
Yep.
Thanks for approving my PTO
for next month.
I didn't think there was a way
to make it happen.
Oh, yeah. Sure.
April.
Did you sign off on Monique's
paid time off for next month?
Yeah.
Saw her request had been
siting there for three weeks.
I hate it when I put in
for vacation times
and nothing happens.
It takes a long time
because someone's always
asking for PTO.
Especially Monique. She took
eight days off last month.
Well, her sister is pregnant,
on bed rest and needs help.
So, how could I say no?
What?
Lisa.
I'm talking to you.
I have a system
for handling PTOs.
You can't take time off
if you're out of vacation.
Monique was out.
Doris gave her
some of hers.
Oh, my God.
You let them swap?
Doris said she wasn't
gonna use them.
No sense letting them
gather dust.
You know what's
gonna happen now?
I'm gonna get hammered
with requests from nurses
who wanna swap days.
Thanks a lot.
You know what?
You don't like the way
I handle things when
I'm doing you a favor...
A favor?
This is a privilege.
Give your privilege
to someone else.
Time of death, 19:22.
There, he's gone.
You won.
I was about to give up,
but then there was
this moment.
Look at me,
I'm not scratching.
I am so happy for you.
Dr. Choi, I can keep
these mirrors, right?
It's so much better.
Of course. And keep it up.
Over time, the itch should
fade away completely.
Excuse me.
Dr. Charles,
surgery would have
been a mistake.
Good call steering her away.
Yeah, but, you know,
I certainly understood
her desperation for relief.
Do you know that,
scientifically,
itching is ranked
as one of the most
distressing sensations
a human being
can experience?
Really?
You know what, Dr. Charles,
maybe it's not a good idea,
but some itches
you just have to scratch.
Vicki. Hey.
What do you say
we go for a run?
Like old times?
Sure. Call me sometime.
My shift's over.
How about now?
Okay. Let's do it.
Okay, look, my way
isn't the only way.
You're doing a good job.
Thanks.
And I confess, it sucks
when you realize that
you can be replaced.
Yeah, I know.
Oh.
Wanna get a drink?
Maybe two?
Yeah.
Sam.
You'll be happy to hear that
Keegan's feeling much better.
Your smoke and mirrors?
Temporary fix.
She'll be back here
in six weeks
to get that surgery.
Well, that's the way
you see it, I, uh...
I guess I see it
a little differently.
Until next time, Daniel.
Good night.
An atrial caval shunt.
My cowboy.
Dr. Rhodes.
Three operating rooms
upstairs were open.
You could have
treated your patient
in any one of them.
Maybe, but I didn't want to
risk him dying in transit.
That is why
we have a Hybrid OR.
The gallbladder surgery
you interrupted,
I'm rescheduling it
for tomorrow.
In the Hybrid OR.
Ms. Goodwin, this idea
to repurpose my room
is misguided and reckless.
Your room?
Well, the board is considering
closing your room
unless it starts
proving its worth.
That's why I'm gonna make sure
it is always earning money.
Great. Then I'm gonna keep
fighting back, because I'm not
gonna let Gwen Garrett
turn the Hybrid OR
into an ATM.
Gwen Garrett has nothing
to do with this.
I decided to put
general surgeries in there.
So, you pull
this little stunt again,
and I'll show you the door.
I don't care what she says.
I saved his life.
I'd do it again.
Come here.
We're a lot alike,
you know.
You'd do anything
to get what you want.
You're that bad, huh?
I'm that bad.
Abigail's organs
are off to recipients.
That's good.
Maybe you want this back?
No, I don't.
Natalie, I wanna marry you.