- Oh, God!
- LOC on scene.
But awake when we got
there with a GCS of 13.
What have you got?
17-year-old. Auto versus
multiple peds at a high school.
Facial fracture, abdominal pain,
sounds like she dropped a lung.
BP, 110/70, tachy
after one liter.
- Her name's Gayla Ray.
- Break out epistaxis tray, page Trauma.
Do you have any medical
problems we need to know about?
- That's a yes.
- Is this the full-arrest crush injury?
Pinned between a car and wall.
Kids got nailed on the steps at school.
- Drunk driver?
- Worse.
16-year-old got
a driver's license.
Still no pulse.
- Resume CPR.
- You tube her in the field?
She's anterior. I
had to scoop and run.
Car versus pedestrian,
steel wins every time.
- Chest full of sub-q air.
- Thoracotomy?
Tube in every hole and pronounce.
Since Pratt's wearing a tie this morning...
- let him needle the pericardium.
- She's young. She might convert.
And there might be a new Hyundai
behind door number 1, but more likely...
- it's 50 cases of elbow macaroni.
- Vaseline gauze.
I'll give you $200 if you've
got a surgical candidate.
ENT, Ortho, and general
to start. Let's turn her.
I can't breathe.
Gayla, don't try and swallow,
okay? We'll get that blood out for you.
I'm scared. ROMANO: Don't be.
I never let anything happen
to pretty girls like you.
Tachy at 120. BP's 100 systolic.
Frazier-tip suction
for the nose.
Zygoma is mobile.
- It looks like a LeFort three.
- It hurts when I press here?
We need to operate on
your belly, but you'll be fine.
Robert, have a minute
to speak privately?
I've got a girl losing blood by
the pint. But sure, what the hell.
Call and tell Maser
we have a hot e-lap.
- You think posterior bleed?
- Place to start.
- Left you a number of messages.
- Cefotetan.
Make sure the blood
bank gets a clot.
You were sent a memo.
She stable enough for CT?
- Tachycardic and hypotensive.
- Let's get this little minx upstairs.
- I'll take her.
- What are you doing?
Based on your fine assessment, an
e-lap. Have a surgical residents scrub in.
- I did for Dr. Romano.
- Even though he has no O.R. privileges?
- I'm a supervising Attending.
- On operations you can perform yourself.
- What are you saying? I can't scrub in?
- I'm saying read my memo.
Now let's get this
young lady to the O.R.
Oh, and congratulations, Kerry.
No one deserves it more.
If you can't vote, you
shouldn't be able to drive.
- I got my license the minute I turned 16.
- You were never a "teenager" teenager.
You were responsible.
I was a total idiot.
All I cared about was
finding a boyfriend.
Mm. Nothing like now, right?
Do you think Carter can
cover the last hour of my shift?
- He's leaving for Belize.
- Ah. The scuba thing.
Mm-hm. A week of fun in the sun.
Yeah, while you get
stuck here in the rain.
But all of his diving buddies are
nitrox certified, whatever that means.
And I can barely snorkel.
- Still.
- Do you have a date or something?
Friend set me up with some guy.
Blind date.
It just proves that some of us
never really leave high school.
Sasha Melman, 16, bilateral femur
fractures. Amazing she's not worse.
Books, shoes, blood everywhere.
- It hurts so much!
- Sasha, I'm Dr. Lewis.
Can you wiggle your toes for me?
- I don't think I can.
- Good popliteal pulses.
- Okay. Page Ortho.
A gram of Ancef, 300 of gent.
- My friends okay?
- Yes. We're helping them.
Helen Broznich. Limping at the scene.
No LOC, no chest or abdominal injuries.
- Any ETOH or drugs on board?
- She denies both, but she's agitated.
- Thing's choking me.
- This the driver?
Helen, I'm Dr. Weaver.
Where are you hurt?
Everywhere, all the time.
- What's open?
- Trauma 2.
- Come on, damn it.
- Still agonal.
Try Isuprel, wide open.
What's going on? You completed
the P.E.A. algorithms 10 minutes ago.
- We wanna give her a little longer.
- You gave her longer. Call it, or I will.
Oh, sorry. I thought
the room was clear.
- Is she dead?
- Get Helen to another room for now.
That's Terri. Is she dead?
- Gallant.
I thought I hit the brakes.
Time of death, 11:29.
Hmp. What do you figure
this cost the taxpayers?
"Kerry, congrats to
the best doc in Chicago.
- Alderman Bright."
- Think he's trying to get her...
to change teams or what?
My guess? "Or what."
Hmm.
I can pick up a bottle of this
stuff for us tonight if you want.
That stuff is about
200 bucks a pop.
- Well, I guess you're buying then.
- Ha-ha-ha.
Dispo'd Mr. Pagini.
Waiting on a bed on Mrs.
Golove. Mary Galloway is up in CT.
I'm off to the second largest
barrier reef in the world.
- Bring Dramamine.
- And repellent.
They got mosquitoes the
size of eagles in Belize.
- Not to mention pirates.
- So Deb?
- Hmm?
- You and Pratt, huh?
Yeah, I guess.
- You guess?
- Well, we're not exclusive or anything...
- ER. Maggie. Let me check.
- We're just kind of casually attached.
Frank, we hear anything from
OB about a bed for Kim Cohen?
No. But I got your
mom on line one.
- Abby, line one.
- Yeah. I'm on my way out.
- Can you take a message?
- You mean another one?
- Maggie called?
- Twice.
- Why?
- I don't know.
She wants to talk to me, make
it up, be a family, whatever.
- You're not interested in doing that?
- No. Not really.
If you're mad at your mom, you
should tell her. Don't just ignore her.
Okay, thanks.
I took a split shift so
I could see you off.
- My flight's not for hours.
- I know.
- Did you see the car coming?
- Mm-mm.
Two-inch scalp lac,
GCS 15, no LOC.
I was gonna throw in a 5-0
nylon and give her a head sheet.
- Did you hear the brakes?
- Switch to Prolene.
Blue stitches are
easier to find for removal.
- Any other minor injuries in the accident?
- Just the driver in Curtain 3.
Bad ankle. She lost
control of her car.
Dr. Lewis, this one's got a clotted
PICC line. Can you take him?
Sure. Give me a
couple minutes, okay?
16 years old with stable lateral
malleolus fracture and multiple abrasions.
- Blood alcohol and tox screen?
- First thing I checked. Came back clean.
- Head CT's negative...
- She's concussed?
Well, it's hard to tell.
- Hi, I'm Dr. Lewis.
- I remember you.
Says she was here last week,
got diagnosed with hepatitis.
Oh, yeah, right. So, Helen,
what happened today?
There were these squirrels at
my school. I saw them in the road.
- And you swerved?
- Squirrels are rabies carriers.
So are raccoons.
Is my dad here yet?
We'll go check, okay?
She's not jaundiced enough
for hepatic encephalopathy.
Yeah. She'd be
altered, not just weird.
Dr. Lewis, your
blind date called.
The restaurant you
picked doesn't work for him.
- Oh, for God's sake.
- He wants you to call him and regroup.
- Hey, you choose someplace exotic?
- Yeah. A steak house.
So Keener's thyroidectomy will
now be supervised by Dr. Corday.
- Correct.
- What about Jocelyn Gaines' Billroth II?
Push it if possible. I'm buried
in administrative backwash.
- If not?
- Anspaugh will take it.
Robert. ROMANO: Kerry.
- There's gonna be a press conference.
- I wouldn't miss it for the world.
I know you wanted the position. I
just wanted to check and make sure...
- you were feeling okay about all this.
- Well, how am I feeling?
Pretty damn grateful, actually.
I've got a good heart, good soul...
and, unlike our new
liaison, two good legs.
Dr. Weaver, we're ready for you.
Ask yourself what you
did to deserve this, Kerry.
- A lot of hard work, actually.
- And what the alderman wants in return.
He doesn't want anything.
Not everyone's an
opportunistic asshole like you.
Yeah. So I'm told.
- Still okay with me going?
- Yeah. I said I was.
You meant it?
What are you thinking?
Nothing.
- Work?
- No.
- Your mom?
- God, no.
- Go on, tell me.
- It's a song.
- Oh, yeah? Which one?
- Mm-hm.
From the '70s.
- It's goofy.
- "Blinded by the Light."
- No.
- "Love Will Keep Us Together."
- What?
No.
Something, something.
You done?
Oh, no. Please
don't. Please don't.
- You want to get that?
- No.
It's an utterly
thankless position.
No money, endless
paperwork, countless meetings.
But it still remains
a great honor.
Therefore, on behalf of the
board of commissioners...
I am proud and privileged to name
Dr. Kerry Weaver as medical liaison...
to Cook County's public
healthcare administration.
Thank you, alderman. I couldn't
have accepted this position...
without the continued support
of my colleagues here at County.
Dr. Weaver, how are you
qualified for this office?
You mean can a
nonpolicy wonk do the job?
Uh... Well, running a trauma center is
perhaps the ultimate training ground...
for public healthcare, and
we are in a healthcare crisis.
This position allows me the
opportunity to apply practical solutions...
to problems that have been dealt
with all too bureaucratically in the past.
Are there any other questions?
How will balancing two demanding
jobs affect your home life?
It won't.
She's single. So am I.
We make a handsome
couple, don't you think?
- Congratulations, Dr. Weaver.
- Thank you.
I reached Helen
Broznich's father.
- No chicken either, huh?
- I'll come back.
Really. They actually fry tofu.
Okay. Well, I'll see
you tonight at 7. Bye.
Your date's a vegetarian?
No, a vegan, whatever
the hell that means.
Nothing with a face.
No meat, no eggs, no dairy.
Oh. Oh, you're the
guy with the PICC line.
Sean.
- Need a doc over here!
- Oh, got to go. You want these?
Wilma Rasmussen, 94 years
old with altered mental status.
- BP 85/60.
- That's pretty low. Pneumonia?
She's had that
before. This is different.
- Her daughter.
- She live with you?
No. I live with her.
Hey, save some Donnatal for me.
Cut it out.
- What? I just need two tabs.
- Oh. Sorry.
No. Actually, I'm the one
who should be apologizing.
I was out of line earlier.
This is work. And the last thing
you need to deal with is gossip.
I get that and I respect it.
You do?
Yes, I'm the same way.
Hey, Pratt. You have a patient
waiting for you in Curtain 1.
I'll be right there.
So are you two
gonna get engaged?
No. Not even close.
I don't know about that.
Pratt's been acting all in love.
Dizzy, weak, lightheaded.
Classic symptoms
of a low blood count.
Tinnitus, palpitations...
Drove my wife nuts over it.
She divorced me because of it.
Trouble is you
don't look anemic.
Yeah, but in pernicious
anemia, symptoms may occur...
even in the absence
of a low hemoglobin.
Trust me on this, doc. If I don't get a
shot soon, it's gonna get a lot worse.
- You've been taking B12.
- Up until two months ago.
I went to see my doc in '86
because I was feeling really run-down.
My doc made the diagnosis.
Since then I've been feeling real fit...
as long as I stay regular on it.
The bastard died
on me a month ago.
My doctor. That's why I'm here.
- For your B12 fix.
- I take up to 100 micrograms a month.
I think since it's been so long, I should
take half a milligram. I'm way overdue.
I'll need to check out a few
things before prescribing anything.
Save yourself the trouble.
"Victims of Pernicious Anemia"?
You're looking at the president.
- What do you think it is?
- Your mom has a kidney infection.
- Does that explain why she's so groggy?
- Possibly. She has other health problems.
Haleh, can you send this up
for culture? And 500 of Levaquin.
Start her on dopamine
at five mics per kilo.
- Well, that sounds serious.
- At 94, everything's serious.
Our friends were brought here.
There was an accident at our school.
- What are their names?
- Terri, Sasha, and Janey.
- And Lissa got hurt too.
- Can we see them?
Excuse me. We can only give that
sort of information out to relatives.
But they're our best friends.
Have your parents call the school,
and they'll update you on everything.
- Was it that bad?
- Did they die?
- Oh, God. We totally cut class today.
- I can only give information out to...
Was she there? Did
she see this happen?
Hey, you can't go in there.
Helen, you have to
tell us what happened.
- Why are you asking me?
- Who all got hurt?
- You don't even know me.
- Forget her. She's a freak.
Let's call my mom. She's
friends with the principal.
They're popular.
- You did good, kid.
- You think?
I only wish I'd fallen off
a stage two years ago.
Would've kept us from appointing
your god-awful predecessor.
Still having trouble with that?
Kennedy had chronic back
pain and ran the country.
The least I can do is
tolerate a bum knee.
You know what? Let me write you a
prescription for some more Vicodin.
- That's all right.
- Don't be ridiculous.
Why suffer if you don't have to?
- Touch base later this week?
- Look forward to it.
Don't put your pen away. I need
another signature for a subdural.
So congratulations on your
appointment, by the way.
- Thank you.
- So, what is it?
- A county committee type thing?
- Something like that.
Well, if you can get us two
more nurses a shift, I'm all for it.
- Still no word from Dr. Kovac?
- Nope.
- And you tried calling him again?
- Yes, ma'am.
This is Luka. Leave a message.
Yeah, Luka. This
is Kerry Weaver.
I'm down two Attendings
and up 40 patients.
If you don't start working
your scheduled shifts...
I'm gonna call the INS, tell
them your green card's a fake...
and have your ass deported.
You'll need longer arms if
you're treating her from here.
- Why haven't you cleared her?
- She needs a posterior splint.
Hold on. Look, we're
buried here, Gallant.
- I realize that...
- If you and your Attending can't handle...
a simple ankle fracture,
I'll do it. Now, clear the bed.
Where do you want it?
The lounge. I don't
wanna be disturbed.
- What'd I miss?
- Two more messages from your mother.
- She says it's important that you call.
- Right.
- Carter get off okay?
- Yes, he did.
Mm. Five Sigma Nu's loose in Belize.
I hope they brought a lot of bail money.
I have friends on the P.D. who can
run a background check on your date.
- Already checked. No arrests.
- Or he hasn't been caught yet.
Aren't you the optimistic one.
- You don't have plans tonight, do you?
- Excuse me?
Carter's off with the boys.
It'd be fun. Dinner and drinks.
Don't let her talk you
into being her chaperone.
- How's everyone know about my date?
- You told them.
I got a lady won't get out
of my cab. I need a doctor.
- Where's she hurt?
- I don't know. She ain't moving.
Know her name?
Yeah, she showed her birth
certificate before I picked her up.
Ma'am? Ma'am, wake up!
She's been beaten up. Come
on. Open your eyes for us.
She's got a weak radial pulse.
There's blood on her hands.
Ma'am, can you tell
us what happened?
Oh, wow. CHEN: Oh.
Come on, let's go! Let's go!
I'm not gonna get paid, am I?
- No hemotympanum.
- Systolic's 120 after the first liter.
This may burn a little.
- I'm just numbing up your belly.
- Do you know who did this to you?
- Kids.
- Kids?
I need to pick my
kids up from school.
We can have them brought here.
We need to know your name first.
Monica Walker.
Monica, we have to figure
out if you'll need surgery.
Gotta go. CHEN: No, no.
You have to talk
to the police later.
No. Can't do that. Please.
Somebody beat you pretty badly.
- It's okay.
She owes me 11 bucks and
change. Check the bra for cash.
- What?
- She's a hooker. It's where they keep it.
Hey, get the hell out
of here. Now. Out! Out!
- What have we got?
- Penetrating abdominal injury...
- of uncertain depth. And these are?
- Three lab-coated tumors.
- You're teaching?
- This is a teaching hospital.
- Good bowel sounds, normotensive.
- Can you tell how long the knife was?
You collect box tops to get into med
school? You didn't get in on your IQ.
Help me retract here. - Okay.
Only into the sub-q. But there could
be an intraperitoneal component.
Deep fascia's intact. Gram of
Ancef and update her tetanus.
- No surgery.
- That's right.
You boneheads in the
ER are gonna have to work.
Irrigate the wound, loose approximation,
and follow serial exam. Let's go.
Whose signature do I get for the chart?
- Excuse me?
For the official
surgical consult.
I'm head of surgery
and chief of staff.
That should do it. That way.
Turn left.
- I don't like to be touched.
- Dr. Weaver's almost finished.
- They'll hate me even more now.
- Who will?
Everyone at my school.
- Why? Because of what happened?
- Helen, what happened was tragic.
But it was an accident.
It was raining...
you lost control of your car.
- Who's your Attending on this?
- Dr. Lewis.
Get her.
Helen, do you ever have any
problems with rigid muscles or jerkiness?
I can be a real spaz sometimes.
You shouldn't be
so hard on yourself.
What is it, Kerry?
She has gold-colored
deposits on her cornea.
I don't like to be touched.
- Kayser-Fleischer rings.
- Pathognomonic for Wilson's disease.
- What's that?
- Your body may have an inability...
to excrete copper, so it
builds up in the liver and brain.
- Really?
- We need to run some tests to be sure.
But I'll be right back, okay?
- She was here a week ago?
- I treated her and released her.
- Did Gallant do an eye exam?
- Of course he did.
But Wilson's is a total
zebra to a med student.
- What's your excuse?
- The rings may not have been...
- as prominent last week.
- Okay, send off a serum ceruloplasmin...
and find me when
you get the results.
- She's having trouble breathing.
- Who?
Your old lady. Pulse ox
down to 82 on five liters.
- What's happening?
- Respiratory rate's up to 30.
The fluid we gave to raise her
blood pressure is going to her lungs.
So, what do you do?
Normally we use Lasix
and nitroglycerine...
- but they'd lower her pressure further.
- Oh, God.
I know you love your mother very
much, but you need to think about...
how aggressively
you wanna handle this.
You don't
understand. I need her.
- Of course you need her.
- No. I need her social security checks.
Another 4-0 nylon.
He was a regular.
Just went nuts on me.
- It might be time for a new profession.
- I gotta feed my kids.
How old are they?
Luke's 7, Christy's 12.
- They know what you do?
- No.
Don't need to.
I'm there when they leave for
school, there when they get back...
and I'm there till they
go to sleep at night.
Wait. You go out
after they're in bed?
Look, I'm not a junkie.
And I don't have a pimp.
I just work enough
to support my kids.
But they're home by themselves.
That was fast. MONICA:
I don't wanna talk to him.
They have to
document the assault.
I don't want to
talk to the police.
She doesn't want
to file a report.
- You Abby Lockhart?
- Yeah?
Officer Beechum, Chicago P.D.
- We were asked to come find you.
- Me?
Minneapolis P.D. reported that an aircraft
your brother was flying has disappeared.
Your mother asked
us to notify you.
- She was unable to reach you by phone.
- Okay.
Okay, what does that mean,
disappeared? Where was he?
Well, radar last picked him up
over Lake Superior 11 hours ago.
You can call the FAA up
there for more information.
I'm sorry.
Okay. Explain to me how
somebody just goes off radar.
What you're saying is you
think he went down. Right. Just...
What are the
other possibilities?
Okay, did you have any communications
from him? Like a mayday or whatever?
No.
Yes, I'm reachable here.
I thought he was an
air-traffic controller.
He always wanted to
fly. He just got his license.
Did you reach Carter?
I had him paged in Miami. I
guess the flight already took off.
- Does your mom know anything?
- I haven't called her.
Do you think you should?
I think I'm stressed
out enough as it is...
- without having to deal with her too.
- Yeah. You should go home.
Do people know?
About Eric? Some.
I'd rather they didn't.
- You should still go home.
- I'm gonna stay. Thanks.
Hold, please. Radiology needs
you to send Stewart back up.
- Film's bad.
- Abby, guy from the school district...
- dropped off Monica Walker's kids.
- Who?
- The hooker with the slashed belly.
- Okay.
Hi.
- I'll take you to see your mom now.
- Is my mom gonna be okay?
- Yeah, she is.
- Did she get mugged again?
Thanks anyway.
Her kids are here.
Go ahead. Go right in.
Hey, guys. Oh, good to see you.
She denied everything, told
the cop she fell through a window.
Probably tell her
kids the same thing.
You think it would be better if
she told them a john slashed her?
- Are you all right?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
Mr. Marshman? Could you turn
your hearing aid down, please?
- Thank you.
- What?
Labs back on your
B12 guy, Vitelli.
Hemoglobin's 14,
hematocrit's 42.
Anything wrong?
Stan, my man, this
is your lucky day.
- You giving me my shot?
- No.
Your doctor never did a
Schilling test on you, did he?
I knew it was unlikely,
given your age, your ethnicity.
My grandmother's
from northern Europe.
90% of pernicious anemia patients
have the anti-parietal cell antibody.
And your blood test
was negative for it.
So I'm in the 10 percent
without the antibody.
You have a normal
cobalamin level.
- Do you know what that is, Stanley?
- Vitamin B12.
And what causes
pernicious anemia?
B12 deficiency from
lack of intrinsic factor.
You don't have the
disease. You never did.
I can stay home
and take care of you.
Don't even think about
missing school on my account.
He's only trying to get
out of a math test anyway.
I am not, butthead.
My little brother's goofy.
Ignore him. That's what I do.
Were you talking to me?
They're good kids.
I do the best I can, you know?
I really do.
I don't think I'm gonna be able to
get home as early as I'd thought.
- Well, how about a late supper?
- Kerry, labs are back on Helen Broznich.
Sandy, I'm gonna
have to call you back.
- Father here?
- Yes. Want me to tell him?
Absolutely not.
Hello. I'm Dr. Weaver.
Walter Broznich. Hi.
This is all so terrible.
How are the other girls?
I'm not sure.
I shouldn't have let Helen drive in
that damn rain. Is she gonna be okay?
In addition to the injuries your
daughter sustained in the accident...
we found that she has a rare
disorder called Wilson's disease.
I'm confused. Last week you
people said she had hepatitis.
She does. In the sense
that her liver is inflamed...
as a result of
copper accumulation.
I have some in my brain too.
Wilson's is a genetic
condition that can cause...
both psychiatric and motor disorders.
In particular, jerky movements.
It's usually not symptomatic
until adolescence.
Is that why I hit the
gas and not the brakes?
That would be my
suspicion. Yeah.
- It's curable?
- It's manageable.
There's a Rick Kelly
who's a wildlife artist.
- Click on that other web site.
- You think it's the rock climber?
How cute, especially
with those tight shorts.
- What are you doing?
- Googling your blind date.
What? That is so rude. If you wanna
know anything about him, just ask me.
- Why? You've never even met him.
- Wow.
- Buns of steel, huh?
- Hmm.
Maybe I can live with the vegan
thing. Are you sure this is him?
What's so funny?
What?
Sorry about what's
happening with your brother.
Hopefully they'll find
him safe and sound.
Well, I'd better get
back to the phones.
- Where's that Bell's palsy patient?
- Exam 1. Here, I'll show you.
- I wish you'd go home.
- Why? So people can talk more...
- about my tragic family?
- That's not where it's coming from.
You know that.
They're concerned.
Yeah, I know.
All we can do is
interview the children...
get a better sense of home life.
If she's got customers going home
with her, there could be endangerment.
- Who's this?
- Bruce Dorchester, social services.
I'm new. I don't
think we've met.
So if your findings support removal,
will the children be kept together?
- We'll make every effort, yeah.
- Great.
- Why are you doing this?
- I know you mean well...
- but we're trying...
- But what? They're good kids.
Their mother provides for them.
- Yes, by actively prostituting herself.
- She has been arrested twice.
Is she under arrest now?
She admits to leaving her minor children
home alone at night. That's neglect.
- We've seen much worse.
- By law, we have to report this.
Look, I shouldn't have
to explain this to you.
You have to explain it
to somebody. It's wrong.
- This isn't your call.
- Is it yours?
You're a nurse, Abby. You don't have
the power to make this kind of decision.
I think this sucks.
What is her problem?
She's using accessory
muscles to breathe now.
- Is she talking at all?
- Asked where her daughter was.
- Where is she?
- Bathroom, I think.
Go to 20 mics of dopamine.
Mrs. Rasmussen?
I need to talk to you
about your condition.
Your lungs aren't working too
well anymore. Neither is your heart.
If it gets much worse, we're
going to have to intubate you.
Your daughter has asked us to
do everything we can to save you.
But in situations like this, often the
treatment is worse than the condition.
There's something you can sign
called a "do not resuscitate" order.
Plums.
What?
There are plums
in the back yard.
They're so lovely, sweet.
Do you like plums?
I brought an
umbrella just in case.
- It is beautiful from up here, isn't it?
- Yeah.
Listen, if you need any help,
need me to make some calls...
- answer some questions, I...
- Do you believe...
- people can die instantly?
- Sorry?
I don't know. I'm a nurse.
I don't know if I believe
it happens instantly.
A second can
seem like a lifetime.
Like when you hit the
brakes to avoid hitting a car...
it seems like it
takes forever to stop.
But maybe if you go
nose-first into the water...
at 200 miles an hour,
it is instantaneous.
At least I hope it is.
Why do you think
he went nose-first?
I don't know.
I'd better get back to work.
So you say you're sick, you're broke,
you're unemployed and uninsured.
Yeah, sure. Come on over.
Mr. Willner is regular again, and
I'm out of here. What you getting into?
I think I'm gonna
stay, do some studying.
- I missed a diagnosis.
- It happens to the best of us.
- Hey, you get one of these?
- "Greetings from Baltimore."
- Frank, Exam 1's clear.
- Tell it to the next clerk. I'm history.
- Damn it.
- Sounds like Leon's having a nice time?
- Guess he's adjusting okay.
- Yeah.
- Abby, Carter's on the line for you.
- I'll take it in there.
- Well, have a good night.
- Yep. You too.
Plan on it.
- Hey.
Stanley, thought you'd be
out painting the town by now.
Well, all my friends
are too tired to go out.
- You're kidding me, right?
- They all have pernicious anemia.
Everything in my life
was built around it.
Support groups,
therapy, committees.
- What do I do now?
- Well, you could try enjoying yourself.
How?
So your flight
was all right then?
Yeah.
Um...
Eric's plane disappeared.
It went off radar or something.
They don't know.
Have you been in the water yet?
No, Carter. You
don't have to do that.
Carter, he could
show up in an hour.
I just want to wait and
see what happens, okay?
Okay?
All right, I have to
go. I'll call you later.
- Good night, Abby.
- Good night.
- I hope everything's okay.
- Thanks.
- Okay, I'm taking six more.
- Cut down on the caffeine.
Or give some to Conni. Her
shift started 10 minutes ago.
- Need something done?
- A Nipride drip in 1.
- I'll do it.
- You rock.
- Have you been here since yesterday?
- Well, there's no place like home.
Help. I think my mother's
having a heart attack.
How's this?
Smells better anyway.
I don't know how you
people stand all this crap.
Me either.
- You want some privacy?
- I wanna get out of here.
All right. I'll see
what I can do.
- They still haven't found a bed upstairs?
- My dad went to find out about it.
Did anybody else die?
In the accident? A couple
of girls were seriously injured.
But they're in Recovery
now. They should be okay.
- So just Terri died?
- Yeah.
Not Sasha?
No.
I don't know how that happened.
It was raining pretty hard.
Sasha was meaner.
- Sorry?
- They weren't very nice to me.
They were never very nice to me.
Come on now. - No! No!
It'll be all right.
- Mommy!
- No!
Why are you
letting them do this?
Everything'll be all right.
- Mommy! No!
It's just till I get better.
Everything's gonna
be all right, all right?
- Mommy, no!
- I love you.
It's okay. - No! No!
She left them alone at night.
Yeah.
- What happened?
- She coded.
Shocked her twice, intubated
her, and she converted.
Guess this rules you out as a
second signature for her DNR.
- It's what she wanted.
- I need to talk to you about Helen.
Keep her systolic above 90,
and let's get her up to the MICU.
- It may not be the disease.
- What? What are you talking about?
Helen hated those girls. And they
weren't too crazy about her either.
Teenagers torture each other in
high school. Believe me, I remember.
Yeah. But they get upset
when they run over classmates.
Her flat affect could definitely
be part of the Wilson's.
Just because she
has a disorder...
doesn't mean she didn't
know what she was doing.
Are you implying that she
hurt those girls on purpose?
She seems disappointed more of
them didn't die. That's what I'm implying.
- Doctor, the appy in 4 is asking for you.
- Excuse me.
Your blind date called and
said he'd just pick you up here.
- Fine.
- I have a brother that's single.
Clotted PICC line.
Maybe I missed my turn. I got
up and walked around for a while.
Here's a tip. Never give up your place
on the waiting list at a county hospital.
- It's no big deal.
- Yeah, it's a huge deal. Come on.
No, really. It gave me a
chance to people-watch.
Well, that's putting
a positive spin on it.
So why do you have a PICC line?
Uh... Stage 3C
testicular cancer.
These two should be
reviewed in surgical committee.
- You got it.
- I remember you.
Rocket.
How'd I do?
Very, very well.
Because you promised
you'd take care of me, right?
Get some rest.
Send them to the QA office?
Mr. Dresden can
transfer to Four West.
And I am going
home to soak my feet.
Donald, have a minute?
- Dr. Romano, what can I do for you?
- Well, I read your memo...
and I think your
concerns are valid...
so I'm willing to limit my surgical
supervision to fifth-year residents.
- Keep going to physical therapy.
- Wait, look. Hear me out.
They already have
all the skills they need.
I'd just be there to
comment and observe.
You have physical liabilities.
It'd be one or two cases a week.
I wouldn't have to lift a finger.
We simply cannot expose patients
or the hospital to unnecessary risks.
Look, look, look.
Just keep me on the schedule,
even if it's in name only.
- Dr. Romano...
- Damn it. Please don't make me beg.
Until your recovery
has progressed further...
let's use your expertise
to help our students.
- They ready for us?
- Almost.
I'd like to get a psychiatric
consult before admitting Helen...
to the medicine
floor for treatment.
Why?
Mr. Broznich, although the
disease impacts the brain...
it doesn't necessarily
explain all behavior.
What do you mean?
Your daughter has the
ability to make decisions.
She goes to school.
She drives a car.
I don't understand.
I think you need to speak
with the police again.
I'm a spastic. You said that.
No, Helen. I didn't say that.
That's why I hit the
gas and not the brakes.
- I'll send the detective in.
- Wait.
- It's not the disease?
- That will have to be decided.
It was her?
- I don't know.
- She could have done this?
I don't know.
Okay. I'm going to inject something
called streptokinase into your port...
which should dissolve the clot
and make your line functional.
A good thing, because your white
blood counts are almost nonexistent.
I had chemo 10 days ago.
Your neutrophiles
are below 500...
making you susceptible
to life-threatening infection.
The ER is the last
place you should be.
Really? I kind of like it here.
Okay. Now I know you're sick.
When you're done with this, go home,
take your temperature every four hours.
Anything above 100.4 and
you get your butt back here.
- Wouldn't it just be easier to stay?
- No.
- Hey.
- You out of here?
- Yeah.
- Any word?
- Nothing.
- Is Carter coming back?
- No. I told him not to.
- You don't have to be alone tonight.
Go with you on your
blind date? I don't think so.
- Call me if you need me.
- I'll be fine.
Good night.
Is that him?
Uh... Yeah.
Have fun.
Hi. Heh.
- I'm Susan Lewis.
- Rick Kelly.
So are you ready to go?
Actually, I have to stick
around with a patient.
A kid with testicular cancer.
I should've called you.
- I drove in from Lincoln Park.
- Oh, I'm sorry.
Okay, then. Should
we reschedule?
Probably not.
Really?
Well, you know when you
meet someone and you can tell...
if there's a connection or not?
Actually, I don't wanna
give up steak. I'm sorry.
What happened to your date?
Oh, it wasn't meant
to be, I guess.
Let's get you a
shot of Neupogen.
CHEN. Mm.
Did you get new furniture?
It feels different in here.
- It's less crowded.
- Ah. Maybe that's it.
You miss him?
Sometimes.
I never lived with anyone
aside from my parents.
- No?
- But they weren't around much.
Guess that's why sometimes
I love my alone time.
Not me. I grew up around a whole
bunch of cousins and kids in the projects.
- Mm.
- I like it loud. The more the merrier.
You like kids?
Why do you ask?
I don't know. You ever
think about having them?
Okay, okay. You're
not the maternal type.
No. No. I love kids.
Well, good. Me too.
I...
I had one.
You have a kid?
I gave him up for adoption.
Why?
I don't know. It's complicated.
He's being raised
by good people.
Aren't you good people?
I guess I wasn't ready.
Well, I'm gonna
go take a shower.
- Mm.
All right?
Mom, are you there?
Look, I'm sorry I didn't
call you back earlier.
But I need to talk to you now.
Mom, if you're there,
could you please pick up?
Okay.
Maybe you're sleeping. Um...
Call me back. I should be home.