Ramona Davis has been
trouble for a long time.
I have a confession
to make.
I did shoot myself
with a nail gun.
I'm concerned that
you're a danger to yourself.
You don't need to be
nervous around me.
I am very comfortable
around you.
I'm taking her blood
to an outside lab.
You're unblinding her
without the company knowing?
That's what
caused her seizure.
So, we won't need
to unblind her.
No, I don't think
it's necessary.
Her heart's
not pumping properly.
I thought we had
all this time together.
My clinical trial
is the best option.
You know the risks
of an experimental drug.
If this were
any other patient...
But it's not
any other patient.
It's my mom!
Everything okay?
Yeah.
I wanna jot down some notes
for our meeting tomorrow.
Mmm. It's gonna go great.
I just wanna make
a good impression,
you know?
Everyone at Kender is
already so impressed
with your work in the trial.
Because, you,
Dr. Halstead, are a star.
Well, thank you.
Okay, so,
I get that I'm grounded,
but why do I have to
come to work with you?
We need to talk.
You know I've been
working late
a lot recently,
that's on me.
But today, at lunch,
you and me are gonna
sit down and talk.
I thought we talked
plenty last night.
Honey, this is the third time
you snuck out of the house
in the middle of the night.
Third time in less
than a month,
in the middle
of the night,
I find your bed
stuffed with clothes.
Dad, you don't let me
go out and do anything.
I'm like a prisoner.
I'd love to give you
more freedom, but, you know,
that would require a certain
amount of trust, and pro-tip,
sneaking out of the house
ain't the way to get there.
This is so unfair.
I'm sorry you feel that way.
Ramona.
Hi, Dr. Charles.
What are you
doing here?
I've got my outpatient
psych clinic this morning.
I thought I'd stop by
and say hi.
Oh. Okay.
Is this your daughter?
Yeah.
Hi, I'm Ramona.
Anna.
Hey, don't you wanna
be getting upstairs?
You don't want to be late
for your appointment.
To be honest, I really
don't know if Dr. Lancaster
is helping me.
Hmm.
It's only been three weeks.
Probably a good idea
to give the process
a chance.
He's really very,
very good,
else, I never would have
recommended him to you.
It's nice to meet you.
Nice to see you.
She's weird.
Morning, Nat.
Morning.
How's your mom?
You know what?
She's doing good.
She has an appointment
with Dr. Young
to see how her
heart's doing with
the LVAD today, so...
Oh, I'm glad it
all worked out.
Thank you.
Ambo pulling up.
Big rig overturned
on the Kennedy.
Car got crushed.
We're heading to Baghdad.
How many injured?
One. Coded on the way.
Courtney talk to me.
John Brady, 52,
triple zero,
intubated and bilaterally
needled in the field.
John?
You know him?
Yeah, one of
my trial patients.
Downtime greater
than 15 minutes.
Fifteen? Let's move it.
John, we got you, buddy.
On my count, one, two, three.
Thank you.
Okay. Pause CPR.
PEA. Continue CPR.
Push a milligram of epi.
Come on, John.
Come on.
Check pulse.
We have a pulse.
Sinus rhythm.
All right, ultrasound.
Let's fast him.
Okay.
Fast is negative.
Pressure's dropping.
Let's get him a unit
of blood and then FFP
on the rapid transfuser.
V-fib.
Damn it. Charge to 200.
Charging.
Come on.
Here we go. Clear.
Again.
Push another
milligram of epi.
All right. Clear.
Pulse.
Check pulse.
Still v-fib.
Come on, John.
Breathe for me.
Breathe, John. Clear.
Keep up compressions.
Charge again.
Clear.
Let's go. Keep going.
I mean, he was doing
so well in the trial.
His heart was improving.
Only to get killed
in some freak accident.
I'm so sorry, Will.
I found these
in Mr. Brady's belongings.
Trial meds?
Yeah.
Those have to
go back to Kender.
All right. I'll put it
in the outgoing box.
I gotta go pick up
my mom right now.
But if you wanna
talk later, I'm around.
Thanks, Nat.
Yeah.
My heart is getting worse?
How can that be?
I've been feeling better.
You have been having
palpitations.
Only in the last
couple of days,
and they go away
very quickly.
I'm afraid that's just
the first sign
that your heart's
getting weaker.
Your heart has become
more dependent on the LVAD.
Wasn't that the point of
getting it in the first place?
Not exactly.
The, uh, LVAD is just
meant to be a support
until cardiac
function improves,
or if that doesn't happen,
until a donor heart
becomes available.
Oh.
So, what are our options?
I'd like for you to stick
around for a few hours,
so we can give you
some IV fluids.
And then I can go home?
I also want to run
a few more tests.
Then we'll take stock
of where we are.
Okay?
Hey, I'm sorry.
I know that's not what either
of you wanted to hear.
I really hoped the LVAD
would have been
a better solution.
Yeah, I still think
it was the right call.
I'm not blaming you.
I thought it was
a better option, too.
But you know what?
I'm gonna go talk to Will,
see if he can still
get her into the trial.
Even if he did, your mom
could still get the placebo.
I know, but I need to
explore all of our options.
Yeah. Of course.
Hey.
How'd your mom's
appointment go?
Not great.
Um, the LVAD's not helping
as much as we'd hoped.
Sorry to hear that.
Look, I know at first,
it was either your
trial meds or the LVAD.
We couldn't do both.
Yeah.
All trial patients
have to fit
the same criteria.
Sure, but if she
was on the medication,
would it react adversely
with the LVAD?
It's a great drug,
but this is
uncharted territory.
If Mom understood
the risk,
is there any way you could
still get her into the trial?
Nat, I'm sorry,
I wish I could.
Enrollment's closed.
Isn't there anything
you can do?
I'll tell you what,
I'll ask Dr. Virani.
See if she can make
an exception.
But I can't promise anything.
I understand. Thank you.
Okay, we'll be right there.
Hey, Dean. I need you.
Yeah. What's going on?
CFD just called.
There's been an accident
at a house under renovation.
Two injured. One seriously,
open abdominal wound
and he's trapped
under debris.
Are they gonna need us
to do a field amputation?
Uh, I hope not.
But they said
he's trying to
get the guy free,
and they need us to bring
blood and plasma.
Let's gear up and go.
Mrs. Forbes,
I'm Dr. Marcel.
This is Nurse Sexton.
Hi.
My husband Robert.
Excuse me. I see
you've had COVID.
Yeah.
You're experiencing
chest pain and
shortness of breath.
When she woke up
this morning,
it was pretty bad.
How long have you been
having these symptoms?
On and off since I
had COVID, but it's gotten
worse the past few days.
She's been testing
negative for weeks, but it
doesn't seem to matter.
Unfortunately,
some people experience
symptoms for weeks,
even months,
after the virus is gone.
Sats 93.
Heart rate's
elevated, too.
Right before COVID,
we just started trying
to get pregnant.
We waited so long
to start a family.
I'm just ready to start
getting back to our lives.
Yeah. Let's figure out
what's going on
and get you fixed up, okay?
I'll see you in a bit.
Doc?
Yeah?
You think there's
something wrong
with her heart?
Oh, we're just covering
all our bases.
Don't worry.
Okay.
We're gonna take
good care of you.
It's good to get out
in the field
for a change.
Yeah.
Know what this is
reminding me of?
Helmand.
Crammed inside that Humvee.
Hotter than hell.
I sweat just
thinking about it.
Jacked up on adrenaline,
not knowing what
you're gonna face.
Hey, it was
a crazy time.
Yeah, no kidding.
Got incoming.
Dr. Halstead,
you're going to Two.
Desmond?
Ramona Davis.
30-year-old female,
persistently vomiting.
GCS 15.
Heart rate 133.
BP 112/82.
Gave her half
a liter of saline
in the field.
All right. Let's get her
ready to rotate.
Ramona, remember me?
I'm Dr. Halstead.
I can't stop throwing up.
How long's that
been going on?
About an hour.
All right. On my count.
One, two, three.
Thank you.
I'm gonna be sick.
All right, just hold on.
Go ahead.
Okay. Okay.
Thank you, Kristen.
Let's check your eyes,
Ramona.
Pinpoint pupils.
All right.
Ramona, I have to ask,
did you take something
to make yourself sick?
Okay. What did you take?
Ramona. What was it?
Miss Davis?
Tell us what you took.
I want to see Dr. Charles.
EKG, CBC, BMP
and send her blood
for an expanded
toxicology panel.
Got it.
Ramona, I wanna
help you feel better.
But you gotta help me
and tell me what you took.
Dr. Charles. I'll only
speak to Dr. Charles.
Never showed up
for her appointment
with Dr. Lancaster
this morning.
And after our encounter,
she must've gone home,
taken something
to make herself sick.
And Anna
was with you, right?
That makes me
a little nervous, Daniel.
How do you want
to handle this?
Look, I can't say
I didn't see it coming.
All right?
Last time she was here,
in order to treat her,
I had to get her to
trust me, which I did.
But in the process,
I became the new
Dr. Bridges.
Right, so, look.
I don't like it either,
but it seems like
I should talk to her.
Are you sure?
This patient harms herself
to get attention.
Aren't you just
rewarding that
by giving her
what she wants?
But if not me, who?
It certainly doesn't
seem like she's gonna
engage with somebody
she doesn't trust.
Sooner or later,
she's gonna run
out of luck, right?
And one of these
attention-getting schemes
is gonna kill her.
I don't know.
It just seems
a little irresponsible
to keep kicking
the can down the road.
Look, I understand
your concern,
but in this instance,
I'd rather wait
for the tox screen.
Hopefully, that will
give us the answer we need
without your intervention.
This will help you,
Miss Davis.
Miss Davis? Don't worry.
We'll take care of you.
Hey, Brett.
Hey, glad you guys
are here.
This is
Dr. Dean Archer. Surgeon.
How badly is he hurt?
Uh, head trauma,
broken arm.
The victim trapped
in the basement
is in much worse shape.
Thanks.
Joe, got here
as quick as we could.
What happened?
They're renovating the house.
Guy cut a truss to install
some ductwork.
Cut a little too deep.
Whole floor caved in
on top of him.
Circular saw
cut him as he fell.
How long until
you can get him free?
My team is working as
fast as they can, but there's
a lot of unstable weight.
This way.
We're trying to secure
the floor with struts
and cribbing
to avoid
a secondary collapse.
It's just down here.
Oh, thank God.
Eddie, it's gonna be okay.
Mrs. Howard, please,
it's safer for you outside.
No, please,
I want her here.
Let her stay.
Watch your step.
Thanks.
Okay, we need to
give the doctors some room.
Let's wait over here.
Hey, Violet,
talk to me.
Eddie Howard,
34 years old. BP 110/70.
Large abdominal wound
with evisceration
from circular saw.
Meds?
Ten milligrams
of morphine IV.
All right, thanks.
We'll take it from here.
Yeah.
Hey. Eddie, I'm Dr. Choi,
this is Dr. Dean Archer.
We're gonna take care
of you, all right?
My wife told me
to hire an HVAC
contractor,
but I thought
me and my buddy could
do the work ourselves.
Let's hang some blood.
We'll wrap his intestines
with some saline
to keep them moist.
You're not gonna
put 'em back in me?
No. We're gonna
protect them for now.
We'll put them back
where they belong when
we get you to the hospital.
Hang in there, Eddie,
we're going to get you
out of here soon.
Okay. Good news.
Your EKG shows no sign
of any irregularity.
Then why does it feel
like my heart
is gonna pound
out of my chest?
Let's take another listen.
Definitely bounding.
Take a deep breath for me.
Yeah.
Honey, hey.
This should help you
breathe a little easier,
okay?
What's happening to her?
It's possible that
she's developed
a pulmonary embolism.
It's a blood clot
in the lungs.
We've seen it in patients
who've recovered from COVID.
It's treatable.
I'm gonna send you
for a chest CT,
then we'll know for sure.
April, if we can start her
on a heparin drip
and then send her
for a CT, PE study.
Sure thing.
Sats are dropping!
Okay.
Ramona, I'm gonna listen
to your lungs, okay?
Slow and deep breaths.
She's tight.
125 Solu-Medrol,
breathing treatment, stat.
Okay, that's it.
Breathe deep.
All right, Ramona,
this has gone on
long enough.
You need to tell us
what you took.
Ramona, whatever
you ingested is working
its way through your system.
If we don't treat it properly,
you can have some
serious complication.
You may even die.
Tell us,
so we can help you.
I want Dr. Charles!
He's clear.
Oh, thank God.
Let's slide him out.
I'm here, honey.
You're gonna be okay.
All right.
Someone grab the backboard.
Let's roll him.
Ready?
Yeah.
Roll.
Back right,
he's on it.
Let's get that
stokes basket in here.
All right, careful with that.
Let's get this guy
to the hospital.
Let's transfer him
on my count. Ready?
Watch his arm.
Yeah.
Everybody ready?
One, two, three.
Get down!
What the hell?
Just got word from PD.
Gang fight broke out.
Neighborhood's on lockdown.
No ambulances in or out.
This man can't wait, Joe.
If we don't get him
to the hospital soon,
he'll die.
It's not my call.
I'll let you know
if I hear anything else.
All right.
Hey, Dean. You okay?
Huh?
You okay?
Yeah. Fine, fine, fine.
What's happening?
Courtney.
Come on, Michelle,
let's get you some water.
Eddie?
Eddie, stay with us.
BP's tanking.
He's not protecting
his airway.
I'll bag him.
Hang another
unit of blood.
This is the last one.
Oh, God. More laps.
More laps!
Where's all this
blood coming from?
It's coming from the liver.
Laceration on the right lobe.
Can you repair it?
Maybe a Pringle.
Clamp the inflow
of blood to the liver.
But it's dark,
non-sterile environment.
Hey, this guy is bleeding out
right in front of us.
We have to.
Yeah. Uh...
Dean.
Yeah.
Get me a clamp,
gauze, anything,
to soak up the blood.
See what the hell
I'm doing.
Okay.
Your CT was normal.
No PE.
Then why is my wife
having trouble breathing?
So far, we haven't
been able to find
any physical explanation
for your symptoms.
Mr. and Mrs. Forbes,
I spent a long time
in the COVID ward.
I saw patients
on ventilators for weeks.
A lot of them suffered
emotional trauma
from their time in the ICU.
Wait. You think
this is in my head?
Considering the stress
you've been under
for the past few months,
it would be understandable
if this was anxiety based.
She's not imagining this!
No, no one is saying
she is.
Look. Anxiety, if that's
what's behind this,
can cause
very real symptoms.
You can't do anything
to help my wife?
We'll continue to
monitor her symptoms,
run tests, but...
But what?
If all else fails,
it can't hurt to speak
with one of our
in-house psychiatrists.
You paged me?
Dr. Halstead?
Ramona's going
downhill fast.
What about
the tox screen?
Whatever she took
didn't show up.
Daniel?
Looks like
we're out of options.
So, um, wish me luck.
Thanks.
Mmm-hmm.
Ramona.
You came.
Look, you're
running out of time.
You gotta tell us
what you took,
so we can help you.
If you agree
to be my doctor.
I already
am your doctor.
I never stopped
being your doctor.
You know what I mean.
I'm an emergency
room psychiatrist.
All right?
We talked about this.
I'm simply not available
to give you the kind
of care you need.
Dr. Lancaster,
though, he is...
But I want you.
Just like
you wanted Dr. Bridges?
Look, here you are,
back in the hospital.
You're different
from Dr. Bridges.
You listen to me.
You hear me.
That's all I need.
Someone to hear me. Please.
I'll make you a deal.
All right? You tell me
what you took,
and I will come back
and we can talk
about this a bit.
Insecticide. Malathion.
Oh, my God.
Give her a DuoDote
of atropine
and pralidoxime.
You got it.
Yeah. Shouldn't take long
to see improvement.
Give me a shout when
she's out of the woods.
Yeah.
Help!
We need help.
She can't breathe.
It hurts.
Easy, easy.
Oh, God.
Does this look like
anxiety to you?
All right.
Sedate her and set up
for a bronchoscopy.
We need to scope her.
It's okay, it's okay.
We'll take a closer look
at your lungs, okay?
Come on. Do something.
Do something!
Nice and easy, okay?
We're taking care of it.
All right.
What's happening?
There you go.
It's okay.
Brought you
an afternoon pick-me-up.
Always so thoughtful.
Listen, um,
Dr. Manning's mother
is in heart failure.
I know
enrollment's closed,
but is there any way
we can get her
into the trial?
I'm sorry, Will.
Letting her in now
would compromise
the data
we've already collected.
I get it.
It's just
Carol is an old friend.
And she's getting worse.
Our drug could save
her life.
There's no guarantee
that she would get
the actual drug.
And even if she did,
we don't know how
effective it would be.
The drug works.
The preliminary data
has been encouraging, but...
No, it works. I know it does.
It's a blind trial.
How could you?
Will?
I unblinded a patient.
What?
A couple months back.
You did this
behind my back?
I didn't want to.
But I had to.
For the sake
of my patient.
Do you have any idea
what you've done?
You've jeopardized
the whole trial. Not to
mention both of our jobs.
Look, Sabeena,
I've told you this
in confidence.
We're having drinks
with Mark Barragan tonight.
How am I supposed to sing
your praises, knowing you've
broken the most basic rule?
I'm sorry.
Really, I am.
I have no idea
what I'm gonna do.
But I can tell you this.
I'm not making
any exceptions
to the enrollment.
Okay.
Hey, Nat.
Yeah.
So, I talked
to Dr. Virani,
and there's just
no way to get your mom
into the trial.
I'm sorry.
What if I talk to her?
Explain how serious
Mom's condition is?
Trust me. She's not
gonna change her mind.
Okay. Um,
thank you for trying.
Yeah, hey, I really wish
there was something more
I could do.
I guess we'll just
stay on course
with Dr. Young. Thanks.
How are you feeling?
Good, now that
you're here.
I like your tie.
My father
wore a tie every day.
He had very
fine taste in clothes.
You know,
speaking of your dad,
last time you were here,
I was struck by...
You said that
you didn't think
he cared about you.
Those were your words.
Not mine.
Oh.
We were very close.
Tell me a little more
about him.
There isn't any more.
How about your mom.
Was she around?
She left us.
Sorry to hear that.
How old were you?
I don't know...
Um... five or six.
Anyway, it didn't matter.
How's that?
My father said
we didn't need her.
We were a team.
No brothers or sisters?
Just me.
Some kids
in that position, they...
I don't know, sometimes
would wish that they
had a little brother or sister
to play with. But not you?
I didn't.
I was very happy.
I mean, I guess
you didn't have to
share him with anybody.
What you thinking about?
Ramona?
You know, um,
I could use a snack.
How about you? You hungry?
A sandwich? Jell-O?
Jell-O...
I like orange.
Me, too.
I'll be back.
All right.
Come on.
74/60.
I can't find the artery.
I can't find it.
Can't find it.
Dean.
Dean, what's going on?
Talk to me.
Hey, hey. Dean, Dean.
I know what
you're going through, okay?
I've been there.
I've been there with you.
In Helmand. All right?
Yeah.
Hey? We got through that
and we're gonna
get through this.
No.
Yeah.
No, no.
You can do this.
I can't do it.
Yes, you can.
You're the finest surgeon
I know.
Hey, hey. Look at me.
Look at me.
Deep breaths.
Yeah.
There you go.
Okay, I need you.
This patient needs you.
Okay.
Okay?
You got this, Dean.
All right.
PD's got the situation
under control.
It's safe to leave.
Hold on, hold on. Dean?
Found it. Clamped.
Bleeding's stopped.
Pressure's coming back up.
Good job. Good job.
Let's go.
Yeah.
Bring them in.
Copy that.
Okay, need a hand.
Mrs. Forbes,
you doing okay?
Almost there.
Okay, I'm seeing
several small lesions
in the distal airway
of your lower left lobe.
What does that mean?
Tumors?
I'm not sure.
Can I get a sample
for biopsy?
Come up a little bit more.
Right there.
I know it's hard,
try not to worry.
We'll know soon
what we're dealing with.
Okay, stop. Open.
Carol?
Mmm.
I'm sorry to say that
even with the fluids and
adjustments to the LVAD,
your heart's still
having arrhythmias.
So, what do we do now?
I'd like to add an AICD.
And what is that?
It's a device
that's implanted
in your chest
that can help
regulate your heart.
If an arrhythmia
develops,
it can shock your heart back
into a normal sinus rhythm.
Does it hurt
to get shocked?
My patients do say
it causes discomfort.
One patient describes it
as feeling like getting kicked
in the chest.
Who can say no to that?
Mom, I think
you should just
hear Dr. Young out.
It's a minimally invasive
procedure and it will help
the LVAD work better.
So, in addition
to lugging
my LVAD around,
I get the added benefit
of getting kicked
in the chest?
I do think you should
consider the AICD.
I'm sorry, what kind
of quality of life is that?
It's not ideal, but it
will keep you alive until
you can have a transplant.
Um... Good. I'm tired.
Would you take me
home, please?
Thank you, Doctor.
Okay.
Endometriosis?
My sister had that
in her uterus.
Yeah. That's usually
where it occurs,
but in very rare cases,
the endometrial cells
can migrate
to other parts of the body,
like the lungs.
And once there,
they respond to
hormone fluctuations
from your menstrual cycle
and can grow,
causing bleeding,
and even a collapsed lung.
How do we treat it?
Since it's fed
by hormones,
I would recommend
inducing early menopause,
either by removing
the ovaries or through
a series of injections.
You can't put me
into menopause.
We want to have a baby.
Honey, we gotta do
whatever it takes
to make you better.
We've dreamt of having
a family for so long.
I am not giving up on this.
Dr. Marcel?
Yeah.
Okay.
There is another option.
I can perform a surgery,
a lobectomy,
whereby I remove
the portion of the lung
with endometriosis.
Now, it's only
a temporary measure.
There's a strong chance
it could come back,
requiring additional
surgery,
and potentially putting
your lungs at risk.
Okay.
Okay. If it means that
I can still have a baby,
then it's worth it.
Robert? I need you
to be okay with this.
If this is what
you want...
I am.
Okay. I'll have
one of the residents
come get you pre-op'd.
I love you.
So, you were saying that
you and your dad
were a team.
Did I get that wrong?
You keep asking
about my father
and I keep telling you
I don't wanna
talk about him.
But why is that?
Did something bad happen?
No, no. My father loved me.
I mean, he was always there.
We did
lots of things together
when I was little.
Not so much
when you got older?
It was different.
Huh. How? How?
My father didn't
like me as much.
Really. Why do you think
that was?
I couldn't
please him anymore.
I wasn't good enough.
Not good enough
how, though?
He couldn't
stand to be around me.
Yeah?
I did
everything wrong.
I'm sorry.
It's really no big deal.
Dr. Charles, I'm sorry,
but your daughter
needs you.
I'm busy. I'll be
a little while, thanks.
Okay, she said
it's an emergency.
What's the issue?
I don't know.
She didn't tell me.
It's okay, Dr. Charles.
No.
I understand.
She's your daughter.
No.
Let's stick
with this, okay?
No, really.
I could use a moment.
Please, go ahead.
All right.
I'll be right back, okay?
Right back.
Unbelievable.
Okay. I'm sorry.
The guest network
is too busy and I can't
stream this lecture.
And I'm not gonna
be able to get my
assignment done in time.
Honey, anybody
on the nursing staff
could've given you
the Wi-Fi password.
All right?
I'm trying to help
somebody over here.
Where's Ramona?
I don't know.
There was
a combative patient
in Treatment Four,
I had to help.
I wasn't gone that long.
Okay. Check the front.
Tell security.
Yeah.
Picking up
a package for Kender.
Package for Kender?
Um, I'm sorry.
Someone already
picked that up.
Okay. Thanks.
Mmm-hmm.
Wow.
Peanut butter whiskey.
Who'd have thought?
I'm not gonna lie,
I didn't think I'd like it.
But that's really good.
It's delicious.
You know, Will,
I have to tell you,
I am absolutely thrilled
with your work on the trial.
I can't believe
this is your first
experience as a PI.
Hey, it certainly helps
working alongside Dr. Virani.
She's a great advisor,
and really got me
up to speed.
One of our best.
Your trials always
run so smoothly.
You care to divulge
your secret?
Strict adherence
to protocols.
I think Dr. Virani's
being modest.
She also prioritizes
patient care.
I mean, that's why
we're all here, right?
To save lives.
Yes. Indeed.
Will, Sabeena and I
have talked about you
taking on a bigger role
within the company.
Multiple trials.
That is something
that we've discussed
in the past.
But?
Dr. Halstead has told me
that he considers himself
an ED doctor first,
and a PI second.
Well...
Let me be blunt.
Would you be willing
to leave the ED
and make clinical trials
your full-time gig?
I think that's something
I would seriously consider.
I'm sorry.
I have to take this.
Sure.
How's he doing?
I'm hopeful
he'll make a full recovery.
So, Dean...
I gotta get out
of these scrubs, okay?
We need to talk about
what happened today.
There's nothing
to talk about.
Dean...
I'm fine.
No, you're not.
Hey, listen.
I think you're
suffering from PTSD.
I just got a little rattled.
It's not every day
you find yourself
in the center of a gun battle
with some guy's guts
on the floor.
We've been through
worse in Afghanistan.
Come on.
Hey.
Yeah.
The things
we saw over there...
I'm still rattled by them.
But Dr. Charles helped me.
And he can help you, too.
Therapy? Come on.
If you broke your leg,
you'd treat it, right?
Mental health
is no different.
There shouldn't be
a stigma attached to it.
Listen.
It's not about that at all.
I don't need therapy.
PTSD just doesn't
go away, Dean.
And therapy
gives you the tools
to deal with it.
That's what a good
single malt is for.
I'm serious. Hey.
You need to get help.
Look, you were
the commanding officer,
always putting
the needs of others first.
It's time to take care
of yourself.
Please.
Listen to your old friend.
Text Dr. Charles,
set up a time to talk.
You're not leaving me
much choice, are you?
No, I'm not.
All right.
I'll do it right now.
Good.
Yeah.
Curly.
Hey.
Hey. I heard Mrs. Forbes'
surgery went well.
Yeah, I managed
to resect the area
with the lesion,
and thankfully,
avoided a lobectomy.
So she's resting
comfortably now.
Wonderful.
Yeah.
You okay?
Yeah, I just...
I thought her symptoms
were caused by anxiety.
Hey, look.
You made a diagnosis,
a very plausible one,
based on your experience.
That's what medicine's
all about, right?
Building on what
you already know.
And a lot of docs,
they get their MDs,
that's it.
They know it all.
You're not like that.
You keep going for it.
That's how
you make a difference.
Thanks, Crockett.
Yeah, I'll see you, okay?
You ready to get out
of here, sweetie?
Um, that lady
who ran away earlier,
did you ever find her?
Not yet.
Is she dangerous?
I think only
to herself, really.
You know,
she's just a very sad,
troubled young lady.
Okay, it's my fault
that she's gone.
If I hadn't made you
come out of her room
in the first place,
then she'd still be here.
She wouldn't have left.
Anna, it is not your fault.
Trust me.
She wanted to leave.
She was gonna find a way.
Yeah, but I keep
screwing up.
I bet you wish
that I'd gone to live
with Mom instead.
I don't wish that.
Not even a bit.
Okay, but look at everything
that you do for me, and then,
look what I do.
Anna, honey,
I'm your dad.
Okay, you don't
owe me anything,
nor is it your job
to please me.
But it is my job to do
everything I can to
help you thrive in life.
But, honey,
that's not gonna matter
if I can't keep you safe
in the first place.
Right, which is
why, honey,
I can't just fling open
the barn door
and let you roam around.
You understand
that, right?
Oh.
Oh. Thank you, honey.
But I'm just...
Really, I'm not hungry.
Mom, you need to eat.
Mmm.
And remember what
Dr. Young said about
staying hydrated.
Here you go.
Thank you.
Mmm-hmm.
Do you think
that I made a mistake
by not agreeing
to have the other surgery?
I don't think
it's a bad thing to take
your time and think about it.
Mmm.
But in the meantime...
I want you to take these.
Dr. Young
didn't mention new meds.
They're from
a different doctor.
I showed him your chart,
and he thought these
would work well for you.
He said they've been
really beneficial
for patients
with heart failure.
Okay.
Let's have at it.
Yeah.