You're here early.
Trouble sleeping?
No.
Just wanted to get out of
my apartment and to work.
We work you plenty
hard enough. Go home.
Making sure you're rested
is also part of the job.
I understand.
What should I tell a patient
if they don't think they're sick,
but I think they have
pancreatic cancer?
You think one of our patients
has pancreatic cancer?
Seventeen.
He's burped 17
times in 10 minutes.
It's a frequent symptom
of pancreatic cancer.
Shaun, it's acid reflux.
He's also jaundiced.
No, he isn't.
Paul's skin is definitely not the
same color it was six months ago.
- Paul?
- I looked at his mouth
when he was telling
me about his daughter.
- She just...
- Walk with me.
Say nothing.
Hey, Shaun.
Do a CBC, CMP, amylase, lipase,
CA-19-9 levels and CT abdomen,
pelvis pancreatic protocol.
And do not tell him why.
You want me to lie?
I don't want you
to tell the truth.
The discoloration, if
there is any, is very minor.
I don't want you scaring the
crap out of the man over nothing.
Excellent. I've
been practicing lying.
I lied to you when I said
I just wanted to get out of
my apartment and to work.
Take Claire.
Hello, I'm Dr. Lim. How
can I help you today, Asha?
I want plastic surgery.
Sweetheart, this is
the Emergency Room.
If you want, I can make an
appointment for you with...
You do vaginal
rejuvenation, right?
Yes. On much older,
much vainer women,
generally after
having many children.
I don't know what the
boys have told you...
Examine me.
Please.
Please take off your underwear.
Were you in an accident?
No. Can you help me?
- Did your father do this to you?
- No. Please, just...
Did your mother? I need
to know who did this to you.
No, you don't. It
doesn't matter who.
When I was two years old,
I was tied down, and
I was circumcised.
Please. I'm hideous.
Will you help me?
Yes.
Why do you need to confirm
a diagnosis of acid reflux?
Because we're doctors.
It's what we do. We just
like to be sure of everything.
There are a few
remote possibilities...
I've got this.
Are you familiar with the
hospital employee manual?
Section 17, subsection C-Ill?
- No.
- Good.
- "Good"?
- Yes.
It requires that all
employees shall be subject to,
and I quote,
"Any and all possible
necessary tests to confirm
"any and all diagnoses,
no matter how mundane,
"the cost of which tests shall be
borne by the hospital," end quote.
The board wants to make sure
that no one is exposed to patients
if there is any chance that they
have any communicable condition.
I had the flu last week.
Why didn't anybody
do anything for me then?
- It's a new policy.
- You might have pancreatic cancer.
What? What'd he say?
Female genital mutilation
is the ritual cutting,
or removal, of some, or all, of
the external female genitalia.
Over 200,000,000
victims worldwide,
it is almost
universally practiced
in a number of African
and Asian countries.
Where was she born?
Wisconsin. Yeah, it's way more
common here than you think.
What religion is she?
- I didn't ask.
- This isn't about religion.
No legit religious
organization endorses this stuff.
We're gonna do the labiaplasty
first thing in the morning.
The damage done to her
nerves is not going to get undone,
nor is the psych damage,
but at least she'll
look like other girls.
We should be able to have her
out of here by 6:00 in the evening.
Outpatient? Why the hurry?
So her mother will simply
think she's in school,
then out studying
with her friends.
She loves her parents
and doesn't want to tell them
that she's rejecting one
of their cultural traditions.
They won't stay
in the dark for long,
since we're legally
obligated to report them.
That "cultural tradition" also
fits the definition of abuse.
They'll also find
out when we ask
for their permission to do
this surgery. She's a minor.
Her ID says she's 18.
Yes, her fake ID says she's 18.
Her number starts with an H, which
means she was born in the '50s.
Also the photo background
is green instead of blue.
Also, six other things.
Maybe we can get Legal
to get a court order...
If I believe that ID is real,
then I am entitled to
perform this surgery
without seeking consent of
anyone other than the patient.
And, as legally
required within 36 hours,
I'll report the
evidence of abuse
under the name and
address listed on that ID.
If the investigation
of that report
doesn't begin until
the girl is long gone
and happens to lead nowhere
because the name wasn't real,
that's no fault of mine.
You sure you wanna
risk your medical license
- to protect an abusive mother?
- If we do this by the book,
we never see that girl again
and no one gets helped.
If we do this by the book, maybe
the cops lock the parents up,
we shine a light on this thing,
her community gets scared,
and maybe the next girl
doesn't need our help.
Or maybe the testimony of the
girl about what happened to her
when she was two
doesn't help the cops at all.
Maybe the parents just
take their daughter home,
and maybe we scare the next
girl into not even asking for help.
I'm doing the
surgery, to this girl,
under this name, tomorrow
morning at 7:00 a.m.
I can't believe people ever lie.
There are so many questions
people might ask you.
But if you tell the truth, you
already know the answers.
And also, it's wrong.
But sometimes you
shouldn't tell the whole truth?
No. Of course not.
Because that lets
you be honorable,
and tell the truth and
be a good person.
But at the same time, you get
to completely deceive the person.
- No, I don't think that's...
- Lea came back.
Wow, Shaun, that's great.
She's staying with me
until she finds her own place.
You must be so excited.
Yes.
You're not excited?
I said, "Yes."
Paul has one year to live.
He has pancreatic
cancer, stage three.
No metastatic lesions, but
local nodes are involved.
And there's partial encasement
of the superior mesenteric artery.
That puts it past the point where
we can cure it with a local resection.
We could do Whipple surgery.
That's not advised for stage
three pancreatic cancer.
Not quite. It's not
advised for stage four.
For stage three,
it's discretionary.
In my discretion, he's better off
with 12 semi-comfortable months
rather than the risk of
dying on the table tomorrow.
If he doesn't die on the table,
he could have many years.
It isn't our call to make.
I'll talk to Paul, advise
him of the parameters.
Let him make his own decision.
No. Shaun should do it.
Claire can do it.
Yes, she can, which
is why you should do it.
This is a teaching hospital.
Andrews is right. Being a
surgeon isn't just about cutting.
Would it be okay if we
spoke someplace more quiet?
You need someplace quiet
to tell me I have acid reflux?
I think we should
be someplace quiet
because people
sometimes get very upset
when they find out they probably
only have less than a year to live.
Okay, uh... Can
I call my family?
They should probably hear
what you have to say, too.
I'd rather just talk to...
Of course you can.
I'll elevate it with a
6-inch Ambler tissue hook.
You separate the underlying
tissue with iris forceps.
I got it. Tenotomy scissors.
Think we're ahead of schedule.
Might get her home in
time to do her homework.
Back to the bosom
of her loving family.
We'd remove as much
of the cancer as possible
by removing the head of the
pancreas and other attached organs,
but then we'd have to
reconstruct the anatomy.
The easiest way is to
bring up a loop of jejunum...
Shaun...
Sorry.
The jejunum is part
of the small intestine
between the duodenum and ileum.
It's a complicated,
very dangerous surgery,
and even if it's successful,
post-operative complications
are frequent and serious,
and recovery can
be very painful.
But if it works, he's
better? He'll be healthy?
He would still need chemotherapy,
and a lifetime of monitoring,
but hopefully a long lifetime.
Let's do it, Dad.
What do you say?
What should I do?
It's your decision.
All we can do is present
you with the facts.
Yeah. Here are the facts.
Dad, the surgery may kill you.
Not doing the
surgery will kill you.
- Can you give us a few minutes?
- Of course.
It was very nice of Dr. Andrews
to give you an office,
even though you're
on medical leave.
Yeah, he is a prince.
- Who's your surgeon going to be?
- I haven't...
I haven't decided yet.
You should definitely go
with Dr. Joshua Atkinson
at Stanford Medical Center.
His mortality index is 0.3.
It's too low.
Not enough of his
patients are dying?
No, Shaun.
Sometimes patients die,
doesn't matter how
good the doctor is.
But when your mortality
rate is as low as Atkinson's,
it means you're
turning away patients.
You turn away patients, it
means you lack confidence.
You lack confidence, I don't
want you inside my head.
And I'd like to be able to
dress myself when I'm all done.
Shaun, what are you doing here?
You showed up at
work early this morning.
Go home. Get some rest.
I won't rest if I go home.
The surgery went great.
Once everything's healed,
I think you'll be very
happy with the results.
What time is it?
Not quite 5:45.
We just need you to pee, and...
- I need to go home.
- And you will, very soon.
- It hurts.
- I told you it would.
We did a lot of cutting and
scraping. You had a lot of scar tissue.
- It hurts a lot.
- We'll give you some Tylenol,
and you can tell your
mother you're cramping.
Ow!
Hang ketamine, 130
micrograms per kilogram per hour.
Why does it hurt this much?
I don't know.
But you're not going home.
No!
She's heavily sedated.
What did we do to her?
What if this is good news?
I know you haven't been
a doctor all that long,
but pain is rarely a
sign of good news.
It is if you're talking about a part
of the body you thought was dead.
What if this means there are
still viable nerve endings in there?
What if this means we can
actually reconstruct her clitoris
and that it's capable
of sensation?
Maybe. All we know for sure is she's
not gonna be home anywhere near 6:00,
which means we're about to
have a missing child on our hands.
We have to bring
Andrews up to speed.
I did a bad job of telling
you that you're dying.
Is there a good way?
I can't figure out when
I'm supposed to lie,
when I'm supposed
to tell part of the truth.
And it doesn't really matter
because I can't figure
out how to do it anyway.
You did fine with me.
You never need to lie.
Lies don't protect
you from the truth.
I don't like your haircut.
Okay.
Maybe sometimes, when
the truth can't help someone,
we should definitely just lie.
Do you think praying will
help you reach a decision?
I've already reached a decision.
I'm praying to help me find
comfort with that decision.
My family wants surgery.
And what do you want?
I want what my family wants.
- I love them.
- But they love you, too, right?
Don't they want what you want?
Long ago, I made a decision.
To be there for them,
no matter what.
And if the last choice I make
in my life is consistent with that,
I'm comfortable with that.
I'm surprised by you.
I arguably made
errors in judgment,
but it was all in an
effort to help a patient.
Yes, that would make
sense if you thought
you'd never have
another patient ever again.
And if there wasn't currently
an opening for chief of surgery.
I didn't know that
was on the table.
See, that's the difference
between you and Melendez.
I have no doubt that as
soon as I got this promotion,
Melendez had done the
math and reacted accordingly.
But I suspect that even
if you had done the math,
it wouldn't have changed
how you handled this patient.
I don't view that as a weakness.
I'll handle the
administrative fallout.
You notify the
parents immediately.
I can't.
We don't know the girl's real name,
and we have to keep her sedated,
so there's no way to track...
She's a teenager.
She's got a phone.
Next time it rings, answer it.
- Feel the mesenteric artery pulsing?
- Yes.
You shouldn't. You're
too close to the vein.
Great. Dr. Browne, pass
a Penrose drain through.
Bovie.
Suction.
Got it all.
I see leaking pancreatic fluid.
That'll eat holes in
everything it touches.
- Our duct tie didn't hold.
- Suction. Needle driver.
Excellent. You have approved a
scrub nurse, and a circulating nurse,
and seven other personnel.
Everyone and everything is
covered except for an actual surgeon.
Yeah, I think we
may have to postpone.
Have you notified your tumor
to stop growing in the interim?
I think any possible
damage from the delay
may be more than offset by
having somebody competent
- digging around in my brain.
- "Competent."
- What's wrong with Sanders?
- 6% mortality rate.
- Taylor?
- I don't like the way he's planning
on dealing with a carotid tear.
- That's nowhere near your tumor.
- It's the principle.
- Unger?
- He doesn't like me.
- No one likes you.
- No. You don't like me.
He doesn't like me. That's two.
Just pick a name.
I don't care who.
I don't care if they're a
doctor. Just pick a name
because in 48 hours, you're
either getting your surgery,
or you're getting
a new oncologist.
She's in pain?
That's why she's asleep right
now, because of what you did to her?
What I did to her,
I believe, revealed
that what you did to her
didn't do as much damage
as we initially feared.
- We wanna do a second surgery...
- How can you stop her pain?
It's called "clitoral
reconstruction."
The nerves of her clitoris are
exposed. We can sheath them...
Our daughter wants this?
Asha wants to be like other
girls. She wants to be able to fully...
Mara told you that?
That's our daughter's
name, not Asha.
You don't know her at all.
We need to do this
surgery to relieve her pain.
No. There must be another way.
We want a second
opinion, not at this hospital.
How soon can our
daughter be moved?
Excuse me. Dr. Lim?
I'm Ellen Vahtra, from
Child Protective Services.
Until I complete my review,
I'm afraid you're not going to be
moving your daughter anywhere.
How did it go? Is Dad okay?
There were complications,
but we found solutions.
It went very
well. We got it all.
Oh, my God!
There's still...
I don't think I did that
well. They're too happy.
Post-surgical complications are
still a major concern that they should...
Let them enjoy the good news.
Is deceiving someone in a
way that makes them happy
better than deceiving someone
in a way that makes them sad?
Shaun, I think there's
someone here to see you.
Hey. I had some time,
so I thought you might wanna
have some lunch with me.
I do not have time.
What's wrong? What did she do?
Shaun. Shaun.
You don't want to talk to
Lea. I don't understand.
I don't understand.
You're not being
fair to her, or yourself.
- She's always been nice to you...
- No, she hasn't.
She's your friend.
Whatever's happened,
you have to talk to her about it.
Be honest about what you're feeling.
I can't be.
Of course you can.
I don't know!
I don't know how I feel.
I can't be honest if I
don't know how I feel.
Our 16-year-old daughter
is lying in a hospital bed,
unconscious, to protect
her from overwhelming pain
because of what this place
did to her without our permission,
and you are investigating us?
Your daughter is suffering
because you butchered her
when she was two years old.
Dr. Lim, please refrain from
unsubstantiated allegations.
Either they're the butchers, or
they're protecting the butchers.
If you didn't do
it, tell us who did.
It was an aunt and a
grandmother from Kenya.
They were watching Mara
while we were on vacation.
Well, you must
have been horrified.
Did you take her to a doctor?
That girl's sex organs were
covered with scar tissue.
She had no medical attention
to treat any of her wounds.
She was fine. She
was happy, laughing.
It's not that big a deal.
I was cut.
My mother was cut.
Her mother was cut.
It is a rite of passage, connecting
our women to their ancestors.
She will not find a husband
in our culture if she is not...
So, she'll find someone else.
It's not that big a deal.
These parents forfeited
the right to make any calls
about their daughter
a long time ago.
Our daughter is
an honor student,
taking three AP
classes in her junior year.
Went on a mission to
Haiti to build a school.
We have raised her well.
She's a good person.
We're proud of her.
I'm sure she is a good person,
but you're not gonna convince
me that what happened to Mara
when she was two years old is
anything short of an abomination.
But that's not the issue today.
The issue is how do we
best help this girl now.
The clitoral reconstruction
should protect the exposed nerve...
"Should"?
That is the surgery that, in my
medical opinion, is called for.
But it's not the only option?
We could ablate
the peripheral nerves,
and remove the
remaining clitoral tissue.
And is that surgery
safer or more dangerous?
It's simpler, but that's
not the only factor here.
It's the only factor to us.
We want to know
that our daughter
won't spend the
rest of her life in pain.
Please. For a moment,
can we think about something
other than Mara's pain?
Can we think about her pleasure?
We have a chance
to give her a healthy,
meaningful sex life.
That is what she
came here looking for.
Wake her up.
She's in pain, and she's
already told me what she wanted.
Yesterday, she was
requesting cosmetic surgery.
Today, you're asking her to risk
a lifetime of pain for
a chance at pleasure.
From everything I've heard,
she's mature enough
to make the call herself,
even if it means suffering
for a few minutes to do so.
Dr. Unger has a mortality index
that is not too high and not too low.
It's not gonna be Unger.
You have not eliminated Dr. Ko.
Not yet.
I may have to go out of
state to find a neurosurgeon.
Plus, I may have to find
myself a new oncologist.
You've used Dr. Ko many times.
Did you think she
might kill your patients?
No.
Do you think you're
better than them?
Yes. A little.
That was a joke.
You don't want
to talk about this.
No, I don't want to
talk about this, Shaun.
That, in fact, is the
point of the alcohol.
Okay, I understand.
Good.
Why can't we talk about it?
Because it's upsetting.
Is that why you're stalling?
Because you're afraid of dying?
I'm not afraid of dying.
Really? Why not?
You should be.
Dying is terrible.
Yes, dying is terrible,
but there are worse things.
What's worse than dying?
Not dying.
That doesn't make sense.
Makes sense to me.
It's the middle ground, Shaun.
Brain surgeries have a tendency
to end in the middle ground.
Brain surgeries can be
considered a success,
even when the patient
ends up compromised.
He can't walk. He can't talk.
His hand can't stop shaking.
I've been terrible at a
lot of things in my life,
but I am damn smart,
and I am a damn good surgeon.
And if I can't be those things,
then I don't know who I'd be.
You'd be my friend.
Well, thank you, Shaun.
I have to go. My
patient just crashed.
It's not enough, is it?
No. I'm sorry. It isn't.
Mom? Dad?
We're here. We love you.
We just don't understand
why you'd turn your back...
Hello, Mara. I'm Ellen
Vahtra. I'm a social worker.
Your parents know what happened,
and Dr. Lim gave you a nerve block.
- It hurts. It still hurts.
- I understand that,
and we are going to try to get you
back to sleep as quickly as possible.
But something
happened during surgery,
and we need you to make a
decision about what is done next.
We believe that despite what
was done to you as a child,
the reason you're in so much
pain is because you still have
functioning nerves
in your clitoris.
Nerves that had been
covered with scar tissue.
I'd like to repair that. We can
make you physiologically complete.
But there's no
guarantee that will work.
I am confident.
There is a safer choice.
We could remove
your entire clitoris.
This is your choice.
You will be protected,
no matter what.
- Take it out.
- Mara, we could make you whole...
I made a mistake! Take it out.
She's on medication,
she's in pain...
Dr. Lim, please let
her go back to sleep.
And prepare to remove
the damaged tissue.
Hang fresh frozen plasma. It
looks like he's going into DIC.
Give me another hemostat.
BP's 71 over 53. We should
have warned the family.
Can't see anything in here. There's
too much blood. More suction.
I think you got
the hepatic artery.
A warning wouldn't
have made any difference.
Bleeding is not slowing down. We
need to ascend the aorta to the celiac.
- I need to see it to clamp it.
- They would have been prepared.
A-line systolic's 54.
He's bottoming out.
- No, they wouldn't.
- You two, shut up
and pack his abdomen with
laps while I sort through this mess.
I won't do it. Can we
appeal this? Do you know?
I've spoken with
our legal department.
Unless we can prove the
social worker was biased,
we're stuck with this ruling.
Well, then you're also
stuck with "I won't do it."
You're a good doctor.
This hospital will miss you.
You're gonna fire me because
I won't butcher a teenage girl?
Of course I am. This
hospital will face lawsuits,
suspensions, perhaps
criminal charges.
And this little girl will still
get the surgery you hate.
Could Dr. Lim at least
talk to Mara again?
You wanna wake
her up again in pain?
Every woman deserves the right to
make decisions about her sexuality
without her parents
hanging over her.
Okay.
When I was 15 years old, my
father caught me with a boy.
I mean, we weren't doing it,
but my top was off and,
well, it doesn't matter.
My father hit me.
I still have a small scar.
Our relationship was never the
same, but that's what growing up is.
Not everyone gets called a slut,
not everyone gets butchered,
but everyone becomes
a man or a woman
and stops being a child.
I wanna take a piece of
tissue from inside your cheek,
and I wanna graft
it to your clitoris.
We can make you feel love.
I can't turn my back on
my family, on my traditions.
Traditions connect
us to the past.
What about the future?
Please. No. I'm in pain.
Cross-clamping his aorta.
He's in ventricular
fibrillation.
Starting chest compressions.
- Okay.
- Everybody, clear.
Prep the cheek as well.
She's taking the graft?
The paperwork doesn't say...
She consented verbally.
I didn't wanna keep her awake
longer than absolutely necessary.
I wanted to help
her as much as you,
when she wanted help,
but if she doesn't want this...
She wants this.
Dr. Lim just told us.
Prep the cheek.
I'll tell the family.
No. Claire, you do it.
This isn't the
time for learning.
I'm sorry. Paul
died during surgery.
He had a gastroduodenal
artery rupture.
It is a common complication
of a Whipple surgery,
especially when someone's
cancer was as advanced as his was.
We did everything we
could, for as long as we could.
He didn't suffer.
You did this to him.
Dad didn't want this.
You saw that look on
his face. He was scared.
In my experience, it
does no good to dwell on...
Of course he was scared.
That doesn't mean...
He just wanted to live
his last few months...
Stop it. Nobody made
your father do anything.
He knew the risks.
It's your fault, too, Mom.
All of us.
He would do anything for us.
We killed our father.
It's not true.
Paul wanted this surgery.
He told me he
wanted this surgery.
Was that true?
Paul told me
when the truth can't help
someone, we should lie.
Mom?
How are you? Does anything hurt?
Not much. I'm better.
Looks like she's doing well.
Thank you, Doctor.
There should still be some
discomfort at the surgical site.
A nurse will bring you some...
Sorry. A nurse will
bring you some Tylenol,
which should really
be all you need.
Thank you.
You're gonna be great.
You're here?
Yes. I live here. You know that.
Well, I was starting to doubt
it the last couple of days.
You come home after I'm asleep.
You leave before I
can even get up. Wow.
Thank you.
Please take this.
No, this is yours, Shaun.
I gave it to you to
remember me by.
It hurt.
I didn't want to tell you the
truth because I didn't know it,
but I have to tell you the
truth because it will help.
Every night, I would come home,
and I would look
at that baseball,
and I would think of you.
The baseball was
here, but you weren't.
- That's sweet.
- No, it isn't!
It hurt. You hurt me.
Okay, Shaun, you know...
You went away, and it
hurt, and it kept hurting,
and now you're back.
If you stay, you will go away
again, and it will hurt again.
So, I want you to
go back to Hershey.
I know you don't
mean that, and I know...
Please, go back to Hershey,
or anywhere other than here.
Feeling okay?
Yeah, sure. Super-duper.
I wanna thank
you for your trust.
I will do my best to deserve it.
Well, that's all I can ask.
You know the drill.
Ten,
nine,
eight,
seven...