For most people, a
hospital is a scary place.
A hostile place.
Sorry.
It's mine.
A place where bad things happen.
You can't pay with that.
Oh, it's, uh... it's my AA chip.
- Six months sober.
- Good for you.
Most people would
prefer church. Or school.
Or home.
Damn it, will you stop crying?
You stop crying.
But I grew up here.
While my mom was on rounds,
I learned to read
in the OR gallery.
I played in the morgue.
I colored with crayons
on old ER charts.
A hospital was my church.
My school.
My home.
A hospital was my safe place.
My sanctuary.
I love it here.
Correction: loved it here.
- No way.
- Yeah.
- No freaking way!
- Right?
Oh, my God. OK, um...
- Were you trying to...
- No! Total accident.
- I used the thing.
- Oh. So are we
happy about this?
Or are we exercising
our legal right to choose?
OK! All right!
- Congratulations! Let's hug it out.
- OK.
- My God... Have you told him?
- No, I just found out.
- Teddy.
- Derek.
- You gonna tell him now?
- Yeah.
- OK.
- How's the Teddy
and Owen thing going?
Oh, fantastic. It's going
great. I'm completely over it.
This is very adult.
I'm really proud of
you, Meredith Grey.
- I'm... proud of me, too?
- Yes, yes.
OK.
- Hey, I hope it has his hair.
- Me, too!
You know where I can find
the chief of surgery? Excuse me.
- Chief of surgery?
- No idea. Sorry.
Go ask a nurse if
you can find him.
- You paged?
- She's in a lot of pain.
- OK.
- Ruby Kendall. Age nine.
Fever, tenderness
over McBurney's point.
All right, appendix.
Let me check your belly.
Ow!
Oh... Yeah, you have
a very angry appendix.
That's surgery?
She needs surgery?
Yes, she does. But the good news
is, it's the easiest surgery in the world.
I mean, she's a baby
surgeon and she could do it.
You're gonna let me do it?
You're going to let
her do the surgery?
No, of course not. I'm gonna
do it. I'm kind of fabulous at it.
Ruby, you are gonna be
out of here by tomorrow
with a teeny, tiny little scar,
and a good excuse to have
your parents feed you ice cream
every night of the week.
Dr. Grey, admit her to peds
and make sure she's comfortable
while we get an OR.
- What?
- Jason Perkins, six-year-old
with a comminuted
tibia fracture.
You could be nicer. He peed his pants
and I cleaned it up before you got here.
Sorry. Good man, Alex. Thanks.
Hi.
You got paged, too?
Come on, Teddy. Cristina's not
talking to me, you're not talking to me.
- Come on.
- I don't want to talk about it.
I don't want to go over again how
you told Derek to give my job away.
I don't want to discuss it, or hear you
apologize or forgive you, or anything.
You know what I want?
A little bit of peace.
- What do you got?
- 18-gauge. Get ready to move.
- Shut up.
- I'm sorry. I'm truly sorry.
- Honey, are you hearing this?
- I told you.
- You know, I told her, Dr. B.
- That doesn't mean I like it.
I really can't have my
second surgery today?
Dr. Percy.
Your hemoglobin and
hematocrit are extremely low.
Your tank is empty. You need a
blood transfusion before we can operate.
- Shut up.
- Yes, ma'am.
Do you know how long I've
been living with a colostomy bag?
A bag of my poop
is attached to me.
Do you know what that's like?
It's gross.
It's truly the grossest thing
I've ever had to deal with.
And I'm starving, because I can't eat
solid food for 24 hours before surgery.
Starving. I would
eat you if I could.
Yeah, on the plus side, that
means no poop in the bag.
- Bill!
- OK, we're gonna
get blood in you
and Dr. Percy is gonna
monitor your blood levels.
And tomorrow, we'll see if
we can help lose the poop bag.
Let's get you some food
so you don't eat Dr. Percy.
- I don't like him
but he's useful.
- Can I have real food?
Like pizza? From that one
place near that one spot?
With pepperoni and
sausage and ham?
If you get the pizza, you also get the
bowel prep and enema that comes with it.
Totally worth the
pizza. Bring it on.
Back in 15 minutes.
- How hot is my husband's ass?
- It's very hot, ma'am.
He's dead, isn't he?
- Is he dead?
- He's not dead, ma'am.
You can't go in there.
The doctors are working.
He has a serious gunshot
wound. They need to concentrate.
They said he was
in a car accident.
He was shot? Someone shot him?
- I don't...
- Oh!
Pete! Oh, my God, Pete!
- Please, wait... Pete? Pete?
- Extend your incision.
- This guy hit me.
- Good.
I stopped the car to give
him my insurance card.
- Stats are still dropping.
- I get out and he shoots me.
I'm in. Chest tube.
Pete... Pete?!
- Bag him.
- Pete!
There's blood in the
chest. Clamp that!
Call the OR, tell
'em we're on our way.
- Get him ready for transport.
- - They're taking him to surgery.
- Please, he's my husband!
- Let her say goodbye.
Owen, there's no time.
Goodbye, baby. I love
you. I love you, OK?
Don't die, 'cause I love you!
Oh, God! What's happening?
- Out of here, now!
- Chest tube secure!
- There wasn't time to waste.
- There was time.
That might be the last time she sees
the man she loves. There was time.
You paged? You
heading to the OR?
Yeah, but I need you to
cover my post ops, I'm sorry.
- I'm not going into surgery?
- Cristina.
I'm talking to Dr. Altman.
- I need you
to cover my post ops.
- OK, fine. No problem.
Let's go.
- MRI?
- Yeah.
We're running!
Watch out! Coming through.
Clear that line!
Excuse me, I was asking if someone
could tell me where I can find the chief.
I'm sorry, sir. If you could
just give me a minute, OK?
Coming through!
- The lead was loose.
- I'll
let him know. Hold on.
- Excuse me, ma'am?
- It's "doctor," what?
I was wondering if you could tell me
where I can find Dr. Derek Shepherd?
Um... You know, I don't know.
Can you tell me where his
office is? I'm kind of turned around.
Sir, I have a patient having seizures
in there. Find a nurse and ask them.
- Ma'am...
- You're not supposed
to be back here.
I'm not a tour guide.
I'm a surgeon, OK?
Dude, what the...?
Hey! You paged?
I like to say hello to
my wife every 48 hours.
You didn't come home last night.
I told you, every Tuesday
night, I'm trolling for cases.
Last night, a guy
crashed his motorcycle,
had rebar jammed
in the base of his skull
and Shadow Shepherd
let me do the extraction.
You know what I've
been doing? Paperwork.
Know what I have to look
forward to today? More paperwork.
This job is just... I would love to
have something jammed in my brain.
That way I'd see
the inside of an OR.
OK, well... Are you gonna
come home early tonight?
Because we can order in and
I have some stuff to tell you.
Yeah, I'll be there.
I have to go. I'm
on Sloan's post ops.
I hate that you're so happy.
Derek, there's gonna be a
lot of dirty sex for you tonight.
Look forward to that.
Hm... Hm.
I'm looking at injuries to the
pulmonary artery and the vein.
- Hold pressure in there.
- More lap bands.
I'm going to try a
temporary Satinsky clamp.
Dr. Altman, Mr. Linehan has
hemolytic anemia and elevated LDH.
I suspect post-operative TTP. Shall
I start exchange plasmapheresis?
- Yes. Good catch, Cristina.
- Hold on, Dr. Yang.
We need to open up the
pericardium to gain proximal control.
Dr. Yang should scrub in and
Mr. Linehan can wait for an hour.
No, thank you. I'd
rather not scrub in.
Keep this stable.
Dr. Altman, I'll be right back.
- Cristina.
- You pursued me. I didn't.
I gave you an out, and
you pursued me. You said...
Do you love her?
Or do you love me?
I'm done. We're done.
- Cristina...
- We're done.
No...
Dr. Kepner...
- April, what is it?
- Do you know I grew up
on a farm?
- What happened?
- I...
I grew up on a farm, so you
know, blood doesn't bother me, I...
I slaughtered a pig once.
That was a lot of blood.
"Bleeding like a stuck
pig." That's a saying.
To bleed like a pig, you
know. It means something.
But you don't think of people
as having that much blood.
I mean, you learn in med school
how many pints we all have in us,
but you don't realize
it until you see it.
You don't get how much blood...
And a skinny person? I mean, my
God, Reed, she's almost anorexic.
She's like, five pounds, you wouldn't
think she'd have that much blood,
- but she did. She did...
- April, April, April!
You're in shock. It's all
right. Tell me what happened.
Reed's dead.
Someone shot her.
Excuse me, could you tell
me where to find the chief?
Dr. Shepherd? He's
probably in his office.
Yeah, I've been
to his office before.
Can't seem to remember
how to get there.
Keep going in circles.
It's in the east wing. That's
over by labs, across the catwalk.
Sorry, that's...
You've just gotta cross
through the patient floor on three,
then follow the signs
to the main lobby
and you should
find it, no problem.
- Thank you.
- Mm-hm.
Have a nice day.
You, too.
The police are on their
way. What's the procedure?
You're the head of hospital
security. How do you not know?
I know it's never
happened before.
I found it. "Lockdown.
Nobody moves in or out."
Yeah. Nobody moves, nobody
breathes until we know what's going on.
Here...
Police are almost here.
I'm gonna leave you
here. You OK by yourself?
You're leaving... You just said
that nobody leaves,
nobody moves...
Nobody but me.
I'm the chief.
This is my hospital.
- But what if you
get shot, or...
- Be right back. I'm the chief.
- Jason Perkins?
- Got the chart here somewhere.
- Peds?
- Can you page
the younger Dr. Grey?
Tell her to get my appy moving?
We're on lockdown.
- What? Why?
- Oh, come on.
It's a joke, right? It's
a drill or something?
OK. It's no joke.
Everyone... everyone!
We're sealing the floor.
I don't know why and
it doesn't matter why
but nobody goes in or
out, past the double doors.
Check on your own patients and
then come back and check and see
if there's any others in the queue.
We don't have a lot of hands on deck.
And people, do not alarm
the makers of the tiny humans.
They will eat you alive.
- I really thought
that was a joke.
- Sick joke.
- Excuse me?
- Uh... Nothing.
What? You can't be stuck
on the same floor as me?
- That's a hardship for you?
- Yeah. Frankly, it is.
- Hey, how are you?
- Bill hasn't come back
with pizza yet.
So, still starving.
But, full of fresh blood,
which is disgusting.
- Like I'm a vampire.
- Mary, you complain too much.
But I do it with a smile.
Face it, I'm an awesome
patient. I make your day.
Let's see...
- What's wrong?
- Nothing, just a... page.
I can't get control
of this artery.
- He's crashing!
- I need more light
and another clamp!
- How's it going in here?
- Touch and go!
Avery, got a second?
- Has anybody
checked their pager?
- No, too busy.
There's a shooter
in the hospital.
I don't want you to say a
word. When the patient is stable,
I want you to tell
Hunt and Altman
that nobody goes out
of here until they are told.
- Can you handle this?
- Yes, sir.
All right, then.
OK, BP is dropping.
I've almost got the
pulmonary artery controlled.
- One more second.
- What did Shepherd want?
Dr. Avery?
Nothing, just wanted to know
how long we'd be. He needs the OR.
OK, get in here and suction
around where Dr. Altman's working.
Shaky hands, Dr. Avery?
Won't make it as a surgeon if
you can't keep your hands steady.
Yes, sir.
Hey.
Did you get that page? Lockdown?
Yeah, I mean, whatever.
It means we can't leave.
I never leave here
anyway, so what do I care?
Know what? It's probably just a
drill. Or a psych patient got out.
Or a baby went
missing from the nursery.
Or there's an axe
murderer on the loose.
- Axe murderer would be fun.
- Mm-hm.
So? How did he react?
Was his world made whole because
your womb is not empty and dry?
Did he weep like a bitch baby?
I didn't tell him because
he was in a mood.
So I'll tell him later tonight or
something. It should be special, right?
Well, you found out in the
ladies' room squatting over a stick.
That wasn't very special.
Why does he get special?
I don't know. I feel like
my head's gonna pop off
because I haven't told him
and I want to and I hate that.
It's good news. He
should know, right?
Mm-hm.
- You know what? I'm telling him now.
- OK.
- What...?
- I'm coming.
- I wanna see
the bitch baby tears.
- Cristina...
I'll stand in the hallway.
He'll never know I'm there.
I, um...
- I broke up with Owen, OK?
- Oh.
OK, come on.
They want attending approval to
do the auditory evoked potentials.
- Can you sign for it?
- Lockdown.
Kind of crazy, right?
Think it's serious?
- Can you just sign...
- This Karev thing serious?
- Mark...
- I miss you.
- Can you just sign the order?
- Sir, you can't leave this
area.
The hospital is in...
- Get down,
get down! Get down!
- What just happened?!
Let's get out of here!
No. No, no, no...
- No, no, no.
- Come on!
- She's dead. She's dead.
- Come on. I'm getting you
out of here.
- Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
- Come on! Come on!
Two more units on that side!
Goes corner to corner.
- Waiting for a...
- OK, let's go.
Excuse me.
Guys, go around...
Have you talked to
the administrator? Sir!
- Officer! What's the situation?
- You gotta stand back.
I'm Richard Webber. I'm
the chief... I'm the former...
Look, this is my
hospital. What's going on?
A shooter took down
one of the doctors.
We're not sure whether or
not he's still inside. No, sir!
No one in, no one out. The
SWAT team is on the way, sir.
- No one in, no one out.
- Are you evacuating people?
- Are you getting them out?
- Department policy
is a lockdown.
Until we know who the
shooter is, where the shooter is,
everyone stays
in the same place.
- It's safer that way.
- Those are my people!
- If someone is shooting...
- My guys have this. We do.
We're gonna take care of it.
OK?
OK.
What happened?
I grabbed everything
I could think of.
I am so incredibly
pissed off right now.
- Alex, you've been shot.
- - Have to get him out of here.
He could come back, Mark.
We have to get him out of here.
There's no exit wound.
No exit wound. We're
gonna have to flip him.
Lexie, grab him
under the shoulders.
We have to get him out of here.
He's losing blood. We can't
move him, now shut up and help!
Nothing. Damn, the bullet's
still in there somewhere.
We're gonna have to wing it.
Start an IV. I'll set
up a chest tube.
You're gonna be
OK, Alex. All right?
I'm gonna kick that
guy's ass when I see him.
Has anyone seen
Olivia Kagan's chart?
I need albuterol meds
for the asthma kid.
Time for 18's dose of
ceftriaxone. 34 needs his mommy
and the kid in 35
won't stop crying.
We have, what, 42 kids? Four doctors
and nine nurses? That's not enough.
Why don't you put all
the kids in the playroom?
We don't have enough
staff for a whole floor.
At least they'll all
be in one place.
We can keep an
eye on all at once.
You can't put a bunch of sick
kids in the playroom with their beds.
Sure we can.
Stable ones can walk
and we have wheelchairs,
so let's do it. Move.
- Thanks!
- Whatever.
- Do you want to talk about it?
- No.
- Owen, I mean.
- I know what you mean.
I don't want to...
I can't. It's just...
OK, he doesn't
know who he loves.
And if it's not me, then... I
don't want to talk about it.
- Let's talk about
something else.
- OK.
You realize you're
about to be a godmother.
I'm godmother?
OK, what do I have to do? Talk God
to the fetus? I'm not gonna do that.
It means you take
care of the kid if I die.
Derek takes care
of the kid if you die.
If we die, if we die.
OK, so, if you and Derek are
in a plane crash and you die,
- the kid is mine?
- Yes.
Have to admit, I kinda hope
you and Derek die, just a little bit.
So I can raise the kid
with decent priorities.
- I have priorities.
- Oh?
- Surgery.
- OK, then.
You can raise a good
little surgeon. I take it back.
Hey, what are you doing here?
- Uh... Walking.
- We're in lockdown.
We're not walking outside.
That's not what lockdown means.
It means stay where you are.
- Did you know that's what...?
- No, I thought it meant...
- Get in here.
- Why are we...?
There's a shooter
loose in the hospital.
- What?
- Stay here. Don't move.
I'll come back and
get you when it's clear.
Just stay here. Don't move.
Your pulse is coming down.
We have to check
your blood counts,
but I think you'll be good
to go for surgery tomorrow.
That's the fifth time
you've checked your pager.
Uh... It's... habit.
Dr. B., my husband's
late. He's never late.
And you're hanging out with me.
You don't really strike me
as the hanging out type.
What's going on?
OK, there is a situation.
I'm not exactly sure what it is,
but hospital procedure dictates
- that when we're on a...
- He's on the floor.
- Who?
- The shooter.
A shoot... There's a
shooter in the hospital?
Oh, my God.
It's all right, all right?
Put the gun down. Come
on, man, don't do anything.
No, please!
- Dr. Percy, hide!
- What?
Just hide! Mary, play dead.
Wait, what's happening?
Shh! Just do not
move. Do not breathe.
Dr. Percy, go hide now!
Oh...
This is too much.
OK... OK...
OK...
OK. OK.
- Please, I...
- Are you a surgeon?
Please.
Are you a surgeon?
Yes, sir. Yes, sir, I am.
Oh, no. No, no! No, please!
No! Don't!
Are you a surgeon?
Answer me!
No!
No! I'm a...
a nurse. I'm a nurse.
I'm a... nurse.
I'm sorry...
for the trouble.
For the mess.
I'm sorry.
You're doing great,
Alex, really great. Now...
I need to put in a chest
tube. You're with me, OK?
No chest tube.
I'm OK. Don't cut me.
Lexie, you get the Betadine
ready. I'll do the rest, OK?
OK.
Oh, my God.
Shut him up. Shut him up.
Oh, my God. Oh, God.
Shhh!
Alex...
OK, OK...
Shut him up, Lexie. If that guy
with the gun hears the screaming,
he's gonna head this way.
Now do something to shut him up!
OK, OK. Alex? Shh!
I know that it hurts,
but you have to be quiet.
OK?
Lexie!
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. Shh...
The bad news is, less
privacy. But the good news is,
your bunny can make friends with
a very attractive bear down the hall.
- Hey, watch it.
- Sorry. Sorry.
I thought we were
gonna be friends.
You want to talk about this now?
We're in lockdown, moving kids,
God knows what's happening,
- and you wanna talk about this?
- We're stuck here.
We have to be together, so,
yeah, I wanna talk about this.
OK. Fine.
I tried being friends.
Rising above. Tried
that and I'm over it.
I'm gonna go the more traditional
route of totally hating your guts.
OK.
Christopher? Tyler.
Tyler? Christopher.
You both hate chicken. Discuss.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, I
don't deserve this, OK?
I have treated you with
nothing but respect and love...
You think you have,
but you haven't.
I'm sure it feels great to
act like I'm the bad guy,
but that's the biggest
load of you-know-what.
I've spent the last month
trying to convince myself
that I don't need
kids to be happy.
Giving lectures to myself, saying
it out loud to you and to Mark.
Turning myself inside out
to want what you wanted
and then I stopped and I
thought: Did you ever try?
To imagine what it would
be like? To change for me?
Because I don't think you
did. You dismissed my dream.
Which says to me that you
don't give a rat's ass if I'm happy.
I never understood squat about who
you are and now I do and I don't like it.
Oh, really, really?
I'm supposed to change for
you? Why? 'Cause we're in love?
Because you fall
in love all the time.
- Men, women...
- Excuse me! Dr. Robbins.
I don't feel good!
Oh, my. Oh, my...
- He shot me. He shot me. I'm shot.
- You're going to be OK.
Mary, over there, some gauze
and surgical pads. Get them for me.
No, I gotta go. I gotta go
home. We shouldn't be here.
My husband, I have
to find my husband.
- And that man,
he could come back...
- Mary!
You're not going anywhere.
That man is not coming back.
I need you to pull yourself
together and bring me those supplies.
OK?
- I was doing charts
and now I'm shot?
- OK, you're just fine.
You're just fine.
Good, very good.
OK...
All right, Mary?
Go over to the window
and see if there's anybody
out there that can help us.
Mary, come on, come on!
Go to the window now! See if
somebody can help us. Go on.
Go on! OK?
Um... There's... There's...
a dead security guard.
He's dead.
There's no one else to help us.
There's no one else.
That's fine.
That's...
Where's that...
water coming from?
Dr. Bailey? You're crying.
You're crying.
Mary, you need to come over,
wipe my face so I can keep working.
OK, OK, OK...
OK. We're all gonna be fine.
- OK, he's ready for transport.
- Jackson, get him up to ICU.
- Start warming him up...
- I can't, sir.
- Excuse me?
- We can't leave here.
That's what Shepherd told me.
There's a shooter
in the hospital.
- We're supposed to...
- There's a what?
- Shepherd said...
- This patient is hypothermic.
Start warming him up before
he starts to circle the drain.
You didn't bother to
mention this until now?
- You didn't bother...
- Shepherd said...
You already told me
what Shepherd said!
OK...
I'll take him up myself.
Everyone else, stay here.
- I'm coming.
- No, you stay put.
I'm a cardiothoracic surgeon. He
has a penetrating injury to his chest.
You don't get a vote this
time. I'm coming. Let's go.
OK.
Her blood pressure's
90/60 and dropping.
Let's hang more fluids.
I have the portable ultrasound.
Check her
appendix. I'll be back!
When are you gonna forgive me for
not being a good enough lesbian for you?
When you do convince me
that you're falling in love with me
and not with being in love.
When you convince me that I'm
different than George O'Malley,
Erica Hahn, Mark Sloan,
the girl at the coffee cart...
You have a huge heart,
and I love that about you.
But I don't trust
you. Why would I?
Dr. Robbins!
Her appendix...
- You OK?
- I've been hurling
every day this week,
around... yep, right on schedule.
OK, we gotta get out of here,
'cause I'm not staying in here
after you stink up this
place with your vomit.
Oh, my God! Meredith, get down!
- What, what?
- Shh, shh!
- I...
- Shh!
That's the guy
from the elevator.
- What do you mean?
- It's the guy
from the elevator.
He asked me for directions,
how to get to the chief's office.
- I don't...
- Meredith,
the guy with the gun
is looking for Derek.
Dr. Shepherd?
Sir, you shouldn't
be here. It's not safe.
I know it's not safe here.
That's the point.
This hospital isn't safe.
You don't recognize me, do you?
Mr. Clark.
Sorry, I have a situation. You should
go someplace safe so you don't get hurt.
I'm already hurt.
You hurt me when you
decided to kill my wife.
- BP's 60/palp.
- He's losing a lot of blood.
Damn it. He needs a transfusion.
I don't know what
we're gonna do.
I'll go. I'll go get it.
That's insane. I'll go.
No. I don't know what to do.
You know what to do. I don't...
I can't do nothing.
Alex?
Don't die. Please don't die.
OK? It's me. It's Lexie.
I will be right back.
Hey, Sloan.
Try not to kill me.
Doing my best.
- Oh, my God.
- Mr. Clark.
- Shut up. No talking.
You're not the man here.
I'm the man.
I told my wife I would be.
And a man looks after
his wife. But I didn't.
I let you decide
that she should die.
I wasn't a man then.
But I'm a man now.
No, no, no...
Mary, Mary, see the
sticky circles there?
Give me three of those.
There. And... Mary! Get
me three of those, please.
And the other thingy.
Yeah.
- It's this thing?
- No, not that.
The other thing with the wires.
- I'm dying.
- Shh! Shh! No, you're not dying.
Don't lie to me.
Don't tell me that
lie we tell everybody,
"You're fine.
You're doing great."
Don't lie to me.
Please, you gotta promise
to tell me the truth, OK?
You are not dying. If you
were, I would tell you, OK?
OK.
OK, that's there...
Shh! You are not dying!
Mary, hold Dr. Percy's
hand, please.
Stay here.
What kind of hospital is this?
It isn't safe here.
Somebody has to
protect people. From you.
Handing down
judgments like you're God.
- Mr. Clark...
- You don't get to be God!
No talking!
Mr. Clark, listen to me.
I know your loss.
I lost my father.
When I was a kid.
Two guys killed my
father for his watch.
Right in front of me.
I didn't become a doctor
because I wanted to be God.
I became a doctor because
I wanted to save lives.
Look at me.
Please.
Look at me in the eye.
I'm a human being.
I make mistakes.
I'm flawed.
We all are.
Today, I think... for
you, it's just a mistake.
You want justice.
You want somebody to pay.
You're a good man. I
can see that in your eyes.
Can you see it in mine?
Can you?
Dr. Shepherd! Thank
God you're back!
I learned to read
in the OR gallery.
I played in the morgue.
I colored with crayons
on old ER charts.
A hospital was my
church. My school.
My home. My safe place.
My sanctuary.
I love it here.
Correction: Loved it here.