Your family, whatever that means.
If you're single, if you're married,
if you have kids or if you want kids,
your family should be
the most important thing.
And your family
is the most important thing to us.
ADDISON:
What are you doing?
I'm supporting my eating disorder.
Using handbags to fill the sexual void.
Emotional health
is as important as physical health.
I create a safe place to talk.
Well, I am avoiding Sam's kisses.
I'm avoiding Dell's kisses.
I am avoiding being kissed.
- I'm gonna donate my lips to chocolate.
- Yeah.
Well, the cop still hasn't called.
Two weeks, no call.
These lips? Dry.
Virgin lips untouched by a man.
[GASPS]
I am having sex with Bottega Veneta.
I put my hands inside a woman's body
and fix what's wrong.
But every woman's body is different.
Every woman's story is different.
We get our bonus checks this week,
and I say we blow it all
on Mnemba Island.
It's Zanzibar, Coop. It's unsullied.
Let's go sully it.
Cooper?
Are you listening?
Gonna have to call you back.
How do you know you're doing what's best
to take care of your child?
Who's gonna help you
if the baby won't eat,
isn't gaining enough weight,
has a fever?
That's my job.
Come here to me, now.
I use Eastern medicine
to prevent illness.
I solve problems before they start.
PETE: So I waited outside
Addison's house for, like, two hours.
She didn't show up.
I don't wait outside women's houses.
She should be waiting.
- Does she even know you're interested?
- She'll know. I'm on it.
- She has you on a string.
- Yeah? You get anywhere with Naomi?
Hey, that's not the point.
Okay, I'm not on a string.
I'm in charge. I'm in control.
I got this.
Yeah, how do you have this?
I don't know yet.
A doctor's office should be a sanctuary.
The care you receive
should be personal.
It's good.
Really good.
Naomi did a good job.
It looks like it cost way more
than she said it would cost.
Is this gonna affect our bonus checks?
- I need my bonus check.
- You're gonna get your check.
PETE:
We sound professional,
but is it just me
or is it a Gap ad for medicine?
Yeah, we're branded.
We're a brand like a perfume.
Symptoms, a fragrance for men.
- Dell, what did you think?
- You cut my line.
I wasn't even in it.
Not one single shot of me.
SAM: Your wives.
PETE: Your husbands.
At Oceanside Wellness,
our family takes care of your family.
- I really need my bonus check, Sam.
- Yeah. Sam, bonus checks.
Everybody's getting their bonus checks.
- She's avoiding me.
- I'll talk to her.
Nai, the video looks good.
Yeah, it's gonna run on the Internet,
in the lobby on the monitors,
and I also lined up a group of dentists
who are gonna show it in their offices.
It cost a lot of money,
but you spend money to make money.
That's the goal. Make money.
- You okay?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
- Your files, and these.
- Thank you, Dell.
If you have time,
we should have a meeting.
I have wall-to-wall patients today, so...
Okay.
He try to kiss you again?
Did Sam? Because I'll punch him.
Verbally, I mean.
I can do verbal punching for you.
I would do that for you.
- Nai, are you...? What's wrong?
- Nothing. I am fine.
I've got patients.
What happened to the paper cups?
They're not justifiable. Environmentally.
VIOLET: Mugs. Are they justifiable?
DELL: In the dishwasher.
VIOLET: Cooper, guess who's been
to the travel agent?
Mnemba Island.
Zanzibar.
Don't you feel drunk just looking at it?
I don't know if I can go away this year.
- We go away every year.
- I have a patient. We'll talk about it later.
- Dr. King.
- Dr. Freedman.
I assume you're here
on important hospital business.
- I am.
- Well, let's talk.
COOPER:
Can I tell people about us?
CHARLOTTE: What?
- I mean, just Violet.
It's getting secret-y. I don't do secret-y.
And my bonus check comes this week.
You wanna pay me for the sex?
I thought we could use the money
to go away together on vacation.
You and me on a vacation?
COOPER:
Yeah, like a normal couple.
I tell Violet everything.
She's like my sister.
She's like my hot sister,
and we use our bonus checks
to go away every year.
- But I think if I went away without you...
- Do not say it.
- I might miss you.
- Cooper.
- Yes?
- Either get back on top of me and shut up
or keep talking
and watch me walk out that door.
- There is a lack of paper cups.
- Dell's going green.
- So, what are you doing with your bonus?
- Maybe buying paper cups.
Do you wanna go out sometime?
- Out?
- On a date.
Well, that's... Uh...
Do you think that's wise?
- Is there someone else?
- Yes.
No. There was a person,
an officer of the law,
but we never connected,
so no, no, there's no one else.
Okay, then.
Think about it.
Hey, Molly Madison is on her way in.
NAOMl: She was just here
a couple of days ago. L...
Nervous mommies.
I do not have time for nervous mommies.
Hey, Addie.
Can you see a patient for me?
She's in Room...
- Four.
- Yeah, I have time.
NAOMl:
Thank you.
- What's her story?
- She's just got the jitters.
It'll be 10 minutes, tops.
So Pete asked me out. Do I go?
No, I mean, do I go
with the dry, untouched lips and all?
I'm making human life here.
Patient. I will see her now.
NAOMl:
Thank you.
Hi.
You asked me out
and then you blew me off. Hi.
I didn't blow you off.
I had training for the SWAT team.
- I'm SWAT now.
- You show that to all the girls?
No, just the cute ones.
But I'm here now. I'm available.
I have a patient,
and you are just a stranger.
Some guy I met, you know.
And I don't get blown off.
I'm not the kind of woman you blow off.
- You have your pride.
- I have my pride, yes.
Go away. Go SWAT something.
Molly, Eric?
Hi, I'm Dr. Montgomery.
- Where's Dr. Bennett?
- She has another patient.
We need to see Dr. Bennett.
Well, why don't we just see
if I can find out what the problem is first?
Let's see.
Twenty-seven weeks pregnant,
ultrasound from two days ago
looks good.
Oh, it's a girl,
and placenta positioning looks good,
so, what's the concern?
I need to have this baby.
Well, everything's on track.
No, that's not what l... Eric.
We need to have this baby now.
- Today, if possible.
- I'm sorry, I'm not understanding.
You're only six months pregnant...
You have to induce or do a C-section
so that I can have this baby.
Today.
It has to be born. Please, just...
He'll die if you don't.
He is dying, damn it.
I'm sorry. Who is dying?
Our son, Jason. He's 7.
He has acute lymphoblastic leukemia.
The baby's cord blood
is the only thing that can save him.
SAM: You're avoiding me.
- I am not avoiding you.
I've just been busy running the practice
and raising our daughter.
Always keeping the trains
running on time.
Trains or no trains, we will talk.
- Do you have a minute?
NAOMl: No.
No, she does not.
What?
Molly and Eric Madison.
You selected the embryo
that matched their dying son.
And implanted it. Selective IVF.
You chose a genetic match
for their dying son
and impregnated her?
Yes. I do not understand
what the problem is here.
The problem is that
she's carrying a child.
Except to her it's not a child.
It's an organ donor to her.
- She's growing organs for her sick son.
- Not organs.
The umbilical-cord blood
is gonna be collected at birth, processed,
then infused into her son
to save his life.
Same thing, Nai.
Morally, ethically, it's a gray area
to grow a child's genetic match.
This is done all the time as a backup.
But he is dying now,
and she wants her daughter delivered
three months premature
with no regard for the baby's health.
NAOMl:
Oh, God.
I didn't...
What...?
They had a partial-match donor.
The partial match has pneumonia.
Addison,
that means...
Their son has had his immune system
stripped in preparation for the donor.
He's in the hospital right now.
If he doesn't receive that cord blood
within the week, he dies.
What did you tell them
about delivering?
- I said no.
- Why?
Thank you for the update, Dr. King.
You're welcome, Dr. Freedman.
Hey, I was just...
So on Mnemba Island
there's no phones,
there's no computer,
there's no television.
Our bonus checks
will be put to very good use.
- Um... I don't know. Maybe.
- We can touch monkeys, Cooper.
- We can touch monkeys.
- You made that last part up.
- I have patients.
- I have patients too.
And as I'm seeing them,
part of me will be conjuring images
of touchable monkeys.
- Dean.
DEAN: Hey, Dr. Coop.
- How you doing?
- Good.
- How about you? How you been?
- Good month.
What I like to hear.
Dell, the new patient gowns blow.
They keep ripping.
We're working out the kinks
with new vendors.
What's wrong with old vendors?
Where...?
Dishwasher.
Everything looks good.
Everything at school good?
Good. I have a girlfriend, Amy.
- She's amazing.
- Good.
- You taking it slow?
- We haven't done it,
yet, but she's going on the pill
so we will soon.
Believe me when I say
I will not be the first of my friends.
No, I know, but condoms, okay?
Hey, STDs don't care about the pill.
Condoms are your friend.
Lots of condoms.
Or better yet, you know, wait.
If this is the girl,
you gotta enjoy the time before
because once you're on the other side,
you can't go back.
Hello. You just heard,
blah, blah, blah-blah-blah.
Dr. Freedman, I'm gonna have sex,
and I really like her.
It's not all skanky.
It's right.
I, like, love her and everything.
Well,
now I go back to my condom speech.
So I am your friendly neighborhood
condom pusher man.
Condoms.
If you can save their son
by delivering the baby, I don't...
Six-month preemies are at risk
for brain bleeds, blindness,
hearing loss,
not to mention respiratory distress.
And no one would advocate
bringing a child into the world
before she's ready, and you know it.
Did you even consider the fact that this
little girl is arriving into a family unwanted?
What happens when she discovers
that the reason she was conceived
was to save her brother?
We are talking about saving this family
from suffering the death of a child.
- You gave them hope they shouldn't have.
- I'm trying to save a child's life.
You discuss this stuff with us.
When any of us come
into an ethical gray area, we all discuss it.
We decide as a practice what to do.
I meant to, all right?
- I just forgot.
- Since when do you forget anything?
If I could get one guy to do
a colonoscopy with no complaint...
I mean, like I'm happy
about going all up in there.
What are you looking for?
I'm trying to leave you a note,
but I can't find a pen that works.
- Well, what's the note?
- How I can't find a pen that works.
Dell's decided to go green.
Tissue-paper gowns, no cups, no pens.
I'm about saving the planet,
but he's killing me.
- You want me to talk to Dell?
- We both know who Dell listens to.
Was this Naomi's idea?
I have no clue what Naomi's ideas are.
My woman's giving me trouble.
Your woman's giving you trouble.
These women, Cooper.
What?
Fourteen-year-old kid,
I've been treating him since he was 5.
He's found this girl, he likes her.
They're gonna have sex.
That's hardly a shocker.
But don't tell me
you're getting nostalgic.
It's Dean Miller.
- Oh, man.
- Why does that name sound familiar?
We debated whether
we should take him on as a patient.
He's the kid who...
He's HIV-positive,
but that wasn't the debate.
- He doesn't know he's HIV-positive.
- His parents won't tell him.
And he doesn't know
he could kill that girl.
He thinks he has a kidney condition
and he's doing quite well.
I mean, the majority of his symptoms
are from the antiviral cocktail.
How do you keep something
from your kid for 14 years?
It was before the prognosis changed.
They didn't think he was gonna be alive
to understand.
So that explains the first six years.
I'm not allowed to tell him
about the HIV.
I'm not allowed to tell the parents
anything Dean tells me.
Doctor-patient confidentiality all around.
Can't let them know
about the girlfriend.
No, or that they're gonna do it.
This is a good kid.
He would not endanger this girl
if he knew and he doesn't.
Hormones are full roar. He likes the girl,
he wants the girl, he's gotta have the girl.
- We've all been there.
- Yes, we have.
Anyway.
You know what? I've gotta try
to get his parents back in my office.
MOLLY:
He loves bugs.
He sneaks ladybugs into the house
in his pocket.
He likes meatballs and French fries.
And he's still afraid of the dark,
but he thinks he's too old to admit it,
so I have to pretend to forget
to turn off the light at bedtime.
And he likes to read.
And all he wants for his eighth birthday
is to never go to a hospital again.
He's a wonderful boy.
I can see that,
but Mrs. Madison, I can't.
In good conscience,
I can't deliver your baby early,
- because I'm sure she's wonderful too.
- We are good people.
And we didn't go into this lightly,
having this baby.
And we will love her, we will.
It's just we don't know her yet,
and I know Jason.
I've held Jason. I've smelled his skin.
I know Jason.
I'm so sorry.
MOLLY:
I've checked you out.
You're a specialist.
If anyone can deliver
a premature baby safely, it's you.
There's nothing I can do.
How can you look at my 7-year-old son
and know he's going to be dead
in a week and do nothing?
Please.
- Addison.
- Don't talk to me.
Don't say anything. Please don't.
Addison,
I was not trying to manipulate you.
I just thought if you saw him, maybe
you would realize that you can help them.
I can't help them.
You gave them hope they shouldn't have
and now I am the bad guy.
VIOLET:
Addison.
I told you not to say anything to me.
- Hey, I really do need to talk to you.
- Not now, Dell.
Are you okay?
SAM: What's going on?
PETE: Has there been bloodshed?
Because Naomi's in the kitchen
inhaling the candy supply.
Come on, it was low to begin with.
- Dell refuses to buy any new candy.
- He's withholding candy?
He told me to make do
with the SweeTarts from last Halloween.
Well, nobody can handle
old SweeTarts.
- We need chocolate.
- I told him...
This has nothing to do
with candy.
I can't do anything.
I can't save that child.
I can't deliver the baby
to the best of my medical expertise.
- I cannot do anything.
- Well, don't beat yourself up.
It's not your mess, it's Naomi's.
Wait, you mean the Madisons? Because
Naomi did what she thought was right.
You do what you need to do
to save your family.
She had no way of knowing the donor
would back out.
But we always discuss these things
as a group.
Naomi went ahead and did this
without talking to anybody.
Maybe she's off her game. She's seeing
a record number of patients a day.
- She's been really on edge lately.
- Yeah, it's not like her.
Well, guys, I mean,
she does everything.
We just eat the candy.
She's hiding something.
Has anybody even asked her
what's wrong?
- Where are you going?
- This I can do something about.
Who'd win in a fistfight?
Naomi or Addison?
- Not in the mood for a lecture.
- I'm not gonna lecture.
I'm gonna block the exits until you decide
to tell me what's going on with you.
- We're gonna be here a very long time.
- Well, I can wait.
COOPER: They're not saying anything?
They're standing.
- A test of wills.
- A battle of champions.
You guys are so immature.
Oh, yeah? You mentioned a fistfight.
That's true.
DELL:
Cooper.
Dean's parents are here.
And everyone else.
There's a lobby full of patients,
in case anyone is interested
in working here
or running this place.
ROBIN: There's a girl Dean likes,
but sex is a long way off.
I've had pregnant 13-year-olds
whose parents have said the same thing.
Dean needs to know his HIV status
before he starts experimenting.
- And he will.
COOPER: What I'm saying
is you can't afford to wait.
MARK: You have any idea
what it's like for HIV kids?
A kid in Chicago got shot.
Another kid, they tied him to a car bumper.
That's before people were educated.
Nobody needs to know but Dean.
ROBIN:
He's not old enough to deal with this.
Not yet. You want them to be children
as long as it lasts.
Things are so sweet,
they can still be anything.
- As soon as that's over...
- I wish it could be longer, but it can't.
You say people are educated,
they'll understand?
If it was your kid,
you wouldn't be so sure.
- Could you live with yourselves...?
- Do you not hear me?
If he gets another kid sick,
- what happens when he finds...?
MARK: We will do what's best for him.
- And don't you overstep here.
- You're not leaving me much choice.
Say one word to Dean
and I'll take your license.
I will sue you for everything you've got.
Nai. Come on, you can tell me anything.
It's not like you
to get the Madisons pregnant
without discussing it with the rest of us.
I know you must have had a good reason.
You have a good heart.
Just talk to me.
They paid the practice $80,000,
and I don't have a good heart.
They had cash and we needed the money
and so I took it,
even though I did have reservations,
because Naomi always keeps the trains
running on time.
What do you mean?
I keep the trains running on time.
That's what I do.
I run things, I mind the details.
I mean,
this time it just got away from me.
What got away from you?
You can't tell anybody. You cannot tell
the others. You have to promise.
What...? Okay, I promise.
What are you...?
You're talking about the practice?
We own the building,
and I saw a chance
to refinance the mortgage and I thought...
Now the balloon payment is due,
and no one is billing enough,
and there isn't enough.
There is never enough.
And so I used the last of the money
to make the video.
- Naomi.
- We are broke, Addison.
If things keep going the way
they have been, the practice is finished.
Soon.
COOPER: You know what? Screw them.
Let them come after me.
The jury is gonna back them
when they're happy
to let their son infect some girl
from the burbs?
The law says they have the right to do this
how they wanna do this.
I'm taking my chances.
I'm gonna tell Dean.
If they sue, they sue the practice.
Why don't you think about someone
other than yourself?
Naomi, Coop's just trying to do
the right thing here.
He's talking about getting us sued.
There are responsibilities.
So you think that family has the right
to hide important information
from each other?
Sometimes people hide things
for good reason.
- Hiding things is no way to protect them.
- It is when you're the one in charge.
- Whoa, whoa. Everybody breathe.
SAM: Cooper's gonna figure out a way.
He always does.
- Hey.
- Is it wise?
- Huh?
- Our date?
Oh. Um...
I haven't had time.
Can we talk about this tomorrow?
So you ready to talk yet?
No, I am not ready to talk.
About anything.
- Good night, guys.
- Okay.
- Wait. Hey, hey.
- Night.
These women.
- Shots?
- Yeah.
Cooper always figures out a way?
Cooper does not always
figure out a way.
Know what's gonna make you
feel better?
- Mnemba.
- Monkey touching.
- I have the pamphlets right here.
- Violet.
There's pretty girls in the pamphlets.
They might do dirty,
trashy things to you
when I'm in the spa.
Is that what this is about?
A girl? Is there...?
Do you have a woman
that I don't know about?
A non-cyber woman?
- There's no woman.
- Then what is it? It's bonus time.
We always blow half of it on sunburns
and hazy memories, Coop.
Violet, don't count on me this year.
[LAUGHING]
You wanna play
Naughty Little Schoolboy?
Mistress and Butler?
I could be the warden,
you could be my prisoner and...
How about boyfriend and girlfriend?
Damn it, Cooper.
You really know how to dry a girl up.
Okay, first of all, it was a suggestion.
And second of all, I lied today.
I told Violet a lie.
- I told her I wasn't seeing anybody.
- Rather lie to Violet
and play Naughty Schoolboy with me
or tell her the truth
and play with yourself?
Why do we have to keep it a secret?
Because you all
are one big incestuous family,
and I'm not joining the family.
This isn't that serious.
I'm sick of keeping secrets and I'm sick
of keeping secrets from my best friend.
So maybe you should just go.
I'm wearing crotchless panties, Coop.
No, no. No. I'm not your toy.
There's a lot of other things
I could be doing.
Better things. I could be traveling.
- I could be touching monkeys in Mnemba.
- Mnemba?
Zanzibar.
And you could be with me,
if you weren't pathologically allergic
to human relationships.
[DOOR CLOSES]
[SIGHS]
Crotchless panties.
SAM: Hey.
- Hey.
Did Naomi say anything to you?
What...?
- What do you mean?
- In the kitchen.
- Did she tell you what was wrong?
- Oh, no. I think she's just tired.
I think it's me.
I've been pressuring her
to talk about us.
I just wanted a second chance,
and I don't think
she wants to give it to me.
I think this is her way of telling me
that it's over between us.
No, Sam. I'm sure that's not what it is.
- Then what is it?
- It's like I said. She's just tired.
All right.
[ELEVATOR DINGS]
ADDISON: Yeah. All right, okay.
SAM: All right.
Addison?
He has no idea
what is going on with you.
- If you...
- No. No.
[PHONES RINGING]
- This is Dr. Montgomery.
- This is Dr. Bennett.
We'll be right there. I'll drive.
I'll call Charlotte King
to get you surgical privileges.
Dell, cancel my patients
for the rest of the day.
You said this was an emergency.
I thought there was something in his labs.
He's fine.
Dean,
your mom and dad,
they still think of you as being a kid.
Well, I am.
- Mostly a kid.
- Yeah, but you're not a kid.
That's not what I see.
That's not what I hear from you.
I think everybody needs
to know the truth here.
We're fine with how things are.
Then I have no choice. I have to reveal
something that legally I'm not allowed to.
I thought we were clear about this.
- Dean, your parents...
- Stop.
This is not your place.
This is my child.
This is my little boy
and I will do what's right.
Dean's planning on having sex
with his girlfriend.
ROBIN:
No.
Mom.
I trusted you.
Why would you do this?
Why is this such a huge deal?
It's not the end of the world.
What's going on?
Dr. Freedman, could you step out?
Yeah.
ADDISON: What happened?
- She's not dilated or effaced
but her water broke an hour ago.
Plus she's bleeding
and the baby's showing signs of distress.
- We gotta get that baby out now.
- Naomi, if you collect the cord blood,
I have a team standing by
ready to transplant.
- Jason's prepped and waiting.
- Yeah.
- What did you do?
- Her water broke.
I am the best chance
your baby has of survival
but I will walk out of this hospital
right now
and leave you, your baby
and your son's lives
to some nervous OB resident
if you lie to me again.
I am sick of lies. What did you do?
I broke my water myself
with a knitting needle.
ADDISON: I need an OR. Call Anesthesia,
make sure we can get a spinal.
And notify NICU, we've got a preemie
on the way. Let's go. Now.
- Is the baby okay?
ADDISON: Picking up the placenta.
And the umbilical cord.
- Who's closing?
- Over here.
ADDISON:
Get in here.
MOLLY:
No.
Is the baby okay?
ADDISON: Apgar's four, ET tube
and a straight blade.
- Wait, is the baby okay?
ADDISON: No, no, she's not okay.
Please. I'm sorry.
Please just save her. Please.
ADDISON:
I'm doing everything I can.
NAOMl:
Molly, Eric and I are leaving.
Jason should have his father with him
just in case.
Okay.
- Maybe we should...
ROBIN: Stop!
Enough!
What am I gonna tell people?
Sorry, I forgot I have AIDS?
You don't have AIDS. Okay, HIV, if...
HIV. You take care of yourself,
you're gonna live a long, healthy life.
You knew. And all this time,
you didn't tell me.
- I thought you were my friend.
- I couldn't tell you the truth before.
And now I will tell you
everything you need to know
and I swear I'll do everything I can
to help you have the life you want.
But you can't. It's too late.
We had sex last night.
It's too late.
Cord blood's on its way to Jason and...
Oh, damn.
I'll get the parents up here
to say goodbye before she goes.
Wait. We're gonna try
liquid ventilation on her.
- That's highly experimental.
- Yes.
- Have you ever done it before?
- No, but I'm about to do it now.
The fluid expands her lungs
so they don't collapse.
We're simulating the womb. Keep an eye
on her SATs. If they go up, it's working.
- Montgomery, SATs are falling.
- Give me a second.
Come on. Come on.
Come on.
There we go.
Montgomery. Where the hell
have you been hiding all my medical life?
I like you too, Charlotte.
Hey, I came by
to check on the Madisons.
- How are they doing?
- Mom's in recovery from her C.
Jason's receiving cord blood infusion.
Montgomery's keeping the baby alive
through force of will.
It's a mess.
You ever miss the good old days?
When life and death was decided
by God instead of doctors?
We'd be out of jobs.
Man, it would be good, though,
to just not be in control.
To just let go, let God.
I could travel.
I could go to Africa.
I could touch monkeys.
Whatever.
How's Jason?
We'll see.
How's the baby?
- Thank you.
- Yeah.
- Okay.
Yeah.
PETE:
You did the right thing.
COOPER:
I know.
- You did what you could.
- I know.
But that doesn't make it any better.
Nope.
I have to talk to you.
Dell, I don't have time
for your stuff right now.
It's gonna have to wait.
You know, I've been covering for you
the best that I can.
The bills, the late notices,
the vendor calls.
While you're working to stop
the hemorrhaging, I've been trying
to catch things you forget,
stuff you don't see.
I've been keeping your secrets
and I've been hiding your mistakes.
And I just wanted to say something
so I could help you.
- I thought that you...
- I know what you thought. You thought l...
You thought I wanted to talk about us,
but I get it.
There is no us.
So daily patient schedules,
phone sheets, vendor lists,
and my keys to the office.
- Dell...
- I quit.
Naomi's running the practice
into the ground.
I wasn't thinking.
Something has to be done.
I can't be the one to do it.
I'm new here. I haven't earned the right.
And she's my best friend.
Well, I'm her husband.
Was.
I was her husband.
Now I'm not anything, so...
Sam, something has to be done
and you have to be the one to do it.
Yeah.
You're here late.
I'm catching up on patient notes.
Me too.
Wanna know the truth?
I'm trying to remember what I did
before Cooper got a life.
It's ridiculous.
He used to need me.
Now I need him.
I'm trying to figure
what it is about Addison
that makes me act
like a 14-year-old boy.
It's humiliating.
I gotta start sleeping around again.
Do you wanna come
to Zanzibar with me?
Pretty girls in Zanzibar.
I've been.
You can touch monkeys there.
I knew it.
You can't tell anyone about us,
but I will consider a vacation.
Somewhere close.
Somewhere I can flee from easily,
like Napa or Palm Springs.
I'm here.
I came crawling back, okay?
- I'm crawling.
- In crotchless panties?
In no panties.
[DOORBELL RINGS]
- You know where I live?
- I'm a cop. I know where everyone lives.
Funny.
- Listen, I have had the worst day, so...
- Well, we could go out.
We could go out and have fun
in a casual way
that is fun and casual.
I know I'm some guy you barely know,
some total stranger
who is not in your world but l...
The "not in my world" part is good.
So...
Show me the SWAT thing again.
[LAUGHS]
I just...
I just want...
Can we just be us again?
I just need something to work.
Dell.
DEAN:
This is my girlfriend, Amy.
What you said yesterday
about answering questions?
We have a lot.
Why don't you all come into my office?
MOLLY:
Thank you.
Dr. Montgomery.
I did what I had to to save my family.
You would do the same thing
in my situation.
I heard you kicked
liquid-ventilation ass yesterday.
I did okay.
- So?
- Pete, I can't.
Things around here are about to...
And I am seeing someone.
- As of last night, so...
- I got it.
I'm sorry, Pete. L...
Not wise.
Hey.
- You ready for this?
- She came over last night.
She came over last night and we...
- I'm supposed to do this now?
- What's the alternative?
You do what you have to do.
You do what you have to do
to save your family.
Okay?
Okay.
Here we go.
Hey.
I need to see you
in the conference room.
- I can't.
- Now.
It won't take long.
Thank you.
- Bonus time.
- Amen.
- So Mnemba?
- Yeah?
I'm just gonna go on my own.
You know, do the single-girl thing.
Yeah?
Okay.
Okay, so it's that time of the year.
Bonuses.
That's very funny, Sam.
This money came
from my personal checking account.
It's 100 dollars apiece.
It's all I had to give.
If you want more,
earn it.
The practice is broke.
We don't bill enough,
we don't see enough patients,
and we always expect Naomi
to do everything.
So we're broke, people.
You told him?
- You knew?
- Addison.
Wait... Naomi, what happened?
Wait. Don't look at Naomi.
You look at me.
I don't think this is the way to...
If there are any questions
as to how the place is going to run,
from now on, you look at me.
As of this moment, Naomi is relieved
of her administrative duties,
and I am taking charge of the practice.
VIOLET:
Okay, I actually don't think this is legal.
I actually think that if you look at the...
We're a family,
and this practice is our home.
The life we save could be your child's.
- Your wife's.
- Your husband's.
At Oceanside Wellness,
our family takes care of your family.