Robin, look at me.
No!
Robin. No, no, no, no!
Robin, do you know
where you are?
Help me.
Her symptoms,
they're not consistent
with a psychiatric disorder.
A tumor?
So I was crazy.
Your dad's hardly
left your side.
His name is Jack Kellogg.
Behavior indicates
a malignant narcissist.
He threaten to hurt anybody?
Is Dr. Charles ready
to see me?
He had a family emergency.
Tell him that I'm not going
to be treated this way.
Dr. Charles.
Mr. Kellogg?
Daniel.
You secured the gun?
Yes, ma'am.
Check him.
Daniel. Daniel, I'm here.
Oh, God.
It's okay.
Do you know who I am?
Uh, Sharon.
Yes, yes.
Do you know where you are?
Uh, Med.
Yes, that's right.
That's right.
He's alive.
But heavy scalp bleeding.
What the hell happened?
He got shot in the abdomen.
He's lost a lot of blood.
Baghdad.
No, we're going straight
to the OR.
Tell them we're on our way up.
Hang on, Daniel.
Stay with me.
We're going to take good care
of you, Dr. Charles.
Stay with me, Daniel.
So, it's been a few months.
How are you feeling overall?
You know, pretty good.
Really, pretty good.
I might get a little tired
towards the end of the day,
but, uh...
You could have taken
a little bit more time off.
I was going nuts.
How are you doing
emotionally?
Hey, who's the shrink here?
I'm doing fine, thank you.
Thank you for asking.
So you had some pain
when I palpated your abdomen.
So I'd like you to get a CT
and a CBC with white count
and make sure that you
don't have an abscess.
Can't do it today.
It's actually
Jack Kellogg's trial,
and I'm testifying.
Oh, crap.
Boy. Guy could've died.
It would've made everybody's
life a little easier, huh?
Please tell Robin
that I'm truly sorry
that I can't be there
when you bring her home.
Yeah, sure.
Thank you, Doctor.
Not a worry.
Dr. Reese, Dr. Charles left,
said you should do rounds
without him.
He doesn't know when they're
gonna call him in to testify.
It is awful he has
to relive that night.
Yeah. Right.
As long as it helps
put that schmuck away.
The hubris, trying to get off
with an insanity plea.
Yes.
It's ironic, isn't it?
By saving lives, we put
our own in jeopardy.
I guess.
You know,
nothing's been done
to improve security.
We need a police
presence here,
both inside and outside
the ED.
I'm all for cops, Dr. Stohl,
but the people you most
need to worry about,
they're not afraid of guns.
Which reminds me, what do you
want to about your gunshot,
Mr. Jameson?
The wound is through
and through, not serious.
He needs some in-home care,
but there's no reason for him
to be taking up space here.
Discharge him.
All right.
Hey.
Natalie!
Hi.
We thought we lost you
for good.
Why? It was just
a little sabbatical.
We didn't hear from you
for three months.
I'm sorry.
I should have called.
I just got caught up
with family stuff.
Dr. Halstead.
Look who decided to come back.
Hey, Nat.
Hey.
Good to see you.
You, too.
Uh-oh.
You're gonna have
to catch up later.
Incoming.
Welcome home.
Brian Cutler, early 40s.
High speed crash,
prolonged extrication,
unresponsive,
unable to intubate.
You're going to Trauma 3.
GCS 5,
heart rate 78,
BP is 120 over palp.
His wife is right behind us.
Natalie, take the husband?
Doris, Noah with me.
Yep.
Brian. Brian.
Judith Cutler,
GCS 15, vitals stable.
My husband, Brian.
Seatbelt sign
on her right neck.
Go to trauma one.
It's okay.
He's being treated.
I'm Dr. Halstead.
I said terrible things.
I'm going to take
good care of you.
Oh, God. Brian.
Monique, let's go.
On my count, one, two, three.
All right, Doris,
take over bagging.
I need to intubate.
100 of sux, 20 of etomidate.
FAST him, Dr. Sexton.
Yes, ma'am.
And also I need
a chest x-ray.
Yes, Doctor, flying in.
All right.
We were fighting.
He didn't see the other car.
Mrs. Cutler, are you
always this hoarse?
What? Uh, no.
We got seatbelt sign.
Chest wall tenderness.
Hey, I want a 4-vessel CT
angiogram
with laryngeal cuts
and a CT c-spine,
chest, abdomen, pelvis.
Right.
Help Brian.
The things I said...
I didn't mean them.
Have to tell him I'm sorry.
Don't worry. We're taking
good care of him.
You'll see him soon.
FAST is clear.
I'm in.
Chest is clear.
All right, let's send him up
to CT for a panscan.
You have to tell him.
Have to tell him
All right.
Have to tell him.
You'll still experience some
symptoms of the encephalitis,
but to a lesser
and lesser degree.
What kind of symptoms?
Memory loss,
phonemic paraphasia,
Substituting "Ken"
for "pen," that kind of thing.
You might also experience
sleep issues, hypersomnia.
Impulsivity, disinhibition,
irritability.
Sounds great, huh?
Look, nothing
a vintage bottle
of Clicquot can't fix,
right?
Champagne? No. Alcohol is
definitely contraindicated.
You'll still be on
prednisone, Ativan, Geodon,
Trileptal, and labetalol,
and you'll be receiving
bi-weekly at-home
immunoglobulin infusions.
Nice.
Can I get some of that?
Thank you, Sarah.
I get the picture.
Okay.
I'll check in with you.
You know what would make me
feel better than champagne?
I'm with you.
Mmm-hmm.
Yeah, sorry, we can't
lock the door.
Well, we'll be home
in a couple of hours.
Yeah, but who wants to wait?
Yeah.
Dr. Manning.
It's good to have you back.
Thanks, Ms. Goodwin.
Glad to be back.
Sent the husband
for a panscan.
Wife's getting a CT, too.
Good.
Enjoy your sabbatical?
Yeah.
It's good to get away,
gives you perspective
on things.
Oh, yeah?
There was a lot going
on here.
I had a lot to think about.
Hey, Sarah.
Where you going?
I got us some sliders.
Uh, courthouse.
I want to be there
when Dr. Charles testifies.
Oh, right, right.
I get it. Moral support.
Yeah, he's the reason
I went into psychiatry.
Dr. Charles taught me
everything I know.
Yeah, he's kind
of like your dad getting shot.
My dad? Okay, my dad.
I have not seen my dad
since I was six.
There's no comparison
between him and Dr. Charles.
Dr. Charles, can you identify
the man who shot you
the night of May 11th?
Uh, yes. He's sitting
right there, Jack Kellogg.
We're all very grateful you
pulled through, Dr. Charles.
There's certainly
no one here would blame you
for wanting to see Mr. Kellogg
pay for the physical
and emotional distress
he's caused you.
Now, just a few weeks
before Mr. Kellogg shot you,
he'd been a patient of yours,
right?
Yes.
And at that time,
his actions and his behavior
warranted enough concern
to place him
on a 72-hour psychiatric hold
for further observation.
That's right.
So you were aware
that Mr. Kellogg was
a severely troubled man?
Yes. Yes, I was.
The jury's already
heard testimony
from some other experts
who claim
that Mr. Kellogg's
mental state
does not meet the threshold
of what would be considered
legally insane.
But they weren't able
to evaluate him
until well after the incident,
correct?
That's correct.
And they weren't there
in the moment
when Mr. Kellogg shot you
and then himself,
were they?
No. They were not.
Then would you say
they're qualified
to evaluate Mr. Kellogg?
No. In fact, I wouldn't.
With all due respect
to my colleagues,
I feel that I am uniquely
qualified to answer
the question at hand which is
what was Jack Kellogg's
mental state
at the time that he fired
those bullets.
And I believe
that he was legally insane
at that time.
So, in your
expert medical opinion...
I think that Jack Kellogg
should be declared not guilty
by reason of insanity.
Thank you, Dr. Charles.
Hey.
Why would you
perjure yourself
up there?
I didn't perjure myself.
You said that Jack Kellogg
is legally insane.
We both evaluated him,
and we concurred
that he was, and I quote,
"a malignant narcissist
with overt sadistic impulses."
Toxic, yes, and in definite
need of treatment,
but not something that rises
to the definition
of legal insanity.
Sarah, I revised
my diagnosis.
Why?
And why didn't you tell me?
Because Mr. Kellogg
began to present
with definitive signs
of dissociation and paranoia.
In other words,
after he shot me,
it occurred we might
have missed
some underlying
psychotic disorder.
You said he'd hid the gun
in his pocket.
Concealing it alone suggests
an awareness of impropriety.
You want to know
why I didn't tell you?
It's cause of this.
You're emotional
about the shooting.
And while I
very much appreciate
the sentiment behind that,
really I do,
I also think it's affected
your objectivity.
Objectivity? You think
you're being objective?
Look, I got to get back
in there for cross.
You know how you can help me?
Go back to the hospital
and treat patients.
Okay? I'll be back at the end
of the day,
and we'll talk some more.
It started a couple of weeks
ago with a headache,
and next thing I know,
he's fiery like a furnace.
101.
Hey, Ryan, I'm Dr. Choi.
So I hear this has been going
on a few weeks?
I know I should have brought
him in sooner.
I got laid off last year,
and we lost our coverage.
Everything is out-of-pocket
right now,
so until I'm working again...
Sorry about this, Mom.
Honey, I told you there is
nothing to be sorry about.
It's okay, Ryan.
Dr. Choi will fix you
right up.
April, let's get a CBC, CMP.
Oh, no.
Not again.
Also start him on fluids.
And Doris, grab some towels.
Let's clean this up, okay?
Yeah.
So I picked up roast chicken
and some hummus,
unless you want
to unpack first?
I got a better idea.
I guess lunch can wait.
Mmm-hmm.
Okay, good news.
Abdomen and pelvis scans
were clean.
Your laryngeal CT did indicate
some mild swelling,
but your arteries look good.
No damage to
the major vessels.
Hi.
Hey.
Mrs. Cutler, I'm Dr. Manning.
I've been treating
your husband Brian.
Can I see him?
He's still unconscious.
The panscan showed his spine,
chest, and belly were clear.
However, his head CT showed
diffuse bilateral
intraparenchymal bleeding.
I'm afraid we're talking
about a bleed in the brain.
Oh, God.
This is not something
we can resolve surgically.
So we've taken your husband
to the ICU.
The hope is that we can
control the bleeding
and the pressure enough
so that he will wake up.
He has to.
Please, I...
I have to tell him I'm sorry.
I said such horrible things.
Mrs. Cutler,
since you're still hoarse,
I've just paged the ENT
to scope your larynx
just to make sure there's no
damage to your vocal chords.
As soon as we do that,
we're gonna take you up
to see your husband.
Thank you.
What was that all about?
Tell him she's sorry?
Yeah. they were
having a fight
when the accident
occurred.
She's afraid she won't
get the chance to
tell him how she really feels.
Were you aware that
Dr. Charles was testifying
in Kellogg's defense?
I found out today.
Dr. Charles wants him remanded
to a psychiatric facility.
Which means
he won't go to jail.
That's absurd.
The man came here
and tried to kill a mental
health professional
because he wanted attention.
Well, I'm as upset
as you are.
I'm the one who found him
bleeding on the sidewalk.
Jack Kellogg is
a devious sociopath.
He'll con his way out
of a mental institution
and be back on the streets.
We have a responsibility,
a public responsibility,
to make sure
that doesn't happen.
Unfortunately, Dr. Reese,
there's nothing you
or I can do.
It's up to the jury.
Help! He can't breathe.
Heart rate's spiking,
statting at 88%.
Get him on oxygen.
Got it.
All right, breath sounds
diminished on the left.
Give me the ultrasound.
Yes, Doctor.
Hey, hey. Why don't we wait
outside, okay?
Left side's full of fluid.
Let's give him four morphine
and two of versed.
We need to get
in a chest tube now.
Lidocaine?
Need the tube, now!
Got it.
Stats are coming up.
He's stabilizing.
April, let's get a blood
sample for cultures,
and Doris, when you finish
taping the tube in place,
get that pus off the wall
before environmental services
has a fit.
I'm sick of this.
Getting stuck
with the dirty work.
Cleaning up pus and vomit
while you get to run labs.
What?
Just 'cause you and Ethan
are sleeping together.
Excuse me?
Mr. Wilson.
A little short of breath?
Afraid so.
Let's get him
on a nasal cannula.
Yes, Doctor.
Dr. Bardovi, the patient's
cardiac index
is 1.8 by Fick.
What would you suggest?
Increase dobutamine
from 3 to 4 to improve
cardiac output.
Correct.
Mr. Wilson, we'll be back
to check on you later.
Thank you, Dr. Latham.
So, any thoughts?
Normal presentation
of non-compaction syndrome.
The patient's in non-ischemic
heart failure.
And?
With his tachycardia,
we can't increase
inotropic support
without risking
cardiogenic shock.
That gives us, at best,
a few more days
to find him a new heart.
Unfortunately, yes.
Carry on.
Dr. Bekker.
Busy day.
How are we progressing?
I completed
my valve replacement,
triple bypass
is being prepped now,
and Dr. Rhodes'
pulmonary thrombectomy
is set for this afternoon.
Robin was discharged
this morning.
Dr. Rhodes will be here as
soon as he gets her settled.
You know, Dr. Latham,
I'm thinking
my bypass patient is stable.
In fact, he could probably
use another day or two
for his heart to rest.
And?
Pulmonary thrombectomy,
that's a difficult procedure.
With everything Dr. Rhodes
is dealing with today,
I could take some
of the pressure off
and perform his thrombectomy.
With your permission,
of course.
That's very considerate
of you.
We're a team.
Hmm.
Yes. Take the thrombectomy.
I'm sure Dr. Rhodes
will appreciate it.
Oh, come... Do you really
have to go?
It's a pulmonary
thrombectomy.
It's not something
you see every day.
That's a high-profile case.
Did you have to wrestle
Cruella for it?
Ava Bekker?
No, it hasn't quite come
to that yet.
You want to wrestle with me?
Oh...
Well, that is very,
very tempting.
But I really do have to go.
Come on, it will be quick.
No.
I wish I could.
You know, I never understood
why women in movies
have sex on kitchen tables.
It just... It seems so
uncomfortable to me, but...
I don't know.
Maybe we ought to try it.
See what we've been missing
out on, right?
What's the matter?
I shouldn't be late tonight.
Connor.
You'd tell me if something
were wrong, wouldn't you?
Robin, don't worry.
Maggie.
I need some help here.
Barry, what's going on?
Dr. Stohl discharged
this patient.
Mr. Jameson, are you okay?
What happened?
Nothing.
I couldn't leave him at home.
Why not?
First off,
his brother was supposed
to be there
to take care of him.
He wasn't.
Couldn't get away from work
so he's coming tomorrow.
Number two, there's guys
hanging around
waiting to pop him again.
He needs his brother
as back-up.
For real.
Garfield Park.
And there's no place else
for you to go
until your brother gets there?
But...
Okay, 24 hours.
That's all you have, okay?
I'll be back
for him tomorrow.
You better be.
Could use something to eat.
What?
Hey, Reese, I need
to ask you something.
You mentioned, uh,
disinhibition, impulsivity
as things that Robin
might experience.
Can you get a little more
specific for me?
Uh, impulse buying, gambling,
maybe hypersexuality,
hyperphagia...
Hypersexuality?
Are you concerned
about Robin?
Yeah,
of course I'm concerned.
You're sure that she was ready
to be discharged?
Yes.
You're confident about that?
I am, and if my opinion
isn't good enough,
her neurologist and internist
both concurred, okay?
I am trying to figure out
if I'm dealing with Robin
or her antibodies here.
Look, if you're not up
to managing her care,
we can find...
I am.
I'll talk to my husband about
that and we'll see if we can
do it on Thursday.
Beth, where're you going?
We've got a case.
Oh, they gave it
to another team.
The patient's already
in surgery.
Dr. Latham.
Uh, the pre-op team said
that my pulmonary thrombectomy
was already taken to surgery.
I don't understand.
Dr. Bekker kindly offered
to take the case.
I okayed it.
Why?
With Robin's discharge
this morning,
Dr. Bekker thought
you'd be relieved
to have such a difficult
procedure taken off
your plate.
Really?
How considerate of her.
Ah, that's what I said.
It's gratifying, Dr. Rhodes,
to see the two of you working
so well together.
Yeah.
Dr. Choi,
Ryan's labs came back.
White count of 16,000
with a left shift,
plus bicarbs are up...
He's dehydrated.
Let's give him
another liter of fluid
and check on his gram stain.
Um...
Doris thinks
we're sleeping together.
She does?
Did you say something?
No.
Ethan.
April.
I swear I didn't say a word.
Hey, if it's out, great.
No, don't.
Come on.
Why do we have
to keep sneaking around?
Because you're a doctor.
I'm a nurse.
Not the first time
this ever happened.
Exactly.
I do not want to be
that cliché.
Is that what you think
of us?
No.
But other people will.
Who cares?
That's really easy
for you to say,
'cause you're the doctor.
Someone help my son!
Somebody help my son.
He's having a seizure.
April, push two of Ativan.
On it, two of Ativan.
He's burning up.
We need to get him upstairs
for a head CT now.
Yes, Doctor.
April, let's move.
Okay, here we go.
What is happening to my son?
Ma'am, I promise you,
we're going to find out.
Intracranial pressure's
way up.
Henry, five of morphine.
BP's spiking.
Heart rate's down to 42.
Cushing's response.
Give him another 70
of mannitol.
Will, his pupils are blown.
Veronica, turn up the vent
and hyperventilate him.
Will, we've lost him.
Damn it.
We maxed out on his meds.
There was nothing we could do.
I know.
Dr. Manning.
Yeah?
I understand you just lost
a patient
to an intraparenchymal bleed.
Yes, Brian Cutler.
And we're about
to inform his wife.
Ah, well, there's something
I need you to ask her.
Can I go see
my husband now?
Mrs. Cutler, I'm afraid
we have some very bad news.
Your husband.
Oh, my God...
We were unable to control
the bleeding in his brain.
He suffered what we call
herniation.
That's when pressure on the
brain cuts off blood supply.
Brian is...
He's brain dead.
Unfortunately,
it's irreversible.
Oh, no.
No, no, no, no.
We're very sorry.
But I... I never told him...
No... No...
Mrs. Cutler.
We know this is
a terrible time for you,
but we need to ask.
Your husband was not
registered as an organ donor.
This can't be happening.
There's a young man
in this hospital
who needs your
husband's heart,
but we need your consent.
Brian.
Mrs. Cutler,
your husband's heart will save
this young man's life,
and the sooner we act,
the better.
May we have your permission?
Yes.
Thank you.
This is my case.
Was your case.
And I don't need
to your assistance.
And you open him up?
I had him scheduled
for interventional radiology.
To resect a saddle embolus?
No, that would have been
a great idea
if you were trying
to kill him.
You poached my case and
now you changed the procedure.
Dr. Rhodes. Outside now.
Please.
I can make better use
of your time than kibitzing
with Dr. Bekker.
Dr. Latham...
She is eminently skilled
and qualified
to perform the thrombectomy.
Yeah.
We have a patient
in cardiac failure.
A heart has just been
procured
for transplantation,
but it presents
a significant size mismatch.
So you will have
to completely reconstruct
both the
in and outflow tracks.
No. You will have
to reconstruct them.
It's your case.
Dr. Charles, prosecution's
calling a rebuttal witness.
What do I need to know
about Sarah Reese?
What?
Tell me your own resident
isn't here to poke holes
in your testimony.
So you also
treated the defendant,
Mr. Kellogg.
Yes, I did.
Dr. Reese, is it safe to say
that you disagree
with Dr. Charles?
Yes.
We want to believe
that the only thing
that can explain
aberrant behavior
is some sort of insanity.
But even in my short time
as a psychiatric resident,
I've found that that's not
always the case.
And it is certainly not
the case with Mr. Kellogg.
Lying bitch!
Sit down.
You're a lying bitch.
Deputies, restrain
the defendant.
Let me go. You're a liar.
A damn liar!
Mr. Kellogg, control yourself!
Let go!
You're a liar!
Order in this court!
You'll pay for this.
Get off of me.
Off of me.
You're a liar!
Let go of me.
Get off of me!
You're a liar, damn it!
Ryan has an infection
in his brain?
It's called
a subdural abscess.
He contracted an infection,
and as it spread,
a small collection of pus was
walled-off inside his brain.
How does this happen?
We're hoping you might be
able to help us answer that.
Mrs. Potter, can you think
of anywhere Ryan
may have been exposed
to a fungus or parasite?
Did Ryan go camping?
Possibly swimming
in a lake or river.
No.
Nothing like that.
Any dental work?
We haven't been
to the dentist in ages.
Never. It's too expensive.
Severe tooth decay
on the left posteriors.
Small abrasion on the surface
of the gums.
Could have allowed bacteria
to enter the bloodstream
and travel to his brain.
Am I going to be okay?
We'll start you
on antibiotics,
but you'll likely need surgery
to drain the abscess.
I'll get you a referral
for an oral surgeon.
How could this happen?
He never even complained
of a toothache.
Mr. Jameson,
why are you still here?
Uh, there was an issue.
Maggie.
Yes.
Why is Mr. Jameson sipping
on a juice box in my ED?
He couldn't be left at home.
Maggie, we are not
running a hotel here.
But if he goes home
by himself,
he could get shot again.
However unfortunate
that situation may be,
it is not our problem.
We treat 'em, we street 'em.
That's what we do.
Treat 'em
and street 'em is fine
for people who live
on your street.
Not his.
Maggie, I'm not...
Dr. Stohl.
You're rightfully concerned
about someone getting shot
in the ED,
but what about
the people who live
with that kind
of thing every day?
I cannot correct
society's ills.
I patch people up.
Now discharge Mr. Jameson.
So you got plans tonight?
You and Dr. Choi?
Why you trying
to start something?
Am I wrong, April?
You're not sleeping together?
Yes, you're wrong.
Don't blame my mom.
She didn't know.
It was just a toothache.
I shouldn't have
kept it a secret.
Just a toothache?
I can't imagine how much
that hurt.
She's always worried
about money.
I didn't want to worry
her more.
It's my fault.
No.
You did what you thought
was best.
I know what you're thinking.
About secrets.
All I'm thinking is
that's one brave kid.
Our secret...
It's up to you, April.
I want you to be comfortable.
You said you'd
keep him 24 hours.
The Chief
of Department said no.
You have to go home.
He's helpless.
They'll kill him.
What do
you want me to do?
Maggie.
Bring the patient over here.
You feel that?
Yeah.
Push your foot
against my hand.
Can you feel that now?
Um, no.
I suspect there
may be nerve damage
we didn't pick up earlier.
I'd like to admit Mr. Jameson
for inpatient physical
and occupational therapy.
Hmm.
Robin. Hey, you okay?
Yeah, I was thinking
about this afternoon and...
You just seemed...
I don't know.
Everything's good
with us, right?
Uh, yeah, everything's good.
So, I'm just being paranoid.
Do you know what, never mind.
Don't... Don't answer that.
Um, if you want I could look
pasta for dinner tonight.
You mean "cook"?
Cook, yes.
Cook pasta.
Honey.
Are you taking your meds?
Yes, I'm taking my meds.
Wha...
I'll be home before long,
okay?
Okay.
I hear you one-upped me.
Heart transplant with a
significant size mismatch.
That looks good on the CV.
Guess you have me to thank,
taking that thrombectomy
off your hands.
Ava, I'm really not
in the mood.
You should go home
and get some sleep.
Oh, there you are, Dr. Reese.
Uh, you'll be happy to know
that Mr. Kellogg
was found guilty.
I'm not happy, but I am
satisfied with that verdict.
He'll still receive treatment
in jail.
Through the Department
of Corrections?
You have any idea
what their success rate is?
In that environment?
His chances of rehabilitation
are practically nil.
Not that it really matters,
because more than likely
his temper will get him killed
within a week.
Those outbursts are an act
calculated to convince
you he's crazy.
Is that what he was doing?
Dr. Reese,
I've been evaluating
psychiatric patients
for more than 30 years.
Is it conceivable to you
that I might have more insight
into his behavior than you do?
Daniel.
Give us a moment, Dr. Reese.
You recruited her
because you liked
that she thought for herself.
Don't hold
that against her now.
Sharon,
Kellogg is not a criminal.
He's a confused guy in a lot
of pain who needs some help.
Like someone else I know.
What's that supposed to mean?
Look, I didn't say anything
when you insisted upon
returning to work
before you were cleared to,
because I got it.
It was important to reclaim
your agency.
But now here you are,
the one person in Chicago
willing to champion the cause
of the man who tried
to kill you.
I got to say, it concerns me.
Why? 'Cause I want
to send him to an asylum?
Not a day spa,
instead of a prison?
Because I want... I want
to treat his illness
instead of punishing
him for it?
It's still my patient.
Very noble, Daniel,
but I don't think
that's what this is about.
I think this is about
your guilt and your ego.
You had a killer
on your hands,
and you missed the signs.
And now you're trying
to make up for your mistake.
You're trying to fix it
and get back in control.
You've been through so much,
Daniel.
Let it go.
Stop torturing yourself.
Dr. Rhodes.
I've been thinking about
your pulmonary thrombectomy.
I can't help but wonder
if Dr. Bekker didn't...
What's the word? Manipulate
me for her own gain.
I wouldn't worry about it,
Dr. Latham.
I know that fellows compete
for the most challenging cases
to improve their resumes.
Perhaps in the end, you fared
better than Dr. Bekker.
Is that why you gave me
the transplant?
I'm not sure.
Sometimes my motivations are
a mystery to me, to be honest.
Good night, Dr. Rhodes.
Good night, Dr. Latham.
Mrs. Cutler.
The transplant was successful.
The young man, the recipient
of your husband's heart,
he's doing well.
The last thing Brian
heard me say
was that I didn't love him.
May I see him?
The young man.
The heart recipient?
Yes.
Please.
Closer. Please.
I'm so sorry, Brian.
I love you.
Sorry I wasn't here to help
ease you into civilian life.
I mean,
for all the good it did,
I probably should've skipped
testifying all together.
It's okay, Dad.
I wish I could have
been there for you.
Oh...
I mean, at least
I knew you were
in Connor's
very capable hands.
What? What is it?
He doesn't trust me.
What do you mean?
I saw a look on his face.
He thinks my feelings
for him are part
of my disease.
Oh, honey.
Is he right?
Or is this just...
All in my head,
and that's part of
the disease?
Dad,
how do I know what's real?
Come here.
I mean,
we're all driven by so many
different things.
Truthfully, a lot of the time
I don't have a clue
why I do the things that I do.
But I mean, even if you can't
always trust your brain...
In my experience,
you're usually pretty safe
trusting your heart.
You know?
Good night, Dr. Choi.
Good night, April.
I feel for that woman.
Having to live
with those regrets.
Yeah.
Well, good night, Will.
Night.
Natalie.
When you left, you knew
about me and Nina.
But I didn't get a chance
to tell you
why I broke up with her.
It was because of the feelings
I have for you.
Those feelings haven't
gone away.
You don't have to say
anything.
I don't have any
expectations.
I just...
I felt I had to tell you.
My, um...
My sabbatical.
The things I needed to
think about...
It's you.