Previously on The Good Doctor...
Coming back to California,
and moving in with you,
it's been harder
than I anticipated.
Hershey meant
everything to me, Shaun.
I took the biggest chance
of my life going back there.
And then it just went away.
Deep brain stimulation
was used to treat anorexia.
You want to use brain surgery
for a psychiatric disorder?
DBS isn't FDA-approved
for anorexia treatment here.
It's not a real option.
My wife's decided against
the valve repair surgery.
At least, until she's tried
the deep brain stimulation.
You won't be a part of the
surgery. Or any of my surgeries.
You went around me,
directly to the patient.
You're booting me
off your service?
- Oh, he's very affectionate.
- Ooh.
Yes.
Cats are smart and independent.
I don't think my first pet should
be something I'm allergic to.
Oh.
Mmm.
Did you know constrictors
don't crush their prey?
They induce arterial
circulatory collapse.
He looks like a Hubert.
The pH should be maintained
within a range of 7.1 to 7.3.
And we're supposed to add
three drops of Klor-out
to neutralize the tap water.
Don't worry, Hubert. Daddy just
shows his love in a different way.
Mmm-hmm.
No. You don't
come by for a month,
and then you think this store-bought
pie is gonna make it all right?
It's from the farmers' market.
- Uh-huh.
- Mmm-hmm.
Fine, hand it over.
And bring it in.
- Hey.
- Thanks for coming.
How is she?
Why didn't you tell me things were
getting so bad? I would have come.
You're busy.
I will always make
time for you, Kay.
Good, 'cause you're not leaving
until the three of us
finish a bottle of Merlot.
Did you call that oncologist doing
the new ovarian cancer PARP-I trial?
The intake doctor said I don't
have the right tumor markers.
- Then you need to go back to your...
- My...
My team put me on
hospice last week.
- Do you want a dose of morphine?
- No, I got it.
Just give it a minute to pass.
Her doctors keep upping the
dosage, but it's not helping anymore.
Nothing is.
Oh.
Hey. Um...
Um, my college
roommate was diagnosed
with stage IV ovarian
cancer a year ago.
She's had six
cycles of carbo-taxol
without cytoreductive surgery
due to widespread disease.
They stopped chemo when
she stopped responding.
She has a month at most.
Wow. I'm so sorry
to hear that, Claire.
As am I. And I assume you're
not here just seeking sympathy?
I've reviewed her scans,
and she can't be cured,
but this metastatic lesion
extending through her diaphragm
is causing most of her pain.
Her surgeon has ruled out
removing it due to vascular complexity.
But I think laparoscopic
debulking is possible.
Difficult, but possible.
I know you're upset with
me, but she, she's my friend,
and she's in pain.
I need your help.
I'll take a look at her today.
Thank you.
We need a surgeon over here.
He fell down the stairs
at a construction site
- while holding a nail-gun.
- Portable head X-ray STAT.
Any other injuries?
Nah, just yank it off,
and slap a Band-Aid.
- Any weakness?
- No.
All right. On my
count. One, two, three.
Let's get you that Band-Aid.
I could have done that for free
at home with a pair of vice-grips.
You don't pay for our equipment.
You pay for me to tell
you that he got lucky.
It's superficial.
His pressure's dropping.
- Are you feeling faint?
- A little banged up...
All right, something else is
going on. Let's log roll him.
What's wrong with my brother?
- I see a puncture wound in his flank.
- There's a nail in his abdomen, too.
Let's get him up to the OR.
How bad is the pain?
Maybe a six.
She's lying. She, uh, hides it well,
but she's in terrible pain all the time.
But Claire said you're
not out of options
until Dr. Melendez says you are.
So, am I?
I think we can make
things a little easier for you.
- How soon?
- Dr. Park and I will do it today.
What about Claire? I
came here because of her.
Dr. Park is excellent.
You're in very capable hands.
When my doctors gave up
on me, Claire found a way.
I trust her. I won't do
the surgery without her.
Dr. Park and Dr. Browne
will prep you for surgery.
- Well, try that again.
- Show me.
- Swing... Straight, yeah.
- Almost.
- Then pull back up. That's good.
- Thank you.
The nail completely
ruptured the kidney.
Renal hilum's blown,
too. Four-O on a driver.
This isn't working.
Clamp the renal vessels.
He's gonna have
to live without it.
Expose the other kidney, make
sure it's got that new-car smell.
The adrenal gland is low-lying.
You won't find the
left kidney there.
You expect her to
find it on the right?
No. The most likely reason
for the gland to be lower
is unilateral renal agenesis.
He was born with one kidney.
Is that the vena cava?
There's so much tumor in there,
it's hard to tell
what anything is.
We need to free this segment
without nicking that vein, or...
Park, pull on that
fragment very carefully.
Got it.
Right, Claire, I
need you to tilt...
Exactly.
The tumor's invaded
the vessel wall.
I think you got it.
Why isn't there tumor tissue
penetrating her diaphragm?
Hmm.
The CT scan showed...
The segment we removed was
displacing the diaphragm upward,
giving it the appearance
of chest infiltration.
If the cancer's just
in her abdomen,
she could be a candidate
for HIPEC treatment.
Treatment? Not pain relief?
We may be able to give
her a little more time.
It's called HIPEC surgery. I'd
remove as much tumor as possible,
and then we'd
infuse your abdomen
with a chemotherapy
solution for 90 minutes.
It could give you
another six months.
It comes with a big risk.
This is a major operation,
and your body's frail.
You could die on the table.
Uh, I... I want more time, but
her pain is finally manageable.
I'm afraid to press
our luck anymore.
The thought of gambling away
your last few weeks terrifies me, too,
but this wasn't luck.
Dr. Melendez has proved that despite
all of the challenges of your cancer,
he can safely navigate
inside your abdomen.
I think it's worth putting
your trust in him again.
Okay.
We'll start with a complete PET-CT
scan, so, we can plan our approach.
He has extensive
vein thrombosis.
There's a clear segment we
can use for an AV dialysis graft.
It's short, but we can
attach it to the brachial artery.
Oh.
Hello, Lea. I'm
sorry, but I can't talk...
There's a problem with Hubert.
Oh, okay.
Yeah, the pH is exactly 7.2,
temp's 73, everything is perfect.
- Perfect?
- He looks bored.
Bored?
He can't be bored. He's a fish.
He's just floating
there with nothing to do.
I thought you
were working today.
I was, from home.
Now, I'm procrastinating
with Hubert.
You should work.
Okay. Can you pick up
one of those little castles?
Mmm.
Okay.
I'm not sure who's being
domesticated. You, or the fish.
Uh, yes, I'm still here.
Call us if anything changes.
Due to his tissue type, UNOS
doesn't expect to locate a match in time.
We'll need to
find a living donor.
You did a great job today.
Oh!
You want some pirate booty
and a juice box with that?
You keep me waiting for hours on end.
Now, at least, I have something to do.
- Cancer's keeping you waiting.
- Yeah.
We're ready for you.
- Here you go.
- Well, you can keep that.
Oh. Thank you.
Bye.
- His story is not gonna end well, is it?
- Mmm.
You know, the yo-yo has been around
for 1,400 years since ancient China.
Watch this.
You're not my only patient.
Yeah. Remembering
and executing these tricks
will help with my
sequential memory,
and protect my brain
against your radiation.
With this new targeted therapy, I
can better focus on just knocking
the things out of your
head that I want to.
Of course, I'm also
making a little wish list
about other things I
might want to get rid of.
I'm worried. Whether it's
tomorrow or a few months from now,
Dash is gonna lose me.
And he'll be devastated. He's
an amazing, loving husband.
I want you to go out with him.
What?
You two get along, you
even have chemistry.
We're friends.
If Dash is gonna
move on with his life,
he needs something to live
for. I think that could be you.
We need to begin now.
Okay.
Don't say a word.
It's none of my business.
- Dash seems like a nice guy...
- Shut up.
- You're a perfect match.
- Great.
We just need you to
sign the consent forms.
Donation carries several risks,
including blood
clots, infection,
hemorrhage, lung
collapse, and possibly death.
There are also lifelong risks
such as high blood pressure,
which can cause a heart attack,
and protein-losing nephropathy,
which can impair
your remaining kidney,
leading to the need
for a transplant yourself.
- It's a big ask.
- Yes, it is.
I'm happy to sign the
forms, on one condition.
I'm not selling the business.
I told you 10 times,
we're not taking that offer.
Either sell, or buy me
out at the same price.
- You know I can't afford that.
- I can't afford anything.
Look, Dad left you in charge,
but all of my money is tied up in it.
I got investment opportunities, I
got things that I'm excited about.
Dad left me in charge
because when things got tough,
you took off to college
while we rebuilt.
Now, you want to cash in?
We'll both cash in.
The deal I negotiated
is way over-market.
I don't care how good
the deal is. I like what I do.
And I like my kidney. Seems
we both need to make a sacrifice.
I'm not selling.
Kayla's back in her room.
We finished her staging,
and everything supports
our operative plan.
Do you have any questions
about her upcoming surgery?
Uh...
Did Kay bring up
anything about, uh...
Us?
Oh, my God. I'm so sorry.
I told her not to do that.
I mean, it's, uh...
It's nuts, you know.
Well, that's a little insulting.
Uh...
I'm kidding. It's insane.
Just, you know, we'll just
forget she mentioned it, okay?
Will she?
I mean, we both said
no. What's she gonna do?
You've been married to her eight
years, and you still ask that question?
Well, we, uh, do
have one other choice.
You guys have a
chapel here, right?
- He's exploiting the situation.
- Yes. He's entitled to.
You don't think an organ
donation should be an altruistic act?
Can it be?
A majority of donors do it to make
their own lives more worthwhile,
and almost a quarter do it to
relieve guilt over a past mistake.
Redemption... Meaning...
Sure. But not money.
So, you never take an opportunity to
get ahead at someone else's expense?
I'm competing, not
trafficking organs.
I need Armando's kidney.
And I need it without getting
dragged into their family drama.
Which is why I have residents.
So, you two find a
way to make it happen.
This central line will allow us
to monitor your heart
during tomorrow's surgery.
Have you considered my proposal?
I have been more
focused on your surgery
than seducing your husband.
- Typical.
- Ah.
You got me. I'm not dating
my cancer-riddled friend's husband
because I have commitment issues.
You've been sprinting away from
men as long as I've known you.
Yeah, I will find the time
when I have the time.
It will never be the right
time. You're afraid to get hurt.
I know how short life is.
I don't want you to miss
out on the best part of it.
All done.
What do I owe you for
the therapy session?
- Date my husband.
- Do you know how stupid that sounds?
I want someone to take
care of the man that I love.
- Does that sound stupid?
- Yes, very. But...
Please, please, would
you just drop this?
I will drop this if... One date.
One dinner. That's all.
But a real one, not a latte in
the cafe. I want a real date.
Appetizers, main course, wine.
- I'm on call.
- No wine. But candles.
I want candles.
One date. I will never
mention any of this again.
It's a federal crime to barter a
human organ for anything of value.
I'm not selling
Santiago anything.
You're receiving
money from a third party
in exchange for your kidney.
He's receiving money from
a third party for his business.
So is his brother.
He should love
him enough to not...
I love him enough
to give him a kidney.
He should love me
enough to accept
an offer that would
improve my life, too.
I mean, it's a much lower
ask than a vital organ.
You're not allowed
to ask for anything.
Are you saying
that if he agrees,
you're not gonna
perform the surgery?
- He doesn't agree.
- He will.
Everything in life
is transactional.
And in this case, I've
got all the leverage.
The leverage?
It's what you have
that they need.
It's how you shift
a deal in your favor.
You guys have no leverage,
and no cards to play.
Yes, we do.
I don't believe you're
willing to let your brother die.
A good negotiator doesn't bluff.
If you cave on a threat,
you lose all credibility.
And Santiago knows
I'm a good negotiator.
So, he won't die, precisely
because I'm willing to let him.
- I'll talk to your brother.
- Okay.
Um...
How long do we have to stay?
She said dinner, so, I
assume till we're done eating.
Okay.
- Dessert?
- Do you want any?
- Not really.
- I think we're good.
- Okay.
Hmm?
Look at that old clock.
It's the same as the one that
they had at Meline's, off campus.
Oh, yeah.
Hey, remember that time we
went there on that double date?
You set me up with
your English TA.
Yeah. Kay said
it was a bad idea.
I just remember him
droning on about...
Dryden's influence on
eighteenth century literature.
If you hadn't stepped
in, I think I might have
stabbed him with my salad fork.
Ah, Kay always knew better.
Yeah. She fixed me up three
times. And then she gave up.
Until now.
You should sell the business.
Excuse me?
You would live.
And you could take the
proceeds and start a new business,
without your
brother as a partner.
It's a good deal.
Benitez Builders is
my father's legacy.
He built it from nothing.
He was committed,
hardworking, honorable.
He expected the same
thing from both of us.
My dad was difficult to please.
I work hard to be someone
that my father could be proud of.
And I'm the one he trusted
with the controlling share.
I'd rather die
than let him down.
- Is that bothering you?
- Yeah. A little bit.
Oh.
The graft is failing.
Oh!
What's happening?
Infusing heparin.
He's hypercoagulable.
The tunnel catheter is
gonna clot off just like the graft.
That gives him
even less leverage.
It should convince Santiago
to accept his brother's offer.
Santiago? Why him?
I'm negotiating.
With the wrong brother.
The catheter's
already obstructing.
Whatever we're doing, it needs to
happen in the next couple of days.
We'll do a live donor drive.
Okay. One in 100,000
chance of success,
but better than
planning his funeral.
I think the odds
are better than that.
We don't need to find a match.
We just need the parade of selfless
family members to embarrass Armando
into doing the right thing.
- Evening, roomie.
- Hubert is dead.
- Yeah.
Hmm.
That's odd.
I'm not sure if I overfed him,
or if it was when I changed
the water to clean his pebbles,
but yeah, definitely dead.
We can get another fish.
We don't need to.
There are many fish in the sea.
I said, no.
- You wanted a pet.
- I got one.
- Very briefly. I'll go tomorrow and...
- No.
Are you crying?
Are you sad?
I'm sad.
And I'm angry, and
frustrated and upset.
We should get another fish.
The fish isn't the problem.
I am. I'm pathetic.
I went home to Hershey because
I wasn't fulfilled with my life.
I thought I could help my
bull-headed brother save the shop,
and be a part of something I
was really passionate about.
And instead, we ended
up tanking it together,
along with our relationship.
I came back here to
get my life back on track.
How am I supposed to do that if I
can't even keep a damn fish alive?
I'll make it through this.
It is okay to be afraid.
How was your dinner with Dash?
Forget about that. How are you?
If I don't make it, you have to
give this thing with Dash a real shot.
Kayla, please, stop.
Promise me. You have to.
No. You can't put that on me.
That's right. Claire never
turns her back on a friend,
as long as it doesn't
put her heart at risk.
That is not fair.
What you're asking...
I'm asking you to trust my
judgment about the two of you.
No. You're trying to pressure
me into something that I don't want.
Like you always do.
You need pushing because you've
never known what's best for you.
So...
So, is that why
you dragged me out
to pledge week to be rejected
by every sorority on campus?
Or... Or went behind my back and
invited my mother to graduation?
At least you tried. You
put something at risk.
No. Give me a break. This
was never about me, none of it.
You always have
to have it your way.
You are a neurotic control
freak who thinks she has the right
to dictate how everyone
else should live their lives.
- It's time.
- I'm ready.
Kayla...
I'm sure you recognize Rafael,
your second cousin from Oxnard.
He drove up as soon as he heard.
Either we get lucky here
and you look like an ass,
or we don't, and you look
like an ass with a dead brother.
Mmm.
He won't give his life for
a contracting company.
He's not dying for the company.
He's dying for your father.
What makes you think that?
He would rather die
than let your father down.
He thinks that that's
what Dad would want?
Santi did everything
the old man asked of him.
Worked twice as hard, did everything
twice as well as Dad ever could,
but nothing was ever
good enough for our father.
And no matter what we did, he
was always right there to point out
where we had gone wrong.
You know what he told
me on his deathbed?
Said that he wasn't proud of
Santi for following in his footsteps,
that he was disappointed
that he settled.
You should tell
your brother that.
It's a good card to play.
He was wrong.
You are the most loyal, hardworking
and principled guy I've ever known.
And you deserved Dad's respect.
You greedy, lying snake.
You will say anything
to get what you want.
Even trying to ruin the
memories I have of Dad.
Your memories of Dad? He
was horrible. You know that.
Get the hell out.
- Santi, I'm not trying to...
- Get out!
Give me the consent forms.
My father told me he
wished I hadn't been born.
I wasn't worth the trouble.
But I knew I was
worth the trouble,
because my brother
always looked out for me,
even when it
made his life harder.
Five-O prolene. Position
the kidney in the pelvis.
Dr. Murphy.
Your stat cultures came back
positive for Ichthyophthirius multifiliis.
Thank you.
It's not for this patient.
- Do you need to deal with it?
- It's too late.
You have a security problem.
I will get my badge and my gun.
Somebody stole my
wallet out of the locker.
- Are you sure you left it there?
- Yes, I'm sure.
You were worried
about it getting stolen,
so, you gave this to me
before your session today.
Mine. Sorry.
Stupid. Don't read
anything into this.
- Uh, how is she?
- We removed a lot of the tumor,
and she's having the
chemotherapy bath now.
- Mmm-hmm.
- So far, she's doing well.
Oh. Okay.
- Kayla would want you to eat.
- Yeah.
- Of course, she would.
She'd forget to eat, herself.
I really hate all...
All this waiting.
Hey, just sit. Breathe.
You know, Kayla's
dealt with so much.
Prodding, and nausea,
fatigue, so much pain...
I just wish she would let
me do something for her
to make things easier.
I want to protect my wife.
Instead, I'm just
sitting here, waiting,
waiting for her to die.
Dash, I'm sorry. They
need me back in the OR.
Oh. Yeah, yeah.
Push another 60 of Lasix.
- MAP is 26.
- She's in cardiopulmonary collapse.
Second chest tube in.
SATS are still dropping on 100%.
It has to be heart failure. We
need to crash her on ECMO.
Her cardiac index was fine.
It must be a toxic inflammatory
reaction to the chemo.
She's intolerant.
Stop the chemo.
What if the fluid build-up isn't
a reaction to the chemo bath?
What if it is the chemo bath?
Her... Her mediastinum
is widening.
If her diaphragm perforated,
fluid could be leaking into her
chest, compressing her heart.
The tumor we removed yesterday
was clinging to her diaphragm.
If we close the hole, she
can finish her treatment.
Let's reopen her incision.
I just wanted to see
how you were doing.
His kidney numbers
are starting to improve.
Take me back to my room, Doc.
Mandy.
Thanks for the kidney.
You're welcome. Just don't
come looking for another one
without a big
check in your hand.
Jerk.
That's good.
Hey! You're just in time for
some, uh, celebratory ice chips.
- Kay, I'm sorry.
- Don't be.
You weren't entirely wrong.
I can be a little manipulative.
No. No, I was wrong.
You don't try to
control everything
because you think you know
better than everyone else.
You do it because
you're a caring friend.
You focus all your energy,
trying to protect us from
pain and suffering, and...
And that lets you not
think about your own.
But you have to.
You are dying, Kayla.
I know.
You're dying,
and it is not fair.
And it is painful and scary.
- It feels like you're all alone...
- Please stop.
But you're not.
Dash is here.
And so am I.
Thank you for
everything you did.
Of course.
I, um... I meant
what I said to Kayla.
You really are the most gifted
surgeon I have ever worked with.
You did well today.
Thanks.
I'll report back to
Dr. Lim in the morning,
if that's what you want.
That's probably for the best.
Shaun, I don't
need another fish.
- I don't want another fish.
- I do.
Our goldfish died.
You need to provide
a replacement.
Store policy,
once a fish leaves this store, all
responsibility for its well-being...
Hubert had
Ichthyophthirius multifiliis.
A common goldfish parasite,
picked up in pet stores.
You have no leverage,
and no cards to play.
Pick a fish.
You didn't kill Hubert.
He was defective.
We'll try again.
Thank you, Shaun.
Caring for a fish won't
sort out my problems.
Although, that
one's pretty cute.
Platies are very hardy
fish. They are difficult to kill.