Can two people
really be meant to be...
For her patient.
And I had to rearrange
some of your surgeries.
MFEO?
Check the OR Board
for any changes.
Soul mates?
I have one last thing to say.
Some of you may run
into Arizona Robbins today.
It's her first day back.
So if you see her, just
make her feel welcome.
Or maybe... Maybe just
don't make a big deal at all.
It might be better.
Noted. Thank you.
Hold on. I just want to
address one more thing.
Most of you are aware
that a group of our doctors
have filed a lawsuit
against our hospital.
Some of you may be
wondering what this all means
and how it's gonna
affect our staff.
I'd like to be clear.
It doesn't... At all.
Let's just let the
lawyers worry about that.
That's their job.
Our job is to continue
to work together
and support each other
in giving the great
standard of care
that we have always given.
Let's not let something like
this get in the way of that.
Thank you.
It would be nice if it's true...
That we all have someone
out there waiting for us...
Us waiting for them.
That was good.
Anything else?
Yeah.
The fire house. I'm not
staying there anymore,
so I was wondering
what we should do.
I mean, if we
should sell it or...
I wondered what
you wanted to do.
You should do what
you like. It's your house.
I'm just not sure I believe it.
Okay.
Red eagle has landed.
What? Arizona just got here.
I had an intern
wait at the entrance
and then text me
when they saw her.
I also put the weirdo over
there on wheelchair duty.
Now listen, she'll
be tired and in pain
but she won't ask for it
unless she sees it's close by.
Just don't shove it
in her face. She hates that.
You know what I hate?
That you won't stop talking.
Well, then you two will
get along just fine today.
Oh. Red eagle.
Red eagle. Don't... Don't...
Don't look up. Don't look up.
Keep reading, yeah.
Hi. Robbins.
Oh, hey. Good. You're here.
Well, I gotta run.
Derek's all, "Fix my hand."
"No rest till I'm healed."
We got a big schedule.
There was a 9-year-old
that came in last night
with abdominal pain,
a 6-year-old with
a Wilms' tumor,
there's a 10-year-old that
needs a kidney transplant.
You know, he's
a really cool kid.
You're gonna like him.
Well, call them back and
get the deposit back then.
Well, I'm glad your
sister likes the view,
but I'm the one who has
to put on the poufy dress.
You know what? This
conversation is over.
Well, I love you, too.
Red panties and a lace bra.
He wants to have a
Christmas wedding...
In a rustic mountain lodge
with red ribbons and
mistletoe and a tree
with ornaments
made of our photos.
That sounds beautiful.
No, it's stupid.
What kind of self-respecting man
cares this much about a wedding?
I did.
Yeah, but I did the
wedding thing before.
I'm gonna make all those people
who showed up the first time
sit through another ceremony
because, maybe I'll mean it this
time? You were there with Adele.
You got me a set of ramekins.
And I'd be happy to
get you another set.
I want to get married in a field
with wildflowers everywhere
and butterflies that are
released when I say "I do."
And I want to have these
little mints that say "mint to be."
You get it? 'Cause
they're mints...
There will be no mints.
We're going to the courthouse,
have a little
cocktail party after.
Yeah, we'll see about that.
A man who puts down a deposit
is a man who means business.
Well, he has till the 12th
to get his money back.
That's two days.
He'd need two years to
get me to agree to a wedding
with Santa Claus running around.
Wait. Today's the 10th?
Yep.
It was good that Owen
said that about the lawsuit.
What, his "one big,
happy family" crap?
It's very sweet
unless you're me.
It needed to be said.
Yeah, unless you're the
deformed wife chained in the attic.
Well, what do you
want to be to him?
You left him. Do you
want to be something else?
Well, I don't want to
be chained in the attic.
Hey, guys, have you seen
Jackson? He's not answering my texts.
Why, you looking for
some Jackson action?
Oh, my God. What did I tell you?
Thirty years as a nun,
she cannot get enough.
So you haven't seen him?
No, but we will tell him
that you really, really,
really need to see him if...
Bye, April.
Okay, so if we
go to the axilla...
And then down the
forearm to grab the MABC,
there are two branches.
Okay, now this is the
really cool part, okay?
It's so freakin'
state-of-the-art,
I can't even believe it exists.
That's a lot of build-up.
Better be good.
We take just the anterior branch
and we use that part
for the cable graft.
What else you got?
Did you hear what I just said?
Yeah. What else you got?
Okay. Yeah.
We could
do an end-to-side transfer.
The statistics are
really, really good.
What else?
Derek, I went to the
trouble of making a slide.
Could you please look at it?
You know as well as I do
that those stats come
from studies on rats.
And as far as the end-to-side
transfer, yeah, it's state-of-the-art,
but once you take
away my good nerve,
I will have less function
than I did before.
You don't have it. Keep trying.
I practiced with
Arizona last night.
She made a much
more enthusiastic Derek.
What's wrong?
Dr. Bailey,
did you know the ten
coldest counties in the country
are all located in Minnesota?
You're glad to be back.
I'm glad you're glad.
Now did you double-check
the history of the
heart valve like I asked?
Grumpy.
Yes, and based on the history,
we've chosen a
pericardial bioprosthesis.
I made sure the OR has it ready.
Okay, and Dr. Ross, you
took care of our room situation?
East-facing window like
he likes. It's also private.
Good. Okay.
Hey. MAN: We've arrived!
Hi. Dr. Bailey!
How does the liver
look? Is it a good one?
The best.
Dr. Ross spent the last 24
hours on the phone with UNOS
to make sure it didn't
go anywhere else.
They were threatening
to send it to Portland,
but I went all "Dr.
Bailey" on 'em.
That's my man.
A little thank-you
for all your hard work.
Thank you.
For you. White birch rosemary.
And... Look at you.
What's new on the wedding front?
Have you gotten a wedding dress?
You know it's all
about the dress.
He got knocked down by
some woman at the mall
and fell pretty hard
into a perfume stand.
He's got some abdominal
pain and a deep lac on his hand.
All right. Why aren't
you suturing him?
I paged Plastics.
The patient's
a little difficult.
Okay, well, you're a doctor.
It's your job to deal with difficult.
I know, but...
Mr. Freeman, I'm Dr. Grey.
Do you mind if I examine you?
All yours.
Great. Okay.
Please let me know
if you feel any pain...
I'm sorry.
Dad! I am so sorry. Ignore him.
Dad, I swear to God.
This is why Danny and Tim
don't talk to you anymore.
I never grabbed Tim's ass.
No, you grabbed Tim's
wife's ass, and Danny's wife.
It's okay. It's okay.
I need you to lean
forward for me.
And take a deep
breath for me, please.
Another one.
And we're done here.
What is wrong with you?
It's a compliment.
It's horrifying.
I tried to warn you.
You did a lousy job.
There's some
abdominal tenderness,
so let's get a CT, and get
me the results right away.
Grey, I just got out of surgery.
You got a patient
with a hand lac?
Yeah, he's over there.
And watch your ass.
What do...
Jackson, we need to talk.
I...
Right now.
All right.
What's up?
I'm late.
For what?
Four days. I have never
been four days late in my life.
Four days late for...
Oh.
Oh... Oh...
Of course.
Just when I start thinking
that maybe this could work...
Something that feels so
good can't be bad, right?
I don't know. Maybe Jesus
is okay with premarital sex.
He made that rule when
people got married at 16.
He never expected people
to wait till they were 30.
But now I have a
baby in my uterus,
and it is clear that
he is not okay with it.
Okay, Jesus. I get it.
Relax, okay?
You're not pregnant.
I am a clock. I am never late.
We use condoms. Condoms break.
They don't break.
Sometimes they break. Just...
We're gonna have
you pee on a stick,
and we'll know in five minutes.
No. No. Those things
can give off false positives.
It has to be a blood test.
Fine. You're right.
We'll go draw your
blood right now.
Okay? Uh-huh.
Jackson...
Hey, we are not gonna
worry until we know for sure.
Okay? Okay.
Dr. Kepner, we need you.
14-year-old in a
horseback riding accident.
Hypotensive and bleeding
through his bandages.
I'm around all day,
so just text me later.
Wexler, Lewis, Trauma one now.
Hey, Avery, you're
helping me research a plan
for Shepherd's hand today.
Uh, can it wait?
I'm a little busy.
Oh. Well, every second, the
nerve is dying a little bit more.
As we stand here and
argue, his nerve is dying.
Yes, but...
His nerve died just a little
bit more. Let's go. Snap, snap.
Hunt. Nice speech this morning.
Very, "Once more unto
the breach, dear friends."
Shakespeare. Henry V.
Yeah.
I mean, the point is that
you're handling all this well.
Thanks. You need something?
Just checking in. You
all right with this meeting?
Yeah, I'm just telling
them what happened. Why?
No reason. It's just, you
know, a lawsuit like this,
reminds a hospital
that it's a business.
The angles change
pretty quickly.
So don't let 'em
back you in a corner.
I should be fine.
Of course. Of course. Look,
you know what you're doing.
Just ignore me.
Dr. Hunt, I'm sure you're
aware, members of your staff
have now lodged
an official complaint
with intent to sue Seattle
Grace-Mercy West hospital.
I am.
So today is just a
preliminary interview
to prepare the hospital's case.
This is a confidentiality
agreement.
You can look it over.
It just says that...
You should make note
that it specifically mentions
your wife Dr. Cristina Yang as
one of the plaintiffs in the case.
Yeah, I saw that.
So we understand, this is
an unusual situation for you
and a clear conflict of
interest for the hospital.
Don't worry. Whatever
we say here will stay here.
Great. No awkward conversations
around the dinner table.
Okay, so let's start
with why your team flew to
Boise Memorial on that day.
Boise asked us to help with
a conjoined twin separation.
We'd had success with a very
complicated procedure months earlier.
Graham Cunningham, 65,
presented with cirrhosis
approximately seven years ago.
He's now in
end-stage liver disease
and has subsequently also
developed valvular heart disease.
Well done, Dr. Ross.
I've been practicing.
Why didn't we treat
this valve disease...
Right away? Because the
valve replacement surgery
would've caused
his liver to fail.
But the liver transplant
would've caused his heart to fail.
That's why we'll do
both surgeries today.
First the valve replacement,
then the liver transplant.
Good.
You almost make me
want to learn your name.
Dr. B, You're confident
this liver's the one?
We're not gonna
get halfway to the OR
and have to turn
around like last time?
All signs point to
this being the one.
We just had to date a
bunch of others to find it.
Kind of like you,
kissing all those frogs
before you met me.
A dirty old man touched
my butt today, twice.
Really?
How was your day?
How was Callie?
Well, she didn't touch my butt.
Derek. What?
I'm all for burying things with
sex, but this is your career.
You want to talk about it? Yes.
Why do the surgery at all?
I've always wanted to
spend more time fishing.
I just got Zola her first
fishing pole. It's pink.
Derek.
There is no good
solution. There's half fixes.
Maybe there's more
function. Maybe there's not.
And if they can't
fix it, then that's it.
It's done. It's over.
It's not over. You find a fix.
You used to be so dark and
twisty. Now you're optimistic.
We're not talking about me.
Let's just not talk at all.
That's it. Good.
Avoid twisting the
cables too tightly
or they'll cut
through the sternum.
What is this I hear about
you letting your intern
do a procedure on my patient?
You tattled on me?
I didn't spend the last
three months on liver watch
so you could kill this guy.
Hey, no one's killing anyone.
She's good. Better than you.
No gloating.
Yang.
Do you know how long
this man's waited for a liver?
So long, he was
married to a woman
the first time he came in here.
Now he's come out.
He's met the man he's meant
to spend the rest of his life with.
This is not the man we
let an intern practice on.
Okay, relax. She won't do it.
Since when did you
become such a romantic?
Boo-hoo.
You're lucky you even
get to work with me.
Does that hurt at all, Sean?
Good. Good.
All right. You
having any fun here?
I heard there was a
pro basketball player
making his way
around the halls here.
Did you get to
meet him? Tall guy.
He probably hit his head
on the door on the way in.
All right. Well, we will
check back with you later.
Bye.
Good job.
You said $20 if I didn't
ask about the fake leg.
I only got $10 on me.
Then next time she comes in,
I'm gonna tell her how you told
me that I couldn't say anything.
Keep your trap shut.
Hey, is he always that quiet?
Yeah. Strange kid.
Dr. Robbins, Dr. Kepner
needs some extra hands
on a horse
trampling, 14-year-old.
All right, tell 'em we're
on our way. Yeah.
I'll catch up with
you. No, I can wait.
No, a kid got trampled
by a horse, Alex. Go.
Can I help you?
No. I just got lost
on my way to Radiology.
Can you take over
the ultrasound?
He's got abdominal tenderness,
and I need to get
control of this bleeding.
I think he may have
lacerated his femoral vein.
My sneakers. What's that?
Don't lose my sneakers.
They're 200 bucks.
That's why his leg
slipped through the stirrup.
You have to wear a shoe with
a heel when you ride a horse.
Kid spends 200
bucks on sneakers,
he's obviously not the
king of awesome choices.
All right, there's possible
blood on the upper left quadrant.
Great. Let's get him up to CT.
Hold on. Wait for Robbins.
Are you kidding me?
She's on her way.
He just got dragged
20 yards by a horse.
He's totally stable. Look,
it's her first day back.
He did a stupid thing. I'm
not gonna let it ruin his life.
Let's move this
gurney right now!
Right away, doctor.
Okay, somebody
step out and call.
It looks like...
There's some calcification
of the aortic annulus here?
Is that a statement
or a question?
I will check again.
Oh, no.
Look at that. He comes
bearing bad news.
It's gonna be fine.
The plane taking the transplant
team got delayed by rain.
We'll know more in an
hour. We've heard that before.
You don't know. Maybe
this is a good thing.
Like maybe the
plane has to be late
so the transport ambulance
doesn't crash into an 18-wheeler.
Things happen for a reason.
Here we go.
Well, they do.
I always say, I would
never have met Hank
if my ex Carol hadn't
forced us to move to Seattle
to be closer to her family.
You wasted 30
years in that marriage.
No, it wasn't a waste. It
got me here. I met you.
Thirty years too late.
Better late than never.
Things don't always
happen for a reason, Graham.
I was alone all that time
and you were scared.
And I don't believe that that's the
way things were supposed to be.
We were supposed to be together,
have our entire lives together.
So I can't just sit back
and be okay with you losing
the one thing that can get
me my 30 years with you.
I'm sorry.
He's just a little scared.
You're damn right I am.
You don't screw this up.
We won't.
Dr. Ross, you'll make
sure that the liver gets here?
If I have to drive to Oregon
and pick it up myself.
See? Maybe that's why I had to
say things happen for a reason,
so you'd yell at them.
Good news. Your
scans came back clean.
So you're free to go home.
Thank God. You
got lucky this time.
The next lady in the
mall might have a gun.
And so Dr. Wilson can assist you
with any other questions
that you may have,
and I will write you the
prescription for the painkillers. Ah!
Nice.
That's enough!
I am all you've got
left, Dad. And I'm done.
You sit around and mope
about how Mom left you,
but of course she did.
You'd be crazy to
stay married to you.
How long has this been
going on, the touching?
I don't know.
My Mom left him,
like, two years ago,
but it was at least
a year before that.
And before that?
He was normal.
He was my dad.
Dr. Grey, what's going on?
Excuse me for a second.
Did you see the way he
was grabbing my pen?
That's a grasping reflex.
It's a frontal release sign.
I thought that went
away after infancy.
Well, it does unless you have
a tumor in your frontal lobe,
in which case,
primitive reflexes
come back along
with disinhibition.
Patients start becoming impulsive,
saying things they shouldn't.
Grabbing ass. You're so smart.
Stop sucking up.
Go get a CT. And page Neuro.
Hey. I'm about to head
back into my meeting.
Bailey and I are doing the
heart-liver surgery today.
I'm lead cardio on it, and
Russell wanted you to sign off on it.
Okay. That all?
No. Why am I here?
What? You pushed
to have me back.
I am curious why, because
you don't seem to want me here.
You're gonna do great things,
Cristina, and I'm running a hospital.
I'd rather have you do
that under our banner.
You're good business.
That's the only reason?
You moved away. You
asked me to stop calling you.
Now you're back.
What do you want?
I don't... I don't
know. That's...
Well, let me tell you what we do
know. We want different things.
Every time we try to ignore that,
we end up hurting each other.
We don't work.
That's what we know.
And that hasn't changed.
Nothing's changed at all. I
have to go back to my meeting.
The brochure has a picture of the
place decorated with icicle lights.
And those reindeer
made out of twigs.
That's gross.
What about a cupcake
tower instead of a cake?
You could do red
and green frosting.
Come on.
You guys are in love.
Why not celebrate that?
'Cause sometimes love
makes you do stupid things.
Suddenly you're screwed
the rest of your life.
What he said.
Why are you even talking?
I need that answer about
the radial nerve transfer.
Yeah. Slow reader here.
Hey. Hey.
Arizona!
Hey, Dr. Robbins. You're
working with horse kid, right?
Yeah, I am. Karev's
got him in pre-op.
And Dr. Kepner, was she also
in pre-op or is she probably...
Excuse me. Why would she
know where your girlfriend is?
Read the article.
Hey, I'm gonna do an
exploratory lap on this kid tonight,
so I might be
home a little late.
You're doing exploratory
surgery your first day back?
- That's a lot of standing.
- You think that...
You might get bored? 'Cause
I get bored just standing.
And sitting... I also
get bored sitting.
Hey. Bailey and Ben are
having a Christmas wedding.
They're gonna have carolers.
I love Christmas carolers.
There will no carolers.
Torres, I'm gonna be right back.
No, no, no. I need you here.
Jackson.
Sorry. I thought you were...
You two having a sex date?
We are not having a sex date.
Not everything is about sex.
You okay?
Yes.
No.
Oh, God.
April? I had a plan.
I was gonna be married
and have a husband.
Our wedding would
have the mints.
We'd be "mint to be," committed.
I was gonna tell my
husband that I was pregnant
by giving him a t-shirt that
said "world's greatest dad."
Now look at me.
You're pregnant?
I think so.
Well, I don't know.
Plans never work out the
way you think they're going to,
especially with babies.
You try and try to get
pregnant, and you can't.
And then a baby comes
when you least expect it,
probably because
you didn't plan it.
Plans don't mean anything.
Hey.
I was just leaving.
Tell us about your decision
in using Skytrip Express
as the charter company.
It wasn't my decision.
The hospital has a
deal with that company.
Has the hospital always
used that company?
I have no idea.
Were you aware that Skytrip had
a history of mechanical issues?
What?
FAA reports four
incidents since July 2010.
No, I didn't. Of
course I didn't.
You don't remember
switching to Skytrip
from another charter
company last December?
I'm not... I'm... I
wasn't aware of that.
I run a surgical
staff. I'm not a...
In a round of budget cuts
heading into fiscal 2012,
transportation policy shifted from
your previous company to Skytrip,
who it appears subcontracts
to several smaller companies...
Who had mechanical
issues. That's right.
This is how we save money, by
jeopardizing our people's lives?
Who are vetting these guys?
Who approved
switching to a company
without checking their
damn safety records?
Is this your
signature, Dr. Hunt?
I don't remember
this specifically, but...
Yes. Yes, I approved this. I...
I did it.
So what happens now, I resign?
This interview is
just to ascertain...
That is the last
thing that we want.
I'm sorry. Can I interject
something here, off the record?
Dr. Hunt, I am Roberta
Thompson. I am new to the board.
Yeah, we've met. Right.
I just want to be clear here.
You said it yourself.
You run a surgical staff,
and you do a hell of a job at it.
You wouldn't do it so well
if we expected you to chase
down every zero on a budget report.
Owen, a mistake was made...
An oversight, and
it cost us, all of us.
God knows it cost our doctors.
And you, your own wife has
paid a terrible price for this,
but the board wants you to know
that you have our
full support in this.
You okay?
Yeah.
You? Yeah.
I don't know. I know.
I guess I should've
been on the pill.
Yeah I guess, we
were both pretty stupid.
Jackson, I can do
this myself, you know?
What?
Just, if this isn't
what you want.
Why...
What the hell, Kepner?
Our surgery's about to start.
I'm anemic. STD screen.
Great timing, though,
'cause I just finished.
And can you get that?
Perf. Thank you. Yeah.
All righty. And see ya.
Dr. Bailey.
Hey. We're almost ready for you.
After this bile duct,
we'll be just about done.
Dr. Bailey, Dr. Warren's
calling the front desk.
He was wondering what time
your surgery would be done.
Yeah, I bet he is.
He probably found
another inspiration picture
in a bride magazine
he wants to discuss.
Do we do silver bells or
snowflakes on our invitation?
Garland or poinsettias
on the centerpiece?
Suction.
It's just a wedding.
Come on.
Out of all people, I thought I
could count on you to have my back.
Do you think I wanted that
wedding at Meredith's house?
That was for Owen.
Put on the dress.
There are bigger battles.
Right, 'cause that
philosophy worked out
so well for you
and Owen. T-tube.
Here you go.
Ugh!
Dr. Kepner? Sorry, this PDS
suture isn't holding, and
I can't get hemostasis.
Horseback riding is
supposed to be fun,
but even if you wear the right
shoes and a helmet and everything,
protection doesn't always work.
You know what? What's the point?
You might as well
just ride bareback.
Karev, can you take
this over for a second?
Yeah, sure.
You, whatever your name is, can
you stop stalking me with chairs?
I'm stretching, which is normal.
We all need to
stretch sometimes.
So can you just get
that thing away from me?
Pickups. WOMAN: Here you go.
You were right.
It's a tumor. Move.
But this Neuro guy says
it's too far along to operate,
so they're just gonna
send him home.
She spent all these years
thinking he was just a dirty old man,
and now she knows it's a tumor
and that's not who he
is, it's too late, and...
I'm talking to myself.
Dr. Yang, I'm
almost finished here.
You can get ready
to close the sternum.
Boki, I think Dr. Yang prefers
sternal cables, not monofilament wire.
Dr. Edwards, how would you like
the honor of closing
for me today?
No. You heard me. No
interns closing up this patient.
Dr. Bailey, I might not give
the best wedding advice,
but this is my intern
under my service,
and she's been practicing
this procedure for days.
I am more than
confident she's prepared.
Fine. Let her close.
Prepare the sternal
cable, please, Boki.
Dr. Bailey, should there
be this much bleeding?
He's not clotting.
Let's get some FFP
and Factor VII up here.
Get in there with some lap pads.
We need to apply pressure quick.
All right, guys.
Okay, let's make sure
that we check pulses
every two hours.
I'm gonna go
talk to the parents.
Everybody out.
I said get out.
You okay?
Robbins, are you hurt?
Did you hit your head?
I was... I was so
proud of myself.
For getting through
today and the surgery,
like nothing was different,
and I'm such a big shot
that I went and put all
my weight on my left foot,
I don't have a left foot.
And now I'm on my ass.
And you should... You should
see the look on your face.
Are you gonna... Are
you gonna help me up?
Yeah. Come on.
Come on.
How's the bleeding?
Still won't stop.
Can we try more RBCs?
That'll just overload him.
What's his lactate level?
It's gone from nine to
17 in the last 30 minutes.
No.
Come on. No. No.
Damn it.
What is it? Why'd you stop?
See how the liver's patchy?
He's rejecting it?
Does this mean I
don't get to close?
Okay, so if we
did a pedicle flap...
We could do a tendon transfer
to get back motor function.
Where are you? What?
You've been staring
at your phone all day,
like some 16-year-old girl
waiting for a creepy
college guy to text her back.
I need you to focus.
I'm sorry, okay?
But we both know Shepherd is
just gonna shoot this thing down.
He doesn't want
to do the surgery.
He doesn't know what
he wants. He's just scared.
He wishes this never
happened, but it happened,
and now it's up to us
to come up with a plan
that makes him feel
just a little less scared,
makes him believe
it'll all be okay.
And we can do that. So come
on. Are you with me here?
I gotta go do something.
What?
Hey. What's up?
Look at this.
A mesio-orbital
frontal lobe tumor.
He's the grabby guy.
He's a father.
His whole family's
horrified to be around him.
I thought we could help him,
but Clemens says it's inoperable.
No, it's not.
I thought so.
All right, I'll page Clemens,
let him know that he's an idiot,
and walk him
through how to do it.
Derek. Yeah.
He's not gonna do
as good a job as you.
No, he's not.
Which is why you have
to get your hand fixed.
I don't... I don't
have the results yet.
I told you I would text you.
I'm in. All the way.
What? Come on.
I know it might not be what you
planned or how you planned it,
but we can do this.
We'll get married, have an
awesome kid, be amazing parents.
I'm in.
Don't say that if you
don't mean it. I mean it.
We can do this.
You really think that...
You said it yourself.
Something that feels
this good cannot be bad.
So you... You really want this?
I want this.
We get married.
We have a house.
We get a big yard.
And we have a wedding?
We have a huge freaking wedding.
In a... In a field
with butterflies.
Butterflies, a field...
Whatever you want.
Okay? Your family's
gonna be there.
My family... I mean, my
crazy mom's gonna be there.
She'll probably bring Webber.
Whatever. That's fine.
Oh, my gosh.
Are we really...
You sure we can do this?
We can do this.
How did you know?
Eleven years in your job.
You want it back? No.
You know, they're usually
looking for a scapegoat,
someone they can lay all the
blame on and then set 'em adrift.
That's what happened?
No, the board, they
have my back completely.
Well, that's great.
Yeah.
Why wouldn't they just fire me?
I don't know.
What?
You're married to
someone on the other side.
They seem unhappy about that?
Richard, thanks.
You said it was a perfect match.
It was.
Just sometimes for reasons
we don't always understand,
the body doesn't want
to accept the new organ.
So what now? You...
You put him back
on the transplant list?
Yeah. We made calls.
But given Graham's condition...
He needs this.
Look at him.
You can't tell me there
are sicker people out there.
That's the point, bug. I'm sick.
Better they give it to someone
who could make it last.
How long do I have?
A week, maybe.
That's good.
It's not 30 years.
But it's better than nothing.
I'm sorry.
Hey, you don't get to
leave. Come back here.
I'm old. And I've
had a good life.
I found people to love
who loved me back.
You save your tears for
someone who needs them.
I mean it. You did good.
We've got this week...
And we're gonna make it count.
Good night.
All right. Then I'll
see you tomorrow.
Here we go.
"Not pregnant."
Oh, God.
Thank you, Jesus.
Now we don't have to
get married. We're free.
We just... We just
dodged a bullet.
Like, the biggest bullet ever.
Thank you. Thank you,
God. Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you. Thank you.
No. No, Jackson,
no, I didn't mean...
Just, you know, now
things don't have to change.
We could stay dating, just
not while also raising a child.
Everything can stay the same.
You know, I'll just go on the pill
so I don't have to freak
out every time that I am late.
It's cool. Seriously,
don't bother.
What? Jackson...
Maybe this was a sign, you know?
That we needed to stop.
Honestly, I think
it's for the best.
Okay. I mean, if that's what...
It is.
I gotta go check in on
Torres. I will see you later.
Okay.
Hey, weepy.
No big deal, but
don't do that again.
It's gross.
Sorry.
What? You cared about him.
No, I didn't.
You did, just like you cared
about that other intern so much,
you fought me to teach her.
Just like you cared
about my wedding
enough to give
me personal advice.
Good advice that I'm
actually planning to take.
So I don't know
what happened to you
in that frozen hell of a tundra,
but you've changed.
I did not.
No. No, no, no, no, no!
You're supposed to...
You're supposed to wait. I'm
coming up with another plan.
It's not like the others.
Okay, great.
Well, let's hear it.
No.
No, you're just... You're
gonna crap all over it.
I've been busting
my ass for you on this
and making PowerPoints
and losing sleep
to talk to surgeons
in Switzerland
when I should be talking to you.
You want to fix your hand?
Then help me, damn it.
That came out a little
stronger than I intended.
You're right. Okay? So
here's what we're gonna do.
We're gonna throw
out everything we have.
We're gonna get new studies.
We're gonna come at
it from a different angle.
We're gonna clear our heads,
and then we are gonna figure it out.
So do we start right now?
Tomorrow.
You need to take the
night off. Thank you.
Oh, thank God.
Have I changed?
How?
How would he know that?
Who?
He says nothing has changed, but
what if I'm the thing that's changed,
but he won't
friggin' talk to me?
I'm all caught up now.
Do you think I've changed?
Well, you want Owen back.
I don't.
Yeah, I want Owen back.
We've changed. It's good.
I'd like to see that.
Dr. Hunt. Is there
something else?
Yeah, a question.
My conflict of interest here doesn't
seem to concern you too much.
Well, like we said,
it's unusual for...
What about my wife's
conflict of interest?
She's married to me, too.
Well, that...
I booked the plane,
and my wife could benefit
financially from my negligence.
You're hoping that because
I'm married to Cristina,
the judge will throw
this whole case out.
Whoa, Dr. Hunt. Let's
not over think this.
The board supports you 100...
Let me just remind you that
the confidentiality
agreement that you signed
is punishable by termination
and financial penalties.
I understand.
Have a good night.
You will be getting an
invitation in the mail soon.
There will probably
be elves on it.
You, however, will
not be getting me a gift.
Are you telling me that if
I get you a waffle maker,
you'll send it back?
I do like a waffle.
Well, it's gonna be fine.
You promise?
No. But I'll have
your back either way.
I wouldn't be able to
show up to work again.
It wasn't that bad.
It sounds pretty bad.
I cry during sex
sometimes. It's not that bad.
All right.
You look like crap.
Yeah. That's about right.
Beer. MAN: Sure.
So, Kepner's knocked up?
I mean, she was acting
a little weirder than usual,
you were taking her blood.
Here you go.
Well, not that it's
any of your business,
but no, she is not knocked up.
That sounds like
something to drink to.
Can we get another
round? Coming up.
No more calling her "weird."
She is. Yeah, I know. Just...
You're not allowed to say it.
Can you dance? Can
you show me your moves?
Hello. Can you dance with me?
Hi.
What's going on here?
We're having a
little dance party.
So... I guess you
had a good day?
Yeah, yeah. I fell down.
What? What happened?
I got back up.
Hey, I started dinner, but then
little miss wanted my attention,
so do you mind
finishing the salad?
Sure. Hi, baby. Hi.
Hi, Mama. Hi, Mama.
Do you want to dance?
Hi.
You see my necklace?
Maybe I do believe it...
All this "meant to be" stuff.
Hey.
So, I talked to Clemens.
He referred the tumor patient to
somebody over at Seattle Pres.
Great. Take a look at
the shirt that I bought Zola.
It's in the bag on the counter.
Meredith, guys don't get all
goo-goo over baby clothes.
Just look.
What is this?
Why not believe it, really?
Who doesn't want more
romance in their life?
It's only three weeks so I
shouldn't even be telling you.
I mean, I still have
a hostile uterus,
and terrible things are
constantly happening to us,
which is why I haven't told
anyone. I haven't even told Cristina.
So if you tell anyone,
I swear, I will kick you out
of this house that you built.
Don't worry. And good
things happen to us.
We're gonna have another baby.
We are gonna have another baby.
Maybe it's just up to
us to make it happen...
To show up and be
meant for each other.
Thank you for coming. Yeah.
We should talk.
We should.
At least that way,
you'll find out for sure...
I think...
We should get a divorce.
That's what you want?
If you're meant to be...
Yeah.
Or not.