Surgeons have a saying,
"All bleeding must stop."
It's sort of our version
of "This, too, shall pass."
Every crisis will
eventually come to an end.
You'll either save your
patient, or you won't.
Are they gonna ask me about...
- Ben.
Right. You can't tell me.
How's Omar doing?
I can't...
Can't tell me that, either.
Just doing my job.
Thank you, Chief.
Ah. It's a good thing I'm
not trying to save lives
so I can see that the
elevator doors are open.
So...
One way or the other,
the bleeding will stop.
Actually, as far as sayings go,
this one's really not
all that comforting.
Omar Singh, post-op day one,
following abdominal
and chest surgery
to repair injuries sustained
during a car accident.
DeLuca? Shortly after surgery,
Omar went into cardiac arrest.
Dr. Shepherd placed him
on therapeutic hypothermia
as part of a new
resuscitation protocol.
Tell me why. We hoped
that cooling the patient...
He's regaining consciousness,
and he's breathing spontaneously,
so they'll extubate soon.
Thank God.
Uh, Grey, you should go.
They're waiting for you. Okay.
Oh, I put together
an advisory panel...
Grey, Hunt, Pierce.
They're going to review
the Warren situation.
Bailey, we talked about this.
As the leader of this surgical
staff, you need to take charge of it.
As the leader of
this surgical staff,
I need to know my limitations.
And I know I cannot be
impartial about my husband
and the future of his career.
As a leader, I am taking
charge of my lack of impartiality
by convening an advisory
panel to review the matter.
Once they give me
their recommendation
for how to proceed, as a leader,
I will make a final decision on
what happens with my husband.
As a human being, I'll
stand here and thank the Lord
that my husband
isn't responsible
for leaving three children
without any parents at all.
Warren, have a seat.
When Miranda told me that
there was an advisory committee,
I pictured a bunch of
lawyers and hospital suits.
Okay. I'm, uh,
glad it's you guys.
Let's do it.
Dr. Warren, be apprised
that the purpose
of this committee
is to understand the incident
and to make recommendations
for disciplinary action,
should it be called for.
A lack of full cooperation
with or withholding of
information from this committee
will result in your immediate
dismissal from the residency program.
Okay.
You accept these conditions?
Yes.
Okay. Let's begin then.
Wait. So, she's still
accusing me of harassment?
I mean, I tried to
meet her halfway here.
I tried to take the
high road. This...
Apparently, the high road is
paved with restraining orders.
I'm sorry. I'll be quiet.
The restraining order
actually works for us.
When we take her to
court to have it lifted,
she won't be able to prove
any of these allegations,
and her character will
be called into question,
which is exactly
where we want to be.
Because? Because
once that baby is born,
you will have a very good
shot at obtaining full custody.
Full custody?
No. He would never.
He would.
Look, I know that I'm
just here for support,
but why would Jackson do that?
Because it's exactly what
I would advise her to do.
Whether you
meant it or not, April,
this restraining order
started an arms race.
The restraining order was a
mistake. Can't we just take it back?
I'm serious here. Do
not try to talk to him.
The restraining
order needs to stand.
We have to do
this together, okay?
This is exactly what
I was trying to avoid.
After everything that
happened with Samuel, I just...
I just want to keep
this baby safe.
Good. See? You felt
your baby was in danger.
That's great. That we can use.
Wow.
Fractured pelvis?
Stepped on by a horse.
So, tomorrow's the day.
Preminger Grant,
yes or no, stay or go.
Oh, you haven't given
them an answer yet?
You thought I would
have given them an answer
and not talked to
you about it? No.
No. I'm just saying,
the Preminger Grant's a
once-in-a-lifetime opportunity.
If I say yes,
I will be moving to New
York for at least a year.
Right.
And you're fine with that?
Are you fine with that?
Well, like you said, it's...
Once in a lifetime.
Yep. Well, I got to get
this pelvis into the OR.
Reggie Dalton?
I'm Dr. Jo Wilson.
Your chart says that
you have a hernia.
Yeah. It's the worst.
Okay, well, let's take
a look. Just lay back.
I'm gonna lift up your shirt.
Okay, so, how long has
this been going on for?
Uh, I had surgery,
like, uh, six months ago,
and after a while,
this little guy
just started
popping out of there.
Six months ago? Yeah.
I had it looked at once before,
and they said
they could operate,
but that it wasn't urgent.
So, I put it off, and...
Oh, God. Oh, no. Oh, no.
Reggie, are you okay? Yes.
So, this is the thing...
It's allergy season, and
every time I sneeze...
The little guy pops out.
I think maybe I've waited
a little too long to
get surgery because...
Oh, no! Okay,
Reggie, don't fight it.
It's only gonna make it worse.
Worse than this?
Is my baby gonna die? No.
It's open before
you even touch her.
I know that's
what it looks like.
That's what it is,
Warren, right there.
You said you didn't
see the doors open.
Yes. I mean, no.
Well, which is it? Did
you? Or didn't you?
I didn't see them open.
It is right there
in front of you.
I know, but I didn't see it.
It didn't register.
Okay. Help me here. Was it...
Had you already
decided to cut? No.
Or did you decide
getting in the elevator
and up to the OR
was just gonna take too long?
No.
Ben, lying right now is going
to make this end very quickly.
I didn't see them open.
I spoke with your grandma,
and she'll be here
in a couple of hours.
Your dad still has a long
recovery ahead of him,
but the fact that he's waking
up is a really good sign.
You said I can see
him when he wakes up.
I did.
And you will.
When? How about now?
Yeah? Come on.
Now, before we go in,
your dad's connected
to some tubes,
- but that's normal...
- Coming through!
So, don't be scared when the...
Wait, Jasmine!
Daddy? STEPHANIE:
DeLuca, get the suction...
Okay, got it. - Daddy?
Push more lorazepam.
What's wrong with him?
We're gonna need to put
him back on the ventilator.
Prep for RSI.
Jasmine, they need to help him.
You said he was awake.
You said he was okay!
I know. I know, honey.
Come on.
They were done
with me for the day.
Okay.
They needed to talk to
the other doctors involved.
I see. I wanted to
check on my post-ops,
but they told me I
couldn't go back to work
until all of this was...
Yeah, it's best that you
not have contact
with any patients.
Okay, then...
Well, I guess I'll just pick
up Tuck early from school.
You know, he's been begging
me to go to this new arcade.
Did he clean his room?
I don't know.
Well, he can't go to the arcade
unless he's cleaned his room.
You know that, Ben.
I'm a grown-ass man,
and I was there when
we made the rule.
I don't need you to tell me...
Well, apparently you
do because you're...
Okay, stop. Stop. Just stop.
Miranda...
Look at me.
Miranda, I...
You were mean.
This morning, you were mean.
I'm sorry.
But this is just... This is
running over me like a truck.
I feel... I know.
Me, too.
Okay, so, we need
separate this out, um...
The Chief and
Dr. Warren over here
and Ben and Miranda over here.
Church and state, okay?
Church and state.
Dr. Bailey, Omar
Singh's mother is here.
Tell her I'll be right there.
Ben... I'll see you at home.
Is home church or state?
Church, I think.
Post-surgical hernias are
not actually all that uncommon,
but given its size, we're gonna
need to do a special procedure
to close the gap
without tension on the...
What are you doing?
Uh, I've gotten in the habit
of just sort of shoving
it all back in there.
Is that not okay?
Um...
Hey.
Um, Wilson, we
will be right back.
Come on.
What are you doing?
Wilson called for a plastics
consult for your CSR,
which I obviously can't
do with you standing here,
unless you want to violate the
terms of your own restraining order.
I'm not...
I'm not violating anything
because you're gonna go, okay?
Just send someone else, please.
Why don't we ask the patient?
He'd want a consult from the
best plastic surgeon in this hospital.
You know that
this is just as much
a general-surgery
case as it is a plastics.
Right, and there are
plenty of general surgeons
and only one of me.
I was here first.
Holy crap!
You ignored the
moment completely.
What moment?
The moment where I
say, "Go to New York,"
and then you ask me to
come to New York with you...
The moment. What?
Wait.
You didn't even want
me to meet your kid.
No... You met my kid.
My kid loves you. It's fine...
Callie, you live
here in Seattle.
You... You have
family. You have a job.
You can't just drop everything
and move to New York.
I know, but still!
Still what?
It would have been
nice to have been asked.
What?
You are the
most adorable woman
I've ever seen right now.
Really?
And, of course, I want you
to come to New York with me.
But it's impossible.
There is, always,
long distance.
Well, that's true.
Weekend trips.
Dirty phone calls.
Mmm. Mmm.
Exactly how dirty?
Mmm.
Mmm. Mmm-hmm.
Oh, my God.
Oh, God!
Um, uh, I need a suture kit.
No, you know what,
actually, I don't need it. Bye.
Guys, we can't go
back in time here.
I mean, there's no way to know
how it would have turned out.
I mean, I sure wouldn't have
opened her up in a hallway
if I didn't have to,
but Warren's saying that
he didn't have a choice.
Except for those
doors... I mean...
Yeah. The doors were open.
How do you not see those doors?
And as for the baby?
He was acidotic,
not oxygenating.
We had to put him on ECMO.
Which was unsuccessful.
That kind of perfusion can
be too much for smaller babies.
Riggs suggested
ECMO. We all agreed.
Wait. So, Riggs suggested it?
Yeah.
And you agreed with that?
Well, I was worried, but
we were out of options.
So, the ECMO that
Riggs suggested,
it exacerbated the problem?
Like I said, we
were out of options.
Okay.
Well, I think that's all we
need from you guys. Thank you.
Yeah. Sure thing.
Thanks. Good luck.
Listen, we should
meet again tomorrow.
With whom? We've
heard from everyone.
We haven't met with Riggs.
Oh, my God. What?
Nothing.
What do you think
will happen to Warren?
Oh, I don't know.
You're already leaving.
If he goes, too, they're
gonna work us to death.
Mmm, we're gonna
get all the surgeries.
I mean, I feel bad, but
we gonna run this place.
Holy...
What is going on with your
phone? What are... Hey, stop!
Stop! No, no, no! What?
- Please give it back.
- Who's Kyle?
And why does he want to
do things with his tongue...
Answer the question.
Okay, come here.
Please. Shut up.
Okay, do you know
Shepherd's MS. patient?
Oh!
Guitar Hero?
You are doing tongue
things with Guitar Hero?
No. Not yet.
I told him maybe we would go
out when he got back from touring,
and so we've been texting,
and now he's melting my phone.
That's kind of hot,
and really dirty.
Yeah. I call my
mother with this thing.
Oh, God. Wow.
Like this.
How am I supposed
to respond to this?
Oh, like this.
Oh, my God!
Mmm.
Thank you.
Do you think you
can teach me that?
Yeah.
Your suture kit. I'm so sorry.
It's fine.
Um, I should have
knocked, I guess.
She's leaving. Huh?
New York.
The Preminger Grant.
I'm so sorry. But, you
know, I don't know.
I mean, that doesn't
mean that it has to be over.
Long-distance relationships
aren't impossible.
Yeah, I don't know if we
can survive long distance.
I'm so afraid that
it'll all fall apart.
Then don't let it.
I mean, decide you want it
to work and make it happen.
It's New York. It's
a six-hour flight.
It's weekends and phone calls.
You can figure it out.
You will. You... You should.
Thanks. Mmm.
Hey, Callie. Yeah?
Maybe next time,
like, an on-call room,
something with, like,
a lock on the door.
You stole my patient?
He's my patient, all right?
And you should
probably step back about,
I don't know, 100 feet.
All right, now.
This man needs
a plastic surgeon.
And a general surgeon.
Which is why Dr. Webber
is going to be scrubbing
in with me, all right?
I'm the head of Plastics.
I have seniority here.
So, I'm not gonna step down
just because you decided
to file a restraining order.
This... This is not...
Okay, you know... Okay.
Now, that's enough.
Now, this patient isn't
gonna get less than our best
because the two of you are not
allowed to be in the same room.
I'm scrubbing in with Avery.
End of discussion.
I'm free tomorrow after 4:00.
So, he may never wake up again?
He did wake up,
but then he suffered
a prolonged seizure.
He may have been
oxygen-deprived.
We're still trying
to figure out why.
But you should know,
reviewing his most recent
scans, there's not much activity.
They suggest he may have
suffered severe damage.
So, even if he did wake up
now, we're not sure what's left.
Your son didn't
have a directive.
These forms will determine
whether you want us to
try and resuscitate Omar
if his heart fails.
I don't know what to do.
It's a very difficult decision.
No, he's my baby.
I can still remember
how it felt to hold him.
I can't just...
I don't know what to do.
What do I do?
You should sign the papers.
Daddy wouldn't
want to live in a bed
connected to machines
with his eyes
closed all the time.
He would hate it.
And he would...
He would want to be with Mommy.
I need a pen.
We love you, Daddy.
Any change? No.
How'd the Warren thing go?
- It's still going.
- It shouldn't be.
This is just Owen
being pissed at Riggs.
I mean, I get that there's
bad blood there, but...
Well, it's really bad blood.
Owen only ever
told me headlines,
and I had to drag it out of him.
It was impossible
to get him to talk.
Probably because
you were talking.
Uncool. Be nice.
Yeah, and you know Riggs
cheated on Owen's sister.
What? What?
That's why she got on the
helicopter, and disappeared
because she was leaving him.
Still, it's old business.
And he lied about
it right to my face.
He made up some sad story
about how he tried to stop her
from getting on the helicopter,
but she had to save a
patient, and he had no choice.
He made himself
look pretty good.
Wow. That's...
Psychotic. I agree.
So, Owen does not trust him,
and I'm not inclined to, either.
Heart rate's dropping.
I'll get a crash cart.
No, no, wait. He's DNR. Yeah.
I hate this part.
Mer?
Bailey will want to know.
You didn't wake me.
Where are my keys?
Why didn't you wake me?
Have you seen my keys?
They... I got called in.
Yeah, which is why I want to
know why you didn't wake me.
I had them in my hand
when I walked in the door...
I wake you. You wake
me. That's the rule.
You get paged in the
middle of the night,
you wake the other person.
You wake me so I
know to listen for Tuck,
so I know not to
rush out of here
for the hospital in the morning
thinking you did the morning
thing and just had an early surgery,
so I don't leave our child in
the house asleep in his bed
when I should be waking
him, making him breakfast
and taking him to school
because that's my job,
because that's the rule,
because that's what happens,
because when you get
paged, you wake me.
Would you stop looking
for the damn keys
and tell me why you
didn't wake me, Miranda?
Omar is dying,
and while you stand
there and yell at me,
three children are
becoming orphans.
I did not wake you
because I didn't want
to talk to you right now.
Keys.
That was...
Seriously, you have skills.
I don't work alone.
Teamwork.
I don't, though, work alone.
I'm gonna be
miserable without you.
You never asked me to stay.
I can't.
Penny...
Penny, I want you to stay.
I would give anything
for you to stay.
But I know better than to ask.
I have been here before.
This is the beginning of a
whole new adventure for you.
I could never ask
you to give that up.
I love you too much.
You...
I love you.
Hey.
No, no, don't cry.
I love you.
And you love me.
And now I have to go all
the way across the country
to save lives...
Which sounds really noble,
like in some movie, but...
Actually, it just really sucks.
Penny...
It's the moment again.
The moment.
Ask me.
Go ahead.
Sofia, get those
teeth brushed, missy!
I want to hit the road
in about 10 minutes!
Hi. Something is
wrong with the baby...
Really, horribly wrong.
Wrong? Wrong how?
I was driving to the hospital,
and, um, I got so scared
that I couldn't breathe,
and your place is
closer, so I just...
What... Hold on, April. Slow
down. Tell me what's going on.
Jackson was right, wasn't he,
that I was wrong to not check?
Okay, hey... I can't!
Arizona, I cannot do this again.
I can't.
Ooh, you are being
such a good little helper.
Let's walk a little
faster, though, okay?
Oh, Andrew!
Andrew's gonna show you where
all the best coloring books are, okay?
I am? Yeah.
Okay. Come on.
I refused the ultrasound.
I needed this baby
to be healthy so badly,
- and now, if I caused this...
- Okay, okay. It's okay.
If we could have
prevented this...
All right, let's
just take a look.
Let's take a look,
okay? Okay, okay, okay.
There.
There's the little one. Oh!
That's... That's it.
That's the feeling.
What is that? What is that?
That's your baby moving.
Look.
Very strong fetal heartbeat.
That's the baby moving?
Samuel never...
I know. You've
never felt this before.
I'm gonna check the cervical
length just because of the cramping,
but I am confident
that this is just
what a healthy baby feels like.
Advisory panel?
The situation
seemed fairly clear.
Well, that doesn't make deciding
disciplinary action any easier.
I suppose.
What if it were you and me?
Would it be so easy for
you to make that decision?
You and I would never
be in this situation.
Well, you never know.
Yes, I do, 'cause if you
did something like this,
I'd just strangle you
with my bare hands.
I wouldn't be
the one to do this.
I'm talking about you.
Oh, please, please.
This is all of it, I think.
All of what?
Well, I got joint purchases,
marriage license,
post-nup, divorce decree.
Our attorneys asked Jackson
to put together
whatever he could
to help create a
timeline, a paper trail.
Do you have to do this now?
Yeah, I got to get it back to
him by the end of the week.
Well, I'll leave
you to it, then.
Oh, and thanks again,
sir, for yesterday.
Appreciate you backing me up.
I didn't back you up.
I backed up a patient
whose doctors couldn't
get it together long
enough to do their damn job.
The baby was in
respiratory failure
despite maximal
ventilatory support.
He fit the criteria, so
ECMO was the only option.
I agree.
All right?
What was his oxidation index?
Around 45 for at least
20 minutes. Okay.
And you used
aggressive resuscitation?
Yeah, of course.
They tried to clear his
metabolic acidosis with fluids,
but he had a pH of...
I mean, I can pull the chart.
We have the chart.
So, what is this about?
This is about Dr. Warren.
Thank you,
Dr. Riggs. You can go.
Sure.
This was fun.
So, if Riggs' recommendation
killed the baby,
then we should...
I would have made the same call.
There was nothing else
left to do. We don't know that.
Okay, we need to bring
this back to the point
because you have, frankly,
been wasting my time
on a needless witch hunt.
This is not about Dr. Riggs,
and it is not about you.
The point here is to
answer one question,
do we think Ben Warren
is telling us the truth?
So let's answer it.
His blood pressure
keeps dropping,
and his heart rate
is all over the place.
Well, it's been hours,
and he hasn't had any
further seizure activity.
We could give him
medication to control his heart,
and fluid to boost his pressure.
No.
Mrs. Singh?
He's gone.
My son is gone.
Is Omar...
Is he gone?
You can tell me that.
We're still waiting.
Church?
State.
So, did you find
something new or...
Warren, we need
you to tell us why.
Why what?
Why, when the
elevator doors opened,
you chose to ignore it...
I have told you and told you...
And cut open Gretchen
McKay, anyway.
That I did not make a choice!
I wasn't given one.
I was forced to use the
knowledge and resources I had
to fulfill the oath I
took to save her life...
Because the door didn't open.
No, it did. It clearly did.
I'm saying I didn't
see it happen.
I just don't understand
how you didn't see it happen.
You do. You know.
You should know.
You're surgeons.
You know what it's like. You...
When you operate,
when you control if a person
breathes another breath, when...
When you hold their
beating heart in your hand,
when you are
responsible for that life,
you don't see or hear
or feel anything else.
The rest of the
world just disappears.
You know that.
You all do.
You can't tell me you don't.
Okay. What's happening?
He's having runs of
v-tach. I think he's going.
His mom just took the
kids down for lunch, too. I...
Should I bring her back up here?
Chief?
Crash cart. What?
Yeah. I need a crash
cart in here now!
Start CPR.
Oh, Dr. Bailey, I don't
think we're supposed to.
Okay, push an amp of epi.
What is this? Uh,
Dr. Shepherd, I...
Bailey, what are we doing?
Okay. Good. Charge to 100.
Mmm-mmm. Isn't he
supposed to be DNR?
Yes. His mother agreed.
Clear!
Okay, charge to 150,
and get that epi on board.
Bailey, we told his mother
we would not resuscitate.
Clear!
200! Bailey!
His heart stopped?
Yes, it did,
but only just for a
second, and then...
You decided to resuscitate.
But I signed those papers.
Jasmine and I, we
made a decision.
Yes, I know.
I wanted to give him
one more chance.
So you think there's still hope?
I don't understand.
Just yesterday, we were
discussing brain damage.
Chief, a word.
Bailey, just explain
what you are thinking.
My patient has a signed DNR.
The patient deserves a chance.
His family deserves
for this hospital to
respect their wishes.
Shepherd...
It is not fair
to make a patient suffer so
that Warren doesn't have to.
You know that.
Dr. Shepherd, watch yourself.
You were right, and thank you.
I love being right.
What was I right about?
Penny. We figured it out.
Oh, yay. Yeah.
Yeah, no, Sofia was saying...
I can totally go with her.
What? No. It seemed impossible
until I really, really looked
at it, but it's not impossible.
It's an adventure.
You're kidding.
Are you kidding? I
know. It's crazy, right?
But I can get a job
anywhere out there,
and probably with
new research money,
and I have colleagues out
there who can help me get...
Wait. Yeah, no, but you...
Well, you have a
daughter. Yeah. No. I know.
It's a lot to
figure out, I know.
But you were right,
it can be figured out.
It's a six-hour flight,
and you'll be able to see
Sofia whenever you want.
And we'll figure it out, right?
Oh, crap. Um, so, we
will talk about it, okay?
But just thank you.
Every surgeon who worked
on Mrs. McKay and the baby
said the same thing,
including Dr. Warren.
That they were backed into a
corner and they didn't have a choice.
The only difference with Warren
is whether or not
you think he's lying,
whether you believe he
didn't see that door open.
And do you think he was lying?
No. We don't.
We believe Warren
missed the door.
We believe he was
completely focused
on his responsibility
to the patient.
Well, thank you all.
Mmm-hmm.
Sounds like they feel he tried.
And yet two people
are still dead.
What are you gonna do?
Six months?
No surgery for six months?
Uh, to be clear, it's a
six-month suspension
from the residency program.
I'm suspended from the hospital?
Yes.
How do you...
Do you have any idea
how far behind I'll fall?
I'll never get caught up.
What am I supposed
to learn from this?
Do you feel even
the slightest remorse?
Yes. Yes!
How can you ask me
that? Of course I do!
All I do is play it over
again in my mind,
trying to figure out
how I could change it!
Of course I do.
But six months,
it's not discipline.
For a surgeon, that's
a death sentence.
I might as well drop out now.
That's all, Dr. Warren.
I tried to save her the
only way I know how.
You... They know that, right?
You know that.
Sofia.
Hi!
Hi.
You ready? You ready?
Let's go.
Oh, thank you.
Get inside!
Pierce, before you go,
Tacoma wants to send a
patient with failed stenting.
Emergency four-vessel bypass.
I didn't want to authorize it
until I'd checked it with you, but...
Uh, well, is the patient
stable enough to transfer?
As far I'm concerned, yes.
Okay, yeah. Go ahead.
What?
Nothing. Nothing.
What did Owen tell you about me?
Meredith. She said, um...
She's my sister,
and she told me...
She told you about Megan.
Why would you lie
about something like that?
You know, I shouldn't have
asked. This isn't any of my business.
And I'm not usually
a person who...
You don't owe me an
explanation, obviously,
but you're a good guy
and a great
surgeon, and I just...
Why?
I didn't lie to Meredith.
It's fine. Forget it.
Look, everything
I told her was true.
There was a patient.
There was a helicopter.
I just left some parts out.
The part where we fought,
where I cheated,
where I failed the best
person I've ever met,
the only woman I've ever loved.
And those parts are
for me and Megan.
You're right. I don't
owe anyone that.
I made a mistake.
A big one.
And I've paid for it ever since.
Okay?
Okay.
I'm glad you're being
strong about this.
I know how hard this is.
I know how bad you feel.
You loved this person once.
There's a child involved.
But I'm gonna tell you,
the one thing that all custody
cases have in common
is that they are
always a battle.
And no matter
what, even if you win,
you will still feel like
you lost something.
So, are you sure this is
a battle you want to fight?
My ex-wife wants to
move across the country
and take our daughter, so...
Yeah.
Hey.
Stop.
No. No more, okay?
I'm done. Just stay
away from me. All right.
Look, I'm not gonna
come any closer, okay?
I just need to talk to you.
I need to say something.
I need you to hear me.
Please?
Fine.
All right, I have been
going over the paperwork,
you know, for the lawyer, the
prenup, post-nup, whatever.
You know, I just...
I don't need this.
At first glance, it was
actually really frustrating,
you know, 'cause I
wasn't finding anything
that was actually
gonna help my case.
It was just so fair.
And I realized that was
because it was written
by two people who
really loved each other...
Two people who really
wanted to protect each other,
who really wanted what
was best for each other.
And, April, I...
I don't know where
those people went.
I don't know if we
can fix us, April.
I don't know if we should.
But I know I don't like
who I am turning into.
I don't want to treat you...
This person who wrote
this, who signed this,
was your best friend.
You were my best friend, April.
My favorite person.
And I realized that that's
who I should be dealing with.
We should treat each other
the way we did on this paper.
You want to feel something
unbelievably awesome?
Oh.
Was that a kick? Yeah.
He's kicking?
Or, she's kicking.
This baby can kick?
Our baby can kick.
Oh, he did it again.
Why are you still here?
You have to go back
to them. You have to...
Hunt, and this committee. You
have to get them to reconsider.
There's... They have
nothing to reconsider.
They made a
recommendation. I made a call.
It's very simple, and I'm
done talking about this here.
Church and state.
There's a reason that it's
separated. To hell with state!
You're really gonna
come back at me
with "no special
treatment"? Six months is...
Six months is special treatment!
What?
If you had been anyone else,
you wouldn't have
been suspended.
You would have been fired.
They told you to fire me?
No! I wanted to fire you!
I was talked down!
Do you have any idea
what you are doing?
Do you have any
idea what you've done?
I made a mistake, Miranda.
People make mistakes.
Surgeons make mistakes!
I don't, not like that.
You made an astonishing
error in judgment
that I'm trying to
accept and forgive.
And it's gonna take me a
lot longer than six months.
All bleeding must stop.
Well, I am sorry
I disappoint you.
Sometimes it does so at a cost.
So am I.
You lose the arm,
remove the organ.
You choose to
live with the loss.
Chief?
Because at the end of the day,
you'll do whatever
you can to stay alive.
In the last hour,
he started moving,
responding to verbal stimuli.
And now, vitals are
stable. He is re-oriented.
What... This is
one in a million.
It should not have happened.
And sometimes, by
some miracle, it works.
The bleeding stops.
Well, does he know yet,
about his wife and baby?
No. Not yet.
He's asking.
I was wrong, Bailey.
You saved his life.
And now I have to
go in there and ruin it.
But sometimes, no
matter how hard you try...
It's still not enough.