In a rare instance
when a patient died while
hooked up to brain monitors,
doctors saw an increase
in brain activity
right before
and after his heart stopped.
Call 911.
Come on.
911. What's your emergency?
The brain waves that surged
were associated with dreaming,
information processing,
and memory recall.
Push another epi.
Please, Jackie.
Still nothing.
Someone get me a T.E.E.
right now.
It confirms what we often hear
when we revive a patient
in cardiac arrest --
that right before
their heart stopped,
they saw their life flash
before their eyes.
After everything
we've been through,
I thought this was
impossible.
Me too.
Not that I remember it all,
but...
Mm...
E.R.
I have to go.
Can you stay?
I'll look for you
as soon as I can.
I have nowhere else
to be.
Bailey,
have you seen Yasuda?
I paged her 10 minutes ago.
Nothing.
That's because she doesn't
work here anymore.
She quit the program.
What happened?
Just being back here
where her sister died,
it was too hard.
It's unthinkable.
I wish there was more
I could've done to help her.
Oh. She's tough.
She'll -- She'll find a way.
I'm not so sure
about the others.
Millin isn't handling it
very well.
First year of residency, your
fellow interns are all you got.
I'll keep an eye on her.
Thank you.
Thought we were closed
to trauma.
Bring it in.
Bring it in this way.
All right. Hold up right there.
Watch yourself. Watch yourself.
Watch your backs, folks.
Watch your backs.
Make room
for the emergency vehicles.
What the hell happened?
Warren left us open
to trauma,
so you're looking at
the consequences.
I was going to set up
an additional triage tent,
and then I was gonna
come up with some workarounds.
I was chief of staff
at the Army Medical Command.
This is not a workaround.
This is a fireable offense.
So if you get the urge
to make another decision
without consulting me,
don't.
This is Altman.
Go ahead.
What did you do?
Not the time.
Ben!
All right. That's the last one.
We are closing to trauma!
Adams!
I'm okay.
It's not all time.
Jo Wilson, 38-year-old female.
Wilson?
Jo?
I'm gonna have to call you back.
What happened?
Got a gunshot wound
over here.
Yeah. His name is Damian.
28-year-old male.
GSW to the right chest.
No exit wound.
Intubated on the scene.
He was with you?
He held up the store.
All right. I'll go.
Stay with Wilson.
Let's get her inside.
She's bleeding.
You were shot?
No.
I...I'm pregnant.
I got you.
I really appreciate you
taking me to my hotel.
I know they need you
at the hospital.
Teddy hired a bunch
of outside doctors to pitch in.
She has plenty of help.
I can't believe
you still drive a truck.
What was it you used to drive?
An old Silverado?
I just remember it took up
two parking spaces.
Yeah, and it didn't go
over 45 miles an hour.
And only one
of the handles worked.
It was not what you would call
a chick magnet.
You could have driven
an RV,
and I would have thought it was
the sexiest truck on earth.
You hated me.
I was madly in love with you.
I thought you knew.
Hold on.
Okay.
You were mean to me.
You were my best friend's
older brother,
and I was a teenage girl
who didn't know
how to tell a boy I liked him.
W-Wow.
Are you okay?
Yeah. I'm fine.
It's just, um...
It's pain where I had
the surgery.
It happens sometimes.
You had the surgery
weeks ago.
I'm running you back
to the hospital.
No, no. That's not necessary.
Any amount of pain
could indicate a complication.
We're not taking
any chances.
Beautiful day,
isn't it?
It's 108 degrees.
The sun is out.
Everyone's working together
towards a common goal.
Mika quit.
What?
Why?
Well, her sister died here,
and she almost died,
and I think she wasn't
into the weather,
but that's just
an observation.
You okay?
You two were close.
I didn't come here
to make lifelong friends.
Did you?
No.
People come and go,
and I still have a job to do.
Do you see anything?
What's going on?
Why won't her heart start?
Ndugu?
Right there.
The aortic root aneurysm
dissected and extended down,
occluding the left
coronary artery.
The blockage is keeping
her heart from starting?
It's the tear.
Caused a massive infarction.
We need to revascularize
her coronary artery
to restore blood flow,
then put in an aortic graft.
Let's prep
for a sternotomy.
I know you wanted to take care
of this first,
but I maintain
that this was the right call.
She could have dissected
no matter what.
At least she did it
in the safest place,
where we can treat it.
An aortic dissection
is never safe.
Jackie's already been under
for hours.
We need to move faster.
Let's go.
Dr. Shepherd?
Whatever it is,
it's got to wait.
It's Dr. Adams.
He wants you to know he's okay.
Get us up to speed.
Single GSW
to the right chest.
No exit wound.
He's hypoxic.
He has a right hemothorax.
His FAST exam on his heart
was negative.
We need to prep
for a chest tube.
Okay. Bullet fragments are
localized on the right chest.
Let's order a type and cross
and trauma panel.
Can I do the chest tube?
Get her sterile gloves.
His sats are dropping,
so we need to move quickly.
I bet when he walked out
of the house with a gun today,
he didn't expect to be the one
getting shot.
Ready?
Mm-hmm.
All right.
You're gonna make an incision
between the fourth
and fifth rib space.
Now you're gonna pop through
the pleura.
Mm-hmm.
Good.
And now dilate
by opening the clamp.
Time for the tube.
Yeah.
Keep going.
All right.
He's putting out a lot of blood.
We need to call up to the O.R.
Nice work, Millin.
BP's 105 over 65.
That's...good.
Uh, how many weeks are you?
Sixteen weeks.
I, uh, had an appointment a week
ago, and everything looked fine.
Have you paged O.B.?
I can do it.
No, you will not.
You will get yourself checked.
Dr. Warren?
Come on. You heard her.
Let's go.
No. I-I was just grazed.
It can wait.
Do you think
your colleague
wants you to see me do
her ultrasound?
No.
Go. Now.
Don't let him out of your sight.
W-Wait. Adams.
Thank you.
Come on.
Let's go.
Bailey, I need to see
for myself.
You are not your doctor.
Okay?
We paged O.B.
In the meantime...
hmm.
All right.
The placenta looks great.
No abruption.
And where is the...
We have a strong heartbeat
right there.
Mm.
What about the other one?
There's an "other one"?
Okay.
Let me see.
Oh!
There it is!
Oh, beautiful.
Just these two,
right?
As far as I'm aware, yeah.
You okay?
Mm.
Nope. Okay.
Aah!
All right.
Someone help me get her to O.B.
And where's Lincoln?
All right.
Hold on.
We were finishing a surgery.
Are you okay?
It's just superficial abrasions.
Steri-Strips and I'm good.
And I've got psych coming down
for an eval.
Yeah. I don't need that.
Yeah. Well, hospital policy.
You have to be cleared
before you can go back to work.
No. I know it's important.
You got to process.
Have you called your mom?
Do you want me to call her?
I really do not.
Oh, they just extubated
Jackie.
Go check on your patient,
all right?
There's already too many people
standing around this bed.
All right.
You stay with him.
Kwan can cover post-op.
Okay.
Woman on P.A.:
Dr. Davis to Cardiology.
Dr. Elizabeth Davis
to Cardiology.
And, uh, I also have to go
check on...something.
What happened?
Wilson and I went to the
convenience store to get ice.
A guy tried to rob it.
I got lucky.
He's on his way up to the O.R.
Thank God you're okay.
Griffith, I need you
to help Millin
transport this patient
up to the O.R.
That's him.
That's...
No.
I c-- No.
Y-Yeah. You can.
He's just another patient.
Except he tried to
shoot you.
But he didn't.
Just another patient.
Mm.
I have to do a consult.
Have him prepped by the time
I get up there.
Chief, I'm on
Ndugu's service --
It's all hands on deck.
And if he's got a problem with
that, frankly, I don't care.
So, Dr. Marcus is
on his way.
No. Absolutely not.
Literally anybody else.
Uh, well, DeLuca is in Italy.
Patel's on leave.
Kincade's in the O.R.
Isn't, um, Dr. Marcus
the chief O.B. resident?
It doesn't matter!
He's not taking a trip
down there.
Okay. I know it can be difficult
to be the patient
with someone
you usually work with.
But you need somebody
in h--
Wilson! God.
I-I just heard what happened.
Are you okay?
You're...
Marcus?
Yes.
I finished med school.
Undergrad only took me
two years.
It's Bailey, right?
Wow! Twins?
It's a party.
So, based on
the initial workup,
it's likely stress
that's causing the bleeding.
Okay. Okay.
That's good.
She's also having
acute back pain.
Wilson, next steps?
Kidding.
Uh, pain and bleeding could also
indicate other complications,
so I'd like to --
I was just getting
the kids settled.
I came as fast
as I could.
It's okay.
I'm okay.
What about the bleeding?
It's slowed down, but I'm --
I'm feeling heaviness below.
I'd like to do
a pelvic ultrasound.
I'm assuming
you're dad.
So let's give them
a minute.
Mm-hmm.
Woman on P.A.:
Dr. Rolfe to the O.R.
Dr. Emma Rolfe
to the O.R.
No. You're right there.
Hey.
Do you need a minute or...
My son is throwing
a tantrum,
and my ex wants me
to calm him down.
Tell me you have
good news.
Well, your EKG is normal,
but your white blood cell count
is elevated,
which means --
I know what that means.
Last time, I needed surgery.
Is that what's happening?
Do I have to go through this
all over again?
Could just be a mild infection
or even stress or dehydration.
Let's not worry until there's
something to worry about, okay?
Hey.
What's happening?
Uh, just some chest pains
and hopefully a disproportionate
amount of anxiety.
Her EKG's normal,
but she has leukocytosis,
and she is slightly febrile.
We're still waiting on
blood cultures.
All right.
Let's admit her.
Start her on broad-spectrum
antibiotics.
Get a chest X-ray
and CT with contrast.
Is now a good time to worry?
It's just --
It's been such a day.
You know what?
Why don't you go with her?
I can get Cass to come down
and help out.
It'll help with the scans going
much quicker if you're there.
Okay. As long as you and Beckman
have it covered.
Yeah.
Woman on P.A.:
Dr. Aranda to the E.R.
Dr. Angie Aranda to the E.R.
Yes.
No.
I know.
I-I do still love you.
I just --
I just needed some space
and like a minute away
from school.
I'll --
I'll call you tomorrow.
Dave?
Uh, yeah.
He called like eight times.
I had to pick up.
I just --
I didn't know what to say.
I didn't want him to know
that I was here, so I just --
I just tried to pretend
like everything was normal.
It's -- It's fine.
It's anything but fine.
I didn't think this through.
And you're slammed.
I-I shouldn't have just
showed up out of nowhere.
No, no.
It's really okay.
At some point,
I need to give Dave an answer.
It's not his fault
that this is...
...this is what it is.
I really need to answer this,
but I want a chance
to talk about this.
Hang out at my place,
and we'll talk all about this
tonight.
If you need to go home,
you'll go home.
I'll never understand
how a person can point
a loaded gun at a stranger.
Well, people can hurt each other
in all kinds of ways.
I'm sure it's killing Yasuda
having to leave you --
Don't.
Sorry.
I didn't mean to bring it up.
When you want to talk about it,
we will talk about it.
I won't be talking about it
with you.
Did I do something?
I'm just sick of pretending
like we all mean something
to each other.
I get that interning here
is hard
and that we're all
trauma-bonded or whatever,
But we're just co-workers.
I don't need you to comfort me
or to understand how I feel.
I can take care of myself.
I've been doing it
my entire life.
How's it going in here?
Fine.
Great.
He's about to code.
All right.
Griffith, strap him in.
Millin, prep him.
Can you grab the other side
of the belt?
Yeah, I got it.
Did anybody contact the
blood bank to activate the MTP?
Uh, I'm not sure.
I can check it.
You are the intern
on this case.
You need to make sure you are
on top of the orders.
I'll do it right now.
All right.
He can't wait.
Okay.
We need to scrub in right now.
Yeah.
I was able to successfully
clip the posterior aneurysm,
but we ran into
a complication
when we tried to
wean her off bypass.
Uh, so what happened?
Jackie's stable, but
she had an aortic dissection,
which caused
a heart attack.
My 17-year-old
had a heart attack?
I opened her chest,
and I put in a graft.
And thankfully,
she's an athlete,
so her heart was able
to recover from the M.I.
I-I don't understand.
Why do these complications
keep happening?
Well, we knew her heart
was at risk
due to the root aneurysm.
Her brain was at
greater risk.
At the time.
Her post-op labs came in.
Thank you, Dr. Kwan.
How long does
the anesthesia last?
Hey, baby.
You still feeling groggy?
In my feet.
Your feet?
And my legs.
Dr. Kwan, would you get me
a needle, please?
Yeah.
All right. Jackie, let me know
when you start to feel this.
Did you start yet?
Why can't she feel
her legs?
There's no written rule
on it,
but people usually stand
on the other side
during a pelvic exam
to respect the area.
Right.
Sorry.
I need you to relax,
Wilson.
Okay.
You heard about Kincade's
uterine sarcoma case?
Poor woman's
second recurrence.
She's got four kids
and a death sentence.
You should see the scans.
They're awful.
Honestly,
it's like a horror movie.
Puppies.
Mm. They're adorable!
And calming.
I'm thinking about getting one
for Pru.
So, your cervix
is at 18 millimeters.
So an imminent risk
for preterm labor.
But you're just 16 weeks.
She's 16 weeks.
Which is why I'd recommend
a cervical cerclage.
It's placing a suture around
the cervix to keep it closed.
He's a doctor.
Oh!
Hospital babies.
Are you gonna name them
Grey and Sloan?
Just...
What are the risks
of the cerclage?
Um, well,
I could get an infection.
Or it could cause damage
to my cervix,
like, um, scarring
or stenosis.
Other options, please?
This is the option besides
terminating the pregnancy.
Cervical cerclage is very safe,
and it is the absolute best way
to preserve the health of Dr.
Wilson and the babies right now.
But if you'd like, I could give
you some time to think about it.
No. Give me the consent forms.
That'd be great. Thanks.
My 4-year-old listens
better than you do.
Yeah. Well, unless your toddler
is also a surgeon
during a record-breaking
heatwave,
I don't think that's
a fair comparison.
You shouldn't be
seeing patients.
I'm still on the schedule,
and the E.R. is over capacity.
Okay.
Let me rephrase.
I can't let you treat patients
right now.
I'm fine, all right?
I see life and death
every single day.
Business as usual.
All right. You know what?
Fine.
If you want a job to do,
why don't you head over
to the clinic and help out
with the cooling center?
Mrs. Long in bed 6
needs more stool softener.
Uh...
Do you see anything?
Not yet.
You championed me.
What?
You told Sky I could do this.
You told me I could do this.
Now I'm sitting here,
silently panicking
about what I've done
to this young woman,
and you're hardly saying a word.
You don't think I'm panicking?
You're not the only one
who operated on her.
I should have said no. From
the second you brought me in,
I had a bad feeling about this.
Why didn't you say anything?
Because you prematurely
accepted the case.
You knew it had a
cardiothoracic component to it,
but you accepted it
before getting my opinion on it.
She was admitted
before I even saw her.
No. No.
Do not put this on me.
You could have said no right
after you walked out the door.
Maybe you didn't because
of how you treated her mother.
Nurse Connie said
a cold front coming in.
The heat should break
soon.
At least there's that.
Scans are up.
Kwan, what do you see?
Uh, head CT is negative
for stroke.
But the CTA shows
the dissection flap propagating
into the descending aorta,
which means...
Blood flow to the spinal cord
is compromised.
I think it's...
Okay.
Is this...this the way?
Hey.
Radiology's a little
backed up.
We'll get you in there
as soon as we can.
You don't have to
babysit me.
Remember how annoyed
you would get
when your mom would make you
watch me and Megan
when she went to the store?
But that was a chore.
This is...
An excuse?
You made that face earlier
with Teddy.
What face?
I thought I sensed
some tension.
Um, sorry.
You don't have to answer that.
I-I think my surgical
complications removed my filter.
Or maybe it was my divorce
or -- I don't know. Sorry.
It's fine. Marriage is...
Marriage is complicated.
But I can't let this happen
any longer.
Are you trying to go up
or down?
Up.
Up?
Okay.
Damsel in distress.
I hate myself.
Don't -- Yeah. Yeah.
There.
Oh.
Hi.
Um, radiology's ready
for you.
So, um...
Oh.
...I'll go find an orderly,
okay?
Okay. Good idea.
Yeah.
Why don't we just first
start you on progesterone
and increase
your monitoring?
Why can't you trust that
I'm making the right decision?
I'm a pregnant OB-GYN.
I want a cerclage.
I'm getting a cerclage.
Well, you can't just wave your
specialty in front of my face
every time we have
a disagreement.
I've done hundreds of these!
I do them all the time.
But you don't get them
all the time.
What about Marcus?
How many has he done?
Should we be waiting
for somebody
born before TikTok?
He's in my year.
I have T-shirts
older than him.
Link --
Okay.
Our heart rate's elevated.
Um, maybe some deep breaths.
God.
I wish Dr. DeLuca was here.
First of all, I would never have
had Marcus' hands inside of me.
And second of all, she would
tell you how safe a cerclage is.
Maybe she could tell you that
this isn't just your decision.
She would never
tell me that.
Are you thinking clearly?
What?
You witnessed a shooting
today.
You could have been
seriously hurt.
Okay.
Time out.
Okay. You are now the one
who is seriously hurting her.
Her B.P. is 140 over 90,
and that's too damn high
for her and for me.
Add to that
an 18-millimeter cervix,
and you are tripling
her chances for contractions!
Take a walk.
Okay. I'm sorry.
It's just --
I am not asking.
Look at me.
In.
And out.
Good.
In.
Out.
I've exposed
the damaged tissue.
He's gonna lose an entire lobe
of his lung
due to one bullet.
GIA stapler.
His bullet that he loaded
into his gun.
We should invite the lawmakers
voting against background checks
to assist
on these surgeries.
Violent crime rises
along with the temperature.
Read a story about a guy
who drove his truck
into a hardware store
during a heat wave
and killed four people.
There's some bleeding
at the staple line.
All right.
2-0 PDS.
Thank you.
Damn it.
I can't get visualization.
Suction.
No.
All right.
Griffith, Millin, what do we do?
Tilt the table.
Tilt it more.
Exactly. All right, team.
You heard them.
Anesthesia, when you're ready.
Oh, my God.
Why is he moving?
All right! Stop!
Stop! Stop!
Watch his line!
Secure airways and lines!
Page some orderlies!
Let's assess him and get him
back on the table right now!
Gently. Gently.
Let's keep him on the ambu until
we get him back on the table.
Where are those orderlies?
Damn it.
His central line has come out.
All right.
Shut off all the lines.
Got it.
Lap sponge.
All right.
Keep pressure on his I.J.
Should we pack the thoracotomy?
No. Here you go.
All right.
Millin, get me a wet towel.
Millin!
All right.
Take this.
How the hell
did this happen?
He must not have been
completely strapped in.
Millin, hold here.
If your wife finds out, she's
gonna fire me all over again.
Keep applying pressure.
Bring in the orderlies.
Come on, fellas.
We're gonna carefully lift him
back on the table.
Everyone set?
On my count.
One. Two. Three.
You want to puncture
her spine?
We place a small tube
in Jackie's lower back
to drain the excess fluid
around her spinal cord.
There is a chance that it could
reverse Jackie's paralysis.
This morning, you assured us
that you could take care
of her aneurysms.
You seemed...
so certain about it.
That was before I saw
the larger aneurysm.
She is my only child.
When did you know
that this was going south?
Was it when you had to open
her skull?
Or when you had to stop
her heart?
Or when you noticed there was
something wrong with her spine?
Sky...
I mean, I-I need to know.
I need to know.
Did you ever think
that you could save my child?
Or was I just a fool
for believing it?
I did think that I could save
your child.
And she is alive
and aneurysm-free.
I do not make
false promises
because I have seen
too many bad outcomes.
This is not
a bad outcome.
Not yet.
You trusted me once.
Trust me again.
We have to act fast.
Okay.
I will trust you --
mostly because I
don't have any other option.
All right.
Her BP has settled down.
What do you think
you're doing?
Jo clearly doesn't want me
in the room.
Neither do you, so I thought I'd
help with an ex-fix in O.R. 3.
Well, you thought wrong.
W-What the hell am I
supposed to think, then?
Ever since we found out
it was twins, Jo has...
She's shut me out.
And I-I'm usually pretty good
at carrying on,
but today I can't.
Come here.
When I was in labor
with my son,
his father was getting
emergent brain surgery.
Now, I initially
didn't know about it
because my O.B.
never let it show on her face.
She knew that I was
at my most vulnerable,
and she supported me
with a strength
that I will never forget.
Jo has to do that
on a daily basis.
She treats those at their
most vulnerable and stays calm.
Right? They could be bleeding
or have a prolapsed cord.
She stays strong and encouraging
because that's her job.
But today...
it should be yours.
She's terrified.
So pull yourself together...
so she can fall apart.
Okay.
Central line's back in.
There's no signs of bleeding
or expanding hematoma.
Well, there's some bleeding
from the intercostals.
Probably from the fall.
2-0 silk.
I gave you
specific instructions
to strap the patient in
on the table.
Now's not the time.
Let me finish.
Your mistake was
extremely dangerous
and completely
unacceptable.
We give our patients
the very best care
that we are capable
of giving,
no matter who the patient is
or what he has done.
And if we can't,
then we leave
before our personal
distractions kill someone.
I should kick you out
of this O.R.
But instead, I'm gonna make
you stand there
and watch
these repairs,
which shouldn't even be
happening in the first place.
Am I clear?
Hey.
Yeah.
Once the temperature started
to drop, people started leaving.
Do you know
where the fans go?
You've worked here
longer than me.
So you don't know where they
keep the extra ice packs?
Just pack it up. You know,
someone will figure it out.
Who?
Don't ask
or it'll be you.
Don't move!
I hope we don't have
another heat dome anytime soon.
That's probably just
wishful thinking at this point.
But...
Adams?
Okay. Okay.
All right.
Come here.
Just take a seat.
Take a seat.
Hey.
Feel the ground under your feet?
Do you feel the ground
under your feet?
Good. Good.
Then just keep looking at me.
Keep looking at me
right here.
You're in the clinic.
You're not alone.
And you're safe.
You are safe.
Yeah.
Just breathe.
I just came down to say
a prayer, and...
I can't get
the words out.
May I?
Yeah.
Yeah. Jackie's always been
so full of life.
Seeing her in that bed
just...
It just breaks my heart.
She's strong
and resilient.
Whatever happens, she'll keep
kicking ass and taking names.
There's no doubt in my mind.
Yeah.
I'm not
a very observant Jew,
but I've always been
so moved
watching people stand
during services
and give a mi shebeirach
for their loved ones.
It's the prayer
for healing.
It's a mouthful.
I know.
It sounds beautiful.
Mi shebeirach avoteinu --
Avraham, Yitzchak,
v'Yaakov,
v'imoteiu -- Sarah...
You okay?
Can't feel a thing, so no.
We're hoping
to change that.
All right.
I'm going to insert the drain.
My mom's scared that this
is gonna make things worse.
She tries to act all cool
around me,
but deep down,
I know she worries.
Are you scared?
Not really.
I was scared at first
when I got diagnosed.
But now?
I don't know.
I feel like if I think too much
about it,
I'll be too scared
to do anything.
Kind of like what Coach says
about overthinking free throws.
You just got to shoot
your shot.
All right. The drain is in.
I'll let you rest,
and I will check back in a bit.
Cool. If I'm not here
when you get back,
it's 'cause it worked
and I walked away.
Here you go.
Sorry.
Uh, that was embarrassing.
No apologies necessary.
Yeah. I'm not really a...
feelings guy.
Yeah. No kidding.
I can't tell if I'm enraged
or...sad or freaked out.
Probably all the above.
There's no one way to feel
about this sort of thing.
So what do I do?
As far as I know,
there's no rulebook.
But I know
where you can start.
Yeah. You want to page psych
or should I?
I'll do it.
When I feel ready.
All right.
But in the meantime,
back to work.
Really?
Yeah. You had a panic attack,
not a heart attack.
I'll tell you what.
I'll, uh...
I'll figure out where all this
stuff goes so you don't have to.
Thank you.
Hey.
Is that for good behavior
or for you to soften the blow
for whatever
you're about to tell me?
Your scans are reassuring.
The stent is not infected.
Oh, my God.
That's --
Thank you.
Your white count
is still elevated,
so we want to keep you in
for a few more doses
of the antibiotics,
if that's okay with you.
Yeah.
Of course.
Why do I think there's more
you want to tell me?
I don't think I should be
on your care team anymore.
I'm sorry.
The freshman me resurfaced.
Or at least the part
that had a crush
on her friend's
older brother.
I-I shouldn't have tried
to kiss you.
It's not only you.
Oh.
Yeah.
So, uh, I'll have Teddy
check in on you.
I'm just going to check
his vitals.
I'll be quick.
He's a good guy.
He just...is going through
some stuff.
We both lost our jobs.
And then his friend Eddie
got sick,
and then he just...
shut down.
He stopped hanging out
with his friends
and stopped talking to me.
I just -- I don't know why he
thinks he needs to do it alone.
Well, let's hope this is
a wake-up call.
I'll be back in the morning.
You should get some rest.
I'm getting the cerclage.
Good.
I'm sorry.
It's just a couple
of hours ago,
I found out you were involved
in a shooting.
Ten minutes later,
I'm hearing "imminent labor."
You know, our whole world
was in danger,
and I-I freaked out.
I just want to do
whatever will keep you safe
and whatever
keeps them safe.
If that means Marcus
and a cerclage...
If I have to get a cerclage...
Stop saying "cerclage."
I know you and I
have been...
It's been rough.
But I just want to be here
for you.
For them.
Just tell me
what you need.
Keep Marcus from talking
during the procedure.
Okay, then.
All four of you ready for this?
Do you play tennis?
You'll have your own built-in
game of doubles now.
Marcus, I'm gonna need you
to keep all chatter
to medically relevant
information.
I love you.
How does the drain look?
It's draining.
How are you feeling?
Same as when you
last checked.
I'd say there go
my WNBA dreams,
but those were already
in the trash.
Mm, I'm guessing you'll have
new dreams to chase.
Maybe. But basketball
will always be my true love.
There's got to be a way
to keep it in my life.
Jackie, your toes
are moving.
They are?
Yeah.
Oh, my God! They are.
Mom, look!
It's working!
The drain's working.
Cue one-hour neuro checks.
This is good.
Thank God.
Thank God you're okay.
Update me
on her progress.
You're gonna keep going,
aren't you?
Impossible cases.
Well, I'm never gonna be able
to look somebody in the eye
and tell them I'm not
gonna try to help them.
I mean,
if that's a problem for you...
No. I'm not scared of
a challenge, Amelia, all right?
I...I take in the miracle
I always have.
But what you did today
was reckless.
I don't do reckless.
So if you need a miracle,
okay.
Give me all the information
up front
or find another surgeon.
Hey.
How are you feeling?
Cerclage went well.
No complications.
Babies are still inside,
so I'll take it.
But, um, I-I'll need to take
a few days off.
Yes, you do.
Hey, um...
Hm?
Thank you.
For staying with me.
It really meant a lot
with, um...
with Link and Marcus --
Oh, God.
Marcus.
I can't stop picturing him
between my legs.
I'm gonna have to quit!
He saved your babies.
Just think about that.
Get some rest.
Ah.
Hey, I'm...
Uh, sitter's all set.
How are you doing?
Are you hungry?
Can I get you some food?
I, uh...I've been
making decisions on my own
my whole life.
And being in
a functional relationship
and allowing someone else
to weigh in on everything,
I-I-I'm still...
I know.
And I love you
so much.
I love you.
And Harry and Fanny.
It's my favorite great-aunt
and -uncle.
What do you think?
Is that your BP?
Yeah.
Mm.
Should I get you a juice?
Yeah.
I'll take orange juice.
Thank you.
Uh, Dr. Webber?
Millin, you okay?
It was me.
I didn't strap Damian
to the table.
I thought I did, but I-I
must have gotten distracted
and then, when Dr. Altman
called Griffith out, I froze.
I should have taken
responsibility for it then,
and I didn't, so I am taking
responsibility for it now.
I'm sorry.
I appreciate that.
But I'm not the one
who needs an apology.
Hey.
Go easy on that arm.
I've had worse injuries
playing soccer.
Are you okay?
I wasn't sure if this
might have brought up
some memories for you.
Yeah, a few.
I mean, that day shaped
my whole life.
Probably Derek's too.
You were his favorite,
you know.
He always saw something
in you.
Oh, and you didn't?
I found you infuriating.
But Scout and I love
having you around.
You coming home tonight?
Uh...
That's okay.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Hey, Chief.
Uh, you got a minute?
No,
but you're already here.
Um, so, uh, about today.
I'm sorry. I was --
I was only trying to help.
You said that the hospital
doesn't have emergency plans
for, you know, heat domes.
Well, it turns out that we
don't have ones for wildfires,
tsunamis, and a few other
natural disasters.
And they're only increasing
with climate change.
So I want to put together
a committee
to fill in the gaps --
with your permission, of course.
Permission not granted.
Uh, can I ask why not?
As much as you can't seem
to grasp this,
you are a resident
on a trial basis.
You have no business devising
protocols that you can't follow.
If I were you,
I would spend less time assuming
that you have
a permanent position here
and more time proving
that you should have one.
We're done here,
Dr. Warren.
Hey.
You busy?
Well, a patient fell off
the O.R. table, so...yeah.
Um, do you mind getting
the kids?
Uh, sure. Sure.
Yeah.
Um, could you check in
on Nora Young before you leave?
Yeah.
Of course.
After all these years,
she still gets under your skin,
doesn't she?
Yeah.
Yeah, I guess she does.
What happens in our brains
in the moments before we die
has puzzled scientists
for centuries.
While we have some evidence
of our lives flashing
before our eyes,
there are still many questions.
Temperature dropped
21 degrees in two hours.
How's Adams?
Oh, he's okay.
He's okay.
I'm used to seeing patients
come off rigs every day.
Hundreds of them.
Some worse than others.
But I can handle it.
Always have.
But if one more resident
comes off a rig,
I don't think I can.
You talk to Altman?
Not yet.
No one knows exactly
why it happens.
Some people think it's biology.
Others believe it's spiritual.
Hi.
Hey.
There are people around.
I don't care.
It's been a long day.
What we know for sure is
that you can try to look away,
pushing down all
the uncertainty and pain...
You and me.
It feels like
such a long shot.
I mean, you're here.
And I'm in California,
and it's --
it's already so messy.
Stop, stop, stop, stop.
Don't -- Don't --
Don't overthink it.
Well, I have to
sort of think it.
Well, then think
about this.
I've never stopped
loving you.
What if that's enough?
Blue.
Say no to Dave.
Turn down his proposal.
Look. I-I don't want to
get this wrong.
If you and I
start something
without breaking it off
with him, it-- it'll feel wrong.
So go home...
and tell him.
And when you come back...
I am never losing you again.
So say no.
But your life will catch up
with you in the end.
-- Captions by VITAC --