- Previously on The Resident...
- Hey, Noni.
You are looking
lovely today, as always.
Every reputable hospital
is trying to recruit Carver.
How are your surgical
error and complication rates?
- Excuse me?
- Transparency and accountability force us
to weed out the bad
and grow the good.
- I need Bell.
- You know what to do.
I pushed Dr. Okafor to
exceed my expectations,
and, sadly, on this
day, she wasn't ready.
So you are finally cleared for
your bone marrow transplant.
We can start your
conditioning today.
Lily's in acute renal failure?
If we proceed with the
transplant, she'll die.
What's going on?
You were right.
We have to do
something about Lane.
Have you thought
about the wedding?
No. It stresses me out.
150 guests is well
within our budget.
150 guests is within our budget,
but none of these 150
guests include friends,
- only our families.
- Well,
we got to have
our families there.
Mmm, but do we, really?
Okay, maybe not yours.
This is why I want to elope.
- Lunch later?
- Sure.
Or...
we could just stay home, okay?
No. I'll be late for work.
- Yeah. I don't care.
- I know you don't care,
but I need you to care.
I'm serious, Devon.
It's my job...
That was nice.
Yeah. Yeah, very much.
You don't have to stay.
You trying to get rid of me?
Let's just call this
what it is, Conrad:
a rebound thing.
It's not.
It's not a rebound thing, I...
Nic and I, we split
up a while ago.
No, I meant it's...
it's my rebound thing.
Oh, yeah, right. You and Tucker.
All right. Okay.
I should go.
I...
I got to get back to my
place. I got to change.
No one's stopping you.
♪ Shadows twist in the night ♪
♪ Oh, what a life ♪
♪ I just gotta roll
with the dice ♪
♪ I bet your bottom dollar
and my soul with a price ♪
♪ Ooh-ooh, ooh-ooh, ooh-ooh ♪
♪ Ooh-ooh, ooh-ooh, ooh ♪
♪ Howlin' to the moon ♪
♪ Calling out for you... ♪
It's big.
And getting bigger.
Oh, it hurts like hell. Oh.
Yeah.
I think I need
to go to a doctor.
♪ ♪
Ooh. Someone didn't
go home last night.
Apparently not.
Ooh, look at you,
pretending not to care.
I'm not pretending.
Hey, when you get a minute?
- Yeah.
- You had a chance to talk to Conrad about Lane
and her near-miss with Lily?
Yeah. He said,
- "Well done."
- Well done?
You saved her life.
That's kind of what
we do around here, Nic.
Yeah, but wouldn't
it be nice if your job
was to help sick people,
not save sick people
from their doctors?
It would be my first choice.
Yeah.
What's on your mind?
I want to report Dr. Hunter
to the state board
for overly aggressive treatment,
but if we could just
get a closer look
- at her patients files...
- She keeps all
of her patient
records at her clinic.
She doesn't even let
Lily's doctors see them.
I know... but
what if you told her
that you were interested
in writing a research paper
on her protocols?
What's up?
Hey, um, just talking about,
uh, Hunter's patient,
Darryl Phillips.
Judy called in sick,
so I'm helping her out.
I thought Lane banned
you from her patients.
Yes, so I'll keep a low profile,
and you'll keep your voice down.
70, retired postal worker,
just got some bad news.
"CT scan and tumor markers
"are highly suggestive
of small-cell lung cancer
with obvious mets to the liver."
Lane didn't give
him a prognosis.
He has maybe six months or less.
And she wants to do a
biopsy, chemo, radiation.
She might be able to buy
him a couple extra months.
Look, I was just hoping
you could talk to him
and help him figure
out his priorities.
How was your evening?
Stayed in. Watched TV.
Hmm.
Oh, Mary. Why don't you shut up?
No, you shut up, you old toad.
Nicki, please get this
stoop lady out of here,
or I'll get a restraining order.
Well, aren't you two adorable?
Darryl, Mary. This is
Dr. Conrad Hawkins.
He's gonna ask you
a series of questions
designed to help you figure out
where you want to go from here.
Well, I know where
I'm going. Home.
Okay, that's a beginning.
Tell me what
you're most afraid of.
Well, besides dying and going
to hell, I'm not a fan of snakes.
He's afraid of being serious.
Oh, I'm serious.
I'm serious as
stage IV lung cancer,
which I have, apparently,
even though I still feel
pretty damn good, right now.
I'm guessing that'll change
if I start all these treatments
Dr. Hunter wants to do.
But Darryl, what if
those treatments work?
Where you been, Mary?
There's nothing
that's gonna fix this.
Dr. Hunter says she
can extend your life.
It's possible.
She's had success
with many patients,
- but there are no guarantees.
- I know too many folks
who've been through this hell.
All this will do is rob me of
the few good months I have left.
Isn't that the truth, Doctor?
- It's a possible scenario, yeah.
- Well, I don't want that.
I don't want a few more
days in the hospital.
I've accepted there's not enough
time to drive across country,
so I'll settle on just
cleaning out the garage.
The garage? Why you keep
bringing up that damn garage?
The man asked me
what scares me, Mary.
What scares me is leaving you
with hospital
bills you can't pay
and a hoarder's garage.
There's a lot of
crap to sort through.
Tons of boxes, old paint cans...
and a certain VHS
tape you misplaced.
Shush.
Peter will help me.
I want to help you,
and that means
skipping the treatment.
Dr. Hunter wants to do a biopsy.
Why? We know
what's wrong with me.
To identify the type of
tumor and target therapy.
Well, no therapy,
so no biopsy. Simple.
Okay.
That's clear to me.
Great. More time at home
with the ball and chain.
All right, I'll have Dr. Hawkins
talk to your doctors
and we'll get you discharged.
Well, I was hoping
to start this meeting
with some good news.
However, it seems that
Chastain has fallen out
of the Top 50 Hospitals
on the U.S. News & World Report.
Well, maybe that's
one of the reasons
that we couldn't convince the
best surgeon in the northeast
to leave St. Grace
and come to Chastain.
Yeah, what happened
to Carver, anyway?
I thought Randolph
here was a closer.
Well, we were
miles apart in salary,
and Dr. Carver was also
pushing for publicly
disclosing complication rates,
- which leave us susceptible to lawsuits.
- True.
But I have been thinking
it's time that we consider
more transparency
here at Chastain,
on our own terms.
Some of the same hospitals
that are beating
us in the rankings
are doing just that.
Like tracking and identifying
offending physicians.
Just get rid of
repeat offenders.
Like Dr. Mina Okafor.
Okafor is not a problem.
She removed the wrong
testicle from a patient.
Terminating Dr. Okafor
will send a message
to coasting physicians
without resorting to a
disagreeable amount
- of public transparency.
- Okay, look.
If we terminated doctors
based on medical errors,
this room would be empty.
But if our CEO prefers,
I will send Emory the
more challenging cases
that made Chastain famous,
and we can focus on becoming
the tonsillectomy
capital of the world.
- Dr. Smooth?
- That's his nickname.
His real name is
Spalding Massero.
He's a concierge doctor
who practices out of New York.
His patients are
rich high-profiles
from all over the world.
He charges the big
fees, we do all the work.
First time I've been
in the VIP wing.
I haven't even stayed
in hotels this nice.
There they are. Come
on over, gentlemen.
Conrad, you remember
Dr. Spalding Massero.
Our residents,
Dr. Hawkins, Dr. Pravesh.
I remember Conrad Hawkins
via the U.S. Marine Corps
in Afghanistan. How's your dad?
- The same.
- Devon Pravesh.
Harvard Medical and Yale?
- Or is it the other way around?
- You got it right.
Dr. Massero was just telling me
about his hole in
one at Spyglass.
Oh, was it official?
Any witnesses?
Ah, well, you insult him.
And Steph Curry.
- And Larry Ellison.
- Oh, okay.
We done fluffing here?
As will all of
Dr. Massero's patients,
- this has to be handled discreetly.
- Yes.
Bobby, get off that leg.
Whoa, whoa, whoa...
That is Bobby Singer.
The first baseball
game I ever went to
with my dad, Bobby pitched.
I am looking at the two doctors
who stand between
my patient and his dream
to finally pitch in
a World Series.
I had knee surgery a couple
years back, so I figured
- I tweaked it, but...
- Team doctors don't think
- it's structural.
- Yeah, it looks like
- deep vein thrombosis.
- That sounds bad.
DVT is a blood clot.
It's good you're here.
Yeah, he'll need blood
thinners and a surgical consult
- for a possible thrombectomy.
- Like surgery?
- We're in the middle of a pennant race.
- Yeah, I know.
Surgery's good.
You want surgery.
Surgery's quick, and
so is the recovery time.
Before we address his return
to the game, let's figure out why
Mr. Singer's leg is swelling...
We'll need ultrasounds
of his upper and lower
extremities and a CT pelvis.
- What else, Harvard?
- If he has a clot,
he'll need a full
hypercoagulable workup,
including factor V Leiden,
protein C, and S levels.
If all goes well, we'll
get you out of here
- in a couple of hours.
- No. We'll keep him overnight,
- just for observation, hmm?
- We're gonna do
everything we can to get
you back on that mound.
All right. Thanks, man.
I mean, Dr...
Devon.
- Just... you know what, just call me Devon.
- Devon.
All right. Thanks.
So why do they call
him "Dr. Smooth"?
Massero hates
conflict, he hates drama
and he really hates
delivering bad news to patients
who pay him a lot of
money not to hear it,
so he outsources the
tough love to grunts like us.
Which makes me think
Bobby has a big problem.
- Hey.
So, Noni?
We've got a DVT consult on Six.
He might need
surgical management.
- Can you see him?
- Yeah, I'll check my schedule.
Fair to say you're over Nic.
Our clinical volume
is growing so fast,
we're having difficulty moving
them through the system,
which is probably what
happened to Mrs. Shea.
Okay, and Darryl Phillips?
I need someone to
perform his biopsy today.
Excuse me. Uh, regarding
Mr. Phillips's biopsy.
Are you following Mr. Phillips?
He is not.
I am now. I was
asked to speak with him
after he had second
thoughts about his treatment.
As you know, his
prognosis is terminal.
And how would you know
that for sure without the biopsy?
CT scan and tumor
markers are suggestive
of small-cell lung cancer
with mets to the liver,
stage IV.
His prognosis is extremely poor.
Yes,
and with what little
time he has left, he'd like
to get his affairs in order
and be at home with his wife.
Well, a biopsy helps
us definitively tailor
his treatment,
especially in the event
that it's not
small-cell lung cancer.
Mr. Phillips doesn't want the
biopsy, since he doesn't want
a treatment that's unlikely
to change his outcome.
Unlikely?
We punt on unlikely
outcomes now?
We do not.
Even if it is small-cell,
chemoradiation is still
an option worth exploring.
I will speak to the patient,
make sure he understands
- the upside of chemo one more time.
- O-Okay,
so i-in the future, just so I'm
clear, in these tumor board
meetings, we don't factor
in what the patient wants?
I'm just asking,
so I don't waste
any more of your valuable time.
That's enough, Conrad.
All right, I need
someone to perform
Mr. Phillips's biopsy today.
Where is Vincent?
I'm free this afternoon.
- I can do it.
- Thank you, Jude.
But I think we should
wait for Dr. Vincent.
Okay, thank you, everyone.
Conrad.
I want you there when
I talk to Mr. Phillips,
so there's no more confusion.
What was that?
The patient doesn't
want the biopsy.
Well, I didn't argue for one.
I just volunteered
to do the procedure.
Darryl Phillips just
wants to go home and die,
but there's no money in
it for Chastain if he leaves
- without more treatment.
- Okay, calm down.
What is this?
Is this about me and Nic?
This has nothing to
do with you and Nic,
and everything to
do with Darryl Phillips,
whose dying wish is to go home.
Okay, don't you forget:
I'm the attending, and
you're the resident, brother.
So, technically, you outrank me,
but that doesn't change the fact
that you don't know
what you're talking about.
You and I aren't in the
military anymore, brother.
I don't even need to salute you.
You're here to tell me
you saved my job today
at the board meeting.
Word gets around fast.
Oh, it does, when you're
the one spreading it.
They were looking
for a scapegoat,
I made sure it wasn't you.
That should make you
the opposite of angry.
No, I'm here to tell
you we'll be able
to work together
again as partners.
I think we had some
nice momentum going.
I'm not ready.
I'm sorry.
I am not ready to work with you.
You were right, what you
said at my M&M hearing.
I wasn't ready.
I want to be ready next time.
Well, we won't put
you in a position
to fail again.
No, thanks.
I'll serve my penance studying,
and doing prostatectomies
on the Titian.
Well, y-yeah. You
need permission...
I sought and received permission
from the residency board
to work under Dr. Kays
for the next three months.
Excuse me.
What kind of research project?
On your promising treatment
regimen at your clinic.
A retrospective review
focused on outcomes
and disease-free intervals.
When it's published, it could
bring in even more patients,
- and save lives.
- And you think you're the first resident
to approach me about
writing a research paper?
Of course not,
but they're not me.
Hmm.
Well, thank you,
but a manuscript for
a prestigious journal
is already in progress.
Anything else?
No.
Appreciate your time.
She definitely wasn't into it.
Doctors don't mind multiple
papers published, as long
as they're favorable. She just
doesn't want you poking around.
Yeah, maybe it's time I
quit thinking like a doctor,
and start thinking
like a journalist.
Darryl, I know my aggressive
regimen can seem daunting,
but cancer is a
relentless enemy,
and you have to fight it
with extreme prejudice.
You have to fight
it with fire and fury.
You can't just give up.
That's why people from all
over the world come to my clinics,
because I never give up.
Yes, the survival rate for
your prognosis is not great.
Not great?
- It's nil.
- You're wrong.
There's always a chance
that you can be the outlier,
someone who beat the odds.
I told you, honey.
But I need to know
my enemy to fight it.
What do you think, Doc?
Dr. Hawkins is an
incredible doctor,
but he's an internist.
He doesn't treat cancer.
I'm your oncologist,
and I know what I'm doing.
Okay, I guess.
Do the biopsy.
Oh, okay.
Yes.
Thank you.
I saw you pitch a two-hitter
against Chicago
in 2014 and lose.
Yeah, on a throwing error.
- What are you testing for?
- Find out what's causing
what's causing the clot.
You've been through
Tommy John surgery.
You can come back from this.
All right, so after you fix it,
when can I start throwing again?
- That's up to your team doctor.
- And you,
- but you can't come back too soon.
- Why?
- What would happen if I did?
- Well, that depends.
- It depends on the results of the test.
- Yeah.
This conversation's not
really constructive right now.
Bobby, I want you to meet
the chief executive officer
of Chastain. She wanted
to come up and say hello,
and, uh, see how you're doing.
We've actually met before.
You helped us raise
awareness and finances
for our children's hospital.
That's right. It's
good to see you.
- Well, thank you, Doctor. I'll take it from here.
- Right.
- And can I speak to you for a second?
- Absolutely.
Thank you again for
choosing Chastain.
Of course.
And, uh, we'll be back
to check on you later.
All right, man.
Hey, is this a bad time?
Yeah.
All right, I'll come back.
Hey, it's all right.
Come on in.
I can sign those for you.
Oh, uh, not for me.
Some of the kids
in the pediatric ward
heard you were up here.
That's great. Here.
- I'm happy to help.
- Thank you.
I can get some swag
for the kids.
Hats, jerseys.
Aw, that's really sweet.
Here. Let me get
your phone number.
It's fine.
Look, if you want, I can
just give you my number,
- and you can contact me when...
- Oh, no, no, no.
It's fine, sorry. Here,
I'll just punch it in, here.
There you go.
Thanks again for these.
Oh... this has peppers.
I think it's yours.
So how's it going with
that, um, that Pinetree story?
Pinewick.
I told you, there's not
enough evidence yet
to link the toxic
landfill to the clusters.
Right.
Hey, uh, just curious... Were
any of the cancer patients
you interviewed
treated by Dr. Hunter?
Your Lane Hunter?
Yeah.
No. Why?
Uh, just wondering. If
they'd been treated by her,
maybe there'd be evidence
that could link their cancer
with the landfill.
Evidence I could help you get.
That's nice of you.
Just trying to be supportive.
I suppose there could be
patients in the cluster study
that I didn't interview who
were Lane Hunter's patients.
I could try to find them.
Why?
Is there a story here?
Maybe.
For sure, there would be
a conflict of interest
for the both of us,
and the possibility of
bad publicity for Chastain,
so... I would ask
you to just, please,
tread lightly?
Oh, you've got to be kidding me.
Everything okay?
Your baseball player
just sent me a picture
of a swollen appendage
that is definitely not his leg.
- Okay, thanks. Yeah, I got it.
- I mean...
Thank you.
I'm gonna talk to
Bobby. He can't do that.
No, don't. I can handle it.
It's not the first time
this has happened.
Jude send one too?
- Very funny.
- All joking aside,
I'm talking to Bobby Singer.
Conrad, I'm serious. I don't
want you going up there.
And, for the record,
Jude and I are just
friends, unlike you and Noni.
Hey.
Yeah, okay. Fine.
Everything all right?
I need a surgeon to do
the Darryl Phillips's biopsy.
Hastings signed in.
He got pulled into a Whipple.
- Well, Mina's the on-call resident.
- Mm, she's in
the penalty box. I'll get Jude.
Yeah, don't bother
knocking. Come on in.
Is there anything
else I can get you, sir?
He's good.
Can I have a moment, please?
Go ahead.
Mm.
Bad news?
That little selfie you
sent to one of our nurses?
I know you think
it's all in good fun,
like sending over a drink
to a woman you don't
know, but you're wrong.
It's harassment.
So before you leave,
apologize to her.
All right.
If that nurse got a problem...
then she can come
and tell me, all right?
Oh.
- Oh.
- Sit down.
Don't tell me to sit down.
Sats are dropping. He's
acutely short of breath with
pleuritic chest pain. We
need to rule out a PE.
- I'm drawing an ABG.
- Am I having a heart attack?
Doubtful, but we need
more tests to be certain.
First test will be drawing blood
to check its oxygen content
to see if the clot in your leg
traveled to your lungs,
but it starts with you
sitting the hell down!
Fine. Don't sit. We'll
do this the hard way.
- Oh! Oh!
- Put him on oxygen and get him to CT stat.
- You enjoyed that.
- Just a little.
What the hell happened?
CT shows a pulmonary
embolism with a small segmental
filling defect. We may have
to switch his anticoagulant, but
this should be treatable
without surgery.
He said you two
got in an argument.
Bobby throwing a clot from
his leg to his chest is unrelated
to our discussion of how
he sexually harasses nurses,
and has everything to do
with his deep vein thrombosis.
We have to treat everyone,
from sexists to Nazis.
- That's the gig.
- Yeah, and we can still treat him,
but nowhere is it written
that patients are allowed
to send pics of
their junk to nurses.
Well, this isn't
just any patient.
Too bad for Chastain,
I'm not just any doctor.
So you didn't get the
name of this big shot
VIP Massero's sending us?
He didn't want to tell me
the name of his patient,
just that it's some wealthy
Chinese businessman
who's gonna be in
the U.S. next month,
so we have to keep it quiet.
Well, shouldn't be too hard.
You haven't told me much.
Massero wants a
headliner for the surgery.
Face of the hospital.
I suggested you.
That's wonderful. I
look forward to that.
I suggested you, even though
you challenged me
at the board meeting.
Claire, I was just
speaking truth to power.
Truth? I'm not so sure of that.
Massero also has
one other condition.
He doesn't want Conrad near
any of his patients anymore.
Not the Chinese
billionaire next month,
nor Bobby Singer,
starting right now.
I'm happy to talk to Conrad,
but we need to
have a conversation
about transparency.
I'm about to get on
a call. We'll do it later.
Definite compression in the
left iliac vein, causing the clotting
- in the iliofemoral vein.
- May-Thurner Syndrome.
Treatable with anticoagulants
and surgery, but...
Your idol gets hit
with a line drive
while he's on a blood thinner...
Uncontrollable
internal bleeding.
Bobby's not gonna pitch
this year, maybe even next.
Well, let's pull it together.
Let's come up with a
path that might save
the rest of Bobby's career,
and then put a plan together
to present it to Dr. Smooth.
Conrad, I need to speak to you.
The guy sent Nic a picture...
- Yeah, it's called sexting.
- It's called harassment.
Look, we need Massero
funneling his high-profiles
to our VIP wing.
And membership
has its privileges?
You confronted one
of Massero's patients,
and he thinks you
aggravated his condition.
- Seriously, you believe that?
- Doesn't matter what I believe.
And you know what, if
Nic doesn't want to invite
this type of behavior,
she shouldn't be giving
her number out to a
professional athlete.
Oh, come on. Did you
just say that out loud?
Yeah, and I'm gonna
say this even louder.
We don't want you in a
room with Bobby Singer.
Or any of Massero's
patients ever again.
First assist, you
can close up now.
Yes, Doctor.
I have, uh, some good news.
I've been asked to perform
a very delicate surgery
on a foreign VIP next
month... Very hush-hush...
And I've chosen you to assist.
What's in it for me?
In success, your skills will
have international exposure,
and, more importantly
for the short-term,
it will impress your doubters
on the board of directors.
Thank you, but I'm happy here,
and my attending
is very pleased with my work.
Well, that's nice.
But any doctor who handles
a scalpel at Chastain Park
answers to the Chief of Surgery,
which happens to be my title,
and that means you're
back assisting me.
Is that understood, Dr. Okafor?
Welcome back.
- Bell's leveraging you.
- I refuse to do all the work
for no credit while
he gets all the glory.
I'm not the damn help.
I'll tell the board I'm
not ready for surgery,
that I am a menace to medicine.
Council of elders
will never believe you.
You come off as too arrogant
to fool anyone that
you're incompetent.
Thank you.
Anytime.
Okay...
advancing through the carina
into the right main bronchus.
And now into the right
upper lobe bronchus...
and into the lung.
Yeah, I can see the tumor. Okay.
Collecting sample.
Got you.
Here we go.
All right.
And withdrawing the scope.
You can go ahead and call
for my next patient, please.
Oxygen sats are
acutely dropping.
Stethoscope.
I got decreased breath
sounds on the right side.
Give me a 28 French tube, now.
Collapsed the lung.
Scalpel.
Who do you think you
are? You confronted Bobby?
God, you just had to be a hero,
- after I told you not to go up there.
- He's a VIP.
I went to talk to him
because I knew you couldn't.
Couldn't or wouldn't?
Because I can, and I will.
If you complain
to your supervisor,
they'll just blame
you for being up there
- in the first place.
- So let 'em.
What did you accomplish, Conrad?
- Now you can't take Massero's patient.
- Win-win.
I don't care if I ever see
Massero again, and guys like
Bobby have to learn they
can't get away with that.
And guys like you have to learn
that sometimes, we want
to take care of ourselves.
You just can't help yourself.
Darryl.
That's unbelievable.
Jude perforated his
lung pulling out the scope.
Great, so now Darryl is
stuck with a chest tube
and the drainage system
until his air leak heals.
He's fine.
We can start radiation
mapping tomorrow, as planned.
I disagree, respectfully,
with that approach.
The biopsy results came back.
It's everything that we thought.
Stage IV. Small-cell.
Statistically hopeless.
Now Darryl can go home.
No, now Darryl
can start radiation.
Once he's mapped, I've
got him pre-scheduled
for twice-a-day treatments.
He'll need 30 over
the next three weeks,
and he'll alternate that
with his chemo cycles.
He doesn't want it, Lane.
Patients don't know
what they want, Conrad.
It's up to doctors to
frame their care in a way
so they understand
what's best for them.
Or frame it in a way that hides
everything that's bad from them.
Bottom line, no one's
hopeless in my world.
I look forward to the day when
you're proud to be a doctor.
This was the easy part?
Where's Jude?
In the call room. Why?
I missed a layup.
You're not the first doctor
to cause a pneumothorax.
That air leak will take
two weeks to heal.
Not exactly like he
had a lot of time left.
Well, we need
you out there, so...
you just... you
just got to forget it.
Everything okay in here?
Yeah.
You all right?
You know, Conrad
coming at me today,
and then laying
into Bobby Singer?
That's about you.
No, it is not about me.
It's just what Conrad does.
He'd do it for anyone here.
That's true.
I think he still loves you, Nic.
You need to decide if
you're still in love with him.
Drinks are on me.
That's what she said, right?
I think I paid
last time, didn't I?
I'm sorry to interrupt.
I am Dr. Okafor.
We know who you are, Mina.
I just wanted to
personally thank all of you
for my second chance.
- Second chance?
- The opportunity
to assist Dr. Bell in
the important surgery
of the top secret foreign VIP.
I am grateful for the confidence
the board is showing in me.
I have learned from my
mistakes, and I promise
to make Chastain proud.
I will never again remove
the wrong organ from a patient,
VIP or otherwise.
Thank you again.
Excuse me.
Hey.
Finally.
- Where's Wilmot?
- You got to do this alone.
I'm off the case.
Dr. Smooth doesn't
want an intern telling him...
First of all, don't call him
Dr. Smooth to his face.
Second, Wilmot,
our dedicated attending...
He split for the weekend.
- It's Tuesday.
- Yeah.
- Hello?
- Uh, Dr. Massero.
Hey, we're about to
make our approach.
I don't have a lot
of time. What's up?
Okay, first, Bobby is
stable on blood thinners,
and his PE symptoms
are in control.
But, uh, the bigger concern
is that Bobby has May-Thurner.
- Damn it.
- Uh, we are suggesting an angioplasty
of the iliac vein
with stent placement.
- Excuse me?
- Followed by six months
of anticoagulation until
the stent incorporates.
Where the hell's the attending?
Yes.
Dr. Wilmot was pulled into a...
emergency consult.
Would you like to wait,
or should I get Conrad?
No. Uh, no, not him.
If we start
the treatment plan now,
Bobby could be ready
to play by midseason next year.
- Next season?
- Yes.
So you're telling me
Bobby's gonna miss
this postseason and
most of next season?
- Yes.
- This might have been his last shot
to play in the Series.
He's gonna be devastated.
I'm sorry.
I, uh... If only I could
tell him in person,
but I got Banksy waiting
in a Seattle hotel room
with carpal tunnel.
If you want, I could
tell the patient.
Yeah? Oh, that'd be
great, and then I'll follow up.
Devon, next time
you're in New York,
you're sitting with
me at a Knicks game.
Oh, great. I'm a big Knicks fan.
You're not a Knicks fan?
No, no. I said I am
a big Knicks fan.
- That's too bad, 'cause they're courtside.
- No, wait.
Listen, they're telling
me I got to shut this down.
- No, wait. Wait, wait, wait.
- Thanks.
Massero.
Welcome to the club.
You just got Smoothed.
We have to tell Bobby
Singer that his season is over?
No. Not we. You.
Hey, Conrad.
Massero doesn't want a resident
telling Bobby the bad
news. He could go off on us.
Massero wouldn't
care if a candy striper
told Bobby the bad news,
as long as it wasn't Massero.
Hey.
I found four new
patients of Lane Hunter.
You're kidding. How?
Social media. I was
able to flag posts
from five new cancer patients
asking for prayers for
their upcoming treatments
at Lane's clinic.
- You're amazing.
- I kind of am.
I'll get contact
info on the patients
and call them saying I'm working
on the cluster story and ask
about their treatment
regimen with their oncologist.
Good, but keep this on the DL.
We don't want to make
anyone suspicious.
Suspicious of Lane?
Should they be?
Devon, you know how much
I respect what you do
for a living.
But if there's a story
here, I'll chase it.
There's no turning back.
You understand?
Go for it.
You will eventually be
working there with me
- in surgery...
- Randolph.
Yeah? Excuse me for a second.
I've spoken with Massero.
According to the Chinese
government, no doctor
below an attending can
assist in the operation.
That means no residents.
Are you okay with that?
Of course. Why wouldn't I?
Good.
Excuse me.
Listen, we'll
pick this up later.
Bobby, you're not
gonna be able to play.
A contusion
from a hard-hit ball while
you're on blood thinners
could cause internal
bleeding, and you could die.
So that's it, huh?
It all ends here.
No. No, not necessarily.
It is not unrealistic to think
that you could be back
midseason next year.
But...
I'll be 38.
This was supposed
to be my last season.
Didn't Massero tell you that?
No.
No, he didn't.
All right.
Okay.
All right, so when can I
start having sex again?
Four to five weeks.
Oh, and by the way,
somebody wants to see you.
Do you really think women
are turned on by stuff like this?
I mean, come on,
you guys are the ones
who are fascinated
with body parts, not us.
But you know who does
get turned on by them?
Gossip Web sites.
So, if you send
one of these to me
or one of my colleagues
again, I will blast this picture out
with your name on
it to Page Six, TMZ,
The New Yorker, Deadspin...
you see where I'm going with this?
Yeah.
I'm sorry.
Good.
It's a start.
Time for your radiation mapping,
Mr. Phillips.
I'm ready, I guess.
Honey, relax.
I'll be fine.
What could go wrong?
Well, I guess if I get
more time with Mary,
- this will all be worth it.
- But will it?
Dr. Hunter says we can
increase his survival time 25%.
What does 25%
longer survival mean?
Months? Years?
It's an estimate based on
patients with similar cancers
using Dr. Hunter's protocol.
She's saying they lived
an additional five weeks.
Five weeks? Stop this thing.
Someone has to
talk to me straight.
You're elected.
Give me a sec, guys.
Dr. Hunter could be talking
about new radiation techniques
that I don't know about.
I'm an internist, but all
treatments and tests have risk.
Chemo and radiation are toxic.
They have to be,
to kill the cancer.
Just tell me if these treatments
will make me die sooner.
They will make you
feel sicker, nauseous,
and will weaken
your immune system
and that means you're more
in danger of getting infections.
And some of those
infections can kill you.
Why didn't anybody
tell us this before?
No one wants to
take away hope, Mary.
What would you
do if you were me?
I wouldn't want to
spend the time I have left
at Dr. Hunter's clinic.
I'd want to spend every
minute I have left with her.
Start the paperwork now.
Discharge me or I'll
walk out of here myself.
Honey, you can't do that.
Can he?
It's a hospital, not a prison.
We can't hold
him against his will.
It's called eloping,
when a patient slips away
without being discharged.
What about this,
uh, chest tube thing?
Well, we changed you
to a portable system
to make it easier for you
here. Mary knows how it works.
It's easy and your
dressing is changed, so...
you're good to go.
We're gonna have
Hospice check on you
when you're settled back home
if you choose to leave now.
Honey, what do you think?
That garage ain't
gonna clean itself.
It's been fun.
Come on. Wait, wait, wait, wait.
- Take that off.
- Help Mr. Phillips back to his room
- and take out his IV, please.
- Easy, easy, easy.
- You all right?
- Yeah.
Thank you.
Oh, uh, by the way,
you two make a very cute couple.
Hustle, Mary. In
case you missed it,
my end of the hourglass
is very low on sand.
Shut up or I'll
leave you right here.
I slept with Noni.
Well, I haven't slept with Jude.
Maybe I did it to get over you.
That kind of sucks for Noni.
No, she's fine
with it. Believe me.
So, how'd that work out for you?
What do you think?
Dr. Lane Hunter.
What about her?
Tell me everything.
Captioned by Media
Access Group at WGBH