I still can't believe
you talked me into this.
Come on, honey, you're
gonna throw him off.
It's okay, I'm almost done.
A little more
light on your hips.
God.
Why couldn't you have come
up with this before I had two kids?
You look amazing.
Okay, I think... Yeah, I'm
done. Want to come take a look?
I can't.
You first.
No, we'll look together.
I don't understand. I thought...
What the hell is that?
Honey, it's okay.
This is not what we
discussed, or what I paid for.
I don't understand. I think this
is one of the best I've ever done.
I want my money back.
I'm sorry, but this is not some
department store photo studio.
And this is not my wife.
Yes, it is.
You asked me to paint her exactly
as she looks. That's exactly what I did.
Honey! Stop it!
What's going on? Brandon.
That check better be in my
mailbox by Friday, or I'll be back.
Come on.
What happened?
I don't know.
They saw the painting,
and they just freaked out.
Brandon, what is this?
What do you mean?
It's her portrait.
What's wrong with it?
Why is this in here?
First column, last entry.
Today is going to be a good day.
This him?
No. Yes.
She means, are you
the private investigator
whose bills I've tried to slip
through as medical expenses?
Oh. Hi. I'm Lucas Douglas, PI.
This hospital is not putting a
private investigator on retainer,
nor is it going to pay any more
phony repairs on
vending machines,
cryostats, or elevators.
Information saves lives.
Saving lives saves money.
No, saving lives costs money,
which is why I'm trying to
make sure there's still some left.
You want your own personal PI,
you're gonna have
to pay for him yourself.
Sorry. No, I understand.
Hey, I like the
shoes, by the way.
Oh.
Thank you.
You don't like her
shoes, you like her legs.
It sounds less creepy
if you say shoes.
Less creepy, more gay.
That's my firm's motto.
What is a cryostat?
No idea. Whoever fixed
ours is about to get stiffed.
There's no distorted perspective
in any of his other recent works.
Not much talent either.
It's like the symptom
just came on.
Acute onset visual agnosia
points to a stroke or brain tumor.
MRI revealed no
stroke or brain tumor.
We should do
another with contrast.
If he's like the other
struggling artists I've known,
he's also into drugs.
We should... What
are you looking at?
Apparently a moron.
One, ER routinely
tests for drugs.
If it was positive, we
wouldn't be looking at this file.
Two, who pays 12%
interest on a car loan?
How did you... Did you
run a credit check on me?
No, that would be illegal.
Interestingly enough, paying
someone to run it for me, though...
What? It's part of my job.
Your job is to
diagnose patients.
Which I do with a team.
How am I supposed to know
how best to utilize that team
if I don't know
everything about them?
Say that Van Gogh turns
out to have neurosyphilis,
and our last vial of
penicillin is in a storeroom
at the end of a 20-mile hallway
with a two-foot-high ceiling.
You've discovered that one
of us has been hiding the ability
to stretch or shrink themselves?
No, I would never out
someone's superpowers.
This, on the other hand...
You crawled 20 miles?
My name's in the Guinness Book.
I'll bet that really
impresses the babes.
I didn't do it to get the babes.
No, that would cheapen the
purity of your achievement.
Sorry to interrupt, but we have a
patient with a probable brain tumor.
Who needs an MRI with
contrast. We've established that.
What do you got on Taub?
I got nothing on Taub.
Could also be environmental.
We should check his studio
for toxins, mold, fungus...
Taub's wife, on
the other hand...
House.
That's enough.
Dad's right. This is
no time for gossip.
Patient desperately
needs our help.
Check his head and his house.
Can't Lucas... No.
He's very busy.
If there is a tumor,
this test will show us...
Is that stuff dangerous?
This is just the
contrast material.
There is a small risk of
an anaphylactic reaction.
I could stop breathing?
Don't worry. We're prepared
to deal with whatever happens.
You know, I did some drawings
this morning and they seem fine.
So, maybe it was just a
reaction to something I ate.
How many people you
know have reactions like that
to something they
ate for breakfast?
But if I'm getting better...
You'll continue to get better.
If you're not, we
need to know why not,
so we can start
treatment immediately.
Baby, let them do the test.
Can lead poisoning
cause visual agnosia?
Not without lead showing
up in the blood work.
Nothing in the medicine cabinet
except some harmless toiletries.
No signs of mold or
fungus anywhere, either.
You think House really
got something on your wife?
No, not that I care if he did.
Wait, your wife's doing
the doorman in your bed,
and they're sweating all over
the sheets that you paid for and...
My wife's not doing the
doorman. How do you know?
We don't have a doorman.
And I just do, okay? Drop it.
In college, my friends and I came
up with an Inverse-Square Law.
Sounds like a real fun group.
The girls who you think are the
most inhibited, straight arrows?
They're the ones
you hook up with.
Are you saying my wife's a slut?
I'm saying if my wife was
a slut, I'd want to know.
His place was clean.
So is his head.
Even with contrast,
no masses, no lesions.
A neurological symptom with
no apparent neurological cause.
Time course means we
can rule out cancer and MS.
That just leaves
toxins or drugs.
You called Thirteen a moron
for thinking it was drugs.
Yeah, when she said
it, she had other options.
And I really just wanted a segue
into her stupid loan and your...
A cavernous angioma
in the brain could leak.
Once the blood gets reabsorbed,
pressure goes down,
symptom goes away.
He'll never consent to
petrosal vein sampling.
Really?
He was nervous about
an injection of contrast.
Is his girlfriend hot?
I'm not talking fever, here.
I mean, is she all
curvy and perky?
Very. And if he dies, it's
good news for all of us, but...
That explains why
all his paintings suck.
And what's wrong with him.
Where are you going?
To tell him he may have
a massive brain tumor.
He doesn't.
I know. I'm not a
moron. It's drugs.
You seem to have a
massive brain tumor.
Who are you?
He's Dr. House. He's
pleased to meet you.
We've found no trace
on any of your imaging,
so we need to cut
your head open.
It's risky, but it's the
only way to save your life.
No.
Wrong answer.
I'm not allowed to say no?
You're not allowed
to not be terrified.
There's only two good reasons
not to be terrified in a hospital.
You're delusional, but then you're
not afraid of contrast material either,
or you know you're fine. Since
we haven't told you you're fine,
you obviously have
information that we don't have.
What drugs are you on?
His drug tests were clean.
Drug tests only test for
drugs they've made tests for.
What are you talking about?
Hottie thinks that
he's a great artist,
selling art to the
rich and tasteful.
She's stupid enough to
be fooled by the canvasses,
but bank accounts don't
lie. He needed money.
There are not many jobs you
can do that don't require time,
training and intelligence.
And I know you're not a
news anchor or supermodel
because those jobs seldom
cause agnosia. He's a guinea pig.
Companies pay him to
test their untested drugs.
Did Hottie go for
a pee or coffee?
'Cause either way, I don't think we
should waste any time on denials.
The clinical trials were
supposed to be safe.
The drugs are about to
be approved by the FDA.
"Drugs"? How many
trials are you on?
Three.
Admirable. Not many idiots
have that much ambition.
You've been symptom-free
since your admission,
so whatever you took has
probably cleared your system now.
You'll be fine.
Keep him overnight
just to make sure,
and get the names of
all the trials he's been in.
You gonna tell Heather?
Couldn't, even if I
cared enough to want to.
Not bad. You almost
made it the whole day.
What did you find out?
The point is to see
how everyone reacts.
You may go get
the rest of the gang.
Cut the crap, House.
Your wife has a
separate bank account
in her name only.
She's been making weekly cash
deposits for about a year now.
No withdrawals yet.
That's it? A bank account?
A secret bank account.
What makes you
think it's a secret?
Because if it wasn't you
would call it "the" bank account.
Damn, always forget to use
the right article when lying.
It's not secret.
We're refurnishing.
We set the budget,
set up an account.
I just couldn't make it to the
bank the day we opened it.
You're spending almost
$100,000 on furniture?
Yes.
- What happened?
- I don't know.
He was fine, then all of a
sudden he started seizing.
He said you told
him he was better.
What's happening?
What's wrong with him?
She is hot.
Obviously, the drugs
weren't out of his system.
None of these drugs, nor
the drugs they're derived from,
are known for causing
seizures. By themselves, no.
But three unproven,
untested drugs?
It's like The Mod Squad,
no one can stop them.
It's ridiculous that
they let people take
potentially dangerous
drugs for money.
Just to short circuit
that discussion,
people should not be testing
drugs because they're desperate.
But people won't test drugs
unless they're desperate.
We need drugs to save
children and puppies,
ergo we need desperate people,
ergo welfare
kills sick children.
First drug...
Why don't we
call it Bisexidrene?
Clinical trials involve
experimental drugs.
Means they don't have
comforting, catchy names yet,
just random,
unmemorable trial numbers.
Go ahead.
Bisexidrene is designed
as an anticoagulant.
Phase one indicated some
risk of nausea, ED and insomnia.
Second drug...
Cuckoldisol.
She is having an affair? Worse.
Sex can be dismissed as hormonal
or emotional, can be easily regretted.
Money is always a
calculated decision.
My wife has her own bank account
that House doesn't
think I know about.
Shocking. Discuss.
Drug B is an autoimmune
treatment, almost no side effects.
But even if it's doing what
it's supposed to be doing,
it doesn't mix well with
anticoagulants or anticonvulsants.
Which is the third drug?
World's-sorest-knees-isil.
Cuddy used to have
that title, by the way.
There's a million ways
these drugs could interact,
if they're doing what
they're supposed to.
If they're not, two million.
And it'd be interesting to
know which of those interactions
was causing the problem.
Unfortunately, we don't have to.
We just have to
stop the interacting.
If we don't know
which... We stop them all.
Put him on dialysis,
clear out his system.
Rapid detox risks arrhythmia,
another seizure,
hepatic failure...
Difference is we know what
those risks are. Put him on dialysis.
Dialysis. You use that
for kidney failure, right?
Don't worry, your
kidneys are fine.
He's not worried
about his kidneys.
He's worried about
how he's going to explain
the dialysis to his girlfriend.
I just don't want her to worry.
You mean you don't
want her to leave you.
What's wrong with
that? I love her.
It's not like I've lied to her
about anything important.
I am an artist.
I've sold plenty of
paintings in the past,
I just hit a bit of a
dry spell lately, so...
So tell her that.
He can't.
He wants her to be happy, too.
He's telling her what
she wants to hear.
You didn't know.
No.
What are you gonna do?
She's not sleeping around,
she's not gambling it away,
she hasn't even spent any of it,
so I don't see a
reason to do anything.
You don't think
a conversation...
How many people do you know
in completely happy
and fulfilled relationships?
None. I am.
Most people cling to some storybook
notion of what a relationship is.
You can't have an
imperfect thought.
You can't have a
private zone. You can't...
Steal money and hide it
away in a secret account?
She makes me happy. I
make her happy. It works.
Because we don't do storybook,
and I don't plan to
poke into her business.
You were right
about the dialysis.
He made it through the night
without any more seizures
or visual symptoms.
And I'm gonna be just as right
after breakfast up in my office.
The only difference is I'm gonna
be right in front of other people.
Which means you're not
here to talk about the medicine.
You can screw with
me all you want at work,
but stay out of
my personal life.
What did she say?
Did you just hear what I said?
I heard the part about
"You can screw with
me at work all you want."
You want my
advice? Of course not.
Good, because I have no
idea what you should do.
I only know what
you're going to do.
You're gonna... I said I
didn't want your advice.
I said this is not advice.
You are going to forgive
her for opening that account,
and you're gonna confess
everything you've done
and then you're gonna
beg her to forgive you.
What purpose could
that possibly serve?
None, which is why I'm not
saying you should, but you will.
What's your end game?
Where are you?
I'm at the track.
That's like six miles away.
How cool are these things?
I feel like an idiot.
I'm not giving you
any more of my stuff.
Do you have those
night vision goggles?
No.
You're lying.
You like making him miserable.
You like driving
people away from you.
He deserved to know the truth.
There was no truth
until you dug it up.
You do know that stuff exists
even when you can't see it, right?
It was a truth that
mattered to him
and a truth that
mattered to her,
why did it matter to you?
First of all, stop saying "a"
truth. There is only one truth.
That may be true for you.
Miserable people
save more lives.
If your life has meaning, your
job doesn't have to have meaning.
Screw-ups are more palatable if
you have someone's arms to go cry in.
That makes sense.
Usually, I have more
of a fight on that one.
So why are you
making Taub miserable?
I just said...
He left his last job
to save his marriage.
If his marriage falls apart, you
think he'll be working harder for you?
Or you think he won't
be working for you at all?
His head and neck
are completely swollen.
I need a Trach kit.
His throat's closing.
Can't find any landmarks.
Just start cutting.
An exploratory trach?
We don't have a choice.
I got it. Here.
His face is so swollen it's
squeezed his tear ducts shut.
We've been lubricating
his eyes by hand.
We've started
him on steroids, IV,
and cream to
reduce the swelling,
but it's having limited effect.
Negative for thrombosis and
Chagas. Could be infection.
Cultures still negative.
Could be his immune system's
on hyperdrive, cytokine storm.
Why would you pay for a
three-year gym membership
and only go twice?
Sorry. You guys
still diagnosing?
I thought we finished hours ago.
You remember, when we
decided it was the unproven,
unapproved cocktail of drugs he's
been downing like... Like a cocktail.
He just completed
a total dialysis.
If it was the drugs,
he'd be better.
Or he'd be worse.
I take it none of you
saw Trainspotting.
You think swelling is a
symptom of withdrawal?
You think it's a coincidence that
three new symptoms cropped up
as soon as we took
him off the drugs?
It's possible some
of the symptoms...
Either the drugs are the answer
or the drugs are a coincidence.
If it's one, we have to find
a better way to detox him.
If it's two, we have to know which
symptoms are withdrawal related
before we can
formulate a diagnosis.
Which means we have to
find a better way to detox him.
So how do we do it?
Hair of the drug that bit him.
That's ridiculous.
If it is the drugs, they're dangerous,
and they've already caused...
That's why we're gonna
put him back on the drugs,
then wean him off again.
Just much slower.
Why are you looking at him?
Try it out.
You heard the boss. Go!
Taub... I didn't talk to her.
Why are you...
Excuse me.
Uh, sorry.
He does look like
me, doesn't he?
You gave him your hat?
I needed you out of here so
I could go through your desk.
Of course.
Nice blouse. I really
like that color on you.
Tell House that if he wants
to know what I'm doing,
all he has to do...
It's not House. It's me.
I was... I don't know.
I was thinking maybe we could
get together for a drink or something.
I wasn't sure exactly what
you like to do, so I thought...
You'd spy on me? No, no,
not spying. More like research.
I think it's a good idea to
get to know a little bit more
about a woman
before you ask her out.
Show you care about more
than just what she looks like.
As romantic as you
make that sound,
pretty sure that
what you're doing
is not so much caring as creepy.
That's not fair.
You were scrounging
through my desk.
What the hell am I going to
find out? You went to Michigan.
You like your sandwiches
a little light on mayo.
You stay in touch
with your mother.
You rented The English Patient
and you gave money
to Amnesty International.
There's not one thing
I can find out in here
that you wouldn't tell a co-worker
while riding in an elevator.
I'm not a creep. I just thought
you seemed interesting.
I'll go now.
Yeah, these...
I'll give you embarrassing
info on House.
In exchange for...
No. No need for a date.
You'd be employing me, so
I'd have all the time in the world
to ask you all about
you and it would fall
under the category
of socializing,
instead of creepy stalking.
And I'd be paying
you? I know it's weird.
But if you pay me while I
check you out, it's all cool.
And you'd get value. You'd
get leverage against him.
Help you keep him in line.
You think I need help
keeping House in line?
No.
Nope. I'm sorry.
This hospital can't afford...
Oh, whatever you can afford.
How did you know I liked roses?
I was in your house last night.
No, I'm kidding.
Who the hell doesn't like roses?
I forgot to tell you,
the Parker Quartet is going
to play at the library fundraiser.
That's it? It was your idea.
They'll be great.
Mmm-hmm.
You okay?
I couldn't find
the letter opener.
I went through some of the
drawers in your desk, looking for it.
There were a bunch of statements
in there from Jefferson Mutual.
I was so close.
To what?
You've got $83,000 socked
away in a secret account.
Not anymore.
I wanted to keep it a surprise,
but I bought you the car.
Uh...
The one that I...
I knew you would never buy
it yourself, so I've been saving.
And it's gonna be
delivered on Friday.
You are amazing.
Lucky you.
We've gradually
reduced your dosage.
You're actually drug-free now.
I feel great. Thanks to you.
All part of the job.
Your blood pressure is
normal. Can you sit up?
Hey!
What are you...
What happened to his face?
Question is, what
happened to his hormones?
We're gonna need
an ice pack in here.
We can rule out the clinical
trial drugs at this point.
His system has been
completely cleaned twice.
So unless the drugs found a
hiding place under the stairs...
Drugs could have set off a
dormant neurological condition.
Good point. Coming clean
causes a lot of damage.
Alienation, divorce...
My wife's buying me a car.
I was talking about the
patient. You were wrong.
The divorce was metaphorical.
What about Kl端ver-Bucy Syndrome?
Bilateral lesions in
the temporal lobes.
Visual agnosia and hyper-sexuality
are the key symptoms.
Good thing he's
got that girlfriend.
If it's Kl端ver-Bucy, his
brain will melt down,
he'll try to swallow
his own hands
and she can take care of him
for the rest of his talentless life.
You owe me an apology.
Any rationalization
you had for meddling
in my private life disappeared
when she had good reason...
You're right.
Fact is, nothing I said applies.
You had no reason
to forgive her,
therefore no reason to seek
forgiveness, no reason to be an idiot.
Kl端ver-Bucy wouldn't explain
the seizure or the cytokine storm.
Withdrawal complications.
Then again, she is
handing you a giant gift
that you don't
think you deserve.
The fact that the MRI showed no lesions
on the temporal lobe tends to rule out
your "lesions on the
temporal lobe" theory.
The damage can be a circulatory
issue, rather than structural.
We wouldn't see that on the MRI.
Foreman's right.
Go call your wife, tell her
you're not coming home,
say you have to give a
patient a cranial MR angiogram,
then say good night and hang up.
Odd that a man who can't run
would own so many pairs of sneakers.
You mind hanging this
up when you're done?
I have to find something
embarrassing about you.
No, you don't. I
ordered us Indian.
Not too embarrassing.
Just something credible.
Well, if you hand her that, she's
not gonna need you anymore.
If I don't hand her anything,
she'll think I'm incompetent.
I don't care if she thinks
you're incompetent.
This isn't gonna work.
It's worked so far.
I'm not good at lying.
I know.
That's why your cover
is that you want to do her.
I like her. I don't
want to do her.
Then what's the
point of liking her?
I meant I don't just
want to do her. I like her.
What do you think you're
gonna find out about her?
Something personal,
something embarrassing.
I spend half my life
negotiating with that woman.
Anything I can use to
scare her into saying yes.
Okay.
"Okay"?
You're okay with being paid
twice to facilitate blackmail?
I'm okay. I don't believe
you. But I'm okay.
You're doing this for the
same reason I'm doing this.
We'll see who gets there first.
Here it is. Circle of Willis,
the vessels are narrow.
Narrow for you, normal for him.
If there were problems
with the vessels,
he would have had
symptoms long ago.
Not if something else changed.
Like? TAUB: His heart.
He could have recently gotten
an intermittent arrhythmia.
I know "heart" and "head"
start with the same three letters,
but you've got to read
all the way to the end.
The experimental drugs
cause an arrhythmia
which causes low blood pressure.
Combine that with
those narrow vessels,
the brain doesn't
get enough blood.
That causes all of his symptoms.
If we can trigger the
arrhythmia and identify it,
we might be able to
stop it from killing him.
Been home? No.
Good. Do an EP study.
Find the arrhythmia.
We're gonna insert three
electrical catheters into your heart.
Tell Dr. Hadley I'm sorry.
She understands, and
you should tell her yourself.
Maybe I should
tell Heather about it.
You're gonna be fine.
She's so supportive, she's
so great. All I do is lie to her.
What happens if you tell her?
I don't know.
You love her, right?
More than anything,
and she loves me.
If you open your mouth,
one of two things happens,
she either forgives
you or she leaves you.
At best, you wind up exactly
where you are right now.
It's noble to want to
confess. Really, it is.
But if the result's
just damage and pain,
that's not noble, it's selfish.
Stimulate right atrium.
Normal conduction.
How long you plan on
keeping me from going home?
Until you're convinced
I'm a different person,
one who won't do
anything stupid?
Guilt fades quickly. By
Wednesday, you'll be fine.
Right ventricle. And why
do you want it to fade?
Why do you suddenly
care about my marriage?
Because if it ain't broke...
You obviously think it is broke.
And you obviously
think it ain't.
Your marriage is
like a broken toaster.
Bread keeps popping out,
and you keep calling it toast,
which is weird because you've
put your bread in a lot of toasters,
and apparently you don't see any
difference. It's kind of fascinating.
He's going into V Tach.
What's wrong?
Good news, test is working.
Your heart's freaking out, but
it's cool that you're still conscious.
Try to overdrive.
Didn't work.
This might burn a little
bit. Charging to 60. Clear.
Ow!
Going again. Charging to 120.
Have you been dyeing your hair?
No. House. Clear.
Right.
Your hair's growing in red.
His heart rate is stabilized.
Does your theory include
any genetic mutations
that could cause his
hair to change color?
Then either he's
lying about dyeing
or just dying.
Red hair means
it's not Kl端ver-Bucy.
Melanin affects hair color.
What affects melanin?
Hormones. Hormone
panels were all normal.
Age.
He's turning
prematurely crimson?
A genetic disorder.
Waardenburg Syndrome causes
arrhythmias and can change hair color.
And make you deaf. Next.
I found a long QT interval. I
think it's Romano-Ward Syndrome.
Explains the irregular
heart rhythms.
But not the ginger nut.
If he's got Romano's, he's
got at least five gene mutations.
It's not a big leap to think he has
others that would give him the hair.
It also gives him the likelihood
of sudden and unexpected death.
Beta blockers don't work.
His heart can't handle an ICD.
Pete Best.
Good God, has none of
you ever read a history book?
The original Beatles drummer.
A bunch of nerves controls
the tempo of the heart.
They're all playing in time, except
one dude who can't keep the beat,
wrecks the whole
thing, so we hire Ringo.
Pete Best was actually
a great drummer.
But I assume you mean the patient
needs a cardiac sympathectomy?
I probably should
have just said that, huh?
You start cutting nerves, you risk
his swallowing, vocal cords, sweating...
So he saves a fortune on
karaoke machines and deodorant.
You think he's stable
enough for surgery?
If he was, he wouldn't need it.
Wow.
Wow. Yeah.
Do you have any
brothers and sisters?
One sister.
He told me he was
on the lacrosse team.
In high school.
In college he just cheered
the lacrosse team on to victory.
Wow. Yeah.
How was your
relationship with your dad?
Fine. You have
three more questions.
How was your
relationship with your mom?
Fine.
When did you
lose your virginity?
Not something I discuss
with co-workers in an elevator.
And...
You know, don't you?
Bit of a wasted third question
'cause the answer
is "Know what?"
Okay, bear with me here,
because some people
sometimes consider
my thought
processes complicated.
I'm into you 'cause
you're hot and smart,
in that order, but
both are needed.
Photos can be retouched,
and House is an evil genius,
which makes this photo suspicious.
And yet you're not suspicious.
Which means either you're not
smart enough to be suspicious,
in which case, I am
less interested in you.
Or you're not suspicious
because you know
this is actually a
doctored photo of House.
In which case, I am
more interested in you.
But I'm wasting my
time because you know
this is a game we
are playing on you
and I am busted and I'm screwed.
I know the photo's a fake.
I know this is a game.
Sorry.
Too bad.
Goodbye.
So you knew that I wasn't gonna
give you anything worthwhile?
And you were never gonna
give me anything worthwhile?
Then why did you bother
coming out with me?
I wanted to screw with House.
By wasting my time?
That doesn't make sense.
No. There must
be another reason.
Hmm.
Is it okay if I sit
back down here?
Your heartbeat's out of control.
We need to surgically sever the
connection between your heart and brain.
We believe it's necessary, but
you need to know the ramifications.
You'll never be
able to feel angina.
You may not know if
you have a heart attack,
may not be able
to get help in time.
Where are my regular doctors?
Regular doctors?
Dr. Taub and Dr. Hadley.
Why aren't they telling me this?
Brandon, I am Dr. Hadley,
and this is Dr. Taub.
What are you talking about? I've
never seen you before in my life.
We can't do the surgery.
We're back to where we
started, visual agnosia.
We need to re-examine
neurological disorders,
something slowly progressing.
This isn't progressing.
It's there, then
it's not, then it is.
It's a new symptom,
intermittence.
It's irrelevant.
Since when is a new
symptom irrelevant?
Since it points towards
the same disease.
Intermittence can fit
with Romano-Ward.
We still need to do
a sympathectomy.
Maybe we missed
something, toxins.
When? When you
checked every bottle,
every can, every tube of paint,
or when you detoxed him twice?
Maybe there was a
batch of toxic paint
that he used up
a few months ago.
Then he would have been
sick months ago, not now.
He's lost weight
since he got here.
That's a symptom of
trying to cram hospital food
down a throat he can
barely get air down.
It's not a symptom,
but what if the toxins were
stored in his fat cells a year ago,
and now they're being
released into his bloodstream?
So where are you gonna get
this old paint, the city dump?
On his old paintings. We
know he hasn't sold one in ages,
but there weren't many in his
studio. He's hid them somewhere.
If you're wrong,
he could drop dead
from Romano-Ward at any moment.
You okay with that?
Just give me a few hours.
You got one.
I need to talk to him alone.
It's about your
work. Your paintings.
I need to look at all the
ones you've sold recently.
Honey, can you give us a minute?
To talk about your paintings?
Brandon, please. Tell
me what's going on.
I've only sold two paintings in
the last three years, since we met.
One was to my cousin.
I've been making money
enrolling in drug trials.
Two, three at a time.
Why did you lie to me?
I want to be...
The way you look at me,
the way it makes me feel...
I want to be what you
see when you look at me.
You think I'm that shallow?
When I look at you, I see you.
So,
where are the
ones you didn't sell?
It's not the paint,
it's the drugs.
He's not on the drugs
I know it doesn't make sense,
but I'm looking at his
paintings for the last six months.
They're normal April,
June and August,
but they're distorted
May, July, September.
Every other month, he
was having visual agnosia
because every other month, he
was on all three drugs simultaneously.
The statin was one
month on, one month off.
I don't know why the symptoms
keep coming and going,
but it is the drugs.
They're hiding under the stairs.
In the fat? That
doesn't make sense.
These drugs aren't fat soluble.
I said stairs, not closet.
What was the last drug he was
on before the drugs he was on
when the symptoms started?
I'm not sure, I think...
Antacid.
How do you know? It makes sense.
Also, I'm looking at the file.
Yes.
It's Dr. House.
Wake him up. We're done.
No, no, he says he needs
surgery, but not this one.
Did he give any specifics?
Abdominal surgery
to remove a bezoar.
It's like a hairball, but it's
made up of undigested food.
You can get it if your
stomach acid's low,
which Brandon's was because
of an experimental antacid.
The fruit and vegetable
fibers and skins
get stuck together
and form a ball.
It gets sticky, ferments, grows.
It starts sucking up some
of the pills he'd taken.
Some are never heard from
again, but some get released.
For the last week, it's
basically been giving him
massive doses
of all three at once.
That is why I won't
let Cameron buy a cat.
He should be fine.
Are you glad he
told you the truth?
Yes. Of course.
But were you happier
before you knew?
About 10 more feet.
I do know what it looks like, so
maybe this whole blindfold thing...
Shh. My gift, my rules. Bump!
All right, if you
don't like the color,
apparently we can exchange it,
but I'm hoping... You ready?
Ta-da!
Do you like it?
Baby, are you okay?
We need to talk.
She didn't buy it.
Damn.
So, you didn't get anything?
Nothing. We
probably overstepped.
You're really not
the cheerleader type.
On the other hand, I figured
she probably wouldn't figure me
as the "Photoshopping
a photo and planting
it in an obscure college
paper" type either.
Yeah. About that,
I took a little trip
to your alma mater.
You took a little
trip 150 miles?
Online, by phone. I
meant I did research.
That's a real photo, isn't it?
Wow, that is humiliating.
There was a girl.
Even more so.
That's too bad. You wanted
her to see you in a different light,
and not only didn't she see it,
but she didn't even
believe it was possible.
You know, people hate people
who have theories about people.
You want me to back off?
Would you?
I barely know you.