I didn't sleep well last night, and
I woke up with a scratchy throat.
I just don't feel so
good. Uh, cough.
Yeah, um-um, I have a bit of an
upset stomach too, and I
think I'm running a fever.
I'm just worried I
might be contagious.
Inventory. Tomorrow. I'm—Yeah,
I'm sure I'll be feeling better by then.
Thanks, Mr. Innabe.
I cannot believe
you just did that.
I-I really do have a cough.
Oh. So you weren't lying.
You'd be curled up in bed
with a bowl of chicken soup...
Even if you didn't have
a horny girl in your bed?
Yes. Because I really do— Hey.
I really do have a cough.
You also have a little rash.
Um, I'm not sure
we should be kissing.
Oh. It's okay. Because I have
almost no interest in kissing you.
Perfect. Good.
Uh-uh-uh.
Oh, baby.
Oh, Brandon.
Brandon.
I know I'm good, but come on.
Brandon?
Brandon. Brandon. Brandon.
Brandon! Brandon!
Any additional R. N. to Surgical.
Why do you want
me to treat this guy?
Blood pressure's not
responding to I.V. fluids.
No, no. I didn't ask how you
plan to con me into treating him.
I asked you why you
want me to treat him.
He's sick. I care. I'm pathetic.
There are about a billion sick
people on the planet. Why this one?
Because this one's in our emergency
room. Ah, so it's a proximity issue.
If somebody was
sick in the third-floor
stairwell, that's who'd
we be talking about.
Yes. I checked the
stairwell. It's clear.
Okay, then. Emergency
room guy it is.
Wait. Why was that so
easy? You know why.
- Blood pressure's not responding to
I.V. fluids?
- Yeah.
That's just weird.
C.B.C. was unremarkable. Abdominal
C.T. scan didn't show anything.
So, people, differential
diagnosis. What's wrong with her?
- Him.
- Him. Her. Does it matter?
Does anyone think it's a
testicular problem? No. So, Chase?
- Yersinia infection?
- No. You wouldn't get the rash or cough.
What about arthritis? Accompanying
vasculitis causes nerve damage...
- No. It wouldn't cause
the blood pressure problems. Allergy?
- The kid's got abdominal pain.
Maybe carcinoid? No. But
then you wouldn't get the...
Foreman, if you're going
to list all the things it's
not, it might be quicker
to do it alphabetically.
Let's see, now. "Absidia." Excellent.
Doesn't account for any of the symptoms.
- No condition accounts for
all these symptoms.
- Oh, good.
Because I thought maybe he
was sick. But, apparently, he's not.
Who wants to do up
the discharge papers?
Okay. Unless we control
the blood pressure,
he's gonna start circling the drain before
we can figure out what's wrong with him.
Treat him for sepsis,
broad-spectrum antibiotics,
and I want a Cort-stim
test and an echocardiogram.
You all right? Yeah.
The Cort-stim test will
tell us if your pituitary
and adrenal glands
are working properly.
- His glands? What does that mean?
- We have a few theories we're working on.
- You mean you don't know.
- Mindy.
I'm just saying, if they knew they wouldn't
be testing you, they'd be treating you.
Yeah, well, that's the
way it works. First we
find out what it is,
then we get you better.
You're half an hour
late. Busy caseload.
One case is not a load.
So how are we doing
on cotton swabs today? If
there's an acute shortage,
I could run home...
No, you couldn't. Nice.
Hello, sick people
and their loved ones.
In the interest of saving
time and avoiding a lot
of boring chitchat later,
I'm Dr. Gregory House.
You can call me Greg. I'm one of three
doctors staffing this clinic this morning.
Short. Sweet. Grab a file. This
ray of sunshine is Dr. Lisa Cuddy.
Dr. Cuddy runs this
whole hospital, so,
unfortunately, she's much
too busy to deal with you.
I am a board-certified
diagnostician,
with a double specialty of
infectious disease and nephrology.
I'm also the only doctor
currently employed at this
clinic who is forced to
be here against his will.
That is true, isn't
it? But not to worry.
Because for most of you, this job could be
done by a monkey with a bottle of Motrin.
Speaking of which, if you’re particularly
annoying, you may see me reach for this.
This is Vicodin. It's
mine. You can't have any.
And, no, I do not have a pain
management problem. I have a pain problem.
But who knows? Maybe I'm
wrong. Maybe I'm too stoned to tell.
So, who wants me?
And who would rather wait
for one of the other two guys?
Okay. Well, I'll be in Exam Room
One if you change your mind.
Jodi Matthews?
Please accompany
Dr. House to Exam Room One.
Dr. Chase.
I'm not sure scaring your boyfriend
is the best medicine for him right now.
I know. I get stupid when I'm
scared. Don't go rock climbing.
Look, I was wondering. Before
this happened, we were having sex.
What? You're wondering if whatever
he has, you might've gotten it?
It-It's unlikely. We ran a
complete S.T.D. panel, so...
No. I'm wondering if maybe I
did this to him. I was kind of rough.
It was yellow. It was?
It's not anymore.
Well, that's a shame.
I thought that might be a
problem, so I brought you this.
Your mucus was "pale goldenrod."
Last week, yes. Should I
be worried? Oh, yes. Very.
Really? I thought
it was okay now.
And yet, here you
are. What happened?
Paramedics took a week
to respond to your 911 call?
You're not a very
nice doctor, are you?
And you are very bad
at whatever it is you do.
You don't even know me. I
know you're gonna get fired.
That's why you got the new glasses.
That's why your teeth are sparkly white.
You're getting the most of your
health insurance while you still can.
I might be quitting.
If you were quitting, you'd
have known that last week when
your snot was still pale
goldenrod. You're getting fired.
I just don't like
being told what to do.
I can get you in for a full
body scan later this week.
Thanks.
It's got to be viral. We should
start running gels and titers.
Maybe we should look into the girlfriend's
theory. She thinks she rode him to death.
What'd you tell her?
I told her 22-year-old
men don't die of sex.
- What'd you ask her?
- What do you mean?
I mean, I hope you got some
specifics on exactly what was going on.
If the girl thinks it could kill
you, it's worth knowing about.
Have you ever taken a life?
We should stop the antibiotics.
It's too soon to say
they're not having an effect.
They're having an effect.
His B. P. 's falling fast.
There's fluid filling his lungs.
His creatinine is rising.
His kidneys are shutting down.
Our treatment isn't making
him better. It's killing him.
So, we had six symptoms
that didn't add up
to anything. Now we
got seven. Who's excited?
I don't think it
complicates things. The
kidney failure was
caused by the antibiotics.
- Maybe.
- Typically, low blood pressure
and abdominal pain means an infection.
An abdominal infection causes
sepsis, low blood pressure.
Except we checked
for abdominal infections.
But what if it's the other
way around? What if the
low blood pressure's
causing the abdominal pain?
Viral heart infection.
The intestines aren't
getting enough blood,
and the result is belly pain.
- I know it's not
the standard presentation.
- It's a 10 million-to-1 shot.
I thought that's what
we dealt with here.
It explains the cardiomyopathy,
the pain, the low B.P., the fever.
You read the book. Impressive.
It's a ludicrously long
shot that explains every one
of those symptoms— except
for the cough and the rash.
Should we just erase those?
Well, anything can cause a rash.
Okay. Cardiac infection.
- Cameron, you thought allergy.
- Mm-hmm.
Chase, what was it
you thought? Carcinoid?
Then there's hypothyroidism.
Could be parasites.
Finally, sinus infection.
If you're gonna list all the things it
can't be, you're gonna need more colors.
Cameron was right. No condition
explains all these symptoms.
- But orange and green covers everything.
- Orange and green?
Two conditions
contracted simultaneously?
Occam's Razor. The simplest
explanation is always the best.
- And you think one is simpler than two?
- Pretty sure it is, yeah.
Baby shows up.
Chase tells you that two
people exchanged
fluids to create this being.
I tell you that one stork
dropped the little tyke off
in a diaper. Are you gonna
go with the two or the one?
- I think your argument is specious.
- I think your tie is ugly.
Why is one simpler than two?
It's lower, lonelier. Is it simpler?
Each one of these conditions
is about a thousand-to-one shot.
That means that any two of them happening
at the same time is a million-to-one shot.
Chase says the cardiac
infection is a 10 million-to-1 shot,
which makes my idea
10 times better than yours.
Get a calculator.
Run the numbers.
We'll run the tests.
Tests take time.
Treatment's quicker. Start the kid
on Unasyn for the sinus infection,
- and... what was orange?
- Hypothyroidism.
My uncle has
hypothyroidism. Not like this.
Intravenous
Levothyroxin is an artificial
thyroid medication that
should take care of it.
Also, the nurses are going to start you
on Unasyn. It's a more targeted antibiotic.
For the sinus infection? Yes.
- The other stuff is
for something else entirely.
- Bad luck, huh?
Don't worry. He should be
back to ditching work in no time.
Brandon?
Hey, Mom.
We're his parents.
How's he doing?
Um, Brandon is...
Uh, Mom. Dad— This is Mindy.
I was gonna bring her home for
Christmas. Um, we're engaged.
Dr. Hall to the
recovery room. Dr. Hall—
Did you tell the
family House's theory?
Two odd conditions striking completely
coincidentally at the exact same time?
I didn't phrase it quite that
way. They agree to treatment?
Of course they did. We're doctors.
They believe whatever we tell them.
So, is that our job?
House's puppets?
He comes up with an insane
idea, we get to pretend it's not?
His insane ideas are usually right.
We've been here long enough to...
We've been here long enough
to have Stockholm syndrome.
What, because we don't hate him?
He thinks outside the box. Is that so evil?
He has no idea where the box is.
If you guys think he's
right, go home. Relax.
Just wait for the
kid to get all better.
I'm going to the lab to
test for viral infections.
Negative for
Coxsackie "B" virus.
Seven down, about 5,000 to go.
You really think we're gonna
come up with your mystery
virus just by running
gels till we guess it right?
No. I think we're gonna do it by standing
around watching other people work.
I'm waiting for the
Epstein-Barr virus.
- She's weird, isn't she?
- Bad idea.
- What?
- Bad idea. You work with her.
What did I say?
Is weird some new ghetto euphemism for
sexy, like bad is good and phat is good?
- Then what the hell does "good" mean?
- "Ghetto euphemism"?
You don't think she's hot?
No.
Wow. Then you're brilliant. And I
am using "brilliant" as a euphemism.
Obviously, the girl is hot. Y-You're
not talking about her aesthetics.
You're talking about if I
want to jump her. I don't.
Brilliant.
Your Epstein-Barr is ready.
What are you doing? Level four.
No, no. I mean— I know
what you meant. We're waiting.
My throat hurts. So you said.
How long are we waiting? Two minutes less
than when you asked me two minutes ago.
- Hi.
- Hi. I'm Dr. Cuddy. Nice to meet you.
Dr. Cuddy, thanks for the consult. His
throat seems to have some condition.
Say "Ah." Ah.
He has a sore throat.
Of course. Yes, why didn't I...
I mean, because he
said that it hurt, and I
should have deduced
that meant it was sore.
I was in a board meeting.
Patients come first, right?
Wouldn't want to prescribe a lozenge if
there's any doubt about its efficacy, huh?
You once asked me why I think I'm always
right, and I realized that you're right.
At least, I think you're right.
I don't really know, now do I?
- Hey. I'm here.
- Go home. Drink some hot tea.
Excellent counsel.
Negative on parvovirus B-19.
I'm impressed. Thank
you. I was born to run gels.
I meant about Chase.
What about Chase?
Well, the man has no
physical interest in you.
He has a completely
professional relationship with
you, respects you as a
colleague and a doctor.
And yet, he can't look at
you without thinking sex.
Because I asked what
kind of sex could kill you?
You now have total control
over your relationship with him.
So, a woman can't
express her interest in sex
without it being some
professional power play?
No. If you look the way you
do and you say what you said,
you have to be aware of the
effect that it's going to have on men.
- Men should grow up.
- Yeah, and dogs should stop
licking themselves.
It's not gonna happen.
What's going on?
- Yeah, what are you doing here?
- Looking for you guys.
- Why didn't you page us?
- 'Cause I knew you'd be here.
Who told him? No one.
I assume you're trying to
prove my crazy, two-illness
theory wrong, so, obviously,
you're gonna be in the lab.
- You spin the urine?
- Not yet.
Talk to me when you have.
What'd you find out? Kidney
failure. It's acute interstitial nephritis.
- I wonder if that's significant.
- It means the antibiotics
didn't cause the kidney failure.
How'd you know?
If you guys hadn't been
so busy trying to prove
me wrong, you might've
checked in on the poor kid.
You visited a patient?
I was sitting by his bed all morning, just
so he'd know someone was there for him.
I looked in on him.
He's much better.
Ergo, the treatment's working.
Ergo, me right, you wrong.
Hey, I'm glad for the kid.
That smugness of yours really
is an attractive quality. Thank you.
It was either that
or get my hair
highlighted. Smugness
is easier to maintain.
I get that you're not a big believer in
the "catching flies with honey" approach,
but do you honestly think you'll
collect a jarful by cleverly taunting them?
Flies, no. Doctors, sure.
If I'd said to Foreman,
"Nice try. Great
guess, but sorry, not this
time," what do you think
he'd be doing right now?
I think he'd go home not feeling
like a piece of crap. Exactly.
You want him to feel like a piece of
crap? No. I don't want him going home.
Dr. Foreman.
Still have the cough. I'm
feeling a lot better though.
His fever is gone.
His rash is going away.
I see. Is everything okay?
Just ordering some tests.
Absolutely nothing to worry about.
- How much longer?
- 9:30. I figure she was on
the eighth hole when I paged her.
You probably got
another half hour.
I ran a T.S.H., T3 and
T4. The patient's negative
for hypothyroidism. I'm
not talking about you.
The fact that he's getting better would
indicate the unreliability of the tests.
If I'm right and it's a viral infection,
one of two things always happen:
the patient dies, or the patient's
immune system fights off the invader.
What's with her?
Her leg hurts after running six
miles. Who knows? Could be anything.
He's getting better.
That doesn't prove you're
right. That just proves
he's getting better.
It-It's not two illnesses.
It can't be two illnesses.
I am so glad you work here.
If I'm right, the antibiotics
you prescribed...
could box his kidneys and liver, impeding
his ability to fight off the virus.
- It could kill him.
- Well, that certainly would be a concern.
Fifty bucks?
Don't look away. The space
monkeys will be all over you.
- You wanna bet on the patient's health?
- You think that's bad luck?
You think that God will smite
him because of our insensitivity?
Well, if God does,
you make a quick 50.
- Oh.
- Go check his white blood count.
If he's fighting off a virus
like you think, it'll be way up.
Hey. Cuddy said you needed
a consult. What's up? I'm busy.
Oh!
- I was just being glib.
- You haven't said anything.
No. Before, when I was
talking about Brandon's
girlfriend thinking
sex could kill you.
I was just making a joke
because I was uncomfortable.
Oh, I don't even remember what
you said. I'm uncomfortable about sex.
- Well, we don't have to talk about this.
- Sex could kill you.
Do you know what the human body
goes through when you have sex?
Pupils dilate.
Arteries constrict.
Core temperature rises, heart
races, blood pressure skyrockets.
Respiration becomes
rapid and shallow.
The brain fires bursts of electrical
impulses from nowhere to nowhere.
Secretions spit
out of every gland,
and the muscles tense and spasm like you're
lifting three times your body weight.
It's violent, it's
ugly, and it's messy.
And if God hadn't
made it unbelievably fun,
the human race would've
died out eons ago.
Men are lucky they can
only have one orgasm.
You know that women can
have an hour-long orgasm?
Hey, Foreman. What's up?
- Hey, Foreman.
- Hey.
- White cell count isn't up, is it?
- No. We were both wrong.
White cell count is down—
Way down— and dropping.
His immune system is shot. We
need to get him into a clean room.
Can you walk, Brandon?
Yeah. A little.
Okay. 'Cause we'll need to
leave the chair outside. Thank you.
Where's April? April?
Can you take that chair,
please? Thank you. Yes, Robert.
I'll need to take your, um—
Your mask and your robe too.
You might wanna block your
ears for this, it's quite loud.
Something's made him
immuno-compromised.
His white blood cell count is down, which
means his body can't fight off infections.
If he gets sick, he'll
die. Sick? How sick?
If he gets a cold, he'll die.
Okay. I'm gonna push the needle into
your hip bone and take some of the marrow.
That's not so bad.
Uh-uh. That was
just the anesthetic.
The core biopsy
needle, it's a bit bigger.
Hey, man. Take a deep breath.
This-This is gonna hurt... a lot.
Your marrow makes
the blood cells.
We take a peek at it
under a microscope,
and maybe we
find a viral infection.
Maybe we find some fibrosis.
Something to explain why
your blood count is so low.
There we go.
One step closer to an answer.
If you don't find one,
I can't stay here forever.
- The patient could've died.
- The one with the pulled muscle?
Those symptoms are consistent
with a dozen other conditions.
- I'm entitled to a consult.
- You are not getting out of clinic duty.
Come on. You got a hundred other
idiot doctors in this building who go...
all warm and fuzzy
every time they pull a toy
car out of a nose—
You don't need me here.
No, I don't. But working with people
actually makes you a better doctor.
When did I sign up for that course? When
did I give you the impression that I care?
Working in this clinic obviously
instills a deep sense of compassion.
I've got your home number, right? In case
anything comes up at 3:00 in the morning.
It's not gonna work.
You know why?
Because this is fun.
You think of something
to make me miserable.
I think of something to
make you miserable...
It's a game, and I'm
gonna win because I
got a head start. You
are already miserable.
Uh— Is this important?
Uh, no. Good.
What's with you and her? Don't.
You have a thing for her? The
only people who can get to you...
No. There is not a thin
line between love and hate.
There is, in fact, a Great
Wall of China, with armed
sentries posted every 20
feet between love and hate.
Thirty-six Vicodin.
Who's the patient?
I am. You can't...
Dr. Wilson is the
prescribing physician. Yeah.
You will lie, cheat and
steal to get what you
want, but you're incapable
of kissing a little ass?
We all have our limitations.
House? Wrong
bottle. Do me a favor.
Take one of these,
wait five minutes for it
to kick in, then find
Cuddy and kiss her ass.
What was the
kid's first symptom?
You did the history. Of his 800
symptoms, which one hit him first?
Uh, the cough.
Gout.
Um, are we talking
about Brandon? Gout?
Uric acid crystals
in the joints?
The symptoms are
pain, swelling, redness,
stiffness. Not one of which
do I see on that board.
Because he doesn't have gout.
Every day, cells die.
We survive because the remaining
cells divide and replace the losses.
The colchicine, a gout medicine,
blocks mitosis and stops cell division,
which will result in
abdominal pain, rash,
nausea, fever, kidney
failure, low blood pressure...
and will also mess
with the bone marrow.
But he doesn't have gout. Why
would he have gout medication?
Because you guys were right. He didn't
have two conditions at the exact same time.
First, he got a cough. And because
he's an idiot, he went to a doctor.
In order to justify
charging $200, that
doctor felt he should
actually do something.
Oops. He wrote a prescription.
Seven thousand people die each
year from pharmacy screw-ups.
Not nearly as many as
die from doctor screw-ups,
but still, not something they
use in their promotional materials.
The pharmacist gave him gout
medicine instead of cough medicine.
And the only
thing it wouldn't do,
it would do absolutely
nothing to relieve his cough.
Occam's Razor...
The simplest explanation is almost
always that somebody screwed up.
But once he checked into this
hospital, he was completely in our control.
Our food, our
pills, our everything.
So even if you’re right,
no more gout medication.
He'd either continue to deteriorate,
or he would've gotten better.
But he got better,
and then he got worse.
It doesn't fit. It
doesn't make sense.
Okay. Two people screwed up.
Not as simple as one, but...
He's resting. He's—
I'm Dr. House.
I'm your son's physician. Oh.
You're the one we haven't met yet.
You're the one he hasn't met. How can
you treat someone without meeting them?
It's easy if you don't
give a crap about him.
That's a good thing.
If emotions made you act rationally, well,
they wouldn't be called emotions, right?
That's why we have this nice division of
labor. You hold his hand, I get him better.
If I start tucking him in at night,
well, that's not fair to you guys.
And if you start prescribing
medicine, well, that's not fair to me.
So, what I wanna know is, who
stepped on my side of the net?
Who cared enough to get stupid
enough to give him his cough medicine?
When we checked
in, Dr. Foreman...
Tuesday, he's getting better.
Wednesday, he's getting sick again.
Somebody gave him his
cough medicine Wednesday.
Come on. Nobody's gonna be mad.
I just wanna know
who tried to kill the kid.
- Dr. House, maybe we
should— - His throat was sore.
Page Dr. Occam. He's gonna
wanna hear about this. I'm sorry.
He was coughing, and I just
wanted to help him— Aren't you a dear.
Where are the pills? He took the last of
'em before he was switched into that room.
They're all gone? It
was just cough medicine.
No, it wasn't.
Where's the bottle?
We need to know exactly
what you put in this bottle.
We think it was colchicine,
a gout medication.
If the prescription said cough
medicine, that's what I dispensed.
The family is prepared
to waive liability, all right?
We just need to know what it was, what
dosage it was— It was cough medicine.
Refill it.
He's gonna be okay.
You don't know that.
Does Brandon like
that quality in you?
You're a little negative.
Things don't always work out for
the best. Doesn't hurt to hope they do.
No. Not unless that
makes you figure you can do
whatever you want, like
give people cough medicine.
This is cough medication. This is
what Brandon was supposed to get.
They're small, round and yellow.
Can you tell this man
what the pills in your
son's medicine bottle
actually looked like?
They were small, round
and yellow, exactly like this.
Those were the pills
that Brandon was taking.
Hey, I'm just a pharmacist, but I know
what cough medicine looks like, Doctor.
It was so perfect.
It was beautiful.
Beauty often seduces
us on the road to truth.
And triteness
kicks us in the nads.
So true. This
doesn't bother you?
That you were wrong? I
try to work through the pain.
I was not wrong. Everything I
said was true. It fit. It was elegant.
- So, reality was wrong?
- Reality's almost always wrong.
The cough medicine
did something.
Aggravated the condition.
It's all over the place.
Must be in his blood.
- What if it is his blood?
- Lymphoma?
Unless you've got
something better.
We foolishly ruled out lymphoma because
his C.T. scan showed no adenopathy,
C.B.C. showed a normal differen-smear,
bone marrow showed no— Screw the tests.
Do an exploratory laparotomy
and find out what's in there.
He has no blood pressure, no immune system
and no kidneys. Surgery will kill him.
Yeah, you're right. Let's
stick with the wrong pill theory.
I'll schedule him for surgery.
Okay, Brandon, we're running
this tube through your heart...
and into the pulmonary
arteries in your lungs.
The sensors will
give us information we
need for the exploratory
surgery later this afternoon.
- My fingers are numb.
- Try not to move.
We're in the right atrium, trying to
catch the flow through the tricuspid valve.
I think the catheter's
curling in the atrium.
Got it. We're in the R.V. now.
Ectopy.
- You must've irritated the heart wall.
- It'll calm down.
He can't tolerate any
cardiac arrhythmia. Pull back.
He needs the surgery.
Pressure's dropped.
- You still with us, Brandon?
- Get the curtains.
V.F.
Charging. Clear.
Sinus rhythm.
I got a pulse.
Yeah, but no surgery today.
- How're you doing?
- Okay.
Great. I'm doing good too.
I get to knock off an hour
early today. You know why?
Because I kissed my boss's
ass. Do you ever do that?
I think she just said yes 'cause
she wants to reinforce that behavior.
Wants me to kiss a lot of other people's
ass, like she wants me to kiss yours.
What would you want? A doctor
who holds your hand while you die,
or a doctor who ignores
you while you get better?
I guess it would particularly suck to have
a doctor who ignores you while you die.
- I should go.
- You think it's gonna come out on its own?
Are we talking bigger
than a breadbasket?
Because, actually, it
will come out on its own.
Which for small stuff
is no problem. It's
wrapped up in a nice,
soft package, and plop.
Big stuff, you're
gonna rip something,
which, speaking medically, is
when the fun stops. How did you...
You've been here half an hour, you haven't
sat down. That tells me its location.
You haven't told me what it
is. That tells me it's humiliating.
You have a little birdie
carved on your arm. That
tells me you have a high
tolerance for humiliation.
So I figure it's
not hemorrhoids.
I've been a doctor 20 years.
You're not gonna surprise me.
It's an MP3 player.
Mm.
Is it—Is it because of
the size, or the shape,
or is it the pounding bass line?
What are we gonna do?
- I'm gonna wait.
- For what?
Okay. It's 3:00. I'm off.
Would you tell Dr. Cuddy there's a patient
in Exam Room Two needs her attention?
And the R.I.A.A. wants her
to check for illegal downloads.
Brandon's not ready
for surgery. Okay.
Let's leave it a couple of
weeks. He should be feeling
better by then. Oh, wait.
Which way does time go?
He crashed during prep. He's
also experiencing pain in his fingers.
Think some bug may have
gotten in the clean room.
I think we should double
his dosage of G-CSF to
temporarily boost his
white blood cell count.
Pain in his fingers. Right.
Hi again. He can't...
Where's he going?
Hey. How you all doing?
Interesting fact. Every seven years, it's a
whole new you. Inspiring metaphor, huh?
Dr. House, this is a clean
room. Yeah. I read the sign.
But cells of different organs
reproduce at different rates.
So, you get a new
kidney every three years.
Get a new stomach
lining every week.
This is why colchicine poisoning causes
all these symptoms, but not all at once.
But we went to the
pharmacy. We saw the pills.
Colchicine does its damage
in a very specific order.
First of all, there's the
pain in the abdomen, the
rash, the fever. Isn't
that what you got first?
Then the kidneys go, which
is exactly what happened to...
- Brandon.
- Right.
Then it screws up your bone
marrow, and then neuropathy.
A painful tingling in
the fingers and toes.
And what do you suppose
happens after that?
Hair loss. The bad news is...
your special boy is
doing drugs. No, he's not.
Ecstasy? No.
- Twice with Dan and Mike.
- You know what they cut that stuff with?
Apparently, colchicine.
Unless you ingested the
colchicine through your
contact lens solution,
or skin cream or some
other drug you're lying about.
I don't know how it happened. I don't care
how it happened. It happened. Start, uh—
- Brandon.
- Lovely name.
Start Brandon on FA B fragments, and get
him some Tylenol for the hair I pulled out.
And get some air in here.
Make a note. I should
never doubt myself.
I think you'll remember.
You know, it wouldn't
hurt you to be wrong
every now and then.
What, you don't care
about these people?
The colchicine interferes with the
ability of the heart muscle to contract,
pumping blood, lowering
your blood pressure.
The antibodies we're giving you
should neutralize the colchicine,
allowing your heart to
beat at its normal rate.
When will you know?
We know now.
Thank God.
Mmm.
Big weekend? It's not
for me. I'm fully stocked.
- Cuddy got you doing inventory?
- Nope. Trying to solve that kid's case.
The gout medicine O.D.? Yeah.
The fact that I know
it's a gout medicine O.D.
would indicate the
case is already solved.
Well, you'd be wrong.
What about the fact that the kid is now—I
believe the technical term is— "not sick"?
You know how many forms of
colchicine there are on the market?
- Stop it.
- Neither do I. But it's a lot.
Pills, powders,
liquids, I. V. fluids.
Somewhere at a party, in his coffee,
up his nose, in his ear, this kid had some.
You're not happy with
your Ecstasy theory?
- He said he used it twice.
- People lie.
- If you're gonna lie, it's— - You
know what? I'm not interested.
- Not curious?
- No. Because I'm well-adjusted.
Right.
Temperature's normal. I
want cousin Sharon there.
If we invite Sharon, we
have to invite all the cousins.
So what? My side of the
family doesn't need anything.
I don't suppose I could have some of those
cough pills, huh? They're okay, right?
- Yes. You're doing great.
- You should invite Dr. House.
- Will he come?
- No. But he'll send a gift.
I'll make sure it's a good one.
There's a letter on
the back of these pills.
Your old pills didn't
have a letter on them?
No. Round and
yellow, but no letter.
Well, these will
help your cough.
Hey, you wanna go get some— No.
That's some bad hat, Harry.