♪ You shake me like tambourine ♪
When you're little and
you announce to your parents
that you want to be a doctor,
they're thrilled.
Hey! Look. It's family day!
It's "Nanny has the flu day and
three kids is so many kids day"!
You want my coffee?
I have no kids,
- thank God.
- Bless you!
"Thank God"?
It's hard to just up
and move countries
when you have bambinos,
that's all.
You practice medicine on your
stuffed animals. And you dream.
Hey, we could get a place
in Fremont.
We have a place. My place.
Yeah, but your place has a
roommate with a hairless cat.
Good morning!
- Hey.
- You know what we should do?
We should do like a breakfast
or a pre-work double date...
- Never.
- What?
- Carina.
- Dr. Bello's rounds are too early,
and she doesn't want to get fired.
Not hungry!
And I don't want to get fired.
Or be late to rounds,
which I am.
Bye.
You know, we live together now.
Playing house with a stalker.
How sweet.
It's not playing house, when it's
an actual monogamous relationship
that goes past three months.
So, if you ever get there,
please let me know.
When you were a baby, I wanted
to put a pillow
- on your face.
- Okay, Carina.
It's not too late, you know.
The dreams turn to plans...
pre-med, med school,
residency, fellowship.
Maggie, how long
are we going to do this?
All right?
It was kind of sexy at first,
the petulance, the silence,
- but now...
- Petulance? Wow. Pot, kettle.
Who's the pot? I'm not the pot.
You think I'm the pot?
Petulance is childlike sulkiness.
You are a grown man who never
learned how to apologize.
I am excellent at apologizing
when I've actually done
something wrong.
My mom always said
men show you who they are
from the very beginning,
if you're paying attention.
I'm pretty sure she stole
that from Maya Angelou.
It takes almost 15 years
to prepare to be a surgeon.
Can I sit with you?
I'd like that.
But no matter
how much you prepare...
15 years isn't enough.
He's been in there for days.
Has he slept?
He sleeps.
In the chair.
How worried should we be,
like on a scale
from one to super worried?
I think he's okay.
I think...
I think he'll be okay.
I'm not so sure about Alex.
No progress on Kimmie?
I found a doctor in Chicago
who's doing a similar
kind of ultrasound research.
Uh... she hasn't published
much yet,
but I'm hoping she's further
along in the process than I am.
Text me
if anything changes.
- Whoa. Where are you going?
- Rounds.
- Uh, skip this one.
- Uh, I really can't.
No, you can because
Ollie is dying,
and Richard doesn't need
to hear you say it again.
There are protocols.
When you break them,
you're Meredith Grey.
When I break them,
I get a write-up.
Okay. Fine.
Just do it out here.
Okay.
Roy?
But I need to see the patient's
latest vitals, in the room...
Be creative. Qadri?
Uh...
That's... right...
That's Molly...?
Ollie. Olive Warner.
She's 66.
End-stage liver failure
and cardiomyopathy.
Surgical protocols were rejected
in favor of end-of-life support.
Excellent, Bello. Move along.
It's the chemo that makes me
so sick, not the tumor.
No, it's the chemo
that's keeping you alive.
It's the chemo that's making me
wish I wasn't alive!
Come back later.
Kimmie...
I tried it your way, Dr. Alex!
All this time, I stayed here,
and I tried to shrink the tumor,
and I waited on
your miracle cure.
It didn't come,
and it sucks.
But...
it's not your fault.
You tried.
Now... just...
I want to go see some shows.
I want to see Broadway before I die.
And not just on my computer.
I... I want to touch it,
and I want to smell it,
and I want to sing...
like I'll just stand on
the street,
and I'll sing. On Broadway.
Maybe that sounds ridiculous,
but...
it's my dream.
I've... I-I have a surgery
on another kid to prep for,
but when I'm finished,
I'm going to come straight back here,
and we'll talk about this.
Over ice cream.
I'll even bring
the peanut butter to put on top,
as gross as I think that is.
Just hang tight.
Okay?
Okay.
Dr. Aronson to the ER.
She's not taking any food?
Are you the only one
doing the the feedings?
My mom has her when I work.
Oh, okay, good.
Hey, something is going on
with you, little one.
We're going to figure out
what it is, okay?
Obviously,
I think that might be her heart.
She has a coarctation of the aorta,
and I think that maybe
we should start her
- on...
- I'm sorry.
I thought I could do this,
but I can't.
- Every time I look at you...
- You'd like another doctor.
I-I know you were Ruby's
No, I was... I was her doctor in utero,
and now that she's out,
it's perfectly appropriate.
I will have someone else
come and see her.
Whatever you need,
Matthew.
No! No, no, no.
They do not go in there.
Are you serious?
This is a teaching hospital.
Yeah. Well,
this is a teaching moment.
He is a father who lost the
mother of his baby in childbirth.
And now the baby has
a failure to thrive,
and he is breaking,
and he needs a minute!
Go!
Ruby has failure to thrive?
What do you think it is?
April, please don't go in there.
No, I won't.
You know, I have research
- to do.
- Look, I am your chief,
and I made you my right hand
for a reason.
So you can cover my service
for one day
while I get caught up
on my TrailBlazer.
You know everybody's calling it
the TailBlazer, right?
Excuse me.
Are you Chief Bailey?
I am.
Hey, how you doing this morning,
Dr. Bailey?
I'm Agent Martin Fields.
I... I need to talk
with one of your surgeons.
Uh, Agent Fields?
I'm sorry.
Are you FBI? Or...
Oh, no, ma'am. I'm with Immigration
and Customs Enforcement.
Yeah, it says here
it's a surgical intern.
Which one?
*GREY'S ANATOMY
Season 14   Episode 19
Episode Title :
"Beautiful Dreamer"
Okay, if this is about
Mr. Bartlett's ventilator,
I barely bumped it,
and the plug
was never technically all
the way out of the socket...
It's not about that.
Good, because I think
it was already loose.
If anything, I saved him...
We don't have a lot of time,
but I need you to pay attention,
and I need you to stay calm.
Okay, he's waiting in my office.
Who is?
There's an agent from
Immigration and Customs here,
and he wants to speak to you.
No. No, no, no, no.
Okay, Bello,
what is this about?
- Are you undocumented?
- No! I'm a Dreamer.
I'm... I'm here under DACA.
I have a work permit,
so I'm protected.
Okay, and everything is
up to date, your status?
Of course! The only way
I could get deported
is if I break the law, but I-I don't!
I... I don't speed. I don't do drugs.
- I don't do anything wrong.
- Okay. This is good.
Okay, so they probably just want
to check your papers or something.
No.
I have to run. I-I-I have to hide.
- I...
- Bello, Bello, calm down.
I have a friend from high school.
She... She was at work...
an intern in a law firm.
ICE came to her work. They
said they just wanted to talk.
Two days later, she was
dropped off in Mexico City
with a bag of clothes
and a check from her family
she had no way of cashing.
She just...
She doesn't even speak Spanish.
She came here
when she was 2.
Dr. Bailey, how do I calm down?
Okay, I found Dr. Bello.
- Great!
- Sadly, she is in surgery.
And how long will that take?
Well, it's a renal
reconstruction
with ureteral implantation.
If all goes well, barring
any complications, it's...
difficult to say, at this point,
when it would be over.
When will you know?
When it's over.
- Ah.
- Yeah.
I will wait.
Okay!
Hey, I need you to postpone
this morning's colectomy.
And, Helm, I need a favor.
You didn't call me Hellmouth.
What's wrong? Who died?
Is it Vik?
Tom Koracick sings your praises.
- Oh, Tom.
- I know. I'd love to compare data.
We successfully did the
ultrasound procedure
on a hypothalamic tumor,
but we have a patient
with a mass
that's encroaching on Wernicke's area.
I'm giving a lecture next week at UW.
Maybe I stay a few extra days,
and we can share acoustic
spectrum secrets.
That would be incredible.
And I bet
I can get the foundation
to pay for your expenses.
- How's that?
- The foundation?
Grey Sloan is a
Harper Avery hospital.
Oh.
Shoot. I didn't realize that.
Is that a problem?
Yes, unfortunately, it is.
I'm really sorry, Dr. Shepherd.
Nice talking to you.
Good luck!
Wait...
What was that?
Dr. DeLuca, uh, Dr. Grey needs you.
Dr. Grey?
DeLuca's on my service today.
I'm sorry, but she needs you
right now.
She's 3 months old, and she
has a coarctation of the aorta.
Her complaints include
occasional vomiting,
difficulty feeding, failure to thrive,
tachycardia, irritability.
We were hoping we could hold off
on cardiac repairs
- until she got older, but
- Did you talk to Karev?
Well, he has a surgery
that can't wait,
which is why I'm giving her
to you in the meantime
because I trust you,
and I need this baby to be okay.
- Mm.
- She's going to need a cardiac consult.
Dad is emotional...
this is a hard place for him to be...
but you cannot let him leave
with her.
Okay, but I have a busy pit today,
so...
I'll cover it.
Sorry. I was eavesdropping.
I'll cover the pit. You
just take care of Ruby.
Please.
Okay. I'll take care of them.
Who even called them, okay?
They can't just take you.
They can, Andrew.
They can detain me for
as long as they want.
And if they decide to, they can
send me back to El Salvador.
But you don't even...
- Have you ever even been to El Salvador?
- No.
My entire family moved here
when I was one.
I don't know a single person there.
You should get married.
People have green card marriages
all the time.
Right. Okay. Let's do it. Today!
What? You're ready
to get married?
- Well, I... Do you not want to?
- No, yeah.
I-I-I just, I thought we were
still figuring stuff out.
Yeah, no, it is soon.
It's really soon, but...
I just didn't know that you were
there... that we were there yet.
No, sure, but I want to see
if we can get there.
And we can't get there
if you're not here,
so if we need to get there to
see if we can get there, then...
Okay, let's just keep
our eye on the prize, okay?
- Right.
It won't work.
It doesn't work that way
for Dreamers.
Getting married
won't give me legal status.
Well, bright side, that was the
worst proposal I've ever seen.
No, no, no. I wasn't...
That's not
how I would actually do it!
Okay, we'll figure
something else out.
Oh, here she is!
Dr. Robbins is here!
Hi. Dr. Robbins, I don't think
they actually gave me the epidural
because I still feel the soccer
ball with the knife-like edges.
I just increased her dose.
I know it hurts, Lanie,
but it's going to kick in
any minute now, okay?
Is everything progressing well?
Yes. She's five centimeters
dilated
and contracting
three to four times in ten.
Great! So you are
in active labor now.
So the baby's heart is okay?
And my heart is okay?
Everything looks really great, Lanie.
She has a history of a Fontan
operation for a single ventricle,
which was also evolving in the baby.
So I did a fetal aortic
valvuloplasty at 26 weeks,
and it's been smooth sailing
for the little guy.
Isn't a C-section indicated?
- I wish!
- No.
A vaginal delivery is safer here.
There's more potential for blood
loss with a C-section.
But then it would be over faster.
I know. I know that it hurts, okay?
Just keep breathing. Keep breathing.
I want an EKG, her most recent echo,
a nasal cannula,
oxytocin, bisoprolol,
digoxin, and a setup for vacuum
delivery all by Lanie's bedside.
Oh, I also want
a cardiologist on standby.
Am I missing something?
You just said she was fine.
Wait. Are we supposed to lie to moms?
Arizona, she's fine.
You have too many statistics
from the maternal mortality
project in your head.
She's not showing any signs of...
Neither was the last patient
who died postpartum.
She wasn't showing any signs of anything.
Go get my stuff.
- Any word?
- Still at it.
Let need to be clear with you,
Dr. Bailey.
If you're lying about
the whereabouts of Dr. Bello,
you're breaking federal law.
Oh, I am clear on that, sir.
And I assure you that Dr. Bello
is in an operating room.
Did Dr. Bello break any laws?
I'm not at liberty
to discuss her case with you.
I apologize.
Stomach trouble?
Always.
When was your last physical?
Why do you ask?
Because you've been sitting
still for quite some time,
and your jugular is bulging so much
that I can see your pulse
from here.
I'm gonna say 120, resting.
May I?
- Let's see.
- Dr. Bailey, you don't...
Mm-hmm.
Hmm.
Yep. Your pulse is irregular.
Have you seen a cardiologist?
Dr. Bailey, let's not play
this game, okay?
I'm just doing my job.
As am I, Agent Fields.
Look, heart health is nothing
to mess around with.
I will just wait here
for Dr. Bello, okay?
Thank you, though.
Mm-hmm.
- Bello's from El Salvador?
- Barely.
But if we don't come up
with something,
they're going to put her in
a van, put a bag over her head,
and send her back there.
I don't think that's how it works.
Still, I need ideas.
Don't you know anyone?
- What?
- Your dad...
he was a drug dealer, right?
Isn't there an underground or something?
My dad was a drug user.
He didn't know crap.
You know who you should talk to?
You're going to need $1,500.
- I don't have...
- We'll get it.
You're going to go to New York,
and you're going to talk
to a guy named Mikey.
I'll vouch for you.
Mikey will file a false police report
and get you a death certificate.
It's usually from someone
who died in another country.
The tricky part is getting the corpse,
but Mikey has some sort of side
hustle with the city morgue.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa...
- I don't want to become another person!
It worked for me.
Is that what you did?
You faked your death?
No. That was my Plan B.
I just legally changed my name,
and I moved states.
But I was just hiding from
a person, not a whole country.
I graduated college magna cum laude.
I was valedictorian of my high school.
I was captain of the dance squad.
Okay, what does that have to do with...
She's saying she's not
the fake-your-own-death kind of person.
- Okay.
So we'll think of something else.
Okay, so what exactly
is the problem, then,
or what was the problem?
I really can't say.
I'm just trying to help here.
So, did you used to work for us?
Or is this a noncompete situation?
No, I mean I cannot say.
I signed a legal agreement that
says that I can't talk about
the legal agreement that I signed.
Okay, well, my grandfather
has passed,
so you can feel free
to discuss anything with me.
- Where'd she go?
- Yeah. She does that.
What? That's rude.
All right, we'll get
somebody else, then.
No, there is no one else. I need her.
I can't look at Alex
and tell him that I'm done
trying to save his favorite patient.
I need fresh eyes. I need fresh in...
I-I need her.
- Hey.
Lanie wants to walk around
and let gravity do its job...
Oh, no. No, no.
She needs continuous monitoring.
Code blue!
Are you okay?
It's hard.
It's hard to see Matthew here with Ruby.
I know, and I'm so sorry about
that, but Lanie is fine.
She's progressing well, and
she's experiencing no signs...
Crash cart.
- What?
- I... I need a crash cart.
- Who's crashing?
- No, no, no.
I need a crash cart
for before they're crashing!
Oh! Bloodbank.
All right, you need to come with me.
And bring all that stuff.
Hey.
How he's doing?
Well, he'd be doing a lot better
if I could get him
to take a walk, get some air.
I'm gonna get him
a hot meal.
Even if he doesn't eat it,
at least I'll feel
like I'm doing something.
Right. Hey, have you heard
of Dr. Rebecca Froy?
Neuroscientist
based out of Chicago?
- Why?
- Well, Shepherd wanted to meet with her
about her ultrasound work,
but when she heard
we were a Harper Avery hospital,
she canceled.
I guess she signed some
agreement with Grandfather?
I think I do remember that.
Yeah, some dust-up over research.
Harper took her to court.
She lost. End of story.
You know how
your grandfather loved a fight.
Yeah.
You know what? Maya Angelou
and your mom were right.
People show you who they are.
I've done that.
I've shown you I'm loyal.
You know I'm not a gossip.
And you certainly know
I'm not just going to
stir up drama for no reason.
What you've shown me
is that you keep secrets
very effectively
and that you lie by omission,
and if you've demonstrated
loyalty to anyone, it isn't me.
- This is where you wanted it?
- That's perfect.
Thank you, Dr. Parker.
What's that?
EKG machine in case you change your mind.
Is that like a blood-draw thing?
Like needles?
No. Just a few stickers.
Takes five minutes.
Owen! I need you to call Megan
and ask for a favor.
- What?
- Sam Bello needs a hole
to hide in for a while.
I'm gonna need more information.
Because our government is
in the habit
of deporting neurosurgeons
in the making.
- Wait. What?
- Sam Bello is a Dreamer,
and ICE has come for her.
We're trying to get her someplace safe
so she can get an immigration lawyer
and get this stuff sorted out.
We smuggled Megan's kid into the country,
so I figure she owes us one.
- Okay, just wait...
- She's great, Owen. She's my best...
It doesn't matter how great she
is if she's not law abiding...
Have you met Sam Bello?
She is not a criminal, Owen!
She's my favorite intern!
Please help!
Okay, so you want to send her
down to Southern California...
- Yes!
- Where she'll be far away
from immigration problems?
Can you call someone in the Army
and have them talk to ICE?
I think you're grasping at straws.
If it's the man, call in the man.
- Isn't that how it works?
- Nope.
Dr. Parker with NICU.
It's great, right?
I just found this emergency
cart, gutted the thing!
It's got room for everything.
But is someone gonna
need this somewhere?
- There are more, right?
- But you did this all wrong.
How is it wrong? I just made it up!
Because you put the hemorrhage
supplies in the bottom drawer.
- So?
- I mean, okay, what drawer
do you put your underwear in?
- Um... Pass?
- You put it in the top drawer
because it's what you grab first.
Then surgical equipment
in the bottom drawer.
Cardiovascular event,
and then preeclampsia,
sepsis, hemorrhage...
this zone.
- And that's... hold on, and then I think
- Yeah.
That I want to put
this in here.
This is the EKG for Agent Fields.
Is this a patient of yours?
Uh, that gentleman.
He works with ICE.
And he's here to talk with Dr. Bello,
whose Dreamer status is in question.
There's an ICE agent here?
Yes, for one of our star interns.
But hey,
that's neither here nor there
because this man's heart...
Oh! Okay!
Yeah, I can run all the tests.
I can do an echo.
I can do a treadmill nuclear stress test
Just look at the EKG.
Yeah. I'm gonna look at it.
I'll look at it really thoroughly.
I'm going to...
I could even do a PET scan
if you need more time...
Dr. Pierce. Look.
Oh.
ST and T wave changes.
This isn't good.
This is what I'm talking about.
Is this Dr. Bello?
Oh, no, this is Dr. Pierce,
our chief of cardiothoracic surgery.
She just looked at your EKG...
Oh, come on. Dr. Bailey,
I've been here all day.
Agent Fields, I had a heart
attack a couple of months ago.
It almost took me out of the game
and left my child without a mother.
Please, sir. Listen to
what Dr. Pierce has to say.
Hey, I thought
you were covering the pit.
I am. It's covered.
Have you heard from cardio?
Not yet. I was just telling Matthew...
I don't think it's her heart.
- Why?
- I don't know. It's just a feeling.
But we have her medical records.
No, I know, but...
You don't have any kids.
Look, if Harriet had this,
I'd be thinking all sorts
of other things,
like GI obstruction or reflux,
pyloric stenosis, sepsis.
But Harriet doesn't have
a known heart condition.
- Ruby does.
- No, I know.
I know, but
can you please check it out,
I mean, since you're waiting,
anyway?
Please.
Of course I will.
- Thanks.
- Sure.
Nurse Parker to the cath lab.
- Hey.
___
Sam's an American, okay, just like me.
She came here when
she was a baby with her mother,
just like me!
___
Andrea! I deported no one!
I would never do something
like that to you, to her...
Wow.
_
♪ Are you gonna finish
what you started? ♪
♪ The hour is late ♪
♪ You're the only hand
that can resolve it ♪
♪ You took more than you ever even wanted ♪
Hey, hey, hey... hey!
- Where are you going?
- We're checking out.
Did Alex... Did Dr. Karev sign off?
Dr. Karev won't sign off.
He'll never sign off.
Dr. Shepherd is looking for a
new partner for the ultrasound.
Dr. Wilson,
you've all been so good to us.
I asked you to fight for Kimmie,
and you fought.
Now I want to do
what Kimmie wants.
I'm taking her
where she wants to go.
Does Alex know?
♪ Come back here ♪
Will you tell him I said...
thank you?
And that when I said it,
I was smiling?
♪ Unraveling ♪
♪ Are you going to stand there
watching me unraveling? ♪
Hey. How was surgery?
Ah! Good.
Quick and easy.
Were you able to help out Bello?
Uh, no, I don't think so.
I think I actually
just scared her.
So... Um-hmm!
So, no church wedding.
What?
I thought that we could
start wedding planning.
So, maybe a restaurant or a bar.
I mean, not Joe's Bar.
Or maybe Joe's Bar
if we decorate it...
We got time to figure it out
and plan it.
I know. I just...
I thought
it might feel good to
plan something.
Thanks. I got to check on Kimmie.
- Alex?
- Yeah?
Kimmie left.
What? When?
Just a bit ago. She...
She told me to...
Dr. Teller, extension 2219.
- Hey.
- Hi.
Mocha. Extra shot.
You're such a good boy.
Mm.
How's she doing?
She takes
about one breath a minute.
It's very slow, very painful.
Not for her. For Richard.
Sorry to hear that.
Well, you let me know if
there's anything else I can do.
Oh, I spoke to Evan in legal
about the Rebecca Froy thing.
Oh, leave that alone, honey.
It's not worth your time.
Well, Shepherd's trying to save
children with brain tumors, Mom.
Some petty fight over research
should not get in the way of that.
I've asked the lawyers
to waive whatever agreement
Harper made with her.
- You did what?
- Yeah. Took five minutes.
Handled.
Hey, how is she?
- She's in love.
- What?
With her healthy baby boy,
who has yet to be named.
5 pounds, 14 ounces.
She only pushed three times.
No bleeding?
No... No - No complications?
No forceps,
no... no vacuum extraction?
- None of that.
- Oh! I was just trying to be cautious.
I know.
So... should I return the cart or...
You should just...
just leave it, Bloodbank.
So it's not her heart?
No, it's her belly.
She has pyloric stenosis.
See this area here?
It's a little spot where
the muscle is getting too big
and won't let
the food pass through.
And what happens now?
It is a simple,
simple surgery.
Half an hour, and she's going to
be good as new.
Okay. Okay.
Thanks.
I-I'm sorry. It's, uh... It's a lot.
I know. I know. You're taking
care of her on your own.
I'm sorry. I can't imagine...
Yeah. It's, uh, tough.
Nights are tough.
But she cries, and I go in
and take one look at her,
and I'm just so happy
to see her, you know?
I'm sorry. Thank you for catching this.
Oh, no, I didn't. Dr. Kepner did.
- Dr. Kepner?
- Yeah. She's a mom.
And she had a feeling.
I'll come find you when
we're done, okay?
Okay.
Pyloric stenosis?
Yeah. She didn't have
all the obvious symptoms,
but at least we caught it early,
and she's gonna be just fine.
- Oh, thank you.
- Yeah.
Help!
Oh, my God... help! Someone help me!
My wife is bleeding!
She's bleeding! Someone help!
Hey, Schmitt, Schmitt!
Grab the cart and follow me.
- What happened?
- Somebody help her!
You have to help her!
She had a vaginal delivery late
last night... no complications.
Ahh! Something's wrong!
Start her on high-flow O2, 10 liters,
and we'll need a bolus
of 10 units of oxytocin IM
followed by an infusion.
Okay, no, hold on.
Sorry... it's right there.
Schmitt, top drawer, oxytocin.
- Speculum and 4x4s?
- Got it.
- Balloon catheter?
- Bottom drawer.
- I don't see it.
- It's on the right.
No, it's on the left,
underneath the packing.
- Got it.
- Look at me.
Hang on there, okay?
Just hang in there.
We got you. You've got this.
It's... It's not good.
You have severe defects
in blood flow to your heart
during stress, which suggests
major occlusions...
- Occlusions?
- Oh, blockages.
Your coronary arteries
are almost completely clogged shut...
Leaving you at high risk
for a heart attack.
Very high risk.
I thought you guys
were just stalling me...
- Right?
- But no, no. No, we, um...
You're in very grave danger.
I swear to God, if this
is some sort of game...
Agent Fields, I swear to God it is not.
I'm recommending
a cardiac catheterization.
I'll go in, open up
the arteries right now... today.
Well, can I... Can I call my wife?
I mean, she-she's gonna be
out of her mind with worry.
Of course. Right, yeah.
Call whoever you need to.
- We'll get you started.
- Mm-hmm.
Dr. Bailey, thank you.
I'm grateful.
But I'm going to have to call my office,
and they're going to send
somebody else for Dr. Bello.
Agent Fields...
hey, I know that there are protocols,
but can you please just tell me...
did Dr. Bello break the law?
- A red light?
- That's what he said.
Said they have her on camera.
Well, I run
a red light once a month.
They can deport her for that?
Apparently.
I was at work for 36 hours.
There was a six-car
pileup in the pit,
and I scrubbed in on...
on three different surgeries,
and I was floating all the way home.
Till I heard a horn, and some
guy behind me riding my bumper.
And the light turned yellow,
and no one was coming,
so I pumped the gas.
I thought I made it through. I thought...
I thought I made it through.
Okay, if...
if you end up in El Salvador...
it's likely your medical
accreditation won't transfer,
and you'll have to
start over from scratch.
Look, we will do everything
we can
to try and land you somewhere
at the same level you are here.
My mom took my sister and I
out of that country
because there was a war,
and she saw my dad get shot
on our front porch.
We moved to Florida,
and she worked two jobs...
20 hours a day... to keep us safe.
No, I not going back there.
I won't.
We should run.
I have a friend in Canada.
We get somebody to drive us
across the border.
We hole up, and we wait.
- No.
- We run, and we wait.
You can't run.
Listen... I'm all for
driving the getaway car,
but right now, they are treating you
like someone who snuck into this
country in the trunk of a car.
Don't become
what they're trying to make you.
If you run, you're a criminal.
If you're a criminal, you could
never practice medicine again.
Do not give them that.
- Hey.
Lanie is stable,
and so is the baby boy, Gryffin,
named for Gryffindor.
Steady numbers
across the board.
Our patient with the postpartum
bleed is stable, too. Thank God.
She would have bled out
in minutes
if we didn't have all this,
you and your little cart.
You saved her.
I think that we're finished.
What?
Our project. Maternal mortality.
I think this cart is
the next step.
I mean, if we had one on
every OB and delivery floor,
then we're prepared for
any postpartum complications.
The key to not turning birth
into a trauma
is to prepare for it
as if it is a trauma.
You're brilliant.
Are you...
Are you going to move to
another country?
What?
Well, just...
You're a free spirit, and you...
you like the freedom to just,
you know, move countries.
But...
Listen. Your research is almost done,
and our project is almost done,
and I...
I'm running scenarios,
and I just want to be prepared.
I want to know how loaded
my crash cart should be.
I don't want a crash cart.
You... You don't...
You don't want a crash cart?
Or you don't want a crash?
I'm sorry. I just...
I'm mixing up my metaphors.
I don't want to leave you, Arizona.
If you have someplace else to be,
I can page you
when I'm done here.
Oh, no, I'd like to see him
through to the end.
I'm dying?
No. Um, if I make a diagnosis,
I want to see my patient
through treatment.
I don't like doing my job halfway.
I don't like doing my job at all.
I don't even like wearing the jacket.
Some guys like wearing the jacket.
I used to.
I used to feel good about it.
I believe in law and order.
You know, I...
I grew up watching Westerns.
I wanted to be the sheriff
that rode in at the last minute
and saved everyone.
Now...
I don't know what we're doing.
Staking out schools,
taking kids...
doctors...
I don't know what we're doing anymore.
Okay, I talked to your mom.
She's trying to reach a lawyer.
I don't even know
if I can take a bag.
Do you know if they let you take a...
Here's a plane ticket to Zurich.
I'm going to Switzerland?
You are voluntarily leaving the country
to continue your studies
at the prestigious cardiothoracic program
at Klausman Institute.
Congratulations on your acceptance.
- What?
- You applied last year.
I did?
Here's your application
and your essay.
They were very impressed.
- Who wrote this?
- You did.
With the help of Dr. Pierce.
When you land tomorrow, somebody
will be there to meet you.
They will help get you settled,
and Dr. Yang is expecting you.
You're going to love
working with her.
She was also the best
in her class.
♪ And I'll fall on my knees ♪
♪ Tell me how's the way to be ♪
♪ Tell me how's the way to go ♪
♪ Tell me all that I should know ♪
♪ And I'll fall on my knees ♪
♪ Tell me how's the way to go ♪
♪ Tell me how's the way to be ♪
♪ To evoke some empathy ♪
♪ Danger will follow me now ♪
- ♪ Everywhere I go ♪
- I want to have kids with you.
I love how much you care for Kimmie,
and it really makes me
want to have kids with you.
♪ And take me to my home ♪
And if it's okay with you,
I would really like
to take your last name.
Because I've never had the last
name of anyone who's loved me.
♪ And I'll fall on my knees ♪
♪ Tell me how's the way to go ♪
♪ Tell me how's the way to see ♪
♪ Show me all that I could be ♪
♪ And I'll fall on my knees ♪
♪ Tell me how's the way to be ♪
♪ Tell me how's the way to go ♪
♪ And tell me why I feel so low ♪
♪ Danger will follow me now ♪
♪ Everywhere I go ♪
♪ Angels will call on me ♪
♪ And take me to my home ♪
♪ Well, these tired eyes ♪
My supervisor will be here
in the morning,
but I can get you started
at least with the paperwork.
So, are you looking to foster a child?
Or foster to adopt?
Foster to adopt.
We spend our childhoods
writing our dreams in diaries.
As adults, those dreams quietly
come true every single day...
only sometimes we forget to notice,
until it's too late.
I'm coming with you, okay?
As soon as I can.
No... Andrew,
I don't even want to go!
Yes, I am, okay?
I love you, Sam.
- You can't...
- I'm in love with you.
You're not throwing your life
away because I have to!
No, I'll beg Dr. Yang for a job...
No. I...
I followed you here. I'm a liar.
I'm... I'm a crazy stalker,
and you should stay away
from me.
Sam. Stop.
Hey.
We work.
We don't.
No, even when we do,
we don't.
♪ Angels will call on me
and take me to my home ♪
I have to go.
♪ And danger will follow me now ♪
Stay here.
♪ Everywhere I go ♪
♪ Angels will call on me ♪
♪ And take me to my home ♪
♪ Angels will follow me now ♪
♪ Lead me to my home ♪
Andrew, I'm so sorry.
So slow down.
And take it in.
- Hey.
- People can't be
with the people they love.
What?
All over the world, people can't
be with the people they love
because of stupid laws and
stupid life and stupid death.
And so I see where
my aggressive avoidance of you
might come across
as ever so slightly petulant.
But I still wish
that you would apologize.
I just need you to see
that what you did was wrong.
- Maggie, April kissed me.
- That wasn't... No. I get that.
And I am not mad about that!
I am mad because you didn't tell me!
I'm mad that you
thought I couldn't handle it!
Because my whole life,
people have been talking over me
and talking down to me
and assuming that just because
I'm a little awkward
and... and... goofy,
that I can't handle simple information!
That's not what I was doing...
Do you think I can't see
that what you and April had
was big and complicated?
I mean, do you think you need
- to protect me from that?
- I wasn't protecting you.
I was protecting April.
I was probably protecting
myself, honestly, from this.
- From...
- From all of this.
Maggie, you think of yourself
as this goofy underdog.
I mean, that's an old idea.
You're beautiful.
You're brilliant. You're powerful.
You have all the power here.
I'm over here sunk.
And you keep showing me
how capable you are
of just walking away.
You have all these reasons...
over and over...
reasons to resist us, reasons
why we can't be together.
First it's April,
and then it's what, our parents?
Then it's the fact
that we all work together.
Now it's this. It's just another thing,
one moment I had with April when
I was trying to be her friend.
And now you're convinced again
that you can just walk away
again and again.
This keeps hap...
I'm not.
I am not capable anymore.
Well, then maybe I am sorry.
Let yourself feel it.
Oh, love. I'm so sorry.
It's all right.
I'm all right.
Are you?
No.
None of us are all right.
Jackson...
Jackson ruined us.
Richard, we are ruined.
Because sometimes even
the most beautiful dreams...
disappear when the sun comes up