Where's your little girl?
I don't have one.
Where's your little boy?
I'm all by myself.
Are you sick?
No, no, no.
Then why are you here?
For a job.
You don't have a job?
Do you see those
pretty fish over there?
Did you lose your job?
My daddy lost his job.
Did you get a new job?
Yes, I did.
Giving big shots
to little girls.
Mommy!
Big shots.
There you go.
Mrs. Riblet...
weak and dizzy all over.
Be still, my heart.
Do you smell something?
Yeah. Uh-oh.
Ma'am. Ma'am...
Smoking's not
permitted in the hospital.
This is my glaucoma medicine.
My grandson grows it.
Oh, no. No, thanks.
Put that there.
You know, why don't
we put these away
so that we don't get busted.
Smells like primo stuff.
Yeah?
God, I miss the '60s.
New computer?
Yeah, CD-ROM.
I'm connecting us up by
modem to Mount Sinai.
Pooling our resources.
A couple more things to go over.
Dr. Benton goes
nuts if you're late
or you don't answer a
page on the first beep.
He's also got a
pretty bad temper.
I'll have to remember that.
And never, ever,
ever contradict him
in front of an Attending.
Who made brownies?
Wendy Goldman.
Hi.
Damn.
What's wrong?
I think I deleted Radiology.
Well, did you back it up?
Was I supposed to?
Try Alt Q. That sometimes works.
Hit-and-run pulling up,
10-year-old girl.
Where's Ross?
Job interview.
Hit and run, no witnesses.
Found unconscious,
responsive to pain.
BP 140/90, Resp low at 10.
Tubed her in the field.
Multiple facial lacs.
Possible fracture to
right lower extremity.
Get Radiology down here!
Trauma 2.
What's her name?
Lunch box says Molly Phillips.
Somebody call her parents.
All right, nice and
easy. Keep bagging her.
Here we go, people, on my count.
One, two, three.
All right, people,
let's learn something.
Carter.
How do you check
for a spinal cord injury
on an unconscious patient?
Look for absence of
deep tendon reflexes. Do it.
Poor little thing.
Harper, what film
do we want first?
Chest?
I'd do a cross-table lateral
to rule out a C-spine fracture.
Deep tendon reflexes
are present bilaterally.
Babinski is normal.
Harper, let's talk head trauma.
What study should we do?
Um...
Come on, Harper, pay attention.
Pressure's falling, 50/30.
What do you hear?
Uh... Um...
Diminished breath
sounds on the right?
Is that a question
or a statement?
I appreciate air movement
bilaterally. No pneumo.
No, Carter, that's
upper airway sounds.
I see a tracheal shift
to the left. So do I.
Tension pneumo.
Good call, Harper.
I'll teach you
how to do a needle
decompression.
Carter, run the
blood up to the lab.
Our new Urgent Care Facility
could use someone
with your experience.
Urgent Care's a smart move.
Most of our emergencies
are run-of-the-mill stuff,
sprained ankles, concussions.
Right up my alley.
But you'll spend most of
your time on ear infections
and well-baby checkups.
Hey...
Private practice is changing.
We're chasing PPO contracts
to compete against the HMOs,
but we won't sacrifice
our commitment to children.
That's what Pedes is all about.
We're a family here.
The kids you take care of today
will be the parents
of the kids you'll
see in 20 years.
We believe in continuity
and commitment.
So do I.
So do you want
to join our family?
Yes, I do.
How's she doing, Peter?
She's stable.
We're just going
over her films now.
Nasty break.
Anybody want to take a crack
at reading it?
Type three tibial
and fibular shaft fracture,
with complete displacement.
30% chance of
nonunion. Excellent.
Were knee and
ankle films ordered?
I don't believe so.
With tibial shaft fractures,
knee and ankle
films are necessary
to rule out injuries
from transmitted forces.
She's right as rain,
Peter. Order the films.
Come with me.
Got a couple
of interesting Colles fractures
you might want to look at.
Have you ever seen
a middle ear bone fracture?
Hey...
How'd the interview go?
Great.
Yeah, well, what did they say?
They said I was great.
Did you get the job?
90 grand a year and nobody dies.
Hallelujah. Auf wiedersehen.
I'll see you around.
You okay?
Sure.
This what you really want?
Do I have a choice?
Molly...
Molly, do you know
where you are?
You're in the hospital.
You were hit by a car.
We're taking very
good care of you.
You like my ring?
I know you're scared,
but I'll stay with you.
We called your parents.
They'll be here very soon.
Okay...
Let's extubate her.
Carter?
What's her tidal volume?
500 cc's, gases are good.
All right. Excellent.
Okay, we're going
to take this tube out.
Squeeze my hand.
Make sure the cuff is down
before you extubate her.
Good.
Now, what I want you to do
is pretend like you're
about to blow out
your birthday candles, so
take another deep breath,
and when I say go,
blow out real hard, okay?
Go.
Nice!
Good job.
Okay, let's send
her for a head CT.
I'll be in Exam 2.
What's your name?
What?
I'm Harper.
This is John.
Hi, Molly.
Other eye...
Your optic discs
are perfectly normal.
Are you sure that
you have glaucoma?
My medicine must be working.
How long have you
been lightheaded?
I wouldn't call it lightheaded.
It's more like I float.
How long have you been floating?
About two weeks.
And how long have you
been smoking marijuana?
About two weeks.
Having trouble?
I lost Radiology.
That's bad.
No kidding.
You have a file-recovery disk?
No.
Hmm. Let me have a go at it.
Hmm, there are a couple
of damaged clusters,
but everything looks intact.
Jerry, could you keep
Mrs. Riblet's valuables
while she gets a CT?
Help yourself, honey.
Sure thing.
Can't I stay and watch Geraldo?
And disappoint Radiology?
What are you doing here?
Mozart ring a bell?
Fantasy of the opera,
The Magic Flute?
No.
The charity ball?
You promised you'd go.
That's tonight?
Yeah, the tickets
cost my company
300 bucks.
So here's your costume...
Don Giovanni.
No, no, no, no, no, it's tights.
I'll just wear a tux.
No.
Pick me up at 7:00.
That'll give you
an hour to change.
Yeah, right.
What are you going as?
Carmen.
Don't be late.
Yeah.
I think you're
going to need this.
Hmm...
Mrs. Wilson is being admitted
with coffee-ground emesis.
Patient has been
admitted 14 times
in the last three years
with the same symptoms.
I'd like you to
order all her charts
and write a summary
of all her discharge notes
by tomorrow.
You got the computer fixed?
Yeah, Linda Farrell.
You smell like dope.
Where have you been?
With a patient.
Are we hooked up to Mount Sinai?
Yep, beating the
crap out of them.
What are you doing?
Playing "Doom II".
How long does it take to play?
Months.
I've done thoracotomies
that were less bloody.
He just doesn't understand
the educational value.
Die, bastard, die!
Come on!
How are you feeling?
Okay. I knew you'd come.
Oh, sweetie, sweetie,
of course we would.
I want to go home.
Your daughter will
be in the hospital
at least several days.
Excuse me.
Will both of you stay with me?
Of course, sweetheart.
And, Daddy?
You'll come back
to live with us.
Well...
We'll talk about that later.
How could you let her
ride her bike in the rain?
Don't blame me for this. Ahem.
Well, who else let her do it?
I do the best I can.
Maybe if you spent
more time with her
and less time at the office
with Sarah...
Um, the plastic surgeon
will be here soon,
if either of you
have a photo of Molly
it will help him repair
the laceration on her cheek.
Same picture.
Lake Geneva, it
was a great vacation.
I just need one.
Hey, pumpkin.
You handled that very well.
I had practice in my own family.
Aah...
♪ Yes, I was born
With a curious mind ♪
♪ I asked this man
Just what did he mean ♪
♪ When he moaned
If he'd be so kind ♪
♪ And he'd just go Um,
um, um, um, um, um ♪
♪ Um, um, um, um, um, um ♪
Help, help, please help!
Please, help! Help me.
What?
Please, please! My
brother needs help!
Why, why? What are you saying?
Hurry! Hurry, he's gonna drown!
Okay, all right,
hang on, hang on.
Hang on, hang on.
♪ Now that I've grown up... ♪♪
We were playing in the tunnel.
My brother got trapped.
Come on.
Here you go.
Give me your hand.
Hang on, we're coming in!
Are you hurt?
My leg's stuck.
All right, hang in
there. Don't panic.
We'll get you out of here.
What's your name?
Ben.
Hey, Ben. I'm Doug.
Let's see if I can...
move some of this
stuff out of the way here.
Ugh! Ah!
How the hell did you
get caught in here?
We were up at the canal,
and the water started
coming real fast.
Just get it out,
please! Just get it out!
Mom told us to stay
out of the tunnel!
It isn't my fault, Joey.
The water just pushed me!
All right, settle down, fellows!
It's nobody's fault.
Are you okay?
I'm cold, and my leg hurts.
All right, let me
take a look at it.
It's your lucky
day. I'm a doctor.
Let me check this.
Now, does this hurt?
Ow! Yeah, a lot.
All right, try not to move it.
Is it broken?
It might be.
Oh, no!
Don't cry, Ben.
Yeah, Ben, don't cry!
This is nothing compared
to what I've seen.
Get him out, okay?
Please, please,
get me out of here!
This is going to
be a piece of cake.
When I was a kid,
I used to build forts
in these tunnels.
You did?
Yeah.
Of course, you've
got to watch it,
because when it rains,
the water comes up really quick.
Joey, listen to me,
you go find a
phone, you call 911.
Okay.
You tell them to
send a rescue squad.
All right, Joey? Go.
Go! Go! Go!
Where's he going?
Well, this grate...
this grate is locked.
I'm going to need a little help.
You said you could do it.
What's that light down there?
I don't know.
All right, I'm going
to check it out.
Wait, don't leave!
It's okay, I'll be right back.
Wait, just don't.
Ben, listen to me. I'm going to
get you out of here. I promise.
But you gotta do
me a favor, okay?
You gotta trust me.
Can you do that?
Okay.
Okay? All right.
Now, here's the first
thing I need you to do.
You got to curl up
like this, into a ball.
Real tight like that. As
tight as you can, okay?
That's going to keep you warm.
Now, I'm going to
see what that light is,
and I'll be back as
fast as I can, all right?
Like a ball. Like that.
Now, sit tight.
All right!
Ben! Ben!
Ben, can you hear me?
Yeah!
All right! Are you okay?
Yeah. Did you find something?
Come on!
Aah!
Help! Is anybody there!
Ben! Ben!
It was locked!
I'm so cold.
That's all right, buddy.
Can you wiggle your toes?
No.
That's okay.
Let's see, how
about your fingers...
Can you move those for me?
There you go.
Can you feel me
squeezing your hand?
A little.
Good! All right, all right.
Now, all you gotta do is
just think warm thoughts.
You gotta think Hawaii,
and you gotta think...
the Sahara Desert.
You got to think about...
Hey! Hey! Hey!
Hey, come here! Come on.
Listen to me, you've
gotta stay awake!
You've gotta stay
awake for me, all right?
It's okay, all right?
I'm so tired.
I know that.
Why don't we just sing a song?
You know songs, don't you?
No.
Well... all right, yeah.
Yeah, how about, uh...
How about "Take Me
Out to the Ball Game?"
All right, all right...
♪ Take me out to the ball game ♪
♪ ...ball game ♪
♪ Take me out To the crowd ♪
♪ Buy me some peanuts
And Cracker Jack ♪
♪ I don't care If I
never get back ♪
All right, listen to me.
Come here. I got
to go get some help.
No, don't go! Just don't!
It's okay.
Please, don't!
You've gotta sing
as loud as you can,
so I can hear you, all right?
Say yes to me. Come here. Yeah.
All right. Here we go...
♪ For it's root, root
Root for the home team ♪
♪ If they don't
win It's a shame ♪
♪ For it's one, two
Three strikes, you're out ♪
♪ At the old ball game ♪
♪ Take me out To
the ball game... ♪
Okay...
Hey, hey! Hey!
Hey! Hey!
I couldn't find it!
Come here! What?
I couldn't find a phone!
I couldn't find a
phone anywhere!
I couldn't find a phone!
Come here! Come
on! All right, listen,
you go in there,
you find a phone,
and you call 911,
and you stay here till
help gets here, you got it?
You understand? Go! Let's go!
Hey, Ben!
Ben!
You all right?
Hey! Hey, buddy!
I... I sang it four times.
I knew you could do it.
Hey... Hey, hey, hey.
You stay awake.
You've gotta stay awake for me.
Come on, You've
gotta stay awake.
All right, this is
gonna do the trick.
We'll use this jack
to get your leg out.
So you a Cubs fan?
Yeah?
Who's your favorite player?
Who's your favorite player, Ben?
Hey! Hey! Come on!
Who's your favorite player?
M-Mark Grace.
Mark Grace?
What are you, nuts?
Shawn Dunston's the man.
The best shortstop in the game.
I'll tell you what I'll do.
Next season, I'll take
you to Wrigley Field.
Hey, come on! Stick with me.
Stay here!
I'll take you to
Wrigley Field...
Come on, damn it!
We'll get a couple of dogs...
and we'll compare Grace
to Dunston, all right?
There you go.
Hey, stay up. Stay awake.
Keep your head up!
Keep your head above water.
All right,
so you think
that you know a
lot about baseball,
do you?
All right, ask me a question.
Come on. Ask me a
tough one. Let's go.
Stay with me. You stay up.
You stay up!
The most home runs.
The most home runs?
Hank Aaron beats Babe Ruth.
That's nothing.
That's an easy one
Here we go. You ready?
Okay, we got it.
We got it! All right, come here.
You've gotta push your leg out.
You ready?
I... I can't feel it.
That's okay. I'm gonna help you.
All right, here we go.
Ow! Ow!
All right, ready?
It's okay. Come here, come here.
All right, listen.
Give me your hands.
You gotta hold on right here.
Hold on with both hands.
You hold on,
and you gotta keep your
head up above water.
You understand me? Yes?
I can't. I can't
hold... Yes, you can!
I can't hold it...
I can't...
I'll knock out these hinges.
No, I...
I can't!
Yes, you can!
I can't! Yes!
I can't! I...
Yes, you can!
Damn it, you hold on, damn it!
You hold on!
You hold on! You understand me?
Hold on! Here we go!
We're almost there!
No, I can't...
No! Ben! No! Ben!
Aah!
Ben!
You're not dying on me, Ben!
Not now!
Hey! I shot the Hell
Knight with my plasma rifle,
but he nailed me
with a rocket launcher.
Watch out for the fireballs.
Excuse me, Dr. Benton?
Yeah.
I sorted through the charts
and compiled all the
discharge summaries.
I think your patient has
a paraesophageal hernia.
If you need anything else,
I'll be in the Suture Room.
Where are we going?
We're moving you
to a nicer room.
My lunch box.
There you go.
Don't you be scared, okay?
I'll stay with you
till we take you upstairs.
I made it in school.
It's beautiful.
It's for... you.
Thank you.
Ah! Nice.
Yeah.
Hi, sweetie.
Plastic surgery called.
They'll be down
in a few minutes.
Oh, we won't be needing
your surgeon after all.
Excuse me? My plastic
surgeon's on his way.
Who? Fred.
Fred Mendoza?
He'll cost a fortune.
It's only your daughter's face.
Maybe we could...
I hate him.
That's why you called him.
He's the best in Chicago.
For lopsided breasts.
Touchy subject.
My God!
Is he all right?
Mouth-to-mouth's not working!
His airway's blocked!
Paramedics should
be here any minute.
That Medevac
copter will take us.
That's a TV news chopper.
Is my brother going to die?
No, he's not!
No, he is not!
Come on.
What are you doing?
I'm a doctor. I need
to clear an airway.
You got a pen?
What?
A pen? Do you have a pen on you?
All right...
All right, here we go.
Come on.
All right.
Come on!
Breathe, damn it!
All right, we got him.
Come here. Help me up.
Get him up, get him up.
I got it.
I got him.
What do you got?
I got a 12-year-old
trapped in a culvert.
Possible fracture to
the left lower extremity.
So don't jostle him!
He's hypothermic. Could
cause an arrhythmia.
I'm Dr. Ross from County ER!
I need a number six ET Tube.
There we go.
I need a portable
O-2 and an ambu-bag!
You got it!
We picked up the paramedic call.
What happened?
He saved my
brother. He's a doctor.
Okay, let's roll on this.
We're at the scene
of an incredible rescue
in Grant Park.
It appears that a doctor
has saved a little
boy from drowning.
All right, we got
it, doc! Call Mercy.
Wait! Wait! Wait! Mercy's
not a Level 1 trauma center.
It's the nearest
treatment facility.
This boy needs a
surgeon. Probably an ICU.
We gotta follow
base station protocol...
What's your transport time?
In this weather,
maybe 12 minutes.
Where's your pilot?
Hey, Jimmy! Over here!
Sorry, doc. We gotta move!
Wait, wait, wait, wait!
We're losing time!
What's your flying
time to County ER?
15 minutes.
Can you take us?
The chopper's not equipped
for medical transport.
This boy is hypothermic.
He needs special care.
Mercy's closer.
Yeah, by three minutes,
and then he dies
because there's no ICU.
Or else he dies in
a news chopper...
Look, I don't have
time to argue with you.
I will take full
responsibility for this!
This boy is gonna die!
Let's do it. It's a great story!
Let's go!
What are you doing?
I need supplies.
I need a portable defibrillator.
I got a spare!
You're taking a
hell of a chance.
Damn right. Let's go.
Go!
Go! Go! Go!
All right, on my
count. Here we go...
One, two, three!
All the way in.
Not enough room for cameras.
Here, take that.
There's no room in here!
Give me the camera!
All set!
Get a minicam van
and meet me at County!
Here! Here!
Close the door!
Let's go, let's go!
Patch your headsets
back to the station.
How's he doing?
He's okay.
You filming this?
We're live from Chopper Five
with Dr...
What's your name, doctor?
Doug Ross.
Dr. Doug Ross
from County General.
Just minutes ago,
Dr. Ross rescued a
boy from a storm drain.
I can see
you're attaching some electrodes
to the boy's chest.
What are those for, doctor?
What are those for, Dr. Ross?
Patch me through to County.
Dr. Ross has just asked me
to patch him through
to County General.
You need a red key.
Look out for the lost soul.
Use the rocket launcher.
Look, Mount Sinai's shooting us.
Cheaters! Get them! Get them!
You do it.
I need a bulletproof vest.
Blast him with a BFG 9000.
Oh, look, his guts
are all over the place.
Quiet, you guys.
This is County
General. Go ahead.
This is Chopper Five
from Channel Five news.
We've got a Dr. Ross up here
flying in a hypothermic kid.
Doug Ross?
That is correct.
Hold on, Chopper Five.
Mark, Doug is on a news chopper
bringing in a hypothermic kid.
What?
It's on the MICN.
What's he doing
on a news chopper?
Look. There's Dr. Ross.
Turn up the volume.
Where's the remote?
Doug, do you read me?
Mark, is that you?
What are you doing?
I've got a 12-year-old
with hypothermia.
I gotta warm him up fast.
I'm doing the best I can.
What's our ETA?
About three minutes.
We're seeing a rescue in action.
Live from Chopper Five.
Stay with us as
Dr. Doug Ross struggles
to save the life of this child.
And what are you doing?
How's he doing?
How's he doing, doctor?
Malik, we need
heated saline IVs.
Warm up half a
dozen to 106 degrees.
Wendy, get heated
blankets and a mattress.
Jerry, call Benton.
Tell him we may
need him down here.
Heated peritoneal lavage?
Yeah, that's right.
Let's go. Now!
Come on, let's go!
Is there anything you can
do to warm him up now?
How's he doing, doctor?
What's wrong? Why is
the monitor doing that?
He's having runs of
abnormal heartbeats.
And what are you doing?
Trying to stabilize his rhythm.
Come on.
He's in V-fib!
Come on!
What are those
paddles for, Dr. Ross?
To stabilize his beat.
They didn't charge
the batteries! God!
Oh, my God.
I need your help.
Turn the camera off.
Turn off the camera!
We've momentarily lost
contact with Chopper Five.
This is Warner Saunders
bringing you rescue in action...
All right, squeeze the
bag when I count to five.
Here we go... one, two, three,
four, five.
Like this? Yeah, there you go.
One, two, three,
four, five. Yeah.
One, two... We're
going to lose this.
Oh, God!
Three, four, five.
Mark?
Mark, where are you?
Where the hell's County?
You told me to turn it off.
Get County on the line.
Tell them we're gonna need
a crash cart on the roof now!
You got it.
Come on! How far out are we?
I can see it.
One, two, three...
Keep bagging him.
Squeeze it like that! Like that!
Keep bagging him!
For you, Dr. Greene.
It's Morgenstern.
Hey...
Yeah, I... I did think
it was kind of risky.
No, we're watching Channel Five.
Oh, they're trashing
us on Channel Eight.
Listen, you do not
need to come in, okay?
Yeah, everything
is under control.
We have an unconfirmed report
that resuscitation
efforts may have failed.
It's always a danger
up there in that copter
in the Windy City,
and bouncing around
a child with hypothermia
can cause a fatal
cardiac arrhythmia...
She's right outside?
Jerry, turn that off.
Ugh! TV doctors.
Jerry, get security
to escort Dr. Mahoney
to a less conspicuous place.
Let's get the life
pack and drug box.
Any sixes?
Nope. Go fish.
How are you doing?
My stomach hurts a little bit.
Yeah?
Ow.
Let's get a CT of her
abdomen along with her head.
Probably just a bruise
from the accident.
Where are her parents?
They're in the coffee shop.
I get next game, okay?
Coming through!
Coming through.
Doctor, is he dead?
Please, get out of the way.
Dr. Greene, can you
confirm or deny this report?
Malik, can you get security
to get these people
into the press room?
Do you question
Dr. Ross' decision
to fly the child here?
Not for a second.
Come on, move now.
Let's go.
Hurry!
We're ready.
Move it! He's hypoxic.
All right, let's move!
Clear the blades,
and we'll shock him.
Let's go!
Where's the crash cart!
Go!
All right, the paddles!
Chopper Five has just landed
on the roof of County General.
Doctors are taking out paddles.
Charging! 100.
Clear!
Several doctors are
trying desperately
to revive Ben Larkin.
150! Clear!
So far their
efforts are failing.
0.4 epi.
Charging 200.
Will he make it?
Shock him again! Let's go!
One more time.
All right. Charging 200!
Clear.
All right, let's get him inside.
We'll try it again.
Are we going to lose him?
We got warming
blankets, we're all set.
Hurry! Hurry!
Damn...
Go!
Shock him again,
and then we'll try
rapid rewarming.
Hurry up!
Get that gurney out of there!
That little girl?
Molly? She crashed in the CT.
Pressure dropped,
and now she's unconscious.
Said her stomach hurt.
Could have blown
a mesenteric clot.
Harper, get four units O-neg.
Stay with us, Ben.
Paddles. Paddles!
Charging 200.
Clear.
Charging 300.
I got a faint pulse.
Pulse ox is 80.
He's hypoxic.
Let's change him
over to a Shiley.
Dr. Greene, the
press is going berserk.
They want a statement.
Yeah, well, we're a
little busy right now.
Tell them that he's
holding his own.
Right.
Let's get a CBC, lytes,
blood gas and coags.
What's his core temp?
82 degrees.
That's too low.
Put him on heated,
humidified O-2.
Heated saline.
Let's start him on lidocaine,
0.8 mgs per minute.
Hope he doesn't
go back into V-fib.
Doug, you're a mess. Go
change into some scrubs.
You're freezing, Doug. Go
get some coffee and warm up.
Hey, I need you here. Go change.
I should never have put
him on that damn chopper.
Got it, Carter?
I'm almost in.
Got the O-neg.
Hang it.
Oh, my God! What happened?
Get her out of here.
Somebody call my husband!
We think Molly has
internal bleeding
from the accident.
Whoa!
Molly!
Somebody get
her out of here now!
Molly, no! Molly, no, please!
All right, give me some suction.
My God, no!
All right, number
five ET Tube, please.
It's in.
Bag her.
Give her 0.3 of epi
and 0.6 of atropine now.
Come on, Molly.
Come on.
Epi's in.
Dr. Ross!
Hey, Joey.
He saved Ben.
We're his parents. How is he?
It's too soon to tell.
The news said his heart stopped.
It's going now. How's he doing?
Coags look good.
Lytes are normal.
Blood pH is 7.37.
Thank God for small miracles.
How's the patient?
He hasn't gone into DIC.
That's a good sign.
There are reporters crawling
all over this place like ants.
What's his temp,
Wendy? 85 degrees.
Not warming up fast enough.
Heated pleural lavage?
We could try, but I don't
think his heart would take it.
We could bypass it and
warm his blood directly.
That'd be the fastest
way. What do you think?
You're the Attending.
Wendy, call Cardiac Surgery,
tell them to send
down a perfusionist
with a bypass pump
and a heating unit.
Lily, go get Benton.
Peter, Mark needs
you for bypass access.
Gotta stop the bleeding
first. Thoracotomy tray now!
We have to go to
the waiting room.
No, no, I wanna stay.
No. We have to go.
Come on. Come on.
10 blade.
Retractor.
Carter, start compressions
while I cross-clamp the aorta.
Uh, yeah, I got it. I got it.
She's clamped.
What happened?
Abdominal bleed. She coded.
Start an atrial line.
Carol, I need two
15 French cannulas
and space...
Mark, little girl's coding in 2.
Molly Phillips. Hit and run.
Recent onset abdominal pain.
Her pressure crashed,
and she went into asystole.
We've infused
four units of O-neg,
given her two rounds of epi,
and then cross-clamped her.
Mesenteric rupture?
Probably.
There's nothing you
could have done about it.
Peter, I'll take over.
Hypothermic kid in Trauma 1.
Needs femoral
lines for a bypass.
Infuse another unit.
Peter, it's about damn time.
Cut down!
We're trying internal paddles.
Charge to 10.
Charging.
Clear.
Charge 20.
Charging.
Clear.
20 again.
Charging.
Clear.
As I remove the obturator,
be ready to hook up the
cannula to the bypass.
What's his
temperature? 86 degrees.
He's going into
V-tach. Rate's 180.
Give me 100 of procainamide.
Come on, Ben, you can make it.
Hold on, buddy.
Hold on.
Time of death, 21:25.
I'll go talk to her folks.
Doug?
Doug, your friend's awake.
Hey...
You're in a hospital.
Don't try and talk.
Doug...
You made it.
Pretty nasty cut.
Yeah.
Could probably
use a few stitches.
We can do that
in a little while.
What's his temperature?
93. Vitals stable.
93. Way to go.
You made it.
How about that, kiddo?
Excuse me.
Are you the parents
of the little boy in the tunnel?
How does it feel
to know that Mercy Hospital
was clearly three minutes closer...
Excuse me. Excuse me.
I think you'd better leave.
I'm sorry.
I'm talking with these people.
No, you're not.
Hey. How are you feeling?
You made it.
Just like you promised.
Thank you.
It's all right.
Hey, you remember Wrigley Field.
We got a date.
Sit down. Let me finish.
That one was crooked.
Yeah? Well, next time,
you can do it yourself.
Hey, Mark, thanks.
For what?
You did all the hard work.
I don't think
I could have gone
up in that helicopter.
I just got lucky.
No.
You know about kids.
As good as new.
Where are you going?
Check for reporters.
All clear.
Get some sleep.
My car's in Grant
Park with a flat.
We'll pick it up tomorrow.
I'll grab you a cab.
Come on.
I guess I missed the opera.
Linda will understand.
Here, take my coat.
Thanks.
Grab a bite?
Yeah.
There he is!
Dr. Ross... Dr. Ross!
Over here, Dr. Ross? Over here.
Can we have a statement,
please, Dr. Ross?
Can you tell us
how you're feeling right now?
how long the child will
be here in the hospital?
Dr. Ross, can you
give us a statement?
Can you tell us
how does it feel to
be a hero, Dr. Ross?
Just a moment of your time...