Hey, Natalie.
I was hoping
I could catch you
before my shift started.
Well, you caught me.
So, uh, you want to do
something later?
Maybe grab some dinner?
I was up all night
prepping for the M&M today.
By the time my shift's over,
I'm gonna be running on fumes.
We can keep it mellow.
Make some spaghetti,
watch a movie.
Uh, maybe.
We'll see.
Okay, everyone, heads up!
CPD! Dr. Choi?
Auto versus ped.
Officer Kate Windham found
unresponsive in her driveway.
Who?
Officer Kate Windham.
Down for
an unknown period.
Tubed in the field.
Mags?
Baghdad.
She was hit in
her own driveway?
Freak accident.
Parking brake gave out.
Her SUV rolled into her.
BP 111 over 77,
heart rate 136.
Dropped to 32,
and then shot back up.
Cushing's response.
Brainstem herniation?
Let's not go there yet.
Transfer on my count.
Ready? One, two, three.
Any sedation or
paralytics in the field?
No.
Pupils are fixed
and dilated.
Not initiating a breath.
Resume bagging.
No corneal reflex.
What's with Maggie?
Officer Windham
arrested Maggie last year.
Lieutenant Windham,
as I explained,
your wife's CT showed
massive bleeding.
The tests confirm
she's not responsive
to stimuli,
and her blood flow
study indicates that
the pressure in her brain
is greater than
her blood pressure.
She has no blood flow
to her brain.
Unfortunately,
all of these things tell us
that your wife is brain dead.
I'm very sorry.
You're telling me
she's dead?
My wife's dead.
We're right here
for you, Darryl.
She was just walking
to the mailbox.
Mmm-hmm.
I don't understand.
I don't get it.
She was...
She was walking
to the mailbox.
I know this must be
a terrible shock for you.
Lieutenant,
I did see on her records,
your wife is
a registered organ donor.
Yeah.
Kate was all about
helping others.
Our charge nurse will
coordinate the donations.
Mmm.
Lieutenant Windham,
this is Maggie Lockwood.
You're the nurse,
that's the nurse...
That's, uh...
You're the nurse
from last year.
Okay. We'll give you
some time, Lieutenant.
Again, I'm very sorry.
I am gonna be right back.
Dr. Choi, can I talk
to you for a minute?
Given the history
between your nurse
and Officer Windham,
we have a problem.
It's hard enough
on the Lieutenant.
He doesn't need this.
Maggie's a pro.
She'll do her job.
Doctor, if you're
not gonna handle this,
I'm gonna go
over your head.
I understand
you're taking care
of your own,
but I need to do
the same.
I'll talk with
Ms. Goodwin.
Hey. So, why'd Maggie
get arrested? What happened?
The charge was
interfering with
a police investigation.
But Maggie was
protecting a patient.
In my opinion,
Officer Windham
overreacted.
Hmm.
Dr. Manning, you set
for the Morbidity and
Mortality Conference?
I am, Doc...
Good. See you there.
Remember, M&M is non-punitive.
It's a learning experience.
Okay.
Dr. Halstead?
Yes?
I expect to see you
there too.
As her attending physician,
you are ultimately responsible
for Dr. Manning's actions.
Right.
I am so sorry to put you
in this position.
Oh, I'm not concerned.
You did everything right.
Except my patient died.
Natalie, hey,
you're being too
hard on yourself.
You know, sometimes
things just don't break
the way we want them too.
If you need backup,
I'm available.
Thanks, um,
but I've got it covered.
Med students
don't present, Clarke.
Doctors only.
I knew it.
Sawfly larva.
Hmm?
I ate half of that apple
before I saw it
crawling out of the core.
That's nice.
Nice?
Sarah, what is
the matter with you?
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
I didn't get any sleep
last night.
This neurology rotation
I'm doing,
Dr. Abrams had me pull
a second shift.
Tell Abrams that residents
aren't supposed to work more
than a 12-hour shift.
Well, yeah,
you tell him. I gotta go.
Here.
I have something.
What is that?
Espresso beans.
Robusta from Brazil.
Highest concentration
of caffeine.
Take five every hour.
Chew thoroughly.
Really?
Yeah.
Thanks.
Hey.
Abnormal heart tones?
No. Heart rate is 150.
Strong and steady.
How do
the measurements look?
Give me a second.
Crown-to-chin
length measurement
is 30.9 millimeters.
Well within
the normal parameters.
So, the TB meds...
Don't seem to be
causing any problems.
That's great news.
You were right.
I'll see you
back downstairs.
No. The heart recipient
has already been notified.
I need an echo,
bronchoscopy, liver biopsy,
standard chest X-ray,
and chest CT.
Send the results to me,
and I'll forward it
to the transplant team.
Yep. Thank you.
Maggie, I heard about
Officer Windham's accident.
Yeah.
I think it's best
we let April be
the liaison on this one.
No worries. I'm already
into it with the labs.
Even so, I know what
a hard time you had
with the arrest.
Why stir up all
those feelings?
I don't need coddling.
I can do my job.
Maggie, we need to consider
the patient's family as well.
I think it's better
for all concerned that
we get in front of this.
It's too loaded.
You're taking me off?
Sharon, come on.
Let April handle it.
Mr. Koslow,
I'm Dr. Halstead.
You were brought
in unconscious.
What happened?
Uh, I'm laying here
practically naked, Doc.
You could call me Felix.
Uh...
Last thing I remember,
I was coming back from a run
feeling a little lightheaded.
Well, according to
the paramedics, you were
passed out in the bathroom.
Yeah. But I'm fine.
And I can't stay here.
I'm a jockey.
Just been busting my ass
getting ready for a race
at Santa Anita tomorrow,
so I must have
just overdone it.
Ever happen before?
Never.
I really don't
need to be here.
Tell me if this hurts.
Ow! Ow! Ah.
Just kidding.
When I was a kid, my dad
used to take me down to
the racetracks at Hawthorne.
The man never
picked a winner.
Most kids dream about playing
in the World Series.
For me, it's all about
the Kentucky Derby.
Took years of riding
at BS tracks to get over
to Churchill Downs.
Been working
my way up there,
but, you know, in the winter
the track closes down,
so I've been picking up
mounts on the West...
West Coast.
Uh-huh.
Open wide for me.
Very possible this is just
a bout of overtraining.
You say
you're feeling fine.
You sure?
Hmm. A little weak,
but nothing
that's gonna stop me.
I'm on
a great horse tomorrow.
Well, let's make sure
you're fit to mount up.
I'm ordering
an EKG and an echo
to check your heart.
I'm still waiting
on those lab results,
so for now, sit tight.
Dr. Manning!
Brett, talk to me.
Car crash.
44-year-old female.
GCS 14.
Large laceration
to the head.
Pale and sweaty.
LVAD keeps alarming.
Page Dr. Rhodes
and let him know we got
an LVAD down here.
Bria, honey?
Copy.
You go to Trauma 1,
Dr. Manning.
Got it.
Court.
17-year-old female.
GCS 15.
No LOC. Vitals are stable.
Hands and feet moving.
Complaining of
neck pain.
Bria!
Mom?
Dr. Choi,
you're going to Trauma Two.
Copy.
Bria! Baby!
Mom!
Here we go.
On my count.
One, two, three.
Okay, let's transfer
on my count. Ready?
One, two, three.
Where's my mom?
Easy, easy.
Eyes on me.
She is right next door.
You're gonna see
her real soon, okay?
She has a bad heart.
They called.
We were coming in
for a transplant.
Okay. Heart surgeon's
on his way down.
Can you tell us
what hurts?
My neck. It snapped back
after the airbag hit me.
I got a call saying
a heart's available,
said to get here.
Guy ran a red light.
Where's my daughter?
She is in good hands.
Right now we need
to worry about you, okay?
Let's get her
hooked up
to the monitor
and rapidly transfuse
two packed red blood
cells and two plasma.
Then get X-rays
of her chest
and pelvis, okay?
Okay.
All right, I'm gonna
take this off now, okay?
I tried to swerve,
but I was going too fast.
Ow! It really hurts!
We're gonna give you
something for the pain.
Then we need
to make sure you don't
have any fractures, okay?
Let's get a CT of her
neck and thoracic spine
and 0.2 milligrams
of hydromorphone.
Got it.
All right, let's give her
50 mics fentanyl IV push.
No. No.
I'm a recovering alcoholic.
Meghan?
Dr. Rhodes.
I made it.
I'm ready for the transplant.
Okay, you just try
to stay calm, okay?
We're gonna
figure this out.
She's having suction events.
She's still hypovolemic.
Let's up her volume.
Okay.
I need to close up
this head wound.
Can you check her LVAD?
Yeah. You got it.
Skin stapler?
Right away.
Here you go.
Argh!
Where's Bria?
Where's my baby?
We're gonna take care
of her, all right?
Let's get some
pressure on this.
Yes, Doctor.
I'm... I'm okay.
I got a hard head.
You just relax.
What happened?
Auto accident.
How bad is it?
We've got a donor
heart in Baghdad.
She needs to be able
to tolerate the surgery.
I'm hoping
the head wound is
just superficial.
We won't know anything
until she gets a CT.
We're headed up there now.
All right, well, keep
your fingers crossed.
She's got better odds
of hitting the lottery
than she does
of matching to another
heart before it's too late.
Yeah.
Lieutenant Windham?
Hi. I'm April.
I'm very sorry
for your loss.
Yep.
I'll be handling
your wife's care.
I thought it was the, uh...
It was the other nurse.
I'm coordinating with
the transplant teams today.
Your wife's organs
are in the process
of being matched
to people in need.
Once that's complete,
we'll go ahead
and schedule surgery.
You're free to stay with her
throughout the process.
And tell me, how many
people will she save?
That depends
on the organ
evaluation results,
but she could
potentially save
seven, eight lives.
We've already found
a match for her heart.
That's Kate.
Always going
above and beyond.
I'm here for you
every step of the way.
Please don't hesitate
to reach out
should you have
any questions
or need anything.
Thank you.
Hey. When you call the lab,
make sure you deal with Sue.
She gets the blood
and tissue samples
analyzed faster
than anybody else.
All right.
And once they match
the other organs,
make sure that you...
Maggie, I know
how to do this.
I'm sorry if you feel
like I'm stepping
on your toes.
You're not stepping
on my toes. It's just...
It's my responsibility.
Meghan, we got
your test results.
Your CT scan looks fine.
Then I'm okay to have
the surgery, right?
Unfortunately,
there's another problem.
We do a tox screen
as part of your
pre-op workup.
Your blood alcohol
content came back 0.06.
No. It can't...
That's a mistake.
I... I told her not to,
but that doctor
must have given me
pain medication.
Pain medication
would have no effect on
the blood alcohol levels.
Check it again.
I'm sorry.
I screwed up.
Can you explain
your actions?
Margaret Brazetti.
She's my age. Three kids.
Been on the transplant list
two years.
Met in a support group.
Was always positive.
Always laughing.
And she got me through
some really hard days.
She died this morning.
I slipped.
Two shots.
First time
in three years.
Then I got the call
about the heart.
I asked Bria to take me.
If I hadn't asked her,
she wouldn't be hurt.
The asking wasn't
the problem.
The drinking was.
Does this mean
I don't get the heart?
That's the committee's
decision.
You should try
and get some rest.
Rest?
Is Bria, um,
back from her CT?
We'll have somebody check.
As I recall,
you vouched for her.
I did.
Quite an
unfortunate choice.
All the other
matches are in?
Yeah. Got teams
flying in from Wisconsin,
St. Louis, and Des Moines.
April, is it possible
for some of us
to be in the OR
with Darryl during
the procedure?
He could use
the support.
I will have to talk
to the surgical charge nurse,
but I'm sure we can
work something out.
Thanks.
Excuse me.
Um...
I was the one who
asked for someone else
to take charge of this.
It really
wasn't personal.
I was just thinking
of the Lieutenant.
You understand?
No.
Everything's good.
Uh, flying out at 9:00.
Yeah. I'll see you
first thing for
the morning workout.
Yeah.
Got your labs back
and the results
of your echo.
Yeah. I'm sure nothing's
wrong with me that these
bags of fluid haven't fixed.
Well, you're dehydrated.
It will help with that.
Felix, your creatinine
and sodium are high,
and your potassium is low,
and I noticed enamel erosion
around some of your teeth.
Now, all these are
indicators of bulimia.
Bulimia is
something girls get.
Well, actually, a third
of those suffering from
bulimia are men.
Eating disorders are
not specific to women,
and you should know
they're treatable.
I don't have
an eating disorder.
I've got a job that
requires me to make weight
or I don't get to ride.
All jockeys flip.
Flip?
Yeah. Stick our fingers
down our throat.
If that ain't enough,
some guys sit in
the hot box and sweat it out.
Some down laxatives.
I take diuretics.
Because of the purging
and diuretics,
you're considerably
underweight,
which has caused
a mitral valve prolapse.
Meaning the valve
in your heart
has become floppy.
And it's treatable.
I'd like to put a tube
through your nose
into your stomach
to feed you calories.
Now, over time,
this may reverse the MVP
and fatten up your heart.
What happens if I don't?
Is it gonna kill me?
With your lifestyle,
you are putting yourself
at a much greater
risk of infection,
cardiac arrhythmia,
or even heart failure.
I've been riding
Executive Chef
for a year.
That's four wins
and a place.
I am one ride away
from that derby mount.
Felix...
No, I'm finishing
this fluid
and I'm getting
the hell out of here.
We have a pre-op consult
upstairs in six minutes.
Dr. Reese, Dr. Abrams.
How's it going?
I need to break her of
all your bad habits.
I've found my most
successful residents
happily volunteer
to work well past
the standard 80-hour week.
Dr. Charles.
Meghan Scott,
my transplant patient
you evaluated.
Yeah.
Turns out that
you were right about her.
She fell off the wagon.
Really?
I'm very sorry
to hear that.
The way I put you on the spot
about your decision,
I owe you an apology.
No, you don't.
I appreciate
the gesture,
but my evaluation...
I vetted her.
It was my call.
I should, um...
I should probably
check in with her.
The, uh, Transplant
Committee's gonna want
another assessment.
If you'll excuse me,
I've got to get to the M&M.
Yes. Thank you
for telling me.
Of course.
The patient became unstable
due to an unrecognized
pericardial effusion,
which was stabilized
by emergent
pericardiocentesis.
You presented the images
of the MRCP demonstrating
cholelithiasis
to support your diagnosis
of pancreatitis
due to choledocholithiasis,
but you aren't showing us
any images of the lung
bases or heart.
Those images
were not obtained.
Why not?
The patient's movement
resulted
in unreadable images.
Why didn't you
repeat the scan?
The study captured
adequate detail within
the area of interest.
So, had you been
more vigilant
at this juncture,
perhaps you would have
identified this patient's
pericardial effusion
and avoided his subsequent
cardiovascular collapse.
In hindsight, yes.
At the time, I believed
I had what I needed.
Let's move on.
You mentioned placing
the patient on BiPAP,
which exacerbated
cardiac tamponade.
How did you respond?
How are you feeling?
Like I screwed up
two lives.
Let's get you
two together.
I'll have
this dividing wall
opened up.
How is she?
Is her neck okay?
Good news is there
are no fractures.
Okay. What's the bad?
It's not necessarily bad.
It might be minor,
but Bria's CT showed
a mass in her upper
thoracic spine,
unrelated to
the accident.
Oh, God.
A mass means tumor, right?
It could be
a number of things.
My poor baby.
She's had some back pain
in the last few months.
She tried
to convince me
it was nothing.
I should've
brought her in.
This is my fault.
Meghan, until
we do an MRI
to get a better look
at what
we're dealing with,
the best thing
you could do is
try to stay calm.
Son of a bitch!
I need this
damn thing out!
Mr. Koslow, please,
you need to calm down.
And you need to take
this out of my arm.
I'm two pounds over.
Hey, hey, hey.
It's just water weight.
That IV is the only reason
you're feeling stronger.
You need to leave it in.
You know, screw this.
You're not gonna do it,
I'll pull it out myself.
No, no, no.
Please don't do that.
Okay. Fine. That's what
you want, let's get you
back to your room...
Hell, no!
You're gonna try to
give me something.
I'm done with this crap!
No! Mister...
Get off of...
Hey.
Now you're bleeding.
I'm fine.
Okay. This is why
you need to be treated.
I did that, and now
I'm too fat to ride.
You cannot take
diuretics again.
You are playing
Russian roulette.
There are only so many times
you can pull that trigger.
Let me go, now!
Mom, I'm fine!
Oh, it's just a blanket.
I don't need it.
Everything okay?
Oh, she just
seemed cold.
And you shouldn't be up.
Can I help you
back into bed?
Dr. Reese?
I'm doing a rotation
in neurocritical care.
The mass we found
is not a tumor.
Oh, thank God.
It's a spinal AVM,
which is
an abnormal tangle
of blood vessels.
Is it serious?
Bria's probably had it
since she was born.
Quite often, we don't
find it until it starts
causing problems.
What kind of problems?
Down the line, uh,
numbness, hemorrhage,
even paralysis.
So, the back pain
was a sign.
We could've caught
this months ago.
Let's focus on the fact
that we caught it now.
It can be treated
surgically.
Dr. Reese will do
a neurosurgery consult
with you,
and then our head
of neurosurgery,
Dr. Abrams,
will come down
and go over the details.
I'm so sorry, Bria.
Stop it.
It's not your fault.
No. I wasn't thinking
about you.
I was only thinking
about myself.
Having an AVM
is unfortunate,
but finding it now,
as early as we have,
is the best we could ask for.
Dr. Manning then
paged me to perform
a pericardiocentesis.
Did you recommend sending
the fluid for analysis
and obtaining a CT chest,
abdomen, and pelvis?
I did.
The CT showed a large mass
in the right middle lobe
with bulky hilar
and mediastinal
lymphadenopathy.
And that's when
Dr. Manning called
for an oncology consult?
Yes. And their recommendation
was chemotherapy.
Dr. Rhodes?
I recommended
an alternative
course of therapy.
Since the primary
mass was resectable,
I thought it best
to move forward with
surgery without delay.
And Dr. Manning disagreed?
I felt the radiation
would give the pancreatitis
time to cool down.
What was his
Ranson's score?
It was...
What difference
does that make?
There's no reliable way
to predict
tumor lysis syndrome.
Dr. Manning,
if your white knight
plans on continuing
his medical education
at this hospital,
I recommend that you
advise him to remove
himself from my presence.
Let's take
a five-minute break.
How dare you?
I know.
I shouldn't have said...
I am not a damsel in
distress, and I do not
need you to defend me.
I was only trying to help.
You humiliated me in there.
Natalie, I'm sorry.
If he gets on that horse,
he's not only a danger
to himself,
but every other jockey
in the race.
I don't disagree.
Can we keep him
on a psych hold?
No, we can't. I mean,
from everything you told me,
his stated intention
is to win the race.
He didn't say anything
about doing intentional harm.
And if we do hold him,
he'd probably
sue the hospital
and you personally.
If you can't
convince him
to stay,
get him to sign
that he's leaving
against medical advice.
Oh, he's already asked
for the paperwork.
Then it's settled.
Damn it!
That ultrasound
was a huge relief.
Yeah.
So, now that we know
everything's okay,
there's something
I'm hoping
you'll consider.
For the baby's sake.
Maybe it would be good
if you stopped working
for a while.
Just until the kid is born.
I know how you feel
about your job.
I'm not asking you
to give that up.
But a few months could help
to take away some stress.
If it was up to you,
there wouldn't even
be a baby.
April, I told you
I'm sorry.
The only reason I wanted
to consider terminating
was I thought
the baby would have
no quality of life.
I didn't want
to put you...
Us through that.
My job's not endangering
the pregnancy.
The second I feel like work
is negatively affecting me,
I'll stop.
For now, I'm fine.
We are fine.
So, Dr. Charles,
you assessed
Meghan Scott today.
Yes, I did...
I don't understand
why we're debating this.
An alcoholic must be
sober for 18 months
before being eligible
for transplant.
Those are the rules.
This patient
disqualified herself.
Dr. Latham,
right now in the hospital,
we have an excellent match
for a heart,
an organ which you know
has a limited window
of viability.
We may have to think
beyond the rules.
What stops her from drinking
the next time she gets upset?
Ironically,
relapse can be a very
important part of recovery.
Happens to most addicts
at some point
and it's very often
the utter misery
of falling off the wagon
that motivates
those that suffer
to finally get serious
about staying sober.
And you believe this is
the case for Ms. Scott?
I also think
it's been a very real
wake-up call for her.
Until the accident,
Bria was performing
the caretaker role,
but now Meghan realizes
the importance of stepping up
and taking responsibility,
not just for herself
but also for her daughter.
So, bottom line,
are you saying the committee
should give Ms. Scott
the currently
available heart?
As a human being,
I would love
to root for Meghan.
As a doctor,
I'm just more
aware than ever
of the power that
this disease can have
over somebody.
Dr. Rhodes?
Uh, I was confident
when I pushed for Meghan
to be put on the list.
Regretfully,
I am less confident now.
If there are
no more questions,
I move the committee
take a vote.
All those in favor
of Meghan Scott
receiving the heart,
signify with a "yea."
Yea.
All those against,
signify with a "nay."
Nay.
The nays have it.
We'll look for
another recipient.
You remain conflicted
about Meghan Scott
despite her breaking
the clearly defined rules
for being
a transplant candidate.
Yes.
I... I remain conflicted.
I've worked with
a lot of alcoholics,
and I know real regret
when I see it.
Real regret?
Can you elaborate?
What exactly did
you see in Ms. Scott?
Well, I saw real sadness.
You know, there were tears
rolling down her face,
and, um, her jaw
was clenched, you know,
and her body sort of drooped
with what looked like shame.
That's interesting.
Are you sure you're
gonna be all right?
Sweetie, you need to
stop worrying about me.
All I want you
to think about is
how much I love you.
And when you wake up,
I'll be right there, okay?
I love you, baby.
I love you, too.
Please let her
be all right.
While debatable
choices were made
by all involved,
no one physician
is to blame.
My recommendation is
to revisit hospital policy
on requiring doctors
to be present when
radiation is administered.
Only with more
skilled eyes on the ECG
can future incidents of TLS
be identified and treated.
Hope you've all learned
something here today
that will make
you better physicians.
On a personal note,
it's ill-advised
for residents to date
medical students.
Uh-huh.
Is there something that
I can help you with?
Yeah. I was looking
for April.
She's on a break
right now.
But I can answer
any question
you might have.
Yeah. Uh, my wife, Kate,
has this necklace,
and, uh, I think it was
a gift from her mother.
And, you know, anyways,
she always wears it,
but the clasp broke,
uh, during the accident.
And I know she'd want
to have it with her.
I just...
I understand.
It can be in her hand
through the surgery.
I can make sure
April gets it.
We can put them back together,
but we can't change
their behavior, right?
"I'm indeed a king because
I know how to rule myself."
Pietro Aretino. He was
a 16th century poet.
What are you
getting at, Doc?
Well, put it this way,
in this case,
the king might be in
for a rude awakening
when they drug test him
before the race.
Yeah, if he gets tested.
Testing's random.
I don't know.
I mean, somebody could make
an anonymous phone call,
you know, tipping off
the track that, uh,
he took a diuretic.
You never know.
Somebody maybe already did.
Dr. Charles.
Those signs that you
talked about earlier,
the sadness in the eyes,
the clenched jaw.
I don't see them.
I'd like to know
why they elude me.
You know, I might have
some literature in my office
that could illuminate
some of this stuff for you.
You got
a couple minutes?
Mmm-hmm.
How's Bria?
Dr. Abrams just started
cauterizing the AVM.
He's a really
good surgeon.
I just wish
he wasn't such a dick.
Keep me posted.
Mmm-hmm.
Rough day, huh?
Yeah.
Grab a bite?
I'd like that.
Dr. Rhodes, Daniel.
We found another recipient
for Officer Windham's heart,
but the woman lives
in San Diego,
and that's at least
a four-hour flight.
If there were a delay,
we couldn't guarantee
the heart's viability,
and we cannot
postpone harvesting
due to the needs
of the recipients
of her other organs.
So, therefore?
Meghan Scott will
be receiving Officer
Windham's heart.
Due to the circumstances,
it's the only option we have.
I guess dinner
will have to wait.
Yeah.
Sharon?
Yeah?
Can we talk?
Of course.
That's the form.
Here, take this.
What's up?
Sharon, I want to take over
Kate Windham's care.
Come on, Maggie.
We've been through this.
You know my concerns.
Yes, and I respect them.
But it's closure for me.
And in a way for
Kate Windham, too.
And what about her husband?
What about his feelings?
I promise you,
I'll make sure
he feels comfortable.
I need to do this.
All right.
I'll talk to April.
Okay.
Can I speak
to you, Lieutenant Windham?
You good? Okay.
When I became a nurse,
I took an oath.
I swore to devote myself
to the welfare of those
committed to my care.
That's my job.
When your wife arrested me,
she was doing her job.
I bear her no ill will.
I'm very sorry
for your loss.
But I want to
honor your wife,
if you'll allow me.
Yeah.
No. No.
Ms. Scott, we need
to get you upstairs.
No, I don't care.
I'm not going anywhere
until I find out about Bria.
She's still
in surgery but doing well.
Right now, the best thing
you could do
for your daughter is
to take care of yourself.
We'll be right back
with someone to
take her up to the OR.
Hey.
You know today wasn't
a defeat, right?
I guess.
The whole experience has
been a lesson in humility.
Humility. Always been
a tough one for me.
Good night.
You know, Clarke...
He was out of line today.
But he was really
in your corner.
Yeah.
Hey, Jeff!
You want to get a drink?
I'll meet you over there.
Okay.
A nice move, Daniel.
Anonymous phone call.
We do what
we can, sister.
Yes, we do.
So, the M&M.
Stohl called you
my white knight.
I know, Nat,
and I feel terrible.
I...
And I heard what
he said about dating.
No, Jeff.
I can handle that.
I'm just really sorry.
It should be me
apologizing to you.
Why? I'm the one
who made everything worse.
I haven't been
fair to you.
Stohl also said that
he hoped we all learned
something today.
And I did.
When Jeff died,
it created this void,
this hole in my life
and in my heart.
I needed someone
to fill that void.
To take the pain away.
And there you were.
I feel like I used you.
You gave me the illusion
that my life was
fixed and whole.
But it doesn't
work that way.
It can, though, Natalie.
It can work that way.
And look, I want to be...
Jeff... I think
you're a great guy.
You're just not
the great guy for me.
This is it?
Yeah.
Dispatch to 2436.
Dispatch to Officer Windham.
Dispatch to
Officer Kate Windham.
Officer Windham,
your work here is done.
Officer Kathryn Windham
graduated the Chicago
Police Academy in 2008.
She served with distinction,
receiving the 21st District
Officer of the Month
three times,
two department commendations,
and in 2014, received
the Lifesaving Award
for pulling the driver
from a burning vehicle.
Officer Windham is
survived by her parents,
Robert and Felicia,
her brother, Richard,
and her husband, Darryl.
We thank you for
your dedication, loyalty,
and years of exemplary
service to the Chicago
Police Department,
the citizens of Chicago,
Illinois,
and the United States
of America.
Know that your strength
and love lives on
in your husband and family,
and your honor will
live on in all of us.
End of watch,
January 12, 2017.
Officer Kate Windham,
star number 2436,
is 10-7.
Gone but never forgotten.
Rest in peace, dear friend,
and protect us from above.