Since our hospital
is a teaching program,
many of our patients allow
their surgeries to be filmed.
♪ He is more real than myself ♪
It's great as a teaching tool.
But if you screw up,
it ends up online for
the whole world to see.
Your mistakes will
be scrutinized,
analyzed, studied,
written about...
Richard's plane should
be landing soon. You should go.
...argued over...
We have patients. You sure?
You came for a tour.
You ended up working overnight.
Hold up, fellas.
You deserve the break, man.
Go be there for your mom.
And Miranda.
I hear you.
Let me finish with this burn.
...watched and re-watched.
♪ Did he take me ♪
We all make mistakes.
We all have moments when
we weren't the best surgeon
- Okay.
- Or even the best person.
Carotid duplex. Echo.
CT to rule out stroke,
tremors,
intracranial hemorrhage.
Urinalysis
to rule out UTI.
Did they run
a tox screen?
Uh, and you
ran a tox screen?
Clean.
Okay.
Well, thank you.
Uh, we'll confirm
when we've received them.
Let's round up the troops.
We all have moments
we'd rather not relive.
♪ My father's guarding me ♪
Hey, I just checked
on the kids upstairs.
Is he here yet?
En route.
And I volunteered to
take over Pierce's cases
so that she can
focus on Richard.
And I'm still catching up
after the conference,
so I'm supposed to be
in three places now at once.
You know, I'm gonna
rearrange the cake thing
and see if my mom can
take care of the kids tonight.
- You need some sleep.
- Cake thing?
What cake thing?
You asked for
the wedding planner
to bring over a bunch of cakes
for us to try?
Oh, right. God, I-I'm sorry.
I... It's just...
No, no, no. No.
I get it. We all are.
Yeah. It's Richard.
See ya.
You think your body's
reached maximum capacity,
and then you just
keep growing.
I'm a human tissue
expander.
No. You're...
If you say glowing,
we're done.
Any updates on Richard?
No.
But I've cleared my day
to work him up.
Ow!
Oh. What happened?
You okay? Is the baby okay?
Should I page OB?
No, I'm fine.
It was just a big kick.
We still have
a couple weeks left.
You can't have
a panic attack
every time the baby kicks.
Can't make any promises.
Your mom made these
for you every day?
Why did you move out?
She also folded
my underwear,
threw away articles
of clothing
that didn't flatter
my nice butt,
and every time I tried
to talk about a problem,
she just shoved
a plate of food at me.
Like I said,
I don't get it.
Well, I can't go back.
You replaced me with
Schmitt, didn't you?
He's gonna be your
new best friend,
and I'm gonna be with
my kid all the time,
covered in bodily fluids.
Sorry. Just, um...
Due date's
getting closer.
I'm starting to, uh,
wrap my head around the fact
that my life's over.
Well...
you had a good run.
Yeah. I did.
We've got
a 65-year-old male
suffering from
memory lapses, tremors,
depression and mood swings,
and erratic behavior.
Yes, I am talking about
Richard Webber,
but today,
he is not the Richard Webber
you know and love.
He is our number-one patient.
Two days ago,
he suffered a public...
episode at
a medical conference.
Patient's history includes
an appendectomy,
a hip replacement,
surgery for a brain tumor
pressing on
his optic nerve.
He was also electrocuted
several years ago,
which led to surgery for
a pancreatic pseudocyst.
Jo did that surgery
for the pseudocyst.
- Oh, sorry. Uh, Dr. Jo.
- Let's review what we have so far.
You're crashing with
an attending. We get it.
This is a list
of possible diagnoses.
Some, we have
already ruled out.
This, we still need to.
Meredith.
Uh, we'll run
all the labs.
We'll do the blood cultures,
vitamin levels,
check the thyroid function,
and we'll check the urine
for heavy metals.
Mm-hmm.
Prepare yourselves.
He's not himself.
We saw the video.
Unless you get called
in for something emergent,
this is your job today.
Yes?
Uh... hi, Dr. Bailey.
Hi. Tom Koracick, neuro.
I know we don't
want to think it,
but have we ruled out,
uh, dementia?
No, we have not.
Get a PET scan,
throw in a beta-amyloid tracer,
and look for Alzheimer's.
It's not Alzheimer's.
Everything is on the table.
Nothing is out of the question.
Let's get to work.
Here he is. Dr. Lincoln,
meet Vera and Herschel Katano.
I just did her ER intake,
and we got imaging back.
Lisfranc injury with,
uh, fractured first
and second metatarsals.
Oh, nasty break.
What happened?
Uh, we were
in our home office,
and I was standing
on a chair
reaching for this textbook,
"The Elements of Statistics."
- We're professors at U-Dub.
- Mm-hmm.
It has one
particularly useful section
on game theory
that I love.
The contents of the text
are irrelevant, dear.
Oh, right.
Well,
it's a hefty tome.
And as I was
pulling it out,
it slipped and landed
on my wife's foot.
It's really broken?
It's really broken,
but we'll fix it,
and we'll put her toes
back in place.
A book lands exactly
wrong on her foot.
What are the chances?
Uh, certainly higher than
getting struck by lightning,
but less than getting
in a car accident.
What are the chances
of you letting
these nice doctors
do their job, hmm?
Hunt, you give me
a hand in the OR?
- Yep. I'll see you up there.
- I'm supposed
to make
a presentation of a paper
in a university
in two days.
You still can.
From the chair.
Can you stomp
on his foot, hmm?
Look,
I can get myself
into a bed.
Sorry. Hey.
Where have you been? And what
the hell are you wearing?
I was with Warren on the
physician response team vehicle.
- Don't worry about it.
- You smell like a garbage fire.
Okay. Richard,
how are you feeling?
How am I feeling?
Well, I was just wheeled
into my own damn hospital
like I was someone who's
lost control of their faculties.
We're gonna run a few more tests, okay?
No, that is not okay.
And stop treating me
like I'm an infant.
Catherine was with me
at the conference.
Will you tell them that
they're being ridiculous?
Actually, Catherine...
Yes, sweetheart,
I was there,
and your speech
was brilliant!
But you started feeling
badly right after.
So, please, let us just
take a few more tests,
and then we can go home.
Promise.
Oh, alright.
But I'm only doing
this for Cleopatra.
Add visual
and auditory hallucinations
to the list
of symptoms.
Okay.
Hey.
Tom, I wanted to...
Not get married
to someone else?
I wanted to talk.
No, I got it, but sincerely,
there's nothing to talk about.
I hope you
and Strawberry Shortcake
live happily ever af...
Tom, what is it?
Tom.
It's been a long time.
Hi. I'm...
I'm Dr. Teddy Altman.
Hi.
I'm, uh, Dana Hamilton,
formerly Koracick.
And this is my son,
Guthrie.
Honey, say hi to
Dr. Altman and Dr. Tom.
Nice to meet you.
My mom said you might be
kind of freaked out
because I look like my brother
who died before I was born.
And I would say sorry,
but... I can't really
change my face, so...
God,
you even sound a little bit like him.
Maybe you...
Can you change your voice?
I can try.
I know the resemblance
to David is uncanny.
I'm sorry.
I should have called.
But I didn't even know
that you would pick up
if you saw that
it was me.
Um...
- Guthrie has a brain tumor.
- Hm.
And apparently,
it's spread to his spine.
And it's bad, Tom.
I wouldn't have come
if it weren't.
I just wouldn't have come.
Yeah.
You know what,
let's get you checked in,
and then we'll take it
from there.
Tom,
do you want me to...?
- Mm-hmm.
- Yeah.
Mrs. Hamilton, will you
follow me, please?
Nice to meet you, Dr. Tom.
*GREY'S ANATOMY*
Season 16  Episode 20
Episode Title: "Sing It Again"
Aired on: April 02, 2020
Sync corrections by srjanapala
Guthrie Hamilton,
10 years old,
diagnosed with primary
medulloblastoma in his brain
that has spread to
his spine at C3.
Presents with
sensory deficits
and motor weakness
in his extremities.
He was in his cooking class,
and he just collapsed.
It was awful.
Pastry class, actually.
We were baking
croissants.
I never got to try mine,
but the teacher said
they were pretty good.
If you were stranded
on a desert island
and you could only have
one food, what would it be?
He asks everyone this.
Hummus.
No.
Brie.
What about you,
Dr. Tom?
Um...
escargot.
A man of excellent taste.
Um...
We should, uh... We should
get him some new scans.
Let's... Let's... Let's get him
up there right away.
Excuse me.
I already
paged Shepherd.
I don't know what
your ex-wife was thinking.
She was thinking
I'm the best.
I could never let this child die
if there's a single thing
I could do to stop it.
It's David, Teddy.
It's him. And it's not.
And I'm...
Tom, I'm here.
I'm staying close.
- Can you walk?
- Yeah.
Okay.
Yeah.
I'm late? Felt like
I was walking fast.
Abdominal midline incision
extending from the xiphoid
to just under the umbilicus.
What's that about?
Uh, he's going through
the steps of a Whipple
to prove to us that
he has not lost his mind.
"Famous Surgeon Implodes
at Medical Conference."
"Medical Meltdown
of the Year."
It doesn't stop.
Catherine's on the phone with
the foundation publicist
to try to scrub it off
of the Internet,
which isn't really
possible.
Inspect the peritoneum
and the surface
of the liver
for metastasis.
"When you think
you cured cancer
but you really
just got dumped."
I hate everyone.
I... Myself included.
I was so busy
sexing it up with Winston
I didn't even realize
what was happening.
And I should have.
He called me Meredith
when he saw me.
Wait, what's a Winston?
I'll tell you later.
Hepatic flexure
of the right colon
mobilized and reflected
medially.
There.
Now, would I be able to tell
you all that if I lost my mind?
The answer is
no, I wouldn't.
Is he right?
About the steps?
He is right.
You're doing great, Richard.
You're almost there.
Okay.
No indication of Lewy body
dementia or Pick's disease.
No increased signal
to the temporoparietal lobes,
so maybe not Alzheimer's.
But if it was in the early stages,
we wouldn't see it.
It isn't Alzheimer's.
I've had a front-row seat
to this disease.
This is not it.
Are we done yet?
Drilling the K-wire.
Any word on Webber?
Last I heard,
just more tests.
Amelia was up all night
watching that conference video
over and over again,
looking for clues.
Worried me.
Yeah. They've always
been close.
I know, but stress
and exhaustion
can cause hormone levels
to fluctuate,
which can induce
preterm labor,
and, you know, suddenly,
we've got a little dude
who showed up to the party too early.
Well, Amelia's close
to term, you know?
Baby's gonna be just fine.
You're nervous?
Name a worry,
I've had it.
Will Amelia have
an easy delivery?
Will we make it to
the hospital on time?
Will the baby
be scared of me?
Scared of you?
Yeah, I mean,
I've got big hands.
I don't know.
What if that freaks the baby out?
I know what you're gonna say...
That I'm just spinning out
and soon as the baby
gets here, I'll be fine.
Nope. I wasn't
gonna say that.
- You weren't?
- No, because I like you.
So while everyone else
is saying "Cherish this time,"
I'm gonna tell you
the truth, okay?
Parenthood
is scary as hell.
Your kid is in the safest place
he's ever gonna be right now.
When he comes out,
you're never gonna sleep again.
Wire cutters.
Thanks.
Hey.
Hey, what's up?
Oh, we're swamped.
I need you to jump in.
I need you to evaluate
beds 2 through 7
for smoke inhalation
and clear them.
But I've been helping
with Dr. Webber.
Hey, Schmitt, no offense,
but whatever's wrong with Webber
won't be solved
by a resident.
Oh. Uh, okay.
Why are you still
standing here?!
Alright. I'm going.
I'm going.
Sorry.
Take him over
to bed 10.
So, I-I-I'm sitting on this
park bench the other day, right,
and I look across,
and I see this squirrel,
and he's... he's hauling this
giant slice of pizza, right?
Then he starts
dragging it up the street.
I mean, the thing must have
been twice his size.
I don't even know how he was doing it.
Oh. You finally here
to let me go?
Um... waiting
on blood cultures.
T-The ER's slammed,
so the lab's backed up.
Dr. DeLuca?
Have I been
in any way unclear
about your suspension?
Come on, Bailey.
I can't visit a friend?
Webber's a mentor of mine.
We hang out socially.
I saw the news.
I got worried.
Fine. But after visiting hours,
you're gone.
Understood.
Hey, y-you need to add
decreased appetite
to his list of symptoms.
- DeLuca!
- Look, Dr. Riley says
that we learn more from
our patients in conversation
than traditional questioning,
right?
So, she's out of the country
right now, but she e-mailed me
this list of topics
to get him talking,
a-a-and I think
that it could open more avenues
for... for research,
and... and he could...
Visiting hours
are almost over.
And forward me that list.
Okay.
Hey. You paged me?
I'm still pretty busy with
the Richard thing, so...
We have a 10-year-old
with a medulloblastoma
and a drop met
on his cervical spine.
And... Koracick needs me
because...?
It's his ex-wife's son.
Apparently, the kid looks
exactly like David.
David was...
No, I know.
I-I knew David.
Oh, my God.
What are the chances Dana's
gonna lose another 10-year-old?
Hopefully not.
Hopefully
you can save him.
'Cause Tom certainly can't.
The tumor is getting bigger.
It's encroaching
on the brain stem.
Do they know?
I'll talk to them.
I will take it from here.
Okay.
Dr. Lincoln was able to reduce
the toes back into their place.
The surgery went
extremely well.
We'll leave
the splint on,
but no weight-bearing
on this foot for 12 weeks.
You understand?
Oh, thank you
so much, doctors.
- Thank... Thank you.
- Sure.
Hear that, Vera?
I'm waiting on you
for 12 weeks.
84 days.
Hand and... foot, honey.
Cup of tea,
those samosas from
the place you love.
Ha! Whatever you need.
We'll check on you in
a couple hours, okay?
♪ Excuse me, but why
are all of you singing? ♪
♪ Weren't all of you
singing just now? ♪
Uh, s-s-sweetie, uh...
no one's singing,
besides you.
♪ What is happening? ♪
- Maybe we should...
- Yep. Paging neuro.
♪ Oh! ♪
You need to work harder.
Everyone's doing the best
that they can, Mom.
Well, you look like
a bunch of feckless interns.
Figure this out.
It's happening again.
I'm gonna lose him,
too.
I promise I will try
to get the brain tumor
and the spinal met
in one surgery.
You are in great hands
with Dr. Shepherd.
No offense,
but we came here f-for Tom.
Dana, I use all the same
techniques as Tom.
I trained under him.
He taught me
everything he knows.
I did not bring him
here to hurt you.
I-I ran out of ideas.
I didn't know
what else to do.
I can't...
I can't, Tom.
Tom, I can't
go through this again.
I won't survive.
I can't.
Uh, we're family.
Or were.
And h... hospital policy,
uh, forbids surgeons
from operating on...
And my schedule is
extremely hectic.
I'm being
paged right now.
Shepherd is...
She's excellent.
I've got Guthrie.
Why don't you stay with him?
Excuse me.
Did you give her some weird kind
of pain meds or something?
Is she loopy?
♪ Herschel's voice
goes up an octave higher ♪
♪ When he's anxious ♪
She had a general anesthesia
and a post-op painkiller,
but we don't usually see
singing as a side effect.
Pupils are equal
and reactive.
Usually?
Or... not ever.
♪ I feel completely present ♪
♪ I just hear all
this music in my head ♪
♪ It is remarkable ♪
Tom Koracick, neuro.
These doctors
broke my wife.
Vera had surgery on her
Lisfranc injury this morning.
She woke up alert
but... singing.
Physical exam's normal. Labs normal.
Everything appears...
normal.
Uh, let's order
a brain MRI and an EEG.
Vera, we're gonna rule out
an intra-operative stroke,
but this could be something
called "musicophilia."
What on Earth is that?
A spectrum of neurological
phenomena related to music.
So, you've seen
this before?
No. It's
exceedingly rare.
How do you fix it?
You...
Singing lessons.
Page me when she's
in the scanner.
♪ Herschel ♪
♪ I wish you could be
experiencing this ♪
I-I am, dear.
I am.
Nico just posted again
on Instagram.
He's having
the time of his life.
His smile doesn't
even look fake.
It's like
I never existed!
Are you really talking to me
about this while we're in gridlock?
Well, I just assessed
beds 3 and 4.
Congratulations.
We're still gridlocked.
Is that my fault?
It's not not your fault!
Schmitt,
half the attendings
are in a room right now
working on Webber.
This is your moment
to step up, to rise, to shine,
to take care of incoming before
you get run over by a gurney!
And if you look
at your phone one more time,
I'll give you so much scut,
you'll wish you were never born!
Hey. So, Shepherd is
taking Guthrie to pre-op.
Thank you.
God, ever since David died,
I've had this thought...
What if I got to the hospital
in time to operate?
Maybe... I could
have saved him.
And now it's like...
he's here, and I can't...
I can't be in the same room
without feeling like
I'm... drowning.
That thought I've been
holding on to... it's a lie.
I got to update
my patient.
Okay, so,
the first one is,
we are going to repeat
this pattern.
Mm...
Um... you know what?
Let's come back to that one.
Okay, sure.
So, let's draw
this 3-D cube.
Mm-hmm.
Okay...
Okay.
Right here.
Well, why don't we just,
uh, skip to this one here
and draw a clock?
And we want the time
to say 10 past 11:00.
Okay.
Alright, this is...
Okay. I got this.
Yeah.
You got this, Richard.
Uh-huh.
Great.
Mm-hmm.
Okay, you know, we can take
a break for right now.
We can
come back to this.
Okay, well, hang on.
I wasn't finished with it.
It's okay.
I'm sure you're tired,
and it's been a lot.
♪ I guess singing
could help hold ♪
♪ Students' interest
in empirical probabilities ♪
Honey, you're about
to publish.
We're about to publish.
And you don't want people
questioning your state of mind.
There's no signs of stroke
or bleeding, and the EEG's negative
for seizures.
Okay.
So, she's just
like this now?
Which is good news,
Herschel.
It's most likely
a complication
from being
under anesthesia.
We're gonna keep her
here overnight
for monitoring purposes,
but you should be able
to take her home tomorrow.
Great.
Yeah. Great.
Hey, any update on Richard?
Uh, n-no idea.
I'm not here
with an update.
It's just me.
I don't need you, Jackson.
Richard needs you.
Okay, Mom...
You're letting him down.
Do you know that?
He's given this hospital
the best years of his life,
and you all are
the best minds in the field,
and no one even noticed
that he wasn't himself,
that he was deteriorating?
In fairness to us, I think
we thought that he was depressed
because his wife
both left him
and bought the hospital
that he was working at.
You don't think I've been
dying inside already?
I'm sure you have,
and I'm sorry, Mom,
but us fighting isn't...
Do you think I haven't
been kicking myself
for the last 48 hours, wondering
what I would have noticed
if I could just
have put aside my pride?
I should have
been there.
I would have
seen something.
I'm his wife.
So I can't be on his
medical team, but you can.
So you get back in that war room
and figure it out.
Now.
Okay.
♪ Is somebody bringing me
another pillow? ♪
The nurses went
to get one, dear.
Hey. Coffee?
- Thanks.
- Yeah.
How you holding up?
Mm.
You know,
about five years ago,
I spilled an iced tea
all over my car's dashboard.
It fried something in
the electrical system
and caused my seatbelt alarm
to constantly beep.
Even if the belt was buckled,
"Beep, beep, beep."
I was trying to
meet a book deadline,
so I couldn't
get it fixed,
so for weeks...
"Beep, beep, beep."
And...
...I learned
to live with it.
It faded in the background,
almost became comforting.
Will this ever fade?
Maybe. Yeah.
Or you could...
grow to like it?
And I've read that it
can help these patients
if you give them
an instrument to play.
Vera and I work at home because
the library is too loud.
If an oboe or something like
that comes into my life,
I will have
very dark thoughts.
Oh, um, please...
Don't tell her
that I compared her voice
to the broken seatbelt
in our 1997 station wagon.
No.
It stopped.
Oh, my God, it stopped.
Thank you, thank you,
thank you!
Vera! Are you okay?!
- What's happening?!
- She's hypoxic and tachycardic.
Uh, Herschel, we need you
to wait outside.
B-B-But she was fine
a second ago!
I-I-I'll update you
as soon as we know anything.
Now we identify
the cerebellar tonsils.
That's awesome.
We're not even at
the hard part yet.
I still have to
resect the tumor
without injuring
the brain stem.
Ow!
Are you okay?
Yep. Great.
I feel great.
Okay, inspecting
the inferior vermis...
Holy Mother of...
Ohh!
Helm, put down the retractor
and go get Dr. Koracick.
- Ohh!
- But, uh...
Helm, I am in labor.
Run!
And page Atticus Lincoln!
What the hell happened?
I am having this
baby, like, now!
Did your water break?
- Tom, not yet, but that doesn't mean
- ...Okay, until it does, you have time.
You can finish.
Just keep going.
Tom, do you hear
yourself?!
I'm... I'm... I'm
begging you, Shepherd.
Don't make me do this.
Tom, you saw the scans.
You and I are the best
two in this hospital,
maybe this country,
to remove this tumor.
This kid deserves one of us.
I can't do it.
So get in there and scrub!
Now!!
Congratulations,
Dr. Shepherd.
Richard clearly has
some type
of rapidly progressive
dementia,
and so far, none of our tests
can point to a cause.
This could
very well be...
Meredith, I'm not gonna
not say it.
It could...
Richard?
Okay, let's split up.
- Uh, I'll look around here.
- I'll take the OR floor.
I'll find Catherine.
Page when you find him.
Everything looks good.
There was some bleeding,
but I packed it off.
Ohh!
The tumor's almost
fully exposed.
Tom.
You can do this.
Ohh!
Pickups.
Probe.
♪ Some folks are born
made to wave the flag ♪
Continuing dissection.
♪ They're red, white, and blue ♪
End-Tidal CO2 decreasing.
BP just tanked.
He's crashing.
Dr. Koracick?
♪ When the band plays... ♪
Do I need to page someone else?
Do I need to get
Dr. Shepherd in?
Or call in Nelson?
♪ They point the cannon
at you ♪
Tom.
Listen to the sound
of my voice.
Breathe in.
Breathe out.
Focus on the tools
in your hand.
The feel of them,
the weight of them.
There's a monitor
beeping in front of you.
There is a patient on your
table who needs your help.
This is a place that you have
been a thousand times.
You can save him.
♪ It ain't me, no ♪
♪ I ain't no fortunate one ♪
Air embolism.
Trendelenburg.
Let's get his head
below his heart.
Helm, I want you to irrigate.
Drown him in water.
Knox, give him 100% O2, aspirate
through the central line.
Now!
Before he strokes out.
Come on.
- Let's turn him. Let's turn him.
- Come on, come on, come on.
More, more.
Easy. Easy.
Come on.
Turn him. Turn him.
Come on, buddy.
You can do it.
Here we go.
There!
Gotcha.
End-Tidal CO2's
coming back.
BP's rising. -
He's stabilizing.
That was amazing.
We're not out
of the woods yet.
Let's get him back
into position. Let's go.
♪ It ain't me ♪
Easy.
Tension pneumo,
maybe from intubation.
I'm gonna need
a 14-gauge needle.
Okay?
Alright, Vera.
I know it's hard,
but you need
to try to relax, okay?
Thank you.
Vera,
on the count of three,
I'm gonna insert
this needle, okay?
One, two, three.
Better?
Vera! Are you okay?!
I thought...
I thought
I was losing you.
♪ Ohh, much better ♪
♪ Thank you ♪
Vera, even if you're
singing, I don't care.
I just want you
to be okay.
♪ I love you ♪
♪ More than words
can say ♪
♪ I love you, too ♪
You gonna get that?
I'm just enjoying
the moment.
- Oh, God.
- What?
It's happening.
Ame... Amelia.
It's... It's happening.
Go. Go, go, go.
We got this.
Go!
- Are you okay?
- Ohh!
Oh, God. Oh, God.
What can I do?
Where's Carina?
She's on vacation with
her stupid girlfriend!
That's okay.
T-That's okay, right?
No, no!
Nothing is okay!
This whole time,
I've been thinking
that if I could just give birth
to a healthy baby boy,
that... that... that I would
have won some kind of race,
just crossed
the finish line,
but that's not where
the finish line is.
- I know. There is no finish line.
- No, there's no finish line!
Once this baby is out
in the world,
literally anything could
happen to him...
Cancer, car crash,
baseballs!
- Baseballs?
- Ahh, make me feel better!
Here.
N... ju... ju... ju...
- I-I'm freaking out!
- What are we gonna do?!
- I don't know!
- Stop yelling at me!
Aaaaaaaah!
Scalpel.
You're late, Grey.
I was just about to proceed
with the initial incision.
Richard.
You in or out?
What's it gonna be?
Let's see...
Uh, uh... what surgery
are we performing?
Um, the ex-lap.
I'm glad to see you've
come to your senses.
I could use the assist.
Okay, Richard.
Uh, we need to, um...
Hmm?
...ch... check the, uh...
The scalpel to make sure
it's been sterilized properly.
Sterilized?
Of course it's sterilized.
- Richard, please.
- No, no, no.
I... It needs
to be me, okay?
I'm the only one who
can fix what's wrong.
No, that is not true.
Yes, it is!
Richard, I can fix you.
And I know I can fix you
because you are the one
who taught me everything I know.
And I'm not just
talking about surgery.
You taught me how
to be a better person,
how to be
a better mother.
And what about
my children?
I want them to grow up
and know who you are.
Please.
And I still have things
I need to learn.
I need you. I'm not ready
to let you go yet.
And I know
other people aren't, either.
Hand me the scalpel,
please.
Ellis.
Something's...
wrong with me.
Yes.
It's okay.
Take my hand, Richard.
Let's go, now.
Come on.
We removed the primary tumor
and the spinal metastasis,
so he'll need some radiation of
the brain and the spinal cord,
but as of now,
Guthrie is on the road to recovery.
Okay?
Okay.
Okay. Yeah.
Hey, Doc, uh,
I don't know
how we're ever gonna
be able to thank you.
Mm.
I thought
you couldn't do it.
Still can't believe I...
I did.
I'm sorry.
No, no, no. No.
And thank you.
Thank you.
Yeah.
And Guthrie's, uh...
It's a good name.
Oh. Another one?
Is it bad?
Ohh, you know when guys
get kicked in their... guys?
How do you know
what that feels like?
Everything goes black.
You want to throw up.
Your whole body goes cold
all over because of the pain.
That's exactly what
it feels like.
Hoo! This is worse.
We're gonna have a baby!
Good news,
Dr. Shepherd!
Based on the pelvic exam
and cervical length
on ultrasound,
it looks like Braxton Hicks.
Braxton Hicks?
False labor.
When the uterus contracts
and relaxes.
I know what
Braxton Hicks are.
S-So, no baby?
Not today.
♪ We touch the fire ♪
I really thought
this was real.
Same.
♪ And we don't get burned ♪
Suddenly,
they hurt less.
♪ It takes us higher ♪
♪ And it's what we learn ♪
♪ And it's what we le-e-e-arn ♪
♪ It's everything
that we cannot see ♪
♪ It's the mystery ♪
♪ Ohh ♪
♪ It's going to be ♪
Thank you.
♪ It's going to be,
it's going to be ♪
Tom, I'm...
♪ It's everything
that we cannot see ♪
I'm so sorry.
'Cause you've had more
than enough pain.
♪ Ohh, it's going to be,
it's going to be ♪
You've taken away
more than
- you've caused.
- ♪ It's going to be, it's going to be ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh, oh ♪
- Hey!
- Hi.
What do you want
to watch?
Uh, I'm going back
to the hospital.
Oh, did they
extend your shift?
Uh, to sleep.
And I-I-I don't want
to be a fish.
A fish?
Levi, what are you
talking about?
House guests and fish.
After three days,
they both start to stink.
My mom taught me that.
Okay, your mom also
taught you
to hide the best parts
of yourself.
Why would you ever
listen to her?
Well, you keep telling me
how great I had it at my mom's
and spent the whole day
yelling at me.
Yeah, because you weren't
doing a good job.
I'm not gonna change
the way that I work
just because
we're friends.
I know that I wasn't
an attending when we met,
but I am now, and that means
I'm gonna snap at you
when you get things
wrong.
Otherwise, you're never
gonna become the surgeon
that you should be.
And you're not a fish.
You're probably
the main reason
that I'm at all sane
right now.
So...
what are
we watching tonight?
Something with hot guys?
Ohh! Sold!
Okay.
Hey. I'm gonna
go get the kids.
I would sing with you
if I had to.
But I really can't sing.
What?
♪ Though you're still
not around me ♪
Come on.
Come here.
♪ Oh, I went down on my knees
to pray ♪
♪ I asked the Lord
to accept you ♪
♪ Though you're still
not around me ♪
Screw the plans.
Huh? What?
♪ I'll keep moving ♪
I want to be
married to you.
As soon as possible.
Mm.
♪ I'll get through this ♪
Let's do it.
Let's do it
this weekend.
♪ Times get tough at times,
I'll admit it ♪
♪ It looks like I'm drowning,
like I'm sinking in it ♪
♪ But I won't let you down ♪
♪ I'm not giving up tonight ♪
- I love you, Teddy.
- I love you.
There are certain
moments in my life
that I wish I could relive...
First day of internship,
first solo surgery,
first time I held
my children in my arms.
Oh, oh, where am I?
You're in
the hospital, Richard.
What? Seattle Grace?
Grey Sloan.
Oh, well, um,
um, send for the interns.
I-I want to start
rounds right away.
Adele will kill me if
I'm late for dinner again.
The last lucid conversation
I had with my mother.
♪ You'd know how to
make this go away ♪
Okay.
Mom.
Hey.
I can't do this.
Yeah, you can.
We can.
Alright?
We're gonna fix him.
We're gonna figure it out.
I'm right here with you.
- Jackie!
- I know.
But for every one of those...
I'm gonna fix him.
...there's one I wish I could
forget or do differently.
♪ Tonight ♪
Those are the moments
that keep me up at night.
♪ I'll admit it ♪
♪ It looks like I'm drowning,
like I'm sinking in it ♪
♪ But I won't let you down ♪
♪ 'Cause you're here
with me tonight ♪
Did Bailey tell you
to come here, kick me out?
♪ Oh, oh, oh ♪
What have you thought of
that we haven't?
What do you mean?
Are you going to pretend
you're not in here
trying to figure out
what's wrong with Richard?
I'm just trying to
go over some of these points
'cause just...
It doesn't make sense.
It doesn't.
So, what do you have?
Because we're not leaving here
until we figure this out.
Really?
Thought I was supposed to, uh,
go home, get some rest.
♪ I won't let you down ♪
Are you with me or not?
♪ Tonight ♪
Okay. This is
what I got so far.
♪ Oh, I pray ♪
And no matter what I do,
they keep coming back to haunt me.
♪ 'Cause you're here
with me tonight ♪