Yeah.
Uh-huh.
Yeah, that's not a problem.
We'll take care of it.
What's your ETA?
Okay. No problem.
Have you seen Dr. Lewis?
Suture Room.
Baby coming in,
respiratory arrest.
They're five minutes out.
Susan...
Susan.
Oh. Uh...
turn off the
overheads, would you?
We've got an infant on
the way. Unresponsive.
The lights.
They'll be here soon.
Okay.
You up?
Mm-hmm.
You sure?
Yeah.
Mm-hmm.
Susan?
Yeah. I'm up. I'm up. I'm up.
Oh...
top on, lock it in again,
and open this. You see this?
Top of the key...
He shoots and he...
This is Melody. Melody?
Those Indians,
were they pretty
close behind you?
No. You're wrong, Dr. Welby.
Nadine's going to recover.
Yes, she will recover,
but you must be
aware of the fact
that there was damage.
Damage can be corrected.
Nadine is strong.
She always has been.
I know what she can do.
She's going to
make a full recovery.
I'll make sure of that.
You used to like her.
No, I didn't.
Yeah, you did.
Before Rodman
you used to talk about her
all the time.
What have you got for us, Sarge?
Responded to a
domestic violence call.
Boog was out in the street
buck naked, waving
a gun, screaming.
We're going to need a light.
He shoot someone?
Nah, he ran inside,
slipped on the stairs, and
passed out drunk as a skunk.
Man...
you better not have dragged us
out of a nice, warm firehouse
for a booking check
on a drunk, Sarge.
Bunch of jelly-doughnut-
eating pendejos.
Hey!
Dumb and Dumber.
Nobody got you out of bed
for that piece of crap.
We got you out of bed for them.
Holy Mary, Mother of God.
Welcome to Calcutta.
Twenty-two children,
ages six months
to nine and a half years,
found in a single
apartment on Calumet.
Malnutrition, suspect marasmus,
kwashiorkor, who
knows what else.
Northwestern took
four, Mercy took three,
and we got the rest.
Where are their parents?
Nobody knows.
Children and Family Services?
Yeah, they're on their way.
The cops took
custody of the kids.
They arrested some guy
who claims to be the uncle.
Yeah, so he says.
Of all of them?
I've got a toddler in 2.
How many you seen so far, Doug?
Four of them.
Thrush, chronic
otitis media, ringworm,
diarrhea, malnutrition,
electrolyte imbalances...
let's get CBC, Chem-20,
protein, albumen, transferrin,
globulins, iron, UA,
and a folate level.
Doug, that baby's
refusing formula.
You can drop a feeding tube,
about 13 pounds,
maybe a year old.
Okay.
Who's this?
Can't get a name.
Says she's three years old.
You're three, sweetheart?
Okay. What's your name, darling?
Come on. What's your name?
All right.
Let's get these
sores cleaned up.
Start her on Keflex, 250 mgs.
That looks like impetigo.
Let's hope the others
haven't caught it.
Chem-20, CBC, UA?
Yeah, and let's
get height, weight,
head and arm circumferences.
I'm gonna go make myself useful.
Okay.
Last three.
We've got the beds?
Suture Room.
Hi, I'm Dr. Greene.
What's your name?
Ty.
Listen, are these your
brothers and sisters?
Uh-huh. Some.
Who are the others?
I don't know. Cousins.
Do you know their names?
You know a few?
Some.
Right. Some.
Lydia, why don't
you find Ty a bed?
Come on, Ty.
Where's his shoes?
Couldn't find them.
Looked over the whole place.
There's only enough clothes
for half the kids there.
Rubadoux.
Would you excuse
us for a moment,
Mr. Rubadoux?
Sure.
Thank you.
Dr. Benton?
Post-op, day nine.
Patient was presented
with a type A aortic dissection,
which was repaired using
the clamp-and-run procedure.
Patient's surgical course
was unremarkable,
though there is evidence
of partial paraplegia
of the lower extremities.
And this morning?
Echo shows ejection
fraction of 15%.
BUN is 45.
Creatinine, 2.
BP's 180/110.
Suggesting what?
Congestive heart
failure, renal insufficiency.
None of this attributable
to our recent, life-saving
aortic-aneurysm surgery.
Well, I am worried
about her paraplegia.
Well, it's too soon to determine
whether it's not temporary.
Course of action?
Increase her cardiac output
so we can transfer her
to a long-term facility.
Get her off of our
service. Exactly.
How?
Well, given her condition,
I'd suggest a dobutamine IV.
They wouldn't accept her
in a nursing home with an IV,
would they?
Anybody else?
Um...
Mr. Carter. A thought?
If we put her on dobutamine,
she might get
better for a few days,
but she's likely to decompensate
and bounce back here.
Why not try an ACE inhibitor?
We could do that,
couldn't we, Dr. Benton?
It worsens her renal problem.
Carter?
Nitrates.
Decreases her preload.
Digoxin. Kidneys can't clear it.
Diuretics.
Decreases cardiac output.
Quite the conundrum.
Well, I'm sure
there's a solution.
A pinch of this,
a touch of that.
We have to use
our clinical judgment.
How many are you
currently carrying, Mr. Carter?
Five, but I can handle
another one, no problem.
Well, in that case,
why don't you
show us what you can do
without resorting to
Dr. Benton's dobutamine?
Amaze us.
Impress us.
Work miracles.
Bad case of ringworm.
Well, with kerion.
Let's get him on
oral griseofulvin.
Open up.
Yeah.
Ty, you had enough to eat?
Yeah? Like what?
We eat stuff.
Fruits? Vegetables? Meat?
Sometimes.
What about the babies?
They get formula?
My mom gives me the stamps
when she don't need them
and I get us stuff.
Milk for the babies,
bologna, bread.
Your mom gives
you the food stamps
and you do the shopping?
I'm good at it.
Trey okay?
He one of your brothers?
I looked after him. He's sick.
How sick?
Cerebral palsy.
He has cerebral palsy?
He's in Trauma 1.
Doug's checking him out.
CBC, Chem-20, protein studies,
transferrin, iron, and a UA.
Let's call a dental school
and get some of those
students over here
to take a look a these kids.
Now I'm going to go see
how your brother Trey's doing,
okay?
Where's Doug?
Trauma 1.
How's she doing?
Anemia,
neutropenic, thrush,
chronic otitis media,
and pediculosis.
Lice.
You betcha, and
if she's got them...
They've all got them.
Jeanie, grab a basin
and enough RID to go around
and start shampooing.
All of them?
It's great to be
the new kid on
the block, isn't it?
Susan, weren't you off at seven?
Yeah. Jeanie too.
I've got a performance
review this afternoon.
I might as well stick around.
Come on, Jeanie.
Lice patrol.
Isn't that a nurse's job?
No, not today, it isn't.
Susan, why don't
you finish this one
and then go home?
We've got it.
You know, I signed them in.
I want to make sure
they're okay before I go.
Ah.
Is this the kid with CP? Ah.
Yeah. Five years
old, weighs 28 pounds.
Lethargic.
Slight abdominal edema.
Kid's starving to death.
Take a look at this.
Look at that.
Cigarette burns.
Yeah. Welts too.
You're...
You're going to
have to bring him in
if he won't go down
to the ambulance.
Who the hell just paged
me down from rounds?
Hey, if I got shot
I'd want to come
in to the hospital.
This had better be important.
No. Look, lady,
I'm not going to talk to him.
I'm a clerk, not a priest.
Call 911 or get on the damn bus.
The page?
How should I know?
Ask around.
Benton? What?
Al Boulet, Jeanie's husband.
Oh, yeah. Hey. How you doing?
I've been better.
Have you seen her?
No. Is she working?
Well, she was supposed
to be off at seven.
She was gonna
meet me for breakfast.
Do me a favor.
If you see her, tell
her I'm looking for her,
okay? Yeah.
Find out who's paging me
and tell them
they damn well
better be down here
the next time I come.
What was that all about?
Dr. Personality? Who knows?
Any of you seen a
DCFS around here?
Mark Greene?
Dr. Mark Greene?
You Child Services?
Sorry, no.
Process server.
Sign here, please.
What for?
Summons.
Third line, please.
Have a nice day.
Right.
Patient?
Hope not.
Jennifer's suing me for divorce.
Oh, no.
You Dr. Greene?
Not if you want
me to sign anything.
What?
I'm Mark Greene.
Pete Tuteur,
Department of Child
and Family Services.
I understand you
got some kids for us.
We need more water.
Okay.
Now, see, that
wasn't so bad, was it?
All right.
Got another one for you.
Alrighty.
Hi, there, sweet pea.
I'm Jeanie.
Do you have a name?
That one doesn't talk.
Okay.
We're going to shampoo your
hair and make it look all beautiful.
Is that too hot?
Is that too cold?
Must be just right, then.
How many more we got?
We've already done eight, right?
Nine, I think.
Mommy.
What's that, sweetie?
Did you say something?
I didn't hear what you said.
I was talking to my friends.
Will you be my mommy?
Where's the husband?
Cafeteria.
Renal or Cardiology been up yet?
Oh, yeah.
And?
Renal wants to use hydralazine.
Cardiology wants
an ACE inhibitor.
Ah, the Renal-Cardiology
push-and-pull.
What about Pulmonary?
Oh, they sent over
an incentive spirometer.
Yeah, right.
Well, that should solve
all of her problems.
Partial paraplegia?
Still present.
You know, your
beeper's going off.
Yeah, I'm not deaf, Carter.
All right. Well, hurry
up. Do something.
Time's wasting.
40 milligrams IV
push of Lasix, please.
Won't that volume deplete her?
Just do it, please.
Okay? Sorry, but...
Three of the girls
aren't even supposed
to be living with the mother.
The court awarded custody
to a grandmother.
God knows where she is.
Why were they all
in one apartment?
22 AFDC Payments.
Uncle's on disability.
The rent is maybe 300.
Hell, they're netting four
grand a month for crack.
Your tax dollars at work.
Sounds like a press release
for welfare reform.
Yeah, that's all we need.
Less money trickling down
to keep these kids
from starving to death.
Look, as soon as you
get these kids cleaned up,
I'll take them over to
Columbus/Maryville.
These kids are
malnourished, dehydrated,
their electrolytes
are screwed up,
and they've got infections.
No one's leaving here
until I'm satisfied
they're okay.
Fine. I mean, it's not as if
we have anyplace to put them.
Have you seen Benton?
I keep paging him.
Oh, he's around.
You ever get the feeling
that the system isn't working?
Ah, you're just
figuring that one out?
One of the boys
has an inguinal mass.
He needs a surgical consult.
Reducible?
Yeah, but it's there
when he's crying
and he's crying a lot.
I don't think any of these kids
have ever seen doctors.
She had me served at work.
Jennifer?
Yeah. I was hoping we
were going to be able
to handle this amicably.
I guess this blows
that one to hell.
I'm going to need
a good attorney.
Why don't you come over tonight,
and we'll order in a pizza?
You can watch me
give Susie a bath,
and if you're really nice, I
might let you change a diaper.
I'm just going to go home
and wallow in self-pity.
Any time.
Hey, they find homes
for those kids yet?
Not yet.
The DCFS took
some of the older ones
to the emergency shelter,
and we admitted three.
You want anything
from the machine?
Yeah, how about
some of those, uh,
peanut butter crackers?
Got it.
He's cute.
Raul?
Mm-hmm.
Uh, you're not his type.
Really?
You ever dress up
like a lumberjack?
Longshoreman?
Greco-Roman wrestler?
He's gay.
Really?
Randi, who's paging me?
Not a clue.
Well, isn't that your job?
No, it's not.
Check the board and the charts.
You should have seen this place.
Twenty kids, no refrigerator,
no heat, roaches everywhere.
Only thing in the kitchen
was a can of SpaghettiOs.
You really got to wonder
about these mothers,
and then you got to think,
what about the families?
You know, their neighbors?
I mean, can't these people
take care of their own kids?
What the hell is that
supposed to mean?
What does what mean?
"These" people. Come on.
Yo, partner. Catch.
Why can't these black folks
take care of their kids,
right?
He didn't say that.
Yeah, well, that's
what he meant.
Hey, if that's what I meant,
that's what I would have said.
What's going on, guys?
David Duke here
is enlightening us.
Oh, Malik, that's not fair.
Do you think those kids deserved
to be living like that?
Whatever happened to
personal responsibility?
You think it's equal?
He's the surgeon.
I'm the fireman.
Yeah, well, you would
find it that simple, huh?
Because we all know the system
works the same for everybody.
The system seems to be
working pretty well for you, Doc.
Let me tell you something.
You don't know a damn
thing about what works for me.
Peter, where have you
been? I've been paging you.
Trauma 2.
What the hell
was that all about?
You, man. That's what.
Loretta?
Yeah, it's one of her kids.
Sore throat. Temp's 101.
Where's Ross?
Still tied up with those kids.
Loretta, how you been?
Good.
Uh, this is Annie.
This is my Jimmy.
His throat's sore.
Oh, yeah?
Well, let me take a
look there, Jimmy.
Great.
Jimmy, can you just
open your mouth?
Stick out your tongue.
That's good. "Ah."
Ah.
Uh-huh. Ooh.
Does that hurt when you swallow?
That hurts, too, huh?
Glands are swollen.
He still has his tonsils.
Yeah, well, you got a little
strep throat there, Jimmy,
but don't worry.
We can clear that right up.
How about you, Annie?
Is your throat sore at all?
No, I'm okay.
Okay, and Mom,
how are you doing?
I'm doing really good.
I still got that office job,
and we moved into a new house.
The PID hasn't flared up?
I get a little
bleeding sometimes.
Yeah?
Lydia, why don't you
take the kids outside
and I can talk to Mom.
It's no big deal.
Come on, guys.
I think we got some videos
around here someplace.
You seen The Lion King? No.
Yes, you have.
Go on.
I'll be out in a minute. Go on.
So, uh...
how long have you been bleeding?
All right, what do we have?
Seven-year-old male.
Small, reducible,
right-sided inguinal mass.
It's all right, Michael.
This is Peter. He's a doctor.
He's going to help
you feel better, okay?
Did you page me
this morning too?
Yeah. Where were you?
On surgical rounds,
which you pulled
me off of for nothing.
Oh, excuse me.
I thought you were
assigned to the ER.
No, no, no, no. I'm assigned
to the surgical service.
I cover the ER,
and when I'm paged,
I expect somebody
to be waiting for me
when I come down.
Well, we've been a little
busy down here today.
Almost over, Michael. Almost.
There's no hernia.
Check him again.
You're wasting my time.
Peter.
It's not there.
The hell it isn't.
Check him again.
It's still reducible.
I'll put him on the
surgical schedule.
Operate tomorrow.
Draw pre-op labs.
Peter, what is the
matter with you?
If you're angry with me,
you take it out on me,
not on some little boy.
What?
Give us a minute, Connie.
That little boy in there
is scared to death,
and you're poking around on
him like you're stuffing a turkey,
telling him how
he needs surgery?
He's never even seen a doctor.
Is that it?
No, that's not it.
Peter, if this is
about you and me,
get over it.
If it's about something else,
get over that
too. I'm sick of it.
Don't you turn your back on me.
That little boy in there
needs compassion.
If you can't find
that in yourself,
get out of medicine.
69-year-old male, history of MI,
experienced sudden onset
of chest pain.
Took a nitro tab,
called his son.
Paramedics found
him unconscious.
One, two, three.
They tubed him.
He's hypotensive. 40 palp.
O-2, 100 percent.
Let's get a 12-lead.
Pulse ox, chest x-ray,
CBC, Chem-7, cardiac enzymes,
and grab a blood gas.
You the son?
Yes.
He's had a heart attack before?
Yeah, about two years ago.
He's hypoxic.
Rales bilaterally.
Jugular venous distension.
Haleh, let's get an echo.
Dopamine?
Yeah, 200 mics per minute.
Call Cardiology.
Hi, I'm Dr. Greene,
and you're Mister...
Mills. Howard Mills.
Your father's in heart failure,
and it's too early
to know exactly what's happened,
but we're running tests.
And we'll let you know
as soon as we know.
Can't I stay with him?
Why don't you get some coffee
and let us do our work?
When your father's stabilized
I'll come get you, okay?
Okay.
Bobby. Sorry I'm late.
No problem.
How about a cup of coffee?
It's only about a week old.
No, thanks.
I'm already on
my 10th cup or so.
I was on all night.
How's it been going?
Okay.
I'm a little concerned
about your first
student evaluation.
"Pleasant, helpful,
lacks assertiveness.
"needs to take control
"if she's going to be useful.
"Good skills,
"but may not be well-suited
"for work in the
Emergency Department."
Uh-huh.
Is that from a Peter Benton?
Who?
Dr. Peter Benton,
surgical Resident?
No.
Residents don't evaluate
physician assistant students.
No, this is from...
Carol Hathaway, RN, MS.
I didn't realize the
nurses evaluated us.
Look, I realize
that putting PAs into settings
where nurses had a monopoly
can cause problems,
but liked or disliked,
we have to do a better job,
so I need to know,
can you cut it?
Because if you can't,
I can't afford to have
you fail down there.
I can cut it.
Are you sure?
Yeah, I'm sure.
Mark? Jennifer
filed for divorce?
Word travels fast.
I knew you were breaking up.
I just always figured
that you would find a
way to hold it together.
Trying to make me feel worse?
No, it's just
if you can't make
a marriage work
how the hell am I going to?
What are you still doing here?
Home away from home.
Mark, Cardiology's
here on your MI.
I want you out of here by five.
Excuse me. Can
someone help me, please?
Uh, Randi? Randi.
Can I help you?
Yes, I'm looking for
my grandchildren.
They were living in an apartment
down on Calumet.
Police say they
brought them here.
The name's Proulx.
The littlest one, Trey,
has got cerebral palsy.
What are her I's and O's?
150cc's in, 800cc's out.
Pressure?
Down. 80/40.
Down? Why didn't you call me?
You didn't put
it in your orders.
Give her a 300cc bolus
and monitor her
pressure, please.
How's our girl doing, Doc?
Oh,
not much improvement
yet, Mr. Rubadoux.
Oh, Ruby, please. Call me Ruby.
Coffee?
Come on. I bought an extra.
Oh, no, thanks.
Oh, come on. A
little cup of hot joe.
You look like you could
stand a little pick-me-up.
Mm.
Now, that's good coffee.
You should have seen her
50 years ago.
Backstage at the Majestic.
Great gams.
Hell of a looker.
Pal Joey,
Way to the Forum,
How to Succeed.
Broadway, off-Broadway,
you name it.
Huh.
I did a couple musicals myself,
back in school.
Pippen.
Fantastiks too.
Oh, yeah. Good shows.
Yeah, bet you were wonderful.
Not really.
I don't believe that.
I bet you were great.
Mr. Carter...
Uh, mostly I embarrassed myself.
Doctor?
I'm not ready to let her go yet.
Carol.
Can I talk to you?
Sure. What's up?
I just had my student evaluation
with my program coordinator.
You've been
unhappy with my work.
I think you're
competent but timid.
If you want to be down here,
you need to be more aggressive.
I've been trying.
Look, the ER
isn't for everybody.
You know, don't feel bad
if you're not
comfortable down here.
Have I done something
to offend you in some way?
This isn't
personal. It's just...
you're always waiting
for somebody to
tell you what to do.
It's like this conversation.
I tell you I need you
to be more aggressive
and you want to stand
here and discuss it.
I don't have time to
hold people's hands.
You've just got to do it.
So it's not a PA thing?
No, it's not, but hey,
I've got nurses who have
been here for 20 years.
Physician assistants
go to school
for a couple of months,
and they have the right
to tell us what to
do? Two years.
Two years of training.
Two years of internship.
I went nights while
I worked full time,
so my training
took me four years.
If you want to stay in the ER,
stop looking for validation
and start doing the job.
You do that, and
we'll get along fine.
Please make sure
that everybody's ready
for Wednesday's
dog and pony show
for the trustees.
I don't want a repeat
of last fall's disaster.
Dr. Vucelich,
you were looking for me?
Yes, I was, Benton.
Have you met my
assistant, Claire?
No. Hi.
Hello.
So, is Mrs. Rubadoux's
paralysis subsiding?
No.
Don't be so disappointed.
It was an emergent situation.
What was our other
choice? Death?
Besides, the woman
was a bad risk.
Pulmonary disease,
history of hypertension.
I'm concerned her
condition might be my fault.
I performed the procedure.
Oh, please. Don't
be so melodramatic.
Your technique
was letter perfect.
We'll have to exclude
her from the study.
She was never an
appropriate candidate.
I think it's time
we made Dr. Benton an
official member of the team,
don't you think, Claire?
Research associate?
Yes.
Claire will make sure
you have everything you need.
I don't know what to say.
"Thank you" will suffice.
Yeah. Yeah.
Mr. Mills?
Howard, please.
Uh, Howard,
we suspect that your father
had a right
ventricle infarction.
Another heart attack.
Yes.
We're going to send him
up to the Cardiac
Intensive Care Unit.
They'll place a
Swan-Ganz catheter
to better monitor the
pressure in his heart and lungs,
and they'll do an echo
to confirm the diagnosis.
It doesn't look good.
I think...
he wants to go.
My mother died last year.
Breast cancer.
They were married 50 years.
This is you.
Coffee's in the lounge.
Bathroom's past the elevators.
Research staff
meets every Tuesday,
8:15 sharp.
Fill this out
and get it back to me
as soon as possible.
You have an assigned
parking space?
No, I park in the
Residents' lot.
Not anymore, you don't.
AW4?
All research associates
receive a stipend,
and your first referral payment.
I'm Carl's secretary, not yours.
You want your phone answered,
get a machine.
Anything else,
I'm at the end of the hall.
Yeah.
Hey, Trey, how are you doing?
He's doing better now.
Yeah, he is, isn't he?
Mrs. Proulx, may
I speak with you
for a moment, please?
I'll take the little girl.
Oh, that's okay.
Ty, can you come over here
and look after your
sister for Nana?
Mrs. Proulx, Trey's well enough
to be released to the DCFS.
This is Mr. Tuteur.
We'll be taking him over
to Columbus/Maryville.
It's an emergency shelter.
Do you know what that is?
Yes, I've been there before.
So, you're not going
to let me keep them?
The department's been
granted temporary custody.
There'll be a court
hearing next week.
Well, they were with
me till a month ago,
then their mother came
and got them again.
I told her
they should be with me.
They all have their own rooms
and their own beds in my place,
and they like it there.
Mrs. Proulx, I'm sorry,
but why did you
keep the kids there?
You have custody.
They're your responsibility.
Well, she said she
was doing better,
and children should
be with their mother.
You know, she
wasn't always like this.
She loved those babies.
She loved them a lot,
but you know, it's the drugs.
Are these jackets for them?
Mm-hmm.
Okay, children.
Let's put these coats on now.
Ty, help your brother
on with his coat, sugar.
You be a good girl,
now, you hear, okay?
Okay.
How we doing?
All ready? Come
here, sweetheart.
Now, you take care
of little Trey, now, Ty.
Yes, ma'am.
Come on, sweetheart.
Come with me.
Here we go. Got you, sweetie.
Okay. We ready?
Let's go.
Ty...
now, you take good care
of little Trey, you hear?
Yes, ma'am.
51-year-old woman,
abdominal pain and cramps.
Thinks she ate too
much on New Year's.
Got to weigh 300 pounds.
Is this day ever going to end?
So, Mrs., uh, Saunders,
did you have a little
too much holiday cheer?
She's been in pain for days,
and I still had to drag her in.
When did the cramps start?
New Year's Day, after dinner.
Any pain here?
Mm-mm.
Vomiting?
I've been nauseous.
Diarrhea? No.
What did you have to eat?
Usual holiday stuff.
Potato salad, ham, cheesecake,
pumpkin pie, some sushi.
Jeanie, get a stool culture,
Rule out salmonella,
and a rectal.
Chuny will help you.
I doubt if it's appendicitis.
It's probably viral
gastroenteritis
or a touch of food poisoning.
Let's get a surgical consult.
CBC, Chem-7, UA,
abdominal series.
Set up for a pelvic
and find Benton.
7-3-5-2-9-0-1.
Date of admission, 12-26-95.
Dictating...
Dr. Vucelich, can I
interrupt you for a minute?
Well, you already have.
Uh...
Mrs. Rubadoux isn't improving.
I've tried Lasix,
nitrates, pressors.
She just keeps
seesawing back and forth.
Either she's volume depleted
and her pressure's dropping
or her pressure's up and
her pulse ox is dropping.
Put her on dobutamine?
Uh, you told me not to.
So, do you always
follow instructions
even when you've surmised
that they're incorrect?
Mrs. Rubadoux is a sinking ship
and you spent all day
rearranging her deck chairs.
You're probably right.
Once we've buffed her
up and bundled her off,
she will decompensate
and end up right
here in the hospital,
but she will not
be on our service
and she won't be your problem.
Um, let's see...
Dictating discharge summary
on patient David Piscuscus...
Did I make her worse
today?
She's dying, Mr. Carter.
Nothing you did is
going to change that.
Date of admission, 12-26-95.
Date of discharge, 1-8-96.
Patient presented
with claudication
of the right lower extremity...
Marcus Miller?
Bill Evans?
Wynton Marsalis?
You got to know Marsalis.
The Jay Leno show?
Hold up a second, will you?
Excuse me.
It's Malik, right?
Yeah, that's right.
Look, about
earlier, I just, uh...
I hope you didn't misunderstand
what I was trying to say.
Nah, man, I didn't
misunderstand.
Hey, Shep, come on.
I've only got 10 minutes.
It's just, you know,
I think that, you know,
we're all doing okay,
and nobody owes
anybody anything.
Let's get on with our
lives, and do what we can.
Sure. Whatever, man.
Hey, Shep. Let's go.
Yeah, hold up.
Hey, I was just
trying to be nice...
What do you want me to say, man?
That I don't think
you're a bigot?
Fine.
I don't think you're a bigot.
Shep, God. Please.
I'm not a racist.
You think I'm a racist?
Okay, you know what?
Just drink your coffee.
I ride with Raul
60 hours a week.
My sister dated a
black guy for two years.
Raul and I go to the Y
twice a week and play ball.
I'm the only white guy there.
I'm the only one.
I'm not a racist!
I'm not.
What do we have?
51-year-old with abdominal pain.
Mark figures it's
gastroenteritis,
but wants you
to rule out appendicitis.
The pain's getting worse.
Does it hurt here?
How about here?
No. Oh, God!
What's happening?
When did the pain
become this severe?
I don't know. I just walked in.
There. Better.
Chart back yet?
Chuny went to get them.
Keeps coming in waves.
How often?
About every minute.
Anybody do a pelvic exam?
Not yet.
Mrs. Saunders, when
was your last period?
Year and a half.
Oh, God! Here it comes again.
Okay, okay, look,
just put your legs up.
Her leg, grab her leg.
45 seconds apart.
Uh-huh.
She's fully dilated.
She's crowning.
She's what?
Get OB-GYN.
Somebody find Greene.
Don't push, okay?
Don't push. What's going on?
Get Mark fast. B.O.A.
Dr. Greene!
Dr. Greene! What's
happening to me?
You're not overeating, Mrs.
Saunders. You're in labor.
She's having a baby?
Where the hell is
everybody? Let's move!
She already went
through menopause.
Carla, honey, call Daddy. Oh!
Oh, God! Here it comes again.
Don't push.
No, don't push!
I haven't delivered a
baby since med school.
They showed us
a video in school.
Just guide the head.
Okay. First time
for everything, huh?
Okay. All right, Mrs.
Saunders. Okay, good girl.
Okay, breathe. Blow
through your mouth.
Okay, good. Okay, good.
She's doing better.
Guess I'm going to have to start
watching myself
around those nurses.
Yeah, we put her on dobutamine.
Hi. How are you feeling?
Very tired.
Dr. Carter is going to have you
back again dancing in no time.
But for now,
why don't you just try and
get some more rest, okay?
And you too, Ruby.
Why don't you go home
and get some sleep?
Oh, I...
I promised Helen I'd stay
until she could
come home with me.
Uh, Ruby, I think you should
at least consider
the possibility
that your wife may
need long-term care.
You don't know my Helen.
She's a real trouper.
A real trouper.
Right, sweetheart?
Uh...
this is my...
my beeper number.
If you need anything,
tonight or whenever, just...
give me a call.
Okay?
You're the only
person around here
who gives a damn.
Thank you,
for both of us.
Mark, you missed all the fun.
That fat lady had twins.
My abdominal pain?
In Curtain Area 3 over there.
You should have
seen Benton's face.
Benton?
That's why I was paging you.
We moved them up to Postpartum.
Mom is fine and
the babies are too.
Boy and a girl.
Loretta Sweet.
Biopsy came back.
Really?
Damn.
Stage 1B carcinoma.
Missed those annual pap smears.
She still around?
Left with her kids hours ago.
Call her. Get her back.
Already tried.
Number's disconnected.
Want me to send out a
social worker to round her up?
No.
You know her address?
1604...
North Sedgewick.
Out by Cabrini-Green somewhere.
Cervical cancer. That's tough.
Couple of kids.
Want me to give
you a ride out there?
No. I drove in today. Thanks.
Okay.
'96 is going to be a
hell of a year, huh?
Hi.
Hey.
Thanks.
I got you some pecan pie.
Looks good.
I don't like pecan pie.
Since when? Since never.
Thanks for meeting me.
You said it was important.
How's work going?
Uh, fine.
Your folks? They fine?
Yeah, they're fine too.
Look, Al, um...
I've been on my feet
since four o'clock
yesterday afternoon,
so if it's just the
same with you,
can we just...
Let's just do this
some other time.
Maybe we should
give it another try.
give us another try.
I'll have kids
if you really want them.
I've been thinking about
it, and kids would be okay.
Great.
Isn't that what you wanted?
Yeah, it was. I got to go.
I'm sorry.
I'm ready now.
Kids, being home...
No more playing around,
no more lies.
I got to go.
Michael, right?
Hey, I'm Dr. Benton.
We met earlier this morning,
remember?
Michael,
you're going to have
an operation tomorrow
for a hernia.
Do you know what a hernia is?
No.
It's when you have a balloon
poking out in your groin
below your belly button.
A balloon?
Well, not a real balloon,
but the part of your insides
that look like a balloon.
If we don't fix it,
you can get sick.
Will it hurt?
Nah, you'll be asleep.
But I'm scared.
That's all right.
It's okay to be scared.
You'll be fine.
I'm going to be
doing the operation.
You will?
Mm-hmm. It's no big deal.
A lot of kids have had it done.
Will you stay with
me for a while?
Yeah.
Sure.
Hi.
Did I wake you up?
Oh, uh, well, I
was on last night.
I'm sorry. I should have called.
No, no, that's okay.
Uh, Susie went down early,
so I just sacked
out on the couch.
I brought pizza and beer.
I should have called.
I'll see you at work tomorrow.
What kind of pizza?
Meat.
Lots of meat.
Pepperoni?
Probably some in there.
You have any
diapers left to change?
Always.
Hello?
Hello. This is John Carter.
Somebody beeped
me from this number?
Mr. Carter, this is Ruby.
Mr. Rubadoux.
Hi, Ruby.
How's she doing?
It's so late.
I'm sorry about the call.
Is it okay?
No, no, no. It's all right.
I told you you could call.
She's having trouble...
She's what?
She's having trouble breathing.
Oh, that's... that's...
that's normal.
Yeah, that's going to happen.
Yeah, I'll talk to the nurse.
Hi. This is Carter.
What's her pressure?