Previously on ER:
If we're gonna do this...
we have to do this together.
Remembering a dream I
had last night. Sam was in it.
- I don't beg.
- In my dream you did.
- This is Ortho.
- I start today.
Dr. Rasgotra, I'd like you to
meet doctors Ramsey, Craig.
Heard great things about you.
What position did you play?
- Center forward.
Love, trust, truth,
higher power.
You can't have any of those
without faith. Especially love.
No, this is your office.
Nice desk.
Ah. Imagine waking
up here every morning.
- Bettina, I can't afford this.
- Yes, you can. I did the math.
- You did the math?
- Mm-hm.
Time to move out of your med school
apartment and invest in something.
My apartment is fine.
- So, what do you think?
- Oh, it's beautiful.
Told you. The sellers did a
great job on the renovation.
The kitchen, the moldings,
these yummy floors.
Bamboo flown in from Brazil.
And there's a gym and a children's
game room in the basement.
You two got kids?
- No.
Listen, don't rush it.
When you're newlyweds and it's
just the two of you against the world...
well, you can't beat that.
Okay.
It'll be gone by the end of the
week, so if you're at all interested...
make an offer.
No, thanks.
- It's, uh, the first place he's seen.
- Think about it.
- I'll call you tomorrow.
- No, don't, please.
I'm just looking.
Hey, Sam.
- It wasn't just the battery.
- Where'd you get my keys?
- You also had alternator issues.
- You stole my keys and fixed my car?
I think the proper response
would be, "Thank you, Tony."
Also, I tightened the connections
and got you all charged up.
Ooh. That sounds like fun.
- Thought you were dating the chaplain.
- He's talking about my car.
Car.
She made a reasonable
assumption about our relationship...
and you had a seizure.
I wasn't feeling the
realtor. I wanted to get out.
We're adults. The topic of
commitment shouldn't be off-limits.
- It's not off-limits.
- Really?
You haven't looked me
in the eye since we left.
Come on, it's not like that.
- Pratt.
Hey, Pratt. There's a kid and an old
guy who've been pulled out of the lake.
- Take one with Grady.
- You got it.
Let's talk about
this later, okay?
You're admitting there's
something to talk about.
- Hey, Chaz, how you doing?
- Fine, thanks.
What up?
Robert Truman, 68. Jumped in
after a kid who fell into the lake.
Thought I could get
in and out. Too cold.
Heart rate's 68, pulse
ox good. Temp was 90.
- My lungs froze up, couldn't swim.
- Does anything hurt, sir?
I'm fine. Take care of the boy.
- Barely moving air.
- Too cold, can't get a sat.
- Twenty-four gauge PIV, that's it?
- He needs central access.
- Mom is here. It's okay.
This is your fault.
You made this happen.
He needed my help. I
thought if I could only do...
Why won't you leave us alone?
- No, I'm sorry, I tried to...
- Stay away from my son.
- He's hypoventilating.
- We need to bag him.
- Doctor, please take care of that child.
- We're gonna concentrate on you now.
If you wanna help me,
you need to help that boy.
- Mr. Truman...
- Please save him.
Save him or I'm going to hell.
The nurse wants to bump our
meniscus repair until tomorrow.
Tell her to kiss your ass,
or maybe mine. She's cute.
- What's up, Ortho girl?
- Morris, what are you doing here?
- I'm a surgeon for the day.
- What?
Yep, it's the ER's new
trauma-exchange program.
- I never heard anything about this.
- ER staff can spend a day...
following trauma
patients to the O.R.
- You gonna scrub in on cases?
- Hope so.
Be good and Harold might
let you hold his retractor.
Definitely. MORRIS: Ha-ha.
Dude, I gotta go. There's
like a hundred doctors here.
- After you.
- No, after you.
Rasgotra, you're up.
Silas is our snowmobile versus
brick wall. Post op day one...
She's so cute, isn't she?
- Day one from laparotomy...
- With her little accent.
Hemoglobin's stable, slept well.
Got a chest x-ray. No infiltrates.
Mild atelectasis bilaterally.
- Okay.
- That means areas of collapsed alveoli.
We know what atelectasis is.
It's probably nothing, but I can
repeat the film this afternoon.
Okay.
Hey, what's the definition
of a double-blind study?
- Two ortho docs looking at a chest film.
- Zing.
Don't pretend that's not
funny. You taught me that joke.
Oh, my God, I love this girl.
He was collecting samples
from the lake for a science project.
- Something about algae in winter.
- Core temp's 74.3.
More suction, please.
Then that man just appears
out of nowhere again.
Tube.
He's been to the store,
trying to talk to me while I work.
I thought he was just
some lonely old guy.
And yesterday, I saw
him outside of my house.
Then when he saw me
looking, he just walked away.
And then today at the lake...
I went there to tell
him to stay away.
I told him I was
gonna call the police.
Gabriel must have slipped
in while my back was turned.
I have no idea how long he
was there before I realized.
That man jumped in after him?
He said, "Call 911,"
and then he just jumped.
Sam, call Respiratory for a vent
and set up for bilateral chest tubes.
Have Central bring in a
circulating-water blanket.
- He'll do better with a Bair Hugger.
- Both work.
- Bair Hugger's better.
- Show me the data.
You kids work it out.
You guys all right in here?
Yeah, his core temp's up to 94, but
his EKG shows ischemic changes.
Could have been caused
by the strain of the cold swim.
- Hey.
- These flattened T waves.
I've had those for years.
It's definitely not an MI.
I'm a doctor. Retired six years,
but I can still read an EKG.
Okay, well, let us check
your troponins just in case.
- Yeah, just knock yourself out.
- Where'd you practice?
Stateville, 12 years.
- Stateville Penitentiary?
- Yes.
Bet that was intense.
You guys seem fine.
- I'm going back in with the kid.
- How is he?
- I can't talk about his treatment.
- Of course.
Hey. Fun rounding
with you this morning.
- Hi, Archie.
- Want some advice?
- No.
- You need to work on your style.
- Excuse me?
- Yeah, you're too serious.
Have fun, take
some joy in your work.
- I'm fun.
- You're English.
I get it. It's hard to let your hair
down. You are in America now.
You know, I don't know what
you're basing this on since...
You know how hard it was
to find a jersey that small?
- Hockey?
- See? I'm fun.
We're gonna finish
then head to the rink.
Oh, Neela, this is so hot.
- Can you do a triple axel?
- Dude, that's figure skating.
- Oh. GROSSMAN:
You friends with that guy?
- Sort of.
- Oh, tell the truth. We slept together.
She gave me a rash.
- Hey, I'm sorry about the last few days.
- Oh, hey.
I've been working 11 a.m. to 11
p.m., which is like falling off the planet.
It's okay. I've
been slammed too.
I'm leading a seminar at the
CAHC tomorrow and I'm way behind.
What's CAHC?
Complementary Alternative
Health Conference.
- I told you all about it.
- You didn't.
You may have been
in a post-coital stupor.
But I am presenting data on
the effects of prayer on healing.
- They actually have data on that?
- Yes. Ahem.
Several studies have shown that patients
who have people praying for them...
get well faster than
those who don't.
- Ooh. Spooky.
- Shut up, the results are cool.
When you get a minute, I
got a guy for you in Trauma.
No, no, not another consult.
I have to get this talk
together or I'm screwed.
He saved a kid from
drowning in a lake.
The kid's not doing so
well and he's freaked out.
Come on, now.
Okay. I have a baby-naming
ceremony in the NICU...
and then I am meeting
with a statistician...
to go over the
slides for the talk.
I'll come back after that.
- Thank you.
- Chest x-ray on Robert Truman.
- Good.
- You're kidding me.
- Ugly, right?
- Yeesh. Who's that?
- Old lake guy.
Order a chest CT and I'll
get an official read on that.
Tell me you don't need a
radiologist to see this film is abnormal.
- Diffuse lung nodules, I know.
- Lung mets.
I called you to get your
take on the differential...
before I go in there and tell the
man he has metastatic cancer.
Couldn't it be miliary TB or
cocci or sarcoid or something?
Yeah, but in a 68-year-old
guy, odds are it's gonna be mets.
- Great.
- So anything else?
Guess not.
Thanks for the consult.
Dr. Truman.
Robert, please.
In your days as a prison doc, did
you ever get tested positive for TB?
No, I had the PPD
every four months.
Any coughing,
fevers, night sweats?
Huh. The chest x-ray.
Metastatic prostate cancer.
It spread to my lungs and my
bones before I even knew I had it.
- I'm sorry.
- Well, I guess it's my retribution.
Excuse me?
When men try to do God's
work, bad things happen.
I wish I'd realized this
before I killed that boy's father.
Another run of V-tach.
Two hundred of bretylium
and start an infusion.
- Core temp's down to 71.
- He's getting colder?
Cold blood in his extremities...
rushes up to his heart
and drops the core temp.
Your Bair Hugger
worked a little too well.
His heart can't beat
normally at this temperature.
Sam, call the ECMO tech.
Don't you think that's jumping the
gun? What about peritoneal lavage?
- What's ECMO?
- Cardiac bypass.
It's the only thing that's
gonna warm the core.
It's too dangerous.
His temperature is 71.
He's having runs of V-tach.
- We're there.
- Bleeding, infection...
- He knows the risks.
- Thank you.
But I'm with Sam. Gabriel's
got a pulse and a decent BP.
Exhaust all options
before jumping to ECMO.
I'll get the stuff.
Put a tube in belly and flush warm fluids
to see if we can raise his core temp.
- Hey, Sam, what's with you today?
- Nothing.
- Then why do you have to plan B me?
- Plan B you?
Whatever I say, you
have a better idea.
- That's not true.
- Yeah, Sam, it is true.
Bair Hugger versus water
blanket. Morphine versus fentanyl.
Okay, come on, you sound crazy.
Whatever I want,
you give me that look.
- What look?
- That look, that one, right there.
I don't accept orders
from someone...
because they come
from a doctor or a man.
I've been doing this a
lot longer than you have.
If you don't like
that, it's too bad.
Back at Stateville, my job
was to give lethal injections...
to death-row inmates.
- Wow, that's heavy.
- Yes.
People could watch
through a window.
And I remember...
I remember her.
Trying to be brave for the
baby as I injected the thiopental...
the Pavulon...
potassium.
Gabriel was only 2.
He never knew his dad.
Dr. Truman, you don't
really have to talk about this.
No.
Back then, I thought
it was the right thing.
I thought there were
criminals who deserved to die...
and lethal injection was
the most humane way.
As time went on, my
thinking's changed.
About the death penalty?
Who lives and dies should
be decided by God, not a jury.
I've spent the
last five years...
tracking the loved ones
of the men I've killed.
Trying to make amends
with those families.
And how do you make amends?
Financial aid, mostly.
It's all I have to offer.
I paid a mortgage, bought
a car, sent a child to college.
Some people told me to get lost.
Others took what I could offer.
Well, that's really brave.
- And generous.
- No.
They're all acts of contrition.
Small things.
Nothing will ever bring back
a husband or a son, father.
Saving a kid's life
isn't a small thing.
I'm just trying to tell God how
sorry I am for what I've done.
Please.
I need that boy to live.
Tell that freak to
stop staring at me.
Not many people would jump
in a frozen lake for a stranger.
- He's not a stranger, he's a stalker.
- V-tach, lost the pulse.
- Starting compressions.
- Oh, my God. What's happening?
His heart has stopped
beating effectively.
We can't shock it
back until he's warmer.
This looks like the right room.
- Who called for ECMO?
The conservative route wouldn't
work so I gave Teddy the heads-up.
Put him on. This is a
cardiopulmonary bypass machine.
It will function as
Gabriel's heart and lungs.
- Sam, you should've listened to me.
- Well, let's hope it works.
Celia, do you have any
family we need to call?
Or Gabriel's dad?
- His dad's been dead a couple years.
- How about your family?
Father's out of the picture.
Haven't talked to my mother.
Anspaugh's on his way to cannulate.
- Do it here.
- Surgery has to. It's protocol.
- Chief is coming for a central line?
They're a little short-staffed today.
All up at a big conference or something.
- Yeah, let's do this, let's go.
- Rasgotra, isn't this fun?
Uh, especially the part where I get
to see my Attending in his jock strap.
Okay, go.
I'm streaking to the blue
line in the dump and chase.
- What do you do?
- Head to the far corner, dump in the net.
- That is exactly right.
- Okay, everybody, listen up.
Smart, aggressive, no mercy.
Smart, aggressive, no mercy. Smart...
Machine is doing the
work for his heart and lungs.
We're gonna take
out the breathing tube.
I see.
When his temp's up, his
own heart will kick back in.
Well, that's the hope.
What do you mean,
that's the hope?
Well, I'm sure Dr. Gates has
explained that Gabriel's tissues...
may be permanently
damaged because of the cold.
I explained that, but we're
trying to think positive here.
Right.
Look, we all hope this brings him
back, but he's been down for a long time.
Did over an hour of CPR.
Celia, call someone.
A friend, family, it doesn't matter.
You just need some support.
You don't know what I need.
I'm a single mom.
I know asking for help feels
like cheating sometimes.
Jimmy, Gabriel's dad...
he was one of those guys
who couldn't stay out of trouble.
Running drugs, stealing cars.
I was an idiot. I
thought he'd change.
That's human.
And I told my mom Jimmy and I
were gonna raise the baby together...
and she kicked
me out of the house.
She said, "You may be lost...
but I am not gonna have a guy
like that around the rest of my kids."
Looking back, she
was probably right.
Celia, there's a very good chance
that Gabriel's heart won't start up again.
No, please, please don't
say that. This is gonna work.
Guys, I need another
liter of NS and an ABG kit.
Okay. Yeah, I got it.
And check an ionized calcium while
you're at it. The last one was low.
555-0172.
That's my mom.
Could you call her?
Right away.
Yeah!
Game on.
- Who are we playing?
- Pedes, I think.
I saw the pathologists
practicing in the parking lot.
And now, the starting lineup...
of County General's very own.
Unstoppable, irrepressible,
the Mighty Docs.
Playing right wing,
Lucien Dubenko.
They are such drama queens.
We're playing the
trauma surgeons?
Beat them in the last five
seconds of the finals last year.
Left wing, Dusty Crenshaw.
Oh, my God.
On defense, Harold Zelinsky.
Playing center:
- Archie Morris.
- Oh, no way.
- Way.
- Oh, this explains everything.
Weird behavior, the program...
Ruse to play on this
team and kick your ass.
- He's a ringer.
- Yeah, baby, huh?
I had a 26-year-old kid on the
table, convicted of killing a cop.
I could see his family,
pleading, praying.
I injected the drugs
and he didn't die.
He lay there, awake, quivering.
Lethal doses of three different
agents and he was still alive.
Parents were crying,
claiming a miracle.
- What happened?
- The IV infiltrated.
The drugs pooled in his soft tissues
instead of going into his bloodstream.
So I placed another IV, drew up
another round of meds and pushed.
And this time...
it took him 90 seconds to die.
Seven months later, a
police officer came forward.
The boy was framed
for the murder. Hm?
He didn't do it.
You couldn't have known that.
God tried to stop me from
killing an innocent man...
and I ignored the sign.
How can I even
hope for forgiveness?
I think...
sometimes it's easier to
feel guilty than forgiven.
Which means what?
That maybe your guilt over these
deaths has become your reason for living.
Maybe you need a
new reason to go on.
I don't want to go on.
Can't you see I'm old? I
have cancer. I've had enough.
The only thing that is holding
me back is that I am afraid.
- I'm afraid of what comes next.
- And what do you think that is?
Oh, you tell me.
Is atonement even possible?
What does God want from me?
I think it's up to each one of
us to interpret what God wants.
So people can do anything?
They can rape, murder, steal, all
in the name of God and it's okay?
- No, that's not what I'm saying.
- What are you saying?
Because all I'm hearing is some new-age,
God-is-love, one-size-fits-all crap.
- Hey, Dr. Truman...
- No, I don't have time for this now.
Greg, it's okay.
- Look, I understand...
- No, you don't understand.
You don't understand.
How could you possibly say
that? Now, you listen to me.
I want a real chaplain who
believes in a real God and a real hell.
You're frustrated, but
you need to ask yourself...
No, I don't need to ask
myself. I need answers.
And all your questions
and your uncertainty...
are only making things worse.
- I know you're upset.
- God.
I need someone who
will look me in the eye...
and tell me how to find forgiveness
because I am running out of time.
- I'm trying to help.
- Well, don't. Just get out.
Get out! Get out!
Hey, Julia. Julia, come
on. Listen, come on.
Come on, the guy's just freaking
out. He didn't mean what he said.
Yeah, he did. He absolutely did.
Okay, don't choke,
Neela. Don't cough it up.
It would be real embarrassing
if you lost that puck to me.
Neela. MAN 2: Yes. Stay down.
Yes!
Get up!
Oh, let's see. Your eye, crap.
Concentration, crap.
Coordination, crap.
How do we let this girl operate?
Hit me. Come on, hit me.
- You know you wanna.
- I don't.
- Come on, hit me.
- Lucien.
Everybody wants to take a
shot at their mentor, don't they?
Ha!
Come on, Neela. Untie the
piano, you'll skate faster, huh?
Ah! Oh, no.
Go, go, go.
I got it. I got it.
I got it.
Neela, you're dead.
Whoo!
Hey, Gates, hold on. Have
you seen Julia around?
- No, not since this morning.
- She's not answering her pager.
She usually turns it off
when she's with patients.
This guy in 1, it's a mess.
Do you have any questions
for us, Mrs. Davies?
No, Celia explained it all. She
always had a head for science.
Gabriel does too.
He wants to be a
marine biologist.
ACT is 224.
- Let's keep the heparin where it's at.
- You sure you wanna do that?
Never mind.
What are you doing here?
I wanted to let you know...
- You can't be here.
- Please, I want to say...
Get out. Please, just go.
- Maybe you should just go back to bed.
- Hold on, Sam, hold on.
Look, ma'am, he tried
to save your son's life.
Just give him a chance to
say what he came to say.
And afterwards you'll give
this family their privacy, right?
Yes.
Sorry.
I'm sorry for all the
trouble I've caused.
I'm praying for your boy.
Sir, thank you for your
bravery. I'm very grateful.
So is my daughter.
Right, Celia?
Celia, tell him.
Tell this man thank you.
Thank you.
Like you mean it.
I am not 3 years old
anymore. I have to call work.
That's... That's all.
Come on, let me get
you back on the monitor.
- Lucien, five hole or top shelf?
- I don't care, just make it count.
We need a goalie here.
Hey, you guys ever
seen Neela drunk?
You should have seen her
at the ER Christmas party.
She gave Anspaugh
a lap dance. Woo-hoo.
Could have blocked that with
a wad of toilet paper, Morris.
I hear she still sleeps with a
blankie. She calls it her nubbie.
What the hell are
you talking about?
Whoa!
Nice. MORRIS: That's right.
Your career as a
goalie doesn't pan out...
you can go back to
work at the Jumbo Mart.
You guys know she used to
work at the Jumbo Mart, right?
Hey, Skye.
Have you seen Julia around?
- No.
- She had trouble...
with one of my patients
and went AWOL.
- What happened?
- Are you ready for this one?
My guy in 1 gave a lethal injection
to the father of your boy in 2.
- What?
- He was a prison doctor.
He used to push the drugs
into the guys on death row.
I guess he's had a change
of heart. Excuse me.
Hey, Chaz, hey. Hey, man.
Hey, Celia.
- Everything all right?
- Yeah.
Yeah, it's just work, you know?
I guess she wants a
commitment, but I don't know.
Maybe I'm not that kind of guy.
So why don't you
just tell her that?
Bettina's great.
It's not like I'm looking
for something better.
You been together
for a while now.
- Yeah, nine months.
- Hm!
That must be a record for you.
I like her, all right?
So that's not the issue.
Well, why don't you just give
it a try and see what happens?
It's easy for you to say.
You're 20 years old
and still playing the field.
Greg, I've been with the
same guy for almost a year now.
Really? Why didn't
you tell me that before?
- You never asked.
- All right, well, I should take these.
- Cool, thanks for the coffee.
- Oh, anytime.
Hey, what's his name?
- Andrew.
- Well, I'd like to meet him sometime.
We can all go to a
drag club or something.
Ha! Just kidding,
man. That'd be cool.
What you got?
Mass cas at the ice rink.
Ortho versus Trauma.
What? CRENSHAW: You.
You were a complete
goon out there.
- I hit you because you elbowed me.
- Headhunter.
- Octopus - Slasher.
- Can't we all just get along?
- Rasgotra, this isn't over.
I saved your ass so
many times out there.
Well, maybe I wouldn't have
to if you weren't such a goon.
You should
practice a little more.
You've had plenty of
practice swinging stick.
Could you lay down? I don't
recognize you standing up.
Hey, get off of him, you wanker.
The ECMO tech needs you in
T-2 right away. That kid's awake.
Cripes!
What's going on?
We see this after a few hours on
the machine. They just wake up.
Sat's okay on room air.
Mommy? What happened?
Oh, baby.
Hi, baby, hi. You're okay.
- Attaboy, Gabriel.
- Oh, thank God.
- He's okay. He's gonna be okay.
- I know, baby.
Core temp's up to 94.
This family will never forget
what you did here today.
Just doing our job.
Well, I don't care what
you say. It's a miracle.
What do you say we take
this kid off the machine?
- Sounds good.
- Size 8 gloves okay?
Looks like good news in there.
This doesn't absolve you.
Don't think it does.
I don't forgive you.
I will never forgive you.
You have to live with
what you've done.
Julia.
Well, the lake
kid is doing great.
But our guy...
He needs you in there.
I can't.
All right, well, I
need you in there.
He's asking me all kind of questions
that I don't know how to answer.
You know, doubt...
it's uncomfortable.
But certainty...
I don't think it's real.
I mean, I went to seminary.
I studied Buddhism, I
spent time at an ashram.
Who really knows anything
with absolute certainty?
Not me, that's for sure.
That's why I thought an
inclusive approach to spirituality...
would work well
in a place like this.
It does. It does.
The patients, they
appreciate what you do.
No, people in crisis want
rules. They want structure.
Something to
lean on, I get that.
But it's not me.
You know, we all wonder what
we're doing here sometimes.
That guy needs help.
So come on.
Come back in there with
me. Let's go talk to him.
I don't think so.
All right.
Ramsey, did you
trip over the blue line?
Yeah, fell on me.
Morris, hurt yourself
doing a triple axel?
So who won?
It was a mutual forfeit.
- Didn't know you had it in you, Mayday.
- Me neither.
- X-ray's negative, home with splint.
- All right, who's next?
Hey, Neela, how's your boo-boo?
It's my dominant hand.
- If I can't operate, you're dead.
- Wuss.
You hack.
Beyotch.
- Who are you yelling at, Harold?
- I don't really know.
- No tenderness, bearing weight.
- Hey, how's my team?
They need ibuprofen, a
hot tub and a glass of wine.
- I like the way you think.
- Okay, listen up, everyone, fun's over.
Orthopods are rounding
on the hall in 10.
- Trauma to the ICU.
- What about me?
There's an ingrown toenail in
Exam 3 with your name on it.
Sam. What's up, buddy,
you sick of us down here?
No, I like it.
- You like it? You're a weird kid.
- He likes the Jell-O.
Thanks again, doctor.
You're welcome. You take
care of your mom, okay?
Sam, any beds open up?
Well, I had to threaten the
charge nurse with physical violence.
But something opened up.
All right, we're going to Ike
Ryan's. You should come.
- Should I?
- Yeah.
As long as if I order you a beer,
you don't change it to vodka gimlet.
I don't know. I have to report
upstairs. I gotta do stuff here.
How often do we get
an outcome like this?
A pulseless ice
cube turned into a
Jell-O-loving 11-year-old
in the same shift.
- That doesn't happen every day.
- That's for sure.
- Well?
- Well, I'll see if I can make it.
I have sinned against heaven.
And in your sight
are no more worthy.
Gracious God.
My mortal sentence I accept.
Stop.
- What the hell are you doing?
- I am in hell.
Do you understand? I am in
hell already. I might as well go.
Listen to me. You
saved a little boy's life.
No, it is not enough. I
can't change my destiny.
There isn't time.
Did it ever occur to
you that your destiny...
was for you to be on
that pier this morning?
That maybe your life's path and
all the choices that you made...
led you right there.
- Why?
- So you could save that kid.
Why? Why would God do that?
Why would he have me
kill 17 people to save one?
You may not understand it...
but that little boy is alive
because you were there.
Now, whatever you need
that to count for, it counts.
It doesn't make sense.
It doesn't have to make sense.
That's why it's called faith.
All right.
- Hey, guys.
- Hey, Sam, great job today.
- Thank you, you too.
- Hey, Gabriel all tucked in?
Yes. The ICU nurses
are fawning all over him.
- My turn to win some money.
- All right.
- So, what are you drinking?
- Actually, I can't stay.
So you came here to tell
me that you can't come here?
- Yeah.
- Really?
Have you heard
of the cell phone?
You know what, you're right. It's dumb.
I shouldn't have come. I wasn't thinking.
Wow, she admits that she
wasn't thinking. Alert the media.
- Screw you, Gates.
- Come on, stay here.
Will you get her a beer, please?
- You got it.
Vodka gimlet with a twist.
- Okay.
Definitely the most insane shift
I've worked since I started here.
You said that exact
same thing yesterday.
I did not.
So are you going
to Ike's after this?
No, I'm not much
of a group person.
I need my alone time
at the end of the day.
Is that why you're not married?
No.
Then why isn't a hot, smart woman
such as yourself shacked up by now?
And I'm not hitting on you.
Just wondering if some people
aren't cut out for commitment.
Nobody's cut out for commitment.
It fights our DNA.
- You don't believe in monogamy?
- No, I believe in monogamy.
I just don't believe in
the concept of forever.
People force the issue and then
act surprised when it doesn't work out.
You know, some people
might say that your theory...
is a cover for a
fear of commitment.
Well, it takes a lot
of courage to reject...
the widely embraced
social construct of marriage.
Most people assume you've
got some kind of problem.
Well, seems like you've
got it all figured out.
Some days.
- Night, Skye.
- Night.
How'd you hurt your shoulder?
Checked by Grossman after the
face-off. But I hurt him worse later.
Ever seen bonobos at the zoo?
What's a bonobo?
Pygmy chimp.
Famous in the primate world
for their social-sexual behavior.
How fascinating.
In bonobo communities...
sex is a way to say hello.
- Oh, really?
- Mm-hm.
Hello.
- This is so awesome. NEELA:
I didn't know these were here.
Hot tubs are for therapy
during the day, but night?
They belong to the hockey team.
Lucien, Skye, how's the water?
Hot, very hot.
Guys, this job rocks.
I'm not sure what the
point of that would be...
other than to make him feel
guilty on top of everything else.
Uh, I gotta go. Okay, bye.
- Hey.
What's up?
We need to talk.
I'm sorry about this morning,
okay? You had the right to be mad.
Apology accepted.
Look...
This is all new to me, okay?
I haven't been down
this path before.
But I really, really
want this to work.
Do you know if you stare at an
x-ray for more than 38 seconds...
you start to see
things that aren't there?
Because that's
what's this is, Greg.
We've stared at
this thing too long...
and tricked ourselves into
seeing something that isn't there.
You're not listening,
okay? I wanna do this.
This morning, you
seemed totally unsure.
Who's sure about anything?
This shouldn't
have to be this hard.
Eventually you know we would
end up right back in the same place.
And frankly, I
don't have the time.
- Thank you for waiting with me.
- No problem.
Oh.
ECMO was a good
call with that kid.
We probably should
have done it sooner.
It's annoying but
you were right.
Thank you.
And, Sam, I do like
working with you.
Other than the relentless
interrogation and second-guessing...
and you constantly
blowing me off...
- Shut up.
- When I give you orders.
I hate you.
I hate you too.