- Morning.
- I don't know...
- Hey!
- Hi, Dad.
Oh, sorry, Mom. I've got to go.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
What'd I do?
Nothing.
You are perfect.
- Bye, honey.
- Bye. See you this evening.
- How are you feeling?
- Fantastic.
They're giving me the
steroids in the infusion.
So I feel like I could run a marathon.
Look what I found.
Hmm?
Remember that trip we took
to Mackinac Island
when Robin was three?
No cars, nothing but horses.
I remember
that "Rainbow Brite" t-shirt.
Nothing but saltwater taffy
and ice cream.
What a trip. That was a great trip.
No, it wasn't, Danny.
You were horribly depressed.
You stayed in the hotel
room, laid in the bed,
and stared at the ceiling.
I kept telling Robin that
you wouldn't come down,
because Daddy didn't feel good.
- Hmm.
- Wow.
I mean, I remember maybe
a couple of dark days.
But, um, on the whole, uh,
didn't... didn't we have...
Danny, what are you doing?
I just thought you'd like
seeing these pictures.
That's all, you know.
I know you were trying
to rewrite history
to paint a pretty picture
of a happy marriage and it
wasn't always like that.
It's pure fantasy, Danny.
I know Med is not
a for-profit organization...
But this report?
If my board saw numbers like this,
they'd be calling for a
vote of no confidence.
Mr. Rhodes, you can see
that one reason
for our fiscal issues is
the E.D.'s Hybrid Room
which you only partially funded.
I think the rest of the
Board would agree with me
that my contributions have
been more than generous.
No, in fact, what I'm seeing
is a lot of your pet projects
not working out so well.
Let's look at the refurbishment
of the VIP wing.
A lot of empty beds there.
After Dr. Downey's death,
we became less of a... a... a
destination hospital
for our CT patients.
We're still in the
process of re-branding.
But in the meantime, since you
were such a vocal advocate
of the Hybrid O.R., Sharon,
it seems only fair that
you should find cuts
in other departments to make
up for some of our losses.
Well, I will certainly
take a look.
But I'd hate to put us in legal jeopardy
or lose our reputation
as the premier medical
center of the Midwest.
Well said, Sharon.
Very, very well said.
We certainly would not want that.
Mom, seriously, I'm fine.
That's not what
you said this morning.
You could hardly get out of bed.
Jenny Simpson, 17.
Abdominal pain.
Hi. I'm Dr. Manning.
This is Dr. Choi.
Hi.
Mom and dad?
Uh, E... Evie.
That's my husband, Joel.
Hi.
This is so unnecessary.
It... it was probably that sketchy
salad I had last night.
Remember I said it smelled weird?
Jenny's been in pain since we
left Fort Wayne three days ago.
Hoosiers, huh?
Winter getaway?
College tour.
Jenny got into Northwestern.
Perfect SATs.
Wow, congratulations.
Jenny, are you feeling any nausea?
I mean, a little
but I'm better now.
I don't know why you
guys are freaking...
Oh, honey.
We thought maybe appendicitis.
No rebound tenderness.
BP 100/62.
Heart rate 103.
I told you it... it's just
food poisoning.
All right, well, I'd still
like to do a quick ultrasound
just to see if I can get a
visual on the appendix, okay?
- An ultrasound?
- Mm-hmm.
- It'll just take a second.
- No, I... I don't want that.
- Honey.
- I want to go.
Jenny, appendicitis is serious,
but it's easily treatable
if we catch it early.
But I have to take a
look to do that, okay?
Jenny.
Okay.
I guess.
Great.
Well, good news is, it
doesn't look like appendicitis.
So what is it?
Well, it's hard to tell just yet.
But I would like to run some tests
just to rule a few things
out if that's all right.
- Oh, of course.
- Yeah, absolutely.
Monique, CBC, BMP, coags
and a quant hCG.
Mm-hmm.
We'll be back to check in
once we get the test results in.
Thank you.
Did you see how scared she got
when I mentioned the ultrasound?
Yeah, she was pretty defensive.
- You thinking what I'm thinking?
- Pregnancy?
Thinking an endometrium,
but I didn't see an embryo.
Well, she could've had
a miscarriage or an abortion.
But whatever it is,
she is definitely trying to
keep her parents in the dark.
Yeah, but I don't think
that's going to be possible.
- Heads up, Maggie.
There's probably going to be
more spending cuts coming down.
More?
Gwen hasn't met her goals
and she's feeling the heat.
We're already short-staffed.
We're using those cheapo
central line kits.
What more does Gwen want?
- Oh, speak of the devil.
- Oh.
She's got a big fish
coming into the VIP wing.
Ooh!
Wow!
Oh, man, I love it.
Thanks.
It's a lot easier to manage.
Hey.
New hairdo?
It looks good.
Uh, so we still on? Drinks for tonight?
Um, I'm sorry.
I can't. Something came up.
Something?
Yeah.
Um, tomorrow then?
Uh, that's not going
to work either.
This weekend?
Can I let you know?
Yeah.
No big deal.
New hairdo?
Women don't do that for no reason.
I'm guessing there's a guy.
You're suddenly an expert
on women.
Too bad, Choi.
I'll be using what's
called the "David Procedure"
to resect your aneurysm.
It will allow us to
preserve your native valve.
Our Chief of CT, Dr. Latham,
is going to be assisting
me on the operation.
Uh, do you have any questions, concerns?
No concerns.
My people did their research.
You were at the top of the list,
just under the late Dr. Downey.
Dr. Rhodes was
Dr. Downey's star protégé.
I'm aware.
I wanted to let you know,
Mr. Montero,
that as you recuperate, we can
offer you spa-like amenities.
Massage, facials.
With your doctor's
permission, of course.
We also have a concierge
at your disposal.
Here is a list of all
our personal services
and our menu options.
You can almost forget
you're in the hospital.
Why is Dr. Rhodes scheduled
to operate on Mr. Montero?
It's out of my hands.
Dr. Rhodes is
on the trauma service.
I'm the attending in CT.
Mr. Montero's case should've come to me.
Dr. Bekker,
Mr. Montero specifically
requested Dr. Rhodes
and Mr. Montero gets what he wants.
Jenny Simpson's test results.
What's going on with you and Phillip?
Are you seeing him?
You know, like, seeing him, seeing him?
Mm-hmm.
I thought it
was headed that way.
He is a lovely guy, Maggie.
But so is Big Red.
It is way more complicated
than that and you know it.
Ethan.
Jenny, where are your parents?
They went to get coffee.
We have to ask you something.
Jenny, we got your blood work back
and it indicates pregnancy.
No, I'm not pregnant.
- Let us explain.
- I'm not pregnant.
We understand how hard this is.
But your test results and your symptoms
shows that maybe you
had a miscarriage or...
No. No, I didn't.
I don't want to talk about it.
Jenny, in order for us
to treat you properly,
we really need to know what happened.
Please, we are not here
to judge you.
- No.
- We want to help you.
The whole thing was stupid.
So stupid.
When I found out that I was pregnant,
I didn't know what to do.
I'm finishing high school
and I'm going to college.
I understand.
So I went online and... and
I read about these pills.
And what were they?
Mife-something.
Mifepristone?
Did you take the follow
up pill Misoprostol?
I couldn't get it.
Not without a doctor.
Jenny, that's why
you're in so much pain.
Without the second pill, you
haven't fully aborted yet.
Help me.
Please.
Just don't tell my parents.
They'll hate me and
they'll never forgive me.
Please.
I think you might be
underestimating them.
No, I know them
and you can't tell them.
Jenny, I'm sorry...
We're not going to tell
your parents
but I am going to give
you the second pill
so that you can expel whatever
is left in your uterus, okay?
- Thank you.
- Yeah.
Nat, she's a minor.
We can't give her medications
without her parents' consent.
Yes, we can.
Uh, Dr. Manning?
Have you found out what's
wrong with our daughter?
Uh, we were actually
just discussing that.
Unfortunately we're still
waiting on some test results.
The best thing you can do
right now is just be patient.
Wait... wait, that's it?
You have no idea?
I know how frustrating
this must be
but I promise you, we are doing
everything possible for Jenny.
I'm sure that you are.
Come on, hon.
What do you think you're doing?
I'm honoring my patient's wishes.
- And lying to her parents?
- I did not lie to them.
You withheld the truth, Nat.
They have a right to know.
A legal right.
That's Jenny's call.
If you have a problem with
it, take it up with Goodwin.
Dr. Lanik, FBI medics
have landed.
April, you're up.
FBI?
Special Agent Sam Pearson.
Low speed motor vehicle collision.
GCS 10, LOC on site,
nasal airway in place.
Hey, I know this guy.
Let me work him up.
Self-starter.
Who am I to interfere?
Okay, on my count.
One, two, three.
Hang in there, Sam. I got you.
- What's the story?
- Air bags deployed,
but his chest caught most of the impact.
He's not protecting
his airway, got to intubate.
20 of etomidate, 100 of sux.
Get an x-ray in here.
Meds are in.
Heart rate 124, BP 132/88,
sats 95.
I'm in.
Bag him.
Good breath sounds bilaterally.
Let's get that chest X-ray.
Yes, Doctor.
Clear.
Chest shows multiple rib fractures
and bilateral pulmonary contusions.
I need a CBC, CMP, blood gas, and coags.
I'm seeing PVCs on the monitor.
Got it.
Is he going to be okay?
Ingrid.
He's in rough shape, but stable for now.
Were you with him?
Yeah.
- Let me check you out.
- No, I'm fine. I'm fine.
Just... just keep my partner alive.
Dr. Manning boxed us
into this situation.
You want to talk about boxed in?
The only reason we're in this situation
is because Jenny had no options.
The family lives in Indiana.
Where she would need
parental consent.
And she was afraid
to talk to them,
so there was nowhere else to go
so she went online to find medication.
This generation's back alley abortion.
We don't make the laws
but we have to obey them.
Jenny's a minor and that means
we have to tell her parents
before we treat.
No, her pregnancy test
is still positive.
Therefore, under the
law, she is emancipated.
She was pregnant.
Not anymore.
Uh, technically she still is.
Ms. Goodwin.
I'll admit it's a thin argument.
Emancipation covers a woman's decisions
regarding her pregnancy,
but, uh, my understanding
is that Ms. Simpson has
already made her choice.
So we betray this girl's trust?
Well, that's not what
I'm suggesting.
We have to obey the law
and tell her parents.
Oh, that's not
exactly right either.
If we had provided a medical abortion,
which we didn't, then yes.
The state of Illinois says
we're obligated to inform the parents.
But since she obtained
the medication herself
out-of state, I'm not so sure.
So you intend to keep
the parents in the dark
based on a technicality?
No, because our patient asked
us to keep it confidential.
Look, I would suggest
you continue to treat her
according to her wishes
until our lawyers make a determination.
Thank you, Ms. Goodwin.
Why are you here?
I'm scrubbing in on your surgery.
No, Dr. Latham is assisting.
He reconsidered.
So just like that, he pulled out.
- What did you say to him?
- Really, Connor?
Why wasn't I consulted?
Don't worry.
It's been made very clear to me
that Mr. Montero is your patient.
I'm only here as your humble assistant.
By the way, I had my last HIV test.
I'm clear.
I'm glad to hear it.
Since you were the one who
so carelessly cut me,
I thought you might be.
How is she?
Cuts and scrapes.
Nothing serious.
Ingrid.
How's Sam?
Wait and see right now.
Can I get you anything?
No.
Haven't seen you at
the dog park lately.
It's... work.
I'll keep you posted on Sam.
Where are we?
The PVCs were all unifocal,
but his airway pressures are bad.
PaO2's at 50
and peak pressure's at 55.
All this from a car crash?
They said he wasn't
even going that fast.
He shouldn't be this sick.
Crank the O2 and
increase his PEEP to 12.
See if we can improve his oxygenation.
Okay.
These bruises.
They don't look like
they're from an air bag.
They're too extensive.
The air bag shouldn't
have touched his legs.
We still waiting on those CT scans?
Radiology's been slammed
all morning.
Get him moved up.
Don't take no for an answer.
These injuries just don't add up.
You got it.
Proximal anastomosis done.
I'm working on the distal now.
Temp's coming up.
33 degrees.
We need to move faster.
Look, I realize that,
but the graft is coming down unevenly.
If I keep tugging, I
could tear the aorta.
A suggestion?
What?
Try pulling on the
non-coronary commissure.
I think that'll move the
graft into proper position.
Okay.
That did it, thank you.
Of course.
All right,
let's finish the anastomosis.
No, I haven't told him, but
I don't feel good about it.
Don't you think he has a right to know?
Uh, I've got to go.
I'll talk to you later.
You need something?
No.
Okay.
Help! Dr. Manning!
Dr. Choi!
Oh, my God.
- Help her!
- I feel dizzy.
Jenny, keep looking at me.
Keep talking, okay?
Mmm, Mom.
You'll be okay, honey.
Mommy is right here.
- I don't feel good.
- Oh, God.
What is happening to my daughter?
There's so much blood.
It's a gynecologic hemorrhage.
She's passing retained tissue...
We need to control the bleed.
Monique, hang a unit of typed
and crossed-matched blood,
give her 0.2 milligrams
of methergine IM,
and I need a stat CBC and coags.
Wait, we need
her parental consent.
Ethan.
To start the transfusion
and administer the medication.
Yeah, wh... whatever
you need to do.
Go ahead.
I may have distorted the
graft with that last stitch.
I'm doing this backhand. Do
you have a better angle?
I think so.
Dr. Rhodes's phone.
Take a message.
All right, last couple of stitches
then we're coming off pump.
- Dr. Rhodes?
- I said take a message.
Dr. Rhodes, he says
it's an emergency.
All right.
Look, I'm in the middle of an operation.
What?
Is this some kind of joke?
How do I know that?
All right. All right, all right.
What... what do you want me to do?
What is it?
Okay, yeah, okay.
Yeah, look.
No, I won't hang up. I promise.
- I have to leave.
- What?
Finish the anastomosis.
Check the competency of the valve.
Connor, no!
You've done this before.
You'll be fine.
- That's not...
- No!
I'm not... I'm not hanging up.
I promise.
All right, we have
a patient on the table.
Let's get back to work.
I just left the operating room.
I'm headed out now.
You finished already,
Dr. Rhodes?
No, I'm still here.
Okay, I won't hang up.
Dr. Rhodes?
No, I'm still here. I'm still here.
The elevator is really slow.
Look, I'm moving as fast
as I can, man, I promise.
_
Can I talk to her?
Okay, okay, okay, okay.
I'll do whatever you say.
All right, I'm leaving now.
Just please, don't hurt her.
Robin, it's Dad.
Can you, um, can you call
me as soon as you get this?
My bank is on the corner
of LaSalle and Van Buren.
I'll be there in 20 minutes.
_
Trudy, it's Dan Charles.
I-I need to speak to
Hank Voight immediately.
What the hell is going on
with Dr. Rhodes?
What do you mean?
Halfway through Mr. Montero's surgery,
he left the O.R. and the hospital.
What?
You know how important
this patient is to us
and if his outcome is less than perfect,
I will fire Dr. Rhodes
and that'll be the
least of his problems.
I'll sue him and then I'll
bring him up on charges.
I know there is a reasonable
explanation for this.
If this blows up, Sharon,
he won't be the only one without a job.
I'm heading east on Lake.
You're late... you said you'd
be there in 20 minutes.
I can't help the traffic.
Are you playing games with me?
I am doing the best I can!
Whatever happens to Robin,
that's on you, man!
Just... just don't touch her!
Move! Move!
Since your patient,
Jenny Simpson, is a minor,
legal is concerned about liability.
Of course they are.
Bottom line, if you feel the need
for any further medical procedures,
you must obtain parental consent.
Good, thank you.
This isn't right.
I'm sorry, Dr. Manning, but
you've given her Methergine.
- Yes?
- Yes.
So let's hope she passes
any retained tissue
and that should take care of it.
Hi.
Could we have a moment to examine Jenny?
Oh, of course.
When are we going
to know something?
Honey, let them do their job.
Come on.
Thank you.
How are you feeling, Jenny?
Not good?
Well, I'm going to do
an internal exam, okay?
So I just need you to lift
up your legs just like that
and then just let them fall open.
Perfect. Um, and I apologize.
This is going to be a
little uncomfortable, okay?
Thank you.
All right, you ready?
You okay?
What is it?
Well, your body hasn't
expelled all the tissue
related to the pregnancy.
The medication we gave
you is supposed to help
but unfortunately,
you're still bleeding.
It means you're going to need
a D&C, dilation and curettage,
a surgical procedure
to remove the tissue.
But we do need your parents'
permission for this.
N-no. You can't tell them.
We have to.
Jenny, your temperature
is elevated,
which means you could be
developing endometritis,
which is a very serious infection.
It could be life-threatening.
No. No, no!
Jenny, I know you're afraid
of what your parents will say,
but they love you and they
would never want to lose you.
So I'm going to go talk
to them, okay?
Wait.
My mom...
Ask my mom to come in.
Okay.
Mrs. Simpson, Jenny would
like to talk to you.
Oh.
Um, hey, why don't you, uh,
go get a cup of coffee?
I-I think this is mother-daughter talk.
No, it'll be okay.
Agent Pearson's CT results.
Is something wrong?
Sam's CAT scan.
Bilateral diffuse pulmonary white out,
bilateral subclinical pneumothoraces,
sternal fracture, subcapsular
liver hematoma...
What does all that mean?
Looks like blast lung.
These injuries were not
caused by a car crash.
Ingrid, what really happened?
Tell me.
Will it affect how you treat him?
Of course it will!
- What happened?
- Okay.
We... there was an explosion and
Sam took the brunt of it.
What kind of explosion?
A meth lab.
What are we talking about then?
Acetone peroxide? Red phosphorus?
Yes.
What else can you tell us?
Ingrid!
God's sakes, Will,
isn't that enough?
Convert him to lung
protective ventilation.
Drop the tidal volume to 4 cc's
per kilo and up his rate to 28.
On it.
You.
I knew it.
I knew it all along.
You had no right to keep this from us.
It was Jenny's wish.
Well, of course she didn't
want us to find out.
She knew it was wrong.
What she did was... was murder.
Mrs. Simpson, um,
you should know that Jenny
didn't want to tell you
because she was afraid you
wouldn't love her anymore.
No...
No.
No, no, no.
Listen, no matter what
your beliefs are,
that's your daughter
and she's very sick.
Oh...
Look, can I give the consent for the D&C
without my husband?
Yes.
Do whatever you have to do
to save my daughter.
Just don't tell Joel what happened.
I don't want this to destroy my family.
But doesn't he have
the right to know?
He's her father.
Actually...
Actually, he isn't.
And no, I never told him.
All right, I'm here.
Ginny, Ginny, hi. Hi.
Hello, Dr. Rhodes,
what can I do for you?
I need to take $50,000
out of my money market account in cash.
Cash?
Yes and please,
I am in a bit of a hurry.
It'll take a few minutes.
I'm not sure the tellers
have that much on hand.
I may need to go into the vault.
Ginny, whatever it takes,
just please do it. Thank you.
All right, did you hear that?
It's going to take awhile.
No. No, no, no, no, no.
I-I-I-I didn't call them. I swear!
No, no. No, no, no. They...
They... they can't be outside!
I didn't call them! Please! Please!
No, no, no! Don't hang up!
I am getting you the money!
Hello? Hello, you there? You... hello?
No. No, no, no, no, no, no, no!
No!
No! No, no, no, no!
I told you not to call the police!
They saw you! They're going to kill her!
- They're not.
- You don't know that.
- Yes, I do.
- Dr. Rhodes.
Robin was never kidnapped.
No, she was.
I-I-I-I-I heard her.
I heard her scream!
- It wasn't her, buddy.
- No, it's a scam.
Dr. Rhodes, it's a scam.
Scam?
When I finally reached Robin,
she had no idea what
I was talking about.
You... you spoke to her
and she's fine?
Was never in any danger.
Watch out.
BP 92 over 56.
Heart rate 48.
Sats 73 and dropping.
He's bradying down.
Bilateral tension pneumothoraces.
Two needle kits?
Yeah, gotta decompress his chest.
What's happening?
Air's leaking into his
chest from his lungs.
Now his lungs can't inflate.
Second needle?
Sats and heart rate climbing.
Set up for bilateral chest tubes.
Otherwise his lungs are just
going to collapse again.
Right.
We'll need to send him up to
the ICU and get him on ECMO.
Is this because you didn't know?
It didn't help, Ingrid.
Evie.
What's happening? Where
are they taking her?
They'll explain.
We're starting your daughter
on broad spectrum antibiotics
and we're taking her up to surgery.
Why?
We... we were unable
to stop her bleeding,
and also we were concerned
she could become septic.
Oh, God.
The procedure to address
this is simple, very low-risk.
In all likelihood,
she'll be able to go
home with you tomorrow.
Okay.
I'm still not clear.
This procedure...
Uh, it's to remove
degenerating tissue
that's trapped in her uterus.
- Her uterus?
- That's right.
Okay, as long as she's
going to be all right.
Yeah.
Do you have any further questions?
- No. No.
- Okay.
Then why don't we have
someone take you up
to the waiting area?
Monique, take Mr. Simpson
upstairs to join his wife.
Sure.
This way, sir.
Thank you.
Robin.
- Hey.
- Oh, my God.
Oh, it's okay.
I'm fine.
I was... uh, I-I was just so worried.
You know... Dad, you know
I go swimming during lunch.
Do I know that?
Uh, I don't think I know that.
Yeah, well,
maybe you should listen.
How were they even
able to pull this off?
I mean, they must've
known so much about you.
The cops said they
must've hacked my email.
I mean, apparently this sort of
scam has been happening a lot.
I'm really sorry.
I-I-I've got to get back to the O.R.
Oh, I'm fine, Connor.
Go.
- Okay, thank you.
- And change your passwords.
Dr. Rhodes?
Ms. Goodwin, I will explain
everything when I can
but I... right now I have got
to get back to the O.R.
There's no hurry.
- Mr. Montero?
- Did fine.
They're closing him up now.
Um...
uh, that's good.
Since you ran out in
the middle of the surgery,
I'd say it's very good.
And now you have time to
tell me what happened.
Hey.
Sam is stable, on ECMO.
That'll take the strain off
his lungs so they can heal.
He's got a long road ahead of
him but he should pull through.
Good.
And look, I'm sorry.
Even if I had known earlier
what caused his injuries,
I don't think it would
have made a difference.
Thank you.
You can go and see him.
Okay.
You're still not gonna
tell me what happened?
We're fortunate Dr. Bekker
was able to take over
for Dr. Rhodes when he
became incapacitated.
She is a brilliant surgeon
and she's proven herself a
worthy successor to Dr. Downey.
Thank you.
You're most welcome.
I think we can all agree
that, thanks to Dr. Bekker,
we're on our way to becoming
a destination hospital once again.
I heard what happened.
That's awful.
But Robin's okay? It was just a scam?
- Yeah.
- So cruel.
Well, thank you for stepping in.
Of course.
I'm going to
go write up my notes.
Looks like it all worked out
well for her.
Yeah.
Dr. Choi, Dr. Manning.
I thought Jenny might be hungry.
And I wanted to thank you.
The OB said she's gonna be fine.
Yes, everything went well.
Yeah.
She's a good girl.
Mr. Simpson.
Take care.
I will.
Thanks.
That man's being lied to
by us, his wife, his daughter.
I don't get you, Ethan.
You believe that everyone has
a right to make decisions
about their own body.
It's not that.
It's the dishonesty.
Listen, some people
don't want honesty.
They find living with a
lie to be a lot easier.
Not me.
April?
April, it's Ethan.
Ethan, what are you doing?
If... if you're seeing another guy,
just tell me the truth.
Uh, y... you have no right
to come to my apartment
demanding anything.
You keep making excuses.
You cut your hair.
My hair?
So what?
Just be honest with me.
I can handle it.
You're going to wake the baby.
Emily.
Why don't you come in?
- Hey.
They're probably not going
to extubate him for a few days.
You should go home, get some rest.
Okay.
Will, it wasn't because of security
that I didn't tell you.
I trust you.
Then why?
I just didn't want
to burden you with it.
Ingrid.
I'm not really good
at letting people in,
but I do know...
sometimes burdens are easier
to bear if they're shared.
You can tell me.
Tell me.
That raid on the meth lab?
The suspect was supposed to be alone,
but he had his kids with him.
Twins, girls, six years old.
And, um, rather than
surrender, he lit a match.
Um...
After the explosion when the
smoke started to clear,
I could see that Sam was down.
And then I, um...
I just saw bits of them everywhere
and then in the middle of all it...
I-I saw a little girl's
toy, a pink unicorn.
It was perfect.
There wasn't a scratch on it.
I got you.
Bernie just needs some time.
So April said I could stay with her.
But what's he doing at his wife's?
- He left her.
- He did.
But he misses her and
he misses his daughter.
So we talked about it and
thought it would be good
if they spent some time
together and, you know,
just work things out.
Work what things out?
He has a baby.
- Your baby.
- She knows that.
Obviously you're fine with this.
They're doing the best
they can, Ethan.
It doesn't sound that way to me.
See, this is why I
didn't want him to know.
Okay, come here.
Don't you want to meet your nephew?
Come here, Em.
Come on.
His name is Vincent.
Vincent.
After Grandpa.
Mm-hmm.
You know, I did cut
my hair because of a guy.
Vincent likes to pull on it.
Yes, I got that.
Hey, Ma?
So Dad has had a bit of a rough day
and wants to know if we can all
go out to dinner together.
So why isn't he asking me himself?
Oh, I wouldn't want you to think
that I was being manipulative.
Oh.
Tell him I like steak.
Not for nothing, you were
absolutely right this morning
about Mackinac Island.
Okay, now you're being
really manipulative.
www.tvsubtitles.net