Previously on "ER."
How long have you been sober?
Almost five years.
Your mother's not coming.
John, we're getting divorced.
‐ Stop! Oh, you're hurting me!
‐ 'Paul, Paul.'
‐ Please stop!
‐ Check the stylet.
We believe he may
have schizophrenia.
Paul wouldn't hurt
anyone. He couldn't.
I'm not deformed!
‐ Temperature's 95.
‐ No!
Don't stick that!
Get off of me!
‐ Get pregnant!
‐ I was pregnant!
I had an abortion.
You never even told
Richard, did you?
'You were supposed
to wake me up.'
'I'm not your
damn mother, Brian.'
'Why the hell is
it so cold in here?'
'I called the super twice!
What have you done?'
'I was studying
so I can get a job'
'that pays enough for us
to move out of this pit.'
'You don't even
realize how you talk'
'to me sometimes.
It's disgusting'
'You just don't
know when to stop.'
‐ 'You just keep pushing me.'
‐ 'I have a life too.'
'And I cannot keep waiting
on you hand and foot.'
'You know what
your problem is‐‐'
'We're supposed
to be working together'
'as a team, but we don't'
'do that because you don't'
'treat me as a equal,
you treat me like crap.'
'How do you think
it makes me feel?'
'You're constantly belittling
me, even in public.'
'Can you give me
at least five minutes'
'in the morning before
you act like a bitch‐‐'
'Shut up!'
Both of you, shut up.
'You know what
your problem is, Brian?'
'You don't need me.
You don't even like..'
'...cook and clean and pick
up your dirty laundry.'
'But guess what,
that's not why..'
'Hi, this is Abby,
leave a message.'
'Hello, Abby?'
'Abby, are you there?
Hello? Abby?'
'Thought I'd catch
you before your shift.'
'Anyway, I wanted to
wish you a happy birthday.'
‐ Hi, mom.
‐ 'Did I wake you up?'
No, I was just getting up.
Thank you.
Ooh.
Ooh! Ooh, your
feet are like ice!
I'm sorry.
Uh, I put on some coffee.
What time is it?
It's about seven thirty.
Mm‐hmm.
You sleep okay?
Yeah. You?
Hmm. Except for the snoring.
Well, I don't snore.
Oh, yeah, right.
Like a truck driver.
I don't snore.
Stop it.
Oh, no!
Oh, yeah?
Oh, wait a minute.
I've arranged
for a nurse's aide
for you for while I'm at work.
‐ A nurse?
‐ Just for a couple of weeks.
I've got half a dozen people
in this house every day.
Well, then one more
isn't going to hurt.
If it gets any
colder, I'm going to
winter in the Bahamas.
Alone.
I thought I heard someone.
Is it just me or is
it freezing in here?
Mom, what are
you doing here?
I assumed you
could use a hand
while your
grandmother recovered.
How are you
feeling, Millicent?
I've been better.
‐ Where's Jack?
‐ Uh, Kansas City, I think.
You don't know?
He's on an extended
business trip.
We missed the pleasure
of your company at Christmas.
You know how
the holidays can be.
‐ Where are you staying?
‐ I was hoping to stay here.
‐ In the house?
‐ Yes, if that's alright.
‐ Yeah?
‐ It is freezing in here.
Would somebody please
turn up the furnace.
‐ I will go get Alger on it.
‐ 'It won't start.'
‐ 'Did you flood it?'
‐ 'No, it won't even turn over.'
'Did you leave your
lights on again?'
‐ No.
‐ You probably did.
‐ Excuse me.
‐ No, I didn't. Hi.
‐ Hi.
‐ Do you have any jumper cables?
No, sorry.
I take the El.
I guess you're not
the only one today.
Give me the keys.
My husband's not
really a morning person.
Hi, I'm Joyce.
We just moved here a few
weeks ago from Virginia.
‐ Hi. Abby.
‐ We're in 205.
I know. I think you
guys are right beside me.
Nice meeting you.
‐ So, I guess we're neighbors.
‐ Just a wall between us.
Well, maybe, uh,
you could come over
for coffee
or something sometime.
Sure.
Hey, can we give you
a ride somewhere?
‐ No, thank you.
‐ Are you sure?
It's really cold out there.
I'm fine.
I told you.
You flooded it.
Welcome to Chicago.
Oh!
Oh, son of a bitch.
You're leaving?
I phoned the Pediatric
Cancer Society
to inform them she wasn't
coming to their luncheon
and they managed to corral me.
You don't really
have to do that.
She wasn't
planning on going.
She just does
that for effect.
I'm aware
of her behavior.
But they actually
were expecting her.
‐ You'll be back tonight?
‐ You're really staying?
Yes. Unless
I'm not welcome.
No, no, it's just..
...I thought you
were covering.
Dad's in Denver, actually.
‐ Your father told you.
‐ Well, it was pretty obvious.
He was here for two days
at Christmas without you.
You thought he
was still here.
Uh, we, uh, left it
a little open‐ended.
‐ Really?
‐ I'm sorry, John.
I should have phoned you and let
you know that I was coming.
Yeah, well.
It's good to see you.
Sanitation guys found
him in a dumpster.
Minimally responsive to deep
pain, thready pulse in the 50s.
‐ You sure he's not dead?
‐ He's still moving air.
Barely.
Abby, can you bring this guy in?
I haven't even clocked in yet.
I know, but you have a coat on.
Hey, I know this guy.
Oh, man!
Is this great, or what?
Empty chairs, empty racks.
Nothing like
sub‐arctic temperatures
to keep the freaks at home.
Yeah, except it's
freezing in here.
Maintenance is
checking the furnace.
This is what we get for punching
holes in the ozone layer.
Uh, isn't the greenhouse effect
supposed to make it warmer?
Greenhouse effect, my ass.
It's 40 below out there.
‐ What's this?
‐ This is Icicle Andy.
You want him, he's yours.
I thought he froze
to death last year.
‐ The iceman cometh back.
‐ Okay, Trauma One's open.
Get his core temp,
pump in some warm saline
and throw a heating
blanket on him.
Oh, I'd keep that
on if I were you.
He's bradying down.
No luck. Now it's A‐fib.
Sounds like
rhonchi on the right.
Probably pneumonia.
I think he's
decreased on the left.
Do you wanna
put in a chest tube?
'Uh, not if I can help it.'
This guy's got
bad vascular disease.
‐ We'll never get a line in him.
‐ Fine, prep for lavage.
Oh, man, look at this
dude's hands. Ugh.
‐ Can you get a pulse ox?
‐ I don't know.
Can barely get the monitor..
Ugh!
What's wrong?
It snapped off.
Ah, he gave you
the finger, huh, Abby?
‐ Can they reattach that?
‐ Not without superglue.
Okay, let's get
a central line kit
Betadine and some
warm blankets to start.
No, no, you can't come in
here. You have to go back.
‐ Where's my mom?
‐ She's not in here.
Yes, she was.
‐ You got this?
‐ Yeah.
Warm liter of IV saline..
You lost your mom?
It's not one of these
two ladies right here?
She was in there.
Okay, well, maybe
she's all finished.
Do you wanna see
if we can find her?
I'm Abby.
What's your name?
‐ Douglas.
‐ Douglas what?
‐ Douglas Leeman.
‐ Okay, Douglas, right this way.
What's your mom's name?
‐ B.
‐ B?
Is that short for Beatrice?
Barbara? Betty?
‐ Just B.
‐ Just B? Okay.
‐ Abby, can you help me?
‐ Uh, sure.
Frank, this is Douglas Leeman.
He's lost his mom.
This is Frank. He's very
good at finding people's moms.
Douglas, you
like doughnuts?
When did the chest
pains start?
This morning, but I've
been feeling crappy for..
...a couple of days.
I thought it was just
a cold or...maybe the flu.
Bibasilar rales.
Have you experienced
any shortness of breath?
Yeah.
I thought I'd step outside
catch a breath of fresh air,
I got so dizzy I fainted.
Three plus pitting
edema on both feet.
Have you ever had
anything like this before?
‐ Never.
‐ Do you have a heart condition?
No.
Are you on birth
control pills?
No, I‐I'm trying to,
to get pregnant.
I've been taking
fertility drugs.
‐ FSH.
‐ For how long?
‐ Um...what's today?
‐ Uh, the tenth.
‐ Yeah, then I'm on my tenth.
‐ 'Alright.'
Let's get a CBC, Chem‐20
a DIC panel and a D‐dimer.
Am I having some sort
of reaction to the drugs?
It's possible, but we
need to run some more tests
to know for sure.
You've got fluid
in your lungs
which could be
a sign of a blood clot.
A blood clot?
It's unlikely, but I
just want to make sure.
It could be a possible side
effect of the medication.
Well, let's do a Doppler.
I'll be back.
Do you want me to
call your husband?
‐ I'm not married.
‐ Oh, boyfriend?
I decided to..
...have a baby on my own.
Got tired of waiting
around for Mr. Right.
I know that story.
Chest x‐ray and an EKG?
Yeah, and set
her up for a VQ.
Haven't seen you
around lately.
I've been working nights.
‐ How was your Christmas?
‐ Quiet.
‐ What'd you do for New Year's?
‐ I worked.
That's always fun.
Did you make
any resolutions?
Uh, I'm going
to help out more.
‐ Help out more where? Here?
‐ Uh, no, Europe.
I've, uh, volunteered
to go to Bosnia
for two months with
Doctors Without Borders.
‐ Bosnia?
‐ Yeah, I speak the language.
‐ What brought this on?
‐ I don't know.
Change of scenery.
'Good, huh?'
Hey, nice hat, Snoop.
Hey, Frank, I thought
you said you were
gonna get the heat turned up.
‐ They're working on it.
‐ Oh, really?
Is that why the thermostat
in the lounge says 56?
Get used to it, we're
heading into another ice age
like the one that
killed the dinosaurs.
Cold didn't kill the dinosaurs,
Frank. Cholesterol did.
Mr. Ellis in Curtain
Three can go home.
Miss Renfrew in Four
needs to be admitted.
‐ Got a minute?
‐ Uh, no, not really.
I hope your day's shaping
up better than mine.
Doubt it.
I was picking up
Rachel's laundry
after you left and this
fell out of her jeans.
She's smoking.
I don't think she uses
it to light campfires.
‐ What are you going to do?
‐ I don't know.
Did you find anything
else in her pockets?
No.
Mark, what if it's
not cigarettes?
Her boyfriend tested
positive for marijuana.
Ex‐boyfriend.
‐ I should search her room.
‐ You think that's wise?
Well, if she's doing drugs,
I wanna know about it.
You know, asking her
doesn't guarantee
I'm gonna get the truth.
Yeah, but searching
her room, that's such
a violation of her privacy.
You suggested that I
rifle through her pockets.
In the course
of doing laundry.
Dr. Greene, 29‐year‐old male
eight foot fall, no LOC.
‐ Can we talk about this?
‐ 'Come find me.'
'Normal vitals.'
This is adorable.
Don't you think?
It's pretty cute.
You wanna buy it?
No, they won't let me
send him any gifts.
He must be getting
pretty big now, huh?
Yeah, oh, they
sent a video of him
walking just before
Christmas. It's..
It won't be long now before
he's asking to borrow
the keys to the car.
You know, I'm
starting to wonder
if I'm making any
right decisions lately.
Uh, it's mid‐year. Something
will open up by the spring.
Yeah, well, maybe they'll
open back up at County.
Hey, cool.
Have you seen these?
These are really neat.
John, um..
...what would you
say if I told you
I asked the waitress
at Doc Magoo's
if she remembered
Weaver being paged
the night we lost
the Marfan case?
I'd sa‐a‐ay that place is
full of people with pagers.
I know. I was desperate.
So, what, she
didn't remember?
Not about Weaver
getting paged.
But she remembers
Weaver coming back in
looking for her pager
and finding it in the bathroom.
She couldn't
answer my page, John
because she didn't
have her pager.
‐ Are you sure?
‐ I believe it.
Don't you?
Yeah, that explains it.
What are you going to do?
‐ He die?
‐ Yup.
‐ Did you know him?
‐ Only as Icicle Andy.
I think he was
a Vietnam vet.
I heard bums are reincarnated
as pigeons when they die.
Really?
I think it's
the other way around.
Check it out.
Tickets to tonight's
Blackhawks game
and they're
good seats too.
Whoa. Where'd
he get those?
‐ Any ID?
‐ Mm‐mm.
Just two dollars,
some change and matches.
Are you gonna
keep the tickets?
‐ No.
‐ Can I have them?
‐ Why not?
I think it's
called grave‐robbing.
He ain't using them.
Well, somebody might
come to claim the body.
‐ Ha ha ha.
‐ I'm serious.
Yeah, right. Seriously.
‐ I need them.
‐ No.
Look, the tickets are
only for tonight, Abby.
‐ Nobody coming for this guy.
‐ Forget it.
Oh, come on, Abby.
Abby, look, he's
straight‐up dead.
Abby, can you take
a look at something?
‐ What patient?
‐ Uh, Mr. Paninski.
Unstable angina.
I called CCU.
I just wanted to make sure
I didn't miss anything.
‐ Did you do a rectal?
‐ No.
‐ You better.
‐ Because?
Because if his stool
is heme‐positive‐‐
The heparin,
right. Thank you.
‐ Frank?
‐ Yeah?
You said you were
gonna find his mother.
I tried.
No B. Leeman
checked in today.
I'm beginning to think
somebody dumped him.
He said his mother was in
Trauma One with a headache.
Can you double‐check
it with the admit log?
Sure.
'Abby. Hi.'
‐ Richard.
‐ How's it going?
What are you doing here?
It's colder in here
than it is outside.
You look great.
Thank you.
Shift work becomes me.
‐ So, how are things?
‐ They're good.
Good. That's good.
You seeing anyone or..
Oh, yeah.
I'm breaking hearts
all over town.
What do you want, ex?
‐ "Ex?"
‐ Yeah.
Can I call you ex?
'Cause it's almost like
sexy so people might think
it's short for
ecstasy or triple‐X..
...which stands
for porn, uh, now
except for in cartoons where
it, where it stands for poison
which I always
thought was funny, but..
What do you want?
Oh, look, I, um..
Well, I‐I wanted to
talk to you in person
so you didn't hear this
through the grapevine.
‐ Oh, my God.
‐ What?
Are you going to jail?
No.
Uh, I'm getting married.
‐ Married?
‐ Yeah.
You'd think I would've
learned my lesson.
I'm glad one of us did.
‐ What, is she rich?
‐ Hardly. She's a teacher.
Not that one you
had at the museum.
No, no, no.
Her name's Corrine.
She's, uh, she's really great.
She's really down to Earth.
I, uh, I think you
might even like her.
‐ How old is she?
‐ She's 34.
She has a,
a six‐year‐old son, Adam.
Really great kid.
‐ You're gonna be a father?
‐ Stepfather, yeah.
It's kind of hard
to believe, huh?
Yeah, it's like
a‐a instant family.
I always wanted kids, so..
Since when?
Uh, you know, just a while.
I guess we just never
talked about it, you know?
And you, uh, felt
that today was the day
you had to tell
me about all this?
Is today a bad day?
Nope.
Um...so, what?
Am I supposed to
give you my blessing?
That's up to you.
Well, I have to
get back to work.
Richard.
I hope that it
works out this time.
'Thanks.'
‐ 'Aspen's great.'
‐ 'Mm.'
There's three
separate mountains.
So you‐you don't
have to be an expert.
Mm‐hmm.
Mm.
What is that?
What?
Yeah, they got
runs for every level.
‐ Is that your jaw?
‐ What?
That click,
click, click sound.
Oh, my God.
You can hear that?
‐ Yeah.
‐ I can't help it.
I think I have this
TMJ hap‐happening thing.
‐ Here, chew.
‐ No.
Come on. Just chew
so I can hear it.
No!
'Get out of here.'
‐ I'm gonna get back to work.
‐ I'm gonna take care of this.
You should see
a dentist about that jaw.
Yeah, either that
or you should find
someone else
to eat lunch with.
I'm sorry about that.
What?
I should have said
something to you sooner.
It just sort of snuck up on me.
I hate it when that happens.
Well, it's really more about
friendship than anything else.
'Really?'
Never seen you
kiss Frank like that.
‐ Abby‐‐
‐ Don't sweat it, Carter.
‐ Where's Frank?
‐ Don't know.
Hey, Douglas.
Did you find your mom?
Are you getting hungry?
‐ Yeah.
‐ Would you like to eat pizza?
A hamburger?
My mom says fast food
isn't good for you.
Well...she's right,
but the fast food we serve here
at the hospital is specially
formulated to be nutritious.
So would you like
some French fries?
Okay. Sit tight.
Hey, Frank!
‐ I'm working on it.
‐ Well, work harder.
He's been here for
a couple of hours.
If I find his mom, can
I have the hockey tickets
you pinched off that stiff?
‐ No.
‐ Has anyone seen Dr. Kovac?
‐ What do you need?
‐ Mrs. Stipes' pressure's down.
Frank, find Luka.
What happened?
She got dizzy.
Systolic's at 80.
I opened up the saline.
How you doing, Merril?
‐ 'Is it a PE?'
‐ I don't know.
Crank her oxygen up to 15 liters
and grab some dopamine
off the crash cart.
She's got muffled
heart sounds and JVD.
Malik, we need
a pericardiocentesis
tray and a SonoSite.
‐ Okay.
‐ Pressure's down to 70.
You think it's tamponade?
Unless you got
any better ideas.
‐ What happened?
‐ Hypotensive.
Signs of pericardial infusion.
He thought she had a clot
from hyper‐stimulation?
You can third space anywhere,
even around the heart.
‐ There it is.
‐ Here you go, Abby.
Okay, glove up.
You can assist.
Lidocaine's ready.
Abby, I think I
found that kid's mom
if she doesn't have
the same last name as him.
I don't know. Maybe.
Okay, hook up
the alligator clip.
Belinda Matheson,
she came in last night
with a headache. Turned
out to be a brain bleed.
‐ Insert subxiphoid, 45‐degree‐‐
‐ Last night?
Yeah. They admitted
her to neurosurg.
Watch for injury current.
I can't believe that
little boy sat in chairs
all night and nobody noticed.
'Can you take him
upstairs to his mother?'
Uh, that could be
difficult. She's dead.
What?
Blood pressure's back up to 90.
She stroked out
a few hours ago.
‐ 'Second syringe.'
‐ What do you want me to do?
Abby?
Um, well, just...
try to find his dad.
‐ Systolic's 110.
‐ And get him some French fries.
Okay. Good pickup.
'Did you get in
touch with the father?'
He said he lives
in Los Angeles.
‐ He doesn't know the number.
‐ It wasn't in here?
‐ I couldn't find it.
‐ Did you call his school?
No.
Well, I'm sure they
have a number, Frank.
I thought you
used to be a cop.
‐ I was.
‐ Well, act like a cop.
Track the guy down.
'Did someone from neurosurg
come down and talk to him?'
Not yet.
‐ Which doc treated his mother?
‐ Weaver.
She's working a half shift
today, so she's not in yet.
Do you want me to page
somebody from neurosurg?
I don't know, I think
somebody should come down
and tell the little
boy his mother died.
No, she didn't.
Douglas, I need to talk to you
about your mom's headache, okay?
Let's sit down.
Alright, um..
Uh, it was pretty bad.
Um...it was caused by
a blood vessel in her brain
that...ruptured.
It broke.
And the doctors
tried really hard
but they couldn't fix it.
Can she go home now?
No, Douglas, I'm sorry.
She died.
My mom has a headache.
She's not sick.
I want to see her.
‐ Where is she?
‐ Douglas!
Mom! Mom!
‐ Mom!
Mom! Mom, where are you?
‐ Douglas.
‐ Mom!
‐ Listen.
‐ Mom! Mom!
‐ Douglas, she's dead.
Stop saying that.
Why do you keep saying that?
I know it's hard
for you to understand.
‐ I want my mom.
‐ I know you do.
I just want my mom.
Shh.
Shh, it's okay.
'He finally went down?'
'He's exhausted.'
Poor kid.
I finally got
a hold of his dad.
He's in Australia
on a business trip.
Australia?
The soonest
flight he can get
is a red‐eye
tomorrow night.
So, social services are going
to have to take him till then?
Sorry. I'll call them.
That's alright.
I'll do it. Thanks.
Can you grab me
the minute he gets up?
Sure.
Abby, do we do psychiatric
transfers to other hospitals?
What?
I have a patient
in Curtain Three.
He was admitted
with a tiny scalp lac
from a slip‐and‐fall,
and he's insisting
he be moved out of Curtain Three
and he wants me to call his
caseworker from some
private hospital.
Is he altered
from the fall?
No, but he seems
pretty agitated.
Did you...get
a psych consult?
‐ Not yet.
‐ It probably wouldn't hurt.
The paramedics brought
me to this hospital.
I didn't want to come here.
Can you just please
call my caseworker
'and move me to another room?'
'Please stop,
that's not necessary.'
‐ You don't have to do that.
‐ It's just a precaution.
‐ What happened?
‐ I slipped. That's all.
Is this your patient?
Yeah. I saw him in the hallway.
Brief LOC after he
slipped on some ice.
‐ 'History of migraine.'
‐ It's not his only history.
‐ Why the hard restraints?
‐ I don't wanna cause trouble.
Just...please, just
call my caseworker.
We will. Dr. Lewis.
Ca‐ca‐can you please just
get me out of this room?
‐ Don't worry. We'll move you.
‐ What kind of caseworker?
Psychiatric. He's monitoring
my conditional release.
‐ He has the card.
‐ Release from where?
Dr. Lewis, now.
Okay, two of IV Ativan,
five of Compazine
and a trauma panel.
'Someone call my, uh..'
‐ He's schizophrenic.
‐ He's been here before?
He stabbed Carter and killed
a med student two years ago.
‐ Him?
‐ Yeah.
‐ He stabbed Carter?
‐ Yes.
‐ What's he doing out?
‐ I don't know.
The police are on
their way, but I think
we should transfer him
before Carter sees him.
‐ No. I need to get a CT.
‐ Let him get a CT at Mercy.
He has a head injury.
He stabbed two
people in that room‐‐
Loss of consciousness
and he's vomiting‐‐
And killed one of them.
Abby, I'm not
transferring a man at risk
for an intracranial bleed.
I don't care what he did.
'Am I calling this
psychiatrist or not?'
No. I'll call him.
We'll find out his
status, we'll get the CT
and then we'll take
it from there, okay?
Abby, the morgue called.
They're ready for you.
Move him to the suture room,
close the blinds.
‐ Don't let Dr. Carter see him.
‐ 'I got it.'
And get his name off the board.
She looks like Snow White.
Mom.
Mom?
I drew you a picture.
'You took him to the morgue?'
'He didn't believe
his mother was dead.'
Well, then you call psych.
Advice you might have
given yourself 18 hours ago.
Hey, hey, hey.
She vagaled in triage.
No one even told me
she had a kid with her.
‐ Well, she did.
‐ Did you call social services?
‐ Not yet.
‐ Why not? Abby, why not?
Because we're trying to
find another family member.
‐ Who's we?
‐ Uh‐uh, me.
‐ That's not your job.
‐ I know.
But I don't want him to go
to another strange place.
Well, their holding facility
is a lot more comforting
than the ER or the morgue.
He'll keep being passed from one
stranger to another stranger.
They have the personnel
and resources to deal with it.
Call them now.
'"You're honest, forthright'
"and a judge, a good
judge of character.
"You often ramble
incoherently when agitated.
Even your dog
doesn't like you."
‐ My dog died a year ago.
‐ It's a joke, Frank.
This amuses you?
‐ Carter, what's your sign?
‐ Gemini, why?
Oh, horoscopes
from the Internet.
"You're open to new ideas,
compassionate, a risk‐taker‐‐"
That's true.
"You tend to overstay
your welcome at parties
and you often
smell like cheese."
Don't you have
some work to do?
‐ Abby, your turn.
‐ No, thanks.
‐ What's your sign? Come on.
‐ Out of order.
'Hey, who moved Libertique
out of the suture room?'
The hand surgeon
is stuck in surgery
for the next 40 minutes
and we needed the room
for an extensor tendon repair.
‐ Oh, I'll do that.
‐ No, no, no.
The‐the, uh, surgical
intern's got it.
Can you take a look at this
ex...plosive watery diarrhea?
‐ You need to start an IV?
‐ Maybe. I don't know.
He's...he's
pretty miserable.
‐ She.
‐ You okay?
‐ Yeah. Mm‐hmm.
Abby, the light source
on the fiber‐optic is down.
‐ Get me a spare?
‐ Okay.
'Can I see a doctor
this century?'
Hang on.
I hang on any longer,
I'll be dead.
If you're talking,
you're not dying.
He was found not guilty
by reason of insanity.
Shouldn't he be in
a state forensic hospital?
He was, he was,
he was stepped down
to a less restrictive
facility about ten months ago
and now he's on
conditional release.
‐ 'Bradying down with 60.'
‐ Mig of atropine.
‐ I need that scope.
‐ I've got it.
Pulse ox 78.
'I need a smaller tube.
Number seven. Suction.'
‐ He's agitated.
‐ He's nervous.
The guy's been out
of board and care
for less than a week,
he hits his head on some ice
and the paramedics bring
him here of all places?
‐ He‐he get out in two years?
‐ Who are you?
I was working when
he attacked my friends.
‐ I'm sorry.
‐ He was a law student.
'A professor there
got some colleagues'
to do some pro bono work.
They filed a writ of
habeas corpus and won.
‐ That's u‐unbelievable.
‐ But I can't say I disagree.
Most schizophrenics
are non‐violent.
Well, this one
was, wasn't he?
And when they are,
they rarely are twice.
He's not a danger
to himself or others.
‐ Really?
‐ 'Not on his meds.'
There are safeguards
in place, he needs
to be supervised taking
his medication every day.
‐ Did he get his head CT?
‐ They're almost ready for him.
Abby, can you check this foley?
I think it's overflowing.
‐ Clamp it.
‐ I did. It's overflowing.
Just get him out of here.
Anyway, I want those
restraints removed.
‐ Uh, no.
‐ He is coherent and lucid.
I have been working
with him for over a year.
‐ No.
‐ Abby.
‐ Susan, I swear to God, if‐‐
‐ Abby, I‐‐
Keep somebody posted
outside his door.
But he needs reassurance
and respect right now.
‐ Respect?
‐ Yes!
‐ I‐I'm sorry.
‐ 'Abby.'
‐ He needs our respect?
‐ Abby, go.
Looks like over a liter
in the last hour.
Uh, BP's 110 over 70
and her sats are up.
Good. You need to send
out a repeat potassium.
Right. Thanks.
He said something
about the ICU.
Um, yeah, maybe
for a couple of days.
Just for safety.
It's the fertility drugs, isn't
it, that's doing this to me?
The doctor has to,
uh, review your labs.
I could try to find
him now, if you like.
‐ I'm sorry.
‐ It's okay.
It must be the,
the damn hormones.
‐ I'm not usually a crier.
‐ It's okay.
Thanks.
Sometimes being
a woman sucks, you know?
It has its moments.
You grow up praying you,
you don't get pregnant
every time you have sex,
and then, when you finally
do wanna have
a baby, you can't.
It's so unfair.
You've been trying
for a long time?
I just keep thinking that maybe
I had my chance and I blew it.
‐ You don't know that.
‐ No, I've been pregnant.
A few years ago.
It was an accident.
I had just started
a new job and this..
...this new relationship.
It didn't seem
like the right time.
It happens.
I only waited till I was ready
so that I could be
the best mother I could be.
I'm sure you're going to be.
Unless I waited too long.
‐ 'Weaver's looking for you.'
‐ What?
She wants to know
why you didn't call
family services on that boy.
I am. I will.
I..
'I'm gonna check
in with my office'
and get some release paperwork.
‐ I'll be right back.
‐ Okay.
The on‐call social worker
for the ER, please.
‐ 'Did someone claim 'em?'
‐ What?
‐ The tickets.
‐ Oh. No.
Lewis was asking for one.
Muah.
Thank you!
No, just have him paged. Thanks.
Abby, when you get
a chance, I need
a thick‐and‐thin smear
and a culture in Curtain Three.
Yeah.
Oh, and your
diarrhea patient was
heme‐negative.
Just a little PO‐challenged.
So, I sent him home
with some Imodium.
Carter, I have a five‐year‐old
with abdominal pain
and I'm‐I'm worried
about intussusception.
Is there any
blood in the stool?
No, but he had
a, a palpable mass.
‐ 'There he is.'
‐ 'Hey, sweetheart.'
‐ 'There's daddy.'
‐ 'Hey...muah!'
'Hey. Hi.'
‐ 'I'm okay. I'm okay.'
‐ Carter..
'Daddy slipped and fell and'
'and he hit his head,
but I'm okay.'
‐ 'They put you in restraints?'
‐ 'Yeah.'
'It's just a precaution.'
'They're a little paranoid.'
Oh, it's you.
I'm sorry.
What happened?
What's he doing here?
He slipped and fell
outside his office building.
His office building?
He's on conditional release.
‐ You're out?
‐ I'm better.
I'm sorry.
'That wasn't me
who did that to you'
to your friend.
You know that, right?
You're a doctor.
You know it's a disease.
'I'm being treated.'
I'm okay now.
Great. I'm glad you're okay.
I think I'm
starting to get it.
Although that little puck
is‐is hard to keep track of.
They should give it a color
so your eye can follow it.
‐ What, the puck?
‐ Yes.
I mean, like
bright pink or red
or flashing
lights or something.
Okay, a flashing pink puck.
‐ Why not?
‐ 'Cause it's hockey.'
It's gonna be a great game.
I love.. I love the Hawks.
You got the tickets.
‐ Hey, hey, what's wrong?
‐ Uh, nothing.
‐ I hugged him.
‐ You what?
Oh, yeah, I'm
the Bruce Lee of love, girl!
Maybe I just need
some fresh air.
Hold, hold...wait
a minute. You're not out.
‐ Huh? Who are you hiding from?
‐ I'm not hiding.
Wait a minute, well,
then what the heck was that?
You don't want your
friends to see us together?
They're not my friends.
They work for me.
How do you think
that makes me feel?
‐ I'm sorry.
‐ You came on to me.
‐ You are not out.
‐ I am not out at work.
‐ Well, you need to be.
‐ Sandy..
I'm sorry. I don't
got time for this.
‐ Okay.
‐ 'And I'll come straight..'
Okay.
Bye, dad.
‐ He'll be here tomorrow.
‐ Great.
Have you ever been
to Los Angeles?
‐ Once. Disneyland.
‐ Oh.
I think you'll like it
there, 'cause it's sunny.
Not cold like it is here.
Excuse me.
Can you give this
to Dr. Carter?
I think you'd better do that.
Well, th‐they're
discharging Paul.
I have to drive him home.
They wouldn't have released
him if he weren't better.
He's taking his meds.
He's in therapy.
He has a disease,
but it's being treated.
'I mean, that's
what you do here.'
'You treat disease so people'
'can try to move on with life.'
Yeah.
He's my husband.
We're his family.
I can't give up on him.
Good luck.
Hey.
Um, Lewis
discharged Sobriki
and his wife asked
me to give you this.
Guess you couldn't protect
me from her either, huh?
Uh, yeah, I'm
sorry about that‐‐
‐ Don't worry, forget it.
‐ I just, I..
Are you off already?
Half shift.
I'm off in a half hour if you
want to get something to eat.
I should get home.
Or maybe just..
...coffee and pie?
I had a pretty
crappy day myself.
Gammy just got out of
the convalescent hospital.
I should go home
and check on her.
Are you going to be okay?
Yeah, I'm going to be fine.
Thank you for asking.
'Any time.'
‐ No!
‐ I have a real nice place‐‐
‐ No. I wanna stay here!
‐ But you can't, Douglas.
‐ Abby!
‐ Douglas, Douglas.
I want, I want to stay here.
I know. But this
is a hospital.
And you have to go someplace
where you can get some sleep.
‐ No.
‐ 'And get something to eat'
‐ 'And maybe take a bath.'
‐ I'll stay with you!
‐ Douglas, I don't‐‐
‐ No!
I don't stay here
all the time, honey
but you can come visit me
whenever you want, okay?
‐ I promise.
‐ No.
‐ I've got you.
‐ Abby!
‐ 'Come on.'
‐ 'Abby!'
'We'll get you some
ice cream when we get there.'
You'll be fine, Douglas.
Wait! I'll stay with you!
Abby! Please! Abby!
Abby, my cellulitis patient
is allergic to penicillin.
‐ No.
‐ Can you give IV erythromycin?
‐ 'What about vancomycin?'
No! I'm not your attending.
I'm not a resident.
I'm a nurse.
You want me
to assess a patient
you want me to push meds,
you want me to check vitals
explain a situation to
a family member, that's fine.
What I will not do is carry
you through med school.
You wanna be a doctor?
Start acting like one.
Rachel, can I talk to you?
‐ 'What are you doing?'
‐ Just picking your stuff up.
‐ You're searching my room.
‐ It's a pigsty.
That doesn't give you the right
to go through my things.
You mean these things?
I can't believe you did this!
Are you smoking now?
I asked you a question.
Hey, Rachel!
Are these your cigarettes?
I bought that pack like
a month ago on a dare.
‐ A dare?
‐ To see if I could pass for 18.
And the condoms?
What kind of a dare is that?
They gave those
out in health class.
And you decided to keep them?
Why? You'd rather
I not have them?
‐ You need to stop lying!
‐ Why?
You don't believe me
anyway, you search my room
and go through
my private things.
I was looking for drugs.
You said you
were picking up!
‐ Who's lying now?
‐ You're right!
The truth is I was
searching your room
because I don't know
if I can trust you.
Then fine! Believe
whatever you want.
I'm smoking! I'm on drugs!
And I'm having sex!
'Lots of sex with lots of guys'
'cause I'm the school
slut. You happy?
Yes, this is John Carter.
I have a private duty
nurse for my grandmother
who was supposed to start today.
She's not here.
Yeah.
‐ 'I sent her home early.'
‐ What?
She was aggravating Millicent
so I sent her home early.
She'll be back at 6 a. m.
It's a 24‐hour service.
I'll get up...
if there's a problem.
‐ What are you doing?
‐ Pardon?
I mean, you show up
unannounced, uninvited.
Uninvited?
And now you're making
health care decisions?
Your grandmother asked
me to ask her to leave.
‐ I was trying to be helpful.
‐ Well, do me a favor.
Don't try to be helpful.
It's not one of
your strong suits.
Excuse me, John.
I've had enough abuse
from my mother‐in‐law today.
I don't need any
more from my son.
I'm sorry?
I'm sorry, but I have
helped gamma through this.
I have tended
to her medical needs.
I have made her
health care arrangements.
So you need
to consult with me
before you do
anything like this.
‐ Fine.
‐ Call them back.
Yeah, you bet I will.
But I'm not
leaving this house.
And I don't care
if I'm uninvited.
I'm not going to let your
father break up this family.
Family, huh? What
family would that be?
Don't be sarcastic.
You checked out of
this family 20 years ago.
‐ Excuse me. I'm going to bed.
‐ No.
I'm not gonna let you put
some kind of revisionist spin
on this with you as
the injured party, no.
‐ Step aside.
‐ No, I got stabbed!
I got stabbed in the back!
Where the hell were you?
You were the same place that
you've been my entire life!
You were someplace else!
‐ We came back.
‐ Three weeks later.
We were stuck in Tokyo
and you said you were fine.
Well, I wasn't fine
and it wasn't okay.
Are you gonna blame
me for taking drugs?
No, I am blaming you
for not being my mother!
Bobby died.
And I lost a mother.
May I go to bed now?
Yeah, run away.
Oh, God!
Thank you.
Gotta call the super
about that too.
It gets stuck in the cold.
And I'm guessing it's going
to stay cold for a while.
‐ Hopefully not this cold.
‐ 'Good.'
I told Brian January
wasn't the best time to move
but that's when
the semester starts.
‐ 'He's in law school.'
‐ Did you get locked out?
We had a fight...
so I went to the store.
Another half hour,
he'll be asleep.
Are you from Chicago?
For a while now, yeah.
'Originally?'
Minnesota. You?
Idaho. The potato part,
not the white supremacist part.
'You want a beer?'
No, thanks.
Come on. Have a seat.
You look like
you've had a long day.
Thank you.
Mm, you got a card.
Mm‐hmm.
'It's nice to get one
personal piece of mail'
'mixed in with all
the bills and junk.'
Your birthday?
‐ Huh?
‐ Is it your birthday?
‐ Yes.
‐ 'Today?'
Mm‐hmm. 8:03 p. m.
'Well, congratulations.
You've made it.'
Happy birthday.
Thank you.