Previously on "ER".
You should know
you're being considered
for chief resident next year.
I'm pregnant.
‐ Roger's out of town.
‐ Is he ever around?
We haven't been gettin'
along too well, lately.
What do you want, Kerry?
I thought you might be hungry.
No, no, I'm not, and I have
a ton of work to do so..
Your mother has just
been transported
to her commitment hearing.
Aren't you supposed to testify?
Mrs. Wyczenski's released
on her own recognizance.
She needs hospitalization.
I'm not debating it
with you, miss.
Why do you think I'm here?
'Cause you know
she needs your help
even if she doesn't want it.
I just hope you didn't order
from that Thai place again.
Very good.
My turn now?
Hey, he finished
his breakfast?
No, but I got him
to eat some strawberries.
Ah, Cleo, he's supposed
to have hot cereal
before he gets treats.
These are just as nutritious
if not more so.
And they're yummy, too.
'At least tell
the baby‐sitter'
'to make sure
he has a good lunch.'
I cancelled the sitter.
‐ What?
‐ I'm off today.
Cleo, Reese needs
a lot of attention.
Peter, I'm a pediatrician.
Alright.
Hey, see you, man.
Say, see you
at the game, daddy.
What are you talking about?
I didn't say I was gonna
play tonight.
You're not. You're going to sit
in the bleachers with Reese.
'Come on, it'll be fun.
I'm playing first base.'
Hey, he doesn't
have a jacket here.
I'll go to Carla's
and pick one up.
'No, you know what,
I'll do it.'
‐ I can go.
‐ I said I'll go, okay?
‐ I'm on the cell.
‐ Okay.
Wanna play trains?
God, I slept so great,
and dreams..
...so wonderful
to be able to dream again.
Obviously, the therapy sessions
are helping and these walks.
Good.
You know what you don't
have to stay home all the time.
I'm sure Luka
would love to see you.
It's only been
a couple of weeks.
‐ He's a good man.
‐ Yeah.
‐ So's your friend John.
Must be fun to have
two men interested in you‐‐
Ah, ah, mom.
I've had men interested
in me all my life
you know,
just not good ones.
Actually, I think
your father was the best
compared to all the rest.
But, certainly blew that.
Think we should head home?
Why is it we can't talk?
We're talking.
No, I mean about
important things.
You‐you know, Dr. Legaspi
says it‐it might be
easier for us to do it
in a therapy session.
‐ Do what?
‐ Talk.
She wants you to come
to one of the sessions.
No.
I want you to
come too, please?
You could come
during lunch break.
I'm gonna head back.
Abby, will you come?
I'm gonna go to work.
Come on, just, just
think about it, alright?
Hi.
Can I help you?
Uh, I was just
dropping something off.
For Kim?
She's in the shower.
I can give her that
if you want.
No, thanks.
Uh, I'll pass it on later.
Well, you're welcome
to come in and wait‐‐
No, th‐thats, uh, won't
be necessary, thank you.
Well, if you give me your name
I could tell her you stopped by.
‐ Dr. Greene?
‐ Uh, huh?
‐ Yeah, uh, sorry.
‐ Ugh.
I need to, uh,
get some lab slips.
Oh, sure, sure.
‐ Baby keeping you up, huh?
‐ Oh, not really.
She slept for six hours last
night ten minutes at a time.
How long we gotta wait here?
Been in the hall for
five minutes
can't find a doc
to save my life.
'What do you got?'
Seven year old boy
tried to
put out a fire
in a garbage can.
Partial thickness burns
over both hands.
‐ Need some help?
‐ Sure.
‐ BP 110/60.
‐ 'Get it out!'
Is that him?
He sounds agitated.
You could say that.
Hey, I'm Dr. Mark Greene.
You want to tell me your name?
‐ No!
‐ It's Ben.
‐ I want this out of my nose.
‐ That's to help you breathe.
It's only for
a little while, okay?
‐ Are you his mother?
‐ Next door neighbor.
‐ He's a friend of my son's.
‐ 'No one's at the kid's house?'
Good air entry.
Both lungs are clear.
Any way to contact
the parents?
He just has a father,
I left him a message.
I wanna go home.
‐ Let's go.
‐ Get it out!
Randi, what do you
see me in a Beemer
or a Porsche?
Most of the time
I see you walking.
Okay, you can
forget about a ride.
Carter? Buy or lease?
Dr. Dave, behind
the wheel, huh?
This is topaz
blue metallic.
What do you think?
I think it's out
of your price range.
Moon lighting at a doc
in the box, my friend.
There you go, three months,
I got my down payment.
Ooh, and then what happens?
Yeah, fake my own death.
Hey, uh, you playing
ball tonight?
We're gonna kick
sanitation's ass.
Maybe.
Neck pain in curtain one
is asking for you.
Yeah, I'll be right there.
Black or sand interior?
Dr. Malucci, I hope
you're not keeping
patients waiting while
you shop for a car.
No, no, no, I'm all over
that board, chief.
Don't worry, he still has to
pass his driver's license test.
Dr. Carter, can I speak
to you a minute?
Sure.
‐ 'Morning.'
‐ Morning, Dr. Chen.
‐ Hey.
‐ Deb.
‐ Could you excuse us a minute?
‐ Oh, sure.
Your application was
intercepted by administration.
The processing time
has improved.
Ah, you realize you're still
on a probationary period?
Which will be completed
by the time
the chief resident slot
needs to be filled.
Why do you wanna
do this?
Well, it gets me closer
to a junior faculty position.
Looks good on the CV.
No, I mean why risk
compromising your recovery
by taking on a new
and very demanding position?
I guess I don't
see it as a risk.
Having teaching and
administrative responsibilities
along with your
clinical shifts?
I'm in the program.
I've been managing my stress.
I got myself...back up
to speed.
Carter, you'd all but give up
nights and weekends.
It's a tremendous
amount of work.
I'm ready for it.
You can't just gloss over
what happened last year.
Neither can the committee.
You're returning
my application?
Did you honestly think that
you'd make the first cut?
‐ Get your hands off me!
‐ He's all yours.
Yeah, let me take
a closer look.
Don't touch me!
It'll feel better
in a second, I promise.
‐ Mild erythema, no blistering.
‐ It hurts. Stop!
You have to let
the doctor finish, okay?
You wanna tell
me what happened?
No.
I think, he may have
lit the fire himself.
Shut up!
'Why don't we get
a burn tray for Ben here?'
Sure.
‐ He's home by himself a lot.
‐ I said, shut up!
Just wish he would stop
hangin' around my son.
Hey, good news.
Our second baseman
has a stomach flu.
Luka, I'm not
playing softball.
But, you don't have to be
great, it's just for fun.
Actually, I happen
to play very well.
‐ So go, it'd be good for you.
‐ I can't.
One night away from your mother
isn't gonna do anything.
I miss you.
Have a good time tonight.
Connie, can you dispense some
ketoconazole to exam one?
‐ Sure.
‐ Thanks.
Emergency ringworm, huh?
Yeah, pretty hard
to avoid, the guy has 40 cats.
You might want to give him a
flea bath while you're at it.
So what's going on
between you and Weaver?
Not much.
Except for her denying my
application for chief resident.
Apparently, I still have
a scarlet A on my chest.
Oh, wow, I'm
really sorry, John.
Don't be.
Makes you a shoo‐in.
‐ There are other candidates.
‐ Not really.
I guess congratulations
are in order.
Congratulations,
you deserve it.
‐ Thanks.
‐ Not as much as me, but..
Yeah, right.
‐ Hey.
‐ It's on the chair.
‐ I put a cap in there, too.
‐ Alright, good.
Just stay a while
and have some coffee maybe?
Uh, you know what,
I need to get back.
You alright?
Yeah.
Hmm, Roger..
...moved out a few days ago.
'I'll be okay.'
You sure?
It would've saved us both
a whole lot of trouble
if we had just stayed
together, you know, Peter?
Would've been better
for Reese, anyway.
He said he never
loved me.
You know, Carla,
people say a lot of things
they don't mean
when they're fighting.
I don't know.
I think, uh, it's true.
Maybe we never had anything.
It'll work itself out.
You and I..
We had somethin'.
Didn't we, Peter, hmm?
Hmm?
Sometimes I think
we still do.
I'm not doing this, Carla.
'Peter don't go.'
‐ Yeah?
‐ 'That's a nice hello .'
Cleo.
Did you make it to Carla's yet?
‐ 'A few minutes ago.'
‐ 'Good.'
'Hey, how about picking up
Deli on the way home?'
'We can have a picnic
on the field.'
Uh, sure, yeah, whatever.
‐ You alright?
‐'Yeah, why?'
'I don't know,
you sound funny.'
‐ 'She giving you a hard time?'
‐ Who?
‐ Carla.
‐ 'You know, I'm sorry.'
'I'm‐I'm just in a rush.'
Oh. Reese, wait!
‐ 'What's he doing?'
‐ Hang on, Peter.
Oh, my God!
Cleo, what happened?
Is there somethin' wrong?
Read it and weep.
No bleeding, no hydrocephalus,
no midline shift
no subarachnoid hemorrhage.
Okay, do an LP.
Hey, crying
neck pain patient.
Well, you want me to give
a Demerol junkie a spinal tap?
CT's are only
95% sensitive, Dave.
Ooh, what are you two,
a tag team?
I know what I'm doing.
Oh, to be a junior
resident again.
Not.
‐ Dr. Chen, can I see you?
‐ Sure.
‐ Good luck.
‐ Thanks.
As you know, chief residency
is typically an extra year
completing the emergency
medicine program.
In rare cases we
make an exception
and allow a senior to be
promoted into the position.
Right.
Unfortunately,
your maternity leave
put you three months behind
on shifts and procedures
keeping you just shy
of senior status.
Um, but I'm in the process
of making that up.
Yes, but the academic
year ends June 30th.
And I'm planning
on working every weekend
'and every holiday
until then.'
Hospital policy actively
discourages work weeks
in excess of 60 hours
and given that limitation
it‐it doesn't
seem feasible
that you'd succeed
in making the deadline.
Oh.
And, as a result I'm afraid
you won't be a candidate
for chief resident this year.
I'm sorry, I‐I know
it doesn't seem fair‐‐
Wait, this is completely
sexist and discriminatory.
Excuse me?
You all but offered
me this position
prior to my pregnancy.
Yes, and at that time
I anticipated your
completion of the program.
I had a baby.
I think I made
a choice that was
both legal
and responsible.
‐ Of course you did.
‐ I made a sacrifice.
Largely for the sake
of my career
and becoming chief resident
is a huge part of that.
‐ Jing‐Mei..
‐ I'm a good doctor.
I've offered to make up for lost
time, and I didn't screw up.
Under the circumstances,
I think I deserve a chance.
I appreciate your thoughts
and I'll take them
under advisement.
I'd hope you would.
‐ What is that stuff?
‐ Thermazene cream.
It'll make you
feel better and it helps
to keep it
from getting infected.
‐ My fingers feel funny.
‐ How?
‐ I can't feel the ends.
‐ No?
‐ Maybe with this hand.
‐ Hey!
You know,
that's not funny.
‐ Everything okay in here?
‐ Yeah.
Little Ben here
just tried to grab me.
She was hurting my hand.
Oh, yeah?
Let me take a look.
He says he can't
feel his fingers.
Let me see your hand.
Show them.
‐ Ouch!
‐ Oh, it hurts there, huh?
‐ Did you fall?
‐ I don't know. Maybe.
Let's get an X‐ray
of this left hand, just in case.
Ouch! Ow.
‐ Whoa, hey, hey!
‐ Hey, hey, hey!
‐ Settle down.
‐ My head.
Yeah, okay. Let me take
a look at your head.
Hey, do you remember
when you hurt your ear?
Huh?
You gotta pretty
bad bruise back here.
Six disc cd changer,
tinted windows that's.. Hello?
Here's an ACL arterial
exam two.
‐ Yeah, I was on my way, chief.
‐ Yeah?
Dr. Malucci, you're a resident.
You can't afford a car!
What was all that about?
A misguided sense
of job security.
Lot of that
going around.
I heard you came
by the house.
Yeah, I was in the area and
on a whim I thought I'd stop by.
Lori said that
you had a letter
but that you didn't
leave it?
Just didn't seem like
the timing was very good.
I can see how you
would feel that way.
How long have you two
been seeing each other?
Not long.
I'm sorry. I know this
must be painful for you.
No, I'm fine,
I mean, it's fine.
Okay.
'Kerry?'
‐ You take care of yourself.
‐ Yeah, you, too.
Okay.
I'm sorry. I didn't
mean to interrupt.
You didn't.
You two okay?
Oh, Dr. Legaspi.
‐ Hi.
I was wondering
if you could tell me
how it's going
with my mother?
Oh, I'm sorry, Abby.
I really can't discuss
her therapy with you.
Even if she said
you said
I should attend one
of her sessions?
I think that it would be
mutually beneficial, yeah.
Okay.
Could you, uh, give me a little
bit of an idea what to expect?
Well, it's not an ambush.
I'm sorry. It's just that,
she lies a lot.
We meet at 1:00.
You don't have to come
if you don't want to.
Still hurt? I'm sorry.
Oh, baby, look at you!
Oh, it's alright.
Mommy's here.
How bad is it?
He's got a fracture
of the fifth metacarpal.
His hand is broken?
He's going to have to wear
a cast six to eight weeks.
‐ How is he gonna sign?
‐ He's not.
Alright. It's okay.
'Mommy's here.
It's going to be okay.'
I'm sorry, I just looked
away for a second
and he was at the piano.
Listen, uh, why don't you
give us a few minutes, okay?
Of course.
Hey.
This is your fault,
you know?
I am so sorry.
Uh‐huh. Reese is
not like other children.
I know.
Then how come you
didn't stay in his eyeline?
It was an accident.
Carla, I don't know
what else to say.
I feel horrible
about this.
I want you to stay
away from my son.
Carla, can we just‐‐
What would have happened
if you had turned away again?
What would've happened if Reese
had run out into the street?
He is deaf! You cannot
just call out to him!
Alright‐alright,
Carla, Carla..
You have to be
with him every second!
I don't want
to see this bitch!
‐ I said back off!
‐ Anywhere near Reese again..
‐ You hear me, Peter?
‐ Go.
‐ Hey.
‐ Hi.
Hit and run.
ETA is five minutes.
Kind of like, uh,
waiting for thunder
after the
lightning strikes.
Dr. Legaspi and I..
It ended.
'I'm sorry.'
Something changed?
Yes.
Do you love her?
Then you should go
forward, not back, hmm?
50 year old male changing
a blowout on the shoulder
got sideswiped by a car.
LOC at the scene.
But started coming around
in the rig.
Obvious femur
fracture. Vitals?
Initial at 90 palp.
BP's up to 115/70.
'after 1500cc's of saline.'
'Sir, can you
tell us your name?'
Jim Vogel.
God, my legs!
‐ Trauma two. Go.
‐ 'Serial crits.'
Type and cross times four get
a C‐spine, chest and pelvis.
Got one more, doc.
She won't come out.
Restrained, but got
a small forehead LAC
from the rearview mirror.
Brother said she's
developmentally challenged.
‐ This is her baseline.
‐ What's her name?
Won't say. I'm not sure
she understands the question.
'Hi, I'm Dr. Weaver.
Can you tell me who you are?'
Jim's sister.
Okay, well,
we need to make sure
you're not seriously hurt,
so can you come out?
‐ I want to go again.
‐ I'm sorry?
On a ride. It's fun.
She's been smiling like this
ever since they
got her on the rig.
Here we go.
Crepitation's on the right
with decreased air entry.
I need that chest tube.
Tachy at 110.
I'll set it up.
God, I can't stand it!
‐ What'd you got so far?
‐ Pneumo on the right.
Unstable pelvis
and fractured right hip.
Where's Bonnie?
Is she alright?
‐ Is that your sister's name?
‐ Yeah.
Another doctor
is checking her
and she appears to have
only minor injuries.
Mr. Vogel, does Bonnie have
any medical conditions
other than her
developmental delay?
No, she's‐she's
always been healthy.
Okay.
'In reality, I was used
to being disappointed..'
Sorry I'm late.
It's fine. We're glad
you could join us.
‐ Hi.
Please know that
we both understand
how awkward it can be to step
into someone else's therapy.
It's okay. I'm fine.
Maggie, do you want
to continue?
Sure, um..
So, uh, Dr. Legaspi
and I were talking about..
...well, we were talking
about a lot of things
'but we were talking about ways
that I could stay healthy.'
You know, how to
position myself to..
...get it together,
keep on track and um..
Part of that is..
...that I've
decided to go home.
‐ Have you talked to Eric?
‐ No, not Florida.
Um, home‐home.
I‐I'm going back
to Minnesota.
Uh..
Uh, you‐you haven't been
to Minneapolis in 15 years, mom.
I know that.
I know I‐I haven't.
But I grew up there,
and I feel like I belong there.
'I've got, you know, a little
bit of family and some friends.'
What friends?
Gina. You remember Gina?
'Well, I'm gonna
stay with her and..'
'She has a spare room.'
She thinks she
could get me a job
at the Convalescent Hospital
where she works.
Really? And when did
you arrange all this?
Last week. I..
She accepted a collect
phone call from me.
She was glad
to hear from me, Abby.
'She was glad
to talk to me.'
Anyway, I‐I, I'll,
I'll save enough money
and I'll get
a place of my own.
A place of your own?
'Yes, a place of my own.'
With no roommates, no men,
just me. Maybe a cat.
A cat? That would be
a great pet, a cat.
Abby, are you reacting
to your mother's plans?
I'm not reacting.
I...I'm just..
Just‐just what?
Nothing.
Abby, I can't
stay here, in Chicago.
I don't want
to go to Florida.
It's just too easy for me
to be a drain on you and‐‐
You know, I think we're
way past that at this point.
What is your objection
to your mother going home?
Nothing.
It's very romantic.
You're not happy about it?
I...I don't know what‐what
you want me to say.
Yippee, she's going home?
'Fabulous. That solves
all the problems? Uh, what?'
Then what is your solution?
I don't have a solution.
I‐I don't have..
I don't think
there is a solution.
'And to talk about
this as if it were'
some sort of
"life‐management" problem
that you can plan your out
of is...well, it's absurd.
Then what do you suggest?
I‐I don't know.
You know what? I don't know.
I don't know.
So, I guess you're right.
You have to do
something, mom. Good luck.
So, what, you're leaving?
You wanted to tell me.
You told me.
Well, I'm not going
for a week or so.
Okay, great.
See you later.
When did Ben Fossen's
father arrive?
‐ A while ago.
‐ Someone should've told me.
Hi, I'm Dr. Greene.
Derek Fossen. Thanks
for taking care of him.
Sure. Could we
talk outside?
Yeah. I'll be
right outside, Ben.
Mrs. Shayotovich
told me about the fire.
‐ Your neighbor?
‐ No.
He's always getting
into trouble.
‐ Yeah?
‐ Yeah.
His mom's
out of the picture
and I think
it makes him act out.
Mm‐hmm. Well, those
burns will heal.
Oh, good. Thanks.
I'm just waiting on the
psychiatrist come talk to Ben.
Psychiatrist? Why?
We found some unusual bruising
on your son, Mr. Fossen.
‐ Do you know about that?
‐ No.
You've never
noticed the bruises?
Well, he gets
into scrapes at school.
‐ Fights?
‐ Yeah.
‐ Any serious injuries?
‐ No more than any kid.
Well, I'm sure he'll
tell that to the doctor.
Look, he doesn't need
a psychiatrist
and I have to get
back to work, so‐‐
I know, I know.
This won't take long.
We're supposed
to be at the park.
Is that where you were driving?
2:00 to 4:00
we go to the park.
But we had a crash.
I know.
My parents had a crash.
When's Jimmy coming back?
I don't know.
Did they die in the crash?
Your parents?
So what do you do...in
the park, Bonnie?
‐ The slide.
‐ Hmm!
‐ Anything else?
‐ The swing.
You know,
Jimmy pushes me..
...not too high, though.
Do you have any other
brothers or sisters?
Nope.
C‐spine is clear.
No perihepatic fluid,
but I can't see the spleen.
‐ Where's Bonnie?
‐ She's fine.
‐ She's getting some sutures.
‐ Oh, thank God.
Minimal blood in the Thora Seal
but his repeat crit is 34.
‐ He's bleeding from somewhere.
‐ Probably here.
‐ 'What's wrong?'
‐ You shattered your pelvis.
‐ 'That'll heal, though, right?'
‐ Yes.
But the edges of the bone
may be cutting an artery.
We need to do
a CAT scan to see
where the bleeding
is coming from.
'Lydia, call radiology.'
'Tell 'em we need abdomen
and pelvis with contrast.'
‐ Will I need surgery?
‐ We'll know after the scan.
Because I can't be laid up.
My sister‐‐
Yes, yes, I know.
We'll try to stop the bleeding
by injecting a clotting
agent into the artery.
BP is down to 95/60.
Okay, hang
another two units
and call for six
type‐specific.
Okay, we need to go now.
I'm gonna bring Carla home.
Then go by your place
to pick up his stuff.
Fine.
Listen, Cleo,
I told you. You know.
Reese, he needs
special attention.
Peter, I know that.
I made a mistake.
Alright.
You know, but you're acting like
I deliberately let him get hurt.
I'm sorry
about what happened.
Carla gets upset.
Well, I don't get called
a bitch by anyone.
'Bonnie?'
Where are you
supposed to be?
‐ Finding my brother.
‐ Okay.
Jing‐Mei.
Oh, Bonnie, you're supposed
to stay in that room.
I have to tell my brother
what I want for dinner.
Why is he back?
Dropped his
pressure upstairs.
There he is. Jimmy!
'BP's only 80 palp.'
'Hang another two units on the
infuser. What'd the scan show?'
'He crashed before we even
got him on the table.'
'Dr. Weaver?'
'Open a peritoneal lavage kit.'
We'll go supra‐umbilical.
Lydia, drop an NG.
My sister has special needs.
Let's worry
about you right now.
‐ 'Hemocue's ten.'
‐ 'Okay.'
We need central access.
Somebody get Dr. Chen!
There's no one else but me.
Okay, Jim. Dr. Chen,
put in a subclavian.
'Got it.'
'Pressure's down to 70,
pulse ox dropped to 84.'
Jim? Jim?
He's not breathing.
Give me an 8‐0 tube!
'Bag him on a 100%.'
Get in that line!
'Luka, if the tap
is positive he goes to the OR.'
'If not, maybe we can
embolize the pelvic bleeders.'
‐ I'm in.
‐ Okay.
Squeeze in
all the blood you can.
Call for eight more units.
‐ Well, the hand's okay.
‐ Look at the wrist.
Is that
a Colles fracture?
Ben says he never
hurt his wrist.
Or maybe he was
too young to remember it.
His dad doesn't
remember, either.
How'd your talk
go with him?
Well, he's
a pretty hostile kid.
Clammed up when
dad showed up, though.
Yeah, it was hard
to talk to him.
His dad was standing
outside the door
the whole time
and Ben knew it.
He's terrified of him.
I think he is, but, uh..
He says there's no
violence in the home.
You saw that bruising.
That's him getting
pulled by his ear.
He says that he doesn't
remember how it happened.
You don't forget a broken bone
or bruising like that.
‐ 'Lost his pulse.'
‐ He'll never make it to angio.
Pump in that blood. Order two
units of FFP. He's in V‐fib.
Starting compressions.
'Okay, charge to 200.'
Clear.
‐ V‐fib.
‐ Thoracotomy tray.
It's blunt trauma.
It's an isolated
pelvic injury. Clear.
'Lydia, close the
blinds to suture.'
'Still in fib.'
'360. Clear.'
'I'm starving.'
'What'd we pick
something up from Doc Magoo's.'
You know, if I were smart,
I would have gone for lunch.
Instead of getting reamed
by my mother and Legaspi..
And I don't get it,
because a week ago
she wanted
to have her committed
and now she's
completely on her side.
‐ Not about sides.
‐ Well, it felt like it was.
All of a sudden, it was all
about me and what was my problem
that I couldn't get on board
with this plan she figured out?
Would any plan
have made you happy?
No.
When was the last time
your mom was in therapy?
I don't know like,
10 years ago.
‐ That's different.
‐ Yeah.
So, you've got a choice,
you are gonna either hope
that she makes it
this time or...give up.
Right.
Doesn't seem like
you want to do that.
I don't know
what I want to do.
Weaver dropped a bomb
on me this morning.
'What happened?'
She bagged me
for chief resident.
Really?
Apparently, my rehab
is caught up to me.
Oh, no.
I'm sorry.
It's not your fault.
Not exactly.
I guess part of facing
the problem is accepting
that some people
won't get over it.
I'm sorry, John.
Me, too.
For you.
'Get a ten pack of platelets.'
‐ Heart's not filling.
‐ 'Units nine and ten are in.'
‐ 'Hold compressions.'
‐ 'Still in fib.'
‐ 'Vasopressin'?'
‐ 'On board.'
'Another 100 of lido.
I'll take the internal paddles.'
‐ How long's he been down?
‐ Thirty‐Five minutes.
Charge to 20.
Jimmy?
Bonnie, you have to go outside.
Clear!
‐ I don't like that.
‐ Charge again.
‐ Lydia, Lydia, Lydia.
‐ I don't want you to do that!
No, we‐we're trying
to help him.
But it hurts him!
‐ Clear!
‐ 'It hurts him.'
'Charge again.'
'Clear.'
Heart's empty.
Asystole.
Should we try pacing him?
Okay, that is it.
Time of death?
17:10.
‐ Can you close the chest up?
‐ Yeah.
Clean him up but leave
the tubes in for the coroner.
I'll tell his sister.
Want me to
come with you?
Yeah.
'I'm‐I'm tired of it, here.'
'I think Jimmy and me
should go home.'
Well, the doctors are going
to talk to you now.
‐ Hi, Bonnie.
‐ Hi.
Bonnie, this is
your brother's doctor.
Is he ready to go?
Bonnie, Jim was very hurt.
And he couldn't recover
from his injuries.
‐ Cover?
‐ Get better.
Your brother died, Bonnie,
I'm sorry.
'Do you understand?'
Like Ernie.
He died.
Um, who's Ernie?
My hamster.
We put him in a box.
'Okay.'
Well, like your hamster,
Jim won't be with you anymore.
I got a new hamster.
His name is Ernie, too.
You know how
your parents went away?
In the crash?
Jimmy went away
like that too.
But it's library night.
'I know.'
And I get scared at night.
Bonnie, you're gonna
have to be very brave.
Where's Jimmy?
There you are.
‐ Hi.
‐ Do you have a minute?
Sure. Am I in trouble
or something?
I don't usually do this,
but I think that it's important.
Okay.
I think you need to give
your mom one more chance.
Didn't I just do that,
today?
Well, you started to,
and then you ran away.
Maybe that's because,
I've heard it
about a hundred times,
before.
I think this time
it's different.
Do you? Why?
Well, for one thing,
she hasn't been willing
to go to therapy for ten years
now, she's embracing it.
I'd love to believe,
that meant something.
Don't let your mom go away
without being able
to really talk to you.
That won't make,
either of you happy.
I don't think happy
is on the table.
‐ Why not?
‐ Look, I'm not in therapy.
Fair enough.
But I'll consider it.
What you said.
Okay.
She has the mind
of a seven‐year‐old.
No other relatives?
Her brother
was her only family.
I tried ARC, protection
and advocacy, no luck.
Well, the facilities
were all full.
She'll have to take a
temporary place at a group home.
No, I don't want her,
sent to a place like that.
I mean, they've got four
or five people in every room.
Well, unless you want
to take her home
this is all, I can offer.
Okay, but‐but
I don't want to hear
about her, sleeping on
a couch or on the floor.
Alright, well,
I'll pass that along.
You'll have to
get her there, yourself.
They're too backed up
to come, pick her up.
‐ Oh, come on!
‐ I'm just the messenger.
Look, in time,
she'll adjust.
Adele, this stinks.
They've got job
training programs
and hopefully,
she'll learn a skill.
Adele, ready?
Oh, yeah.
Sorry.
It's about time.
Ben has not eaten,
since noon.
‐ 'We'll get him something.'
‐ We'd rather just go.
Mr. Fossen,
this is Adele Neumann.
‐ She's a social worker.
‐ Hi.
‐ Hi, Ben.
Look, my kid does not need
any more counseling or whatever.
I'm afraid Ben's gonna have
to stay here for a few days.
What?
We're taking him into
emergency custody.
What are you
talking about? What for?
I'm not comfortable with the
bruising I found on your son.
Oh, God forbid
you're not comfortable.
And I also found evidence
of a broken wrist
'which neither
of you mentioned.'
I told you that he fights.
‐ Would you tell them, please?
‐ I fight a lot.
You know what, if that's true
then you'll get to go home
in three days.
‐ But right now, I need you to‐‐
‐ I don't want to.
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
You're not doing this!
You're not doing this to us!
Security!
Get your hands off from me!
You don't have a choice here,
Mr. Fossen.
You think I hurt my kid?
You're crazy.
I suggest you contact,
a lawyer.
‐ They'd sue your ass!
‐ It's for your protection, Ben.
I don't want to go away!
Please let me stay with him!
‐ I'm sorry.
‐ Leave him alone!
‐ No! Dad! Please!
‐ You bastard!
‐ Please!
‐ Why are you doing this to us?
‐ Dad! Dad!
‐ Hi.
Guess what? The super,
finally fixed the stove fan.
So, I cooked dinner.
Cucumber soup,
a little salmon.
Why don't you invite,
Luka to dinner?
He's playin' softball.
That sounds like fun.
Are you gonna go?
I don't play, um..
The reason why,
I ran out today
like that, is because
it's just, um..
It's scary to hope
too much, you know?
Yeah, I know.
I know, I might not make it,
but Abby..
...something happened to me,
in that ICU room.
I realized
I don't wanna die.
And more than that..
I don't want my little girl
to watch me die.
I can't do that to you,
not ever.
That's what I wanted
to tell you today.
I'm gonna handle my life.
And I want you to
get on with yours.
Okay.
You can't put your life
on hold anymore.
‐ It's not on hold.
‐ What do you mean?
You won't even go play softball,
with your boyfriend.
So? I don't wanna play.
Stop sitting things out,
Abby.
I don't.
Yes, you do.
You can't use me
as the reason
for not doing the things,
you want to do in life.
‐ Go to medical school.
‐ Well, that's not so easy.
‐ Get married.
‐ I was married.
‐ Get pregnant!
‐ I was pregnant!
What happened?
What happened.
I had an abortion.
Some people aren't
meant to be mothers.
Abby, I was a lot younger
than you are now
when I had my first
manic episode.
I've watched you since,
you were a little girl.
You're not bipolar.
No, but my kids could be.
But they might not be.
They could be anything
and you would just love them,
that's all.
You never even
told Richard, did you?
No, I...I think that was
the beginning of the end for us
'cause we just stopped
talking about everything.
I just was, too scared.
I cou..
I couldn't risk it.
I just,
I didn't, want to..
‐ Turn into me.
‐ Yeah.
Or have to end up
taking care of another me?
Oh, honey.
Oh, sweetie,
sweetie, sweetie.
That's all
there is, is risk.
You just have to take a chance
and leap into life.
Otherwise, sweetheart,
you're going to miss out
on all the great things.
Abby, you deserve,
all the great things.
Do you hear me?
But I like, my home.
Someone there
will take good care of you.
This man's gonna
drive you, okay?
Jimmy was gonna make me
hot dogs tonight.
Okay, take this woman
to this address
and make sure she's met by
an adult before you leave, okay?
‐ Yeah, alright.
‐ Will they have hot dogs?
I don't know, but I'm sure
they'll have something good.
Here you go.
I better go to my home.
I'm sorry, you can't.
But I like my home.
I like my bed
and my blanket.
Bonnie, you can't live alone.
But I need my blanket.
Jimmy always
gives me my blanket.
Yeah, there'll be someone there
to give you one, okay?
And he gives me,
hot dogs when I want.
'I like my home.'
'I don't want a new one.'
Bonnie..
Zip‐up your jacket, sweetie,
it's chilly.
Hey, batter, batter!
No batter, no batter!
Strike one!
‐ That's good, right?
‐ That's good.
‐ 'Put it right here, doc.'
‐ You got it, big guy.
Yes! Strike two!
‐ 'Whoo!'
‐ 'It's alright.'
'Right here.'
Luka, look alive, man.
'Hey, batter, batter!'
No batter!
‐ Yes!
‐ Strike!
‐ Changed your mind?
‐ Yeah.
I even brought
my own glove.
‐ 'Hey, Abby, you playing?'
‐ Yeah.
Alright, then pick your weapon
'cause you're up right,
after Carter.
'Alright, guys keep your head
in the game.'
'You brought your mom?'
Go get 'em, John!
Thank you, Maggie.
Alright, Carter,
get in there now.
'You see it, right?'
Luka, I didn't know,
you played softball.
I don't. I'm last
in the batting order.
You should put Abby up,
She was an all‐star
on her little league team.
‐ How about you?
‐ I'm just gonna watch.
All‐star?
I like you,
in that hat.
Almost looked,
American huh?
Almost.
Some vocabulary
for a seven‐year‐old.
Bone survey turned up
bilateral, healed
spiral fractures
of the radius.
‐ So, you were right.
‐ Pin a rose on me.
Kim.
Hi, Kerry.
Um, this is for you.
What is it?
It's how I feel about things,
about, about you.
And I never really told you,
and maybe it doesn't matter now
but I‐I wanted you to know.
Okay.
You broke,
both your arms, Ben.
No, they're fine.
Uh, these're your X‐rays,
and these lines, are fractures.
That was a long time ago.
I tripped at school.
Uh, you don't get these
kind of breaks from fallin'.
After I tripped,
I fell down the stairs.
No, Ben.
You know,
what I think happened?
I think somebody,
grabbed your arm
with two hands
and then twisted it.
'Like‐like you do
with a wet towel.'
I'm bad, a lot.
You are?
I make too much noise,
playing.
I leave messes.
And dad punishes you?
Well, how does
he punish you?
Sometimes, like you said.
He calls 'em Indian burns.
Yeah?
It's my fault. He wouldn't
do it, if I wasn't bad.
No, Ben.
Nobody should break your arm,
no matter how bad you are.
You understand?
I don't care.
I just want to go home.
You can't go home
right now, Ben.
I'm sorry.
Come on, Malik,
show 'em where you live!
‐ Yes!
‐ Whoo!
‐ 'Run, Abby!'
‐ Run, Abby!
'Way to go, Abby!'
Brought your cheering
section, I see.
'That's my girl!
That's good!'
Go get 'em.
Alright, Luka just
make contact with the ball.
Just meet the ball like we
talked about, alright?
Hey.
‐ 'Strike one!'
‐ 'Alright.'
You were so great!
You were, great!
Did you hear
me cheering?
Yes.
I think everybody
heard you cheering.
‐ Strike two!
‐ Luka, don't crowd the plate!
What?
The plate!
Get back!
He's very cute,
but he's no, Mickey Mantle.
No.
Ball one!
‐ Are you cold?
‐ No, no, I love it.
‐ Thank you for bringing me.
‐ 'Ball two.'
You looked like
you were having fun.
I was.
That's good.
That's really good
‐ 'Foul ball!'
‐ 'It's a foul ball! '
That's a foul ball!
That's a foul ball.
‐ I know.
‐ 'It's a foul ball.'
I don't think
he knows that.
Run, Luka. Run!