Three gunshots. One looks fatal.
You should have let us
land ten minutes ago.
Suspect was pinned down.
He was still firing.
He was shooting at the school?
They were shooting everywhere.
A unit responded to
armored truck robbery.
The suspects opened fire.
I'll take this one.
Where are my glasses?
‐ Is he alert?
‐ Sort of.
Name's Daniel.
Daniel, do you know
where you are?
I lost my glasses.
Can you tell me where you are.
School.
Exit wound out the right temple.
What kind of ammunition
were they using?
One had a large caliber
assault rifle
to shoot through
the engine block.
We'll never get her back
with a head wound like that.
Stop compressions.
My dad..
Somebody call my dad!
I'm Dr. Kovac.
What's your name?
Nicholas.
Take a deep breath, Nicholas.
Could you call my dad?
Vinny Rosato.
He works at Covin.
312‐54..
How's he doing?
Chest is clear,
good radial pulse.
Titrate four of morphine.
54... 548.
'Don't worry.'
'I'm sure the school has it.'
That could take a while
we're evacuating
out of the front
of the building.
Why?
We've apprehended two suspects.
There might be another one.
Might be?
'Can you feel your leg?'
'Kind of.'
It's like going to sleep.
‐ Like, pins and needles?
‐ Yeah.
Where are the paramedics?
We're wavin' them through.
You got any ancef?
Red bag, side pocket.
Is yours stable by ground?
He should be, bullet fragment
missed the brain.
What about yours?
'Clean through the shoulder'
But, there's one to the groin
with a cold foot.
Ah, we've got to
revascularize within..
Okay, clear out.
‐ What?
‐ Go! Now!
He's in the building,
comin' out!
'Let me examine him.'
We have to search him first.
Is he still breathing?
Yeah, he's clear.
Alright, come ahead.
You shot him through the vest?
‐ Right chest.
‐ Alright, BP?
Sir, I'm a doctor,
I'm here to help.
‐ Can you talk?
‐ Go to hell.
Okay, I'll take that as a yes.
Diminished breath sounds
on the right.
BP's 100 over 65.
His pulse is at 88.
Alright, let's get
a large‐bore IV.
And let's roll him.
No exit wound.
Alright, he needs a chest tube.
Let's get betadine
and steri‐drape
and take that mask off him.
‐ 'You got this?'
‐ Yeah. Lidocaine.
I'm sending the eye
by ambulance
and taking the leg
in the chopper.
Hold on, hold on I might need
to fly this guy. Ten blade.
No room. Take him by ground.
Hold on, I just want to make
sure he's stable.
You can bring him to Mercy.
County's the closest
pediatric trauma center.
Just wait until I get
the chest tube in.
Alright, 32 French, come on.
Chris, take two units
of O‐neg from the cooler
in the chopper.
I'm loading my kid.
I said wait!
Kovac!
The suspect is apparently alive.
We are waiting
for confirmation on that.
If you are just joining us
this is a live shot
of Phalen elementary school.
Is that Dr. Kovac?
I dunno, it's hard to say.
No, he's too short to be Kovac.
Has anyone seen the tool kit?
‐ What tool kit?
‐ The do‐it‐yourself kit.
The one with the hammer,
pliers, screwdriver.
What are you gonna do
build a tree house?
I got a guy
who drilled a wood screw
into his tibia
with a power drill.
Somebody gonna get that?
Thanks, Abby.
What are you guys watching?
Where have you been?
A shooting near a school.
Weaver sent Benton and Kovac.
Hmm, why'd they get to go?
Because they don't
get sick in the chopper.
Hey, I already told you
I had the flu, okay.
I got it.
What are you going to do
take it out with a screwdriver?
Yeah, You got a better idea?
MVA comin' in, single auto
versus parking structure.
‐ ETA?
‐ Five to ten.
Alright, get Weaver.
I'll meet you in trauma two.
Hey, hey, why do you get it?
I'll call you
if he needs his oil changed.
The drive might be faster
with morning traffic.
It's your call.
Hold on. Pulse
is weak and thready.
Hey, man, are you still with me?
Heart rate's up to 120.
The chest output's over 500cc's.
He's bleeding out
through his chest.
Spike a unit of o‐neg.
BP's down to 70 palp.
‐ Alright, follow me.
‐ But, where you going?
We'll transport by chopper.
Half liter bolus, then TKO.
‐ He's bleeding out.
‐ What?
The guy, the shooter,
he's bleeding out.
I need the chopper.
Where are we going
to put him?
We're gonna have to
take the boy off.
He has a pulseless leg.
Yeah, but we got five hours
to revascularize.
I'm not going to waste time
transporting by ground.
This guy's pressure's crashing!
Then, give him blood.
‐ C'mon, get out of the chopper!
‐ No way.
Look, my patient
is more critical.
Your patient killed people.
That's not our call.
Come on.
Close the door.
Let's go.
Kovac, open up the door!
Stand back.
Open up the door!
Stand back!
‐ Ow! Ow! Ow!
‐ IV's in.
That's it, I'm out of here.
‐ Screw you!
‐ Oh, you're welcome.
‐ Thank you, Doris.
‐ Anytime.
What have you got, Carter?
A combative single MVA.
Ran into a parking lot booth.
Get this thing off my neck!
‐ Was anybody in it?
‐ No.
I can't breathe!
He's altered, tachy
and hypertensive.
He'll need a head CT.
Get this thing off!
Neck looks clear.
Okay, remove the collar.
BP's up, 200 over 100.
Okay, hold still.
‐ Get it off.
‐ That's what I'm doing.
Looks like a posterior
hip dislocation.
Alright, titrate
200 of fentanyl
'and six of versed.'
I'll reduce it.
‐ You might wanna look at this.
‐ What's wrong?
It's a goiter,
I think a big one.
That's one of versed
and 50 of fentanyl.
What are you doing?
Don't touch me!
Keep going.
He can take a little more.
Hey, did you notice
any hand tremors?
No, he was moving around
all over the place.
That's another 50 of fentanyl.
You thinking thyroid storm?
IV Inderal, 100 PTU.
'So, he's not on drugs?'
No, his thyroid is hyperactive.
I'm going to
kill someone, I swear.
'How much inderal?'
'Titrate a milligram'
every two minutes.'
Okay, he's out.
Have you ever reduced
a hip before?
No.
You just want
to stabilize the pelvis.
No, from above, up.
‐ Yeah.
Alright, I'm
going to pull up.
On three.
One, two, three.
'Oh, my God!'
'Carter!'
Carter, are you alright?
'Let me up, I wanna get up.'
Carter!
Push another two of versed.
Okay, somebody grab Malucci.
He can do this.
‐ I can do it.
‐ 'John, sit down.'
I said I can do it.
'Stay off me.'
‐ Is he out this time?
‐ Yeah, he's out.
I don't want you to
aggravate your injury.
Are you ready?
‐ You ready?
‐ Yeah.
Thank you, now maintain
downward pressure.
Don't be gentle.
One, two, three.
Okay, I got it.
Femoral head is back in place.
Good job, Carter.
Ah, it's just like
fallin' off a horse.
'Heart rate's down to 110.'
Dr. Weaver.
Got a hot MI In curtain three.
‐ You got it from here?
‐ Hard part's over.
Let's get him up to radiology
and then we'll get
a post‐reduction film later.
'I'm sorry about that.'
Now you know. It takes a lot
of counter‐traction.
Hey, can you baby‐sit
him in radiology?
'Sure.'
Thank you.
'Did I leave his chart in here?'
Is it over on the mayo stand?
Uh...no.
Just cleanin' up.
Yeah.
There it is.
Over on the pulse ox.
‐ What?
‐ The chart is over there.
Thanks.
Oh, look at this, a needle
stick waiting to happen.
Can't be too careful.
That's right.
Hey, make sure they do a head
abdomen, and pelvis on that guy.
Sure.
And, come find me, hunt me down.
Let me see the films.
‐ Okay.
‐ Thanks.
‐ Yeah.
‐ 'Thank you.'
What's his last
pressure?
‐ Stable, 110 over 70.
‐ How is he?
GSW to the groin
with a pulseless leg.
What about the arm?
Through and through..
Does he have sensation
in the foot?
We're losing it.
I'm going to lose my leg?
Not if I have anything
to say about it.
Send burns for
a shoulder X‐ray.
Subramaniam needs
a dilantin level.
What the hell is that?
Mr. Goodwrench
is tunin' up a patient.
What?
You got to hold still, man.
Malucci, what are you doing?
Hey, boss.
Ah, you know what?
Let's take a break, okay?
‐ Okay.
‐ All good.
Guy drove the screw
into his leg.
Yeah, I can see that,
I think he needs
a little more lidocaine?
He won't even take an aspirin.
He says "it interferes with
the healing process."
Did you tell him he's wrong?
Yeah, the chief even tried
to talk sense into him.
Malucci, tell him if he wants
to be a masochist
he can't scream so much.
He's gonna scare
the other patients.
Right, right, I'll have him
bite down on a bullet
or something.
Carter, I hear you got punted
across the trauma room.
Yeah? Who told you that?
I hear everything.
‐ Haleh?
‐ Yeah.
‐ Malucci.
‐ I know.
So did you hurt yourself?
No, it just knocked
the wind out of me
but everything's working.
Another tough guy.
‐ Something rolling up?
‐ Rolling down.
It's the kid from the shooting.
I thought I might jump in.
Well, don't jump
off any gurneys.
Yes, sir.
So, did you call any
of those psych referrals?
What patient?
That list I gave you.
‐ Oh, yeah..
‐ Uh‐huh.
How'd it go?
Um, you know, okay, I guess.
It's kind of tough to tell.
Yeah, it could take a while.
'CBC, lytes, PT, PTT.'
Type and cross for two units.
Can we give more morphine?
Another four, and get
a chest X‐ray and pelvis.
You want ancef?
Gave it in the field.
Nicholas, we are just going to
take a look at you here
and then we'll bring you
upstairs for an operation, okay?
On my count, one, two, three.
Did they call my dad?
We'll take care of it.
Mary, call the police
the school or whoever
to reach his father at work.
It's been all over the news.
I'm sure his dad's
looking for him.
‐ Make sure.
‐ Got it.
Lungs are clear.
BP 115 over 75. Pulse 80.
Left inguinal entrance wound,
where's the exit?
Couldn't find one for the leg.
The bullet's still inside.
We should see it
on the pelvic film.
‐ No pulse by Doppler.
‐ Let's look at the back.
It's through and through,
missed everything.
I assessed it in the field.
I need to examine it myself.
Okay, let's roll him.
'Hold on, Nicholas.'
We need to move
you on your side
so we can look at your back.
‐ Carter?
‐ Carter.
Yeah, I got it.
'Let's roll.'
Did you hit your head
or pass out?
Of course I hit my head,
it's rugby.
Any pain in your chest
or your belly?
No, nothing.
I didn't want to come in
but the fellas made me.
Hey, hey, hey,
what are you doing?
Oh, we need to cut off
your shirt
so that we can examine you.
Like hell you do.
We just got these jerseys.
If you've broken your collarbone
it will be very painful to lift
your hands above your head.
Pain is relative, mate.
What was that?
someone who didn't want us
to cut off his shirt.
‐ Right.
‐ Okay, Abby?
Abby, go ahead.
You are blue. Did you
know that, Mr. Tanner?
Yeah, it happens as soon as
you sweat in these new jerseys.
Well, maybe you should
wash them first.
It's brand‐new.
Okay, let me know
if you feel any pain.
'Uh, yeah, yeah.'
Probably a mid‐ shaft fracture.
Yeah, it looks like it's broken.
Will I be able to play
next week?
I doubt it, but we're going
to wait and see the x‐ray.
Be right back.
Abby?
‐ Get a clavicle film.
‐ Right.
Is everything okay?
‐ Yeah.
‐ Are you sure?
Do you have a minute?
I don't see a bullet.
It must be higher up
in the abdomen.
Let's shoot a KUB.
Are you sure your
stomach doesn't hurt?
It's just my leg.
PVC's on the cardiac monitor.
Where's the chest X‐ray?
Whoa, run of five.
Bolus 60 of lidocaine.
'Start one per minute.'
What is it?
Just an extra heartbeat.
Nothing to worry about.
You're not going
to believe this.
‐ 'What?'
‐ I found your bullet.
Oh, God, it's in his heart.
'It traveled through
the femoral vein.'
From there to the IVC.
Into the right atrium
and ventricle.
Lydia, call the OR.
Tell them we're on our way up.
Carter, make sure
there's an open cardiac room
with a perfusionist standing by.
He may need a bypass.
I got it.
We're gonna have to
revascularize
the leg at the same time.
Let's put him in
right lateral decubitus
reverse trendelenberg.
We don't want it
embolizing to the lung.
Nicholas, we need to move you
onto your side again.
What's wrong?
Remember I said
we would take you upstairs?
Yeah.
Well, we are going now.
Hey.
Good effort.
18‐year‐old college student
mugged outside her dorm
stabbed in the lower abdomen.
Hey, Peter.
200cc's in the foley.
Type and cross for six units.
Have two of FFP on hand.
She's going to
fix you up, okay?
Hang in there, buddy.
‐ You'll get my dad?
‐ I'll get your dad.
'Send up the O‐neg
incase they need it.'
Hey, Peter, Elizabeth needs
another surgeon.
‐ Congratulations, he's dead.
‐ Who?
The man he abandoned
at the scene.
I didn't abandon him.
He went into asystole five
minutes outside of Mercy.
They cracked him,
but it was too late.
And what? ten minutes would have
made a difference?
We won't know, will we?
Hold on, are we talking
about the shooter?
First rule of triage,
"The most critical patient
"that's the priority."
The boy has a bullet
in his heart.
It can embolize at any minute
and he could lose his leg.
Let's debate this later,
Peter, get upstairs.
You didn't make
a medical judgment
I made both!
Upstairs, Peter!
He was crashing
and you didn't care, man!
I was caring for the boy!
Hey, hey, hey! That's enough,
that's enough.
Kerry, I need to talk to you.
BP's 118 over78, pulse 84.
Can you describe the man
who stabbed you?
I‐I don't know,
it happened so fast.
Chuny, get an ultrasound and
a fetal monitor to trauma two.
Cleo, you need some help?
Yeah, I might.
Kerry, now, it's important.
You saw the boy.
He needed to get
to a trauma center.
Calm down.
Go help Cleo.
I'm supposed to delay care
while they take the guy who was
shooting at kids and cops?
Go help Cleo!
'One, two, three!'
Can you give me any kinda
physical description?
He was, um, darker,
maybe Mexican.
‐ What is it?
‐ Victim of assault.
Single right stab wound
to the lower right quadrant
four centimeters
off the midline.
What was he wearing?
A gray sweatshirt, I think.
Okay, a full trauma panel
and check a hemocue.
How far along are you, miss?
What?
What month are you in?
‐ What do you mean?
‐ Your pregnancy.
When are you due?
I'm not pregnant.
You look about eight months.
‐ Got the ultrasound.
‐ Better cath a urine.
Anything else you can
tell me about the attack?
No, he‐he just ran up,
grabbed my purse.
When I didn't let go
he stabbed me.
'Okay, I'll be back.'
'Fetal heart tones are 142.'
'Hemocue's 13.4.'
No intraabdominal
bleed on mom.
How about the baby?
32‐week size,
good cardiac activity.
I'm pregnant?
‐ Very.
‐ Oh, my God.
‐ Hold on.
‐ What?
There. A blood clot.
Abruption?
Could be.
12 milligrams
of betamethasone, now.
You can't tell my parents.
What's your name?
G‐Gloria... Gloria Milton.
Gloria, the stab wound
has damaged the placenta
causing it to bleed
which would cut off
oxygen to your baby.
I didn't even know I had a baby.
'Well, you do.'
Right now, it looks okay,
but we may need
to bring you upstairs
for a C‐section.
You mean, cut me open?
Yes, 32 weeks is early
but we are giving
you steroids now
to help mature the baby's lungs.
No, wait!
I‐I don't want an operation.
You might not have a choice.
If the abruption continues,
the baby will die.
But nothing bad will happen
to me, right?
Right now,
you're alright, but‐‐
Then, don't.
Don't cut me open.
Don't do anything.
Hey, it's Dr. Torquemada.
Who?
Nothing.
You discharge your screamer yet?
He was pretty tough, Carter.
You, couldn't tell that
from out here.
He took on the hurt
and won, my friend.
You got to respect that.
Right, no brain, no pain.
Some cultures see pain
as a right of passage.
Well, somebody call
a staff meeting?
No.
Hey, you know the kid
made it up to the OR okay.
Cardiac team's in,
Benton's workin' on the leg.
Good, thanks.
At age 13, the Masai warriors
of Tanzania scar themselves
with red hot spears and yank out
their bottom front teeth
with no novocaine, mind you.
Hmm.
Hey, Dave, why don't
you give us a minute?
Oh, yeah, sure, sorry.
Carter, hold on.
‐ What's up?
‐ I think you know.
Ah, look at that.
The guy leaves, like
a millimeter of coffee
in the bottom of the pot.
Abby saw you.
She saw me what?
Abby.
I saw you inject the fentanyl
into your wrist.
What?
In the trauma room when you said
you were cleaning up.
I was cleaning up.
John, I have the chart here.
You drew up 200 of fentanyl
into the syringe.
What is this?
You gave 150 mikes
to the patient.
Okay, hold on, slow down.
This is a mistake.
And you stopped
after three cc's.
Yeah, Haleh gave him a bunch of
versed, you were there.
What happened to the rest
of the fentanyl?
I don't know.
Must have wasted it
down the sink.
Somebody's supposed to witness
you doing that.
Come on.
Come on, we do that
all the time.
We have a protocol for
disposal of narcotics.
Okay, fine, whatever.
That doesn't mean
that I injected it.
Abby.
If you thought you saw something
why‐why wouldn't you
come talk to me?
It's appropriate for Abby
to come to us.
Not when she's wrong.
Carter, are you still
on pain medication?
Why? What?
For your back.
Yeah, why? A little, why?
How much is a little?
Well, that's between me
and my doctor, isn't it?
So, you're not overmedicating?
You think I'm a drug addict?
Hmm?
Do you honestly think
I'm a drug addict?
That I'm, what? Sneaking around
injecting whatever
narcotics I can find?
You guys, you know me,
this is ridiculous.
So you deny this.
Yes, I deny it. Abby..
I, uh, think you're
seeing things.
Maybe you're on drugs.
Yeah, I think I saw you
with a needle once.
'Okay, Carter.'
If this is a misunderstanding,
I apologize.
This is a misunderstanding.
You know why we had to ask you.
Can I go back to work now?
Thank you.
And thank you, Abby.
I really appreciate that.
‐ He's lying, Mark.
‐ I know.
'We'll call someone
you can talk to'
it doesn't have
to be your parents.
It can be a friend,
a roommate‐‐
No, please, I don't want
to talk to anyone.
Gloria, we don't have much time.
If we're gonna save that baby
we need to operate now.
I told you, I don't want it.
'You can give the baby
up for adoption.'
Your mom and dad would
never have to know.
I don't want an operation
so just leave me alone,
all of you!
‐ Okay, okay...
‐ Just leave me alone.
Okay, but you're going
to have to keep monitors on.
Why?
For your own safety.
We need to know if you
start bleeding internally.
Dr. Kovac.
Why don't you spin
another crit
and cycle the dynamap
every five minutes?
17 years of practice, I thought
I'd seen everything.
Are you taking her up?
I can't, not if
she doesn't want to.
The fetal heart rate
is down to 100.
The abruption is progressing.
She needs a C‐section.
I made the consequences
very clear to her.
She doesn't care
about the consequences.
You can't cut
a woman open without
her consent, that's assault.
‐ The baby will die.
‐ I'm aware of that.
And you can stand by
and watch it happen?
‐ There's nothing I can do.
‐ You can operate.
No, I can't, I'm sorry.
I'm calling another OB.
Who? I am the head
of the department.
We don't force C‐sections
on women in this hospital.
What if I can get her
declared incompetent?
I dunno, she seemed
coherent to me.
I think the stab wound
was self‐inflicted.
You can prove that?
She's delusional.
She claims she didn't know
she was pregnant.
She was lying. That
doesn't mean she's crazy.
What kind of woman carries
a child for eight months
and then refuses
to let us help her baby?
You know what?
Call psych, give it a shot.
Then I can bring her up?
Yeah, if they say yes.
Side‐biting clamp.
5.0 prolene.
If you ask me, Peter we're lucky
to have this extra time.
Oh, Kovac didn't know the bullet
moved to his heart.
Well, I'd have trouble
prioritizing someone
who shoots at a
playground, too.
BP's down, 80 palp.
Is that you?
No, no active bleeding.
Femoral vessels are clamped.
Shirley, recheck the pressure.
Still falling, 70 palp.
What is it?
Did the bullet embolize?
Fluoroscope on.
It's still in the heart for now
but it is moving closer
to the pulmonary artery.
We got blood
dripping on the floor.
'Where from'?
Shirley, take the towel
off the shoulder.
'He's bleeding out.'
Aw, damn it.
Saline sponge now.
We need six more units
of packed cells up here.
What are you doing?
‐ I've gotta Locate the source.
‐ I just opened his heart.
Well, It won't make a difference
if we don't stop the bleeding.
Wait, wait, just wait.
‐ Clamp the auricle.
‐ I can't.
Just for a second,
the other bullet
must have hit the
axillary artery.
Clamp the subclavian.
I need to get this bullet out.
Then I'll do it myself. Move.
Potts, let's go.
Pressure's down to 60.
Where's that damn blood?!
Shirley, give him
a saline bolus.
Come on, damn it.
'I can't reach the artery.'
Alright crank the sternum
open a little wider.
he's in V‐fib!
Paddles, paddles!
‐ Peter, get your hands out now.
‐ Hold on, hold on!
Clear, now!
Got it, go!
I don't know what to tell you.
But I've got a
tournament next week.
I can't miss the tournament.
You've broken your collarbone,
Mr. Tanner.
Aside from seriously
hurting yourself
you'd be worthless on the field.
Well, can't you just put
a cast on it or something?
No, we sling it, and you rest.
Well, then it
can't be that bad.
Yosh, could you get
Mr. Tanner a sling?
I'll have to call central.
All we have are smalls,
he looks large.
Hey, Mark.
You better make that
extra‐large, mate.
I'll be back to discharge you.
So, I talked to legal.
Did you use his name?
No, I spoke in hypotheticals.
Bottom line,
we need more evidence.
But he can't treat
patients, right?
It's one accusation,
we have to be careful.
Can we ask him to drug test?
He's taking
a prescribed pain medication
he'll test positive
and I'm afraid just asking
will push him further away.
What do you want to do?
I want to get him some help.
Let me talk to him again.
He might open up
if he doesn't see it
as a threat.
Mark, how could we
let this happen?
I mean, he showed all the signs.
I know, I know.
But it's Carter.
your mind just doesn't go there.
'She's a little calmer now,
that's a good sign.'
He'll talk her into it.
How do you know?
He has to.
‐ 'Dr. Kovac?'
‐ Yeah?
'This is Vinny Rosato,
Nicholas' father'
The boy from the school.
Oh, yes, yes. Hi, Mr. Rosato.
‐ Your son is in surgery.
‐ How bad is it?
He was shot in the
leg and the shoulder.
The surgeons should be able
to repair those injuries
but one bullet has traveled
to his heart.
‐ He was shot in the heart?
‐ No, no, no.
The bullet was swept
through the vein
but there shouldn't be
any major tissue damage.
Can they get it out?
We should take you upstairs.
There you can get
more updated information.
I'll take you, Mr. Rosato.
Thank you, Cleo.
'She's certainly
emotionally distraught.'
She could be
clinically depressed
and even have
a personality disorder.
Can you declare her incompetent?
But she's not
acutely psychotic.
She understands that failing
to perform the C‐section
could endanger her baby's life.
You mean kill it.
She's willing to take the risk.
It's not a risk,
she wants it to happen.
She stabbed herself
to make it happen.
You have no evidence of that.
And she's a danger to others.
‐ Who?
‐ The baby.
Doesn't count,
it's still her body.
Is the C‐section necessary
to save her life?
Somewhere there has
to be a point‐‐
Is it?
No.
Then without a court order,
you can't touch her.
I don't have time
for a court order.
That baby needs to come out now.
We can try to expedite it.
Our legal department
knows friendly judges.
You'll have to write up
an affidavit.
Yeah, whatever.
When'd you start smoking?
Well, that depends,
does it make me a druggie?
Ask the surgeon general.
I'm worried about you,
Carter.
Look, I'm okay.
I got angry,
and I shouldn't have.
Not that I didn't have a right.
I'm okay.
You didn't talk
to anyone, did you?
Any psychiatrists?
‐ No.
‐ Why not?
'Cause I didn't
feel like talking.
Look, I'm gonna be fine
or I hope that I‐I will be.
It's been rough.
You can understand that
I got stabbed in the back twice
with a six‐inch butcher knife.
I'm in a lot of pain
and this place isn't exactly
the easiest work environment.
Lucy's dead,
which is partly my fault.
I haven't slept in months.
I‐I had to take more pain
medication just to function.
I didn't steal it.
It was prescribed to me.
Did you take
the prescribed amount?
Yeah, more or less.
I think you need help, Carter.
Look, I understand that you have
to make this your business.
But please, please let me
deal with it.
When are you off?
Midnight.
Okay, I don't want you
to see any more patients.
You can work
on QA Chart reviews.
I can see patients.
There's nothing wrong with‐‐
Carter, you have to trust me.
Let me figure this out.
We got to write this one up.
Oh, yeah, including the part
where you lifted
him off the table
while I was opening his heart?
And cranking his chest
with one hand
and suturing with the other.
I still have a few moves
you haven't seen.
Listen, okay, dibs on the
bullet, alright.
‐ No way, it's mine.
‐ What are you talking about?
‐ I was the one that called it.
‐ Yeah, but I fished it out.
‐ Yeah, but‐‐
‐ Hey, Cleo.
Hey, we just made a great save.
I can see that.
Yeah, we got the bullet out
of the boy's heart
and Peter saved
his arm and his leg.
The father's outside recovery,
waiting to talk to someone.
Oh, okay. I'll do it.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
Hey.
Dr. Carter, I didn't
know what to do
so I asked Dr. Greene.
I'm sorry.
And I know I don't
know you very well
but I think you're
a good doctor
and I know you've been through
a lot in a short time
and I'm sure I couldn't
handle it myself
but I felt
I had to tell them.
You feel better?
Because I have work to do.
Okay, Mr. Tanner,
here's a prescription.
You'll need to take one
every six hours for pain.
And you're going to wanna
ice that, Mr. Tanner.
Mr. Tanner?
Yosh, get Dr. Greene, now!
‐ What is it?
‐ Barely has a pulse.
Lily, I need a BP.
What did he present with?
'Fractured clavicle'
'absent breath sounds
on the left.'
Must be a tension pneumo.
Get a 14‐gauge needle
on an open syringe.
Come on, let's go.
'BP's 50 palp.'
‐ Betadine?
‐ Yep.
Quickly, quickly,
get him on a pulse ox.
I got it.
Okay, check a pulse.
It's stronger.
Still need a chest tube.
Already has broken collarbone.
Not anymore.
Satting at 95.
Okay, give me a ten blade.
Carter, what are you doing?
I'm saving this guy's life.
You must've missed
an occult rib fracture.
I'll take it from here.
The needle decompressed.
Give me the Kelly.
I got it, Carter.
I'm almost in.
Right. Right, you take it.
32 French.
'Suction's ready.'
'BP's 100 over 60.'
You're welcome.
'I'm in. Hook me up.'
Abby..
Call as soon as you know.
‐ Yes, thank you.
‐ He didn't sign it?
They got there at 6:30.
The judge had already left
but the clerk is trying
to track him down.
Can't we try another judge?
They're already working on that.
I‐I can't wait.
Luca. you can't do anything
until we get it.
I've waited too long already.
Promise me that you
won't do anything.
No, I'm going
to change her mind.
We need to do this tonight.
'I don't believe it.'
Well, it makes sense.
He's been so unpredictable
I thought he might be bipolar.
Carter? Come on, no way.
He as much as
admitted it to me.
Peter, he's using.
'I don't know for how long'
'but the behavior's
been there for a while.'
But is this the right way
to do it?
He might feel ganged‐up on.
It's either this or we have to
kick it to some committee.
You know, I'd rather approach
him as a small group
'that he knows and trusts'
'and give him a chance
to clear it up.'
And what about Romano?
No, we don't want
to bring him into this.
you know what,
Carter can be stubborn.
He might just walk out.
And we have to be
prepared for that.
All we can do is
be compassionate but clear.
He has two options, that's it.
Are you with us, Peter?
'Kerry?'
‐ You needed me?
‐ Yeah, Don.
So, what's the big emergency?
'Why don't you have a seat?'
Fetal heart rate down to 60.
Get a baby warmer in here.
Gloria, I don't have time
to argue anymore.
This baby needs
to come out now.
I want another doctor.
The placenta's detaching.
You could hemorrhage to death.
You're trying to scare me.
You should be scared.
If you don't care
about your baby
at least think of yourself.
I don't believe you.
You would've done
something already.
'Heart rate's down to 50.'
You're going to
have a boy, Gloria.
I can tell
from the ultrasound.
You really want
to kill your son?
Leave me alone.
I want another doctor!
Down to 40.
Okay, that's it.
100 of ketamine, IV push.
Dr. Kovac..
You heard me.
Draw up the ketamine.
‐ You can't.
‐ I'm the attending!
I'll take full responsibility!
‐ What are you doing?
‐ Please don't do this.
I‐I don't want the baby.
C‐section tray, prep her.
I don't want the baby!
Heart rate's down to 20.
Please! Please, help me!
Cleo, set up the suction.
‐ No, I won't.
‐ Then get out of the way!
Luka, she didn't consent.
‐ You could lose your license.
‐ Ten blade.
Lost the heart rate.
You can't do this.
You can't.
Is it over?
Carter?
Got a minute?
No, I'm done with these.
If you guys don't want me
to see patients today
‐ I'm gonna go home.
‐ Not yet.
I need to talk to you.
Is this my suspension?
Not here, come on.
Oh, God.
Give me a break.
Carter, just listen.
No, I told you I am on
painkillers for my back
but I'm functional.
'Dr. Carter.'
You would be wise
to be quiet and listen.
My van is parked outside.
We have a ticket to Atlanta.
There's a drug rehab..
There's a drug
rehab center there
that specializes in treating
doctors with addiction.
Well, that's great but I'm on
prescribed painkillers
and that doesn't
make me an addict
and I think you all know it.
I'm not finished!
It's apparent to all of us
that you have a drug problem.
'Therefore we cannot allow you'
'to continue working here or
anywhere else as a physician.'
'So you have two choices'
'get in the van,
go to the airport'
'check yourself in'
'and when you come back'
'we will support you
in any way that we can.'
Or I'm fired?
Yeah.
'Everyone in this room
cares about you.'
No one is judging you.
Yes, you are.
You've already judged me.
You have no idea
what I've been through
these last few months but I've
been here, I've showed up.
I haven't made excuses.
I haven't complained.
‐ That's not the point‐‐
‐ No, that is the point.
Can anybody tell me that
uh, uh, that I have
endangered patients?
I mean can anybody here say that
my performance has changed?
Hmm? That I'm some kind
of liability?
John, you put a patient
into anaphylactic shock
by giving her bactrim
when she told you
that she was allergic to it.
And you almost killed somebody
by leaving a guide wire
in their chest.
Is this about mistakes?
Hmm?
Who here hasn't made a mistake?
Hell, I saved your ass
this afternoon.
'John, you've demonstrated'
'compulsive, drug‐seeking
behavior.'
When? Just tell me when?
You know, I think
mainlining fentanyl
in the trauma room qualifies.
Well, I told you
I didn't do that.
You want to call me
a liar, fine
call me a liar,
but I didn't do that.
‐ Okay, show us your wrists.
‐ What?
Show us your wrists!
Are we looking for track marks?
Yeah.
Well, there, see?
Here, want me to roll up
my sleeves?
Take off your watch.
Uh, you know, you know what?
Forget it, forget it.
This is your only
chance, Carter.
Great, I quit.
Well, is that it?
No.
What are you doing?
I don't need this.
I've never needed this.
I wanted to be a doctor
I wanted to help people
but I don't need
their damn job.
Carter, you don't
want to do this.
No, I'm not doing it, they are.
‐ Carter, wait!
‐ No.
Carter, what are you going to
do? Piss it all away?
Everything you worked for
eight years of your life‐‐
They're the ones there
handing out the ultimatums.
No ultimatums, Carter!
You're getting in that van!
Like hell I am.
You're not gonna do this.
They tell you that
I'm some kinda junkie
and you believe them
and you come
down and ambush me!
Carter, you're
out of control, man!
If you can't see that,
then I don't care
but you're getting
into that van.
‐ No.
‐ Get in the van.
‐ Don't touch me.
‐ Get in the‐‐
Don't touch me!
Where does it end, man, huh?
This week fentanyl,
next week you end up dead
or worse, you end up
like your cousin
some babbling gork in a nurs..
Carter, you want to fight,
that's cool, man
but either way you're getting
your ass in that van.
It's alright, man.
It's alright, Carter.
‐ Good job, that's good.
‐ He's crowning.
Almost there, Gloria.
One more push should do it.
Ready? And push.
Push.
The head is out.
Okay, you can stop now.
Clamp.
And cut.
Does she want to see him?
Would you
like to see him, Gloria?
No.
You want me to pronounce him?
No, I'll do it.
Time of death, 19:47.
Did he get on the plane?
I don't know.
Peter hasn't called.
‐ I wonder what he said.
‐ Who knows?
‐ I just hope Carter gets on.
‐ Yeah.
Well, it's nice to see
the ER Brain trust
is diligently
working after hours.
Hello, Robert.
ICU is a zoo.
Seems nice and
peaceful down here.
Yeah, same old stuff.
Here the fun never stops.
Elizabeth, Walt Newman
the intussusception upstairs.
‐ What about him?
‐ Tried to reduce with an enema.
Left a big mess.
‐ We have to go in.
‐ Now?
Yeah, it's not quite as sexy
as snakin' a bullet
out of the heart
but it's a life‐saving
procedure nonetheless.
Coming right up.
Thank you.
Goodnight, all.
‐ I guess I lost my ride.
‐ That's right.
That's alright.
I'll take the El.
‐ You sure?
‐ Yeah, I'll see you at home.
I'll try not to wake you.
‐ Goodnight, Kerry.
‐ Goodnight.
Want to go get something
to eat or something?
Uh, no, I‐I think I'll wait
to hear that he got on.
‐ Okay, well, call me.
‐ Okay.
‐ Thanks.
‐ Uh, just a minute.
‐ Uh, Dr. Weaver?
‐ Yeah.
I've got legal on line three.
They say to go ahead.
The judge signed a court order.