Previously on "ER."
I'll take him up myself.
Dr. Romano, your arm.
Damn it!
I'm fine.
Let's just, let's go.
Let's roll.
We're going to
Las Vegas tonight.
Are you ready?
I've asked
Robert to consider
sharing the chief of staff
position with you.
I'd rather cut
off my good arm.
Fine. Congratulations, Kerry.
You've just become
chief of staff.
That was a gift.
From a grateful patient?
Grateful girlfriend.
I have a few meetings
with department heads later.
Otherwise, I
would have waited.
Oh, yeah, of course.
I'll have all this sent
to your home by week's end.
‐ Dr. Weaver?
‐ Yeah.
‐ Maintenance is here.
‐ Send him in.
What happened
to Brenda?
We had to let her go.
She seemed unwilling
to make the transition.
'Centered, right above
the backs of the chairs'
and at museum level.
Oh, museum level
Always hated
the Impressionists.
Look, it's a lateral
move, Robert.
All that sugarcoating
of the truth.
Believe me,
it wasn't my idea.
Dr. Anspaugh
thought it might be
a good interim step.
That's strange,
because this little power play
smacks of a certain
estrogen‐based malice
I've grown all too familiar
with over the years.
You know..
...I really wish you'd
try to appreciate the fact
that we're trying
to do you a favor here.
What you're doing
is bending me over
and driving it up
the chocolate highway.
Let's be honest.
You're a one‐handed
surgeon, Robert.
Not to mention a human
resources nightmare
'and a lousy administrator
who's burned more bridges'
than you've ever built.
You're lucky to
have options at all.
Oh, you're
suggesting I have some.
Yes, you do. You have three.
It's this, it's
teaching or it's out.
Oh, Dr. Romano, can I
get your home address?
Bite me, Nancy.
Dr. Romano, I have
some billing givebacks
from Anesthesiology‐‐
Not my job.
Cardio admin's
on line one for you.
‐ Take a message.
‐ Well, what do I tell them?
That I don't work here anymore.
'What are you doing?'
I'm taking Mrs. Tucker to x‐ray.
That's what orderlies are for.
Park granny and go help
someone drain an abscess.
‐ Yeah, but I got‐‐
‐ You're a med student.
You're not doing scut,
you're not doing squat.
Hey, green card, I want all your
performance evals by day's end.
Why?
I want something to read
when I'm on the can.
Why do you think, Igor?
You're on my hit list.
Who supplies
the nurses' scrubs?
‐ Allied.
‐ Switch to Lindeman's.
They hug booty better.
What the hell are
you looking at?
Oh, hey, hey, hey,
everybody! Great news!
Pinata out in the parking
lot. Andale, andale.
They're here for
one of their kids.
Yeah? Well, they need
to stop having kids.
‐ Clear 'em out or you're fired.
‐ What?
Let me rephrase that.
You're fired.
‐ You can't fire nurses.
‐ I just did.
‐ Hey, pituitary boy.
‐ You talking to me?
Yeah, I lost my arm,
not my olfactory nerve.
Sic security on the bum
taking a crap over there
and get me a list of
every staff member's salary
including yours.
What was that
all about?
Meet the new boss.
And get rid of this
coffee machine in here!
You losers can pay
for your own java!
Oh, at times
like this
I wish I practiced
in Florida.
Nah, it's too humid.
Plus, you'd miss me.
Huh, well, I wouldn't
miss the wind chill.
Hey, Dr. Chen, how many candles?
Hey, I said no cake.
Happy birthday,
Jing‐Mei.
Like you even knew.
‐ Yes, I did.
‐ Uh‐huh.
And I got you something.
‐ Really?
‐ Mm‐hmm.
And I figured if you
weren't busy later
I would take you
over to the Grotto
and we'd get some
champagne afterwards.
Ooh, you thought this
through, didn't you?
Yes, indeed.
Why wouldn't I?
How you doing?
CDs, jewelry
and personal accessories
all at discount rates.
Uh, no, thanks.
Ladies lo‐o‐ove stuffed animals.
Five bucks for
this little cutie.
‐ Don't make me hurt you.
‐ Hey, hey, this is America.
If you can't sell
crap on the street
then we're not a free society.
Come on, get
out of my way.
Okay, I should be back
by six. She woke up early.
So make sure she
takes a nap, okay?
Hey, hey, you like
the sign I put up?
Yeah, yeah. It's, uh, sweet.
Okay, my darling, bye‐bye.
Hey, kids love
stuffed animals.
'Five bucks for
this little cutie.'
‐ No, thank you.
‐ It also comes in pink.
‐ You're scaring her.
‐ I got dolls in here too.
Go, go!
My foot! My foo‐o‐ot!
Told Haleh
she was fired.
Said it was
a management tool.
Always fire someone
the first day.
Lets them know who's boss.
He can call himself king
as long as I get severance.
Hey, Abby, can you park
Mrs. Strohm here in Exam One?
Uh, no.
We lost another exam room.
We'll park her in the hall.
Weaver never had an office.
Said he'd take the lounge
if we're not careful.
And put our lockers where?
‐ Triage?
‐ Oh, that's great.
So, now our personal
stuff can get stolen too.
Too late.
Brand new leather gloves
right out of my locker.
Real leather?
Yeah. Why?
Animals died to make them.
Right, and we should
all wear canvas shoes.
Oh, Go‐o‐od!
I could use
a little help here.
'What happened?'
Corday's nanny
ran over his foot.
With her freakin' minivan.
I'm crippled.
How did this
become your problem?
Elizabeth decided
that it was an ER case.
Yeah, it's typical.
We got any open beds?
'Yeah, if he's
a paying customer.'
Otherwise, park him in the hall.
For anyone late
for his or her shift
be advised that
I am now in charge
of this human cesspool.
Say goodbye to the warm fuzzies
of the Weaver era and hello
to the age of efficiency
and cost effectiveness.
Future tardiness will result
in a docked paycheck
and/or letter to file.
And once you do get to work
on time, you will treat
you will street
and you will do so
as quickly as humanly possible.
Any questions?
Didn't think so.
Medivac, two minutes out.
Auto versus ped.
Kovac and Carter. Keep
dispositions under 20 minutes.
Doctors Lewis, Chen and Pratt
can focus on clearing the board
and you can get me
a breakfast burrito
extra cheese,
hold the salsa.
‐ Please?
‐ Get your love at home.
Should be interesting.
Romano in charge.
Seen any
movies lately?
Nope.
Tried that sushi place
at Navy Pier yet?
No.
It's good.
Long time now..
...that you've been
together, yeah? A year?
Almost.
That's nice.
Josh Rushing, 37.
Found him down
along old Route Ten
outside of Pembroke.
Long way from
County, huh?
Busy day. We go
where they tell us.
Scalp lac,
multiple contusions.
Probable hit‐and‐run.
He's suffering from exposure.
Been down a while. Homeless?
After a couple of days out
everybody looks homeless.
Is Susan Lewis
working today?
Yeah. Why?
Jackknifed rig on the Dan Ryan
with an SUV
trapped underneath.
Damn it, we gotta go!
Okay, on my count.
One, two, three.
CBC, lytes, BUN and creatinine.
Let's get an Accu‐Chek.
Wallet says he's
an accountant from Indiana.
What's he doing walking
the back roads of Illinois?
Got a clavicle
deformity on the left.
Maybe he was exercising.
Eighteen in the right
AC with a liter up.
Accu‐Chek is, uh, 96.
‐ Not in loafers.
‐ Pretty isolated out that way.
Lucky they
found him at all.
Alright, what do we got?
We got a possible
car versus pedestrian.
Vitals stable
but unresponsive.
This is why I went to med school
so I could practice
veterinary medicine.
On the monitor.
Systolic, 96.
‐ SonoSite.
‐ Both lungs are up.
‐ He doesn't need a chest tube.
‐ I'll be the judge of that.
Dr. Kovac, a call
for you on line one.
‐ Not in the middle of a trauma.
‐ Who is it?
It's a collect
person‐to‐person from Zagreb.
‐ 'No blood in Morrison's.'
‐ Your dad?
'No free fluid,
no pericardial‐‐'
Someone named Gordana.
Nothing. Catch.
‐ May I? Hello.
‐ 'Hello.'
Uh, don't ever call
this number again.
Why did you do that?
Hey, you want to chew the fat
with the peasants back home dial
Ten‐Ten‐Call‐the‐Third World.
Okay, C‐spine, chest
and pelvis to start.
'He needs a rectal.'
Oh, um..
...I took the liberty of
checking the union manual.
You can't fire nurses.
They have their own
administrative authority.
You have to lodge a complaint
with the nurse manager.
Fine. Tell Hally, or whatever
her name is, that she can stay.
‐ She already went home.
‐ Uh, fine. Good, good, good.
Then have her come back,
but make sure she deducts
for the time she was gone.
And give me
bullet points on who
I can pink slip,
and for what reasons.
There are six unions
on the floor.
That's 12 volumes
of material.
Fine, do yours last.
Dr. Lewis.
So what's the story here?
Sammy got ahold
of dad's nail gun.
Who knew he'd use
it as a weapon?
He's a seven‐year‐old boy.
Everything's a weapon.
This the nail gun injury?
Yeah.
Well, Dr. Corday's
got this now.
Apparently, Sammy
didn't think it was loaded.
No. I knew.
Well, the puncture appears
to have glanced off the rib.
You'll be fine.
DT and a gram of Ancef?
Yeah.
And, uh..
...a psych consult
for the son, perhaps.
So, how's it
going down here?
Want to hear
something scary?
I miss Weaver.
Fresh pot.
Enjoy it while you can.
‐ How you doing?
‐ Very well, thanks.
New digs, new challenges,
crappy coffee.
Interest you in a cup?
I'll pass.
Smart woman.
Look, I think it's awful,
just to let you know.
A waste..
...really, of your, of
your skills, your talents.
But, um, I'm sure
it will be temporary.
Yeah.
Anything I
can do to help?
You could shoot me now.
BP's stable 120/78,
and the tox screen's back.
No drugs or alcohol
in his system, crit's 50.
Hemo concentrated.
Neuro exam looks non‐focal.
I don't know, on his own, no car
out in the middle of nowhere.
Think he was robbed?
Still had his
wallet with him.
Maybe he got dumped.
I don't know.
Maybe his
wife knows.
He's wearing
a wedding ring.
They're trying
to track her down.
Hundred of thiamine,
just in case.
‐ Did you know about it?
‐ What?
‐ The Romano coup d'etat.
‐ No idea.
‐ Does it mean anything?
‐ Yeah, we're screwed.
'Push the admin meeting to four'
'and tell the alderman
I'm out of the office.'
Dr. Weaver.
John, I have to turn over
a number of
outstanding projects.
Resident's time study.
A Q/A of our portable
ultrasound training.
I‐I‐I'd be really grateful
if you'd see them through.
‐ Sure.
‐ Excellent.
So..
...how long is Romano
going to be down here?
What makes you think
it's not permanent?
Because whoever
runs the department
has to have good communication
and clinical skills.
He is, uh..
He's an experienced physician.
His background
is entirely surgical.
John..
...you have to be
associate professor before
you can be considered
for department head.
I don't want
his job, Kerry.
I just don't want to
have to do two of them.
Alright.
Which one of you
smartasses stole my crutch?
Do you have any
plans for tonight?
Oh, me and this
guy named TiVo.
We're going to curl up
in front of the TV. You?
Nah.
Everything okay?
Woman I went to med school with
has a patient who's very sick.
Young boy.
Is he terminal?
Post shunt tetralogy
with pulmonary atresia.
‐ Oh.
‐ He's outgrowing the shunts.
He needs unifoc
and complete repair.
That's a pretty
specialized procedure.
Yup, so special
it can't be done there.
Nicky Broomer,
fell while running.
Shoulder dislocation
and probable rib fracture.
Vitals normal except
for pulse of 120.
‐ This guy's a runner?
‐ He's a junkie.
He gets chased by the cops
on a regular basis.
He fell on the sidewalk,
alright? It was wet.
Are you high
now, Nicky?
No, and he's
staying that way.
Mint condition.
The entire lot.
The sky's the limit
as far as mark up
and the whole shebang's
yours for only 30 bucks.
Hey.
I thought you said
you couldn't walk
your foot hurt so bad.
I hopped.
I'm on the phone here.
Yeah, take two Tylenol
every four hours
and get a real job.
‐ Hey, it's at 3 o'clock.
‐ What?
‐ Cake for Chen.
‐ Oh, right, right.
So, Chuny, what do you
think? Flowers or candy?
Ah, it's gotta be something she
can wear or what's the point?
Okay, let's see who's
losing the dispo race.
Why, that would
be...Dr. Pratt
who will now be punished
for his indolent ways.
Lower back pain in two
and an unknown intestinal
disturbance in four.
Chop, chop.
In second to last place
we have Dr. Lewis.
Well, that's to be expected
from one who ovulates.
She gets the maggot
infestation in two.
And then, of course,
we have Mr. Gallant
who's doing Cadillac
work ups on Yugo patients.
How are you, hun?
Don't tell me. Don't tell me.
Says right here,
"My blood pressure is high."
Well, hell, so is mine.
But rather than
go to a busy ER
I stay home and take
my prescribed medication.
Have you tried
that at all?
She's also diabetic
and her EKG is‐‐
Is entirely unnecessary.
Give he a sublingual nifedipine
and send her to clinic.
Yeah, but that's not a‐‐
Are you filling some
sort of special needs
quota here, Mr. Gallant?
You need me to say it slowly
in the language of your people?
Sublingual nifedipine.
And when you're done
with her, pick up six more.
She's your patient,
not your mother.
They letting any bottom
feeder with a check
into med school these days?
Actually, Gallant is one
of our best med students.
Well, that doesn't
bode well for the future
of emergency medicine,
but maybe by the time
he gets his license
we'll all be dead.
Uh, typically,
as chief resident
I assign the med
students their cases.
Ah, when?
Every other Tuesday?
Any patient here over
six hours is a failure
of your management skills,
not mine. Treat, turf, or dispo.
With all due respect,
you don't have
a background
in emergency medicine
and quite frankly,
it isn't all that simple.
‐ Feast or famine?
‐ Hey, you're back.
Yeah, another chopper
beat us to the punch.
‐ Is Susan around?
‐ Yeah.
Okay, your screaming isn't
making our job any easier.
‐ This is hard for him.
‐ Settle down, okay?
It hurts like a son of a bitch!
It's going to continue to hurt
unless we pull your arm out.
‐ Radial pulse is still strong.
‐ Oh, God, please help me!
Maybe you should
just go ahead and give
him more
of Versed or fent.
Yes! Yes!
We already did,
he should be unconscious.
Then why is he
still screaming?
‐ I don't know.
‐ His ribs are broken.
Yeah, that and he's
going through withdrawal.
I can't take it, baby!
‐ Hey, Susan.
‐ What?
I gotta guy here who
says he's your husband.
‐ What's he look like?
‐ 'A‐a‐ah!'
Uh‐h‐h, tall,
dark hair, flight nurse.
Yeah, that's him.
You were in Las Vegas
for, like, two days.
And three nights.
We met on the plane
on the way over there.
Hung out all weekend.
Were you sober
at any point?
Sunday night,
we wanted burgers
so we took a cab
to this drive through.
Turns out to be...
a mini‐chapel.
Ah, so you figured, "What
the hell, let's get married."
I know, it was impulsive.
Impulsive?
Okay, it was really,
really stupid.
Susan..
I'm getting it
annulled anyway.
I haven't seen him
since the wedding night.
My flight left the next morning.
He stayed there for a week.
He could have married
six other women by now.
Hey, do you remember
his name at least?
Uh, Chuck..
...Martin
I think.
Good luck.
Hey, stranger.
Hey.
Look, nifedipine
is contraindicated.
I'm not bottoming
out her pressure
and stroking this lady out.
Gallant, you are
preaching to the choir.
He's the one that needs
to be educated about this.
Oh, and he wants to hear
that from a med student.
Look, obviously he needs‐‐
Blah, blah, blah.
Go talk to him.
If there's a problem
I'll take care of it.
‐ Got a lot of people scared.
‐ Not you.
Still need to pay my rent.
Oh, come on, Romano's bark
is so much worse
than his bite.
Easy for you to say. You
can walk away if you want to.
So, Susan got married, huh?
Can't call her indecisive.
Call her crazy.
When are you people
going to do something?
So I spoke
to an attorney.
Uh, yeah, me too.
He said annulling the marriage
should be fairly easy.
That's what my guy said.
I have to admit,
I was a little worried.
Why?
Well...you know?
It was consummated.
Oh, yeah, right.
A few times,
as I remember.
More than a few times.
‐ The cabana?
‐ Right, right.
Right, but since we
never lived together
I figured it
shouldn't be a problem.
Did you say
anything to anyone?
Like who? My mom?
She'd kick my ass if she knew
I deprived her of a wedding.
Same with mine.
I kinda figured it wasn't
anyone's business, you know?
Exactly.
And pretty tough
to explain too.
Please, who
are you telling?
You kinda had to
have been there.
Yeah, made sense
at the time.
Guess you have to
get back to work.
Yeah.
‐ So play hooky.
‐ Yeah.
Morales buddy, you don't write,
you don't call.
No time to radio.
Twenty four‐year‐old female
passed out at Marshall Field's.
No trauma, no seizure.
What? You were shopping?
‐ We were registering.
‐ Debra's pregnant.
Don't tell me, you were
going to say that next.
BP's 100/60.
Sats are good.
Do you remember
falling, Debra?
I remember feeling weak.
But I haven't been eating.
Okay. Start a second line
and put up another liter.
‐ Morning sickness?
‐ Oh, bad.
My first wife had three kids.
She never even burped.
Maybe I'm not cut out for this.
‐ What have we got?
‐ Debra Strickland.
Pregnant syncope, 18 weeks.
Hi, Debra.
‐ Any cramping or spotting?
‐ No.
Okay, let's spin a crit,
check her glucose
and dip a urine to start.
Ow!
That hurts?
And my belly.
It never did before.
‐ How about when I do this?
‐ Ow!
Abby, can you see if
Linda Woo is still here?
I can check.
Finally get
a surgical candidate?
Oh, God, I‐I need an operation?
‐ 'Not necessarily.'
‐ Stripe in Morrison's.
Yup. And in
the paracolic gutter.
'Probably blood judging
from her hypertension.'
Put the probe back
over the kidney.
It is.
Doesn't look like it.
It's not.
Surgery's here.
What do you have for me?
Twenty four‐year‐old,
18 week
IUP with hypertension
intraperitoneal fluid
and a renal mass.
Obvious ex‐lap for tissue
diagnosis and staging.
‐ Who are you?
‐ Dr. Robert Romano.
Head of surgery
less than a week ago.
‐ Who the hell are you?
‐ 'This is Dr. Woo.'
She started yesterday.
Ma'am, do you have any
medical problems or allergies?
Are you deaf?
‐ Um, let me page Corday.
‐ I'll do it.
BP is dropping, 86/62.
Any moron can see she needs
surgical intervention
for hemostasis. Take her up.
I'm sorry, what's
your position here?
Your practical
and intellectual superior
with over 20 years
of surgical experience
versus the two years of ass
wiping you call residency.
‐ Take her up.
‐ Done.
'He was diagnosed at birth.'
But access to any kind of care
has been limited at best.
He's been revised?
Twice.
The last time,
five years ago
and the surgical team that
performed it in Croatia
has disbanded since then.
And there's nothing
else in Europe?
Nothing they
can afford.
And County's pediatric
thoracic group
does unifocalization
all the time.
Free of charge.
Yes, but he's not a citizen.
Neither are we,
but we are here.
Look, even if you
get a surgical team
to donate services, who's going
to pick up the hospital tab?
With some PR, charitable
contributions could cover it.
Yeah, but Kerry would still
have to sign off on it.
Are you on good
terms with her?
‐ Uh, not really.
‐ Well, neither am I.
Look, leave it with me,
I'll see what I can do.
Thanks.
‐ Where's Dr. Woo?
‐ She...left.
You need to teach your residents
to have thicker skin, Lizzie.
She only cried a little.
‐ Pratt's consoling her.
‐ Oh, dear.
Right.
Intraperitoneal
fluid and a mass.
And pregnant with
profound hypertension.
My guess, renal cell CA.
Necrotic mass
obscuring and deforming
the capsule of the left kidney.
Bleeding across
the peritoneum
more like metastases.
She'll definitely
need surgery.
Hello.
I'd like a CT of
the abdomen if I can
and have OB involved as well.
She's stable enough now.
Yeah, sure, why don't
we get a third consult
maybe, uh, ask
the janitor what he thinks.
I'm down here less than
a day, already I'm starting
to hate surgeons.
Is something wrong
with the baby?
No. The baby's quite
healthy, actually.
‐ Dr. Romano, you have a minute?
‐ Less than.
It's about my high blood
pressure patient this morning.
I should have, uh,
pointed it out to you
but the use of
sublingual nifedipine
is no longer indicated
because of a number
of case fatalities
from stroke.
I never said nifedipine,
I set up her metoprolol.
Works fine for hypertension.
No, actually you said
nifedipine and you said‐‐
Okay‐okay‐okay,
listen, okay, goofus.
‐ I'm the doctor, you are not.
‐ You know what?
It seems to me that
it is your intention‐‐
My intention is to
serve out my time in this
hell hole without having
affirmative action
imbeciles like you
make me regret ever
having gone into medicine.
Your minute's up.
Hey, where are my bullet points?
Uh, right.
Well, obviously you can't
fire medical students
but failing them is a bad
idea because then they
just have to
repeat the rotation.
‐ I'd suggest a marginal pass.
‐ Alright, what else?
You can, however,
fire care partners.
What the hell's
a care partner?
It's like, uh,
non‐union orderly.
Hey, you.
What's your name?
‐ Jim.
‐ Yeah, you pay union dues, Jim?
‐ No.
‐ Good. You're fired.
‐ I need something!
‐ That is putting me on edge.
Yeah, well, it was a lot worse
when his girlfriend was here.
Tell Lewis to gag him,
sedate him, or kill him.
‐ She's on break.
‐ What?
Is there some prerequisite
for working here?
You have to be
a know‐nothing drag‐ass
who doesn't wear a watch?
I always suspected Weaver
would kill her own mother
to get out of this dung
heap and now I know why.
Because, apparently, only
the chief of emergency medicine
is concerned with
clearing the board!
‐ You gotta help me.
‐ Hands off, lowlife!
Alright, you, where
are your parents?
I don't have any.
They died in a car
crash last year.
Bummer! So,
what's your problem?
I need it bad, man.
I need something really bad.
Hey, Chuny, can you
move him to Exam Four?
My pleasure. Come on.
Wait. Just one more paragraph
in the lab tech union manual.
Can you make sure that I
see all of Romano's patients
before anyone gets
dispo'd today?
Sure.
‐ Thank you.
Doesn't mean you don't
have to work with him.
Okay, where were we?
Um, I reached
for the soap
down I went, landed
right on my...rump.
Well, that's not good.
Any loss of consciousness?
No, just loss
of dignity.
I know, I know,
I'm late, I'm late.
I had to move Nicky.
He was driving everybody crazy.
Oh, sorry,
thank you.
And I sent up labs on
your hyperemesis patient
dispo'd your
no‐longer‐itchy rash guy.
‐ Yikes, was I gone that long?
‐ I'll tell you what.
If you take Sandra here,
we'll call it even.
I got to go check
on a patient up in CT.
Done.
Slip‐and‐fall in the shower
possible wrist fracture.
Congratulations.
On what?
Your newlywed status.
‐ Ooh, lucky.
‐ Excuse me.
Oh, I've probably been
looking for Mr. Right
ten years longer than you
and still haven't found him.
Last time it happened,
they kept me here.
You done?
I think so.
What happened
to your arm?
Are you physically incapable
of keeping your mouth shut?
I mean, were you born
that way or something?
None of your beeswax.
Breathe deep.
Hey! What do you
do for soft asthma?
A couple of nebs
and some prednisone?
You're asking a nurse?
Yeah, what you said
only I take
an adult dose now.
What he said I said.
Then discharge with follow‐up.
Okay. That took
all of eight minutes.
See people,
it can be done!
What can be done?
Oh, BS‐ing your way
through a shift, I suppose.
Hey, listen, I didn't
mean to be nosy before.
Just making little talk.
‐ Small talk.
‐ Dr. Kovac.
Your exposure guy is coming to.
‐ Any word on Rushing's wife?
‐ No.
They're still trying
to get ahold of her.
Mr. Rushing?
Mr. Rushing, can
you understand me?
Yeah.
Do you know what
happened to you?
Car..
...crashed.
Your car?
Where are they?
Who?
My kids.
We were driving..
...walked to get help.
Oh, my God.
Go get the police.
His kids are still
out there somewhere.
So, how long have
you been married?
Um, two years.
Some people think the age
difference is a problem
but I can't
keep up with him.
We're going to
minimize the exposure
to...protect the baby.
"Our little accident"
Bill likes to call him.
'Oh, you're having a boy?'
Uh, just a guess.
Will you be
able to tell?
No, not with this.
Oh, good. I wanna be surprised.
'Okay, you have
to lay very still'
and there's an intercom
in case you want to talk.
'Uh, CT abdo‐pelvis with..'
...and without.
Fine cuts right
through the kidney.
Debra, when we shoot the rest
of the dye in, you may continue
to feel kind of a warm
tingling sensation.
Uh‐uh, okay.
'There it is.'
Smaller masses in
the abdominal cavity too.
Hey, I'm just the tech.
'Hematoma and fluid from
where the main tumor bled.'
She's gonna need a nephrectomy.
'Yeah, like now.'
I guess Romano was right
about one thing today.
'Is it almost over?'
What are their names?
'S...Sally..'
...and Tim.
Do you know how
badly they were hurt?
It was dark.
I just remember crying.
BP's stable. 128/80.
Pulse is 106.
They were so scared.
'Luka..'
Uh, another liter
of warm saline.
Do you recall
where it happened?
when it happened?
No.
They're dead, aren't they?
'We're trying to find them.'
I'm going to start
calling some of this in.
Okay, this guy's
approaching the six‐hour mark.
‐ Is he stable?
‐ Just finishing up a Heimlich.
Which is the cheesy ER way
of dealing with a pneumothorax.
I did it so he could stay here
in case his
family's found.
So turf him to medicine.
Let them hold hands
and sing "Kumbaya" there.
His kids could
be seriously hurt.
Yeah, that's right.
But he's not.
So get him the hell
out of my trauma room.
‐ Look‐‐
‐ What, what, what?
Is this mandatory therapy crap
making you a little soft, Kovac?
Do us both a favor.
Stop seeing your shrink.
I mean, I don't believe
in it, and frankly
if you're that screwed up, quit.
Where the hell have you been?
Back to work.
‐ Hey, welcome back.
‐ Right.
X‐ray's backed up and she's
complaining of a headache.
Alright, let's get her
to curtain area three
and give her some Tylenol.
You could probably
use a lunch tray by now.
What I could
use is a husband.
Does yours
have a brother?
Oh, no. Damn!
Hey, Kippy, my man!
What's happening?
Foot still hurts like hell!
I should sue you clowns!
Yeah, yeah, yeah, listen,
look, I'm in a rush, man.
What you got
for the ladies?
‐ Stuffed animals.
‐ No, man.
I need something
that a lady can wear.
Uh‐h‐h
got some handmade jewelry
some perfume...tie‐dyed T‐shirt!
‐ Uh‐uh.
‐ 'Wait.'
We got some new items in.
How much?
What's this doing here?
Uh, we always have cake
when it's someone's birthday.
Woman pops a kid out,
what the hell difference
does it make what day it is?
No more official
or unofficial recognition
of birthdays.
Oh, you can't be serious.
Singing, blowing
out candles, eating.
By the time
it's all said and done
everybody's had
a half‐hour break with pay.
It fosters community.
Yeah, and lethargy
by the looks of things.
‐ Sandra Haycox.
‐ What about her?
She has a broken wrist.
Cast her and cast her off.
She's complaining
of a headache now.
Uh‐uh, tell her to take
a number and get back in line.
One complaint per visit.
Hey, who ate my cake?
‐ Nana, Nana!
‐ What happened?
Eight‐year‐old front‐seat
passenger in single‐car MVA.
Seat belt, shoulder harness.
Air bag deployed.
Pretty hard
from the looks of it.
Facial abrasions.
May have a ruptured globe.
Why was she sitting
in the front seat?
Ask grandma.
The tumor outgrew
it's blood supply
then part of it died,
ruptured and bled.
That's why
you passed out.
It could rupture
again at any moment
so it's important
that we remove it
and the kidney
as soon as possible.
Well, what kind
of a tumor is it?
We don't know.
And we won't know until we get
a pathology report.
Do you think it's cancer?
Let's take this
one step at a time.
My mother died of cancer.
If that's what this is,
I should know.
‐ Debra.
‐ I should know.
It appears likely to be
renal cell carcinoma, yes.
'And if it's as
aggressive as it seems'
it's possible that
you would require chemo
and radiation therapy
following surgery.
Unfortunately chemotherapy
is unadvisable while pregnant.
You said it was aggressive.
‐ Yes, but..
‐ Take it out.
Take everything.
Are you saying you wish
to terminate as well?
Just...just do it all at once.
Typically, those procedures
would be done separately.
'If you had the surgery
and then waited'
until after
the baby was born‐‐
I want the chemo!
‐ 'Honey!'
‐ I want it now.
We're going to leave
you alone to talk.
I guess she figures
she can try again
if she beats the cancer.
In three weeks' time
the fetus might be
viable outside the womb.
She could fight it then.
She doesn't want
to take that chance.
She's young.
‐ She's scared.
‐ Yeah.
♪ La gallina busca
el maiz y el trigo.. ♪
pH is still over nine.
Pilar, how many
fingers do I have?
No veo nada!
♪ Los pollitos dicen
pio, pio, pio.. ♪
Do you think
the blindness is temporary?
I've seen alkali
keratitis go both ways
but this doesn't look good.
How's grandma?
She needs an immobilizer
for her knee.
Otherwise, she's fine.
What a difference
height makes, huh?
Why would anyone put
their kid in the front seat?
She begged me to.
She's my only grandchild.
'I just wanted
to make her happy.'
Could you grab
a couple of Morgan Lenses
from the eye
exam room?
Yeah, sure.
Okay, this
isn't going down
as one of my
better days.
That applies
to all of us.
Wait a minute.
Why is it quiet
all of a sudden?
Unbelievable!
It was too hard to watch.
So you went out and scored?
You weren't doing anything.
'I had to.'
You want Narcan?
Put him
on a monitor.
At least
someone's happy.
Of course, it would be pro bono.
Have you looked
at our budget lately?
Every time we open our doors
we're working pro bono.
We're in a deep
deficit, Elizabeth.
I could contact
local cardiac surgeons
and specialists, ask them
to donate their services.
Which would account
for about 25%
of the total costs,
and forget about Medicaid.
The boy's not
even a US citizen.
Well, that might
be something
that would
interest the media.
I mean, look at
the‐the separation
of the Guatemalan
conjoined twins.
Well, somehow,
I don't think
a Croatian kid
needing a tet repair
is gonna get the same draw.
Kerry, he's nine years old.
He'll die without it.
And we're just not able
to help right now. I'm sorry.
Kerry, can I ask you something?
Are you as concerned
about Robert as I am?
Uh, more precisely..
...his mental health.
He seems..
...broken by this assignment.
He's a cockroach.
He'll refuse to evolve,
and yet survive us all.
Talk to me
about residents.
Well, you need
beaucoup documentation
but you have a more
powerful weapon
in scheduling.
As long as
they don't pull
more than 16 shifts a month
or work more than
three nights in a row
you can book them
for every weekend
holiday, or playoff
night you want.
‐ That's good stuff.
‐ Thank you.
How come the delinquent
hasn't been dispo'd yet?
Uh...that wasn't on
my list of things to do.
You didn't give Eddie
enough prednisone
with his albuterol.
Let me get something straight.
‐ You overrode my orders?
‐ Yeah.
Before he can leave,
he needs to be able to walk
and hold normal sats,
which he can't do.
‐ Uh‐oh, you screwed up.
‐ No, I did not.
Maybe you haven't
been listening.
Look there's
a lot of basic‐‐
Because I believe
I've made myself clear.
And there's
a lot of people‐‐
You don't
question my judgment.
You do not override my orders
and you sure as hell
don't get too comfortable
here, Dr. Carter!
This is my ER now!
It stays for one thing!
Everyone's replaceable!
Even you.
I just need to know what
to tell the guy. Alright.
‐ That better be a local call.
‐ It's a police matter.
They haven't
found the car yet?
Hey, we checked every
road, bridge and river
within five miles
of where we found him.
Why not ten or fifteen?
There's no way
he could've walked
that far with those injuries.
He was getting help
for his children.
‐ He could've walked 100 miles.
‐ What can I say?
We're already covering
a lot of territory.
With search teams,
with dogs?
It's 40 degrees
out there.
Look, we're
doing all we can.
Luka, where's Dr. Romano?
I don't know
and I don't care.
‐ Hey, Chuny, how's it going?
‐ Don't even.
‐ John.
‐ 'Thought you were long gone.'
Yeah, I just wanted to check
and see how Robert
was doing.
As expected.
He was abysmal.
He has no patient rapport
severely stunted
interpersonal skills
and he's incredibly
hostile.
Qualities consistent
with most surgeons‐‐
Kerry, the guy doesn't
know what he's doing
and he doesn't wanna learn.
And he almost killed
a patient today
by prescribing
an antiquated treatment.
But obviously, you stopped
him from doing so.
Yeah, but I can't stay
on top of the guy 24/7.
Yeah, we're trying to shift him
to a more administrative role.
What are you gonna do,
chain him to his desk?
Look, the ER may not be
the best fit for Dr. Romano
but it's all the man has.
Just make it work
or‐or better yet,
work around him.
Okay.
Excuse me. I'm Diana Rushing.
I got a message saying
my husband was brought here.
Yeah, Dr. Kovac.
He treated your husband.
‐ What is it?
‐ It's Rushing's wife.
‐ I'll take you to him.
‐ Is he okay?
I've been worried sick
the whole drive over here.
I'm from Indiana.
He's stable,
but he's obviously very upset.
When did you see them last?
Josh left home four
days ago. Who's "them?"
Your husband and your children.
What children?
He said he was with them
in a car when he crashed.
We don't have children.
Her caretaker says
she's been complaining
of white discharge.
She have her period yet?
Says she's a real woman.
Mindy, hi, I'm Dr. Lewis.
‐ How are you feeling?
‐ Good.
We're gonna do a test
on your private parts, okay?
Set up for a pelvic.
It's probably a simple
yeast infection.
Sandra? How's your headache.
Did the acetaminophen help?
Sandra...Sandra?
I need a crash cart.
I thought she came
in with a broken wrist.
‐ 'She did.'
‐ What happened?
I don't know.
Pulseless and apneic.
V‐fib. Charging to 200.
And clear.
Unit number six, going up.
Tumor mass has invaded
the renal artery wall
and sections of the vena cava.
You want me
to call again?
They won't tell me anything
I don't already know.
It's stage 4B by the size
and the spread of it.
Let's take the kidney out.
'Dr. Corday, call on line one.'
If it's path,
put it on speaker.
Pedicle clamp in place.
Metz to divide the vessels.
‐ 'Dr. Corday?'
‐ Yes, Dr. Meechum.
What are your findings?
'Furhman Grad Four'
'with sarcomatoid pattern'
'and a high mitotic picture.'
‐ 'Sorry.'
‐ Thank you.
‐ Done. Steel bowl.
‐ That's bad, I take it.
Irresectable. We'd be doing her
a favor if she bled to death.
Her chance of survival
is less than 2% at this point.
Get her husband up here.
I want to speak to him now.
Charge again to 360 and clear.
Asystole.
It's been 20 minutes.
Uh, try another amp of epi.
'And...clear.'
'No pressure, no pulse.'
'A headache, a fall,
a blown pupil.'
Possibly jogged an aneurysm
she already had.
'No way you could've
known about it.'
'No way she could've
Yeah, I'm sure she wasn't
planning on dying today.
18:27.
Well, he's depressed.
That combined with aspects
of dissociative disorder
allowed him to create
this weird, negative amnesia.
‐ Was it a psychotic break?
‐ Mm, not per se.
But he definitely needs
in‐patient psych care.
When he talked about them
he made them sound so real.
Hm, to him they are.
Right now, anyway.
But they won't always be.
With the right meds,
it'll all fade away.
Ow!
Cervical motion
tenderness.
PID?
Yup.
Mindy, do you have
a boyfriend?
Uh‐huh.
You're pretty young
to be having sex
much less
unprotected sex.
You need to tell
him to use condoms.
What are those?
That's not a good sign.
Can you tell me his name?
'So we can make sure
he gets checked?'
He‐he cleans floors.
He says he loves me.
400 of cefixime
and a gram of azithro.
We're just gonna help
you get dressed, okay?
Oh, man!
You want me to call
the facility?
Nah, call the police first.
It's official. This has been one
of the worst days of my life.
Careful. Don't jinx yourself.
Goodnight, everyone.
‐ 'Happy birthday, Dr. Chen.'
‐ Oh, thanks.
‐ Hey, my gloves.
‐ What?
Camel colored with lamb skin
inside, are those mine?
‐ No.
‐ No. Greg just gave them to me.
They were in my
locker this morning.
Yeah, so what? I bought
those out on the street.
You bought these
on the street?
Yeah, from Kippy.
‐ Oh, my God.
‐ It's a long story.
Uh, I'm sorry.
Listen, I'm sorry,
I mean, what..
I can't believe you bought my
birthday present on the street.
Yeah, but it was a good deal.
I mean, they're genuine leather.
If I were you, I'd put
them under a Wood's lamp.
Nice.
‐ Hey.
What are you doing here?
Well, I know we're not supposed
to see each other
until the lawyer's office,
but I figured
if your day was half
as bad as mine
maybe you could
use some company.
Well, eight‐year‐old
blinded by an air bag
woman keels over
of an aneurysm
junkie shooting up
in the ER
and a teenage Down's Syndrome
girl with the clap.
Hm, we had a family of four,
trapped in a burning vehicle
only one kid survived.
He's 18 months old.
You win.
What'd you get?
Oh, the, uh, burger
and fries we never got.
Knit one, purl two?
You take much longer,
you're gonna be sewing scabs.
If I go faster, the edges
don't evert well.
I love watching
med students suture.
It reminds me how good I am.
Was.
What did you say?
He said, "Was."
Loose stools in Exam Four.
Knock yourself out.
We're almost there.
Skin stapler will be next.
‐ Cut, please.
‐ Pressure's steady at 110/68.
He's here.
Mr. Strickland..
...I'm afraid we've discovered
a highly malignant
and inoperable cancer.
‐ God!
‐ Stapler ready.
Your‐your wife's
chance of survival
even with the most aggressive
form of chemotherapy
is extremely poor.
But not impossible?
The one sure thing is that
she will survive long enough
to deliver your baby
'if she doesn't seek treatment.'
However, in order
for that to happen
you'd have to reverse
her decision.
‐ OB's here.
‐ How close are we?
Almost closed.
Mr. Strickland.
If you wish to overrule
your wife's decision
you're going to have
to do it quickly.
The GYN team here is standing
by to perform an abortion.
I want her to live.
Your wife is going to die.
She's gonna fight this.
Do you understand
this baby has a chance?
I ca...I can't.
I just can't.
'Dr. Corday.'
Dr. Corday.
Mr. Strickland.
Let's get her draped.
Start with the sterile spec.
Another?
Yeah.
And stop skimping
on the peanuts.
Hey...how about putting
somethin' on
for those of us in the room
without hairy knuckles?
Something wrong
with this show?
Yeah, it only appeals to adults
making less than
20 grand a year.
30 grand.
Oh. Car wash gave
you a raise. Good for you.
I'm a copier tech.
Well, that explains
the dirty fingernails
but...not why you enjoy watching
half‐naked chunky‐trunks
pull tractors with their teeth.
Must be some sort of homo‐erotic
thing for you, I guess?
♪ And I'm goin' down ♪