Previously on "ER.."
Your East Coast
squeeze is here.
She's kind of a
looker in an..
...interstate,
off‐ramp kind of way.
I'm here now, baby.
‐ Bobby hit me.
‐ What?
‐ Broke a rib.
‐ I'm sorry.
I didn't know,
but you didn't say anything.
Why didn't you go
to the police?
He is the police.
A compass?
Seeing as how we always
find each other.
‐ Can we talk?
‐ What?
I'm pregnant.
What are you doing?
Well, Christmas
was two weeks ago.
I figured it's time
to put it away.
Leave it. I like it.
You want to be one
of those people
dragging some dead brown tree
out into the street
in the middle of April?
I like those people.
They don't give up easy.
I made this
for Maggie when I was..
I think, six.
We were living in a motel.
The Minnetonka.
Don't you have a search
committee meeting this morning?
I could skip it.
‐ We can talk some more.
‐ No, you should go.
I have to be
in soon, so..
I guess we haven't
figured anything out yet.
Yeah, I really..
...don't want
to get into it again.
Have you made a decision?
Well, we don't even know
what we are to each other.
‐ No one ever knows that.
‐ Oh, come on.
We've been friends
for a long time.
‐ Good friends.
‐ Yeah?
Been through a lot together.
That doesn't mean we could
take care of a child.
It has to be your choice.
I know that.
Ground‐level fall
in the ambulance bay!
‐ No head trauma, no LOC.
‐ Okay, it's alright.
‐ I'm fine.
‐ Complains of right hip pain.
‐ Can't bear weight.
‐ Would you stop it?
I'm just trying
to be professional.
It's annoying.
Whose job is to
de‐ice the entrance?
Just get back to work.
It's only a bruise.
‐ I'm fine.
‐ You know what?
I'm going to go
find you a bed.
No, no, I don't
need all that.
Hey, acetaminophen OD,
should I give mucomyst
before the level's back?
Dr. Weaver,
can you look over..
Hold it. I am not..
I'm not even on today.
Guys, guys, easy, easy.
Look, she had a nasty little
slip on the ice
'so let's give her
some space.'
Okay?
Thank you.
‐ Alright, what?
‐ What, what?
What do you want?
I need a few weeks off.
Why?
My band got a recording deal.
We're going to LA.
Back away from the gurney
or I will impale you
with my crutch.
Kerry..
Back off, Elvis.
Ah! This damn salt's
ruined my shoes.
Yeah, well, New York's
been snow‐free all year.
Why don't you go back there?
These are Jimmy Choos.
Timmy who? And why are
you wearing his shoes?
Choos, and they
cost me about 400 bucks.
A, number one, you
shouldn't be wearing shoes
that cost more than
other people's rent
and B, number two
it's January in Chicago.
Get some damn boots.
Hey, let me
tell you something, Vic.
‐ You're not a morning person.
‐ No, I'm not.
Hey, excuse me.
Excuse me.
Can I get some
more coffee please
and some splenda,
about a fistful?
'No problem.'
‐ What?
‐ Shut up.
All I'm saying is
you're not really prepared
for winter here, are you?
So?
So, so, so why don't you
stay at my place today?
I want to see Michigan Avenue.
Alright, fine, just
don't buy it, will you?
I can shop
if I want to here.
On whose credit card?
You're still
worried about Bobby.
I told you that
I severed all ties with him.
Just because you severed
all ties with Bobby
doesn't mean that he severed
all ties with you, okay?
He has no idea
where I went.
No, of course not.
He has no idea.
Of course, he would never think
of you being with me.
He doesn't know where you are.
No, no. He's a freakin' cop.
How hard you think that is, huh?
What, are you stupid? I mean..
How stupid
do you have to be?
‐ What?
‐ Give me some money.
‐ What for?
‐ For a cab. Give me some money.
Oh, come on. Don't do this.
Don't be ridiculous, okay?
Just don't.
Give me the money.
Yeah, I need another 20.
Come on.
Don't do this.
And you know what
you should think about?
You don't touch me.
You should think about getting
into some meditation classes
or maybe some pilates or
something, because you, Vic
are getting very ugly.
And I mean that in the most
metaphorical sense, okay?
Come on, don't walk away mad.
What? Now I got to go get myself
some boots, you jerk‐off.
Oh, come on.
Come back here.
Jody?
I'm sorry, I'm having trouble
clearing a bed.
You know, this really
isn't necessary.
I'm sure I can
get to my office.
Oh, you should let me
examine you.
Alright. Alright.
Just treat me like
any other patient.
‐ You sure?
‐ Yeah.
‐ Get me out of the hall.
‐ Neela, let's run the board.
I have to take
my broken hip lady..
Hey! Not broken.
Ted Cunningham, 23.
Lost his shiley
at the nursing home.
Found him cyanotic,
put a 7‐0 in the neck.
Okay, Pratt,
go with them.
He had a lot of mucus.
We tried to suction him,
but his trach tube came out
and he turned blue.
‐ You from the home?
‐ No, I'm his mother.
Ted, can you open your eyes?
He can't follow commands.
Okay, excuse us.
NG tube and a #6 shiley.
94 and 15 liters.
He needs an NG?
You use it as a guide
to change the airway.
How long has he been like this?
Two years.
Ever since the night
he turned 21.
His friends took him to a bar
and made him drink 21 shots.
On the way home,
he stepped into traffic
and got clipped
by a pickup truck.
You spend your whole life
raising a kid right, and then..
one...stupid night
turns him into this.
'Where are you?
It's time to open the presents.'
Just making sure.
Well, I think
you can stop now.
We could find a way
to make it work.
‐ If that's what you want.
‐ I don't know what I want.
I am 37 years old.
If not now, when?
You know how
I feel about it.
Everything happens
for a reason.
It scares me, Luka.
Having it,
or choosing not to?
Yeah.
Pull the NG and bag him.
Abby.
Bag him.
Is he alright?
He should be much better
now that he has a new tube.
Thank you.
Sats up to 99.
What's Coburn doing here?
Oh, Kovac's got
her down on this lady
with ovarian torsion.
Dr. Rasgotra..
Someone seems to
have left this.
So...how's
married life?
It's very nice,
thank you.
We're looking for a place
of our own.
Ah, sounds exciting.
The army wants Michael
to finish his residency
at a military hospital.
And where's the
closest program?
Fort Hood, Texas.
I'm hoping he can end up
somewhere not too far away.
Tenderness over
the greater trochanter?
Yeah, it's probably
just a contusion
from where I hit the ground.
I'm going to check
your range of motion.
Ow!
Oh, God.
Pain with internal rotation.
You know.
That's happened before.
I just need an ice pack
for ten minutes
and it'll stop.
And something
for the pain, perhaps?
Percocet, Vicodin?
No. No, I have
too much work to do.
800 of ibuprofen, and,
uh, call for a hip series.
Well, I'll have to run it
past my attending fir..
I'm sorry.
Hey, pull the curtain, please.
How's she doing?
A bit cranky
at the moment.
Yeah, well, you'll soften
her up for me, right?
‐ What?
‐ For my TO request.
What do you need
time off for?
Neela, do you know
who Barry Ginsberg is?
Gynecologist
on fourth floor?
No. No, he's
a record producer.
A mogul, an idol‐maker.
He took a listen to
a couple of tracks
my boys laid down, and,
bang, we are going to LA
and we have a gig
at the key club.
And if all goes well,
we get to record a demo
at his studio in Venice.
‐ Italy?
‐ California, on the beach.
Congratulations, Ray.
That's really awesome.
Here, super‐infected
foot fungus in Four.
Uh, only thing is, is, I'm gonna
need a little time off.
‐ How much is a little?
‐ Eh, just a month.
That's not a little.
Hey, can you check out
this patient for me?
Amanda Ramsey, 15,
presented with vague pain.
I'm sorry, I have
to get some ibuprofen
and a hip series
for Dr. Weaver.
Please?
I'll trade you.
‐ I didn't tell her yet.
‐ Thanks a lot.
Amanda, I'm Dr. Rasgotra.
How much longer
do you think it'll be?
'Cause I didn't mean
to make a big deal.
I probably just need
some motrin or something.
We ran a test
on your urine.
Do I have a bladder infection?
You're pregnant.
Did you know that?
You didn't tell my parents,
did you?
They've been told that
you were here, but that's all.
Who's the father?
Some guy from school.
Boyfriend?
No.
I can get our
adolescent clinic
to come down
and talk to you.
No, my parents won't like that.
There are a number
of options.
Yeah, I can keep it,
or put it up for adoption.
Or you could choose
not to have it.
I could never do that.
It'd be against God.
‐ They stabbed me in the heart!
‐ PP Perkins, mugging victim.
Stab wounds to the chest,
arms and abdomen.
I got blood coming out
everywhere!
He's only satting 82.
‐ You guys need a hand?
‐ No, we're on it.
Chest tube in here. Come on now.
Come on, let's move it!
Okay, we're gonna need
to remove an ovary, Sara
but that's why
God gave you a spare.
It's gonna be fine.
Um, prep her in Two.
I should be up in...15 minutes.
‐ How's it going?
‐ Oh, well, good.
She's young, and
the other ovary looks good, so..
Uh, no, I‐I meant..
Oh, "how's it going?"
Oh, well, fine.
‐ You?
‐ Good.
I just got paged
for an ultrasound.
Do you know anything
about that?
Uh, no.
No.
Um, but I remember hearing
that you started
your own practice?
Yeah, yeah. It's going,
uh, very well, you know.
The only problem's the boss.
Ooh, what a bitch.
‐ I'm the boss, Abby.
‐ Right.
Now you're
patronizing me.
No. I...um, I just..
I just, uh, might want
to come and see you.
I need an OB.
Congratulations.
Wow. I had no idea.
I'll shut up.
Yeah. It wasn't
something I expected.
Is it something you want?
I'm not sure
I'm at the...right place
in my life for this, so..
So, you don't want
to keep it?
‐ Oh, I'm sorry.
‐ Okay. I'm always prepared.
Here.
Thanks.
Um, I've got office hours
every afternoon.
Just come by any time.
I can help you,
whether it's prenatal care
or termination,
whatever you decide.
Thank you.
And whatever
you do, Abby, it's..
...gonna be the right thing.
Thanks.
Oh, God.
Systolic's only 86.
Almost there. Get the thoraseal.
Okay, a little pressure now.
Alright, so who
really jacked you, huh, PP?
It was some‐some guys
I know, man.
Sats coming up.
We was drinking
by this fire in this alley.
Right, must be some real
good friends.
They avoided stabbing you
in the heart, huh?
Hey, Malik, did somebody
call the cops?
‐ Yeah, they're on their way.
‐ Don't call no cops.
‐ No cops, man.
‐ BP's better, 110 over 75.
No cops? These guys
could have killed you.
No, I got problems, yo.
I got problems.
Cops only gonna make it worse.
I feel you, bro.
Trust me, I feel you.
Then do me a solid, man.
Anything for you, PP,
anything.
More lube.
‐ It's cold.
‐ Oh, sorry about that.
‐ Dr. Coburn.
‐ I called OB.
'Could there have been a mistake
with that other test?'
Mm, I don't think so.
Here. You see this?
That's the
heart beating.
It's about
seven weeks old, I'd say.
They won't understand.
‐ Your parents?
‐ They'll say I've sinned.
I can help you talk
to them if you want.
Can I have a minute?
You were in with a patient, so
I thought it was best to just..
Yeah. It would be better
if you presented to me first.
Well, either way,
I had to call an OB.
She's 15 and scared.
Family on the way in?
They're very religious people.
Call me when
they get here.
How'd you do this?
Tried to hop a bus.
Did you slip on the ice?
I was skitching.
‐ Fell off the fender.
‐ Ah.
Might be easier
just to pay the fare.
Do I look like I got
surplus income to blow?
‐ Can I get another 3‐0 ethilon?
‐ 'Mm‐hmm.'
Were you, uh,
on your way home?
I haven't been
home in a while.
Since, like, May.
Well, your folks
must be worried about you.
Yeah, they worry a lot.
Always wanting to know what
I'm doing, what I'm up to.
Gets to be a real
drag, you know.
Doesn't sound so bad.
I'm an independent spirit,
you know?
I want to be on my own.
Do they even know where you are?
No.
Just left one day.
What if I don't know
how to love it right?
'Abby.'
Maybe I'm not strong enough.
Being a parent
makes you stronger.
And it breaks your heart.
You told me that.
That's not what I meant.
I'm sorry. I didn't mean..
No. Don't‐don't
use that as a reason.
I'm sorry.
What if I go shopping and
leave it in the supermarket?
Don't worry.
I'll do all the shopping.
I'm afraid
I'd mess it up, Luka.
We won't.
Okay, um..
Keep the wound clean and dry.
Come back in a week
to have the stitches removed.
‐ That's it?
‐ Yeah.
Unless you want to talk
to somebody from social work.
‐ Your daughter's right in here.
‐ Mandy, are you okay?
I'm fine, mom.
I'll, uh, leave you
all to talk.
Could you stay?
Sure.
Mom..
Daddy..
Something happened, and, um..
‐ I'm real sorry.
‐ What happened, sweetie?
We ran a test
and did an ultrasound.
Amanda's pregnant.
'We're waiting for
some blood results.'
‐ As soon as they arrive..
‐ That's fine.
There are a number
of places
we can refer you to
for counseling.
We'd like to be alone
with our daughter now.
Thank you.
No free fluid on ultrasound
waiting on surgery
to evaluate.
Not anymore, red.
What have you got?
‐ Morning, sunshine.
‐ Who are you?
‐ Clemente. Who are you?
‐ I'm Surgery. See the badge?
Oh, yeah, you must be
the bedside manner coach
I heard so much about.
Uh, multiple stab wounds,
stable after the chest tube.
‐ Anything enter the peritoneum?
‐ Uh, not sure.
‐ Ultrasound's negative.
‐ Doesn't answer my question.
Hey, I got the cops
out here.
Relax, relax.
I got your back.
If you can get a smile
out of Surgery here
I'll pay for the date.
You're right on the cusp of
sexual harassment, Clemente.
The cusp. That would be
a new position for me.
Hey, guys, I'm the attending
physician on this case.
‐ Clemente?
‐ Yeah.
Now, the thing is,
this dude is very sick.
He's out of it,
completely out of it.
So, he's not gonna be able to
give a statement today, okay?
‐ I'm sorry.
‐ Hold on a sec.
‐ You're Victor Clemente?
‐ Yeah.
Were you listening to me? He's
not gonna be able to give you‐‐
Easy...we're not here
on your patient.
We're here for you.
Dubenko's feisty gopher
is at it again.
What?
The chief resident
from the death star..
‐ She's down on a consult.
‐ Albright?
'He's hemodynamically stable'
with no peritoneal signs.
So why'd you call me?
Look, missy,
it's protocol, alright?
You didn't really just
call me missy, did you?
Okay, look, the‐the case
meets Trauma criteria.
Next time, call me when you know
what you got on your hands.
‐ Are you Dr. Albright?
‐ He was stabbed in the belly.
I need to know
if he needs surgical repair.
Neela Rasgotra.
I heard you were here.
I wanted to catch you
about doing a Surgery elective?
Right.
Work up your patient.
Image the belly
explore the wounds,
figure out how deep they are.
If they enter
the peritoneal cavity, call me.
I'll be more than happy
to get involved.
One third of stab wounds
enter the peritoneal cavity
and damage the viscera.
One third go in,
and don't hit anything.
And one third..
...are shallow and tangential.
The trajectory was suggested
by the hilt mark of the knife.
He won't need surgery.
You should pay more attention
to your interns, red.
‐ I'm an R2, actually.
‐ Okay, R2.
Call me about
that elective.
We might be able to
work something out.
Parking violations. Come on,
you got to be kidding me, right?
Okay. But you had some other
problems back east, didn't you?
What kind of problems
you talking about?
You left Newark General under
some very serious allegations.
I never...I never, never, never
compromised a patient's care.
Do you understand me?
‐ I never..
‐ Okay, okay.
Let's just get back
to Mrs. Kenyon.
‐ She had some issues..
‐ What do you want me to say?
Issues? What issues?
She had no issues.
She was a nurse,
I'd ask her for 6‐0 vicryl
and she'd bring it to me.
No issues.
Can I go now?
Thank you.
Not yet.
Alright, you,
alright, you do realize
that son of a bitch
hits her, right?
‐ So, you have seen her?
‐ You realize that?
No, I haven't seen her.
But I can see what's going on
here, and it's pretty low.
To sic you on me 'cause he
can't keep his own wife happy.
That's pretty pathetic.
Right now, all we know
is Mrs. Kenyon's
a missing person
who might be in trouble.
Well, she'll be in
more trouble if you find her.
Meaning what?
Meaning, sometimes
people go missing
because they
feel safer that way.
My advice to you,
stop looking for her.
Don't you go missing okay, Vic?
‐ 'Cause I want to talk to you.
‐ Why would I go missing?
Why would I go missing? Why?
Are you confusing me for one of
your lowlife, fascist scumbags‐‐
Hey, you might want to settle
down before it gets embarras‐‐
You know, I hope this
conversation doesn't throw me
off my game today, especially
after all the cops' lives
I've saved, I'd hate to
be less than 100 percent
when one of your brothers
comes in with a bullet
through his belly.
I think we're done for now.
Take it easy.
Hey, we got any
loperamide in stock?
Yeah, I'm sure he has.
Well, I got you
the good stuff.
‐ Today was..
‐ Hey.
Oop, sorry. It's turkey day
in the cafeteria.
‐ No.
‐ No what?
Is the answer to your question.
Can I at least state
my case first?
Okay.
This is big.
This is a big
opportunity
for my band
and for me.
And you never know
when you're going to get
another shot like this.
My recollection is that
you were warned last year
about your commitment
to this job.
Yes, I was.
And to your credit,
you've done an excellent job
showing us that
you want to be here.
‐ I do.
‐ You're a good doctor.
Thank you.
We don't need to
discuss this any further.
You're valuable,
you're valued.
Conversation over.
Have you tried
the stuffing?
It's great stuffing.
And, you know,
I got you an extra piece..
‐ Dr. Barnett.
‐ Look, Kerry..
Dr. Weaver, um..
Have you ever
dreamed about something
without ever believing
it would actually happen?
Because that's what this is.
I've..
This is so huge to me
that if I couldn't do this
I would seriously
consider quitting.
Far be it from me to stand in
the way of the next Springsteen
or KC and the Sunshine band.
Resignation accepted.
What?
Why do you want
to do Surgery anyway?
I'm curious about it.
The hours suck,
the attendings are slave drivers
and the residents stab
each other in the back.
Oh, not like down here
where we're just
one big, happy family.
What's wrong with you?
Ashlee Simpson get caught
lip‐syncing again?
‐ I think I just quit.
‐ Quit?
To go to California
with my band.
Oh, great. Yeah.
No, bold move. I like it.
Keeping that
music dream alive.
Nah, you'll love California.
Everybody.
Ray Barnett, rock God!
Morris, I've already sent
my paperwork up to Surgery.
Well, get it back.
I can't spare you.
Especially now,
with Ray on his way out.
If we're not fully staffed,
you're not going anywhere.
I don't care what
Dr. Cruella says.
Um...3:45. That'll work.
Yeah, thank you.
‐ Ray's on his way out?
‐ Yeah, just up and quit.
Not going to let the man
keep him down.
‐ I don't think he meant to.
‐ Hey, guys?
Guys, guys, come here.
You know the girl
I've been hanging out with?
‐ Jodie?
‐ Yeah, we love Jodie.
She taught me how to tie
a knot in a cherry stem
using only my tongue.
‐ Really?
‐ Alright, come on guys.
‐ Anybody ask for her?
‐ No.
You never saw her, okay?
And is anybody asks,
the same goes for me.
‐ What?
‐ Pretend you never heard of me.
Lockhart, uh, Pratt's
bringing in a patient.
‐ Get with him, okay?
‐ Okay.
‐ He gets weirder every day.
‐ Look, Morris..
You heard what
Dr. Albright said..
So what? She's the
chief resident upstairs.
I'm the chief down here.
‐ You work for me.
‐ Oh, come on.
‐ That's not fair.
‐ Fair? What's fair?
Excuse me, doctor?
‐ Mr. Ramsey.
‐ Oh..
I can sign whatever I need to
and we'll get out of your way.
Would you like me to call
anyone for further treatment?
Thank you, uh, I think we'll
arrange our own prenatal care.
Amanda decided to keep it?
The, uh...baby.
It's just that she's young
and it was an accident.
No. No.
I don't believe in accidents.
Now, I know you
may not understand this
but it is God's will
for her to have this child.
I only mean, you may want to
consider the long‐term effects.
And you might want to consider
the spiritual effects
of what you're suggesting.
It's my job to make sure
the patient understands
all the options
available to her.
'A human life has
just been created'
and, I'm sorry, but anything
that interferes with that
is morally indefensible.
Finished a cycle of chemo
two days ago.
'Couldn't get an IV.
He's too dry.'
'Pratt? OR needs
an attending to sign off'
'on your
pancreatic pseudo cyst.'
‐ Where's Clemente?
‐ 'On the roof.'
We getting
a chopper patient?
No, he just, uh,
says that his cell phone
gets better reception
up there.
Alright, place
a subclavian and bolus him.
‐ I'll be back.
‐ Okay.
Triple lumen tray
and one percent lido.
He's tachy at 132.
Little bit cold here.
I was never the sickly type,
you know?
‐ Yeah?
‐ Always very healthy.
Used to do triathlons,
you believe that?
Me, too.
Really?
Smoking, drinking
and watching TV.
You should stop that.
I have.
Six years ago
I find out I inherited
the Philadelphia Chromosome.
Ran on my mother's
side of the family.
I never knew.
'Screwed by genetics.'
'The first time I was panicked'
'the baby would be bipolar.'
'And I'm not so sure
I've changed that much.'
'Well, the chances are slim'
'you know that.'
Crossing the street is a risk.
If you let it get to you
you'd never have children.
Nobody would.
Well, maybe some people
aren't supposed to.
Well, I don't think
you're one of them.
Yeah, well, you don't know
what it was like..
...with Maggie...and Eric.
God, you're looking
for reasons again.
And what are you looking for?
Someone to have a baby with?
Is that what you think?
Because if it is, then
what the hell are we doing here?
Happy New Year.
A whole cascade of things
have to happen to cause CML.
Philadelphia Chromosome
doesn't mean instant cancer.
No.
Just that you're born
with a big strike against you.
As soon as you get this message,
you call me, okay?
I want to talk to you.
Immediately. Right away.
Maybe you're
trying me right now
so I'm just
going to hang up, and..
...and you, and you
got to call me.
You going to jump?
It's not
a trick question.
Yeah, sure, it's not.
Here, I need you
to sign off on this.
What the hell you doing
up here, man? It's freezing.
Yeah, well, I got
a very high core temp.
It's a, it's a Latin thing.
You want to talk
or something?
No. Why would I?
I don't know.
You seem a little ragged.
Yeah, well, I just got
some chick trouble, that's all.
Then I'm your man.
Except I don't like to share.
You know, I heard
you never stick anyplace.
Maybe people don't
go to the mat for you
because they have
no idea who you are.
Alright.
Alright, so there was..
There was this crazy nurse
at my last hospital.
‐ In Newark?
‐ Yeah.
She's just
a piece of work
and it just,
just ended bad.
It usually does.
So, you know, I came here,
I just came here just to focus
to stay on the straight
and narrow, you know?
Sounds like
a good idea.
Yeah...one would think.
Except it's
easier said than done
'cause this girl..
She's got my number,
if you know what I mean..
...and a very
pissed‐off husband.
Yeah.
See? I'm starting
to like you more already.
Yeah.
Damn, so many patients. God.
‐ Don't you feel better now?
‐ Not really, no.
Can't say that I do.
Type, RH are back on Amanda.
Oh. Then we're done.
You off already?
Yeah.
I have a doctor's
appointment.
Oh.
I'm going to see Coburn.
‐ Coburn?
‐ At her practice.
Uh..
I'll, uh, I'll get
Clemente to cover.
‐ It's okay. You're working.
‐ No, I should come with you.
It probably would be
easier if you didn't.
Hey. Hey.
When I say
I want us to keep it
you don't like
the way it sounds.
But anything else
is a lie.
Luka? Neela's waiting for you
to sign off on the Ramsey girl.
‐ Get Clemente to do it.
‐ He's MIA.
I don't know
what else to say.
Don't say anything.
Take one of these every day.
It'll help keep you
and your baby healthy.
‐ Okay.
‐ Where are your parents?
Oh, my mom's making some calls
and my dad had
to go to a meeting.
Okay, if it makes
you nauseous
try taking it at night
before you go to bed, okay?
This is some more information
that might be useful.
And, uh, we got this for you
from the ultrasound.
I wish this didn't happen.
I wish I could make it go away.
Well, everything
happens for a reason.
There was this party..
...at my friend Ginny's house.
And I drank some beer
and I did some other stuff
with a couple of guys, and..
...and I must have passed out
in a bedroom because..
...when I woke up..
...my jeans were on the floor
and there was blood
all over the sheets.
'I tried to change the covers..'
Amanda..
Were you raped?
I always thought
the first time would be
with someone I loved.
Why didn't you say something?
I don't want this. Please.
You need to explain
to your parents what happened.
They'll understand.
You have to tell them.
I did tell them.
Mrs. Ramsey.
I'll call you back.
Amanda told you
what happened to her?
Yes.
And you still
want her to do this?
That baby can't be punished
for how it was conceived.
It's not up to us to determine
who gets to be born.
We're talking about
a 15‐year‐old girl
your daughter, who was raped.
And you'd force her
to carry this to term
and change the course
of her life?
I‐I wouldn't force her
to do anything.
She believes the same
things that we believe.
This is an inappropriate
conversation.
Inappropriate? She's terrified.
‐ She doesn't want to keep it.
‐ Okay, let's take a walk.
Think for one minute
'about what's in
your daughter's best interests.'
'Neela!'
You think it's in her best
interest to kill the baby?
Because I can assure you
that in the eyes of God,
it most certainly is not.
Excuse me.
Okay, leave these
people alone now.
They've made a decision.
The parents have
no legal rights.
The pregnancy emancipates her.
There's nothing else you can do.
That girl's head
is so far twisted
she doesn't understand
she has a choice.
She doesn't want an abortion.
She doesn't want
to have the baby either.
Anyone can see that.
What about misoprostol?
It's used as an abortifacient
all over the world.
Oh, she won't consent to that.
Just, just let it go, Neela.
You're the wrong person
to talk to about this.
Excuse me?
I would like your permission
to consult another attending.
Someone who's not Catholic.
Listen to me very seriously.
I'm a doctor first,
above and beyond anything else.
And I don't let
my personal beliefs
get in the way
of a patient's best interests.
Ever!
Now give me that chart
and move on to the next one.
I'm sorry.
It's just that there's got to be
something that we can do.
You're done here.
'Do you want to have this baby?'
I have to.
Is it what you want?
No.
No, it isn't.
This is called a laminaria.
'It goes into the cervix'
'where it
absorbs water and swells'
'creating a larger opening.'
'After that happens'
it's possible that the fetus
might fall out.
‐ Possible?
‐ You might have a miscarriage.
‐ Does it hurt?
‐ A little.
There might be some cramping.
Is it a sin?
It's just a...medical way
we have of, uh..
...giving God
a chance to reconsider.
'Abigail Lockhart?'
Oh, my God!
Nobody was out today.
‐ I had a pick of the litter!
‐ Hey, come on.
You gotta leave.
Hey, what the hell
is wrong with you?
Hey!
Cops are on me.
They're on my ass.
And why? Because your
dick of a husband Bobby's
put out a missing persons
report, that's why.
‐ He did?
‐ Yeah.
How long you think we got
till he traces you to me, huh?
How long you think
before I'm walking around
with my testicles in a jar?
‐ You tell me.
‐ Vicky, Vic, Vic..
Ooh. I love you.
But sometimes you can be
such a little faggot.
‐ Oh, yeah?
‐ Mm‐hmm.
Well, I'm gonna
get a big boyfriend
who's gonna kick
your maniac of a husband's ass.
How do you like that, huh?
Huh? How do you like that?
Hey. Ow!
You're ripping the leather.
Just quiet, will you?
Yeah, that's great.
That's great.
‐ 'You got to pay your tickets.'
‐ Just great, damn it.
Vic, what's going on?
Hey, x‐ray, how's it going?
So this must be Jodie, huh?
Who, her? That's not Jodie.
‐ Hi.
‐ Hi. You know what's weird?
I've parked here a lot of times.
I never had a problem.
Yeah, that's really weird, huh?
‐ But we're gonna take the L.
‐ Alright.
‐ Nice meeting you.
‐ Likewise.
'Yo, Ray.'
Bret. Hey, how was practice?
Thanks for meeting me, man.
Can we grab some coffee?
Yeah. So I took care
of everything.
Schedule's all cleared up.
I thought we were gonna talk
before you did anything.
Did something happen?
Don't tell me Ginsberg
isn't interested.
No, it's still on.
Here's the thing, Ray,
you've been pretty busy
with this whole
doctor thing lately
and kind of distracted,
you know?
Oh, true, true.
But I'm 100 percent
on board now, okay?
110, actually.
Well, we all got together
and talked about it.
Who did?
The guys. This morning.
Kind of decided the band's
got to make some changes.
Changes?
What do you mean changes?
You'll need to come back to
have the laminaria removed.
Probably feel a little pain
but nothing to worry about.
You can take ibuprofen.
That should help.
"Before I formed thee
in the belly
"I knew thee.
"And before thou camest forth
out of the womb
"I sanctified thee
and ordained thee
a prophet unto the nations."
Jeremiah 1:5.
"Man was born of dust.
"It was only when God
breathed life into Adam
that he became a living soul."
Genesis.
You're a Christian.
What do I tell my mom?
She'll think
you're having a miscarriage.
And you will be.
♪ Cold ♪
♪ Cold water ♪
♪ Surrounds me now ♪
♪ And all ♪
♪ I've got is your hand ♪
All done.
‐ You can take her home now.
‐ Okay. Thank you, doctor.
Weaver's MRI results are back.
‐ What happened?
‐ Sorry?
What were you doing in there?
Taking care
of the patient.
Hey, Abby, it's me.
Um...I guess I've missed you.
'Um...nothing.'
I'll...I'll see you soon.
Okay?
Advanced degeneration
with a cartilaginous flap.
At least that explains the pain.
I've seen
that kind of thing heal
with enough bed rest
and physical therapy.
I've been putting this off
for years.
Maybe it's time
to face the music.
I'll need
a total hip replacement.
Not necessarily.
Just when Henry's starting
to run around like a crazy man.
‐ How is he?
‐ He's great.
You should see him.
He looks just like Sandy.
I went by your place
but I figured you might
come home this way.
I don't want
everything we have
to come down to
this one decision.
We can get past it.
'You did what you had to do.'
Doesn't mean
we can't be together.
I didn't do it.
I couldn't.
I want to keep it.
♪ Cold cold water ♪
I want us to have this baby.
♪ Surrounds me now ♪
♪ And all ♪
♪ I've got is your hand ♪
♪ Can you hear me ♪
♪ And all ♪