Previously on "ER.."
She's pregnant.
‐ Who?
‐ Nicole.
Oh, yeah, yeah, my stuff
just leapt into her bag.
Nicole?
You know, I used to have
a crush on you.
I used to have a crush
on you too.
I'm glad you came back.
Me too.
‐ Get in.
‐ No, I'm good.
No, you're not.
Go on, get out of here.
Come on.
‐ What was that about?
‐ I'm being subpoenaed.
'For what case?'
Reese. Roger's suing
for custody.
'He drew this?'
Yesterday afternoon.
He's got talent,
don't you think?
Hey, Jackie.
Hey.
Thanks for dropping
him off.
No problem.
Hey.
I missed you last night.
I know.
I had to work late.
No, no, no, I can't play.
I'm gonna come back
and put you to sleep.
‐ Yeah.
‐ Yeah?
Dr. Benton,
Romano wants you to assist
on a post‐op colectomy.
I'm off at 8:00.
It's 7:55.
Call Edson.
Oh, damn it.
'What is it?'
Uh, it's the ER.
I thought of something,
remember how Carla wanted Reese
to be with you on Father's Day?
It says a lot.
‐ The judge should know.
‐ That's good. Yeah.
‐ We'll be okay, right?
‐ Yeah, it's just first day.
Maybe I should be
there to help.
Jackie, you are helping.
Rachel Greene. I need a copy
of her attendance records.
‐ You could've told me.
‐ I didn't know.
Okay, I'll hold.
Who's allergic
to lilies?
She may not have appreciated
the symbolism.
‐ Symbolism?
‐ Lilies are for funerals.
Oh, God,
I'm sorry.
I just wanted to send
her some flowers.
You got his grandmother
flowers?
I can't seem to get
in her good graces.
How's her leg, anyway?
I think she's still more
concerned with the girl she hit.
I already met
with the vice principal.
I thought that girl
was better.
Yeah, she's on her upswing.
About to have a much
bigger bank account.
‐ She settled?
‐ Very good offer.
Good, so you can fax it to me?
'Who's paging me?'
They need you in room two.
‐ Where's Corday?
‐ Upstairs.
‐ Isn't she on for trauma?
‐ We just got here.
I thought
she was out on leave.
She's been cleared
to operate.
What about
all the dead geezers?
You know, there's no evidence
of any wrongdoing.
Good news.
When the paramedics
roll me in, I'll take Romano.
Entrance left temple, no exit.
What type of gun?
Cops said a .32
at close range.
Pupils are five millimeters
and fixed.
‐ Who shot her?
‐ Does it matter?
Got caught in a gas station
holdup.
‐ Absent blink reflex.
‐ Probable brain stem damage.
‐ Alright, did we push mannitol?
‐ I'm still assessing her.
‐ What are you waiting for?
‐ We're checking for signs‐‐
Alright.
Let's push the mannitol.
Load Dilantin
and hyperventilate.
I was taking Gallant through‐‐
Why don't you treat
the patient first? Okay?
ABG, gram of Ancef
and a head CT.
‐ What's the GCS?
‐ Elizabeth, it's 8:20.
Sorry, I had to change.
Let's call Neurosurg if there
is something fixable on CT.
‐ What's the rush?
‐ 'I have to be somewhere.'
'Heart rate's dropped to 50.'
Push an amp of atropine.
Is there a problem, Peter?
Yeah, you're late
and I have to get
the hell out of here.
'What's the caloric reflex?'
Slow deviation to the stimulus.
And then?
Uh..
Saccadic return to the midline.
Date of birth, 9/12/73.
Dr. Benton ever in a good mood?
He has his moments.
'Go ahead.'
'No response.'
Looks like she's a donor.
I'll be right back.
Is there any other family
we can call for you?
Her‐her parents live
in Minnesota.
We were, we're gonna
drive there today.
‐ This is Dr. Corday.
‐ I'm so sorry, Mr. Pruitt.
Are you gonna operate?
The bullet passed
through the brain stem.
I'm afraid no surgery
can repair that.
Well..
...is there any chance
that she'll s‐survive?
She's no longer breathing
on her own.
We have to wait and see
if she regains consciousness.
But it's highly unlikely.
The medical exam is consistent
with brain death.
I was still asleep
when she left.
I know this is a difficult time,
but we found a donor card.
A‐a what?
Your wife wanted
to be an organ donor.
Oh, yeah, I‐I guess
that's what she wanted to..
‐ Can I go see her?
‐ Yeah, sure.
Elizabeth, we need you in here.
Started an 18 gage
in the left AC.
Rudy Escalona, 15 years old,
LOC from blunt head trauma.
One, two, three.
'Boxing league. He took a lot
of punches during practice.'
Any medical problems, Rudy?
Huh?
No, my son's in good shape.
Do you know where you are?
I hit him, man.
I hit him good.
Pulse ox is 98
on two liters.
Pupils equal and reactive.
Do you know what year it is?
Nobody thought I could do it.
Answer the doctor.
But I did it.
Squeeze my hand, Rudy.
‐ Haleh?
‐ He's not responding.
We need to get some information
from you, sir.
Airway's okay.
Still has a gag.
No, I‐I'll stay.
Uh, after the X‐rays
you can come back.
Abdomen soft,
no guarding or rebounds.
‐ How late are you on?
‐ Peter should be back by 6:00.
I'm on till 10:00.
Can you check Rachel's homework?
Sure. Lateral C‐spine
and a head CT.
She needs help
with her trinomials.
Normal Babinski.
I believe
I failed algebra.
It's either that
or the Revolutionary War.
I'll stick with math.
Why can't you talk
to Human Resources?
It won't change the outcome.
Nicole's had a tough time.
She deserves a second chance.
Is that your objective opinion?
Okay, she made a mistake
but I know it won't
happen again.
Look, the‐the hospital
has a zero‐tolerance
policy against stealing.
But, if you explain
the circumstances
they might reconsider‐‐
There is nothing
to explain.
Kerry, just do it
as favor to me.
I'm sorry, I can't.
Or you won't?
Please, I got her the job.
You should have screened
her first.
Carter, what is this abscess
still doing in exam four?
It's peri‐rectal.
Yeah, it definitely
needs surgery.
So, you're on this too, Susan?
Carter wanted
a second opinion.
No. Call Surgery, we're busy.
One doctor per patient.
Have fun suturing.
Have fun
with your rectum.
When was your last tetanus shot?
Uh, you better ask my dad, I..
Jorge, this is Dr. Lewis.
Hi. How's his exam?
Uh, two centimeter lac
on the labial mucosa.
I'd suggest an interrupted
4.0 vicryl.
‐ How did you get hurt?
‐ Ow.
He‐he was boxing.
‐ And the other guy?
‐ You tell me.
The other patient in trauma one.
Jorge's little brother, Rudy.
Yeah, he got in a good one,
I kind of lost it
but I didn't mean to hurt him.
Not bad.
There you are.
‐ How's Rudy?
‐ They say he's gonna wake up.
He's gonna be alright.
You okay?
He needs a couple
of stitches.
‐ Does it hurt?
‐ No.
This is one tough kid.
Be careful of your reaction
to the testimony.
No sighing, no faces.
What if I need
to ask you a question?
Write it down,
I'll address it.
Schedule change,
they switched judges on us.
‐ Who did we draft?
‐ Alter.
Is that good or bad?
Well, he always favors
the mother.
It's not a problem
in this case.
Even though it wouldn't hurt
to show your maternal side.
‐ Right.
‐ That the tie you're wearing?
Mm, what's wrong with it?
Well, it's a little showy,
don't you think?
And when it comes your turn,
don't get too emotional.
You don't wanna come across
as cold or unfeeling either.
You make it sound like
it's some kind of performance.
Well, it is.
That is the whitest tie
I've ever seen.
It's blue.
She's breaking out in hives.
It's like an allergic reaction.
‐ To what?
‐ I don't know.
Nobody's figured it out.
We've been to three ERs
this week.
Fifty of Benadryl
in the field.
Push 125 of Solu‐Medrol.
We've found guided
imagery helps.
Close your eyes, honey.
Who's your doctor?
Oh, he's in Syracuse.
'We're on our honeymoon.'
'Go to your peaceful place..'
Oh, better hide
the good silver.
What's she doing here?
Meeting with personnel.
I heard
she's getting fired.
Let our souls intermingle.
Uh, any new soaps or pesticides?
Everything's the same.
‐ What about latex?
‐ What do you mean?
Yeah, some people are allergic
to, uh, rubber gloves
tennis shoes, condoms..
‐ Condoms?
‐ We stopped using them.
‐ 'When?'
‐ A couple weeks ago.
We're trying to get pregnant.
Everything's alright.
Feel the warmth of the sun.
Just embrace the joy.
Rudy's vital signs
and oxygen level are good.
‐ Is he awake now?
‐ Uh, not quite yet.
But he might be able
to hear you.
‐ Go ahead.
‐ Thanks.
'Even before I married Carla,
we discussed it.'
I knew it would be
a challenge but..
...we agreed
that our first priority
would always be Reese.
You took a variety of steps
to be a good parent
to him, didn't you?
I learned to sign, I..
I've always been in contact
with his teachers.
I've been volunteering
at his school
ever since he started.
'And you're self‐employed?'
'I run a website company
out of my home office.'
'What kind of hours
do you have?'
Completely flexible.
I make my own work schedule.
Have you ever needed to hire
a babysitter for Reese?
No.
Ever needed
to have someone else
pick him up from school?
No.
'So you've never passed'
'Reese's care‐giving
to anyone else?'
Never wanted to.
But Dr. Benton often requires
help, doesn't he?
Objection.
Outside his scope.
Uh, Mr. McGrath
has direct knowledge.
He can testify
to what he's observed.
Overruled.
Peter has a long list of people
who pick Reese up from school.
His girlfriend,
his sister, his niece.
'They're all involved
in looking after him.'
And even Dr. Benton
himself has asked you
'to help him out, hasn't he?'
Yeah.
He asked me to get Reese.
'But I don't mind.
Uh, I wanna be with him.'
Did Reese ever mention to you
where he prefers to sleep?
'Your house or Dr. Benton's?'
He likes my place.
'Why is that?'
He says it's his home.
Once the procurement teams
arrive
we'll move her to the OR.
She'll be on a ventilator?
Yes.
So her heart will
keep beating.
So she'll be alive when
you remove her organs.
Mr. Pruitt, your wife's brain
is not functioning
at its most basic level.
There is no medical
distinction
between brain death
and cardiac death.
You said that the machines
are keeping her alive.
Not exactly.
They're merely keeping
her organs viable.
Can't you just let
her die naturally?
To get healthy organs,
we procure
while the heart's still beating
and there's oxygen
in the bloodstream.
I‐I don't know.
I don't know.
I mean, we never
talked about this.
Look, I know she filled out
the card and everything‐‐
I understand.
I'm not so sure
that I can do this.
Why don't you take
some time with her?
I'll come back
and we'll talk some more.
Dr. Corday,
pre‐op's ready.
We're gonna wait a bit.
Abby, I need morphine now
for a perilunate dislocation.
How much?
Uh, get 20
just to be safe.
What's the patient's name?
Bovard.
I saw Nicole.
They let her go?
I'm sure
she'll find another job.
It's not important.
She might wanna
take it easy now
with the baby coming.
She's keeping it?
You thought she wouldn't?
Uh, I don't know,
it's‐it's tough
being a single mother.
Maybe she won't be.
Um, I'll need some Versed too.
You can't be serious.
She's a good person.
You met her, like,
five minutes ago.
It's the right thing to do.
Did she ever take
a pregnancy test?
‐ Of course.
‐ Did you see it?
‐ I mean, in front of you?
‐ I trust her.
What, exactly, has she done
to deserve that?
How can you be so‐‐
Even if it is yours
there's other ways to help.
How much Versed?
‐ I'll do it.
‐ No, I'll do it‐‐
I said I'll do it.
There was some bleeding
deep inside Rudy's brain.
How bad is it?
The problem's usually
a weak arterial wall.
If we can prevent any further
hemorrhage, he should be okay.
He's always begging to get in
the ring with his brother.
I shouldn't have let him do it.
Um, this isn't from boxing.
It's a pre‐existing condition.
What do you have to do?
The neural radiologist
can use a catheter
to mend the artery
from within.
‐ And then he'll be okay?
‐ He should be.
Look, you didn't
cause this, okay?
It could have happened
at any time.
It happened when I hit him.
Susan, you have curtain two?
Woman with hives?
No, I've got
the thyrotoxicosis.
‐ It's me. It's mine.
‐ Is she ready for dispo?
No, I'm still working her up.
Hey, have either one of you guys
ever heard
of an allergy to semen?
Maybe an aversion,
but not an allergy.
There's hundreds of proteins
that are potential antigens.
Is that your best diagnosis?
It's a possibility.
You must be desperate.
This is Sean Gatley.
My foot's stuck.
You doing okay, buddy?
Dad wouldn't let us
break the thing.
The toilet?
It's a personal
hygiene system.
Ugh, you're out
of your mind.
Hey, Dr. Weaver, right?
Sandy Lopez.
‐ Right.
‐ Good job last week.
I hear the lady
and the baby are doing okay.
‐ Yeah. Hey, Abby, I got this.
‐ Okay.
‐ Do you need something?
‐ I was looking for Luka.
He's with a patient.
Oh.
Do you wanna
a cup of coffee?
So, based on your extensive
observation of Dr. Benton
and Reese, how would you
summarize their relationship?
Peter's completely
devoted to Reese.
He's always focused
on what's best for him.
'I can't imagine anyone
being a better father.'
Thank you.
Are you and Dr. Benton married?
No.
Living together?
We've discussed it.
How long have you been a couple?
Almost three years.
So, you didn't break up in June?
It wasn't exactly
a break‐up‐‐
And get back together again,
about two weeks ago?
What are you, tracking
my love life?
Objection. Argumentative.
Sustained.
Let me ask
do you consider yourself
a stable factor in Reese's life?
I do.
How can we be sure
you won't break up again
next week, or next month,
or next year?
Objection. Calls for prophecy.
'Goes to the stability
of the home.'
Point taken, but you can answer.
It's my intention to be around
Peter and Reese for a long time.
'You occasionally babysit
for Reese, don't you?'
Quite often.
We get along well.
There was an incident
with a piano.
'Could you explain?'
‐ Reese hurt himself.
‐ Under your care.
I, it wasn't my‐‐
So, that's the supervision
Dr. Benton entrusts his son to.
‐ Objection.
‐ I looked away for two seconds.
When he's the one who should
have been looking after him.
Are you gonna ask a question?
Counselors, let's all breathe.
15 minute recess.
Thanks.
Is that decaf?
No.
Oh, I shouldn't have caffeine.
Oh, right, I forgot.
Luka told you?
Have you had
a pre‐natal exam yet?
‐ Not yet.
‐ I used to work in OB.
I could do an ultrasound.
That's nice of you,
but I‐I'll take care of it.
How do you know you're pregnant?
Thanks for the coffee.
This is not the way
to get Luka.
What are you talking about?
The truth.
What happened to your father?
I told you, he killed himself
when I was little.
And then, miraculously
came back to life again
so he could kick you out
when you were 16?
Is this funny to you?
No. I'm just trying
to figure it out.
You haven't told anyone
the same story twice.
My mother remarried
and my stepfather
didn't want me around.
Okay, I guess you have an answer
for everything.
I guess everything's
your business.
I just don't wanna
see him hurt.
Maybe you don't wanna
see him happy.
'I know what won't
make him happy.'
A made‐up life.
I, you know, if‐if this
if this is all for real,
that's great, go for it.
But if it's not,
he's gonna figure it out.
He's not stupid.
You know, I never got a chance
to thank you for the‐‐
Saving your life?
Uh, yeah, that.
Listen, no sweat.
It was a crazy night.
That's a pretty crazy job.
I haven't met too many
female firefighters.
Only one in Company B.
Must be
pretty challenging.
No, not really.
I'm just one of the guys.
Anyway, I'll see you around.
Did you get a wound check?
‐ Hmm?
‐ Your hand.
Oh, uh, I don't like doctors.
You should let me take
a look at it before you go.
Maybe some other time.
‐ What happened?
‐ Rudy dropped his sats.
BP's 230/120.
Pulse ox 78 on 15 liters.
‐ He stopped breathing.
‐ One of pavulon, 100 of sux.
‐ What's going on?
‐ Let's check the fundi.
There's increased pressure
in your son's brain.
What are you gonna do?
Well, we're gonna help
him breathe first.
Multifocal PVCs.
‐ Dr. Greene?
‐ Push another 100 of lidocaine.
Heart rate 58.
‐ It's Rachel.
‐ I can't talk right now.
Start nipride at 70 mics.
She says you told her
to check in.
Elizabeth will be home at 6:00.
I'm in.
Lily, another 60 of nimodipine.
I'll get it.
Looks like V‐tach.
‐ Oh, God.
‐ No pulse.
Charge to 200,
and start compressions.
Have you ever tried
a non‐heart beating protocol?
I observed one
at Case Western.
They take the patient
to the OR, turn off the vent
and wait for the heart
to stop beating.
Meanwhile, lack of oxygen
can ruin the organs.
You remove them after only two
minutes of cardiac arrest.
They should still be viable,
and she'll get a natural death.
She's dead either way.
This approach only compromises
the success of the transplant.
It's the only approach
the husband will consent to.
You know that for a fact?
You presented this
to Mr. Pruitt?
'Luka?'
I‐I suggested it as an option.
Without consulting me.
She's my patient too.
You're not the one
who needs approval
for an unconventional procedure,
nor are you the one
going to have to do it.
‐ Can you take a break?
‐ Yeah.
Dr. Weaver, is there anyone
in exam four?
The middle bed in there's free.
Uh, I don't wanna
tie up a monitor.
Hey, do I have to keep
this in my arm?
Yeah, if I'm right,
you might even need
emergency meds.
What if someone comes in?
These doors lock
from the inside.
‐ Oh, my God.
‐ Is that what I think it is?
Ah. Just give me one second.
Malik.
I thought this guy
was going to the morgue.
Yeah, I was just about to.
‐ We need epi in here.
‐ How many amps?
As much as you can carry.
Maybe this isn't
such a good idea.
No, it will be fine.
Charged to 360.
Clear.
‐ 'Asystole.'
‐ How long has he been down?
‐ Forty five minutes.
‐ Alright. Resume compressions.
‐ How much epi?
‐ Push another four milligrams.
‐ How much longer are we going?
‐ Uh, I'm gonna bring 'em in.
‐ You're calling it?
‐ Not yet.
Rudy hasn't had a heartbeat
in almost an hour.
How could this happen?
He had a massive hemorrhage.
No.
It damaged the part of his brain
that controls his heart
and his breathing.
You said
they could fix it.
There wasn't enough time.
Keep trying, please.
We've shocked him repeatedly.
We've used every drug.
Nothing is working.
Do you wanna say goodbye
before we stop?
You fought hard, Rudy.
You never gave up.
I'm proud of you.
'We'll never forget you.'
Shut up.
We love you, mijo.
You'll always be
in our hearts.
Shut up! Shut up!
Can you hear me?
'Shut, shut up!'
Shut up!
Just let us know
when you want us to stop.
I hope it snows.
I'd like to see
the city covered in white.
Yeah, it's pretty.
Till your car won't start.
Maybe I can get a job
shoveling sidewalks.
Might be good if you don't work
for a while.
'Take care of yourself.'
The baby.
I need to work.
You don't need to worry
about the rent.
I talked to my friend.
I think I found a job.
Wow, that was quick.
He's opening a cafe in Montreal.
'He wants me to help run it.'
I can't move to Montreal.
You've been very generous.
I'm thankful for everything.
S‐so..
...what are you saying?
That's it?
'You could leave like that?'
Listen, m‐my shift's
over at 7:00.
Let's‐let's talk
about this tonight.
I'll call you in a few days.
Are you angry with me?
No, of course not.
Do you think I'm angry with you?
I hope not.
Then why? I‐I, I thought
we both felt the same.
You're a good person
but you talked yourself
into loving me.
This isn't real.
'I'll leave the key inside.'
I made an OB appointment
for Friday.
It's not necessary.
It is.
No, it's not.
I'm not pregnant.
I felt safe for the first time
in a long time.
I didn't wanna lose you.
So I made it up, Luka.
I'm sorry.
I made it all up.
I think we need two layers.
You know how to bury the knot?
Take your first bite
in the center deep
and then come up sub‐Q.
‐ You hear something?
‐ You're nuts.
‐ I hear banging.
‐ What's that noise?
Oh, I think they were working
on the pipes or..
Oh, that don't sound
like pipes.
‐ You got this?
‐ Yeah, yeah, I think so.
‐ Who is in there?
‐ My allergy patient.
‐ The lady with hives?
‐ And her husband.
Don't tell me
you are tying up
a room
so they can have sex.
I'm...conducting
a clinical trial.
Send them to an allergist.
No, that'll take weeks.
They're young.
They're aroused.
They want their answer now.
Does Weaver know
you're running a brothel?
It's not a brothel
if they're married.
Dr. Lewis, lab's back
on Escalona.
I didn't order any labs.
Rudy? Kid who arrested.
‐ Oh, I had the brother.
‐ That's mine.
It wasn't your fault.
Sometimes things happen
you can't explain.
Rudy's labs came back.
Did he ever take any stimulants?
I'd never let him do that.
There was ephedra
in his bloodstream.
‐ Ephedra?
‐ It's a natural supplement.
It's in, uh, power formulas.
He drinks Beta‐Morph sometimes.
‐ From where?
‐ From the store.
He wanted to drink a six‐pack
before we sparred.
He said he wanted
to dust me for once.
The ephedra probably raised
his blood pressure
causing one of the vessels
in his brain to rupture.
Why would he do it?
To enhance his performance.
He wanted to make
you proud, dad.
You knew about this?
He was never tough enough
for you.
Why didn't you stop him?
You kept pushing him
and you never let up.
‐ Calm down, guys.
‐ No, he was just a kid.
No, he wanted to be a champ.
No, that's what you wanted.
It's over.
I'm through.
This is not the way
to honor your brother.
It's my choice.
It's not your choice.
You were born with a gift.
‐ Look, come on, Jorge‐‐
‐ No, here's your gift.
Here's your gift.
Man, he's spinning everything
his way.
We'll get it all back
on your testimony.
Hey.
Hey, everything alright?
Yeah, I just couldn't sit
at home
not knowing what was going on.
We're just getting started.
You testify yet?
No, Roger went first.
What did he say?
That I was the world's
greatest father.
Peter.
I asked him to help out
with Reese a couple of times.
He made it seem like
it happens all the time.
He lied.
It's his version of the truth.
Isn't that perjury?
Isn't there something
you can do?
‐ 'Jackie.'
‐ Why were you lying?
‐ Jackie?
‐ Leave us alone.
‐ 'Jackie, don't.'
‐ Get away from me.
Wait a minute, stop it,
and tell the truth.
‐ Ma'am, step away.
‐ 'Jackie, you're not helping.'
Get your own family.
He got us here.
His choice.
‐ Reese is our boy.
‐ Jackie‐‐
‐ He's our boy!
‐ Jackie.
What are you doing?
Getting caught up
on my charts.
‐ You were listening.
‐ No.
You were, you were listening
to them have sex.
I am not.
You usually chart at Admit
or in the lounge.
I can chart wherever I want,
and I don't need to listen
to your porno patients
for kicks.
‐ They stopped.
‐ See?
‐ You were listening.
‐ Do you think she's okay?
Do you think we should check?
What's going on in there?
Ask Carter.
You broke your fifth metacarpal.
Damn.
Hey, that's what they call
a boxer's fracture.
You're gonna be in a cast
for about six weeks.
‐ Good.
‐ Dr. Greene?
'Teenager with a ten‐foot fall
coming in.'
Get Carter.
Clear trauma one.
Hey, you want me on that?
Numb him up first.
Hematoma block.
Does my dad know?
Uh, not yet.
It would be better coming
from you.
Listen, Jorge, uh..
...everybody has a hard time
talking to their father.
Well, it's different with him.
I mean, he's old school.
He grew up in Cuba.
And when did he come over?
Before I was born.
He was a great fighter.
When he tried to leave,
they broke his hands.
Well, that's, uh, why
he pushes you so hard.
Yeah.
I guess he just wants us to have
what they took away from him.
You ever talk to him about this?
'Well, maybe you should.'
I'm sorry, honey.
Maybe you just need
a little break.
Carter.
Well, he never used to have
a problem finishing.
That dead guy freaked me.
Well, you need to use condoms
until you can try again
under medical supervision.
I never used to be allergic
to sperm.
It's the semen, actually.
Oh, what would cause that?
Sometimes multiple
sex partners‐‐
Have you had more than ten?
‐ Ten?
‐ Let's go, honey.
I thought it was just me
and Kenny Markowitz.
What else haven't you told me?
That's a very good job there.
‐ It's very diplomatic.
‐ It was your diagnosis.
No, I bring people
together, Susan.
Oh, yes, you and Cupid.
Sixteen‐year‐old male
fell from a lamppost.
‐ 'Carter.'
‐ Uh‐huh.
Good vitals.
No LOC.
An obvious ankle fracture.
No meds, no allergies.
Okay, everybody,
grab hold, on my count.
One, two and three.
Pulse ox 99 on two liters.
‐ You got any pain here?
‐ No, I'm fine.
‐ Turn your head towards me.
‐ 'You need any help? '
Yeah, can you Doppler the foot?
‐ You got it.
‐ Okay if I cuff him, doc?
'Yeah, do it on the right side.'
‐ Turn away from me.
‐ BP's 124 over 78.
‐ 'Does it hurt?'
‐ 'No.'
Neck's clear. Let's get him
off the board.
Bounding dorsalis pedis.
‐ Go.
‐ What's he in custody for?
Kids were stealing street signs.
‐ Anybody else hurt?
‐ No, girl's fine.
She's in the car
with my partner.
Okay, we're gonna
sit you up now.
What's your name?
Andrew.
Don't I know you?
That your daughter?
'She's not under arrest?'
'No, situations like this'
we just like to scare them
a little bit.
Take them down to the station,
call their parents.
‐ 'They'll release her to me?'
‐ 'I'll call the sergeant.'
‐ Don't think it'd be a problem.
‐ I'd appreciate that.
Got a phone I can use?
I adjusted her meds,
have the nurse call
if she has any questions.
‐ 'Sandy.'
‐ Hey.
Still got time
for a wound check?
Uh, I thought you had
to leave AMA.
Oh, it wasn't bothering me
until I jammed it
rolling some hose.
‐ Still bleeding?
‐ I don't think so.
‐ Come on, let's take a look.
‐ Okay.
'What happens when
you're on call?'
We work 12‐hour shifts.
7:00 a. m. to 7:00 p. m?
Half the time.
And the other half,
you work overnight?
There's always a surgeon
in‐house.
‐ So, you cover weekends too?
‐ Sometimes.
Well, looking at your schedule,
it appears
that over half your shifts
are weekends or overnights.
Well, I'd have to check.
Take me through what happens
when a gunshot victim
enters the ER.
Well, I evaluate the patient
and I take them
to the OR, if necessary.
Gunshot to the chest.
How long of an operation
is that?
‐ Well, that depends.
‐ 'On what?'
The path of the bullet,
extent of vascular damage
if bypass is necessary
for cardiac repair.
So, it could take
over an hour?
I'd say three hours
was a reasonable estimate.
Sometimes longer?
Five hours?
Sometimes.
'So, if a patient comes in
at 6:30 p. m.'
who takes over for you at 7:00
when you go home to Reese?
Well, I try to get someone
to cover for me.
And if you can't?
Then I stay with the patient.
If an operation takes five hours
you'll be there till midnight?
That's a rare situation.
But it happens?
It's possible.
So, when you're tied up
in surgery all night
'who's looking after Reese?'
Well, I have the support
of family and friends.
Like Dr. Finch, for example?
Yes.
Cleo is very good with Reese.
'Yes, we've already
covered that.'
Who else helps you out?
My sister, Jackie picks him up
from school if I have to work.
‐ And makes him dinner?
‐ Sometimes.
And puts him to bed while
you're working the night shift?
That's right.
Is she always available?
Jackie's become like a mother
to Reese these last few months.
But initially, after Carla died
Jackie wasn't so receptive
to the idea
of caring for Reese, was she?
It was a tough time.
She has her own children,
doesn't she?
Joanie, her daughter.
Wasn't there a boy?
Yeah, uh, Jesse, my nephew.
He died last year.
The death was gang‐related,
right?
‐ Objection.
‐ He can answer the question.
Yes.
How is your sister handling
that loss?
You know, I'm sorry.
I don't, uh..
I don't see how this pertains
to my fitness as a father.
Your Honor,
this is far afield.
Goes to the stability
of the person he's identified
as primary caregiver.
I'll give some latitude.
Is Jackie under the care
of a psychiatrist?
I don't know.
For situational depression
and pathologic grieving?
She lost her son.
Is she currently
being managed by medication‐‐
This has nothing
to do with Reese
or my ability
to care for him.
...whose side effects include
insomnia, sedation
and anxiety?
Gentlemen!
Why don't you ask me
what kind of father I am?
about how I was there
when he was born prematurely
how I stayed in the hospital
in the NICU
watching over him,
making tough decisions
and praying over him
day and night?
Why don't you ask me that?
Your Honor,
a moment with my client.
Dr. Benton‐‐
Your Honor, there's no question
before the court.
No, why don't you ask me
about Reese
so I can tell you that
there's nothing more important
to me in this world
than my son?
Why don't you ask me that?
You can't let that happen again.
They were provoking him.
You better get used
to it, Peter.
I said what I had to say.
Well, I hope you feel better
'cause it sure didn't help.
What did the judge say
in chambers?
That he was impressed
with Roger's availability.
‐ Availability?
‐ I'm available to Reese.
We're gonna have
to make a better showing.
Alright.
I'll do better tomorrow.
That's not gonna do it.
Your hours are hurting us.
He's a surgeon.
'It goes with the job.'
Do you wanna keep your son?
What do you think?
That you need
to start setting priorities
'and making some hard choices.'
'That's what I think.'
How well do you know Andrew?
What's that supposed to mean?
Does he do drugs?
‐ I don't think so.
‐ Are you sure?
‐ What's this?
‐ Results of his tox screen.
He tested positive
for marijuana.
Aren't you supposed
to keep that confidential?
Were you smoking with him?
No.
Have you ever smoked with him?
I wouldn't do that.
Good.
Then you'll test negative.
Are you serious?
You don't trust me?
I trusted you to go home
after school.
Dad, he was gonna
drop me off
but then,
he wanted to stop.
We agreed no rides.
‐ I missed the bus.
‐ You should have called me.
I didn't wanna bother you.
Sure didn't work out that way.
You want me to pee in a cup?
Yep.
Yes, a gram of Ceftazidime.
Michael, did the family choose
a mortuary yet?
‐ What?
‐ Rudy Escalona.
We need to get him
to the morgue.
No. Not the ICU, the ER.
Thanks.
Oh, you need me to do something?
Ask Frank
for the decedent packet.
‐ Luka?
‐ Hmm?
You weren't here so I gave
Collins the gent first.
Thanks.
I...I had to go out.
Everything okay?
She's leaving town.
‐ Why?
‐ I don't know.
Dr. Kovac,
exam four's vomiting blood.
What about the baby?
There is no baby.
I started another line
on Zahler.
Did you have a written order?
It was right up there.
Why was Abby about to discharge
my bowel obstruction?
I have no idea.
Because you can't write
between the lines.
‐ Oh, sorry.
‐ 'Carter, is this one yours?
'Twenty five‐year‐old woman,
severe allergic reactions‐‐'
‐ Mrs. Urman?
‐ 'Gave her 50 of Benadryl.'
‐ What happened?
‐ I guess you were right.
‐ We followed our bliss.
‐ Where?
To our pickup truck.
I figured we'd be safe right
by the hospital, so, uh..
I'll get her started.
300 of cimetidine.
I will be right there.
Ooh, that's a very nice suit.
Thanks. I was in court all day.
‐ A patient?
‐ No.
‐ Something wrong?
‐ No. Everything's cool.
Dr. Benton, they need you
in the OR.
Mr. Escalona.
Uh, if you'd like,
the nurse said
that we can make arrangements
for the funeral home.
W‐we used, uh, Rose Hills
when his mother died.
But I‐I never
thought that..
He was a good kid.
He made everybody smile.
Jorge..
'...he was the serious one.'
I didn't mean
to lose my temper.
It's been a hard day,
you know?
He doesn't wanna see me.
He doesn't understand.
You, uh, should give him
a shot.
You know,
he might surprise you.
Sorry to be brief
but my nanny gets off
in six minutes.
Diane Pruitt,
GSW to the head.
Transplant teams are flying
in from Indiana and Michigan.
‐ The gas station robbery.
‐ Yes.
Romano has agreed
to a non‐heart beating protocol.
When did we start doing that?
Today, apparently.
That's the husband over there.
If you could review
the procedure
with him once more?
He's already consented, right?
Yeah, of course.
So what is there to talk about?
Uh, the man needs
some reassurance.
Elizabeth, you had him
for 12 hours. You deal with him.
He wants to talk
to the operating surgeon.
Peter, what's the matter?
Nothing. Go home.
Mr. Pruitt?
Hi.
I'm Dr. Benton. I'll be
coordinating the procedure.
As soon as the out‐of‐state team
gets here
we'll take her to the OR.
Okay.
I, uh, I tried to explain it
to her, but, uh,
she's too young.
I don't know how
I'm gonna do this by myself.
Well, you'll do the best
you can.
You're supposed
to be on light duty.
I was moving some gear.
No, you went on a run.
I get a little stir crazy.
Okay.
Looks pretty good,
no sign of infection.
That's it?
No. You need a new bandage.
So, is, uh..
...Captain Devlin
still at the seven‐five?
I know the name.
Yeah, those guys
used to hang out
at a place called
the, um, Moose and Squirrel.
Yeah. Every Friday night.
That was a fun place.
Uh, you should have someone
remove the stitches
in four days.
I know where to find you.
Listen, Sandy..
Oh, gosh, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
‐ Oh, I bunched it up.
‐ That's alright.
What were you saying?
Do you wanna do something?
Excuse me?
Uh, sometime?
You know, something.
Something?
Uh, I don't know.
Lunch, or a movie,
or ice fishing?
‐ Like, go out?
‐ Yeah.
I mean, unless I'm totally
off base here.
No.
No, you're on base.
How's it going?
Fine.
Your drug screen came back.
Everything was negative.
Don't look so disappointed.
I know you're upset.
But I had to do this
because I want you to be safe.
I care more about that
than about your being angry
with me.
I wanna be able
to trust you.
It's something we both
have to work at.
Can I go now?
‐ Is the recipient ready?
‐ Yeah. All I need is a liver.
Alright. The heart team
gets first crack.
But tell them
to make it snappy.
Sternal saw's up.
Open the O Dexon,
atraumatic needle.
‐ All set?
‐ 'Good to go.'
After two minutes
of cardiac arrest
I'll call it, and then
we'll begin procurement.
How's her oxygenation?
'Fine. Satting at 100 percent.'
'Good. Turn it off.'
Respiratory support
discontinued at 20:37.
Oh, they're sweet.
I hope they get pregnant.
Shouldn't be a problem.
The endocrinologist can wash
the sperm
and then it's safe
to artificially inseminate.
Hmm.
That's a new one.
Just goes to teach you
never to doubt my diagnoses.
Yeah, no matter
how loony they are.
I can't believe
they did it
in the back
of a pickup truck.
‐ They had a camper shell.
‐ How do you know?
‐ I saw it.
‐ You did?
Yes. In the front
of the hospital.
It's their honeymoon suite.
Very weird.
Not so weird.
Ferris wheel, that's weird.
‐ Really?
‐ I‐I was young.
It was my first real boyfriend.
Where else?
Your turn.
Camping. Where else?
In a tent? That's the best
you can do?
Uh..
On a train to Seattle.
Really?
With who?
I was by myself..
...but it was memorable.
Mm. It's cold.
Yeah. We should probably go in.
Yeah.
Carter..
You don't have any allergies
I should know about, do you?
Oops.
Where were we?
‐ How long has it been?
‐ Forty nine minutes.
Tissues could be
getting ischemic.
Alright, let's send an ABG,
lytes and a lactate.
Who's in charge here?
I ordered liver an hour ago
and I haven't seen my waitress
since.
The patient's breathing
on her own.
Ugh. How inconsiderate.
Well, this could take hours.
Page me when she goes.
What do you wanna do,
Dr. Benton?
Let's just wait.