"There's nothing else
we can do for you."
These are the last words a
surgeon wants to tell a patient.
Eight surgeons have
said this is inoperable.
I mean, even the tumor
board at Cleveland Clinic.
I can see why.
Giving up doesn't
come easy to us,
so we do everything
in our power not to.
Catch.
What's this for? Heads,
we do it. Tails, we don't.
You're insane.
It's a gut check. I get a
feeling when it's in the air,
what I want it to land on.
Flip it.
For surgeons, "lost cause"
just means "try
a little harder."
Oh, damn it. I screwed it up.
"Gag Zola," really?
Those aren't G's. Those
are Y's for "Yay." "Yay, Zola."
See, a normal person would've
just written, "Happy Birthday."
Well, I couldn't fit all
those letters on the cake.
Okay, who used up the
last of my deodorant?
Oh, that might have been me.
Sorry, kinda had a
workout last night.
Not mine. ALEX: Coffee.
Fresh out, chief.
Wait. No. That's impossible. I
just bought some three days ago.
You're out of OJ, too.
Hey, you're still here?
Oh, yeah. I was on my way
out, and then I saw these cheeks.
So cute.
Oh! We don't touch the baby
because we don't know
where those hands have been.
Alex does.
Okay, so I have a meeting
with Owen, so I'm off.
Party is at 8:00. Don't be late.
I got 20 minutes before
work. You wanna, you know...
Yeah. Good. Come on.
Round two!
We need to move.
Do we?
Okay, take a look.
I took a little
more off this time.
No, I love it. Hey, look!
Ooh! I want that. Move.
I've got surgery in an hour,
so we'll do you tomorrow.
And you, I will see
tonight at Zola's party.
Yes?
Love you. See ya.
"See ya"?
Yeah. "I love you, too" is the
appropriate response to "I love you."
Yeah. Why wouldn't you...
We've been dating three
months. It's way too early for that.
Oh, no! No, no, no!
This is classic Mark!
He found out Lexie
and Jackson broke up,
and now he's suddenly
getting cold feet about Julia.
You and Lexie are over, okay?
That ship has sailed. And sank.
This has nothing
to do with Lexie.
Okay, I'm gonna take Sofia
to daycare. Come here, honey.
Hello! Yes, my little baby girl.
I love you.
Bye. I love you, too!
Morning, Dr. Webber. Morning.
Dr. Webber. How are you?
Dr. Bailey.
Congratulations, sir.
Big day today. Yes, it is!
But I don't want everybody
making a big deal out of it.
We won't. Good.
I mean, you'll do something?
Yes.
I mean, it is my 10,000th
surgery, that's a lot of surgeries.
I've reserved the
main conference room.
There will be a photographer
from the hospital newsletter.
The cake is your favorite,
red velvet and cream cheese.
It is huge, the size
of four cakes. Yes!
There will be several speeches
from admiring colleagues
and a toast with
sparkling cider.
We will also hang a banner
that says "Congratulations,
Dr. Webber, on your 10,000th surgery!"
There will be three exclamation
points after the word "surgery."
We also have confetti.
Happy now?
Yes.
Oh, except for the confetti.
Might get in the cake.
Oh, take a seat, Grey.
Okay, so I know I haven't
logged a lot of OR time lately,
but I've been getting a
routine down with Zola,
and I've got it under
control now, so I'm all set.
Is that it?
You still haven't
declared a specialty.
I know. It's a
really big decision,
and I have been
thinking about it.
You ditched neuro,
you wasted time in OB,
you're my only fifth year who
doesn't know where they're going.
You're drowning, Grey.
"Drowning" is a strong word.
How about general?
You've been helping
Bailey with the diabetes trial,
and Webber's always been a
mentor, not to mention your mother.
She was one of the
best general surgeons
this country's ever seen.
With that legacy,
you could be a natural.
How did you repair it that fast?
Well, it was luck more
than anything else.
He could've gone
into pulmonary edema.
No, it wasn't luck. You were
in the zone. That was amazing!
Oh. Dr. Altman!
It's lasagna.
And this is a spinach pie.
That's so sweet. Thank you.
It means a lot to me.
More widow casserole.
"Your husband's
dead. Have some food."
What is that? I'll
put it with the others.
Oh, hey. How'd the surgery go?
I'll see you in the pit.
Glad to see she's not
mad at me anymore.
She's very busy.
We just did a mitral valve
repair without bypass,
and she threw 25
stitches in 10 seconds.
I've never seen
anything like it.
How long's it been
since you slept?
I had a huge nap.
Whatever, I've done, like, eight
surgeries in the past 72 hours.
Teddy's boundless grief is one of the
best things that's ever happened to me.
What is that? Is that trauma
or administrative crap?
No, none of your business.
Go home and get some sleep.
Oh, trauma. Hey,
hey. No, Cristina...
Take that. Hey!
I was paged here. I
already ordered the CT.
He's my patient.
This isn't finders, keepers.
I'm taking over the
patient. What do we got?
Back off, Yang. I
met the ambulance.
Everyone, take a
breath. What happened?
A 32-year-old ran his bike
into a wrought iron fence.
Yeah, and this is the fence
going directly into his heart.
I know how to deal
with these injuries.
He's my patient.
I can remove it
thoracoscopically.
Yeah, and that's
when the poor guy dies
because if you do that, you
won't have a direct visual.
Plenty of people use the VATS
technique to remove impaled objects.
Now you're the expert?
You don't get every
cardio case, Yang.
Enough, all of you.
McQueen is the doctor
on call, he can handle it.
Karev, you will assist.
Altman, I believe that
today is your day off.
Go get some rest.
Dr. Altman has way
more experience,
and this is gonna be a
complicated procedure.
Well, both of you have been
up for the past 48 hours straight.
This is a liability issue.
Hands off the patient.
Dr. Altman?
Fine.
Enjoy your nap.
His neuroblastoma is more
complicated than most I've seen.
It's very rare that
someone his age...
They're mostly in
younger kids, I know.
It's in a very large
region of his spine.
There is the very
likely risk of paralysis.
From his upper body down.
There's also the risk of death,
a death that he is gonna
meet in three months anyway
if you don't do this surgery.
I understand the
risks, Dr. Shepherd.
The surgeon in
Boston compared it to
dismantling a bomb
with your eyes closed,
and the one in Chicago said it
was patching a dam with gum.
You're the ninth
surgeon I've talked to.
So what I want to know is, are
you gonna say anything different,
or do I have to take
my kid somewhere else?
There is only a 5%
chance of success.
Maybe a little less.
Yes, if you're
willing, I'll try.
Okay. Should I go tell Wes?
Wait. There's something else.
He doesn't know about his tumor.
He's 11, a young 11,
and knowing that he's
very likely gonna die
is not something that's
gonna do him any good.
Why does he think he's here?
A backache.
A very bad backache.
Hey, Dr. Bailey.
Chief Hunt says I need
to declare a specialty.
He suggested general.
Good for you. Mini Ellis Grey!
No. I'm still on
the fence about it
because there are a lot
of specialties out there...
Don't be an idiot. It's
in your genes, Grey.
It makes perfect sense.
Oh, Karen and Marcy,
I'd like you to meet
Dr. Bailey and Dr. Grey.
They'll be performing the
liver transplant with me today.
Nice to meet you.
This IV really hurts.
You think it could be infected?
I mean, I'm already missing
my family vacation for this.
I'd hate to die of staph.
You're not gonna die, Marcy.
I am the one in liver failure.
It doesn't look infected. A
little discomfort is normal.
Thank you! I'm
sorry. I'm just nervous.
I've never had a
major surgery before.
But when your sister calls
you to come and save her life,
I mean, you take that call. How
lucky I am to have just that sister.
Yes, you are.
Well, the labs look good.
We're ready for transplant.
In the meantime,
why don't we relax?
Relax? In a hospital?
It'd be a lot easier on
a white, sandy beach.
I'm gonna reimburse
you for this trip. I promise.
I just hope I
don't die in there.
I mean, it would be hard
to reimburse me for my life.
Thank you, Marcy. I just
can't thank you enough.
Oh, you're welcome.
Fort Ticonderoga is
probably my favorite.
It's not giant like Gettysburg
or famous like the Alamo.
You feel any pain
here, Wes? A little.
Still, it was a
really important fort.
It changed hands a bunch
of times in just a few years.
Benedict Arnold
even fought there.
He's got a thing
about battlefields.
I see that. Hey, relax.
My mom says I got it from my
dad. He died when I was two.
We've gone to 18
battlefields in the past year.
We homeschool
because of the back pain.
It's so cool.
I wake up, and we get to
decide what I do that day.
Next week, we're
going to Pearl Harbor.
That way, my mom can
have a beach vacation, too.
Actually, Wes, we may
be postponing Hawaii.
Dr. Shepherd thinks he
might be able to fix your back.
Really? Then I won't
have these aches anymore?
Well, that's the plan.
What about ortho? Callie
would be a great mentor.
Bones? Oncology.
Depressing. Trauma.
I've had enough
trauma for one lifetime.
Well, just pick something.
This decision is important.
Check it. Fence guy,
heart's the size of a football.
From hitting a fence? From
being impaled on a fence.
Don't worry, Yang. I'll send
you pics from the surgery.
Hey, is it too late
for me to pick cardio?
Yes. Cardio's mine.
You don't have to do
this, you know? I want to.
He's the Chief of Surgery. And
that heart is the size of a football.
He's leaving.
Okay, go.
Go now.
Mrs. Vanderburg, I'm Dr. Yang.
I'm so sorry to hear about
your husband's accident.
Are you one of his doctors?
I'm not, but I'm
familiar with his case,
and I just wanted to assure you
that everyone here is doing
everything they can for him.
That's so nice.
I'm sure they've assembled a
wonderful group of surgeons.
Dr. Altman really
is the best there is.
Wait. No.
I don't think they
mentioned an Altman.
No, they said something
about a Dr. McQueen.
Is that right? Is he good, too?
Dr. McQueen?
Oh, sure. He's fine.
Fine?
Well, he's an
experienced surgeon,
but he's not the head
of the department.
Dr. Altman is the
head of the department.
You know, I...
With the extent of
your husband's injuries,
I just... Look, I just assumed
she was on the case.
But
I'm sure there's
nothing to worry about.
Dr. Altman probably
wasn't available anyway.
She's very busy these days...
Saving lives.
You swam with the dolphins?
Kaylee swam with the dolphins.
Okay, honey, Mommy needs
to go save Aunt Karen's life now.
Bye-bye, sweetie.
I love you, too.
I am risking my life here.
It's not like a
ride to the airport.
Believe me, after this,
I will never ask you
for a ride to the airport. I will
never ask you for anything again.
What is that supposed to mean?
Just need a little blood here.
Because I am never
gonna hear the end of it.
You're gonna lord this
stupid piece of liver over me
until we're both dead,
just like everything else.
One more tube, and
I'll be out of your hair.
Everything else? Like
all the checks I sent?
Or the jobs I lined up?
You managed to get yourself
fired from most of those.
And I have never asked
you for anything in return.
Oh no, just my lips
glued to your ass 24/7.
You know what?
Keep your damn liver.
Oh, here we go.
You know, I have no job, no
husband, no kids. You won, okay?
So just, hey, forget
the transplant.
Just... You're off the
hook. You're off the hook.
Catch your plane to Maui, swim
with your precious dolphins...
Karen, what hurts? Don't worry.
When I'm winning the
fight, she doesn't feel good.
I'm in liver failure.
Classic drama queen.
I need some FFP
and octreotide in here!
There's bleeding in the veins
at the bottom of your esophagus.
That's a symptom of
late-stage liver failure.
You have surgery
in a couple of hours.
You have to try not to get
worked up between now and then.
I told Dr. Grey, I'm
not having the surgery.
I want to go back
on the transplant list.
There's no time for that, Karen.
When these symptoms
start, we can't wait any longer.
Karen, you're going
to die. Don't be stupid.
Okay, enough from you.
Fine.
I'll take her liver.
Thank God.
Honestly, the things you
put our family through.
I'll call Harry and the kids. They'll
be so thrilled you've chosen life.
You got it? Yeah.
Here you go.
Did the tumor grow more?
What did you say?
I know what I have.
I overheard some doctors
talking about it at the last hospital.
Does your mom
know that you know?
No. She'd just freak out.
She's your mom.
She needs to know.
She cries in the bathroom.
She cries at night.
She cries in the morning when
she thinks I'm not awake yet.
She cries all the time.
And the only thing that makes her
happy is to think that I don't know.
You can't tell her.
If I'm happy, she's happy.
I promise. I won't tell.
You're not lying?
I'm not lying.
Do you think I'm gonna die?
I've worked with
Dr. Shepherd for a while now.
And your mom could not have
picked a better doctor for you.
He's the best.
Well, this one has a
patio and a garage,
but this one has hardwood
floors and a washer/dryer.
You sure you want to move?
Meredith and Derek have a baby,
and you're living with
your ex. We're moving.
I'll move. Zola's
killing my game.
Every girl I bring home wants
a baby the minute they see her.
No! I'm not living with you.
I am trying to get
away from you.
All right, then you and me.
You don't want to
live with Mary Poppins.
No, she cooks, she
cleans... I'm also your friend.
What the hell? I need
food for Zola's party.
I thought I was gonna
have time to go to the store,
but Richard's 10,000th
surgery is gonna take forever.
You think Teddy's gonna care if I
take some of her widow casseroles?
No. Go for it. You know
what? Take this one, too.
It's turkey
tetrazzini. Ooh, yum!
You and McQueen
finally find a patient
who's willing to let
you operate on them?
Bite my ass.
Oh, Mer, proctology.
There's your specialty.
Explore the mysteries of the butt.
Why aren't you just doing
general like your mom?
It's a no-brainer.
And good marketing.
When people hear the name Grey,
they know they're
getting quality.
No, you can't win following
in the footsteps of a phenom.
Said the lame, mediocre
grandson of Harper Avery.
Hello, Julia. What is this?
She's you. You're
Julia. Go with it.
You know, I've been thinking,
it's been a really great few months,
and I just want you
to know that I love you.
Get out of my relationship.
Funny, coming from you.
What's your problem? She's
smart and pretty and funny and...
And she's not annoying.
Come on, it's awesome.
We can all vacation together.
We can buy houses
next door to each other.
Yeah, and Sofia can
have a village. Yes.
Don't you want your
daughter to have a village?
Come on. You know you love
her. Now you just need to tell her.
Who do you love, Julia? Hey.
Hey. Wait. You're
here? I love your hair.
How are you? Yeah,
I'm good. Thanks.
So what's going on with Julia?
Did he just leave because of me?
Oh, no. No, he's
just being Mark.
No, no, no. 'Cause you're
great. You know, weird.
All right, sir, are you smiling?
I'm wearing a mask.
I'm not sure it matters.
Oh, yeah. You can
see a smile in the eyes.
For the love of God,
take the damn picture.
Ten thousand! Incredible!
Nice work! All right. Okay.
All right, now get out.
Get on with your day.
Nice job, Dr. Webber.
Kepner, take a look.
It's... Sir, it says you're
needed in the lobby.
Can you tell 'em that I'm in the
middle of my 10,000th surgery?
Oh, are you sure we
shouldn't just send an intern...
Handle it, Kepner. Got it.
And that's great,
thanks. Thank you.
Cristina, what are
you still doing here?
I'm gonna watch a
surgery. Derek's tumor thing.
You need sleep. Yeah,
I'm watching neurosurgery.
It's a lot like sleeping.
You're not mad that I
gave the case to McQueen?
I didn't say that.
And Teddy, she...
Owen. I know.
I know. You don't
want to talk about it.
What do I do? How do
I get past this with her?
Her husband's dead.
She's taking it out on you.
You just gotta
deal with it. I know.
I know, but I just wish that...
You know what? Never mind.
I'm talking to you when I
should just try to talk to her.
Mmm-hmm.
Well, see you at the party?
Yeah. Okay.
Somebody paged Dr. Webber.
He's in the middle of a transplant.
Yes, over there.
Mrs. Webber?
Where is my husband?
Do you know where he is?
I found her on the street.
She was trying to walk here.
I live next door to the
Webbers. It's seven miles away.
Oh, God. Where is he?
I want you to go
find him right now!
Yeah, I will go
find your husband.
Would you just stand here,
just for one moment, please?
Could you just stay with her
until I can talk to Dr. Webber
and figure out what to do?
I can try. She's
pretty insistent.
Okay. Well, I have an office on
the third floor, if you could just...
What? Wait, wait. Mrs. Webber?
Oh, no! No, no, no!
Mrs. Webber, there you are.
I don't understand.
What's going on? Where
are Richard's things?
Yeah, I know this must
be very confusing...
This used to be Richard's
office, but now he's...
He's gone? He left me?
No! No, no, no. He's just...
He's in surgery right now.
It's his 10,000th surgery.
He always wanted
to leave me for her.
He finally did. No.
He never loved me. Never!
Oh, God. It was always her.
And now he's gone?
And he just left? He
didn't even tell me where...
He's just gone. No.
Okay, Mrs. Webber...
Richard. I need you
to please try and...
Just try and calm down...
I can't do it alone.
I can't. I can't do it alone.
Please, Richard, don't leave me.
Richard, I can't do it
alone. I can't. It's all right.
Transect the parenchyma.
Watch the aspirator,
Grey. Got it.
Nice. Nice technique.
Well, you've certainly
got your mother's hands.
Don't get too excited. I
haven't declared anything yet.
Well, what else are you
gonna do, neuro, cardio?
You want to waste
your talent playing with
one little predictable organ
for the rest of your life?
I'd rather spend my
days leaping from the liver
to the pancreas to the
stomach to the bowels,
and anyone could
go wrong at any time.
Okay, sure there's nothing
wrong with knowing one organ
and knowing it well,
just like there's nothing
wrong with being fifth-chair viola
in the back of the orchestra.
But it's a hell of a lot more
fun being the conductor.
Now...
This goes to the chief.
Are they ready? Yeah.
But I can give you a few
more minutes, though.
No, we're ready.
Wes, time to put
the computer away.
You are gonna be okay.
And the doctors are gonna
take really good care of you.
Mom, don't cry.
You know me, I cry when
you leave for a sleepover.
Well, don't.
Dr. Shepherd's the best.
You're right, as usual.
Give me a hug.
Oh, you're still here.
Listen, I know you
don't want to talk to me,
but this has gone on too long.
Now, I understand why. At least,
I want to.
We need to talk.
Can we just talk?
Now is not a good time.
Teddy. Don't!
It's wrapped around more of
the vessels than the scan showed.
What do you think, Dr. Grey?
We should start with the T4?
Yeah, I still think that's
the best approach.
There's no clear
prevertebral plane.
All right, well, take me
through it, step-by-step.
Okay, we get up
above T3, maybe T2,
we get control of
the aorta proximally,
and then dissect
the large vessels free.
We preserve the radicular
branches as we go,
especially Adamkiewicz...
He's paralyzed if we go
anywhere near the Adamkiewicz.
If we don't get this tumor,
this surgery is for nothing.
Right.
So, we go in for
lateral instead?
Are you asking me or telling me?
I'm telling.
I mean, we could
mobilize the great vessels,
and that way we get access
to the tumor on both sides.
Can I get some suction in here?
I have attached the hepatic veins.
Now I'm reconstructing the portal vein.
He left me. He left me. I
don't want to see him working.
No... He's always working.
No, no, he didn't leave
you. He's right there. See?
Oh, he's with that woman?
You tell that woman to go away.
That's my husband, not hers.
Richard!
Dr. Webber.
Richard, why are you
doing this to me, to us?
Adele? You lied.
You said that you weren't
working with her anymore.
Dr. Webber, I'm sorry. I
didn't know what to do.
Ellis! You let him go.
Dr. Webber, do you want me to...
No, no, keep the line open.
Adele...
That's not Ellis, Adele.
What kind of woman would
break up a marriage, huh?
Ellis Grey, what kind
of woman are you?
I'm sorry. Well, I
should just scrub out.
No, no, I need the extra hands.
I will not have you down
there with my husband.
Do you hear me?
I will not have it.
Richard, you just send her away.
Adele, I'm right here.
I'm not leaving you.
Tell her something
that'll ground her.
A happy memory. Richard!
A happy memory, it
worked for my mom.
Richard.
Richard, you need
to come out of there.
Richard.
It's our wedding day.
You were the most
beautiful bride I've ever seen.
Oh, Richard.
And for our first dance,
they played My Funny Valentine.
Because we were getting
married on Valentine's Day.
Happy Valentine's Day, baby.
I love you.
I love you, too.
Tell Bailey to cancel the party.
So, once the
vertebrectomies are complete,
we take the tumor down off
the dura, do a myelotomy...
And, again, hit the Adamkiewicz.
Paralyzed, dead in three months.
We resect it free
from the aorta...
Spinal shock. Dead.
Harvest a radicular branch that
doesn't have tumor involvement.
Dead, again.
Okay, stop saying that.
Dr. Grey.
No, we told him that we
would try. You're not even trying.
Because the
surgery will kill him.
We have no choice.
We have to close him up.
No.
Dr. Grey, I think it's time
you just... No, you're quitting.
Okay, it's, it's not right, not
when we said that we would try.
There's a 5% chance.
We owe him... There is
no longer a 5% chance.
Gelfoam, please.
No.
He knows about the tumor.
He has known all along.
I told him that we would try. I
told him that you were the best.
Now please, Derek, just...
Please.
Leave the OR right now.
All right, let's close him up.
No party? Cancelled.
Help yourself to cakes.
Karev, why aren't you
still in McQueen's surgery?
Oh, Altman and Yang took that.
What?
I could be wrong.
You have to tell him.
But I thought he already knew.
No, about the tumor.
Not that we didn't
do the surgery.
His mom's not gonna tell him.
And he's gonna wake up,
and she's gonna tell
him that it all went great,
and he's gonna go home
thinking that we did the surgery,
not that he's gonna
die in three months.
You need to tell him.
She's the parent.
It is not our call.
I'm sorry, no.
We can't tell him anything.
That looks more
like a heart. Right?
What are you doing?
McQueen wasn't qualified.
I think I was clear in the ER.
Yeah, I'm head of the
department. I made the call.
Put another pledgeted
suture right here.
Right here between these two?
Yeah, but closer to the atrium.
You should've informed
me. There wasn't time.
Dr. Yang stopped and
had a nice little chat with me
a couple of hours ago on
her way to what I believe
is this procedure. And
then I spoke to you...
Well, we didn't know that we
were doing the surgery then.
I think you're lying
to me. Both of you...
You know what? This is a
fairly complicated procedure.
Can we get into this later?
Shall we do an
intraoperative echo?
Yes. Why don't you pull it over?
Find me when you're
finished, Doctor.
Mmm-hmm.
Did you see that throbbing vein?
In his forehead?
I have the hardest time keeping
a straight face when it pops up.
The surgery wasn't as
hard as they first thought,
which is good.
'Cause that means we
can make it to Hawaii now.
You're done. No more
surgeries or doctors.
That's it. It's just us.
And we're gonna go on
another trip after that, too.
Maybe even Normandy, like
we said. Doesn't that sound fun?
You didn't do it.
What?
You said, after the surgery, I'd
be stuck in here for a few weeks.
That's right. I did.
You know, sometimes when
we get in there, things change.
That's why you get to go home.
Which is a good thing, honey.
It's all gonna be fine.
You're gonna be okay.
Mommy's gonna make sure of it.
And you don't have
to worry. I promise.
You're gonna be okay, too.
You don't have
to worry about me.
I'm gonna be with Dad in heaven.
How'd it go? Great.
You are the proud new
owner of a fully functioning liver.
Thank God.
Don't thank God. Thank me.
I'll never be able to
wear a two-piece again.
It's a horrible scar.
I have thanked you,
Marcy, about a million times.
Okay, enough. We're
not gonna do this again.
But it doesn't seem
to make a difference.
You just don't get it.
So I'm done.
Excuse me? I am
done thanking you.
You are not allowed to mention
your extraordinary generosity anymore,
except once a year
on Thanksgiving.
Okay, you're
gonna hurt yourself.
And on that night,
I will thank you.
But if you don't
follow my rules...
Oh, there are rules? Yes.
I will have to bring up
everything about you
that I have happily
chosen to not mention,
like how you've lost
thousands of dollars
in that lipstick-selling
Ponzi scheme.
That's none of your business.
And how sometimes,
when you're drunk and sad,
you sext your college boyfriend.
You wouldn't? Yes, I would.
Which is why you will not
mention my liver ever again.
My liver is dead to you!
Fine. Your liver's dead to me.
What about the money you owe me?
Enough! Enough!
Both of you, stop talking.
She is... No, I mean it.
You are in a time
out, especially you.
No more talking.
You can't talk to me like this.
This is...
He's still in serious condition,
so I'll be staying the
night to monitor him.
Actually, I'll stay
with him tonight.
Really?
The head of the department?
I'm happy to do it.
Oh. Thank you.
I can stay with you.
Your Zola's godmother. You
have to go to her birthday party.
Besides, I'm just gonna stay
here and eat widow casserole,
feel sorry for myself.
Go. Out!
Okay.
Happy birthday!
Hey, girl.
Look who didn't
just wake up, huh?
Look at you.
You look so beautiful.
Look at that bow.
Got you.
You made it.
Of course.
Adele insisted I didn't
miss little Miss Zola's party.
So she's feeling
better then? Much.
The night nurse is with her. She
was already asleep when I left.
And this is for
the guest of honor.
How are you doing,
little Miss Zola?
You look very pretty
for your birthday.
Yes, you do.
I need 800 bucks.
Told you, if you're dumb enough
to buy groceries,
I'm gonna eat 'em.
No, not for groceries.
For a security deposit.
We'll lose out on a
really great three-bedroom
if we don't get it to
the landlord today.
Now you want to
live with me? No!
You're gross, and a
pig, and a skank magnet,
and you leave your dirty
boy socks everywhere.
Keep going this way, and
you'll wind up old and alone,
wandering the streets with
some ancient form of syphilis.
All right, I think what
she's trying to say is, yes.
She would be happy if
you'd be our roommate.
Cool.
So...
We couldn't afford the nice
apartment just the two of us, right?
Hardwood floors
and a washer/dryer.
What can I say? I
want what I want.
She'll forgive us, right? Well,
she won't remember anything.
A picture, right?
Yeah, picture. Yes.
Here we go. Here we
go. Yeah. Happy birthday!
Happy birthday.
Perfect! Da-da.
Happy 10,000th, Dr. Webber.
For me? No.
Come on. It's not every day you
get to celebrate 10,000 surgeries.
Thanks.
Hey, the dress you guys
got Zola? She loved it.
Sofia loved it, too.
Didn't you love it, Mark?
It was adorable.
What can I say?
I have great taste.
I'm gonna get a refill. Anyone?
Oh, I would love a glass of red.
Enough of that. Oh, Mark.
You two are the
ones that love her.
It's like you want to take
her behind a mini-mart,
knock her up, and
have all her babies.
Oh, my God. You guys would
have such beautiful babies.
Well, then Sofia
would have a sibling.
Except I'm not there yet.
She's great, and I'm
happy you all get along,
but I'm not rushing this.
I rushed it with Addison.
I tried to force Lexie to be a
grandmother, for God sakes.
I'm not doing that again.
Wow. That is so adult.
You know what Aunty
Cristina did today?
I operated on a heart.
This... Actually, no.
This big. This big.
It was as big as a bear.
They're not called lost
causes because they're fun.
I don't need them to be fun.
I just need them
to not be like today.
Mmm.
Okay. Let's flip.
Heads, you keep
doing lost causes.
Tails, you do the fun stuff.
I'm in. Of course I'm in.
Good. Come on.
Let's go join the party.
Okay.
I know you're
mad, and I'm sorry.
Sorry that you did it, or
you're sorry that I'm mad?
Teddy never came to
find me after surgery.
Yeah, well, she's tired. I bet.
I'm taking you off her
service permanently.
I'm not sure what she's gonna do
without you as her
security blanket...
Absolutely not. Well,
this is the downside... Did
you hear what I just said?
Absolutely not.
I think "thank you" is what you
were looking for, because frankly,
I could've fired you both.
You have no idea what's
going on here, do you?
I have a very good idea.
You let me operate on her
husband, and now he's dead.
She gets whatever she
wants. Do you understand?
Anything she
wants from me, ever.
I heard the good news.
Bailey says you're
declaring general.
Actually, I'm not sure anymore.
Oh, okay.
Thought it was a done deal.
I mean, it makes
sense since you're...
Because of my mother, I know.
Don't you mention her, too.
That's all anyone ever says.
"It's in my blood,
it's my legacy."
That's why I
don't want to do it.
I don't want to
be like my mother.
Meredith, look at
everything you did today,
this party for your daughter,
what you did for me in that OR.
You don't have to ever worry about
being anything like your mother.
I knew her,
and you're nothing
like your mother.
You have a gift.
Don't waste it.
It was an impossible
situation. Yes.
And it was your call.
You put Henry on my table.
And then you had me lie
to Teddy, just like you did.
Those were your decisions.
Now, you want to be chief?
These are the consequences.
Don't talk to me
about consequences.
You can't even accept a simple
punishment for what you did today.
You don't get to punish me.
It's not my fault Teddy hates you.
But don't take your
guilt out on me. Guilt?
I have nothing to be guilty
about. This is all about you.
It's always been about
you. It's what you want.
That's always
been your position.
We live like you want,
and how you want.
You get whatever
you want, all the time!
When do you throw in the towel,
admit that a lost cause
is sometimes just that?
Hey, do you remember
your first surgery?
Well, sure. I was a
third-year resident.
Third-years could take
the lead on surgeries.
A gallbladder.
Constantly! You do what
works for you. You don't care...
There comes a point when
it all becomes too much.
Or who gets hurt!
It was one surgery.
Okay? It was one surgery.
It was not one surgery!
Do you hear me?
This was every choice
we've made in the last...
It was a life that I
envisioned for myself, okay?
This is not one surgery.
When we get too
tired to fight anymore.
So we give up.
It all comes back to this?
Yeah.
Crazy, right? That I would
ever bring it up again.
Yes, okay? Yes. Yes!
Okay? It was a horrible
situation, but it's over.
Is it too much to ask that
we just try and forget it?
You killed our baby!
You don't ever forget that!
That's when the
real work begins.
To find hope where there
seems to be absolutely none at all.