You work, you
study, you prepare...
Months and years
leading to one day...
The day when you step up.
Okay, let's get started.
Yeah, let's do it.
Got a lot of standing
around to do today.
He's right, people.
Starting today, fifth-year
residents rotate in as lead surgeons.
We've alerted the morgue.
On that day, you have
to be ready for anything.
Attendings, you will
observe and stay silent.
Offer help only when
you absolutely have to.
Yeah, before you help them
swim, let 'em sink a little.
But there's one thing you
can never quite prepare for...
The next order of business,
effective 9:00 a.m., this morning,
I have resigned
as Chief of Surgery
of Seattle Grace-Mercy
West Hospital.
I will stay on
the surgical staff.
I will turn this meeting over
to the new Chief of Surgery,
Dr. Owen Hunt.
The day when you step down.
Thanks, Dr. Webber.
I know this comes
as a surprise
to all of you, too.
And I appreciate, over
the next couple of days,
your help and your patience.
So, now I have your call
schedules, but I can have them...
Wait. What happened?
Why did it happen?
Is this the board? Are they
forcing you to step down?
Hmm?
Hunt. You're the
new Chief of Surgery.
Nice.
Hey. What's going on?
Anything new on Zola?
Oh, no. We were
supposed to hear yesterday,
and then yesterday, they
said today, so is it up yet?
Don't know. You okay?
I have no choice. I'm clipping
my first aneurysm today.
Well, I've got a
valve replacement.
My valve replacement. Altman
just has to shut up and watch.
I hope I get a good OR.
Is it up yet? Not yet.
Hey, you heard about Zola?
I haven't heard anything.
And she's clipping
her first aneurysm.
Are you sure you don't want
to start with something simpler?
Yeah, like juggling chain saws?
Thanks. That's helping.
Hey, is it up yet? Is it up yet?
It's going up now.
Hey, you heard anything?
Haven't heard anything.
How are you even here?
Well, there's nothing I can
do, and I have to do something,
so I might as well do this.
It's up. It's up.
OR 3. Yes!
I love OR 3.
Bowel resection? I thought
you had a Peds case.
I switched last minute.
You can't just switch.
Plastics. I thought
you were the Gunther.
Wasting all your
capital on boob jobs?
It's a cleft lip. I'm
changing a kid's life today.
Look at Kepner, she's
fixing a bum knee.
Way to shoot for the stars, kid.
Okay, guys. You also start
teaching skills labs today.
I made up a schedule
for the month.
It's up on the
board in my office.
In your what?
When did we get this?
We didn't. It's for the
chief resident, actually.
This is good. I
can sleep on this.
Yeah, I got that on
Craigslist. It's mine.
We got a fridge?
Okay, guys. Why
is my name on this?
These are this month's
intern skills labs.
Each of you has been
given one skills lab to teach.
No, I can't teach today.
I'm on a mitral valve.
Okay, well, then just switch
with one of these guys.
Aneurysm. I got a baby's face.
Guys, come on. I
divided these up fairly.
You come on. Every
surgery we do this year
could end up on the oral boards.
And they love picking
the crappy outcomes.
This could affect
which fellowship I get.
I mean, it's not just
life or death, April.
Now it's our careers.
Okay, how's this? Whoever
has the worst outcome today
teaches all the skills
labs for the whole month.
That's good. I'm in.
That's terrible.
You guys get this e-mail?
You know, that's disgusting.
No, no, no. There
will be no wagering
on patient outcomes.
That's an order.
So you're out, then?
You know, okay, just...
Everyone out of my office.
Whoa! Webber resigned.
He's no longer Chief of Surgery.
Dr. Owen Hunt is
now Chief of Surgery.
What?
That the Alzheimer's
trial? Heard from the FDA?
I'm sending it to Phoenix.
Carl Baumann is taking
over. I'm blacklisted.
I may never do another
clinical trial ever again.
Yeah, I've been
blacklisted, too.
And now you're
gonna let them fire you?
I fired myself.
It's one thing, taking
the blame for Meredith
and losing the trial, but
why are you doing
this to yourself?
You know, I came
to ask if you heard
anything about your little girl.
No, I have not.
This isn't right.
Hope you hear soon.
How does he not tell
me he's Chief of Surgery?
Well, is it because you...
Didn't have his baby?
I mean, has he said anything?
No. We haven't talked about it.
At all? Is that bad?
That's bad, right?
Well, I mean, it's just...
Oh, hey. Oh, hey.
Is it true?
Uh, yeah.
Oh, my God. When did...
Well, Webber talked
to me last night, but...
I was gonna tell you, but
you were already asleep,
and then this morning,
you had already gone...
Yeah. My mitral valve.
Right. Right. Right, sorry.
Sorry. Good luck.
No! No. Oh, God,
you... You, you're the...
Uh, this is great.
We should celebrate.
I guess so, yeah. Um... Dinner?
My surgery.
Mitral valve takes, like, a
minimum of seven hours.
Sometime. Okay?
I gotta... Congratulations.
Thanks. Yeah.
Congratulations.
Yeah, that was bad.
Hey. I need an intern to
assist on my bowel resection.
Well, everyone's booked,
so good luck finding someone.
Isn't that your job?
No, my job is making the
schedule that you screwed up.
Ah, Karev.
I just saw that you turned down
my three-month-old's esophageal
atresia surgery for Webber's...
I'm so sorry.
I was trying to say
Webber's bowel resection,
but then I fell asleep.
I just thought I could use more
practice with bowel resections.
No, you're trying to pad your
boards with good outcomes,
so you went for the
easy A. You keep that up,
and you're gonna lowball
yourself out of the fellowship.
Is that what you're doing?
Or is this about
winning that stupid bet?
Just find me an intern.
Karev, you ready
for your surgery?
Uh, I think so, sir.
Kepner's having a little
trouble getting it staffed.
What's the problem? I've been
treating Sam Kenton for years.
I don't want to have
to postpone him.
No, sir. No, sir. I will
find someone to assist.
I'll get it covered, even
if I have to do it myself.
Well, great.
Great.
So if Rob's out of surgery,
then I'll pick him up from school,
but if not, then I'll text you,
and you can drop him at Kathy's.
Yeah, thanks so much. Okay, bye.
Sorry, I just...
Have to make sure we
got the kids squared away.
I totally understand.
You have kids?
Let's get back to your surgery.
So I will locate the aneurysm,
which is the bulge in
the wall of your artery.
And then I will
take a steel clip,
which is like a tiny clothespin,
and I'm gonna place it across
the neck of the aneurysm.
And that will stop
the blood supply.
That way, we don't have
to worry about a rupture.
How do you know if you fixed it?
Well, we do what we
call a matador move.
I'll take a needle, and I poke
the dome of the aneurysm.
And if we see a
tiny amount of blood,
then we know it was successful.
And if it wasn't
successful, it bursts.
Possibly.
And I die.
Not if I get it clipped.
And what's your success
rate? How many have you done?
This will be my first.
I sort of wish you
lied about that.
Yeah, well, after today, her
success rate will be 100%.
Dr. Grey is the best we have,
and I'll be there the whole time.
Do you have any other questions?
No. No, thanks.
Try and rest easy.
I'll see you after.
Yeah. Okay. Thank you.
Thank you for that.
Yeah.
Have you heard anything
from the social worker?
No. Have you?
No.
I'm worried. If we haven't
heard back by now,
that it's not gonna go our
way. Well, I'll call again.
No, don't. We've
called too much.
Derek.
Yes.
What if we don't get Zola back?
I mean, what happens to us?
What do you want to do?
Do you want to stay together?
We have a surgery.
Let's just focus on that.
You.
Ruth Bennet, 50,
mitral valve replacement,
patient complained
overnight of stomach pains.
These stomach
pains, what did you do?
You.
We tested her cardiac
enzymes, ran an echo.
Both were normal.
Did anyone touch her stomach?
No one touched the patient?
Are you guys the slow class?
Palpating the patient's abdomen
is first, before tests or labs.
Basics, people. Fundamentals.
I'm all about not
skipping steps.
Ow!
Oh, sorry.
Does it hurt more or less
when I take my hand away?
More.
See? Basics. You should
be doing this in your sleep.
Take Mrs. Bennet
for a triple-contrast CT.
Try not to get lost.
He just seems so little.
I thought it could wait.
I understand, but I assure
you that now is the right time.
By fixing those muscles early,
his maxilla, his
whole upper jaw,
will have a real shot
at forming properly.
But he'll have a scar?
Well, I'm gonna do what's
called a straight-line repair.
So that'll leave a little scar,
which I'll hide right in the
contour of his lip right here.
And then over time,
it'll fade altogether.
Shouldn't even be noticeable.
Then he'll look
even more handsome
than he does right
now, if that's possible.
He is a pretty
handsome guy, isn't he?
He certainly is. Yes, you are.
You want to wait here with your
mama while I go get you all set up?
Yeah?
I'll come back this
afternoon, all right, buddy?
Thank you, Dr. Avery.
My pleasure. He'll do great.
Excellent.
You couldn't have been clearer,
you answered her questions.
You eased her fears.
Thanks. That's...
Mark Sloan's gonna
do the surgery, though.
How's that? It's not you.
You're great.
You're the Gunther.
But you're planning
a straight-line repair,
and I'd rather the kid
get a Millard rotation
so that we don't risk the
lip shortening over time.
But I was actually...
For the kid's sake,
I gotta have Sloan
do it. He's an artist.
Dr. Robbins,
it's my procedure.
I'm sorry, Avery.
Just not this time.
This is Sam Kenton, 55.
He's here for a bowel resection
due to chronic
mesenteric ischemia.
This is Sam's third
surgery with us.
Third time's the charm.
And this is Sam's son, Jason.
Jason should be in school
instead of here, playing nursemaid.
It's one semester. Think how
much money I'm saving you.
Well, I'm worried, you're
not getting any smarter.
Kid's not very smart.
Wonder where I get that from.
Did he just call me stupid?
I think he did.
Sam's been Dr. Webber's
patient since...
Kepner, just give
me the bullet, okay?
Sam Kenton, 55, presents with
chronic mesenteric ischemia.
Nonresponsive to
revascularization.
Scheduled for an
exploratory laparotomy
and possible bowel resection.
Oh, it's so sad. I mean, how
many years was he chief for?
Eleven.
I mean, are we
supposed to all pretend
we don't know what
really happened?
Oh, why did he cover for her?
I mean, what's
his deal with her?
Hey. Hi.
Good morning, ladies.
Uh, uh, so what's
the system here?
Does everybody have a spot or...
Anywhere is fine.
Oh. All right, then.
Right... Here.
And I will see
you this afternoon.
You all have an excellent day.
You, too. Already am.
I mean, he's trying so hard.
He talked to his sandwich.
Well, what are...
Doctor... Sorry. Chief.
Larry Jennings sent
you this bottle of scotch
to say congratulations.
Thanks. Just put it somewhere.
Okay. And, Dr. Torres,
I need to push
my meniscus repair to tomorrow.
I have to teach a skills lab.
A skills lab over a surgery?
Yeah, and then I have to assist
Karev on a bowel resection.
You should be
delegating that stuff.
I tried, but no
one would cover it.
Don't try, Kepner.
Just order them.
Leadership isn't
about making friends.
Well, then I'm doing it right.
That was nice.
Very chief-y. Mmm.
Dr. Hunt.
May I have my call
schedule, please?
Sorry? My call schedule,
which I usually get at the
staff meeting, but I didn't,
because you said you
would distribute them,
but you haven't, so I
had to come find you,
and you're not very easy to
find, not unlike my call schedule.
So may I have my
call schedule, please?
Of course. Just as soon as...
Thank you.
That was way less chief-y there.
Okay. What did I do?
Nothing. Nothing. She was
Webber's right-hand man.
She'd hate anyone
in your position.
Yeah, I know it's not
about making friends,
but you really want
Bailey as your enemy?
I was right. Ruth Bennet's
scans show appendicitis.
The morons missed
it. I'm turfing her to
general surgery for
an appendectomy.
Why don't you do the appy?
Where do I start?
Because it's general
surgery, and I'm on cardio.
Because it's first-year
surgery, and I'm a fifth year.
Because... You know
what? This is great.
I mean, Ruth has
a heart condition,
and we have to
monitor her anyway.
And because of her COPD,
she has to have an open appy,
and we don't want
some moron doing it.
And you get a procedure.
It's a very basic procedure.
But you love the basics. And
you're all about the fundamentals.
Can I ask you something,
just about his recovery,
specifically the,
like, bathroom part?
Will I need to be
in there with him?
'Cause my mom was here
for his other surgeries, and...
Right.
I'll do it. I'll totally do
whatever he needs.
I just want to be prepared,
you know, 'cause...
He'll be embarrassed and I'll...
Well, neither of
us is gonna like it.
Yeah, there are a couple
of possible outcomes.
And it all just sort of depends
on what Dr. Karev
finds during surgery.
So I'll have him come and
talk you through them, okay?
Is that guy cool? He
seems a little... Douchey.
He's good, very good.
He can be a little douchey...
But he's a good guy,
and a very good surgeon.
Thanks.
Meredith, uh...
Oh, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. I never
meant for any of this to...
I know what you
wanted to do for me.
But... I do.
I saw you were clipping
your first aneurysm,
wanted to say good luck.
I am trying to figure
out what clip to use.
Well, you can't,
not until you see it.
Yeah.
Every aneurysm is
different, a different approach.
You'll know what to do
once you get in there.
It's a big deal.
A resident's first
aneurysm clip.
Derek leads the whole
OR in a round of applause.
I...
Don't know that he'll
do that today, but...
You two all right?
I, uh, only ask
because if you can't
communicate with your attending,
you have no business
being in that OR,
no matter how prepared you are.
We're okay. We're fine.
All right.
I need your pig.
I have to remember how to
do an open appendectomy.
No. Does a pig even
have an appendix?
Let's find out. Who
wants an aneurysm?
I'm about to have one.
I have to do an appy.
On a pig? Does a
pig even have one?
On a person. I haven't
thought about one in...
Three years. Well, come on.
Who wants to
trade? I'll do anything.
Clipping those things
is like defusing a bomb.
One wrong move, and it explodes.
Well, I'm worried
about Derek exploding.
Can I have your pig? ALEX: No.
How about just the head, huh?
Want to clip an aneurysm?
Good luck, MacGyver.
There you are. Alex...
Does a pig have an appendix?
I don't know.
I thought you were
teaching my skills lab.
I am. I just left them to
practice whipstitches. Alex...
Stop. Turn out the
lights. Close the door.
Check this out.
Injected fluorescein dye,
it makes any viable
part of the bowel glow.
Nice. Yeah, in high school,
I had a Metallica
poster just like this.
You might win the bet.
Yeah, with a color-coded colon.
No kidding.
I have a bomb to defuse.
This is crazy. I gotta
find a book or a skills...
Oh, skills lab.
I gotta get some instruments. I'm
just gonna use the head, all right?
Will you talk to Jason Kenton?
He has some questions...
I'm busy. Turning a
pig into a lava lamp?
My patient... It's not
my job. You talk to him.
Show of hands, who knows the
steps of an open appendectomy?
Dr. Bailey, your call
schedule. Sorry it was so...
Uh-huh.
So, Bailey, I know
you've taken over
Dr. Webber's islet cell trial.
And I wanted to offer you some
protected time for your research.
I can reduce your OR schedule,
lighten your teaching load,
make sure you get
that time that you need.
How does that sound?
You telling me I don't
manage my time well?
No. No. No, no, no.
I just wanted to make sure
that your research got the time...
Oh, you're telling me
how to use my time?
Not at all. I wouldn't. I'm
sorry. Just forget I mentioned it.
Now I don't get the time?
No, you do. You do. You
can... You can, just do what...
No, leave it up. Leave it up. I'll
just do the meniscus repair myself.
Great. And now I
lose a procedure.
This is worse than
being an intern.
Yeah, being chief
resident sucks. I did it once.
Well, how'd you do it? How'd
you get them to listen to you?
I didn't. I sucked.
Oh.
Look, it's...
It's not about making friends,
but it is about getting
them on your side.
You want to be the person they
come to, not the one they run from.
You know, kinda
like your little contest.
You know, getting them to
compete for good outcomes.
I know. It's awful, right?
No, that was a good idea.
They thrive on competition.
You gave them what they needed.
And either way,
the patient wins.
That was a good idea.
Okay.
That wasn't your idea, was it?
No.
Well... Don't give
up. You'll be great.
Or maybe you won't. I never was.
It's perfect.
It's a perfect Millard rotation.
On a pig.
This pig is now more
attractive than your average pig.
I deserve to do it.
I'm ready. I can
do it. I deserve it.
You're right.
You go, Gunther.
Next step? You.
Lift up peritoneum, open
transversely, and enlarge the incision.
Enlarge how?
With scissors? Are you
asking me or telling me?
With scissors.
Okay. Okay, good.
Then what? You.
Pull out and isolate the
appendix. Mmm-hmm.
Cross-clamp it
at the base, and...
And go on.
I can't remember.
Unacceptable. God.
You should know this.
Cross-clamp the
appendix at the base...
Yeah, you already did that.
Okay? Hurry up. He's dying now.
Tie off or... Wait. Ligate...
Hurry. You're losing him. Beep.
Beep. Beep. Wait. Hang on.
Beep. Wait.
Wait. Beep.
Call the morgue,
moron. He's dead.
Okay, who's next?
You.
Open transversely,
enlarge with scissors,
insert retractors,
deliver appendix,
cross-clamp at the base.
Hey, so... You going
in for your mitral valve?
My mitral valve
turned into an appy.
Oh, right. Well, good luck.
So, does that mean
you'll be home tonight?
I mean, an appy's what,
two hours, tops, right?
Right. That is true.
Oh, do you want me
to pick something up?
Or I can. Chinese?
Oh, fine. Whatever.
No, no, you choose.
Do Chinese. Chinese is great.
Good. Right. Well, good luck.
And you, too, Grey.
You have to talk
about it because clearly,
you can't talk about anything.
You two are like bad roommates.
How? How do I bring it up?
I mean, does he even
want me to bring it up?
And what is there to talk
about? 'Cause it's done.
I can't undo it. It's done.
Yeah, but it's not.
We have surgery.
Don't screw it up. You, too.
Did you know Sam's
wife took care of him
after his last two surgeries?
She died of a stroke last year,
so Jason dropped out of college
one semester before graduating.
He was happy to do it
'cause... What the hell, Kepner?
Why are you telling me this?
Talking to patients
is your job, Alex,
because they're
more than just...
An easy A or some
bet you can win.
It's your job.
No, it's not. Not anymore.
My job is to open
him up and fix him,
and if I can't do it, no
one's gonna do it for me.
It's on me. So I can
spend time talking to him
or I can use that time
figuring out what I'm gonna do
when I open him up. Which
one do you want me to do?
You're really nervous.
That's why you didn't
want to work on a kid today.
Look, you'll be fine.
You're ready.
I mean, you feel ready, right?
I am thoroughly
enjoying this book, Karev.
That's great.
Hopefully, I'll
finish it in there,
because as long as I'm reading,
it means that you're
not screwing up.
Will I finish this book today?
Yes, sir. All right.
Have you got the pre-op scans?
I already looked them
over. I want to look again.
I think you should
do the surgery.
Why?
Because we're not
a team right now.
What happens if the
aneurysm ruptures?
Put a temporary clip
on the feeding artery.
And if the aneurysm
still bleeds?
I gain control of the
common carotid in the neck.
What kind of clip are
you gonna go with?
I won't know
till I get in there.
You're ready. Let's go.
What are you doing?
You're the lead surgeon.
You're on that side.
Yeah.
You practiced it the
other way, didn't you?
Is there a problem?
No, sir. 10-Blade.
What are you doing now?
Are we still doing the thing
where I have to tell
you every little move...
Never gets old.
What are you doing now?
Blunt separation of
the oblique muscles.
Neat.
You know, you have a kid
and you worry a lot
about screwing 'em up.
Like something
that you do or say
or something you don't
say will change 'em forever.
Yes, ma'am.
I was just thinking that
you're totally determining
the course of this kid's life.
You will determine
whether or not
this kid gets made
fun of for his looks,
or if he cries at his
school picture every year.
And today, you will decide
who he goes to the prom with,
and who he will marry or I
mean, if he gets married at all,
or if he dies alone,
unattractive and unloved.
Did you want me to call Sloan?
Okay, I've isolated
the aneurysm.
I can see the whole neck.
What is that?
It's an angled seven millimeter.
I'd go smaller,
use a straight one.
No. No?
You only get one shot
at this. Use a smaller clip.
I may need the extra length.
You could hit one
of the perforators.
Not if I look where I'm going.
Put the clip down.
What are you doing now?
I am isolating the appendix.
And now?
I am cross-clamping
the appendix at the base.
And what are you doing now?
Okay, you can get
as pissed as you want,
but there is a reason that
I'm having you do all this.
I want to... Shh.
I beg your
pardon? I don't... I...
I can't remember
what comes next.
Anastomosis is holding.
Nice work.
Okay. We gotta run the bowel.
Make sure there isn't any...
Okay, crap. Okay...
Cautery.
Lift up peritoneum,
open transversely...
All right, this is what
I am talking about.
Why would I have you
replace... Deliver the appendix...
A mitral valve when you
can't even remember a...
I can if you just
please shut up.
I can't tell if any
of this is viable.
Well, what about here? I
mean, this... No, it's crap.
Is the fluorescein in?
Have we started the dye?
Starting now.
It's in.
Lights. Now. Kill the lights.
Use the five millimeter.
I'm looking right at it,
Derek. You have to trust me.
No, I've done it hundreds
of times. Use a smaller clip.
Damn it.
Okay, I'm gonna do
the matador move.
Can I have the needle
and the Penfield retractor?
I've got the suction.
Okay, everybody, stop.
Okay. It's holding.
Holding perfectly.
Okay, suction, please.
Come on. Come on.
Give me something.
Alex, there's not enough.
Shut up.
Lights.
I can't remember the next step.
Well, you might
remember this the next time
you're screaming at an intern
for skipping the fundamentals.
Will you just do it, please?
Take your time. It'll come back.
No, it won't. Honestly. I
can stand here all day.
It's not gonna...
Oh, my God. You
don't know, either.
Don't try to make this about me.
Okay, then tell me what to do.
You should know what
to do. So should you.
Well, it's been even
longer since I've done one.
Well, I need your help.
We need to be
helping her right now.
You probably want to
ligate at the proximal edge,
apply a straight
clamp, and lay down
a purse-string
suture at the base.
Right. Of course. Thank you.
I got it. I got it.
No shame.
No shame at all.
You're still the goober.
It's Gunther. Sure.
Uh, I can't...
If I close him, I'm leaving
him to die. He'll die of sepsis.
Can I revascularize?
I can find the clot,
I can do a transverse arteriotomy
and bypass the vessels.
No. There's way too
much dead bowel.
Do I pull it? I
mean... Do I pull it all?
Put him on a transplant list?
Hope for...
What do I do?
Do I close him and let him go?
Let's close.
Thank you. Thank you so much.
That's fine.
Can we make a deal?
Let us never speak of this.
Deal.
Night.
Do you want me to talk to him?
No.
You did everything you could.
You really did.
He won't be able to
understand that, but I do.
And you should, too.
I don't want to go home.
I don't, either.
Do we really have
to talk about it?
Yes, you do.
Maybe I'll come over later.
Oh, that would be great.
No, actually, that would be bad,
because that would
mean my marriage is over.
Here you go.
Did you finish your shift?
All right. So who lost the bet?
Not me. My bomb
was defused perfectly.
My appy was flawless.
Except it was
finished by a nurse.
Who told you that?
Karev's guy didn't even
wake up. Septic shock.
You blew a bowel resection?
That's like misspelling your own name.
Hey, guys. No, it's Karev.
Sorry, dude.
Enjoy that skills lab.
Can I just point out that Jackson
never even touched his patient?
Sloan did the whole procedure.
What does "between
you and me" mean?
So it would seem to me
that he loses by forfeit.
Loser. Forfeit.
I don't think that that's...
You want a rematch?
We could go again tomorrow.
And the next day.
Nurses' station.
Dr. Bailey. Hold up, please.
I learned in the army
that a leader is only as good
as the people around him.
Now, you are one of the
best people on this team.
And...
I just want to make sure
that I have you on my side.
Have I done something wrong?
No.
Is there something
in my job performance
that prompts you to ask me this?
No.
Or do you just
need me to like you?
It's not that. Are you sure?
Carry on, Dr. Bailey.
If you want to be mad at
someone, be mad at me.
I'm not mad at
you. Yes, you are.
Everyone knows who to be mad at.
The only thing
Meredith did to me
was to give my wife
a little more time,
and I'm damn sure
gonna spend it with her.
I'm happy, Bailey. I'd like
you to be happy for me, too.
I'll try.
You're gonna have
to give me a while.
I'll wait.
Well...
That was good.
You know, I'll get the
dishes. No, no, no, I'll do it.
No, no, I've got them.
You know, I've been feeling...
Terrible.
Okay.
No, I mean it.
I know.
Do you want to talk about it?
Did you have the spring rolls?
We should never have been
in that OR together today.
What do you mean?
We're not a team, anywhere.
And when we get Zola back,
before we get that phone call,
we need to figure
out if we can be one,
if we can even be together. So
now's the time to say how you feel.
I can't. I'm gonna
say things that are...
Oh, Derek, just say it.
Whatever it is,
we can deal with it.
I can accept the consequences.
Meredith, you have never
accepted a consequence in your life.
Since the moment
you switched those files,
you haven't suffered one bit.
That is not true.
While those around
you have lost their jobs
and lost their reputations.
And I lost Zola.
So did I!
Because you do things...
Without a thought, you just
dive in and never give a damn
how deep the water is or
who you're gonna land on.
I know I messed up,
but all of this happened
before Zola was
even in the picture.
Don't you think I've changed?
I don't think you can change.
You stole the baby, Meredith.
Oh. I told you why I did that.
What do you need,
for me to say I'm sorry?
I need you to be sorry.
Of course I'm sorry.
You did it again
today in the OR.
What? I had a
successful surgery today.
You refused to listen to me!
I didn't listen to you because
I didn't need to listen to you.
I knew what I was
doing and I was right.
You just couldn't trust me.
Why should I ever trust you?
Why should I trust you?
You ended my trial,
you set back my career,
you nearly ended your
own, you destroyed Richard's.
I have no reason to trust you.
Well, then why are you with me?
Because of that.
Because I meant that!
I promised I wouldn't run.
I promised I would love you.
Even when you hate me.
Even when I hate you.
I am trying, Meredith.
I am trying, but you
make it so damn hard.
I understand.
And I don't want you
to keep the promise,
not if you don't want to,
and not if you can't trust
me with our daughter.
I do. I trust you with Zola.
Well, you just said...
That's not what I said.
I know that you took
her to protect her.
I know that you altered the
trial for Adele and for Richard.
You stood in front
of a bullet for me.
I know why you do all of it.
It's what I love about you.
And what you hate about me.
Yeah.
So you can't trust me at work?
No, I can't.
Well, that's easy, then.
So we just don't work together.
So what are you saying?
I'm off your service.
That's my consequence.
If we want to stay together,
with or without Zola,
we just can't work together.
Sometimes it
happens in an instant.
We step up.
We become a leader.
We see a path forward.
Never again.
I told you not to order from that
place. Their floors are disgusting.
Yeah, but then you always
say you like their spring rolls.
Don't say...
Don't say it.
Oh! Oh.
Thank you.
I'm not gonna kiss you.
Let's go to bed.
Oh, no, no, no, I
want to stay here.
Come on. Let's go to bed.
Oh, no. It feels good
here. It feels good here.
Okay. Come here.
There you go.
Oh!
We see a path, and we take it...
Even when we have no
idea where we're going.