There's no milk.
Oh.
Damn, I forgot.
All I ask is for you to get the groceries.
And I forgot. I'm sorry.
You know, I-I-it's not
like I'm sitting around.
I'm-I'm looking for a job.
Well, now we're gonna
have to stop for coffee
before you drop me off at work.
Even good marriages fail.
One minute you're standing on solid ground.
The next minute... you're not.
Baby's up.
You change the diaper. I'll get the bottle.
And there's always two versions...
Yours...
and theirs.
So they're living together
at your house,
Kepner says.
This is my house.
Did she say how they're doing?
No. I didn't ask.
I don't care.
You...
You want me to ask, for you?
No. I don't care, either.
Hand me a rock.
Okay. I'm... I can't-I can't-I can't.
Um, I can't have sex when there's a baby
from a broken home in the next room.
I...
Both versions start the same way, though.
Both start with two people falling in love.
Yeah, you can.
Just look at me.
It's just you and me.
Dude... you snore like a truck.
I'm gonna put a note in your chart,
'cause you mix apnea with your heart crap,
and you're dead before you're 60.
Excuse me.
- Hey.
You guys going to that breakfast thing?
Uh, yeah, after we drop her off at day care.
Oh, my god. Look at her. She's so beautiful.
Oh, oh. Hey.
- Hey, you are so beautiful...
- Here you go.
And you've got the best mommies.
Did you know that? Yes, you do.
Oh, you do.
Oh, you so do.
Hello. Hello. Hello. Hello.
What is wrong with her?
Mm, she's getting laid.
She's unnaturally cheerful.
Oh. Yes, you do. Peekaboo.
A month ago you were in med school
being taught by doctors.
And now you are the doctors.
Will we be going into an O.R. today?
Oh, I hope so.
Oh.
Oh. New interns.
I hate new interns.
Seriously? Ugh. Mm-hmm.
I love new interns.
They're the future,
the next generation...
filled with hope and promise, innovation.
Wow.
The sex with Henry must be really good.
Earth-shattering.
- Shh. Sex.
- Not even Yang's gonna get me down.
No, she's not.
Good morning
And welcome to your fifth year of residency.
- Oh, morning.
- Morning.
See you guys up there.
I hear there's an omelet station.
- Thank you.
- Okay
you have a good day.
Okay, now. Bye-bye.
Okay, um, I'll see you later...
- Okay.
- At the thing.
She slept through the night...
- Hey, Zola.
- And ate like a champ.
I missed you.
Can we talk?
I want to spend time with Zola
before I drop her off at day care.
Are you gonna call Glen today?
I don't know.
I, you know, the g... the guy is an ass.
Do I really want to work for him?
Maybe you should stop being so choosy.
Well, I just got laid off
four months ago. All right?
I mean, these things take time.
It's all about pursuing leads
and making connections.
I know how a person gets a job, Danny.
I have one, remember?
Good morning, and, uh,
welcome to your final year of residency.
Um...
This-this breakfast is the one time
when all the fifth years and the attendings
will be in the same room,
so... so use your time wisely, residents...
Find a mentor...
Ask questions, get advice on your futures.
And, um, I see you're already chatting away,
so that's... that's good.
Just carry on.
Dr. Bailey, how did you do it?
I put down the english muffin first,
- then the bacon, then the eggs.
- Oh, no...
Now some people may be
surprised by this method,
thinking you put
the bacon on top of the eggs,
and those people
would be right, because...
You see what I'm doing?
Bam!
An extra layer of bacon
right on top.
Then you put on the other
half of the muffin.
And there you go.
That's a breakfast sandwich.
Uh, no, no, I, uh, I mean,
how did you get people to listen to you
as chief resident?
Dr. Kepner, I am eating.
Leave me alone with my food.
Figure it out on your own.
Oh, w...
Did he talk to you?
No, he won't even look at me.
Well... you tampered
with his clinical trial.
He thinks that's kind of unforgivable.
- It was for Adele and the chief...
- You know, I know you...
You regret that you messed up his trial
but not what you did, I know.
You don't have to defend yourself to me.
I'm kind of...
unforgivable myself, remember?
But you're not. Not yet at least.
Have you told him?
Well...
I call him, he doesn't pick up.
He sees me, he walks away.
Okay, I'm not gonna yell...
"I didn't get the abortion yet"
down the hallway.
Well, so are you going
to go through with it,
or are we gonna sit there again
and not get the abortion?
Tonight. 6:00. I'm doing it.
Oh. Gotta go suck up to Teddy.
You want plastics?
I don't see it.
Is this about Lexie?
'Cause I thought you were good with that.
This isn't about sex. It's about medicine.
Then I don't understand.
You're a good surgeon.
Not a great surgeon,
which is why I was surprised
Lexie was even into you.
But this isn't about Lexie.
Nope.
How's she doing, by the way?
Wow.
Oh, god. What is she doing here?
I don't... What?
Is what you're thinking, right?
I mean, you thought that
I would run away to Germany
and you wouldn't have to see me again,
which was a relief,
I mean, after all the drama
that we've been through
in the last year.
I'm right. Tell me I'm right.
I...
Okay, so here's the deal... I'm here
and I'm in a happy place
and I'm done with drama.
So if you want to learn, I want to teach.
G-g-great.
Yay.
Alex, this is serious.
If you want the peds fellowship next year,
you're gonna have to earn it.
I just brought over a bunch
of sick kids from Africa.
Well, did you publish and article about it?
Because all the people
applying for peds fellowships,
they've all been published.
You're already getting resumes?
Yes, and you're way behind.
Listen, I-I hate to kick
a guy when he's down, but...
Down? Who's down? I'm not down?
Everybody hates you because you
narced on a fellow surgeon.
You're a pariah.
You're living in the hospital,
and you look like a bum and you've...
got really bad breath.
Really...
really bad.
Do you need me to go on?
- I...
- No, I'm good.
Oh! Look, here's the chief!
Chief,
is there, uh, anything you'd like to say
as we embark on our final year of residency?
You all know what you're doing.
Just don't kill anyone.
Uh, Meredith, can I see you in my office?
Well, that was very... inspirational.
Thank you, chief.
Nobody gets married
thinking it's gonna fail.
Well, you're the one who
needed the big wedding.
What is that supposed to mean?
It means, if we still had our savings,
my being laid off wouldn't
be such a big deal.
No, we decided on that together.
We both wanted that wedding.
No, we didn't.
You and your mother are the...
- Stop the car.
- Calm down.
- I mean it, Danny.
- You're being crazy.
What, are you gonna walk to work from here?
What the hell are you doing?
Stop the car!
You think yours is
the one that's gonna make it.
Derek's refusing to work with me, isn't he?
The board met this morning.
They feel that a suspension
would send the wrong message.
They feel that what you did
disgraced the hospital...
the profession.
I'm sorry, I...
I did everything I could.
So what are you saying?
You're fired,
effective immediately.
You're no longer a doctor at Seattle Grace.
And so it always comes as a shock...
the moment when you realize, it's over.
You walk away, and I swear, that's it.
All right, I-I am not gonna chase after you.
You get out of this car, and we are done.
Susannah!
Whoa! Ohh!
One minute you're standing on solid ground.
The next minute you're not.
We're going to the scene
of an onsite amputation
woman's trapped under her car.
You guys are gonna get swamped with bodies.
Kepner, you're in charge till I get back.
Yes, sir. Have fun.
At an amputation?
Uh, I-I meant good luck.
You know what? There's bound
to be piles of head trauma.
Derek's gonna have to talk to you.
I got fired.
What?
The chief fired me.
You son of a bitch.
I mean, are you happy now?
'Cause this is all because of you.
You and your big fat, stupid mouth!
- Get off me. Get off!
- Kepner, control your people.
- Stop! Stop!
- All your fault!
- Get off.
- There's no hitting. No hitting.
- Would you stop right now?
- Ow. Ow. Ow. Ow.
- You going to the scene?
- Yes.
Wait. Wait. I didn't tell you
you could go. I need you here.
42-year-old female.
Lost consciousness en route.
Unable to get airway
secondary to tracheal injury.
Last B.P. is 89 over 60.
Don't worry. We'll figure something out.
Make sure there is a crike tray
set up with the intubation kit.
Yes, doctor.
Come on. You can't be here. You need to go.
It's not stable. Get away from there.
- Oh, Dr. Torres?
- Yeah, hi.
Dr. Hunt?
Karen Lorenz, in charge
of search and rescue.
We're still pulling
victims out of the debris,
but we have a couple...
Danny and Susannah Wilson...
stuck down there.
He has a head wound and
his ankle's messed up,
but I don't see any other obvious injuries.
We could potentially bring him up,
but he won't leave without his wife,
and her leg is stuck under the car.
Take it easy. You'll be all right.
I hope you've got me with a decent resident.
I'm not babysitting any
first-day first years today.
Yep, I got you with Meredith.
- Coming through.
- Oh, wait. Um, that's not gonna...
that's okay.
Uh, not a problem. I can fix this.
Uh, Jackson, can I get
you with Bailey today?
I'm already with Sloan. Sorry.
Uh, okay. Uh, Yang. Yang.
- Can I get you to...
- No.
Okay.
Um, sorry. Hang on.
Let me just, um... just figure this out.
Hey, Grey. You're with me.
Yes, ma'am.
Uh, okay. Great. There we go.
Dr. Kepner, three more coming in.
Okay.
It was a water main break on 3rd.
Probably been going on for weeks,
and it just gave way.
- Here you go.
- Thanks.
We've got a vitals monitor and a camera,
- so we have a visual.
- Danny, can you hear me?
She's-she's not talking anymore.
You gotta-you gotta get down here.
- We need help.
- Danny, Danny, I'm Dr. Hunt.
Can you read out for me
the top three numbers on the monitor?
Um... 87.
63.
122.
B.P.'s 87 over 63.
She's shocky. How do we get down to her?
You don't. It's too unstable.
The whole thing would cave
in if we sent you down there.
By the time we get it shored up enough
to get someone down there,
she'll be dead for sure.
I thought that's why we're here,
for the amputation.
You're gonna talk him through it.
You want him to cut off his wife's leg?
Hey, you guys, I think she's dying.
You gotta get us outta here!
Please hurry. Hurry!
Dr. Yang, can you tell me
why you entered the pleura
with a Kelly clamp?
Why? What's wrong? Am I too low?
Do you suspect a traumatic herniation?
No, no. I just want to know you're thinking.
'Cause that's how you put a chest tube in.
Why?
What do you mean, why?
So you don't kill
the person when you do it wrong.
Well, tell me like I'm an idiot.
Uh, like I'm a medical student.
Why?
I need to make sure that
your foundation is solid.
Why? I'm asking the questions,
Cristina, not you.
Tell me why you entered the pleura that way.
What? Is Zola all right?
It's not-it's... she's fine. It's me.
- I have to go.
- Derek...
Meredith, I can't. I just-I...
I got fired.
What did you think was gonna happen?
Danny, you've got a kit.
Now they're sending down a second harness.
The doctors are gonna talk
you through this, okay?
Okay.
What can I do?
Kepner called. She wants
you back at the hospital.
I can't go back there.
Yeah, it sucks that everyone hates you.
But you're not hiding out here. Go.
Did you get the kit open?
Almost.
Oh, my God. No.
No. No, no. No, no, no. I-I-I can't do this.
Danny, Danny, you can do this.
We have one chance to bring you both up.
In order to do that,
you have to amputate Susannah's leg.
Oh, no. No.
Oh, God. Oh.
I need a C-spine!
Coming through, people.
Come on. Watch your back.
You guys headed back?
Yeah, we are.
Does anybody have a kid?
Has anybody seen a kid around?
Where'd they pull this guy from?
We'll need immediate transport for her.
Yeah, give me just a minute here, doctor.
I just gotta stabilize her.
I need some help over here!
He's not breathing.
Get an ambu bag and some oxygen over here.
Right away, doctor.
Oh, jeez. What happened? No.
No, no, no, no, no, no. I need help.
I-I think my patient's coding.
You think your patient's coding?
What's his rhythm?
Uh...
S.V.T.?
- Sinus tach?
- Okay, there shouldn't be a question mark
at the end of that sentence.
I don't know. I'm freaking out.
It's my first day of internship.
How could this be happening?
Go back to your patient.
Does he have a pulse?
He has a pulse.
Good. Now check for breath sounds.
Uh, I kinda hear some,
but maybe the right sounds less?
You gotta stop with the questions.
It kinda looks like
he's barely breathing at all now.
Move, move, move.
Tension pneumothorax.
Grab the biggest needle you can find.
What are you doing?
Tension pneumo. This guy's freaking out.
Step away, Grey.
Uh... 14-guage? 16-guage?
The biggest needle you can find!
Okay. Get this man a chest tube.
And next time, call your resident.
I'm sorry. I-I thought
that she was a resident.
No, she is not a resident.
She was fired by this hospital.
Had this man died under her care,
the hospital would be sued,
you would be sued,
hell, maybe even I would be sued.
Now get this man a chest tube, and, Grey,
get the hell outta here.
Pulse is not good.
His breath sounds are shallow.
His name's Nicky Hoffman.
Pulse is minimal on this side, too.
Come on, Nicky. I need you
to do better than this.
Thready pulses,
multiple rib fractures with
decreased respirations...
His body's shutting down.
Could be compartment syndrome.
That could be why his radial
pulses are so decreased.
We need to do bilateral fasciotomies
and relieve the pressure.
Do we have a scalpel?
Push 5 of morphine.
Got it.
Okay.
All right.
Okay, you do the fasciotomies.
You're the fifth year.
All right.
Okay, his pulse is stronger now.
Good. Do the other one.
Sponge.
- Here you go.
- Thank you.
Nice job. You got this?
- Yeah.
- All right.
Hey.
Hey, Nicky. I'm Alex.
I'm a doctor.
You had a pretty bad accident.
We need a gunther.
Dr. Bailey, it's the first
day of fifth year. I...
And they're at each other's throats.
We need a gunther.
I've got more pressing problems.
I'm trying to find a new
spot for Meredith Grey.
You know, I heard they have
a new research fellowship
at Mass Gen.
I thought a recommendation from you might...
You want me to write a recommendation
for Meredith Grey?
By the end of the day would be fine.
"To whom it may concern,"
"Meredith Grey is an excellent example"
of the kind of resident"
"you absolutely should not hire."
"She undermines groundbreaking
clinical trials,"
"she has absolutely no
respect for rules, authority,"
"or, as it turns out,"
"the oath that she took
when she became a doctor."
"She will most likely tarnish
the reputation of you,"
"your doctors, and your hospital."
"Sincerely, Dr. Miranda Bailey."
Meredith Grey is
the reason we need a gunther.
Jerry Hoffman.
C.T. showed a traumatic
subarachnoid hemorrhage.
I cleaned and splinted his humerus fracture
and sutured his facial lacerations.
Well, he won't need surgery,
but let's do a neuro exam
every two hours just to make sure.
Let's take a look at your handiwork.
Oh, dear god.
My grandmother could sew
up a stuffed turkey...
- It was...
- Better than this.
Pretty, uh, jagged in there, so...
- You ever heard of burying your stitches?
- All right.
So I will fix it.
Oh, Jackson.
There's a new patient in bed 3.
Kinda busy, April.
Yeah, kinda busy turning
this guy into Frankenstein.
Go. Go. Make yourself useful.
All right, I'm gonna fix this.
Mm-hmm.
Don't you think you're being
a little hard on the kid?
He's a lightweight.
Be thankful you have Meredith.
She was fired.
She okay?
I don't know.
Mr. Hoffman? Dr. Shepherd.
You're at Seattle Grace hospital.
There was an accident. A sinkhole collapsed.
My son?
Nicky's on his way in.
He's had some severe injuries
that they need me to assess,
but I promise you, I'm gonna
take good care of your son.
Nicky Hoffman, sustained crush injuries
and was very unstable in the field.
Robbins is holding a trauma room.
We called Shepherd from the field.
Which one are they in?
Um...
Oh, god. I-I don't... I don't know.
Well, find out.
Well, it's supposed to be on the board.
People, I need you to make sure
you're updating these boards.
April, I need you to reassign these cases.
Uh, Yang, take over Meredith's cases.
- No.
- Cristina.
I'm with Altman, and Meredith
should keep her cases.
I am your chief resident.
You have to do what I say.
April, it's fine.
I can wait. Just sign them
when you have a minute.
You're just gonna give up?
I was fired.
So what are you gonna do about it?
You have to go talk to the board.
The board fired me.
Yang.
What are you doing?
I presented as thirsty,
so... treated the symptoms
with 8 ounces of water.
Now that I'm finished,
I will place this bottle
in the recycling bin
so as to avoid excess strain
on Seattle's landfills.
That's funny. You're a funny girl.
Come on. We have patients.
You need a plan. Come up with a plan.
Okay, now pour on that brown soap.
And pick up the thin silver knife.
Good.
Okay, now here's the thing...
you're gonna have to really
put your weight into it.
Try for smooth cuts, okay?
Okay.
Now you see that area
just below the tourniquet?
That's where you're gonna cut.
Do it horizontally, as deep as you can.
Are... are you...
are you-are you sure
she's not gonna feel anything?
No, she's unconscious, Danny.
She won't feel a thing.
Okay.
I-I can't.
Danny...
take that blue towel
and cover her face.
It'll help.
All right, now remember to put
your weight behind it, okay?
Here we go.
One...
two...
three.
Oh, god!
Ah. I-I hit... I hit bone.
I-I think I hit bone.
That's good. That's good.
Okay, put the scalpel down now.
Now take the curved clamp
and move it back and forth beneath the bone.
Ah. Ugh.
God. God, I-I can't. Uh, it-it won't...
Put your hand in the incision
to get more traction.
I can't.
Danny, I know this is hard,
but we need to create more space
so you'll be able to saw through her bone.
No, I... No, I-I can't.
Okay? This-this is my wife. All right?
I-I-I'm gonna kill her.
- She's bleeding now...
- Danny, you can't stop.
No, you need to come down here.
I can't do this.
I won't do this!
I'm going down.
No, Dr. Hunt, I can't let you go down there.
- He can't do it.
- Yes, he can.
He can't. We are asking too much.
- I'm going.
- If it starts to go,
- I'm bringing you...
- I should go. I'm the orthopedic surgeon.
You have a wife and a child.
I'm going.
You're breaking up. Can you repeat that?
What?
I have a plan.
Okay.
I'm gonna be a mom.
Okay... Mer, there's a giant sinkhole.
Teddy is all over me.
Don't page me 9-1-1 unless
you have a serious...
This is serious.
Maybe getting fired was a good thing.
What do you cheerful people say
when something crappy happens
and they make it sound
like it wasn't crappy?
A blessing in disguise?
Yeah. Maybe that's what this is.
This is that.
And I can...
make jam and drive car pool
and have playgroups.
And maybe that's enough.
And maybe I'll be a great mom.
Okay. Okay. I'm gonna go vomit.
Uh, call me when Meredith comes back.
And maybe you want to be a mom, too,
and that's why you can't go through with it.
I wish I wanted a kid.
I wish I wanted one so bad,
'cause then this would be easy.
I would be happy.
I'd have Owen, and
my life wouldn't be a mess.
But I don't.
I don't want a kid.
I mean, I don't want to make jam.
I-I don't want to carpool.
I really, really,
really don't want to be a mother.
I want to be a surgeon, and please...
get it.
I need someone to get it.
And I wish that someone was Owen.
I wish that-that... that at any minute,
he'll get it and show up for me,
but that's not gonna happen.
And you're my person.
I need you to be there at 6:00 tonight
to hold my hand,
'cause I am scared, Mer,
and sad,
'cause my husband doesn't get that.
So I need you to.
I am a terrible person.
I know. Awful.
I got Meredith's surgeries.
I'm reaping joy from the fact
that my sister got fired.
A terrible person wouldn't feel terrible
about reaping the joy.
Oh, uh, Jackson, Jackson,
- I need you to take over
on a couple of these.
- I can't.
I have to see a man about
redoing some sutures.
Please.
I'll take one.
Thank you. Bed 4.
Bailey needs her spleen
patient taken to the O.R.
Uh... he's in bed 3.
So... he just, um, he needs a consent form.
Make sure that the consent
form gets put on his chart.
Uh, right.
Zola, peekaboo.
Peekaboo.
Hi, Janet.
Hey, Meredith.
I'm just finishing up your home study,
and I thought I'd check
and see how Zola's doing.
She is doing great.
I heard about the sinkhole on the radio.
I figured you'd be busy today.
Yeah, I'm just, uh, in between surgeries.
So... how are things going?
Is she sleeping through the night?
No, I... not really.
Um, she's up a few times.
But it's fine. I don't mind.
Just you, or are you guys taking turns?
No, he's great with her. He's...
Derek's great with her.
Dr. Grey, are you taking Zola home now?
Because it says here that
Dr. Shepherd's got her tonight.
Wait. I don't understand.
You two aren't together?
No. We are.
We take turns dropping her
off and picking her up.
I'm not taking her home.
I just came to, uh, to-to say hi.
I actually should get back to work.
Okay, Zola. I'm gonna go.
Okay.
It was nice to see you, Janet.
You, too, Meredith.
How's Nicky doing?
I gotta do my final exploration,
check for any missed bleeders,
and then I'm out.
The kid had a renal artery thrombosis.
I thought his kidney was a goner,
but Alex did an interposition
graft and saved it.
He's doing an amazing job.
I need to stabilize his spinal fracture.
So what do you got,
about another hour or so?
Well, with the rock star over here,
you never know.
I'd keep your pager close by. Mm.
- Dr. Shepherd.
- Mm-hmm.
Janet Meyers with social services
- needs to speak with you.
- Oh, what now?
She's waiting in the lobby.
I heard about Meredith. I'm sorry.
But you know, Meredith's strong,
you're strong.
- You're gonna make it through...
- Could you guys just keep it down?
I'm trying to concentrate. Please.
All right. Just page me
when you're ready, okay?
I'm so... I'm sorry.
- I'm sorry. Oh.
- Danny?
I'm sorry.
Danny, look at me.
You're doing great.
Now I need you...
I need you to cover her head.
Keep her head safe, all right?
All right.
I couldn't do it. I c-I couldn't...
- I couldn't do it. I couldn't.
- Danny, you did it.
You did the hard part.
All right?
Now, Danny...
Danny, look away.
All right, she's free. Good job.
I'm gonna finish up,
and we'll both be right behind you.
All right?
Take him up.
Meredith, what'd you say to Janet?
Nothing. Why?
I just finished answering
a whole slew of questions
about Zola's sleeping arrangements.
She's finishing her home study.
- That's routine.
- Okay, there was nothing routine
when she said that there were
inconsistencies with our stories.
What did she say?
She said that she spoke to you
and that some red flags went up.
Well, I did see her earlier,
but I didn't say anything.
I gotta go. I got a surgery.
Well, I'll-I'll talk to Janet and I'll...
No. Don't. Don't do anything.
Don't talk to her. I will talk care of this.
You've already... Don't talk to her.
Dr. Sloan, I think you're
gonna be really impressed
by the buried sutures I did here.
After you.
That is impressive. It is.
- Gender reassignment, huh?
- Yeah.
Normally they don't teach
that till next year.
That's a mistake. This is not...
Call me when you find the right patient.
I don't have time for this.
Hey, uh, I need you to prep trauma 1.
We got another sinkhole victim on the way.
Stop asking me to do your work.
Do it yourself.
- And how about you tell me
where Jerry Hoffman is?
- What?
Jerry Hoffman?
Um, uh, well, he's supposed to be in bed 1.
That's what the board says. He's not there?
Does it look like he's there?
Oh, wait. Wait. That can't be right,
'cause if the patient
from bed 2 is in bed one,
then that means the patient
from bed 3 must be...
Oh, no.
Oh, no, no, no, no, no.
The patient is Mr. Chuck Wallace.
He's having a splenectomy
secondary to injuries
- sustained in the sinkhole.
- Yes, Dr. Grey,
let's move on before my patient bleeds out.
Okay, I'm almost ready Dr. Bailey.
I just have to have the nurse
show me the consent form
as part of the checklist.
Scalpel.
Wait a second.
Dr. Grey,
- you're sterile. What are you...
- Okay, hold-hold on.
Wait a minute. I'm...
I think that there...
something might be... off.
I'm thinking that maybe this is...
not our patient.
Then whose patient is it?
I don't-I don't... I don't-I don't know.
I just-I...
You don't know? I'm holding
a scalpel in my hand.
I think you had better find out.
Stop! Don't cut!
Uh, it's the wrong patient.
That's Mr. Jarvis,
who needs a lung resection,
not Mr. Wallace with a splenic hemorrhage.
I-I'm-I'm sorry.
I-I-I am so, so sorry.
Would you make sure this gets to
the medical staff office, please?
Yes, doctor.
Meredith.
What?
Nothing.
Grey, we've got a guy with
severe crush injuries,
and Callie's come in
with a field amputation.
Let's move.
- We gotta get these trauma rooms ready...
- I got fired. Okay?
I got fired.
I'm sorry. I didn't know.
Yeah, well, now you know.
I have to go. I have a...
Owen.
She didn't have the abortion.
She wants to and she can't
do it because of you,
because she loves you.
And instead of loving her,
you're punishing her.
For what?
For being the woman that
you fell in love with?
- This isn't any of your business.
- Okay,
do you know what will happen to Cristina
if she has a kid that she doesn't want?
It will almost kill her.
Trying to pretend that she loves a kid
as much as she loves surgery
will almost kill her,
and it'll almost kill your kid.
Do you know what it's like
to be raised by someone
who didn't want you?
I do.
To know you stood in the way
of your mother's career?
I do. I was raised by a Cristina.
My mother was a Cristina.
And as the child she didn't want,
I am telling you, don't do this to her,
because she's kind and she cares
and she won't make it.
The guilt of resenting her own kid
will eat her alive.
All right. Coming through.
No one was updating the board
even though I kept telling them to.
I know-I know...
I have to make people listen to me
but in all fairness,
I've been chief resident for 12 hours
and... and yes I mean
I could have lost his...
his perfectly good spleen
but he didn't because of
a checklist I implemented.
No, I haven't had excuses
for what happened. I...
It's okay, just yell at me.
- I can take it.
- A...
It's-it's okay.
Shh...
No, I-I-I can... I can take it.
Really. I-I swear, I can take it. I...
How deep are you placing the tube?
21 centimeters
exactly.
Hallelujah, I'm in.
Great.
Now explain why you chose
that size endotracheal tube.
Because I'm in my fifth year of residency
and I know what size tube to
use for a basic intubation.
Why are you treating me like a first year?
Because no one ever did.
I bet your first year,
you could do things better
than most third years.
Well, yes, I could.
Why are you punishing me for it?
I'm happy.
That makes me see you differently.
Your arrogance is not your fault.
You're arrogant because you're so good.
People let you slide by, skip steps.
They gave you the hard stuff
But let you skip the easy stuff.
I have no doubt that you can tell me
how to do a coronary artery bypass.
But I'm not sure that you can tell me
why you chose that size endotracheal tube.
Look, I know what you heard,
but Meredith Grey is one
of the most qualified...
Yeah, I understand.
Yeah. Thank you for your time.
Not now, Karev. I'm in no mood.
You need to get Meredith her job back.
What do you think I've been doing?
I've spent the whole morning
trying to get her a job.
Meredith doesn't need a job.
- She needs this job.
- It's not gonna happen.
The board's already made their decision.
Let me talk to them.
I mean, maybe I don't know what I saw.
Maybe I-I-I-I lied to get
- the chief resident...
- I can't let you say that.
Oh, the hell you can't.
Karev, this is not on you.
Yeah, it is.
It's all on me.
Looks perfect, Jerry.
Second time's the charm.
Sutures look a lot better.
Really?
That's great.
No. No, no. Not great. Better.
Which isn't saying much
considering the crappy job
you did the first time.
You-you just said it
looked a lot better, s...
This guy just fell into a sinkhole,
his kid's in surgery,
and now he's got a scar
to remind him of this terrible day
for the rest of his life.
You want to go tell him that,
big shot?
Go ahead.
Dr. Sloan.
Is Nicky out of surgery?
Uh, Dr. Avery was just
about to go check on that.
Um...
Wait. Bailey paged you, too?
Any idea why?
Who cares? As long as it
gets me away from Altman.
Oh, god.
She's gonna fire us, isn't she?
Why would she fire us?
There was that patient mix-up in the O.R.
Oh. You should be fired.
Me? You guys didn't update the board.
That's why she looks so pissed off.
That's not good for it.
Uh, let me see that chart.
What is she looking for?
What have you got?
A field amputation with
complicated extrications.
Still assessing her multiple crush injuries,
but I felt a broken pelvis for sure,
and her B.P.'s in the toilet.
Yeah, this is a gunther.
Really?
Really.
Do you think they can handle a gunther?
Oh, I think they need a gunther.
Uh, what's a gunther?
Hey. I got your message. What's up?
We should wait till your husband gets here.
You paged Derek?
Well, he's in surgery.
That could take hours.
Can't you at least tell
me what this is about?
I could tell something was up
when I ran into you at Zola's day care
so I made some calls.
It would have been better
if you told me that you had been fired
and that you and
Dr. Shepherd were living apart.
- But I can explain...
- I'm sure you can.
But you understand my concern.
So-so what happens now?
Worst-case scenario.
Let's not even go there.
Well, they couldn't take Zola, right?
I'm not really comfortable
discussing this without your husband.
Well, this is urgent, so I'll go get him
and I will be right back.
Do you have what it takes?
If your marriage is in trouble,
can you weather the storm?
When the ground gives way...
and your world collapses...
He's losing his S.S.E.P.s
push I.V. steroids.
Maybe you just need to have faith...
Scrub in. I need you.
I just got your page.
And trust that you can
survive this together.
Maybe you just need to hold on tight...
Oh, what did I do?
What did I do?
And no matter what...
Don't let go.
When my mother left my father,
she didn't tell him she was leaving
and taking me with her
until we'd landed on
the other side of the country.
In those days,
it was called family troubles.
Today it'd be called kidnapping.
Could you page Dr. Shepherd one more time?
I paged him two minutes ago.
It's really very important that
I speak with him right away.
He's a brain surgeon.
Everyone looking for him
thinks it's really very important.
I'll let you know when he calls back.
Sir, you know how I said
I wanted to do a gunther today?
I sent you an e-mail with
my new screening criteria
for my clinical trial.
Did you get a chance to look at it?
Not yet. Uh, Torres has
a patient from the sinkhole.
She would be perfect for...
You know, I'm inserting an islet cell device
this afternoon.
I'd like you to be there,
see how it works, okay?
Oh, no. You're gonna do a hundred of 'em.
Can I see the next one?
Today's just not a good day...
I'd like it to happen today.
No, sir. The fifth years are
at each other's throats.
And it's affecting the work.
I almost pulled a spleen out of
a man with a hole in his lung.
I need you in this surgery.
I can't have you supervise a gunther.
Torres can supervise. It's her patient.
Who doesn't love a gunther?
Fine. Do a gunther.
But be in my O.R. by 4:00.
4:00. Okay. Come on. Go.
Cristina.
What are you doing?
Oh, Bailey paged 9-1-1.
Well, what happened to the chest tube?
An intern's doing it
'cause it's intern's work,
which I love.
I'm-I'm loving
the back-to-the-basics thing.
It's so valuable, but, uh, 9-1-1, so...
- Hey.
- Oh, and you have to go.
So no worries. We'll talk later.
Um...
I had such a good attitude today,
- and now it's gone.
- Dr. Webber called.
He's gonna put the thing in.
Now?
At 4:00.
Wait. They just call... why would he do that?
I don't know, but I'm not complaining.
I just want the damn thing over with.
So I'll, uh... I'll call
you when I'm in a room.
- Okay.
- Okay?
- Bye.
You see that?
I wish I did. I can't see anything.
Hold the nerve root retractor.
It's yours again, Dr. Shepherd.
Why is my pager going off every 30 seconds?
Gloria's checking on it.
His S.S.E.P.s are coming back up.
There's still a lot of epidural bleeding.
Dr. Shepherd, when you have a second.
Does it look like I have a second?
What the hell is the problem?
They said it's something about your baby.
She was pinned under her car,
her leg was amputated in a pit of dirt,
her abdomen is pulp,
and her pelvis is probably crushed.
You will work together
to assess her injuries and repair them.
Oh, in the O.R.?
No, at the jiffy lube. Yes, in the O.R.
Now Dr. Torres will supervise your work.
If you're killing her, she will step in.
Otherwise, you're on your own.
Don't screw this up
like you screw everything
else up you've touched lately.
Ladies and gentlemen,
step away from the patient.
- Is she... is she here?
- She is,
- and as soon as...
- I want to see her.
Hey, hang on. We need
to check you out first.
- Does she know about her leg?
- She's unconscious.
All right? I'll go and see
how she's doing, okay?
Hey, lie down.
I will see how she is doing.
I'm gonna get someone to take you to C.T.
and then I will come
back with a full report.
Okay?
Okay.
All right.
It's an open book pelvic fracture.
And a comminuted femur fracture.
Has anyone fully examined the stump?
Pneumopericardium and
an enlarged cardiac shadow.
She needs a chest tube and a C.T.
Free fluid. She needs the O.R.
An embolization and angio
would help stabilize the pelvic bleeding.
- An angio's just gonna waste time.
- We could pack her in the O.R.
Call the O.R. Tell them to
- prep for an emergent laparotomy.
- Hello? A C.T.
Excuse me.
- I'm telling you guys...
- Oh, no, no.
- Something is going on with her heart.
- What do you mean, no?
That's my patient.
- We're doing a gunther.
- What the hell's a gunther?
It's, uh, like a team-building exercise.
See, the hospital does it when the residents
aren't working well together.
It seems to help.
If the patient doesn't die.
One time, the patient died,
and then it didn't help at all.
Oh. Um, so what, they,
uh, prep her and then...
Uh, no, no, no. No attendings.
Just the bunnies.
In the O.R.?
Yes, the O.R. Why does no
one seem to get that part?
No, no. Not this patient.
I just pulled her out
of a hole in the ground
that almost ate her alive,
and her husband had to cut off her leg.
- Dr. Torres will be there every
step of the way.
- Bailey...
- They can handle this.
- I said no.
Unh. The chief said yes.
I'm sorry.
Oh, yeah? Who died and made you god?
Okay, look, I think what we need to do is,
we just need to take a moment...
April, you're chief resident
not chief of surgery.
Did somebody call the O.R.?
No, because she needs a C.T.
to assess her cardiac injuries.
- What did I say about...
- No one gives a crap what you have to say.
Still want to take her to radiology?
Maybe wait in line for a little
while till the machine's free?
Is somebody gonna call the O.R.?
They're still finding their groove.
Mm.
You've reached Dr. Meredith Grey. I can't...
Let's check the liver first.
It's the most likely source.
What? No.
- Hey, Yang. Where's Meredith?
- I don't know.
She's in cardiogenic shock.
That's our main concern.
- Yang...
- They-they fired her.
Maybe she's putting
anthrax in Karev's locker.
B.P.'s tanking. We need to up her fluids.
No. Her pericardium is
filled with air and blood.
- Do you listen to anyone else, ever?
- All the time. Just not you.
- Or me, apparently.
- Look,
she's not answering her phone or her pager.
I haven't seen her. I was in the pit.
She's not in the pit.
I was in the elevator.
She's not in the elevator.
Page Dr. Grey.
I just did, sir. She didn't answer...
Page her again.
Chief.
Henry just told me that you called him in
to insert the device today.
Yeah. I had an opening.
Well, but he hasn't had his pre-op labs
and he hasn't had...
Well, we can rush the labs. It'll be fine.
Well, but he could come in in a week.
I mean, it just seems a little
weird to race him in here...
Look, it is a simple procedure.
It'll be over in an hour.
Don't worry about it.
Dr. Bailey.
I wanted to keep an eye on the gunther.
An intern just pulled me o...
I need you now.
You need to spend some time with the mice.
This is why I left my gunther?
Once you put a couple of devices in mice,
putting one in a human's a breeze...
All that space.
Sir,
I have a full schedule
that I already had to take apart
so I could watch you put
this thing in a person
this afternoon.
Henry... Altman's husband.
I would like to keep an eye on the gunther...
Put on a mask, Dr. Bailey.
Even with mice, you need a sterile field.
This...
is mouse T.
He's skinny.
So it won't be easy.
Get yourself some gloves.
Danny, you have a little
bit of blood in your brain,
so I'm gonna have one of my colleagues
take a look at your films.
Is it bad?
It's probably nothing,
but I just don't want to take any chances.
Did Susannah wake up?
They're starting her surgery now.
And she does have some internal bleeding
that they need to repair.
Well, and wh-when will y...
when will you tell her about her leg,
after the surgery?
We'll just see how it goes, all right?
But-but... I-I... will she be able to feel it?
- I mean, what if... what if she sees it...
- Danny...
And nobody's told her?
Her leg is not the big
problem right now, okay?
She just needs to get through the surgery.
But she has...
an incredible team working on her.
Really, they're... unbelievable.
Give me a 10-blade, please.
Don't give her a 10-blade.
The woman just had her leg hacked off.
She doesn't need her chest cracked open
for something we're not even sure she has.
Yeah, well, I'm sure,
and if her heart craps out,
she's not gonna give a rat's
ass about her leg.
Look, we know that she is bleeding
from her pelvis and her abdomen,
which gives her plenty of
reason to be hypotensive...
- Let's just do an X-lap and see
what we're dealing with.
- No!
- Karev, start the incision.
- Oh.
W-why him? Just because you're
pissed that I'm chief resident
doesn't mean that you can
pretend I'm not here.
Nobody cares that you're chief resident.
Can everyone just shut up, please?
We are wasting time arguing.
The only logical conclusion is,
take care of the heart first.
Hey, is the E.R. still a zoo?
No, they got everyone who survived
out of the hole a while ago.
- It's quieted down.
- I'm right.
The changes were subtle on the X-ray,
she got the crossword down there?
Sudoku. You ever try it?
- Bores the crap outta me.
- Amen.
A major potential source of bleeding.
You're outvoted, Yang.
Who do you think the gunther is?
- This is not a democracy. This is surgery.
- What do you mean?
Is this your first one?
Yeah, and there are certain rules to follow...
Hmm. The name gunther comes from
the doctor, not the patient.
One of the residents always kind of emerges
as a leader when they do this.
And the first time, it was
this little quiet guy named Gunther,
and everyone thought he was
gonna flame out of the program,
- but it turns out, he's the alpha dog.
- Great.
Airway and breathing are taken care of...
We know it won't be Avery.
He doesn't have any balls.
Well, Karev's got the balls,
but everyone hates him.
So I don't really see
them following his lead.
You know what? I'm not...
Bound to be Yang.
I don't know. Kepner's kind
of a dark horse these days.
Your anatomy book a good read,
you'll realize that the heart...
You feel good about that position?
- It's the main pump.
- Huh?
- It goes, everything goes.
- You willing to back that up?
Tell us what you think
is wrong with her heart.
- What, like, 50 bucks?
- Finally.
I think she has a tear in her pericardium.
- You think she has a cardiac tamponade?
- Bring it.
She doesn't even have any...
but she's hypotensive.
We got a plenty of other reasons
for the hypotension.
How are they doing?
Still trying to agree where to start.
I just had to put an islet cell device...
in a mouse.
Do you know how small a mouse's omentum is?
I'm gonna go with really small.
Strongly consider a thoracotomy.
Up the dopamine to 15.
Happy now. She's bottoming out.
Well, if we'd get in there
and pack the pelvis,
that alone will help
the blood pressure, right?
Well, yeah, I hope so
'cause her systolic's down to 68.
Because her heart is exploding.
- Okay...
- Is this where I step in?
We need to stabilize the internal bleeding
- and then we can get a T.E.E.
while we're in there...
- Yang!
- What are you doing?
- Opening her chest. What does it look like?
Rib spreader.
Oh, my god.
We'll have these lab results
back in a few minutes,
then you'll get a happy cocktail,
and they'll take you up to the O.R.
- I mean, his glucose levels
aren't spiking or anything?
- No.
I mean, nothing that would
make you want to push this up?
Nothing. We got an opening.
- Opening, right.
- Yes.
Okay.
Are you nervous?
No.
She's nervous. It's kinda cute.
All right. I'm...
I'm-I'm gonna go.
I love you so much.
And you have made me...
so happy.
I mean, like...
like really, really happy
for the first time in my life, I think.
Are you saying good-bye?
No. No. No.
'Cause you-you keep telling me,
this is a simple procedure.
It is. It is.
It-it's... it'll, um...
It'll-it'll... it'll be fine.
Yeah, but that sounded like,
"and if I never see you again,
remember I love you."
It did.
I should go.
I think it's a good idea.
It's a rim subdural.
It'll probably reabsorb.
I'm not that concerned.
You should keep an eye on it.
Good.
Everything all right?
Uh, Meredith disappeared with Zola.
Wh-what do you mean, she disappeared?
She... had a rough day.
She probably just went out for a walk.
Derek, there are a hundred
possible explanations.
Don't assume the worst.
You know why I do that?
Because lately,
the level of insanity in my wife's behavior
defies imagination.
I know, but sometimes... even with Cristina...
sometimes, they surprise us.
Got some bleeding in
the upper right quadrant.
Give me more suction and lap pads.
Do you see any bile or
pancreatic secretions?
- None here.
- Negative.
Hey, I'm watching Henry's surgery today.
- We should set up for autotransfusion.
- Why?
'Cause the chief loves an audience.
Not because he's worried
that something's wrong
and he-he wants you there to help?
- I don't think so.
- What are you doing about it?
Have his accu-cheks been bad?
No, but he wasn't supposed to be in surgery
for another two weeks...
And then this morning, he calls Henry up
and has him race into the hospital...
He's getting batty in his old age.
Oh, well, that's great,
'cause he's cutting open my husband today.
I'll be standing there,
contemplating my mortality.
If the batty acts up, I'll lend a hand.
Did you check the duodenum?
Something is not right.
You can detach the omentum
from the anterior...
You know what you sound like?
- To get a better look.
- I'm aware of that.
- Metz.
- A wife.
Cardiac rupture, like I said.
A lot of bleeding down here.
Jackson, uh, help her hold pressure there.
Lap pads down in there, please.
- Looks like Yang's the gunther.
- Did you get it?
Yep. No surprise.
What does that mean?
It means she took over while everyone else
is standing around looking like idiots
doing whatever she says.
Can you suture it?
I mean, look at Avery. Useless.
I gotta go. Kepner.
What was I thinking?
More lap pads over here.
Oh, no. No, no. This is the opposite...
- of what she should be doing.
- I need a clamp in here. I got a bleeder.
I'm trying to teach her some humility,
and she's running
the O.R. on a massive trauma.
What can you do?
Some people are racehorses.
She's a racehorse.
V-fib.
I need the paddles.
Charge to 20.
Clear.
No change.
Okay, I need 1 of intracardiac epi.
- Someone take over massaging the heart.
- I got it.
Ow! Oh, my god.
Ah.
Oh, my god. Oh, my god. Alex?
Look at me.
Alex, look at me. Alex?
- Oh, my god, Alex!
- What the...
Alex!
- Racehorse?
- My bad.
What the... what the hell just happened?
Epi. Give me another epi.
- Here you go, doctor.
- I can't find a pulse.
Why the hell doesn't he have a pulse?
I need a crash cart.
An epi doesn't stop
a healthy person's heart.
- What did you do?
- I don't know.
All right. Her heart's back.
I'm gonna deal with the pericardium.
Forget about the pelvis for now.
She's bleeding
through the packing in
the right upper quadrant.
- Should I repack it?
- Try a pringle maneuver. Graft, please.
Hey, uh, get me and
Dr. Altman gowned and gloved,
and I need something to stand on.
Dr. Bailey, it's under control, okay?
We got a lot of hands in here,
and two more surgeons
are only gonna confuse matters.
I'm gonna ask you to step back, please.
Can I get another pledgeted
3-0 prolene? Suction.
- V-fib.
- Charging to 200.
Clear.
Alex?
Alex? Alex, can you hear me? Alex?
You crazy bitch.
You almost killed me.
Oh.
I called home. I scoured the hospital.
I even had an intern call
every E.R. in the city
to make sure she wasn't run over by a bus.
There's no simple explanation.
Uh, why don't you let me
handle talking to Nicky's dad?
- I don't mind.
- I'm fine.
How is he?
There were three fractures in Nicky's spine.
We repaired the damage.
Looks like, neurologically, he's intact.
This is the "wait and see" part.
Can I see him?
He's in recovery right now.
They're not gonna let you see him.
I can't believe that this is happening.
We were just walking down the street,
talking about why...
people don't have gills.
I was holding his hand,
and he just...
slipped away.
How do you go through the day
when one minute to the next,
your child could just...
Excuse me.
I'm sorry.
He's...
Let's go find Nicky.
I thought you said,
they weren't gonna let me see him.
Well, we're gonna figure something out.
You need to see your son.
Don't touch me.
I'm not touching you.
Don't touch my gurney!
All right, get this artery. See right there?
Yeah.
Good. Now do a tie on the hemostat.
Who'd have thunk it?
Avery's the gunther.
What the hell happened?
Yang almost killed Karev,
and Avery's the gunther.
- Avery?
- Mm-hmm.
- Get outta here.
- Hand to god.
Avery...
Good job, son.
Thank you.
I'm right here if you need anything.
Oh, damn it.
My guy won.
We're gonna be great together.
Sorry.
A little hiccup in the gunther.
Well, take your time.
You know, I've seen you
open an abdomen before.
Whereas Dr. Grey...
I don't want an observer. I want an assist.
Oh, okay. Is something wrong?
No, this is a teaching hospital.
And you're not too old to learn.
Yeah, but it'd be good
experience for Grey to see...
Dr. Bailey, if I wanted a resident's help,
I'd ask for it.
Here you go, doctor.
Thank you.
Whenever you're ready.
All right, then get back to me
with her post-op crit.
And make sure you're aggressive
with the dressings on her leg.
I'm still worried about an infection.
Okay.
Hey.
You know why she just
did what he said, right?
Because he's the gunther.
How did it go?
We'll have to go back
for definitive repairs,
but we stopped the major hemorrhaging,
- got the leg all cleaned out.
- Good.
- Nice work today, Avery.
- Thank you.
- Thank you, doctor.
- I just hope she, uh, pulls through.
Mm.
How's Alex?
He should be fine.
Apparently, he had an underlying arrhythmia,
so the epi...
I was moving too fast and I made a mistake.
You think?
Boy, you got a mean streak.
I mean, you look like a nice girl, but...
scratch the surface...
Don't mess with the nice ones.
Mnh-mnh.
I think I stole a baby.
Okay, first of all,
you didn't steal the baby.
She's your baby.
What you did is,
you took her for a nap...
in a very odd location
And you failed to answer your phone.
But, you know, many people
find all the technology
in our lives to be intrusive.
So you're not the first person
who didn't answer her phone...
or her pager.
Well, and, you know, all we have to do is...
is find a reason why you
were awol for an hour.
Four...
hours.
Janet was gonna take the baby, so...
I took off.
Okay. Okay.
You know, people make mistakes.
I mean, I almost killed
Alex in the O.R. today.
So we'll just figure it out.
How?
- I don't know.
- No.
How'd you almost kill Alex?
With a C.C. of epi.
What-whatever. You know, he'll be fine.
Just, um...
just stay here. I'll fix this.
- What are you gonna do?
- I'm gonna fix it.
Hand me a 10-blade, please.
Okay.
Have to be careful not to cut too deep
into the omentum.
Uh, Dr. Webber.
Yes.
Hi. Uh, Teddy Altman here.
Yeah, nice to see you.
I-I thought that
Dr. Bailey was just observing.
Yeah, well, she's here,
so she's gonna make herself useful.
Dr. Webber, I'm a surgeon.
That's the word on the street.
You have an attending assisting you
in a simple subcutaneous device insertion.
You rushed Henry into surgery
with an hour's notice.
What... wh-what are you not telling me?
Dr. Altman...
Is there something that he didn't tell me
about his checkups?
I mean, is-is-is his hba1c to high?
Here we go.
Look, I am a doctor
and I know when something is wrong,
and something is wrong.
Dr. Altman, I'm fond of you,
so I'm gonna count to 30 in my head
before I call security.
Richard, I'm-I'm just asking you...
Get out of my O.R. right now.
I don't need to be here.
They just want to observe me
and make sure I don't pass out again.
Mm.
Not a bad idea.
How'd the kid do?
He has a few spinal fractures,
but it looks like he's out of the woods.
You need to make up with your friends.
Whatever.
One of them almost killed you today.
It was an accident.
Nobody has your back.
Nobody is looking out for you.
That's when accidents happen, okay?
This isn't a personal problem.
This is a professional one.
It makes you a bad hire.
Also, it means that
I have to worry about you,
because no one else is.
And I don't want to worry about you.
I'd much rather be kicking
your ass on my peds ward.
Cristina.
Do you want to sit and talk for a minute?
I do. I...
I really very much do,
but I have to go do something right now,
and it can't wait.
Please...
please believe that I want to talk to you
and I'm not blowing you off
because I'm a terrible person
or because I don't care about you.
None of that is true.
She okay?
Uh, no change.
I just...
I don't want to mess this up
like I messed up everything else.
What? You were great in the O.R.
I wasn't the gunther.
I was a super-duper assistant.
Are they gonna fire me as chief resident?
No.
It was your first day.
They'll just...
make you do it again.
It's time to place the device.
What do you want me to do?
Place the device.
Sir, is there anything you want to tell me?
Don't screw it up.
A surgeon doing the early stages
of human trials on
his experimental procedure
never hands over the reins
to someone else, ever,
unless something is wrong.
Altman said this was weird,
- but I just thought she was being a wife.
- Bailey...
Are you drinking again?
Ooh, that would explain a lot.
Yes, it would. God,
I wish it were that simple.
Pick up those forceps, Dr. Bailey.
Now watch the superficial arteries.
That's where it gets dicey.
Let's get more retraction, Dr. Grey.
Right. Okay. Don't-don't... don't rush it.
All right. You see those blood vessels?
Yep.
Implant the device as close
to those as possible.
Without their oxygen supply,
the islet cells would die off.
Good.
And eventually the vessels
will just take over the oxygen delivery
to the device completely.
Look at that.
It's interesting, right?
It's actually kind of beautiful.
Nice work, Dr. Bailey.
Close him up.
Did-did-did he just...
He just left?
Get up.
No. I'm under 24-hour observation
because you almost killed me!
I revealed an arrhythmia
you didn't know you have.
I probably saved your life.
I'll run an E.K.G.
on you later. Just get up.
You're supposed to have my back.
I made a mistake.
All right? I-I-I was drunk,
- I was pissed off...
- Oh, for the love of g...
No, I screwed up! You screw up all the time.
I don't have anybody.
You guys are all I have.
- You have to forgive me!
- Fine!
Whatever. Forgiven.
Just... get up out of the damn bed.
Oh, sorry. I was paged here.
That was us.
We paged your wife, too.
Do you know where she is?
Well, that is the question of the hour.
I have no idea where she is.
Well, we'll fill her in later.
Shut the door, please.
Dr. Webber just informed me
that he tampered with the drugs and placebos
in your clinical trial.
Excuse me?
N-no.
It was, uh... Meredith.
Dr. Grey apparently was covering for him.
She knew and she...
was trying to protect him.
You have my apologies.
I destroyed your trial.
She wasn't covering for you.
What the hell are you doing?
I'm protecting your wife.
What are you doing?
This is wrong, and you know that.
What are you trying to do to her?
She was trying to save Adele.
She was trying to save me.
At what point are you gonna
stop punishing her for that?
And there's no pain in your abdomen?
Nope.
Really? Or are you just being stoic for me?
I'm a man in a gown. I can't
pretend to be brave and strong.
You can.
I kinda lost it today.
Dr. Webber kicked me out of the O.R.
Really?
Okay, um, so...
You know how we both figured
that since I was a doctor
that... I would be really calm
- while you were having your surgery?
- Mm-hmm.
That may not be the case.
You're just a mess,
like any ordinary wife would be?
Yeah, it's pathetic.
I think it's adorable.
I have a chronic tumor condition.
I'm a frequent flyer in the O.R.
I'm gonna be a basket case every time.
So sad.
Uh, if you're headed in there,
you may want to wait.
They're acting like he just
came back from the wars.
What?
Something happened with the chief.
W...
Where have you been?
We've been trying to reach you for hours.
I'm sorry.
Where's Zola?
Hey. Susannah just got out of surgery,
and it went as well as it could have.
We're not gonna know
much for a little while.
Okay.
Look right here.
We had such an awful fight right before.
I...
I brought up her mother in an argument,
and th-that-that is one of the red buttons.
I swore I would never do that.
Why-why did I do that?
She'll forgive you. You saved her life.
Maybe for a while,
and then she'll get better
and she'll remember why
she got out of the car.
Maybe she won't. You know?
Maybe you both just decide
to forget, move on...
Pretend it never happened.
Does that work?
It can't hurt to try.
You're married?
I-I'm sorry. It's... it's not my business.
I didn't mean to pry.
Oh, that's all right. Yes.
Yes, I'm married.
What did you do?!
I want you to shut the door
and then I want you to sit down.
You're throwing your whole career away
for that damn girl?
This is not the end of my career.
The FDA will never come
anywhere near you again.
That is the end of your islet cell trial,
not to mention any other thing
you might be cooking up with
- the FDA...
- Sit down!
You...
Open it...
What...
And read the first page.
"The artificial pancreas:
A cure for diabet..."
How about "The artificial pancreas:"
"A-a huge missed opportunity that you blew"
- "because you..."
- Read the next line.
"Principal investigator: Miranda Bail..."
It's yours now.
I have no pending trials with the FDA.
Ever since her surgery,
Zola's had weekly blood tests,
and, uh, the results I got today
were a little weird,
so I wanted to take a look at her.
Yeah, and, you know, with babies,
I mean, when a doctor calls... I got worried,
so I just rushed her right in,
and I must have left my phone
in the day care center.
And your pager.
My pager I had to turn
in because they fired me.
What's wrong with her?
Her white count was elevated.
14.5. Um, I wanted to make sure there wasn't
a post-op infection or a
C.S.F. leak or something.
Um, on my exam, she looks fine.
No signs of spinal shock.
I re-ran her C.B.C.,
and her white count was 8.
Totally normal.
Must have just been a stress reactant...
Or a fluke in the labs, 'cause,
uh, well, she's fine.
It's true.
C.S.F. leaks are a problem
with spina bifida babies.
That's... that's great you caught that.
I'm sorry. I didn't mean for any of this...
I didn't mean for any of this to happen.
I know. I know.
I still don't understand
what you possibly could've been thinking.
They fired me.
Janet basically told me
they were gonna take Zola away.
I mean, possibly send her back to Malawi.
You and me?
I just needed some time.
I just needed to hold her and look at her
and just think about how everything...
everything got so screwed up.
You should take Zola.
Janet has a problem with me, not with you.
And we need to do whatever we can
to make sure they don't take her away,
and if that means that you have
custody of her and I don't,
well, then that's what we need to do.
You're not fired.
Richard's gonna take the fall for you.
What?
He can't do that.
I'm not gonna let him do that.
Yes, you will.
If you want to keep this baby,
you will let him protect you.
Dan?
Oh, my god.
Sweetheart.
Danny, I was scared.
Oh, I know.
I didn't know where you were.
I'm right here.
You-you were asleep,
and they-they didn't
want me to wake you up.
I fell down.
You sure did.
You stayed, though.
I'm not going anywhere.
Don't go anywhere.
I'm right here.
Oh, I love you so much.
You're a big baby.
- Mm.
- Okay.
All right, the top row
all got the device on the first round.
Dr. Webber tweaked the protocol
pretty substantially after that,
which means the second set,
that's these guys here,
they all... tend to do a lot better.
I've been off the project for
the last couple of weeks,
but I'm pretty sure I remember the drill.
I can walk you through it.
It had to be mice.
All right.
Let's take it from the top.
How's it looking?
Can't tell.
They can't just take
the baby away, can they?
I don't know.
Meredith says you didn't do it yet.
I didn't change my mind.
I know.
I know. You don't change your mind.
You'd cut off my leg for me, wouldn't you?
Well, I wouldn't botch it like that guy did.
I'd leave you a good stump so
you could get a prosthesis.
When's the appointment?
Now.
Okay.
Let's go.
I...
Oh, god.
They're not gonna find
a better family than two doctors.
It's-it's gonna be fine.
Anybody want to go check on Sofia?
Why?
'Cause when somebody's talking about
taking someone's baby away,
you want you to see your baby.
Oh, you guys. She's fine.
I'm right behind you.
Ma-maybe we should leave, too.
I mean, I'm sure they don't want us
just sitting here staring at them.
I don't know.
They're trying to keep a family together.
That's... not easy.
You know, it can't hurt to stick around,
make sure they're okay.
You see, this-this is
why you're the gunther.
I have terrible leadership instincts.
That doesn't make me a better leader.
A better person maybe, but...
We are in a bit of a bind right now.
A lot of questions came up today
about your relationship,
about your employment...
Well, she got her job back.
That was a misunderstanding.
She disappeared.
Well, that was a-a miscommunication.
And the part about you two
living in separate houses,
that's miscommunication, too?
Look, I get it.
It's not easy bringing
a child into a relationship.
You're allowed to have
some bumps in the road.
But this afternoon, when it looked like
you two had split up, your wife got fired,
she lied to me about it
and left with the baby.
I set off some alarms.
Now I'm trying to dial them all back,
but it's not that easy to do.
Once the system is set in motion,
there's a certain protocol
that has to be followed.
Once the agency believes
that there are questions about Meredith...
Janet, Meredith is the best mother
a child could have.
She loves Zola. She loves me.
And if there is a flaw with her, it's...
she loves people so much that
she'll do anything for them.
Derek, please.
I hear you.
But no matter what I say,
social services still has
to reevaluate the placement.
And while that happens,
Zola can't be in your home.
I'll give you a minute to say good-bye.
We should... we should let her sleep.
She's ours. Nobody's taking her away.
And...
she'll wake up in half an hour,
and then we'll...
take her home for dinner.
So...
- Nah. We should wake her up.
- Yeah.
Hi, little baby.
Daddy's here.
- Boo.
- Hi.
Daddy's here...
Hi, sweet girl.
Little goose.
Adele. Honey.
Yeah, I'm on my way home.
No, I'm not working late.
I told you, I'm having dinner with you.
Yeah, well...
This time I mean it.
Okay.
I'm gonna give you
an injection to numb the cervix.
If you'd like some I.V. diazepam,
it won't knock you out,
but it'll calm you down.
Okay.
I want to ask you one more time...
Are you absolutely sure
this is what you want to do?
Then let's get started.
Sorry...
It's... time to go.
Derek.
Here you go.
Okay. Hey.
Janet is a very nice lady.
We like her a lot.
Yeah.
She's gonna find you a very nice family
to go stay with for a while.
And then you're gonna come right back to us,
and everything's gonna be fine.
Okay?
Okay.
She likes her bottle
room temperature, not too warm.
And she cannot sleep without that giraffe.
It's in the front pocket of the diaper bag.
And there's extra pacifiers in there.
You're gonna need them when
you p-put her in the car.
You think that true love is the only thing
that can crush your heart...
the thing that will take your life
and light it up...
or destroy it.
Then...
you become a mother.
Sync by YYeTs
Corrected by MystEre
www.addic7ed.com
www.tvsubtitles.net