In the 1800s,
one of the more common reasons
women visited the doctor
was "hysteria."
Granny, I don't know where
your nice shoes are,
but aren't you staying home?
Can't you just wear
your slippers?
Well, what about
next weekend?
I'm in Miami
for a National Conference
on Neuroscience.
Miami is a six-hour flight
from Seattle.
I could get on the red eye
Friday night.
We'd have
all of Saturday,
and then I could fly back Sunday
in time to pick up Scout.
- Is that insane?
- A little.
I wish I could get on a plane
to Minnesota right now.
I'm not in Minnesota.
You're not?
Where are you?
A now-defunct diagnosis...
♪ Walkin' on water
down the devil's road ♪
..."hysteria" was used
to describe
a wide array of symptoms...
Chest pain, anxiety...
I wish I could kiss you
right now, but I'm at work.
...a swollen abdomen...
- Hi.
- ...mood swings.
Hi.
They tried a variety
of treatments for hysteria,
ranging from rest
to psychosomatic therapy.
Please can I watch
your bowel resection?
You stay home from school,
you keep up with your work.
That was our deal.
I will never need to know
anything about
the French Revolution,
ever.
If you only know
about medicine,
what will you talk
to your patients about?
You talk to your patients
about European history?
But true relief for these women
didn't exist...
I have to catch up
with Maggie and Nick.
Go to my office.
I'll see you soon, okay?
...until physicians tried using
what they called
pelvic massage.
Hey. Zola's skipping
school again today.
Well, she had another
panic attack,
so what was
I supposed to do?
The cure was called
a "hysterical paroxysm"...
Wow.
What are you doing here?
None of your business.
I'm a private citizen.
...which today has come
to be known as an orgasm.
Uh, yeah, I may have, uh, given
her and Dr. Wilson permission
to use the interns
for a special project.
You gave away our surgical
interns for the entire day?
Well, I mean, the project's
important, and...
do you really want
to tell Bailey no?
Modern medicine continues
to recognize
the stress-reducing benefits
of the female orgasm.
But doctors no longer
perform the cure.
Sign these.
What are they?
Release forms.
- For what?
- Okay, new rule...
No questions before 8:00 a.m.
- Well, we just want to know what we...
- Save it for 8:01.
I'll be in the pit
if you desperately need me
and there is absolutely
no one else
in your general vicinity
who can help.
- Okay, but where...
- People, it's very simple... no questions.
You just didn't tell us
where we're going.
- You're with Dr. Bailey.
- Who's Dr. Bailey?
Wow, blasphemy.
I am Dr. Bailey.
What are you waiting for?
Let's go.
I'm so sorry.
I-I thought I met
all the attendings.
I'm Mika Yasuda.
No need to apologize.
I don't work here.
Dr. Bailey was chief of surgery
until about six months ago.
I left to spend time
with my family.
That's nice.
It was, and then
the Supreme Court went
and stripped women
of our reproductive rights.
Dr. Wilson has been helping me
with a sex-ed curriculum
to teach teenagers
about their bodies
because we now live
in a country
where the only way
to guarantee
you don't have to carry
an unwanted pregnancy
is to not get pregnant.
And
statistically speaking,
teens need some big help
with that.
So we are making
sex-education videos
to put up on social media.
We want to go viral...
You know, like that cat
that plays the piano.
Oh, come on, people,
get with it.
Dr. Bailey,
we're surgical interns.
We have progress notes
and nurses paging us,
and we're behind
on discharge summaries.
I don't even have time
to look at my phone.
I've got
like 600 unread texts.
Nurses love me.
You won't be bothered today.
And in exchange
for your cooperation,
you get the benefit
of working
with yet another
world-class surgeon.
Dr. Montgomery.
Oh, don't look so miserable.
You're getting paid
to talk about sex today.
Sex is fun, and I need you
to look like it.
*GREY'S ANATOMY*
Season 19  Episode 03
Episode Title: "Let's Talk About Sex"
Aired on: October 20, 2022.
Captions by VITA...
Synchronized by srjanapala
Okay.
Addie, you really pulled out
all the stops on this one.
And I am
so grateful.
Well, I spend
every waking moment
obsessing about the state of
women's health in this country,
so this was an easy yes.
Yeah. How much fallout are you
experiencing in California?
Last week,
I had five patients
asking for prophylactic
tubal ligations
before they go
to college,
because they're afraid
of getting pregnant
in hostile states.
18-year-olds wanting to get
their tubes tied.
I mean,
it's the actual apocalypse.
18? I didn't even want kids
until I was 30.
Hi.
I'm Jo Wilson.
We actually met during
your grand rounds
on uterine transplants.
And Dr. Schmitt is a g...
is a good friend of mine.
Unless you didn't like him.
Then I hate him.
Dr. Wilson,
I've heard great things.
Ugh...
- Would you excuse me just a minute?
- Mm-hmm. - Sure.
I cannot believe it.
Shep...
Dr. Montgomery.
It's a... an... an honor
to be working with you.
I'm... I'm a huge fan of...
of... of fertility
and... and your work in it,
specifically.
Hi.
I'm Dr. Montgomery.
Simone Griffith. Dr. Griffith.
Dr... Dr. Simone Griffith.
Sorry, I'm starstruck.
What do you mean,
I don't have any interns?
They're off on some
special assignment.
Well, what, did they enlist?
Bring them back, Owen.
I have a full pit,
one surgical resident,
and you, who's worse
than useless to me.
You know what?
Talk to someone who cares.
- Oh, excuse me, Dr. Altman.
- What?
Well, as much as I respect
the purpose
and intention
of Dr. Bailey's project,
I could really use some more
hands-on experience in the pit.
I'll do H&Ps, run labs, suture,
drain abscesses.
I'll do anything
you need.
Mm. You happy now?
Don't answer that.
You're never happy.
I'm a very happy person.
He's just bitter and broken.
Let's go.
These are your scripts.
Stick to them.
STDs, menstrual cycle,
anatomy,
and you're all
on contraception.
Uh, Dr. Webber,
there's plenty to go around.
Would you like to
pick a topic? Richard?
Uh, when I was 15,
I was handed a sack of flour
to care
and treat like a baby.
Do you have that?
I'll be in my office.
Alright, uh, any questions,
comments, concerns?
Um, yeah.
This is very important and all,
but I am not your guy.
Never had sex before?
This is your assignment today,
so you are our guy.
I think what Dr. Kwan
is trying to say is, uh,
we're not
exactly qualified for this.
Yeah.
Okay, do you understand
that hundreds of thousands
of teenagers
will become pregnant
this year?
And now a lot of
those children
will be forced
to carry their babies to term,
or worse, give themselves
back-alley illegal abortions,
get septic, and die.
So if you all want to go hold
a retractor, go ahead.
The rest of us will be here
saving lives.
Hmm.
Oh, s-so, we just talk
into the camera?
Not quite.
Come on in.
I've organized volunteers
at my son's high school.
Actual nightmare.
No.
Can't teach
without students.
- Hi.
- Hi, everybody.
- There we go.
- Hi.
Excuse me, young man.
Where's labor and delivery?
- Are you looking for someone?
- Yes, my daughter.
Her name is Denise.
Have you seen her?
No. Um...
She's having my grand baby today.
I brought sustenance.
Hey, Adams!
Come here.
Um, this is, uh...
Joyce... Joyce Ward.
Can you help her
find her daughter?
She's in labor.
Can't an orderly do that?
You want to go back
to sex class?
Please follow me, ma'am.
- Hey.
- Yeah?
Uh, is it true that you, uh,
gave away the surgical interns?
Yeah, it's just for one day,
though.
How much of the day?
'Cause I need them to round
on Maggie's patients.
Otherwise, I'll need to round
on her patients,
- as well as my own patients.
- Right.
What are they even doing?
Uh, sex videos to prevent
teen pregnancy.
Sex videos?
Uh, no.
Uh, sex-education videos.
Oh, okay, well, that...
That's an important word
in that sentence.
It is.
Okay, I guess
I'll start rounds, then.
- Okay.
Dr. Seip, 4617.
Dr. Jen Seip, 4617.
Hey.
What you doing down here?
Uh, just going
to the bathroom.
Y-You're going
to the bathroom?
You walked across
a pedestrian bridge,
you took an elevator
down three flights,
when there's a bathroom
in your mom's office?
That's what that door is?
What's up?
Okay, fine, I was looking for
a gallery to watch surgery.
Ah. Please don't tell my mom.
I can't do more
history homework. I can't.
Yeah, well, I never really liked
history either.
All the battles
you have to memorize,
the old dudes
with the wigs.
Who thought
that looked good?
Okay, well, I don't have to be
in surgery for a few hours.
You want to see
something cool?
Okay, let's go.
Track your menstrual
cycle with pen and paper, no apps.
If you get an abortion,
hostile states might be able
to use your phone as evidence
against you in criminal court.
If your period is late,
take a pregnancy test.
Um, medical abortions
are still, uh,
legal and available
in many states.
But, um, uh...
But you have to know
that you're pregnant early
if you want to use it.
Take one birth control pill
by mouth
every day at the same time.
Or you can get an IUD
or an implant.
IUD goes into the uterus.
An implant goes into your arm.
Both are 99% effective
at preventing pregnancy.
Morning-after pill.
Uh, if the first layer
of contraception fails,
take this as soon as possible
to, um, prevent pregnancy.
Oh, look, see, that girl over
there is paying attention.
Oh, wait, no,
I just didn't see her phone.
"Get young people,"
you said.
"They'll be good at this,"
I know. I am sorry.
I forgot.
I've got too much going on.
Well, I will do it tonight
when I can't sleep.
Look, can we talk
about this later, please?
Okay. Bye. I love you.
Hey.
Are you okay?
Do you remember
when the state fair was?
Was it three weeks ago?
Oh, I'm sorry, I don't.
I don't live here.
Doesn't matter.
Either way, it's late.
What's late?
Oh.
Okay, well, um,
your period can be late
for all sorts of reasons.
But if you want, I can take you
for a blood test,
just to be sure.
Are you a doctor?
Yes, I am a doctor.
And you won't tell
my parents?
No, this is between
you and me.
I... Okay, I get it.
Did you tell the coordinator
that the patient's
a rare HLA match?
Okay, well, call them back
and send the latest labs.
Thank you.
Okay, what you want to do
is you take the left grasper
and pass the peg
to the right grasper.
Huh.
Did I do it wrong?
No, you did it,
uh, seamlessly.
You sure your mom's
never shown you this before?
- No, I swear.
- No?
Okay, well,
I'm not gonna tell you
how long it took
for me to nail that.
Did you always know
you wanted to be a doctor?
Me?
Wow.
Uh, no.
Gosh, no.
Um, at first
I wanted to be the Flash.
I thought he was underrated
but cool.
Then I thought I was gonna
play professional baseball.
That did not work out.
And, uh, then I decided I was
gonna be a science teacher.
And then what happened?
Well, um...
Well, my mom died.
You know, I forgot one.
At one point, I was gonna be
an astronaut.
You liked space?
Uh, no,
I liked the ice cream.
What?
Where is your enthusiasm,
your... your passion
for science?
We're losing them.
We're reading all the facts
you gave us.
You've turned it
into ASMR.
You need to modulate
your voices.
You know, connect!
If I wanted someone to just read
facts from a sheet of paper,
I could have
done that myself.
Respectfully, we are not
the problem.
These are boring factoids
that you could look up online.
We need to teach these kids
something they want to learn about,
engage their
sexual curiosity.
No. Dr. Wilson wrote
a thorough curriculum.
Just stick
with the script.
Be better.
Aah!
Hey, hey, can you tell us
what hurts?
She's tachy.
And she feels warm.
Uh, get me a gurney right now.
Dr. Wilson...
Wow. It's basically
like a video game.
10 years of training,
and I could have just been
playing a video game.
I don't think they made this
back then.
Wow!
Ouch. Okay.
Mind if I use
one of these tables?
Oh, hey. I didn't...
I didn't know you were here.
Oh, I came up last minute
to see Amelia.
Thought I'd do some
data analysis
until she's finished
with work.
How's the, uh...
How's the trial?
We are hoping to start
the next phase
in the next
couple of months
if David doesn't fire
this latest research director.
Yes.
Meredith Grey is not easy
to replace.
No. No, she's not.
She's not.
- How's the new gig?
- I like it.
I think
I'm pretty good at it.
Uh, Zola,
what do you think?
Mom says you take big swings.
Did you do that
just now?
Mm-hmm.
Is it okay?
That's a cognitive puzzle.
Most adults can't do it
that fast.
Hmm.
You know, I have six
other grandchildren.
But Denise is my baby.
She needs me with her.
Uh, excuse me.
We're looking for Denise Ward.
This is her mother.
Griffith...
Denise Griffith.
She took
her husband's name.
I'm not an O.B. nurse.
And you have a tablet
in your armpit.
Just...
Are you sure
Denise came here?
Uh, maybe she went to
Seattle Pres.
No, no, she said
Seattle Grace.
Uh, okay, got it.
Just give me a minute
to find your daughter's chart.
You know, if they have a boy,
they're gonna name him Calvin.
I don't love it,
but I'm staying out of it.
I hope it's a girl,
'cause if they have a girl,
they're gonna
name her Simone.
Isn't that beautiful?
Simone.
Did we get a hold
of her parents?
Mom's on the way.
She also said it could
just be bad cramps,
because Diamond has
"extremely traumatic periods."
"Traumatic"
or "dramatic"?
It's unclear.
Diamond,
are you on your period?
Did my mom
tell you that?
She tells everyone when
I'm on my freaking period.
I get a bad grade
on a math quiz,
she tells my teacher
I'm on my period.
Like, we bleed.
Why does it matter?
I'm the virgin who likes anime,
who passed out
during sex-ed class.
Wow!
That's a giant cyst
on the left side.
Look, it's... it's displaced
her entire abdomen.
And look, whirlpool sign
on the right.
The vasculature is twisted,
suggesting ovarian torsion.
She'll need surgery
right away.
Well, then let's go.
Book an O.R.
and call her parents.
Dr. DeLuca is still
in her hysterectomy.
I have never done one of these
on my own.
Well, good thing we know
someone who has.
Find Dr. Montgomery.
She's gonna need privileges.
So are you.
Double up
to protect against STDs.
The pill and a condom,
an IUD and a condom,
but never use two condoms
at the same time.
They'll break, and you...
Ooh!
Could get pregnant.
What are you doing?
Just got paged to the pit. Bye!
You don't want me
demonstrating condoms.
I mostly have sex
with women. Mm.
Uh, and I don't want to.
Why did you even go
to medical school
- if you don't want to help people?
- Do want to help people.
When they're under anesthesia
and can't ask me questions.
- Are you a Capricorn?
- That's not a real thing.
Okay, no,
that... is for the condoms.
Who wants to know
where the clitoris is?
The vaginal opening
is right around here.
And then you go up, up, up,
and this point at the very top
is the clitoris.
Now, it's a bundle of
extremely sensitive nerves.
So, if you touch it too hard,
you will cause pain.
You want to approach gently
with a flat hand.
Gently, no poking.
It's not a button.
Yeah, and for those of you
with vaginas,
getting to know this part
of your body on your own
is the easiest way
to avoid getting pregnant.
Have you ever tried to...
really hold on,
like you're riding
on a roller coaster,
and you're not allowed to scream
until you get off the ride?
That is the pull-out method.
It is truly an excellent way
to accidentally
get someone pregnant.
Dr. Millin?
Thank you, Doctor.
♪ It's amazing, we made it
- Dr. Kwan?
- Thank you, Doctor.
Now, hold it at the tip
of an erect penis.
That part's
very important.
And then
you roll it down...
You out of practice?
Never had to put a condom on
anything as small as a banana.
You get a condom,
you get a condom,
you get a condom!
Everybody gets a condom!
Whoo!
Any more questions?
♪ Whoo
Ah, Schmitt.
Just the person
I was looking for.
Oh, Dr. Montgomery,
please don't make me
teach sex ed
to high schoolers.
I hated high school.
I-I can't go back. I can't.
This isn't about sex ed.
Oh, well, in that case, hi.
How are you?
I have a patient.
She's waiting on
a pregnancy test.
I have got to run into
an emergent ovarian torsion.
Can you keep an eye out for
the results and deliver them?
Of course.
And, Schmitt,
she's scared.
Oh, I can relate to a scared
high schooler.
One of our students collapsed.
She has an ovarian torsion.
I want to get her in the O.R.
right away.
May I have privileges?
Uh,
I-I didn't catch that.
Could you say that again,
louder?
I am requesting privileges,
please.
- Do you have a résumé with you?
- For real?
Standard operating procedures.
Any references?
- Are you done?
- Privileges granted.
What about the sex ed?
Oh, she needs
experienced hands,
but if you want to check
on the interns...
No, thank you.
Dr. Teller,
extension 2219.
Denise!
Where's my grand baby?
Granny, uh, it's me...
Simone, your granddaughter.
Denise isn't here.
Remember?
That's not funny,
Denise.
I'm not Denise, Granny.
I'm Simone.
No, no, no, no.
Mom died. Remember?
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
- I want to go home.
- Okay.
Well, I'm working right now,
but we can call Dad.
- He'll be...
- No. Get away from me.
I don't want you.
I want my daughter.
Granny, come on.
I said no.
Mrs. Ward, it's okay.
Get away from me.
Granny, come on.
- Somebody help!
- It's me.
Hi.
Can I help?
It's okay, it's okay.
I got this, okay?
Ma'am, can I help you?
What do you need?
Should we take
some deep breaths?
Deep breaths.
There we go.
How can I help you?
Can you
help me find my daughter?
I would love to help you
find your daughter.
- Did he page you too?
- Yeah.
What's going on?
Why isn't Zola
doing her homework?
Well, we got...
We got sidetracked.
And you called us
because...?
Well,
Meredith's in surgery,
and I needed someone else
to see this.
Look at this. Is she doing
neurocognitive puzzles?
No, she's not doing them,
she's killing them, one after the next.
I have never seen anything
like it. Watch.
Did she just...?
Yeah.
I couldn't even understand
the instructions that fast.
Look at her. She's so
relaxed, like it's nothing. Yeah.
I mean, what do we do with this?
What is this?
"Guinness Book
of World Records"?
You skip high school,
go straight to college?
What am
I looking at here?
Feel like I'm watching
the U.S. Open.
Uh, hey, could I steal you
for a half-hour?
It's for a sex-ed thing.
Uh, yeah,
we talked about this.
I'm your superior.
I...
No, it's for
a literal sex-ed thing.
I need help with
a literal sex video, Link.
Wow.
Still very not-okay.
And, you know, I'd prefer
if you call me Dr. Lincoln.
Everyone calls you Link.
Everyone except you,
moving forward.
Okay,
can you just do it?
I mean, we are flying by
the seat of our pants up there.
No. No, I don't want
to lose my job today.
It's teaching.
Or harassment.
And I don't want to
tempt fate.
Which one of us
is being harassed?
I don't think it matters.
Find an actual couple.
Ah, Dr. Ndugu,
could you and Dr. Pierce
please demonstrate
sexual consent
for a roomful
of teenagers?
I...
No.
Consensual sex requires no
verbal persuasion or convincing.
If you have to beg for it
or force it, it is not consent,
and you're
doing it wrong.
So...
let's learn
how to do it right.
There are 11 erogenous zones
on the female body...
The ear, the neck,
the armpit...
Wait, what,
the armpits?
Yes.
You wouldn't know that,
because like most men,
you go straight for the...
But the nipples
on many women
can be as sensitive
as the clitoris,
so going
straight for them
without any foreplay
to the erogenous zones,
can be painful
and overstimulating.
The other erogenous zones
can be the stomach,
the inner thighs, the feet,
the back of the knees...
Have you ever had someone lick
the back of your knees before?
Wouldn't you like
to know?
...the more obvious
erogenous zones.
The external
vaginal region...
Wilson,
tell me what you see.
You are draining the cyst to get
access to the torsed ovary.
And I've created a barrier to
prevent spillage
from the cyst's contents
into the abdomen,
in case of malignancy.
Torsion's a rare complication
of cysts,
and I used to caution
my patients
from imagining
the worst-case scenario,
but now, after the stripping
of Roe v. Wade,
everything feels like
the worst-case scenario.
Amen to that.
I have
constant rage inside.
Yeah, I've thought about going
to one of those places
where you pay money
to destroy things.
Doesn't help.
I also have rage.
I moved to O.B. for joy.
I wanted joy, and now I'm gonna
watch teenage girls die
from sticking coat hangers
up inside of themselves.
I mean, what if it's like
the '70s all over again,
and there
are septic wards?
Someone should
make a video
about how dangerous
a coat hanger is.
That's an excellent idea.
There's bleeding here.
I don't know where it's coming from.
Lap pad.
Let's extend
the incision.
That exponentially increases
her risk for complications.
She's 17 years old.
What if she wants to have a baby someday?
If the other ovary is torsed
and it doesn't re-perfuse,
this may be all she has.
So, come on, let's go.
- Okay.
- Now.
Lucia?
I'm Dr. Schmitt.
Dr. Montgomery
is in surgery.
Do you have my results?
It's positive.
You're pregnant.
We did it one time.
Did you not think that you could
get pregnant the first time?
I-I'm not stupid.
I just didn't think I would
get pregnant the first time.
Do you think that you might want
to keep the pregnancy?
No! I'm sorry.
I-I have to ask.
I can't have a baby.
I'm a stupid
high schooler
who hasn't fed her fish
since Tuesday.
All I have to do
is put in a pinch of flakes,
and I still
haven't done it.
A kid needs food every day...
Real food.
I would be the mother
who forgets to feed her baby,
and I would get arrested
or something.
Oh, my God, I don't want
to be pregnant senior year.
Do you know how mean
kids are?
I do.
I think my parents
might actually murder me.
Hey.
They don't have to know
if you don't want them to.
As long as the embryo measures
under 10 weeks,
you can have
a medical abortion.
We'll give you pills so that
you can manage it at home.
They say it's like a...
Like a really bad period.
Yes, please,
get me the pills.
Can we please
just get this over with?
I'll get the ultrasound.
She's calmed down now.
She's with Adams.
Thank you.
How long?
Uh, two years.
Gotten a lot worse
the last six months.
My mother
had Alzheimer's.
When I was an intern,
she got brought in here
with diverticulitis.
She kept
running out of her room
thinking she was late
for surgery.
My grandma keeps thinking
I'm my mom.
You must look
a lot like her.
Look alike
in some photos.
She died when I...
was born.
I'm sorry.
Now you have to keep
telling your grandmother
- over and over that her...
- Ooh, I... I can't do this.
I can't watch this.
I, um...
I-I put every effort I could
into matching across the country
so I wouldn't
have to watch this,
and that went to hell,
and now I'm here.
I'm stuck in that house,
and...
I love her.
She's my grandmother.
She raised me.
She's why I made it this far.
It might be helpful if you don't
tell her that her daughter died.
I know it's not easy,
but living in her reality
is the most humane option.
I don't think
I have it in me.
Nobody does.
You'll find it.
Is it okay if I stay out here
a little longer? I just...
Of course.
I really feel your pain,
Griffith.
My door is always open.
What's going on?
Is Zola okay?
Oh, yeah, she's okay.
She's in there with Amelia.
Okay. I thought she may have
had another panic attack. No, no.
But she did find
some of Kai's puzzles
that they use for
neurological evaluations.
The puzzles mainly focus
on visual-spatial skills.
Yeah, I'm familiar with them.
What... What's going on?
Meredith, she's aced every single one
at a level far higher
than most of the adults I see.
I'm aware
that she's smart.
My question is, why is she being
evaluated without my consent?
Right, well, it...
Yeah, it was an accident.
Zola discovered the test
when she and I
were in there practicing
on the simulators.
She's supposed to be
in my office doing homework.
Mer, based on Kai's time
with her,
Zola is
extremely gifted,
which could explain
the panic attacks.
When giftedness
is undiagnosed,
it can contribute
to behavioral issues...
Anxiety, a feeling
of being untethered,
a feeling
that you don't belong.
Because you don't. Her brain does
not function like other kids her age.
She needs challenges
that they don't.
She needs to be around peers
who can relate to her
and the way she thinks.
I'm gonna go see my kid.
Penetration is not necessary
for mutual pleasure.
For starters, most women,
or people with vaginas,
can't achieve orgasm
through penetration.
Yes? How come
that's not in porn?
Because porn is to actual
human sex
as the "Fast & Furious"
is to actual human driving.
That is to say,
it bears no resemblance.
If you are having sex
with your partner,
and you are trying
to make it look like porn,
your partner is experiencing
little to no pleasure.
I would disagree.
Well, you would disagree because
the girls you are with
are also making it look
and sound like porn.
But that is just an act.
A real man wants to give a woman
a real orgasm.
So you want to be a real man
or some candy-ass actor
for whom a woman has
to pretend to enjoy sex?
Guess they were right.
This is
definitely going viral.
Oh, not yet.
Need music.
And dancing.
Hot dog!
Boston again.
Mrs.
Ward, you're killing me.
Well, I guess you're lucky
that you're handsome, huh?
Where are you from?
Uh, Connecticut,
but my dad's from Barbados.
Ah.
Denise!
Honey, you okay?
Hi, Mom.
Did you have the baby
already?
It's a girl.
A girl?
Simone.
♪ Let the seasons change
- Simone.
- ♪ Well, they will anyway
- Can I see her?
- Not yet.
The doctors
are cleaning her up.
Oh.
You want to sit with us
while you wait?
Dr. Adams, your pager is going off.
Let... Let me play
a couple hands.
♪ It's not yours anymore
Don't go easy on her,
Mrs. Ward.
- ♪ If the wilderness between us ♪
- Oh, you cleaned him up.
- Yeah.
- ♪ Remains
There was quite a bit of
damage to Diamond's ovaries,
but we were able
to salvage them,
hoping to preserve
her fertility as best we can.
- ♪ We got a reason to stay
- So she's gonna be okay?
She will, yes.
I told her she just had
bad menstrual cramps
and that it runs
in the family.
I gave her
a hot water bottle.
I never even took her
to see the gynecologist.
Oh, this isn't your fault.
No, unless someone specifically
educates you
on what to look for,
it's hard to know what's normal
and what's an indication
of an underlying problem.
I'm just so grateful she was with you
when this happened.
♪ We'll find a reason
to stay ♪
♪ Ohh ohh ohh
♪ We'll find a reason
to stay ♪
Ready?
♪ Ohh ohh ohh ohh
♪ I know by the look
in your eye ♪
First, you'll take mifepristone.
It's just one pill.
It'll stop the pregnancy
from growing.
Then, after 24 hours,
you'll take misoprostol.
It's four pills.
Put all four pills under
your tongue for 30 minutes.
And then after 30 minutes,
swallow whatever is left
of the pills with water.
And then a few hours
after you take the misoprostol,
you'll experience
some cramping and bleeding,
like a very heavy period.
Then you'll pass the pregnancy,
and the pain will stop.
How do I know
if something's wrong?
It's extremely rare
to have complications
with a medical abortion,
but if something feels off...
Fever, no bleeding,
too much bleeding...
Then I want you
to call me.
You'll be here?
Yes, I will be here
for the next few days.
So you call me,
day or night.
♪ Ohh ohh
- ♪ Don't let the dust settle down ♪
- Can I take it now?
You can take it
whenever you're ready.
♪ There's a silver line
on the edge of this town ♪
We're making reels.
Just dance and point!
We need energy, people.
It's for the kids.
♪ Preach
♪ Mmm, teach me, baby, teach,
ah ah-ah ♪
♪ So, preach it, baby
- What are we pointing at?
- Oh, the facts.
- We'll put them on the screen later.
- If you say so.
♪ Soul loving,
do the soul loving ♪
♪ Preach it, baby
♪ Whoa, whoa, whoa,
baby, preach ♪
♪ Mm, teach me, baby, teach,
oh oh-oh ♪
But why little videos?
Because I can't get Tuck to look
up from his phone long enough
to have
an actual conversation.
And we have to speak
their language
if we want them
to learn.
Are you sure we're not gonna
get sued over these?
If someone wants to take me
to court
for educating people
about their own bodies,
they better be prepared
for a big fight.
So, when do you think
we'll see you again?
How does tomorrow sound?
Oh, you ready
to come back to work?
Ohh.
Look, I just can't sit idly by
while my daughter
doesn't have the same rights
as her brothers.
This is
a humanitarian crisis.
I would like to reopen
the clinic
and dedicate it
to reproductive health.
I-I would run it
20 hours a week,
and the rest of the time,
I will be an attending,
teaching the next generation
of surgeons
who we are depending on
to be in this fight
for the long haul.
Mm. Well, Meredith's still
interim chief.
She's just
waiting on you to...
No,
I-I don't want chief.
I'm telling you
what I want.
I want to teach and cut
40 hours a week,
and then go home to my family
without the added stress.
That's my best
and final offer.
Take it or leave it.
Sold!
Welcome back,
Dr. Bailey.
Hi.
Thank you for staying
with my grandmother today.
Ah, she's incredible.
Doesn't remember
her address,
but still seems to be
an ace at cards.
Yeah, it's always
been her thing.
Growing up, all the kids
played Scrabble and Monopoly.
I played bid whist
with Grandma's book club.
You sure you're okay?
Yeah, fine.
You're not gonna tell everyone,
right?
Is it a secret?
I don't want
anyone's pity.
I don't want to be
the broken-home girl.
It's bad enough
the chief knows.
I think people are just
trying to help.
I know
you're a Shepherd.
What?
- How...
- Something was weird with you
and Dr. Montgomery this morning,
so I looked you up.
She's your Auntie Addie.
You tell anyone?
Not yet.
I'll keep your secret
if you keep mine.
Okay.
- ♪ My skin is pale, it hurts to breathe ♪
-  Hey.
Kai and I
are about to head out.
♪ Ceiling
You okay?
They used to make me do these
puzzles all the time as a kid.
They'd stand over my shoulder
with a stopwatch,
take notes on a clipboard.
I spent years
of my childhood thinking
that there was something
horribly wrong with me.
My mind would race.
I-I-I couldn't speak in front
of the class.
I sobbed at every
social interaction.
I... panicked.
♪ You don't even notice me
And now you're living it
all again with Zola.
No, not reliving it.
I completely missed it.
I love Zola so much.
How did I miss it?
It's hard to see ourselves
in others,
especially when
it's a side of us
that we feel like
we've left behind.
And then when somebody
points it out,
it's suddenly
all that you can see.
Mine is downstairs in the pit
doing sutures right now.
I know
that extreme intelligence
does not mean that there's
something wrong with you,
but my gift certainly
gave me some struggles.
- ♪ While I sit in silence
- What helped?
A kind child psychiatrist
who gave me tools
that helped along the way.
Zola will get
her tools.
♪ Hide it
We'll make sure of it.
♪ So I will love you
from the outside ♪
♪ When your friends
are telling you ♪
♪ That I am different
and I won't fit in ♪
Have you got any plans
for dinner?
Well, you should
come on over.
I mean,
Catherine's home.
You know she makes
way too much food.
Oh, I really should
keep working.
Addie, you're gonna
run yourself ragged
trying to solve the world's
problems every waking hour.
You know, it's a marathon,
not a sprint.
I mean,
you know me, Richard.
And what they've done,
what they're continuing
to do,
it just...
I just feel...
Erased?
♪ On the inside, with you
Yes.
Erased.
I feel...
♪ I know I don't belong here
...erased.
I do know.
And I also know that
even if you spend every day
fighting the good fight,
I mean, you have to live,
I mean, you have to eat.
So come on over.
Catch up with old friends,
get some rest.
And wake up and do it
all over again tomorrow.
♪ I know I don't belong here
- Okay.
- ♪ Belong here
So, how long are you gonna
stay mad at me?
A day, a week?
What do you think?
Let me know.
- I haven't decided yet.
- Okay.
I mean, I'm lost with Zola
right now.
And it just doesn't help
that all the people I love
go behind my back
and break all of my rules.
I mean,
she's a great kid.
She is.
And she's brilliant.
I mean, there's a lot
to figure out here.
But, uh, we got a big piece
of the puzzle.
I mean, it's got to feel
pretty good, doesn't it?
Yeah, it does.
Ah!
Did I get a smile?
See? You can't stay mad at me
even when you try.
When done properly
and consensually,
sex can be medicine.
♪ Fear has had its reign
Okay.
- ♪ Over you and I
- Yeah.
We know it reduces stress and
strengthens the immune system.
♪ It kept coming in waves
♪ Till we were paralyzed
It even rejuvenates
your brain activity.
You know what I find
super sexy?
Me.
I was
gonna say "surprises,"
but, yeah,
- ♪ The downs were different
- you.
♪ Is the chapter finally done
♪ Or is it still
being written? ♪
♪ Say goodbye
to the long crash ♪
But sex without connection
can leave you feeling empty.
So
I, um...
I learned about
the erogenous zones today.
♪ Brace yourself
for the whiplash ♪
Did you know that there are
spots on your feet that, um...
Should I... stop?
It's just a foot rub,
right?
Friendship, laughter,
simple human touch...
♪ Ohh ohh
- Done.
- Aah!
Again!
You're good at this.
I'm good
at a lot of things.
...these are
stress relievers, too.
♪ A bad impression
Because truly,
it's about connection.
♪ For a new direction
♪ And say goodbye
to the long crash ♪
When you're physically close
to another person...
♪ Better days are coming fast
Mmm.
It's just this once.
Agreed.
It's not
happening again.
♪ Fade the dark age
to deep black ♪
No feelings.
I don't even like you.
I'm not for everyone.
- ♪ It's time the highs had a comeback ♪
- ...the nervous system responds...
♪ Brace yourself
for the whiplash ♪
...the body is flooded
with feel-good hormones...
♪ We're so close
♪ To the breakthrough
You should have taken sex ed
- much sooner.
- ♪ We're so close
♪ We're so close
Head upstairs.
♪ We're so-o-o close
♪ To the breakthrough
♪ Oh oh-oh-oh
♪ Say goodbye to the long crash ♪
Captions by VITA...
♪ Oh oh-oh-oh
Synchronized by srjanapala
...and everything else
just fades away.
♪ Brace yourself
for...  ♪