Your body contains aproximately
35 trillion cells,
and every one of them
is constantly being pulled down
to Earth by gravity.
Look at these losers.
Looks like they're eating
each other's faces.
I once made out through a tornado.
Really?
Went for gum later,
and the 7-Eleven was gone.
And a guitar?
Probably on their way to an open mic.
I play guitar.
That's different.
When you're lying down,
gravitational forces
are spread between
the thorax, abdomen, and legs.
Get a dorm, face-eaters!
Don't they know that
all love sucks eventually?
Too bad there's no sappy love songs about
the part where your husband leaves you,
you cry every time
you see his toothbrush,
so you're living on
your best friend's couch.
Well, stay as long as you want.
It's been perfect, hanging out
and watching bad movies,
trying every dinner special
at Kung Pao's.
It's been nice to think about anything
other than Amelia.
Hear she's back at work,
by the way.
Yeah, I heard that, too.
Stand up too fast,
and blood rushes downward,
away from the brain.
It causes dizziness or even fainting.
So, he moved there, and he's not
coming back to say goodbye?
I don't want to talk about it.
How's Jo?
She's staying with Link for a few days.
Other than that, she doesn't
want to talk about it.
Oof. This is massive.
This is a sea change. How are you?
I don't really want to talk about it.
Ah, right. You're probably not one
to judge someone for leaving town
with no goodbye or return date.
It's a minor miracle
our cells get anything
done at all.
How's Link? Have you spoken to him?
If Link can't love me for me,
no matter who the father is,
then we don't have anything
to talk about.
Because the human body
has to perform even
the simplest of tasks...
I'm guessing you don't want to
talk about that, either.
...under unimaginable pressure.
Well, my mom e-mailed
some venue suggestions... 13.
Planning this wedding
is gonna be a part-time job.
Or a full-time job.
That's why they call it
a wedding planner.
We could hire one.
'Cause you don't want
to plan the wedding?
No, of course... of course I do.
I'm just a little anxious
to check in on one of my patients,
and this elevator just
doesn't seem to want to...
Oh.
You coming or...?
Yep.
Dr. Hunt. Dr. Altman.
Kiddos. You're looking like... kids.
We...
There's a VIP guest today, uh, Hunt.
Uh, Griffin Ford. Tech billionaire...
blew up a rocket over a gas station.
Oh, yeah, thanks for the heads up.
Oh, oh, you betcha.
Will you be visiting the cardio floor?
Depends on how bored he is.
Oh, mm, two more
wedding venues from my mom.
I'll forward them to you.
Maybe it'll help you figure out
what it is you want.
Great. Thanks.
It's important to know what you want.
It's...
Let me know what you think, okay?
Okay, yeah. Love you. Okay.
- You got the kids?
- Yeah.
Okay. Oh! Sorry.
Oh! Hello.
- Sorry.
Okay.
Hey, do you have a minute to discuss
Mr. Paxton's pacemaker?
I do.
Uh, do you want to go get his chart?
Um, sure.
- Great.
- Mm-hmm.
You're acting weird.
I'm being nice.
Which for you, with Owen, is weird.
My pillow still smells like your hair.
I'm supposed to be mean to the guy, too?
Well, he's gonna know something is up.
Something is up.
I mean, as much as I... as I enjoyed
the... the up-ness of it
and hope it continues,
I think we should take a minute
to discuss what it means.
It doesn't mean anything.
I'm sorry, but I acted
impulsively because
I'm afraid of... something,
which might not even be true.
That wasn't much of an apology.
Tom, you're a good man.
I try to be, but you
haven't been helping.
Hi.
- Okay.
- Mm-hmm.
Uh, so, Mr. Paxton...
his, uh, last X-ray showed a...
Something is happening.
Well, he did have an arrhythmia.
Yeah, I'm not talking about Mr. Paxton.
You asked me if you were crazy.
I said you weren't.
Then I share an elevator ride
with you, and I feel
the need to take a shower.
Okay, fine. I slept with Tom.
What?! No, no, no, no, no!
Don't tell me that!
I thought you were saying that...
I was speculating!
God, talk about a telltale heart.
I know! I know! I feel awful.
I-I panicked, and he was there,
or I went there...
Oh, God, I want to die!
Okay, Mr. Paxton?
I'll cover it.
Great. Thank you.
Oh, no, no, no.
I got it. I got it. I got this.
That is a donation from
the Victoria Hughes apology fund.
I was gonna bake you something.
But...
"Sorry I sorta kinda
moved into your place
without telling you,"
doesn't really fit on a cupcake,
and I wasn't sure you wanted to see me.
I just wanted communication. That's it.
If you need to crash at my place
'cause you're looking for an apartment,
of course you can.
Just maybe ask first.
Yeah. Yeah, well, thanks for the offer.
But I already
found the perfect spot, so...
- Well, good.
- Yeah.
That's good news. What part of town?
Lake Union. Dean's place.
Dean? Really?
Okay, so, he's moved out
of that houseboat?
- No, no, no.
- We're boatmates, I guess.
Or, he just had a kid so technically,
I have two boatmates.
But it's great news, right?
It's, uh... It's news.
That is certainly news.
Um, well, I'm gonna go see Rigo
and give his wife some coffee.
- Okay.
- All right.
It's really good news, Jackson.
It's all good. No worries.
Who... Who sent you?
Look, I-I want a name.
Was it Catherine?
You know, I want to see
that invoice there.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
- What?
- Uh, uh,
let's just... I'm sorry.
I'm Chief Bailey.
Can I help you?
He's the one who needs help.
Someone sent back my office
furniture from Pac-North,
and I told these guys
that I didn't send for it,
I don't want it,
and they can take it back!
- Whoa, wait, wait!
- Hey.
A-All of it?
Are you planning on sitting on the floor?
You know what?
I don't have time for this.
I have a skills lab to teach.
Dr. Rager to Peds.
Dr. Sara Rager to Peds.
So, we're taking it all back?
Noelle Webb, 43,
complains of abdominal pain and dizziness
after falling off a ladder.
- Hi, Noelle. I'm Dr. Grey.
- Hi.
Did you just lose your balance?
Do you have any other symptoms?
I-I was painting this house,
and I just got woozy for a sec.
Fumes got to me.
I need my phone.
I think it's still at the site.
Okay.
Noelle, we'll get your phone for you.
Ohh.
Do you have any other health issues
that I need to know about?
Oh, I-I'm a type-1 diabetic,
but I take care of it.
You know, I-I-I'm good about what I eat.
- Oh! Oh!
- When's the last time
you checked your blood sugar?
Recently... ish.
Ohh, my Giggle Days rating
is gonna go in the toilet from this.
- Ooh!
- What's Giggle Days?
It's an app for small jobs.
Gig economy. They think they're cute.
Connects you to people who need help
or their Internet hooked up
or their couch moved,
or, in my case, a house painted.
But it's so un-cute
if my rating goes down.
I see some free fluid there.
What's that? Is that bad?
Well, we just need to run
some more tests to make sure.
Dr. Schmitt, let's admit
her for observation.
Get a full set of labs
and order a CT trauma series.
And my phone!
We will ask the paramedics
if they have found your phone.
I'll see you soon, Noelle.
Dr. Daniel to Pediatrics.
Heads up. She may seem nice,
but she just wants a condo on Mars.
Oh, no. No, no, I'll take the kindness,
even if it's insincere.
Most of the people in this
city think I'm a monster.
Well, big company, big accident,
classic clickbait. The firefighter,
Rigo Vasquez, is here recovering.
I know he's eager
to thank you for covering his,
uh, medical expenses.
Mm-hmm. Yeah. Listen, before we, uh...
before we get to that...
This thing is, uh, catastrophic.
My investors are spooked.
"Woke" Twitter is eating me alive.
Well, th... there were no fatalities.
"Billionaire explodes
rocket over Seattle"
is the only thing anyone cares about.
And now there are rumors
of a criminal investigation.
People got hurt on my watch, by my hand.
I made mistakes, Tom.
Mistakes that are... beneath me.
Now, I may fail sometimes.
I was a crap husband, and I suck at golf.
But my critical thinking,
my calculations,
my understanding of physics...
that's never failed me.
Now, I don't know if it's a brain tumor,
some neurological disease,
if it's cancer,
but I need you to find
whatever it is and fix it
before this nightmare wipes out
all the good I've done.
Well, you've come to the right place.
Why don't you text her,
see if she wants to talk?
About what?
The baby that might be Owen's
or the relationship she just ended?
Or the weather? I'll pass.
If she wants to talk to me,
she can find me.
I'm done chasing her.
Okay.
Brad Spencer, 22.
Found unresponsive with burns
on three extremities.
GCS of 6T.
We got him back after
multiple rounds of CPR.
He jumped onto a train track
and got electrocuted.
He didn't jump. He fell. We were kissing.
We were saying goodbye,
and we thought that
the train was still behind us.
Then he turned around
too fast, and he just fell.
Oh, my God! Link!
It's the face-eaters from this morning!
All right, okay, we got to go!
- Trauma one!
- Go, go, go!
Synced & corrected by -robtor-
www.addic7ed.com
Third-degree burns on this arm.
- Head trauma?
- I paged Koracick.
And he's busy. What happened?
Brad fell on his guitar,
which fell on the train tracks.
He was making out with his girlfriend.
I don't have a pulse in either wrist,
and this arm is cold and tight.
- This one, too.
- Okay, right leg's okay,
but I'm not getting
anything in the left foot.
- Compartment syndrome.
- Compartment syndrome, okay.
- Okay.
- Scalpels and sterile gloves!
Simms, you ever done a fasciotomy?
Does a cadaver count?
You and Jo take the arms.
I'll take the leg.
Pupils are equal and reactive,
but I can't rule out a head injury.
He needs a CT ASAP.
After we save his limbs.
Okay, fasciotomies on my count.
One, two...
Wait, wait! Is that her?
She should not see this.
All right, one, two, three.
Do you care if I stand?
Stand, sit, whatever you need.
I don't need to stand.
I just p-prefer to, I guess.
Okay, whatever's more comfortable.
You don't think that's possible?
To be comfortable here?
I think that when your bosses tell you
that you can't operate
until a counselor signs off,
it sort of casts a mood.
Okay, what kind of mood?
Look, our patients were
at extreme risk, all right?
And I keep coming back to the fact that
if I'd behaved differently,
they'd be dead.
- Mm-hmm.
- And that's all it was...
just passion for the work.
Trying to save lives.
It's not some manic, uh, whatever.
I didn't say "manic."
Are you experiencing symptoms of mania?
No.
Agitation, inflated confidence,
rambling, increased sex drive?
N-No. No, none of that.
I just... I've... had
a very stressful couple weeks.
That's all.
Okay.
"Painter left job unfinished,
spilled paint on porch.
Do not hire this person.
Shrug emoji, poop emoji,
thumbs-down emoji.
Zero stars."
I'm sure you can have that removed
if you contact customer service.
You sound like someone
who's never tried to do that.
Schmitt, she should've had a CT by now.
And what's the status on her room?
Apparently there's an issue
with admissions.
A lot of people got moved around.
Some VIP thing.
Do I get some kind of
discount for the wait?
I do have her lab results, though.
Oh.
Whoa. Noelle, these
numbers are kinda high.
Are you taking your insulin regularly?
I'm pretty good about it.
"Pretty good"... what does that mean?
We're not gonna judge you.
I just need to know so these
numbers make sense.
Are you taking your insulin?
Okay, the deal is
I just moved my folks
into assisted living,
and that's not cheap.
I've been working all these apps
trying to make ends meet.
But there isn't always
enough left over for me.
So, um, I've been rationing my insulin
until my situation's more stable.
Unfortunately, that's not how this works.
I'm... I'm sure that's why
you got dizzy and fell.
Dr. Grey, Chief Koracick needs you.
Well, tell him to wait.
He says it's an emergency.
Okay, let's get her a CT,
check on the status of her room,
page me as soon as she gets in.
- Okay.
- Okay?
Dr. Grey. Thank you for coming.
Why's this floor empty?
You said this was an emergency.
Oh, it is. Emergent, uh, consult.
Griffin Ford is here today.
The billionaire rocket guy?
Yeah, maybe don't call him that.
Wait a second. Please don't tell me
you let him buy out this entire floor.
No, of course not. He got it for free.
He's a great friend to
the Catherine Fox Foundation.
The emergency room is overflowing!
Patients need rooms.
My patient needs a room.
Well, all... all the more reason
to get this taken care of
and get him on his... on his way.
Th-This guy is about a lot more than,
uh, spaceships, Grey.
He's working to fight
climate change, uh, end poverty.
And... And I'm pretty sure,
uh, he's... he's single.
Okay, not interested.
Okay, you don't have to be
nice, but be a pro.
Yes. Yes. Good girl, Emmie.
Dr. Mochrie to OR 3.
Hey.
Dr. Julia Mochrie to OR 3.
Teddy, what... what was that?
Oh, I... Well, I just, uh...
I just wanted to take the stairs.
Teddy, what's wrong?
I know you too well.
Something has happened.
Just tell me.
Amelia's baby might be yours.
I mean
Might be, as in might not.
I just...
I don't... I don't think she knows yet.
Jo.
What does Jo have to do with anything?
She mentioned something in surgery.
She said, "What would you do if..."
How do you even know this?
Did Amelia tell you or...
- No.
- Then who?
It doesn't matter. Te... You just told me
that I-I might have another
baby with another woman.
Amelia, your ex-wife.
I need to make sure that you didn't hear
- some rumor and run with it.
- Run with it?
I want to make sure that it's real.
It's real, Owen!
It's a real baby,
and you might really be the father!
If you have a baby with Amelia,
what does that mean for us?
I...
Wow.
Teddy.
I enjoyed your article.
Which one?
Uh, "The List."
Exposing all those problems
with the healthcare system.
I bet that ruffled
some feathers around here.
We survived.
Reasonable people adapt
themselves to the world...
unreasonable people persist
in adapting the world to themselves.
Therefore, all progress depends
on unreasonable people.
- Huh. Profound.
- Hmm.
The future should ruffle
feathers. Don't you think?
Sometimes your vision demands
that you light the spark,
you storm the palace.
- I've been there.
- Hmm.
You don't agree?
I just find it ironic
that someone who has
a whole hospital floor to themselves
is talking about storming palaces.
I didn't ask for an entire floor.
You didn't have to.
You just asked Catherine Fox for a favor,
and, boom, here you are.
Grey, time to check his thyroid.
Excuse me.
Ooh! Look at that.
My patient's in CT.
Your patient's right here.
He's someone else's patient now.
Mr. Ford, may I introduce you to
- Dr. Jackson Avery?
- Grey.
We're rolling out
the red carpet for Mr. Ford,
and it doesn't get any redder
than Dr. Avery.
Wh... What's going on?
Your mom, your mess.
Brad's electrocution injury
affected the tissue in his limbs.
We had to cut through
both of his arms and his leg
to preserve the circulation.
Still, the damage was extensive.
His head CT shows a small
epidural bleed in his brain,
which I'll evacuate in the OR.
It could have been a lot worse.
We think that the neck of his guitar
took most of the impact.
It probably saved his life.
Wow.
One second, he was there,
and then he just disappeared
like he fell through a trapdoor.
You didn't hear the train leaving?
We... We just graduated from U-Dub,
and Brad got this internship
at a music studio here.
But I won a Rhodes Scholarship,
and he's been so sweet,
singing me these corny love songs.
But it's been torture just knowing that
we were gonna be apart.
And I was on my way to the airport today,
and he just got this look on his face
and... and he said, "Screw it.
Let's go to England together."
And then he kissed me, and it was like...
everything was solved.
Not even the "ding-ding"
of the doors closing?
The annoying loudspeaker?
Okay, uh, we are gonna
take Brad to the OR
and then move him to the ICU.
We will let you know
if we have any updates.
Okay.
What are you doing here?
I wasn't sure if you could leave,
so I paged everyone.
There's a guy up there with
the entire floor to himself.
Meanwhile, this woman
is rationing her insulin
just to stay alive.
It's infuriating.
Oh. Scans are up.
Big retroperitoneal bleed.
Kidney's shattered. She needs an ex-lap.
Let's book the OR.
And if any billionaire
tries to get in your way,
push them aside.
Are you okay?
Huh? Uh...
Have you talked to Amelia?
About...?
Help! I need help!
BP's dropping.
Abdomen's more distended.
Let's get an intubation tray.
Book the OR.
Hey, I got your page. What's wrong?
Let's talk in your office.
Ta-da!
What the hell did you do?
What? I had the movers
bring up your old furniture
from the basement and arrange
it like it was before.
Look, I-I know
you're still feeling down
about Catherine and everything else.
So o-of course you didn't
want that Pac-North stuff.
You think you know what
I want and what I don't want?
I never wanted
this furniture moved in here
in the first place!
And it came anyway!
And if I had wanted this old junk back,
I would have asked for it!
Look, I want an empty room!
Why is that so hard to understand?!
You know, you're just like her.
You presume to know what's best!
Okay! Okay.
It's an easy fix. Ri... I d...
I'll just call
building services and right...
Ah.
Okay, apparently,
Tom Koracick has decided to
wreak havoc on the hospital.
Look, I-I'll come back, and I'll fix it.
Don't bother! I'll do it myself!
Hey, I texted. You didn't reply.
Uh, yeah, I got stuck helping
babysit a billionaire.
It screwed up my entire schedule.
You should go enjoy your day off, though.
You know, I can swing by the boat later.
Maybe I can bring a housewarming
present for you and Dean.
Jackson. Jackson, hey.
What's up?
I move in, you're mad, and I move out,
and you're still mad.
So, what... If you have
a problem, just tell me.
Please.
Okay.
Look, I know you and Dean are friends.
- Okay, I get that.
- Mm-hmm.
I also think he has
a thing for you, so...
What? No, he doesn't.
He doesn't have a...
He also hit on Maggie
when we were together,
so I kind of question his whole...
Oh, you don't need to question anything.
He didn't know she had a boyfriend,
and when he did, he backed off.
And then he invited you to live with him.
No, no, he did not...
He did not invite me. I asked.
Which somehow makes it worse, okay?
- It...
- Not... You live with him now.
You're raising a baby
together, all right?
You haven't even met my child.
You haven't invited me to meet her.
'Cause we're not there yet!
Then where are we?!
Because it sounds like
we're in the place where you freak out
when I get too close
and when I live my life.
So pick a lane.
Look, I don't want to fight with you.
- Well, I do!
- I'm at work.
I have a VIP patient to deal with.
So I'd like us...
...to be able to talk about this
completely later.
You know, I'm sorry. If you can't answer
the simple question of where we are,
I'm not sure we have
that much left to talk about.
Oh, you know what? Come on, okay?
You don't get to suddenly
dictate the timeline.
You made choices that
I was not involved in.
Give me a second to process.
Process what? That I have friends?
Okay, all right, yeah.
You have your process.
Let me know how it goes.
We'll need to page Avery post-op
to take a look at these wounds
for closure later.
Hematoma drained.
He's lucky that guitar didn't jam
straight into his brain.
It was a cheap guitar.
So much for dumb love songs.
What is wrong with making out in public
and singing to each other
un-ironically, saying,
"Screw it... let's go have an adventure"?
Isn't that what being 22
and in love is for?
Yeah, until the part where
you get cooked on a train track.
Word.
Hmm. I'm done here.
Do you two need help
dressing those wounds?
No, I think we got it from here.
Yeah, and we're good
to update the girlfriend
if you have somewhere you need to be.
"Word"? Really?
I know.
I'll be right with you guys, okay?
Hey, Chief! Uh, I think
I got the overflow handled.
So...
DeLuca, telling me you're doing your job
isn't a part of doing your job.
Right, but I just thought now
that that's taken care of,
I could maybe start
treating some of the patients
- that I've been moving?
- Oh, that isn't our deal.
Look, I've been seeing
the counselor, all right?
I did that. And now with Dr. Webber
handing off his entire service,
I just thought I could help.
Webber handed off his entire service?
- Why?
- You know what?
I don't really know because
gossip isn't a part of my job.
I'm a surgeon.
Please, Chief, let me work.
This... This...
Chief? Is that a yes?
It is not.
I can't find the bleeding. She's in DIC.
Can we control it with a REBOA?
She's lost too much blood.
She couldn't afford her insulin.
She was healthy.
She was doing everything
she needed to do.
She was taking care of her parents.
She had her whole life ahead of her.
This shouldn't have happened!
Dr. Crone to Peds ICU.
Dr. Alexandria Crone to Peds ICU.
Hey.
I told Owen.
Okay, did he... Should someone warn Tom?
No, not about that.
About the baby, about Amelia's baby.
I told him because she wouldn't
and he deserves to know,
and I deserve answers,
and Link deserves answers,
and, I mean, who does this?
Who gets this far into the pregnancy
and just toys with people's feelings,
with... with their lives?
I was just starting to really like her.
And I was just starting
to really like you.
I mean, who does this?
Who cheats on her fiancé
with a man who is clearly
desperately in love with her?
And before you go judging Amelia,
let's just take a second
to remember how long you waited
before you told Owen
that you were pregnant.
You're right. You're right.
I'm... I'm sorry.
Yeah.
That's my sister you're talking about.
Yeah, aside from low Vitamin D levels
and some ligament wear and tear
in your C-spine,
you're the picture of health.
When we have bad outcomes,
we tend to blame the conditions,
but sometimes, it's just human error.
And we need to take the hit and move on.
You know, ironically, I'm getting that,
"You are the picture of health,"
is not the news you were hoping to hear.
You don't think there's a chance
that one of your team made an error?
More specifically,
um, that you made an error?
I've read about rare conditions...
a tiny bubble in an artery,
a blip that most doctors would miss.
I mean, if you were to find
something like that,
it would explain everything.
The world is falling apart, Tom,
and people act like, "Well,
somebody's gonna save us."
But I don't see that person.
And I sure as hell can't be that person
from a jail cell.
Just think of all the good you could do
with my resources, my cash.
You could research anything you wanted.
You'd be a legend.
And if anyone ever
caught you, you'd just say,
"Uh, oops, I misread his scan.
Human error."
Take another look at the scans,
just in case there's
something you missed.
Okay, Tom, my patient just died.
So if your billionaire needs a lollipop
or a foot massage,
please go to someone else.
If you had his kind of money,
what would you do with it?
Wh...
I don't know.
I'd triple the size of the clinic.
I'd make half our cases pro bono.
I could develop a research lab
and come up with our own medicine
so we could cut out
big pharma completely.
Public healthcare initiatives.
We could put a stop to food deserts.
We could get healthcare
and nutrition to the homeless.
The point is you'd do good, lots of it,
because this world
never runs out of people
who need help.
How do you decide which rules to break?
How do I decide?
We're surgeons. We live by
rules, precedents, protocols.
I mean, annoying as they are,
they reproduce success,
so, Meredith Grey,
award-winning rule breaker,
how do you decide which rules to break?
I-I just go with my gut.
And I hope that whatever I'm doing
improves this mess of a world
just a little bit.
We believe he's out of immediate danger,
but there's no question
he's gonna have a long recovery.
Does he have family nearby?
Yeah, um, I called.
They're on the way.
He'll also need additional surgeries
to treat the burns and close the wounds
on his arms and leg.
Right.
So...
England...
Um whoever takes care of Brad
needs to be prepared to spend
a lot of time in hospitals
for a while.
I can't... I can't do that. I can't stay.
You don't have to make
that decision right now.
No, but I already decided.
And... And he decided to come with me,
but I was always gonna go,
with or without him.
What does it mean if
he would leave his dream for me,
but I... I won't stay for him?
Wow.
That went from forever to over
in less than a day.
You called it, Jo.
All love sucks eventually.
No.
It doesn't suck.
I've spent all week trying to hate Alex,
and nothing works.
Because every time I get into my car,
I see this little trash bag
that he put in my side pocket
so that I had somewhere to put
my gum wrappers and tissues.
And I felt... I felt so loved
that he did that.
And now he put me in the trash
with the gum wrappers and the tissues.
I'm so mad.
I'm so hurt.
But I also know that he is the reason
that I will get up again.
I will climb out of the trash,
and I will rise.
I'll rise so high
that I'll make him a fool
for ever having left me,
and I'll do it
because of how well he loved me.
I am changed because of him.
He helped me feel worthy of love,
and even though it's over,
that is mine to keep.
Link, don't blow it with Amelia.
I didn't do anything.
She pushed me away. She ended it.
She didn't push you away.
She gave you a choice.
I never had that.
Why did Andrew DeLuca
tell me you'd handed over
your entire service?
Well, lately, um,
the smallest thing sets me off.
And when that happens...
...I-I see red.
I'm sorry.
I know you were just trying to be kind,
and I was wrong to
treat you that way.
That doesn't answer my question.
This isn't something I arrived at easily.
♪ Stars fade out
I've decided to step away from surgery.
Indefinitely.
I don't care how you arrived at it.
It's the wrong destination. No!
M-My mind is made up, Bailey.
I want to focus on
my PATH Pen and other innovations.
You can do that while you operate.
You know, a little while ago,
you asked how you could help me.
Well, this is how.
Support me on my next adventure.
This room reminds me of another time.
Another me.
It clutters my mind.
- I want to look ahead.
- Richard...
...this place needs you.
And that's how I want to step away.
At the top of my game.
We've both seen people
cling to their scalpels
longer than they should have.
♪ And we will, too
Mr. Ford.
Can I have a minute?
I took another look at your scans.
You have an aneurysm
in your anterior cerebral artery.
I, uh... I missed it, uh, initially
because it's... it's minor.
It's barely detectable.
There's no doubt that it could
influence your judgment.
It's the sort of thing that,
uh, could resolve on its own,
but you may need surgery down the road.
Um, when... when will we know?
Hmm.
Well, when we see the size of the check.
Thanks for waiting.
It was a hell of a day.
- Yeah.
- I had it all pictured.
I was gonna buy you coffee,
and then I was gonna
tell you about the houseboat,
and you were gonna be
really happy for me,
and it was gonna be so nice.
This doesn't feel right, Vic.
And I'm saying that to you
because I have been through
a, um... when...
when something's not right...
Mm-hmm. ...and you hold on too long.
You know, it's like
two people carrying one stone,
- never...
- Okay, stop talking
like a fortune cookie and just say it,
Jackson.
You don't want to see me anymore.
I am past the time in my life
where I can just go with things...
move in and out on a whim,
move in with a friend who
you tried to set up with my ex,
who has a kid now,
but, hey, it's all good.
Nah, it's not all good.
We're not teenagers.
Okay, but sleeping together
with no commitment...
that's good? Or friends with benefits?
What... that's... that's
state of the freakin' art, Jackson.
What an adult!
Vic.
- We moved really fast.
- Mm-hmm.
I'm just saying we could
take a little time
to get to know each other better,
be... be friends for a little while.
I have friends.
Bye, Jackson.
You too, huh?
God.
You know, on days like this,
Alex would be the one
who would make me laugh.
Dark, gallows humor,
but he made me laugh.
My first day of residency,
when the chief gave us that speech...
you know, "The seven years
you spend here"...
I stood in that room dreaming of being
the last one left of my class,
of being the kind of surgeon
that I have become,
of winning.
Then one by one, they dropped off
till Torres and I were
the only ones left.
Then she left.
At some point, it stops
feeling like victory
and just feels lonely.
I just don't know if I know
how to do this without him.
Or if I want to.
I'm not talking about Alex.
Richard Webber is
stepping down from surgery.
What? Why?
I don't... I don't want to talk about it.
Hey.
You're right.
You deserve a way better apology
than I managed this morning,
which wasn't even...
I'm sorry.
I'm... I'm sorry that I used you.
I'm sorry that I hurt you.
I mean, everything was fine.
I was happy.
Owen and I finally
found our way back to each other
after years of bad timing.
We finally worked.
You know, I-I really
don't think I'm in the mood
to hear how you and Hunt are working.
And then I felt... I...
I feel that he might
choose another woman again,
and I have been through...
with my whole body,
I'm remembering unimaginable loss
and unbearable pain, and you...
You make me laugh.
You make me feel good.
You make me feel like
my life isn't completely
spinning out of control.
And... And I-I hate that that hurts you
because you're such a good guy.
Stop. St... Stop saying that.
I'm really not a good guy, Teddy.
I don't think that's true.
It is true.
Hey, you look like
you could use one of these, huh?
Cheers.
So, Alex. Crazy, right?
Sorry about that.
But on the plus side,
we are both free now.
So we could, uh, make the best
out of a bad situation,
take away each other's pain.
I mean, come on, you're beautiful.
You're brilliant. And where is he?
Nowhere. He doesn't respect you.
Do you think Meredith
respects me? Please.
I think he's
a complete idiot if you ask...
You're not okay. You're not yourself.
Listen to people when they tell you that.
Get help before it's too late.
You would think weightlessness
is a good thing, but it's not.
Because people weren't meant to float.
Hey.
The kids are down,
and I thought you'd be starving,
so I roasted a chicken, and, yes,
I put a whole stick of butter
into the potatoes.
My favorite.
I know.
Owen, this is, um...
Wait, wait. Me first.
You didn't do anything wrong, okay?
All you did was tell me the truth.
I was shocked, and I froze.
But for our future, Teddy,
I need you to know you are not
a replacement for anyone.
And if you need to tell me anything,
my answer will be, "I love you."
I love you, and we're
gonna figure it out.
And that's my answer now.
That's my answer tomorrow.
That's my answer always.
And I'm sorry.
Without gravity, we lose blood volume,
bone density, muscle.
Without it, we're untethered.
- Oh, hey.
- What are you doing?
I wanted to write you a song,
but I can't write songs,
uh, as fast as I needed to come here
and, um, tell you...
I don't want to live without you.
You seemed pretty clear
about how you felt
if the baby isn't yours.
I was hurting. I was in pain.
But that doesn't mean I don't love you,
Amelia, because I do.
Doesn't mean I don't want you.
Because I do... I want you.
You're the only person
that makes me feel all the things
that I thought I was too smart
or too damaged to feel.
You make me want to write
love songs in the rain!
You make me want to be a parent.
And I don't... I don't
give a crap whose baby it is.
I don't want to feel
this sad and this lonely,
not if I don't have to.
I fell in love with you, Amelia,
and I fell in love with this baby,
and that is what matters to me.
So when you feel yourself
being pulled toward something,
it's not necessarily a bad thing.
So, you want to do this?
Even if he isn't yours?
I do.
I really needed to hear that.
Because I got the results.
- And he is yours.
- It may keep you centered.
But you still got to write me that song.
It may keep you safe.