Whoa! Oh, no, you
don't! Where are you go... bu...
W... Aah! Fine. Oh!
Okay. Don't want to brush
your teeth in there?
You can do it right
here. There. Brush.
Surgeons don't like
to take "no" for an answer.
Especially when it comes
to saving our patients.
Come on. Let's go. Let's go!
Time to brush the yucky away.
Oh, baby girl, work with
me. Mama's got a big day.
We needed to be in the
car 15 minutes ago.
♪ In the jungle
♪ The mighty jungle
♪ The lion sleeps tonight ♪
♪ In the jungle,
the quiet jungle ♪
♪ The lion sleeps tonight ♪
♪ Ooh-ee
If your heart
stops on our table,
we'll fight to start it again.
We'll begin chest compressions
to resume blood flow.
Okay. I know you said
simple, but hear me out.
Okay. Rock Hills Farm.
We could do the ceremony
overlooking the bay.
We can do the reception
in the mansion...
You hate it. You hate the bay.
You hate me looking for
wedding venues without you.
Actually, I love
all those things.
But isn't that place
booked years in advance?
I know. My cousin said
he could hook us up.
Second weekend in June,
but we have to decide fast.
Even though I know you
want to do your research
to make sure this one's the one.
I really, really
do!
All right. I'll,
uh, send you a link.
We have till next
Monday to tell him.
Aah! Oh, my God! Are you
kidding me? W-What happened?
There's no hot water!
I went for a run and I smell,
and there's no hot water.
Is that Trey?
Hey, Yasuda. I'll
call you later.
All right. Love you. Bye.
If that's not
enough, we'll shock you.
If we need to,
we'll do it again.
And again.
If that doesn't work,
we'll inject epinephrine
and start the process all over.
Okay. Leo's art class
switched to Fridays at 5:00.
But that's when the departments
are supposed to turn in
their funding requests.
So I'm just gonna
need... Here, baby.
I'm just gonna, um...
I'm just gonna need to do all
of that at the nurses' station,
naked with streamers.
Huh?
What is naked with streamers?
You know what? I
will take the kids.
You go save lives unsupervised.
Okay.♪ Na-na, na-na-na-na
The last thing we want
is to give up on you.
We're your doctors.
We're all in.
♪ Na-na, na-na-na
Did your roof finally cave in?
Ask Lucas.
I've already apologized twice,
and I'm gonna pay the gas bill.
Could you pay it yesterday?
We have to shower here,
like we don't spend
enough time here.
You know there's a
thing called AutoPay.
You know there's a thing
called not your business?
I wish there was a thing
called not your roommate.
Well, you could always
move back into the van.
I am not the one who
didn't pay the gas bill.
Bailey.
I made you another pie.
It's in the lounge...
If it hasn't been eaten.
You know I have an office.
Okay. I just know how
difficult the budget can be.
And I really appreciate
all your support.
Every doctor deserves
to be adequately trained
no matter where they live. Mm.
Oh, have you seen the article
about Addison on the PRT?
Doesn't she look great?
Mm.
Well, I mean, she kind of
looks a little annoyed.
No, not Addison. The PRT!
She's a... a mobile hero.
Wow. Have you seen
these comments below?
What? Are they
trolling the PRT?
I'm pretty sure they're trolling
the person behind the wheel.
Oh.
Hey!
Hi! Hey. Miss me?
O-Of course. Um,
where's my PRT?
Illinois.
I was running low on
cash, so I sold it.
Got a great deal.
I flew in.
The PRT's in hiding until
the press dies down.
How you doing? You holding up?
Is that a jab at my
wardrobe or my hairdo?
No. It's... It's about
the online trolls.
I know what it's
about. I'm fine.
I'm great. I'm here.
- Okay.
- Come on! Let's get to work.
All right. Well, this way.
All right.
So we'll see if we can change
that out just a little bit here.
Turn the beds for privacy
and... Oh. Here they are.
Hi! Good morning, everyone!
Ah. So, I'm
Dr. Miranda Bailey.
And I'm thrilled to
welcome you to Grey-Sloan
as our inaugural class
of out-of-state OB/GYN
reproductive healthcare
and advocacy fellows.
You have traveled
from Idaho, Arkansas,
Texas, even Tennessee
to be with us.
And I know you'd rather be
getting this clinical experience
in your own residency programs,
but we are honored to offer
this rotation in abortion care.
Because how else are you
going to learn, right?
You've all chosen OB/GYN
as your specialty,
and now your respective
states are restricting
how you practice that specialty.
But we are here to make sure you
get the education that you need.
I'm sorry. I'm
Dr. Addison Montgomery.
And I've been to
some of your states.
I've seen the desperation.
I've seen the pain,
seen the heartbreak.
I've seen lives lost.
So, anyway, who's
ready to get to work?
Come with me.
- This is Dr. Jo Wilson. - Woman: Hey.
How come we don't get to work
directly with Montgomery?
We did. We made sex-ed videos.
Yeah, that was before
she was a rock star.
Did you see the Chicago
Tribune story about her?
It's our hospital.
It's not right.
Well, neither is having
to go to another state
to get fully trained
in your specialty.
I'm just saying we
are five feet away.
We could join them.
Jessica Hall, 22.
Idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis.
Has been waiting for a
bilateral lung transplant
and is here today...
Uh...
Uh, sorry. Um...
Why is she here? Right.
Uh, she's here today for
a single lung transplant
from a directed donor.
Are you sure she shouldn't
stay on the list,
hold out for two lungs
rather than the one?
She's been on the list for
two years without matching,
and her condition is worsening.
A single lung will
help prevent her
from deteriorating
into heart failure.
You're just mad RJ's the match.
My boyfriend offers to save
my life over a Sunday dinner,
and she answers by asking
if he's finally
finished his degree.
We were both
feminist-studies majors.
Men only major in
that to meet women.
Go ahead.
Say it. I'm a...
You're sexist. Yeah. Mm-hmm.
And if he didn't major in
that, we would've never met,
and I wouldn't be
getting a lung today.
Are you? Where is he?
Who's late for surgery?
Surgeons, actually. It
happens all the time.
Uh, maybe not that much.
Well, I'm sure
he'll be here soon.
We're not gonna
start without him.
Well, obviously.
Adams, let us know
when he arrives.
When did we reorganize
our triage orders?
And who categorized
our patients this way?
Yeah. That might have been me.
I was running the ER last week,
and they weren't quite right
according to how we do it
upstairs in cardio, so...
Oh, did you check and
see if it was quite right
for us down here in
the trauma department?
Okay. Everyone, listen up.
Just in case there
is any confusion,
I am back as Chief of Trauma.
Do you want to know
what else is back?
The way I used to do things.
And I want to return to
our old triage protocols
and revert back to my
old filing systems.
Any questions,
comments, concerns?
Hey. Dr. Ndugu bought
us lunch on Fridays.
Will that continue?
Huh! Well...
I'd be happy to let Dr. Ndugu
continue to buy you
all lunch on Fridays.
Okay. Let's
get you into a bed.
And we can go over
your medical history.
Chief Bailey.
Not Chief anymore,
Marcus. Just Doctor.
Either way, we've got
some protesters outside.
They're trying to
block the entrance.
Oh. Well, there's
always a few.
They're usually peaceful.
Define "peaceful."
Millin. Did you page Ndugu?
I thought you were
back running trauma.
It's a blunt trauma to
the chest. So I should...
Page cardio, five minutes ago.
Get a chest tray on standby.
Let CT know that we may
need to jump the line.
And let the OR floor know that
we may have a new patient.
Right. Thank you.
Okay.
What do we got?
Ryan Jenkins, 24, MVC.
Blunt trauma to the
chest and abdomen.
Multiple rib fractures.
Patient's splinting,
and his oxygen saturation's
in the low 90s.
Just... I just... just...
It's okay. Save
your strength, okay?
Let's get him
inside. Let's go.
Okay. Marni Young?
You're in the right place.
And you're here for
a... medical abortion?
H-How many weeks are you?
Oh. 34 and already
very uncomfortable.
I don't want to think
about how 40 weeks feels.
Okay. Uh, well, you know,
medical abortions are done
in the first 10 weeks.
And even a surgical abortion is,
um, not gonna happen for you.
No. No, no, no.
Okay. It's for me.
I need the
abortion. Six weeks.
Oh, thank God. Oh.
Andra's my support system.
We're best friends.
Born two days apart.
Our mamas met in Lamaze class.
Now we're both pregnant,
except I don't want to be.
So here we are.
I brought snacks and
movies and card games.
So we're ready. Great.
All right. We're just gonna
do a quick physical exam.
And then we'll get
you your medication.
Any questions?
This clinic kills!
Is
that gonna go on all day?
This clinic kills!
Hey, Bailey.
Hey. When I call you eight times
in a row, it means pick up.
Sorry. Richard and I are trying
to fix a budget situation.
Well, help me with
my situation first.
- Here. - We have picketers.
- How many?
A lot, and it's my fault.
Uh, they're here for me.
I don't know how they
figured out where I am.
I had to change planes
twice. I didn't take the PRT.
My... My locations
are off on my phone.
I... It's not on you, Addie.
Look, um, security wants
us to close the clinic.
How long? We
recommend the day.
That... That...
That is dozens...
That's dozens of patients.
There's 100 people
out there right now.
Well, then call
in reinforcements
for crowd control!
What do you want
us to do, Altman?
Crisis protocols are
on the second shelf.
Stay open, call for backup,
and keep me posted.
Got it. Bu... Hey,
keep your ringer on.
Yeah.
Okay. You heard her.
Call for backup.
Adams still hasn't
uploaded the scans.
Uh, yeah.
Well, give it a minute.
Maybe the system's
being sluggish.
Or he is.
I'm sorry. I'm... tired.
It's okay.
How are you?
Uh... yeah.
I'm good. Good. Busy. Yeah.
I went to pick up
organs in San Francisco,
San Antonio, and Santa
Fe last week, so busy.
No plans for a trip to Boston?
Well, you don't really
plan to pick up organs.
- You know what I mean.
- Yes, I do.
- Have you spoken at all?
- Um, I get a text message
about her getting lost
in the streets of Boston
about, uh... about once a week.
Mm. Those are very
complicated streets.
Yes.
She's overwhelmed. Yeah.
If it helps at all, I get
all my updates from Zola.
I told her I loved her, and
she pretended not to hear me.
She's complicated.
Yeah.
You make her happy.
Don't give up.
Okay. So I-I dropped off,
uh, Jessica's lab work
and finished her
admission orders.
And the scans?
I-I just uploaded them.
Sorry. I was... I was
dealing with a house thing.
In a few hours, Jessica's gonna
be open on an operating table
with her vital
organs in our hands.
You cannot get distracted
with house things.
Or anything. I-I know.
I-I'm sorry.
Uh, the scans are in.
Let's, uh... Let's
take a look, shall we?
I'm seeing multiple
displaced rib fractures
and a massive hemothorax
on the right side.
Once I place the chest
tube, we'll rush him up to CT.
Right. Agree.
And then to the OR, depending
on his chest tube output.
He has a bad lung contusion. I'm not
sure how long he'll remain stable.
Ryan Jenkins. Our... Our
patient's already in the system.
What? Like he's
been here before?
Like he's supposed
to be here today.
Directed lung donor, OR 3.
Recipient's Jessica Hall.
That's Maggie's patient.
She's been waiting on a
transplant for almost two years.
Jess... Jess...
Just take... take
my... My lung.
- Take... Just take...
- He's hemorrhaging!
Take it.
O2's dropped to 70s. Damn it.
- Let's get an intubation tray.
- Hang two units of blood.
As soon as he's tubed, we're
heading straight to the OR.
Here's the blood.
Are you sure it's him?
Can I... Can I see him?
Ryan had his driver's
license on him...
RJ. He goes by RJ.
Either way, it's him.
Dr. Hunt, our trauma surgeon,
is prepping him for surgery now.
He needs surgery?
What kind of surgery?
RJ suffered some
injuries to his chest,
and he's lost a significant
amount of blood.
Oh, my God.
His chest... Is it his h-heart?
It's his lungs.
- How fast was he driving?
- Are you serious?
Are you really asking
that question right now?
Okay.
Jessica, Jessica.
I know this is a lot to take in.
But due to the severity
of RJ's injuries,
he's not going to be able
to donate a lung today.
Or possibly ever.
I don't... I don't
care about that.
Jessica. Please get out.
I can't... I can't
listen to you right now.
Please get out, Mom.
And please... please save him.
- Do whatever it takes.
- I'll do everything I can.
Let's, um... Let's
give her a minute.
A vaginal ultrasound
helps determine
how far along the pregnancy is.
You are counseling the
patient, not persuading, okay?
Offer the facts,
answer questions,
give options, okay?
That's the mifepristone.
It'll block your
body's own progesterone
to stop the pregnancy
from growing.
After you take that,
we'll start you on
the misoprostol.
If you're not sure, you can take
some time and think about it.
I'm sure. I just
don't like pills.
Okay.
I'm two years older than
my mom was when she had me.
She was married, they
lived in a townhome,
and when I look back at pictures,
she seems like a grown-up.
But I'm not there yet.
I'm still working through the
lasting damage she did to me.
So maybe one day I will be
mentally ready to take that on.
But right now, I can't.
♪ Do you think that
you're the only one? ♪
I can't be a mother.
But I can be an aunt.
I can and will be the most
incredible aunt to your baby.
Do you want me to
play you some music?
I made you a playlist.
For my abortion?
You made me one for
when I give birth.
♪ To find your way back home
So different.
Okay. Cards it is.
No. No, no, no, no.
I'm trying to... I'm trying
to pay, not stop service.
H-Hello?
Oh. Y-Yeah... Yeah.
Can I... Can I...
Can I just give you my
account number or...
Adams.
Uh, how long have you
been standing there?
Long enough that you
should've hung up the phone.
Come up with a plan for how you
would adjust Jessica's treatment
and meds in order to
prevent heart failure.
She'll need discharge paperwork
since she's not getting
a transplant today.
Do you need to be
writing this down?
Uh, sure. Uh...
She will remain
on the UNOS list,
but we'll have to send over
her pre-op labs and scans
in order to make sure that
her status hasn't changed.
Uh, yeah. Got it.
Everything all right?
Uh, fine. Fine.
I'm just working with
Marsh and Pierce today,
and, uh, she's on my case.
Uh, p-pass code... Do you...
Do you know the pass code
to the gas-company
account for the house?
Uh, Meredith and Maggie
handle the utilities.
Did you ask Maggie?
Could you? 'Cause she's already
kind of annoyed with me.
No, because then I would have
to be annoyed with you, too.
Okay. Fine.
Dr. Cameron
to the step-down unit.
Dr. Cameron to the
step-down unit.
All this scrubbing is
drying out my hands.
At least the water's warm.
Well, you know, my place
isn't too far from the house.
You can come use all
the hot water you want.
My roommate's pretty cool. You
won't want to have sex with her.
What?
Adams.
Is that what he's
telling people?
We didn't sleep together.
We just... kissed maybe twice.
Wow. Uh, I was bluffing.
But now that we're
here, was it good?
Good kissing? I'm engaged.
Right, right. All right.
Trey is a good
guy. He is stable.
He's a grown-up who
pays his bills on time.
And he makes me happy.
Kiss was that good, huh?
Bed 5 is asking for a
birth-control implant.
I'm gonna show Yasuda
how to do that. Mm-hmm.
And Kwan is finishing
an STD test in bed 3,
so that'll be opened up soon.
Okay. - Let me know if you need help.
- Okay.
And I want to let you know how
excellent these trainees are.
They should be.
They were picked from
more than 100 applicants.
You know, one of them wrote
that the one silver lining
of not being able to get
this training at home
is being able to learn from
the great Addison Montgomery.
Oh. Well, that's very kind.
No. It's true. You know it is.
You know, we could run
trainings... every month
if you want to come back.
I don't know.
No. Okay.
I know that you're
busy with the clinic
and... and the travel
from Illinois to L.A.
must be just, you know, hard.
And of... of course, um,
visiting your family
takes priority.
But, you know, we'd
love to have you
if you
could squeeze us in.
Oh, my God!
- Oh, my God.
- Hey. Everybody get down.
Down, down.
Okay. You're bleeding.
He's bleed... Oh, my God!
No one goes in or out of the
clinic... not till I have
enough security to
safely evacuate.
Okay. Thanks, Bailey.
A brick was thrown through
the window of the clinic?
With "Montgomery
murders" written on it.
- It hit Kwan in the head.
- How bad is it?
Have you read these manuals?
- Cover to cover.
- You know what?
If I had to read giant manuals
for every crisis in Iraq,
I wouldn't have
made it out of Iraq.
Altman, you're supposed to read
them when you're not in a crisis.
- When is that exactly?
- Is Kwan okay?
He's bleeding, but he
seems to be doing okay.
What do the manuals say
about a large-scale
protest at the clinic?
Nothing.
They were written before
Bailey took over the clinic
and before the Supreme Court
ruled on Dobbs. Perfect.
Where are you going?
To make sure that no more bricks
are thrown at this hospital.
You're doing it wrong.
Y-You should really
hold your fingers
about 12 inches
away from my face.
Just follow the stupid finger.
Any dizziness? Changes
in your vision?
I'm fine.
Just put the Steri-Strip on
so we can get back to work.
I am so, so sorry.
Pretty sure you didn't
throw the brick.
I kind of did.
I-I posted this this
morning on the way here.
I assumed it was
okay. I'm in Seattle.
People believe in
reproductive rights.
I never thought...
People would use it as a road
map to Addison Montgomery?
They threw a brick at us.
What do you think
they'll throw next?
- Kwan.
- I'm sorry.
I feel awful.
I'm gonna resign
from my position.
I mean, they're gonna...
They're gonna fire me
once they find out
about the post anyway.
Just the idea that I could've
endangered the one person
that's given me... any hope
in these last few weeks
makes me sick.
But for the first
time in months,
today I woke up proud, because
I was joining the fight.
We shouldn't have
to hide who we are
in order to practice medicine.
So don't resign.
If you do, that
means one less doctor
has made it their
mission to help.
And then they win.
Hilum's intact.
Lung's shredded.
Uh, they want
everyone in the hospital
to stay away from the clinic.
The ongoing protests
have become violent.
You need to
get back downstairs?
I will as soon as I figure out
where this blood's coming from.
Are you gonna do a
lower lobe resection?
If we do that, then
RJ can't be a donor.
But that's not the
priority. He's bleeding out.
All right. Okay. What...
What if I use a hilar clamp
to temporarily stop the bleeding
and do a wedge resection?
It will preserve
more lung tissue
and could allow him to donate
the other lung at a later time.
If you shut off the
circulation from one lung,
- won't his pressure tank?
- Only for a few minutes.
A few minutes could
cost him his life.
Or I could repair
the lung by then.
Fine. We got
to move fast, okay?
Griffith, get
ready with suction.
And, Millin, take
over retraction, okay?
All right. Clamp.
Do you want me to do it?
No. I got it.
All right. Stapler
and lap pads.
Patients are getting restless.
The woman in bed 4 threw
a granola bar back at me,
and I found a trainee
crying in the bathroom.
She's fine, but she's scared.
I think everyone is.
Oh.
Um, team meeting... right now.
Okay. Guys, come. Come, come.
Everybody here? Okay.
Um, so, this clinic is named
for my mom, Elena Bailey,
because...
When I was, uh, 7, I went with
my mom to the grocery store,
and, uh, we got in line
behind a young woman
and her fussy baby.
Um, for whatever reason,
the woman didn't have enough
money to pay her bill,
so my mom did.
And later, I asked my
mom, "Do you know her?"
And she said, "I know her enough
to know that she's struggling.
And when we can help someone
else going through a tough time,
we should."
These are tough times.
We are struggling as doctors,
as advocates for women's health
and reproductive freedom.
We need to help
each other, right?
We need to lift each other up.
That's how we get through.
Dr. Montgomery has been
on the front line, right?
Traveling all over the country.
Do you have any advice
for our young doctors?
Excuse me? Someone?
A doctor maybe?
Yeah. I think her
water just broke.
Oh. Um, you heard her.
Let's go!
Okay.
Oh, are those, uh,
Jessica's discharge papers?
Crap. I-I still
need to print them.
Sorry.
That's okay.
Meredith left.
I'm aware.
And now I don't know
what I'm even doing here.
Hm.
I just... I keep screwing up.
With patients,
with... with papers.
And I-I can't even
pay my gas bill,
and, um...
I-I-I want to believe that
I'm here on my own merit,
but I keep wondering if I'm
just here because of her
and not because
I'm supposed to be.
Right.
Okay. So... we were supposed
to do a-a directed
donation today.
Our patient fasted.
Our donor fasted.
We were prepped and ready.
It was a transplant
surgeon's dream scenario.
And then RJ gets hit by a car.
And in a brutal coincidence,
that accident injures
the very organ we need.
Yeah. Is this story supposed
to be about me somehow?
I'm saying... the
things you worry about
are almost never the things
that really go wrong.
And the things
that do go wrong...
you couldn't have dreamt up.
Your aunt did not accept
you to this program
out of sentimentality.
She's too good for
that, and so are you.
Get Jessica her
discharge papers, okay?
Yeah.
He...
I'm
sorry. I just...
needed a breath, and I, uh...
and I can't go outside, so...
Oh.
Um, you know, there's this woman
that stands outside the
clinic every Tuesday
with a sign that says,
"Please don't do this."
She doesn't, you know, yell
or try to get in the way.
Even her sign's polite.
And it's still upsetting.
I can't even imagine doing
what you're doing out there.
I got a bulletproof vest.
A what? Yeah.
Yeah. Okay.
An old O.B. friend of mine
in Texas, uh, suggested it.
I thought she was overreacting.
Then I found out her usual
advice is to carry a gun
or hire a bodyguard with a gun.
Clinics are being set on fire.
I know.
You know, staff are having
acid thrown in their face
on their way to work.
With the PRT,
they... they just...
They broke one of the windows.
Don't worry. I
had it replaced.
I'm not worried
about the window.
They doxxed me.
All of my information
is online...
My home address, my
cellphone number.
I got over 500
calls in one night.
Then they broke into our garage
and graffitied Jake's car.
So now he and Henry are
staying at his sister's,
so, you know, mom of the year.
That sounds awful,
and I am so sorry
that I suggested that
you go out there...
No, no. Don't you...
Don't be sorry.
I wouldn't have done
anything differently.
I'm not gonna...
I'm not gonna
quit. I can't quit.
I mean, patients need
this care, you know?
But I-I put my family
in danger. I put...
Your clinic is in danger.
You are in danger because of me.
You... And how am I gonna
go tell these new OBs
that they're gonna
be okay when I'm not?
I am exhausted.
I am terrified.
I'm not okay. Oh, honey.
Oh.
Okay,
okay, okay. Okay.
Come on. It's okay. It's okay.
It's okay.
Oh.
We're setting up an incident
command post with PD now. North parking lot.
- Copy that. Thanks, Marcus.
- Have you heard from the clinic? Jo's not responding to texts.
You need somebody
to go over there?
That is exactly what I do
not need someone to do.
Well, have you considered - closing to trauma?
- Not yet.
I really think you should...
The media will probably
want a statement.
Do you want me to work on one?
Dr. Altman, there's a situation...
All right. Everybody stop!
I need to be able to think,
which is impossible to do
when everyone is coming
at me at the same time.
So can you please
quiet your voices
so I can hear the
one in my head?
Okay. Whatever helps.
What is going on?
Did you want the voice in
your head to answer or...
Talk, Schmitt.
They're clinic patients,
but the protesters wouldn't
let them in, so they came here.
They have appointments
for their annual Pap
smears, glucose tests,
cervical-cancer
screenings, STD panels.
Do I just... send them home?
No.
Do you want to help?
All right. How we doing?
She's fully dilated.
Andra, it's time to push.
Oh, my God. We're doing this.
No, no, no, we're not.
We're not doing this.
- Andra, the baby's coming.
- Well, tell her no!
This is not how this
is supposed to happen.
I don't have my epidural.
I don't have my husband.
I don't have Dr. Kiu.
Her OB. It's okay.
You have like... 20
other doctors here.
And I'm here.
But I paid
for the upgraded delivery room,
with the soft lighting
and the comfy chair!
And I'm supposed to
have my warm blanket
that my mom sent from Maine.
And... And... And what
about the delivery playlist?
My baby's supposed to be
born to sounds of joy.
Instead I have
this starchy sheet
and a chorus of protesters,
and all I can hear is
"Baby killer. Baby killer."
So please,
do not make me push.
♪ In the jungle,
the mighty jungle ♪
♪ The lion sleeps tonight
♪ In the jungle
♪ The quiet jungle, the
lion sleeps tonight ♪
♪ Ah-weem-ah-weh,
ah-weem-ah-weh ♪
ah-weem-ah-weh ♪ Eee
♪ Ah-weem-ah-weh,
ah-weem-ah-weh ♪ Eee-ee-ee-ee-ee
♪ Ah-weem-ah-weh, ah-weem-ah-weh
♪ Ah-weem-ah-weem-ah-weh
In the village.
♪ In the village, the
peaceful village ♪
♪ The lion sleeps tonight
Near the village.
♪ Near the village,
the peaceful village ♪
♪ The lion sleeps tonight
♪ Ah-weem-ah-weh,
ah-weem-ah-weh ♪ Eee
♪ Eee-ee-ee-ee-ee ♪
Ah-weem-ah-weh, ah-weem-ah-weh ♪
♪ Eee-um-um-ah-weh ♪
Yes.
Yes, yes, yes, yes.
Andra, are you ready to push?
Good. Push.
Let's push.
All right. Reload stapler.
Vitals are dropping.
BP's in the 80s.
Okay. Keep suctioning.
Systolic's in the 70s.
We gotta move. All right.
There are tears everywhere.
Overload him with fluids.
We have to work faster.
Saying that over and over
won't make it happen.
2-0 prolene.
What are you doing?
Hold my hand.
You're gonna want
to remember this!
How could I forget...
Aah! Oh!
Good.
Okay, Andra.
- Stop pushing for a moment. - Okay.
What?
Head's bobbing.
Okay. You... You switch. You
and Bailey apply pressure.
May I? Sure.
Andra, I'm Dr. Montgomery.
Do you know - what you're having?
- A girl.
Good. She's about to
welcomed by about 100 women.
And you. Get more ice chips.
Okay. Andra, your baby's
shoulder is stuck.
But Dr. DeLuca and Dr. Wilson
are going to bring your
knees back into your chest,
and Dr. Bailey's going to
apply pressure to your abdomen,
and I'm gonna take her out.
You promise? I promise.
All right. We ready?
You ever hear the joke
about how many doctors it
takes to deliver a baby?
All right. Ready? Push.
Okay. Let's see.
Oh, let's go this way.
♪ Sometimes your life feels
like a broken roller coaster ♪
140 over 82. Very good.
♪ A thousand useless
moving parts ♪
♪ Sometimes you
spend your nights ♪
♪ Too scared of getting closer
♪ Hiding out in the
back seat of your car ♪
All right. I've got your
discharge paperwork.
Can I stay a little longer?
I want to be here when
RJ wakes up from surgery.
I want to see him.
♪ The clouds are in your head
Systolic's in the 60s.
He's about to code.
All right. Done!
Removing the clamp.
Pressure is coming back up.
Okay, Millin. What is the next
step after this clamp's removed?
We ventilate the lung, and then
we wait to see if it inflates.
- And if it doesn't, Griffith?
- Means there's still a leak,
which you'll have to repair
and then continue to monitor
the chest tube for
air leaks post-op.
- Good.
- All right. It's off.
You can ventilate.
♪ Hold on
♪ 'Cause somebody loves you
♪ You know trouble's
always gonna be there ♪
♪ Don't let it bring you
to your knees, yeah ♪
♪ Look up
♪ Hold on Okay.
We're almost there.
Andra, I need one more push.
I don't think I can
do this anymore.
You can. I know you can.
Okay. Ready?
Push.
Yes!
There she is!
There!
Ready to see your baby?
She's perfect.
There you go.
♪ Look up
Hi, baby.
♪ There's flowers in your hair
♪ Hold on
♪ 'Cause somebody loves you
♪ You know trouble's
always gonna be there ♪
♪ Don't let it bring you
to your knees ♪[ Laughs ]
Hey. Is it okay if she...
Of course.
♪ All these changes
feel like death ♪
Can... Can I touch him?
Absolutely.
♪ Yet my heart...
Dr. Ndugu was able
to stop the bleeding
and only had to remove
minimal lung tissue.
We'll see how he recovers,
but RJ may still be
able to be a donor.
I don't care about that.
He just needs to be okay.
♪ I can see my breath
You remember our first kiss?
Under that street lamp on 24th?
We were arguing over
some essay, and...
I just leaned in
and went for it.
And when you kissed me back...
no one had ever kissed
me like that before.
You changed my
life in an instant.
♪ Metamorphosis
♪ Give it a little more time
♪ A little more time
♪ My wet wings, they
will dry Thank you.
Teddy.
Hi.
The clinic overflow
setup looks great.
Thank you. Oh, you're welcome.
I'm just glad we didn't have
to turn those patients away.
Mm. Today was a tough day.
I mean, people had
questions and opinions.
They threw them at you.
But you never lost sight of
the most important thing...
Keeping everyone safe.
You did well, Altman.
♪ ...in the faith
of letting go ♪
Thank you.
You were, uh, an excellent
choice for chief.
Are you complimenting
yourself now, sir?
I believe I am.
♪ Here I go
♪ Oh, pain and growth,
you feed my soul ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh
Seattle PD's almost finished
dispersing the crowd.
We should be able to exit
folks out the back soon.
Oh! Music to my
ears!
Oh. Um, get Kwan and Yasuda
to help you organize people.
Last thing we need is a
stampede out the door.
We heard.
Not that we were eavesdropping.
Come on.♪ Give it
a little more time
♪ A little more time
I made you a Montgomery Mix...
Orange, cranberry,
and apple juice...
To keep your blood sugar up.
I made one for you, too.
- Thank you.
- How are you feeling?
A little crampy but okay.
How about you?
Relieved. Tired.
Maybe a little delirious.
It was the hardest thing
I've ever done in my life.
But was it ever worth it.
♪ Give it a little more time
♪ A little more time
♪ I was born for this
Adams.
We should start her back
on a combination therapy
with a tyrosine kinase inhibitor
and an antifibrotic agent.
I confirmed she's been
vaccinated against influenza
and pneumococcal infection.
And I arranged consults for
physical therapy and G.I...
For Jessica.
I mean, this could buy her
time for a transplant, right?
Yes. That is exactly right.
Yeah.
I wish I had just said
all that to Pierce.
Yeah.
You know, it took me four
times to get through the MCATs
and get into med
school... Four times.
Seriously? Yes.
I didn't want to sit
through the test.
The standardized questions
felt like an absurd way
to measure one's ability
to take care of people.
I-I would sit there, I
would fixate on that,
and at some point... wshh!
I'd get up, and I'd... I'd go.
But it worked out, right?
It worked out only because
someone helped me figure it out.
Come here. Sit down.
Come on. Take this.
I'm gonna show you how
to present to Pierce
in a way - that she needs to hear it.
- Okay.
Ignore everything else around
you except for the case.
Everything. Fewer
words, fewer details.
Now, present me the
patient, name first.
You're gonna do it twice with
the chart and once from memory.
All right. Let's go.
Uh, Jessica Hall, 22.
When it
comes to saving lives,
surgeons won't go
down without a fight.
Many of us refuse to give up
easily in our own lives, too.
Hey. Done early? Hey.
No. I'm taking a break
between surgeries.
I'm about to hit the cafeteria.
I haven't eaten
since this morning.
Hey, what do you think
about a doughnut bar
instead of a wedding cake?
Aw, you hate it.
Okay. I'll stop.
No, no. I just...
I think we should get
married before June.
Uh, like April, May?
Or like next month.
Oh. Wow. Okay.
I want to do it while my
grandma can still come.
We could do it in my
grandma's backyard.
It's not Rock Hills Farm, but
I think it'd mean a lot to her.
And to me.
You hate me.
No.
I love you.
And I'll get to be your
husband that much sooner.
And it will be better
than a bougie mansion,
'cause it will be home. And
we need to find a great...
I'll stop. No. Go ahead.
We can be
stubborn and competitive.
We don't like to lose.
- Protesters still out there?
- Uh, just a few.
PD arrested some and
pushed the rest back, so...
All right.
Um, well, after this consult,
I'll run back up
there and check on RJ.
That's was an amazing
save today, Ndugu.
I don't know if you
were still considering
the vascular fellowship,
but patients would
suffer if you went back
to being a student in the OR.
♪ So I'm letting go
Okay. Got it.
Great.
Hey. Hey.
Oh, God. It's been a day.
Well... it suits you.
♪ I am a wave
Thanks.
♪ I'mma keep on rollin'
♪ Through all the change Okay.
But we're also human
and can get discouraged.
When that happens,
we have to look for
inspiration around us...
Okay.
You got this, okay?
Just tell her the truth.
Dr. Montgomery? I just
wanted to say thank you.
My... My partner wanted
to do a babymoon,
but I really wanted to do
this, and I'm glad that I did.
How far along are you? 28 weeks.
But there's something you
should know... Oh! Um...
Oh. Here. Let me
help get this.
There's something that you
should know about today.
Earlier... Wait. What?
I posted that you were here...
Get out of the way!
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
♪ Hey, hey, hey, hey
Oh, my God.♪ Hey, hey, hey, hey
♪ Hey, hey, hey,
hey G-Get gurneys!
Stay back!
I need backup!
Addison, don't move.
Don't move. Don't move.
♪ Hey, hey, hey, hey
Stay back! Stay back!
Addison?
And find the strength
to keep going.
♪ Mm, mm
♪ I am a wave